When researchers
studied the way surgeons
make decisions in the OR,
they found newer surgeons
tend to rely on the standard
operating procedures
they learned in school.
I don't like this one.
You haven't even seen
it. Keep an open mind.
I did that in New York
and New Hampshire.
Brookline STEAM
has one of the best
science programs in the country.
And, you know,
Harvard Medical School
is just right down the street.
I want to stay in Seattle.
It was so much better there.
You said the kids at
SEA-TAC Science were snobby.
It wasn't that bad.
♪ I'm tryna make you move
Are you feeling worried?
Do you need to take
some deep breaths?
No, I just want to go home.
This isn't a punishment.
You are an extremely
gifted child.
You are going to do
great in a school
where other kids are
as gifted as you.
And we can check out
the aquarium after.
Zola, we're in Boston.
You're signed up to shadow.
Let's just check it out
so you can make an
informed decision.
To make sure I hate it.
If you hate it, you never
have to come back here again.
Okay?
Let's go.
♪ Make you move
It makes sense.
Newer surgeons have limited
experience to fall back on.
But seasoned surgeons
are more intuitive.
Uh-huh.
They mine from years of practice
to make quick and
effective decisions.
What about in your brown jacket?
Go look.
And put your dad on.
Instead of looking for
his lucky baseball card,
Henry could be using this time
to actually study
for his math test.
Hey.
Oh, good. Crisis averted.
Okay, babe, I'll
see you tomorrow.
I love you. Bye.
Sorry about that.
I'm all too familiar
with the "Mom, I can't
find it" emergencies.
Was it in the brown jacket?
Of course it was in
the brown jacket.
We know where everything is.
It's our mom superpower.
I mean, you'd think they'd be
more impressed that we're doctors.
Please. Tuck
couldn't care less.
But Cynthia is
thrilled we're coming.
Yeah, how do you know
her, again, med school?
Oh, no, college. She was
my first-year roommate.
Grew up in Chicago.
I thought she was
very cosmopolitan.
How'd she wind up running
a clinic in Pullman?
Uh, her husband got a job
teaching music at
the university.
Oh. She likes it?
Well, Pullman,
Washington, is no Chicago,
but she loves
running the clinic.
And she loves having
a couple of doctors
coming to volunteer even more.
Patients from Idaho have
been flooding the place
ever since the state
restricted abortion.
Okay, should be coming up here.
The more experience we
have, the less likely we are
to be thrown when we
encounter complications.
We can shift gears more
easily when it's needed.
Oh, come on!
Whoa.
Babies don't choose abortion!
You're stopping a beating heart!
Hey, you're terminating
lives, and you know it.
Just keep moving.
You're killing babies.
You're a baby killer
'cause abortion is murder!
And you took an
oath to do no harm!
You took an oath!
Hey. How was the bus?
Fine, but I took
it for a reason.
I know. I can't
say good morning?
You did, right
after you woke me up
to make lunches for
Ellis and Bailey.
Hey, I really appreciate you
helping out while Meredith is out.
I worked three
16-hour days in a row.
I'd just fallen asleep.
C-Can we not talk
about this here?
Oh, I have an epidural hematoma.
Can you take him to daycare?
No, I have rounds.
I have an emergency.
I would ask any trusted
intern to do this,
and I assure you, they
would be more than happy
to help the chief of neuro.
I will let them know
that you're coming.
Okay, bye, baby.
Uh...
Uh, where's... So,
where's daycare?
Okay.
Oh, it's so good to see you.
So, how long has this
clinic been open?
45 years.
Last year, we provided
more than 2,000 patients
with birth control,
prenatal care,
abortion care, STD testing,
cancer screening, pizza parties.
Hm?
Come on. Look outside, guys.
Let me at least crack a joke.
Well, it seems like
there's plenty of demand.
Yeah, we added a construction
trailer when Roe was overturned,
and I moved our staff
offices and break room
so we could convert more
space for these exam rooms.
Smart. Okay.
Cynthia also somehow
fit a full-size couch
in our dorm room,
and a mini fridge.
Yeah, well, I can
figure out space,
but without volunteers like you,
coming from Seattle and
Spokane, I'd be sunk.
Alright. Put us to work.
Okay, these are the patients
who are ready to be seen.
These are the patients
who have not been seen.
It's a low-tech operation,
but somehow it
gets the job done.
Okay. Okay.
Have fun!
If that couch could
talk... Hey, hey.
Is this where the family
reunion is happening?
And by "family," I
mean my #workfamily.
You want a photo? Let's
get one. I don't, actually.
Good morning, Tom. I
see you haven't changed.
Well, you might want to stop by
ophthalmology, seventh floor,
east wing, because I've
toned the glutes and the abs.
Wow. No, Bostonians
are noticing.
I haven't heard that.
Catherine, you look
radiant as ever.
Shall we?
Where are you two going?
We got a little project.
You want to elaborate?
Oh, it's not your business.
Well, I run the foundation,
so actually it is.
I'll loop you in when
the time is right.
Come on.
Should I text you to
tell you I'm here?
Oh! Hey.
Hi. Hey. What's going on?
Tell me everything.
Can we go up to your office
so that I can have my
nervous breakdown in private?
Okay, Jessica, uh, do you
have enough prenatal vitamins?
They're still free.
I could use more. Okay.
Okay, come back in
two weeks, yeah?
Um, great.
I made all my
appointments weeks ago.
It's too hard to get
in here otherwise.
Alright, take good care.
I loved my "measure and
listen" appointments
when I was pregnant with Tuck.
My favorite part
about being an OB.
Mm-hmm. So, what
have you had so far?
Um, I did consults
with six women
who wanted medication abortions.
I gave pills to five.
Did someone need a D&C?
They changed their mind.
We are making progress. Mm.
Progress is neither
swift nor easy.
Marie Curie.
First woman to win
the Nobel Prize.
Think she knew what she
was talking about. Mm.
Dad-o.
Uh, yeah, yeah, yeah, I got
him, I got him, I got him.
He's in there somewhere.
Dad-o. Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, I'm looking for him,
I'm looking for him.
Ah, here's Dad-o, here's Dad-o.
Aw, damn it.
C-Crap.
I mean, u-uh... Uh,
whatever, whatever.
Sorry.
You getting out?
No. You?
Going down.
Wow. He's Lincoln's.
And Shepherd's.
We know what's up.
I'm just dropping
him off at daycare.
Shepherd had an emergency
and needed a favor.
Wonder what other kinds
of favors he does for her.
What's that?
You going to the
lunch-and-learn today?
Dad-o.
Oh, my God, he just
called you Dad.
No, no, no.
It's h-his dino.
He... He... He
can't say "dino."
Alright. Isn't the
daycare two floors up?
Uh, stairs are good exercise.
I miss paper.
Same.
Except, at least with e-records,
I can read my own notes.
I've got a 39-year-old with a
cesarean-scar ectopic pregnancy.
C-section scar?
Yes, the fetus can attach to
the scar on the uterine wall.
Her OB found it on an
ultrasound this morning.
He wouldn't remove
it. They're in Idaho.
It's a life-threatening case,
so there should be an exception.
There's cardiac activity. He
didn't want to take the risk.
The law is confusing.
Nobody wants to be the first
one to lose their license
or be charged with a felony.
Alright. I'll see
her. Which room?
Across the border in Moscow.
She called from the
OB's parking lot.
Also, her car won't start.
You wanted to help.
I'll get the keys.
What do you mean
"panic attacks"?
You know, she gets
dizzy, her body shakes,
she has trouble breathing.
How often is this happening?
Often enough.
I mean, her grades are slipping.
She can't relate to her friends.
Because she's scared
of Alzheimer's?
I-I mean, she's very bright,
and she's under-stimulated
at school, and her mind
goes in 17 different
directions at one time.
And she's very aware that Ellis
died of early-onset Alzheimer's.
And so of course
her mind goes there.
She's afraid that I will get
it, that Maggie will get it.
Alright. So, how
you handling it all?
Therapy or...
We go to therapy once a week.
But it's not enough.
I mean, she has severe anxiety,
and I completely missed it.
She was always my
cheerful child.
I never had to worry about her.
Right. So you didn't.
I just want to help her.
I just want to comfort her.
I don't know what to
do. I am so exhausted.
I stay up every
night, just reading
pages and pages and pages
about Alzheimer's, thinking,
"Oh, if I cure Alzheimer's,
I can help Zola."
Ridiculous.
Makes absolutely no sense.
It's ridiculous, I know, but
I just feel powerless and...
I hate that feeling.
What if it wasn't ridiculous?
What?
What if you try to
cure Alzheimer's?
Henry.
Baseball emoji, smiley
face, sunflower.
I'm going to interpret
that as affection.
Wait 'til he's a teenager
and you just get letters...
B-R-B... Mm.
I-D-K, and the enigmatic K-K.
Why the two K's?
Tuck claims it's
more respectful.
But, you know, what do I know?
I'm just his chauffeur.
Speaking of which, I-I
can take over driving.
I like to drive.
It's 20 minutes to Moscow.
Never thought I'd have to
drive across state lines
to pick up a patient.
Hm. Feels like
we're on the lam.
The medical Thelma and Louise.
Didn't they drive off a cliff?
Bonnie and Clyde.
Shot to death.
Bailey and Addison?
American heroes.
Is it okay if Kyle
picks her up after five?
I really appreciate it.
No, no, no, no.
I'll be fine.
Yeah. You're doing plenty.
Oh, uh, they're here.
I gotta go. Susan?
Dr. Montgomery?
Yes. That's me.
Thanks so much for the ride.
I didn't realize the clinic was
such a full-service operation.
Well, Dr. Bailey
is also a surgeon.
Yeah, this is just
our side hustle.
Water? Ah, yes. Thank you.
Seat belts.
Are you sure no one needs
an assist in the O.R.?
Or... pit?
The square knot is the
foundation for all knots.
15 minutes a day is a
good investment in time.
Damn it. Too loose. Ahhhh.
Yeah, your guy's still bleeding.
Oh, I hope that's not his face.
Or his liver. Or his heart.
9-1-1.
Oh, God forbid it's someone who
needs stitches. Something good?
I-I don't know yet. The pit?
Uh, yeah, something like that.
You sure your son hasn't
got us figured out?
Did he seem suspicious of
you? How could he not be?
I'm a Greek sculptor's
dream, and you're only human.
Oh, please. No.
Sneaking around
with the boss's mom
is not gonna help my
performance review.
This is between you and me.
Don't let Jackson get
all up in your head.
Oh, so, what you're saying is
we're gonna have to kill him.
Be serious, Tom.
Okay, fine. I'll
kill him myself.
But you... you got to
deal with your husband.
Tom, could you just please
tell me about my scans?
It's not the news we wanted.
So, the tumor is bigger?
Two millimeters.
Two millimeters?
That's nothing.
It's not "nothing."
It's growing.
How you feeling? The same.
Mostly well. Occasional pain.
Two millimeters isn't
worth this conversation.
Catherine, two months
ago, we did a scan
and we noted your
tumor had grown.
And?
And you said if it grew further,
you'd consider more treatment.
I know what I
said. And it grew.
Two millimeters.
Your son thinks you're
still in remission.
It's two millimeters!
It's not remission.
You need more treatment.
And you need to talk to
your husband and your son
and let them know
what's going on.
And you need to remember that
my name is on this building.
So I'll be the one to
decide what I need.
I-I got a text
about Scout Lincoln.
Something about an
accident? Is he okay?
He's fine. He's just wet.
Oh.
We used his backup
clothes last week,
and we never got
new ones. Okay...
We tried his parents, but
they're both in surgery.
We had your information
from this morning.
What? So I'm supposed to...
A few parents have found
clothes at the gift shop.
I'm sure you don't want
him to be uncomfortable.
Tina's bringing Emily
home with Colette,
so you can pick her
up there after work.
I canceled the piano lesson,
and can you pick up fruit
snacks and Pirate's Booty?
It's our week to bring
the snacks to soccer.
Martha said she'll come
get me when I'm done.
I'll be fine.
Love you, too. Bye.
What'd I do with my keys?
I had them when you
picked me up, right?
I'm sorry. I don't remember.
Don't be.
I'm usually ready for anything,
but ectopic pregnancy
wasn't on my calendar.
It kinda threw me.
Totally understandable.
Bracelets.
My daughter makes them.
Take one. Heck...
Take two, please. Aww!
She's made enough for everyone
this side of the Mississippi.
But it keeps her busy when I'm
trying to get ready for work.
We get it. We have kids.
How old's your daughter?
Five. Aww.
She turns six next week.
Ooh, sweet. Ahh.
She only asked for,
um, one present...
A sister.
She's been calling
the baby Sundae
'cause she loves ice cream.
I can still get pregnant
after this, right?
It's hard for me to know without
doing further imaging tests.
But it is possible.
Ohh!
Dr. Montgomery?
This is bad, right?
Ahh! Ahh! Ah!
IDH inhibitors, CDK inhibitors,
immune checkpoint inhibitors...
Please. I'm not
one for inhibition.
And historically I've
been grateful for that.
But these trials have really...
I've already done one of these.
And it helped. It helped.
But it made me feel
like absolute hell.
I said I would consider
more treatment.
I did. It's not what I want.
Okay, so don't do it for
you, hmm? Do it for me.
If you think about it,
you really owe me one.
I'm getting help, if that
makes you feel any better.
Mm? I met a medicine
man in Bali.
I met a shaman in Peru.
I learned all about energy
medicine and frequency medicine,
medicines that don't make
me feel like I'm suffering.
T-That's because
they don't work.
According to you.
I have an acupuncturist
who's done more for my pain
than any pill you
ever prescribed.
And studies show that
Reiki will reduce pain
and it can improve
post-op recovery.
Catherine, please...
Tom, Tom, Tom.
I know you mean well.
And you've been
carrying my secret.
But this is my cancer.
Mm.
This is my choice.
Ah. Got it.
This group of neuroscientists
from Brussels...
They applied for a grant
to expand their research
on the connection between
Alzheimer's and...
Gut microbial composition.
I've read studies on it.
There are also some
that link gut integrity
with brain plaque production
and neuro-inflammation.
I-I saw this all in the
Parkinson's research.
Of course.
You already know more than the
group who applied for the grant.
It's your areas of
specialty... Gut and brain.
Yeah. It's all theoretical.
Like you didn't just do
a record-breaking study
on Parkinson's based
on something that was
initially theoretical?
Come on. You should do this.
We could help fund it.
And we got facilities,
equipment, tech.
We have this amazing partnership
with MIT's brain
science program.
They could be a resource.
You should just fund the
people from Brussels.
They're not you!
Meredith Grey studying the
disease that killed her mother?
That's a story that
would get funding,
and funding is what
cures diseases.
This is exciting.
What's... What's going
on? Where'd you go?
Zola was miserable this morning.
And I could never move to
Boston if she didn't want to.
I mean, she's been
through so much.
So much trauma.
She lost her birth
family, her birth country,
her father died, I almost died.
You know, all of
that stuff is...
Is just now coming
to the surface.
I really need to focus on her.
Okay. I hear you.
I love you both.
Not exactly gonna give up
on this entirely, okay?
Not just yet.
When did you become
so relentless?
When I took this job.
9-1-1. What's your emergency?
Yes, this is
Dr. Miranda Bailey.
I have a 39-year-old female
with a ruptured
ectopic pregnancy
on a cesarean scar.
She's alert and oriented,
but hemorrhaging.
Pulse is weak. Abdomen
is rigid and distended.
We are in a blue Grey-Sloan
van on Highway 270.
Can you send an ambulance?
On its way. Thank you.
How's it going back there?
We're okay.
Doing okay, Susan.
What are you looking for?
Uterine balloon tamponade?
Not gonna find one in there.
My OB just said I was okay.
Well, it's difficult to predict
if or when an ectopic
pregnancy will rupture, Susan.
This looks like a lot of blood.
Is... Is this a lot of blood?
The pregnancy invaded
the muscle layers
and likely tore open
the uterine incision,
which is why we have to... Ha!
What is that? A
Foley catheter.
If I insert this into your
vagina and inflate it,
the pressure against your
uterus will slow the bleeding.
Is that okay? Is it safe?
It's safer than letting
you keep bleeding.
Y-Yeah. Okay, do it.
Just... ohh! Make it stop.
Okay. I'm inserting it.
Okay. Try to hold still.
Bailey, no sudden moves.
Could I have prevented this
if I didn't get the C-section?
You didn't do anything
wrong. C-sections are safe.
This kind of ectopic
pregnancy is extremely rare.
You doing okay? Uh-huh.
Okay, I'm gonna inflate
the balloon now.
You're gonna feel a
little bit of pressure.
Hold still. You got it.
Okay.
That should buy us a
little bit of time.
And how much time?
It's okay.
Do you want a
bag? No, I'm good.
Oh, good luck with that. I
asked Schmitt for a day off.
He looked at me like
I killed his dog.
Uh, a bag, bag... I need
a bag. Oh, hey, Skywalker!
Hey. W-What are
you, uh, doing here?
Getting snacks.
Apparently the vending machine
is too lowbrow for Dr. Kwan.
Yogurt-covered pretzels?
I need brain food.
Cashews and almonds.
Ah, is that what
powers that ego?
What are you doing?
Uh, s-same. $32.75.
Wow. That is a lot of snacks.
I, uh... Geez.
I forgot my wallet in my locker.
I'll spot you, but I
get your next appy.
Hey, that's my... Ooh, ooh, ooh.
Wow.
I may be wrong, but I think
these are a little too small.
They're not for me.
They're for the...
Let me guess.
Daddy Daycare?
Oh, Schmitt. Oh, Schmitt.
It's okay.
I'll let him know that you
have child care issues.
Should I get another bag, or...
Yeah, and you were
interested in neuro,
and you set that
aside for Derek.
Oh, it was a bit more
complicated than that.
Like how hard it was to
choose general surgery
because of Ellis?
I wish I could make
one decision in my life
where people didn't
bring Ellis into it.
A couple years ago,
I actually got to spend
some time with my father.
Realized my entire life
he had loomed so large.
He was this...
mountain of a man.
And I spend some time with him,
I realize he's just some guy.
With wasted potential
and regrets and flaws.
You didn't want to be like him.
The scary part is, I
wasn't that different.
I mean, I was living in
cruise control, you know?
I wasn't fulfilling
my potential.
Feeling that similarity
to him was painful.
But it also
propelled me forward.
I mean, I'm happier here,
doing something I'm
passionate about.
Maybe it's not an accident
that you're up all night
researching Alzheimer's.
Or you're feeling so
much pain about Zola.
Maybe it's all these pieces
of your life coming together.
I kinda think you're
having a breakthrough
rather than a breakdown.
Relentless. No.
I'm just being a
friend, alright?
I've seen you push through
so many things before
and ignore them.
I'm just saying that
this might be something
you don't want to push through.
I think you should
let it help you grow.
Once upon a time, I did
want to cure Alzheimer's.
Exactly. But what if it fails?
Oh, it's probably
gonna fail. Right.
But, I mean, you could
definitely move the needle.
That means something.
Zola sees that her mom is
doing everything she can
to cure Alzheimer's.
I mean, that's pretty amazing.
Do you see an accident?
An ambulance?
No. Nothing.
How much longer will
the catheter hold?
Not sure.
Susan?
Susan, stay with me, hey?
Okay? Talk to me.
Tell me, um...
Tell me about Emily's
birthday party.
It's a spa party.
I don't know where
she got the idea.
But her teenaged
cousins are coming to...
To paint the kids' nails.
And she... She
wants a coffee cake.
Like the kind from school.
Ah. I... I haven't
baked it yet.
I need to be okay.
I need to bake her cake.
I want to see her turn six.
I want to see her
lose her front teeth
and learn how to read.
I... I want to teach
her how to drive
and send her off to prom.
I want to drop
her off at college
and miss her every day 'til
she comes home for summer.
I... I want to...
I want to... want to
watch her f-fall in love.
I w... I want to see her
start her first real job.
I want to be there
for all of it.
Okay?
I'm not ready to
go. I'm not...
Susan?
Susan!
What? I can't feel a pulse.
I'm starting CPR.
I'm pulling over.
9-1-1. What's your emergency?
This is Dr. Miranda
Bailey calling again
about a patient hemorrhaging
from a ruptured ectopic
pregnancy on Highway 270.
She's coding.
We're starting CPR.
We need immediate help!
We dispatched an ambulance, but
there's a significant accident.
Road is stopped in
both directions.
Hopefully we'll be there soon.
♪ What's gonna leave?
♪ What's gonna stay?
♪ It's gotten hard for
me to recognize myself ♪
♪ Think I was born
in this disguise ♪
♪ Staring down at the hand
that I've been dealt ♪
♪ Trying to see through
different eyes ♪
She's bleeding into her abdomen.
She's in hypovolemic shock.
The compressions
won't do anything
without giving her more blood.
If I stop, her heart stops.
She has no pulse.
I'm not stopping.
Addison.
She's gone. No. No.
♪ What a time, what
a time, what a time ♪
♪ Mm, mm, mm, mm
♪ Mm, mm, mm
♪ Ooh
Time of death, 13:34.
♪ Ooh ooh
♪ Mm, mm, mm, mm
That stuff keep you up at night?
Herbal tea. No caffeine.
Ah, I meant consistently lying
to your friends and family.
Tom, I thought we were done
with this conversation.
Well, persistence
is part of my charm.
Y-You can't fault me for trying.
My friend's life is at stake.
I spent the last six
months traveling abroad.
And everywhere I went,
all I thought was,
"Thank God I'm not
in an oncology ward."
If I stay the course
without chemo,
I'll have a few good years left.
I want to spend them living.
If the cancer gets
more aggressive,
if there's some
promising new option,
maybe I'll change my mind.
But if I'm gonna be
stuck in a hospital,
I want it to be as a
doctor, not as a patient.
At some point,
everyone's gonna
know you lied, hmm?
How... How about we just
let Jackson in on it...
No. Okay, Richard?
Tom, this conversation with
you is exhausting enough.
I'm not gonna have
it with anyone else.
I am lying to protect my
privacy and to protect my peace.
I'm happy with this decision.
You know what? I'm not
even gonna ask. Oh.
Nothing to know.
How about if you're ready
to go? Can I ask that?
What, you... you cutting out
early? Harriet has ballet.
I told her she could just
wait for the recital, but...
Wait? Child, please.
I'm here. Let's go.
I don't want to miss anything.
Dr. Kwan, have you seen Adams?
Uh, last I saw him, he
was at the gift shop...
buying clothes for your son.
Don't worry. Your
secret's safe.
Oh. You know?
About you two? It's
pretty obvious.
Is it? Yeah, when
you see you together.
You know, it might
be less obvious
if you gave the rest of
us some more neuro cases.
Do you have a special
interest in neuro, Dr. Kwan?
I have a special
interest in gaining
as much experience as I can
before I declare an area
of special interest.
I also have steady hands.
And many skills in other areas
if your interests
are... expansive.
You think I'm playing favorites
with Lucas because he's...
Dr. Shepherd, I
need a consult.
Is there supposed
to be a patient?
I got to tell you
something. Okay.
Oh, hey, I'm glad
you finally told
the other interns
about us, by the way.
They think we're together.
Together like... dating?
M-More like sleeping together.
What? H-How?
W-Why? W-Why?
Why? I-I don't know.
They assume things.
W... Did you tell them
that they're wrong?
Lucas! You have to
tell them! Oh, my God!
Kwan was just offering
me sexual favors
in exchange for
surgeries! Wh...
I might throw up.
Oh, b-but I just...
No, no, no. There's no "but."
You have no idea how fast
rumors spread around here.
I don't want people thinking
that I am dating my nephew.
Just sleeping together.
Stop saying that!
Just... Ugh!
Fix it!
♪ Six feet
How long has it been going?
32 seconds.
Maybe we'll get to a minute!
♪ It's just like the one that
you showed me in Oakland ♪
♪ Thought you were joking, but
I shoulda seen it comin' to me ♪
Hey. Hi.
This looks so cool.
It's a gyroscope.
The spinning wheel is
creating angular momentum,
and it's going so fast.
When you apply force,
it changes momentum
in multiple directions,
not just linear.
That's what keeps it
upright. It's physics.
It certainly is.
♪ And it still keeps
me up at night ♪
Sonata.
My mom's here. We've gotta go.
Bye, Zola. Hope
we see you again.
Bye, Matisse. Bye, Sonata.
Bye-bye.
♪ Barely on my mind
♪ Sinkin' in your teeth
♪ Actin' like you're
sweet, car crash ♪
They seem so nice.
How was it? Eh, it was okay.
Just okay, huh?
Can we go to the aquarium now?
Yes. Are you hungry?
♪ It's barely on my mind
Excuse me. They said
you're her doctors.
Uh, we treated her today.
I'm looking for records, scans,
anything that might
help with the report.
Well, you're gonna have to
talk to her OB in Idaho.
And while you're at it,
you might want to ask him
why he refused to treat her.
He was following the law.
Just like this
gentleman is doing.
Right. No. You're right.
It's the lawmakers.
They should actually be
made to come out here.
Yeah.
Have a look at the
carnage they've caused,
take a look at all the blood.
I mean, how are we
supposed to be doctors?
How are we supposed
to treat patients?
We're hamstrung by laws
that are written by people
that are so far away from this.
I have a medical degree.
I have decades of experience
treating pregnancies.
What... What experience
do they have?
Why do they get to decide?
No. It's wrong!
And it's infuriating!
I am infuriated, okay?!
Women's lives are on the line!
And our hands...
that are trained to help them...
our hands are tied.
It's...
They want us to stick
around a little longer.
In case we need to
answer more questions.
We've answered
everything. Twice.
I know.
But they're about to tell a
husband he's lost his wife.
And then he's gonna need to tell
his child she's lost her mom.
I would like to
be here for that.
If this is the
future, it's bleak.
You know, I've always
supported the right to choose.
But I... just, you
know, personally,
I... believed it wasn't
the choice for me.
But then I got pregnant.
A girl.
Then I miscarried.
Oh, Miranda. I'm so sorry.
And to add insult to injury,
the miscarriage was incomplete.
So I needed a procedure
to prevent infection.
Now, I did not
choose an abortion.
But I've had a D&C.
It is the same procedure.
And I'm worried doctors
are afraid to use it.
I'm... I'm worried
the next generation
won't get enough training on it.
I'm... I'm worried
that is our future.
I want to offer
it at Grey-Sloan.
Train anyone who
wants it. I-I...
I want to prepare health
care professionals to help.
That's an excellent
plan. Yeah, I know.
And it won't be nearly enough.
You take care of business?
No. I, um...
Lucas. It's your
mess. Clean it up.
W... mess?
D-Do you know why all the
interns think we're a couple?
Y-Y-You follow me
into on-call rooms.
You hover over me with
apartment listings.
You got me on Daddy
Daycare with Scout.
I asked you for help
with one thing...
Don't blow my cover at work.
And you've refused to do it.
So...
that makes it okay
to tell people
that we're sleeping together?
I didn't tell anybody anything.
It is not my job to correct
people's misconceptions.
Yes, it is. You are an intern.
I am an attending.
There are rules about
these things for a reason.
We're not actually together!
They don't know that.
You know, all my life,
everyone's always assumed
I only get anywhere because
of my family connections.
And all my life,
I've been my family's
biggest disappointment.
I hav... I haven't lived up
to anybody's expectations
as a Shepherd.
So I thought I'd see what
happens when I'm not one.
But now, thanks to your
lack of discretion,
everyone believes
we're connected,
just in a-a different way...
A way that is
admittedly disturbing,
but for this particular purpose,
better.
You have three days.
And then if you haven't
told them, I will.
So, when does the clinic open?
A couple of days.
I'm already thinking
of how to expand.
I want to do more, too.
I, uh...
I have to do more.
You will. From L.A.
No. No.
I want to... I want to go to
places where people need me.
Places like Pullman, you know?
I mean, I can't just sit.
I have a unique set of skills.
I know I can make a difference.
I...
Guess I just need
to look at a map.
Southern Illinois.
It's right near
Missouri, Arkansas,
Tennessee, Kentucky,
Mississippi...
All states that
have abortion bans.
They're expecting
up to 14,000 women
to cross state lines for care.
Yeah? How do you know that?
'Cause I thought
about doing it, too.
But I got the baby girl who
recently lost her father.
So, she needs me at home.
But you, though, you... you go.
You go and give more
women access to care.
I just...
Susan. It's just...
Wh... N... Okay. Stop.
You know you did everything
you could for her
under the circumstances.
No, you, y...
You needed the right
tools, the right supplies.
You needed an ultrasound.
You needed...
What?
The PRT.
Huh?
No. Okay. So, my husband...
He... he convinced
the fire department
that he needed this O.R.
on wheels, but it...
Okay, the city sidelined it.
So we helped fund
it, and now it...
It just sits in the motor
pool collecting dust.
Oh, I can think of a
much better use for it.
You said you liked driving.
Come on.
With enough practice,
surgeons learn how and when
to pivot from standard
operating procedures.
Well, do you like
it, the lobster roll?
Mm-hmm.
Did you know lobsters
can be yellow or blue?
It just depends on
their pigment protein.
Mm.
Did you learn that
at the aquarium?
Brookline STEAM has a
marine science lab. Right.
Experience gives us
more context to know
when we need a
different approach.
It gives us more options
to help our patients.
I saw you laughing.
I saw you making friends.
Why don't you like it there?
What if we move and I
still have panic attacks?
Or I fail school?
You will not fail.
And we are going to
continue the therapy.
We'll have left
Seattle for nothing.
And you'll have
given up your job.
Zola, let me worry about that.
That's my job.
You run a hospital.
People depend on you.
What if I told you Uncle
Jackson offered me a job
here in Boston,
working on a cure
for Alzheimer's?
♪ We're golden
What if...
What if I decide I don't
want to be a doctor?
That's completely fine.
Really? You wouldn't
be disappointed?
Not at all.
You are so intelligent
and so creative.
You are going to make your
mark no matter what you do.
You think so?
I know so.
You have always been and
will always be extraordinary.
♪ A new day has just begun
So, is it Brookline STEAM?
Mom...
I love it here.
I want to sign up
for robotics team.
They do this competition at MIT,
and last year they
won first place.
And I want to be
in the orchestra.
Can I please take cello
lessons when we move?
You can.
You can take cello
lessons when we move.
One-size-fits-all solutions
don't always work.
Every patient is different.
Just like every
person is different.
♪ And we're only
We each have various
factors to consider
when facing life's
big decisions.
♪ And we're only, we're
only at the start ♪
So we gather the facts.
We analyze the options.
And we use our knowledge
and experience...
♪ And we're only, we're
only at the start ♪
♪ A new day is dawning
♪ Oh, a new day has just begun
♪ I got hope here in my heart
to make the choices
that are right for us.
♪ And we're only, we're
only at the start ♪
Captions by VITA...