♪ All the pretty girls
lookin' sad all summer ♪
Thanks for helping, by the way.
You are very welcome.
I helped in other ways.
♪ Strangers in a world
full of lonely lovers ♪
Beer? Thanks.
♪ Find someone and
take 'em by the hand ♪
Well, come on, eat.
Can't you just bring
the beer to me? No.
Turn around. Best
tacos in Seattle.
♪ All the pretty
boys wanna dance ♪
It takes approximately
13 years of training
in order to stand in
an OR and cut into
an actual human being
without supervision.
Cheers! Thank you
for everything!
Good work.
Congratulations for...
♪ So all you summer
lovers, make ya sway ♪
♪ Been solo for so
long, no co-pilot, no ♪
♪ And all of these love
songs make you sick, I know ♪
We need a college degree
with a close-to-perfect GPA
and an excellent
score on the MCATs
to be lucky enough to be
accepted into a medical school.
♪ All the pretty
boys wanna dance ♪
♪ Strangers in a world
full of lonely lovers ♪
♪ Find someone and
take 'em by the hand ♪
And then, after four
years of med school,
we face 60 months of
surgical residency.
♪ I'm in a mood, so all you
summer lovers, make ya sway ♪
♪ Make you sway ♪
Well, did you get me a donut?
No.
♪ All the pretty girls
lookin' sad all summer ♪
We tell ourselves that
the lives we touch
and people we help
will make all the
sacrifices worthwhile.
♪ Strangers in a world full of
lonely lovers ♪ Just kidding.
I got it. I got it.
But until you've done it,
there's no way to know for sure.
♪ So all you summer
lovers, make ya sway ♪
♪ Make ya sway ♪
What's all this?
A high-protein breakfast
for your big day.
You gotta fuel up
to get a home run.
Oh, I'm operating on a Seahawk.
Huh? It... It's football.
They score touchdowns
and field goals...
Yeah, I will never
absorb that information,
so save your energy.
Okay.
This is...
Thank you!
Um, do you mind if I
take it to go, though?
'Cause I-I do want to get
to the hospital early. Yeah.
Are you nervous?
No.
I mean, yeah, there's...
there's pressure.
The kid's the team's
number-one draft pick,
and he's got his whole
career ahead of him.
And now the key
to saving his knee
and his entire NFL
future is in my hands.
Yeah. The most capable
hands in the whole state.
You're the one and
only ortho surgeon
to the Seattle Mariners!
That's the baseball
team. There it is!
And, you know, I wish Nico wasn't
traveling with them right now,
because I could really
use him as an assist.
You don't need him.
Think of all the people who
can walk and play sports
and enjoy their life
because of your hands.
That last part sounded
dirty, and I recognize it.
But you are a uniquely
gifted surgeon.
Oh, this is disgusting.
Your words.
Thank you!
Thank you.
Oh, hey, Altman.
Altman, hold up.
Um, is everything okay?
I mean, I haven't heard from
you since I submitted your offer
for chief of surgery,
which expires...
at 6:00 p. m. today.
Well, I still have
a few hours, then.
Look, since Marsh
left for a few days,
I'm filling in as
chief of surgery
and residency director,
on top of chief of chiefs,
which at my age is about
two chiefs too many.
I took a look at the offer.
And?
Owen has never had a kind
word to say about being chief,
Bailey quit, Meredith left,
and you didn't
exactly sell the idea
when I first inquired about it.
I just... I-I don't know
if I want it anymore.
It's a good offer, Altman.
You need this.
The hospital needs this.
I've got till,
uh, 6:00, right?
Oh, look at her.
Oh, she looks so happy.
Oh, audio.
She just started.
I am not laughing at Zola.
I am thinking about Meredith
living with a beginning cellist.
Morning.
Hi. Morning.
Whoa.
I would rather listen to a
squeaky cello than that silence.
How's therapy going?
Oh, every therapist in
Seattle is booked solid.
Our first appointment
is in three weeks.
So we've instituted a
ceasefire until then.
That silence was a ceasefire?
Silence is better
than every single word
that comes out of
either of our mouths.
Morning, Lincoln!
Dr. Bailey.
How's it going?
Good. You?
I'm great. Yeah. Hunt?
Oh, yeah, same, yeah.
You all want to meet the Tank.
Well, I may have,
uh, some free time.
Yeah. I've worked on
a lot of busted knees,
and I love the Seahawks.
Not as much as me. Wh...
You want to say
something? Say it.
Dr. Lincoln.
Do you need an assist?
Oh, you're a Seahawks fan, too?
Oh, well, the Tank and I
went to the same high school.
Listen, I-I
appreciate the offers,
but the Tank doesn't need
a room full of doctors
making his procedure seem
like a bigger deal than it is.
Now, were you surprised
at all by the draft pick?
Nah. Nah, not really.
Good morning.
Dr. Lincoln. Man of the hour.
I think that's you, the Tank.
Man of the year, according
to our Sunday feature.
Ken Bendix, Seattle Times.
Oh, yeah. I heard
you were coming.
And how are you feeling, hmm?
Any jitters? Come on, now.
The only jitters I get is waiting
for the football to be snapped.
Then folks better
watch out, because I'm coming.
Preach now. Yeah, we're
all rooting for you.
Half the hospital lobbied
me to be on your case.
The other half is...
in this room.
Yasuda, you want to present?
Jermaine Talbott, 22.
Tear to the left ACL
due to football injury.
History of multiple injuries,
including MCL repair
and meniscal cadaver transplant.
Today, he will receive
a bridge-enhanced anterior
cruciate ligament repair,
also known as the BEAR.
And why is this his best option?
It uses a collagen graft
soaked in the patient's blood,
instead of donor tissue,
which allows the
body to heal itself
and yields better results
than traditional ACL repairs.
Excellent. You're
scrubbing in.
Okay, yeah, but how else is the
BEAR important to my career?
It's less invasive.
Because it heals faster.
True, but not the
answer he's looking for.
It will allow him to ambulate
and return to play sooner.
Also yes, but no. Come on,
guys. I know someone's got this.
The Belser Bears. Played
as a true freshman.
Led the team in sacks and
tackles all four years.
Congratulations, Kwan.
You're scrubbing in, too.
The three of you will
report to Dr. Schmitt,
who I believe is,
conveniently, right outside.
It's every person
for themselves now.
I am not losing another surgery.
We don't have to
compete over everything.
First person to do
an actual procedure
gets the bedroom to
the left of the stairs.
What? I already
drew that room.
And I'm appealing
the draw. What?
Help! Please!
- I'm on it!
- Mine! Paws off!
Hi, I'm Dr. Adams. Can
you tell us what happened?
I failed, doc. I
couldn't do it.
You couldn't do what?
The Pho-Nomenal
Challenge. What is that?
The Pho-Nomenal Challenge
is three pounds of meat,
three pounds of noodles,
three liters of broth.
If you finish in an hour
and a half, you win $250.
Did you just come from there?
No, I tried it five days ago,
and I have not been able
to take a crap since.
Please help me.
Oh, God.
What do you got?
A 23-year-old male, 5 days
without a bowel movement
after participating
in an eating contest.
Eating challenge.
Severe abdominal pain,
bloating, difficulty sitting.
Hey, I'm Dr. Schmitt.
Have you tried increasing
your water intake,
eating adequate
sources of fiber?
Exercise helps, reducing stress.
How am I supposed
to reduce stress
when my entire body
is full of pho?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm just... I'm
very uncomfortable.
Excuse me. Um...
Can I borrow one of you?
Me! Is it surgical?
Go, Millin.
Get a KUB and then do
a digital rectal exam.
Wait, I'm sorry. Digital?
Yeah, a finger. It helps us...
Okay, d... Never mind.
After ruling everything out,
you can try a stool
softener or an enema.
If none of that works, then we
can consider doing a procedure.
Ow! God!
Still want that room?
Oh! God!
Lupe. Lupe, I'm on
the phone, amor, okay?
Okay.
Uh, Sierra Deleon?
She can cover?
Great. Thank you.
Okay, sorry.
I needed to make sure
my shift was covered.
Um, I'm pregnant with my
third, and I'm spotting.
Uh, here,
sweetie. Come here.
Yeah. It's a plane.
You can play here.
Okay, so how long have
you been spotting?
A few days.
At first, I didn't
think too much of it,
but now I'm starting
to get a bit stressed.
Oh! Lupe.
Okay.
Sorry about that.
Here, go
sit down. Go sit down.
Go sit.
Have you experienced
any clotting or noticed
an increase in the
amount of blood?
Maybe.
I'm not really sure.
Lupe's dad drives
cross-country rigs,
which means I'm lucky if
I get out the front door
with deodorant on.
Alright, I'm going to page OB.
We're gonna get
you an ultrasound
to see if we can find the
cause of the bleeding.
Okay.
Alright, I'll see you in a bit.
Eeh!
Thanks.
Oh, now, I'm texting
this to my husband.
He's gonna be jealous.
He's a Tank fan?
Ah, saw you play at Royer High
before you were even the Tank.
He predicted you
were gonna be a star.
Oh, okay. So I guess
he's gonna be jealous
and smug. Mm.
I was on a nighttime ER
rotation in the Caribbean
when you had that pick
six to win the Rose Bowl.
First time I tore my meniscus.
But we won the championship,
so... worth it.
Storm took out the
hospital Wi-Fi,
and I had the only hot spot.
Everyone... patients, doctors...
They all had opinions
on how to treat you.
Oh. One of their own.
And now you're my patient.
Mm, that's an interesting angle.
Do you have a few minutes?
Could I ask you some questions?
Uh...
Bring it on.
How about we step outside?
Eh... hold on.
Oh, daycare.
Oh.
I'd better see what that is.
Um, thank you for
the photo, Tank.
No problem.
Bye.
Dr. Azzi to Oncology.
Dr. Yasmin Azzi to Oncology.
This one?
You know, I had a couple
ACL repairs in college.
Oh, yeah? Yeah.
Busted my knee ice skating.
Used to be pretty
competitive. Used to?
Your recovery didn't
go well or something?
No, no, it went great.
But you couldn't skate?
Oh, I didn't have time.
I got into med school.
Then it's on and popping.
Ayyy! I feel that.
I know you do, now.
Hey, the kids
okay? I just got paged.
Yeah, me, too.
They probably threw
blocks at each other again
and file some sort of
injury report or something.
Huh. Hey, there is another
plus about being chief.
They usually bring
that paperwork to you.
Okay.
And you get a part-time
administrative assistant,
which is essential for
such an important job.
Richard told you that
if I took the job,
that you'd be chief of
trauma again, didn't he?
No.
Oh, my God.
He briefly floated it.
Once again, it's all about you.
No, it's about us.
Yeah, when it's
convenient for you.
Were all the parents paged?
Just the parents
involved in the bite.
Your kid bit my kid.
Which? Allison. Bit Pru.
That seems like
a one-parent job.
Let's make this one about you.
We are so sorry.
Okay, Sierra, you're
about 11 weeks along.
Hit the nail on the head.
There is a strong
fetal heart beat,
and your cervix
was closed on exam,
so everything looks good.
Your pregnancy is
right on track.
You just need to rest and
avoid strenuous activity.
Her BMP came back.
She's dehydrated.
So just make sure she gets some
fluids before you discharge.
Yeah, absolutely.
Okay, so we'll get you that IV,
and you'll be out
of here in no time.
Oh. Great.
Mommy, the phone.
Thank you.
Hey. What? She can't come in?
But she told me she was
gonna come in at 10:00.
Excuse me. No.
I'll... I'll call her.
I'll call her.
Is everything all right?
Not really.
Yes.
Everything's okay.
Thank you.
Well, I'll get you
those IV fluids,
and, um, you just
sit tight. Okay.
Dr. Kurtz to Oncology.
Dr. Fritz to oncology.
I didn't know colleges
had ice skating teams.
Of course you didn't.
Because we were hitting
the ice at 5:00 a. m.,
and the football team was still
getting their beauty sleep.
I had to stay focused
so I could go pro.
But now I gotta
kick it up a notch.
For the team?
For my family.
Playing ball is what will let me
bring them over
from Port-au-Prince.
Haiti? My real hometown.
Yeah.
A scout saw me play when
I was in the sixth grade.
He asked my uncle, would
he let me train in Seattle?
Guess what he
told the guy? Hm?
"Why
the hell not?"
So I moved by myself.
I was 11.
I get to go home and see my mom
and my little brothers
every Christmas,
but that's about it.
This is my chance to finally
get everyone back together.
So I gotta get back
on that field ASAP.
You want to succeed
so it means something.
Sit up for me.
And deep breath.
What if it doesn't work?
What if he can't repair it and
I'm stuck bagging groceries?
What if I can't play ball again?
But what if you can?
That is a
lot of fecal matter.
It's really good pho.
It's a hole-in-the-wall
in the CID.
You should try it.
Well, since you like it so much,
why don't you go in
and give the enema?
Are you offering the bedroom?
If you throw in two
weeks' groceries.
No deal. I know
how much you eat.
Not as much as this guy.
Oh, you know what?
Screw it. Gimme that.
Okay, bye. Mwah. Mwah.
Again, I am so, so
sorry. Oh, please.
I spoke to her.
It was a one-time thing.
Allison had something to say,
and she couldn't
get the words out.
Kids bite. It happens.
Thanks.
So, have you thought
more about chief?
Well, it's a great
title and a pay bump,
but is that really enough to...
No. No?
No, it's not a pay bump.
It's more like a
nudge, a small tap.
It certainly
isn't enough to justify
the relentless paperwork
and protocols and meetings
and complaints.
So... many... complaints.
That's why Webber
doesn't have any takers.
But you are in a
very interesting
negotiating position, Altman,
'cause they need you.
And if I were you,
I'd ask for the moon.
And the planets.
And Pluto.
What exactly do you think
that all looks like?
Well, if it were me...
A full-time
administrative assistant
who will be the point person
for any staff complaints.
And this person will also attend
budget meetings in my place
if I am unavailable and
take notes for my review.
I will need an additional
three weeks off
and double the pay increase
that you're currently offering.
And a... a stipend for research.
Oh. Well, this is
a lot to consider.
These are my terms... Sir.
Um, I-I'm gonna need some
time to think this over.
I'm sure you understand.
Of course.
Hey. Hey.
I thought you were
clipping an aneurysm.
Yeah, I finished.
What are you working on?
My case report for my
partial heart transplant.
The one on the
baby? Arlo Fischer.
Why would I write "socks"?
I have no idea. But
you know who might?
I'm not breaking the ceasefire.
And I need to get this done
in less than three weeks.
You're worried another cardio
surgeon might beat you to it?
I need a win.
I need a victory, because I feel
like I'm failing at my marriage,
and I do not fail.
I hate failing.
Hiding from the hard parts
won't make it less hard.
It'll just make it last longer.
Trust me.
It's not a durag,
Mommy, it's for surgery.
I wore it for the last
two, you remember?
You look so adorable.
Now, let me meet
everyone in that room.
This is Dr. Kwan.
Hi.
And this is Dr. Griffith.
Very nice to meet you.
Where's Dr. Lincoln?
He's already in the OR.
We're about to take
Jermaine there now.
Both of you look at me.
My son has broken
records with his talent.
Yes, ma'am. And noses.
Yes, ma'am.
You know where he
got that strength?
His mama.
Take care of my baby.
I love you.
Eyes forward.
You hear me?
Na pale pita.
Na pale pita,
chéri. Je t'aime.
I'm ready. Mm-hmm.
Hey. I just wanted to
wish you good luck.
Not that you need it.
I'll take it.
After everything Jermaine's
sacrificed to play,
he doesn't deserve to
be riding the bench.
I just
gotta stay sharp.
It's been a while since I've
been in the pressure cooker,
you know? Well...
you've never folded before.
You're not gonna start now.
I know it.
Oh. Thank you.
So, uh, I have
considered your offer.
Ready to shake
on it? You know,
Grey-Sloan is a place where...
Where legacies are built,
history is written.
Working here, for me, I mean,
evokes a feeling of... duty.
It's an honor to serve.
And often, service
requires sacrifice.
It's a little weird
to put it that way,
especially to someone who
actually served, but...
Uh, I'm... I'm not done yet.
Oh. Thank you.
When I see these
doctors, these patients,
it brings me joy.
It makes me happy,
um, fulfilled.
Oh.
And thinking about all of this,
well, Altman, I've decided
to take the job myself.
I-I
love being here.
I even love the building itself.
And, um, I'm... I'm happy
with the money that's
already on the table.
It's not about that for me.
So, um...
thank you for your
time, Dr. Altman.
Fine. We can lose the stipend.
Oh. Okay.
We will... lose the... stipend.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Hey.
Hey. What'd I miss?
They sutured the ACL and
are making the tunnels.
They're about to prepare
the implant for placement.
He wasn't asking me, was he?
Very much not.
Man, I hope this goes well.
The Tank has suffered
enough setbacks.
Are, uh, things better at home?
You know, all due...
All due respect,
the last time we talked,
you gave me some advice
that kinda blew up in my face.
Maggie's been
staying with Amelia.
Wh... Oh. Um...
I'm sorry.
It's... It's my fault.
I should have thought twice
before I took advice from you.
What's that supposed to mean?
I mean, how are
things with Teddy?
Fair point. Yeah.
The tunnels are made.
He's ready for the scaffold.
As amazing as I am, the Tank
weighs close to 320 pounds,
and he can run 40 yards
in less than 5 seconds,
which means he can
take down a quarterback
with roughly 1,700
pounds of force.
Never mind what that's
doing to his brain.
That's a whole
other conversation.
But it takes a
toll on the knees.
How long
can he sustain that?
Oh, on average, these defensive
players get about six years.
So it's only one year longer
than residency and he's done?
Let's hope he's
better than average.
Third
floor nurses' station.
O. T. Morell to the third
Is everything okay?
Sorry.
Lupe threw my
things on the floor
and I-I haven't
picked them up yet.
Well, your IV is almost done.
Are you experiencing any
pain in your abdomen?
Sierra?
I can't help but
notice you seem...
I just have a lot on my mind.
Sorry, I-I know you're busy.
Hey, don't apologize.
I know what it feels
like to be overwhelmed,
and I only have myself
to take care of.
If there's something
on your mind,
you can talk to me
about it if you want.
The condom broke.
My husband and I use condoms
because I hate the way
birth control
pills make me feel.
And it broke.
I wasn't trying to get pregnant.
Especially after my other two.
And, don't get me wrong, I
love the hell out of them.
I do.
But I'm scared it's
gonna come back.
What's going to
come back, Sierra?
After I gave birth
to my two kids,
I just felt this huge
wave rushing towards me.
I would look at them,
and I know I love them,
but I was so exhausted
and so defeated.
Depressed?
It was really dark.
I was really dark.
Both times.
Both babies.
And the doctor called it
postpartum depression,
and he prescribed me
a few medications,
talk therapy, but
nothing worked.
And it lasted for
months and months.
So when I saw that I
was spotting, I felt...
like I could breathe.
Sierra, did you... do anything
to try and terminate
this pregnancy?
No. Okay.
But when I thought I was
having a miscarriage,
I wasn't so terrified about
having to go through that again.
I wasn't so terrified that I
wouldn't be here for my babies.
How much is an abortion?
Our reproductive clinic
provides counseling
and abortion services
on a sliding scale.
Would you like me to call
someone from down there?
Okay.
That's the smallest
incision I've seen
for a procedure so complex.
When I was training, they used
to flay open the entire joint
and staple it back together
Frankenstein-style.
Mm. These days...
art.
Alright, okay. Well
done, everybody.
Now let's bandage
up the Tank's knee
and roll him back to
recovery and let him rest.
No gawkers in the hallways
waiting around awkwardly
for autographs.
And absolutely no selfies.
What are you doing?
Can't rush the rectum.
Wh... Uh, you're a surgeon.
We are surgeons.
Yeah, and general surgery's
all about poop in
the pipes, Skywalker.
Curtains or shades?
My room gets a lot of light.
Eh, it's not your room
until you have success.
Yes!
Jared, how are you feeling?
I feel like I just
lost 10 pounds.
Pho-tastic!
It's another dish on the menu.
I want to say thank you
so much for your help.
Now I can go back.
Uh, um, I'm sorry?
To the restaurant. I
need to win that $250.
Uh, sir, I really think
you should let your digestive
system... Am I free to go?
Yeah, you are free to go.
Uh, yeah, you just have to
sign some forms at the... desk.
Good luck!
Curtains it is.
Oh, wait. Stop scrolling.
His mom's phone number.
You think Dr. Lincoln
will let me call Nadine,
let her know Jermaine's
out of surgery?
Nadine? What, are we on a
first-name basis with his mom?
Yeah, it's called
listening to your patient.
You know, compassion,
bedside manner,
that kind of thing.
Okay, so you're saying I
don't have any of that?
Oh, you said it, not me.
Sats dropped to the 70s.
Heart rate in the 140s.
So in terms of
physical therapy...
Dr. Lincoln!
What's going on?
His vitals just
started plummeting.
BP is now below 90/70.
Damn it. He was fine
two minutes ago.
Alright, start him on pressors.
We need to
re-intubate him. Now!
Get Ndugu and get me an
intubation tray. Yeah.
I don't see anything.
His D-dimer's elevated,
his sats are failing, he
has right heart strain.
There's a clot.
Then where is it?
Dr. Lincoln. I'm
sorry, I'm just...
Kwan, get him away from there.
Found it.
Large saddle PE
at the bifurcation
of his pulmonary artery.
He needs an emergent
embolectomy.
Alright, he needs a heparin
infusion immediately.
Alright, let's get to
the IR suite right now.
Let's move.
Half your assistant's salary
is gonna come off your side.
Now, I can't double your pay,
but I am ready to offer you
25% above your initial offer.
Which is insulting.
75% over, and you pay
for the assistant.
You know, when I look
at these halls...
Oh, please.
Tell me about how
you served again.
Dr. Webber. Dr. Altman.
Uh, Shepherd?
I hope I'm not too late.
I would like to be
considered for the position.
Chief of surgery.
You have got to be kidding me.
At 11 weeks, we can
do an in-office procedure
to terminate the pregnancy.
Do you use a knife?
No. We use suction. No blades.
Will you put me to sleep?
Because I have to pick up Manny,
and I have to cook them dinner.
No, you'll be awake.
We can even have a
volunteer take Lupe
for ice cream during
the procedure.
Will it hurt?
You'll feel discomfort at times,
but we use an anesthetic
to numb the area.
I love my kids.
I want to stay alive for them.
I want to be okay for them.
I can't do this again.
Okay.
Do you want to assist?
I'll see you in a bit.
He's young, the
surgery went perfectly.
I don't understand how a clot
this size formed this quickly.
It shouldn't. But it can.
You're saying I should
have seen this coming?
I'm saying there's nothing
you could have done
to prevent this from happening.
Is that a V-Fib?
Get me a crash cart.
I'm pulling the wire.
Paddles.
Charge to 150.
Clear.
Push another epi.
Charge to 200.
Clear.
Again.
Come on, Tank. Come on.
Clear!
Come on.
Eyes forward, Jermaine.
Eyes forward.
Yes, I love you, too.
If you have to leave, it's okay.
I'll be fine.
He wants to stay on.
Is it okay if I'm on the phone?
Of course. Yes.
Okay, are you ready?
Okay.
I'm going to use my hands
to do a bimanual exam
to determine the shape and
location of your cervix.
Okay. I wish you
were here, too.
Now we're going to
insert the speculum,
just like a routine pap smear.
Okay.
And we will hold it still
with this instrument.
Okay.
Alright.
Now, Sierra, you may
feel some discomfort
as we administer two
shots to numb the area.
Okay, ready?
You're doing great.
Okay.
Millin, we'll wait a few minutes
for the paracervical block
to take effect before
we dilate the cervix.
How are you doing, Sierra?
I'm okay. Okay.
Yes, I'm still here.
No, no, no. I'm fine.
Okay, let's follow
along via ultrasound.
It's just an ultrasound.
It doesn't hurt.
Gel's just cold.
We'll measure the
length of her uterus
before we dilate the cervix.
Okay, Sierra, you ready?
Okay, Dr. Millin,
what do you see?
The uterus is 10 centimeters.
Okay, great.
We're going to
dilate the cervix.
Here we go.
Okay.
Doing great, Sierra.
Okay, last one.
Okay.
Now, Sierra, I'm going
to use this catheter
along the walls of your uterus.
Okay, are you ready?
Yes. Okay, here we go.
Doing great.
And, okay, removing
the catheter.
Dr. Millin will use ultrasound
to verify completion.
Uterus is clear.
Okay.
Removing the forceps.
And removing the speculum.
That's it?
And that's it.
It's over.
Yes, I'm okay.
I'm okay.
Charge again.
Link. Charge again!
We've been doing this
for two hours, man.
He's gone.
Time of death...
15:45.
Okay.
I'll walk out first.
Maybe I can stall the press.
No. No.
All they see is a
football player.
Stats and dollar signs.
He was just a kid
doing what he loved.
Now he's gone.
That's on me.
- Mommy.
- Oh.
Hey!
You got that?
Yeah. Okay, so, you, um,
you may experience some cramping
and some spotting over
the next few days.
It's totally normal.
If you feel uncomfortable,
ibuprofen will help. Okay.
Uh, if you feel any dizziness
or experience heavy bleeding,
please call us.
Thank you both.
You're an incredible mom.
Come on. Let's go.
Hey.
Dr. Wagner in Radiology.
Great work today, Millin.
A lot of interns can
regurgitate a textbook,
but not many can talk
to a patient like you.
What?
I-I've just never had someone
compliment my work before.
It's safe to say I-I grew
up a little left of normal.
My parents taught me
to clear energy fields
and roll a joint at 10.
That kind of reputation
didn't exactly pave
the way for success.
Well, coming from
someone who didn't have
the most conventional
upbringing, either...
you saved that
woman's life today.
You could've walked
away, but you didn't.
You stayed and listened,
and Sierra is better off for it.
Excuse me.
And not to mention,
I've just come off
an award-winning research
project on Parkinson's,
which will boost the
profile of this hospital
if I'm the new chief.
Are you asking for anything
specific in the offer?
Well, I would need
twice the existing rate
and full flexibility to
travel to visiting labs.
Also, I found out what they're
paying at Seattle Pres.
You should be a
little embarrassed.
Why do you have to
visit other labs
when we have a lab
right here for you?
I don't need to go anywhere.
I'm sorry, Dr. Shepherd.
I'm unable to consider
your application.
I've already offered
the job to Dr. Altman.
75% above your existing rate,
a full-time administrative
assistant, and a stipend.
A small stipend.
Deal.
You're welcome.
What? Bailey sent me in here.
I didn't want to be chief.
♪ Slow motion colliding ♪
♪ Come hold all that's mine ♪
♪ I'm tongue tied,
tongue tied ♪
♪ Cards out on the table ♪
You okay?
♪ I need something stable ♪
I told Dr. Lincoln
I would call Nadine.
♪ Right now ♪
It should be us. We met her.
We owe her that.
But I don't know what to say.
I've been on the other
end of that call.
It's sickening.
It's impossible, and
there is no right way.
There are no right words.
Will you do it with me?
♪ Took the long road
and I got lost ♪
Yeah.
♪ Off the deep end,
I'm treading water ♪
♪ Throw a line out ♪
♪ I am on the way down ♪
♪ You know me better
than I know myself ♪
♪ Take the darkness ♪
Nadine: Hello?
♪ And heal me from it ♪
Mrs... Nadine.
♪ I am on the way down ♪
Ma'am...
there was a complication
with Jermaine's surgery.
No. No, please. My baby.
Please. My baby.
Please! No!
No! No!
♪ Feet, don't fail me now ♪
I heard about Jermaine
Talbott.
♪ Please don't let me drown ♪
I'm sorry.
♪ Keep me dry, keep me dry ♪
Thanks.
♪ Keep me dry ♪
Um, I started the paper.
I can send you the introduction,
if you want.
I just lost a
patient. I'm sorry.
I thought it would be
a good distraction.
No. Okay.
No. That's what you do.
You bury yourself in work
to avoid your feelings.
Says the man who is
switching specialties
to avoid his wife.
Who is making this a bigger
deal than it needs to be.
People die, Maggie.
Young people.
Strong people. People
who deserve better.
And you want to throw
away our marriage
because I applied
for a transfer.
And you want to throw away
your ability to save lives.
♪ Shine a light out ♪
Didn't make much of a
difference today, so...
But you tried.
And not everyone
can be resuscitated,
but you have to
try. You're right.
♪ Shine a light out ♪
♪ Shine a light ♪
Not everyone can
be resuscitated.
♪ Shine a light out ♪
♪ I'm on the way down ♪
♪ Let me ♪
♪ Shine a light out ♪
[ Elevator bell dings ]
♪ Shine a light ♪
♪ Took the long road
and I got lost ♪
♪ Off the deep end,
I'm treading water ♪
♪ Throw a line out ♪
♪ I am on the way down ♪
So, I had this patient today,
and, I mean, the lengths that
some people will go to...
♪ You know me better
than I know myself ♪
♪ Take the darkness
and heal me from it ♪
♪ Shine a light out ♪
♪ I am on the way down ♪
What do you say to sushi?
I'm pretty sure
we can afford it.
Hey! Wait, you don't know?
What? The press are
having a field day.
They're saying that Link
killed Jermaine Talbott.
Oh, my God.
Yeah.
And I'm chief.
Okay.
What happened to
Jermaine Talbott?
Was Dr. Lincoln
responsible
for the death of
Jermaine Talbott?
Where's Dr. Link?
No comment.
22 years old.
He had his entire
life ahead of him.
Now he'll never have children.
He'll never fall in love.
Grow old.
Because of me.
Hey. Look at me.
You did
everything right.
It was a clot. It
can happen to anyone.
Come here.
♪ Mm-mm-mm-mm-mm-mm-mm-mm ♪
♪ There's a time to break ♪
♪ And there's a time to grow ♪
I... Oh.
♪ There's a time to break ♪
Oh. Okay, you're...
you're drunk
and you're sad,
and... I'm sorry.
I'm...
It's okay. I'm so sorry.
No, it's okay. I'm
gonna go upstairs.
No, no, no. It's
okay. It's okay.
Sometimes, the things
we fight hardest to achieve
end up costing us the most.
But it doesn't mean
the effort was a waste.
♪ We will find our way ♪
Every experience can
teach us something
if we choose to
receive the lesson.
♪ There will be rain ♪
♪ Ah, ah, ah, ah ♪
Simone?
Trey?
What are you doing here?
He said he knew you.
Don't worry, I searched
your Insta photos
to confirm before
letting him in.
Plus, he brought snacks.
♪ And we don't
have to be alone ♪
I should've come
a long time ago.
♪ As we float down the river ♪
Now, who's this?
He's my roommate.
♪ ...down the river ♪
But what we learn may
completely surprise us.
♪ Mm-mm-mm-mm-mm-mm-mm-mm ♪
Captions by VITAC...