♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
I have to go to work.
And I feel used.
Gabriel.
We were at a wedding,
we got carried away, that's all.
Move to D.C. with me.
Oh. Thanks.
That's where
I'm going too.
The doctors there
aren't expensive, are they?
I'm already working
at a bar
to put myself
through grad school.
Don't worry. Our patients
are our first priority.
So you're one of the doctors?
Yes. I'm Dr. Montgomery.
Oh. You're the one I'm coming
to see. I'm Patty--
Patty? What is it?
Oh, my stomach.
Okay. Okay.
It's okay.
It's okay, Patty.
What did you give me?
I feel better.
It's an antiemetic.
Helps with the nausea.
That's tender?
Okay, you know what?
I'm gonna do an ultrasound.
Have you had
any other symptoms lately?
Any recent changes in health?
Patty, what is it?
I had an abortion
two months ago.
I tried to go to this clinic,
but outside were all these...
Protesters?
The things
they were yelling,
calling me a murderer,
a baby killer.
I couldn't go in.
I tried to find
a private doctor,
but most of them
won't do abortions.
I'm lucky my girlfriend
knew a doctor who would.
Yeah. Well, it's hard
to do your job
when you're getting
death threats.
Some doctors aren't even trained
in the procedure anymore.
I want kids. I do.
Just not now.
I mean, babies are expensive,
kids need time and attention.
It seemed wrong to bring one
into the world
I couldn't do right by.
Patty, you don't have to justify
your decision to me.
The doctor told me I might have
some cramping and tenderness,
but I didn't expect
to feel this bad.
Okay. Let's take a look.
What is it?
Is something wrong?
Patty, I'm sorry. Uh...
You're still pregnant.
The fetus looks to be
about 19 weeks.
But this-- I can't--
I can't be pregnant.
Charlie and I, we used a condom.
I had an abortion.
Sometimes when an abortion
is done early,
the pregnancy is so small
that the doctor
can miss the embryonic tissue
when removing it
from the uterus.
But I got drunk
last weekend.
I smoked two packs
of cigarettes.
You have to do
something.
You can just do it again,
right?
Patty, you need to understand
that this isn't just tissue.
You're carrying
a fetus now,
and the procedure
is much more difficult.
What would you have
to do to me?
There's something
called laminaria,
seaweed sticks
that absorb fluid and swell.
They would be inserted into
your cervix to help it dilate.
Twenty-four hours later
you would be brought back in,
put under general anesthesia,
and the fetus would be removed
using forceps and suction.
Could the baby survive?
No, not at 19 weeks.
The baby needs to be
at least 24 weeks
to survive
outside the uterus.
The fetus would die
during the procedure.
I think I'm gonna be sick.
Look, um,
there are other options.
You can carry the baby
to term.
Don't you think I considered
all the options last time?
I can't carry a child,
I'm on my feet eight hours
a day, I have no money.
God, I'm pregnant.
Look, I, uh--
I know that this is a shock,
so why don't you take some time,
think about
what you wanna do?
Okay, say hello
to a married man.
Sam &amp; Naomi:
Hey.
If two people get married and
you don't actually witness it,
did it really happen?
Sorry about that.
Mm-hm. Well, congratulations.
Thank you.
Any word from
the medical board?
Well, I still have my license,
so I have every right
to be here.
Wait, that's--
that's not what I meant. I--
Addison:
Sometimes I hate being a doctor.
My new patient,
she's 19 weeks pregnant,
and she may want
an abortion.
A partial-birth abortion?
Partial-birth is not
a medical term. It's political.
Okay, late-term abortion,
second-trimester, d&amp;E.
Who cares what you call it?
You can't do it.
Yes, she can.
It's at the doctor's discretion
and it is legal.
Did you even counsel her
on her options?
She was counseled
before her first abortion.
Her first abortion? Is she using
the procedure as birth control?
No, she used condoms.
Why are you judging?
There is no judgment from us,
we are doctors.
And we all know that
birth control sometimes fails.
I didn't wanna tell her
because it would freak her out:
The doctor she went
to the first time was a quack,
who didn't know
what he was doing,
and now she's come to me,
and my job is to help her.
How did you leave it?
She's gonna think
and make her choice.
Maybe the choice
has been made.
What does that mean?
I mean, condoms
are usually effective,
and failed abortions
are negligible.
So maybe this baby
was meant to live.
Sheldon:
You wanna force a woman
to give birth and raise a child
that she clearly doesn't want?
After what she did,
Patty should give the baby up
for adoption.
What she did was exercise
her right to choose.
Hey. Hey, Pete.
Cooper: So if she comes back,
what are you gonna do?
I have no idea.
Violet:
Oh, my god.
It's Betsey. She's in the E.R.
My head hurts.
I know, baby.
That was a big fall.
I was in the kitchen cooking.
I just--
I should've been watching her.
You have to fix her.
I will, Marshall. I promise.
I don't like it here.
Oh, baby, no one likes
hospitals,
but the doctors
are gonna make you better.
No. My mommy and daddy died
here. Everybody dies here.
Cooper: Is she all right?
Her vitals are stable.
Any loss of consciousness
or focal neuro signs?
Exam was negative.
Addison: C. Spine?
Clear. We're waiting on ct
and portable chest.
I thought social services
placed her with a family
in riverside.
Yeah. What is she--? What is
she doing in St. ambrose?
Her family moved to the Westside
a few months ago.
She's been right here?
Ct shows an extensive contusion
in the left temporal region.
Does that mean surgery?
The swelling could
go down.
We'll need to monitor her
for the next few days.
Addison:
Any other injuries
or signs of trauma?
No, the X-ray looks good.
No broken bones.
Just a healed clavicle fracture,
looks a couple months old.
Betsey broke her collarbone
two months ago
and now she falls
down the stairs?
Now, we shouldn't jump
to any conclusions.
I do this every day, Sheldon,
and to me
that sounds like abuse.
Addison:
Cooper, you cannot jump
to abuse.
We should have social services
make an assessment.
What do you think
we should do?
We can't leave her.
If you guys had
just taken her
when she got left
in the office--
this wouldn't have happened?
Oh, it's not like you took her.
Guys, this
isn't helping.
Okay, Pete. You met the parents.
What did you think?
They were
loving and concerned.
And Betsey is clearly
very attached.
To Betsey,
any parents are good.
Naomi: If they're abusing--
we have to get her out.
I broke four bones
by the time I was 10.
Kids fall all the time.
Pete: Okay, look.
It seems like Betsey's
found a good family.
We cannot risk ruining that
unless we have concrete proof.
Let's get some.
Cooper.
Hi, I'm Dr. Cooper Freedman.
Gina: Hi.
Cooper:
And this is Dr. Violet Turner.
We used to work
with Betsey's dad.
Oh.
Naomi.
Hey, sweetie.
Phil and Gina rakoff.
Behind the video game,
that's our son, Marshall.
Hi, I'm Dr. Naomi Bennett.
Betsey, look how popular
you are. All these visitors.
Uh, why don't we step over here
so I can update you on
what's going on?
I'm so glad to see you.
Why didn't you visit me?
I wanted to, I did. But--
I don't wanna talk to you.
Look, it's okay.
Hey, sweetie.
So how do you like
your new family?
That fall must have been scary,
huh?
You did fall, right, sweetie?
Sweetie, did somebody hurt you?
How about when you--?
When you broke the bone?
I--
I fell off the jungle gym.
Betsey, listen,
even if somebody told you not
to, you can tell me, okay?
I love you.
We all love you here.
But you sent me away.
Gina:
What's the matter, honey?
Phil:
What's going on?
Why's she upset?
Um, to be perfectly honest,
I'm concerned about this fall
that seems to have come
on the heels
of the other accident
where she broke the clavicle.
Kids fall.
They do, but two severe ones,
so close together, it's...
Are you accusing us
of hurting her?
Phil:
We love Betsey.
You have no right--
don't be mean to my mommy.
You're upsetting our children
and you're both way out of line.
Get the hell out
and don't come back.
Poor kid, huh?
Yeah, I suppose
we made our bed.
What, you think
this is our fault?
I think that we--
all of us at the practice.
We make decisions
and we don't think
about the consequences.
All I can think about lately
are consequences.
This Patty thing's really
killing you.
I'm fine.
You're not fine.
You wanna have a baby.
You want a baby so bad
that we broke up and now--
in a few weeks,
that fetus could be a baby.
Not just a collection of cells,
but a baby and...
Sorry.
Thank you.
I should go.
Mm-hm.
When I offered
to take you to lunch,
the hospital cafeteria
wasn't exactly what
I had in mind.
Yes, well, I need to be here
right now,
and I only have
a half an hour.
I gotta pick up Olivia.
Don't get me wrong. I'm happy
to see you as much as possible.
Don't. Do not ask me
about D.C. again, okay? Not now.
Betsey's in icu,
Addison may be performing
an abortion on a woman
who is 19 weeks pregnant.
Hmm. Late-term by definition,
but certainly not illegal.
I mean, I can see how
that might frustrate
someone whose work
is creating life.
That's a careful response.
You don't agree with me?
A fetus may be a life,
but it's not
a biologically independent life.
So in my mind, and in the mind
of the supreme court,
the right of termination
belongs to the mother.
Well, thank you
for the civics lesson.
Maybe you should offer
to assist Addison.
If I felt that strongly
about it, I would.
You know me.
I'm all about going after
what you believe in
as hard as possible.
She hates me.
Betsey does not hate you.
Of course she hates me.
I'm the one who sent her away.
I'm the one
who looked that little girl
in the eye
and sold her a fairy tale
about how marvelous
her new life was gonna be,
because I couldn't tell
her the truth.
Now her foster parents
could be hurting her.
For all we know, she did fall.
But we don't know, do we?
It's just too much.
First Betsey loses her parents,
and then her aunt drops
her off here
like a package that was tossed
into the trash by us,
the people who were supposed
to care. And now tack on abuse?
I-- I had an obligation to
take care of Dell's little girl.
Look, you've gotta stop
beating yourself up.
Or is it me
that you blame for all this?
Well, right now,
I'm the one being blamed.
By Betsey. And that's all
I can think about.
Can I go home soon?
We're working
on it, honey.
I told you to stay away
from my family.
I'm not coming in.
She is.
Gladys?
Hi, Betsey. Remember me?
Our little girl
has a brain injury
and you called
social services?
Outside. Right now.
Amelia:
What are you doing?
She needs to stay calm.
For the next few days, our
main focus has to be her health.
I am worried about her health.
Dr. Freedman, I will follow up,
I promise.
But I think you're wrong
about Phil and Gina.
It is oddly therapeutic,
you know.
Please, you are preaching
to the choir.
My goodness.
I can't get enough.
Oh, but Maya's gonna be back
soon enough,
so I have to enjoy it
while I can.
Okay, I'll see you.
Bye.
Naomi: Bye-bye.
Is Dr. Montgomery in?
She's at the hospital.
She should be back soon.
Can you tell her
that Patty stopped by?
Uh, Patty?
Hi. I'm--
I'm Dr. Naomi Bennett.
Would you like to wait
in my office?
I have some tissues. Okay.
I had a plan. I was gonna
finish grad school, get my mba,
meet a great guy
who thinks I hung the moon,
get married, and around
35 we'd have a baby.
Well, no one is ready,
ever ready, to have a baby.
It's just--
you just do it.
You know, my daughter
was 16 years old
when she got pregnant
with Olivia here.
She hadn't even finished
high school.
And I almost...
No, i-- I tried to force her
to have an abortion,
and I'm so grateful every single
day that she didn't.
But she had you to help her.
My boyfriend, Charlie,
he couldn't get away fast enough
when I told him I was pregnant.
That just means he's not ready
to be a father.
I can't be a mother.
I have nothing.
I have to work all the time.
But being a mother isn't
about what you have,
it's about who you are.
I can't have this baby.
I can't.
I already got
an abortion before,
I can live through it
again.
It's not the same, Patty.
At 19 weeks, do you know
that your child can hear you?
It can be startled
by loud noises.
Your child already
has vocal cords
and fingerprints and air sacs
in her lungs.
She can move her arms and legs,
not unlike Olivia here.
Yeah. Yeah.
I know you're confused,
which is why
I think you need
a little more time
to think about it.
And I promise you
that I can offer you
all the support you need
to get through this pregnancy.
Just please, just consider...
Just consider
carrying the baby to term.
What did you say to Patty?
She comes here to see me
and then you scare her
into changing her mind?
I didn't scare her.
I talked to her.
You had no right.
She needed to think.
This abortion could affect
her for the rest of her life.
Any choice would affect her for
the rest of her life.
All the more reason
to be sure of her decision.
You don't get an opinion,
you don't work here.
Which makes me
the objective person.
The patient was made aware
of her options
and she chose.
End of story.
Sheldon:
This isn't some clinical trial
where we line up
the pros and cons.
There's an emotional component
here that can't be quantified.
It's not just emotional,
this is physical.
When you crush that baby's skull
to get it through the cervix,
it feels that pain.
You don't think I know that?
I don't think you care.
Of course I care.
But Patty is my patient.
You violated the trust
that I established
with my patient.
My patient. You have crossed
so far over the line,
you can't even see it.
I did what I thought was right.
Whether or not to do
this procedure
is not your decision,
it is mine.
I thought it was Patty's.
You didn't wanna do it anyway.
And now you don't have to.
Don't pretend you did this
for me.
You manipulated a terrified
and confused girl.
Preach whatever you want
to your own patients,
but stay away from mine.
How's Betsey doing?
Her intracranial pressure
is holding steady,
so no surgery yet.
Honestly, for once
I don't wanna cut.
I get that.
It's a tricky procedure.
Besides, Betsey is just a kid.
And her father died on my table.
What happened with Dell
was not your fault.
You don't really
blame yourself, do you?
I don't know. I just--
I've got a little girl
in the icu
and all I can think about,
all I can focus on,
is how badly I want a drink.
My mama always says,
"god doesn't give
with both hands."
You're young, beautiful,
brilliant.
Has to be something
you can't have.
Some days I'd give all that up.
That's just the craving talking.
But the longer you go
without a drink--
I drank at your wedding.
I thought it was ginger ale.
I spit it out.
Okay.
Since then?
Nothing.
But I can't stop thinking
about it.
It was an accident.
Don't turn a slip
into a fall.
Get your butt to a meeting.
I will.
I gotta go watch Betsey
a little longer.
Hey. Are you okay?
No.
You know, Betsey's just a kid,
she's suffered a trauma,
so give her some time.
Time won't change the fact
that Pete
didn't let me keep her.
Look, I'm all for blaming Pete
when it's justified,
but this is not his fault.
If you wanted to adopt Betsey,
you could have fought harder.
You've been married
for a minute and a half,
what do you know?
Okay, do you want a shoulder
or the truth?
Spit it out.
Okay.
After Betsey left,
you didn't visit her.
None of us did.
But you judged us
for not coming to her rescue.
You played the guilt card,
the responsibility card.
You made her your mission.
And then the social worker
takes her away and,
you know, out of sight,
out of mind.
Oh, god. I'm vile. I'm selfish.
I am selfish and vile.
Come on, Violet.
We all failed Betsey.
We just have to figure out
how to help her now.
You have to know that
we didn't-- we could never--
where do they get off
accusing us of hurting her?
Look, we all just want
what's best for her.
I should probably take
Marshall home.
You're leaving?
I'm staying with you,
honey, okay?
Hug your sister, hmm?
I need some help in here.
Phil: What's happening?
Pete:
Ten milligrams of lorazepam.
She was fine.
I don't understand.
Amelia: What's going on?
Icp is off the chart.
We need to get her
into surgery now.
Pete:
Come on.
I'm going with her.
I should go too, but Marshall.
You both go, I'll stay with him.
Thank you.
Will Betsey be okay?
Dr. Shepherd is the best.
She'll do everything she can.
You have to make her okay.
You have to. You promised.
Make her okay!
Make Betsey better!
Make her better! You promised!
You said you will!
Make her better!
Sheldon: Hey, Pete.
Hey.
Who's your
friend?
This is Marshall,
Betsey's foster brother.
Mommy says we don't
say "foster."
Sheldon:
Of course. I'm Sheldon.
Hey, can I join you?
Pete: Sure.
Sheldon:
You and Betsey
are about the same age.
Must be nice to have her
living with you.
Yeah. It's fun.
Uh, hey, listen.
I gotta check on a patient.
Do you mind? I'll be back
in a couple of minutes.
Now, I'm sure you got upset
by what happened to Betsey,
but the doctors here
are very good.
They're gonna take
great care of her.
Does your dad ever get upset?
Sometimes.
But does he get more upset
now that Betsey lives with you?
He fights with mommy a lot more.
And mommy gets sad.
I don't like it.
Of course not.
You love your mom.
So, what do you do
to make her happy?
I'm an extra good boy
so she knows I love her.
I tell Betsey to be
extra good too,
and to listen
to daddy and mommy.
And when Betsey
doesn't listen,
does your dad do more
than just talk to her?
Does he spank her or...?
No.
Sheldon: What about your mom?
Is she ever mean to Betsey?
No.
But sometimes I help her
to listen.
How do you do that?
Is that what you did
on the jungle gym?
Betsey's clumsy.
It was her fault.
And when Betsey misbehaves,
I guess that's her fault too.
Must make it harder
for your parents.
Yeah.
And that's not right.
So I guess it makes sense, then,
that she needs to be punished.
I'm done with my ice cream.
Can I have more?
Charlotte: How's it going?
Amelia: It's tricky.
The hematoma's on the tip
of the left temporal lobe.
If I remove
more than four centimeters,
she'll have persistent
speech problems.
You checking up on me?
Worried I'm not competent
to do this?
Actually, I have complete
faith in you.
I'm just worried you lost faith
in yourself.
Amelia:
Sooner or later
this kid's gotta catch a break.
Dell did everything for Betsey
and it still all went bad.
Why do you think having kids
scares the crap out of me?
Cooper must want them.
Charlotte: Of course.
He's giving me the time
to get onboard.
That's nice.
Addison had to choose between
having a kid and being with Sam.
Now she's got neither.
You're lucky to have a man
like Coop.
Got it.
What's wrong?
Damn, there's a bleed.
I need to remove more
of the temporal lobe to stop it.
If I am off
by one centimeter--
Amelia, this is
what you do.
Don't think,
just do it.
I knew Betsey
was holding back.
Marshall didn't admit
to pushing her.
He didn't have to.
The way he talked about Betsey
and his aggressiveness
with Pete.
Marshall's been hurting Betsey.
I can't believe it.
The kid's only eight years old.
Well, did Marshall feel
any guilt at all?
He justifies his actions
under the guise
of protecting his mother.
And there's a pride
he associates
with being a good boy.
So the kid's a psychopath.
No, no one is saying that.
There's a reason why
we don't diagnose kids
with antisocial
personality disorder.
The prefrontal cortex
doesn't really develop
till we're in our 20s.
I know that.
Violet:
While the brain is maturing,
he could be learning ways
to hurt people.
Therapy?
Possibly.
Maybe he needs more love
and attention.
Violet:
Why are we worrying
about Marshall?
Betsey's the one
we care about.
Recent history
notwithstanding.
We didn't give up on Betsey.
Okay? You weren't here.
It was difficult and complicated
and you weren't here.
You need to keep Marshall
away from Betsey.
What are you talking about?
Marshall loves his sister.
You're not involved in this.
Yes, I am.
I'm the one who promised Betsey
she would be safe
in foster care.
She is.
There's something wrong
with Marshall.
Who are you?
Sheldon Wallace.
I'm a psychiatrist.
Of course you are.
Betsey's intracranial
pressure spiked
when Marshall
was about to hug her.
She's clearly afraid of him.
You've never even talked
to Marshall.
I spent time with him
earlier.
And I really do believe
that he's trying to hurt her.
Wait. You interrogated
our son?
He was trying to protect
your daughter.
Phil:
What kind of doctors are you?
We've heard enough. Get out
of here or I'll call security.
How is she? How's Betsey?
She's out of surgery.
She's stable,
but she's in a coma.
I've been calling you all day.
I know.
I just needed some time.
I just wanted to apologize
for Dr. Bennett.
She had no right
to upset you like that.
Believe me, i--
I just wanna make sure
that you're okay
and tell you
that I am here to talk,
to listen, to help you
in any way I can.
Patty:
Dr. Montgomery?
I don't know what to do.
I can't tell you what to do.
I can only tell you
that it's your choice.
Maybe it shouldn't be.
But it has to be.
Patty,
when it comes to abortion,
everybody has an opinion.
Everybody's gonna wanna
tell you what to do.
If this were 1972,
it would have been a back alley
and not my elevator
that you would've collapsed in,
because back then,
you didn't have a choice.
Now you do.
But it's still hard.
And even after you make
the most difficult
and personal decision
that there is,
it's still not safe,
because you have some fanatic
who claims to value life,
who can walk into an
abortion clinic and blow it up.
Patty, you
are the only one who knows
if you're ready
to have a child.
Everybody else's opinion
is just background noise.
So if you wanna keep this baby,
I'll support you.
You wanna give it up
for adoption, I'll help.
You want an abortion,
I'll do it.
I am not here
to judge you.
I just need you to know
that whatever
decision you make is for you.
Not for me,
not for Dr. Bennett.
For you.
Hey. Any word on Betsey?
She still hasn't woken up.
I know I wasn't here
when Betsey's aunt
dropped her off
and maybe I should've
come back from Africa--
we have Olivia to take care of
and we're nowhere near
done with Maya.
Well, as much as she'd like
to think otherwise.
I don't know.
Do you think that she'd be okay
if we didn't see her that often?
Well, she might not
go to Columbia.
Yeah.
On the other hand,
New York is just a short
train ride away from D.C.
Hmm?
Fife asked me to go back
with him. Heh.
And are you considering it?
I know. You don't like him.
He is an arrogant ass.
I mean, I wouldn't pick him
for you.
But what do I know?
How are you doing
since you and Addison split?
I have my good days,
bad days.
You think you two will manage
to stay friends?
You think you will?
You're a good mother, Gina.
You love Marshall.
You spend time with him,
you take care of him.
You knew, didn't you?
He...
He doesn't have friends.
Fights with kids at school.
He says they pick on him,
but the other parents,
the guidance counselors,
they always swear
Marshall started it.
I knew he was different,
but you don't wanna think--
I just-- i--
I didn't wanna see it.
I thought if we brought
another kid into our home,
he'd have someone.
A friend.
That's not enough.
He needs--
Gina: More.
Love, attention.
More of us.
I love you, Betsey.
Wait.
Betsey can't go back
in the system.
Marshall is my son.
He has to come first.
My kid would've been
six this year.
A girl.
I know it would've
been a girl.
Ella.
She would've been
in the first grade.
She would've had the same gap
between her teeth as me.
If you have this much regret
about your own abortion,
then how can you go through
with this?
I know that that may have been
my one chance to get pregnant.
But still...
For me it was
the right decision
at the time.
I do not take this lightly,
Nai.
To try to separate
what I want personally
from what I need to do
professionally
is killing me.
I wanna strangle
the doctor
who botched this up
in the first place.
We've come so far,
right?
Then why can't Patty
get what she needs?
A safe and legal abortion
without judgment?
Why does she have
to go through this again?
Why do I have to go
through this?
I hate what I'm about to do,
but I support Patty's right
to choose.
It is not enough
to just have an opinion,
because in a nation
of over 300 million people,
there are only
1,700 abortion providers.
And I'm one of them.
Okay, Patty. We're ready.
Are you sure
about this?
Yeah, I'm sure.
This is what I want.
But I'm so scared.
I know.
I'm gonna take
good care of you.
I just feel so alone.
You're not alone, Patty.
You're not alone.
Addison:
Prep tray and foley cath.
You did everything
you could.
What if it's not enough?
What if the amount
of temporal lobe
I removed from Betsey
damaged her brain?
She could lose her ability
to speak,
if she even wakes up.
It's been a rough couple
of days.
The hospital can reach you
if there are any changes.
Why don't we go
to a meeting?
I'm grateful
that we are friends
and that you look out for me,
but...
You can't worry that every time
something goes wrong,
I'm gonna drink.
I'm gonna stay here.
But I will go to a meeting
with you tomorrow morning.
I promise.
Thank you.
I know that you were there
for Patty, but--
I was there
for the both of you.
You helped that woman.
I miss you, Nai.
I really miss you.
When you took Patty's hand
in there
and told her
she wasn't alone,
it broke my heart.
Because I am alone.
Somewhere along the way,
you let go of my hand.
And being alone,
it just sucks.
I want
my best friend back.
You wanna get a drink?
Yeah, I do. I do.
Ha, ha.
But, um, can I bring
some wine over later?
Sure. You have plans?
Um, what I have are a lot
of opinions.
It's time for me
to act on them.
What if she doesn't wake up?
Betsey's tough.
She'll come out okay.
What?
You. Ha, ha.
You never struck me
as the kid-friendly type.
I used to think
that anything that took me away
from the lab
was a waste of time.
But now, I don't know.
I guess I can see
the advantages of making space
in my life for others.
I can't go with you.
I love you, Naomi.
And I'm not sorry
I came back for you.
Because I do believe
you have to stand up
for the things
that truly matter.
But you also gotta recognize
when you've lost.
I'm leaving tomorrow.
She's gonna wake up,
right?
Charlotte:
She has to.
I'm lucky to have you,
Coop.
I don't ever want it to seem
like I take you for granted.
We can't take anything
for granted.
Hey, Betsey.
It's me.
It's Violet.
You know, you're right
to be mad at me.
Your dad would be so mad
at me too.
It's sad that the only way
I can talk to you
is when you can't hear me,
but, I don't know,
maybe you can.
Okay.
I'm sorry
that I lied to you.
I didn't want to,
but, uh...
I was afraid that if I told you
that foster care was...
I mean, if you thought that
where you were going
wasn't safe
and happy and full of love,
then it would make it harder
for you to go.
Or maybe it would just make
it harder
for me to see you leave.
I don't know.
But...
You have to know that I care.
And I wanted to help.
I mean, I wanna help now.
So...
So. Ahem.
I promise you
that I am going to find
some people for you
to live with
who will give you all the love
that you deserve.
And I'm not gonna
give up this time, okay?
So you better not
give up either.
Because you have--
you have so much life ahead
of you and you have
so many beautiful things
to look forward to.
But you have to wake up.
Violet?
Man:
What can I get you?
Vodka tonic.
But just one.
You're still here.
I promised.
Thanks for calling. Hey.
I heard you
were feeling better.
Where's my mommy?
Oh, honey.
I'm so sorry.
She loves you,
she does, but--
she doesn't want me anymore.
Will you listen? I'm gonna
find you a family, I swear.
And no matter where you are,
I'm gonna be a part
of your life.
Always.
Where am I gonna live now?
You're coming home with me.
She is?
For how long?
How about forever?
Really?
Really.
Thank you.