- Previously on The Resident...
- We want to make you
the director of our program,
but we need to know by next week.
- So, are you gonna take it?
- Is there anything left of us?
You're the one who made it clear
that not having kids
was a deal-breaker.
Kit Voss offered me a job.
Why would you leave Seattle Children's?
So that I can be closer to you.
You're a good man, Dr. Austin.
I think our child should
witness that firsthand.
- Our child?
- If you're still willing.
I've gone and fallen for someone.
You're afraid the guy's gonna say no?
Reinforcements are here to cheer you up.
I'm as afraid he'll say yes as I am
- he'll say no.
- Go tell the man how you feel.
Hope I'm not too early.
Not at all. Come on in.
- Beautiful evening.
- It is.
I've been looking forward
to this for a long time.
Thank you so much for
offering to babysit.
Are you kidding? I'm so excited.
I can't wait to meet Gigi.
Well, she's asleep now, but, um,
she'll be up in the
next couple of hours.
And if we're not back by then...
We're not gonna be back.
We're gonna live it up, Nic.
It's our first night
out since Gigi was born,
so someone has a little
separation anxiety.
You have nothing to worry about.
I took CPR training for infants,
and I have three younger siblings.
Emergency contacts, just in case.
There's pumped breast
milk in the fridge.
- We heat it up in the...
- The bottle warmer. I've got this.
And I will test it just to
make sure it's not too hot.
Great, and don't forget to
burp her and change her after.
Of course.
I'm more worried about
Nic than I am Gigi.
I'm right here.
You're gonna be fine.
Nice new jacket, Dr. Hawkins.
Ah, you like? Thanks.
Have a great time.
Just call if there's anything, okay?
Bye.
Somebody has a little crush.
Don't be ridiculous.
"Nice new jacket, Dr. Hawkins."
Mm.
♪ Across the railroad tracks... ♪
Daddy.
Daddy, green means go.
- ♪ I sit alone ♪
- Thanks, honey.
♪ And I think of losing you. ♪
Yo, everyone.
The illustrious doctor
scientist graces us peons
with his presence for the last time.
Oh, come on. You know,
I think I liked it better
when you just ignored me
when I showed up for my shift.
Better get into your scrubs.
You're a bit too big for those britches.
Poor guy's gonna hate Baltimore Hospital
for Advanced Science.
Do you know how cold
Baltimore gets in January?
And he's a fragile flower.
Oh, you don't fool me. I
know you're all crying inside.
I'm gonna miss you, a lot.
We're well aware what
this exit is about,
and it ain't science, or money,
because Dr. Voss would match any offer.
Talk to Leela.
Fix this.
I wish I could.
Help! We need help over here, please.
Can't... breathe.
All right, this way.
What's going on?
She-she was a little
short of breath last night.
We thought it was the
baby pressing on her lungs,
but she woke up like this.
- How far along is she?
- Five months.
Mommy, are you gonna be okay?
Of course, baby.
Hypoxemic. Elevated respiratory rate.
Rales up to the mid chest.
Sounds like pulmonary edema.
Let's get an EKG and get her on O2.
- Mommy?
- It's okay.
Can someone... take him?
I'll call Winston in social services.
He'll get someone to look after him.
Come with me, sweetheart.
Fetal heart rate sounds good.
Obvious movement.
The baby looks good.
- Praise God.
- Thank you.
Let's get a stat chest X-ray.
Page Dr. Austin.
What's wrong? What's happening?
Devon always kept the keys
in a bowl in the hallway.
Thank you so much for reminding me.
I'm sorry.
I just really want to get going.
I can't wait for the ultrasound.
Although I already know I'm
pregnant because I can feel it.
My stomach is doing flip-flops.
And guess what, I woke
up nauseous this morning.
I told you to not have
that pizza last night.
It's not the pizza, Leela. I feel...
- different, you know?
- Well, actually,
since I've never been
pregnant, no, I don't know.
Today's his last day, isn't it?
You guys broke up way too fast.
It's a pattern with you.
You're kind of a
relationship wrecking ball.
Oh, come on. Do you remember
when you dumped Rick Stamos
right before prom?
He was ripped and a quarterback,
and you had a killer dress.
- I caught him making out with a cheerleader.
- Hmm.
He can't wait to go.
He's leaving Atlanta tomorrow.
He's only sticking around
for Kit and Bell's
engagement party tonight.
I know he still loves you. Okay?
Everyone knows he still loves you.
And sometimes you can't always see
what's right before your eyes.
There is still time.
Dr. Sullivan, where's your walker?
I know you're feeling better,
but you shouldn't be on your feet alone.
I am discharging myself
from the hospital.
- You... you can't do that.
- Yes, I can.
I'm a doctor.
You can't be your own doctor.
I know my own body, and I feel fine.
Besides, work is the best medicine.
If you're your own doctor,
does that also make you
your own worst patient?
- Ha ha.
- You only got shot three times.
Why don't you go run a
10K while you're at it?
You know what? You are just
the person I was looking for.
Look what you left in my
room on your last visit.
Mr. Giraffe!
He must have been scared in
that dark drawer all by himself.
No, not in the least, he was sleeping.
He's a sleepyhead, but
he did poke his head out
- to ask for some leaves for dinner.
- Silly.
He doesn't eat leaves, he
eats chocolate ice cream.
Oh, right.
I'll drop Gigi at preschool
and meet you in your dad's room.
His lab results are in.
How are you feeling, Dad?
Fine.
No lingering symptoms?
It's been a day and a
half since my little fall.
I'm much better.
Well, it was more than
just a fall. You passed out.
Why are you getting dressed?
- I'm discharging myself.
- You...
You can't be your own doctor.
Oh, wow.
The apple fell directly under the tree.
My father and I are both doctors
who also happen to be patients.
Other than that, we are nothing alike.
Of course you're not. Your labs.
You're profoundly anemic.
Your stomach pain is
getting worse, right?
Combine that with your collapse...
Bleeding ulcer is top of the list.
Ridiculous. No acid
reflux. No indigestion.
- Any blood in your stool?
- Okay.
Before we discuss my bowel
movements in greater detail,
can we clarify...
which of you is my actual doctor?
You need more tests.
There may be a simple explanation
for what's going on here,
but until we find it,
you aren't going anywhere.
Your vision is fine, Randolph.
You had an MS flare.
Okay. Well, yeah, it was kind of rough.
They're not unexpected,
especially near the optic nerve.
With an extra pulse of steroids,
you'll be back to normal.
This should be nothing to worry about.
See? It's great news.
You're good to go back in the OR.
I'm clearing you for surgery.
Great.
I know that look. Talk to me.
Every MS flare feels like
it's the beginning of the end.
The pain is excruciating,
and you're afraid
it's getting worse, but
you're catastrophizing.
- You heard the doctor.
- It is progressive.
Not necessarily.
You could go into total remission.
I love your optimism.
I'm about to marry
Chastain's finest surgeon,
who will hold that
title for years to come.
Please, tell me whatever is happening
isn't going to... harm my baby.
Right now, let's focus
on you, Mom, all right?
Your echocardiogram is showing
that your heart isn't
pumping strong enough
to support you and the baby.
W-what does that mean?
It means that your wife
is in heart failure.
No, how-how can this be happening?
Have you had any health issues recently?
Flu... a few weeks ago.
I-it was pretty bad,
but she finally got better.
Help me!
Step aside, please. It's okay.
Acute hypoxemic respiratory failure.
Pulmonary edema is worsening,
which means her heart function is, too.
Pressure's dropping.
Hanging a norepi drip.
We're having a baby girl.
We've hoped for one
since Miguel was born.
We-we cannot lose this baby.
She's decompensating fast.
We need to intubate now.
Come here.
We are trying to save your wife's life.
Let us work so can
save both mom and baby.
Okay.
Nic.
I forgot to tell Marion to leave
the night-light on in Gigi's room.
I left it on.
How about we put all phones
away just for the next hour?
Well, your new girlfriend
has to be able to reach me.
Oh, she's on my speed dial.
How convenient.
- ♪ The sun goes down on my side of town... ♪
- Wow.
"Neon Moon."
Same song that was playing
right here on our first date.
You don't remember what song
was playing on our first date.
I do. It was "Neon Moon."
- It's always playing on a jukebox somewhere.
- Hmm.
How about we go right to the
dancing part of the evening?
♪ I got a table for
two way in the back ♪
♪ Where I sit alone ♪
♪ And I think of losing you ♪
- ♪ I spend most every night ♪
- This is nice.
♪ Beneath the light ♪
♪ Of a neon moon. ♪
- Winston.
- Hundley?
Yes.
The mom is critical, but
the dad is calmer now.
He wants his son with him.
- Okay.
- Come on, sweetie.
Let's go see your daddy.
Winston.
Dr. Hawkins.
Yeah. Do you have a minute?
I have two minutes. Walk
with me back to my office.
What's going on?
I have a personal question for you.
- Hope you don't mind me asking.
- No, go on.
Well, you know I lost my wife.
Yes. I'm so sorry.
Devon told me you lost someone, too.
A partner who died suddenly.
Yeah, we were together almost 20 years.
He had a heart attack.
Was totally unexpected.
So you know about grief.
I do. It was overwhelming.
How did you cope?
For a while, quite badly.
I almost let what I'd lost destroy me.
But eventually I realized
I had one life to live,
and I wanted it to mean something.
I have my daughter, and that saved me.
But no matter what I do,
for the last four years,
I just can't let Nic go.
I keep remembering this
one specific evening.
First date after we had Gigi.
Maybe you shouldn't
fight these memories.
Maybe they're trying
to tell you something.
The past never goes away.
If you don't deny it,
you can learn from it.
Mr. Alvarez.
How's my wife?
We managed to stabilize her.
Thank God.
And thank you both.
Her heart was damaged,
likely from the flu she had recently.
What she has is post-viral myocarditis.
Her pregnancy makes this
even more life-threatening.
Her heart isn't strong
enough now to beat for two.
We're so sorry to say this,
but the only safe
option for Trini is to...
is to end the pregnancy.
What?
N-no.
No, that-that's impossible.
Y-you're talking
about killing the baby.
That would be murder.
We can't deliver the
baby at five months.
It's not viable.
We understand your pain is enormous.
But we believe your wife will
not survive if we don't do this.
Mr. Alvarez, your son
will lose his mother.
Honestly, it's not a choice.
We can only save one life.
- Hers.
- No.
I-I will not accept this.
There has to be another way.
There is no safe way.
Please, there has to be!
Dr. Voss, we have a problem.
We have a patient who has
to terminate her pregnancy
to save her own life.
Her heart is failing.
- God, how awful.
- The husband is certain
there's more we can do
to save both mom and baby.
And is there?
All we can offer is an
incredible long shot,
almost certain to fail.
And what does the patient want to do?
She can't make the
decision. She's intubated.
Her husband is her health care proxy.
So the real question is,
do we even suggest this alternative
that we think is far too dangerous?
Oh, this is a tough one.
But if he won't agree
to end the pregnancy
to save her life, you have no choice.
Just make the consequences
of your plan crystal clear
so he knows the risks he's taking.
Dad, do not move. You know better.
I have an itch.
We're almost done.
I don't want him to be sick,
but please tell me he can go home.
Let's figure out what's
wrong with him first,
then plan next steps.
I'm so sorry.
He has pancreatic cancer.
I'm a doctor, a good one.
And I had no clue.
Well, that's not unexpected, Dad.
Pancreatic cancer, it can often be
asymptomatic until it's too late.
Okay, thank you for clarifying.
I must have skipped the part
about pancreatic cancer
at medical school.
I'm just trying to help.
Well, you can't help.
Look, I've just been
handed a death sentence.
All right, how long?
How long do I have?
Pancreatic cancer is
a terrifying diagnosis.
For most,
five-year survival rate
is less than ten percent,
but your odds are different.
Look at the scans again.
The tumor appears...
localized at the head of the pancreas.
Yes, which means it's operable.
Now, five-year survival rate
goes up dramatically to 25%.
A cure is possible?
It is. Yes.
Cade, you hear that?
If the cancer hasn't spread.
- You need a complicated procedure.
- The Whipple.
We have a world-renowned
surgeon right here at Chastain.
He's performed the
Whipple hundreds of times.
Dr. Randolph Bell.
Still a dangerous surgery
that could have serious
complications, but...
Okay, can you please stop
measuring me for a coffin?
Let's just be positive for one minute.
Is it too much to ask?
Dr. Hawkins just said
I can survive this.
Since it's obvious I'm not helping,
I'm going to step out now.
You know, if anyone can
survive this, you can.
Well, that went well.
You're under unimaginable stress.
But...
I think you need to recognize
that this is hard for
your daughter also.
Can you take the young man out to
the waiting room for a few minutes?
- Thank you.
- It's okay.
- No problem.
- Thank you.
Mr. Alvarez, we still
recommend you end the pregnancy,
today if possible. It is by
far the best chance for Trini.
Although there is another
option that we can try.
What is this option?
Well, we could put Trini
on a machine called an ECMO.
It would ease the stress
of her struggling heart,
and it might perhaps buy us some time
and keep her alive for a few more months
until she can deliver the baby safely.
That sounds perfect.
- Do it.
- No, it is far from perfect.
You have to understand
that ECMO is very dangerous.
There can be complications
like hemorrhage, stroke,
- infection.
- Brain damage is possible.
She could wind up paralyzed.
Unable to speak. Blind.
And she could die from
any of these complications.
Then the baby would die as well.
But there's a chance
that Trini and the baby could
both be fine with this ECMO?
That is a remote
possibility, Mr. Alvarez.
So, let's be clear, you are giving up
the absolute best chance that we have
of saving your wife's life.
Listen.
If we end the pregnancy now,
down the road, she can
safely have another child.
My heart tells me that
you can save them both,
and I believe that Trini
would want you to try.
Please.
Why does he lash out at me?
He's scared.
Obviously, things have
not been easy between you.
But now is the time for
patience and understanding.
Of course.
I love him.
Despite the fact that I can't remember
the last time he said he loved me.
When I was little,
all the other kids thought
I had the coolest dad.
Charmed them all.
Bought them all ice cream.
Entertained them at my birthday parties.
It took a while to realize that he lives
for the reflection he sees of
himself in other people's eyes,
and I see him too clearly.
Forgiveness and acceptance
is a beautiful thing.
I didn't even talk to
my father for years.
I realized our problems
were a two-way street.
I wasn't as blameless as I thought.
So...
I gave him a chance,
and he was capable of
more than I ever could've imagined.
Now we couldn't be closer.
You only get one father.
You can't change him,
and you may lose him.
Now's the time to accept him as he is.
Thank you.
♪ Dear troubles I long to forget ♪
♪ It seems so many of you
have collected in a day... ♪
Oh, Nic, it's not what you think.
- What are you doing?
- Her name is Anna.
Oh, Anna. Great.
Not exactly the image I want
in my head when I'm at home
nursing our daughter
and changing her diapers.
Will you just let me explain?
Honestly, I just want to go home.
Let's just go somewhere
and talk about it.
Once you know who she is,
you'll feel very differently.
♪ Defaulted in pain and sorrow... ♪
Okay.
I diagnosed Anna's husband
with stage 4 lymphoma
- two months ago.
- Well, if her husband's so sick,
then why is she at a bar alone?
She isn't. She's with her girlfriends.
It's her birthday.
And her husband's in the hospital
after having a bad reaction to chemo.
He's in the ICU.
Her friends decided
to get her out and away
from a situation she couldn't control.
She'll go back in a few hours.
Sleeps in his room.
Wow.
I am so sorry.
I didn't know.
You have nothing to be worried about.
You're the only woman I've loved
since the first moment I saw you.
And I can't imagine life without you.
Oh, I love you.
I'm sorry.
I'll talk to Bell and book an OR, okay?
Just tell me. I can't wait any longer.
Is it good news?
Look for yourselves, ladies.
Leela.
It's a miracle.
♪ Sista, sista! ♪
There's only one thing that
could make this day happier.
This pregnancy journey, it
drove you and Devon apart.
So, please, before it's too late,
talk to him and tell him you love him.
Hey. Came to say goodbye?
We need to talk.
That's a good idea.
Let's part as friends.
Actually, I was hoping
for something different.
I don't want you to go.
Leela, I start at Baltimore
Advanced Sciences on Monday.
I want to try again.
I'm not happy.
You're not happy.
I miss you.
And I think you miss me.
Yeah, I miss you a lot.
But nothing's changed, has it?
Actually, something has changed.
This is my patient on
ECMO. She's desatting.
I want to talk to you about
this, but I have to go, okay?
Promise me we'll talk later.
I have a big surgery, but
if you're still here...
If not, I'll see you
at the engagement party.
Her pressure spiked just
as her heart rate dropped.
Cushing's reflex.
Classic sign of stroke.
It happened faster than we imagined.
I'm going to adjust her arterial support
to get her blood pressure
in a tighter range.
It might be too late.
Let's get her to CT, all right?
And page Billie.
Images coming up.
Here's the problem.
Bleed, left side of the brain.
- Hemorrhagic stroke?
- Mm-hmm. Definitely.
Damage may be extensive.
Potentially paralyzed.
I mean, she may have lost
the ability to speak forever.
And worse still, this
could just be the beginning.
I see more possible
bleeds near the dura.
I mean, this could have been avoided.
Did you make her husband understand
this was likely to happen?
Come on, man, don't you think we tried?
We advised against it
in the strongest terms,
but he is her health care proxy.
And we had no idea that she would
have complications this fast.
Look, all we can do now is double
down on trying to save Trini,
no matter what condition she's in,
and hope we can keep
her on ECMO long enough
for her heart to recover
or for the baby to mature
enough to be viable.
Can you guys give us a minute?
Look, I am perfectly aware
of the risks of this surgery,
so I know that I may not
get off that OR table.
You got the best of me.
And none of the bad.
I am so proud of you,
and I always have been.
You are the child of my heart...
... and if I haven't said it enough,
then I need to say it now.
I love you.
All right.
Now go back to being a tough
bastard and beat this thing.
You got it.
Hi, baby.
Aw. Hi.
- Update me.
- We troubleshot everything,
but as you can see...
Her heart's giving out.
She has a few minutes left, maybe.
Excuse me, excuse me. What's going on?
What's happening to Trini?
Mr. Alvarez, I am terribly sorry...
... but your wife is dying.
Just keep her on the machine, right?
You said that it would
take over for her heart.
- Let it keep working.
- We can't.
Her heart is too badly damaged.
We tried to tell you
this was a long shot.
It didn't work. I'm so sorry.
No. Please.
No.
Mommy?
Do something! Please do something!
Please.
There's nothing more we can do.
We can't bring her back.
She's gone, Matias.
No.
Don't tell me that. Don't tell me that.
And with that,
we dissect the pancreas.
Pancreas is mobilized.
Oh, wait. W...
What's the update?
Well,
looks like the tumor
has adhered to the IVC.
Which means they have to resect it.
- If they nick the IVC...
- That's not gonna happen.
Bell's done this thousands of times.
Dr. Devi...
- ... all yours.
- What is he doing?
He can't pass this off to a resident.
- Leela has never done a Whipple.
- Which is why she has to learn.
Bell's there to back her up.
Satinsky clamp, 3.0 Prolene,
sponge stick and forceps.
Dr. Chu, do you have
Rh null blood up there?
- I do.
- Hang it, please.
We're in for some turbulence. Clamp on.
Dissecting the tumor off now.
Blood pressure's in the toilet.
Going up on pressors.
Okay, Dr. Devi has
finished the dissection.
She anticipated this.
I've identified the defect,
but I'm having a hard time
- getting in position for repair.
- Well, remember your anatomy.
This is Cade's father,
so maybe in this case, you should...
The Whipple is the crucible
of a surgical residency,
it's the final test.
Just get in there and ace it.
It's your OR, Dr. Devi.
- Proceed.
- Right.
Dr. Chu, reverse positioning
of the patient, please.
Okay, that's excellent.
You have a clear path to the defect.
3.0 Prolene to you.
Closing and oversewing.
Hemodynamics settling.
That's strong work, Dr. Devi.
She rose to the occasion.
Yes, she did.
He's gonna make it out
of the OR, isn't he?
Yeah.
Now we just have to make
sure the cancer hasn't spread.
We'll know in a few hours.
♪ Should I stay or should I go now? ♪
Oh, I was so glad you
guys could make it.
- Thank you for coming.
- Thank you for including me.
- Yeah, so happy to be here.
- So, Randolph, what's your secret?
How did you land such an
incredible lady like this?
She has very low standards.
Nope. Nothing but the
best for this lady.
So, when's the wedding?
- Uh, still working on that.
- Mm...
But rest assured, it will
be intimate and fabulous.
And you're all invited.
- Hear, hear.
- Cheers.
♪ Should I stay or should I go? ♪
Hey.
Hey. I got here early so we could talk.
I heard you aced the Whipple.
That's not what I want to talk about.
Do you still feel the
same way you did before?
I do.
I can't promise I'll want a child
in the future, but maybe I will.
- I don't know.
- Today I watched a man
sacrifice his wife's best chance to live
for a baby that hasn't even been born.
He lost them both.
- That's terrible.
- Yes.
But it made me realize
something about myself.
That I'm doing the same thing,
choosing a hypothetical child
that may never exist
over the woman I love.
♪ Roses are falling... ♪
I was at fault, too.
I was impulsive and rash.
And our life together
has to be a decision
that we both make equally.
Do you want to try this again?
- Yes.
- Yeah.
♪ Roses are falling for you, ooh... ♪
A thousand times yes.
♪ Roses from falling for you, ooh... ♪
I have a lovely feeling that Devon
will not be going to Baltimore.
That is a win all around.
You know I pulled Leela into the Whipple
because she's the one who
can follow in my footsteps?
She's going into neuro or cardio, right?
Oh, she just told me she
wants to be a general surgeon.
So I get to teach her everything I know
and she can take my
patients when the time comes.
If the time comes.
Dr. Bell?
I just want to say thank you
for saving my father's life today.
Well, Dr. Devi was integral.
But we got lucky and your
father got even luckier.
The pathology report came back
just before I left the hospital
and the tumor was localized.
So, there's every chance
he'll be cancer-free.
♪ And I'll do my best ♪
I am so happy for both of you.
♪ To be better than the rest ♪
Thank you.
♪ She is so ♪
♪ So sweet and tender ♪
Come here.
♪ And I'm glad ♪
♪ So glad we made it, girl ♪
♪ She's so ♪
♪ So sweet and tender ♪
♪ And I'm glad ♪
♪ So glad we're making love ♪
♪ Oh, I... ♪
I'm pregnant.
Wow. Ah.
So, I'm gonna be a father.
Yes, and I want you to
know that I'm open to you
being as involved as you'd like.
I know you're gonna be a loving dad
and a great role model.
Just meet me halfway and... listen?
I can do that.
But what can I do for you now?
Hmm, maybe open up another 529 account?
For college?
Why would we need two accounts?
♪ So much more than pretty... ♪
We're having twins.
Are you serious?
Yes.
♪ So sweet and tender ♪
♪ And I'm glad ♪
♪ So glad we made it, girl ♪
♪ She is so ♪
♪ So sweet and tender ♪
♪ And I'm glad ♪
- Wonder what that's all about.
- ♪ So glad we're making love... ♪
Well, it's good news, obviously.
I was happy to hear about your dad.
Rumor has it that Kit may offer him
the peds surgery job at Chastain.
I heard. I have mixed
feelings about that.
It would be a big adjustment.
Conrad will help you with that.
He already has.
Uh, so the two of you...
Uh, we're friends.
♪ So sweet and tender... ♪
I mean, I was under the
impression that you and he...
Are also friends.
So far.
I'll be right back, okay?
Hey.
Mm, wild guess,
you're not taking the
job at Advanced Sciences.
And I won't be sleeping
on your sofa anymore.
God, I am so done with your furniture.
That's the best news I've heard all day.
Why are you sitting over here alone?
Get out there and party.
Waylon's...
This is where I met Nic.
We had our first date here.
Our first date after Gigi was
born. A lot of memories here.
Well...
maybe it's time to make new memories.
♪ There's a run-down bar
'cross the railroad tracks ♪
♪ I've got a table for
two, way in the back ♪
♪ Where I sit alone ♪
♪ And I think of losing you ♪
♪ I think of two young
lovers, running wild and free ♪
♪ I close my eyes
and sometimes see ♪
♪ You in the shadows... ♪
Thank you for a lovely night out.
Thank you for being kind about Anna.
Her husband doesn't have much longer.
There's something else
I wanted to tell you.
They have a child.
A little boy. He won't
even remember his father.
That's awful.
We both know what it's
like to lose a parent.
I bought a life insurance policy.
- You did what?
- Yep.
A big one.
Well, you're not gonna die, so...
I certainly hope not.
Mm, that wasn't a
statement, that was an order.
You know, maybe stop
riding your bike to work.
Maybe ease up on the
search and rescue missions.
No matter how careful I
am, anything could happen.
I could get hit by a bolt of lightning.
- Stop, come on.
- We have to talk about this for a reason.
Watching Anna and her
husband in the hospital,
it just made me think,
what if that was me...
... in that hospital bed?
You know, I don't want to talk
about any of this right now.
- Just drop it.
- If something happens to me,
I want you to be secure financially,
and I want you to love someone again.
I mean, don't bring
a date to my funeral.
Oh, my God. Seriously?
Come on.
Unless they're nice and Gigi likes them.
- Then that's fine, okay?
- Conrad.
After a while, I do want you to move on.
You deserve happiness,
and Gigi deserves a father.
Just promise me, whoever it is...
... you'll find someone who
loves you as much as I do.
Hey.
I promise.
Only if you do, too.
♪ Oh, if you lose your one and only ♪
♪ There's always room
here for the lonely ♪
♪ To watch your broken dreams dance ♪
♪ In and out of the beams ♪
♪ Of a neon moon ♪
♪ Oh, if you lose your one and only ♪
♪ There's always room
here for the lonely ♪
♪ To watch your broken dreams ♪
♪ Dance in and out of the
beams of a neon moon. ♪
- Synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -