The Harper Avery is
one of the highest awards
a surgeon can earn.
They always make the
calls to the nominees
on the same Friday
of the same month
at 8:00 a.m. east coast time.
5:00 a.m. in Seattle.
Crap, Mer! Oh, my
God! The phone!
Mer! Oh, the phone!
I'm sorry! No, the phone.
Okay, okay, okay.
Did we remember to...
No, no, it's charged. Oh, God!
It's charged, and the
ringer's on. Okay, hold on.
You got to put on
some lipstick. Here.
My mother was nominated five
times. I've been through this before.
What if...
No, it's not possible,
because Catherine Avery said
that you were on the short list,
and your project
is... It's innovative.
It's gonna lead to the
actual printing of hearts.
Millions will be saved.
What time is it? 5:01.
Did they? Not yet.
Did they? No.
Oh, God!
Okay, listen, if there are five
nominees, it's alphabetical.
Yang is last.
Oh!
Oh, geez, hairball! Oh, sorry!
It's Shane. What are you...
Hey. No. Not yet,
but it's still early.
It's... 5:02.
If the phone rings,
everything changes.
Suddenly, you're a superstar.
If it doesn't... I don't know.
My mom was a superstar.
She always got the call.
Mer, seriously, what
if they don't call?
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
What do I do? Answer it.
It's Boston. It's
Boston. It's them.
Okay.
Wait, wait, wait. Okay. Okay.
You are gonna be
gracious and humble.
You are gonna thank them,
but you are not gonna grovel.
You remember who you
are. You are Cristina Yang,
and you are going to
change the face of medicine.
Go. Just answer the damn phone!
Quiet!
Stay still.
Hello?
Yes, this is Cristina Yang.
He said "we"?
You're sure Shane said "we"?
He said, "Did we
get the nomination?"
The way he sees it, he
and Yang just got nominated
for the highest surgical
honor in the land.
He's gonna be insufferable now.
We have to knock him down a
peg. He's still your swap monkey.
I can't do that today.
I'm not that horrible.
You kind of are.
Hey, Frankie. Hey.
Cristina got nominated!
This is her getting the call.
She's wearing
lipstick at 5:00 a.m.?
That's cute. Hey, Frankie.
We got a round soon,
so don't be late. Okay.
All right, I'm gonna get
these guys into daycare,
and then I'll see
you at the MEG.
All right. I'll meet you there.
See you. Yeah.
You guys got a MEG? Yeah.
It's gonna make
screening candidates
for the trial so
much more efficient.
Doesn't that cost
like a jillion dollars?
Yeah. Derek working for
the government has its perks.
Oh, you want a Harper Avery.
I want to make an
amputee walk using robotics,
and if I win a Harper
Avery in the process,
I won't turn it down.
Well, now's the time.
I mean, Sofia's
almost in school all day,
and the time-consuming
baby days are over.
Unless they're not.
Oh, I say we quit
while we're ahead.
Yeah. Yeah. Sofia's pretty
perfect. Why tempt fate?
Yeah, and I can actually
finally have a thought.
Is that thought, "Where's
my Harper Avery?"
Ooh, hey, maybe.
All right. Maybe.
Hey, Frankie.
Morning, Dr. Avery.
Hey, are you named after that
big award, the Harper Avery?
It's actually named
after me, after my family.
How did you hear about...
Okay. Hey.
Hey. Did you go home?
I must have missed you.
Yeah, I had a 14-year-old
GSW. It was so bloody.
I felt nasty after surgery,
so I went home to change.
Cool news about
Yang, though, huh?
Yeah.
You really didn't know?
I'm telling you, the
nominating committee
is totally separate
from the foundation.
I'm just like everybody else.
Only way handsomer.
Is that a swimsuit?
Yes, I ran out of
clean underwear
and haven't had a
chance to do laundry.
Which is why you send it out.
We have a perfectly good
washing machine at the house.
Says the doctor in a speedo.
Paying someone to do your
laundry is an extravagance.
How much did that coffee cost?
Four bucks.
So, that's like,
what, six a week?
That's like... Give me
a second. Carry the...
Like $1,000 a year
you're just throwing away.
It's not like I'm spending it
on hookers or private planes.
It's a latte.
I'm gonna get you one
of those milk-frothy things.
I'm gonna teach you how
to make your own latte.
Will you do it in that swimsuit?
Hmm? Stop.
Okay, so there was a gang
shooting last night, so the ER's crazy.
And that preemie I told you
about? She gained two ounces,
and the nurses are like,
"Doesn't she look fat?"
And I'm like, "No, she
looks like a naked mole rat."
And my doctor got
nominated for some prize,
and everyone's really jealous.
That's cool.
Not as cool as that.
Yeah.
My parents try to
distract me from the fact
that I'm trapped in a bubble.
Well, aren't you getting
some test results back today
that are gonna get you out?
Yeah.
Here they come. Come visit me.
My brother's room is
end of the hall on the right.
Well, there he is.
Hey, Brady bug.
Braden.
Up high, champ. Hi, baby.
Mom, why are you crying?
Oh, I'm...
I'm not.
I'm sorry. I can't.
Unfortunately, your
T-cell count is still zero.
Your infection
is almost cleared,
but we were hoping for
your T cell count to respond.
I get it.
But I don't understand
why my mom's crying.
There's got to be other
stuff you guys can try.
You're not gonna make me live
in this bubble for the rest of my life.
Dad?
It's not so simple, bud.
Your body has no
ability to fight infection,
and the enzyme's
not working anymore.
Bone-marrow transplants in
kids with SCID can be effective,
so we're still
looking for a match.
They've been looking for a
match for me since I was a baby,
and they haven't found one.
What if you still can't?
No other treatment
for your disease exists.
We're working on it,
but for the time being,
your only safe place
is right where you are.
Hey, Frankie. You're late.
I'm not a patient anymore,
so I don't have to be at rounds.
But you do.
You're right. I'm late.
Want to race? Yeah. Come on.
I got you! Come on! Come on!
Hey, hey! Slow down!
That's not fair! Come on!
Hey, Linkie.
I got you a
chocolate chip muffin
for when you're feeling better.
Well, how are you
feeling, Frankie?
Pretty good. She just
beat me in a race, so...
Looks like that pacemaker
I put in is working.
And...
Seriously, Ivy.
Sour-cream-and-onion
chips for breakfast?
You said I should put on weight.
Good.
So, two weeks
post-op heart transplant,
and Ivy's indices are excellent.
And Mr. Link?
Lincoln McNeil, age 9,
end-stage heart failure,
awaiting transplant, status 1A.
There's a family
history of the disease.
The cause is still unknown.
Link first showed signs of
cardiomyopathy two weeks ago
and has deteriorated rapidly.
An attempt to put him
on a Berlin Heart failed...
Due to something
I can't remember.
Clotting.
That's it.
The patient is now
on ECMO and is...
Stable.
I couldn't have
said it better myself.
Thanks. So, where
are we with UNOS?
Well, Link is at
the top of the list.
How much longer can
he survive on ECMO?
Well, with sweep
numbers this low...
At least a week.
So, we pray for a miracle?
We got one with Ivy.
We're not just sitting
around and waiting.
We are aggressively
looking at other options.
In the meantime...
Heart-healthy food, okay?
So, I put a call in to
these guys from Stanford
who are doing animal testing
with a drug-eluting pump
to prevent clotting.
Never been tried on
humans, but Link is a little kid.
The fit might be
right. It could work.
I'll let you guys
know what they say.
So, that's how
you're gonna play this,
act like it's just another
day at the office?
It is.
No, see, I need details.
So, what did they say?
"Congratulations." And
then what did you say?
"Thank you."
Cristina... No,
no, really, really,
it's just a nomination.
I'm happy about it, but
I've got a ton of work to do.
I want to focus on that.
I really don't want to
make a big deal out of it.
Hey, hey. Let's
go this way. Yeah.
You know, get some breakfast?
Why? I got my chips.
Surprise!
Congratulations, Dr. Yang!
Whose idea was this?
Meredith's.
Congratulations, Yang.
Innovation.
Imagination. Excellence.
Oh, soak it in, doctors.
It's all around you.
It's mostly hovering
around Dr. Yang,
and Shane's kind of hogging her.
I'm not just talking
about Dr. Yang.
Dr. Shepherd is
testing a new machine
that can read emotions
and has applications
for the work that he
and Dr. Torres are doing.
Torres! Me!
Hey, Dr. Grey is
about to do the first
HIV-positive-to-positive
kidney transplant in the state
since the new law went
into effect in November.
That's history in
the making. It's mine.
And Dr. Bailey's looking for
a genetic cure for a kid
who lacks an immune system.
Edwards?
I was on her service yesterday.
She's not doing anything.
She's just staring at
a computer screen.
That is not nothing.
She's thinking.
Her brain is turning,
building up to that
moment of inspiration.
It'll look like nothing, but in a
moment... Pow! The Fourth of July.
Don't blink. You'll miss it.
It was like that with me
and Yang at first, too.
A lot of staring at computer
screens, and now look at us.
Oh, Shane.
Oh, Shane, Shane, Shane.
No.
I wasn't gonna do
this to you today.
I really wasn't. Was I, ladies?
She wasn't. Hand to God.
But you just got too
big for your britches.
It's not even interesting stuff.
I'm just in the printing lab
making sample conduits.
Well, not anymore, swap monkey!
Enjoy working with Dr. Bailey.
Pow! Fourth of July!
Sucks. Swap monkey!
Okay, guys, bear with me.
I know we've gone
through all this before,
but the hospital just needs
your consent one more time.
Go ahead, Murphy.
State your name.
Keith Kalber.
Keith, you understand that
the kidney you're getting today
is being donated from a
person infected with HIV?
I should hope so.
I was there the day
he got his diagnosis.
And although small, there
is a risk of superinfection
by mixing his strain
of the virus with yours.
Knowing this, do you
still wish to proceed?
I do.
God, it feels like
we're getting married.
How would you
know how that feels?
Excuse me?
He always has the best
boyfriends, but he refuses to commit.
Can we just get back
to my huge sacrifice?
Marty, you understand
that the risks of donation
are similar to those involved
with any major surgery, such
as bleeding and infection?
And death resulting
from kidney donation
is extremely rare.
Define "extremely."
.06%.
Um...
We've beaten worse odds.
Oh, yeah.
Now, before we drill
into someone's brain,
we need to make sure they're
good candidates for robotics work.
They need to be motivated,
stable, and neurologically healthy.
This machine gives
us a window into all that.
Hmm-mmm. Yeah, you're
gonna be our baseline.
So, we're just gonna
show you some pictures,
and all you need
to do is look at them.
Okay, Wilson, you ready?
That's the amygdala, right?
It's fired up by powerful
negative emotions,
like fear, rage,
anger, and hate.
Okay, now let's take a look
at her nucleus accumbens.
Her pleasure center? Hmm-mmm.
That's not supposed to happen.
Wilson, what's wrong with
you? You don't like cats?
Hate 'em.
What's wrong with the beach?
Sand in my eyes, skin cancer,
vacations I never got to take as a child.
Uh-oh. Open comminuted
radius fracture in the ER.
There we go. Look at that.
Took a broken arm
to make her happy.
I turned her on to ortho a
few weeks ago. Watch this.
Hey, Wilson, you want to
go set that arm yourself?
I love our new toy.
Yang get too fancy for you, kicked
you down here to the "B" team?
Oh, no. I wanted to see
the work you're doing.
Genome sequencing
is the future of medicine.
May not be a fancy surgery,
but it's gonna save lives.
You want to save lives, or
go to fancy award dinners?
Save lives. Don't get me wrong.
I'm happy for Dr. Yang.
Why wouldn't I be?
I trained her, molded her.
It's almost like it's
my nomination, too.
Keith and Marty are good to go.
Yes. Your high-profile
kidney transplant.
I thought you were
harvesting the donor.
Yeah, while you do
the award-winning stuff.
Yeah, I remember.
Page me when you're ready.
Trained her, too.
Thank you so much
for getting back to me.
I hear you're developing a
drug-eluting cardiac pump
that's getting excellent
results in sheep.
Yes, that's me.
Well, there are four
other excellent surgeons
who are nominated. Thank you.
Yes. Anyway, I
have a young patient.
He's on day 10 of ECMO
and has a protein S deficiency.
Sorry?
I'm 3D printing conduits
for HLHS patients.
Yeah.
Well, I think my patient would
be an excellent candidate
for a compassionate release.
In here. I see.
Oh, God. Oh, no, no, no. What?
The little boy's ECMO
circuit clotted off,
and he's not
responding to fluids.
Page Dr. Hunt and Dr. Robbins.
Okay, let's get
him off that bed...
Dr. Yang?
Dr. Yang, is
everything all right?
Dr. Yang? Hello?
She can't talk right now.
He's clotting, even
on the heparin.
I can't give him any
more or he'll bleed out,
and I can't give him any
less or he'll keep clotting.
We need the
Stanford artificial heart.
We can't have it.
What?
It's not them. They
want to let us try.
It's the FDA.
They're being conservative and
insisting on one more animal trial.
They're six months
away from approval.
Okay, so what do we do?
We hope UNOS calls.
Today.
Yeah.
Okay, time to get you
prepped and ready for...
I can't do it.
Keith's right.
I mean, we've beaten huge odds.
We're still alive while so
many of our friends died.
And I've been healthy
for so long now.
You get a little cocky.
You forget how lucky you are.
And I...
I'm the most horrible
friend, but I just...
I'm scared.
What if I'm one of the .06%?
I don't think I can
give him my kidney.
Have you told Keith?
He's been suffering for so long,
and when the law was
passed, he was so happy.
And then I turned out
to be a perfect match.
And now...
How can I look my
best friend in the eye
and tell him I
won't save his life?
It is unfortunate,
but it does happen.
We misread the
screening, and it turns out
that Marty is not
a suitable donor.
I don't understand.
Yeah, this is outrageous.
I'm completely shocked.
So were we.
Shocked and disappointed.
So, what now?
Well, you'll
continue on dialysis
and go back on
the transplant list.
You know, it's ironic.
I spend years fighting HIV.
I get myself to the point
where the virus is virtually
nonexistent in my body.
I survive.
And now I die of kidney disease.
I'm so sorry. I'm so, so sorry.
It's not your fault. You tried.
You stepped up.
Oh, God.
I don't know what I
would do without you.
What do you do for a living?
I'm an orthopedic surgeon.
Do you enjoy
your work? I love it.
Are you married? Yep.
Any kids? One.
Would you consider
yourself a happy person?
Extremely.
And you want to
participate in this project?
I do.
No.
"No," what?
Judging by these results,
I'd say you are depressed,
and I would turn you
away from the study.
I'm not depressed.
Oh, it's no big deal. We can get
somebody else to
give us a baseline...
Derek, I'm not depressed.
Show me the kitten.
Yeah. See?
I'm happy.
Am I happy?
Nope.
Well...
Okay, well...
No! Why are you...
I really do love kittens.
I do.
Hey, Dr. Torres said you
have a thing for bones.
When you're done
with her patient,
you want to do a
mandibular ORIF?
Yes!
I see you have another beverage.
Iced tea, actually.
It's quite good.
Would you like some?
Oh, I'm perfectly
happy with my water.
Is that a...
Her swimsuit. Yeah. Racerback.
I ran out of underwear.
I'm not understanding.
You don't wear swimsuits when
you run out of clean underwear?
I don't run out of
clean underwear.
You're a resident. When do
you have time to do laundry?
I'm a doctor. I send it out.
Mmm.
The incision looks good.
Where are my parents?
They went to check out
a support group we have
for dealing with tough stuff.
I'm the one who's stuck in here.
You want to talk about it?
No.
Want to play checkers?
Chess?
No.
Come on. You got to let
me beat you at something.
I kind of feel like playing
with someone my own age.
Whoa! Whoa! Careful. You're
gonna rip through the plastic.
That's the point.
Surgery's off. It's off?
Donor backed out.
Please tell Cristina
I'm thrilled for her.
I'm sure she'd love
to hear it from you.
And I would love to
have that conversation,
but I am busy
trying to find a way
for a gene to proliferate
in the body of a young boy.
So, I would be most
grateful if you would extend
my heartfelt congratulations
to Dr. Yang for me.
Okay.
You said he was stable.
You said he had at least
one more week on ECMO.
We thought that we
had it under control,
and we didn't
expect for him to clot.
And six months ago, I
didn't expect any of this.
I was in a carpool
line picking up
my three happy,
healthy kids from school.
And now...
Now I have two kids in
end-stage heart failure
and one being kept
alive with a pacemaker.
You guys can't tell me
why my kids are sick,
and now you're
scratching your heads,
telling me that there's nothing
more you can do for Link except...
Except wait?
I thought you were supposed to
be some award-winning doctor.
Frankie.
My parents keep saying
you're doing your best,
but your best is bad.
Frankie, wait!
Frankie!
Dr. Yang?
I'm an intern here.
I just want to say congratulations.
You are totally gonna win.
Are you from the future? No.
Then shut up.
She means, "Thank you."
Anybody want some meatloaf?
Mmm-mmm.
Isn't that the meatloaf
you had yesterday?
Yep. And the day before that.
Probably gonna
have it tomorrow, too,
'cause there's still
a piece left at home.
Jackson doesn't eat
leftovers, you see.
He says he finds it depressing
to eat food out of a
Tupperware container.
You know what I find depressing?
Paying $7 for a hamburger.
Make her stop.
Her, too.
Hey.
It was low blood
sugar, Shepherd.
Take that food to go.
We're gonna do this again.
Come on! Come on! Let's go!
There she is.
The future of
medicine. How's it feel?
I don't want to talk about it.
Okay.
Your mother was the same way.
Didn't you have that
meatloaf yesterday?
Uh-huh.
Yep. And the day before that.
And probably gonna
have it tomorrow.
Dr. Grey? You're gonna kill me.
I'm gonna thank my
parents, obviously.
Why? They didn't help
you win the Harper Avery.
They gave birth to me.
They should be
publicly acknowledged.
I don't have parents,
so I'm not gonna waste
any of my speech on them.
It's gonna be all about
me. Humble, but...
Self-involved. Exactly.
Can you stop?
What's wrong, Shane?
Swap monkey misses his conduits?
Please. Swap back.
Bailey says she's on the verge.
No, Bailey's been on the
verge for days. I'm keeping Yang.
Where is it? What
are you looking for?
I'm looking for a picture
of the Harper Avery.
Oh! It's my screen saver.
I know what the
Harper Avery looks like.
I'm looking for a picture of
Ellis Grey's Harper Avery.
Why?
I remember being
in medical school
and looking at these
old medical journals
and seeing a picture of her
from the first time she won.
She was young. She
was like 35 or something.
I'm almost 35. You're 27.
My life is stupid and ordinary.
And I don't even know
what I'm doing here.
I'm never gonna
win a Harper Avery.
I might as well just move to
a farm and grow vegetables.
At least I'd be doing
something useful.
Her transplant got canceled.
You want to be on Bailey?
Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
Oh, my God!
Oh! Fries! Yeah!
The surgery is back on?
Well, kind of.
Marty felt terrible, so
he's back on board.
But we told Keith that
they weren't a good match.
You did what?
They're best friends,
and I was trying to help!
You got emotionally
involved. Rookie mistake.
I am not a rookie.
But I don't know how I'm
gonna go back and explain this.
Oh, I do.
Dr. Grey misread the labs.
Her relative inexperience
led to a terrible error.
You two are, in
fact, a perfect match.
Wow!
I mean, this is such great news.
So sorry, Keith.
I'm willing to just put all this
behind me and move forward.
Well, you know how
these young surgeons are.
It's all about PR and
awards, and they get sloppy.
He said he's ready
to move forward.
Luckily, I'm available
to do your transplant,
and I assure you I am
substance over flash.
I thought you were
doing Marty's surgery.
Well, I don't mind
taking Dr. Grey.
Well, why should you settle?
Well, she's, you know,
just taking out my kidney.
How hard could it be, you know?
But she can barely
read a lab report.
You don't know if
she's gonna mistake
your gallbladder
for your kidney.
Guys, I assure you,
I'm an excellent surgeon.
Why don't I get another
doctor to do Marty's surgery?
What?
A good idea.
Yes. Yes.
Thank you.
Yes.
Listen, we need this device.
This will buy the kid time
until a heart becomes available.
That's crap! You're the
FDA! You make the rules!
I just set a broken radius and
assisted on a mandibular ORIF.
How great is this day?
My kid's trapped in a
bubble for the rest of his life.
You and Bailey will figure it
out. That's how great this day is.
Imagination and
innovation are everywhere.
I'm seeing a lot of
misery and failure.
Alex.
Should I take the
private-practice job?
I thought you'd already decided
that you were gonna
call Dr. Butthole and...
So Yang's winning
awards, and I'm selling out?
You're not a sellout for taking a
job doing something that you love.
Private practice
was never the plan.
It was never supposed
to be about the money.
Well, there's nothing
wrong with making money.
What am I gonna buy? A
condo in Aspen? I don't even ski.
Not everyone
who's rich is an ass.
You could take the
job and not be an ass.
Braden? Braden!
Braden! Braden, where are you?
Where is he? Where is
my son? We can't find him!
Braden!
Watch it!
I'm gonna get
you! No, you're not!
No running in the halls.
Come here!
I got you! No, you didn't!
You're totally it.
Frankie! Don't
touch him! Braden!
You can't. He's
immuno-compromised.
Any more exposure,
even breathing on
him, puts him at risk.
Can everyone please
step away from the boy?
It's okay, son. Don't
worry. Brady bug,
we love you.
It's okay, son, all right?
Don't worry. Don't worry.
We're gonna be right here.
You're so strong. We're
not going anywhere.
Don't worry.
Mommy and Daddy are here, okay?
We're right here, son.
Don't worry.
Braden told me he was fine.
Mom...
Is Link gonna die?
I hope not.
But he's really sick.
He's even worse than Ivy was, and
you remember how bad she was?
What?
I have some good news.
It was a no. It was a hard no.
And then I realized
that Frankie was right.
You are a big-time doctor.
So I told them that you were
about to win a Harper Avery.
They placed the cardiac
pumps in 10 sheep hearts,
and 9 out of the 10
worked without clotting.
It's brilliant.
They put me on hold, and then
came back a few minutes later
and said okay.
Just like that... Boom.
Suddenly, you have clout.
Suddenly, you
can get things done.
Using the sheep was perfect.
Their hearts are about
the same size as Link's.
Parents signed consent.
They put the device
on the next plane.
I got Wilson coordinating
with the airlines.
How the hell did you talk
the FDA into doing that?
You're not gonna believe this.
Okay. It was a no. It
was a hard no. And then...
Quiet! Please!
I've got about four hours to
get through all their research.
Can you please take
the party outside?
San Francisco's fogged in. They've
grounded all commercial flights
for at least another
couple of hours.
Well, he's getting worse.
I don't think that he
has that kind of time.
Let's go.
Ross will transport the
kidney once I take it out,
and then you'll join
me for the transfer.
Roger that.
You okay, Ross? You got this?
Ross!
Swap monkey. You can
have your conduits back.
I'm good.
No. Hey! I called swap monkey.
Don't you go into that
OR. Don't you dare!
Too late!
Damn it, Ross.
Hi. I was...
Never mind.
What's a swap monkey?
It's when you want
what someone else has.
San Jose airport's
open. There's a
flight that connects
through Portland.
It can be here in six
hours. That's still too long.
I'm telling you, private charter
is the only way this will work.
Yeah, Richie
Rich, you said that.
I got one! A private jet.
It's fueled and ready
and on the tarmac or
whatever. Yeah, yeah!
Okay! Okay! Get it! Get it!
Yes, very interested.
What would...
It's $25,000.
So, who pays for that?
No, we need board
approval for that one.
You're the board!
Well, you call an
emergency board meeting
because we have to! Come on!
We got to do it!
Just use this, okay?
Put it on my card.
I'll sort it out with the
board later. It's fine.
Thank you, Jackson.
Yeah, thanks.
Okay, Amex. 3768...
It was the night that
UDub made it into the finals.
This poor freshman fell
when blocking a three-pointer.
It was such a freak injury. The
tibia was shattered in two places,
the bone was sticking
out six inches from the skin.
It was totally disgusting.
But I assisted the
attending in the OR,
placing the rod and the screws.
It probably took,
like, seven hours.
I fell in love.
It was ortho all the way.
Yeah, look, Callie, I know
you don't want to hear this, but...
Oh, come on! Nothing?
A lot of people are depressed.
I'm a happy person!
I have a number for
you. This guy's great.
He helped me through
a really difficult time.
My life is perfect. I'm
married to an amazing woman.
We're raising an
adorable little girl.
I'm at the forefront of
groundbreaking medical technology
with robotic limbs.
Not to mention, I'm a homeowner.
I mean, do any of these
things sound depressing to you?
Maybe your stupid,
fancy machine's broken.
Hey. Hey!
I got thrown off my surgery,
so Bailey and I decided
to come visit Daddy.
Hi.
I think you have a
crush on my wife.
Meredith walked in, and
your pleasure center just lit up.
It's still lit.
Nope.
It's not Meredith.
I didn't see you
at the champagne toast
this morning for Yang.
I had rounds.
Mmm-hmm.
Jealous?
Of Yang?
Don't let it eat at you.
Vascular clamp.
When Ellis won, it ate at me.
Didn't make me a better surgeon.
Made me a jealous one.
I'm not jealous!
Okay, I'm jealous. Happy
now? Therapy's over.
Not enough length
on the right renal vein.
We'll need to mobilize it.
Bailey, you have
your genome lab work.
The things you could do,
the lives you can save...
That's award-winning.
Do they give awards to
people who are stuck?
That poor boy spends the
rest of his life in a bubble
if I can't figure out
how to fix his mutation,
and I've been staring at
the research for weeks.
Anastomosing the
external iliac, 5-0 prolene.
Hey! Out of the way!
Medevac with the device
just touched down on the roof.
What'd I miss?
Yang's going over the
procedure in her head.
She's so cool. She's amazing.
She's totally gonna
win the Harper Avery.
And we know her.
I printed one of her
sample conduits.
For the rest of my
life, I get to say that.
What's she doing?
Being amazing.
She's poetry in motion.
Meredith, can you
turn off the intercom?
The kidney's pinking
up. That's just beautiful.
What do you mean...
We just transplanted
an HIV-positive organ,
and you're making a mopey face?
I remember when HIV baffled us.
I mean, the way it could
make its way into cells,
replicate its DNA. I mean,
the perfectly designed virus.
I understand how HIV works.
We never thought we'd
find anything close to a cure.
And now look at Keith.
He's alive.
He's full of T cells.
He just received a
kidney transplant. From us.
We do this marvelous
thing, I'm trying to enjoy it,
and you're bringing me down.
I understand how HIV works.
Yeah, you just said that.
Let's just close the patient.
I need to be around some
sunshine, not rain clouds.
No, no. It's a perfectly
designed virus.
HIV has a brilliant
transport system.
The mechanisms it uses, it...
If I could deactivate it...
Okay, I need to read
everything on gene
therapy and virus vectors.
I need stem cells. I need
to get down to my lab.
I need a mocha latte!
Okay, well, go.
I'll close up. Go.
Go now! Okay.
What'd I miss?
The pow.
I'm gonna start here
to leave a rim of ventricle
to sew the pump to.
Good idea.
Hey, have you googled
any of the other nominees?
No. I have.
You want to know what I think?
No.
Excuse me. Sorry.
Pardon me. Excuse me, sir.
Excuse me.
No one would even know
that you're seething
with jealousy right now.
I'm not seething. I
am happy for her.
Right. I have a machine
that will confirm seething.
I wore waterproof mascara
today because I was sure
I wouldn't make it through
the day without crying.
And if anybody
saw me, I would say
that I was crying
because I'm happy for her.
And they would
believe me because...
Does a jealous friend
plan a champagne toast?
You planned a champagne
toast to cover up your jealousy?
You're a genius.
You should call the
Harper Avery people.
Tell them. Maybe
they'll give me an award.
Hmm.
I just strapped the camera
to the top, and check this out.
You can see where
you're going on your tablet,
and you can talk to anyone.
Look, I know it's
not what you wanted.
It's awesome!
How far does it go?
Two hundred yards. That'll
cover the whole peds floor.
You can visit your girlfriend.
She's not my girlfriend!
Yang's done. Surgery
was a success.
Cool. Did you make that?
Well, it's a $10 solution.
I think it's great.
Well, money lets you
do good crap in the world.
Oh, my God.
You called Butthole.
Yeah. Well, I told
him I was interested.
Yang?
Congratulations
on the Harper Avery.
Just a nomination.
Cristina Yang!
I taught you better than that.
When someone congratulates you,
you look them in the eye and
smile and say, "Thank you."
Thank you, Dr. Bailey.
You're welcome, Dr. Yang.
Kidney function is excellent.
Urine output is good.
Well, that's some
history-making urine.
Swap monkey, Shane.
I think I'll go back down
to Dr. Bailey's genome lab.
Oh, now you want in.
She's mine.
No. You go deal
with your conduits.
Ross!
Oh, Dr. Webber, I'm looking
for a picture of Ellis Grey
with her first Harper Avery.
Do you remember
what year it was?
1988.
Hey, you want to see?
Wow.
She looks so happy.
Yeah. She was happy.
It was a great night.
So far, there's no evidence of
clotting, and his pump is working well.
He's doing really great.
We're gonna keep him
sedated for about 24 hours,
and then slowly wake him up.
Thank you all so much.
I'm sorry that we doubted you.
We shouldn't have.
Doubt is normal. Get some rest.
I have clean underwear?
I'm gonna cry.
You're making me cry.
Don't be surprised
when you see a charge
for, like, $25,000
on the credit card.
What?
Yeah, you know
how earlier I said
I don't spend my money on
hookers and private planes?
I guess, like,
technically, I was lying.
You spent $25,000 on...
On an airplane, okay?
For Cristina's experimental
heart to get here.
And the board is
gonna reimburse me.
Who even has a
credit limit that high?
Turns out I do.
I feel a little sick.
Your credit limit and
trust fund and $4 lattes
are literally just
making me feel sick.
Eat some three-day-old lasagna.
That'll make you feel better.
Hey. Hi. I didn't know
that you were waiting.
You're gonna kill me.
Why?
You are.
Oh, my God. I can't
believe I'm even...
Did you sleep with someone else?
What? No!
Thank God. You scared me.
I want another baby.
What?
Look, I want my life back, too,
and I want time to have
a thought and do my work.
But I also...
Wait... Why on
Earth would you think
I would sleep with someone else?
Because you said that
I was gonna kill you.
After everything that
we've been through,
how you could ever,
even for one second,
think that I would sleep
with someone else is crazy.
I want another baby, too.
What?
I don't want Sofia
to bury us alone
or nurse us through some
horrible, long decline by herself.
She should go through
that with someone else.
That's morbid and awful.
Or practical.
And awful.
Well, you want
another baby, too.
Yeah, because I love babies.
They're adorable and delicious.
And you just realized
that this afternoon?
Yeah, I forgot. And then I saw
Meredith and her baby, and...
Wait. Why are we arguing?
We're gonna have another baby.
We are.
I love you so much.
I love you so, so much.
We're having another baby!
My mom didn't think she'd win.
She thought it was
a popularity contest,
and she wasn't popular.
She was a woman and a fellow,
and her arrogance could
rub people the wrong way.
She hadn't allowed herself to
imagine the possibility of winning
because she wanted it too much.
You know, I have looked
at the other nominees.
I've seen their research.
Me, too. What? Really?
Yes, I looked at everyone's
abstracts and read their articles.
I even called a friend
over at Chicago Children's
who knows Lucas... You
know, whatever his name is...
Who's doing the work on the
ligature tissue-sealing device,
which is kind of...
Derivative. Right? Right?
And supposedly, his trial
patients are not doing well.
Which is bad,
obviously, but also...
I think you're gonna win.
And when they called my mom's
name, she was genuinely shocked.
It was validation of all
her hard work and sacrifice.
I really do.
I think you are going to win.
Me, too.
She came home and told me
she didn't win the Harper Avery.
She earned it.