Well, I did it for love.
I left behind a dream job
and, uh, 7-Elevens, the Yankees...
the things we do, right?
But really, living in London has just
been the absolute best, truly.
That's great to hear, Dr. Goodwin.
And I just got my medical license
in the UK.
Not in the US. Had that one already.
So I'm ready to go back to work.
You just say the word.
We're looking for a urologist.
Not the word I was hoping for.
Get your head in the game. Okay. Okay.
Tell me about your most recent employment.
NHS Hampstead.
Ah, yes. Uh, in what capacity?
-Receptionist.
-Receptionist?
-Mm-hm.
-And the reason you left?
[nervous chuckle] Kind of a funny story.
I got fired, uh, by my girlfriend
for starting an insurrection.
That sounds worse than it is. [chuckles]
[whispers] Here we go. Hot
For six years where I specialized
in the study of infectious diseases.
That is one incredible CV, Dr. Goodwin.
Well, those are just the highlights.
The full reel would knock your socks off.
-Well, you certainly are qualified.
-Thank you.
One might say overly qualified.
Really? Who would say that?
Uh, I would not say that.
I would say I'm just exactly...
[clicks tongue]
the right level of qualified.
Hiring someone who could so easily replace
me doesn't sound like the wisest of ideas.
And before that, you were medical director
of New Amsterdam in New York City.
Perhaps you should have led with that.
I, uh... [chuckles]
Note taken.
May we reach out
to the current medical director,
Veronica Fuentes, for a reference?
I'd really rather you didn't.
It's going to work out.
Look, I know there are a million reasons
not to hire me, but... but I need this.
I mean, I love this.
This is what I was trained to do,
provide care, healing, helping people.
I don't care if I have to see patients
in some back alley...
I will do it. I... I just...
I'm begging you.
Please...
just... put me back to work.
-It's a no.
-No.
Apologies... but no.
We just don't have a position for you,
but I have no doubt
you'll land someplace wonderful.
-It's a no.
-No.
[all] No. [echoing]
How is she? Is she still spotting?
All good there, but, you know,
being on bed rest for 23 hours a day
-is working her last nerve, as am I.
-I guess we're both in the doghouse.
Yeah. But, hey, thanks for covering
for me, man. I got a few job interviews.
-If she needs anything--
-Of course, I'm happy to help.
Okay. All right. Yeah.
-Just... excuse... Thanks.
-Sorry. Yes. Right.
Hey, uh, Floyd, um...
So, do... [sighs]
Do you know your way around?
No. No, no, no.
I've... I've never been inside... here.
-I... haven't been anywhere.
-Okay.
Okay, um... bedroom's upstairs.
-Right.
-Okay. Uh... Yeah.
The lab called. They want
all blood cultures sent in duplicate.
Also, for the love of God,
please stop ordering SED rates.
[background chatter]
And, uh...
obviously, uh, Dr. Shinwari dropped out
of the residency program,
but she failed to fill out
some exit paperwork
and she didn't leave
any forwarding information.
Somebody here must know
where she is, right?
It's for official paperwork, okay?
You wouldn't be betraying any trust,
or anything like that.
Look, I know that one of you
knows where she is, okay? So just--
[door bangs open]
Nico Jerrino, 33,
unconscious, massive contusion.
Hit his head on the stairs
at Madison Square Garden.
All right.
Uh, let's get him to trauma one.
Secondary survey, clear his spine.
Order a head CT. You know the drill.
[PA announcement]
Dr. Singh to radiology lab.
No, it's personal.
And I'm only here
in a professional capacity.
Okay. Maybe I will tell you
after our insurrectionist meeting,
which, by the way,
is highly unprofessional.
Hi.
-Oh! Hi.
-Hi.
What are you doing here?
-Nothing.
-Nothing. I like to come here and think.
I get that. Dead bodies are pretty quiet.
Although if you listen
with your root chakra,
you can hear them from the other side.
Uh...
It's a joke.
[laughs] I'm not crazy, remember?
Right. Totally.
So, uh, you were looking for me.
[Mia] Yes. Veronica placed me
in the oncology department.
So I wanted to reach out and connect.
[Ben] She did? Why?
Well, my work can be very helpful
with patients
who are going through chemo and radiation
and, you know, we're both new here.
-So I thought we could work together.
-Mm.
Show each other
where the bodies are buried.
Pun intended.
Mm.
[Ben] And accomplished.
Uh, so I guess I'll see you around.
-Great.
-[Wilder] Mm.
Are your sessions
always this action-packed?
No, this one's the wildest.
Well, like I've said,
this is your time, so...
Pssh. Not really.
These check-ins are mandated
by the higher-ups, aren't they?
Yeah. That's right, so I'll be checking in
with all of your coworkers
over the course of the year.
Job's fine. Marriage is fine.
You don't want to be
doing better than fine?
Well, at the end of a shift,
I'm too tired for much excitement.
What's that look like? The fatigue.
Tell me about that.
I lie down on the couch,
grab a couple cold ones,
turn the TV on.
My wife asks me questions about my day,
which I don't want to talk about.
She gets mad. I get defensive.
Typical marriage, right?
But you used to interact more,
right, with your wife?
Why'd you stop?
Like I said, I'm tired.
When did this start?
[phone buzzes]
Time to go to work.
-Great talk.
-Yeah. Okay.
Now, remember, as per your employer,
I will be observing you
for the rest of the day, so...
Yeah.
[police radio chatter]
Let's roll.
Mr. Jerrino. Hi, I'm Dr. Bloom.
You're at New Amsterdam Hospital.
You remember hitting your head?
Who won the game?
-Excuse me?
-Knicks. Who won?
Oh, uh, I don't know.
I can ask around later.
Can you check, please? Now?
It's really important, super important.
I was wearing my lucky jersey.
We were up by ten and I think--
-Okay. Okay.
-Oh, wait. Where is my jersey?
Uh, all your belongings are in that bag
at the foot of the bed.
Thank God. Some people think it's trashy
'cause I only wash it when they win.
Like a cleanse, you know,
but it's getting kind of...
99-96. Knicks lost.
-No, impossible. Can I see?
-Yeah.
Damn it! They blew it.
No D. They threw it away.
Out rebounded again
and dumb fouls.
God, they suck!
What a waste.
[breathing hard] I feel nauseous.
Um, metaphorically?
I can't...
I can't get enough air.
Your oxygen levels are good.
[groans, pants]
[beeping]
Let's get a crash cart over here now.
Hey. Yeah, it's me. Just got here.
Um, interviews went, uh, really great.
-Yeah. A lot of good opportunities.
-[woman] I'm sorry, but I'm full up.
-It's going to be hard to...
-[man] Me leg's killing me.
-No cancellations.
-...to pick one.
-See you in four weeks. Just hold tight.
-Anyways, I'll, uh,
-wait around for a little bit and, uh...
-[man] How do you reckon I'll get around?
-If you're, uh, too busy, I'll just, um...
-[arguing in background]
I'll see you at home. Love you.
[man] ...unscrew me leg, then,
and leave it here?
-It's not doing me any good.
-We'll see you in a month, Mr. Chiltern.
-What's that?
-Some information.
Number 37.
Uh, Mr. Chiltern,
I'm Dr. Max Goodwin.
How can I help?
Médecins Sans Frontières
on the Afghan border? Oh my gosh.
What a powerful experience
that must have been.
It got me to understand how much
we doctors can do with very few resources.
I know Hampstead's on a slim budget,
but there's so much to be done
with what's at hand.
I couldn't agree more. When
I became medical director,
I had this overwhelming responsibility
that I had to impart
the best of myself to this institution,
knowing that it was a direct reflection
of me, of my values, my principles.
"Do not follow where the path may lead.
Go instead where there is no path
and leave a trail."
Emerson.
It was a pleasure meeting you, Dr. Sharpe.
Likewise, Dr. Vaishya.
I think I just found my number two!
Ah. He's lovely, I'm sure.
He's devoted his life to those in need
and he quoted Emerson.
-Now, if that's not sign--
-I'm not sure how things are in America,
but we don't see many female hospital
directors in our corner of the world.
-Go on.
-You've been given the rare opportunity
to really start changing
the face of the NHS.
A female deputy could pay dividends
for generations to come.
Otherwise,
who's going to train the next you?
Right. I hadn't thought of it that way.
Hiring a woman
could be a shot across the bow,
but it's your decision, of course.
[exhales]
[Max] Hm. Well, that is a nasty bump.
Yeah, I could've told you that.
Don't make you a doctor,
-does it, mate? Ow! Ow!
-Let's see here.
Sorry. Uh, this is osteoarthritis.
That doesn't sound good.
Well, it's not that bad.
I can get a needle, drain this fluid,
and the swelling should go down
and you should feel better immediately.
You sure you're actually a doctor?
Actually, I, uh...
used to run
America's oldest public hospital.
[laughs]
Yeah, sure you did.
Yeah. So, uh, you stay here
and, uh, I'm going to grab
some medical supplies. I'll be right back.
[clears throat]
Hey, Priscilla.
Hi there. I was out getting
some snacks for my beloved.
I thought you might like one.
What a prince.
I'll give it to her straightaway.
You know what? I was actually thinking
I might give it to her myself.
-Sure. Yeah, of course.
-Is that okay?
-Awesome. Nice to see you. You look great.
-You too. Thank you.
[chuckles]
[PA announcement]
On call pediatric nurse, station five.
What the hell happened to me?
-[Lauren] You had a heart attack.
-Full on?
And then some.
A stress-induced cardiomyopathy,
which has left you
with an aortic aneurysm.
[tuts] You kidding?
My dad runs marathons every year.
My grandpa's still kicking at 93.
Well, you... you've got an aneurysm
that could blow at any minute.
Look, cardiology's going
to come down here for a consult,
but I'm pretty sure they're going
to recommend open-heart surgery.
I... I don't get it.
I take good care of myself.
I drink smoothies every morning
with real kale.
I go on hour-long walks.
-I eat good.
-Well, how long you been a Knicks fan?
I never wasn't one. Why?
Okay. Well, according to this ultrasound,
you got the heart of an 80 year old.
That's stress, adrenaline,
fluctuating heart rate
-based on who wins and who loses.
-What are you trying to say, Doc?
Nico,
the Knicks are literally killing you.
[laughs]
[Ben] Willow, thanks for coming.
Can I get you anything?
Yeah, less cancer would be great.
[Ben]
That's what all we're all hoping for.
Now, you have lost a few pounds
since your appointment a few weeks ago.
My high school self
would be jumping for joy.
[Ben] How's your appetite?
Nothing looks good or smells good.
Just talking about my appetite
is making me feel sick.
So let's just not, okay?
Willow, many patients who are in remission
and have a recurrence feel angry, anxious.
But this regimen,
etoposide, cisplatin, cytarabine,
is still your best shot.
But I am concerned about the side effects.
Yeah, me too.
But I have an idea how to fix them.
That's wonderful.
I want to stop all the treatment.
I give up.
No, wait.
Don't go in my head. Get out. Get out.
[Aya] Hey, lady, you can't be here.
This is a place of business.
You think I don't know what you want?
[chuckles] I know.
You're trying to hide in the internet,
but I get a special text
when you're trying to find me.
Yep. Yep. Sure. Sure.
All right. Move it along. Move it along!
Don't you touch me. Get away from me.
Ma'am, I'm going to repeat this, okay?
You need to move now.
-[woman] Get away from me!
-Okay. You know what? You were warned.
You're moving... now! Let's go.
-Let's go. Don't fight me.
-[woman mumbling]
[Aya] There you go. Okay?
[woman laughs]
[woman] Watch out.
There’s always cops there!
[sighs]
As exciting as it looks in the movies...
-Yeah.
-[woman] You can't just stand there!
So, um, I think I know why
you're so tired all the time.
What are you talking about?
Aya, I believe
you are suffering from PTSD.
[woman] Yeah, I got a table!
I'll admit, I was so excited to learn
that you were also at Cambridge.
I can't believe I just missed you.
I know. And reestablishing our ties
with the university
is going to be a coup for Hampstead.
And having you as a mentor
would be life-altering.
Well... [chuckles] it was such a pleasure
to meet you, Dr. Stewart.
-I'll be in touch.
-Sure.
Thank you.
-Can you sign these?
-Yeah, of course.
I think I just found my number two,
very exciting, a powerful woman.
Just thinking about
Hampstead's Muslim population.
-Okay.
-It's big and growing.
Why not have more clinic staff
that looks like our patients?
Well, I come from
a Muslim background myself.
You do?
You never mentioned it on television.
-Well, I meant my father was.
-That's okay.
It's not front and center for you.
But for many of our patients, it is.
And statistically, being treated
by physicians who look like you
and understands where you're coming from,
leads to better outcomes.
-Uh, yes. That's absolutely true.
-I know you'll make the right decision.
You always do.
You done yet? Can I look now?
Uh... not just yet.
I am repositioning
so I can draw the fluid out.
I don't want to know the details, man.
-Right.
-Needles.
Of course. So, um,
how long have you been driving a cab?
Oh, since I was 18,
I was one of the knowledge boys.
Memorized the blue book
till I knew this city inside out.
Hm.
Always knew this is where
I wanted to be... behind a wheel.
Never wanted to do anything else.
Do you believe that?
Mm.
I cannot imagine
not being able to drive anymore.
I know the feeling.
All right.
Let's not, uh, stop the meter just yet.
Oh, King Ada!
Mate, that needle really hurts.
No, that's not the needle.
That's something else.
Oh, easy, tiger. Easy.
Have you been doing work on your knees,
sanding floors or things like that?
-Lino.
-Lino?
Linoleum?
Yeah. Just done my daughter's flat.
How do you know?
I think the lino work has created a new
effusion here just above the kneecap.
Well, I'm glad I kept
that appointment for next month.
No need to wait a month. I can fix it
right now. Let's see your hand.
Just put some pressure right here
and I'll be back.
I'm going to grab one more thing.
Hey there.
The only thing that woman
loves more than surprises is biscuits.
Honestly, you and Dr. Sharpe
are adorable. Off you go.
Okay.
Nico, I got great news.
-KD blew out his knee?
-No, I got you a spot.
The OR miraculously carved out
a spot for your heart surgery.
So we're good to go.
I got to push it a day.
My guy's got a game. It's a can't-miss.
Okay, Nico,
your surgery is the can't-miss.
Can I wear my lucky jersey?
No. They're going to cut open your chest.
Then no can do.
My guys need me, Dr. Bloom.
Nico, listen to me, okay?
You're going to die.
How are the Knicks losing again
more important than your life?
They are my life.
Look, I don't have a girlfriend.
I don't have a job I love.
I don't have...
a lot.
But these games...
the past games, the draft,
the die-hards like me...
they're my everything.
[PA announcement]
Environmental services worker up front.
Environmental services worker
to admitting.
I think I have a solution...
and I hate it.
[siren wailing distantly]
Floyd?
You're awake.
And you're in my kitchen.
Where's Claude?
Well, he had a few interviews
he couldn't postpone,
so he asked me to look after you.
Tag teaming?
Mm. I prefer not to call it that.
You hungry?
Yes. I'm starving.
I'm craving those pierogies
on the Lower East side.
Yeah.
But soup works for now.
Okay. I'll make you some.
Going through pictures?
You guys look so young.
We were.
And happy.
[phone buzzes]
It's the hospital.
Oh, go. Go, go, go.
I'll... I'll be fine by myself.
Yeah?
[sighs]
[sighs softly]
[Ben] Thank you for waiting.
I would eventually like to go home.
[Ben] I want to propose
an experimental surgery.
It's shown promise in several trials
and I can apply for compassionate use.
It is not without risk,
but we can get the cancer out in one go.
Am I supposed to light up at this news?
[Ben] Let me send you home with
some information about the trials. Okay?
Take your time. Think about it.
If you have any questions, I am here.
I don't need to think about it.
The answer's no.
[Ben] It's a big decision, Willow.
-We can talk about this tomorrow.
-I don't want to talk to you.
I want to talk to Dr. Sharpe.
[Ben] I am sorry, Willow.
I know that these transitions--
Transitions? This is my life.
I don't know you and I don't trust you.
Can I go now?
I'm not remembering some, like, trauma.
No. People with PTSD
aren't remembering trauma.
They're re-experiencing it.
They're responding to stimulus
from an event in the past,
not from what's happening
in front of them.
Today on the streets
with that homeless woman,
you were responding to something
that wasn't there.
What I was responding to was
a screaming nut case in front of me.
-Well, why'd you raise your voice?
--Because she was screaming.
Yeah. At the visions in her head,
not at you.
She barely even looked at you
and then you... and then you grabbed her.
You went straight to physical force
with a person
who wasn't displaying any violence,
who may not have even been
aware you were there. Why?
You know how many reprimands
I've gotten for undue force?
Zero. So you saying
I'm out here being cruel?
-I didn't say cruel.
-Subconsciously freaking out or whatever.
You're wrong.
I do what I was trained to do.
What you saw, that wasn't trauma.
That wasn't even intense.
That was a normal day.
You're sweating a lot for someone
who just went through normal.
How long you had the towel?
Colombo with the towel over here.
How about cold ones?
-How many do you drink on the couch?
-Oh my God.
You're not drinking to relax.
You're drinking to suppress.
Tell me I'm wrong.
Leave it alone.
I can't.
Whatever it is that you are suppressing
has made you aggressive.
That means we're not just talking
about your marriage.
In your line of work,
people could get killed.
[police radio] 10-13 at 48th and 9th.
Suspect possibly armed and dangerous.
2-7 Adam, 10-4. En route.
Crime in progress.
You want to see me at work, get in.
When I saw way too many people that looked
like my parents, cousins and aunties
coming through the hospital doors
with chronic illnesses
too late for us to treat,
I knew I needed to change that.
So I began Healthy Habibi.
It's part pop-up clinic,
part lively street team.
We've been able to create some successful
preventative medicine initiatives
all around Hampstead.
Oh my God. You're fantastic.
I'm sorry. Is that a bad thing?
No, no, of course it's not.
It's just I have, um...
I have a tough and impossible
and debilitating decision to make
and you are so incredible.
You've just made it even harder.
Honestly, I'm at a complete loss.
-I shouldn't burden you with any of this--
-[knocking]
Yep.
Sorry to bother, ma'am, but I caught
this one trying to steal medical supplies.
Hey, babe.
Hey, thanks for coming out
on your day off.
Well, I spent the day trying and failing
to take care of my pregnant girlfriend
at the behest of her husband
in their house.
You know, I marvel at how quickly
your life became this fascinating.
Know what? I'm nowhere in there.
But why should I be?
It's not like they're going to add
a picture of me to the bookshelf,
especially when I'm making
everything more complicated.
All right. You signed up for this. Yeah?
Yeah.
Well, then quit being so passive.
I mean, show her you care.
You got to get in the game,
make some plays.
Not for Baptiste, but for you.
It's the only way
you're going to stay in this.
Uh, what... What the hell is this?
[sighs] You think you got a secret?
If anybody finds out about this,
I am going to kill you with my bare hands.
Okay.
I'd like to press charges for kidnapping.
Okay. I'll let Dr. Wilder know.
You know where she's taking me?
I do and, uh,
I have to say I'm a little surprised.
Willow, this is Dr. Mia Castries.
She's the chair of Holistic Medicine.
Hi, Willow. It's nice to meet you.
Where are the wind chimes?
My bamboo chimes are at home,
but I appreciate the humor.
I'm here all week. Maybe.
[Ben] I need to give you a reason
to trust me.
I don't know Dr. Castries,
but she comes highly recommended.
I don't trust Dr. Castries
because I don't give away my trust easily.
Does that sound familiar?
But I am willing to put all that aside
if she can help you.
Will you let her try?
Hi. Okay.
Can I take your hand?
Okay.
Okay. This is called acupressure.
It's noninvasive.
It's what we call good touch.
This is pressure point P6.
Its meridian pathway travels up your arm
into your chest, into your upper abdomen.
It's okay if it's a little bit achy,
but it shouldn't be painful.
It's... not.
Okay. So I'm going to take your other hand
and I need you to do one thing for me.
Can you say, "I accept healing touch"?
With a straight face?
Energetically speaking,
that is not required.
I accept... healing touch.
I...
accept... healing touch.
[emotionally] I accept...
healing touch.
I accept. [sobs softly]
What are you feeling?
Extremely self-conscious.
Anything else?
Hunger.
[nervous chuckle]
-[man 1] I'm not going nowhere!
-[man 2] Get the hell out of here!
-Stay in the car.
-[cop] Get back inside!
-[man 2] He's costing me customers!
-[cop] Sir, inside now!
[man 1] Get away from me!
-[Aya] Hey, hey, anyone get hurt?
-Guy's a live wire.
-[Aya] Sir. Look at me.
-Back off!
[Aya] I don't want
any more trouble out of you.
I'm not telling you again. You're going
to move your ass down the street.
You want us to take you in? Move it along.
In three, two...
Hey, don't even think about it!
Hands where I can see 'em!
-[Iggy] Hey, whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
[murmuring]
Dr. Frome, get back in the car.
-Get away from me, man!
-What the hell you doing?
-Get back in the car.
-I will. I will.
One sec.
I just want to talk to our friend here.
Leave me alone! All of you!
You and you and you!
Can we please have him carted off?
Please, please, please.
I just want to talk.
Can we do that for a sec?
That's all I want to do.
I'm... I'm Iggy, by the way.
It's nice to meet you.
What's your name again?
Erman.
[Iggy] Erman. It's a solid name.
Love that name.
So what Erman and I
can agree on here is that
when, uh, you're having a day like today,
raising your voice
is kind like the worst thing
we can do, right?
No one likes raised voices,
do they, Erman?
-[Erman] No.
-[Iggy] No.
[Erman] No.
But you do... you do like it here, right?
I mean, you chose this spot
for a particular reason.
I'm assuming
it wasn't the bistro lighting.
It's cold.
The heat lamps. Yeah.
It's cold out here, huh?
-Yeah.
-What about a, uh, a hot coffee?
Erman, you want a hot cup of joe?
Can I get you that?
Can we make that happen?
Can we get a cup of coffee?
-Now you want me to give you coffee?
-I'll cover it.
Thank you. It's on me. Okay, Erman?
Things are... confusing.
[Iggy] Yeah. I bet. It's scary.
Hey, Erman. There's a church up the block
with a heater in the back.
Did you know that?
-You got to push me away?
-No, no, no. Not pushing. Just helping.
Just helping.
-This ain't yours and it ain't his!
-No, of course not.
It's just a lot quieter there. Okay?
And between you and me, the, uh,
the coffee at the church
is better than the stuff they serve here,
but that's our little secret, all right?
Thank you.
Here you go.
But, you know,
things are going to get better.
Okay? I promise you.
-Come on. Let's walk.
-[murmuring]
[distant siren wails]
-[woman] Let 'em through.
-[indistinct chatter]
[Iggy] Hey.
Hey.
-Do you mind?
-No.
Thank you.
Yeah. Good old St. Joe's.
They allow the unhoused
to hang out out back.
I wish I could say
Erman's situation was okay,
but at least he's not in danger, you know?
-That's good.
-Mm-hm.
Yeah, it is.
[sighs]
Last year, um...
I had a terrible call.
Kid getting beaten.
We're supposed to compartmentalize.
Anyway, another call comes in.
Garden-variety
street crazy causing a scene.
I go to move her,
but when I touch her, she freaks out.
She fights back. She's scared.
And I'm doing this hold we learn.
It's what we're supposed to do
to minimize the danger.
But this hold they teach us...
it's so easy to just...
crack their shoulder.
And I did.
She starts screaming.
It was so messed up...
'cause I didn't feel sorry for her,
or regret...
or anything like a decent human being.
I fractured her shoulder in three places
and all I felt was...
-Angry.
-Yeah.
You know, people with PTSD,
they often freeze out the ones they love.
It's like with you and your wife.
You pull back
because you're afraid if you don't,
she's going to see that you're bad person.
But that's not the truth.
You're not a bad person.
You said it yourself.
You're doing your job.
You're doing what you're supposed to do.
But officers are not equipped
to handle a mentally unstable person
who isn't committing a crime.
That's not your job. That's my job.
That's a social worker's job.
What about the next time?
Well, I teach doctors and nurses
how to deescalate psychosis all the time.
I'd be more than happy to teach you.
[sighs]
Everything I do has to be sanctioned,
approved by the committee,
union reps, training.
There's no going rogue even if it helps.
Well, then,
maybe I'll just have to make it official.
Teach the whole NYPD?
Heck, yeah. Why not?
That's crazy.
Okay. But we don't use that word anymore.
Bananas. I will accept bananas.
[chuckling]
-All right.
-All right?
That's bananas.
-How's that feel?
-It's a world of difference.
You are legitimate then, eh?
-On my better days.
-Well, I'll wager this is one of 'em.
-Thanks, Doc.
-Yeah.
Hey, I didn't even get your first name.
-Sid.
-Max.
Be good.
It's a bit smaller than New Amsterdam,
but at least it's outdoors.
No one would hire me.
And I... just wanted to feel useful.
I thought you said that
the interviews were going well.
Yeah, I did say that,
-but I was lying to you.
-Hm.
I was either overqualified
or underqualified,
or just the right qualified
with the wrong references.
Oh, you'll find the right spot.
I know you will.
-That makes one of us. How's your day?
-It's not much better.
-No?
-No.
-Interviews no good?
-Quite the opposite.
The candidates are remarkable,
but they're just somehow not quite enough.
Every community needs representation,
and hiring one
means eliminating the other.
So it looks like whoever I hire,
I'm going to be letting down
some part of this place.
-Hm.
-Some part of myself.
Shame you can't just hire another you.
Oh wait. That's brilliant.
-What?
-Thank you. [giggles]
Of course. Uh, glad I could help...
[PA announcement]
Transport team to unit 7B.
Dr. Bloom?
-[Lauren] Yeah, I'm right here.
-Yeah. How did it go?
Okay. So there were some complications
with your procedure,
-but Dr. Reynolds and his team--
-I meant the game.
Did we win?
-Nico--
-Just lay it on me, Doc.
-They got slaughtered.
-Ah! [groans]
-Total blowout.
-[grunts]
And you wore the jersey.
Nico, I just told you that you almost died
and you're asking me about a jersey.
Why?
Because I'm a Knicks fan.
Because you're an addict.
-[snorts]
-What?
The very definition of addiction
is the compulsive engagement
in rewarding stimuli
despite adverse consequences.
Tell me, which part doesn't apply to you?
Your body is screaming at you
that your engagement with the Knicks
isn't healthy
and you're just not listening.
I did wear the jersey, okay?
But if I'm being honest,
I kind of wish I hadn't.
I need more calm in my life.
Yeah. I'll say.
Less anticipation of failure.
Exactly.
No more obsessing over the Knicks.
Good.
Well, because baseball's
starting up spring training.
Nico, come on.
Let's go, Mets. Let's go, Mets.
You best be kidding.
I'm not kidding.
I just heard we got Max Scherzer.
I think we'll make the playoffs this year.
[Ben] You did wonders for Willow today.
Thank you.
And if we continue our sessions together,
I can help manage her pain
and her nausea as well.
But if you want to do more
and help more people,
we have a way to do that, but...
Veronica can't know.
Are you in?
Are you asking the holistic doctor
if she'll say yes to
something mysterious and unusual?
-[Ben] Welcome to the resistance.
-Hm.
What is this?
-Pierogi Platter from First Avenue Deli.
-Flowers from Sherene's Garden.
[exhales] Uh... [chuckles]
Who sent all this?
[phone rings]
Hey, Floyd. How'd it go?
All good. Yeah.
Um, hey, listen, when you get home
and, uh, Lyn thanks you
for everything you got her,
just... just say you're welcome.
Okay. But wait, I didn't get her anything.
[Floyd]
You have a beautiful home, Claude.
A beautiful life.
Just say you're welcome. Yeah?
[PA announcement] Nurse Stevens,
one-five. Nurse Stevens, one-five.
[clears throat softly]
Spit it out, Zamaya.
I'm here about a theoretical situation.
I'm listening.
What if a few friends of another friend
were worried about that friend
throwing their future away?
But the friends worried about the other
friend are worried about their futures
due to certain... retribution.
Is she safe?
Is... Is she okay?
As I met with you, Narin,
I thought this person really has
something special to offer our community.
And when I met with you, Rahul,
I felt the same thing.
And again, with you, Charmaine.
This hospital's second in command,
who might one day be its medical director,
has to represent
our multidimensional community.
So, Charmaine, I'm hiring you.
Thank you. Oh.
And, Narin, I'm hiring you.
Oh, that's wonderful.
-And, Rahul, you're hired too.
-Thank God.
[laughter]
You're all hired. Now, let's get to work.
-Shall we?
-[laughter]
♪ I'm a man on fire
Walking through your street ♪
♪ With one guitar ♪
♪ And two dancing feet ♪
♪ Only one desire ♪
[Sid] Oi, oi. Maxie.
-Hey.
-All right?
Yeah.
So I hope you don't mind,
but, uh, I've told a few mates about you.
-You... you have?
-Yeah.
I know it's late, but all these fellas
have got appointments months away
and they all need to keep working.
The thing is, we don't know why
you're doing this, but we don't care.
And they don't mind
my little clinic in the alley.
You think they need somewhere posh?
They just need help.
That I can do.
-So this is Ken.
-Hey. Nice to meet you.
-[Sid] Matthew.
-[Max] Hey, pleasure. Hey.
-[Sid] Eric.
-Nice to meet you.
-Dennis.
-How are you? A pleasure.
-[Max] Yeah, we got time for this?
-[Max] Yeah, sure.