I'm gonna tickle you!
I need a refill.
You've already had three.
So what? They're free.
I got a birthday.
Get it yourself.
No wonder he
doesn't get any tips.
All right.
Who's ready to sing the Ralphie's
Rumpus birthday rump shake?
Let's sing, let's ride,
let's bling, let's slide
It's time for Ralphie
We'll dance, eat cake
and do the rump shake
It's time for Ralphie
You okay, man?
You okay?
Okay. All right. Let's
get you in the back.
It's gonna be okay, kids. Sorry.
Got a heartbeat. Jack? Jack?
I need you to step
back. He's my brother.
Jack, wake up!
Call your parents.
Tell them to go to
Princeton-Plainsboro Hospital.
Our parents died.
He's all we've got.
I was not parked
illegally. I live here.
Love note. From
Detective Tritter.
Heart attack.
His cath was clean and echo
showed no structural abnormalities.
Fatigue, night sweats, weight
loss preceded the heart attack.
Eighteen-year-old kid's suddenly
an orphan and a single father of two.
Party of Five. Powerful stuff.
The O.C. of its day.
Stress explains everything
except the itchy feet.
Athlete's foot covers that.
Waiters work 12 hours
a day in old sneakers.
Good idea. Ignore the
symptoms. Makes our job easy.
I'm not ignoring a symptom.
I'm explaining a symptom.
Kid's been hanging over a
toilet despite antiemetic therapy.
Persistent vomiting
could indicate
increased intracranial
pressure, tumor...
Sure. Heart problems.
It's gotta be the brain.
Thank God there's a
neurologist in the room.
Right. It's the feet. If
only I were a podiatrist.
Probably caught an intestinal virus from
one of those feral kids running around.
Repeated vomiting causes
an electrolyte imbalance,
which leads to an arrhythmia,
which leads to the heart attack.
And itchy feet. Nope.
That's it? Nope? I've
said too much already.
This isn't a game, House.
No, it's not. But it could be.
What are you writing? Nothing.
If you know the
diagnosis, why don't...
How are you gonna learn to swim
unless I take off your floaties and
throw you into shark-infested waters?
You can't know what's wrong
after a 30-second perusal of his file.
Apparently, you can't. Now,
what's a game without rules?
No tag-backs. No biting.
You get one test each.
And the clock runs until lunch.
If I'm right, he'll still be alive.
If I'm wrong, this is
a very cruel game.
You're late.
I charge for the time you
were supposed to be here.
Tritter towed my car.
He's frozen my assets.
He's on a crusade.
You're a person of interest
in a narcotics investigation.
You're linked to their
suspect and his activities.
I'm not Pablo Escobar's evil henchman
cruising into Miami in a Cigarette boat.
I'm a physician who prescribed
Vicodin to a pain patient.
This police report you faxed me says
they found 600 pills in his apartment.
You prescribe those?
He's in chronic pain. This is
obviously an abuse of power.
Is that a yes or no?
Patients build up a
tolerance over the years.
Perfect motive for him
to forge those scripts.
Still don't have an answer.
What are we, like,
role-playing? Yeah.
And you suck at it.
Which is really unfortunate,
because you're pretending to be you.
I gotta get to court.
Michael told me you could
help me get my car back.
Yeah, divorce lawyers usually know
the ins and outs of drug enforcement.
You want your car back?
You're gonna have to give
the cops what they want.
Thanks. Usually people feel
helpless in these situations.
Dr. House is
probably going to jail.
You keep on lying for him,
you'll go right along with him.
House was on this page when he got
that annoying "I'm such a genius" look.
What's there? Patient history.
He's 18. Probably drinks,
smokes, does drugs.
How close am I?
Quit drugs when his
parents died. Quit smoking.
House didn't mock my viral
idea. He just said it was wrong.
Which means he didn't
want to give reasons.
Which means I must
have been close.
I'm thinking bacterial.
I'm doing a blood culture.
I am doing an MRI.
If it was a tumor,
intracranial pressure could cause
his brain to herniate before lunch.
Same thing with the stress test.
Which is why I'm ditching it.
What are you doing instead?
Not telling.
Seriously? You're
playing his game?
We're all playing his
game. Might as well enjoy it.
Anybody else sick at work?
I had a stomachache before him.
This isn't your fault,
Will. Keep working.
My brother's in the hospital.
Mrs. Collier won't care
if I finish my homework.
Your brother cares if
you finish your homework.
Can I be your imaginary friend?
He's a doctor.
How are the feet? Still itch?
Is that important?
I don't know. Is it?
What kinds of drugs you into?
You don't have to talk
about that right now.
No, it's okay.
I don't keep secrets from them.
They know I did drugs
before our parents died.
Clever. Admit the
past. Deny the present.
I'm clean.
I'm raising two kids. It'd be
pretty irresponsible, wouldn't it?
But confiding in an
eight-year-old is okay.
If I'm open with them,
then they'll be open with me.
Yeah. Turning the other
cheek's a good strategy in boxing.
Kids don't lie because
they got trust issues.
They lie because they've
got something to hide.
Look at him.
He's sitting there doing
nothing and he's still lying.
We don't lie to Jack.
Spelling test you
failed and forgot to... No.
Math test? No.
Fight with the kid sitting next to
you? He doesn't sit next to me.
And the other one's
probably having sex.
I am not. Yet.
But when you start,
you're gonna lie about it.
Colder. I'm not playing.
Keep very still for me,
Jack. This won't take long.
How much dope did you smoke?
Does he have to be
here? No. Ignore him.
It's not his lungs.
I never said it was.
What about the
cigarettes? How'd you quit?
Gum? The patch? Hypnosis?
He went from two packs
to nothing, cold turkey.
Or we could just
make small talk.
You still seeing
that nurse in Pedes?
I just don't think
she's right for you.
You need someone detached,
calculating, ambitious.
You need yourself in a skirt.
Jack, he asked you a question.
I didn't really quit. I just
sort of lost taste for it.
Interesting. Sounds like one
of those symptom thingies.
He's still puking, and he had
a heart attack and itchy feet.
It's not his lungs.
I never said it was.
Ice cold.
I'm injecting ergonovine
to see if your heart attack
was caused by a spasm in the
vessels surrounding your heart.
Let me know if
anything feels... unusual.
If the problems are at my heart, why
did that other doctor look at my brain?
Yeah. Why did that other
doctor look at his brain?
We're just trying to eliminate
as many possibilities as we can.
So because you think that a
spasm caused his heart attack,
you're gonna induce
another spasm?
Did you consent to this?
Everything's under control.
Tests are gonna identify which arteries
are affected so we can repair them.
Your meds don't seem
to be doing anything.
So either you're wrong,
or his system hasn't been
pushed enough to set anything off.
You wanna get back home, right?
I mean, you're probably already falling
behind with the housework and the bills.
How many sick days you think
you'll get before they replace you?
Heart rate's up. Nothing else.
They can't fire me if I'm sick.
Right. You're irreplaceable.
Who else would they find
qualified to dance with a rodent?
How can you even
support your family?
What happens when those kids grow
out of their clothes? When they get sick?
Still no spasm.
They'll take those kids
away from you, Jack.
Maybe I should bring them in here right
now so that you can kiss them goodbye.
Can't you see his heart
is fine! Stop torturing him!
What kind of doctor are you?
Wonderful. Thank you
so much. Okay, bye.
You're just getting
here? Busses suck.
Where's your
car? It's a hostage.
Tritter wants me to
testify against House.
You're not going to.
Is that a question or an order?
Any sort of conviction will
cost House his license...
Which will cost
this hospital. Relax.
I'm not gonna mess with
your precious resource.
I told my lawyer to tell
Tritter to go to hell. Marco!
Why are all my prescriptions
getting bounced back?
Sorry, Dr. Wilson. I was trying
to call you. Where's your phone?
In my car.
My patients, on the other hand,
are here and needed
their medications.
I'm sorry. I can't. Your DEA
number's been suspended.
Why so sad?
There's still a chance
that Chase got it right.
That was suspenseful
for about two seconds.
Blood culture was
negative for bacteria.
But positive for hepatitis A?
I wonder who could've
ordered that extra test.
Must be somebody who
knew what persistent vomiting,
sudden distaste for nicotine
and itchy feet have in common.
Hep A doesn't explain
the heart attack.
No. But as Chase so deftly
pointed out earlier, puking does.
And hep A explains the puking.
If this had been real life
instead of just a game...
The DEA just revoked
my prescription privileges.
Well, who's gonna
prescribe my Vicodin?
Yes, well, that's why I'm here.
This is a disaster for you.
Relax.
Tritter's just getting desperate.
He's got no real evidence.
He's trying to squeeze
you into ratting.
I'm not gonna let him
squeeze my patients.
They'll be fine. Most of your
cancer medicine sucks anyway.
I'm gonna use your team to do my
prescribing until this is straightened out.
Suddenly this doesn't
seem nearly as dramatic.
Go pump IVIG into the kid,
cure him and get him out of here.
Hep A? No.
"Chase, blood test for bacteria.
"Foreman, MRI, too
stubborn to check the lungs.
"Cameron, nice try. No spasm."
"But the princess
sat and sat and sat,
"pretending not to listen."
Pretending to write in her
journal with the flowers on it.
Pretending she didn't like stories
about eight-year-olds who save the world.
I'm 11.
Which is why you can
no longer save the world.
I'm eight! Yeah.
We're all completely
dependent on you.
Morning. Morning.
Good news. We can
take you off the IVIG.
The hep A has cleared your system.
You'll be good to go by tomorrow.
How do you think I got it?
Well, it could've been
contaminated food.
It could've been from cleaning the
bathrooms at work. Or it could've been...
Don't worry.
They've heard it all.
Anilingus is a common way.
You should just tell the
people that you've dated
they should get
themselves checked.
Don't worry.
I've been too busy chasing
after these guys to go spelunking.
You're gross.
I think. Does your arm hurt?
Arm's fine, bro.
Then why's it
bleeding? It's not. It's...
Raise your arm above your head.
Your ear... And your nose...
High PT and PTT on Jack's
blood panel confirm a coagulopathy.
So, we cure the hep A,
something else pops up.
Interesting.
What infections cause DIC?
You okay?
Hurt my shoulder
playing fantasy football.
Shall we discuss
what causes DIC,
or should we just send the
kid back to his miserable life?
He's not miserable. Right.
He's thrilled that his parents
are dead and his life is over.
The restaurant's probably teeming
with E. coli, Eikenella and strep.
Kids don't wash their hands
between the potty and the party and...
Or it's a food-borne toxin. Jack
eats at that cesspool every day.
And Jack's the only
one who got sick?
Kid's got tattoos, piercings
and probably some nasty little
girl who loaned him the hep A.
Could've also given
him syphilis or gonorrhea.
I need one of you. Take Cameron.
Your idea was dumb anyway.
Chase, I need you to head back to
that cesspool and get me the kid's puke.
Foreman, do an LP and have
Cameron run down that potty-party theory.
Why don't I just test him?
Let's not discuss this
in front of the help.
The amount of
vomiting that kid did,
there wouldn't be enough toxins left
in his system to show up in his blood.
And since he vomited in the
toilet here instead of on somebody,
that restaurant is our only
source of essential vomit.
And you couldn't say
that in front of Foreman?
No, I couldn't say this in
front of Foreman. I need a refill.
Detective Tritter knows
about the scripts I wrote before.
Exactly. If you stop
now, it'll look suspicious.
Does anyone fall
for that argument?
Write the script.
No.
One prescription
isn't gonna make...
We both know it's
not gonna be just one.
I'd rather lose my job
than lose my license.
Daniel Silvers, prostate cancer.
Needs filgrastim, two-week supply.
Andrea Donovan, breast cancer.
Just needs her refill
on her megestrol.
You're not writing.
You want me to write?
Well, you could phone
them in. But eventually, yeah,
probably somebody's gonna
want something written down.
I haven't met these
people. I have.
I've diagnosed them
and everything. I know.
I know. I'm not
saying I don't trust you.
Just my diagnoses.
These are gonna be my
prescriptions. I... They're my patients.
My prescriptions. My name!
That Tritter will
read on the script.
He wants to make you miserable. You
don't think he's gonna ask questions?
Is there anything Jack does that no
one else does? Any special duties?
No, we got lots of bussers.
What kind of cleaning
products do you use?
We got a bunch of kids running around,
sticking everything in their mouths,
so we can't use anything toxic.
This is it. Monday's trash.
So there's no one who can
maybe help get the bags out?
Sorry. Short-handed.
I can tip.
I'm pretty sure Jack's puke is in a
blue trash bag with the wrapped gifts,
but if you find spaghetti
that's the wrong vomit.
How much longer do I have
to stay on this medication?
I mean, I'm
nauseous all the time.
Maybe I should go
back on the tamoxifen.
You're doing so much better
on the anastrozole, Beth.
I'm reluctant to make a change.
I can't play with my daughter
or pick her up from school.
I can barely get up
and tuck her in at night.
There's got to be
something else.
Who is she?
Well, as you know, this
is a teaching hospital.
She's a student?
No, I'm a doctor.
I'm assisting Dr. Wilson today.
Why? Do you think he
got my diagnosis wrong?
No. I'm sure... No. No.
She's just consulting
regarding my prescriptions.
You think he got my
meds wrong? No. It's just...
No. Then why is she here?
What are you doing now?
I'm gonna get a sample of
your brother's spinal fluid.
Where's Will? School.
Is that gonna hurt?
It's gonna help us figure
out what's making him sick.
Shouldn't you be in class,
too? Teacher work day.
For you but not Will?
Yeah, didn't make
sense to me, either.
Can I help?
Well, I guess it's quicker than
calling a nurse and a truant officer.
Okay, grab his shins and push
his knees up towards his chest.
Now hold him there tight.
This all nurses do?
My boss doesn't trust
them to do anything else.
Is he gonna die?
No. No one's gonna die.
In the whole world
ever? That's so great.
I meant... I know
what you meant.
But I also know bad
things do happen.
My dad always had a few
drinks when they went out.
Always said he'd
be okay to drive.
Until he wasn't.
I would just like some
warning this time.
We're nowhere near anything
like that happening right now. Okay?
Let's get him back over.
What was that?
What did you do?
You broke his rib? I
barely touched him.
Which means...
Found it. Fix it.
Osteomyelitis. Means the
infection's spread to his bones,
which means it's either
bacterial or viral and not...
I hired you to take away the
pain. Was there some confusion?
Ever thought about using
your cane on the proper side?
Yeah, that's the issue.
Friday night my cane suddenly
noticed it was on the wrong side.
Can you score me
some Vicodin? No.
I did a needle aspiration to confirm
which... How long till the culture's...
Why do you only do
that when I'm talking?
You gotta rest your shoulder.
And we're gonna get you
on some different equipment.
Nice cane. If I know
what you mean.
Chase, you can stop doing
that. I'm almost finished.
He's got osteomyelitis.
Means you're wrong
about food-borne toxins.
And you can stop,
too. It's syphilis.
You sure? Read the print out.
He's also positive
for Eikenella.
One of you two screwed up. No.
Not a chance.
Or this kid is a lot sicker than
we thought. Finish that test.
Should be impossible to get
two right answers to one question.
It's okay to have
three? Apparently.
He's positive for botulism, too.
So, we knock down one
infection and three more pop up.
I think this game is rigged.
Jack?
Somebody help!
We've managed to clear all
three infections out of his system,
but now he's having
seizures every few hours.
He's gotta be
immunocompromised. No.
White count was normal,
and he was negative for HIV.
Well, if he's not
immunocompromised,
why is he acting like he's
immunocompromised?
What do the seizures
tell us? Nothing.
There were no structural
abnormalities on the CT,
nonfocal neuro exam, no
electrolyte imbalance. Nothing.
What do unexplained seizures and
really sick 18-year-olds have in common?
You thinking trauma?
I'm thinking drugs.
He's an admitted user. The
drugs trashed his immune system.
Tox screen was clean.
Clean tox screen means there's
no drugs in his blood or urine.
There could still be drugs trapped
in his fat cells from the good old days.
If they're in his fat, why would
they be affecting him now?
The keen observer would notice that
he's had some digestive issues lately.
His weight loss could've
burned off fat cells
and released the drugs
back into his system.
There's no way to know. It's
impossible to test fat cells for drugs.
But it's not impossible to
make him lose more weight.
You want us to starve him so we
can drive him into another seizure?
Maybe a heart attack? Just so
we can run another tox screen?
That'd be cruel. Just
sweat it out of him.
I haven't touched a thing
since the night my parents died.
Drugs stay in your
system a long time.
I was high the night the cops
came to tell us what happened.
You know the first thing
I did when they told me?
I laughed.
I'm not the person I
was when they died.
I wish they could see that.
Well, I'm sure they're watching,
and I'm sure they're proud.
That's what Will's guidance
counselor keeps telling him.
What do you tell him?
I tell him it's crap.
Our parents live on in our
memories, but they don't live on.
- Jack?
- Hold him still.
- Don't break his arm.
- We'll fix it.
We need to get a sample.
House.
Bad news.
Look at you.
You couldn't have sent Cameron
down here to this air-conditioned hallway
to deliver the bad news?
Jack seized again, but his blood
was clean. Completely drug free.
So he just happened
to have a seizure at
the exact time that we
stuck him in a sauna?
It's not a coincidence.
He's still seizing every few hours
whether we stick him in a sauna or not.
Oh, my God! Why
are you using that?
I've had it for years.
No, that's... That's gonna
make your shoulder hurt.
You need one of these.
He's a doctor.
Is he still infection-free?
I'm sure not for long.
My point being that something other than
those infections caused these seizures.
Means there's something
in his head. Scan him.
We scanned him. Well, that
was then. This is not then.
Kid keeps changing.
Scan him again.
Where is Cameron?
I am not writing you
a script for Vicodin.
I've only got two pills left.
Cut them in half.
Then you'll have four.
You're prescribing for Wilson.
Wilson prescribes for me.
Write up a script.
You know you have
a problem. Yeah.
It's got a badge and everything.
You're taking too
much... Fine! You're right.
What's the correct amount? Write
up a script for the correct amount.
No answer? That's 'cause
we're having the wrong debate.
This has got nothing
to do with my problem
and everything to do with
you avoiding a problem.
You're afraid that if you
write me a prescription
you're gonna
wind up like Wilson.
Of course I am.
Tritter wants to
win by giving pain.
Do you really want
to be a part of that?
As a doctor, how do you do that?
Here.
This'll tide you over.
Takes the edge off my PMS.
Should do wonders for you.
Why are you looking
at my head again?
Seizures usually indicate
something neurological.
I'm not gonna get better.
Am I?
We'll know more after the test.
I've gotta find out who can
take care of Will and Kama.
Let's not get ahead
of ourselves, okay?
You'll be home yelling at them and
kicking their butts before you know it.
This kid might be
facing a terminal disease,
and he's more worried
about his brother and sister.
Brain stem's clean.
Nothing in the
midbrain. What's that?
The frontal lobe,
upper-right quadrant.
I don't see anything. There.
It's tiny, but I
think it's a tumor.
That size should be excisable. Why
didn't we see it earlier? How could...
Oh, God!
Axial view. There's another one.
Bring up the next slice.
They're everywhere.
Jack's brain is
riddled with tumors.
And you know what
he's doing? Moaning?
Setting up play dates.
Wow, what a guy. Theories?
The obvious one, brain cancer
destroyed his immune system,
left him wide open
for these infections.
House, you're pathetic.
You'll analyze anyone's
faults, hypocrisies, weaknesses,
but this kid's got
some strength,
and all of a sudden there's no time to
talk about anything but the medicine.
He's teaching pre-pubescent kids that
truth matters, God doesn't and life sucks.
I like him. Treatment?
We need to start
him on radiation.
That'll destroy whatever's
left of his immune system.
And save his life!
I know the notion of
self-sacrifice is foreign to you...
You wanna think that he's sacrificing
himself because if one person can do it,
then maybe the world isn't the
cold, selfish place you know that it is.
Radiation could kill
him. Alternatives?
There aren't any.
We saw the tumors...
We could choose to
say they aren't tumors.
They're just pus, which would explain
why they weren't there yesterday.
It can't be an
infection. He got IVIG,
broad-spectrum
antibiotics... Exactly.
Creates a perfect world for
fungus, moves in, gets married,
has little fungi...
If you're wrong about the fungus, you're
wasting what little time he has left.
Not a big sacrifice.
His life sucks.
So let's be right. Go stick
a needle in the kid's head.
If you suck out a liquid,
then I'm right and we
haven't answered anything.
If you suck out a solid, you're right
and no more worrying about play dates.
Okay. Fine. I'll
father your child.
First, you got to write
me a Vicodin prescription,
just so I can get
through the foreplay.
How many days do you have left?
Could probably get through
maybe the next minute or so.
And your coming to me means
your lackeys actually stood up to you.
I'm impressed.
Yes, their cowardice
is inspiring.
Well, you should
be thanking them.
If they caved, it'd
give the cops evidence
that you intimidated
underlings to feed your addiction.
I hate writing thank-you notes.
Would it be weird if I asked Cameron
to write them? You're hooking me up?
Unfortunately, if I cut you
off, it'd give the cops evidence
that you don't really
need the pain meds.
I knew that cleavage was a
smokescreen. You're a genius.
You can't lift your arm.
You can't pee standing up.
Gimme. You been doing physio?
Maybe you pulled... Yeah.
Been training for Pants-Off
Dance-Off. Give me the script.
Your shoulder
problem isn't physical.
We'll find out if you ever
give me that... What's new?
What's different? Any big
changes in your life recently?
Fight with the wife maybe?
It's good. Means your
shoulder's a human being.
It's a start.
I'm right. Right? Yeah.
Just not about me.
I was right, right?
They were abscesses from
a fungal infection. Aspergillus.
But we still have no idea why.
Our kid's immune system
has a factory defect.
It's genetic. It
can't be genetic.
He would've been getting
infections since he was an infant.
Not if he grew up in a bubble.
Or if he grew up on Mars.
No germs there, either. I
don't mean a literal bubble.
A sweet suburban bubble where
mommies and daddies protect their children.
They die. Bubble bursts.
Continuing emotional trauma
triggers the genetic illness.
Question is, which one?
The infections he's contracted
narrow down the possibilities.
Hep A indicates a
problem with his B cells.
Bruton's
Agammaglobulinemia? Eikenella.
Points to a
complement deficiency.
I have a patient.
I need... Not now.
I'll go. You'll stay.
Patient's dying. So is mine.
Not in the next hour.
What does the syphilis tell us?
What does it tell us?
It could mean chronic
granulomatous disease.
And the aspergillus is a T cell issue.
Common variable immunodeficiency.
Genetic testing's
gonna take time.
Given the rate he's
picking up infections...
Why don't we
turn it into a race?
Little late to be
playing games with us.
Not you guys. The
infections. What infections?
The infections we're
gonna give him.
The only way to cure
me is to make me sicker?
Each of the four possible
genetic conditions
is most susceptible to
different types of infection.
What's that?
This is a cocktail of serratia,
meningococcus, cepacia and rhinovirus.
Whichever germ
gains the most ground
plants the flag of its
leader, gives us our answer.
And how are you gonna know
which one gains the most ground?
Well, that's the fun part.
See, if the meningococcus is king of
the hill, you get to have another seizure.
Serratia will shut down your lungs. If
it's cepacia, you'll have a heart attack.
And if it's the
rhinovirus, you'll sneeze.
They can't all be
dramatic. We good?
Hell, no.
Well, the alternative is we guess,
and there's a three out of four chance
that your little brother and sister
will get to cry over another coffin.
You study fractions
in school? We good?
And this test isn't
exactly FDA approved,
so let's just keep it
our little secret, okay?
Little Orphan Annie and Oliver
Twist slept in our hallways last night.
Are they singing?
They're children.
They need a guardian.
Couldn't find a babysitter
on account of not being
able to make any phone calls,
on account of not
being able to breathe,
on account of his lungs
filling up with serratia.
He has chronic
granulomatous disease.
Game over. Our work is done.
Then he's gonna
keep getting sick.
You gotta call Social Services.
Bone marrow transplant would
re-boot his whole immune system.
He'll be healthy enough to win
Miserable Daddy of the Year.
So see if one of
his kids is a match.
My kids are already
testing his kids.
Will's a match. You tested him?
I never consented for
that. It's just a blood draw.
There's no danger. To the
testing. What about the surgery?
The risk for Will
is next to nothing.
What if I don't do it?
What are my other options?
Your immune system
can't fight off the germs
we all come into
contact with every day.
Now that we know, we can
use more targeted medications,
but you'll still get
sick all the time.
You'll be in and
out of hospitals...
But I'll live.
Jack,
your lifespan will be
substantially shortened.
And you'll be too sick to care for
your brother and sister anymore.
You shouldn't have pressured
him into... There was no pressure.
He's eight years old!
You tell him his brother's
dying unless he helps.
What do you think he's gonna do?
He wants to help
you. He has no idea.
It's like you asked him to let me play
with one of his toys. This is surgery.
He could die. He'll be fine.
But you...
You're gonna have a hard time
protecting him like this if you're dead.
I'll do it...
when Will's 18 and
can decide for himself.
Noble. Moronic.
It's a synonym.
Why can't you accept he
wants to protect his brother?
Has to protect his
brother. Doesn't want to.
Wants to run screaming
from protecting his brother.
You're a hypocrite.
"Evidence is everything.
Truth is all that matters."
Except when it comes to people.
Everything we've learned
about this kid says you're wrong.
But you can't accept that.
It's easy to reject
the diagnosis.
Not so easy to reject
your misanthropy,
because then you'd have to
give people a fighting chance.
And that scares
the crap out of you.
Okay.
Let's get some evidence.
It's your lucky day.
Just found another donor
in the registry. Perfect match.
We can do the transplant
with no danger to the rug rat.
Just have to sign here.
Unless there's another
reason you don't want it.
There's a chance I'd die.
A chance you'll be cured.
Maybe you don't
want that, either.
Maybe hanging out in a hospital
getting waited on hand and foot
reminds you of what life used to be like
before you were forced to play Mister Mom.
I don't like being sick.
But you don't want
to be healthy, either.
This is your way out.
Guilt free.
I said I'd do it when Will's 18.
And he's able to take
care of himself without you.
Jack, your brother and
sister need you. I know!
I know every second of
every day that they need me,
but I'm too young
to be their dad.
Good for you.
Don't pretend you're surprised.
Want to go throw stuff
at people off the balcony?
Come on. Mail can wait.
I'm referring my patients
to other oncologists.
I'm shutting down
my practice. Oh, good.
'Cause I was afraid
you might overreact.
I can't just ask
my patients to wait
because Dr. Cameron's boss
won't let her come out and play!
I kept you waiting for
maybe an hour... Three hours!
Anybody die? Not this time.
Cameron's available
now. Use her all you want.
So now's a better time for
me to have my life taken away?
It fits into your schedule
better? Oh, poor you.
Think if you suffer loudly
enough... You committed a crime!
What do you want me
to do? Turn myself in?
Yes! Yes! Do something!
Go in! Show some remorse!
Tell Tritter you'll
get some help!
I don't need help!
House, get out of
here. Get out of here.
You are not gonna make me feel
guilty about what Tritter is doing to us.
You already feel guilty.
Your mysterious shoulder
pain isn't coming from your cane.
It's coming from
your conscience.
That used to be enough.
Despite all your smartass
remarks, I knew you gave a damn.
This time...
You were either gonna help
me through this or you weren't.
I got my answer.
Who's gonna drive me to school,
help me with my homework?
There'll be a mom
where they take you.
A real mom, someone
who can cook.
Don't worry. I'll still be
able to see you guys.
You said you'd make him better.
I'm sorry.
Thank you for not telling them.
You're a good kid.
Three months from
now, six months from now,
you'll be visiting them and you
won't be able to say goodbye.
You're gonna know
you screwed up.
You'll take his bone marrow
and you'll take them back.
And they'll be a
burden and a pain,
and your life will never be
what it was supposed to be.
But you'll be proud of yourself.
And your parents,
they'll be proud of you.
I don't think so.
It's what I wanna believe.