This is kinda fun, right?
It's like being in
high school again,
sneaking around to avoid
getting caught.
Next, staying out
past curfew.
Ow!
Aah! Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Will you just...
Are you sure?
Is this thing
poured in concrete?
Let me do it.
All right.
Now where were we?
Just block it out.
Block it out.
What is that?
Maybe a rain check?
Wasn't this our rain check?
I hope you brought
your dancing shoes, lady,
'cause it's gonna get lit.
I know this promoter.
He's getting us
a table at the club.
You're gonna wanna Uber.
Sounds great.
Dr. Choi, you coming
to my birthday party tonight?
Don't think I'm gonna
make it, Doris.
Happy birthday, though.
Hmm.
To be honest, I don't really
care if he comes or not.
That was just
a courtesy invite.
I can't wait for you
to meet my cousin Paul.
Newly single.
Wait, you're not going
to Doris' party?
What're you gonna be doing?
Literally,
anything else.
Why you care what Doris
thinks is beyond me.
Do I really have to
explain myself again?
You wanna keep us
a secret at work, fine.
But I'm not gonna spend
my off-time pretending, too.
But hey, go have fun
with cousin Paul.
Dr. Choi, April, look alive.
You're going to treatment six.
Abena Kwemo, early-20s.
Found dizzy and disoriented.
BP 150 over 95. Temp 103.
She's having a seizure.
Give her two Ativan IV, stat.
Called East Mercy first,
they said they were full up.
Diverted us here.
There you go.
All right, let's get her
in the bed.
Let's transfer on my count.
Ready.
One, two, three.
Nice job.
Yeah.
Where am I?
Abena, hey, I'm Dr. Choi.
You're at Gaffney Chicago
Medical Center.
You just had a seizure.
Has that ever happened before?
Let's get her a liter bolus
of normal saline.
Order a CBC with diff, CMP,
utox and draw blood cultures.
Also, let's get a chest
X-ray and a head CT.
Got it.
Dr. Choi.
I noticed these when I was
starting to gown her.
They're on her back, too.
Abena, has a doctor ever
spoken to you
about these lesions?
I can't remember.
Abena, these are most likely
Kaposi Sarcoma lesions.
KS is an AIDS-defining
illness.
I'd like to run
a test for HIV.
No, no, no.
Mmm, no.
Look, I know
it sounds scary,
but AIDS is
a manageable disease.
With
antiretroviral therapy,
we can prevent
disease progression.
But first, we need
to confirm you have HIV.
No.
Thank you, Doctor.
No test.
I can't have AIDS.
Turns out Abena has been
to East Mercy multiple times
over the past six months for
AIDS-related complications.
Pneumonia, meningitis,
candidiasis.
But she's consistently
refused HIV testing.
CT says she has
toxoplasmosis of the
central nervous system.
If we admit her, that's
a week-long stay, at least.
What do you mean,
"if we admit her"?
What else would we do?
Turf her back
to East Mercy.
For the record,
I'm not suggesting we do that.
Of course not.
Dr. Stohl, we are not turfing
someone we know has AIDS.
Ms. Goodwin,
we both know how
this story ends.
She dies,
after countless complications
and tests and treatment,
none of which change
the inevitable.
So why not put our limited
resources behind the ones
we actually have
a shot at saving?
Because I'm not ready to
accept that we can't save her.
Toxoplasmosis can cause
cognitive impairment, no?
Mmm-hmm.
So it's possible that she
lacks capacity to give us
informed consent.
She was confused
when she came in.
I supposed we could
pull psych in.
Thank you.
Hey, got your...
I already took my pills,
but thank you.
All right, then.
Wow, new dress, new earrings.
What's the occasion?
No occasion.
Just an impulse buy.
Felt like I needed
a fresh start.
You know what?
It might look a
little better on the floor.
No, no, no, no.
I can't, I can't.
I gotta get moving.
Doesn't your shift
start at 9:00?
Yeah, but I'm on trauma call
today, so they can wait.
Ah! Is that how trauma works?
Come on, whatever happened to
channeling your impulsivity
into other activities?
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
My impulsivity?
So what, when I initiate sex,
it's just a symptom
of my illness?
Okay, yes.
Sometimes I still wonder
if I'm getting Robin
or if I'm getting...
Okay, I get it.
I get it.
But just so you know,
I am feeling more and more
like myself every day.
Well, then, how about dinner
and a movie tonight?
Uh, how about dinner
and no movie?
Please, I need someone
to see my daughter.
She can barely
walk in a straight line,
her foot keeps dragging,
she's bumping into things...
Ma'am, please take a seat.
As soon as I have a doctor...
Denise,
come over here, honey.
Do you see what I mean?
Oh, my God.
Need some help over here!
We got her.
Mom!
Hi, there.
I can't feel my leg.
Okay. I'm Doctor Halstead.
We're gonna figure out
why that is, all right?
Okay.
Thank you so much.
She started complaining
on the plane ride home
from Australia.
She said that her feet were
tingling, that her legs hurt.
I thought it was just
from sitting so long.
Did Denise do
any outdoor activities
while you were there?
Hiking, swimming?
No, no hiking.
We picnicked a couple of days.
Deep tendon reflexes
are absent.
Okay, I'm gonna ask you
to close your eyes
super tight for me, all right?
No peeking.
And when I tap you on the leg,
will you point to which side
I'm tapping on?
Yeah.
Normal sensation
to light touch.
All right, can you lift
your legs for me now?
That's all I can do.
Okay.
Let's get a CBC,
CMP, ESR, utox,
and a brain
and spinal CT and MRI.
And do a full body scan for
rashes and insect bites, okay?
Is she paralyzed?
Let's not get
ahead of ourselves, okay?
While she is showing
signs of paralysis,
it's most likely temporary.
It's probably a nerve
compression injury
from the long flight.
We're gonna run these tests,
and we'll take it from there.
We'll be back soon.
Dr. Reese.
Dr. Charles, I thought you
weren't back till tomorrow.
How're you doing?
How's it all been going
on the floor?
Uh, actually, I've been doing
research projects
the past couple of weeks.
Huh.
Um...
So you, uh...
You haven't been
seeing any patients?
Figured I'd wait till
you got back.
Dr. Charles, welcome back.
Mind if I put you to work?
We need a psych evaluation to
determine decisional capacity.
Catch up later?
Oh.
Oh, hey, Sarah.
I was looking for you, um...
I don't know
if you heard or not,
but Doris, she's having a
thing tonight, and...
Dr. Sexton, Dr. Rhodes needs
a resident right now.
MVC incoming.
Okay, uh, think about it?
I'll check your temp later.
Dr. Sexton, now!
Yes, ma'am.
Spencer Bouren.
16-year-old male.
Lost control on
a patch of ice.
Head-on collision
with another vehicle.
Second driver's en route.
All right.
You're going to Trauma 1.
Yep.
He was unconscious
till he woke up in the ambo.
GCS, 15. BP 124 over 88.
HR, 118.
Uh, sats 100%.
Complaining of right hip pain.
All right,
transfer on my count.
One, two, three.
Let's get a chest
and pelvic X-ray.
On it.
We need a fourth one.
Second driver's
rolling in now,
we need you, Dr. Rhodes.
Somebody else
has gotta be avail.
I wouldn't tap you out
if there was.
I got him, go.
Desmond.
Female, mid-30s.
Unrestrained.
Hypotensive in the field,
gave her a liter.
GCS, 8. Tubed.
All right, let's get her in.
Buckles off.
All right.
Gently on my count.
One, two, three.
Is she gonna be okay?
Try to relax, bud.
Just try to relax.
Lungs are clear.
Clear breath
sounds bilaterally.
Trigger the MTP,
hang two of O-neg.
And give me a kit.
I'm gonna get a cordis
in the groin.
Chest X-ray's negative.
What about the pelvis?
Doing it now.
Up.
Dislocated hip.
Must've jammed it when
he slammed on the brakes.
And the longer it's out?
The higher the risk
of avascular necrosis.
Exactly.
Get me the FastSCAN.
You ever reduce a hip?
I've seen it done
a bunch of times.
I'll talk you through it.
70 milligrams of ketamine.
You're gonna pull on that hip
until you feel it pop back
into the socket.
Relax, relax, relax, relax.
Hold tight.
It popped back in.
Good work.
Her belly's full of blood.
BP's dropping.
All right, Maggie.
Call the OR,
tell them we're on our way up.
Copy.
Oh, my God.
Did I kill her?
Next one is,
if I were very sick,
I would like to do everything
possible to prolong my life.
Very true, mostly true,
you don't know,
mostly false...
That's very true.
Very true.
Yeah, the doctors did explain
to you the benefits
of antiretroviral therapy,
didn't they?
That it would
prolong your life.
They say I won't
get sick anymore.
So could you tell me then,
why it is that you
don't wanna take an HIV test?
Auntie.
What are you doing here?
You should be at work.
Are you the doctor?
I am a doctor, yes.
I'm Dr. Charles.
What's wrong with her?
My baby is always
getting sick.
I told you
on the phone, Auntie.
It's just the flu.
I'm going to get better soon.
Right, Doctor?
We are working on it.
All done.
You were so brave.
Okay, Mom, we should have
the results back
within an hour or two.
Um, I don't understand.
You said her tests
were normal.
They were, but...
But she's getting worse.
She can't move her legs
at all anymore.
We'll have a much clearer
picture once we receive
the results back on
Denise's cerebrospinal fluid.
And we'll ask the lab
to put a rush on these, okay?
Thank you.
Yeah.
Of course.
Will, you saw that girl's CSF.
It was crystal clear.
The lab's not gonna tell us
anything we don't
already know.
And it's obviously not
encephalitis, meningitis,
Guillain-Barré syndrome...
Hold on.
Let's not rule out GBS.
It fits her clinical
presentation almost to a T.
I mean,
normal blood work,
ascending symmetrical
paralysis, absent reflexes.
Let's just do one more
round of labs first.
All right, test for
heavy metal poisoning,
exotic infection,
and if we don't get
anything from those,
I'm all for treating it
as GBS, okay?
All right.
Okay.
You're supposed
to steer into the skid.
Okay, can you flex
your knee for me?
Never slam on the brakes.
Why couldn't I remember that?
Now bring it to
your chest for me.
There we go.
Dr. Sexton, this is
Spencer's mother, Candace,
and his brother, Terrance.
Goodness.
Is he gonna be okay?
Dislocated his hip,
but other than that,
just scrapes
and bruises.
We did a CT of his abdomen,
pelvis, and head.
All negative for internal
bleeds and fractures.
Thank you.
Doctor Sexton.
Shouldn't have let
you drive by yourself.
He just got his license
last week.
Yeah.
Took him five tries.
Mom, I hit someone.
A pedestrian?
No, the driver, they just
brought her in here.
She was right over there.
She was bleeding real bad.
She's in surgery.
Is she gonna be all right?
I told Spencer the best
trauma surgeon in Chicago
is working on her.
What if she doesn't make it?
Don't worry, she...
She'll make it.
Small liver lac.
Spleen is shattered.
Looks like a Grade 4.
Actively bleeding
from the hilum.
Short gastrics are avulsed,
as well.
Hey, Dr. Rhodes,
it's Noah.
I'm a little busy here, Noah.
What do you need?
Yeah, I just wanted
to check in
on the status
of the patient.
I don't know yet.
Okay, yeah, sure.
It's just, um,
the kid who hit her
is really freaking out.
Yeah, I can't help that,
Noah.
Well, if I could just
tell them that
she's gonna be okay...
No.
Don't ever do that.
Wait a minute, she won't
consent to being tested
because she'd rather die
than have her family find out
that she has AIDS?
And you're saying
she's capable
of making rational decisions?
Just because you don't like
the decision she's making,
doesn't mean
she's incapable of making it.
Growing up in Africa,
HIV-related stigma
and discrimination
was probably
something she witnessed
on a daily basis.
Is that her aunt?
Vera.
Abena lives with her.
Rest of the family
is back in Ghana.
Well, she knows
she's not being forced
to tell her aunt, right?
She understands we have
strict privacy rules here.
Doesn't matter.
She's convinced that
if she takes the test,
starts the antiretrovirals,
that they'll figure it out.
But the lesions
won't give her away.
Come on, she's living under
the same roof, for chrissakes.
If she wants to continue
concealing this,
she needs to
start treating it.
Well, you gotta convince her.
You have to convince her.
I'm sorry, I can't
just rubberstamp this.
Dr. Choi, Abena is
complaining of nausea.
Great, now she'll need
a GI consult.
Just add it to her tab.
Her tab?
Sharon, I know you're under
a lot of pressure, but...
Daniel, we're trying
to save her life.
Look, just for
argument's sake,
let's say the toxo
is causing impairment,
and we force the test.
Then what?
Somebody shoves pills
down her throat
every day
for the rest of her life?
I mean, no court is
ever going to mandate...
Please someone help!
Please!
My daughter,
she can't breathe.
Okay.
Hey, Denise.
Look at me.
Deep breaths for me, okay?
In and out.
Can you squeeze my hand?
Can you lift your arms
for me?
What's happening?
The paralysis is
moving up her spine.
10 of etomidate
and 50 of sux.
We're intubating.
You're gonna put
that down her throat?
Okay, why don't we give
the doctors some room to work?
No, please, please,
I wanna stay with my daughter.
It's okay,
we'll stay right here.
Okay.
Couldn't do much of a neuro
exam with her sedated
and intubated,
but if I had to guess,
I'd say she's paralyzed.
Thanks, Sam.
Doing the hokey pokey there,
Halstead?
Huh?
Your foot.
Oh. Yeah,
it just fell asleep.
Kinda banged it this...
No, never mind.
You were right.
We should have started IVIG
and plasma exchange
way earlier.
It was a mistake to wait.
No, you called it.
I don't think it is
GBS anymore.
It's progressing too rapidly.
Nothing else it could be.
I mean, GBS is the only thing
on our differential
that makes a modicum of sense.
When did ED doctors get
so polite with each other?
Are you two dating
or something?
Never mind.
Start with IVIG
and plasmapheresis.
At this point I'm ready to
throw the kitchen sink
at this thing.
Page me when
her sedation wears off.
You okay?
Yeah.
Keep your head still.
Eyes forward for me.
Hey there, folks,
I'm Dr. Rhodes.
Spencer, we met when
you first came in...
Did she make it?
Due to patient
confidentiality,
I can't give you any details,
but I did wanna let you know,
she pulled through.
Can I visit her?
Please, I just wanna tell her
that I'm sorry.
Would that be all right?
I'll tell you what,
I'll check with her husband.
She's just coming off of
anesthesia,
but maybe in
an hour or two.
Mom, an hour or two?
Coach will have my head
if I'm late.
Oh, big game?
Regionals.
We can't leave
your brother here alone.
Spencer's fine.
Really, and I'll keep an eye
on him while you're gone.
Yeah.
Go. Stay for the game.
Are you sure you're gonna
be okay, honey?
I'm fine.
Thank you, Dr. Sexton.
Thanks, Doc.
Of course.
Excuse me, Dr. Reese.
You drive a silver
Nissan Versa, right?
Yeah, that's my car.
Why?
That's all that's missing?
Just my gym bag.
Nothing of any value.
You know,
I know who did this.
Um, her name is Edith Lake.
She slashed my tires, too.
Hold on a sec.
You witnessed this person
slashing your tire?
No, no, but she...
And how do you know her?
She came into the ED
a few weeks back.
Uh, assaulted me.
Did you report it?
I am reporting it now.
Dr. Reese, I don't think
it was that lady.
This is the fourth break-in
we've had this month.
Whoever did this
probably wasn't targeting
your car in particular.
Well, aren't you gonna dust
for fingerprints?
Here's the address
of the website
to retrieve your
police report.
You can use it to file
a claim with your insurance.
We know she has AIDS.
She knows she has AIDS.
Her aunt must know on some
level, this isn't the flu.
Yeah,
but there's a difference
between knowing something
and saying it out loud.
You say it out loud,
and it's real.
April, it's real whether
it's said or not.
She's having
trouble breathing.
Ma'am, please step back.
Ma'am, please put these on.
Why?
Is she contagious?
It's a universal precaution.
She's got fluid in her lungs.
Sats down to 86.
Okay, let's get her on a mask
with 15 liters.
Let's get a sputum sample
and another chest X-ray.
And call pulmonology.
Excuse me.
Ma'am, please put these on
before you touch your niece.
I'm doing everything I can.
Any improvement?
Denise's Hughes functional
grade is still at 5.
Is she triggering the vent?
No.
The IVIG isn't working.
It's way too soon
to know that.
Give it some time.
I think we need to try
immunosuppressant...
Are you okay?
What the...
What happened?
I don't know.
My foot went numb,
and just gave out.
And I can't move my foot.
All right.
Where are we going, Doc?
Dr. Rhodes got the A-okay
from Melody's husband.
Is that the name
of the woman I hit?
Melody?
Yeah.
Okay, ready to roll?
All right, so now
you can be honest.
One on one,
you or your brother?
Definitely me.
You okay, buddy?
Yeah.
I can get you a Tylenol.
Tylenol, please.
Nah, nah. It's...
It's just a...
Stress headache.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Spencer?
Spencer.
No pulse.
I need a crash cart over here.
Coming right away.
Here we go.
Left pupil's blown.
Start bagging, amp of epi.
What happened?
I don't know,
he was talking one second,
said he had a headache,
and then he started
slurring his words.
All right, charge to 200.
Charging.
Clear.
Resume compressions.
Another amp of epi.
Charge 200 again.
Charged.
Clear.
Asystole.
Come on, bud.
Come on.
Noah.
Hey, come on, Spencer.
Noah, stop.
Time of death, 16:29.
We won't know for sure until
we get the ME's report,
but from the looks of it,
I'd say it was
a delayed epidural hematoma.
But Spencer's...
Spencer's CTs were clean,
and...
Must've developed
after the initial scan.
It happens sometimes, Noah.
There's no way
to predict or prevent it.
Maggie, let's get the mom in
here so we can break the news.
I told her Spencer
was gonna be okay.
I don't know what
I'm gonna say to her now.
I can break the news,
if you want.
No.
I appreciate the offer,
Dr. Rhodes,
but I really
should do it.
I'll go lean on the ME
for a cause of death.
No.
I can't feel anything, Sam.
All right, press down on the
gas pedal as hard as you can.
Have you been ill
at all recently?
Is it possible
you're immunocompromised?
How about any interactions
with the patient?
Any needle sticks?
Is there a chance
you exchanged
fluids somehow or...
The only direct contact
I had with the patient
was when she collapsed.
I carried her into the ED.
How about you?
Are you experiencing
any numbness
or tingling in
your lower extremities?
No.
We haven't even established
what Denise has yet,
let alone if it's contagious.
You think it's a coincidence,
your paralysis?
Where are you
with your differential?
We were operating
under the hypothesis
that she had
Guillain-Barré syndrome.
Well, that's obviously
a dead end.
GBS isn't contagious.
I'm gonna get started
on the LP.
Collect everything you've got
thus far on the girl.
Every test you gave her,
you give him.
See if we can find
any patterns.
Now, Dr. Manning.
Let's give her
another bolus of fluids.
She's still
pretty dehydrated.
Sats aren't improving much.
Dr. Choi.
How is Abena doing?
Now it looks like
she's developing
a pulmonary...
Mr. Doctor.
My niece isn't getting
any better.
How can this be the flu?
Ma'am, I completely
understand your frustration.
Don't think I don't know
what's going on here.
We are immigrants
with no insurance,
so you think you don't have
to give us your best care.
Ms. Kwemo, I assure you we're
doing everything
in our power...
Are you?
I don't believe that.
You're right, Ms. Kwemo.
There's more we could do.
There are other tests
we could run.
Tests we need
Abena's consent for.
Dr. Choi, I need to speak
with you in private
for a moment.
Excuse us, please.
You know, Dr. Choi, there's
a pretty important statute,
known as
the HIPAA privacy rule,
that protects every patient's
personal health information
from being shared
with anybody else.
You heard her, Ms. Goodwin.
She wants us
to help her niece.
Still, it's not
for you to tell her.
That's the rule.
With all due respect,
if all we were gonna do
is follow the rules,
we should've done
what Stohl wanted,
and turfed her back
to East Mercy.
Hey, Maggie told me
about your car.
Those punks.
You know,
I've got this great guy,
glass, body, repairs.
Do you wanna give him a call?
I should really call
my insurance company.
Hold off on that.
Come on, join me on rounds.
Take your mind off
of it for a bit.
I want you to meet
this Jane Doe.
You were supposed to
stay with him.
You were the one that was...
You were supposed
to stay with him...
You know what?
I really should get a head
start with the insurance.
It always takes forever
to reach a human.
All right.
When you were knocking on the
other side of the bathroom...
Spencer's family
just got here.
They already suspect
it's bad news.
Just don't keep them
waiting too long.
Okay.
Something happened
to Spencer, didn't it?
He suffered a cardiac arrest.
We think there
might have been
an acute hemorrhage
in his brain.
What are you saying?
That he's dead?
We tried our best to
resuscitate him,
but there was
nothing we could do.
Oh... Oh, my God.
My...
My baby boy.
Oh, God. Oh!
Ma'am.
I... I am so sorry
for your loss.
You said he would be okay.
At the time, given the
information that I knew...
You killed him.
I had every reason
to believe...
I'm sorry!
You killed my baby brother.
You killed him!
Stop, stop, man.
Terrance, stop!
Security!
Someone, we need help!
Hey! Hey!
Get off, get off, get off.
Oh, my God!
Easy, easy, easy, easy.
Shh, shh.
Are you okay?
That kid got you pretty good.
Yeah.
You're looking at two,
three stitches, tops.
PD wants to know if you
wanna press charges, Noah.
Well, of course he does.
He was assaulted.
I asked Noah.
Nah, I don't wanna
press charges.
That family has already
been through enough.
Okay.
You're gonna let him
get away with this?
Sarah, he just found out
his brother died.
How is he supposed to respond?
Not like that.
Maggie.
Mmm-hmm, wait a second...
Maggie, why wasn't security
in the room from the start?
That's not
the established protocol.
Well, it should be, okay?
Reactions to a loved one's
death can be unpredictable.
There should always
be a guard nearby
when a family member
is being informed.
How are we supposed
to do our jobs
if we don't feel safe
and protected?
Hi, do you mind if I come in?
My name is Sharon Goodwin.
I'm in charge of
Patient and Medical Services
here at Gaffney.
Are you the boss?
Uh, something like that.
Where's your aunt?
Cafeteria.
Went to get dinner.
Ah.
Uh, I'd like to share
something with you.
Okay.
Marie Castilla.
Very bright.
Expert Scrabble player.
Beat me every time.
That's Danny Dimoulas.
Had this big baritone laugh.
It would just shake the floor.
Sometimes I still hear it.
Felix Ramadei.
He was a huge sci-fi nerd.
Wouldn't have much to say,
but if you got him talking
about galaxies
and space travel, well,
there went
your whole afternoon.
These are your patients?
They were my patients, yes.
They died in the '80s.
I was their nurse.
It was a terrifying time.
Some days we lost two,
three patients.
See, we barely understood
what AIDS was back then,
let alone how to treat it.
I don't want to see
these anymore.
I know.
It's hard, isn't it?
I could only imagine
who they might've been,
what they might've done
with their lives,
if they had a chance.
They had such promise.
These patients,
how many of them died alone
without their families?
Far, far too many.
I don't want to live
without my family.
And I'm sure they don't want
to live without you.
I can see it in
your aunt's eyes.
I know that look.
She's terrified of losing you.
You're so young, Abena.
Don't rob yourself of a future
that these young people
could only dream about.
I lost a lot of patients.
I don't wanna add you
to this folder.
April,
Abena is asking for you.
I'll take the test.
Abena, I need verbal
confirmation as to what test.
I want to take the HIV test.
These just came in
from Radiology.
Finally.
Thank you.
Damn, I'm not seeing anything.
Why was Will
getting a brain MRI?
What's going on, Natalie?
Is he okay?
Dr. Manning.
Yeah.
The PICU called.
It's your patient, Denise.
They need you upstairs.
All of a sudden I saw
her leg move,
and then she
reached out for me.
Reflexes are
all back to normal.
Denise, I'm gonna have you
stand for me now, okay?
That's great.
All right, now I'm gonna
have you walk to me,
and I'm gonna
let go, all right?
Okay.
Let's go.
Sam, what am I missing?
Best guess?
Some kind of toxin
needed to work
its way out of her system.
But how that got to Will?
I have no idea.
Contagion is one thing,
but this is more
like a game of tag.
Thank you, Dr. Manning.
Well, tag, now you're it.
Nat, what are you doing?
You shouldn't be...
Just look at your MRI.
You see that bump above
your coronal suture?
Yeah.
First I thought it
was a mole, but...
What is it?
Ah, there it is.
There what is?
Nat.
Gotcha.
Ow!
What is that? A tick?
Uh-huh.
Wait, is this Lyme disease?
Nope. Tick paralysis.
The salivary gland
produces a nerve toxin.
This guy came all the way from
Australia, courtesy of Denise.
It must've detached
from her scalp,
but stayed in her hair,
and when you picked her up,
it attached to you.
But if it was off her by
the time we got Denise
into the ED,
how come the paralysis
kept moving up her body?
It typically worsens
for a few hours,
once the tick is removed.
So I'm not out
of the woods yet.
Nope, but the paralysis
is mass-dependent,
so it shouldn't move
as quickly up your body.
But you still have
to spend the night in the ICU.
I gotta get this to Serology.
Don't move.
Ha-ha.
Hey, you need
a ride somewhere?
No, no, thank you.
I have a ride.
You know, I've been wondering
about something you said
earlier today about...
About not feeling
safe in the ED.
It was just
an innocuous comment.
Heat of the moment.
Reese, you and me,
we're both...
We're both
psychiatrists, right?
"Innocuous comment,"
really?
Dr. Charles, I know today
was not my finest hour, but...
What with my car getting
broken into and Noah
getting punched...
Sarah, I get it.
You know, this can be
a very chaotic,
often downright scary
work environment.
And you know what? It's not
necessarily for everybody.
I chose emergency psychiatry
because it was the right thing
for me at the time.
I'm sorry,
are you reassigning me?
Of course not.
I'm just saying
there are other options...
No. Not for me.
I want to be in the ED.
Okay.
Look, I promise
we won't need to
have this
conversation again.
I had a bad day.
That's all.
It's nothing
I can't deal with.
I got lucky, I guess.
My paralysis hasn't progressed
up past my knees.
Lucky?
Getting latched on by a tick?
Must've been the red hair.
There's not a creature in
the world that can
resist this.
That's very true.
I gotta go.
Doris is gonna kill me
if I'm late to her party.
Thanks, Maggie.
Have fun.
Bye.
Well, you know
what the best part
about being in an
isolation room is?
The privacy.
I don't have to be home
for another couple of hours.
Oh, really?
Mmm-hmm.
Hmm.
So, you can still feel
everything above the knees?
We should
probably make sure.
How do you think
it's going in there?
I can't tell.
I mean,
Vera's still in there.
She hasn't left.
That's a good sign, right?
Yeah.
Coming, April?
Yeah, um,
my boyfriend and I
will meet you there.
Good for you.
Pick up your jaw, Doris.
What changed?
Good night.
Noah.
Are you okay?
You're still up
for Doris' party?
Nah, I'm...
I'm just gonna head home.
We're the next party of two.
That's pretty.
You should get it.
Meh, I have
more than enough scarves.
Oh, this is us.
Oh.
You coming?
Yeah.
Could I help you, ma'am?
Um, yeah,
can you unlock this case?
Sure.
You have a FOID card?
A FOID card?
A Firearm Owners
Identification card?
The application takes
a couple of months to process.
That long?
It's required.
Uh, we could start
the paperwork tonight,
but in the meantime,
pepper spray
can make a gal feel safe.