- Previously: - Can I help you?
My name's Miles
Browne. I'm your father.
Go home. I think
you're having a stroke.
I have terminal cancer.
I waited for you and you left.
I thought about you every day.
It's good we're not roommates
anymore 'cause I couldn't do this.
Having sex doesn't make us a
thing. You need to see other women.
- Why? I don't really want to...
- No excuses.
Do you want to come
back to my place for more?
Just sleeping with you isn't good for
me. I want to give Heather a chance.
- Thanks for cooking.
- Mm-hm.
And the new skillet. The
chicken was delicious.
What'd I tell you?
Cast iron kicks ass.
Wait till you sear a steak in it.
You won't believe the difference.
I'll definitely try it.
So you up for a movie?
Actually, I thought
maybe we could just... talk.
Well, we spent
all night talking.
Yeah, about our jobs,
the news, the weather.
But...
we, uh...
never really talked
about the past.
We did. When you
were at the hospital.
Barely.
Have you forgiven me?
You know, I...
I'd rather just watch a movie.
- Claire, I don't...
- If you want to join, great.
If not, let's just
call it a night.
Okay. Movie it is.
Okay.
- How'd your presentation go?
- It was...
long.
Didn't you do laundry yesterday?
I'm not doing laundry. I'm
packing. For our camping trip.
We've done nothing
but work for three weeks.
And neither of
us feels... better.
A weekend in the woods
isn't going to change anything.
Not to mention you can't
even sleep on a couch,
much less outside on the ground.
I agree,
it's going to be a challenge,
but that's the point.
The further outside our
comfort zones we go,
the more distracted we'll be.
Whoa, man! It's me,
okay? Don't shoot!
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine!
Can you put the
gun down, please?
I opened the door and the
alarm went off, it's broken.
Oh, thank God.
- Man.
- I thought somebody, uh...
Hi.
It's not loaded.
Yeah, good.
No, no, not good. I...
store this loaded. Always.
I unloaded it.
For this exact reason.
You could've killed me.
And if you had been an
intruder, you could've killed me.
I'm not an intruder.
I'm me. Hello!
You had the gun
pointed right at my head!
No, I was aiming center mass.
My finger wasn't even on the trigger.
Thank you very much for
the apology, appreciate it.
Apology?
What in the world would make
you think that it was okay...
to unload my gun?
You almost shot me center mass,
okay? But by all means, don't apologize!
I did not almost shoot you!
And if you don't stop
with the apology...
I'm going to bed.
Alone.
The discoloration is a
deeper red than her last exam.
- And it's warm to the touch.
- Ow.
Sorry. How long
has it been tender?
Uh... About a week.
Well, it's not a bruise
or muscle strain.
The AV malformation's growing,
which is why I've been
recommending surgery since she was 5.
- And I've agreed every time.
- It's the first time there's been pain.
And the meds and the nutritional
supplements have been working.
No, they haven't.
And puberty will accelerate
the growth even more,
which puts her at a high risk
for spontaneous hemorrhage.
Turtleneck sweaters are
definitely not the solution any longer.
She needs the surgery.
When?
We can admit her
and start the prep now.
Awesome.
I hate turtlenecks.
Your EKG's normal, cholesterol's low,
and I didn't see any concerning moles.
I wear SPF 50 every day.
There was one thing.
I noticed that you previously
had been on antidepressants.
I stopped taking
those nine months ago.
They didn't help, and I found an
alternative therapy that's working great.
Wonderful. Cognitive
behavioral therapy?
No.
Uh, I'm injecting
a psilocybin serum
that I make from hallucinogenic
mushrooms I grow in my basement.
Okay, that's... crazy. You
need to stop that immediately.
There's tons of studies
online that show that psilocybin
causes dopamine surges
that treat depression.
And even more studies
that show that people
who self-medicate
with street drugs
end up more depressed,
addicted and sometimes even dead.
I spent a year researching
mushroom cultivation
and learning how to
extract the psilocybin.
And most importantly, this is the
first treatment that's ever worked.
I've never felt better.
At least let me do
some additional tests
to make sure there
aren't adverse side effects.
Sure. I'm always open
to new information.
Good morning.
How can I help you?
We're here to camp
at Yosemite Creek.
Great. You have a reservation?
- Reservation?
- Campsites are reservation only.
That's not true.
There are 27 first-come,
first-serve campsites.
There were 27
campsites at 6 a.m.
By 6:45, they were all taken.
- Need you to turn the car around.
- No, we need to go camping.
Sir...
- I understand you're upset, but...
- No, you don't understand
- at all why...
- Shaun, it's okay.
We'll find another place
to camp. Thank you.
Tighten up. Now work
from the outside in.
Eliminate any arterial feeders.
This would be a lot easier if they'd
let me do this seven years ago.
It's not their fault.
They're scared of surgery
for their 12-year-old child.
They're arrogant. And stubborn.
You're quiet.
Oh, sorry.
Well, I was actually thinking
about my own parents.
Miles thinks that we
should "deal with the past,"
so there's not a
barrier between us.
Things have been going pretty good.
You know, why mess with success?
I agree. When it comes to parents,
some things, in fact many things,
should just be left unsaid.
Says the guy who doesn't
have a relationship with his.
Yeah. Because I said things
that should have been unsaid.
Well, I agree with Miles.
I mean, it's not gonna be
an easy conversation, but...
wounds that aren't
treated get worse.
There's blood in her ET tube.
Must be a bleeder in the airway.
Retract the wound.
The research on psilocybin for
drug-resistant depression is promising.
Apex of the lungs look clear.
There's a difference between
"promising" and "proven."
Not to mention a drug
made by professionals
versus some guy growing
mushrooms in his basement.
You're the most skeptical guy I
know about alternative medicine,
- but this you agree with?
- I'm not surprised.
- That Park's a total hypocrite?
- That you two disagree.
You never agree on anything.
I think you just...
enjoy arguing with each other.
You need to get closer.
Can you focus on
the left inferior lobe?
- What is that?
- A lesion.
A fungal lesion.
This isn't camping,
it's tailgating.
There's trees, a place we
can pitch a tent and build a fire.
It smells like gasoline.
Oh.
I think their generator
might have a leak.
Just what you want
right next to a campfire.
We have a view of the lake.
It's pretty, isn't it?
Yeah.
We had to abort the laser
surgery due to a bleed,
but she's conscious and
stable now in post-op recovery.
The AVM infiltrated too
deep into the upper lobe
of the lung to
ablate with the laser.
We'll have to go back in and remove
her collarbone for better access.
Another surgery?
To remove her bone?
We'll put it back after
we excise the AVM.
She'll have to wear a
brace until the bone heals.
Vascular malformations
are chameleons.
It's hard to tell where
abnormal blood vessels end
and normal ones begin.
Well, you were all a lot more confident
in your assessment this morning.
- We want to take our daughter home.
- Yeah.
- Now.
- I'm sorry. That's not possible.
The laser surgery caused
weakening in the AVM,
which means it could
rebleed at any time.
Okay.
You're lucky. If you'd
scheduled your physical later,
your liver and lungs
would be failing.
And after the surgery?
What about my depression?
You're asking if you can continue
a treatment that's killing you?
Before I started the
psilocybin injections...
I was miserable.
I couldn't sleep,
I barely ate.
I can't bear to face
that darkness again.
I don't know if it's the
psilocybin or placebo effect,
or something else
neither of us understands.
But if you found
the light once...
you can find it again.
Okay.
It's a nice fire.
I used the teepee method.
I'm thinking open thoracotomy
and midline laparotomy.
We might be able to use
minimally invasive scope surgery
to get the big lesions
and attack the rest
post-operatively with anti-fungals.
More like minimally effective.
Better to be aggressive,
take them out at once.
That's a huge operation
with a long, painful recovery.
He has a huge problem.
This lesion looks like it
extends behind the liver.
You're the senior surgical resident.
You need to start making these calls.
I'm not so sure about that.
I'm sorry, but I question
Dr. Park's objectivity
when it comes to
Dr. Reznick's ideas.
I don't care where an idea comes from,
and I don't appreciate you accusing me...
It wasn't an accusation.
- Then what would you call it?
- A respectful and sincere question.
What's the answer?
My objective opinion is...
a minimally invasive
approach is best.
Okay.
I want it all mapped out with
a 3D reconstruction simulation
before we go in there.
We'll operate in the morning.
It's actually kind of soothing.
It reminds me of the dripping
faucet in our old apartment.
- The sound helped me fall asleep.
- Hmm.
I loved that building.
It's where we had our first hug.
Definitely not soothing.
This might help.
You brought earplugs
to a camping trip?
Sometimes you snore.
Thank you.
Mm. Ooh!
That's it, I give up.
I have a repair kit.
I don't want to fix things,
Shaun. I just want to go home.
Don't want to go home.
If you want to stay in a cold,
wet, leaky tent, go ahead.
But I am sleeping in the car.
Ah, 29:32.
I used to do sub-25
on recovery days.
Hey, you have time to grab
a quick bite before you go in?
I was actually thinking, uh...
maybe we could talk.
I would love that.
Well, the last time I
saw you, before you left...
I screamed at you because
you missed my birthday party.
And for the longest time,
I thought if I
could just tell you...
I was sorry, that
you'd come back.
It wasn't you, Claire.
None of it.
I mean, you... were a great kid.
So smart and thoughtful.
How could you just disappear?
Things between your mother
and I were such a mess.
One night, she was
having one of her episodes.
Told me...
I was worthless.
The only thing I was
good for was money.
I said, "Okay. If that's all you
want, that's all I'm gonna give you."
I sent her a check every month,
never saw or spoke to her again.
It was mean and petty.
- Pathetic.
- We never got any money.
What are you talking about?
I sent monthly support
until you finished college.
I worked two jobs.
I took out a loan to pay
for tuition and our rent.
Look...
I sent more than enough
for rent, for clothes, for food.
She stole my
money from my child.
- The child you totally abandoned.
- No, not totally.
It's not my fault she
squandered that money.
It's not your fault I
grew up without a father?
Without any social life
because I was so busy
being a mom to my own mom?
The woman that you walked out
on when things stopped being fun?
Okay, listen, I'm sorry,
okay? I didn't mean for this
- to become an argument.
- No, you're not sorry.
If you were, you wouldn't be
blaming her, using her as an excuse.
You took off...
because you were too weak to
do what a father is supposed to do.
To take care of
me. To protect me.
And now you're
back when it's easy?
When I don't need a father?
No, you know what? Forget it.
- Claire...
- Look, just don't... Don't call.
Don't come to the door.
Just leave me alone.
I thought this would be helpful.
I was wrong.
We can go home.
Well...
Why don't we do the
hike you planned first?
Is that what you want?
I think so.
Okay, new plan.
Blueberry pancakes. Then hike.
Then back home to our
warm and cozy and dry bed.
Divide the sternal
attachment of the SCM.
And done.
Removing the medial clavicle.
You have the talk?
- Yeah.
- I never said it would be easy.
You can't excise a tumor
without some bleeding.
Some tumors are inoperable.
He wants to be forgiven.
I... I just can't.
He doesn't deserve it.
Well, it's not the kid's
job to make the parents
feel good about themselves.
This mat of vessels is
invading the upper lung tissue.
- How deep does it go on your end?
- I can see underneath the apex,
but can't tell what's tumor
and what's subclavian artery.
We can't get this out without pulling
out the whole upper lobe of her lung.
Parents are not
going to like that.
No, I'll go.
They don't trust you.
- That's not your problem.
- It shouldn't be the patient's either.
I'll have a better chance
of getting their consent.
Brought some pastries.
Uh, I'm good.
I... I'm sorry that I, uh...
unloaded the gun
without telling you.
Thank you.
I, uh... I appreciate that.
I know that you're
nervous around guns,
which is all the more reason that
you should just leave mine alone.
Maybe there's a better
way to deal with this?
So, what if we kept your gun
in your nightstand, like always,
but we keep the
ammunition in another room?
So your idea of a
compromise is that
I agree to do what you've been
doing behind my back all along?
An intruder is not
gonna wait for me
to collect my bullets from
the guest room closet.
My house is not that big.
I'm so confused. You still
have to run up the stairs
and get the thing either way.
Do you ever notice that
whenever we're talking
about something related to
the home that we both share,
that you always refer
to it as your house?
I do?
This isn't about gun safety.
This is about your house and your
rules, and your wanting to control me.
You don't trust me to make
decisions about my own life.
I'm just trying to find a
way to make you feel safe.
I don't need you,
or any other man,
to find a way to
make me feel safe.
Walk here.
Oh, thank you.
It's actually pretty
outside the campground.
Another half mile and
we can see the lake.
You're really cute. I
want to take a picture.
Go stand on that log.
I'll get you from a low angle.
A hero angle because
you're my hero.
Okay.
Okay, a smidge to the left.
Shaun!
Are you okay?
Oh, my God, you are not okay.
Okay...
- On the count of three. Ready?
- Mm-hm.
One, two...
You were supposed to
wait until I got to three!
I know. But in the movies, they
always go early to catch you off guard.
You don't need the element of
surprise to reduce a dislocated ankle.
Okay, but did it work?
Yes. You...
You relocated it correctly.
- Damn.
- But...
my toes are still
dusky and numb.
The posterior
tibial artery's torn.
I thought it was just pinched.
If circulation isn't restored, I'll
have permanent tissue damage,
maybe even have to
have my foot amputated.
This is not a problem. I can
run to where I can get a
cell signal and call 911.
It'll take at least two
hours for you to run back
- to the campground.
- I'm faster than I look.
You told me you used to skip phys-ed
class because you hated running.
- I can hate it and still be good at it.
- No.
My pocketknife is
as sharp as a scalpel.
The tent repair kit
has nylon thread,
and you can use a fishhook
as a suturing needle.
You are obviously delirious
because there's no way
in hell I'm doing surgery.
It's not a complicated
procedure.
For a surgeon, which I'm not!
I'll guide you step
by step. Okay?
It'll just take two sutures.
I've seen you hem your pants.
An artery is not
a pair of jeans.
There's tequila in my backpack.
You'll need to sterilize the
incision, and I will need anesthesia.
- Shaun, I...
- Tequila! Stat!
We thought you
were certain before.
I know you're scared
and this is confusing.
We brought her in with
some minor inflammation.
No, the inflammation
was not minor.
What we are proposing
would reduce her lung capacity,
but she can still
live a normal life.
No. We're taking her someplace
else. We're gonna get a second opinion.
We can't cut out part
of our daughter's lung.
She'd never forgive us.
And maybe she shouldn't.
You were wrong to refuse the
surgery that Dr. Lim proposed years ago.
Are...?
Are you trying to guilt
us into agreeing with you?
You are guilty.
Ava is in this situation
because you were too afraid
to make a tough decision,
and now you are trying
to blame everyone else
because you can't deal with
the guilt of having messed up.
You need to stop thinking
about what is gonna make
you feel like a good parent
and start thinking about
what your daughter needs.
Careful with that anesthesia.
I need you coherent enough
to guide me through this.
Don't worry, I've calculated
the proper dosage...
No. No, not like that.
The scalpel goes on the left of
the tray, sponges on the right.
- Needle driver and sutures in the middle.
- Okay, got it.
Okay.
And might I suggest not
barking instructions at me?
I'm freaked out enough already.
I'll do my best.
Even with the tequila,
when you cut into my
ankle, I'll be in extreme pain,
which can cause irritability.
- I can't do this.
- You have to.
The worst that could happen
is you mess it up and cause
permanent damage to my foot,
which is exactly what will
happen if you don't do it.
Okay. Tequila, stat.
Suction.
That enough?
Perfect. Mediastinum's cleared.
Now, on to the lung lesions.
I'm having a problem
maneuvering in here.
There's too much peritoneal
scarring from the fungal deposits.
- Can you cut at it sharply?
- I'm too close to the common bile duct.
Need help?
Morgan was right.
There's no way to remove
all the lesions laparoscopically.
All right. Let's pull the
scopes and open him up.
Okay. The blood's pouring
out! What do I do now?
Okay. Okay, tighten the...
tourniquet and then use a
sponge to clear the blood.
Okay.
It's clearing up.
You should be able... to see...
I see it! And the leaking hole.
Now you just need to
use the needle driver
to sew the edges together.
Be careful not...
Be careful not to what?
Shaun?
Put the backpack under my head.
- How's that gonna help with your ankle?
- It... won't.
But I'm about to lose
consciousness from blood loss and...
I don't want...
dirt... in my m...
Shaun? Shaun?
Shaun? Shaun! Shaun!
Shaun! Shaun, come on!
Come on, Shaun. Shaun.
Okay...
Come on, Lea.
If you can hem a pant leg,
apparently you can do this.
All right. Okay.
I have freed the
pleural membrane.
Why does blood have
to be so damn slippery?
How am I supposed to tie a knot if
I can't even grip the damn thread?
Here we go. Here we go. Okay.
Okay.
Here we go.
You're a woman.
Um, yeah.
I've always considered myself a
supporter of women, you know,
equal pay for equal
work, right to choose...
Uh, thank you. From all of us.
Debbie seems
to think that I am...
overbearing and,
uh, controlling.
My ex was a humanities
professor and ACLU chapter head.
But I made more money,
and I don't think he was...
conscious of this, but I do
feel he was threatened by...
my independence.
The more insecure he got,
the more controlling he became.
He had to pick the restaurants
where we ate, the movies we saw.
And I definitely had
my own issues, but...
his need to control me was one of the
many reasons our marriage fell apart.
I can feel my toes.
Are you finished?
No.
Now I'm finished.
There's enough flow to keep the
tissue alive until we get to an ER.
You did this with
a tent repair kit?
And a fishhook.
She is very good
at fixing things.
You're lucky.
Yes.
I am.
And how do you feel?
Like a gutted fish.
Sorry, we had no choice but to
open you up to access all the lesions.
But they were able to remove them
all without damaging any of the organs.
You should recover fully.
Physically.
There are new antidepressants
you haven't tried.
But I also wouldn't stop
the mushroom cultivation.
Really?
After all this?
Cultivation. If this helped you,
it was either the placebo effect
or all the focus you put
into perfecting the process.
Sometimes, distraction
is the best medicine.
Hey.
We are... so sorry.
This is our fault.
It's okay.
I love you.
You know, I thought our
relationship was just a fun distraction.
But when you pushed me away...
I realized it was
more than that.
I was hurt, resentful...
which made every
interaction we had...
complicated.
What are you talking about?
You made sure it
wasn't complicated at all.
We stopped having sex
and now we're friends.
You know it's more than that.
And it can't be. Not anymore.
What does that even mean?
We still work together. We
have to talk to each other.
About work. That's it.
We can't try to keep some
sort of friendship going,
which means no more
jokes, no more teasing.
Nothing that isn't
totally professional.
So, what, we just...
act like robots
around each other?
I don't want that.
It's boring.
Well...
We act like we did before
we ever moved in together
and let ourselves
get into this...
unprofessional mess.
Yeah. Pretending that what happened
didn't happen, that always works.
You were a horrible father.
And you can't undo
the harm you did.
But I should forgive you.
You deserve it.
And I need it.
Because I need you.
So I'd... I'd like to...
keep spending time together...
and talking.
I would love that.
Do you think...
Think maybe we could, uh...
restart everything with a...
hug?
I was wrong.
I convinced myself that I
was right, and I was wrong.
I took choice away from you.
And I will do everything
I can to make it right.
I'm s... I'm so sorry.
You don't have to apologize.
Can you stop doing that?
I don't think I can
make this work.
I have...
had this feeling for months.
It's like a pit in my stomach
and I didn't want to...
face what it was,
but when we were
fighting, I just felt, like, relief,
like I had an out.
You think I don't
respect you. I don't...
I do.
Aaron, you almost walked
out of our wedding because I...
used bad grammar.
That was bad.
That was a bad moment.
Marriages are made
up of moments, right?
So many of our moments
are just... Are great.
Too many are so... Just painful.
♪ And I will hold you tight... ♪
This is crazy.
We love each other.
I love you.
♪ ...will keep you warm ♪
♪ I will build... ♪
I love you so much.
♪ And I'll build a fire... ♪
It's just not enough.
♪ And in our hearts ♪
♪ We still pray for
sons and daughters ♪
♪ And all those evenings ♪
♪ Out in the garden,
with red, red wine ♪
♪ These quiet hours
turning to years... ♪
Thank you.
The rain, the drunks, the
freezing cold night alone in my car,
and you almost
losing your foot was
definitely a bit more of a
distraction than I was hoping for.
But I'm really glad
you took me camping.
You're welcome.
♪ And I'll build a fire ♪
♪ You fetch the water
And I'll lay the table ♪
♪ And in our hearts ♪
♪ We still pray for
sons and daughters ♪
♪ And all those evenings ♪
♪ Out in the garden,
with red, red wine ♪
♪ These quiet hours
turning to years ♪