Previously on Grey's Anatomy...
Dr. Hunt and I go back a bit.
She's joining the program
at Grey-Sloan Memorial.
Perfect Penny killed my
husband. Get her out of my house.
Wilson, go away!
If you're out with Grey,
you're out, and I'm out.
You just signed divorce papers,
and you don't want a drink?
What are you,
pregnant? I think I am.
You have to tell him.
Obviously, I'm going to
tell him. When I'm ready.
If you want to start
over, forget all that.
Well, let's do
it. Just like new?
This is Major Thorpe.
It's great what
you did in there.
I'm just glad I saw it.
Well, we said we'll
follow up, and we will.
I'd like that... To
follow up with you.
That guy definitely just
asked for your number.
And that's what
flirting looks like.
When babies are born,
they usually come out crying
like there's no tomorrow.
It's loud. It's jarring.
And it's completely unfair.
That adorable, tiny baby
was forced out of
its mother's womb.
And forced to
breathe outside air
into its brand-new little lungs.
It's human nature.
No one wants to be
left out in the cold...
Rejected and alone.
I want to meet with the
residents immediately.
When a bedridden
patient stays in one place,
what's the outcome?
Bedsores. RICHARD: Exactly.
When a surgeon stays in
one place, what's the outcome?
One of us has bedsores?
Stagnation. Complacency.
A limited mind.
You have a short time
to learn here, people,
and you've snuggled
up to your specialties
like a warm, comfy bed.
Well, I am your alarm clock.
I'm pulling you out of bed
and broadening your education.
This is a Resident Scramble.
This is filled with
attendees' names.
Come on up and
draw your new service,
at random.
Bingo, Shepherd. Put it back!
But I... Back.
Dr. Grey, I was
told to report to...
Did you see the scans?
Yeah, I'm sorry I'm late.
I just got off the phone
with Bauer Medical.
They said that
Carson's recovering well
and his incision sites
and flaps are doing great.
That is great news.
Yeah, Dr. Thorpe
thought so, too.
He also thought you might've
given him the wrong number.
Thorpe? Who is Thorpe?
He has the right number.
Oh. Okay, so you're just
gonna what, ignore his calls?
Wait. Will someone please tell me
what is going on and who "he" is?
Meredith exchanged numbers with
a hot military surgeon over at Bauer.
He says he called,
but radio silence.
What?
It's nothing.
Why wouldn't you tell me this?
- Because it's nothing.
- Mmm-hmm.
Wilson, are you following me?
I'm with you today.
I'm on your service.
Blake is with me.
No, actually, all of the
residents were switched.
You need to go
talk to Blake, then,
because I don't have the
time to get you up to speed.
So, how hot is hot?
We have surgery.
Hot.
I heard there were puppies!
I thought it'd be
weird, you know,
the small talk, the eye contact,
the polite eating,
but really, it wasn't.
I mean, she was nice.
It was nice.
So you're getting
out there, huh?
I don't know about that.
I mean, it was sudden,
but yeah, it was a date.
Does Kepner know about it?
No. No, and do
not tell her, okay?
Sure. Whatever.
I mean, I'm not lying, you know?
I just don't want her to
hear it from someone else.
I mean, I'll tell her,
you know, when
the time is right.
Uh-huh.
Uh, we all hear the dogs, right?
There are dogs somewhere.
Once a month, a
rescue group brings in
a bunch of puppies for the kids.
It's good for morale
and healing and crap.
No. What's the matter?
Okay, I'm on peds today. No.
Hope you like dogs.
Hey. Long night?
Seventy-five-year-old man
ran his car into an electrical pole.
Electrocution and a
big intracranial bleed.
And a pacemaker implantation.
So I booked a
reservation around 8:00,
so we should maybe head
out around 7:00. That work?
Yeah, I can do that. Okay.
How fancy is this?
Well, first date, so
I took a big swing.
Dr. Shepherd.
Is this Mr. McColl?
Yes, Blake. Why?
The patient's
wife is downstairs.
Why are you telling me
this? Where's Edwards?
Dr. Webber mixed us up
today. I pulled your service.
No. No?
No, where's the wife?
She's downstairs in admitting.
Dr. Webber told me...
Tell Dr. Webber I said no.
Wait. I'm in a
whole other bracket?
Well, yes.
Your income has jumped
significantly since last year
and your husband's hasn't, so...
Are those our taxes?
Hey, Chief, stop
harassing my patient.
Hey, people ask us for free
medical advice all the time.
It's not harassment unless
I don't want to help her.
I just had fetal surgery and I've
been stuck on bed rest for weeks.
Which is actually pretty great
if you're an accountant
during tax season.
Nothing else to do but work.
No distractions
except, well, for this.
See, I normally do our
taxes. It's sort of my thing.
But, Courtney thinks that
maybe we should change...
Hey, you.
Out. You. Present.
You can't tell me what to do.
Fine.
I'll just... Yeah.
Okay, I don't even...
Warren.
Oh. Sorry. Um, just
give me a minute to...
DeLuca.
Okay, uh, Courtney
Hall, 23 weeks pregnant.
She's post-op from a
fetal laser photocoagulation
to separate a shared blood
vessel between two of her babies.
Wow, uh, quadruplets?
Yeah. That's what I
said when I found out.
Oh, good. You got
it. This is for you guys.
No, you did not need to do that.
Yes, we did.
You are the reason all
four of our little deductions
are still alive right now.
Babies. She means babies.
You kept all four safe
inside where they belong.
And I get to lie here for
eight more weeks. Yay!
She means, "Thank you."
Fetal medicine has its perks.
Surgery? Oh, God.
Well, his heart rhythm
had become very erratic,
probably due to
the electrical shock,
so I had to implant a pacemaker.
Oh, no. Poor Griffin.
The other concern is
Griffin suffered a brain bleed,
which I operated on.
A brain bleed?
Your husband will be awake
soon, and we'll know more then.
Oh, he's...
Well, Griffin's not
my husband. He's...
Hello, Lena.
How's my husband?
I understand he's been
in a terrible accident.
I'm sorry. We
thought you were the...
I am the wife.
She's the slut he's
been hitting on the side.
It's been 11 years, Gayle.
How is Griffin? Is he dead?
His accident was severe.
He needed surgery on
his heart and his brain...
So, he's almost dead?
We can take you to see him if...
I don't want to see
him until he is dead.
So, first, we need to check on
Kim Coley's baby's tracheal
balloon, and after that...
Warren. Go someplace else.
Why?
'Cause you're on my
service, and I said so.
Hey. Hey.
How you feeling?
Uh, good. How are you?
How are you feeling?
Fine.
Twelve weeks and fine.
Did you tell Jackson?
I'm worried that you're doing
this alone when you don't have to.
I'm not. I'm not
alone. I told you.
Okay.
Okay, okay. So,
then, let's do this right.
Let's get out in front of it.
I think I'd like to start with
booking a 3-D ultrasound,
and then, I'd like
to run a genetic test
to see if the fetus has
osteogenesis imperfecta.
No.
April, I get it.
With what you went
through last time,
you don't want a
bunch of needles
being stuck in your
belly... Arizona, I don't...
But I can do a CVS,
and then if it's there,
we'll see it and then
we'll just... We'll know.
The baby's not getting tested.
What?
Why?
Because my baby will be fine.
She said, "Because
my baby's fine!"
O.I. can be diagnosed early.
Why wouldn't she take
the test? That's crazy.
I know.
Well, then Avery will
have to convince her.
She won't tell him. I
don't know what to do.
Well, I'm not doing this.
I'm not lying to my friends.
No one's asking you to...
No one asking you to lie.
I say, "Pass me the coffee,"
and I feel like
I'm lying to him.
Well, then, we
need to talk to her.
"We"?
I didn't want to know about
this thing in the first place.
Fine. I will talk to her.
So, what kind of surgeon is he?
Oncology.
We can work with that.
Guessing 40s. Kind of tall.
And he's ranked in the military,
so he has an authoritative side.
I can hear you.
But you can't hear
the phone ringing.
Maybe her ringer's off.
It's not. Suctioning.
Sometimes your ringer is off,
and it's been off for so long
that you forget that it's off,
and you need someone
to help you figure out
how to turn it back
on. But once it's on...
Oh.
Oh! That's it.
Your ringer needs
to be turned on.
You've been on
vibrate for too long.
Ugh. Shut up.
If I answer, then
he'll ask me out.
And then I'll have to say no, and
there will be a lot of back and forth,
and I won't know when
it's okay to hang up,
so why answer?
Dr. Grey, I saw all
your clinic patients.
Can I scrub in?
Did you drain
Mr. Kurtzman's wound?
No.
Okay, Blake, well,
go get that done.
Wilson.
What?
Forget it.
See? Now you're
mixing up your residents.
You need to get that ringer
turned on loud and fast.
My ringer is fine.
Are you almost done?
I have three more
returns to get through.
Don't bother her
during tax season.
It's the first rule.
Should be done in just a second.
Um, okay, there's baby A.
Oh, there's baby B.
Yeah.
She's gonna be a
handful, right, hon?
She's a kicker.
And there's baby D. And...
Go get Robbins, would you? Yeah.
What? What?
Is something wrong?
Nothing. Nothing. It's, uh...
It's quadruplets, right?
Yeah. Why?
I'm just, uh... I'm looking,
and, uh, it's probably
just me, but...
What?
I can only find
three babies in here.
If I had known she
wasn't actually his wife...
You should have known.
- You're right.
You're absolutely
right. I just didn't...
Get your facts straight
before you let me
go spilling medical
information to just anybody.
You embarrassed me. I'm sorry.
She said that she was his...
Why are you even here?
I said to tell Dr. Webber...
Dr. Webber said that
he chooses to
decline your proposal.
Well, then take the day off.
Dr. Webber rejected that, too.
Watch his monitors,
don't touch him,
and stay out of my way.
The nurse will bring
up his personal things.
These are patient
pamphlets on pacemakers.
Give it to the side piece.
She can change his diaper.
I'm waiting for the funeral.
Mrs. McColl, your husband...
My husband, my
dear, was a sweet man
who turned into a
philandering bastard
who only cared about his money,
which I should have known
when he handed me that
prenup for my wedding present.
That thing is as
tight as my Spanx.
I see.
If he dies and we
are still married,
I get his $30 million, which
is way less than I deserve
for putting up with
that son of a bitch.
But it'll have to do.
I'm waiting him out.
Well, I don't think we have to.
He's 75 with a bum heart,
high blood pressure
and a cracked skull.
He probably won't even wake up.
Right, Dr. Shepherd?
We...
We're doing everything we can.
You wouldn't screw
with me, would you?
Oh, Gayle, I wouldn't.
There's not much
hope. So there's hope.
So if you want to just
sit right over here and wait...
Why the hell... Oh, come on.
That's what she wanted
to hear. And it's refreshing.
I mean, most family
members are like,
"Please, please, save him."
I mean, this takes the
pressure off us a bit.
Shepherd, I'm
kidding. That's dark.
Yeah, sorry. Really
funny, though.
Dr. Shepherd. What?
Mr. McColl's waking up.
Ooh, I called that wrong.
What...
Who the hell are you?
Mr. McColl.
Griffin, it's me. It's Lena.
You've been in a
pretty bad car wreck.
You've had surgery...
Where's Gayle?
Gayle! Where's Gayle?
Griffin, just relax, okay?
You need to calm down.
Bugs! Help me. Bugs!
He's hallucinating.
Give him five of Haldol...
Bugs!
He's calling me. I'm Bugs.
He hasn't called
me that in 30 years.
There you are.
Bugs, come here.
Bugs, come here. Come here.
Honey, what's happening?
What... Just...
What happened? Where
would he have gone?
Nowhere. He's in here.
Dr. Warren's just a little
behind on his fetal medicine.
- He's in here somewhere.
- Good.
We came in here with four
babies and we want to leave with...
There! See, there he is. He's...
Just moved down.
Why?
To get away from his sisters?
Courtney, I'm afraid
that you're in labor.
No, I can't be. It's too soon.
Months too soon.
No, I can't have them
now. They'll all die.
I can't be in labor.
I know. I know.
But you are.
Am I even having contractions?
I would notice, right?
When the babies are this small,
sometimes you don't
even feel the contractions.
Well, that's because she
shouldn't be having them.
Are you sure you're not wrong?
No, I'm not wrong. From
the position of baby C...
Charles. We're
calling him Charles.
Okay, Doug, we're
taking her into the OR.
In case something
happens, we'll be ready.
What? No one's coming today.
Doug... No! It's too soon!
They need more time, right?
Please. Do something. I am.
I can start her on
medication to stop the labor
and I can temporarily
sew her cervix closed,
and that might
give us enough time.
Might?
Labor's like a boulder
rolling down a hill.
Once it starts,
it's hard to stop.
But you're stopping the boulder.
I am. I am trying
to stop the boulder.
He doesn't remember me at all?
A brain injury of this nature,
it's not uncommon for some
memory loss to have occurred.
We've been together 11 years.
He wanted a divorce,
but she wouldn't...
Can I talk to him?
Help him remember me?
He's still confused
and agitated.
He's asking for...
It's best if you wait out here.
Her?
I took up with that lady? Why?
Because you're a stupid
son of a bitch, that's why.
Heart rate's looking good.
Wait, why would I take up
with her when I have you?
My wife.
You are the funniest. She is.
She's the funniest
gal I've ever met.
And you got the softest hands.
It's soft as a rabbit's
foot I had when I was...
Griffin. Stop.
Go on. Feel them.
I'll take your word for it.
Suit yourself.
You're missing out.
What happened,
Bugs? What did I do?
Uh, we fought. A lot.
About money.
I don't care about money.
Yeah, well, you
didn't when we met,
but you've done
very well for yourself.
What did I do, Bugs?
Why would I ever hurt you?
Oh, I've been asking
you that for decades.
Dumbass.
It's like a time machine.
I'm good here. You can go.
And magnesium's up.
Okay, Courtney. We're gonna wait
and see if this medication
calms everybody down.
And what do I do? Just lie here?
Yeah, and try to relax.
With four babies trying
to get over the wall?
And I still have 73 tax returns?
Well, I said try.
Contractions increasing.
Can I ask you something?
If a couple's been
married for three years,
why not file jointly? Warren.
I'm just... No, no. It's okay.
Well, that's not the problem.
You guys have a pretty
significant earnings disparity.
Well, I don't know if
I'd call it significant.
It's more than 200%.
A little more than that.
Her income increase is
raising your tax bill by a lot.
This is relaxing me.
Honestly, she shouldn't
even be filing as an individual.
She should incorporate.
Page Kepner.
Tell her to meet me in Exam
Room Five. I will be back.
Do not take your eyes
off of these monitors.
If there is any change in any
of them, you get me back here.
Okay.
Oh! There's another option. You
could both file as single individuals.
Well, how's that?
You could do what some
of my clients have done.
You could get divorced.
Why would we...
For the taxes.
Grey still ignores me.
Gross, gross, gross.
She refuses to fill
me in on her patients.
You can't restart Mrs.
Wheeler on tube feeds yet.
She had high
residuals last time.
Crap. I thought her
ileus was resolved. Crap!
You know, this is urine.
I've been urinated
on three times today.
What did you expect from babies?
I'm talking about
puppies... Dogs.
There are puppies
upstairs with the kids.
Why aren't we up
there right now?
Because the only thing worse
than peds is peds with puppies
because we're surgeons,
not veterinarians,
because we should
not be urinated upon.
I'm being crapped on.
You have to help me with
Shepherd. Shepherd wants me dead.
At least she knows who you are.
Grey keeps calling me your name.
That doesn't even sound new.
Being kicked out of bed was almost
better because then she would see me.
Jo.
She'd have to see my
face to slam a door in it.
All right, you get 10
more seconds. What?
You get 10 seconds to
complain about Meredith Grey.
After that, you're done. No
more talking about it again, ever.
This is an excellent
plan. How is this fair?
You talk and you
talk about Grey,
but you don't do anything
to change the situation.
You get 10 seconds.
After that, the only person you
can talk to about Meredith Grey
is Meredith Grey.
I can't say it all
in 10 seconds.
No, 'cause you have seven.
What am I supposed
to say to her?
She's the head of... Five.
A friend would listen.
A friend would not...
Time.
Ugh!
Never again.
Can I just say
one more... Never.
Hey. I got your page.
What do you need?
Hey. Do you trust me?
Arizona, I am swamped, and...
I'm the only one that you
ever told, so do you trust me?
Yes, of course. I trust you.
I can feel the boulder starting
to roll, and I need to stop it.
So if you trust me,
then let me help you.
And you have to let
me help you my way.
Which means that you
need to tell Jackson.
And you need to let me
give you a full work-up.
You're acting like I'm
not taking care of myself,
but I am a doctor.
I'm not stupid.
I'm just not interested
in getting certain tests.
I don't want you going through
what you went through last time, April.
I'm not worried about me. I am!
And I am trying to help
you get what you want,
which is a healthy baby.
One that's not gonna
go through horrible pain.
Isn't that what you want?
Dr. Robbins. ARIZONA:
Not now, DeLuca.
Dr. Warren sent
me. It's Courtney.
Oh, thank God you're back.
You say her contractions
are more regular?
Yeah, and baby C is getting...
Charles. Charles is
showing recurrent decels.
Okay, Courtney.
I think that Charles is still
trying to make a break for it.
What? How do you know?
Because I'm holding his feet.
How could she not know
she was birthing a baby?
It's a quad at 23 weeks. He's
about the size of your hand.
Quads. Going from
one litter to another.
Peds is weird.
We'll need at least two full NICU
teams down here for the transport.
Okay.
I'm just saying.
I have done our
taxes every year.
Why change it up now?
There was never a reason until
now. Things changed this year.
No, one thing changed this
year, Miranda. One thing. Your job!
It was a pretty big change.
I need warmers and
neonatal resuscitation trays,
and if you don't have
to be in here, get out.
It's about to get crowded.
Hi, Courtney. My
name's Dr. Karev.
You're the out guy. We met
you during our tour of the NICU.
I am, and I can assure you,
we're gonna do everything...
No, no, no. Don't
you talk to me.
Dr. Robbins talks to me.
Dr. Robbins is the
in guy. She's the one.
These babies are staying
in. Dr. Robbins is in.
You're keeping them in, right?
It's Charles, right?
Courtney, Charles
already made up his mind.
He's partially out, and
once he's completely out,
they all come out. Dr. Robbins.
Promise me that
they're gonna survive,
that they'll live
once they're out.
All four babies.
I need four
umbilical line set-ups.
Warren. Wait.
Just one.
I'm sorry? I said
one set-up. Go!
What are you doing?
I'm stopping the boulder!
Heading up to check
on McColl's vitals.
Make sure Blake's
watching monitors.
What is Blake's problem?
What don't you like about her?
She seems on top of it to
me, so what am I not seeing?
She's... No, she's...
I'm the new guy.
So if she's the dead
fish, I'd like to know.
It's personal
between her and me.
You can form your
own conclusions.
Hmm. That's kind of you.
Must be nice for Blake.
What does that mean?
Come on. You and Hunt
are obviously pretty tight.
I'm sure you've formed
some conclusions about me.
We should go to the steakhouse
we went to after our honeymoon.
That place isn't
even there anymore.
I'm sorry, guys. Can I get
in here a second, please?
What's... Something wrong?
Mr. McColl, can you
squeeze my hands
as hard as you can, okay?
Follow the light.
Blake, what is it?
Page Shepherd immediately.
His ICP is climbing.
He needs a
ventriculostomy, stat.
Start a ketamine drip
and grab an intubation kit.
What is going on?
Ma'am, we are going to help
him, but I need you outside.
Have you ever done
a ventriculostomy?
Yes, but I'm not
supposed to touch him, so...
Can you do one? I'm not
supposed to touch him.
You're the neurosurgeon on call.
Shepherd said no, so I'm not
gonna drill a hole in his head.
Would you please just do it?
You're running
out of time, Blake.
So I'm gonna deliver
Charles, I'm gonna stop labor,
sew up the cervix, and then
leave the rest of the three inside
for delayed delivery.
That's impossible.
Yes. Once Charles is out,
she'll keep having contractions
to deliver the placenta.
They'll all deliver.
It's how it works.
Okay, fine. Fine, great.
Then I don't deliver
Charles' placenta.
After I cut the
cord, I sterilize it.
I put it back inside, and
we put Mom on antibiotics.
Do you know how
dangerous that is?
If that placenta stays in, it could
cause an infection, even sepsis.
It puts Mom at risk,
all three babies at...
Alex, I am a fetal surgeon! I
know more about this than you do.
I know exactly how they can
die. Have you done this before?
Has Nicole Herman?
No. I don't know
that anyone has.
Robbins.
Please stop!
Stop. I know that
you're gonna say no,
and I don't want to be in a
position where I go against you.
I know that this
is a judgment call,
but your judgment
is not better here.
I know what has to be done,
and this is the only way
that I know how to do it.
Okay, what I was going to say...
Good luck.
You're gonna let her...
I'm gonna let her do
what she's here to do.
And I suggest you do the same.
What are you doing?
His ICP was through the roof.
Evidence of herniation.
He needed a burr hole to...
Relieve the pressure. Don't
tell me what a ventric is.
Why would you let her do this?
'Cause she caught it.
And she could.
Get out of my way.
Get away from him.
Ventriculostomy catheter.
Did you prep for the EGD?
No. I prepped for a colonoscopy.
When you said scope,
I assumed that that's...
But I don't need you
to assume anything.
Never mind.
Blake knew we were
checking for an upper G.I. bleed.
It's just... I'm sorry.
Let me go and...
It's fine. You're
just not Blake,
and so let's prep for the EGD
and page me when we're ready.
No. I'm not Blake.
I'm Wilson. Jo Wilson.
Dr. Josephine Alice Wilson.
I'm a surgeon. I'm a human being.
I'm not some stupid lump
that you can just kick around
or talk down to or talk down
about or dismiss and discount.
I get it.
You don't like me, but I'm here.
I'm in Alex's life,
and I'm staying.
And you have to
start respecting that.
I don't know where
you're getting this.
I'm trying to move
forward, okay? And I can't
because you're always around
the corner blocking my way,
making everything so damn hard.
You are overreacting.
No, I'm not.
That's exactly what I'm
talking about. I'm done.
I'm done with all of it.
You know, call your
damn Army guy back
and get your own boyfriend.
Are you finished?
Oh, my...
Okay, are you ready?
Just Charles? Just Charles.
His sisters will just
have to deal with the fact
that he wanted
to come out first.
Typical boy. Okay. Okay.
That's good.
It's safer that way, right?
They get more time?
Courtney, I need you to hold on
for a little bit longer, okay?
I need you to trust me. Can
you do that? Can you trust me?
I'm sorry. It's just...
Can Doug be in here?
We had always talked
about the delivery and...
No, we can't risk any additional
bacteria during the procedure.
It's just too dangerous
for you and for the babies.
Okay.
Warren. Can you...
Absolutely.
Don't forget that you need to...
Eyes on monitors.
Okay. All right.
Okay, Courtney.
I just need the tiniest
little push. Okay, ready?
Okay, good. Good,
good, good. Okay.
Okay, clamp.
Karev. ALEX: Right here.
Okay. Okay.
All right. What's happening?
Everything's happening
exactly like it should.
You just breathe.
Okay. Okay.
Here we go.
His CT showed he's
having a re-bleed.
I will operate,
but the fact that
it's bleeding again...
It's not good.
And when he wakes up,
will he be the same, or...
Will you please go away?
This is between
me and my husband.
So please go.
Will he be the same?
There's just no way of knowing.
I just got him back.
I lost 33 years
with that old jerk.
Only a man that I
could love that much
would make me feel so angry.
I just want him back. I just...
I just want to have the chance
to love him again.
Blake, find Edwards
and tell her to
meet me in OR One.
Yeah.
Shepherd, you don't have time to
go chasing around after Edwards.
You need to be in there now.
Blake.
Wait.
No significant post-op
changes. That's good.
Yeah.
He's called how many times now?
Oh, God. Just give me the phone.
I'll send him a nice
blow-off text. No, not a text.
She is not a monster.
But Callie's right,
Mer. We need a plan.
We don't need anything.
God, between you and Wilson...
What about Wilson?
Oh, she just tore into me
about how I treat her like crap.
She really lost it.
What?
You... You kind of
treat Wilson like a...
Like... Callie. Like a gnat.
Yeah. You swat her.
Well, that's what we do to
residents. I've seen you guys swat.
We're all hard on
residents. We swat.
Yeah, but we like them.
Yeah, I like Wilson.
Do you?
Suction.
There's too much swelling.
I want to talk you through it.
I want to tell you
what I did and why.
Blake, I don't need
your excuses now.
It's not for me. It's for you.
I think you'd like to know what
happens when you're not here.
Edwards says you like that.
Just... Suction.
I was tracking his vitals.
He was bradying down slowly
and becoming hypotensive.
He had a dilated pupil.
All classic signs of raised
intracranial pressure.
I knew that he
needed the ventric,
so I asked Dr. Riggs
to prepare it.
He thought I was qualified.
I knew I was qualified.
Suction. More.
Then what?
I used your craniometric
method for the drilling site,
prepared it adequately.
I identified Kocher's point
at 11 centimeters, then...
All right, Betadine.
More. Just pour the
entire bottle on the cord.
Karev, how are we
doing back there?
APGAR score is 3.
I need a smaller tube.
- That's a three.
- Then get me a two.
- Alex!
- Give me a minute!
Endoloops. Is Charles okay?
Dr. Karev is just trying
to get some air into his lungs.
She's still having contractions.
Okay, uh, increase
the magnesium rate.
You know what?
Uh, I'm still confused.
Take me through
the deductions again.
Um, okay.
First, the obvious. Do
you have any dependents?
We do. We do.
One. A son.
Me, too.
I have a son now, too.
You're just packing.
Should we resuscitate?
No.
He's gone.
He herniated.
He was brain-dead minutes ago.
Time of death, 18:09.
Did I...
Was it what I... No.
No.
You were perfect.
He didn't make it.
Should I find Gayle?
No, I will. NATHAN: No, I'll go.
I mean, you have plans, right?
I'll tell her.
But thank you. Yeah, no worries.
Let's go, Blake.
Is he stable?
A little hypotensive,
but oxygenating well,
which is something
for his size, so...
So we got all four.
You got all four.
Thank God.
How's Courtney?
She's stable. She's back in her
room with three fetal heartbeats.
It'll be day-to-day to
see if it works, but...
Well, even just a day or two
more inside will help the other three.
Yeah.
Look, you know I didn't
agree with the whole thing.
I didn't think it
would work, but...
Mmm, Karev.
Are you trying to give
me a compliment?
I'm saying no one else
could have done what you did.
Did you talk to Kepner?
I tried.
I just... I don't think
that she hears me.
We...
We have to do something.
Yeah. I know.
Hi! Dr. Robbins?
You ready to meet your son?
Yeah.
Here we go, hon.
There he is.
Hi!
Hi, baby.
He's so beautiful! Hi!
Hi! Hi!
Hi!
You paged?
Um, Robbins has
requested you for her service
for the foreseeable future.
Apparently, you're really
good with the moms.
Yeah, I'm not. I just
did what Robbins...
No, you helped that woman
through the scariest
hours of her life.
I did, didn't I?
Yes, you did.
And you got us a new accountant.
Wait, what?
I hired Courtney to
do our taxes for us.
'Cause, you know, so
many things have changed,
and, um, we're
both so busy and...
Well, you're a resident, and...
And you're the Chief.
I am.
Are you okay with that?
I just...
Uh...
It's just less work for
you, I was thinking.
Yeah. Yeah, of course.
Okay.
So I'm just gonna go
finish Robbins' rounds.
Okay.
See you at home?
Yeah, see you at home.
I'm sorry. What
are we doing here?
You got to tell him.
If he figures it out,
sooner or later...
Look, he's gonna hear
it from someone else.
Uh-huh.
Look, I'm just saying
the longer you wait,
the worse it's gonna
be. Mmm-hmm.
And you got to
listen to Robbins.
Wow, you and Arizona, you...
You're a great team.
Well, we just want...
No, it's sweet.
Thank you. Really.
You're so invested.
You're like the Supreme Court
just trying to tell a woman
what she can and can't do.
I don't want to see
you guys get hurt again.
Well, neither do I!
I'm not telling him because
we have been through enough.
Especially him.
Because he never
got over the last one.
He never had the chance
to, and I am hanging on
to every last
shred of faith I have
that this time, it'll be okay.
But he doesn't have that.
So it'll just be better
if he doesn't know yet.
It won't. You're
making it worse.
You're right.
I am hard on you.
Alex hasn't had it easy.
Everyone he's ever been with
has run away or stolen his job
or gone crazy or
broken his heart.
None of them stick.
And he doesn't deserve
to take another hit.
But the point is, I am sorry
for squashing you like a
bug or whatever it is that I do.
Thank you.
But, you know, you
are what you allow.
And if you let them pluck off
your shiny little insect wings,
they will.
Um...
Okay.
So don't let them. Don't let me.
Understood?
Yeah.
And for the record, Wilson,
I am rooting for you to stick.
Hey. Are we not going?
I'm sorry.
I have not had a
chance to change. Um...
This day. Ah.
We're canceling.
No. No. I...
I just... I lost a patient.
And his wife lost him, too.
Was it Riggs? Did
he do something...
No.
No, Riggs was great.
I can see why you liked him.
It was Blake.
Blake lost your patient?
Not at all.
Blake has microscope hands,
a level head,
more assured in the OR than
any resident I have ever seen.
She's a natural neurosurgeon.
And now I have to teach her.
I owe it to her, to teach her.
Dinner's off.
No. No. Owen, I can rally.
No. No. It is off.
Come with me.
Come on.
You know, I don't
really like surprises.
You'll like this one.
Excuse me, can we get five
minutes before you leave?
Yeah. Five minutes?
For what, exactly?
Come on. Let's go.
Studies have shown
that petting a dog
can actually lower
blood pressure.
Owen.
And they make a really
crappy day a lot less crappy.
Oh...
Affection,
acceptance
and unconditional love.
We all want it.
We all look for it.
Nice night.
See, right about now,
you're thinking I'm
some kind of stalker.
Yeah, I've called.
And I've texted.
Because I wanted
to see you again.
And I thought I'd ask
you out, but I can't do that
if you don't call me back.
I thought I'd show
up here, ask you.
That way, if you
wanted to turn me down,
you'd have to do it in person.
Looking at my very nice
face makes it hard to say no.
So, what do you say, Dr. Grey?
Would you like
to go out with me?
But when we find it...
It's flat-out terrifying.
Um, have you seen Dr. Avery?
Upstairs in the lab.
Because just as quickly
as we may have found it,
it can disappear.
Jackson, can we...
And we're back
out there in the cold.
Why is she telling me this?
Oh...
Alone.