You were supposed to wake me up!
I'm not your damn mother, Brian!
Why is it so cold in here?
I called the super twice!
What have you done?
I'm studying so I can get a job
that pays enough for us to move out!
You don't realize how you talk
to me sometimes! It's disgusting!
You don't know when to
stop! You just keep pushing!
I have a life too! It's not
waiting on you hand and foot!
- Know what your problem is?
- We should work as a team.
We don't because you don't treat
me as an equal. You treat me like crap!
How do you think it makes me
feel? You're constantly belittling me...
Give me at least five minutes in the
morning before you act like a bitch.
- Shut up!
- Both of you shut up.
You know what your problem
is, Brian? You don't need me!
You don't even like me.
- Keep it up!
I just cook and clean,
pick up your dirty laundry.
But guess what,
that's not why I'm here.
Hi, this is Abby.
Leave a message.
Hello, Abby? Abby, are
you there? Hello? Abby?
I thought I'd catch
you before your shift.
Anyway, I wanted to
wish you a happy birthday.
Hi, Mom.
No, I was just getting up.
Thank you.
- Ooh.
- Ooh!
Your feet are like ice.
I'm sorry.
- I put on some coffee.
- What time is it?
- It's about 7:30.
- Mm-hm.
- You sleep okay?
- Yeah. You?
Mm-hm. Except for the snoring.
- I don't snore.
- Aw. Yeah, right. Like a truck driver.
I don't snore.
Stop it.
Oh, no.
Oh, yeah? Oh, wait a minute.
I've arranged for a nurse's
aide for you while I'm at work.
- A nurse?
- Just for a couple weeks.
I've got half a dozen people
in this house every day.
Well, then one
more isn't gonna hurt.
If it gets any colder I'm going
to winter in the Bahamas, alone.
I thought I heard someone.
Is it just me or is
it freezing in here?
Mom, what are you doing here?
I assumed you could use a hand
while your grandmother recovered.
How are you feeling, Millicent?
I've been better.
- Where's Jack?
- Kansas City, I think.
- You don't know?
- He's on an extended business trip.
We missed the pleasure of
your company at Christmas.
- You know how the holidays can be.
- Where are you staying?
- I was hoping to stay here.
- In the house?
- Yes, if that's all right.
- Yeah.
It is freezing in here. Would
somebody please turn up the furnace?
I will go get Alger on it.
- It won't start.
- Did you flood it?
- No. It won't turn over.
- You leave your lights on?
- No.
- You probably did.
- No, I didn't. Hi.
- Hi.
- Do you have any jumper cables?
- No, sorry. I take the El.
I guess you're not the only
one today. Give me the keys.
My husband's not
really a morning person.
Hi, I'm Joyce. We moved here
a few weeks ago from Virginia.
- Hi. Abby.
- We're in 205.
I know. I think you
guys are right beside me.
Nice meeting you.
- So I guess we're neighbors.
- Just a wall between us.
Well, maybe you could come over
for coffee or something sometime.
Sure.
Hey, can we give
you a ride somewhere?
- No, thank you.
- Are you sure? It's really cold out there.
I told you, you flooded it.
Welcome to Chicago.
Oh.
Oh, son of a bitch.
You're leaving?
I phoned the Pediatric
Cancer Society to inform them...
she wasn't coming to their luncheon,
and they managed to corral me.
You don't really have to do that. She
wasn't going. She just does it for effect.
I'm aware of her behavior.
But they actually
were expecting her.
- You'll be back tonight?
- You're really staying?
Yes. Unless I'm not welcome.
No, no. It's just I thought
you were covering.
Dad's in Denver, actually.
- Your father told you.
- Well, it was pretty obvious.
He was here for two days
at Christmas without you.
You thought he was still here.
We left it a little open-ended.
Really?
I'm sorry, John.
I should have phoned you and
let you know that I was coming.
Yeah, well...
It's good to see you.
Sanitation guys found
him in a dumpster.
Minimally responsive to deep
pain, thready pulse in the 50s.
- You sure he's not dead?
- He's still moving air.
Barely. Abby, can
you bring this guy in?
- I haven't even clocked in yet.
- I know, but you have a coat on.
Hey, I know this guy.
Oh, man.
Is this great or
what? Empty chairs.
Empty racks.
Nothing like subarctic temperatures
to keep the freaks at home.
- Except it's freezing in here.
- Maintenance is checking the furnace.
This is what we get for
punching holes in the ozone layer.
Isn't the greenhouse
effect make it warmer?
Greenhouse effect, my
ass. It's 40 below out there.
- What's this?
- This is Icicle Andy. You want him?
- He's yours.
- I thought he froze to death last year.
- The Ice Man cometh back.
- Okay, Trauma 1's open.
Get his core temp, pump in some warm
saline. Throw a heating blanket on him.
I'd keep that on if I were you.
He's bradying down.
No luck. Now it's A-fib.
Sounds like
rhonchi on the right.
- Probably pneumonia.
- I think he's decreased on the left.
Do you want to put in a chest tube?
- No.
He's got bad vascular
disease. We'll never get a line in.
Fine. Prep for lavage.
Oh, man. Look at this
dude's hands. Ugh.
- Can you get a pulse ox?
- I don't know.
I can barely get the monitor...
Ugh!
What's wrong?
- Snapped off.
- He gave you the finger, huh, Abby?
- Can they re-attach that?
- Not without superglue.
Let's get a central-line kit, Betadine
and some warm blankets to start.
No, you can't come
in. You have to go back.
- Where's my mom?
- She's not in here.
- Yes, she was.
- You got this?
Yeah. Warm liter of IV saline.
- You lost your mom?
- A second line.
- Not one of these two ladies right here?
- She was in there.
Okay. Well, maybe she's all finished.
Do you want to see if we can find her?
- I'm Abby. What's your name?
- Douglas.
- Douglas what?
- Douglas Leeman.
Okay, Douglas. Right this way.
- What's your mom's name?
- Bee.
Bee? Is that short for Beatrice?
- Barbara? Betty?
- Just Bee.
- Just Bee. Okay.
- Abby, can you help me?
Sure. Frank, this is Douglas
Leeman. He's lost his mom.
This is Frank. He's very
good at finding people's moms.
Douglas, you like doughnuts?
- When did the chest pains start?
- This morning.
But I've been feeling crappy...
for a couple of days.
I thought it was just a
cold or maybe the flu.
Bi-basilar rales. Have you
experienced any shortness of breath?
Yeah. I thought
I'd step outside...
catch a breath of fresh
air. I got so dizzy I fainted.
Three-plus pitting
edema on both feet.
- Have you had anything like this before?
- Never.
- Do you have a heart condition?
- No.
- Are you on birth-control pills?
- No. I'm trying to get pregnant.
I've been taking
fertility drugs.
- FSH.
- For how long?
- Um, what's today?
- Well, the 10th.
Yeah. Then I'm on my tenth.
All right. Let's get a CBC,
Chem-20, a DIC panel, and a D-dimer.
Am I having some sort
of reaction to the drugs?
It's possible, but we need to run
some more tests to know for sure.
You've got fluid in your lungs,
which could be a sign of a blood clot.
A blood clot?
It's unlikely, but I just
want to make sure.
It could be a possible side
effect of the medication.
Let's do a
Doppler. I'll be back.
- You want me to call your husband?
- I'm not married.
Oh. Boyfriend?
I decided to have
a baby on my own.
Got tired of waiting
around for Mr. Right.
I know that story.
- Chest x-ray and EKG?
- Yeah. And set her up for a V/Q.
- I haven't seen you around lately.
- I've been working nights.
- How was your Christmas?
- Quiet. What did you do for New Year's?
I worked.
That's always fun.
Did you make any resolutions?
- I'm gonna help out more.
- Help out more where? Here?
No. Europe.
I've volunteered to go to Bosnia for
two months with Doctors Without Borders.
- Bosnia?
- Yeah. I speak the language.
- What brought this on?
- I don't know. Change of scenery.
Good, huh?
Hey, nice hat, Snoop.
Hey, Frank, you gonna
get the heat turned up?
- They're working on it.
- Really?
Is that why the thermostat
in the lounge says 56?
Get used to it. We're
heading into another ice age...
- like the one that killed the dinosaurs.
- Cold didn't kill them, cholesterol did.
Mr. Ellison in Curtain 3 can go home.
Miss Renfew in 4 needs to be admitted.
- Got a minute?
- Uh... No, not really.
I hope your day's shaping
up better than mine.
Doubt it. I picked up Rachel's laundry
after you left. This fell out of her jeans.
- She's smoking.
- I doubt she uses it to light campfires.
- What are you gonna do?
- I don't know.
- Find anything else in her pockets?
- No.
What if it's not cigarettes?
Her boyfriend tested
positive for marijuana.
Ex-boyfriend.
- I'll search her room.
- Is that wise?
Well, if she's doing drugs,
I want to know about it.
Asking her doesn't guarantee
I'm gonna get the truth.
But searching her room, that's
such a violation of her privacy.
You suggested I go
through her pockets.
In the course of doing laundry.
- Dr. Greene?
29-year-old male,
8-foot fall, no LOC.
- Can we talk about this?
- Come find me.
Normal vitals.
Ha-ha-ha. This is
adorable. Don't you think?
It's pretty cute.
You wanna buy it?
No. They won't let
me send him any gifts.
He must be getting
pretty big now, huh?
Yeah. Oh, they sent a video of
him walking, just before Christmas.
Won't be long now before he's
asking to borrow the keys to the car.
You know, I'm starting to wonder if
I'm making any right decisions lately.
It's mid-year. Something
will open by spring.
Well, maybe they'll
open back up at County.
Hey, cool.
Have you seen these?
These are really neat.
John, um, what would you say...
if I told you I asked the
waitress at Doc Magoo's...
if she remembered
Weaver being paged...
the night we lost
the Marfan case?
I'd say that place is full
of people with pagers.
I know. I was desperate.
So, what? She didn't remember?
Not about Weaver getting paged.
But she remembers Weaver
coming back, looking for her pager...
and finding it in the bathroom.
She couldn't answer my page, John,
because she didn't have her pager.
- Are you sure?
- I believe it.
Don't you?
Yeah, that explains it.
What are you gonna do?
- He died?
- Yep. Did you know him?
Only as Icicle Andy.
I think he was a Vietnam vet.
I heard bums are reincarnated
as pigeons when they die.
Really?
I think it's the
other way around.
Check it out.
Tickets to tonight's Blackhawks
game. And they're good seats too.
Whoa. Where did he get those?
- Any ID?
- Mm-mm.
Just two dollars, some
change and matches.
- Are you gonna keep the tickets?
- No.
- Can I have them?
- Why not?
- I think it's called grave robbing.
He ain't using them.
Somebody might
come to claim the body.
- I'm serious.
- Yeah, right. Seriously, I need them.
- No.
- Look, the tickets are only for tonight.
- Nobody's coming for this guy.
- Forget it.
Oh, come on, Abby.
Abby, look. He's
straight-up dead.
- Can you take a look at something?
- What patient?
Mr. Paninski. Unstable angina.
I called CCU. I wanna make
sure I didn't miss anything.
- Did you do a rectal?
- No.
- You better.
- Because...?
- Because if his stool is heme positive...
- The heparin. Right. Thank you.
- Frank.
- Yeah?
- You said you'll find his mother.
- I tried.
No Bee Leeman checked in today.
I'm beginning to think
somebody dumped him.
He said his mother was in Trauma 1.
Can you double-check it with the admit log?
Sure. MAN: Abby.
- Hi.
- Richard.
- How's it going?
- What are you doing here?
I think it's colder in
here than it is outside.
You look great.
Thank you. Shift
work becomes me.
- So how are things?
- They're good.
Good. That's good.
You seeing anyone or...?
Oh, yeah. I'm breaking
hearts all over town.
What do you want, ex?
- Ex?
- Yeah. Can I call you "ex"?
Because it's almost like sexy, so people
might think it's short for "ecstasy"...
or "triple X," which
stands for porn, uh, now.
Except for in cartoons
where it stands for poison...
which I always
thought was funny, but...
What do you want?
Oh. Look, I...
Well, I wanted to
talk to you in person...
so you didn't hear this
through the grapevine.
Oh, my God.
- What?
- Are you going to jail?
No.
Uh, I'm getting married.
- Married?
- Yeah.
You'd think I would've
learned my lesson.
I'm glad one of us did.
- What, is she rich?
- Hardly. She's a teacher.
- Not that one you had at the museum?
- No. No. No.
Her name is Corrine. She's really
great. She's really down-to-earth.
- I think you might even like her.
- How old is she?
She's 34.
She has a 6-year-old
son, Adam. Really great kid.
You're gonna be a father?
Stepfather, yeah. It's kind
of hard to believe, huh?
Yeah. Instant family.
I always wanted kids. So...
Since when?
Uh... You know, just a while.
I guess we just never
talked about it, you know?
And you felt that today was the
day you had to tell me about all this?
Is today a bad day?
Nope.
Um...
So, what? Am I supposed
to give you my blessing?
- That's up to you.
- Well, I have to get back to work.
Richard.
I hope that it
works out this time.
Thanks.
Aspen's great. There's
three separate mountains.
- So you don't have to be an expert.
- Mm-hm.
What is that?
What?
Oh. Yeah, they got
runs for every level.
Is that your jaw?
- What?
- That click-click-click sound.
- Oh, my God. You can hear that?
- Yeah.
I can't help it. I think I have
this TMJ happening thing.
Here. Chew.
- No.
- Come on. Chew so I can hear.
No.
Get out of here.
- I'm going back to work.
- I'll take care of this.
You should see a dentist.
Either that or you should find
someone else to eat lunch with.
- I'm sorry about that.
- What?
I should have said something
sooner. It just sort of snuck up on me.
I hate it when that happens.
It's really more about
friendship than anything else.
Really?
Never seen you
kiss Frank like that.
- Abby...
- Don't sweat it, Carter.
- Where's Frank?
- Don't know.
Hey, Douglas.
Did you find your mom?
- Are you getting hungry?
- Yeah.
Would you like to eat pizza?
A hamburger?
My mom says fast
food isn't good for you.
Well, she's right, but the fast
food we serve here at the hospital...
is specially formulated to be nutritious.
So would you like some French fries?
Okay. Sit tight.
Hey, Frank.
- I'm working on it.
- Work harder. He's been here for hours.
If I find his mom, can I have the
tickets you pinched off that stiff?
- No.
- Anybody seen Dr. Kovac?
- What do you need?
- Mrs. Sites' pressure's down.
Frank, find Luka. What happened?
She got dizzy. Systolic's at
80. I opened up the saline.
How are you doing? - PE?
I don't know. Crank her oxygen up
to 15 liters and grab some dopamine...
off the crash cart. She's got
muffled heart sounds and JVD.
Malik. We need a pericardiocentesis
tray and a SonoSite.
- Okay.
- Pressure's down to 70.
- You think it's tamponade?
- Unless you got any better ideas.
What happened?
Hypotensive, signs
of pericardial effusion.
He thought she had a
clot from hyper-stimulation.
You can third-space
anywhere, even around the heart.
- There it is.
- Here you go, Abby.
- Okay, glove up. You can assist.
- Lidocaine's ready.
I think I found that kid's mom if she
doesn't have the same last name as him.
- I don't know. Maybe.
- Okay, hook up the alligator clip.
Belinda Mathison. Came last night
with a headache, it was a brain bleed.
- 45-degree angle.
- Last night?
- They put her in Neurosurg.
- Watch for injury current.
- That boy sat in Chairs all night.
- There it is.
Can you take him
upstairs to his mother?
That could be
difficult. She's dead.
What?
- Blood pressure's back up to 90.
- She stroked out a few hours ago.
- Second syringe.
- What should I do?
- Abby?
- Um... Well, just try to find his dad.
- Systolic's one-ten.
- And get him some French fries.
Okay. Good pickup.
- Did you reach the father?
- He said he lives in Los Angeles.
- He doesn't know the number.
- Wasn't in here?
- I couldn't find it.
- You call the school?
- No.
- I'm sure they have a number, Frank.
- I thought you used to be a cop.
- I was.
Well, act like a cop.
Track the guy down.
- Someone from Neurosurg talk to him?
- Not yet.
Which ER doc treated his mother?
Weaver. She has a half-shift
today. She's not in yet.
- Should I page someone from Neurosurg?
- They should tell him his mother died.
No, she didn't.
Douglas, I need to talk to you
about your mom's headache, okay?
Let's sit down.
All right.
It was pretty bad.
It was caused by a blood
vessel in her brain that ruptured.
It broke. And the
doctors tried really hard...
but they couldn't fix it.
Can she go home now?
No, Douglas. I'm
sorry. She died.
My mom has a
headache. She's not sick.
- I want to see her. Where is she?
- Douglas.
- Mom! Mom!
Mom! Mom, where are you?
- Douglas.
- Mom! Mom!
- Douglas, she's dead.
Stop saying that! Why
do you keep saying that?
- I want my mom. I just want my mom!
- I know you do.
Shh. Shh. Shh.
It's okay.
He finally went down?
- He's exhausted.
Poor kid.
I finally got ahold of his dad.
- He's in Australia on a business trip.
- Australia?
The soonest flight he can
get is a red-eye tomorrow night.
So Social Services have
to take him until then.
- Sorry. I'll call them.
- That's all right, I'll do it. Thanks.
- Can you grab me the minute he gets up?
- Sure.
Abby, do we do psychiatric
transfers to other hospitals?
- What?
- I have a patient in Curtain 3.
He was admitted with a tiny
scalp lac from a slip and fall.
He wants to be moved out of Curtain
3 and wants to call his caseworker...
- from some private hospital.
- Is he altered from the fall?
No, but he seems
pretty agitated.
Did you get a Psych consult?
- Not yet.
- Probably wouldn't hurt.
The paramedics brought
me to this hospital.
I didn't want to come here.
Can you just please call my caseworker
and move me to another room?
Please stop. That's
not necessary.
- You don't have to do that.
- It's just a precaution.
- What happened?
- I slipped, that's all.
- This your patient?
- Yeah.
I saw him in the hall. LOC after
he slipped. History of migraines.
- It's not his only history.
- Why the restraints?
I don't wanna cause trouble.
Please, call my caseworker.
We will. Dr. Lewis.
- Can you get me out of this room?
- Don't worry, we'll move you.
- What kind of caseworker?
- Psychiatric.
He's monitoring my
conditional release.
- He has the card.
- Release from where?
Dr. Lewis. Now.
Okay. Two of IV Ativan, five of
Compazine and a trauma panel.
Someone call my wife.
He's schizophrenic.
- He's been here before?
- He stabbed Carter...
- killed a med student two years ago.
- Him?
- Yeah.
- He stabbed Carter?
- Yes.
- What's he doing out?
I don't know. The police are coming.
We should transfer him before Carter sees.
- No, I need his CT.
- Let him get it at Mercy.
- He has a head injury.
- He stabbed two people in that room.
- Loss of consciousness...
- And killed one of them.
I won't move him and risk an intracranial
bleed. I don't care what he did.
Am I calling this
psychiatrist or not?
No. I'll call him.
We'll find out his
status, we'll get the CT.
Then we'll take it
from there. Okay?
Abby, the morgue called.
They're ready for you.
Move him to the suture
room. Don't let Dr. Carter see.
- I got it.
- And get his name off the board.
She looks like Snow White.
Mom.
Mom?
I drew you a picture.
You took him to the morgue?
- He didn't believe she died.
- Well, then you call Psych.
Advice you might have
given yourself 18 hours ago.
Hey, hey. She vagalled in Triage.
No one told me she had a kid with her.
- Well, she did.
- Did you call Social Services?
- Not yet.
- Why not? Abby, why not?
Because we're trying to
find another family member.
- Who's we?
- Uh-uh. Me.
It's not your job.
Don't want him in
another strange place.
Their holding facility is a lot more
comforting than the ER or the morgue.
They have the personnel and
resources to deal with it. Call them now.
"You're honest, forthright and a
judge... A good judge of character.
You often ramble incoherently when
agitated. Your dog doesn't like you."
- My dog died a year ago.
- It's a joke, Frank.
- This amuses you?
- Carter, what's your sign?
- Gemini, why?
- Horoscopes from the Internet.
"You're open to new ideas,
compassionate, a risk-taker."
True.
"You overstay your
welcome at parties...
- and you often smell like cheese."
- Don't you have some work to do?
- Abby, your turn.
- No, thanks.
- What's your sign?
- "Out of order."
Who moved Libertique
from the suture room?
The hand surgeon is stuck in surgery
for the next 40 minutes. We needed...
- a room for an extensor tendon repair.
- I'll do that.
No, no, no. The
surgical intern's got it.
Can you take a look at this
explosive watery diarrhea?
- You need to start an IV?
- Maybe. I don't know.
He's pretty miserable.
She.
- She.
- You okay?
Yeah.
Abby, the light source on the
fiber optic's down. Get me a spare?
- Okay. MAN: Can I
see a doctor this century?
- Hang on.
- I hang on any longer, I'll be dead.
If you're talking,
you're not dying.
He was not guilty
by reason of insanity.
- Shouldn't he be in a forensic hospital?
- He was. He was.
He was moved to a less restrictive
facility about 10 months ago.
And now he's on
conditional release.
- Bradying down to 60.
- Mg of atropine. I need that scope.
- I've got it.
- Pulse ox, 78.
I need a smaller tube.
Number seven. Suction.
- He's agitated.
- He's nervous.
He's been out of care for less
than a week, hits his head...
- and they bring him here of all places.
- He get out in two years?
Who are you?
I was there when he
attacked my friends.
I'm sorry. He was a law student. A
professor there got some colleagues...
to do some pro bono work. They
filed a writ of habeas corpus and won.
- That's unbelievable. HAZELTON:
But I can't say I disagree.
- Most schizophrenics are non-violent.
- Well, this one was, wasn't he?
When they are, they rarely are twice.
He's no danger to himself or others.
- Really?
- Not on his meds.
Safeguards are in place. He needs
to be supervised taking his medication.
- Did he get his head CT?
- They're almost ready for him.
Abby, can you check
this Foley? It's overflowing.
- Clamp it.
- I did. It's overflowing.
- Just get him out of here.
- I want those restraints removed.
- Uh, no.
- He is coherent and lucid.
- I worked with him for over a year.
- No.
- Abby.
- Susan, I swear to God...
- Abby, I got it.
- Keep somebody posted outside his door.
- But he needs reassurance and respect.
- Respect?
- Yes!
- I'm sorry. He needs our respect?
Abby, go.
Looks like over a
liter in the last hour.
BP's 110/70, and
her sats are up.
Good. You need to send
out a repeat potassium.
Right. Thanks.
He said something about the ICU.
Yeah. Maybe for a couple
of days, just for safety.
It's the fertility drugs,
isn't it, that's doing this?
The doctor has to
review your labs.
I could try to find
him now if you like.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
It must be the damn
hormones. I'm not usually a crier.
It's okay.
Sometimes being a
woman sucks, you know?
It has its moments.
You grow up praying you don't get
pregnant every time you have sex.
And then when you finally do
want to have a baby, you can't.
It's so unfair.
Have you been
trying for a long time?
I just keep thinking that maybe
I had my chance and I blew it.
- You don't know that.
- No. I've been pregnant.
A few years ago.
It was an accident.
I had just started a new
job and this new relationship.
It didn't seem
like the right time.
- It happens.
- I only waited until I was ready...
so that I could be the
best mother I could be.
I'm sure you're going to be.
Unless I waited too long.
- Weaver's looking for you.
- What?
She wants to know why you didn't
call Family Services on the boy.
I am. I will. Fine.
I'm gonna check in with my office, get
some release paperwork. I'll be back.
The on-call social
worker for the ER, please.
- Someone claim them?
- What?
- The tickets.
- Oh, no.
Lewis was asking. Give her one.
- Mwah! Thank you.
- No, just have him paged. Thanks.
When you have time, I need a thick
and thin smear and culture in Curtain 3.
- Yeah.
- Your diarrhea patient was heme negative.
Just PO challenged. I sent
him home with Imodium.
I have a 5-year-old with abdominal pain,
and I'm worried about intussusception.
- Is there any blood in the stool?
- No.
But he had a palpable mass.
- There he is.
- Hey, sweetheart.
- There's Daddy.
Hey. Hi.
- I'm okay. I'm okay.
- Carter.
Daddy slipped, and he fell.
And he hit his head, but I'm okay.
They put you in restraints.
It's just a precaution.
They're a little paranoid.
Oh, it's you.
I'm sorry.
- What happened? What's he doing here?
- He slipped outside his office building.
- His office building?
- He's on conditional release.
- You're out?
- I'm better.
I'm sorry.
That wasn't me who did
that to you, to your friend.
You know that, right?
You're a doctor. You
know it's a disease.
I'm being treated.
I'm okay now.
Great.
I'm glad you're okay.
I think I'm starting to get it. Although,
that little puck is hard to keep track of.
They should give it a color
so your eye can follow it.
- What, the puck?
- Yes.
I mean, like bright pink or red
or flashing lights or something.
Okay, a flashing, pink puck.
Well, why not?
- It will be a great game.
- It's hockey. Come on.
- I love hockey.
- You got the tickets?
- Hey. Hey, what's wrong?
- Uh, nothing.
- I hugged him.
- You what?
Oh, yeah. I'm the
Bruce Lee of love, girl.
Maybe I just need
some fresh air.
Hold... Wait a
minute. You're not out.
- Huh? Who are you hiding from?
- I'm not.
Wait a minute. Then what was that?
You don't want your friends to see us?
- They're not friends. They work for me.
- How do you think that makes me feel?
- I'm sorry.
- You came on to me. You are not out.
I am not out at work.
- Well, you need to be.
- Sandy...
I'm sorry. I don't
got time for this.
- Okay. DAD: I'll
come from the airport.
Okay.
Bye, Dad. He'll
be here tomorrow.
Great.
- Have you ever been to Los Angeles?
- Once. Disneyland.
Oh. I think
you'll like it there.
Because it's sunny. It's
not cold like it is here.
Excuse me?
- Can you give this to Dr. Carter?
- I think you better do that.
Oh, they're discharging
Paul. I have to drive him home.
They wouldn't have released
him if he weren't better.
He's taking his
meds. He's in therapy.
He has a disease, but it's being
treated. I mean, that's what you do here.
You treat disease so people
can try to move on with life.
Yeah.
He's my husband.
We're his family.
I can't give up on him.
Good luck.
Hey.
Um, Lewis discharged Sobriki, and
his wife asked me to give you this.
I guess you couldn't protect
me from her either, huh?
- Yeah. I'm sorry about that. I just...
- Don't worry about it. Forget it.
- Are you off already?
- Half-shift.
I'm off in a half-hour
if you want to go eat.
I should get home.
Or maybe just coffee and pie?
I had a pretty
crappy day myself.
Gam is out of the convalescent
hospital. I should go home...
- Are you gonna be okay?
- Yeah, I'm gonna be fine.
Thank you for asking.
Anytime.
- No!
- I have a nice place for you to stay...
- till he gets here.
- I wanna stay!
- But you can't.
- Abby!
- I want to stay here.
- I know.
But this is a hospital, and you have
to go someplace where you can sleep.
- No.
- And get something to eat, take a bath.
- I'll stay with you.
- Douglas, I don't...
- No!
- I don't stay here all the time, honey.
But you can come visit me
whenever you want, okay? I promise.
- No. Abby.
- I got you.
Come on. We'll get you some
ice cream when we get there.
- You'll be fine, Douglas.
- Wait! I'll stay with you!
Abby, please! Abby!
Abby, my cellulitis patient
is allergic to penicillin.
- No.
- Can you give IV erythromycin?
- Vancomycin?
No. I am not your
Attending. I'm not a Resident.
I'm a nurse. You want me to assess
a patient, you want me to push meds...
you want me to check vitals, explain
the situation to a family member, fine.
What I will not do is carry
you through med school.
You want to be a doctor,
start acting like one.
Rachel, can I talk to you?
- What are you doing?
- Just picking your stuff up.
- You're searching my room.
- It's a pigsty.
That doesn't give you the
right to go through my things.
You mean these things?
- I can't believe you did this.
- Are you smoking now?
I asked you a question. Rachel!
- Are these your cigarettes?
- I bought that a month ago on a dare.
- Dare?
- To see if I could pass for 18.
- And the condoms?
- I got them in health class.
- And you kept them?
- You'd rather I not have them?
- You need to stop lying.
- You don't believe me.
- You search my room and private things.
- I was looking for drugs.
You said you were picking
up. Who's lying now?
You're right. The truth is I
was searching your room.
I don't know if I can trust you.
Then fine. Believe whatever you
want. I'm smoking. I'm on drugs.
And I'm having sex. Lots of
sex with lots of guys because...
I'm the school slut. You happy?
This is John Carter. I have a
private-duty nurse for my grandmother...
who was supposed to start today.
She's not here.
Yeah.
I sent her home early.
- What?
- She was aggravating Millicent...
so I sent her home early.
She'll be back at 6 a.m.
It's a 24-hour service.
I'll get up if
there's a problem.
- What are you doing?
- Pardon?
I mean, you show up
unannounced, uninvited.
- Uninvited?
- Then you make health-care decisions?
Your grandma asked me to ask
her to leave. I was trying to be helpful.
Well, do me a favor. Don't try to be
helpful. It's not one of your strong suits.
Excuse me, John.
I've had enough abuse
from my mother-in-law today.
- I don't need any more from my son.
- I'm sorry?
I'm sorry, but I have
helped Gamma through this.
I have tended to her medical needs.
I've made her health-care arrangements.
So you need to consult with me
before you do anything like this.
- Fine. Call them back.
- Yeah. You bet I will.
But I'm not leaving this house.
I don't care if I'm uninvited. I won't
let your father break up this family.
- Family? What family would that be?
- Don't be sarcastic.
You checked out of
this family 20 years ago.
- Excuse me. I'm going to bed.
- No.
I won't let you put a revisionist spin
on this with you as the injured party. No.
- Step aside.
- No! I got stabbed!
I got stabbed in the back!
Where the hell were you?
You were the same place you've
been my entire life, someplace else.
- We came back.
- Three weeks later.
We were stuck in Tokyo.
You said you were fine.
I wasn't fine. I wasn't okay.
Are you gonna blame
me for taking drugs?
No. I am blaming you
for not being my mother!
Bobby died.
And I lost a mother.
May I go to bed now?
Yeah. Run away.
Oh, God.
- Thank you.
- Gotta call the super about that too.
It gets stuck in the cold.
And I'm guessing it's
gonna stay cold for a while.
Hopefully not this cold.
Good. I told Brian January
wasn't the best time to move.
But that's when the semester
starts. He's in law school.
Did you get locked out?
We had a fight. So
I went to the store.
Another half-hour
he'll be asleep.
You from Chicago?
- For a while now. Yeah.
- Originally?
Minnesota. You?
Idaho. The potato part, not
the white-supremacist part.
- You want a beer?
- No, thanks.
Come on.
Have a seat. You look
like you've had a long day.
Thank you.
Mm. You got a card.
Mm-hm.
It's nice to get one
personal piece of mail...
mixed in with all
the bills and junk.
Your birthday?
- Huh?
- Is it your birthday?
Yes.
- Today?
- Mm-hm.
8:03 p.m.
Well, congratulations. You've
made it. Happy birthday.
Thank you.