Gosh! I guess he got away.
Can Baby Shoes come out to play?
Come on! Hands on
your head. Climb out.
I can't climb out if my
hands are on my head.
Just keep them where I
can see them, man. Come on.
You high, popo? Yeah, man.
Catching morons makes me high.
Lift your shirt up by your
collar and turn around.
Would you look at that?
Dude's got a weapon.
All right. You have the
right to remain stupid.
Watch the gun.
Anything you say will be
completely incomprehensible.
Seriously, man! Careful!
Seriously, man? Seriously?
Does your mama know what you do?
Oh. It's sweet.
Your dad's proud.
You made the local
paper. For my article.
Give it a rest. You read
what he wrote in the margin?
"Our friend Lazarus sleeps
but I go that I may wake him up."
Yeah. He's not proud of
me, he's proud of Jesus.
Everything I do
right is God's work.
Everything I do wrong
is my own damn fault.
Cop with a sense of humor.
Differential diagnosis.
Guy's in the ER,
bleeding on everybody.
Drugs? He's a cop.
Good point. How about drugs?
Tox screen was clean. He
did, however, get hit by a bullet.
Just mentioning.
He was shot? No,
somebody threw it at him.
I'm thinking trauma. He got
bullet fragments lodged in his brain.
According to Baby Shoes the cop
was laughing before he got shot.
Baby Shoes? The
guy who shot him.
Reliable witness.
His name is Baby Shoes.
How bad can he be?
The fragments are in the wrong
part of the brain to cause euphoria,
so let's expand the search.
Factor in the cough
and the cloudy lungs.
Why are we ignoring
the elevated heart rate?
Because he's in shock.
What if the heart was
already fast before he got shot?
You mean after the foot race?
He's giddy. Indicates
a blockage of oxygen.
Carbon monoxide gas
would elevate the heart rate,
cause coughing and
impair neurological functions.
He got CO poisoning
outdoors? Yeah.
All 'cause those
bastards didn't ratify Kyoto.
Or he got CO poisoning
indoors and then moved outdoors
before he'd inhaled enough
to make him drop dead.
Test his arterial blood gas.
If his carboxyhemoglobin
levels are higher than 15%,
stick him in a
hyperbaric chamber.
You go check the
cop car for gas leaks.
If it was the cop car,
his partner would be sick.
Maybe she is, but just doesn't
have as good a sense of humor.
Also, check his personal
car, his work, home.
I'll check the precinct.
The blood test confirmed you have
low-level carbon monoxide poisoning.
We're putting you inside a
high-pressure chamber that...
You don't really care, do you?
Do you live near a gas supply?
Yeah, me. After,
like, a huge enchilada.
Anything toxic you
have at your home?
Any paint solvents,
anything unhygienic?
No. No, I keep a
pretty clean home.
If you start having trouble
breathing you can press this button
and the chamber will decompress.
Like this? Not now.
If you have trouble.
It's broken.
All right. Well, if you have
problems we'll push it for you.
Muscle contracture.
How bad does
it hurt? Not at all.
Looks wild, though, huh?
Your brain's not getting enough
oxygen. You're losing motor function.
We should start this right away.
Should I be scared?
No, you probably have a carbon
monoxide leak in your place.
We have a guy there
checking things out.
Sounds okay.
How about the gas
intake valve? Looks great.
It's down in the furnace room.
Your system's fine. If you
had a carbon monoxide leak,
half the force would be sick.
Then why are you here?
I was wondering if you
could do me a favor.
Yeah.
I've got a disability.
These are speeding
tickets. A lot of emergencies.
He's feeling better
now but you never know.
I'll see what we can do.
Where does your partner sit?
The place is a cesspool, but I
don't think I need to test for anything.
Nope. Waste of time.
You know about the marijuana?
I've heard rumors since junior high.
The cop's acting high
because he is high.
He's got...
Legionnaires' disease.
It's a good thing Joe got
shot or the whole precinct
would have gotten wiped
out. Anarchy on the streets.
It takes 48 hours to
test for Legionnaires'.
But only two seconds to
recognize that the symptoms fit
while staring at the rancid,
unchanged water of an AC unit.
Marijuana explains
the high carboxy,
the cloudy lungs
and the happiness.
Pot doesn't explain the fact that he's
gotten worse since he was admitted.
Why don't we agree to disagree?
Actually, why don't we agree
that you'll disagree with me
while treating him
for Legionnaires'?
It's not as pithy, but...
I feel a lot better.
The meds are working.
Heart rate is normal. COHb
levels are down. No fever.
Take some deep breaths.
You seem disappointed.
I'm glad you're feeling better.
- You got a problem with cops?
- Please don't talk.
In my experience people who
just don't like cops have a reason...
I need you not to talk.
No rales.
These clouded areas
of the upper lobes,
they're the infiltrates
we found yesterday.
They're not there anymore?
They're clearing up.
You had Legionnaires'.
Now you don't.
So, you didn't find
anything at my place?
Nothing medically relevant.
So there's nothing I
need to worry about then?
Not this time.
What are you doing?
I want to make sure
he sees what's involved.
What we found
was fairly advanced.
These cloudy
areas here and here,
these parts of your lungs
simply weren't functioning.
But they're okay now, right?
Everything's okay now.
I'm fine.
You're blind.
I bumped into something.
That doesn't mean I can't see.
I'm sure this is frightening,
but you only think...
What's Doctor Cameron wearing?
Dark blue pants,
white shirt, black shoes.
Almost, except for the
pants, shirt and shoes.
You're blind.
He really thinks he can see?
He can physically see. His
brain just can't process it.
No chance this is a
practical joke? No way.
Anton's blindness indicates
damage to both occipital lobes.
It must be from the trauma.
Bullet fragments just happened
to hit the same spot in both lobes?
A stroke could cause Anton's
blindness and euphoria.
Officer Krupke is
clotting in his brain.
Start heparin to thin the blood.
Find the clot and yank it out.
The clot would be at the top of
the bilateral vertebral arteries.
Great. Chase, stick
your fingers in there
and grope around
until you find it.
Oh, wait.
When you turn him
into a vegetable,
then there's going to
be frivolous lawsuits.
You know what would
be better? Contrast MRI.
Do we have one of those?
You can't do an MRI. If the
bullet fragments are magnetic,
they'll move and
rip his brain apart.
Well, let's flip a coin.
Heads MRI, tails he dies.
Police-issue Kevlar vests don't
have the ceramic plate insert
that would shatter a bullet.
They would just catch it.
So, the bullet
shattered on its own.
Meaning Baby Shoes was
using .38 caliber hollow points,
which unfortunately
are ferromagnetic.
It's just so cool
that you know that.
We could do an angio
to find the clotting.
Waste of time. The skull
creates too much artifact.
We'll never get a decent view.
It's the next best thing to
an MRI. And a waste of time.
An angio might show...
Oh, God, it's a coup!
Fine, go do your angio.
When you're done wasting your
time, meet me down in the morgue.
We're going to snake a
catheter into your femoral artery
and up into your brain
so we can check for clots.
Keep this on throughout
the procedure,
unless the pot's
already made you sterile.
I have a stressful
job. You got no idea.
I grew up with cops like you.
One part bully, nine parts hypocrite.
What is wrong with you?
Just having some fun.
The man is sick and scared.
The man's a crooked cop.
Maybe you should take
yourself off the case, Foreman.
You don't have to like
someone to be their doctor.
Hey, how you doing there, buddy?
Just sit still and we'll
have you back out there
scaring the crap out
of people in no time.
Happy?
What did the angio tell us?
What are you looking for?
I called my mom.
She didn't pick up.
What did the angio tell us?
That Foreman
should be off this case.
He's a neurologist.
Unless you think the patient's
optic nerve is in his spleen.
He doesn't like cops.
Foreman, policemen
are our friends.
If you and I ever get
separated shopping...
I was just busting
the guy's chops. See?
He was just busting
the guy's chops.
Foreman is essential
to solving this case.
Medically, what
did the angio tell us?
There appears to be some clotting,
possibly around the circle of Willis.
Based on the progression of
symptoms, the clot is growing.
We need to cut into...
Saying that there appears to be clotting
is like saying there's a traffic jam ahead.
Is it a ten-car pile-up, or just a
really slow bus in the center lane?
And if it is a bus, is it a
thrombotic bus or an embolic bus?
I think I pushed that
metaphor too far.
Angio can't tell us
that kind of information.
Oh, so you're saying it
was just a waste of time?
It gave us some information
without killing him.
You don't know that an MRI will kill
him. The bullets have a ferrous base.
Little tiny pieces trapped in his
head. They're not going anywhere.
Maybe it's worth attempting
surgery to remove the fragments.
Surgeons say inoperable and
the patient's on blood-thinners.
Other than that, perfect plan.
You got a better plan? Much.
The bullet's identical to the one
that Baby Shoes popped Joe with.
Let's see how magnetic it is.
Did anybody hear a...
I shot him. He's dead.
The bullet split into four
fragments. No exit wounds.
I only used a
half-load of gunpowder.
It won't be exactly precise comparing
the locations on an X-Ray to an MRI.
How unprofessional was Foreman?
Ask him yourself.
He's right here.
Worse than usual.
Better than you.
He berated Joe
for being a bad cop.
Berated or humiliated?
I'm not sure. I didn't have
my thesaurus with me.
One implies that he
took pleasure in it.
I want to know if it was repressed
black anger or just giddiness.
You think I'm sick?
I think that an appropriate response
to watching your boss shoot a corpse
is not to grin foolishly.
The fact that I've grown bored
by your insanity is proof of nothing.
Doctor Foreman, Doctor
Chase requests your assistance.
I can't even imagine
the backwards logic
you used to rationalize
shooting a corpse.
Well, if I'd shot a live person,
there's a lot more paperwork.
Then it won't be a problem for you
to stand beside the casket at the wake
and explain why a cancer patient
has a bullet hole in his head?
The man donated
his body to science.
Yes, it's a tragedy.
If I hadn't shot him,
his body could have spent the next
year letting first-year med students
use the carpool lane.
He's set. Do not
turn that on, House.
You're mad because I
put a bullet in his head.
At worst, all I'm doing
now is taking it out.
My bad.
They have to shut
down the magnet to fix it.
MRI is going to be out of
commission for at least two weeks.
Oh, it doesn't matter. We
obviously can't use it on this patient.
No, but there are other doctors
in this hospital and other patients.
That helps explains how they
can afford all the fancy equipment.
I'm sure not pulling my weight.
Is doing nothing an option?
I'm just saying, maybe the
clot will break up on its own.
The giddiness seems to have
gone away. The blindness hasn't.
Echo his heart.
Looking for what?
The problem is
obviously neurological.
The clots are in his brain. The
source of the clots may not be.
Do a complete transthoracic
echocardiogram.
Maybe we get lucky. Maybe the
clots are coming from his heart.
Heart's clean. Where
else could we look?
We could ultrasound
his legs, look for a DVT.
I need you to move over.
Joe, are you okay?
Tachycardia. Heart
rate 150 and rising.
Saline wide open.
He's bleeding out.
House wanted to thin his
blood. He sure did a good job.
BP's crashing. He's
going into shock.
Intracranial bleeding. We
need to relieve the pressure.
We need a surgical team.
Foreman, get out!
Boy, is he screwed.
We clot his blood, he
dies. We thin it, he dies.
Am I the only one
who finds this funny?
Oh, man!
I'm not sick!
Did you hear the one about
the guy who bled into his brain
and had to have a hole drilled in
his skull to relieve the pressure?
Hilarious.
Someone laughs, they're
dying? That's absurd.
But not funny.
If I'm not sick, all you're doing
is locking me up with the source.
I'll get sick, prove you right.
If you're not sick, it's not contagious
and you've got nothing to worry about.
If you are sick, the two of you are
staying in here until we find out why.
So you might want to
make friends with the pig.
The good news is I
can finally get my MRI.
No, you can't! You
blew up the machine!
Not the portable one, chuckles.
Chase and Cameron are bringing it
to scan your non-bullet-riddled head.
Where are you going?
To the office. Got work to do.
Eat your meals, take your
temperature every half-hour
and any meds I
command you to take.
So I'm just a regular
patient now? No.
You get your own thermometer.
Check your blood.
Anyone with an elevated sed rate
gets to be Foreman's new roomie.
He should be a part
of this. He's a patient.
He's not irrational.
He's not objective.
He's got the most motivation
to get this diagnosed.
Right. You're not even friends
with him. Why would you care?
There is an area of increased T2
attenuation in the cingulate cortex.
Kind of mushy. Cingulate
cortex controls emotions.
This mushy spot
explains the euphoria.
The question is what's
causing the mush?
A question you might
want to ask a neurologist.
Foreman is a selfish
jerk, but he's a neurologist
and he's the only one
who's been in that apartment.
This is why he
shouldn't be here.
You wouldn't call him
a jerk if he was here.
If you think he screwed up at that
apartment you'd keep it to yourself.
No! I... Well, we'll never know.
As long as he's not here,
he's just like any other patient,
which means we can
dump on him all we want.
What's eating the
selfish jerk's brain?
West Nile or Eastern
equine encephalitis would...
Test Foreman's blood.
Given that he's the
only one who got it,
person-to-person transmission is
less likely than some sort of deadly toxin
that Foreman picked
up in the guy's home.
Who wants to go next?
You're ready to sacrifice yourself for a
guy who doesn't consider you a friend?
He's just the patient,
right? It's the job.
Hey.
You don't have to go anywhere.
Joe's apartment is right
downstairs in the lab.
Foreman brought back
samples of everything.
What was that, "Who wants
to go next"? Some kind of test?
Don't worry. You
made the right call.
Foreman stumbled into
whatever it is without knowing.
And he's way
smarter than you are.
Damn, Chase!
You suck at this.
Sorry, it's this damned suit.
I can do it myself.
And I'll throw that out.
What'd the MRI show?
I can't be a part
of the differential
and I can't even know
what the differential is?
You'd have told any other
patient what you found out.
MRI showed a lesion
on your cingulate cortex.
What's the thinking?
Toxins are in the lead,
viral's a distant second.
Do you think the lesion
could be an abscess?
It's just a small, soft area.
More mush than anything.
Was there inflammation in
the lining of the ventricles?
There was an increased
signal there, yeah.
What are you thinking?
Staph infection.
Toxins lead to neurodegeneration
which causes the lesion.
Not without a fever.
The cop had a fever.
Mine could be coming. I could
have got it directly from him
or a dirty dishtowel
at his place.
Give us Ommaya reservoirs.
Deliver linezolid directly into
our brains, and we're cured.
Samples tested negative
for toluene, arsenic and lead.
What about the blood?
Negative for West Nile
and Eastern equine.
We have to go back to Joe's
apartment, get more samples...
No one goes back to that place
until we know what we're looking for.
Get some of that cop tape, stick
it over the doors and the windows.
I'll take all the HAZMAT precautions.
The chance of infection is next to nothing.
Yeah, I was never
that great at math,
but next to nothing is
higher than nothing, right?
It's not your fault he got sick.
But it would be
his fault if we did.
We should get a sample
directly from Joe's brain.
We can't do a biopsy.
There's too much edema from the
bleeding because you gave him heparin.
I don't think this is the
time to be pointing fingers.
I didn't give Foreman any.
You want to give
Foreman a brain biopsy?
Come on. Really, who doesn't?
This could be a simple staph
infection causing neurodegeneration.
Without a fever? Not a chance.
Joe had a fever. He
also had Legionella.
The mush might be forming an
abscess, and since there was inflammation
of the lining of the
ventricles, it makes sense.
The staph releases toxins,
causes neurodegeneration,
causes the lesions.
This is a waste of time.
We should put an Ommaya
reservoir in Foreman's brain
and start administering
antibiotics...
If I'm going to be arguing with
Foreman, I may as well do it directly.
Kernig's sign, negative.
Brudzinski's sign,
single positive.
Patient Joe Luria, distal and
proximal arm contractures.
Duration four seconds.
Staph infection most
commonly presents on the skin.
Most commonly?
You want to treat me
like any other patient, do it.
But the House I know never
uses phrases like "most commonly."
You're not laughing anymore. No.
You think that's a good thing?
Sort of doubt it.
Staph would be in your heart,
lungs, spleen, liver or kidneys
before it gets to your brain.
Your organs are
clear. It's not staph.
The infection could be
limited to a brain abscess.
Which I would have
seen in your MRI.
Sign this so I can take
out a piece of your brain.
Let me see the MRI.
There was no abscess on
the image. Let me see it, then.
I liked you better
when you were jolly.
MRI was taken over an hour ago.
That soft spot could
now be an abscess.
If it was staph you'd have
a fever, which you don't.
101.6.
What idiot gave you that?
Put the Ommaya reservoir in
my skull and treat me for the staph.
Triangle.
This one?
Circle.
Next.
Foreman, why aren't you
answering? Is there a problem?
Square.
Tell me your date of birth.
Is that House? Yeah.
Next? Square again.
Why is he here? Because my
neurologist is having surgery.
I thought I was
just another patient.
You didn't believe
that crap, did you?
Date of birth.
The Ommaya reservoir is
inserted in the parietal lobe.
My spatial recognition is
the issue, not my memory.
Oops. Did you say Ommaya?
I could have sworn
you said biopsy.
Hey, I'm just messing
with your head.
Mother's maiden name, please.
Get out of my
temporal lobe, House.
Hello?
Are you awake?
They told me somebody
was sick like me.
I'm up.
Your voice...
Aren't you my doctor?
Not anymore.
You're the guy who
doesn't like cops?
Yeah.
Can you see?
You can't? Not a thing.
You've been blind a while.
The fact that you're aware of it
now could be a sign of improvement.
It hurts so much, doesn't it?
I'm okay.
It's going to hurt.
The morphine barely
takes the edge off.
I'm going to die, aren't I?
You die, I die. It's
not going to happen.
Why not?
Are you just too
stubborn to die?
They took a piece of my brain.
Whatever is wrong
with us, they'll find.
Do you believe in prayer?
Not really.
Neither do I.
My dad always prays.
So does mine.
Do you want to try it?
Try praying?
Okay.
How is he? Still dying.
Well, you've almost mastered
another skill, though. That's good.
We have Foreman's
biopsy results.
Non-specific signs
of inflammation.
That's it?
I've also swabbed for staph.
Negative. He's not even a carrier.
Well, at least Foreman
was wrong, too.
Yeah, there's that.
Can I go to Joe's
apartment now? No.
Go back to the lab and start retesting
all the samples that Foreman collected.
For what? Everything.
Bacteria, toxins, fungus,
anything that likes to feast on brain.
That's thousands
of... Better hurry.
Cameron, suit up. You're
going to monitor Foreman.
He's on to hand contractures.
He'll be at Anton's blindness soon.
Run hourly checks, because
when he does go blind
he won't be able to tell us.
We'll use the data to construct a timeline
so we can see how far behind Joe he is.
Why are you still here?
You're being cautious.
You're being common.
When you don't give a crap...
How many of your guys have
caught cancer from their patients?
Let me know when that happens,
then we can have this conversation.
It's just another case, huh?
I'll bet you can even have unprotected
sex with your cancer patients
without catching a damn thing.
Boy, I wish I had your job.
Biopsy showed nothing.
How can it be nothing? You
cut out a piece of my brain.
It's nothing personal, we
just didn't find anything.
Can you up his
morphine for God's sake?
He's already maxed out.
20 milligrams per hour.
What about toxins?
Everything was negative.
There was a cupboard above
the stove. Did you see it?
I didn't check all the food,
but could be listeriosis.
I didn't go back. Follow right.
Who did?
House said we shouldn't
go. Too dangerous.
The answer's got to be in that
apartment. Not going is too dangerous.
I'm sorry. You're thankful.
If House would've pointed
at you instead of me,
you'd be the one in here.
Look straight forward. Tell
me when you can see the light.
It's your job to go back! You're a
doctor! You go where the disease is!
Say when you can see the light.
I'm dying and you're sitting
here measuring how fast I go?
Tell me when you can see
the light. My vision is fine!
Your left-side periphery is
reduced. It's fine! I'll prove it!
Son of a bitch!
Now we're both exposed.
You got two choices.
You can go tell House what just happened
and get your own cot brought in here,
or you can go back
to that apartment.
You save me, the
cop and yourself.
It's not SSPE.
I checked your past
vaccinations against Joe's.
No batch matches.
Did the blood show
antibodies for Coxsackievirus?
Guys, can you
please shut him up?
He's over his limit on morphine.
Where's Cameron?
She said she had some stuff
to do. Said she'll be back soon.
What are you doing?
Foreman!
Imagine being constantly reminded
of the pain you're about to be in.
I can't take it!
Just stop it! Stop
it, stop it, stop it!
Mainlining morphine into his
carotid could stop his heart!
So could pain-induced
stress cardiomyopathy.
Either the morphine
kills him or the pain does.
You're condoning this?
I'm certainly not going
in there to stop him.
I'm going to make
you feel better.
Joe has a new symptom.
Hyperalgesia.
The infection's spreading
into the pain center of the brain.
Please stop! Please stop!
His brain is telling him that
his whole body is in pain.
Because of the location,
painkillers do nothing.
Suit up.
Put the guy in a coma
before the pain kills him.
What if he used cedar
wood to hide the pot smell?
Aureobasidium fungus
could grow there.
Did you find any cedar wood
anywhere? No, but maybe...
Maybe what?
Maybe somebody could
go back, take a second look?
And why aren't you pissed off
that Cameron's playing hooky
while your life
hangs in the balance?
Why doesn't anyone
listen to me anymore?
I decided you were wrong.
God, you are weak.
Guy steals your article,
tells you you're not his friend,
and you still want to
risk your life for him.
Foreman broke my skin
with a tainted needle.
Wow! Yeah.
God, you're weak.
The guy tried to kill you.
First thing on my list of things to do
would be to stab him back, shoot him.
I've got a gun in my desk.
The last thing on my list would
be to lie to my boss about it,
and then give the bastard
everything he wanted.
I'm not here for Foreman.
I'm here to save myself.
Even with a needle stick, your
chances of infection are pretty slim.
That's why you're
wearing a suit.
You wanted to be here.
He just gave you the excuse.
What does that guy have
to do to make you hate him?
Give me the bag.
Mildewed dishtowel.
To re-test for staph.
What is that? Mouse droppings?
Hamster droppings. Could carry Toxocara.
It'd explain the blindness.
Now that I recognize
as oven crud.
Could be meat with Trichinella.
It would explain the high fever.
What's with the rye bread?
Mold could be responsible
for ergot poisoning,
which could explain
the contractures.
There are three loaves. So?
You're going back in there.
A guy who lives on take-out pizza
does not buy three loaves of rye.
That's looking too
far into the future.
Unless he cares about
something a lot more than his diet.
Are you on the roof
yet? Yeah, I'm here.
I don't see any birds.
Whistle or something.
Do that "come hither" thing.
They came that fast because
it's their behavior pattern.
Joe's been feeding them.
Now look down. Do you
see a river of pigeon turd?
No. There's barely any.
It's not weird, it's cheap.
Joe's a guy who
looks for the easy way.
Probably been stealing
cable from his neighbors.
Why not steal fertilizer
from rats with wings?
You see a shovel or a dust pan?
I found a scraper.
It looks used.
Sitting on a bucket.
A bucketful of pigeon crap,
the perfect home for
Cryptococcus neoformans.
Yup.
Fungus enters the brain
through the sphenoidal sinus,
where it dances
its triple threat
of happiness, blindness
and intractable pain.
Let's hope this experience
teaches our cop a lesson.
Don't cut corners when
you're growing your pot.
See you back home.
I was there.
I should have found it.
Yeah, you could have
saved us a lot of time.
Get me a flush of
ampho B and flucytosine.
I'll start us both.
I was waiting for lab confirmation.
I haven't heard from House yet.
Look at his EEG.
Theta band's been increasing
steadily since we put him under.
The guy's unconscious
but still in pain.
Theta bands could indicate at
least half a dozen different things.
One of which is pain.
The fact that he's no longer
screaming makes us feel better,
not necessarily him.
Chase?
How's Cameron?
She's not giddy.
Fever's down. White
count's improving.
Has she said anything to you?
You mean, like, "I completely
understand why Foreman did what he did
"and I hold no grudge?"
What I did, did save my life.
Get in here and
help! Forget the suit!
He's tachycardic. Wide
complex. Looks like V-tach.
It's not Cryptococcus! What?
House was wrong. The
samples were negative.
So what is it? We don't know.
Give him the amio.
Do we have any more
leads? That was our lead.
Foreman!
So this treatment
isn't doing anything.
Foreman, he's in V-fib!
No good. Hit him again.
Come on, man. Come on, Joe.
Hit him again!
Give him an amp of epi.
Nothing.
He has multiple system failure.
Foreman!
Foreman.
Time of death?
No!
Time of death,
12:26 p.m.