Previously on The Resident...
I saw you pocket the pills.
We're not having an
issue with that again.
Your twins are in grave danger.
Just do whatever you have to do.
Please save my babies.
Smaller one's heart
rate is climbing to 103.
I want to see you tonight.
And if this idiot
becomes our new governor,
we'll have less than we ever had.
- He's polling ahead.
- Yeah, I wish
I was there to help. - No.
You're exactly
where you need to be.
I have some good
news. They're trying me
on a new anti-CD20 antibody,
and I'm tolerating
it really well.
State
Assemblywoman Camille Rogers
is in a much tougher
fight than many expected.
Opponent Mark Betz,
the billionaire real estate
and finance entrepreneur,
- is a first-time candidate for public office.
- Hey. I got your email.
I'll have those OR numbers
to you by end of day.
Thanks. I'm trying to
prepare for the worst,
in case Betz becomes governor.
- How's it looking?
- It's too close for my liking.
How is that possible?
Betz hasn't even
held public office.
But he has millions
to spend on attack ads.
So now half the state's gonna
reject an experienced woman
who wants to give them
health care and education.
Yeah, apparently, that
just doesn't resonate
like "billionaire who wants
to slash social services."
Who would actually cut
funding to public hospitals?
Well, let's hope we
don't have to find out.
Is everything okay otherwise?
How's Randolph's
treatment going at the clinic?
He's responding well.
His-his team are...
uh, encouraged.
I'm working on it.
I worry about you when
I get emails at 3:00 a. m.
Oh, it's just this election.
It's got me tied up in knots.
All we can do is vote and
hope for the best, right?
Can't worry about
things we can't control.
Those are the things
that worry me the most.
Georgia's new voting laws
have taken effect,
leading to massive
delays throughout the state.
I can be on time or I can
do my civic duty this morning,
not both.
Democracy needs you.
We can cover.
It's slow here anyway.
Now, you know
you shouldn't have
said that out loud, right?
Relax.
What?
Unbelievable.
Are you deaf?
Quit checking your Bit coin
and move the hell up.
- Are you kidding me?!
- A line
is a social contract
between citizens!
We're all interdependent!
Do you know what that means?!
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
We're all tired of waiting, but
you gotta dial it down, brother.
I'm not your brother. Go
back to where you came from.
Chill.
Did you hear that?
Came from Atlanta, gringo.
Where are you from?
Assault! You all saw that!
This man assaulted me!
- Hey, you need to back off!
- Police! This man's assaulting me!
I'm at St. Anthony of the
Cross Community Center.
There are multiple injuries, a
cardiac arrest, a blunt trauma.
We're gonna need
some medics here now!
♪ ♪
Hey. Any exit polls yet?
Not yet. But they're thinking
it won't be decided tonight.
Well, if you need a distraction,
I could use your
help with a consult.
I can clear
something. What's up?
Well, I just got off the phone
with one of my trial patients,
and he's having
severe back pain.
He tends to be a minimizer,
so I know he's really suffering.
Which trial is this?
Multiple sclerosis.
He's been doing pretty
well with the treatment,
but the pain is bad enough
that he hasn't been able to walk.
So maybe an MS flare.
But if he's not mobile...
Then he can't be a part
of the trial any longer.
Exactly. So I'm hoping
that we can help reverse it.
Happy to take a look.
How's the trial going otherwise?
We're getting good results
with one of the treatments.
Well-tolerated,
limited side effects.
How does it compare to
the new anti-CD20 meds?
Randolph's been
responding well to those.
Oh, that's good news. We
haven't been able to compare it
with any other treatments yet.
We need to expand the study.
- Which means more funding.
- Yes.
Another reason we're hoping
this election goes our way.
I don't see your little sticker.
Oh, I'm gonna hit
the polls at lunch.
Yeah, make sure you do.
All right. And we also got
your lavender essential oils
and palo santo,
which, if you ask me,
looks like an overpriced
bundle of sticks.
Oh. Padma, I'm so sorry...
They only had
regular cheese puffs.
Oh.
That's okay.
Look at you.
Thought I could not get my
hands on some spicy cheesies?
It's about the only thing
on the list I do understand.
Thank you. You have no
idea what this means to me.
- I think I do have an idea.
- You know,
I tried this online recipe
for keto cheesies once.
Never again.
I'm gonna pretend
I didn't hear that.
Uh, I got to go review some
pre-op echocardiograms.
But, wait, I want to show
you this amazing documentary.
Ah, the Himalayas
are gonna have to wait.
I'm done with the Himalayas.
It's ocean docs now.
- Ocean docs?
- See, the thing about octopuses...
Not "octopi," okay, only
pretentious people say that...
Is that they're supposedly so
intelligent and compassionate
that scientists think they're
a life form from outer space.
- "Scientists", huh?
- Mm-hmm, you have to see this one scene.
Uh, look, I really got
to check it out later.
I got to go. See you soon.
Okay, wait, I'll send it to you.
Morning, everyone.
- Doctor Hawkins.
- Doctor Sullivan.
Aw, they still call each
other "doctor" at work.
Very professional. We all
know you're dating, Doctors.
Can't stay out of my ER, huh?
You know how much I
love being surrounded
by undifferentiated illness.
Plus you keep slipping
out before I'm up.
- Mm, a girl's got to vote.
- Uh-huh.
Well, Gigi would love to share
some Nutty Wheats with you
whenever you're ready
to make the big leap.
I was actually thinking
I'd introduce you both
to Crispy Chuck tonight.
- Your ex-boyfriend from high school?
- Mm, good one.
No, it's Crispy
Chuck's Chicken Truck.
It's the best fried
chicken ever.
You have to be on a
secret list to know about it.
Letting me in on
your chicken truck.
Wow, well, this is, this is big.
I'm glad you appreciate
the significance.
Sorry to interrupt this summit.
Hundley called the triage line.
- Multiple trauma victims incoming.
- From where?
There was an all-out
brawl at a polling station.
Democracy in action.
Let's put out a
page for back-up.
I think I can beg off
rounds, help out for a bit.
Knowing you,
you're gonna need it.
Just try and keep up, all right?
40s-ish female, head injury.
- Possible concussion.
- Let's get her to Trauma 11.
I'll get started on
her assessment.
What was she struck with?
One of those folding
chair-cane things.
- Don't ask.
- All right, let's get heat stroke to Bay Four.
Asthma attack to Bay One,
wrist injury to Bay
Seven. Hawkins?
I'm reassigning
you to this periorbital
hematoma, Trauma Ten.
I'm on it. Jessica, can
you take that for me?
- Cardiac arrest?
- We got a pulse back,
- but he keeps going in and out.
- That one's for me.
Thank you. Trauma Nine.
Love the smell of
napalm in the morning.
- What's his injury?
- I'm fine. I don't need any of this.
- He got tackled, might have broken ribs.
- Hundley and I can take him.
You're gonna have to
find a place in the hallway
'cause we're
running out of space.
- Yeah.
- Didn't I tell you never
to say the S-L-O-W
word out loud?
That's a made-up superstition.
From a man who won't
let a sneeze go unblessed.
Because that would be wrong.
Any signs of concussion?
Okay, ondansetron,
fluids and a stat
CT for possible skull fracture.
And a fresh gown for you.
Thank you.
How's the eye?
Orbital fracture,
possible entrapment.
Might be looking at
neurosurg and ophtho.
And we have a possible
skull fracture in Trauma 11.
- Yep.
- So let's get Dr. Sutton in here.
Hawkins, can you tag
team this guy with me?
- Sure.
- He got tackled.
Has acute abdominal pain.
Doesn't want imaging.
Just wants to get out
of here. Says it's his IBS.
- And he got it from the tackle?
- Yeah, I didn't push it.
Mr. Mendez, this is Dr. Hawkins.
How's it going?
- Heard you took a bit of a tumble.
- But his lungs are clear.
- Little angry dude lost it, I'm fine.
- Okay.
Let's take a look at these ribs.
Does that hurt?
Told him I got
IBS. I always hurt.
Well, I'm with Dr. Feldman,
we need to take some pictures,
- make sure nothing's broken.
- Look, I got to get to work.
The sooner we find
out what you need,
the sooner you'll
be on your way.
And we can give you some
medication for the pain.
Fine.
- Page me if his symptoms worsen.
- Thank you.
- Betz is pulling ahead...
- I got the prior authorization
filled out for Mr. S's
anticoagulation,
so hopefully this time
he doesn't forget to take it.
Most new interns hate paperwork.
And you seem like
you actually like it.
I mean, I won't lie, my
family's on me constantly, like,
"When are you going to
start saving lives, Maya?
"This is why we sent you
"to med school." Of
course, I don't mention
I'm the one paying the loans.
Oh, immigrant parents. Am I right?
Oh.
ER just paged out a
major code disaster.
That means multiple injuries.
You want to see some action?
- Bring it.
- Maybe now you'll have something to tell your parents.
¡Sí, mamá, much a sangre hoy!
Hey. Thanks for coming.
Of course. Possible
skull fracture?
Trauma 11, and an
orbital fracture in Ten.
I'd start with the orbital.
Skull can wait, GCS is 15.
- Busy day.
- Yeah.
Hey. I got your page.
This is my intern, Maya
Nuñez. What can we do to help?
I've got a sprained
wrist in Bay Seven.
- That's it?
- Sorry?
Guess we did miss all the fun.
- Don't speak too soon.
- Get off me!
I just need to make
sure nothing's broken.
- Keep your hands off of me!
- Hey.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- She's trying to take my eye out!
It's okay, Stewart. No
one's trying to hurt you.
- I want to make sure you leave here with functional vision.
- Stop! Stop!
Help! Stop!
Help! Let me go!
- Let's get some restraints.
- Call 911!
Get this lunatic out of here!
- Hang on.
- Ow! Stop!
He's a vet. I might have an idea
of what's going on here.
Thanks.
Good news. CT scan shows
your orbital bones
won't need surgery.
- Great.
- Noticed your ink.
I was Navy, too.
Corpsman in the Marines.
15th Expeditionary,
3rd battalion.
Oorah.
How long you been out?
12 years.
It's pretty tough
in the Navy, man.
I was a sonar tech at Bangor.
Never deployed.
So...
what is going on, Stewart?
You seem pretty on edge.
I don't know.
Sometimes I just lose it.
I guess I'm getting old
and cranky like my dad.
Well, I'd like to do some blood
work, check out at a few things.
Can I call someone
to come pick you up?
I'm staying with my sister.
She's not gonna be
happy to hear from you.
You let me worry about that.
Be right back.
Yeah?
Ben, Jasper.
- This is Dr. Voss.
- Hi.
And she is one of our
orthopedic specialists.
- Pleasure to meet you, Ben, Jasper.
- Nice to meet you.
And I'm hoping that
she can help us figure out
what's, uh, going
on with your back.
So, Ben, how would you
compare your symptoms
to your previous MS flare-ups?
Oh, uh, this is
nothing like my MS.
It came out of nowhere,
one morning, boom!
Um, fire shooting down my legs.
Yeah, he couldn't get out
of bed. Excruciating pain.
And before this Ben was
showing some real promise
in the clinical trial.
Yeah, well, my triathlon
days are behind me,
but, yeah, I was
definitely getting stronger.
Of course we want to
keep you on that track.
Any incidents you can recall
that may have caused an injury?
I haven't done anything crazy.
He did help me clean
out the CD closet.
Yeah, well, who keeps CDs?
Not me anymore.
Well, I'd like to
get some imaging.
And I'm going to consult
with our neurosurgeon,
Dr. Sutton.
So there's a chance,
if this isn't my MS,
I can get back in the trial?
I see no reason to give up hope.
- Yeah, we got to keep our star athlete, right?
- Yeah.
Hey, I was just coming by to see
if you still need an
extra set of hands.
Uh, we just got a moment
to breathe, but thanks.
- I think we have it handled.
- What the heck happened?
People attacking each
other at a polling place?
Mostly one crazy guy.
Are you sure you weren't there?
- The bump on your forehead.
- Oh!
Yeah, I hit it on a cabinet.
Doing too many things at once.
Mr. Incredible in the OR,
Mr. Magoo in the kitchen.
Everything's fine, Kincaid.
I didn't say anything.
I know the look.
You're sweet to worry, but...
Look, Seattle was a
long time ago. I'm good.
Promise.
Okay.
Ah.
And if you're good...
Hey, just checking to see
if those head trauma
pictures came in.
Yes, they did. No fracture.
- Just a concussion.
- That was lucky.
Oh, I've been
meaning to ask you,
how's Gigi doing?
No nightmares the past week.
I'm hoping we're
out of the woods.
- Thanks for asking.
- Must be so hard
dealing with all the
parenting stuff alone.
Believe me, all I
keep thinking about
is how great Nic would
have been at dealing with this.
Well, you're doing
an amazing job.
Thank you.
Gigi misses you.
We should all do something
together again soon.
That's okay.
I'm sure your weekends are full.
- Where's my cardiac patient?
- Left AMA.
Said he had to get
back to the polls.
Wow, that's a
dedicated voter for you.
Here. Brought you a fresh one.
- Mmm.
- Oh, no, we're good over here, thank you.
Well, you're not the
one who had to tackle
that Proud Boy in there.
My hero.
He's not still here, is he?
- I'm just running a few tests.
- Right, because "jerky dude"
is so hard to understand?
I should get back.
Hey, you know, if you
need to chill him out,
I got some nature
docs from Padma.
- Thought it was mountain climbing.
- That was last week.
But seriously, though, there's
a cool one where this octopus
thanks a guy after he
saves him from a sandbar.
Excuse me,
I'm here for my
brother, Stewart Mayer?
Yeah, Emma, hi. I'm Dr. Hawkins.
I left you a voice mail.
Do you have a minute?
- Yeah.
- Great.
A scalpel?
Should he
be coming home with me?
So this is, this is new,
this level of volatility?
Yeah, he's been on edge
ever since his wife left and...
lately it's gotten pretty bad.
But before that, he
was just an annoying
- tech bro mansplainer.
- Is he on any medication?
Some over-the-counter
stuff when he had the flu?
All right, I'm waiting
on a few test results.
- You mind hanging out for a bit?
- Yeah, can I see him, actually?
Yeah, sure.
Anybody see this patient leave?
Wait here, I'll
go check outside.
Stewart?
Stewart...
I've been looking for you.
Your sister's here. Why don't
we go inside and talk to her?
Trying to quit, huh?
Yeah, obviously not going well.
Tried everything...
Hypnosis, pills.
Nothing works.
Taking medication
to help you quit?
Yeah, why?
Ben is 52.
Former competitive athlete.
Diagnosed with MS six years ago.
Well, I can see
why he's in pain.
He has a fracture at T11.
Doesn't remember
any impact or trauma.
With advanced MS and
this degree of osteoporosis,
this could have
happened just moving
from his bed to the wheelchair.
He's responding really
well to Devon's clinical trial
and is hoping to continue,
so how do we help him?
Well, given his comorbidities,
my suggestion would be
non-surgical management.
Brace, pain control
and physical therapy.
Which means he
doesn't walk again.
There's no guarantee surgery
would restore his mobility, Kit.
I mean, there's a serious
chance he could end up with less.
And a smaller chance
he doesn't survive at all.
Risks we take with
every procedure.
Ben is an athlete.
He'll be highly motivated
in his post-operative
physical therapy...
Respectfully, Ben's motivation
won't matter if the procedure
ends up paralyzing him,
or he ends up hopped up
on pain medication
for the rest of his life.
That's a real possibility.
If there's hope for Ben
with this procedure,
don't we owe it to him
to give him that chance?
Let's present him
with the options
and let him make the decision.
I appreciate your caution.
I will talk him
through the risks.
Hey, Kit...
Mm?
I don't know what you and Bell
are going through, obviously,
but I do know that
chronic disease
is tough on caregivers, too.
If there's any
support you need, I...
Thank you, Billie.
You're very kind.
But this is about Ben.
I'm fine.
Your brother was
prescribed medication
to help him quit
smoking... Varenicline.
One of the side effects?
Aggression and mood swings.
So anti-smoking medication
is what was making
him act like a lunatic?
I
Wouldn't say "lunatic..."
Uh, I would.
It's rare, but it is
in the warnings.
I gave him some
nicotine patches.
Things should go a lot smoother
once he's off the varenicline.
I'm definitely getting off it.
Yeah. Maybe
stay off Twitter, too.
That can also cause
aggression and mood swings.
Thank you very
much, Dr. Hawkins.
You guys take
care of yourselves.
Officer Carter, APD.
I need to speak with the
gentleman in this video.
Is he being charged?
Excuse me, Officer.
I was a witness in that incident
and the person who started it
is over there trying to leave.
- That's right!
- Look, I don't care.
I just need someone
to make a statement.
I... I will...
He's in respiratory distress!
I want to...
I want to press charges.
You're not pressing anything.
His lung is collapsing.
All right. Give me
a scalpel, a chest
tube and suture.
Fractured rib here
punctured Enrique's lung.
Must have happened when
he got agitated with the cop.
Well, the chest
tube is on water seal
and the lung is re-expanding,
so he should be good
to check out of here tomorrow.
Oh, geez.
- What?
- Padma.
I have entertained her
nature docs, I have
indulged in her aromatherapy,
and now she's on to astrology.
Hey. Look at this.
Hmm.
Looks like some kind of
mass in his ascending colon,
causing partial
bowel obstruction.
When I was doing the
abdominal exam, he said
- he had IBS.
- Well, that's the catch-all phrase
for unknown GI distress.
Let's get him into surgery.
He needs to remove that blockage
before the bowel
loses blood flow.
Let's scan the rest
of his abdomen.
I guess it's good
he broke a rib today.
Well, I'm sure Padma
would say it's in the stars.
Enrique Mendez, 46.
Imaging for a fractured
rib and collapsed lung
revealed obstruction
with threatened bowel.
Oh, looks like he could
perforate at any time.
Yeah, we need to
get in there right away.
- Is there a prognosis?
- Well, it's hard to say with those images.
There's likely malignancy,
but we won't know
until we get in
and see the extent
of the location and the disease.
And would you be
all right if I invited
my intern to come observe?
That depends. She a Capricorn?
Kidding.
Your sister's killing
me with the astrology.
- Oh, sorry.
- Sure, you can join us.
Just buckle up.
Might be a long one.
Thank you so much, Dr. Austin.
And for the record,
I'm a-a Virgo.
First bowel surgery!
Here you see the fracture
causing pressure on the spine.
We're going to remove
this damaged piece of bone
and use rods to
stabilize your spine.
After some physical
therapy, you should be
back to where you were before.
So I'd be out of this chair.
That's the hope.
But what's the reality?
Well, there are several
factors in our favor here.
Ben's history with
competitive sport, for one.
All that grit and determination
will be essential
in your recovery.
Nice to know it's still
good for something.
- However, I would...
- And our chief surgeon
here at Chastain is a
top-notch neurosurgeon.
Dr. Sutton and I will
be operating together,
so it's an ideal
team going into this.
But it has to be said
that there is no guarantee
that you would regain
the mobility you had before.
And we don't know that you'd
be able to continue with the trial.
But if we don't do this surgery,
I'm not getting out of
this chair again, right?
- Nothing is certain.
- But with the progression
of your MS, yes, that
is a likely scenario.
Can we... take
some time to think?
- Of course.
- I-I don't need time.
- I want to do it.
- Ben,
- I think we should talk about this.
- I...
I want to complete the trial.
We were getting good
results. I'm not ready to give in.
I advise that you talk it over.
But hold on to that spirit, Ben.
- Can we talk?
- I like him, he's a fighter.
I know.
That's why I'm concerned.
Every patient in every trial
thinks they're gonna
be in the top five percent
of the best patient outcome.
And as we know, patients with
good attitudes often
have better outcomes.
But that's not enough.
Look, Ben came to me thinking
he was going to play tennis again.
I've done a lot to
manage his expectations.
I don't believe I indicated
he'd be playing tennis.
No, but I don't think we've
given him an accurate idea
of the risks that
he's gonna take
just to get back into the trial,
when, statistically speaking,
it may not even help him.
The thing about
statistics, Dr. Pravesh,
is that people aren't numbers.
Our job is to
illuminate pathways,
warn of pitfalls,
and follow where
the patient leads.
Are you saying I
haven't done that?
Of course not.
I just hope we're ready
to follow where he's
leading, because...
I don't feel good about it.
Okay, Mr. Mendez, we
need you to sign here
and initial here. All right?
I need to go scrub in.
Do you mind taking
this to the nurse in there?
Of course.
If this goes long,
you can wait in observation.
No way. I'm not
missing anything.
This is a retractor.
You can help me adjust it.
Mobilize the omentum with me.
Let's get a good look inside.
What is it?
All through here...
Diffuse peritoneal
carcinomatosis.
- S-So...
- It's metastasized.
Everywhere.
He's terminal.
There's nothing you can do?
Unfortunately, not when
the damage is this extensive.
- It's beyond treatment.
- Let's close, please.
Would you
like to practice closing?
At least you can
work on your sutures.
Can't you remove
some of the bowel,
clear out the tumors?
Help him live a little longer?
Unfortunately,
we're beyond that.
It happens sometimes.
We open someone up and
we see something we can't fix.
It's a peek and shriek.
"Peek and shriek"?
He's someone's father.
I...
I-I told him he was
going to go to sleep
and-and wake up better.
We have to do something.
How can you just give up? I...
I don't understand.
I am so sorry, Dr. Austin,
I will talk to her.
You need to apologize to
your intern, Dr. Devi, not to me.
Why?
You referred to this
patient's inoperable cancer
as a "peek and shriek."
I mean, you should know
to use more discretion
in front of a new intern.
Obviously I know it
sounded bad, but...
I'm well aware why
we use these phrases.
"Watering the cabbage patch."
"Circling the drain."
So we don't have to look this
horror in the face every day.
- Exactly.
- But she doesn't know that.
All she knows is her
mentor sounded like
she didn't care
about this man at all.
Now, help me close this fascia.
Hey, Maya.
Hey.
Look, I know it may have sounded
like I don't care
about Mr. Mendez.
But sometimes we
disconnect from our patients
when they can't hear us,
because when we have to
talk to them and their families,
it can get overwhelming.
I know it sounds terrible,
but it's just a way of
protecting yourself,
so you don't get
compassion fatigue.
And then you won't have what
you need when you really need it.
Can I show you?
As we explained, the
surgery was partially exploratory.
And, unfortunately,
the mass blocking
Enrique's lower intestine
turned out to be malignant.
You mean cancer?
That's why you've
been having so much pain.
With this type of
cancer, Mrs. Mendez,
it's likely it was
already advanced
by the time he started
having symptoms.
So what do we do?
Unfortunately, the cancer
has spread too much
for us to remove it surgically.
And what does that mean?
An oncologist
will be here shortly
to discuss a number of regimens
that may be of
some benefit, but...
as much as we hoped this
was something we could fix...
it's likely Enrique's
time may be short.
No.
I'll give you
two some time to talk.
Thank you for including me.
I'm still learning, too.
Rongeur, please.
Another bone fragment.
His bones are so brittle.
Unexpected for a
man in his early fifties.
Not for a man with advanced MS
who's undergone years
of steroid treatment.
Suction.
I'm having trouble
with a bit of bone here.
- It's dangerously close to the cord.
- I know.
I've almost got it...
We've got a heart rate in
the 160s. Afib with RVR.
- What's his pressure?
- Dropping.
- MAPS in the 50s.
- His heart is failing.
The steroids from
his MS treatment
must have weakened his heart.
- Bolus amiodarone. Now.
- 150 milligrams
IV amio going in.
I'm not sure how long
he's going to tolerate this.
We're working as
quickly as we can.
If we stop, he
doesn't walk again.
We got a heart rate
in the 170s, team.
- Might have to shock.
- Let's move.
It's a race against time.
We have to finish this
surgery before he codes.
Padma?
You okay?
No.
I can't feel them moving.
Okay. Okay, okay.
We'll just get you
into the bed first,
let's get you into the bed.
Let's just...
take a listen, okay?
Okay.
There's a heartbeat.
Okay?
There's the other.
They're fine.
Do you want me to get an
ultrasound so you can see them?
I was sure they were...
That's perfectly normal.
You just went through
a major surgery.
It's not only that.
It's like...
All these
shadows are hiding
that I never saw before,
all these things that
can go wrong and...
and destroy you
and there's nothing you
can do about any of it.
I think that's just
called being a parent.
What am I doing?
I've thought more
about Burning Man
than becoming a mother.
What if I'm terrible at it?
What if...
what if I'm not
ready for this at all?
Well, the good news is,
you're not doing
any of it alone.
Hey.
I'm right here. For
anything you need.
Okay?
Okay.
My sister seems like
such a fearless, free spirit.
And most of the time she is,
but just like everybody else,
she has a breaking point.
So all the essential oils
and crystals I was
making fun of...
They're her way of coping.
She's terrified.
Of course she is.
All right, what does she need?
- Head injury?
- Discharged. Just a minor concussion.
How's Enrique?
Eh, stabilizing in the ICU.
Tough news.
It's very tough.
Well, you should
get to the polls.
That's one thing we can fix.
What?
It was good being in
the trenches with you.
You, too.
So...
should I bring by
some Crispy Chuck's?
That sounds great.
How's he doing?
Stabilizing.
I should have accounted
for the steroid treatments.
It was hard to see
clearly on this one.
MS is such a bastard.
You think you're on
a plateau and then...
it just crumbles.
Things are developing
all the time, Kit.
I know.
Randolph's been doing better.
But it's always there,
like a sword hanging
over our heads.
I think I'm handling it,
or at least compartmentalizing.
But, apparently...
I'm scared.
For what it's worth,
you do a really good job
of keeping that a secret.
I know.
There really is hope, you know?
Just the person
I was looking for.
- Hey.
- I just wanted to check in,
make sure you're okay.
I'm fine. Why?
The guy who lunged
at you in the ER?
Oh. Uh, that feels
like a lifetime ago.
I'm fine. You're the
one who tackled him.
Turns out varenicline
was making him nuts.
Huh. That's...
oddly comforting?
I know, right?
And also, uh...
I don't know how to say this.
You were Nic's best friend,
so every time I see you,
it's like Nic's watching me
through you, or something.
I don't know. I know
that sounds weird.
Seriously, you
have to let that go.
It makes me
second-guess everything.
Like...
Would Nic approve
of me with Cade?
Like I said, I just
want you to be happy.
Whoever you're with.
So would Nic.
Okay. Thank you. I just...
I just had to get
that off my chest.
You know everything
I went through with Nic
better than anyone.
No worries. You're all good.
Um, you know what? I
remembered I forgot something.
Okay.
See you tomorrow.
Yep.
♪ You'll be okay ♪
♪ Everything ♪
Hello? You up?
- Surprise!
- What...
is this?
♪ You'll be okay ♪
No, you have to try it.
You absolutely have to try it.
♪ Everything ♪
♪ Everything's okay ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Here ♪
♪ You'll be okay ♪
♪ Everything ♪
♪ Everything's okay... ♪
You made it.
It was highly controversial
to get this to-go,
but you're lucky I have
an in with Crispy Chuck.
So he was your
high school boyfriend.
- Mm.
- It's okay, you can be honest.
Did I miss Gigi?
Already in bed.
But...
you could see her at
breakfast tomorrow.
That sounds nice.
♪ ♪
♪ Gimme all your love ♪
♪ Gimme all your love,
gimme all your love ♪
♪ Gimme all your love ♪
♪ ♪
- They call it?
- Not yet.
But the billionaire's ahead.
I just wanted to say, I know
that was a rough surgery.
- I hope I didn't...
- I put you
in a very tight corner.
You handled it
with skill and grace.
Not sure how much grace.
Do you want to go get a drink?
I think I'd better
try and figure out
how Chastain is going to
survive without a third of its budget.
We don't know if he's gonna
win. There's always hope.
As we go to the gathering
where Mark Betz is preparing
to speak to his supporters.
Again, Mark Betz,
billionaire businessman
and first-time candidate
for public office,
is the new governor of Georgia.
Boy, do I love Georgia!
So much for hope.
Hey, come on.
We can't give up that easy.
You know what?
I think I do need that drink.
Attagirl.
I'll say one thing:
That little, untested
real estate developer
has no idea who
he's dealing with.
Ooh, I like this Kit.
Maybe all you needed
was a dragon to slay.
Do me a favor: No
silver linings tonight.
Just black clouds, idiot
billionaires and friends.
Don't forget the bourbon.
♪ ♪
Hey.
It's okay. Go back to sleep.
Mm, nope.
Nope. I'm not going to
let you run away this time.
What's going on?
It's nothing.
Just... something
is up with my dad
and I thought I could
put it out of my mind, but...
And why
would you want to do that?
Back in Seattle, he
had this patient, Carmen.
She had Edward's syndrome.
So he operated on her maybe
six times over a few years.
She was an amazing kid.
Everyone loved her, but
my dad got really attached.
So when she died,
he took it hard.
Started drinking
too much and then...
He started writing
himself prescriptions.
Was he addicted?
He always claimed
he had it under control.
And he never hurt anyone.
You know, just himself.
So he operated
under the influence?
I don't know.
It's possible.
But then he quit.
All on his own.
Cold turkey.
That was five years ago.
And ever since, I've
always been on the lookout
for any kind of sign.
What are you seeing?
Maybe it's nothing.
But... the other day,
I saw him take a pill.
I don't know what
it was, I didn't ask.
And then today, he-he had
this bruise on his forehead, and...
He said it was nothing.
But he seemed jittery.
Well...
I don't pretend to
know him like you do.
But...
if he is using
while he's working,
that's...
that's a problem.
To put it lightly.
I know.
Come here.
Captioning sponsored by 20th
CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org