♪ Dashing through the snow ♪
♪ On a one-horse open sleigh ♪
♪ O'er the fields we go ♪
♪ Laughing all the way ♪
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
♪ Bells on bob-tails ring... ♪
♪ I like the sleigh ride ♪
♪ Dashing through the snow ♪
♪ In a one-horse open sleigh ♪
♪ One-horse open sleigh ♪
♪ O'er the fields we go ♪
♪ Laughing all the way ♪
♪ I like the sleigh ride ♪
♪ Bells on bob-tail ring ♪
♪ Making spirits bright... ♪
♪ ...fun it is to ride and
sing a sleighing song... ♪
Excuse me!
♪ I like the sleigh ride ♪
♪ Jingle bells,
jingle bells... ♪
Wh-whoa!
Sorry, Jerry.
I'm sorry.
That's all ri...
I should have got
cross-country skis.
Well, there's still 17
shopping days left
till Christmas.
Slow day?
Not a single patient.
♪ I like the sleigh ride. ♪
I feel like I'm at camp.
Shh!
I love the first big snowstorm.
Did Jen get out okay?
She left yesterday.
I thought she had
till Wednesday.
She went early.
Early?
Ah! Ah!
Sorry. Sorry.
I don't want to talk about it.
Then why'd you bring it up?
Towel clip.
Why are we doing this?
Because sticking his hand
in a bucket of warm water
would be juvenile.
Ooh..! Ooh..!
Shh. Shh.
And it's a mess out there.
This monster of a storm
began in the Rockies,
crept across the plains,
and landed on the
Midwest this morning,
dumping seven inches of
snow on the ground before dawn.
Latest estimates
now put the total
at close to nine inches.
That left the morning rush hour
looking like a demolition derby.
You thought the Kennedy
construction was bad...
What's a four-letter
word for possessions?
Stuff.
That's five letters.
Roxanne, temp clerks
do answer the phone.
I thought you were going home.
My car's snowed in.
I'm stuck.
Nurse call.
You know that blue flu
that the cops get sick with?
She thinks she caught it.
Bob. Bob, why don't you relax?
It's just going to
get dirty again.
All the more reason why
to keep the foot up on it.
Leg. Leg up on it.
You want to help
put up the Christmas
ornaments instead?
Ornaments?
Mm-hmm.
Ack.
He's kind of cute.
Really?
Yeah. He's got beautiful eyes,
thick hair...
That's a low blow.
What's going on? Nothing.
Nothing. We're
just taking inventory.
Gurney number A7403.
You can go back to sleep, okay?
The National Weather Service
says this could turn into
the biggest snowstorm
since January of 1967
when 23 inches fell in 28 hours.
The last half hour...
What happened to
the security camera?
Somebody stole it.
Are you..?
Yeah, I'm ready.
Call everybody.
Jerry, how does this work?
Uh, it's really pretty simple.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I got it. Okay.
All right, come on.
Okay.
Dr. Carter, stat to Trauma One.
Dr. Carter, stat, Trauma One.
Very funny.
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.
No!
Ow! That hurt!
You cheat.
Good throw. No!
Hey, you!
Don't you dare.
Slow morning, huh?
It's dead.
Never say dead
to a charge nurse.
♪ We're in the E.R.
and it's snowin' outside ♪
♪ Brothers in the
C-town are ready to die ♪
♪ 911 ain't gon'
git you a ride ♪
♪ 'Cause the Gs be chillin'
on the nasty south side ♪
♪ Uh! Uh! Yeah! Yeah! ♪
♪ Yeah! Yeah! ♪
♪ We're in the E.R. ♪
♪ And it's snowin' outside ♪
♪ 'Cause the Gs be chillin'
on the nasty south side. ♪
Ah! That's phat!
Come up on a grip!
Yup.
Raise up about that sorry
peach gear though, man.
Yeah.
What?
He likes it.
♪ 'Cause the Gs be chillin'
on the nasty south side. ♪
The, uh, reindeer
pull the sleigh.
Of course.
You have Santa Claus
and reindeer in Poland?
Yes, many. Many.
No! No!
Well, pranksters.
I can't seem to get this off.
You have to let it dry first.
I'm going to go back to bed.
No, Lydia.
Malik, turn that thing off.
Lydia, let's show them.
No!
Show us, show us,
show us, show us,
show us, show us, show us...
Okay, okay. Okay.
Ouch. Nice ring.
Get my shades.
Ooh!
You're finally going to do it.
Congratulations.
You and Tag are
going to be very happy.
Hi, Doug, hi, Linda.
Hey, guys.
What's the occasion?
John Taglieri and I
are getting married.
That's great. Congratulations.
Thanks.
How was Jamaica?
The Bahamas.
It was fabulous.
We went wind surfing.
And I got sunburned.
The snorkeling was incredible.
Lots of jellyfish.
You going to tell them
about that groin pull too?
Groin pull? Ooh.
Hey, congratulations again.
You guys are going
to be very happy.
Thanks.
I'm going to go take a nap.
Call me later, okay?
Okay.
Doug's idea of a
perfect vacation
is to lie on a deck
chair for a week
with one of those
parasol drinks in his hand.
Sounds pretty good to me.
What?
You might want to...
I put up.
Never mind.
And it's getting
worse out there.
If you had an alien baby,
would it show up on
the pregnancy test?
And we have late word that
the Eisenhower Expressway
is completely shut down...
E.R.
Whoa!
Calm down, Mr. Blinker.
When is the baby's due date?
Uh-huh. And how far
apart are the contractions?
Call 911 now.
Mrs. Blinker's in labor,
but she doesn't want
to come into the hospital.
She wants to deliver
watching the snow fall.
She'd enjoy the snowfall
more with an epidural.
County General, this is Dispatch
for status update. Over.
Dispatch, County General
is on full open status. Over.
Ten-four, General.
My Lexus just got snowplowed in.
Could I use the phone?
Sure. Just dial nine.
Wow. Marquis cut, two carat.
Probably an F-SI1.
Platinum setting.
That's a $12,000 ring.
You are here to work.
Get up.
No patients, no work.
Thing about work, there
is always some around.
Now, I want you to
empty the wastebaskets
into the hopper and re-line
them with plastic bags.
I ain't no garbage man.
Child, move. Go on.
Come on, Carol.
County General, how
do you read? Over.
Read you, ten-two.
Go ahead, Dispatch.
General, implement
disaster protocol.
Mass casualty alert.
32-vehicle pile-up on the
Kennedy Expressway. Over.
Is this a drill? Over.
Negative, General.
This is not a drill.
18 majors, 29 minors.
Fire at scene.
Rescue vehicle access
and communication
limited by weather.
We're calling out
a Plan One. Over.
Roger, Dispatch.
Do you have an estimate
on the number of
casualties? Over.
50 To 100. Over.
How many are coming to us? Over.
Mercy's power is down.
Malik, can you turn this up?
You may get them all. Over.
This is the scene on
the Kennedy Expressway
south of the Grand
exit, where 28 cars
and three trucks were
involved in a collision
just minutes ago.
According to reports
from the scene,
the accident started
when a single car
went into a 360-degree spin,
hitting everything in its way.
Police say at least
41 people are injured
and others are still
trapped in their cars.
To make matters worse,
emergency vehicles
are having trouble getting
to the scene on the roads...
Oh, boy.
Here we go.
And it's a mess out there.
This way! This way!
Green, walking
wounded. Yellow, urgent.
Red, critical, and
black, D.O.A. Got it?
Got it.
Three O.R. crews in.
I got it. Roger, out.
Blood Bank come in.
This is Ross in E.R. Come in.
Blood Bank. I need
those. There you go.
We need to know
your availability
on fresh whole blood.
What do you have, Camacho?
Trapped in a cab, second-
and third-degree burns
25% body surface.
Let's red tag him to Trauma Two.
Mark, send Benton to Trauma Two.
Uh... out. Roger. Mark.
Yeah, I read you.
All the way to the green room.
Okay, what do you got?
Scalp lac.
Let's green tag him
to the waiting room.
We're losing her.
All right, curtain two.
Malik, what have you got?
25-Year-old, truck
rolled, no seat belt.
He coded in the rig.
Grahek, do what you can
and then move on, okay?
Carter, jump in. Use your head.
Stay supervised.
Okay.
A.L.O.C. and step
deformity at the T4 vertebra.
Legs are flaccid.
Okay, we have a cord injury.
Gently on three.
One, two, three.
All right.
C.T.'s prepped for her.
C.B.C, type and hold two units.
Who's on neurosurgical backup?
Armstrong.
Flaccid paralysis and
areflexia south of T4.
She withdraws to pain.
Bag the C-spine films.
We'll do her spine and C.T.
Vitals?
90/62, Pulse 60.
Consider spinal shock.
Okay, got it. Go, Mark.
Hey, what are..?
Get out of here!
Security!
You can't shoot in here!
Get out of here!
What do you think you're doing?
I got to take a leak.
Don't move. You could
have a broken neck.
That's whiplash.
Or it's a spinal fracture and
you're a quadriplegic for life.
Mano, mi mano esta que
paso de la corte mucho.
Esta sangrando.
Mi mano.
Es mi mano.
What?
Let me see your hand.
Where's the cut?
Senor, it's a small
puncture wound.
Poquito. Si?
Okay, sir, you
just try to relax.
I'm going to turn you
over to Dr. Bradley.
We got 500 cc's
out of the right chest.
18% second-degree, nine
percent third-degree burns
in the chest, abdomen
and right shoulder.
You're going to be
in good shape, sir.
Susan, what do you got?
Here it is.
Neck, chest and
right head trauma.
Ma'am, my name is Dr. Benton.
I don't want you to
worry about a thing.
I'm going to take
care of you, okay?
All right, let's move it!
We've got a move going.
Let's go! Clear!
Get her in here.
Right here. Stop.
We need some rays and relief.
Morphine five, I.V. Push.
Here we go.
Ah.
Let's lift her and shift her.
All right, cross table C-spine,
right hip and pelvis.
Round up a bone
crusher now. Move.
On my count. On three.
One, two, three.
We need Ortho in Trauma Two.
Ortho in E.R. Trauma Two.
Two fingers.
Now what do you see?
Such a rock. Lucky girl.
Double-patch her eye
and green tag her to the
waiting room now, please.
What? Did I say something?
Uh-uh.
Where's Carter?
Carter, where the
hell have you been?
Grab some scissors. Move.
How soon can she go up?
Uh, I get her pictures, have the
orthopods look at her... 15 minutes.
We need the room.
The O.R.'s opened up.
Let them see her there.
All right, people.
You heard the boss.
Let's heal them and wheel them.
Do you need help?
No.
B.P.'s fallen
70/40. Pulse is 120.
Skin's cool and dry.
What's your name, sir?
Edward Kaplan.
Call me Eddie. You the doc?
Yes, I am. How are you feeling?
Haven't been tied up this tight
since last Saturday night.
Thank you for
sharing, Mr. Kaplan.
On three. One, two, three.
E.R., please hold.
Shoot me if I
take this job again.
Give me a gun.
I'll shoot you now.
E.R.
Call Fire Station 23.
The number's right there.
See if they can pick up
these docs stuck at home.
What do you got?
Smoke inhalation.
Yellow tag him to curtain two.
What do you got?
I kind of hurt my hand.
Whoa! Where's your thumb?
It's right here.
All right, Malik.
Malik, red tag him
straight to the O.R.
Here's his thumb. Take it.
Mrs. Thui, everything's fine.
Just relax.
She okay?
Yeah. Under control.
Ow!
Found her laying
out in the snow.
No idea who she belongs to.
Go.
Dexter Jones, 25.
Van rolled on him. No seat belt.
Left below-the-knee amputation.
He's shocky.
Rescue Seven's looking
for the rest of his leg.
Benton finished in Two?
Uh-huh.
This is his next patient.
They come at you
with that Foley catheter
run, Jack! Don't walk!
Okay, take him up. O.R.
Two is prepped for him.
When the cross-matched
blood's here,
send it up.
Code in seven! Code in seven!
Run those to Benton
in Trauma One.
Go, Mookie!
B.P.'S real bad... 60 by palp.
Put me out!
Call for six units O-neg blood.
Get the lab for a
C.B.C., type and cross.
Come on, bring those in!
Whoa! I got a pumper.
Come on, bring
those pads in here!
Put this on.
All hands on deck, lets move.
Put it on,
and then put your
hand on the tourniquet.
Come on, Mookie, let's
go. I'll make a surgeon
out of you yet.
97.8.
90/50, Pulse 125.
Pretty darn normal.
Doug.
Yeah.
Gas tank exploded.
Trapped in a car.
All right, D.O.A.
Mr. Ramos.
Multiple contusions
and abrasions.
Does it hurt when I do this?
Le duele?
Auto versus pedestrian!
We're losing him!
Exam three.
Green tag Mr. Ramos
to the doctor's lounge.
Here we go. Move him.
All right, duck your head.
Here we go.
Straight back now, guys.
Straight back.
♪ For his eyes are
on the sparrow ♪
♪ And I know he watches me ♪
♪ I sing because I'm happy ♪
♪ I sing because I'm free ♪
♪ For his eyes are
on the sparrow ♪
♪ And I know he watches me. ♪
♪ I like a sleigh ride,
I like a sleigh ride ♪
♪ Dashing through the snow
in a one-horse open sleigh ♪
♪ O'er the fields we go,
laughing all the way ♪
♪ I like a sleigh ride ♪
♪ Bells on bobtail ring,
making spirits bright ♪
♪ What fun it is
to ride and sing ♪
♪ A sleighing song tonight ♪
♪ I like a sleigh ride ♪
♪ Jingle bells, jingle bells ♪
♪ Jingle all the way... ♪
Patrick?
Patrick, how did you get here?
I... w-w-walked.
Why?
Don't have a d-driver's license.
Oh, okay.
They look better
when they're straight.
Yeah, they do. You're right.
Carol!
Okay. Go to it,
Patrick. Go to it.
Si, senorita.
How we doing in here?
One step ahead of the reaper.
That's all you can ask for.
Thanks for the ride.
Like Edward R. Murrow
back from the dead,
he goes to the media room.
Run it down for me, Mike.
A 40-car pileup on the Kennedy.
We're the major receiving.
18 red tags, ten have gone up.
19 Yellows, 33 greens logged in.
Three D.O.A.s, four
black tags didn't make it.
Six O.R.s are operational
and fire's out
bringing in fresh docs.
Good. Go be a doc!
O.R., Morgenstern. I
need a staff status update.
Aliens have implanted
a detector in my nose!
Doctor, hey!
Aliens have implanted...
Why today, Regina?
Carol, will you page Cvetic,
get him down here right away?
Give her a nice quiet
room, and five of... vitamin H.
That's Haldol! Haldol!
This detects abbreviations!
Oh, wow. What a zoo.
I'm glad you're here.
Take the officer up
to the suture room
and give him some stitches.
I haven't done stitches
since I was an intern.
It's like riding a bike.
I haven't done
that since I was six.
I'm Angela Hicks.
Hi. I'm Dr. Ross.
Why don't you
take bedpan detail?
It's not very glamorous,
but very necessary.
That's Dr. Hicks.
I'm the new attending
E.R. physician.
Oops. You won't be
needing these then.
I don't want this life!
He's hypoxic. His
pulse ox is falling.
Get him down.
Bad news.
PC02's 62. P02's 60.
Let's crash intubate.
Get the sux, Pavulon and Versed.
Let's move, people.
Hold it tight!
Come on, man. Just calm down.
B... B...
Dexter? Oh, God. I know
him from the neighborhood.
Let's move.
Don't do no Indiana
Jones on me, B!
Versed first?
Yeah. Two milligrams,
then succynyl choline.
Just land the plane, B!
B, put up the net!
Just put me out!
Come on. Shh.
I got you, I got you.
Okay? I got you.
Would somebody sign
my time card, please?
It's been eight hours.
Somebody get her
the hell out of here!
Where does it hurt?
My chest!
You hit the steering wheel?
No. I was trying
to light a cigarette.
That's the cigarette lighter?
Ouch.
Dr. Ross, is that little
Cuban guy Ramos
supposed to be dead?
Mr. Ramos!
He was fine ten minutes ago!
He started complaining
of chest pains
and went out. There's no pulse.
Damn it! Let me in.
Could I get some help, please?
I just fell
cross-country skiing.
I'll get you an ice pack.
How long do I have to wait?
I green-tagged him
in the waiting room.
He seemed fine.
Come on!
Where we going?
Trauma Two.
Damn! Come on. Come on.
Hey, Steve, does that
look like a fracture to you?
Yeah. Tri-malleolar. Call Ortho.
If you throw a deep dermal
in there, trim that edge,
it'll line up a lot better.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Dietary? We've got an
E.R. full of hungry people.
Damn.
E.R. Okay, I'll tell her.
Carlos, Linda from Novell.
I need 30 large pizzas
delivered to County General E.R.
I know it's snowing.
Well, get a move on, and
charge it to my account.
Peek-a-boo!
Peek-a-boo... peek-a-boo!
So where's the doctor?
I am the doctor, Mrs. Bozinski.
No, I mean a doctor doctor.
Myra, let her do her job.
Where are you feeling
pain, Mr. Bozinski?
I want Dr. Harvey
Stern called this minute!
Perhaps you'd be
more comfortable
in the waiting room.
Huh. That's a good one.
You call Harvey, Myra.
A pay phone's just
past the admit desk.
B.P.'S okay.
Pulse is a little high.
120.
I don't know if
this capillary refill's
what it should be.
Let's do postural vitals.
Mr. Bozinski, are you sure,
when I push here,
this isn't hurting you?
I'll run a 300cc
fluid challenge.
♪ Deck the halls
with boughs of holly ♪
Turn off the music!
♪ 'Tis the season to be jolly ♪
♪ Fa-la-la-la-la-la-
la-la-la-la... ♪
Another milligram of atropine?
Another milligram.
He's flatlined.
Move! Let me in there.
Let's hook him up to
the external pacemaker.
Mr. Blinker, hang on.
This guy's wife's in labor.
Turn up the damned gain!
It's up all the way.
After you broke down the
door, what did you find?
You're bigger than her, right?
Then carry her in here yourself.
Guy's wife locked
herself into their bedroom.
Stuffed a sock into her
mouth so she wouldn't scream.
She really wants to
have that baby at home.
Come on!
Anybody here with him?
Family's on the way.
Pupils fixed and dilated.
Patrick got into the
Christmas tapes.
Come on.
Doug...
it's been 30 minutes.
Let's call it.
Damn it.
I green-tagged him by mistake.
He's the last of
them... Mr. Thui.
Hi.
Thui, Thui...
Ah! Mr. Thui.
We took very good
care of your wife.
She's been sedated, and
she's resting comfortably.
I do not understand.
She wasn't in the
accident with me.
She was home.
I call her to come pick me up.
Wait. What?
I missed it.
You triaged 70-odd patients.
You're human, Doug.
Doctors...
may I?
Yes.
Uh-huh. Yeah.
My brother in faith, I entrust
you to God who created you.
May you return to the
One who formed you
from the dust of this earth.
My brother in faith,
I entrust you to God
who created you.
May you return to the
One who formed you
from the dust of this earth.
Out of the depths, I have
cried unto Thee, O lord.
Lord, hear my voice.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be Thy name.
Thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done on
earth as it is in heaven.
All right, people, let's hook
this up to the suction. Move.
You think the vascular boys
can put Humpty Dumpty
back together again?
They're in for something.
Dexter's always been
a magnet for bad luck.
Hi, kids. I'm Dr. Hicks.
Give me the bullet.
Left B-K amputation.
Estimated blood loss 40%.
Bilateral hemothorax.
750cc's from the
right thoracostomy.
Rapid sequence induction.
Versed, succinyl
choline, Pavulon.
Four liters Ringer's,
six units O-neg in.
Cervical spine
cleared, vitals stabilized.
You're Peter Benton,
right? I've heard about you.
Oh, yeah? Is that good or bad?
He's in fib!
Charge the defibrillator. 200.
Excuse me.
How much longer am
I going to have to wait?
Clear!
Good God! What was that?
His B.P.'s falling
fast. I get 60 palp.
Crit's down. Losing blood.
Run them in fast.
Did Dr. Stein ever tell you
you have an aortic aneurysm?
I don't feel a femoral pulse.
He had one before.
Oh, my God, Doctor,
please. Do something!
Let's get him
into the O.R. now!
Nobody's available. No surgeons?
There's 22 surgeries
going on up there.
Okay, we'll do it here.
I'll get Benton.
Prep a thoracotomy tray now.
I need a surgeon in Three stat.
I've got a triple-A
that's about to blow.
Order a laparotomy
setup from O.R.
Call Anesthesia. Get
Dr. Ashe down here.
You ever cross-clamped an aorta?
No.
I don't feel a thing!
Call the code. Get some epi.
Open the I.V.s wide.
Morris!!
Morris...
Doctors, please. Do something.
Bob?
What are you doing?
Oh, man.
What happened?
It was Bob.
Bob?
Bob.
Police said that
our baby, Ashley...
Oh, my God.
Ashley.
Oh, God.
I love you.
Are you okay?
They found the leg.
Vitals?
B.P.'s 110/70.
Pulse is 112 and strong.
Pulse ox is good: 95 percent.
Great. What's he had?
Eight units packed
cells, four liters Ringer's.
We're in a holding
pattern for vascular.
Why don't we fly
this puppy ourselves?
Send to O.R. for
a vascular tray,
bovie, drapes and
gowns and an ex-fix.
You going to do a
reimplantation in the E.R.?
Not me. We.
Let's get a start on him.
The vascular team
will swoop down
when they smell the glory.
All right. Now you're
talking. Let's go.
Here's the abdominal,
chest and C-spine film.
His B.P. came
up with four units.
Oh, Susan.
Strong piece of work.
I've seen chief surgical
residents do worse.
Thanks. Have you seen Bob?
Officer, escort this
camera crew out of here!
Yo, Dr. Lewis.
Yeah.
They need you to
scrub in Trauma One.
Do you know where Cvetic is?
His exchange hasn't
been able to reach him.
No.
Do you know what
we call motorcycles
around here, ace?
No. What?
Donor-cycles.
Donor-cycles. I like that.
Yeah. You would.
Hurry it up, Carter.
You got a million things to do.
Hi.
What the hell are you doing?
I'm trying to get this cast off.
How the hell do you
change your pants, man?
They put it on me as a joke,
and now it's starting to itch!
Yeah, tell me about it.
Eight casts in six months.
Hog sat on me.
Dropped my Nighthawk.
Oh, yeah.
Relax, Doc.
This won't hurt a bit.
Hey!
Hey! Hey!
That's Mrs. Ramos.
You want me to come with you?
No, thanks.
Mrs. Ramos...
I'm Dr. Ross.
Your husband sustained
very serious injuries
in the accident.
He was brought here.
Um...
Despite our best efforts,
we were unable to save him.
He...
he died.
I'm sorry.
Good night.
Bob?
Now I will never
be a doctor here.
Uh... were you
planning on being one?
In my country, I was a surgeon.
Vas... vas...
Vascular?
Yeah.
You're a vascular surgeon?
Yes.
Uh...
I need to board.
The board.
Oh, you have to, uh,
take the board exam.
Yes.
If I not operate, the man die.
But now,
when they find out,
I will never board.
Wait a minute.
You operated on somebody?
When they find out what I did...
Oh, Bob.
Did the patient die?
No.
Oh.
Well, then, they'll be grateful.
Really?
I'll help you with your
English for the board exam.
You would do it for me, that?
Yeah.
He's cyanotic as hell.
Castro.
How did it go with Mrs. Ramos?
Pulse ox is really bad... 60.
Hemostat.
Check his cardiovascular, Doug.
What is that?
Patrick turned it on.
His pulse is down to 30.
Give .5 of atropine.
Guy on the phone... Mr. Blinker.
Says he's only going to
talk to you, Dr. Greene.
Put him on the speaker.
Dr. Greene?
I'm here, Mr. Blinker.
She wants to push.
Well, look between her legs
and tell me what you see.
Retract here.
Uh... baby... baby hair.
You ever delivered a baby?
I'm a plumber.
It's coming.
Okay, we want
to control the head.
When the head is halfway out,
tell your wife not to push.
And then gently
ease the skin over it.
What? The head?
Yeah. Like putting on a sweater.
Well, the head's
out. It's turning.
Retract here.
That's what it's supposed to do.
Mr. Blinker, gently pull
down towards the floor.
Seven of Proline.
Oh, my God.
Hey, it's a boy!
Good. Good work.
Now place the baby
on your wife's belly.
Get a shoelace and tie the cord.
Wrap them up in a blanket
nice and warm and bring them in.
Okay.
Dr. Benton, your friend has
his posterior artery back.
Vascular team's here.
We've debrided,
re-anastomosed posterior
tibial artery and
saphenous vein,
confirmed flow by Doppler.
Strong preliminary work.
Get him unhooked, ready to move.
All right, Dex,
I'll see you walking
down King Drive.
Doug?
Are you okay?
About what?
About Mr. Ramos.
Everything.
Yes. I'm glad you're happy.
Really.
I'm going to get my stuff
and we can go, okay?
You know, Doug
is a fabulous guy.
We have lots of
fun, and he's cute.
He's great in bed.
Do you think there's
one perfect love?
You know, like
Sleepless in Seattle?
Somewhere under the stars,
one perfect person
for everybody?
I don't know. Why?
Because, for Doug...
it's you.
Hey! Who ordered these pizzas?
Pizza's here!
Great job, folks.
Excellent.
Very nice.
Hey, hey, it's Dr. Bob!
Aw, now what?
All right, Patrick.
♪ Chestnuts roasting
on an open fire ♪
♪ Jack Frost nipping
at your nose ♪
♪ Yuletide carols ♪
♪ Being sung by a choir ♪
♪ And folks dressed
up like Eskimos ♪
♪ Everybody knows ♪
♪ A turkey and some mistletoe ♪
♪ Help to make
the season bright ♪
♪ Tiny tots with
their eyes all aglow ♪
♪ Will find it hard
to sleep tonight ♪
♪ They know that
Santa's on his way ♪
♪ He's loaded lots of toys
and goodies on his sleigh ♪
♪ And every mother's child... ♪
Mr. Blinker? Mrs. Blinker?
Dr. Greene?
Yeah.
God bless you, Dr. Greene.
♪ And so I'm offering
this simple phrase ♪
♪ To kids from one to 92 ♪
♪ Although it's been said
many times, many ways ♪
♪ Merry Christmas to you. ♪