Previously on The Resident...
We can all agree
- it was the misdosed sevo.
- That's never gonna fly.
I covered for
you. Not this time.
We cannot handle
one more lawsuit.
I have installed
recording devices
on every camera in every OR.
Doctors must support each other
through good times and bad.
Time of death, 21:58
I don't understand.
She was stable last
night when I left my shift.
I went home, I left her alone.
I should have stayed here.
Healing hands and
the spirit of care.
Chastain Memorial Hospital.
Incredible things
are happening here.
You got to be kidding me.
Incredible things?
Wow.
Hey.
Mina told me to find you.
Dr. Bell just started the
lipoma excision on your patient.
- Turner was scheduled for that.
- Yeah.
He's out sick. Stomach flu.
Wait, that's TJ's surgery.
Doesn't he have
a latex sensitivity?
You're right. I need to
check on him, and Bell.
Hey.
Go easy on your ankle today.
What ankle?
The spirit of care.
Chastain Memorial Hospital.
Incredible things
are happening here.
Pickups.
- Give him five, imidazoline.
- Anyone seen
the new hospital promo?
Oh, I saw it.
You're fantastic, Dr. Bell.
What about you, Dr. Okafor?
You're in it.
Silk.
How much longer?
Just have to close up.
Some bleeding posteriorly.
Yeah, I got it.
Cautery.
Set to 40:40 blend point.
Mm-hmm.
Damn it.
Shut off the oxygen.
Look, I got to keep sterile
so I can close the
patient. Get the O2 off!
- Get that O2 mask off.
- Rip the drapes down.
More oxygen might
be hiding beneath them.
Hey, Mina, I need you sterile.
Paul. Paul, I need
you to bag him.
It's still open. I got
to cover the incision.
Can't let him get hypothermic.
Someone get those
sprinklers turned off!
Incredible things
are happening here.
♪ ♪
Sorry for the wait, Nurse Nevin.
Ms. Thorpe can see you now.
Please, come in.
- This is Joshua Williams, head of risk management.
- Hi.
Um, what is this about?
Unfortunately, we have
some bad news. Please.
Lily's family is suing the
hospital for wrongful death.
And you're named in the suit.
Uh, I don't understand.
- Just me?
- No.
However, risk management
has to do their investigation,
and until its over, we have to
ask you to stop seeing patients.
Has Lily's autopsy come back?
We'll go over all the details
during the investigation.
Ms. Thorpe.
There's been an
emergency in the OR.
A patient caught fire.
You've done enough
damage, I've got it from here.
I'm his surgeon, you're an
internist. What are you even
- doing on the OR floor?
- He had a latex allergy.
I was double-checking
nothing was missed.
- The proper precautions were taken.
- What happened?
Your chief of surgery
just set a patient on fire.
Look, I've just had
it. I've had it with you!
- Challenging me at every corner.
- Not now. Dr. Hawkins,
go to the ICU; Dr. Bell, a word.
What the hell happened in there?
Well, it's unclear,
but it wasn't my fault.
Oh, just like Mr. Zhou's post-op
bleeding wasn't your fault?
I don't know what
you think you know.
You know what I know? Is
that I have recording devices
in every OR, so I'm
gonna find out exactly
what caused that fire.
Are you okay?
Yeah, the surgery
went perfectly.
I... the resection was done.
And I-I was, I was
closing, and then...
You're not to blame.
I mean, doctors are only as
good as our support staff...
I use a cautery
in every surgery.
This has never happened before.
Don't worry, the
truth will come out.
The truth... it's relative.
It-it looks like my fault.
Worst case, the hospital
settles with the patient.
That's a... like,
another lawsuit.
Randolph.
The board reveres you.
You will survive this.
We will survive this.
Together.
I'm on your side.
Never forget that.
And finally, all charting
must be done immediately
after you see the patient.
I've worked in the
ER before, Irving.
This is your intern
year rotation in the ER.
Today, you're one of us.
Let's start with something
closer to home for an internist.
A nice mystery diagnosis,
Sherlock.
Hi, Olivia Tan?
I'm Dr. Devon Pravesh.
What brings you in today?
I was gargling with
mouthwash this morning,
and I accidentally
swallowed some.
So I called poison control,
and they told me it was
nothing to worry about,
but I think they were just
trying to get me off the phone.
I gargle a lot.
It helps with my
bowel movements.
Got to be conjunctivitis.
Or shingles.
Melanoma?
I think it's a staph infection.
It's a mosquito bite.
And then, my face blew up
like I had a peanut allergy.
Frickin' avocados, man.
That is how my aunt died...
of leprosy.
Right.
You're perfectly healthy.
What's your diagnosis, Harvard?
She's a total nutjob.
I'm discharging her.
Without a thorough workup?
I was as thorough
as humanly possible.
And I've given her a
definitive diagnosis.
- She's a cyberchondriac.
- Hmm.
She surfs WebMD for symptoms,
and she convinces herself
that she has them all.
Not bad, Harvard, not bad.
Now pick one of her complaints
and write her some sort
of placebo prescription
before you discharge her.
Why would I do that?
She's perfectly healthy.
To make sure she
walks out of here
feeling better than
when she walked in.
And more important, that
she doesn't come back
to the ER tomorrow.
Lily's family's filing a suit.
What family?
I never saw them once
the entire time she was here.
Me neither, but risk
management's launching
an investigation, so
they're definitely suing.
I was her internist.
Why haven't I heard about it?
Probably because
they're focusing on me.
This is what they do, find a
lower-level hospital worker
to pin everything on.
Hey.
As soon as the autopsy
results come back,
they'll see that a chemo
overdose caused Lily's death,
and you had nothing
to do with that.
Come here, come here, come here.
Is this a formal investigation?
I'm trying to get to the
truth of what happened
with the fire in Dr. Bell's OR.
This is the surveillance
footage from the security camera.
That scalpel there,
it has a spark.
That's a big deal.
It's a cautery tool.
They all spark.
Yes, but the spark
hit the surgical drape.
He should have
been more careful.
No, it's not that simple.
He's holding the tool
that caused the fire.
Do you see the pure oxygen
pooling from the patient's neck?
No, of course not.
Oxygen is invisible.
Exactly. Neither did Bell.
It's seeping out from
under the patient's mask.
And since pure oxygen
is heavier than air,
it falls to the table and
collects like kindling
waiting to ignite.
The spark hits it
and bam... Fire.
It was an accident.
It sounds like you're
covering up for him.
I'm telling you
what caused the fire.
And it wasn't Dr. Bell.
A surgical fire?
I'm calling in a favor
with the best plastic
surgeon I know, Dr. Rand.
We'll go over our options.
I think I'm cursed.
You aren't cursed.
Fires in the OR are
rare, but they do happen.
In high school, they
called me "Tumor Boy"
because of this huge
mass coming off of my neck.
But surgery was so expensive,
my family couldn't afford it.
So when I was old enough,
I went to work coding,
like a rat in a cubicle.
I saved every penny.
And all I wanted to
do was to look normal.
And-and I wake up...
looking like Freddy Krueger.
We'll do everything
possible to make this better.
I promise.
When Lily came to the hospital
after her final chemo
dose, she was so sick.
Nauseous, vomiting, dehydrated.
And she was scared.
Scared?
Why was she scared?
Earlier that morning, she'd
undergone a massive chemo blast.
It was causing her body
to fail, and she knew it.
Dr. Hunter has her
own powerful protocols
which have had remarkable
success fighting cancer.
And take a toll on patients
in every possible way.
Lily was depressed,
and weak, and that was before
Dr. Hunter bombarded her system.
She wasn't strong
enough for such high doses.
Are you suggesting that
Dr. Hunter was to blame
for Lily's death?
I wish Dr. Hunter hadn't
given her that last treatment.
Lily wanted to stop.
She told me herself.
Dr. Hunter convinced
her to go through with it,
and Lily paid
the ultimate price.
Nurse Nevin,
Lily Kendall didn't die
from a chemo blast.
The autopsy results
are back. They identify
Lily's cause of death as
a potassium overdose.
That's not possible.
The bag of potassium
that you hung for Lily
the night she
died... killed her.
After Dr. Rand has
worked his magic,
the scarring will be minimal.
- Yeah.
- No more Freddy Kreuger for you.
It's amazing what a great
plastic surgeon can do.
How long until I
look almost normal?
Several months to
be ready for surgery
and then heal afterwards.
- Man.
- Oh, come on.
I've already waited so long
to be camera ready, dude.
Camera ready?
I didn't want to do the
surgery just to look better.
I was gonna quit coding. I
was gonna do my own thing.
A NetTube channel.
"ChioffiCoffee with
TJ and Rascal."
Rascal is... my dog.
Yeah, he's a badass.
Oh, dude, he's a total badass.
We'll do a bunch of cool
stuff together, you know?
Like, shred a skateboard.
- I've been training him to box.
- But why wait?
Vlog the whole process of
plastic surgery and recovery.
Just be yourself.
People love you.
You're funny as hell.
Would you subscribe to that?
Are you kidding me? Absolutely.
Hey, sorry to interrupt.
Uh, you have a second?
A potassium overdose?
Lane told me to set the
drip to the slowest setting,
infusing her over eight hours.
Somehow, she got the
entire dose in 30 minutes.
Was there something
wrong with the bag?
What I do know is that
when I set the flow rate,
I checked it and I rechecked it.
You know how thorough I
am. I didn't make a mistake.
And now Lily's family is suing,
so they need a
scapegoat, and I'm it.
- I'll fix this.
- No, stop.
I don't need you
doing anything crazy.
It's only gonna
make things worse.
What do you want me to do?
Help me find proof.
Where do we start?
Okay, there are seven of
Lane's patients here at Chastain.
Run a full blood panel on each.
Okay, seven patients?
What are we looking for?
Anything that shows a pattern
of Lane making mistakes.
Kidney function,
potassium levels.
Okay, but there's a problem.
When the test results come in
on Lane's patients,
they go directly to her.
He's right.
But since I am
in the ER today...
I could run the blood work here
like they're for our John Does.
That works. You're catching on.
One thing. We can't drag
another nurse into this.
They could get
into serious trouble,
so perform the
blood draws yourself.
Okay, okay. Refresh my
memory as to how to draw blood
and we're good to go.
Don't look at me. I haven't
drawn blood since med school.
Doctors.
Dr. Kays. I'm reviewing every
surgeon's complication rate.
Well, my stats are
no cause for concern.
Agreed, but the
same cannot be said
of your surgical
resident, Dr. Okafor.
She's seen more
than her fair share.
Not in my OR.
Ladies.
What brings you to our
floor again today, Claire?
Well, she's worried about
Dr. Okafor's complication rate.
Those concerns were previously
brought to the surgical board
and put to rest.
I'm just interested in
Dr. Kays's assessment.
Uh, well, initially,
I had doubts,
because Mina is arrogant.
Turns out she has a right
to be, because she's brilliant
and careful and fearless,
and I wish I had
ten more like her.
What're your thoughts?
No, I agree. As I've said
before, I think she's a talent.
High praise, all around.
Yeah, that's-that's the
worst the pain's ever been.
It's got to be
another obstruction.
No air-fluid levels,
no dilated loops of
bowel. X-ray's normal.
Then why does it hurt so bad?
- Well, it can be either two things...
- Dr. Feldman.
Multi-casualty MVC just
arrived and bed eight needs you.
I'll give you one shot
of Dilaudid for the pain.
Nurse Hundley will walk you
through dietary recommendations
- and we'll send you on your way.
- Up to surgery.
For a perforated intestine.
Sir, this is free air
under your diaphragm.
Surgery? It's serious?
Dr. Feldman, am I,
am I gonna be okay?
We caught this early.
We'll start antibiotics
and you'll have it
fixed this afternoon
and be recovered
in no time. Hey.
Hang in there.
Good catch.
Call a gen surg consult
then jump into the trauma.
Good looking out.
Lesson two, no matter what
other emergency pops up...
Don't let you kill
the patient. Got it.
You do catch on quick.
May I join you?
So, Claire has been...
asking about your error rates.
And, of course, I had your back.
Oh, like when you blamed me
for the complication
that happened
during your multiple surgeries?
Just tell me what you want.
Well, I wouldn't be surprised
if Claire or someone from HR
reaches out to
you about the fire.
She already found me.
And what'd you tell her?
The truth.
Yes, Nurse Nevin was in
charge of Lily's care that night,
but I can't fathom how a
respected nurse practitioner
could make such
a careless error.
What error, exactly?
Well, obviously, when
the bag was hung,
the wrong flow rate was set.
You're saying that Nurse Nevin
set the flow rate incorrectly?
Well...
it is possible.
But I'm also...
W-Wait. What other
explanation is there?
At the moment, there isn't one.
What happened?
He was fine. His
O2 levels went down.
- He started suffocating.
- Help me.
Help.
Here we go. I can
barely bag him.
The swelling from the burns
is compressing his trachea.
All right, his sats
are down to 78%.
- He's bradying down.
- Start prepping the neck.
Gonna need to do an escharotomy.
He's gonna code, doctor.
Hang on, TJ. Hang on.
We need anesthetic?
Burned flesh has no
sensation. He won't feel anything.
We do need to
worry about infection.
Come on, come on, come on,
come on, come on, come on.
Come on, come on, come on...
His sats are going up.
Slow, deep breaths.
Deep breaths, TJ.
Do you really think they're
gonna blame Lily's death on you?
Not without a fight.
Let's get this over with.
All right.
Needle bevel up, 30 degrees.
Ready?
Yep.
- Ow.
- Sorry.
Okay, um, you're
angling it a little too high.
Try again. Down a little bit.
Lower. Yeah.
Start.
- No.
- Sorry.
Pull the skin
down taut like this.
One more time.
Wow, okay. Um...
I will be drawing the blood.
You're not supposed
to go near the patients.
I am done coloring
inside the lines
in a system rigged against me.
Come on.
Are you kidding me?
I already gave
blood this morning.
It's frozen, Mr. Guzman.
Damn it.
It's not fair. You
know my weakness.
I'd let you have a gallon of
my blood for one of these.
- Thank you.
- Mmm.
Next victim.
Ah, I got to take this.
Wait for me so I can
stand guard with you.
- I got it.
- Nic.
I'm good.
You paged?
Where you been?
Conrad needed
help with something.
Oh, yeah. No, you don't get
to run off during your ER shift
to help Conrad.
We're not busy right now.
Don't jinx us. Here.
Nothing I've tried has
worked and I hate snot.
Luca, bed one.
Let's see what you come up with.
Hi, Luca.
- -Oh, hey.
- What's happening?
Uh, she shoved her father's blue
collectable marble up her nose,
like way up her nose.
We're gonna get it out, okay?
It's okay.
Shh. It's okay.
You're supposed
to be on desk duty.
I know.
Hold on.
Mr. Smith in 5087.
I can't find his vein.
Can you stick him for me?
Sure, no problem.
You'll be great.
Thanks, Doc.
I used a cardiac catheter
to pull the marble
out of her sinus cavity.
Worked like a dream.
You're good, Dr. Pravesh.
Did Conrad tell you to
use the catheter like that?
No, I did it on my own.
Not bad for a Harvard grad. Huh?
Hey, Ashley.
When's my interview?
Your interview's been
cancelled, Dr. Hawkins.
Why?
I just keep the schedule.
Dr. Hawkins.
What's going on, Alexis?
Why was my interview cancelled?
Lily was my patient,
and I was the last
person to see her alive.
Why won't they let me testify?
Dr. Hunter.
She convinced them
that you can't be objective
because you're in a
romantic relationship with Nic.
Conrad, Lane totally
threw her under the bus.
And they believed her.
Now, everyone's afraid
if they stand up for Nic,
they'll get fired.
All right.
Thank you, Alexis.
I promise I didn't
hear this from you.
- Dr. Hawkins, what are you doing here?
- Your best nurse
is getting screwed over.
That's not a risk management
investigation,
it's a witch hunt.
- Okay, Conrad. That's enough.
- Do you know why Lane
barred Nic from treating
Lily those last few weeks?
'Cause Nurse Nevin was
making some mistakes.
No, she doesn't make mistakes.
She catches them.
That's why she was the first one
to see what Lane has been doing.
What do you think
Lane has been doing?
Overdosing patients with chemo,
discharging patients too soon,
- hiding patients' records...
- Okay, this is ridiculous.
You want me to
believe this about one
of our most respected
doctors at Chastain?
Yes. That's exactly what
I'm asking you to believe.
And I can't stop thinking if I
would've listened to Nic sooner,
maybe Lily would still be alive.
Lane's protocols
did not kill Lily.
A potassium overdose did.
And Lane is trying to
pin that overdose on Nic.
Dr. Hunter put Nic back on
Lily's case the day Lily died.
Come on. Clearly, something
is going on here, Ms. Thorpe.
Lane is up to something,
and if we don't do anything...
Okay, Lane is devastated
about Lily's death.
And I am not sure
what you're insinuating,
but she was nowhere
near Chastain
the night that Lily died.
Lane was out to
dinner with Dr. Bell.
Perfect. The Hands of Death
and Destruction is her alibi?
Keep your absurd
allegations to yourself.
If you don't open your eyes
to the truth, hold on tight,
because this entire hospital
will come crashing
down on all of us.
Hello, everybody.
Welcome to ChioffiCoffee.
Have you ever felt like
you might be cursed?
Well, wait till you see my day.
♪ Cautery, cautery ♪
♪ C-C-Cautery, cautery ♪
♪ C-C-Cautery, cautery,
cautery, c-c-cautery ♪
- ♪ Maybe we won't pass that ♪
- ♪ Cautery ♪
-♪ Maybe don't pass
that ♪ -♪ Cautery ♪
♪ Cautery, cautery, cautery ♪
♪ Don't, don't, don't
pass the cautery ♪
- ♪ Yeah, I've got it ♪
- ♪ Ow, that hurts ♪
♪ That is a burn, I
got to be cursed ♪
♪ What just happened?
Why was there a spark? ♪
♪ What's that
cooking? Oh, it's me ♪
♪ Is that prime rib? No,
it's burning neck flesh ♪
♪ Hot, hot, hot, somebody
turn down the heat ♪
- ♪ Get that O2 off ♪
- ♪ Turn off the O2... ♪
Where'd he get the video?
It's a mystery, isn't it?
- ♪ Get that O2 off ♪
- ♪ Turn off the O2 ♪
♪ Get that O2 off ♪
♪ O2, O2, O2 ♪
♪ Cautery, cautery ♪
♪ C-C-Cautery... ♪
Uh, how many hits does it have?
Mm, 560,000 and climbing.
Wow.
♪ That's gonna
leave a scar, yeah ♪
♪ Gonna leave a scar, scar ♪
♪ Put water on me,
put-put water on me... ♪
Wow. I just saw the video.
We need to get ahead of this.
Can we get it off the Web?
No, it's already gone
viral. No one can stop it.
Not even my contacts at NetTube.
Trust me, I've already tried.
Okay, so what do you recommend?
We need to give them
something else, something good.
A human interest story,
maybe a kid from
a... war-torn country.
Build him a face, or hands,
- a limb. Something.
- All right.
- You find the kid, I'll find the money.
- Okay.
♪ Cautery, cautery,
c-c-cautery, cautery ♪
♪ Hey, watch it,
don't give it to him ♪
♪ Cautery,
c-c-cautery, cautery... ♪
Congrats.
Yeah?
You're a star.
And you are a genius.
No, I had nothing to
do with you hacking
into the surgical
learning database.
The hell you didn't.
Chastain could use
a security update.
And I could help you with that,
but I'm... I'm gonna be too busy
finally living my dream.
Thanks, man. You
changed my life.
No more coding in
a cubicle for this guy.
Can't wait to watch
your NetTube channel.
Hey. I...
I thought Dr. Kays was
doing this hernia repair.
She is, I'm just...
I'm just here to see how you're
holding up after this morning.
Claire's making the rounds.
I haven't talked to anyone.
I mean, OR fires are caused
by the anesthesia team.
And I think, before an inaccurate
narrative takes a hold, well,
we got to figure out
what the hell happened.
What do you need from me?
Hey.
Got all the blood work back.
Anything unusual?
All of Lane's patients are as
healthy as can be expected.
Damn it.
Well, at least the
patients are safe.
For now.
I'm being called back
in for more questions.
You want me to come with you?
After your sit-down with Claire,
- you should probably hang back.
- Nic.
Are you sorry I did it?
No.
So we have no record
of the rate at which
Lily received the potassium,
or if you did in
fact, as you claim,
set the flow machine
at the prescribed rate.
If I made an error, I
would admit it, but I didn't.
Then how do you account for
the lethal levels of potassium
in Lily's system?
Someone must have changed
the flow rate after I set it.
So your defense is, is that
some mysterious person came
into Lily's room after you left,
and accelerated the flow rate,
administering a lethal
dose of potassium?
Why would someone do that?
To kill Lily.
Um...
Who would kill a patient
who, by all accounts,
is beloved by the entire staff?
I could guess, but I
don't have any proof,
so I'm not going to do that.
Well, if you have
something to tell us,
it would be in your
best interest to do it now.
My best interest?
None of this is in my
best interest, or Lily's.
We want to know the truth.
- The family wants to know the truth.
- No, you don't.
And Lily's family wasn't
here taking care of her.
Not once over the two
years that she was in and out.
I comforted her.
Talked to her about death.
Bathed her, fed her.
I cared for her.
Not because I liked her,
which I did,
and not because she was
one of my favorite patients,
which she was.
I cared for Lily the same way
I care for all of my patients.
'Cause that is what nurses do.
Now, doctors order
tests, they prescribe meds,
and they go home, but nurses...
You know, doctors think
the patients are theirs,
but they're not.
They're ours.
The nurses'.
Lily Kendall was my patient,
and I did not harm her.
But someone else did.
I think we're done here.
Yeah.
Ha-ha, Roman. Glad
you're feeling better, man.
Okay.
You're on a roll.
But this next one's tricky.
Try Mr. Langdon out for size.
Bay two.
On his first day?
That's not fair.
Oh, whatever it is, I got it.
- Double or nothing?
- You're on.
Hello, Mr. Langdon.
What seems to be the problem?
Snakes.
I got snakes in my throat.
They're crawling,
like, all down here.
I can feel it moving,
like, right now.
Well, let's take a look at them.
W-Will it hurt?
Not a bit.
Okay, Mr. Langdon.
Open wide and say "ah."
Ah...
Nurse Hundley.
Let's get ready for the...
the...
the snake extraction.
- Okay.
- All right?
Magill forceps.
- Y-You almost got it?
- Shh...
- We don't want to scare her.
- Uh-huh.
Almost... there.
Oh, yeah.
Here we go.
One female, beige snake.
- Uh, hard to believe that was in my throat, huh?
- It is.
Specimen jar!
How you doing, Mr. Langdon?
So much better.
Oh.
Thank you, Doctor.
Oh, you are very welcome.
Okay.
While I was giving my
testimony, I suddenly realized...
Lane did this intentionally.
She overdosed
Lily intentionally?
- Did you say that to them?
- No.
But I know it's true.
Who else had the motive?
I mean, think about it.
Dr. Osder probably called her
that afternoon for Lily's files.
There must be
something in Lily's files
that Lane didn't
want anyone to see,
so she made sure that
Osder couldn't get it.
Didn't she tell you she
was leaving for the night?
She made a point of telling me
that she was leaving when
she ordered the potassium.
I think she pretended to leave
and then doubled back
to adjust the flow rate.
Then it's completely
untraceable,
and it looks like you set it
wrong from the beginning.
But you believe me, right?
Of course I believe you.
Dr. Okafor, have you ever heard
Dr. Hawkins call Dr. Bell
the "Hands of Death and
Destruction," or HODAD?
Yes. I have.
Why? I need to know.
You are asking me
to be a whistle-blower.
I need someone to
tell me what's going on.
Whistle-blowers get
fired. Not just at Chastain.
At the best hospitals
in the country,
it happens again and again.
I love surgery
more than anything.
I have given up everything
to be here in America,
practicing, and I want to stay.
I will do everything
I can to protect you.
If you go after Bell,
you are at risk as well.
He'll stop at nothing
to destroy you.
I am the CEO.
His future is in my hands,
not the other way around.
And this is not only about Bell.
It's about saving
patients' lives.
You are a great doctor.
And if great doctors
don't speak up...
nothing changes.
I'll tell you the truth, but
only within these walls.
If you reference
this conversation,
I'll deny it ever happened.
Understood.
You have my word.
Let's start at the beginning,
when he killed a patient
during an appendectomy.
- Well done.
- Hey, next video, you got to be in it.
- How's he doing?
- He's doing great, actually.
NetTube just offered
him a partnership.
Looks like his curse is broken.
The board called an emergency
meeting to discuss Bell.
That fire he didn't even
start might end his career.
Isn't there a word for that?
Irony?
I was going for justice,
but yours works, too.
The fire today is only
the last in a string of errors
caused by Dr. Bell.
Most of which have been
so cleverly covered up,
I have no evidence to present.
You're making very
serious accusations.
And they're all hearsay?
The staff that have come
forward wish to remain anonymous
for fear of reprisal.
Disgruntled staff?
That's your evidence.
Autopsies are rarely
performed these days,
so there is nothing to prevent
surgeons from disguising errors
by listing "complications"
as the cause of death.
The truth remains in the OR,
unless somebody insists
on transparency, and I do.
Which is why I installed
recording devices
in all the ORs.
And this is what we see.
Get that O2 mask off.
Rip the drapes down.
More oxygen might
be hiding beneath them.
This video is damning, Randolph.
Well, it's not, when
you understand
what you're looking at.
See this machine right here?
Sitting beside it
is Dr. Paul Chu,
chief anesthesiologist
here at Chastain.
Dr. Chu?
Dr. Chu, can you explain
the cause of this fire?
Every year in the U.S.,
there are around 600 OR fires,
just like the one
we had here today.
They are preventable
if you replace
antiquated machines
like the ones we have with...
With the newer air-oxygen
blending machines
that allow a skilled
anesthesiologist like Dr. Chu
to limit the flow
of pure oxygen.
A request I made to Claire
right after she began
here at Chastain.
His proposal was
cost-prohibitive.
So you chose saving money
over patient safety.
So this was made...
with Claire's OR camera.
♪ That is a burn, I
got to be cursed ♪
♪ What just happened?
Why was there a spark? ♪
♪ What's that
cooking? Oh, it's me! ♪
♪ Is that prime rib? No,
it's burning neck flesh ♪
♪ Hot, hot, hot, somebody
turn down the heat ♪
- ♪ Get that O2 off ♪
- ♪ Turn off the O2 ♪
- ♪ Turn off the O2, hey ♪
♪ Get that O2 off,
get that O2... ♪ -
As you can see, it's gone viral.
So, in her zeal
for transparency,
she ignored my warnings
about the damage
this kind of footage can
do in the wrong hands.
What we're witnessing
is when hospital
leadership has an MBA
and doesn't understand medicine.
Our CEO needs to be a doctor.
Claire wanted to see me?
Uh, the board meeting's
running late, have a seat outside.
Hello?
Hey, you have a minute?
Oh, you know better than that.
- You have to hustle back to the clinic?
- Yeah.
I should've listened to my
father, gone into dentistry.
In at 8:00, home by 5:00.
Yeah, nothing against
dentists, but you're saving lives.
Well, I'm not alone in
the fight, but thank you.
Really? 'Cause I can't
find another oncologist
who carpet-bombs patients
with chemo in secret,
unsupervised cancer clinics.
Only one patient,
she got scared,
thought she was
gonna die in treatment,
looked for a second
opinion, and...
well, you couldn't have that.
Wow. That nurse, Nic.
Clearly, you two
are sleeping together.
Oh, well, you couldn't have
me testifying on her behalf.
If the committee believed
me, you'd lose your scapegoat.
She must be amazing,
for you to take me on.
The doctor who turned
a PTSD army medic
into a competent diagnostician.
I graduated med school at 22.
I was a fellow at
Sloan Kettering
when you were still
cutting into frogs.
I was an attending physician at
Johns Hopkins by the age of 30.
I have three clinics
with my name on them.
And just recently, Emerson
asked me to head oncology,
which I politely declined,
because I'm kind of busy.
Has this been
more than a minute?
I believe it has.
You come at me like
that again, Dr. Hawkins,
and I'll have you selling
orthotics out of your car.
I will end you
without hesitation.
Didn't Dr. Pravesh discharge you
with a prescription
for omeprazole?
- It's an over-the-counter antacid.
- Mm-hmm.
Look, Dr. Feldman,
we've ruled out pleurisy,
IBS, melanoma, shingles
and leprosy, but we still...
we still haven't gotten to the
bottom of my general malaise.
Hypochondria with
a side of depression.
Cancer, okay?
Specifically, lymphoma.
Look, Olivia, there's
absolutely no reason
for you to believe that...
No, I-I don't want to be
the girl that has cancer
that the doctors don't
diagnose until she's stage IV.
I'm not leaving until
I see an oncologist.
Fine. Maybe if one of the
most respected oncologists
this side of the Mississippi
tells you you're cancer-free,
you'll believe her.
Here's a referral
to Dr. Lane Hunter.
Thank you.
The CEO will see you now.
Dr. Bell?
Where's Ms. Thorpe?
I've taken over the
position of CEO.
I see.
You've been with us a long time.
And you're held
in very high esteem
by your colleagues.
That's... why it's difficult
for me to tell you this.
♪ ♪
♪ Drag me through the dirt... ♪
I heard.
♪ Leave me for dead... ♪
Incredible things.
♪ I'll still be smiling ♪
♪ Like a madman in the rain ♪
This isn't over yet.
♪ And I would love you ♪
♪ Just the same ♪
♪ So do your worst to me ♪
♪ Test my loyalty ♪
♪ I will pass with distinction ♪
♪ Of first degree... ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH