There's this playground
game that kids play.
I'll get him. You
can't pick him up.
Yes, I can.
No, your incision
needs to heal. I got him.
They lock hands, and
on the count of three,
they try to snap each
other's fingers off.
Hurry up before
he wakes up the...
Mommy?
Girls.
You hold out as long as you can.
Or at least longer
than the other guy.
The game doesn't end
until someone says "stop,"
gives up, cries "mercy."
It isn't a fun game.
Move over.
What the hell?
I couldn't sleep all night.
I'm bored. Really bored. Nope.
Oh, don't kid yourself.
Call Hunt.
No.
Then try the Internet
like everybody else.
For porn? For dating.
Find somebody
else to get horny with.
I have a girlfriend.
Oh, she's passed
out with her friends.
Again.
Did she ever sleep with you?
Did you guys have
sex, and it was awful?
Was she awful? No.
Were you awful,
and now you're so ashamed
you can't even look at her?
No. Oh, was it weird?
Is she a man?
Ooh. Secret penis. Shut up!
Well, why don't you
guys ever sleep together?
We will!
Ohh.
You two haven't
done it yet. We do.
You do done it? We have.
Oh, you have? You do? We do.
Okay. We do!
Just get out! Okay. Hmm.
Okay. Let me just
think about that.
'Cause it's been, like, a week
and you haven't closed the deal.
What have you
done to evil spawn?
I was sleeping.
Oh, God! I knew
you'd cheer me up.
Mmm!
Would it kill her to bring me more
than one pair of Sofia's socks?
Frickin' thoughtless.
Where are Sofia and Zola?
Um, um, Derek's
putting their shoes on.
Ah.
Are you sure you can
handle the both of them?
Yes.
They're the only people who
don't piss me off right now.
I'll text you when
they're both in day care.
Hi! Ah! You're a goddess.
And yet my W-I-F-E
still sleeps around.
Okay, ladies!
Yes, here we go!
Here, take your
duck. Here we go!
Take your duck. We're
going on a ferry ride.
Thank you. Thank
you. Have a good day.
Oh. What are we gonna do when
she fixes her marriage and leaves us?
Oh, I think we're a
ways off from that. Oh.
Hey, I'm back. You still there?
Hi. How's everything going?
It's fine.
Uh, not the easiest
patient, but I got his number.
Hey, is he still losing weight?
His appetite's not great.
But that happens. You know that.
Right. And you're sure
you don't need my help?
Absolutely not. Go
snuggle your baby.
Okay.
Will you let me know if his
albumin drops below 2.5?
I'm hanging up. Stop calling me.
Richard Webber.
Seven days status post ex-lap
with pancreatic debridement.
His daily weights
are trending down.
Albumin's low at 2.
OT wants to do a swallow study.
In the meantime, I recommend
starting NG tube feeds.
No.
No tube.
He doesn't seem to want a tube.
Respectfully, Dr. Bailey...
Make sure to replete his
electrolytes, and he'll start recovering.
We've already given
him... Give him more.
Where the hell is Shane? He
was supposed to study with us.
Mmm, more practice for us.
Jo, hit me. Dude, pants!
Crap. Sorry. I'm
stuck on a question.
What's with the underwear?
Totally not work-appropriate.
I'm waiting for Alex
to make a move.
So I'm prepared all the
time. What about grooming?
All the time. That's exhausting.
Why don't you just
make the first move?
'Cause I'm not the slut who
just jumps into bed with someone
right after her
friend died. Really?
Well, I'm not
gonna advertise it.
Trauma in the pit. Gotta go.
It's been a week, and he hasn't
made a move. Is that weird?
Yeah.
Haircut?
Yes.
You can't just say "haircut."
You have to say "nice haircut."
Otherwise, I'll think that
you think it's a bad haircut.
And I'm wearing a
dress and I got a haircut
'cause I wanna look
nice today. Do I look nice?
You look tense.
Say I look nice! You look nice.
Was that so hard? Mmm.
Here we are.
Oh, my God.
Why are we here?
So you can see it for yourself
so this is not just a concept.
There is a hole in this
hospital, and it is leaking money.
But isn't that what
insurance is for?
They are swamped
with storm claims.
Now with this outpatient
surgery wing gone,
all of those patients are now
overloading our regular ORs.
Well, what do you
want us to do about it?
Meet. Make a plan. Be the board.
We're all swamped.
And Meredith and Derek
are on leave. Webber's down.
Yeah, and you and Torres
can't be in the same room.
I have a patient.
You know, right now
this hospital needs doctors more
than it needs board members.
What this hospital
needs is both.
If you people can't be both,
then we are in a lot of trouble.
Hey.
I should go. Why?
We can't be alone together.
We're just talking about work.
Nurses' station. Can I help you?
Ugh!
You all right?
Yeah.
Nurses' station. Please hold.
No. I... No. I
haven't heard yet.
About my boards.
Oh.
Yeah.
But don't freak out. You passed.
Well, if I didn't,
you'll know that the first
time wasn't your fault.
It was all me.
Don't freak out.
Hey. Hey. You're
riding with me today.
Yeah, about that.
Come on, it's a good one.
Coming through!
Oh, what do we got?
- Human pincushion.
- Kathleen Kane, 38.
Woman versus
shattered baseball bat.
Puncture wounds to the chest
and what looks like a
distal radius fracture.
BP 85 palp, pressure 135.
The batter was
jammed with a fastball,
and the bat, it just
exploded, you know?
My jersey's really messed up.
Don't worry about that, baby.
Okay, everybody.
Ready? On my count.
One, two, three.
I'm here. I'm right here, okay?
Somebody paged me?
Possible Colles' fracture.
Uh, sir, I need you to
wait outside, all right?
Right now, she needs
you to give us room to work.
We need another nurse in here!
You're gonna make sure
she's all right, right? Kat? Okay?
All right, I'm gonna show
you where you can wait.
Decreased breath
sounds on the right.
We need X-ray in here stat!
- Right away.
I'm dizzy. It's dark.
Am I dying? LEAH: No, ma'am.
Her systolic's down
to 78. Tell Dante.
You have to tell
Dante. Look at me.
If I die... You're not dying.
You need to tell my
husband. Promise me.
Of course. He needs to know.
And tell him...
I will. What is it?
I cheated on him
with his brother.
What?
What did she say?
Did you hear what she asked me?
People say crazy things
when they're in shock.
- CT ready for us?
- I'll check.
Hey, Kepner, did you
hear back yet, by the way?
No, not yet.
Mmm.
You think that's bad?
You think it's good?
So do I have to tell her
husband? Tell him what?
She grabbed me
with her bloody claw
and said if she dies to tell him
that she slept with his brother.
Whoa.
Bitch.
Why would she ask me to do that?
Maybe she wants
a clear conscience.
Maybe he cheated first
and trashed the marriage.
Maybe he's an inconsiderate
cheating bastard,
and she wanted
to get the last word.
So, I don't have
to tell him, right?
How about you
just don't let her die?
Okay, we can't wait for CT.
We gotta get her into the OR.
We'll put the
chest tube in there.
Uh, sorry.
Uh, just confirming I'll
see you tonight at 7:00?
Yeah, I don't think
that's a good idea.
Callie, we agreed
to couples' therapy.
Yeah, we agreed to
a lot of things. So...
Okay, well, I'll be there.
Murphy, make yourself useful
and put a splint on that arm.
He needs an NG tube, Dr. Grey.
I was hoping you could
call Dr. Bailey and...
Dr. Bailey is gonna
kill me if I call her again.
Richard is just being stubborn,
and Bailey doesn't
want to call him out.
Order the NG tube.
And that way, at
least it will be ready
by the time Bailey
comes to her senses.
But I'm not sure that
she... I have to go.
An hour and a
half to go get milk?
I think, um,
I might've closed my
eyes in the store parking lot.
I really should be studying.
Trust me. You are gonna
want to be in on this.
This is the best
part of the job.
Cara. Carlos.
Guys, this is Dr. Edwards.
She'll be assisting today.
And I have the simulation back.
Mmm, show me. Show me.
Okay, now first, we're
gonna be removing the scars
using tissue harvested
from your back and scalp.
And then I'm gonna
hide our new scars
right here in the facial planes.
And it's gonna look a
little something like this.
Oh, my God.
Really?
You can do that?
You can make me look like that?
Now it's an estimate,
but it is very, very close.
And it's free?
'Cause our insurance maxed
out about two surgeries ago.
We know. That's
why this one's on us.
Hey, Cara.
I didn't think I was gonna
get to go back to work.
She teaches kindergarten.
Yeah, she's afraid she's
gonna scare the kids.
And she can't teach without
feeling her best, right?
You guys!
Thank you so much.
You still want to study?
She has lost a lot of blood,
but she's stable for now.
We're gonna take her into
surgery and remove the fragments.
Okay. Okay, thanks.
Marcus, she's going
into surgery, man.
Is she gonna be all right?
Um... No, it's okay.
He's family. He's my brother.
She's, uh...
I'm
gonna
see you after.
Thanks, man.
In the 17 years since
your infant heart transplant,
your mitral valve
has started to fail.
So replacing it would
increase cardiac function.
And he won't need
another transplant.
- That is the hope.
- I gotta ask you again.
Are you sure that
you wanna do this?
There's a high risk
of tearing the ventricle,
bleeding, arrhythmias...
You're saying he'd need
a transplant anyway.
I'm saying that he could die.
The safest bet is to put Michael
on the list for a new heart.
No.
I understand the risks.
We talked about it.
We almost lost him
waiting for his last heart.
When it was clear he was dying,
I asked the nurse
if I could hold him.
He was so tiny.
I spent a whole night
looking in his eyes,
telling him I loved him,
accepting that I would
never, ever hear his first word.
I held my baby while he died.
And then the phone rang.
But I almost lost him.
And I cannot go
through that again.
The chance that there will be
another donor that matches me,
that I'll live long enough
for us to find that person,
that I'll even get to
the top of the list...
We like these odds better.
Okay.
Well, if your MRI is good,
we'll get started today.
That kid should be
on the UNOS list.
Well, you heard them,
Alex. They wanna take a shot.
And who are you to say
no to a high-risk surgery?
Let's just see
what his MRI says.
Funny thing. I didn't
order an NG tube.
Did you hear me order
an NG tube, Dr. Webber?
No. I...
So you can imagine our surprise
when a nurse brought one
in, along with a feeding pump.
Dr. Webber worried that I had
changed his course of treatment
without consulting him.
Dr. Bailey...
I told him I did not.
So then we got to thinking
about who, perhaps,
could have ordered these things,
and your name came up.
I was trying to be proactive.
In case repleting his
electrolytes doesn't work...
You wanna be proactive?
Get me some soup.
You heard the man.
Hey, what do you mean
"no pro bono surgeries"?
All funds are being reallocated
to storm repair
until further notice.
What? Who said that?
The board did, so, you.
All right, well, my lady's
facial reconstruction surgery
was booked way before the storm.
She teaches kindergarten.
Avery, I don't make the rules.
I just get to be
the bad cop here.
So then I'll just have the board
meet, and they're gonna approve it.
Well, that's gonna be tricky
since everyone on the board
has their own pro bonos
that they wanna do.
So when you all get
together, maybe come find me
and tell me how you plan to
fund repairing the outpatient OR,
so we're not
drowning in patients.
Come on. We're gonna get
to that when things slow down.
Things won't slow
down until we get to it.
Well, if you'd let me finish
my reconstruction surgery...
Avery, we do not have
the money for this surgery.
Listen to me. All due
respect, you said it yourself,
you don't make the rules. I do.
Now Cara McAdams, that pro
bono is not gonna be canceled.
I need you to be a
good cop, a traffic cop.
Uh, I'm sorry?
Move some patients around.
If we're overloaded, then
transfer them to Seattle Pres.
I don't care. But
make some room.
Yes, sir.
So I'm waiting on the kid's
MRI, and if it's too crappy,
I have to put him on the
transplant list and no surgery.
So what do you think?
I think he went to the store
and took a nap in the parking lot.
Where's my nap, Cristina?
I don't know. I
didn't steal your nap.
I'm sorry.
It's just my boobs hurt and
they're covered in lanolin
and I smell like an old couch.
Okay. Got eyes on Webber.
No NG tube.
Damn it, Shane.
I almost touched his arm today.
Webber's?
No. Owen's.
He's so stressed out about the
hospital, and I thought, you know,
I'd offer some support
and touch his arm.
But, you know, you touch
his arm and then you're in bed,
and then, nothing's changed.
Oh, crap. Hold on.
I got my valve kid's MRI.
Mer?
Oh, big help.
The shower works
better when you're in it.
Oh. He's hungry, and my
nipples are no use to him.
I know.
Did you see the look on her face
when you showed
her that picture?
I just... I wanna see
that look on her new face.
I'm glad Chief Hunt came around.
I made sure he got the message
that I am doing the surgery
whether he likes it or not.
Where is Mrs. McAdams?
She was moved out by Chief Hunt.
I don't think he
got the message.
Owen, why do you keep
rescheduling my surgeries?
Well, let's have a board
meeting, and I'll tell you.
Why can't you tell me right now?
Because I'm busy
rescheduling surgeries.
Why? ARIZONA: Owen?
What's this about a purchasing
freeze on the NICU budget?
Good. I have two of you here,
at least, so maybe we could...
Okay. Hey.
We're not buying the babies'
jewelry. We're buying them medicine.
Right now, we're low on NICU
blankets. That's baby blankets.
Don't tell me. Tell the board!
Hunt, where did my pro bono go?
Well, I took your
advice about transfers,
so I found someone at
Seattle Pres who could do it.
That is my patient.
Not anymore.
Your patient is, uh...
Let's see. A gluteal liposuction,
with two lipos after that.
You can't just fill my day
with... Of course, I can.
It's what a traffic cop does.
Gluteal lipo. So that's...
Sucking butt fat.
Is that part of the logo?
It's gotta be the
source of all this blood.
Nope. There's blood coming
from somewhere else superiorly.
We're gonna have
to extend this incision.
Scalpel? MAN: Scalpel.
So I don't have
to tell Dante, right?
I mean, I can just forget
that she said it. Murphy.
'Cause the brother's here now,
and it'll just ignite a family feud.
And maybe I heard her wrong.
What else sounds like brother?
Mother?
Oh, God. She's gonna live, okay?
No. I know.
It's just, there's a big bleeder
that we haven't found yet.
Murphy!
Are you gonna watch me eat?
No. Absolutely not.
Hey.
What are you doin'? Scavenging.
NICU's low on blankets.
What are you doin'?
I have a painful erection
that won't subside.
Oh, not me. Pfft. Uh, cards.
Huh. Oh. My
condition is priapism.
Major causes are sickle cell
and...
Crap. Leukemia.
I hope it goes away soon.
Mmm.
Hey, uh, you know,
you can kick my
friends out if you want to.
I mean, it's your house. They
shouldn't be there all the time.
No. Hey, uh, your
friend died a week ago.
You guys should
hang out or whatever.
Yeah.
Unless you're over it already.
No. I mean, I'm still
really sad, of course.
But, uh, um...
Look, I get it.
I mean, they can crash
however long they want.
You're being really
great about this.
Really, really great.
Ugh.
Your mitral valve replacement?
Yeah. A 17-year-old infant
heart transplant recipient.
Karev doesn't
think I should do it.
His EF's only
25%. Yeah, it sucks.
And there is a lot of
scarring to get through.
Karev is right.
This kid should go straight
on the transplant list.
It's risky,
but the parents want
it, and so does the kid.
Sounds like you're
gonna go ahead then.
Yeah.
Well, good luck.
Thanks.
What?
Normally, I'd kiss you.
I'd wish you luck
and then I'd kiss you.
Hey, you guys did
couples' therapy, right?
Was it good? Did it help?
I mean, obviously not,
right? Look at you guys.
Uh, no offense. Offense.
Well...
Torres.
What?
The only way? No, no, no.
No, you don't cut the clavicle!
No, don't do that without
me! Why would you do that?
Because the subclavian's
bleeding like stink,
and we can't get to
it. She's bleeding out!
And she's bleeding out.
Ugh.
Okay, everybody out. - What?
Everybody out. Get out now!
Now! WOMAN: Why? What?
Come on, get out! Come
on! Get out! Come on!
You do not cut a
clavicle yourselves!
No! No!
She says "no." I don't
think I have a choice.
She doesn't have... I can
hear her! Tell her I'm on my way!
She's on her way. Excuse me!
What do we do?
BP's dropping.
- Give me the saw.
- Here you go.
Oh, God.
What the hell did you just do?
What part of "don't cut the
clavicle" do you not understand?
I fixed it. Massive bleeder
just under the right...
You made a clean
cut down the middle.
Do you have any
idea how difficult it is
to repair bone with
this little surface area?
There was no way to do
the repair without visibility.
Mmm, no, there was no easy way.
And because you're
careless and thoughtless,
that seemed prohibitive to you.
You think you can just do
whatever you feel like in the moment,
and Ortho will just put everything
back the way it's supposed to be.
She was dying! Just go.
Let me clean up your mess.
Come on.
Promise me if it looks too
gnarly you'll just close him up.
Will you stop
wringing your hands?
God. No wonder
you can't have sex.
I can have sex.
Are the hydraulics not
working? I can write you a script.
Look, that's not...
She's just bummed
about her dead friend
and stressed about her exams.
Ugh, those are not valid.
All right. There's been
a lot of girls since Izzie.
A lot of nobodies. But
this girl is not a nobody.
She's... I don't know.
When I think about it,
it just seems important. Like...
Like it's gotta
be the right time.
You want it to be special.
What? Nothing. It's sweet.
Are you making fun of me?
I am not.
Can I ask you one thing?
When we're done here,
will you braid my hair?
Oh, boy.
Mmm.
Last chance to turn back.
Scissors.
Here you go.
Of course I pissed him off.
But transferring my patient to
some other hospital just to spite me?
Seems extreme.
Yeah, he can't do it. Yeah,
he can. He's your boss.
No. I'm his boss. Right?
The board is his boss.
That's a jacked up system.
The system is actually fine.
It's just in this particular
situation, it becomes...
Jacked up? Complicated.
You know what's not
complicated? This.
Unless I'm missing something,
you just suck the fat with that hose.
Well, pretty much.
Okay. And the next
lipo will be just like this?
Oh, it's gonna be a
different butt entirely.
Do you really need me here?
'Cause everyone else is studying.
You said something
about being with me all day.
Thought we were changing lives?
Yeah, but I also wanted to see
the look on our patient's face.
Get out of here. Thanks!
Is he asleep?
No. He hates sleep.
He's staring at the mobile.
Mmm.
I don't know how such a little
kid can puke on so many things.
I don't know.
Are you asleep? No.
Nobody's asleep. Are you asleep?
No, I'm too worried
about Richard to sleep.
He needs an NG tube, and
of course he doesn't want one.
And he's intimidating
Bailey into not ordering one.
But that's what he needs.
He made me his family,
and then I abandoned him.
It's just a mess over there.
Swallow study?
Okay, Ross, I can't
read this. Take this.
Ross. I know.
He's got a PAS score of six?
I know.
Okay, I'm a 60-year-old woman
with abdominal pain, a fever,
and significant discharge.
My initial diagnosis
is that you're gross.
You guys have gotta go.
No study hall at Alex's tonight.
But it's our spot.
We're study buddies.
No, you are a freaking
human chastity belt.
I know we've been
grieving, but it's been a week.
I am all grieved out.
Ooh, celibacy's made you mean.
Heather would understand.
She'd want me to get laid.
Pushing it, but okay.
Okay, look, this is my last
pair of clean, sexy underwear.
Then it's all granny
panties until laundry day.
It has to be tonight.
Oh, no, no, no!
What happened?
I think she stroked
out. Push high dose Epi.
I already pushed high dose Epi.
Did you try Vasopressin?
Kepner, she's been
down for 15 minutes.
What?
No.
Time of death, 16:17.
Oh, dear God.
I'm sorry. I tried.
So, um...
What do I tell the husband?
You tell him,
we did everything we could,
but despite our best efforts, we...
- Not that part.
The part about how
she slept with his brother.
He's about to hear that his
wife is dead. I think that's enough.
Hang on.
The woman trusted you, Murphy.
She wanted him to know the truth.
It's his last
memory of his wife.
Yeah, well, at least
it'll be an honest one.
He deserves to know.
And you made a promise.
You're gonna tell him, and
I'm gonna make sure you do.
What were you thinking?
Hey, what in God's name?
Ross showed me Richard's chart.
But you have
staples in your body!
I took them out. I'm a skilled
surgeon. You have no pain?
I have a lot of pain. It's
called sleep deprivation.
Richard is starving.
We have a plan.
"We have a plan?" Yeah.
He's a patient here. He
doesn't get to make decisions.
No. We do. We who are
here. We who have the plan.
So why don't you go back home...
I will once I know he's okay.
He's not okay.
And it isn't as simple as sticking
a feeding tube down his throat.
It is that simple.
We all know he can't
get well unless he eats,
and he can't eat
if he can't swallow.
You know as well as I do that
a feeding tube is
psychologically devastating.
It takes away a man's dignity.
So does dying.
I really wanna talk to the
radiologist about the swallow study.
Well, fine. Let's go. Okay.
What's in your hair?
Baby vomit.
Give me the damn stroller.
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
You have dysphagia
and laryngeal edema.
Even if you could eat on
your own, which you can't,
you're at risk for
aspirating your food.
You need an NG tube,
or you're gonna starve.
And I'm not gonna let
another one of us die.
You're an intern.
Don't talk to me like I don't
know what's happening.
You're pretending
like it isn't happening,
and Dr. Bailey's letting you.
Dr. Grey is here.
She came all this
way with a baby,
and there's no way
she's gonna leave
without forcing this
thing through your nose
and into your stomach.
And I think you don't want
her to be the one to do that.
I'm offering to take
care of this right now.
Just you and me.
Avery, I have one
more patient for you.
No, no, no. No more.
And I'm calling Cara
McAdams first thing
and I'm doing the
pro bono surgery,
and the board is gonna
discuss your behavior.
Avery, Avery, look.
She's all set for you
first thing tomorrow.
You said you transferred
her. Mmm-hmm. I lied.
You lied? Yeah,
I just moved her.
So that means you decided that
three liposuctions were more
important than this lady's facial...
No, but the three lipos will pay
for this lady's facial
reconstruction.
The money has to
come from somewhere.
So, yeah, I lied, and
now you have the money.
Avery, I needed to
make a point with you.
I know we're all doctors,
and we're all busy,
but until the board
members are willing to solve
the bigger budget problems
caused by the storm,
the doctors' problems
aren't going away.
So you need to do something now.
You are right. Yeah.
You all need to meet.
I can't force you to...
No, no. You can.
You're our boss,
and you can lie.
He's in V-tach, Yang.
You should stop.
They've all been short runs and
then they've all stopped. It's fine.
You gotta get over
this "special" thing.
Just throw her
over your shoulder,
take her to bed, and go to town.
Every girl's dream.
She's the thing that's
special, dumbass.
God, you have the
right person right there.
You both want the same thing.
Wait. Don't...
Don't go too deep.
Stop being scared.
This family is not scared.
This boy is not scared.
I am not doing this
because I want to.
I'm doing this because they
asked me to and because I can.
Well? What are you waiting for?
The arrhythmias
are coming closer.
If I keep pushing, I'll
send him into V-fib.
Even cannulating will destroy
the heart before I get to the valve.
You win. This kid
needs a new heart.
Let's get out of here.
I'm sorry.
So am I.
Dr. Ryan to Imaging.
You okay?
Just lost a patient,
and now I am waiting
for more bad news.
Still haven't heard?
You know, when
I failed last year,
I found out before I
got home that night.
It's been 48 hours, and nothing.
I think if you fail twice,
they just stop talking to you
and hope you get the hint.
I'm pretty sure that's
not how it works.
It's them. It's here.
Go ahead.
Uh...
Me? I'm... No. I don't...
Please? I can't.
What?
Just...
Congratulations.
Yes! Yes! Yes.
Yes!
Oh! Thank you, God! Thank you!
Like you said,
it's all you.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Your wife had a
stroke during surgery.
She had a coagulation disorder,
which is why the
clot formed so quickly.
We're so, so
sorry for your loss.
She was just here.
She was laughing on the
way here. She wanted me...
She wanted me to find
out who won the game.
There is one other
thing I need to tell you.
Before she went into surgery,
your wife wanted
me to tell you...
That she loves you.
She told us to tell
you that she loves you.
Thank you.
Nurses' station.
Shepherd?
Oh, have you seen
my wife and baby?
Wait. Meredith's here?
Meredith.
Crap. I meant to text you.
I woke up to nothing and nobody.
The woman's wearing mismatched
shoes. Cut her some slack.
I have to go check on Richard.
Send me a note next time.
You look like hell.
You know you're in
a building full of beds.
I just need to go lie down.
Yeah.
Ross, what did you do?
You were supposed
to wait until...
He was overdue for the tube,
and nobody seemed to wanna do it.
He was starving to
death right in front of us,
so I did what had to be done.
There was so much scar tissue.
I'm afraid I couldn't get
to the valve to repair it.
Michael has to go
on the transplant list.
The transplant coordinator will
be in to ask you some questions.
Oh, God.
Look, the transplant list
is not a death sentence.
It's a chance. It's hope
that most people never get.
When Michael wakes up, he
needs to hear that from you.
I know it's not what you wanted,
but now we have to move forward.
Michael needs the hope that there
is a donor out there somewhere,
or he won't survive.
You're up?
Barely. I got paged. Me, too.
Well, who would page us? We're
not even supposed to be here.
I was having the nicest dream.
Wait. You guys got a page?
God, what happened to the guy?
Apparently everything.
Hey, you were paged, too?
Why outpatient surgery?
Well, it's a disaster area.
Maybe someone got hurt.
I don't know.
It worked.
I cannot believe
that that worked.
Uh, okay. Where's the trauma?
There's no trauma. This
is a meeting of the board.
There's no trauma?
A meeting about what?
We're gonna have a party.
Is this a trauma, a
meeting or a party?
I'm so confused. I'm so tired.
We're gonna have a party,
folks. A big one. Gala fund-raiser.
We're gonna invite the
richest people that we know,
and we are gonna charm
the money out of them.
But first, Dr. Hunt
is gonna tell us
exactly how much money we
need and where it needs to go,
starting with what
used to be this room.
So, let's settle in. This
is gonna take a while.
We have the house to ourselves.
But I want you to know that
just because I'm about
to jump into bed with you
does not mean
I'm an unfeeling slut
who isn't sad about
Heather, because I am sad.
I'm also very, very...
No more talking.
What? Oh!
Yes! Oh, thank God!
Eventually, I'm
gonna touch your arm,
and you are going to kiss
me good luck before surgery.
Cristina.
Let's date other people.
Okay, it'll suck and it'll feel
forced, but maybe it'll help.
Maybe eventually I won't
want to take your hand
when we get off the
elevator at the end of the day.
No, come on. Don't.
Just tell me you'll try.
I'll try.
Okay.
Oh! Thank God. You came.
I've been wishing
you hadn't told me,
and that we could
go back to our life,
to being happy.
Except we weren't happy.
At least you weren't.
And so we do things like
have sex with other people.
Callie, I made a mistake.
One mistake... Yeah, I
don't think it was a mistake.
I've been picturing you
screwing that woman
over and over
again. And I can't...
Think about her or
talk about her anymore.
I'm all done with
that for right now.
So I'm not going into that room.
But I think you should.
I think you need to.
In the game of mercy,
when one kid cries out...
No.
The other one listens,
and the pain stops.
Please.
I really need to talk.
I really need you to do this.
I know.
You wore the red
dress and everything.
Don't you wish it
was that easy now?
I'm sorry. I know I
haven't been here.
You picked me as your family...
Stop it. Stop it.
I didn't call you my family.
I'm not your father.
I chose you because I thought
you could put emotion aside,
and make the right call.
I knew Bailey was too weak.
But you,
I thought I could trust
not to let them operate
on me when I was all but...
When I was all but dead.
Not to bring me back to
life,
where I have to get my
meals from a...
From a tube.
I thought you wouldn't
be sentimental.
I was wrong.
I chose the wrong person.
It's not a game anymore,
and we're not kids.
You can cry
"mercy" all you want,
but nobody's listening.
It's just you
screaming into a void.