We just arrived.
Yeah. Kids okay on your end?
Good.
Yeah, yeah. He's very excited.
Hey, hey. Listen, I gotta go,
okay? I'll call you tomorrow.
Excuse me.
Get away. Get away.
Sorry about that. Sorry.
What's wrong with him?
Excuse us.
I ought to go back and
kick the hell out of that guy.
She was old enough, she
didn't have to scream like that.
It's okay, Dad. It
didn't bother me.
For the first time, none
of these people bother me.
I just think, "36 more hours."
Thirty-six more hours? How
do you figure that, Kenny?
Tomorrow at this time,
I'm scheduled for surgery.
It's a 10-hour procedure,
throw two in there for prep,
thirty-six until I'm just
another face in the crowd.
Kenny has a frontonasal
encephalocele. It's a midline deformity.
He's here to undergo
a facial bipartition.
And what does that mean?
Well, we have five
surgeons, four nurses.
He's going to require
six units of blood.
Will it fix him?
It'll repair a lot of
the damage done...
We need a sound byte.
Would you say, "He'll be
ready for the junior prom"?
Yeah, yeah. That's
probably true.
No, I mean, I
need you to say it.
Dr. Chase,
we got an issue.
Heart rate's skyrocketing,
he's over 180.
He's in v-fib. Paddles!
Charge to 300.
Turn that camera off.
Is this a reaction
to anesthesia?
Haven't given it yet.
Clear!
Crank it to 360.
I said turn that damn
camera off! Clear!
A teenage boy with a cranial
facial deformity was about to undergo
a reconstructive procedure, when
he had an unexplained cardiac arrest.
Good.
Good?
I mean, go on.
We have the patient
on a pacing wire,
it's the only thing
keeping his heart going.
Yeah, we know. We're doctors.
Right, it was meant
to be just for them.
Just be yourself.
Until we are able to figure out
exactly what is causing the heart block,
the reconstructive surgery
is on hold, obviously.
That's "yourself"?
Fascinating case.
I will see you again
after I have saved his life.
Have a warm bath waiting.
Are you following me?
Darnell will be trailing
you throughout the case.
Pretend we're not here.
But if I do that, won't
I bump into you?
We'll stay out of your way.
No, it was a joke.
See, I became a doctor because
of the movie, Patch Adams.
Listen, do you wanna get
ahead of me and maybe back up,
I don't know, low down,
so I look more powerful?
That's perfect. Yeah?
Also, my eyes look better
in rooms with summer colors.
You know what?
It's black and white...
You think I like the cameras?
You think I want the whole world
watching you check out my ass
and question my wardrobe?
Would it be better if I checked out
your wardrobe and questioned your ass?
A little part of me...
There is no little part of you.
Thought that maybe you would see
what great PR this
could be for the hospital
and not make me force
you to act like a human being.
You using force
on me is intriguing.
On the other hand,
cameras make people act.
Sometimes like human
beings, sometimes just weird,
sometimes they
wear open-tip bras.
It's cold in here.
A less obvious point is that I need my team
to be unafraid of the metaphorical fart.
That production company is covering
all the medical costs for this kid.
So either you let
them continue filming
or the kid goes home
with the same face.
Sorry about that. Private.
She waxes her
moustache once a month
and sometimes gets some
pretty gnarly ingrown hairs.
So, did he hire you flat out or are
you competing for one of the spots?
I'm not sure what
you mean by that.
She's not competing.
She was handpicked by
House. She's safe, like Foreman.
So that takes three
spots down to one.
Where's Foreman?
- He's in the bathroom.
- Good.
Come on. Let's go for a walk.
Walks look good on camera.
They give the illusion of
the story moving forward.
New patient.
Sixteen-year-old boy with
second-degree infranodal heart block.
Post-arrest.
Any reports of
light-headedness or syncope?
Certainly not light-headedness.
Why did you hire her?
Not in front of the company.
Are we gonna be on TV?
I'm making a music video.
Come on. A little
faster, more energy.
Why are you glad
Foreman's not here?
Because he would object
to what I'm about to do.
Oh!
Sorry.
Hey, buddy.
You stay in there, we'll be out here,
making sure he doesn't move again.
God! Finally I
hear myself think.
Our patient has...
Why did you hire her?
Because she has way
more diagnostic experience
than the other swimsuit
models I was considering.
Our patient has a frontonasal
encephalocele with a midline cleft.
Don't stare directly at it.
So what caused "Big
Head's" heart to stop?
Simple. His big head.
Increased intacranial pressure
would cause heart block.
Wrong. Sixteen years they've been
testing that insane noggin to death.
What about a
congenital heart defect?
He has a midline
anomaly on his head,
makes sense he'd have a
midline anomaly in his heart, too.
The 16 years of
testing didn't show?
Why did you bring her
in so late? It's not fair.
The rest of us... Hey,
hey, hey! You wanted fair,
you picked the wrong
job, the wrong profession,
the wrong species.
Forget the deformity.
Treat the patient like he's
any other really, really ugly kid.
Infection? Could
be endocarditis.
Well, since he doesn't
have a prosthetic heart valve,
I assume you're thinking
he's an IV drug user?
House said assume he's normal.
Dealers don't ask for ID and
don't care what you look like.
Nice. You're right
about the habit.
You're wrong
about the substance.
Blackened skin under the nose
equals frostbite from huffing Freon.
Freon's toxic, it
damages the heart.
Discoloration could
be acanthosis nigricans.
It's a common side
effect of these deformities.
There's also discoloration
on the cheeks and forehead.
Do a nuclear study.
If I'm right, you'll see
scarring of the heart.
I'm not part of some game, am I?
I gave up a career because I
thought this was a firm offer.
Yes, this is a real offer.
I think she might be an idiot.
Who?
No, she can't be an idiot.
I mean, she was in
the CIA, for God's sake.
And the Bay of Pigs
was a daring triumph.
She had good ideas in Langley.
All your ideas.
She was able to identify
that they were good ideas.
Stab in the dark
here, is she pretty?
She's new.
She's nervous. She's a C-cup.
She said one dumb
thing in a differential.
They all say dumb
things in differentials.
A D-cup?
If she's no good, just fire her.
I can't. I just hired her.
She left a career.
Wow.
Either that's actual guilt, or I
have got to see this woman.
My son is not huffing Freon.
Mr. Arnold, Dr. House is like a
savant when it comes to diagnostics.
What's his genius theory?
Because Kenny's not normal, he's
doing drugs to deal with his pain?
Maybe the way to look at
this is that you are normal.
And what's that
supposed to mean?
You're like any other parent who
thinks his kid can't be doing drugs.
Doing this because my
dad thinks I'm on drugs?
I was doing drugs behind
my parent's back at your age,
and I had a lot
less reason to be.
Not that your life
must be miserable.
Not that I'm suggesting that
you should be doing drugs.
How's school going?
I'm home schooled.
Really? You're lucky.
Going to school was boring.
My dad took me out, and it
wasn't because it was boring.
I had a rough
time in school, too.
Maybe not like you, but, you know... I
don't mean to compare our situations.
Actually, I guess I am
comparing our situations,
but only to show you
how yours is worse.
You can edit that out, right,
so I don't look like an idiot?
Relax. Everyone acts
like an idiot around me.
Makes you think it's not an act.
Can I have something
for my headache?
Yeah, is that new?
Sixteen years old.
Has the same birthday I do.
I'm gonna start the test now.
Study showed no signs of
scarring on Kenny's heart.
It wasn't drugs.
Well, then, give me
something better.
What's causing heart block?
It could be toxoplasmosis.
We should do an LP
to test for infection.
If it was toxoplasmosis, we'd
have seen enlarged lymphs,
and because you're not pretty enough
to be an idiot, you must know that already,
which means you just said it
because you want to do an LP
to look for
intracranial pressure.
Because it is
Wait, I'm not done.
You thought I wouldn't catch on,
which means you either think
I'm an idiot, which is flattering,
I've been doing
my hair differently...
The kid's got headaches. He's been
popping acetaminophen like peanuts.
How could you possibly
think that I was done?
I prefaced that with an
"either." It needs an "or."
Or, you are an idiot,
which is possible, I'm not
great at judging men's looks.
The OR?
And the MRI room.
Yes...
Dr. House frequently conducts differential
diagnoses in a variety of places.
He feels that a change in venue
often leads to a change
in thinking processes.
I have to go take
care of something else.
Just let me do a CT
scan, see if I'm right.
The sooner we fix the problem,
the sooner we can get to
his reconstructive surgery.
Yeah. Who cares if you're
dead? It's how you look.
Well, since you've given me
nothing better, we're back to drugs.
The one thing we know it's not.
Decreased uptake on
the membranous septum.
Could be an artifact.
We can redo it, but...
Nothing's nothing.
Do an EP study.
EP study means we have
to stop this kid's heart.
I'll set it up.
House, do you have a
minute to be disemboweled?
I'm gonna thread this catheter
through different areas in your heart,
and once I've found the right pathway,
I'll apply some electrical energy.
It'll stop my heart?
It sounds worse than
it is. You'll be fine.
Is it gonna hurt?
There'll be some discomfort.
If you've done
drugs, I understand.
Being different's really hard.
Kenny, it's more important
for you to get better
than to worry about
getting in trouble.
If I did drugs, that could
explain my heart problem?
It could.
And then you could do
the surgery to fix my face?
That's why we're here.
You know how famous people,
everywhere they go people
are watching them, staring?
They never have
a chance to just be,
you know? And a lot
of them turn to drugs.
And people stare at them because they're
beautiful, but, me they just stare...
You okay?
I need to know what kind of
drugs, Kenny, and how much.
Coke, mostly. A lot of coke.
And then when I run out, I
usually go to LSD or acid.
Those are the same thing.
They are?
You don't do drugs, do you?
I drank from my dad's
liquor cabinet one time...
We're not gonna
do this test. No...
I need you to turn on your side.
We need to intubate. I
need some help in here!
Too bad you guys are
going for a theatrical release.
Vomiting blood would
have made a great act-out.
Likely causes?
Mallory-Weiss tear.
No pallor, no melena.
Why are you wearing a tie?
I always wear
ties, I'm a doctor.
Please don't look at the camera.
Sorry.
Nasal papilloma.
Hemorrhage could have
overwhelmed the heart.
Nice lipstick.
Thank you.
Bad idea.
The hemorrhage
came after the block.
House, let them do their job.
Is anybody here more
interested in the medicine,
a little less interested
in the paparazzi?
Upper GI bleed.
Could be something he ate
or drank. Maybe a peptic ulcer.
Good.
Except no abdominal pain,
patient hasn't lost his appetite
and the last I checked,
the gastrointestinal
tract isn't connected
to the heart.
Yeah, but other
than that, real good.
Nasopharyngeal angiofibrosis.
I just said it wasn't
a nasal tumor.
Stomach cancer.
Tumor causes bleeding,
body's reaction to the tumor
causes paraneoplastic syndrome,
which leads to heart block.
Finally, someone who
is not just a pretty face.
You and Taub, run the
scope, find the tumor.
Could be dangerous. If the
bleeding was caused by liver failure
as a result of the
intracranial pressure...
Liver is the one organ you can't
ascribe to intracranial pressure.
True.
Intracranial pressure
can cause liver problems.
It causes an increase in the cavernous
sinus pressure, which causes pressure
in the superior vena cava,
which shuts down the liver.
Did you just think of that? No.
Then why didn't
you say anything in...
Think it would've changed
his mind? Not a chance.
House would have undercut me,
and forced me to do a
procedure I just argued against,
and then I'd look like a hypocrite
in front of the thousands of people
and potential future
employers watching this film.
If you're right, and we stick a scope
back down a kid with liver failure,
he could bleed again.
I know.
He just vomited blood.
Isn't that dangerous?
No. You're in good hands.
Okay. All right.
Well, it's great how he
rebounded from that setback.
What setback?
He didn't tell you about the...
Well, that's his right.
The records were sealed.
Personally, I think he
was just tapping his foot
and reaching for
the toilet paper.
Obviously it was a witch hunt.
You think they singled
him out because...
No. Literally, a witch hunt.
Dr. House is a practicing Wiccan.
It's a beautiful
religion, it's very caring.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
You have an all-access pass to
the case, not my Fave 5s. Now, go.
Come on! Come on! Let's go!
I think I'm going blind.
Hairy palms, too?
She said something idiotic
again and I didn't even notice it.
Foreman had to point
out that it was idiotic.
She's making me an idiot.
It's cute. You have a crush.
No, I think it's
something systemic.
Thirteen's pretty.
You're obviously okay with her.
She killed a patient.
The bitch is pretty.
The bitch is a bitch.
Ask her out.
The bitch? She's a bitch.
No, the one that's
making you an idiot.
It's the story of life. Boy
meets girl. Boy gets stupid.
Boy and girl live
stupidly ever after.
Pretty girl kill again? No.
Elephant boy just
vomiting up blood again.
No tumors in the
patient's stomach, so...
But the scope caused
variceal bleeding.
Took 20 minutes
of banding to stop it.
Taub was right
about the liver failure.
Yeah.
His craniofacial deformity is
causing intracranial pressure...
No. Which is causing...
Where are the nosebleeds?
Where's the labored breathing?
You were right about
me being wrong.
You were wrong
about you being right.
I need new ideas. Anybody?
Does it bother you
that this kid's gonna die
because you won't put down
that camera at all? You know?
Your people should
be extra motivated.
I'm sure they all wanna
look good in the film.
No, 'cause now they're too
worried about looking bad.
Dr. House, heart block plus liver
failure could mean autoimmune.
Maybe scleroderma.
Foreman? Does that make sense?
Not without tight
skin on the hands,
muscle weakness and
a 30-year-old patient.
Liver failure plus heart block
could be a mitochondrial disorder.
Hey, say what she just said.
Liver failure plus heart block
could be a mitochondrial disorder?
Go look for signs of
retinal degeneration.
No, it's ICP. You're
only gonna see swelling.
Take him with you, so he
can see the degeneration, too.
So before you worked here in the
ER, you worked for House, right?
Three and a half years.
Why did you leave?
Hey. I don't wanna be on TV.
I'm not signing a release.
We'll blur you out.
Take off your pants.
You gonna be able to use
any of this if I start swearing?
Did House treat you as badly
as he treats his current fellows?
Loaded question.
That's not even a word.
Fork!
Very clever.
I learnt how to be a
doctor from House.
Or at least a doctor who learnt
how to be a doctor from House,
if that makes any sense.
And you left his team because
you couldn't stand him anymore?
No, no. I love Dr. House.
Now, that's something
we haven't heard.
I mean...
What did you ask me again?
Why you left.
I loved being around him,
professionally.
You know, he was
always stimulating.
Not in an erotic
sense of the word.
Fork. They forked,
and then they spooned!
Lean forward, and place
your chin on the rest.
I can't reach it.
Skooch in a little.
I'll take care of it.
Just like last time?
Maybe we should try
this the old-fashioned way.
Okay, look up to the ceiling
and try not to blink, okay?
Okay, good. Now straight ahead.
There it is. Swelling,
no degeneration.
It's not mitochondrial.
Swelling proves there's
increased pressure in his brain.
Absolutely.
So, now we can schedule
the reconstruction?
Absolutely not.
Your test proved you wrong.
We found exactly what
I predicted we'd find.
Swelling means there's
increased pressure.
You get a gold Star
of David for proving,
yes, this kid has a big head
and big heads cause pressure.
Doesn't explain the liver.
Too much acetaminophen does.
JRA explains all of
it, including the liver.
One theory's better than
two. Treat with steroids.
If you're wrong, steroids are
gonna mess with his immune system,
put off his surgery for months.
You really wanna lose this
argument in front of the camera?
I'll speak to the father.
Dr. House believes
that Kenny has JRA.
Juvenile rheumatoid arthritis.
We need to start
administering steroids.
Will the steroids fix it?
I don't think he has JRA.
I think Dr. House is wrong,
and that the steroid
treatment could be dangerous.
I think I can get House
thrown off the case,
and get Kenny the
facial surgery he needs.
The father refused steroids until
we're sure about the diagnosis.
I am sure.
It's JRA.
And why would
he even doubt that,
unless a former fellow of
mine was chirping in his ear?
The decision was his. I
merely voiced my concern.
Why did you take this job?
He's got a bulging cyst.
Perfectly good plastic
surgery practice, lots of money.
Fluids aren't draining properly.
Temptation to come screw
with me just too much for you?
There's gotta be
a better reason.
He needs surgery to drain it.
Oh, and I think I mentioned
this earlier. You're fired.
What you did was
over the line. Get out.
But don't go anywhere.
You're not fired, yet.
No one is firing anyone
in the middle of this case.
Not while those
cameras are here,
and not while Taub is the only
person that this father trusts.
Where are you going?
To do what I always
do in these situations.
Treat my patient
behind his back.
That's one option.
Or you can do a CT
scan of the kid's head.
If there's no midline shift,
we know Taub's wrong
and you get your consent
to give the kid steroids.
Just a warning.
If we have to start getting consent
every time we do a procedure,
soon they'll be asking
for informed consent.
Didn't think you had
the guts to stage a coup.
Coup failed. I'm scheduled
for execution at dawn.
No, you're not.
No reprieve from the governor.
You're a test result away from
becoming House's front runner.
He doesn't care about what you
said, or what you did five minutes ago.
He just wants the
next good idea.
Show me 20 percent
magnification of the forebrain.
I look at our patient, as soon as I
saw his face, I saw a regular kid.
One thing about being a plastic
surgeon, you don't see what is,
you see what could be.
Talk like that around House, doesn't matter
how many good ideas you come up with.
So,
tell me what you don't
like about yourself.
Gosh.
There's so many things.
Is Dr. Taub available? Because
he was very highly recommended.
Well, he's no longer
practicing with us,
but I've taken
over all his files,
so if you tell me
what needs work...
Do you know why he left?
He had personal issues to
deal with, so if we could just...
My goodness. Is he okay?
Oh, yeah, he's fine. He's fine.
Because my friend had
his ears done by Dr. Taub.
Should he worry that
they may pop back?
No, it wasn't a
professional issue.
I'm sorry, I really can't
go into more detail.
Shall we discuss your needs?
You know that toe next to the big
toe? Mine's bigger than my big toe.
Is there any way to shorten
it? Or make my big toe bigger?
Like, a toe-gmentation?
Did he lie, cheat or steal?
You're not here for a
consultation, are you?
What gave me away?
Was it my obviously
perfect feet?
Hi.
CT shows that...
Let's go.
What are you two doing here?
Skipping three scenes.
CT's back. He's gonna say that
there's evidence of an anomaly,
I'm gonna say, he's wrong.
He's gonna go back to the
father and we'll all end up here.
The defect is pushing
on the right frontal lobe.
This bend is a
sign of herniation.
Or, it's a sign of increased
pressure from JRA.
Dr. Taub would rather
distract you from the truth
with sparkly things,
like four karat diamonds.
House.
Your partner said that you
left for personal reasons,
but your wife said
you lost a patient.
You son of a bitch,
you spoke to my wife?
See, that confused me.
Why would you give her a diamond
if you screwed
somebody else over?
If you screwed her
over, I mean, I could...
Get that camera out of here!
You say anything to her?
Just asked questions.
Get them out of here, too.
We're doctors.
I screwed around with a
nurse. It became a deal.
My partners found
out and I resigned.
There. Happy?
If you could be a bit more
descriptive, I'd be happier.
Some people pop pain pills,
I cheat.
We all have our vices.
Taub, I don't see it.
Stay away from the family.
House, start steroids and
stay away from his family.
Wow, you are ugly.
Wow, you're an ass.
I have a deformity.
I know, that's why you're ugly.
But you're a lucky boy.
Anywhere else in
the animal kingdom,
your parents would
have eaten you at birth.
Your son needs steroids.
Dr. Cuddy agrees.
Does Dr. Taub?
He's not a real doctor.
He's a plastic surgeon.
All he cares is that your
son looks good in his coffin.
So, I'm supposed to believe you?
The doctor who cares.
You shouldn't care if I care.
I don't trust you.
Because I don't think
the surgery's important?
You're putting your trust in someone
who does think the surgery's important.
You're willing to take chances to risk
his life for something he doesn't need?
I do need it.
I can't have real relationships.
I can't even have
a real conversation.
Not even with my dad.
Dad.
I know you love me.
But you don't treat me normal.
You're always protective.
The world can always go to hell.
But you never yell at me.
Even when I screw up.
I wanna be normal.
Take your steroids,
and you get to live.
Then you can do your surgery.
But it'll only change your face.
It won't change who
your face made you.
We're gonna get caught.
Not on film.
All their camera
equipment's in here.
Where did you get those keys?
Blue, the janitor.
What?
That's his name.
His name's Lou.
Owe him an apology.
Just watch 20
minutes of this stuff,
tell me if I'm out of my mind.
Finally, we have video evidence.
Dr. House, heart block plus liver
failure could mean autoimmune.
Maybe scleroderma.
Foreman? Does that make sense?
Not without tight
skin on the hands,
muscle weakness and
a 30-year-old patient.
Can I see that again?
What did you miss?
She screwed up, I didn't...
No, just the part where
she leans forward.
I think you can see
through her dress.
Upper GI bleed.
Could be something he ate
or drank. Maybe a peptic ulcer.
Good.
You thought that
was a good idea?
What am I gonna do?
Just enjoy.
I'm gonna keep her around,
because she makes me an idiot?
Well, you're protected,
Foreman seems immune.
You think he's gay?
Did he become an
idiot around Chase?
I just said it's not a nasal...
Wait a minute, rewind
that. Was that Thirteen?
Wow.
I can't believe I'm that guy.
Every guy is that guy.
I'm not every guy.
What is this? Semantics here?
Okay, all guys are that guy.
I'm not all guys!
Cameron was smart.
You know, I'm
beginning to doubt that.
I wanted to clarify
something I said earlier.
"I love Dr. House,"
and then I qualified it,
which, after thinking about it,
I didn't really need to do.
I did love being around him.
I guess, I just
wanted to qualify
what I qualified before.
I'm looking defensive, aren't I?
No, no. I think that's great.
Clears everything up.
It's no big deal, really...
There's a mass lesion in the left anterior
temporal lobe surrounded by oedema.
Did you just insult
me in Pig Latin?
Dr. House, please.
Will you just take
a look at this?
The defect is causing this
nodular shadow here, you see it?
You're right, I didn't
see that before.
Come on, let's go.
Hey.
I know you think you're feeling
better, on account of feeling better,
but this trusted family doctor
thinks that he's found a mass lesion,
so if you could lie back
down and struggle to breathe...
Okay.
You were right.
I'm thrilled I'm wrong.
This is great, Kenny.
You're gonna get
your surgery now.
First person I'm coming
back to see is you,
because compared to me,
you're gonna look like butt.
Hey!
What, no comeback?
Look at that.
What?
His little finger,
it's twitching.
No, it's not.
Just give it a second.
There. TAUB: And?
He's not better.
What's wrong?
My diagnosis.
I don't know what he has.
Cancel the surgery.
New symptom. Involuntary
muscle movement.
Twitching finger is a symptom?
The body doing something
it's not supposed to do
is the definition of a symptom.
Kid's about to have a life-changing
operation. He's nervous.
Or he's not.
Or you were right.
Kid got better when
we put him on steroids.
This is JRA and it's
under control now.
Or the steroids have just
tempered his condition.
He got a haircut, but
he's still got bad hair.
What about Lyme disease?
It explains everything, the heart
issues, the internal bleeding,
even why he'd get
better on steroids.
On the other hand, if
he has Lyme disease,
there'd be other subtle clues
like a huge target-shaped rash.
But thanks for playing.
Why can't you just accept
the fact that you cured this kid?
You want to stop his surgery!
You're not normal.
So you don't want
anyone else to be normal.
You don't think
normal's healthy.
Could be rheumatic fever.
Also explains why
the steroids helped.
It's a similar
inflammatory disease.
Rheumatic fever doesn't
explain liver failure.
Taub thinks that
acetaminophen does.
Fine. Let's test your theory.
Remove his pacing wire.
If he's better, his heart
will be just fine on its own
and then he can
have his operation.
If I'm right, his
heart will stop.
Kutner, have the
paddles on standby.
Another chance to
blow someone up.
There'll be some
minor discomfort
and you'll feel a slow,
steady pulling sensation.
Are you sure his
heart is ready for this?
Absolutely.
He's convinced he's sure.
Whereas I care about your son,
and have therefore brought
a professional defibrillist.
We're not gonna need those.
Dad, I feel fine, and my
finger hasn't moved in a while.
Okay. Take him off.
Here we go.
Heart rates 85 beats per
minute. BP 110 over 70.
Is he okay?
I feel the same.
He's fine. You're fine.
Thank God!
What do you mean, thank God?
God's the guy
who gave it to him.
Thank you. Thank you.
Can you tell us
about the procedure?
We have to use both an
extra and intracranial approach
to get enough exposure to
reduce the encephalocele cyst
and do the bony reconstruction.
And how are you
participating in this procedure?
She's not.
They don't want me here because
they think the kid's cured. I don't.
And what do you
think the problem is?
I wish I knew.
I just know that if Dr. House is
right, something's gonna go wrong.
Dr. House doesn't
think he's right.
Well, then I'll just waste a
few hours watching a surgery.
See, the danger is,
we have to reconstruct
all the way down
to the cranial base,
and there are some
big vessels down there.
So, what we'll do is we'll
work our way down to here...
When were these pictures taken?
Well, about three weeks
ago. Why? What do you see?
Well, the acanthosis
nigricans was already there.
It's been there a lot longer
than that, probably his whole life.
What about around his hairline?
What? There's no discoloration.
There is now.
I have a new theory.
Their bad ideas don't
indicate a lack of intelligence,
they indicate an open mind.
The willingness not to be
trapped by conventional...
You've got a problem.
Tell me something I don't know.
You hire beautiful girls, enslave
them, force them to be around you
because you don't know how
to have an actual relationship.
If they're qualified, keep them. If
not, fire them and ask them out.
You do realize that, "Tell me something
I don't know" is just an expression?
Thirteen... You think
that just because
she is as beautiful, ergo, you think that
because she hasn't had a decent idea...
No. My point is she's about to enter
your office, so you should shut up.
You were right
about the diagnosis.
Yes, it was JRA. I'm very proud.
No, I mean you were right about
being wrong. He's got Lyme disease.
It explains everything.
Could you just hold up some fingers
so I can see if I'm literally blind?
We ruled out Lyme
disease hours ago.
All the symptoms fit.
I am so ashamed.
Is she really that good looking?
Apparently.
How many lives have been
lost because of pretty girls?
The target rash is hiding.
No one ever looked
at him closely enough.
She's getting
uglier by the second.
We can try and
pretend we're above it
and we can try and
intellectualize it away,
but ultimately, shiny,
pretty, perky things are good
and ugly, misshapen,
teenage boys are repulsive.
The question was, do you resent
Dr. Cuddy's interference in your practice?
Oh.
Well, then I guess my answer
wasn't very helpful, was it?
"Mini-stud", stand up.
I spoke to your other partner.
After Cuddy told you...
No, I stayed away.
Did it all over the phone.
I asked for a reference. Said you
were applying for a plastic surgery job.
Oh, God!
Yeah.
He went nuts. Apparently
you signed a non-compete.
Now, why would
you agree to that?
I don't wanna
practice plastic surgery.
You sign a contract because
someone's making you.
Someone's getting
something from you.
What did they
give you in return?
They agreed to keep
their mouths shut.
So you gave up your chosen
career just so they'd be quiet?
I love my wife.
You risked this job with
nothing to fall back on.
I thought you were wrong.
Sit back down.
You're keeping him
because he's a philanderer?
Where do I sign up?
Ask the Mormon. I'm keeping
him because he's interesting.
Dr. Terzi, would
you please stand up?
Nice.
I have treated you unfairly.
Pre-judged you.
And for me to be
a better person,
I have to rectify
that situation.
You're fired.
You wanna grab some dinner?
Maybe a movie?
Seriously.
Just days ago, with
Kenny's condition worsening.
It was Dr. Gregory House
reassuring Kenny and his father.
I care about your son.
The charming House, who
happens to be a film buff
with a soft spot in his heart for
children told us how he got his start.
See, I became a doctor because
of the movie, Patch Adams.
Determined to save
the boy's life, as well as...
The horror.
Well, it's nice of them
to send us an early copy.
Not so much sent as stolen.
It was Dr. Gregory House
who served as not only a doctor,
but a rock for
Kenny and his father.
You're putting your trust in someone
who does think the surgery's important.
House, one of
those rare doctors...
God!
Who wears his
heart on his sleeve.
I was saying that was
a stupid thing to do!
It's difficult not to be moved.
Oh, stop it.
Suddenly, I don't feel I can
trust Michael Moore movies.
Where are you going?
Kittens to get out of
trees? Deaf kids to read to?
I owe it to the world to make sure
this evil never sees the light of day.
Is there anything else?
Thank you, Dr. House.
Thank you.