Duroziez's sign is a murmur when the
stethoscope is over the femoral artery.
- What's another sign? No.
- Weak pulse.
- Poor cap refill?
- No.
Those are both signs of
shock. It begins with Q. Anyone?
- De Quervain's?
- No. That begins with a D.
However, there is a Q in
it, so you're getting warmer.
Does Quincke's
sign ring any bells?
And it manifests itself how?
With a visible...
P...
- Pulsation.
- Correct. Where?
On the n...
- Neck.
- Navel?
Nail bed.
Good night. Go home.
Rounds start at 7 a.m.
Be sure to read Sabiston's
chapter on the acute abdomen.
So much for the
future of medicine.
Jacy, be sure
to ring Mr. Ingles.
Remind him not to eat
anything after midnight.
I don't want to have to
reschedule his hernia yet again.
- Mm-hm.
- I'm going trick-or-treating.
- Oh, what's Ella this year?
- A cow.
- Wasn't she a cow last year?
- No, she was Dorothy.
I was the Cowardly Lion, and
Mark... Mark was the Scarecrow.
Right.
I get to be a farmer this year.
Happy Halloween.
- Dr. Corday.
- Yeah?
Your med student called. Nathan.
The one who didn't
show up today?
- He said he'd be here in a few minutes.
- Too late.
Dr. Romano would like to
talk with you before you leave.
- Tell him you couldn't find me.
- I heard that.
Check this guy out.
What the hell are
you supposed to be?
- Want a candy, fellow? FRANK:
Put some meat on those bones.
Hi. I thought everyone
was dressing up.
We were supposed
to. There was a memo.
- I didn't bring anything to change into.
- Neither did I.
You're still a nurse.
You should've called.
Then I would be the
only one. I don't think so.
- Frank, where's your costume?
- I don't observe pagan holidays...
- that celebrate devil worship.
- Well, this is only for Satanists.
- What? Shut up.
- It's kind of working for you.
You give me an order I think is
wrong, I'm gonna ask you to clarify.
- Not in front of patients.
- I only questioned the dosage.
- You made mistakes in the past.
- I have not.
- Is there a problem?
- Yeah, you got no guts.
- I'm not working with him.
- Why?
Because he treats nurses like idiots.
- If your boots fit...
- Shoes.
- Whatever.
You're wearing
that for your shift?
Yes. It's Halloween. You
know, Jerry sent out a memo.
- Ooh, naughty nurse.
- I'm not a naughty nurse.
- I like it.
- No, I'm a... It's an old-fashioned nurse.
- Looks naughty to me.
- So you're what, like, a kurva nurse?
- What's that?
- How do you say...?
- A slut? You know, like a tramp, whore.
- Yeah, I got it.
You know, maybe I should've worn
that schoolgirl outfit you bought me.
She's making a joke.
Cautery.
Robert, what are you doing?
Laparoscopic cholecystectomy.
But you can't be.
I had no choice. Poor
swine's full of stones.
Oh, for heaven's
sake. It's a pig.
I hope you're not
expecting me to scrub in.
No, giving my hand a
workout. It's been five months.
I gotta keep my
skills up. Stapler.
Even with one arm, I'm a better
surgeon than the hacks in this hospital.
Robert, you're not cleared to
do surgery, even on barn animals.
Were you aware that Weaver
put through a proposal to hire PAs...
to cover afternoon rounds
for post-call surgical residents?
Yes. It was a very good idea.
Not the point. The point is
nobody talked to me about it.
Last time I checked, I was head
of both surgery and this hospital.
The Residency
Review Committee...
Oh, sweet Mary and Joseph! Would
you look at the size of that gallbladder.
Jeez, you could feed a small Amish
family for a week with that thing.
I know Weaver's formed alliances with
the tribal elders while I was recuperating.
- I expected more loyalty from you.
- Robert...
Rewrite the proposal as if it
came from us. Keep me abreast...
of other covert
Weaver ops. Okay?
The last thing I need is Mata
Hari leading a palace coup.
- What the hell?
- He's extubated.
Get him back under. Hundred of Peridol.
Hold him down! Lizzie, hold him down!
- Bloody hell. ROMANO:
He's a pig. Grab a loin, Lizzie!
Flex. Flex. Keep going.
Ninety degrees. That's good.
Not my elbow I'm worried about.
What's going on down there? Brenda!
All right, the wrist.
Flex.
Keep going. A little bit more.
- Ten degrees.
- Wrong. Check it again.
Ten.
- It was 15 last week.
- Fluctuations are normal, Robert.
With this type of injury, you gotta
give yourself at least nine months.
How does this affect my odds?
- You've still got a long way to go.
- Yeah, I know. The odds.
For full flexion, extension and
opposition of the digits, 20 percent.
But even then, without radial
and ulnar deviation of the thumb...
I'm not sure you'll
be able to operate.
But you can still
be Chief of Staff.
Most of your job's
administrative anyway.
Thanks for the pep
talk there, Marty.
Excuse me. I'm
looking for Dr. Corday.
Yeah, aren't we all. Are
you a bill collector or a suitor?
- Med student.
- Must be a slow learner.
- Career change.
- Cowboy and fireman didn't work?
I'm supposed to start my
surgical rotation. I'm Paul Nathan.
Dr. Romano.
- What happened?
- Tennis elbow.
Fire at a Halloween
party. At least 30 victims.
Gave 10 of morphine IM.
- How you doing?
- Not good.
- What's your name?
- Amy.
Last name?
There was fire at
the party downstairs.
Your last name?
Anybody with her? EMT: Hard
to say. The building's burning.
- A lot of confusion. ABBY:
Soot in nostrils, intra-oral burns.
I need an intubation tray. Get
Corday on the crushed pelvis.
- Excuse me.
- Not now.
Ed Jemena, 35. Full-thickness
burns to the hands and forearms.
Guy was on fire. I tried to put him
out. I didn't have anything but my hands.
Luka, can you get this? - Yeah.
- What's open?
- Curtain 2.
- A trauma room.
- Lucky to get a bed.
- Okay, yes?
- Oh, Paul Nathan.
- Radiology?
- No. Um, surgery.
- Resident?
- Med student.
Good enough. Cellulitis to the
leg after a bug bite to the ankle.
- What do I do?
- Mark the leading edge with a marker.
Nice catch. Whoa,
we're full in here.
- What do you have?
- Doctor, excuse me...
You all need to stay
in your assigned spots.
If a doctor or nurse can't find
you, it'll delay your treatment.
Doctor, doctor, can you tell me
what's happened to my things?
- My apartment's on the fourth floor.
- I'll see.
- The fire was on two.
- Will they let us go home?
- Ask the fire department.
- How did it start? Was it a gas leak?
- I'm sorry, I don't know.
- Carter, we need you.
- Fruits upstairs were smoking dope.
- No one was smoking anything, all right?
- What's that for?
- To keep an eye on the infection.
- What are they giving him to stop it?
- Uh, excuse me. Unasyn.
- That'll get rid of the infection?
- It should. It's an antibiotic.
- Hey, you a doctor?
- Med student.
I need that Mayo stand.
Put it under his arm.
- Got this?
- I'm supposed to be...
Good. I need a cutdown tray.
What are you going to do?
- We're gonna make you better.
- Why can't I feel my hands?
Uh, the burns have
damaged your nerves.
Is it permanent?
I don't know.
- Where's Terry?
- Who's Terry?
My partner. He's
dressed like a jungle girl.
- Etomidate's on board.
- I need to see Terry.
Trauma panel, carboxyhemoglobin,
and ABG. Prime a line of ringers.
What is this?
Rubber mask melted to the face.
- I can barely open the mouth.
- Try fiberoptic. I got the subclavian.
- I thought you left, Lizzie.
- Supposed to be trick-or-treating.
- Little old, don't you think?
- Open a crike tray in case.
- Guide wire's passing well.
- Pre-load an 8-0 tube on a scope.
- Pulse ox down to 85.
- Fifteen blade.
Ten-cc syringe. Let's
check the balloon.
I need a different light source.
Don't open the tray unless
the intubation fails. Don't want...
Sorry. Sorry.
Got the line, run the
first liter wide open.
Robert, you okay?
- 0-silk, Neosporin, and OpSite.
- Robert?
I'm okay.
Keep bagging on 15
liters. Get sats above 90.
If you got this, Lizzie, I'm gonna
go check on the rest of the kids.
Take slow deep breaths.
- I'm trying.
Have you ever had asthma? - No.
- What's this?
- Smoke inhalation with wheezing.
- Decreased breath sounds?
- Possible pneumothorax.
May need a chest tube.
- Vitals?
- I've got it.
Yeah, I'm sure you do. Get a
chest x-ray and show it to me.
Digital escarotomy.
Yeah. He needs
the same on the left.
I agree.
How old do you think she is?
I don't know.
Young.
- Hey, Dr. Corday.
- Yeah? What have you got?
Urine's 60 an
hour. But it's bloody.
Eighty percent burns. She'll need
12 liters in the first eight hours.
Send out for CT abdomen and
pelvis. I still need to do an airway.
- Dr. Corday?
- Yes?
Oh, I'm Paul Nathan. I was supposed
to begin my surgical rotation today.
Yes, you were.
She's got a critical
patient next door.
- Where should I put these?
- Here. Put them there.
No free fluid.
- Liver and spleen look okay.
- Scope is prepped.
Standing by with a
number-five Shiley.
Rounds started at 7 a.m.
- No, I know. I was at my...
- Not interested in excuses, thanks.
- Get my letter?
- Let's take a look.
- Dr. Corday, your nanny's on the phone.
- For God's sake. Take a look around.
- Take a message.
- I did. She said to remind you...
- she has a flight to catch at 10:30.
- I can't leave now, can I?
- What do you want me to tell her?
- To bring Ella here.
Daycare's closed, you know.
I know. NURSE: Pulse ox, 81.
- He's throwing PVCs. Crike him.
- Anything I can do?
Yes. Be quiet.
Okay, bag him.
You wanna make up for it? Go
out there and work up some patients.
- Yeah, but...? CORDAY:
Wanna be a doctor?
- That's why you're here?
- Yes...
Grab a patient, do an H & P.
Present the case to an Attending.
I told Martin 100 times.
You need to put new
batteries in the smoke detector.
But, oh, no. God forbid he
should spend $3 on a 9-volt.
The whole building
could've burned down.
- Um, his x-rays are back.
- Oh, okay. Good.
- How's he doing?
- Better than most.
- Yeah.
- Okay. Next time I go hiking...
- I'm wearing long pants.
- And bug repellent.
Your infection's spreading.
- Uh, is everything okay?
- I'll be right back.
- Excuse me. You're a surgeon?
- That's the rumor.
- Think there's something you should see.
- You're a student.
- You haven't learned to think yet.
- I've got a rapidly spreading cellulitis.
- Excuse me. How rapid?
- Well, I just drew this 20 minutes ago.
And look. This looks like sub-Q
air consistent with neck fash.
Yeah, nice catch.
Let's roll. Get that side.
- We gotta move him upstairs.
- Upstairs?
- To Surgery. What's he on?
- Three grams of Unasyn.
Switch him to 6 million units
of pen G and 900 of clinda.
- Where's he going?
- Newbie caught a neck fash.
- What?
- What's that mean?
Your boyfriend may have necrotizing
fasciitis, a virulent skin infection.
- They gave him antibiotics to help.
- The infection's spreading fast.
Wait, what are you gonna do?
Take you to O.R. and
remove the infected tissue.
- What?
- Everybody off. Off the elevator.
Take the stairs next
time. You'll live longer.
If we don't stop this, it'll move
along and you'll develop...
an infection, which will
lower your blood pressure.
You could die.
Oh, my God.
- Think we caught that in time?
- I hope so. Thank you. I'm Susan Lewis.
Paul Nathan.
- You coming?
- In a minute, yeah.
You okay?
Yeah. It's just... It
takes me a moment...
to get going sometimes. Uh,
I have Parkinson's disease.
- Get up here.
- I'll be up in five minutes, Robert.
Said that 10 minutes ago.
- I'm with a critical patient.
- Find somebody else now, Lizzie!
Good ET placement.
No infiltrates.
Check ABG, repeat CBC
and work on a burn-unit bed.
- What about him?
- Who?
- Him.
- Yeah. What about him?
Pardon me.
I found your CPK,
lytes and UA results.
You headed up to
surgery on the neck fash?
Yes, as a matter of fact.
- Okay. Well, I guess we're done here.
- I am. You still owe eight hours.
- I'm on rounds at 6 a.m.
- Welcome to Surgery.
Excuse me. Uh, where can I find
somebody who was brought in?
Admit.
Come here. Follow me.
Who are you looking for?
Wynn Mathison. He's
in a tiger costume.
- There was a fire in our building.
- Could you direct me to the victims?
- Keep your habit on, man.
- Excuse me?
You'll soon see your
drag queen friends.
I have food and housing
vouchers for the displaced.
- Oh, I'm sorry, sister.
- Please tell me what room he's in.
- What?
- He's with the guy in the tiger mask.
Get some oil of wintergreen.
I hate the smell of rotting flesh,
especially when it's increasing.
Bacteria's moving
faster than you.
- Bovie.
- Systolic's down to 95.
Bolus 500. Lap pad.
Still not bleeding. Myonecrosis.
- It's in the muscle.
- Ten blade.
If it's vascularized, don't cut it.
- That's my plan.
Start there and carry the
incision four centimeters inferior.
- No. That's eight. Goddamn it!
- We need clean borders.
- Where the hell is Corday?
- In the scrub room.
If I don't remove tissue, the
infection could be left to smolder.
Get her. Maybe she can débride this
guy's wound without using a chain saw.
- Hey! CORDAY:
Kris, it's me. Elizabeth.
Don't come. I shouldn't
be longer than an hour.
- Dr. Corday, he's asking for you.
- Be right there.
Okay, but could you take Ella
to your house to finish packing?
Yeah, I could pick
you both up after work.
I could drive you to the airport,
save you the cost of cab fare. Yeah.
Okay. Thank you. Thank you
so much. Yeah. I'll see you soon.
Corazon, would you
mind taking the phone?
Not at all.
Damn.
Was that your wedding ring?
Yep. Yeah.
I can't see it. Can
you call Engineering?
They're closed till
morning. I'm sorry.
- No, it's not your fault.
- Don't hate me. He wants to talk.
- Lizzie, get your ass in here.
- I've lost my wedding ring.
Oh, boohoo. This
guy's about to lose a leg.
I'd say chop-chop, but that'd
be in extremely bad taste.
Call someone, get them
to tape this off for me...
- make sure no water's run down it.
- Sure.
Would somebody please call
Tiffany's search-and-rescue team?
I'm coming!
He's got 20 percent surface-area
burns, mainly upper body.
- Oh, God. PRATT:
Decent prognosis.
We provide ventilatory support
until lungs heal, then extubate him.
Might take a week, maybe less.
What...? What about his face?
He'll need skin grafts. There'll
definitely be some scarring.
Wynn? Wynn, it's me,
Terry. I'm right here.
He can't hear you. He's sedated.
You should have your eye looked at.
- Later, okay?
Can I touch him?
I wouldn't.
Yo, newbie. Come on.
Check jungle perv's eye with the
slit lamp. May have a corneal burn.
- Where's that?
- You still here?
Yeah. Uh, slit lamp. Where
is it? How does it work?
Exam 3. Try the on-off switch.
Hey, hey.
- You changed.
- I just put on scrub pants.
Oh, come on. You know, Carter, my
outfit is really starting to bug me too.
- We agreed to stay in costume all shift.
- I am.
No, you're not.
It's half a costume.
- It's 50 percent commitment.
- Are you serious or kidding?
- Do you know what I'm dealing with?
- Me too, in pumps.
- Wanna see the whole costume?
- No.
- That's all right. Forget it.
- I'm a skeleton. Look at me.
Carter really likes
Halloween, huh?
Perpetual erection.
Drank his daughter's mandrake
smoothie. Police found him chasing women.
- Where do you want him?
- In a cold shower.
- Get a line in and push four of Ativan.
- Are you open, baby? Ha-ha-ha!
Perfect.
First-day labs, charcoal,
and a Foley for the tox screen.
Release me. I am
the Marquis de Sade.
How am I supposed to
pass a catheter through that?
- Inject phenylephrine.
- Into the shaft?
I'm Rod Stewart.
Won't hold still for a blood draw
much less let me touch his penis.
Oh, she can touch it.
Or wait for the
mandrake to metabolize.
Why not give him
Haldol? Make it easier.
Might make him worse.
- Hey, hey.
- Hey. He just grabbed my ass.
- I couldn't reach hers.
- I said four of Ativan.
Ask Abby. I'm done.
Okay. You could be a
little bit more sensitive.
To what?
Amazing how
quickly this spreads.
Any idea how he got it?
A cut, a scratch,
some other trivial injury.
Dopamine's at 10 mics.
- More suction.
Scalpel. ROMANO: Easy, Lizzie.
Is it just me or is this constant
commentary distracting?
- It's not you.
- Just remove the infected tissue.
Let antibiotics and
hyperbaric oxygen do the rest.
- You're not serious.
- Hell, yes. I am.
I'm in posterior compartment.
It's still necrotic soup.
Six hours in a chamber will
increase oxygen saturation...
create a bacteriocidal effect.
Give this guy a chance of a functioning
leg. You two have a problem with that?
How's a guy with Parkinson's
get into med school?
Probably some disability
quota they have to fill.
Med school? How's
he expect to practice?
- Don't want him taking out my appendix.
- He seems to have it under control.
It's a progressive disease.
What about in 10 years?
- Could be dead.
- Or wanna be.
Happy, Abby. Always
looking on the bright side.
I thought you were out sick.
I was until an apartment
fire set us back 30 patients.
Thirty-five, counting
bad popcorn balls.
Wonderful.
- Thanks for coming in.
- Shouldn't have answered.
- Want your messages?
- No. I want the air conditioning on.
- I'm sweating like a pig.
- It's freezing.
That's what you get bringing
Weaver in on Halloween.
- It's the biggest holiday for her kind.
- Lesbians?
Wiccans. Probably riding
that crutch like a broom.
Frank, all women get like that when
they're going through the change.
- Yeah, right.
- Pratt.
What? She's having
hot flashes. She's moody.
- That is so sexist. ABBY:
And stupid. She's too young.
- Early onset.
- You've got early onset.
Whatever you say, Nasty Ratched.
It's nurse, okay? Not nasty, not naughty,
not wet, certainly not had. Just nurse.
- Abby, you're gonna talk to Kovac, right?
- Yes.
County General on Bravo One.
- Rescue One...
Finished the slit lamp,
numbed him with Alcaine.
Who are you?
Meet Nathan, our
newest, oldest med student.
- I'm on surgical rotation with Dr. Corday.
- We have to clear Trauma.
- BOA with newborn hypoxia.
- She asked that I stay and assist in...
Good. Follow me.
Don't worry. She
doesn't bite. Much.
Simone Phillip, 42. Had a home
birth. Newborn in respiratory distress.
Did you have a
complicated labor?
No, it went well.
I didn't even tear.
One minute Apgar was
seven. But he had a little...
- Who are you?
- The midwife.
- What's wrong with him?
- We'll find out. Take him to Trauma 1.
- Where is that?
- I'll take him.
- No, I... It's okay.
- I got it. I got it. I got it.
- Simone, you've lost a lot of blood.
- Something's wrong with my baby.
Lily, stirrups. Gallant, labs.
- Maybe I should've had him in a hospital.
- You did everything right.
- CBC, PT, PTT, DIC screen for four units.
- We're taking care of your baby.
- Let's help you now.
- BP's 80/60.
- Squeeze in another two liters.
- What's happening?
Blood loss from a
retained placenta.
No, I mean with my baby.
Dr. Kovac is taking
care of your son.
I'm gonna pull gently on
the umbilical cord. Simone?
I need you to stay with me.
Pulse ox is 82. He's retracting.
Pedes intubation tray,
number three ET, uncuffed.
What do you hear?
Wet crackles throughout.
Fluid in the alveoli.
Okay, let's go look.
Unhook the bag from the mask.
You can bag the ET once I'm in.
- I've never done that.
- Squeeze the bag every two seconds...
just like he was doing.
Never pass the tube
till you see the cords.
Okay. I'm in.
Call for a Pedes vent. And
set me up for an umbilical line.
Relax, relax. The
hard part's over.
Good.
Notify the NICU team.
- What do I tell them's wrong?
- I have no idea.
It's no good. We're
into the cords.
Have to do an AKA.
Keep débriding.
We're not there yet.
We treat this conservatively
and it spreads...
then it's hip disarticulation
to stay ahead of bacteria.
- Worth the risk. CORDAY:
Of his being non-ambulatory?
Above-the-knee amputation,
he can use a prosthetic.
If it gets to his hip, it'll spread to
the abdominal wall. He'll get septic.
I'm trying to save this
man's leg. Dry the field.
- What about his life?
- He's young. Same thing.
Oh, come on, Robert.
Of course it's not.
Look. This Kelly slices
through sub-Q fat like butter.
Fine. Keep cutting until
you hit viable muscle.
It's above the distal third of
the thigh. It's a hopeless wound.
Fine, take it. CORDAY: Robert.
I said, take the leg.
Bovie, pickups.
Tommy, how are you feeling?
He seems... He seems
a lot better, thanks.
Good. Well...
just keep him on clear fluids tonight
and I'll have a nurse sign you out.
Okay.
What's wrong with him?
Shh. We'll, uh...
We'll talk about it later.
- How are you holding up?
- Good. I think the robot can go home.
- Okay. I'll get Carter to dispo him.
- Okay.
- Can I get you a cup of coffee?
- No, I'm fine. Thank you.
Uh, I like your outfit.
It's very retro.
Thank you.
Um, listen, if... If you
ever need anything, like a...
Like a straitjacket?
Is your dyskinesia
usually this bad?
I don't wanna freeze up on them
at work so I upped the medication.
And this is what you get.
At least it helps
to dispel the myth.
You know, we don't
all have rhythm.
If it happened to me, I'd probably jump
on a world cruise, not go to med school.
I already saw the world.
In fact, I was in Italy when I
first realized I had a problem.
Sipping wine in this café in Florence,
and I noticed my little finger shaking.
I just figured it was from
living on espresso and martinis.
When did you find out it wasn't?
Well, I used to hate doctors so it
took a while for me to check it out.
But once I did, it really
put things in perspective.
Yeah, I guess
being sick does that.
- Her baby's not doing well, huh?
- No.
- How are you doing, Simone?
- Good.
He seems better, huh?
Maintenance fluids are at
five cc's per kilo per hour.
My mother had me at home. I
thought it would be good for him.
Uh, his tests came back.
I'm afraid your baby has
a disease called sialidosis.
What's that?
His body lacks an enzyme that breaks
down the waste proteins inside the cells.
And there is already extensive damage
to the liver, bones and nervous system.
I've been staring at him
for over an hour now.
And I still can't figure
out what I wanna call him.
Would you excuse us, please?
Yeah. Sure.
Children with sialidosis are
mentally retarded, often blind.
He'll never speak or walk.
His life expectancy
is less than two years.
Dr. Kovac, NICU is on line one.
Thanks.
Excuse me.
Is there anyone
you'd like me to call?
No.
There's just us.
I don't think it'll be
necessary. Thank you.
- You having a bad night?
- No worse than usual.
That was a little
bit insensitive.
I had to tell a mother
her baby was gonna die.
- I didn't need an audience? Okay?
- Okay.
I'm starting to get some
complaints about you.
- From patients?
- Nurses.
Don't look so
concerned about it.
First you accused Chuny of being an
idiot. When she's sexually harassed...
- you practically laughed.
- The guy grabbed her butt.
- Yeah, that's sexual harassment.
- Come on. You were there.
The guy's intoxicated with
mandrake. He's harmless.
- This one's all yours.
- What patient?
Mr. Hard-On. Checking his
vitals and he grabbed my boob.
- What's his status?
- Gonna die if he tries again.
- That's his status.
- See?
Every time there's a
problem, she complains.
Everyone complains.
It's part of the job.
Yes. And it's part of my job as
nurse manager to counsel you.
What?
You can give nurses
orders, but cannot critique.
If you have a problem
with a nurse, come to me.
Okay. What about you? Who do I
complain to if I have a problem...?
Here's an idea. Maybe you
should try fighting for the nurses...
- instead of fighting with them.
- Maybe you should sew swastikas...
on that costume. You could
be a naughty Nazi nurse, huh?
- You totally suck, you know that?
- Creating a hostile work environment.
- Where's Dr. Kovac?
- I don't know. Page him.
The baby with
sialidosis is febrile to 102.
- Chuny, where's Kovac?
- Don't know, don't care.
- Feels like he's on fire.
- Why hasn't he gone to the NICU?
- You'd have to ask Dr. Kovac.
- Can you do something?
He needs to be pan-cultured.
How much does he weigh?
- Three kilos.
- A hundred and fifty milligrams IV...
piggyback of Cefotaxime and
amp. Set up for a spinal tap.
- He has sialidosis.
- Yeah. And he also has an infection.
Sixty mgs of Tylenol.
I'll arrange for your baby to
be sent up to the neonatal unit.
- We'll do everything we can for you.
- Thank you.
Why are you still here?
Uh, my piano
recital was canceled.
Hey, it's me, Elizabeth. I'm on my
way home now. See you soon. Bye.
We did the right thing.
You trying to
convince me or you?
I went through a
period of adjustment...
when I became a mother,
every time I treated a child.
You get over it.
Oh, please spare me the
$2 psychoanalysis, Lizzie.
- Fine.
- Hey, look, look.
I know most people don't like me. I
don't care. I don't like most people.
But I'm good at what I do.
I save people's lives every day.
People who no one else can help.
If I can't do that...
Robert...
I know you're frustrated.
You're an excellent surgeon, and you
will be again. I promise you. You will be.
- I'm being paged.
- Elizabeth.
Uh, I'm being paged.
Elizabeth. CORDAY:
I just tried calling you.
I'm sorry. I have to
leave for the airport now.
- What about the later flight?
- This is it.
I threw her pajamas, some
crackers, a couple toys in here...
in case she had to stay
for a while. I'm sorry.
No. It's all right. It's my
fault. We got slammed.
I'll see you Monday morning.
- Yeah, yeah. Have a safe flight.
- Okay. Bye, Ella.
Hey, did Kris take
you trick-or-treating?
- What is it?
- Dropped her pressure to 60 palp.
Dopamine is up. We got two
liters. I'm working on an art line.
- Any word from her family?
- No. We don't have her last name.
- Lily, could you?
- Oh, sure.
- There, it's okay.
- Hello, little cow...
- girl.
- I'll be with you soon, all right?
- Could it be hemorrhagic?
- The CT was negative.
I'm thinking hypoxia.
If we don't find her family,
they'll be ID'ing the body.
Pulse ox is only
82 on 100 percent.
She needs suctioning, Abby. Set up
ultrasound. She may have blown a clot.
I don't know. Second
crit was only 32.
- What happened to Mom?
- In the washroom.
- Where are the suction catheters?
- Try the cabinet.
- What are you doing?
- Weaver ordered antibiotics.
- No. Who did the LP?
- She wanted a full septic workup.
- This is my patient. NATHAN:
The baby spiked a fever.
This baby is in a
chronic vegetative state.
You're prolonging his
and the mother's suffering.
- We treat kids like this.
- You should've asked me.
We couldn't find you.
I told you to leave.
This isn't your case.
Luka. CORDAY: Abby?
Check with me before you
push meds on my patient.
- I have to do a cutdown here.
- Morison's pouch looks dry.
It could be retroperitoneal.
What the hell was all that about?
- You want PEEP on the vent?
- Not until we get her pressure up.
Nathan, why do you
think she's hypotensive?
- Blood loss? CARTER:
Not in this case.
Hypoxia can cause
myocardial dysfunction.
I'm filing a grievance
against him.
Not now, Chuny. IV's
dry. She needs a fresh one.
- I'll get it. HALEH: Panic
value. Potassium is 8.2.
Damn. Rhabdo from the crush
injury. Ten cc's of calcium gluconate.
PVCs. CARTER: Let's push bicarb.
Ten units of regular
insulin and an amp of D50.
Get me Kayexalate and call
Renal. She may need dialysis.
- What the hell are you doing?
- Uh. I accidentally...
It's okay.
Go see if Frank's
found the girl's family.
I'll start another.
- Transducer ready?
- Where's the saline?
I said, go find the girl's family.
- Run of five.
- Hundred of lidocaine. Prep the groin.
- Pressure falling, 79.
Pressure's down to 50.
- Being a little hard on him, you think?
- V-tach. Charge to 200.
- What are you talking about?
- He's doing a good job, considering.
- Considering what?
- He has Parkinson's.
Excuse me?
Clear.
Still V-tach.
- Procainamide's onboard.
- Stand by with amiodarone. Clear.
- No change.
- How long?
- Uh, twelve minutes.
Clear.
- Sinus tach.
- All right.
Way to go.
- Good femoral pulse.
- Set up a Pronestyl drip then a repeat K.
Labs on your baby.
- Thank you.
- Glad to see you two have made up.
Hey, I'm being professional
and she's the one having trouble.
- I warned her.
- Warned her about what?
Nothing.
Oh, my God.
- You're such a jerk.
- What?
You slept with her?
That's what this is all
about. What's your problem?
- Hey, one time.
- One time. One time with Chuny.
One time with a patient's
mother in Radiology.
Hey, you never complained.
I never let it affect my work.
You two need to figure this out.
- So, what do you want me to do?
- Tell her you're sorry.
- Tell her it was wrong. Just fix it.
- I'm not gonna kiss her ass.
That's how this problem started.
- Have them check a gas on 50 percent.
- I'm gonna wait right here for you.
Don't worry about anything.
I love you.
I should've told them
I was his brother.
ICU has strict rules.
He'll need round-the-clock attention
tonight, but his lungs are rebounding.
You know what? You should go home.
They'll let you see him in the morning.
Home?
Our whole lives were
in that apartment.
This dress is all I have.
I've been watching
his heart rate.
It goes down when I touch
him, when he knows I'm here.
- Has his fever gone down?
- A little.
I waited so long for him.
Five years.
Two miscarriages, in vitro.
I lost two boyfriends because I
was so determined to have a child.
I was about to give up.
And then suddenly...
he was here.
- He's here.
- We'll keep treating the infection...
but he will start going
into organ failure soon.
His systems will shut down.
You're so beautiful.
You're my baby.
His heart could stop beating.
I need to know what you wanna
do if something like that happens.
I don't know.
To keep him alive, I may have to
open his chest, maybe even shock him.
And I'm not sure you want
me to do something like that.
No.
I don't know.
Tell the unit I
flushed the Quinton.
He's tenacious.
Gotta give him that.
I wish he'd told me.
Not an easy thing to lead with.
There's Mommy.
Hi, Lily had to run
Wynn's ABG up to the lab.
- Thank you.
- Did you reverse her hyperkalemia?
Yeah. Enough to get her to dialysis.
She still has the burns, though.
- Yeah. But you got her back.
- May I?
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Hey.
Thank you. So did
we reach the parents?
No. The girl was actually
babysitting. It wasn't even her building.
You might've told me sooner, saved
me embarrassment about your condition.
Well, I certainly didn't
mean to embarrass you.
- How long has it been?
- Eight years.
I was misdiagnosed
for the first two.
- And you were late today because?
- My neurologist wanted an MRI.
I'm sorry.
I wouldn't have made you stay.
What the hell? Fresh start.
Try to make as many rounds as you
can, complete the required reading...
take the exam.
I've been reading and taking tests for
two years. This is my hands-on training.
- It's a surgical rotation.
- I understand that.
Probably the most
physically demanding...
emotionally exhausting,
stressful six weeks...
any would-be physician
ever experiences.
Part of becoming a doctor.
I'm offering you a pass, Mr. Nathan.
Trust me. You should take it.
I'm here to treat patients.
You have a degenerative disease.
I know what I have. It
doesn't mean I need a pass.
ER.
I don't want special treatment. I
just want to learn like other students.
- Yeah, she's here.
- You're not like other students.
No, I'm older and smarter.
Okay. Dr. Corday,
burn unit needs you.
- I'm on my way up, Frank.
- It's your melted-mask guy.
Okay. Be right there.
- She's on her way.
- Look, go home, think about it...
report back day after
tomorrow. Use the rest.
- I'm fine.
- It's just not very practical.
Okay, let's go.
- Dr. Weaver?
- What?
- What time is it?
- Are you okay?
Yeah. Yeah, I was...
- I was gonna lay down for a second.
- Can you pronounce a patient?
Did we ever hear
back from the NICU?
- Uh, no. There was no need.
- Oh, come on. It's been three hours.
We can't board their patients.
They have to call in a nurse
from home. If they won't...
- I'll speak to their medical director.
- Dr. Weaver...
Cardiac arrest a half-hour ago.
Excuse us.
You should've come to get me.
How long did Dr. Kovac work on him?
He didn't. She signed a DNR.
Where is he?
- Who?
- Kovac.
He's home. His
shift ended at 10.
All right, I'm gonna
move her to a quiet room.
Call the social worker and get
her referrals for grief counseling.
Are you leaving soon?
I'm just finishing
up with Woody here.
You're the most beautiful
nurse in this hospital.
- Well, thank you.
- You've got class.
- May I play with your breasts?
- Hey.
Excuse me? WOODY: Please.
Last request of a
man on his deathbed.
You're not dying,
Woody. You're drunk.
I wanna go to heaven on the
bosom of a beautiful woman.
I don't think your
HMO covers that.
How long you have that outfit?
- Tomorrow at noon. Why?
- Maybe I could talk you into...
- giving me a sponge bath.
- What's in it for me, bony boy?
I'll give you a bone,
nasty, naughty little nurse.
Elizabeth.
Uh, Robert, can we talk
tomorrow? I have to get Ella home.
I thought you might
want this before you left.
It's my ring.
Amazing what you can do with a
laparoscopic camera and a snare.
Thank you.
- Uh, look, about today...
- Uh, let's not.
It was a momentary weakness
on my part. It won't happen again.
You'll work
through this, Robert.
Of course I will.
- Good night.
- Night.
The patient has gastroenteritis,
vomits to excess...
has hematemesis, no history
of PUD. What are you thinking?
Well?
Mallory-Weiss tear.
Laceration of the distal esophagus
results in an upper GI bleed.
You're both correct and tardy.
- Sorry.
- Don't be sorry. Be punctual.
What if that patient vomits
and develops chest pain?
Boerhaave's syndrome.
Spontaneous rupture of the
esophagus associated with retching.
Usually tears into
the left pleural space...