Our skulls cushion our brains.
What's happening?
Hey, it's me. Do you
want a giant tumor?
Why would I want that?
It's the one from my
wall that Derek drew.
I thought you might
like it. It's here in the hall.
Our rib cage guards our hearts.
The body is built to protect
our most vulnerable parts.
- Is she cleaning?
- At 3:30?
At least,
that's how it's
supposed to work.
Josephine Wilson. Strong in
ortho, plastics, and not a bad head
for neuro, actually. Her
outcomes are excellent.
Yeah, she really rallied.
She had a tough
year, personally.
Never would have
known. Stephanie Edwards.
She's expressed a clear
interest and talent for neuro.
She could write
whatever ticket she wants.
- She's a superstar.
- And very driven.
Yes, she will make us proud.
Well, this is fun.
- Like the Sorting Hat.
- Yep.
Benjamin Warren.
Well, say what you want to say.
Warren's a utility player,
good anywhere you put him.
That's true.
He tends to play it safe.
He goes for the easy
cases, easy diagnosis.
He lays back. No risks.
Ben Warren?
- Have you seen his file?
- He's made very risky moves.
I've had to
reprimand him myself.
Of course, I read his file.
After a mistake like Warren makes,
a resident goes one of two ways.
He either plays it
smarter or he plays it safer.
Warren went safer.
He may not even be
aware it's happening.
Moving on. Martin Carver.
- You talk to Wilson a lot.
- Daily. Why?
She and Karev. You
think they're back together?
I don't know.
- Oh, uh, never mind. Forget I asked.
- Oh! You like her.
- Nope. I'm not doing this.
- No. Hey. Hang on,
hang on. Stop.
You're a good guy.
You want to let that go,
okay? You made a grand gesture,
but she still hasn't said
anything to you, has she?
So, just do yourself a favor.
That's all I'm saying.
Here you go. Friend to friend.
Okay. Let's go fix people.
Doctor Wentz to
Labor and Delivery.
- Hey. Someone paged me.
- That was me. I need your help.
- Very urgent.
- Great. Where we headed?
My place or yours. Tonight.
The minute we are off of work.
I don't care if you have
other plans. They're canceled.
- I have plans of my own.
- So you paged me
for a dinner date.
I mean, sure. We can eat, too.
My plans are more...
naked plans.
Oh. Okay.
To be clear, I mean sex.
Yeah, no, no, I... I got that.
But you're hesitating.
I came on too strong?
You're not ready?
You're weirded out.
Hey.
Are you with someone?
- What's your name?
- Liam.
Liam, hey. Are you hurt?
Are you sick? Do you feel bad?
Okay. Where are your parents?
I don't have any.
- Who do we have, DeLuca?
- This is Holly Harner.
Complaining of generalized chest
and abdominal pain after a fall.
She's also got a pretty,
obvious forearm fracture.
Just waiting for her
X-rays to come up.
- Hi, Holly. I'm Dr. Kepner.
- Hi.
Can you tell me how you fell?
I was having the
best sex of my life.
No, third best.
- I'd hate to see the best.
- No, no. So, then I had to pee.
And it was dark, and I'm
trying to find the bathroom.
I found the front door instead,
walked right out in the stairwell and...
- Oh, no.
- Yeah, two flights.
He slept right through
it. His neighbor found me.
- Does that hurt?
- Yeah.
- And the guy you were with?
- Ah, well, it was one of those
one night things, so he'll just think I
ducked out in the middle of the night.
Which is fine.
It's good, actually.
Oh, my God.
What? What is it?
My pants, they're on his floor.
He's gonna have
to figure that one out.
Um, I'm sorry, Holly,
but it looks like you've
broken your arm in two places.
- Oh, come on.
- Yeah. And there's free fluid
in the left upper quadrant.
We're gonna need to get her up
- for a pan scan
and page general.
- Okay.
Is he single?
Hey, Maggie.
- Hi.
- Are you gonna be home tonight?
- Should be. What are we doing?
I was thinking about
having Nathan over,
but, I don't want it to be
weird or uncomfortable, so...
Well, It's your house. You should
have over whomever you want.
- But, It's your house, too.
- Are you saying
you don't want to have
him over if I'm there?
No, that's not what
I'm saying at all.
It's totally fine.
- Are Holly's scans up yet?
- Uh, not yet.
It's a little weird,
but it's fine.
Okay, forget it.
Forget I said anything.
- Okay, yeah.
- Okay.
Hello?
Hey, Holly. How's
it going in there?
Yeah, um, you know,
it just occurred to me,
uh, when you do the scan,
you might see something weird.
And I don't want
you to freak out.
Uh, don't worry about it.
We've seen everything,
Holly. Trust me.
Uh, well, I've got a giant,
inoperable heart tumor...
- Holy...
- And the... you know,
you should just ignore that.
It's just something I have.
Is it sharp, like
someone stabbing you
really hard, or throbbing
like a, a ball bouncing
against your head?
It just hurts.
- Sometimes I feel
like I've been spinning.
- Like you're dizzy?
Okay. Constant pain. Intermittent
dizziness. It could be vestibular.
Can you tell us who
takes care of you?
- Charlotte.
- And where do you
and Charlotte live?
On a farm.
Wow. That's pretty cool.
You got any animals?
A rat and a goose, a sheep.
Ah, I bet there's a pig, too.
You stay right here
for a minute, okay?
All right, something's
going on neurologically.
We need to get him a head CT.
No, we can't. Not
without consent.
And how do we find
Wilbur's parents?
We've already placed a call out
to police regarding missing kids.
It shouldn't take too long.
Kid's got clean clothes,
seems well nourished.
He reads books.
Or someone reads them to him.
He's... he's seizing.
Liam. Liam. Someone
get something for his head!
Two of lorazepam! And draw
up a loading dose of Keppra!
On it.
So, you have some bleeding
from a spleen laceration.
We'd like to try and do something
called a splenic embolization
- so that we can repair it
without doing surgery.
- All right. I'm in.
- Surgery would only
slow me down.
- Well, as for your heart tumor.
Oh, yeah. Left atrial
sarcoma. It's inoperable.
I've got less than
a year left. It's okay.
Inoperable means different
things to different surgeons.
I've... I've seen six surgeons.
So I know the stages.
You guys are in Stage one.
You see it, your eyes light up,
you're the only
ones who can tame it.
Stage two you make a plan,
a plan unlike any who
have come before you.
You get my consent.
Stage three you
realize it doesn't work
and you feel weird
and you get all sad, and then
you feel you disappointed me
and then make it my job to
convince you that I'm okay,
so, that you feel better.
Can we just skip it?
I know it's complicated,
but I really think...
Yeah, how long am I laid
up till my spleen heals?
How long till I can, you
know, get back in the saddle?
Uh, depends on
the kind of saddle.
Uh, well, I'd like to have sex
with as many men as I care to,
until my tumor tells me I can't.
Goals.
- Impressive.
- That's nice.
This fall really put a
kink in my plans and um,
- not in a good way.
- Well, provided
that your spleen heals
without complications,
you should be back to
your normal... lifestyle
in a few days, maybe a week.
Okay. Any chance we
can shave that down?
Partial deglovement, broken bones,
extreme tissue and nerve damage.
- And what do we have here? Ouch.
- Yup.
A 27 year old got his hand
jammed in a revolving door.
Ah, that'll do it.
What's the game plan?
Well, since his MESS score's a
seven, we're sitting right in the gray area
between salvage and
amputation, so obv...
Actually, I'd like to hear
what Warren's thinking.
Good idea.
Well uh, reconstructive
surgery is out.
If we go that route,
we just, you know,
there's a high likelihood of
failure and we're just back here
in six months, amputating
a nonfunctioning hand.
- Hm, that is true.
- Amputation is simpler.
But some patients,
mentally, can't process that.
Choose wisely, then.
Well, since the mess score is borderline,
we have to look for other indicators.
The LSI, the PSI could give us
a clearer picture of the ischemia,
the bone muscle damage, and
the extent of the vascular injury.
Warren, you're not
writing a research paper.
You're treating a patient
on a morphine drip.
Make a call.
Uh...
according to these numbers,
I say we amputate, then.
Here's a number
for you, Warren, 27.
A 27 year old wants
to keep his hand.
We're gonna do a rotational flap with antibiotic
beads and try to save this guy's hand.
Right. Of course.
Book an O.R., and uh,
give me some images
of his left and right
thighs, also, for the grafts.
All right.
It was a gray area.
Hey. So, Meredith was talking
about bringing Nathan over tonight.
Bringing him home?
- To our house?
- Yeah.
And then it got weird,
and now she's not.
I'm still wrapping my head around
the fact that she's dating him.
Oh, my God. The tumor.
- What?
- That's why she took the tumor
out of her room.
She doesn't want to have sex
with him in a shrine to Derek.
She did not do that
with the last guy.
And look what happened.
Screaming and crying
and us kicking a half naked
man out into the street.
She's clearing a path.
- She's moving on.
This is serious, her and Riggs.
We have to support this.
Now we are in the celiac artery,
and that looks like
the splenic artery.
- Got it.
- Meredith, heads up,
I'm gonna be home late tonight.
Okay. Deploying gelfoam.
More than late, I'm gonna
take another look at Holly's case.
I've got some old records and
studies that I want to... look over.
I thought she
didn't want you to.
Between the scans
and the paperwork
it's gonna take some
time. A lot of time, actually.
You should probably count
on me camping out here
for the duration and
not coming home.
Okay. Just wanted
to let you know.
- Thanks.
- All right.
- Should I ask? Okay.
- No.
Thank you so
much for finding us.
We, uh, we called the school.
We called his friend
Sabrina. We called the police.
He said he took the
train here? Goodness.
We live an hour away.
Liam had a seizure while
we were talking to him.
We took him to CT
to see what's going on.
Uh, David, Marie, Liam
has a very large tumor.
It's called a pituitary adenoma,
and he's gonna need brain surgery.
I'm sorry.
Is that why he's been getting these
headaches and why he's been so tired?
When can we take him home?
Well, that depends on how quickly the
brain swelling goes down after surgery.
Most patients can
be released within...
No, Liam won't have the surgery.
Or anything else. No
more needles, no scans.
We don't believe in
that sort of intervention.
I'm not sure you understand
what we're saying here.
If you take Liam home
without treatment, it gets worse.
- He could die.
- No, doctor, he won't.
Not if it's God's will.
So, thank you for
respecting our beliefs.
How soon can you
discharge my son?
And this states you are
aware you're taking Liam home
against medical advice.
I know this probably
seems a little...
unusual.
I appreciate your understanding.
Do you understand that
"against medical advice"
in this case means
if you take Liam now,
there's a very, real
chance Liam will die?
Thank you, Dr. Edwards.
Who taught you it was okay
to speak to patients that way?
She's not my patient.
The embolization went well.
I was able to stop the
bleeding on your spleen.
We'll just have to monitor
you for the next 24 hours, and...
- you should be okay.
- All right.
I should've just
turned on the light.
I didn't want to
wake him, you know?
Well, that was polite.
No, it was because I
didn't want to talk to him.
He's the kind of guy who always
says, "I'll tell you something,"
before he tells you something.
Like it's good enough
to be announced.
- So he's not a keeper. Uh,
well, I'm not really looking
for a keeper. I'm
gonna be gone soon.
So, I can't hold onto anything.
I'm just looking for what
looks good to me right now.
Hey, Holly.
Uh, your boyfriend's here.
He's asking if he can come up.
Oh, my God.
Okay, his neighbor must've
blabbed. Did he say, boyfriend?
Can you just tell
him that I died?
- Um, we can, tell him that you're
asleep. Then he won't go away.
If he hangs on,
somebody's gonna eventually
have to tell him that I died for real.
So,
let's just spare him that.
- We can talk to him.
- Okay.
Well, he's dumb, but he's cute.
Oh, and he's um...
Mmm.
Hey, feel free to take a
spin. I'm not going back.
Oh, Dr. Minnick?
I think you're right
about Ben Warren.
Oh?
Yeah, I saw something that
may confirm your suspicions.
- I owe you an apology.
- I'm fresh eyes. It helps.
You've known these
kids for years. I haven't.
Well, that's very true.
I was reading Stephanie
Edwards' file, and I noticed...
when her boyfriend
died on Shepherd's table,
Edwards went back to
work almost immediately.
Didn't see any records
of counseling or therapy.
She was fine.
She's very focused.
- So that's a no.
- Why are you interested
in her file?
I noticed some red
flags. Today, for instance,
she was inappropriate with
a patient's family member.
She can be arrogant,
and she can get snarky.
- She's a surgeon.
- Who gets triggered by patients.
Look. Trust me, Edwards knows
more about patients than most of us.
Good night.
You can't tell him she's dead.
But that's what she wanted. I
mean, he needs to know, and,
- it's... it's kind.
- It's illegal,
to say the very least.
- Is this him? Hi.
- Yes. Hi.
- Hi. Yes. Yes, that's me.
- Corey?
- Hi. Did you tell Holly
I'm here?
- Yes.
- Listen, Corey.
- We did, we did. She knows.
Does she think it's weird?
I mean, we just...
we don't really know...
We just met. But,
we got really close.
Is she okay?
Corey...
we have some, very bad news.
- Holly...
- Has had a hell of a day
- and is just not really up
for visitors right now, so... Oh.
Oh, okay, well.
That's... that's great.
I mean, that she's okay.
I was so worried that...
Yes, so you can go home now.
Good night.
Uh, good night.
I mean, she's not
wrong. He is cute.
Maybe you should hit that.
You are a dark, dark person.
I can't get together tonight.
Okay. No big deal.
I just have a patient who's
in labor with a baby with CDH,
and I'm gonna be here
all night. I'm so sorry.
Of course. I understand. Just...
I was looking
forward to it, is all.
I look for you.
All day.
When I um...
when I turn a corner, or I
pass by one of the scan rooms.
Uh, getting on an elevator.
I hope that maybe I'll just...
catch a glimpse of
you. And when I...
see you...
every time, it makes
me catch my breath...
just a little.
And my heart speeds
up. My palms sweat.
Seeing you...
talking to you, and...
touching you.
It's all I can think about.
It is?
I can't wait for
our naked plans.
But one more
night of anticipation,
doesn't have to
be the worst thing.
Hey.
Hi. Nathan.
No, I'm sorry. I have to cancel.
Urgh, I've had a tough day and
I'm just not up for any visitors.
Yes, let's try for tomorrow.
Okay. Good night.
Liam's gone?
You let his parents take him
home? He was my patient!
We can't keep a minor for
treatment against his parents' will,
especially when that treatment
goes against their religious beliefs.
They have a right to those
beliefs, and we have to respect that.
Of course! But maybe... wha...
what if his tumor starts to
bleed? What if he strokes out?
They signed an AMA
as soon as he woke up.
Look, the kid took a train all
by himself to ask us for help.
Actual help. Not prayers
and olive oil on his head.
No neurosurgeon will cut into a
kid's skull without parental consent.
Because it's illegal.
Can we get a court order?
State law protects
families from prosecution
if their faith prohibits them
from seeking medical care.
And I would think that you,
with your history, of all people,
would want to follow the
letter of the law right now.
- How'd it go?
- He didn't come over.
- Uh, why?
- I don't know,
but I heard her
call him and cancel,
and then she didn't come
out of her room the whole night.
- Were you eavesdropping?
- No.
Maybe.
I was curious.
Also, I was in the hall.
I figured I should move the big,
giant, scary tumor or something.
- I have a giant, scary tumor.
- What? I stayed up all night
studying it, and
I think I solved it.
Now you're telling me I could
have solved it from the comfort
of my own home, my
own bedroom, my own bed.
- I want a giant, scary tumor.
- Get your own.
I got to go see my patient.
All night?
I know.
Holly, I know other
doctors have failed you,
but they were not
thinking outside the box.
Now, I have studied your heart,
I've studied your tumor, and
I can get this. I know I can.
- Nope.
- Look...
You know, there's only six doctors
in the world that can do this surgery
and I am one of them?
Look, we have a shot.
No. No, you guys
look, I told you.
No revisiting. No
hatching new plans.
I told you, just
fix up my spleen,
and then send me
on my way, that's it.
Holly.
This could give
you your life back.
Yeah, but this is my
life. I don't need it back.
I don't need the white picket
fence and the bunch of kids
and dogs crawling all over
me or whatever kind of future
you think you could
give me because...
you can't.
I don't need a future. I have
exactly what I want right now.
Is this really what you want?
What I want is to, uh, is
to is to screw a blind man
after he's given me a
spectacular massage.
I want to have really
inappropriately loud sex
in one of those
sound bath domes.
And having surgery's gonna
get in the way with that, so...
thank you, but no.
Can you feel that?
Hold on one second.
Hey, there.
You okay?
I'm looking for Dr. Karev.
Well, I know Dr. Karev.
Liam? What are you doing...
Uh, I got this one. It's okay.
You okay? It's okay.
You're okay, um...
You must really like taking trains,
huh? Let's find you a place to sit.
Just follow me, okay?
Hey! Liam, I thought
you were right behind me.
You all right, buddy? You okay?
Hey, Liam, can you...
can you see me?
Hey, you're doing great.
Touch my finger.
Everything went dark so fast.
And I couldn't see.
Well, you're here
now. It's okay.
Apoplexy.
The tumor's bleeding, could be
pushing against the optic nerve.
- I'm so sorry.
- Honey.
- Why are you sorry?
- I promise, I tried.
I did what they said,
and I prayed and I prayed,
but it didn't work.
God didn't help me.
Can you help me, Dr. Karev?
Can you fix my eyes?
Take a deep breath.
Can you do that?
I promise, Liam, I'm gonna
do everything I can to help you.
But I need to talk to
Dr. Edwards first, okay?
Just wait right here.
Be right back.
What can we do without the
parents? We still need consent.
Not if it's emergent.
We need to page neuro
- and prep him for surgery.
- Shouldn't we page Dr. Minnick?
No. Because Liam
is, having a seizure.
- No, he's not.
- Yes, he is.
We can't... that's wrong.
Watching a kid die and
not helping is wrong.
Look, if he was having a seizure
right now, would you just watch?
He's having a seizure.
So we control it.
Book an O.R. and page Shepherd.
All right, then, I should be the
one to enter it. I'm the resident.
No, no, no.
We're using the
Minnick method today.
I write up the orders,
so I take the heat.
Remember to push,
uh... Lorazepam first.
And... and... and
turn him on his side.
- Right?
- Right.
And give him some Mannitol.
Holly, your hematocrits
have been stable.
- Looks like
the embolization worked.
- Good, 'cause this hospital
has a lot of attractive
men that I'd just as soon
as not proposition,
any of them until I get rid
of these tubes and wires.
She knows I can see her
hovering over there, right?
Hey, Holly, look.
I know you said you don't
want the tumor surgery,
- and I know that you're scared.
- No, but that's
the thing I'm not.
When I was first
diagnosed, sure.
But then I thought, what
would make me feel better?
Find a hot guy, have
a ridiculous night,
and then all would be well. So
I did that, and I kept doing that
until I realized, why
do anything else?
Sex and death.
That's want I want.
Well, you can say you're ready
for death a lot of people do but
as someone who's been around
a lot of death and
been left behind by it,
I can tell you,
trust me, you don't want that.
Especially when you have
someone like Dr. Pierce
telling you she can fix you, offering
you the impossible. Don't ignore that.
The scary thing isn't dying.
The scary thing is surviving
and accepting that you
actually have a life to live.
Don't you want to
stick around and live it?
You really think you
can get the tumor?
I told you I could get it.
I meant it.
Yeah, but other
doctors have meant it.
I'll put you on bypass.
And I'll remove your heart
so I can get all the tumor.
Dr. Grey, Dr. Kepner
will be there to assist.
Holly,
I can get the tumor out.
Go for it.
You sure?
- Yeah, do it.
- Okay.
Dr. Shepherd, I've got
Social Work paging you.
Almost done here. Basin.
Hey, is this Liam? Little Liam
with the religious parents?
- It is.
- I saw his name on the board,
and I couldn't believe it.
How did you get consent?
I didn't need it. He showed up
again and became emergent.
Did what we needed
to do to save his life.
- Karev!
- Is there something
I should know?
You opened this child's skull
without his parents knowing,
after what happened last time?
He seized in the E.R.
Dr. Shepherd, it's
Social Work again.
Nine-one-one. The
patient's parents are here.
- What happened last time?
- Nothing happened.
One of you, better
start talking, right now.
- So, you're holding him hostage?
- I understand
your anger, Mr. Fisher,
but your son just
had brain surgery.
This hospital cannot
release him yet.
It would put him at severe
risk for infection, even death.
She's right. He's
not even awake yet...
Don't you talk to me. You knew
where my wife and I stood on this.
- His intracranial pressure...
- You had no right to touch him!
Okay, if Dr. Karev hadn't
intervened when he had,
this would be an entirely,
different conversation.
Now, according to
Dr. Shepherd, Liam's tumor
was severely
affecting his vision.
It was only a matter of time...
- But he's okay now? He can see?
- Marie!
Dr. Shepherd was able to remove
the entire tumor from the optic nerve.
We'll have to wait till he's awake
to confirm his sight was restored.
Oh, baby.
I hope you enjoyed
practicing medicine,
'cause after I'm done suing
this place, you're all done.
- I know you did something.
- He had a seizure.
- Check his records.
- You could go to jail, Karev.
- Again.
- I'd go to jail for this one.
And, how many
fingers do you see?
Three?
That's right. You
got them all right.
You're doing great, Liam.
- Thank you.
- Aw.
You're very welcome.
- Dr. Edwards.
- Hm.
I will be back.
- It's time to start talking.
- I'm sorry?
Why did Dr. Karev
enter these orders?
He was following your
method. He let me run point.
So, he didn't give you orders to operate
on Liam without his parents' consent?
Like I said, I was
running point.
What did Karev do, Edwards?
- I need you to tell me exactly
what he did...
- Why? It's all in the chart.
We saved his life.
Liam is alive. He can
see, his tumor is out,
and he's alive.
That's the job, right?
Dividing the dome
of the left atrium.
What left atrium?
It's all tumor.
How does she even have
the stamina for all that sex
with this thing sitting on her
chest? When I get home from work,
I barely have the energy
to put on fuzzy socks.
Basin with ice.
Holly's just out there.
Doing anything she wants.
Anyone she wants. Any time.
- I'm kind of jealous.
- Of this? You're jealous of this?
Damn it.
It's invaded all the way to
her posterior pericardium.
Plan B.
Let's see if we can debulk this
tumor off the pulmonary veins.
Warren. Come with me.
Dr. Cohen to Oncology.
What do you see here?
Um, I see surgeries.
No, you see residents
doing surgeries.
- Where's your name?
- I'm covering the pit.
Exactly. You're
a senior resident.
You shouldn't be sewing up toes,
you should be repairing aortas.
Sir, I don't mind covering the
pit. I like going where I'm needed.
You're a surgeon. You're
needed in the operating room.
What you think Wilson and
Edwards stood back and waited
for a chance to
shine? No. They took it.
- Dr. Webber...
- Listen. I know what you can do.
But I'm not the only one making your
fellowship recommendation anymore.
There's a sense
you're playing it safe.
Laying back.
This is coming from Minnick?
You told her she's wrong?
Is she wrong?
You tell me.
Okay, we've freed it from
the pulmonary arteries.
Got to keep going down, gotta
keep following this tumor down.
What are you doing in
here? I've got tumor fever.
I had a brain surgery on a
young boy. Then I heard you had
a big, beautiful tumor
in here. Let me see.
That is massive. That
is a thing of beauty.
The Sistine Chapel of tumors.
It's invaded deep into
her posterior mediastinum.
These tumors aren't beautiful.
They're horrifying and smart
and designed to choke the life
out of someone before they have
- a chance to live.
- Exquisite.
What is it?
It's extended all the
way into her esophagus.
We can't reconstruct
her entire chest cavity.
If it's in her esophagus,
the chances are, it's
also invaded her spine.
You'd risk paralysis if
you tried to take it out.
Look, we can, at
least, remove the tumor
from the heart itself, relieve
some of the symptoms.
I mean, it'll grow back, but it'll be
slow growing, buy her some time.
Maggie...
I'll resect the esophagus
and create a spit fistula,
and then I'll come back
- and reconstruct and...
- But that's impossible.
Well, that's what
we told her we'd do.
We told her we would
do the impossible.
Right, but we'll be taking
away any quality of life she has.
I mean, it sounds awful to
say, but she's adapted to this.
She's learned to live with it.
You're saying I have
to tell her I can't do it?
Can we speed this up a
little? I want to get out of here.
This is getting
you out of here, sir.
I don't want you making any
more decisions for my child.
We didn't. Liam made decisions.
- We supported them.
- Liam is a kid. My kid.
- And that's not your job.
- No, that's yours. We did your job.
Your job is to protect your
child. You job is to keep him safe
and healthy, to tell him
everything will be all right, and then
to move Heaven and
Earth to make sure that it is.
That's your job, and
you couldn't do that.
That is not my job.
That is up to God.
If God did anything for Liam,
God delivered him safely
to us because He saw,
that He made you
so weak and so stupid
that you were going
to kill your child.
You're gonna burn in hell.
Based on what I saw today,
she needs to be suspended.
- Well, hold on now...
- Well, did she injure the man?
- It doesn't matter. Does it matter?
- I just can't believe this
- from Edwards?
- You can't? You yourself said,
her boyfriend died a
former patient of hers.
No counseling, no
support, no time off.
I told you, we watched
her. She showed no signs...
Students like her won't show you
what they need, until it's too late.
She works to the
exclusion of everything else.
She connects with
patients in the extreme
either overly
attached or stone cold.
And now this? These are
indications of resident burn out.
I just wanted to say, I
was not aiming for his head.
I was aiming for the
wall. I'm not stupid.
I was just mad.
- You don't wanna
be funny right now.
- I'm not being funny.
I'm not. I shouldn't
have done it. I was angry.
The patient was a child.
- A sick child.
- He was a little kid who didn't
have any help, at all.
I lost control.
And I'm sorry.
It's startling is what it is.
Edwards has been given
too long a rope, for too long,
and, I don't blame her. She's
a product of her environment.
Poor supervision or none
at all from Webber or Bailey.
And, Karev was
her attending today.
He's hardly a shining
example of restraint.
This is exactly why I
teach the way I teach...
Okay. I'm sorry, but I'm gonna
have to stop you right there.
- I'm sorry. I know he's your friend...
- Hey! Stop.
I'm wearing very sexy underwear
right now and I've been thinking
about tonight since last night.
All I want to do is take you home
and take off all of your clothes,
and the more that you talk
about Webber and Karev, the
less that I want to do any of that.
So, respectfully, shut up.
Just get in the car and
come home with me.
Jo? Uh, listen, do
you want to get a beer?
I have a teratoma excision at seven.
I have to read up on but... tomorrow?
Uh, yeah, yeah, sure, tomorrow.
- Hey, Jo?
- Yeah.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I am. I'm good, actually.
Talking to you is probably
one of the only good things
- to come out of this year.
- Andrew...
Hang on. This past year's
been rough for both of us.
- I know, and I'm sorry.
- You know what? I'm not.
I'm not sorry. 'Cause I feel
like we went through it together.
- I feel like...
- Stop.
Please.
I know what you're about to say.
I... I don't...
- I don't think you...
- And the second
that you say it...
Okay.
Uh...
I'll... I'll see you tomorrow.
His visual field
exam looks good.
We're expecting him
to make a full recovery.
Oh!
Liam made it all the way
to the hospital on his own.
Blind.
It was a miracle.
Or... someone helped him.
Someone drove him here.
The Lord helps those
who help themselves.
So, um...
my tumor's still in there.
I'm so sorry, Holly.
Oh, God, what
did I tell you guys?
Oh, you doctors,
you crazy people.
You just have to try, you
just have to cut people open.
Resecting the tumor
load out of your heart
will help your symptoms
and buy you time.
Yeah, this tumor, it's
just uh... it's part of me.
It's like my hair or my boobs,
or my weird looking toes.
I made room for it.
We just made you
do it, didn't we?
We just made you make us
feel better about ourselves.
It happens every time.
You're in trouble.
Consider yourself warned.
I'm raising my game.
From here on, I'm
gunning for you.
I'm stealing your surgeries,
taking the best services.
You can run, when
you turn around,
- I'm gonna be right
on your heels.
- I won't be there, so...
What do you mean?
What are you talking about?
My privileges got revoked.
I have to go to counseling.
For real?
- For how long?
- Have fun raising your game.
You'll actually have a
shot at beating mine now.
Hey, I'm glad I caught you
in the office. It's Dr. Karev,
Alex Karev.
No, I'm not in
any trouble, uh...
No, I... I don't need a lawyer.
Um, I... I need a referral.
I need to find a guy.
Uh, can you help me out?
Okay, yeah, one second.
Yeah?
The body adapts.
It protects itself.
But it can't close
off completely.
Or, we're not
really living, right?
I reject fuzzy socks tonight.
I need booze. Anyone
want to get a drink?
Yes, please. And
also, like, a man.
Like a nice, new,
attractive man.
- I don't want to fall in love.
- No, I don't want a boyfriend.
I just don't want to wait until
I'm dying before I let myself
- have some fun.
- You guys in?
- Not tonight.
- I don't know.
No doctors.
Strangers. Where would
Holly go? I'm gonna Yelp.
You guys have fun.
Oh, hey. How's Holly? Is
she awake? Can I see her?
Corey,
- the news is not good.
- Okay.
- It's time to let her go.
Oh, my God. She died?
No, I didn't say that.
But you're not going
to see her again.
Corey, hold the time you two
spent together close to your heart.
But don't let it hold you back.
No more sitting
here and waiting.
Grab your new life by the
hand and go out there and live it.
- Okay...
- Change is good.
So we leave the door
open, just a little...
Hi. Haven't see you all day.
Oh. You headed out?
- I am.
- Me too.
Hoping like hell
it's worth the risk.