I'm incising the uterine wall.
You're doing great, really
great. It's gonna be okay.
You promise?
Baby's out.
Umbilical clip. Suction.
Please, can I see my daughter?
Yes, of course.
Sorry. We'll need to
get her into surgery.
We'll take good care of her.
Your new chief
is fashionably late.
Our chief.
Just because I endorsed
Dr. Han to the Board
doesn't mean I don't
have any concerns.
Connections like Dr. Han's
come at a premium.
And he assures me,
will be well worth it
given our current predicament
with the Medical Board.
I'm not just worried
about the money.
When you pay that much,
they tend to think they're worth it.
Makes a person think
they don't have to show up
for their own welcome brunch.
Hi.
The baby's bowel protrusion seemed
less severe in the prenatal imaging.
And it'll have to wait until we're
done with her heart problem.
Now that I'm in here, her septum
looks more like Swiss cheese.
Page the on-call
neonatal cardiac surgeon.
That won't be
necessary, I'll scrub in.
And who are you?
I'm Jackson Han, your
new chief of surgery.
Echo probe, please.
And let's turn that music on.
Advance the delivery sheath.
It's in the patient's
heart, Dr. Murphy.
I think the music
is a little distracting.
I feel the same way about
operating without music.
Take a longer sheath and
Dr. Murphy will need some forceps.
Five-second rule?
It was a joke.
What about her bowels?
Why isn't Dr. Lim inserting it
into the abdomen right now?
There is not enough room...
There's not enough room without
increasing abdominal pressure,
which would critically
decrease blood flow to the bowel.
According to what
hemodynamic principle?
- Dr. Browne?
- Vascular impedance.
Blood flow is driven by the force
induced by the pressure gradient.
And how do you calculate it?
Uh... Um...
I'd have to look it up.
Eight times L-Nu,
divided by Pi-r-four.
Very good, Dr. Murphy.
That's also why this
occluder won't work.
It won't hold up against a huge
pressure gradient in her heart.
- Is there a fix?
- Long-term, I don't have one.
Right now, I need
umbilical tape and PE tubing.
You're making a
pulmonary artery band?
That should buy us some time
to come up with a plan
before we lose this baby.
You canceled my hernia repair?
With no advance
notice, sorry about that.
But so great to meet
you. Jackson Han.
- Neil Melendez.
- Oh, I know.
You did great work on that
piggyback heart transplant.
I need a consult on Minesh Goyal,
he's the founding CEO of a company...
- What's his diagnosis?
- He doesn't have one.
He's here for a full physical,
complete diagnostic workup.
I have a long-standing
executive wellness...
I'm a surgeon, not an internist.
I don't do preventative medicine.
No matter how rich the patient is.
You know what's great
about rich patients?
They allow us to
treat poor patients.
Also, I promised Minesh the very
best. So, really, who else am I gonna get?
BP is 110 over 70.
Jackson...
Dr. Han says great
things about you.
That's very kind.
Normal EKG, optimal BMI,
heart and lungs sound good.
Any reason you're worried
enough about your health
to endure an
entire day of tests?
I'm not worried.
Knowledge is power.
Whenever I enter a new market,
I learn everything I can
about the landscape,
consumer needs, target
market, competitors.
Are you aware your
body isn't a business?
I know I sound
like a rich lunatic
with fantasies about controlling
every aspect of my life.
And I guess I kind of am.
My dad was in good shape, too.
Until he dropped
dead on his daily jog.
Hi.
Hi. Hi, I'm Larry Childs.
I'd shake your hand, but you
know, no functioning immune system.
- Aaron. Hi.
- Good to meet you.
What flavor cancer do you have?
- What flavor?
- Yeah.
Glioma.
Shut the front
door. Brain or spine?
- Brain.
- Dude, we're tumor twins.
What...
What do they have you on?
Ooh. "Vincristine."
I hear that's intense.
My doc thought it
would wipe me out.
You doing okay or
longing for death?
I am hanging in
there. Thank you.
I'm on my third round
of Temozolomide.
I've seen you in
here a few times.
I've seen you in here a few times.
You kinda keep to yourself, huh?
Yeah.
Well, I'm happy to
introduce you around.
- It's a really friendly group.
- I'm okay, thank you.
You have a support
group you go to?
I do not.
Everyone needs a
cancer community.
And try to hold still.
Thank you.
For bringing us in.
This is the new chief's
patient, it's a great opportunity.
Or it's a bunch
of pointless tests.
For which I thank you.
Tell us about Dr. Han.
He's direct, charming,
very sure of himself.
Big ego.
There's nothing wrong with
an ego if you can back it up.
Dr. Han's arterial switch technique
is performed all over the world.
The tests aren't all pointless.
Way to stand firm, Park.
No, look at the
monitor. He has a tumor.
Percy's stable?
We're naming her Persephone.
Yes, I put in a central
line for nutrition.
Percy is stable right now.
We're looking for
solutions to her problems.
Wait? Why does...
Why does she have
all these birth defects?
Diane.
We spoke to her obstetrician.
She said these defects can
happen for no reason, right?
That's true.
Over 50% have no known cause.
I was taking Paroxetine
for clinical depression...
And you went off the meds as soon
as you found out you were pregnant.
She was five, six weeks at most.
My OB told me studies show
antidepressants are safe
to take during pregnancy.
But is that true, or
is she protecting me?
There was a study that associated
Paroxetine with these kinds of defects.
It is a possibility.
You can't tell whether
it's cancerous or benign?
Not until we do the biopsy,
which I've scheduled for later.
We'll know what's
going on by the morning.
Good. That's good.
Maybe you'd like
to call someone?
A family member, a friend?
I'll worry when I
know it's cancer.
We could use a transcatheter
route and patch each hole individually.
Her heart's the size of a walnut,
it's too small to maneuver inside.
A single large patch to close the
holes would withstand the pressure.
Yes.
It would also block
electrical conduction
causing deadly arrhythmias.
Dr. Murphy...
Did you tell the mom that she
caused her baby's birth defect?
No. I said that her
antidepressants could have.
Why did you tell her that?
It's the truth.
And is that relevant to her
current medical situation?
No.
And how do you think that
answer would make her feel?
What did you think would happen?
The mother is devastated.
The father is furious.
I would be, too.
Shaun is a resident.
Residents make mistakes.
Managing these parents'
emotional concerns
is as much a part of this job
as operating on their daughter.
Social cues are hard for Shaun,
but we've been working with him.
You should be focused
on your own shortcomings,
like retaining the formula
for vascular impedance.
Dr. Han...
We could patch each
individual hole in the heart
if we cut open the ventricle.
Don't change the
subject, Dr. Murphy.
I didn't, Dr. Han, we were
talking about the baby.
Really?
You don't see a difference in
the nature of your discussion
before I arrived and after?
We were talking about the baby.
They tried the approach you
suggested at LA Children's.
The baby died a week later.
The suture line didn't hold,
and the cardiac wall ruptured.
Keep looking.
Dr. Murphy, do not talk
with those parents again.
I'll walk with you.
You're pretty tough
on my residents.
Rebuking them in public, pimping
them with questions during surgery.
Shame-based
learning isn't my style.
I'll bear that in mind.
But this isn't about my
treatment of the residents.
You're concerned
about Dr. Murphy.
Well, a lot of doctors have less than
ideal bedside manner. He's young...
Would you ever have said something
like that to a patient as a resident?
As a med student?
And Murphy doesn't even
understand he did anything wrong.
Shaun has hardwired differences
in the way he perceives things.
Exactly. No matter how hard he works,
no matter how hard you try and help him,
his limitations are
not going to change.
He's going to continue to
inflict them on our patients.
All in the name of
diversity and inclusion.
Shaun deserves to be here.
Once you see what he's
capable of, you'll agree.
I look forward to
being proven wrong.
Stay seated for 20 minutes.
Don't want you
passing out in the lobby.
I know, I know, thank you.
This disease changed
my relationships,
changed my priorities,
changed who I am.
- Cancer is an identity.
- Cancer is a cellular mutation.
The people in this
room are my people.
What are you, 20 years
old? I'm triple your age.
I don't think
you're my "people."
Last time I hung out with my
law school friends, epic fail.
The fact that you use the phrase
"epic fail," kinda case in point.
They're all focused on what
firm they're gonna land at,
and I'm all about whether
Candice's leukemia is responding
to her new chemo regimen.
By the way, she has this peppermint
oil, it is great for headaches.
Ooh, I know that look.
Here, here.
Got you, brother,
whether you like it or not.
Show me where we are.
That angle runs pretty close
to the sacral nerve roots.
How we doing?
Tumor's abutting
the iliac artery.
I'm trying not to disrupt the entire
blood supply to his lower body.
Uh, Dr. Han, I'm Morgan Reznick.
I really enjoyed your article
on myotomy for infantile
hypertrophic pyloric stenosis.
I appreciate the thorough
research behind your sucking up.
And you are?
- Alex Park.
- Park. You were a cop.
Medicine as a second
career, good stuff.
Tends to bring a
fresh perspective.
I hit an artery.
Take the needle.
Blood's pooling in the pelvis.
Should we open him up? DR. - No.
Prep the femoral artery,
get me an art cath-set.
- Pressure's dropping.
- Platinum coil.
Nice save.
Next time, don't hit the vessel.
There is no next time.
The biopsy's too dangerous.
It is likely that it's a
benign notochord cell tumor.
They look like chordomas,
but they're harmless
- and way more common.
- But you don't know.
Since we can't
do the biopsy, no.
This is the problem
with broad testing.
Everyone has abnormalities,
most of them are nothing.
But when we do find them,
we have to make
some tough choices.
So, what exactly
is my tough choice?
We could remove the tumor.
This is a very risky surgery.
There's a chance
of paralysis or worse,
you may not make
it off the table.
Or you do nothing.
We'd continue to monitor it.
Do imaging every few weeks,
but chordomas move very quickly.
By the time any change
showed up on imaging,
it's most likely metastasized
throughout your body.
So, it probably isn't cancer,
but if it is, and I wait...
- Then I'll die.
- That's true.
And if I don't wait,
and I get the surgery, then
there's a good chance I'll die.
Yes.
I'm gonna need
to think this over.
This is the May Annals
of Neonatal Surgery.
I just finished March. I
need to read April now.
- I have April, Shaun.
- No.
No, you're supposed to be reading
New Approaches in Neonatal Surgery,
Claire has the British
Journal of Neonatology...
Shaun...
I think maybe you should be
quiet around Han for a little while.
But then how will I
answer his questions?
Direct questions,
absolutely answer.
Otherwise outside of the OR,
you should stay out of his way.
If someone had convinced
Shaun to do that with Dr. Melendez,
he would still be on suction.
Code blue, NICU bed four.
Her O2 sats dropped, and
central venous pressure shot up.
Pulmonary artery band is
failing. Eight of dopamine.
Let's get a mask on her.
She won't last much longer,
we need other options.
I'll update the parents.
Let's get her on
full cardiac support.
What do you got? Anything?
This Cleveland group repaired a
bowel protrusion using enterolysis.
I could cut out this
excess inflammatory tissue
and segment of bowel atresia,
might make her intestines
small enough to fit.
Promising.
Given the size of her abdomen,
I need to remove a lot of bowel.
There's a good chance she
wouldn't be able to absorb food.
We'll have to find the right
balance, it's our only workable plan.
Best bet on the heart is
to cut through the ventricle,
like Murphy suggested.
You were concerned
about the suture line holding.
Well, I still am.
But hopefully horizontal
mattress sutures will work.
They should be able
to withstand the
tension at the suture line.
There's still a risk
of an aneurysm
forming in the
tissue underneath.
Dr. Lim...
I have an idea I'd like to share
even though Dr. Han
didn't ask me a question.
Yeah, go ahead, Shaun.
If we go in through the atrium,
we wouldn't have to
worry about the suture line.
It's the same
issue we discussed.
There's not enough room
inside the baby's heart
to stitch the
patches into place.
So, we don't need to, Dr. Han.
We can make a plug
small enough for her heart.
A PTFE disc with a
stem like a mushroom,
then we can insert the stem
through one of the holes until the disc
presses against the
wall covering all the holes.
Like a stopper in a bathtub?
Yes. The higher pressure
on the left side of her heart
would keep it in place.
We wouldn't even need to stitch.
Great idea.
We should take
this to the parents.
Great idea for the heart.
But we need to tell
them that our current plan
for the abdominal repair is
considerably more of a long shot.
And that fixing the heart,
takes an option off the table.
Withdrawing care.
You can't move that card.
- Excuse me?
- Who cheats at solitaire?
You're literally only
cheating yourself.
Again.
- Good morning, Larry.
- Is it a macho thing?
Like a real man should
be able to make it through
without leaning on a label
or the people who go with it?
Embracing cancer as an identity
is the last thing any one
of us should be doing.
It underscores everything
horrible right now.
We're in a daily
battle for our lives.
I see no value in
dwelling on that.
Candice is late.
Which means either her
niece forgot to pick her up...
Again.
Or she got some bad news.
Or she's already dead.
We are in a daily battle.
I'd rather have some company.
I spoke to my
mother and brother,
and they both think I
shouldn't do the surgery.
Apparently, they're more
scared of your surgical skills
than they are of this tumor.
And where do you stand?
- I need numbers.
- Please.
The stats on something like
this. There are a lot of variables...
But what are the odds I
make it through the surgery
without any complications?
It's a challenging procedure.
Zero complications, I'd say 80%.
But it is very unlikely
this tumor is malignant.
Give me a number.
About 5% chance it's a chordoma.
The numbers agree
with your family. So do I.
I've always been more
comfortable with action than inaction.
I want you to do the surgery.
Certainty comes at a price.
She'll be able to get off
the life support machines?
If everything goes well, yes,
she'll have a strong heart.
How soon can you do it?
You should know we feel less
confident about our plan for her bowel.
The chance of
failure is quite high.
How high?
I put it at 90% that
the repair won't work.
Which would lead to
irreversible malnutrition.
Your daughter would slowly
starve to death over months.
Right now, her body is working
very hard just to stay alive.
If we were to turn
off the machines...
Turn off the machines?
She would pass
quickly and peacefully.
If the heart surgery is a
success, that won't be an option.
Why not try to fix the
bowel first to see if it works?
We won't know if the bowel
is viable until after the heart is.
We have to do the surgery.
But if this doesn't work,
she could starve to death.
- It's worth the risk...
- It's not our risk, it's hers.
So instead you're ready
to give up on our daughter?
I mean, it's like we're
right back at the ultrasound.
We decided together to
continue this pregnancy.
So, this is as much
my fault as it is yours.
My fault? Because
of the medication?
I cannot turn off that machine.
Your guilt is stopping you from
admitting what we need to do.
My guilt has nothing
to do with this.
I am fighting for my daughter.
So am I.
Since the parents can't agree,
the decision about the baby's care
will be made by a judge who
will rely on our recommendation.
So, we make the choice,
but the parents live with it?
Well, maybe that's a good thing.
For parents to have to decide
between letting their daughter die
or fighting for her life knowing
she may suffer horribly,
maybe it's better if
we carry that burden.
Dr. Lim, your decision would be?
Take her off life support.
The odds are stacked against
the bowel repair working.
Those numbers reflect the
general population of doctors.
I think Dr. Lim and I
are better than that.
We can beat the odds.
One of the things I'm not going to
miss about being chief of surgery
is being responsible
for choices like this.
Dr. Han, it's your
department, it's your call.
You've been here all night?
I've been working on a case with
the new chief of surgery, Dr. Han.
- How's that going?
- Not very well.
He plays music in
the operating room.
Oh, jeez, one of those.
And he says I need to focus
on our patients' emotional needs.
Well, that's a tough
assignment for you.
Hmm.
You ever wish you had, you know,
friends, co-workers
on the spectrum?
Not usually,
but maybe Dr. Han
wouldn't notice me as much
if I weren't the only
doctor with ASD.
There's this kid
in chemo, just...
Obsessed with having
cancer. It's all he talks about,
he wants to be friends
with everybody in the ward.
That's very smart of him.
Spiegel et al showed an
increase in overall survival
and quality of life measures
in breast cancer patients
who formed social bonds
with others battling the disease.
What should I do about Dr. Han?
I don't know. Um...
Just do your work...
Be a good surgeon,
be an excellent surgeon.
Over time, he'll forget
about the autism.
Why would that happen?
He'll see that you have the
skill, you have dedication.
I have autism, it's
part of who I am.
The judge?
Accepted our recommendation
and ruled in favor of surgery.
Thank you, Doctor.
Okay, Percy.
Momma loves you.
I love you, Percy.
Should we remove more bowel?
That would take us to the ilium.
She won't gain
enough weight to thrive.
Her abdominal muscles are tight
from developing around an empty cavity.
They're cinched around
her tummy like a corset.
What if we unbuttoned it?
Released the muscle and increased
the abdominal circumference.
- Those muscles are part of her...
- Not if we separate the layers.
Create a plane between
the skin and the muscle.
You good if Murphy
and I start on the heart?
Dr. Browne, you're
with me on the abdomen.
Clearing the field.
Han is on the call
schedule next weekend.
Maybe Carmen will switch
with me, so I can cover with him?
Or maybe you
shouldn't try so hard.
Retractor.
Some of us don't have
a cool former career,
or an easy-going,
mellow demeanor.
People are never gonna crowd my
corner because I'm just so likeable.
Or you could try
being nice to them.
- This is easier.
- There it is.
Does it look like cancer?
It's not labeled.
We're all gonna have to wait
for the pathologist's report.
Probe.
The artery's in the way.
We can't get at the tumor
without him bleeding out.
We're gonna have to
take it from the back.
- But the S1 nerve root...
- Is something he can live without.
Dissecting scissors.
Pledget anchor.
The plug is in position. You
ready to test the bowel repair?
Let's take her off
cardiac support.
Dr. Murphy, it was your
idea, you do the honors.
Abdominal pressure is normal.
Intestines are perfusing.
Pulmonary pressure's spiking.
Prostacyclin and nitric oxide,
we need to get her
lung pressure down.
Oxygen sats are dropping.
No response to
pulmonary vasodilators.
The heart's too strong,
it's overpowering her lungs.
She needs to go back
on cardiac support.
Persephone won't
starve to death,
but she will drown
in her own fluids.
- I'll talk to the parents.
- May I come?
Now that Persephone's
heart is pumping at full power,
her lungs are overwhelmed.
The humane thing to do is to
turn off the machines and let her go.
No, I can't...
I can't give up on her.
Because you've fought for her
every minute since she was born?
Before that, when you were taking
your medication for the depression,
you were fighting to keep going,
so you could bring
her into the world.
Then letting go of Percy
is not giving up on her.
It's listening to what
her body is telling us.
She's hit her limit.
Okay.
I want Persephone to look as
good as possible for the parents.
Let's turn off cardiac support.
Ventilator.
Let's take a minute.
Check valve.
Every time the heart contracted,
blood went into the opposite side of
the heart and raised lung pressure.
The hole reduced the pressure
when it got too high,
because it allowed backflow.
But our repair of the defect
blocked this backwards flow.
What if we made it so
she still had a heart defect,
but only when she needed it?
And it'd be like an unlatched
door in the wall of the heart.
When the pressure gets
too high on the right side,
the door swings open, releasing
the pressure on the lungs.
The rest of the
time, it stays shut.
It should reduce lung pressure
by a third, is that enough?
Depends on how high her
pulmonary vascular resistance is.
PVR is pulmonary artery
pressure, minus wedge pressure,
divided by cardiac
output, times 80.
The last time I saw my doctor,
he told me I had six months to live.
He also told me I should
marry an accountant
and move to North Dakota.
You don't say.
I asked if it would help
with my cancer, and he said,
"Nope, it would just make the
six months seem much longer."
What's the difference between
a neo-Nazi and cancer?
Cancer doesn't discriminate.
I knew a guy once,
his Zodiac sign was Cancer,
it was really ironic how he died.
- Uh... How's that?
- He was eaten by a giant crab.
Aaron, glioma.
Candice, leukemia.
Gin Rummy or Blackjack? How
fast do you wanna take my money?
- Blackjack.
- Cut 'em.
Did you get it all?
Yes, totally clear margins.
But the only way to achieve that
involved removing the nerve
that controls your left foot.
Rehab and an advanced
orthotic may help,
but you will walk with a limp.
Final pathology will let
us know if it was worth it.
I'll let you know
when it comes in.
It doesn't matter anymore.
It's not like you can
put the tumor back in.
Is she okay?
She still has a surgery or
two in her future, but, yes.
She's gonna be great.
Can I hold her?
I think that would be
very nice, for both of you.
Hi, angel.
My baby.
Come, hold her.
You were fighting for her, too.
She's beautiful.
Nice work.
Thank you.
She's beautiful.
Listen to her.
Thank you.
Minesh's biopsy results?
You don't wanna know if we
wasted our time almost killing him?
Can't put the tumor back.
Hello, Dr. Han. You
take the bus, too?
No, Shaun, I just
wanted to talk to you.
You really do have
remarkable diagnostic skills.
I have to admit, you're
an asset to this hospital.
Yes, I am.
I spoke to the residency
director of pathology.
And we both agree
you'll be a great fit there.
I'm a surgical resident.
Well, as a pathology resident
you'll touch cases and lives across
all of the medical departments.
It's an opportunity
for you to help patients
without having to
deal with patients.
Given your difficulties with
communication and social cues,
I think it will be
a much better fit.
No, thank you.
I have been working very
hard at my communication skills.
Hard work isn't enough.
You have to do the job.
I am a surgical resident.
You were.
And you're gonna do
great work in pathology.
Oh, and when the storms
come Flooding through the hall
Rising to the landing
Tearing pictures from the walls
The currents pull us underneath
That bright tide ripped us out
Into a tangled coral reef
Where we will never drown
Now that we're at the end