Previously on ER:
You should come to
my bible group sometime.
Bible group? Okay.
Do you think I wanna wait for you to
find out that he's jerking you around?
You're making me think about
the way I want my life to be.
This is Ben Parker.
He's the new RN.
- Let me take you out to dinner.
- Like a date?
We used to run into
homeless kids like this.
- Please, just help Paulie.
- I can't. Paulie's very sick.
I know your secret name. Mayday.
And there's a crazy,
angry guy following us?
Listen to me, Ames.
Come near my family
again, I'll kill you.
It was kind of fun until the chemo
kid called me Rudolph's skank.
One of them asked me if
you were Sleepy or Sneezy.
What? I'm an elf, I'm
not a freaking dwarf.
- Oh, my God.
- Nice antlers.
You guys look so cute.
I gotta get my camera.
No, that's okay, really.
- Was it fun at least?
- Yeah.
Pedes was a war zone.
Heard you lost the pool, sorry.
- Yeah.
- That's one hot-looking dwarf you got.
- Know what? I'm an elf, damn it.
Whoa. Oh, hey.
As we commemorate
the birth of Jesus...
I find myself contemplating
the vices I've been guilty of.
And also the virtues...
that I, that all of us born in sin and
striving for sanctity should aspire to.
Turning our pride to humility.
Our envy to compassion.
Our anger to mercy.
Our laziness to activity.
Our greed to generosity.
Our gluttony to moderation.
And last but not least, our
lust must be turned to...?
Archie?
Um...
Consummation?
Yeah, no, no, seriously.
Our lust must be
turned to purity?
Uh... Well, I was looking for
chastity, but talk about purity a little.
Well, you know, I've always
taken it to mean purity of spirit...
as opposed to a
literal, corporal purity.
Go on.
Uh... Well, you know, we
all live in the modern world.
Right?
And our virtuousness
shouldn't be locked...
into some antiquated
notion of abstinence.
Should it?
- Shouldn't it?
- So...
You're saying that you
can be sexually active...
and still retain moral purity?
Not just me, sister, if
you know what I'm saying.
Yes. Yeah.
Look, well, no, no.
Because what I'm actually saying
is, at the end of the day, it's just...
It's just us in the mirror...
and we're the ones who
determine our own moral value.
And to me, that's what
Christmas is all about.
So you're not mad at me anymore?
This is the first time in a
week I've seen you smile.
Well, the holiday spirit is just so
infectious, I couldn't help myself...
and I was waiting
for you to lighten up.
Really?
I was waiting for you.
Don't try to be charming
in that ridiculous outfit.
Who, me? Charming?
Back off, Rudolph.
- Be nice.
- You be nice.
Or you're not gonna
get your special present.
What kind of present?
A slightly naughty one.
My favorite kind.
Dr. Kovac?
Sorry. You got a minute?
Yeah, sure. Sure, yeah.
It's about Curtis Ames.
He's filed an order of
protection against you.
- A restraining order.
- That's ridiculous.
Yeah, the judge who
issued it doesn't think so.
- The guy says you threatened to kill him.
- What?
Look, you should've let it go, doc.
Now you look like the crazy one.
Rufus Taylor, 35.
Going 60 on Dan Ryan,
crashed into an embankment.
Icicle shattered the
windshield, I couldn't see.
Icicle, huh?
Came out of nowhere.
It was really big.
- Anything hurt, man?
- My stomach.
Trauma 1, let's go. Gates,
what's the RTS on this guy?
- The what?
- RTS. Revised Trauma Score.
It correlates better than
GCS for traumatic brain injury.
- Traumatic brain what?
- You'll be fine, sir.
What's the matter with you?
My shift was over. I couldn't
leave because you weren't here.
Five minutes late. All right,
10 minutes. I'm here, now go.
You have remedial command
of basics. I can't leave you.
I would love to, believe me,
but it wouldn't be right, all right?
Yeah. What are they gonna
say about it now, right?
Hey, merry Christmas, Neela.
- Where have you been?
- On the floor.
- I thought we were rounding.
- What? No.
The Surgery Christmas
Party is the one time of year...
when we can forget
about disease and death...
and celebrate
goodness, kindness.
I admit I would prefer black
tie, sashimi and Veuve Clicquot...
but still, it's Christmas.
I love it.
- Yeah.
- Are you all right?
Sorry, it's gotta be this punch.
There's nothing even remotely
alcoholic in the punch, Dustin.
Right. Okay. Gotta go.
Neela, I want you to
meet Manish Mehta.
- He's gonna be helping us around here.
- Hi.
Can I get everybody's
attention for a second, please?
Everybody, listen up for a sec.
Thanks.
Listen, it's fitting and
appropriate at this time of charity...
and compassion for me
to be able to announce...
the opening of Chicago's
only paired exchange program.
Yeah.
And as an additional
Yuletide treat...
we will be doing our
first kidney swap today.
Why don't we all get back to work
before we crash from the sugar high?
- Nice to meet you.
- You too.
Neela. Hi.
Rob, you guys know
each other, right?
Neela Rasgotra, I've
heard a lot about you.
- You have?
- You're the golden girl...
Dubenko created a special
residency spot for. That's memorable.
God, you must
really be something.
Okay, then. It's nice
to meet you, Rob.
No, the pleasure's all mine.
Would you excuse me a minute?
- You went to where Ames works?
- The police wouldn't do anything.
And you threatened to kill him,
and I'm the one who overreacted?
- You think I made this up?
- I think you got carried away.
I went to his work to
stop and scare him.
Mission accomplished.
He's scared. He can have
you arrested if you get near him.
Look, I didn't know
what else to do, okay?
I did it because I love
you, and I love Joe...
and I wasn't gonna let that
asshole keep threatening us, okay?
So it wasn't too geeky, was it?
Geeky? Lord, no. Or God, no.
I mean, no. No, I
enjoyed your Bible group.
They were impressed by you.
Yeah, what you said
was really advanced.
- Really? You think?
- Yeah, I do.
Oh, doughnuts. Ha-ha!
The perks of authority.
No, no, no. What
does this look like?
- Gluttony?
- Gluttony, exactly.
I was just testing you. I'm
gonna save these for the kids.
Lenore Simkins, found down on
the street on 18th and Aberdeen.
Pulse ox is 91, looks like
frostbite on the fingertips.
- Cold out there.
- Hi, Lenore. I'm Dr. Morris.
I'd wish you merry Christmas
but as an employee of County...
I'm duty-bound to respect the
separation of church and state.
Are you kidding?
- Is he kidding?
- I think so.
- Hey.
- Got plans tonight?
- Yeah.
Yeah, me too. With Ray.
That's cool, right?
- It's none of my business.
- Okay.
I just wanted to be sure.
You look annoyed.
Well, your friend from Vascular
went in almost 10 minutes ago.
Yeah, I could tell you kind
of aggravated his problem.
What problem?
Rob's got a little
auto-stimulation issue.
You know, he can't help tickling
the Elmo, spanking his monkey.
- It's how he got his nickname.
- What nickname?
We call him McCreamy.
McCreamy?
Hey, guys. Sorry about the wait.
It's okay.
God, it was great to
finally meet you, Neela.
I hope we get to
work together soon.
I gotta go.
- How's that, Lenore? Better?
- Mm-hm.
What are you doing
for the holidays?
Besides taking my kid to go
see Return of the Evil Zombies?
Maybe before you go home,
you can let me buy you that drink?
I don't know. I got
presents to wrap.
- Lenore, were you recently hospitalized?
- I was at City of Mercy till last night.
- What for?
- Chest cold.
Winter's been hard.
How long were you there?
Few days? I'm
not good with time.
Did they release you?
The lady at the hospital said the
ambulance was gonna take me back.
- Back home?
- Don't got one.
I make my own way.
Where'd they drop you off?
They left me in an
alley near 18th Street.
I haven't slept in that
neighborhood in years.
Second unit's infusing now?
I need sterile 10s and a
cordis. He needs central access.
- This is not good. I'll handle this.
- I know how to put in a line, Ray.
Mr. Taylor, we need to do an operation
to stop bleeding in your abdomen.
- Is there someone you want to be here?
- No. You sure this can't wait?
I don't really want
this. Not today.
It's okay, you'll be fine.
It's just, my karma's
not so good right now.
It's not the best time
to go under the knife.
Don't worry, sir.
Here, we treat the naughty as
well as the nice all year round.
We'll take good care of you.
I promise this
is the best thing.
Mayday.
O.R. 2. Dubenko
should be waiting.
Mayday.
Go on, I'll be right up.
- Lizzie's sick.
- We were worried about you.
Lizzie's sick. You need to come.
Your friend? Does she
have what Paulie had?
I don't know. You need to come.
- All right, wait there.
- Pick up the old chart from Records.
- Get the echo from CICU.
- What about the toilet bowls?
- I haven't scrubbed them yet.
- Come with me a minute?
- Oh, thank God.
- Where do you think you're going?
Do you have a toenail extraction
you want me to take notes on?
- Are you too advanced for this?
- If we have problem, spit it out.
- I don't speak bitchy.
- Oh, you seem pretty fluent to me.
- Get somebody else, my intern's busy.
- Stop being an idiot, I need Tony's help.
And you too, I've had enough.
Why don't you either
slap each other silly...
or kiss now and
get it over with?
She got bad last night.
Pains everywhere.
Tell me where, I'll
send an ambulance.
- No. I'll take you.
- Doesn't work like that.
Please. You helped Paulie.
You heard about Paulie?
I came back a few days after.
The man at the desk said
he was at the care unit.
That's good, right?
Come on.
If she's sick, she
needs to be in hospital.
She can't walk and she
won't go to a family again.
Teller.
You come. Mayday and you.
- She can't. We can't.
- You have to.
Or else I'm scared
Lizzie's gonna pass.
All right, I'm out of here.
What? No. What? You can't go.
I got no Kovac, no Weaver,
no Pratt. I'm flying without a net.
I'd prefer to be outside of the ER
when it crashes and burns to the ground.
That's what Vegas
oddsmakers say will happen...
the first time you're the
only Attending on the floor.
Melia. What are you doing here?
Daddy.
Daddy?
Great, another one of
Morris's Petri-dish kids.
- What, Morris has kids?
- Four that we know of.
Hope, could you please...
- Right.
No, I will take her to the break
room, get her all settled in, come on.
Read her a story or something.
Hey, Morris, it's important.
I need a half-hour.
- Okay.
- It's slow, you can spare...
- Did you just say okay?
- Me, you're trying to leverage.
Him, you just let go?
- You're a Resident, he's an intern.
- I have a date.
So? My daughter's
here, Ray. My daughter.
You don't see me shirking.
Fine, go. I'm already over you.
Hey, Sam. You have a car?
I heard snow, I took the train.
- Truck's in the shop, bro.
- I gotta check on a patient for Neela.
Can I talk to your supervisor?
- Hey, what about Malik? Is he around?
- No, he's not in today.
This is the second time I've
called. Can you ask her to call me?
Sam Taggart.
Mercy said she walked out
on her own, as far as they know.
Some administrator's
gonna get into it.
Looks like they already have.
What? Hey, hey,
hey, where you going?
- She's not ready for transfer.
- You the nurse on this?
We're from Mercy.
- We're gonna take her.
- What?
Supervisor said it was
a misunderstanding.
Are you taking me outside?
No. You're not taking her until
somebody explains what's going on.
A patient ended up in the wrong place.
Let's not blow this out of proportion.
No, you heard the
lady. Turn it around.
- How far is this place?
- Just across the bridge.
Hey, watch it, jerk-off.
I heard you needed a ride.
What does the pancreas do?
It makes hormones that help
you process sugar in your blood.
- What are hormones?
- Well...
Whoa, whoa. Okay, okay. You'll
find out about that soon enough.
I was thinking
Dr. Seuss, not Dr. Rosen.
It's okay. I like gross stuff.
Honey, Melia, it is so good to
see you. What are you doing here?
I ran away.
Why, sweetie?
Because of Donald,
Mom's new husband.
He won't let me celebrate Christmas.
He says there's no such thing as Santa.
No. He didn't.
He says there's no
elves, no reindeer...
and Christmas is made up
so people will spend money.
No, that's crazy.
So I decided I would spend
the holiday with my real dad.
That's you.
Crystal meth is
some nasty stuff.
Makes you lie,
makes you paranoid.
I'm clean now.
Good for you.
It's too late.
My wife, my kids, moved
away as far as they could.
I messed up so much.
I missed so much
when I was high.
This is where they live.
Oliver is 11 now,
and Julia is 9.
They've gone so many years
without hearing from me on Christmas.
Mr. Taylor.
I fully expect this
surgery to be a success.
I know but if you're wrong...
promise me you'll
send them something.
It won't be necessary. But okay.
Thank you. Thank you.
We should call this in.
This girl's really messed up.
If you make anybody come,
we'll just run away someplace else.
It will be fine.
Stop. It's here.
Hurry.
What the hell are we doing?
We're helping kids, Ray.
It's down here.
I love what you've
done with the place.
Follow me.
That's great.
A big old mouse hole.
- Jejunum looks good.
- So does the liver.
Lucien, Victoria's
on the phone again.
Wants to know if you'd like her
to wear blue dress or red dress.
Tell her the blue is nice.
Ileocecal junction's clear.
- Hot date tonight?
- Something like that.
BP is down, 86/40.
Retroperitoneum feels tense.
Bovie to Neela, open it up.
Tachy to 120. DUBENKO:
Hang the blood on the infuser.
Whoa. Suction, now.
He's bleeding out. - Satinsky.
Packing. Keep it coming.
- Five-0 Prolene.
One Castroviejos.
PEA, lost the pulse.
Starting compressions.
Amp of epi and call for blood.
It's too fast,
there's no way to...
Oh, crap, it's here. Sponge
stick times two, let's go.
Five-0 Prolene to me.
Drop pressure.
Up above and below.
Okay, release pressure.
Repair's holding.
Stop CPR.
Normal sinus.
- Good pulse.
- Well, strong work, Dr. Rasgotra.
Once you've seen one supraceliac
aortic tear, you've seen them all.
Don't be scared, it's safe.
Oh, thanks. I feel
so much better now.
Ray, I'm sure you've played
gigs in worse places than this.
Oh, God.
Come on.
- Teller's back.
- Who's with him?
You said you'd get Mayday.
It's okay. He
helped save Paulie.
She's diaphoretic.
Please, please, make this go away.
- Yeah, and tachycardic.
Hey, Lizzie, do you
know what day it is?
- It's Christmas. RAY: It's
close enough. She's lucid.
She's pregnant.
She's very pregnant.
The baby's crowning.
I'm sorry. I don't know
how this happened.
Lizzie, give it your
all. Come on, push.
- I can't. GATES: Yes,
you can. Attagirl, come on.
- Attagirl.
- Teller! Teller!
- Who's this baby's father?
- It doesn't have a father.
- Of course it does.
- Lizzie will get the men to help us.
- Ruby, quiet.
- Ray, the shoulder's stuck.
Please get it out. I can't!
- Firm, downward pressure on the head.
- I am. I am.
- Wanna take a shot at it?
- Okay.
All right. Here.
What was she talking
about? What men?
The Greek gives us
food from the restaurant.
The cripple lets us sleep in
the basement when it's cold.
Lizzie takes care of them
and they take care of us.
Okay. All right, here we go.
Here we go. Here we go.
All right. Okay. It's a boy.
It's a boy. It's a boy.
Here you go. Okay.
Here you go, okay?
Hold the head.
All right.
There you go.
He's mine?
He's so tiny.
- What are you doing?
- Calling for help.
Teller, get them and run.
You and your baby need
to be seen by a doctor.
- You're a doctor.
- But we can't do what they need here.
- Teller, get them and go.
- It's okay, guys.
- Teller, go.
- Okay, I won't, I won't, I won't.
You guys need to
spend the night in the ER.
You, Lizzie and the
baby. Just the three of you.
Gates, they all need to come.
They look jaundiced,
anemic, they got...
Others can stay. I won't call
foster care or Social Services.
Gates, what are you doing?
- Promise?
- Yeah, promise.
He lost a lot of blood. It could be a while
before we know his neurologic outcome.
I know.
Where are you
spending Christmas?
Oh, I spend the holidays
with my sister every year.
That's sweet. Older or younger?
Both, actually.
Two years older
but stuck at 17...
in a car wreck the night of her
prom. Her boyfriend was drunk.
That's awful.
It could've been worse, though.
She's in an independent
living facility in Evanston.
I see her fairly frequently.
In fact, I gotta get out of here.
We have a nice dinner tonight.
She likes to dress up.
Your oxygen level's back up.
Am I gonna be able to stay here?
You're getting better, you don't
really need to be hospitalized anymore.
Is there somewhere
that you'd like to go?
Not the street.
Not tonight.
Got any family?
Well, my parents are in
Gary, Indiana, where I grew up.
But we haven't
talked in a long time.
I don't know if they'd
even recognize me.
I'll be back to check on
you in a little bit, okay?
Any word from Mercy?
Not yet.
Poor lady's all
alone in the world.
At least we can clean her up...
set her up with new
clothes for Christmas.
I'll see what I can do.
Hey, Sam, Drunk Santa
needs a banana bag...
and a few hours to sleep it off.
Oh, that is such a shame.
Yeah, sloth, sloth, sloth.
Fifteen-year-old,
postpartum, needs stitches...
little newborn baby,
warmer and Pedes consult.
- Where'd you find them?
- We followed a star in the northern sky.
Okay, Trauma 2.
Children's Services is
on their way. I called up.
- You did what?
- You'll be okay, Teller.
You promised.
- Gates.
- What?
- You swore you wouldn't force them.
- I got them here, didn't I?
You said we could trust you.
That's... Nice job, Gates.
You from Mercy?
Nurse Taggart? Hillary Lerner.
Is it your policy to dump
destitute patients on the street?
- Why would we do that?
- It's bad for your neighborhood.
- No, there was a mistake with Miss...
- Simkins?
- Lenore Simkins.
- Yes. That's why I sent my people...
I'm not gonna release her...
so you can have a second
chance to make her disappear.
- I don't know what she told you...
- Come with me.
You behaved badly, so
here's your lump of coal, okay?
You have your boys take Ms. Simkins
to her parents' place in Gary, Indiana.
Gary? That's over an hour away.
You'll pay for the round trip,
and this will never happen again.
Because I ever get wind of a patient
being dumped by your hospital...
I will call the cops
so fast I'm not sure
if you're gonna get
fired or arrested first.
Yeah. Got it.
Hey, Lenore. This is Hillary.
She's gonna make sure you get
to see your parents for Christmas.
We, by which I mean to say
Dr. Gates, promised no foster care.
Well, that would be a mistake.
By law, they need to be placed.
Getting them to give
up the life they have...
- that takes a light touch, Ray.
- Is that what you call lying?
I wasn't gonna take a
chance on losing them.
You turned us into
every bad adult...
- that these kids were ever screwed by.
- That's so sweet and so naive.
I'll send a van to pick
up the other children.
- Good.
- If you pick them up today...
they'll be gone tomorrow.
These kids won't just submit.
Need to be convinced that
they'll be safe and protected.
We'll try to keep them together.
I can't promise they
won't end up in foster care.
- But you'll make sure they're okay, right?
- We always do.
Come on. These kids are smart.
They know that that's not how it goes.
A social worker will follow
up. It's the best I can do.
No, no, no. That's
not good enough.
I can't believe you got
CPS to agree to that.
Actually, it was
Ray's brainstorm.
The trick's getting
the kids to accept it.
Teller. Listen.
Child Protective Services...
has arranged for all of you to
live together in a group home.
- You said no foster care.
- Hear us out, Teller...
- Wait, Teller, Teller.
- No, I won't go. You lied!
It's not safe out
there, all right?
We survive. No one hurts us.
What Lizzie's doing, having
sex for money and shelter?
- That's hurting her. Hurting all of you.
- Don't say that!
If you weren't sleeping in
old abandoned buildings...
Paulie would have
never gotten sick.
But you fixed him.
He's getting better.
No, we didn't.
Paulie died.
I'm sorry. I wanted
to tell you his...
His infection was too severe
and we couldn't save him but...
I wanna see him.
I know I lied to you. I'm
not gonna lie anymore.
I don't believe you.
It's not working. The way
you're living is not working.
- You're a smart kid. You can see that.
- Let go, let go.
Listen to me. You can't
go on like this anymore.
Teller...
Lizzie agreed to go.
It's the only way she
can keep her baby.
And the rest of us will
just stay with them?
That's right.
And Dr. Gates will come
and visit every two weeks...
and make sure things
are okay, all right?
You need me for anything at any
time, you call me, and I'll be there.
You would do that?
Yeah.
Listen.
Now, I need you to take the social
workers to where the others are.
And let the kids know that
it's okay and safe to come in.
Will you do that?
I'll wait with you
here, Teller. Come on.
Thank you.
Well, that went better
than expected, huh?
Yeah?
That kid may not survive
another round of your games.
Come on, I've been
trying to help the kid all day.
Gates, you'll say
anything to seal the deal.
I understand that. I've done that.
But these are messed-up kids.
- You gotta draw the line somewhere.
- And what line is that?
If you're making promises you
have no intention of keeping...
just cut loose.
Minimize the damage, okay?
This isn't just
about the kids, is it?
No, it's not.
Hey, how about you give me a
few hours to wrap some presents?
- Can we talk?
- Sure.
This scares me.
What, Ames?
What it's doing to you.
To us.
It took us so long to get here.
All of us.
And the way you're acting, how
it's taking over our whole lives...
it makes me scared
we're gonna lose this.
When Jasna and the kids died...
I needed to make a change
and I decided to move here.
Made my brother really angry.
He said...
He said that I was a coward
and that I was running away.
And it's only recently that I've
come to know that he was wrong.
I wasn't running
away from anything.
I was running to you.
And I'll never let
anything take this away.
Did I mention how
hot you look in antlers?
- I think she's in here, Santa.
- Ho, ho, ho!
Has anyone seen a little
girl named Melia Simon?
That's her right there.
Oh, my reindeer needed a little rest,
so I thought I'd come by and say hi.
How do you do? I'm Santa Claus.
Hi, Santa.
Can't stay long,
very, very busy.
Gotta deliver presents to the
whole western hemisphere tonight.
Nice try, Archie.
I know it's you.
Archie? Who's Archie?
I'm 9 years old. I know
there's no Santa, okay?
You know, you're
a bright girl, Melia.
But you're wrong about that.
It's a fake beard
and a dumb suit.
Don't you know
that there's a rule...
that if millions of kids believe in
the same thing, it becomes real?
- That's not a rule.
- Yeah.
Every time you're generous or thoughtful
or help someone who needs help...
that's a little
bit of Santa too.
What are you talking about?
Come on.
Santa Claus represents one of
the last remaining bits of magic...
left in this world.
Now, I still believe, so
don't spoil it for me, okay?
Come on.
Where we going?
Ho, ho, ho, ho, ho!
Wait, it's Santa.
Oh, you were a very,
very nice girl this year.
Top of the nice list.
Would it be all right
if I signed your cast?
Thank you.
To Greta...
Keep on being nice.
Love, Santa.
How'd you know my name?
Come on, I'm Santa Claus, huh?
Merry Christmas.
It's the real Santa, isn't it?
Yeah.
It is.
You lost almost a third
of your blood volume.
Give us a few
days to buff you up.
Plus, I have a present for you.
These are for them.
Things were a little touch-and-go
for a while, so I called them.
- How do I explain...?
- It's Christmas.
You don't have to. Trust me.
Hey, princess.
Hey, buddy.
Look at you guys.
You're all grown up.
You getting out of here soon?
I have a cajillion
notes to write.
- You look nice.
- Thanks.
- Off to your sister's, I take it?
- Yeah.
It's for you. Merry
Christmas, Neela.
I don't normally do this.
Work presents always end up being
something edible and bad for you...
or something impersonal
like organic soap.
Who needs that crap cluttering
up their bathroom anyway?
Oh, loops, wow.
Yeah. That's my very first pair.
Bought them for
myself in med school.
Thank you. It's a lovely gift.
Listen.
You're an intern and I'm an Attending,
and there are certain protocols...
certain hierarchies
that preclude me from...
Lucien.
Being direct about
this, but it's Christmas...
what the hell, I'm
just gonna say it.
You're a really
good surgeon, Neela.
A few more years
and you could be great.
Thank you.
You're gonna try them on?
I will.
Beautiful.
You repeat this conversation to
anyone, and I will deny it. You know that.
What conversation?
Lovely.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- Yeah.
Transplant rounds are at 7.
Thank you. Bye, sweetheart.
Look out, Kriss Kringle.
What's going on, Morris?
Oh, we did okay, Greg.
Just okay?
Either you rocked the house
or you were closed to patients.
No, we just moved
people through.
All right, all right. Go
ahead, you can gloat now.
Tell me all about what a
great manager you are.
I saved Jerry, I diagnosed
D.I.D., yadda yadda.
Know what?
I'm gonna go with
humility this time.
For real.
Humili -what?
Hey.
I learned a lot
watching you today.
Yeah, well, I'm
full of it, Hope.
I get it, Archie.
I know you don't believe
half of what you say but...
You know what?
It doesn't really matter.
Because I saw you today.
And what I saw was a
guy who's trying to be good.
And...
I don't know, that right
there is half the battle.
Have a good holiday.
What are you doing?
What?
Now. Are you going home?
I thought maybe we could...
Grab a bite, get a
drink, see what happens.
Chastity's always
been overrated.
Purity of spirit is what
it's all about, right?
Wait, wait, are you...?
What are you saying?
You know what?
I don't think so.
What?
I hate that I'm saying this.
It's like some dorky angel
has taken control of my mouth.
But...
No.
What?
It's Christmas, and people
get lonely on Christmas...
and we might do something
that we'd both regret...
or could get in the way of a possibly
deeper relationship in the future.
So...
I'm sorry.
Hey. Hey.
You stole my suit.
Well, what about you?
Me?
Yes, where are you from...
what are you doing
here, what's your damage?
I spent a couple of
years in the service...
and managed to spend
my time in Okinawa...
which is a hell of a lot better
than being in Iraq or Afghanistan.
Since I've come back,
I work as a traveler.
Yeah, I did that for a while,
but then I got tired of it.
So wait, you have
what, a week or so left?
It's supposed to be a week.
But this place seems all right.
It seems like
pretty great people.
I mean, like, what we did for
that lady today, what you did...
That was something.
Come on, everyone deserves a
little bit of happiness at Christmastime.
Yeah.
So I called the nursing director,
and I signed on for another month.
Really?
Really.
Well.
Merry Christmas, Ben.
Merry Christmas, Samantha.
Idiot.
Moron.
She was right there.
Right there for the fondling,
and you just let her go.
Why? Why?
Why'd you have to be
such a good Christian, huh?
There's no God.
There's no Christmas.
There's no freaking Santa Claus.
Merry Christmas.
Holy...