Previously, on New Amsterdam...
We can never be more than this.
Tell me you know that.
[Claude] I'm offering you
deputy chair of surgery.
Dr. Reynolds, Dr. Lyn Malvo, my wife.
Floyd's going to be my new right-hand man.
[Hank] You want Dr. Shinwari on your ED.
You want a fifth spot?
Are you talking about a bribe?
I could lose my medical license.
I could go to jail!
-Did you have anything to do with this?
-It was all you.
[Helen]
Mina got into King's College in Cambridge.
I put you down as her emergency contact
and if you would just meet her--
-Not on your life!
-Mom!
[Helen] This place, what happened?
Last month our medical
director packed up and left.
Now we're fighting to hold on.
All my patients, all their despair,
it just becomes a part of me.
And I'm not going to see patients anymore.
[knocking]
[Joe Cocker's "Feelin' Alright" plays]
-Ow!
-Are you okay?
Mm-hm.
♪ Seems I've got to have
A change of scene ♪
♪ Every night I have ♪
Your place is huge.
-Do you want a tour?
-No.
[grunts]
♪ Could have been ♪
♪ Left here on my own, or so it seems ♪
♪ I've got to leave
Before I start to scream ♪
♪ But someone locked the door ♪
♪ And took the key ♪
♪ You're feelin' alright ♪
♪ Oh no ♪
♪ I'm not feelin' too good myself ♪
♪ Yes, you're feelin' alright ♪
♪ Oh no ♪
♪ I'm not feelin' that good myself, yeah ♪
♪ You're feelin' alright ♪
♪ Well, I know that ♪
♪ Oh no ♪
♪ Hey I'm not feelin' that good myself ♪
♪ Oh, you're feelin' alright ♪
♪ Oh no ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm not feelin' that good myself ♪
♪ Feelin' alright ♪
♪ Whoa, I'm lonely ♪
♪ But I'm not feelin' good myself ♪
♪ Oh no ♪
♪ You can turn away ♪
♪ Feelin' alright ♪
[woman] Hey, how are you guys?
[sighs] Look at all this good food
right here at the hospital.
We got carrots, potatoes,
French fries, Daddy's favorite.
Oh, broccoli, yummy.
We got just about
everything we need here, kiddo.
[mimics airplane]
[Greg Street's "Good Day" plays]
[chuckles]
We're back.
♪ We're gonna have
We're gonna have a good day ♪
♪ And all my homies gonna ride today ♪
♪ And all these mommies look fly today ♪
-This is a nice change.
-Hugging is the new biting.
Hey, monkey!
Mwah.
Bye!
♪ 'Cause ain't nobody gonna die today ♪
Yeah, none of them jumping off
the wall for me.
You know what? Forget white.
Why don't we try a nice sunny yellow?
Something upbeat.
♪ 'Cause ain't nobody gonna die today ♪
Oh, I got you, how can I help?
-Oh, thanks so much.
-Sure.
-Oh.
-Mm.
♪ Hairline fresh, new cologne on ♪
♪ Feeling so good ♪
It's going to be
kind of a slow transition into pants.
-Dr. Goodwin.
-Hi!
It's me, Simon, from podiatry.
-Simon, you got huge!
-Right?
I started lifting weights
between Zoom patients and...
18 months later...
New Amsterdam needs an employee gym.
Eighteen months of Zoom appointments
has not been kind to me.
-Melvin, you look great.
I gained 20 pounds
from snacking between Zooms.
Did you know thighs chafe?
[sighs]
Uh, Dr. Metzger, are you surprised
by all the great changes
we've been making lately?
No, Dr. Goodwin,
this isn't my surprised face.
This is my, "I can't believe
I have to shower every day," face.
♪ 'Cause ain't nobody gonna die today ♪
♪ Save that drama for another day, hey ♪
All right, so I know that first
days can be a little bit scary,
but I assure you that this is a safe
and nurturing learning environment.
Also we ordered new desks
for you guys, so...
Um, as your newly-minted
psych residency director,
we'll be spending
an awful lot of time together.
We'll be working closely together
for the next year.
We will be on this ward
with real patients,
and you will have me
in supervision as your teacher,
your protector, your sounding board,
your overall psych Sherpa
on this amazing journey
we're about to embark on together.
Here at the hospital, they heal the body.
On this ward, we heal souls.
[Lauren] Okay, listen up, newbies.
I'm Dr. Lauren bloom,
head of the emergency department,
which means, do not come to me
with your personal problems.
Don't complain to me about your schedule.
And don't expect me
to care if your pet is sick.
Chief Resident Walsh will field questions
and let you know when you screwed up.
If you find yourself in the position
where I'm telling you you've screwed up,
you're going to know it's bad.
Questions?
Good.
I know your internships
were a long hard slog and right now
you feel like you see light
at the end of the tunnel.
I'm here to tell you,
that is not daylight.
It is a train.
So grab a donut and get to work.
Okay, so, I'm Dr. Mark Walsh--
And just so we're all on the up and up,
Resident Shinwari is my girlfriend.
-[Claude] Morning, partner.
-Is it, though?
Nurse Kamoe,
would you be so kind as to crank up
Dr. Reynolds' legendary playlist?
♪ I wake up crying ♪
Love the soul.
This is not time for slow jams.
Next cut, please.
♪ Ain't no sunshine when she's gone ♪
-♪ It's not warm when she's away ♪
-It's a good song.
It's a woman, isn't it?
No.
Floyd.
[sighs] Look, Claude, no one wants
to hear about my love life, all right?
Team?
♪ She goes away ♪
Okay.
Maybe there was a woman,
but, uh, wasn't right for either of us.
So I ended it.
And now I'd like to just move on.
Floyd, if you really care for this woman,
you should find a way to make it work.
♪ Anytime she goes away ♪
It's not that simple.
-♪ And I know, I know, I know, I know ♪
-[sighs]
♪ I know, I know
I know, I know, I know... ♪
So the hottest thing on your hotlist,
which I still prefer
to call your schedule,
is your meeting with Dr. Wilder.
She's been waiting for 30 minutes.
Yeah, uh, sweet Sandra Fall.
I don't want you to focus on my schedule
or my meetings anymore.
Given that's the entirety
of my responsibilities,
what should I focus on?
Joy.
I want you to focus on joy.
Walk me through what that might look like.
Finding it, seizing it. That's what
this new beginning is all about,
refocusing on what truly matters.
Re-examining our lives
to maximize the joy,
the beauty, the people that we love,
and nothing should distract us
from that noble goal.
[alarm blares]
[woman] May I have your attention?
There is a fire in the building.
Maybe we start that joy thing tomorrow.
-[panicked chattering]
-What the hell happened?
We don't know. Everything's on fire.
It came out of nowhere.
[panicked chattering]
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Get out of here! Go!
[Max] Is this even real?
I have thought of nothing...
but you... and this
for so long.
Thought it, but didn't know how to say it.
Or maybe I was afraid to.
And now it just feels
like I have a future again.
With you...
just like this.
I should never have let you in.
[indistinct chatter]
Could've been worse, Dr. Goodwin.
Luckily the sprinklers got it
before the fire got to the gas lines.
You're sure this is arson?
100%. We found multiple points of origin.
Got these patterns here on the wall,
traces of accelerant.
Did security cameras catch anything?
The cameras would have caught something
if they'd come this way.
But they didn't.
Whoever did this knew the layout.
It could be a supplier or--
Or someone who works here.
-[Sandra] Dr. Goodwin?
-Um, excuse me, thank you.
This may seem low priority...
That criteria has changed.
But you still have your ten o'clock
with Dr. Wilder and it is now 11:15.
Can you tell her that the hospital's
on fire and maybe we could reschedule?
Clearly that information
did not compel her to leave.
-Thanks for your patience. The ED's clear.
-Thank you, gentlemen.
-[woman] Pain management to radiology.
-Okay.
Brandon, hi.
Well, yeah, it looks like you've got gout.
That's like some old-timey disease, right?
Fancy people,
sitting around eating all day?
Yeah, not so much anymore.
Uh, just like halter tops and headscarves,
young people are bringing it back.
Nah, I shouldn't be up in here
with no gout.
I'm an athlete. I'm in shape.
You know, my team was in the Final Four
just ten years ago.
-Wait, Brandon Dover?
-Yeah.
I bet against you
in our March Madness pool.
You cost me 15 bucks.
24 points, seven assists, five rebounds.
You know I was supposed
to be the next Derrick Rose?
-So why'd you quit?
-I didn't.
Basketball quit me.
-[door bangs]
-Candy Storell, vaccinated.
Multiple fractures, lacerations,
concussion, fell backwards off
the fire escape while taking a selfie.
-At least she was doing what she loves.
-Walsh, let's get her to trauma one.
Um, Turan, can, um...
can you take over with Brandon?
He needs
two doses of ibuprofen every five hours
and three doses
of colchicine every eight hours.
Write it down so he gets the timing right.
[sighs] We're less than a year away
from needing our own selfie wing.
[Walsh] What've you got?
-Let's hear it, people!
-It looks like a tib-fib fracture.
Some intense reactive inflammation.
Placing a chest tube
to evacuate a pneumothorax.
-Shinwari?
-Arm is irrigated and sutured.
Nice job, everyone.
-Patient is stable and ready for X-ray.
-[Lauren] Too slow!
You guys are going
to need to be much faster
because the next patient that comes in
is not going to be so straightforward.
Nice job on that arm lac.
[Walsh] Let's mobilize for radiology.
Trauma one's a busy place.
Got to clear the room!
[sighs]
Department policy is to, uh,
have a general surgery presence
for all restricted bowel procedures.
I know the policy.
Your husband sent me to assist, so...
Then assist.
You wanted to keep it professional,
we can keep it professional.
Lyn.
-What was I supposed to do?
-Let go.
I couldn't...
I can't, not when I have to look
your husband in the eye every day.
I mean, let go of my hand.
Now I have to scrub it again.
[water running]
[softly] That's my bad.
[sighs]
While the fire department
does their thing,
I want your department to create
a psychological profile of the arsonist.
Uh, okay, yeah, but, um,
that's a really specialized field, right?
What do you mean? Is there no one on staff
who specializes in arson or pyromania?
No, no, there is. Just they're not, uh...
They're not exactly on staff.
Well, then, where are they?
[sighs]
-[buzzer]
-[indistinct PA announcements]
Common Room two.
[door locking, buzzer]
It's so good to see you again, Dr. Frome.
[distant sirens, horns blaring]
Helen.
Hey.
Just talk to me.
-When you, uh, spoke about the future--
-What, was it too soon?
-No, it... it made me sad.
-Helen... Sad?
Why?
When I was in London,
I had this profound feeling.
I was getting Mina settled,
being there for my mom,
it all just felt so...
I felt so exposed.
But in the best way.
It made me realize just how much
of myself that I'd put away.
Packed it up,
crossed an ocean to become someone else
in a place where I have no history.
It was self-preservation,
but what's left now...
of me?
Being home...
broke me wide open and I came spilling out
in a way that I don't have any interest
in boxing back up again,
because it felt right.
I felt right.
You can take some time off.
You take a leave of absence.
You can take whatever you need.
Max, I need to go home...
for good.
We need to push all elective surgeries.
Any patient that can be transferred,
transfer them
and let's double up on security.
-They've already doubled it.
-Then double it again.
Dr. Wilder, I see you're getting more use
out of this office than I do.
You really have a thing
against filing cabinets.
Just prefer a non-traditional approach
to organization.
Max Goodwin, medical director,
very sorry to keep you both waiting.
When I heard the building was on fire,
I did consider fleeing for my life.
Yeah, well, turns out
the fire department counts on that.
Except I was too curious as to why
you wanted to meet with me.
Um, what, uh, well--
[grunts]
Oh.
Just... okay.
Um, here's the thing.
I'm in a bit of a pickle,
a delicate situation.
I'm trying to replace,
uh, someone in oncology.
[Ben] Who's leaving?
Uh, uh, Dr. Helen Sharpe.
Holy s... no! [chuckles]
I'm not interpreting that.
Uh, I have a mouth like a sailor,
but Ben is a prude.
It was very explicit.
She's in London
and no one at the hospital knows,
so there's, uh, a bit of secrecy.
[Ben] Dr. Sharpe is the best there is.
I have always been humbled
by her passion, her intelligence,
and also, let's face it, she's super foxy.
Well, I don't know about...
I mean, I don't... We're not, um...
Yeah, they're big shoes to fill.
There's no doubt.
[Ben] And I'm only a size seven.
But I do make up for it in other ways.
I emailed you Dr. Wilder's CV.
Yeah, I see that, thank you. Um...
Listen, you come very highly recommended
by a lot of good people, but what
I'm looking for is impossible to find.
Dr. Sharpe not only has our oncology
and hematology departments,
but she also chairs
a cancer research clinic that...
Wow, I see you do as well.
The Murtha Cancer Center
at Walter Reed Hospital where
I currently practice surgical oncology.
That's very impressive.
Fellowship at NIH, studied at MD Anderson
and recipient
of The Order of the Star of Ghana.
Oh, I was doing Medecin sans Frontieres
outside of Accra and I saw a few ways
to tidy up the irrigation system
while I was there.
The badge itself,
it's really quite lovely.
Sometimes I'll just wear it out.
Um...
Wow. Uh, you are literally...
Uh, what am I trying to say?
Again, that's why I waited out the fire.
I'm very glad you did,
because you are hired.
Let's introduce you to Chairwoman Brantley
and we'll get the paperwork started.
The parking is really a nightmare,
but I think
we can find you a spot at the top.
[distant buzzer, doors slamming]
I can have other photos brought in for you
if that's what you need.
You know what I need.
I'm not taking you to a burn site.
That is off the table.
Would you profile a patient
from a pile of photographs?
That's entirely different.
Fire is not alive.
Fire consumes oxygen.
Reproduces and moves quickly.
That's more alive
than a lot of my cellmates.
It's too dangerous.
[chuckles]
What am I going to do?
Escape from the fleet of armed guards?
Burn the place down?
I'm not a supervillain.
No, no, no,
I mean, it's too dangerous for you.
For a pyromaniac, fire is a drug,
and for the six years since
you were arrested, you have been sober.
Taking you to a burn site would be like
sending you off on a bender.
All your progress will be--
You will not shrink me.
You are not my analyst.
I am not your patient.
And my progress is none of your business.
Is that clear?
Yes, Mary.
That is clear.
How calm you sound.
How reassuring.
But that little Iggy mind
is in there scheming away,
trying to figure out
how you can reach me...
help me heal.
That...
That was true when we first met.
My job was to analyze inmates.
But right now, I assure you,
I am just here for your help.
You're not trying to shrink me?
Uh-uh.
Protect me from the only thing I love?
Your love killed 13 people, Mary.
Fire is not love.
Fire is rage.
-We're done here.
-The accelerant is homemade.
That means he's educated.
It's a medium petroleum distillate,
which is uncommon here,
but typical in Northern Europe
where he's likely from.
And I say he not only because
of the distance the gas was tossed,
but because
of the jagged pattern of how it fell.
You need strength
to toss the canister like that.
And anger.
Now imagine what I could tell
you if you got me out of here.
Brandon Dover, 28-year-old male
with extreme abdominal pain,
low BP and heart arrhythmia.
I just released him.
Brandon, Brandon, can you hear me?
-Did you take the meds we gave you?
-[groans] Yeah. It hurts.
I need a surgical consult.
-Trauma one.
-[groans in pain]
We got a bleeder!
Got it, suture.
Scissors.
Appendix, liver, spleen, arteries,
they all look fine.
Hm. They're rock hard.
Ischemic loop of bowel?
-No sign of thrombus or infection.
-Well, he came in for gout.
-We gave him medication.
-It didn't help.
-What if the pharmacy screwed up his meds?
-Maybe he didn't have gout.
I saw the crystals myself.
Okay, well, what if he did take his meds
but maybe he took too many?
Why would he OD on colchicine?
-[indistinct chatter]
-[beeping]
Lyn, can we talk?
Professionally?
-Personally.
-[whooshing]
[Lyn screams]
So what are you going to do?
Give up on your practice and your patients
and everything that you've built here
-and go back and what?
-Maybe you should leave.
No, I won't.
-You... you won't?
-You won't know how long I've waited?
Now that I'm here, I'm not just
going to leave, just talk to me!
Let me try. Please let me fight for this.
Okay, all right.
The clinic that I took my mom,
they need a new medical director and...
and they want me.
That's great. I'll go back and forth
every other weekend.
It's a six hour flight. Why not?
You can do the same.
We'll be frequent flyers.
We can't have a long-distance relationship
without having had a short-distance one.
Listen... listen to me.
Why not? [softly] Why not?
I'm here.
Now that I've held you and I've kissed you
and I've humiliated myself
in front of the entire neighborhood.
How have you humiliated yourself?
Hey, New York!
I love this woman!
-And now she's trying to dump--
-Shh!
-No, I'm not going to--
-Shh! No.
-I'll keep going, I swear to God.
-No, shh. Please, Max, stop.
I'm not going to stop until you tell me
-that we're going to try.
-How?
I... London, New York, back and forth.
Tunisia, I don't care.
Anywhere, as long as we're together.
Please.
W... What about Luna?
She can come with me.
She's young enough. It's fine.
It'll be an adventure for her.
It'll be an adventure for all of us.
I just want you to say that
you're willing to fight for this.
Because if you don't,
I am going to run through
these streets butt naked.
[giggles]
I'll do it.
Literally,
I'm taking my pants off right now.
-Here they go.
-No, okay!
-Completely--
-I love you.
I love you.
Do everything you can to secure the
hospital, police, FBI, call it all in.
-[Ben] Max. Max!
-Yeah, I'm sorry. I--
We're here to help.
All O2 tanks and all other flammable gases
need to get disconnected
and someone's got to go around and ensure
that all your fire doors are latching.
Uh, I hate to ask, but...
-[Ben] You don't have to.
-Thank you.
-Hey. Um, well...
Tell me you got something.
-Miss Wheeler's not exactly compliant.
-If we don't find this person,
someone's going to die.
Do whatever you can.
-Okay.
-Thank you.
How you guys holding up?
No signs of concussion.
Just a few scrapes and bruises.
Lauren, Uh, I hate to do this,
-but you need to put the ED on diversion.
-On it.
Let's go over your schedule,
see what surgeries we can push.
Sure, I'll be right back, okay?
If you hadn't been there...
I just wanted to apologize.
It's passed, Floyd.
No, no, it hasn't.
I thought
we could go back to being friends,
but whenever I'm with your husband,
all I do is think about you.
And when we're together,
I just keep thinking about him.
You don't think this has been hard on me?
He may like you more than I do.
[sighs] Something's got to give, Lyn.
Look, either I step down or...
Or what?
[Lauren] Okay, I need every patient
transferred or discharged.
And why isn't Brandon Dover
on anti-colchicine fab fragments yet?
He is. I just haven't
had time to update his file.
How'd he mess up his meds so bad?
I have no idea, considering
we gave him such explicit instructions.
[Leyla] Dr. Bloom?
Hey.
I... I'll just go, um, update that file.
Just go.
[exhales]
You're a sight for sore eyes.
How's your first day going?
Are you serious? It's bad enough you gave
me a medal for cleaning out a wound,
but why'd you tell everyone
we were a couple?
Yeah, okay--
We agreed to wait
until they got to know me as a resident.
You agreed to treat me like everyone else.
But you're not like everybody else.
You're a fully-trained doctor.
They're just a bunch of kids
pretending to be doctors.
I would have complimented them too,
had the situation been reversed.
But the situation can never be reversed
because the other residents
aren't sleeping with their boss.
Okay. Okay, I'm sorry.
Okay, I'm sorry.
I just...
I was just trying to work my program,
you know? Put it all out there.
There's this saying. It's you're only
as sick as your secrets and...
Lauren?
You know what? You were right.
You were totally in the right
and I am wrong.
But I think I know
what's going on with my patient.
It must have been zero visibility.
Everywhere you look, just flames, smoke.
[inhales]
Black and orange, orange and black.
Ah, the doctor disapproves.
No, I'm concerned.
No.
You're scared of me.
You have been
since you walked into my ward.
The only thing I'm scared of, Mary,
is the damage being done to your psyche.
You treat murderers... rapists.
You're alone in rooms with people
who could snap you like a twig
and I don't think you break a sweat.
And here you are acting like
the nice woman of a certain age
is going to take a bite out of you.
Which one of us do you think is having
a damaging psychological experience?
Ahem. You know, Mary,
patients try to drag their doctors
into their pathologies all the time.
When I practiced,
there was a weekly occurrence.
I hate to break it to you.
It's not going to work.
You said when you practiced.
Why'd you stop?
I have an eye for sore spots.
Think I'd make a good shrink?
We're done here.
Tell me why you quit
and I'll tell you who set the fire.
I needed a change.
The hours were terrible.
They were killing me.
I'm giving you a choice
between being honest with yourself...
and watching this place burn.
-Why are you making this about me?
-"She's not too far gone!
We can help this woman! We can save her!"
You said that...
at my trial.
-Mm-hm.
-You yelled at the judge.
You demanded he put me in your ward,
not prison, because you could save me.
Iggy, the white knight,
knew everyone can be saved.
Now you've quit.
Now you've left everyone to rot.
Why?
When does the white knight
stop trying to save everybody?
When he stops believing
that people can be saved.
Out of here.
Now.
Fire isn't rage, Dr. Frome.
Want to know what it is?
God writes in pencil. Fire's his eraser.
It's not for anger. It's for pain.
That's your profile?
The arsonist is in pain?
Just like you.
Just like me.
[Mary whimpers]
Okay. Thank you, Teresa.
-I'll catch up with you in a minute.
-Okay.
Hey, so, it was a mistake
to bring Mary back into this.
It definitely set her back.
The best I got out of her is that
the arsonist is trying to erase something.
-Erase what?
-I don't know. I have no idea.
Is there anything that connects
the location of the two fires? Anything?
Not really.
I mean, one was a COVID overflow unit
and the other
was an auxiliary space for neurology.
-What was it used for last?
-[sighs]
It was our second COVID overflow unit.
Where else
did we annex for COVID patients?
Max! Max!
-Everybody out now!
-[kids screaming]
[Max] When do you fly out?
I have my final interview
with the board of directors next week.
-They said it's just a formality, but...
-I'll go with you.
-Really?
-Yeah.
No, no, wait, sorry, can't that week.
That's Luna's first week of pre-school.
Oh, right.
Yeah, no, definitely cannot miss that.
Um, why don't you come
the following weekend
and then I can fly back with you?
Perfect.
Oh, no, sorry.
That weekend is my visit
to Cambridge to visit Mina.
-Mm.
-I'm trying to broker a truce
between her and my mother.
-Yeah, you got to do that.
-Mm-hm.
Uh, okay, no problem.
Then you fly back and we will spend
the following weekend together.
Isn't that the weekend that you usually
have your conferences in Colorado?
The ones that you're always
trying to get me to go to?
[chuckles]
-You are correct.
-Mm-hm.
And this is--
-Crazy.
There's got to be one weekend
that we can spend together?
Of course there is.
[chuckles]
-Yeah.
-Let's not do this now.
I don't want to ruin this.
It's not ruined.
It's just a scheduling thing.
-Yes.
It's going to work.
I want it to, Max.
I really want it to.
And it will.
-[Helen sighs]
-[Max chuckles]
Lyle.
That's your name, right?
You lost someone?
Your wife?
I can imagine what that's like.
Can you?
Working in this hospital
and not being allowed in that room...
just to say goodbye.
Because of protocol, rules.
She was in our COVID unit.
Right, the one that burned down today?
You mean the room you asked me
to make sunny by covering it up?
That room, where my wife died?
That graveyard you asked me to erase?
I understand.
And I'm sorry.
But above this room
was our third COVID unit.
But you knew that already,
but did you know
that it's back to being
our daycare center?
Where my daughter was playing.
-If anything happened to her...
-[cop] That's him.
Don't move.
...I might want to burn it all down, too.
[handcuffs click]
[indistinct police radio chatter]
Let's go.
Um, I need to correct something
that I said to you earlier
about protecting you.
[sighs] I... I can't.
I can't protect you.
And the truth is,
no matter how much you prepare,
how solid your boundaries are,
there will always be patients
that just consume you.
Always.
They will ruin family dinners.
They will doom first dates
and you'll dread seeing them
because they scare
the ever-loving hell out of you.
Uh, the thing that I failed to mention
about the whole healing souls thing
is that, uh,
it comes with a hefty price tag.
It's a... It's a piece of your own soul.
So the patient is Mary W.
She is a 60-year-old
psychopathic pyromaniac,
who exhibits highly manipulative
and sadistic tendencies.
She's being transferred here today
from the corrections ward
because she wants our help.
But I don't see patients anymore.
You do.
So...
do I have any takers?
[Lauren] Brandon, I think I know why
you messed up the dosage.
When I was younger,
nobody cared about my education.
As long as I could ball.
Not the school, not the coaches.
I was their meal ticket.
It's always been that way,
even throughout college.
Nobody wanted
to hear about my... dyslexia.
Couldn't even get it diagnosed.
When I blew out my knee, that was it.
I couldn't play,
couldn't keep my scholarship.
I couldn't read.
Okay, uh, here's my card.
So you can recognize
my number when I call you.
This ain't your problem, Dr. Bloom.
Once your issues out there
become a problem in here,
it's my job to fix it.
Shinwari.
You left the O2 sat meter on the counter.
It always has to go back on the wall
in the receptor where it belongs.
The next time an asthmatic comes in,
sucking for air,
I can't be hunting around
trying to find it. You got that?
Am I making myself clear?
Yes. Yes, Dr. Bloom.
I'll put it back from now on.
Look who's back in action.
Nurse Kamoe,
I believe this calls for music.
-♪ Hey ma ♪
-♪ What's up? ♪
-♪ Let's slide ♪
-♪ All right ♪
Yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
Let me guess.
You and your girl work things out.
We did,
but still figuring out some details.
♪ All right
And we gon' get it on tonight ♪
♪ Yo, now I was downtown clubbin'
Ladies night ♪
I'm going to go out on a limb here
and guess this interview didn't go
quite as smoothly as your others.
Well, there's definitely
more smoke damage.
Yeah, look, we're criminally underfunded.
We are always in the red.
We've got unfilled repair orders
from 1973.
And I'm losing more doctors
and nurses from burnout
than I can even keep up with.
So, uh, I get it, if you want to say no.
-Max.
You don't build
a good hospital with money.
You build it with good people.
And you have that in spades.
I would love to work here.
-You would? That's amazing!
-But I can't accept.
You want someone to replace Dr. Sharpe.
Something tells me
Dr. Sharpe is not replaceable.
Whoever follows in her footsteps
will be a disappointment.
My advice.
Don't let her go.
But it was certainly
a memorable interview.
Oh, hi.
Hi.
How was your flight?
Sad, upsetting.
Lonely.
More joy.
That's what I told myself.
That's what I learned.
If anything, over these last 18 months,
that's what I need.
And that's you.
You're my joy.
Did you find my replacement?
No one can replace you.
But I think I found someone to replace me.
What?
I'm going with you.
More joy.
[exhales sharply]
[laughs softly]