Previously on ER:
- Told you to get a desk job.
- Bastard shot me in the back.
Lucien, I've withdrawn
my application.
I'm not staying at County.
And talking about every stupid
damn thing that bothers me? No.
You know, I truly believe...
there's something better
out there for both of us.
Better?
Something more right.
- So.
- Listen.
- I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry things got so weird.
- I really didn't...
- Shouldn't have been such a... Okay.
- I know kind of I sprung things on you.
You go first.
I know I've been somewhat
closed-off about all this...
but I was afraid that if I discussed it
with you, you'd convince me to stay.
Well, I certainly
would have tried.
But you know what? It's
a good thing you're going.
- It is?
- Yep.
Adjusting to a new environment,
a new way of doing things.
You will gain so much
confidence from that.
Well, I hope so.
When you're sick of your
third-rate, community trauma center...
Now it's third-rate?
- Demoted from B-list.
- You always, always have a job here.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Six months, six years. I don't
know. Not sure, but you will be back.
County is in your blood.
And until then, my
friend, good luck.
Get out of here already.
Lucien.
I don't know if I can
do this without you.
Of course you can.
You'll see. You'll see.
Now go. You get
out of here. Please.
Go. Please.
MRA's gonna tell us if
there's blood in his brain.
Well, that's the hope.
And if there is, then
what? Brain surgery?
Possibly.
Jay, I know how much
you need to talk to him.
Okay, I'm gonna do everything
that I can to make that happen.
No, no. He has to wake up.
Dr. Brenner. Dr. Brenner.
Your attention, please.
Change of gate
announcement for flight JR-2309.
This flight has
now been canceled.
Where have you been?
Frank really out did himself.
I took Mr. Walters up to the MRA suite,
they're gonna try and squeeze him in.
- What?
- Nothing.
If it turns out to be an aneurysm,
they can embolize it if it's caught early.
You don't think Neela
noticed that you weren't there?
I meant to go, but I
was dealing with this...
You couldn't find five
minutes to stop by?
Gates, I'm signing out
to Morris for a while.
It's me. I'm at the airport.
Could really use some of
your sage wisdom right now.
Can you call me when
you get this? Thanks. Bye.
- What can I get you?
- Glenfiddich straight, please.
Need some warming up, do we?
- Off to someplace sunny?
- Yes, actually.
Beach vacation?
Business trip?
- Sort of.
- Sort of?
- It's a new job. I'm moving.
- Really? What do you do?
I, uh... BRENNER: Neela.
I couldn't let you go like this.
- What are you drinking?
- Uh, what do you got on tap?
No, uh, actually, forget that.
Soda water with a...
With a lime. Thanks.
Thank God for this storm or you'd
be somewhere over Missouri by now.
Geography's pretty
good for a foreigner.
Look, I, um... I just...
I thought that if I didn't catch you now,
then maybe we'd never speak again.
Today's been
strange and difficult.
Yeah. Yeah, I know.
For me too.
Oh, and don't mutter in Spanish
when you're angry. It's a cliché.
I understand a lot more
than you think I understand.
Fine, you win.
I'll stay home with my hair
in curlers, knitting and baking.
You know that's not
what I'm talking about.
- Apple pie or cherry?
- If you'd just listen to what I'm saying.
Give up, Archie. This
conversation is over.
Well, okay. Have a great day.
And please accept my sincere
apology for giving a rat's ass.
- Everything okay?
- Everything is fine.
What do we got?
Uh, one-story fall with
LOC, that's all I know.
- What the hell is that?
- It's something for Neela.
- It's her last day.
- Piñata?
- What is she, 5?
- It's not just any piñata...
I had this custom made.
It's a Gandhi piñata.
That is scary.
Uh, not to mention offensive.
Who's gonna wanna bash
Gandhi's head in with a bat?
You have no sense of culture.
Gary Walters, 53, fell head-first down
a flight of stairs after a few too many.
I slipped on the rug.
Observed LOC, awake
at scene, but disoriented.
- Do you know what day it is?
- I told you, I slipped on the rug.
Okay, Gates, what do you want?
Uh, head CT, C-spine, trauma
labs, tox screen and, uh, ETOH level.
- I'm on it.
- Good. And, uh, get him to surgery.
- They're gonna need to see him.
- Neela's already on the floor.
She's guarding. How's the CBC?
- First was good.
- Send a repeat now.
Does anything hurt you, ma'am?
Remember what happened today?
- Nobody will listen.
Drove her motorcycle into the museum
warning about the end of the world.
- Psych history?
- It seems.
- I'll check if she has a record here.
- Equilibrium is shifting.
I thought that was just me on
account of it being my last day here.
It's Claudia's first day back at work.
- Good.
I mean, I'm not sure that it is.
LFTs and lipase are normal.
I think, ma'am, you might
be my last surgical case.
I thought I was okay
with it. I really did.
It's her job and I respect
that, but she got shot.
Why couldn't I fall
for a nice librarian?
A librarian in Springfield died
last month. Bookshelf fell on her.
- I swear, it was in the paper.
- Guys, we need a surgeon in here.
Andrew, check the tox screen...
and let Dubenko know we've
got a possible laparotomy.
What've you got?
53-year-old male,
fell down a staircase.
Multiple contusions
to head, hip and back.
32 French and draw up some lido.
Decreased on the left, sats in the 80s.
Hello, I'm Dr. Rasgotra.
- Do you remember falling?
- I was dizzy, I guess I tripped.
Smells like ETOH was involved.
- Belly's benign, I figured you'd sign off.
- Happy to help.
Thank God. - I'm fine.
You're not fine.
Just a few scrapes and
this headache won't go away.
- All right, a little pinch here.
- What are you doing?
Well, he may have broken a rib
when he fell, punctured a lung.
- Tube'll help inflate it.
- When is this gonna stop?
- It's not even 10.
- Mom, don't start.
- Woke up this morning with a headache.
- It's called a hangover.
I just needed
something for the pain.
He's a drunk, but you've
probably figured that out by now.
- Let the doctors work.
- Two people ahead.
Type and cross and let me know
when the scan is back, please.
Sorry, uh, my in-laws have
been through some messy stuff.
No worries.
We all have messes in our past.
Shouldn't have been hard on you.
Wasn't the best way to end things.
- You were right.
- I was righteous.
Which isn't my best
quality, honestly.
For my whole adult life, I've
been doing exactly what you said.
- I'm not sure what you mean.
- Disappearing.
Using sex as an escape...
or worse, as a weapon, a
way of disarming people.
Look at you two. So sweet.
Like nobody else is in the room.
- You want another round?
- Uh, sure.
Yeah.
I'm in. 0-silk, elastoplast.
I'll get the Thora-Seal.
Hey, guys, look.
- Irregular rhythm, looks like A-fib.
- Nice pick up.
Do you have a history
of atrial fibrillation?
He didn't tell you?
You didn't tell them?
- I don't know, I forgot.
- Forgot. That's a load of crap.
It's okay. What meds is he on?
Uh, calcium blockers and
some other pill to thin his blood.
- Coumadin.
- He's bad about taking his meds.
He drinks. He forgets.
Or at least that's what he
says. But really, it's a death wish.
He thinks if he doesn't take his pills
he'll figure out a way to disappear.
- Don't talk about me like I'm not here.
- Today...
of all days, you
couldn't control yourself?
What's so special about today?
- It's been 10 years.
- Here we go.
He has this pathetic
need to tell everyone.
Mom. Please.
Um, today is the anniversary
of their son's death...
so everyone's a bit tense.
My dad blames himself.
I let Timmy go.
I'll be outside.
Mom.
Sam, add an INR and
rush the head scan, please.
I keep thinking it's gonna
get easier, it doesn't.
Staircase fall in 1 with a
pneumo and a headache...
and a motorcycle crash
in 2 with a seatbelt sign.
Okay, sounds good. Who
do you want me to see first?
Motorcycle looks like she might
need O.R. and you know what?
- This'll be case number 2500.
- 2500? No way.
Yeah, can you believe it? I'll have
logged 2499 surgeries since internship.
That's impressive.
- Serial crits?
- Not back yet.
Ah, surgeons, perfect timing.
I have a question for you.
- Haldol's in.
- How's she doing?
- Fast is negative, CBC's good.
- Hi, I'm Dr. Dubenko.
- Reckoning is here.
- Okay.
Why are eschatological delusions
common among psychotic patients?
- Escha-what?
- Eschatology.
Pertaining to the
end of the world.
I checked, no psych
hospitalization at County.
She doesn't look familiar.
- There's no hiding from the fifth cycle.
- Okay, sweet dreams, my dear.
- Your girlfriend gets shot on the job.
- Uh-huh.
Seeing that you care about
her and want her to not die...
you gently suggest that she
do another job. Is that sexist?
- No. No. No.
- Yes. Yeah.
- No. Tomato, "tomato."
- What?
Rigid abdomen, probably
needs the O.R. You can scrub in.
- Awesome. She's seizing.
- Oh, boy. Look out.
I see that. Two of Ativan.
Crank up O2. Haldol
lowers the seizure threshold.
Call me when she's
ready for the scanner.
- Andrew, let's go.
- You want me to cover the ER?
Forget about the ER, meet us upstairs.
You've got to log case number 2500.
What's with him?
Denial, avoidance.
Fear.
There's so many things I've
missed out on because I was afraid.
Well, you're obviously not
afraid to fly in really bad weather.
You know, when I was 6...
my, um, aunt took
me to a toy store...
and gave me 5 pounds and
said I could buy anything I wanted.
I wandered around the store
for what seemed like hours...
terrified I'd choose
the wrong thing.
Wrong doll and my
sister would laugh.
Wrong book, my
brothers would take it.
Wrong teddy, the kids at
school would think I was a baby.
I left the store with nothing.
My father put the
money in the bank.
Sensible kid.
Well, the point is, is that for
as long as I can remember...
I've carried this irrational
dread of making a mistake.
It's with me all the time.
And why on earth I
decided to become a doctor...
where the cost of
a mistake is so high.
- It's insane.
- It's masochistic.
I know.
And this is all my way of saying
I know I helped screw things up.
I'm not following.
Well, there's...
So many times in my life,
I've... I've failed to take a chance.
Even when it was clear to everyone
else, including me, that I should have.
That's why I gotta go. Even
if it scares the hell out of me.
I just don't want to be that
person anymore, you know?
Me either.
Don't worry, Neela. I'm not here
to try and convince you to stay.
Then why are you here?
I really, really don't know.
How'd you get past security?
Don't you have to have a ticket?
You bought a ticket.
So you got any, um, good
ideas of things to do in Detroit?
Detroit?
Yeah, well, it was the only way.
It just seemed wrong.
It just seemed terribly wrong to let
you go and not even say goodbye.
Do you wanna take a walk?
Head looks good,
Mr. Walters. No bleeding.
- You didn't need to stay for this.
- I know. I wanted to.
- Jay was my boy's best friend.
- One, two, three.
He pulled Tim out of the water.
Did CPR for an hour till
the coast guard got there.
Let's not go there, okay?
After the funeral, everyone
got on with their lives.
Jay came by every
day just to check on us.
It was just an excuse
to flirt with your daughter.
- It looks like it worked.
- We've been married three years now.
I lost Tim, but you
became like a son to me.
All right, all right.
At least you're affectionate
when you're drunk.
You guys having a party?
We need the scanner.
- Hello, Mr...
- Walters.
- How are you feeling?
- My head's killing me.
But the, uh, CT's clear.
No bleed? No edema?
- Who's that?
- The other case. Staircase fall.
Uh, did you think
of tapping him?
- Uh, tap him? Why?
- I don't wanna miss subarachnoid bleed.
Could be the cause and
not show up on the CT.
- That's pretty rare.
- Extremely rare.
I know, but the cause of his
dizziness, the headache before the fall.
- He was drinking.
- Well, his ETOH wasn't all that high.
- Not for a chronic alcoholic.
- We don't tap all our negative CTs.
Well, if it was up
to me we would.
Let's not risk missing
something we can fix.
- You on board with this?
- Me?
I trust her instincts. She's gonna
be her own boss starting tomorrow...
so I don't have
much leverage, really.
The ad said snake charmer.
I brought tarantulas too if
you think she'd prefer that.
No, I was thinking of a turban
and a flute and a snake in a basket.
Not this S & M getup.
- People dig the outfit.
- It won't work. Go.
Here.
For your trouble.
What was that?
Ah, when Neela first got here,
we kind of got off on the wrong foot.
I said some things I shouldn't have
said about her ethnic background, and...
Frank, come on. That was six
years ago, I'm sure she's over it.
Well, I would just like to show
her how much I've changed.
Why don't you try
something simple, like flowers.
- Flowers?
- Yeah.
That's not even remotely
original or cultural.
Just because her parents
were born in India...
doesn't mean she's gonna
appreciate some kind of Indian cliché.
In fact, she may very
well find it offensive.
What?
She's English, Frank.
Okay, so a Gandhi piñata or
a turbaned snake charmer...
is gonna end up
working against you here.
Well, thank you, Sam, I'll
take that under advisement.
- No free fluid.
- Aorta's intact.
- And IVC.
- Kidneys look functional.
- Ureters.
- I know how to read an abdominal scan.
- Of course you do.
- What's going on?
- I'll meet you in the O.R.
- The O.R? But the scan's perfect.
Rigid abdomen, it's surgical.
Doesn't matter what the scan says.
Her vitals are good, her
counts are unchanged.
Why not watch her in the ICU,
move her at first sign of instability?
- By then she'll be unstable.
- Lucien...
Small bowel perforation,
mesenteric injury.
Let's not risk missing
something we can fix, right?
Meet you in the O.R. in 10.
Sometimes there can be a head
bleed which we can't see on CT.
A more sensitive test is to place a
small needle into the spinal canal...
and remove some fluid.
If the lab finds red blood cells
then we know there's a problem.
What are the risks?
Infection and bleeding are the main ones,
but we'll take precautions to avoid both.
What do you think, Jay?
Right. Fluro's here,
so we should step out.
Hang in there, Dad.
Dr. Brenner, no disrespect
but, uh, this is stupid.
His mental status is getting worse,
we don't have a good explanation.
- Subarachnoid bleed's a theory.
- Except that he's on Coumadin.
The chances of bleeding complications
is higher than even finding a problem.
His INR is less than two.
There's something subtle
that led Neela to ask for this.
Yeah, it's her last day, she
doesn't wanna make a mistake.
But she'll feel bad if the procedure
leads to an uncontrollable spinal bleed.
Got your LP kit.
I'm not gonna do it.
We'll use Fluro,
give FFP, it'll be fine.
You will be there to assist.
We could go in
laparoscopically. Have a look.
- We'll be doing it open.
- Recovery time would be easier.
I'm aware of advantages
of laparoscopy.
All serial ultrasounds are fine,
normal CT, vitals are good, crit is stable.
You wanted to
log 2500 surgeries.
Don't rush a patient to surgery
because you're mad at me.
I'm not mad. I'm amused
by your narcissism...
but the patient has a
surgical abdomen, okay?
I suggest it is your judgment being
clouded by the significance of the day.
Lucien, please.
- Why don't you say what you need to?
- I don't need to say anything.
One minute you're strange and
loopy, the next you're gritting your teeth.
Look, it isn't personal.
Maybe you can just wish me luck.
I'd like to, but I can't.
I can't accept the fact
that you've accepted a job...
at an academically and clinically
inferior institution to spite me.
Oh, now who's the narcissist?
Patient is prepped,
Ancef is running.
Can't wish you luck,
I want you to hate it.
- You are unbelievable.
- I haven't spent these years...
helping you be an incredible talent
so you could work at a B-list institution.
- Ten blade to Dr. Wade.
- Sweet.
- It's not B-list, you're a snob.
- You're better than that place.
They have a busy trauma
service and catchment area.
- No medical school, research.
- Which allows me my time in the O.R.
Why can't you respect that?
I imagined something
better for you.
No, it's not what
you imagined for you.
Which is fine. But it's my life.
If I stay here, I'll always be
your protégée, little Neela.
It's time to move on.
What the hell are you doing?
You just contaminated yourself.
- Hyperpigmentation.
- Starting the incision.
Andrew, wait, stop.
- Go and get the Woods Lamp.
- Why?
Just get it. Go. Now.
- Bingo.
- Wow!
Hey, what the hell?
- Call Heme, they'll admit her.
- Heme?
Doesn't have internal
bleed, she's acute porphyria.
Disorder of heme
synthesis pathway.
Rigid abdomen, hyperpigmentation
on the extremities...
psychosis,
seizures, it all fits.
Yeah, she's the right
age for first presentation.
Okay, reverse the anesthesia,
she doesn't need surgery.
I guess 2499 will
have to be enough.
That's a big needle.
Yeah, well, if we've done our
job right, he won't feel a thing.
You do a lot for their family.
I've no choice,
I married into it.
- Lily's worth it, though.
- That's better. I'm in.
I don't feel right.
Hold on. Almost done.
- Gary? You okay?
- Take the needle out.
- Almost done.
- He's bradying down.
- Damn it.
Another unit of
FFP. Mr. Walters?
Mr. Walters? All
right, Jay, talk to him.
- His heart rate is 48.
- Wake up, do you hear me?
Transcutaneous pacer.
- Atropine in.
Chase it with epi.
I've lost the pulse.
- Oh, my God, what's happening?
- His heart is beating dangerously slow.
It could be a vagal reflex or to do
with what's going on in his brain.
Overdosed on the
calcium blockers?
- Let's get 500 of calcium gluconate.
- Don't do this.
Atropine and set up
for a dopa infusion.
- Let's pace him.
- It was a fight, okay? A stupid fight.
Increase voltage. We
need a hand in here.
I meant to tell you so many
times. It's not what you think.
- Increase the volume.
- It's not what you think. He slipped.
- It was an accident.
- All right. Quiet.
We got capture.
It's a strong
carotid. This is good.
I'm sorry.
I'll go let the family
know he's okay.
Jay. What's going on?
I met a man today who
accidentally killed his best friend.
That's awful.
They were out on a boat, and
they got into a fight over a girl.
And the guy punched his friend
and he tripped and fell overboard.
- And that was that.
- They brought the friend to the ER?
This happened 10 years ago.
Now, the guy never told
the family the truth until today.
And for years they were...
Well, their lives just stopped.
- Sad.
- Yeah.
Thank you for helping
me see that I was stuck too.
You know, I'm the last
person who should be telling...
Neela, look, you were right.
I can't love anyone
until I sort some stuff out.
But maybe, because of
you, I've started to do that.
Simon...
This is why I came here.
Neela, this really...
God, this mattered
so much to me.
Thank you.
Thank you for saying that.
You know, it's gonna be so
weird not to see you all every day.
Frank, the soft collar ever
come down from central?
Yes.
Were you gonna tell
me or keep me waiting?
I forgot. So shoot me.
Don't tempt me.
- Could you get it please?
- No.
- No?
- Oh, I'm gonna miss this.
Neela. Morris has a complicated
hand lac he wants you to look at.
Okay. Well, might be my last consult.
- Curtain 3.
Can you lay hands
on my rule-out appy?
- Page Andrew, I have a plane to catch.
- All right, cool.
Wow, what happened here?
Oh, Dr. Rasgotra,
this is Ed McDow.
And this is what happens when
a tug of war gets out of hand.
Get it? Out of hand? Ha, ha.
Company picnic. The winning
team gets the close parking for a year.
Wow.
Rope wrapped so tight it went numb.
Didn't feel it cutting through the skin.
Well, you're lucky. It almost
took the whole thing off.
I was so focused on the
game. I just couldn't let go.
I was gonna have Ortho do it,
but the edges approximate nicely...
and there's no neurovascular
damage so thought I'd give... Ow!
- Did it go through the glove?
- Ah, yes.
- Damn it.
- I'm sorry.
It's not your fault, really.
I'll be right back.
You need to,
uh, irrigate that...
- then go see Employee Health.
- I know.
- Closed-bore needle is a very low risk.
But you still need
to check for hepatitis.
I know.
Man, what is going on today?
A PCP vigilante chucks a
mayo stand at my head...
a 7-year-old
Republican bit me...
while I was irrigating
his lac and now, this...
Oh, my God. I am an ass.
I'm not following.
- Uh, come with me.
- I'm gonna be late for the...
It's important, I swear.
Frank, I'm gonna be late for the pl...
- Surprise!
- This is amazing.
- Frank did it all.
- Wow!
- Thank you.
Admit it. You thought we forgot.
- No.
- Or didn't care?
- Maybe.
- How could you think that?
Nobody stands up to our
bone-head attendings like you.
Who's gonna get
tough central lines?
Or chew out the lazy
Radiology residents?
Or teach me how to
do, like, everything?
To Neela! ALL: To Neela!
Haleh, I think this is
what you were looking for.
I didn't know if this wall really
existed or it was just a rumor.
I knew this day would
come, but so soon?
Stop it, Haleh, you're
gonna make me cry.
- Excuse me, can you help me, sir?
- You need to find a triage nurse.
- No, I'm sorry. I work here.
- Lucky you.
I'm supposed to start
today. Neela Rasgotra.
Rag what?
You're a really
good surgeon, Neela.
A few more years
and you could be great.
Thank you.
I was wondering if you didn't mind,
do you think you could lead the way...
and stand up there with
me when we do this?
You mean, uh, I'd be
your maid of honor?
I'd be honored.
But out in the bay this
morning, I was, uh...
I was thinking
about asking you out.
I was thinking of saying yes.
Thirty-two-year-old mother of
two with a rare blood disorder.
Still alive tonight.
Dr. Brenner? Dr. Brenner?
Oh, God.
Thank God it's you.
Please tell me I'm not
making a horrible mistake.
Of course, you're
not making a mistake.
But how does one know?
How does one ever know?
- You're doing that thing you do.
- What thing?
That existential crisis-spin-out
thing that never leads you anywhere.
- Hey, maybe you should have a drink.
- I've had three.
Oops! Hey, slow down
everybody. Slow down.
Thursday is my day to do
this childcare swap thing.
I hate Thursdays.
Abby, you'd tell me if you thought
I was making a mistake, right?
- I would.
- You promise?
If this doesn't make sense,
I don't know what does.
Just get off the phone
and get on the damn plane.
Okay.
- I'm hanging up now.
- Okay.
- You still there?
- Yes.
- I'm getting on the plane.
- Good idea.
Bye.
Ladies and gentlemen...
tower's telling us it'll be at least an
hour before they clear us for takeoff.
We apologize for the
delay, we'll keep you advised.
Hey, Sam.
Um, what happened
to our staircase guy?
LP came back positive for blood
as they were sliding him into MRA.
- Tony's upstairs with him in Angio.
- Okay. Thanks.
Hey, Dr. Brenner.
- Have you seen Archie around?
- I'm here.
- What is going on?
- Come with me.
I stuck myself with
a needle today...
and it made me realize that
I was an ass this morning...
about your work thing.
- An ass.
- I get it, Archie.
What's with the pie?
A symbol of my temporary
chauvinism and a gesture of apology.
My original idea was to bake you a
pie wearing nothing but an apron...
but I had to work late
and I don't own an apron.
- Me either.
- See? We're perfect.
If you can handle being with a
guy who gets stuck by needles...
and kicked by patients...
and takes an occasional slug
of radiation to his cojones...
What are you talking about?
Well, then I can certainly
stomach some occasional gunfire.
As long as you promise
not to get shot again.
What?
See, I just wanted to see how
much Spanish you really understand.
- See that?
- Yeah, I think so.
Ten-millimeter aneurysm at
the vertebrobasilar junction.
The headache he had
was probably the initial leak.
Yeah, leak was tiny.
No way it would show up on CT.
More contrast, please.
By all rights, this thing
should have been missed.
- It's nice work.
- Neela was right.
We use electrolytically
detachable coils to fill the lumen.
Cool.
Clot forms around the coils,
blocking off the aneurysm...
leaving the vessel open.
Dome-to-neck ratio looks...
Damn it. Stop the heparin.
- It's off.
- What's happening?
Coil went beyond the
confines of the road map.
- You ruptured the aneurism?
- Looks that way. Contrast.
- Doesn't he need the O.R?
- We can continue with softer coil.
I'm not waiting around
to test that theory.
- Heart rate's down.
- This is Dr. Brenner from the ER.
I need an O.R. and a neurosurgeon
for an acute cerebral hemorrhage.
I believe that's
my call to make.
- Get the portable monitor.
- Systolic's 62.
- It'll limit the bleeding.
- And deprive the brain of oxygen.
- What are you doing?
- Taking care of my patient.
- I got the femoral site covered.
- This is totally out of line.
I'm gonna write you guys up.
Hey.
- You're still here?
- I crashed in the call room for a bit.
The, uh, the surgeons were
able clip the aneurism quickly...
so the bleeding was
contained to a very small area.
Is he gonna have brain damage?
He's got a very good
chance of doing well.
But we won't know the
answer to that for a while.
Where is your wife?
She went home for a shower.
I don't know what
she's gonna do now.
About us.
- You two will work through it.
- Easy for you to say.
The truth is a time bomb.
But once it's out, it
can't hurt you anymore.
You can move on,
you can move forward.
Get some rest, Jay. I'll, um...
I'll drop by later.
Thanks.
I'll appreciate that.
Bill to crack down on
experiments on animals...
is to become law today.
Animal-rights activists have been
pushing for the bill for nine years...
and have taken part in
mass demonstrations.
The bill will outline just what animals
will be allowed to be used in labs...
along with penalties...
- How are you doing?
- Fine, you?
Sure. Fine.
Andrew, what do you think
of the patient's tachycardia?
Uh, probably volume-related...
but could be due to
fever, pain, infection.
Mm-hm. Good, more.
Uh, drug withdrawal,
toxins, vascular.
More.
Uh, trauma, iatrogenic.
- Neela never taught you VINDICATE?
- No.
It's my favorite mnemonic for
post-op rounds. Excuse us, Dr. Brenner.
If you run through this
on all your post-ops...
- you will never miss major complication.
- Mm-hm.
V is for? ANDREW: Vascular.
- I is for?
- Infection?
- Inflammation? DUBENKO:
Don't ask me, tell me.
You can come in now.
What happened to you?
Uh, ahem, I'm sorry,
I was up all night.
I see.
So. How was your week?
Can you excuse me for a second?
Finally.
You're really here?
Yeah.
I really am.