Previously, on
The Good Doctor...
Is there something
you're not telling me?
In meetings together, don't
ever call my ideas ridiculous.
Come on, I'm being serious.
So am I.
Merrill's son asked
for personal advice.
- And he picked you.
- I know, right?
A surgeon needs to communicate.
Can Dr. Murphy do that?
Can he do that under
stress? Can he do that knowing
that a human life literally
hangs in the balance?
Thank you, Dr. Kalu.
You're welcome.
It's a special blend.
I roast the beans myself.
Smells like leather.
Then none for you, Murphy.
I don't drink coffee.
It is dead in here.
That's why they call
it the graveyard shift.
Oh, well, I call it paradise.
You my Trauma virgins?
Doctors Murphy, Kalu,
Browne, meet Dr. Audrey Lim,
your attending for the evening.
- Coffee?
- He roasts the beans himself.
Ah. Kiss-ass.
ER. How long? Got it.
Listen up, everybody,
we got a mass cas
coming in. It's a bus crash,
two dozen passengers. Transfer
all patients waiting for beds
up to the nursing units. Have
maintenance bring down cots.
We're gonna convert the
waiting room into triage.
No one goes home
till we're all clear.
Page everyone on-call. I don't
care what department they are,
tonight, everybody's
Trauma. Glove up and line up.
EMTs will have triaged on-site,
so the patients are
gonna come in tagged.
Love these blank faces
right before Armageddon.
Trauma color
coding, who knows it?
Green, walking wounded.
Yellow, observation.
Red, needs immediate attention.
And black, go
straight to the morgue.
All right. Red tags,
front of the line. Red tags,
front of the line.
Wedding bus blew a tire and
flipped. Twenty-six-year-old female,
second and third degrees burns
to her neck, chest and left arm.
Kalu, you're up.
Trauma Six.
Guy was ejected 30
feet from the vehicle.
Multiple chest contusions.
Acute respiratory
distress on the scene.
Sluggish pupillary response.
- How long have you been doing CPR?
- Twelve minutes.
- Have you shocked him?
- Three times.
We gotta crack him.
Dr. Browne, I got this.
You take the next
one. All right, Bay Five.
We secured the foreign object
and staunched the bleeding,
but didn't wanna
touch it otherwise.
- Good thing, it nicked her carotid.
- What is it?
Right now, it's
a little Dutch boy
keeping her from bleeding out.
Pulse ox is
dropping. She's at 87.
O2 stats down 83.
Forget about the neck, Claire.
Treat her like any other patient.
What are the first steps?
Airway, breathing, circulation.
Good. Grab a kit.
Yeah.
I need help here.
Somebody, help.
Murphy, go!
Let's go! Trauma Three.
I can't stop the bleeding.
- He's bleeding out.
- Do something.
I need a urinary catheter,
fourteen-gauge needle,
arterial guide wire,
occlusion balloon,
and 20 CCs of saline. Stat.
- What's he doing?
- I have no idea.
We don't have one, so
I'm making a REBOA.
A what?
A REBOA.
Is that even a word?
A REBOA will occlude the
damaged artery and stop the bleeding.
Release the pressure.
BP's stabilizing, 90 over 60.
Nice work, Dr. Murphy.
I made a REBOA.
Oxygen's dropping to 89.
Right, light. Open wide for me.
Throat's swollen from
smoke inhalation. Crike kit.
Do you see soot in
her mouth or nose?
No.
She doesn't need a crike,
she needs an escharotomy.
Sats are going back
up. 92 and rising.
With circumferential neck burns,
the shrinking charred
skin is acting like a noose.
Escharotomy relieves
the constriction.
Are you getting
enough air now, ma'am?
Yes. Thank you.
Now get her out of this Petri
dish and into an isolation ward
in the burn unit ASAP.
Yes, sir.
Your heart's a bit muffled.
Am I having a heart attack?
No, but it's not completely
good news. Cardiac tamponade.
He needs a pericardiocentesis.
Yes, I'm aware of that.
Eighteen-gauge and
50-CC syringe, please.
We need a fast
ultrasound in here.
They're both in use.
You don't have imaging,
you could puncture his heart.
Is the xiphoid in the same
place as it was 20 years ago?
- A REBOA.
- Ballsy. Could've gone really wrong.
Yes, well, it didn't.
It was a cowboy move,
something you would
never even dream of trying.
How many times is Shaun
gonna have to prove himself
before you give him a shot?
What happened in the ER? Swan
girl came in and you hesitated.
I wasn't hesitating, I was
thinking of a game plan.
Murphy was thinking of a game
plan. You got overwhelmed.
I wasn't.
First trauma, it happens.
You have to think clearly,
quickly, methodically.
You need to think a
little more like Shaun.
A little more, not identically.
How are you doing? Sorry.
Sorry, that's a stupid question.
You're maxed out on morphine.
I will hold off until it reloads.
How bad is it?
We're making good progress.
I'll have to debride
any deroof blisters,
prevent a secondary
nosocomial...
I need a mirror. It's
the least you can do
since you can't even
look me in the eye.
Oh, my God.
Do you know how many
hideous $300 bridesmaids' dresses
I've had to buy in
the last two years?
I decided that
when I got married,
my bridesmaids are gonna
wear black cocktail dresses.
So they can use
them again, you know?
But now... Now,
I'm Freddy Krueger.
Who's gonna wanna marry this?
I'm gonna find a nurse,
have her adjust your...
Your morphine drip.
Okay.
You've hit your face.
Your jaw got stuck. It hurts.
This shot I gave you is gonna
knock you out so that I can fix that.
Hang tight.
Crash patients' status check?
Twenty-three people total.
One fatality on-site,
lost one in the ER.
Examined all the red tags.
Got 13 yellow and green
still in the waiting room.
I'll take whoever's up next.
Marco Magallanes, severed
femoral artery, crushed femur.
I did the REBOA and then
installed a temporary shunt.
Here are his CT and MRI results.
Find someone else,
whoever's up next.
Finally.
Excuse me, are
you Marco's family?
Yes. We just found out that my
cousin didn't survive the accident.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
It's a bit much.
I'm so sorry. I'm Dr. Melendez,
and this is Dr. Murphy.
I'm Ricardo, Marco's father.
And this is his mother
Lorena, and this is Sonia.
They were getting
married tonight.
How's my son?
Marco's femur was
completely shattered
and his lower leg isn't
getting enough blood.
Can you save his leg?
Marco's suffered too much
bone fragmentation. We can't fix it.
Our only choice is to amputate.
Bay Five needs a
grade-three hyphema.
Head CT and page ophthalmology?
You read my mind.
Been a while. How you
holding up, pulling an all-nighter?
I'll manage. But if you can find
me a caffeine IV, it'd be helpful.
Please move!
Tough night. - Yeah.
- Thanks for coming.
- It's part of the job.
So, when's the big day?
Oh, we haven't set it yet.
Where's it gonna be?
We'll figure it out. Maybe
a beach somewhere?
We should talk about this later.
What? I like beaches. You
have a more romantic idea?
My family likes churches.
We should talk about this later.
Dr. Lim, I think one of your
yellows is about to turn red.
I've got my wedding all
planned out. I've got the dress,
and I've got the flowers.
All I need is a groom.
You available, Dr. Murphy?
No.
You don't want some love?
No. No, I don't.
I don't want love.
Dr. Glassman, neuro
consult, Bay Three.
Thank you.
Hey. I was here first. Shaun.
Shaun!
My patient's scans
are very important.
Well, my patient's
important, too.
I need to see my
patient's scans.
- Is your patient pre-op or post-op?
- Pre-op.
Okay. I'll give you the computer,
but you need to apologize first.
Okay, I'm sorry. Turn it on.
Why was Marco's family crying
when Dr. Melendez told them
his leg would need
to be amputated?
Well, their son's leg is
about to be cut off. It's sad.
Crying is normal.
But when your options are amputation
or death, amputation is good news.
People need time to
adjust to big changes.
Marco's family didn't even get
a chance to pray for a miracle.
It's not possible. The
bone damage is too severe.
A rod implantation won't work.
There's nothing to anchor into.
And the shunt won't last long
enough to do reconstruction.
There are no other options.
What if we could
replace the entire femur?
We're making him a new femur.
With a 3D printer?
3D-printed bones have
only successfully been done
with a mandible.
- We know.
- It's a fairly small bone.
We know.
The femur has to support
the weight of the entire body.
This one will be
titanium. It can work.
It's an interesting idea.
But I need to think on it.
Right now, we've still got
seven yellow tags waiting.
What do you have to think
about? It's a good idea.
It's a brilliant idea. The kid
has brilliant ideas. That...
No, it was my idea. I'm aware
of the risks. Infection, clotting,
- hardware failure.
- Death. It wasn't your idea.
It was my idea! And
the risks are significant,
but isn't that their
call? Don't we have to...
Maybe he said something,
and then you said
something, and together...
My idea. Completely my idea.
The brilliant idea is
100% my brilliant idea.
Why is that a problem for you?
Maybe because I've
known you for six months.
Every day, we learn new things.
Today you learned I'm brilliant.
The idea was brilliant.
And it was mine. And if anyone
can do this brilliant surgery, it's you.
Flattery. Also brilliant.
Sleeping on the job?
I just needed some fresh air.
Feels like I'm suffocating in there.
She's in pain, spilling her guts
out, and every time I open my mouth,
I sound like an idiot.
Dr. Kalu, unable to talk
to women. There's a first.
If you're not gonna be
helpful, Claire, just leave.
You don't need to
talk. Just listen to her.
You get to come out
here, clear your head.
She's trapped in there, alone
with her thoughts, her fears.
You don't think she
wants to get out?
You are her escape.
You wanna put a fake
femur into Marco's leg?
It's not fake, it's real.
It's not a real bone, we're
making it out of titanium.
It's still real.
That's incredible. And Marco
will be able to walk, run, climb?
And swim.
Hopefully. That's the intention.
Well, have you done
this surgery before?
- I haven't...
- We'll be the first.
Nobody has ever
attempted this surgery
with a bone as
large as the femur.
I believe it's a viable
option, but there are risks.
Risks? Could Marco die?
In my estimation,
there's a 10% chance
he won't make it.
Then, no. I'm not losing my son.
Wait, if there's a chance
we can save Marco's leg,
we should at least discuss this
some more. That's what he'd want.
He'd want to live.
He'd wanna have a life.
I know him. He'd want
to take the chance.
I will never forgive
myself if Marco died
because I made a
reckless decision.
Whose decision is this?
Does he have a healthcare proxy?
I don't know what that is.
When the accident happened,
were you on the way to your wedding,
- or on the way back?
- We were headed to the wedding.
Marco's parents are the
next of kin. They decide.
Please, amputate our son's leg.
Murphy.
Why is the primary
closure on the stump so vital
in amputation surgery?
For proper prosthetic fitting.
Why are you marrying Jessica?
Why does anyone get married?
I don't know.
I love her.
I don't understand why having someone
to love is so important to everyone.
You have to stand down.
You can't amputate Marco's leg.
Why not?
I filed an emergency
injunction to stop the surgery.
You were in a car accident,
your neck was punctured.
The repair surgery went well.
You're gonna have to stay put
for a week before we can release
you. You're very lucky to be alive.
My wife, Jenna
Hensel. Is she okay?
Can I see her?
She's not listed.
That's a good thing.
She's probably still
in the waiting room.
I'll find her and bring her up.
She'll be relieved
to know you're okay.
Okay.
What the hell am I supposed to
do with an unconscious patient
whose leg is a
ticking time-bomb?
Judge Singh is en route.
She wants to hear from both
parties and the doctors on the case.
I have to testify?
Hopefully not.
I thought you would be happy.
You thought you
could save the leg,
and I didn't want
that not happening
because the parents are
afraid to make a tough call.
It's their call to make.
And if the accident happened an
hour later, it would be the wife's.
And she wants the fake leg.
It's not fake.
I thought you didn't believe in
just blindly following protocol.
He's their son. Nobody's
gonna love him more than them.
Seriously? All parents love all
children more than anybody else?
People get divorced all the time.
How often do they give up their kids?
So if this was us, you'd want
your parents to decide over me.
- I didn't say that.
- You kind of did.
I was saying there
needs to be rules.
There needs to
be bright red lines
telling us who gets
to make these calls.
It's the parents' call.
Not anymore. Now it's a judge's.
How much time does Marco
have left on the temporary shunt?
Three hours, and
then his leg will die.
- Okay.
- Mmm.
Doctor Torture returns.
Thought I'd scared
you off for good.
Pick a movie.
You deserve to get out of
this room for a little while, too.
You think Groundhog Day's
gonna make a difference?
"I'm torturing you, but, hey,
you get to watch a funny movie."
That is sort of what I
was going for, yeah.
I'm sorry.
I wish there was
something else I could do.
How do you know there isn't?
This is protocol. This
is what they teach...
I lucked out.
I got the world's greatest
expert on burn victims?
You know everything
that can be done?
He loves to rock-climb,
scuba-dive, bungee-jump.
This is insane. His leg is literally
dying while we sit here reminiscing.
Please, we're trying to figure
out what your son would want.
- He'd want to live.
- I want that, too.
But if there is a way that
we can save Marco's leg,
he'd want me to do it.
Mija, do you know
what he wanted?
Most of all?
He wanted to marry you.
He wanted to spend his life
with you, have children with you.
Now, he can do all
that, he can be happy,
with a prosthetic leg.
He's young, he's strong.
Mija, he can get through this.
When we met...
I don't care about your stories.
I don't care that you
met rock-climbing,
or kayaking, or
whatever. I just want...
We met in rehab.
Hey, are either of
you Jenna Hensel?
I haven't seen Jenna since
we took pictures at the hotel.
But she got on the bus?
Yeah, she was
sitting with Noomi.
I think she's still out there.
Hey, guys, we've gotta go back.
- Where?
- To the crash site. Now.
He never wanted you to know.
He's an addict.
He replaced one
addiction for another one,
a healthier one. But he needs...
What?
He needs to wakeboard or
he'll drink himself to death?
This is ridiculous.
No, it's not. We
talked about it a lot.
It's pretty much
all you do in rehab.
Marco has clarity for
the first time in his life.
He knows what makes him
happy. He knows his weaknesses.
He's not as strong as you
think. And that's okay, but...
Marco cheated on you.
It was about a month ago.
He was overwhelmed with
the wedding and the planning.
He ran into an ex-girlfriend.
It only happened once.
You're lying. You're upset that
he had secrets from you, so...
No, she's not lying.
Mija, he was so upset.
He does love you.
Okay, maybe we're
digressing here a little bit
and we really don't
have the time...
It matters.
She doesn't know him like...
Maybe none of us do,
but we are his parents.
And you're not his wife. Yet.
Okay, get the cops,
check everywhere.
Other side of the
road, bushes, trees.
If she was ejected from the bus,
she could be 40, 50
feet in any direction.
Jenna!
I found her. I need some help.
She's got a brain bleed! We
need to get her out of here, now!
Dr. Andrews. I think
Celez may be eligible
for experimental burn treatment.
- Sell it to me.
- I've been doing some digging.
San Diego Community Hospital's
burn unit has been following
a Brazilian hospital's protocol
to wrap burns in tilapia skins.
Now... Now, I know fish
skins sound a bit crazy, but...
But I was thinking we
could do the same thing here.
Dr. Kalu, I applaud
your thinking, but...
Tilapia skins contain more collagen
proteins, both types one and three,
than even human skin,
which aids in tissue repair,
- negating the need for grafts.
- Dr. Kalu...
It can accelerate healing,
reduce risk of infection,
and cut down on a
patient's physical pain.
Are you finished, or would
you like to cut me off again?
Okay. Let's follow this through,
shall we? You have to come up
with a proposal for the experimental
treatment, get it approved
by our institutional review
board, get your hands
on medical-grade
tilapia skins, and then...
Well, I thought you could
help expedite the process.
You think I could bring it down
from three months to two hours?
You finish the debridement?
Okay. I'll take over from here.
Hey. Keep thinking outside
the box. Initiative is good.
I'm in. Bag her. Did
you get me the drill?
Fire truck had one.
What's going on?
Her pupils are blown. She
has a subdural hematoma
causing increased
intracranial pressure.
If I don't alleviate it now,
there's no way she makes it
to the hospital alive.
Unconscious female. Flail chest.
I had to do a burr hole in-field.
Her sats are in the low 70s.
She's good to go to the OR.
Subdural hematoma?
Yeah. She had decerebrate
posturing, a blown left pupil.
When I passed the
drill bit through her skull,
- a whole lot of blood pooled out.
- Good call.
San Diego Community Hospital
called. They're sending the tilapia skins.
They're medevacing 'em in.
Should be here within the hour.
Celez, you meet the criteria
for an experimental treatment
that I think will prevent you
from having to undergo skin grafts.
Hold up. How did
this even happen?
Well, I found out San Diego's trial
allows for multi-site collaborations,
so there's no need for us to get
our own IRB. They give us the skins,
we provide the patient data.
Fish skins?
The tilapia skins have
been cleaned and sterilized,
they're perfectly safe.
You'll do it?
I'll do it.
Well done, Dr. Kalu. Well done.
So help you God?
Yes. Dr. Melendez
can tell you...
He has. But the fake
femur is yours, though, right?
- How confident are you in its design?
- It's not fake.
Shaun, she needs to know...
I know what she needs to know.
She needs to know will it work,
she needs to know
how long it will last.
Yes.
Okay.
He's his doctor?
He is a surgical
resident. He's very gifted...
Is he going to
answer my questions?
Shaun, I really
need you to focus.
- Marco is running out of time.
- Just let him answer!
We already know the
answer. They don't know.
If this thing's never
been done before...
Be quiet!
His toes are changing color.
He's clotting. That's bad.
Page Dr. Melendez, stat.
Murphy, what've we got?
The shunt is clotting. It's
restricting blood flow. It's failing.
We need a decision now. Are we
cutting off the leg or replacing the bone?
There's no doubt in my mind
that Marco's parents and fiancée
all love Marco, but
it's become clear that...
Now. I need a decision now.
His parents know him as their
child. Sonia knows him as a man.
Replace the femur.
Let's go.
Thank you! Thank you.
- And there's the bleed. See it?
- Yes, sir.
You ever clipped an
intracranial artery before?
No, sir.
Go for it.
Just like every first time.
You're a little excited,
a little nauseous.
Hopefully, nobody gets hurt.
Is it good to go?
It's very good.
Forceps.
Are you ready?
Yes.
Be careful the clip blades don't
catch any perforated arteries.
I don't see any
vessels in the way.
Then what are you waiting for?
Very nice.
Thank you.
Everything's dry. Say
goodbye. Close the roof.
Need to get blood back into
his leg in the next minute or so,
or I'm gonna have
to amputate after all.
Insulin's hanging. Loaded
him with calcium. Best I can do.
Let's release the clamps.
Check for capillary refill.
Blood flow is restored.
EKG is normal.
Okay, Kim, I wanna hear words
like "variability" and "delta."
Give them to me.
I'm waiting patiently.
I'm not getting anything.
Show me.
Check the leads?
Still nothing.
Maybe there'll be
some neuroplasticity.
Her brain, it
could rewire itself.
No.
Zero brain activity. I don't
know why, but she's gone.
What?
Your neurosurgery
patient that died tonight.
There's something
you should know.
What?
Okay, Marco, I want you
to try to move your toes.
I can't.
- Is he okay?
- We're not sure if the bone...
But he's not gonna die.
He's not gonna get an
infection, his body's not...
We're monitoring
him very closely.
- The biggest threat is behind him...
- He moved.
He moved.
It worked.
You have a long recovery ahead,
months of physical therapy.
But for now, all you
have to do is rest.
Thank you.
Thank you for saving my life,
for saving my leg.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome, sir.
Are you ready to
finish what we started?
Get well first.
There's plenty of
time for a wedding.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- You're welcome, sir.
You look good.
Tough, like Aquaman.
I look like sushi.
Everybody loves sushi.
It's only for six months.
Your new skin should have
completely grown in by then.
You should have minor scarring.
Thank you.
I misjudged you.
You judged me just right.
She's still sleeping?
- You haven't told her yet?
- No.
Can I have a moment, please?
Of course.
How soon after you found Jenna
at the crash site
did you intubate her?
Almost immediately.
I did a sternal rub, she
had decerebrate posturing,
her left pupil was blown.
I knew she had a subdural hematoma,
so I intubated and did the burr hole.
She also had a flail chest.
Did you check her breathing
after you intubated her?
Yes.
At least I think I did.
Dr. Lim told me that,
when Jenna came into the ER,
she wasn't ventilating properly.
You inserted the tube too deep
into her right main stem bronchus
of her injured lung.
We had no way of knowing
how long she was hypoxic
before we gave her the EEG.
I drilled the perfect burr hole
into her skull on the side of a
road in the middle of the night,
and I screw up her intubation?
Yes.
It was tough conditions
for anyone, resident or not.
Any one of us could have
made the same mistake.
I had a woman come
into the ER once.
A mother, 51 years old.
Francine Parker.
She had two boys.
She had a cough, a
bad one, but a cough.
I checked her out, gave her
some antibiotics, sent her home.
Six hours later, she
was rolled into the ER.
She had had a heart
attack and I missed it. And...
She died.
Not one day goes by
when I don't think about her.
She was your first?
My fourth, actually.
You're not gonna forget this.
You never forget.
But I don't know, maybe we're
better off for it the next time around.
You gotta find a
way to keep going.
Yeah.
Go home, get some rest.
- I haven't even told her yet.
- You're not going to.
You made a mistake.
You're too close to this.
I'm not gonna allow
you to talk to the family,
to anyone else outside
this hospital about this.
Do we understand each other?
Yes, sir.
I don't have all
the words to say
I'm still healing
from my mistakes
I'll take the weight if
it makes you stronger
I don't want to leave
you in this place
I called San Diego Community
Hospital to thank them
for including us in their study.
They said they
were happy to do it,
and they asked that I pass
along their thanks to you
for your very generous
donation to their burn unit.
I know you come from a wealthy
family, I don't begrudge that,
but you can't open your wallet
every time a patient's in need.
The lines can get
real blurry, real fast.
Yes, sir.
Who am I to try and save you
I ain't gonna hide
You have to fight...
What's this?
My healthcare proxy.
Jess, nothing's gonna happen.
Really? That's good to know.
I won't let you down
No, no, no
Well, that was quite a night.
Been a doctor for a long while.
I don't remember a
night quite like that one.
Why did Nurse Ferrara
ask if I wanted love?
'Cause she's a nosy...
Shaun, you really
don't want love?
I loved Steve and my rabbit.
Not anymore.
You don't love them anymore?
No, I don't. They're dead.
You can't love
someone if they're dead.
Well, I've lost people I love.
I miss them. It hurts.
But I still love them.
I don't want love.
Okay.
You want breakfast?
Can I have four
pancakes instead of three?
You can have five.
I only want four.
Okay.