♪♪
Surgeons like to believe
they're the center
of the universe,
that their
million-dollar hands
are the only thing
that matters.
I don't know how you do
the thing you just did...
...but it -mm --
was...spectacular.
Mm-hmm!
Well, I got to give you
a reason to keep me around.
Well, maybe tonight,
I might just
return the favor.
♪ Nobody tryna play you
Ooh.
♪ Red pill, blue,
what to choose? ♪
Maybe sooner than that. Hm?
Richard Webber,
are you still on that?
Come on.
I already told you no.
Well, maybe it's time
to reconsider.
Well, what if something
goes wrong, baby?
Trust me.
♪ Fall in love with me tonight
♪ No need to play it cool,
babe ♪
You only need a scalpel
and the patient to use it on.
No one else.
I used to believe it, too.
Levi!
Um, I'll be
right there.
Check your phone.
But that
was before I had kids.
Oh, my God.
What?
Webber's back as residency
director, officially.
What happened to Grey?
Uh, it says she'll be
splitting her time
between doing surgery
and research.
Levi!
Uh...
Oh, it also says
we were supposed to be
in the skills lab
15 minutes ago!
Okay. I'm coming!
♪ Stubborn like a mule, babe
♪ Trying to save your pride
What?
♪ You ain't got to hide
♪ I can tell how
I look you in the eyes ♪
Truth is, from the time
your patient first gets sick
to the time they're
lying on your table...
Hey.
I thought you were leaving
early this morning.
She started seizing when I was
on my way to the airport,
so I hit her with lorazepam,
phenobarbital
and put her in
an induced coma.
And now I need
a world-class neurosurgeon
to help me figure out
why my landmark transplant
patient is circling the drain.
♪ Come fall all the way
...a team of internists,
specialists, and nurses
have already interacted
with that patient
more than you ever will.
♪ No need to play it cool
I was starting to think
you weren't gonna show up.
I almost didn't.
I can't stand the whining.
Well, you don't
have to stay long.
Is that Roy?
When you write these
testimonials,
I want you to lay it
all on the table.
I want to know every
diagnosis, every symptom.
Did you lose 40 pounds?
Are you sweating
through your sheets?
Explosive diarrhea.
Do not hold back.
Testimonials?
Roy's headed to Washington
next month to lobby.
Won't shut up about it.
We gotta do to the VA
what Barb Simmons did to me
in the fourth grade when I was
hanging on the monkey bars --
pull their shorts down
and expose them.
Bastards.
No, it couldn't be.
Sergeant.
Colonel.
Thought you said you'd never be
caught dead at one of these.
Anyone's dying,
it's you, old man.
Yeah.
It's good to see
you, man.
Good to see you.
You look good.
Roy, I want to introduce
you to Major...
Owen Hunt,
Army trauma surgeon.
Welcome.
And what delightful disease have
you been blessed with?
None, fortunately.
Um, I'm here because
I'm hoping we might be able
to work together.
I'm starting a study
to prove the link
between burn pits
and your illnesses
so that the VA
will have to auto--
You okay?
Roy.
Roy?
Roy, Roy!
Put him on his side.
Call 911!
Is she okay?
Oh, teething.
Well, in that case,
are you okay?
I haven't slept,
all I've eaten is
a handful of cereal --
no, no, no, no, no! --
and I'm late for work.
I'm sorry I asked.
Thank you.
Okay.
I knew how to be alone,
but now I'm alone with Luna.
I'm responsible
for her life.
I'm so tired,
I could drop dead.
Tough stuff being
a single parent.
You don't happen to have
any teething tips, do you?
At this point, I would
try ritual sacrifice.
Earplugs?
Oh.
Help!
I need some help!
Okay.
Oh, I'm sorry, I'm sorry,
I'm sorry.
I don't -I don't know
what's wrong with her.
She just started screaming
and breathing and --
Are you in labor?
I'm not due for
a couple more weeks.
Okay, um...
You're pregnant?
Is it mine?
We've been together
for four weeks.
How would it be yours?
I'm gonna page OB.
Oh, I am OB.
Here. Can you, um,
take her to daycare for me?
Bye, baby.
Gladly.
Okay, um, go inside
and ask for a wheelchair.
Now, now!
Yeah, okay.
Hi. Congratulations.
You're doing great.
Okay, deep breaths.
Nurse Tyler to the OR.
Grey! I thought you'd be
settled in Minnesota by now.
I leave later on this evening.
And I'm only going for
a couple of days a week.
Mm.
And I'm still your
chief of general.
And as long as you credit
Grey-Sloan
when you save humanity,
you do you.
What I want to know
is why Webber has paged us here
to the skills lab.
And cleared
my whole schedule.
You too?
Yes.
Well, I don't know who approved
this, but it sure wasn't --
I did.
Would you like
to tell us why?
It's a big day.
Not only is it
my first official day back
as residency director,
I'm debuting a new
teaching method,
and the two of you
are going to help me.
Uh --
Come on.
Uh...
Alright,
attention, everyone.
Today is gonna be a day
that you will remember
for the rest of your careers.
Each one of you is gonna perform
a lap chole start to finish --
on your own.
Today, you will be attendings.
What?!
Oh, my God!
Are you kidding?
He's serious.
Welcome to
the Webber Method.
I take it back.
What?
You can't
go to Minnesota.
This man has lost
his damned mind.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Yes, God!
Hunt, what's going on?
Roy Davis, 60,
experienced syncope after
an episode of hemoptysis.
BP is 160 over 100,
and he's tachycardic.
Gonna need chest films
ASAP.
Roy.
They won't show anything good,
I can promise you that.
Roy, I'm here.
He has the same thing I have --
pulmonary fibrosis --
more advanced.
Listen, I know you'd rather
chew gravel than hang out here,
so don't --
I'm staying.
Trauma 1 is open.
Okay, let's
get him inside!
You stay in the lobby.
I'll update you as soon
as I can, okay?
Niki, you are 5 centimeters
dilated and having
this baby today.
Congratulations.
But it's too early.
I'm not ready.
And -And -And today's
our one-month anniversary.
Wow! It's a special day
all around.
Who's the dad?
No dad. Just a hook-up.
We had sex.
A lot of sex.
I had a lot of sex with
a pregnant woman.
It works just the same.
Okay, but, like,
I'm pretty sure that's
outside of
my moral code.
W-Why didn't you tell me?
Look at me.
I thought you knew.
I just
thought you were --
Aaaah!
Okay. Uh, Dustin, right?
Uh, Niki is in good hands.
Why don't you take a breather,
go find some ice chips?
For her, not you.
Niki, are you okay?
My chest really hurts.
Okay, Wilson, let's get
an EKG and vitals.
Right.
Okay.
Breathe.
Good.
Okay, now, this system of
concurrent surgeries will allow
us to put experienced residents
in the OR as leads,
and then attendings
can rotate in and out
for maximum efficiency.
I don't like it.
Look, look.
If you look here,
the average lap chole
lasts what -45 minutes?
But the most critical
part only lasts...
5 to 10.
Exactly.
Which means, if each
attending rotates
according to the schedule,
we can be in
each and every OR --
At precisely the moment
we need to be.
Yes.
I still don't like it.
Bailey, this is the answer
to our biggest challenge
right now --
the physician shortage.
A-And it's lap choles.
It's not transplants
and Whipples.
Look, this generation
of residents --
they don't have a thousand hours
to watch us operate
while we work them
to the bone.
I mean, they want to
work smarter, not harder.
And who would blame them?
I don't need
generation education.
I need patients
not to die.
I've been saying
for a long time that
we need to get the residents
out of the lab and into the OR.
Uh...
What do you say, Bailey?
You ready to do
12 lap choles today?
Look, the system only works
with three attendings.
We all have to be
on board.
God help us. Fine.
Let's do it.
You won't regret it.
Okay.
Let's not go that far.
Dr. Wagner to radiology.
Oh, Hayes, hey.
Do you have a quick second
for a pediatric consult?
For Grey's award-winning
abdomen? Sure.
A 14-year-old kid,
plays soccer in a park
near our hotel.
Mm-hmm.
Seemed to be getting
extra winded
the other day.
Um, his ankles look
a little swollen.
Is that --
Is that anything?
Could be. Or not.
I'm sorry.
I'd have to examine him myself
to tell you anything
more definitive.
I was afraid
you'd say that.
So, how'd you meet Noah?
He avoids doctors like
the plague.
I, uh, treated him
and his son recently.
Ah, the accident.
That tree will never
be the same.
Or the car.
Noah's the closest thing
I have to a son.
Met him when he was
a pimple-faced recruit
whose voice had barely dropped.
I watched him
grow up, get married,
have Danny.
Have you met Heather yet?
His wife? No, not yet.
I love Noah, but he punched
above his weight on that one.
The scans are up.
Oh, man. Damn it.
See that nodule there?
Lung cancer.
Probably an early stage,
but since he's also got
pulmonary fibrosis...
Might as well be terminal.
All because the U.S. military
couldn't be bothered
to properly dispose
of its trash.
Lotta silence out there.
Must be good news, huh?
♪♪
CT's negative,
labs look good.
She has no history
of seizures?
You don't think I would
have told you if there's
a history of seizures?
Mm. No family history?
Same answer.
Okay, but it is my job
to ask the questions.
No, I get that, but maybe just
ask smarter questions.
Are you okay?
No, I'm not the patient.
Ask smarter questions
about my patient.
Addie --
No. Just no, no, no.
I'm Dr. Montgomery.
You're Dr. Shepherd.
And we are fixing this woman
who's lost so many pregnancies
and then lost her husband.
We are fixing this woman
whose sisters
literally begged her
not to participate
in my clinical trial
because they were so afraid
of losing her, too.
We are fixing this woman,
Dr. Shepherd.
And, ideally,
we are going to fix her
without having to
remove the donor uterus,
setting my study
all the way back.
Okay, Dr. Montgomery.
I need an MRI.
Um, because she was in status,
let's get an EEG.
And re-run her
electrolyte panel
and her immunosuppressant
levels.
That sounds like
an excellent plan.
Mm-hmm.
Hi.
Back so soon?
Uh, that patient I told you
about -he's here.
Exam Room 4.
That was fast.
A little too fast.
But just make sure you talk
to him like a doctor.
I am a doctor.
Be straight with him --
with both of us, okay?
Okay.
Dr. Hayes,
this is my son, Farouk.
Hi.
♪♪
Mm.
Hm.
Are you...
Praying. Yes.
It's going to be okay,
Bailey.
These are human beings.
These are human beings
with children and parents
and sisters and brothers.
And we're putting
their bodies, their lives
in the hands of...
children.
But they're not children.
But they look like children...
with scalpels.
Well, so did we once.
♪ One time Mnh-mnh.
♪ Oh, yeah
♪ Two times
You've done
this before, right?
In Pakistan?
Years ago.
Many years ago.
Scalpel.
♪ It make me wanna dance
♪ Big sound
♪ In my system
♪ Four times
♪ Is a rebellion
♪ Sweetie make me happy
What are you doing?
I saw Shepherd do it once.
♪ Oh, yeah, oh, yeah
oh, yeah, oh, yeah ♪
Scalpel.
♪ Searchin' for some lovin'
♪ Don't you worry
'cause I'm here ♪
Scalpel.
♪ You're my
♪ One in a million
♪ Oh
♪ Are you ready?
♪ Are you ready for some fun?
♪ Oh, na, yeah
♪ Are you ready?
♪ We can't stop
♪ We've only just begun
♪ Oh, yeah
♪ Ooo
♪ I show you somethin' new
♪ Hey
♪ I'm gonna make you move
♪ I show you something
♪ You're my
♪ One in a million
♪ Ooo
♪ Are you ready?
♪ We can't stop
♪ We've only just begun
♪ Oh, yeah
♪ Ooo
♪ I show you something new
♪ Hey
♪ I'm gonna make you move
Hey, Doctor.
Um, can you give this
to Niki?
She asked me to charge it,
and so it's charged.
Here.
Oh, come on.
You're leaving?
You can't just hold her hand
for a few hours
so she doesn't
give birth alone?
We matched
online a month ago.
I'm not a bad guy.
I work at the Post Office.
I live in a studio apartment.
I'm not ready to be a dad.
And she lied to me.
I mean, don't you think this
is a pretty big lie?
Just give me the phone.
Okay.
Um...
Farouk's EKG shows
nonspecific ST changes.
And I hear
a concerning murmur.
So I'm not losing
my mind.
No.
Is there anything
I should know
about Farouk's
medical history?
He used to get a lot
of ear infections.
He once fell off his bike
and knocked out his two front
teeth, and it was just -Right.
Not relevant.
He was treated for TB about
10 years ago in Iraq.
I don't know anything about the
first four years of his life.
Iraq.
That's where he grew up?
He was born in Syria,
but he came to Iraq
as a refugee
after his parents died.
I raised him while
I was being held as a POW
and, you know,
getting my abs exploded.
You and your brother
both served.
I didn't realize.
How would you?
I want to do an echo.
Do it. Do it all.
Uh, Hayes,
and do you mind
just keeping this
between us for now?
If Owen finds out about this,
he'll freak out,
and I'm already
freaking out a little bit.
I've been there.
Of course.
Thank you.
Hey there, Roy.
Well, you two gonna tell me
what you saw on those scans?
My ex-wife looks happier
to see me than you two.
Noah, you mind
giving us a minute?
No, it's okay, Doc.
He -He -He can stay.
Roy, there was an abnormality
in a section of your lung,
and it looks like it's
an early stage of cancer.
Early.
Doesn't sound so bad.
Well, with cancer,
the usual surgical treatment
would be a lobectomy.
We'd take out
that entire section.
But with fibrosis
this advanced,
you can't afford to
give up
that much
of your lung function.
Well, I didn't exactly
think I had a whole decade
in front of me.
So, what're we talking?
A couple years?
Sooner?
Hmm?
What can you do to get me
to Congress next month?
Well, we could try
a segmentectomy,
where we'd just remove
the mass.
It's very risky, though.
Honestly, I don't know
that I'd recommend it.
But it could buy me
some more time, yeah?
Possibly. A little.
Well, let -let's do it.
Slice me open.
Roy, no.
Send somebody else
to Washington.
Hey, if I collapse
while I'm there,
it might help our case, right?
It's fine.
I have
a little cancer, yeah?
I've spent
my entire career --
hell, my entire life --
fighting.
Why would I stop now?
I want the surgery.
Okay.
Tell me why you
left Scout's dad.
I already told you.
No, you told me you said no
to his proposal,
but you didn't
tell me why.
Uh. Well, everything about it
was a disaster.
I mean, it felt gaslighty
and manipulative
that he did it
at Maggie's wedding,
using Mer's kids as props.
Is he a gaslighty and
manipulative guy as a rule?
No.
Because, you know, the other way
you could see that proposal
is that he was being
incredibly earnest and romantic.
I mean,
if you were a person
who saw the world through
rose-colored glasses,
you know, like people in --
in love do.
Okay, I want to go back
to pretending
we don't know each other.
And we'll do that when
the films are up.
How come you get to
make all the rules?
Because I'm older
and because my patient
might be brain-damaged,
and I need to be distracted.
So tell me why
you said no.
Um...
I knew for months that
I didn't want what he wanted.
We had Scout,
and we had Mer's kids
because she was
in the hospital with --
I heard. I prayed.
Yeah.
So we were drowning
in children and domesticity,
and every day, I felt like
I might die of it.
I love all the kids,
but every day,
I thought I might die
of monotony and boredom
and dirty diapers
and dirty dishes and laundry.
And every day,
I thought about doing drugs.
And every night,
I went to virtual meetings.
And I am here
to tell you that
those virtual meetings...
...while better
than no meetings,
are no substitute for
regular in-person meetings.
They're not the same.
And, so, I was hanging
by a thread,
and, um, Link...wasn't.
He was falling in love
with domesticity.
And he was
the world's most stand-up guy.
And he started proposing
all the time,
despite me saying no.
And he decided that
he wanted more kids,
and I felt like
I couldn't breathe.
And, um, then I judged
myself for that,
like I think
you are judging me now.
During the pandemic,
I drank so much red wine,
I seriously considered
checking myself into rehab.
Really?
Really.
I looked
like a swollen tick.
I lost it.
Lost it.
I just hated -hated --
being stuck at home.
You know,
some people loved it.
They baked bread.
I don't like bread.
I began to truly hate
my video-game-obsessed son
and my husband,
who, by the way,
took up a model-train hobby that
seemed to truly delight him.
No.
Exactly.
Mm.
Yeah, I um -I went
really dark, Amelia.
I had
dark, dark thoughts.
I was daydreaming about going to
sleep and never waking up,
and that thought...
comforted me.
I hate that for you.
And thank you.
Thank you.
Because...me too.
Films are up,
Dr. Shepherd.
♪♪
Venting the ports.
You're already finished?
Yeah.
Is that bad?
Oh, gosh.
Did I forget something?
No, no, no.
It's -It's --
We just got one more
lap chole through the ER.
You're making
excellent time.
How's about
a double feature, Schmitt?
Hell yeah.
Dr. Webber, sir.
That's what
I'm talking about.
Your patient
will be in OR 7.
Khan, you'll assist.
We got two lap choles!
Yes, we did!
0 Vicryl, please.
Looking good, brother.
Okay.
Whoa! Looks like you have
some visitors, Roy.
Eh, just
a few familiar faces.
Look at this
sorry lot, huh?
Eh, Noah shouldn't have
bothered you all.
Well, you knew we had to get
our last licks in
before you went under
the knife.
Ah, yeah.
Listen, if I don't
make it out of there --
Will you shut up?
Of course you'll make it.
You know, at our base,
the guys from the Afghan army
would bring chickens
and cook them for us.
Well, one day,
they brought a live sheep.
Remember this?
And Roy insisted on
helping out.
Told 'em he'd, uh, butchered
pigs before or some lie.
I stand by that lie.
And this sheep -well,
he did not like Roy.
The second he got near him,
he got kicked in the head,
knocked on his ass,
and trampled.
What happened
to the sheep?
Well, he took off,
left Roy on the ground,
bloody and bruised.
That's gotta hurt.
So I run over,
and Roy is out cold.
And just when I start to panic,
his crazy eyes fly open.
He jumps up, screaming,
"Yeehaw!"
And he takes off
after that sheep.
I have no memory of that.
I -I --
Probably
because of the concussion.
Point is, if that angry sheep
can't get rid of you,
nothing can.
Pbht.
♪♪
Okay.
You guys,
I won't forget this.
You all coming here for me.
♪♪
We ready?
We're ready.
Go.
Yeah.
We got your six.
Alright, brother.
You got this,
brother.
Get 'em, Roy.
♪♪
Niki, your
EKG looks normal,
and cardio couldn't
see anything on your echo.
So is it possible that you're
experiencing a little anxiety?
Is it possible?!
I'm having a baby,
and, somehow,
my new boyfriend didn't
notice I was pregnant.
Of course it is possible.
Where is Dustin with
those ice chips?
What is important
right now
is that you take some
deep breaths
and stay calm, okay?
He left, didn't he?
I'm all alone.
I can't do this all alone.
Yes, you can.
I know you can.
All my friends
thought I was crazy
for having
some random guy's baby.
And my parents told me
they wanted no part of it.
So I moved
across the country.
And I was
lonely and scared.
And then I met Dustin,
and he didn't seem to mind.
How did he not notice?
I don't know, Niki.
But -But you wanted
to have this baby,
and you are about
to meet him.
I just wanted someone
to hold my hand.
I'll hold your hand.
Who's gonna
deliver the baby?
Um, hey, uh, can you page
Dr. DeLuca, please?
Now.
Here we go.
We almost have the critical
view of safety cleared.
Are we ready
to move forward?
The field is filling with blood.
Why is the field
filling with blood?
Maybe you
should suction.
But you're my assist.
Maybe you should suction!
Okay, uh, indications to convert
to open cholecystectomy --
adhesions, fibrosis,
unclear anatomy, hemorrhage.
This could be the cystic artery,
the hepatic artery...
We have to open her up.
We?
Get the trocars out.
And somebody
call an attending.
Okay, the good news is,
there's no sign of CVA,
edema, or tumor.
And there's no electrolyte
abnormalities or infection.
Okay, well, that's good news
and bad news.
Why?
Because with everything
else ruled out,
it's likely that
the seizures are being caused
by neurotoxicity
from anti-rejection meds.
Damn it. Damn it!
We can switch her
immunosuppressants
and keep her on anticonvulsants
and watch her like a hawk.
I live in
Los Angeles, okay?
And as much
as I hated them
when I was trapped
in a house with them,
I do love
my son and my husband.
I have to get
back home to them.
I mean, I-I had arranged
for the clinical-trial team
to monitor her
from here on out.
I can, too.
Oh, I can't because
I'm going back and forth
to Minnesota.
But Bailey can
or s-someone can.
What I'm saying is,
we can help.
You'll just have to share
credit when you publish.
Don't say that like
it's a small thing.
I mean, it's risky.
She's had so many seizures.
If she seizes up again,
I --
Well, we've loaded her
with anticonvulsants.
We will watch
her closely.
If we have to take out the
uterus, we take out the uterus.
But let's cross that bridge
when we come to it.
I want
to agree with you.
Okay, so what's
stopping you?
I need to not kill
this patient.
I need to not
let her die.
And -And helping her
helped me.
It excited me.
A uterine transplant?
I mean, the thought of
creating something for her
that didn't exist
before her
made me want to get out of bed
in the morning.
But I don't want to make
a decision that's selfish.
I need to prioritize her life
over the study.
And I need you to tell me
if there's a chance
that you think I'm not.
Dr. Montgomery, your patient
was so in love with her husband
that she is having a baby
with him even though he is dead.
She's so in love with the idea
of becoming a mother
that she entered your study
knowing that she was
risking her life.
You are not
being selfish.
You are doing
every single thing you can
to help her
live her dream.
And that is
an excellent reason
to get out of bed
in the morning.
♪♪
We're almost
ready here, Roy.
Are you sure you still want to
go through with this?
I got a daughter.
She lives on the East Coast
with her husband, two kids.
I don't ever see them.
She took her mother's side
in the divorce,
and that -that was it.
But if someone
had done this to her,
if someone had made her
breathe in that crap
and caused her
a lifetime of pain,
I'd want that person dead.
Roy, we're going to
stop this.
We're going to hold the people
at fault responsible, okay?
I'm responsible.
I'm not sure
I understand.
I authorized it.
The burn pit on our base.
Trash was piling up.
There was no plumbing,
no sewage system.
And it's not like the garbageman
comes on Tuesdays. I --
I heard the, uh,
other bases were burning it all.
So...that's what
I told them to do.
I didn't invent the idea...
...but when I close my eyes
at night,
I see that black smoke
billowing up from the ground,
and I know that I committed
the worst crime...
...complicity.
♪♪
So, at the end of the day,
I might deserve to die.
Everyone else deserves to live.
Let's do it.
Let's go.
What happened?
I-I don't know.
The field filled with blood,
and now I converted to open.
And now --
Well,
you should have waited.
She was bleeding out.
You still should have waited.
I'm sorry, Chief, but --Step aside.
Okay, I need another suction
and I need laps now.
What can I do?
If you want this patient
to live, step aside.
Okay.
Okay, suction.
Okay, clamp.
I have never seen
lung tissue like this. You?
I have -in advanced ARDS,
secondary to COVID.
And it didn't end well.
Suction.
The tissue's just
falling apart in my hands.
Stapler.
Thanks.
Okay.
Thank you for doing this.
I know you didn't think
it was a good idea.
No, I didn't, but I believe
in fighting for what's right,
and if giving this guy
a few more months
helps make life better
for others, I'm in.
Okay. Alright.
He's hemorrhaging.
Hold pressure.
I'll try to find the source.
Yep.
DeBakey clamp -now!
Yeah, yeah.
Come on.
There. Got it.
Alright. So, that's how this
is gonna go, huh, Roy?
I've only known
this guy for eight hours.
I'm pretty sure he's not
going to make it easy on us.
I operated in Boston
for 15 years.
No patient
made it easy on me.
Hemostats.
Finished.
And that, ladies and gentlemen,
is how it's done.
Yes, it is!
Flawless technique on not one,
but two lap choles today.
Take notes if you want
to survive.
Thank you, sir,
for the opportunity,
the patients, the wis--You know,
by working together,
we saved 13 patients
from cholecystitis --
a hospital record.
You should all be proud.
Now, study hard.
Today was lap chole.
Tomorrow, it could be
something more.
Don't come unprepared.
Yes!
♪♪
Hi, Tovah.
I'm Dr. Shepherd.
♪ Every little heartache
Is it gone?
Did I -Did I lose it?
Did you take the uterus?
No.
But, Tovah...
you didn't reject it.
♪ When I was wasted
Is there still
a chance?
There's still a chance.
We're gonna step up
your protocol,
and you're still
in the trial.
Oh, my God, thank you.
♪ I mostly now forget
Thank you. My God.
♪ I flew all around the world
I'm gonna do
a quick neuro check.
Let just...
give her a minute to cry.
♪ It was all the same
♪ It was all a game
Wilson,
what are you doing?!
She won't
let go of my hand!
Okay, you're an OB.
Your job is to deliver
the babies, not to hold hands.
♪ So break my heart
Okay.
A-And she's crowning.
Niki, I need to help
get the baby out,
but I will be
right over here.
No, no, no.
No, I can't do this.
I just can't.
Niki, you're worried
about being alone.
You're not alone.
You have your son,
and as soon as he comes out,
he will be
your whole heart.
And it's hard,
and it's exhausting,
and there are days when you will
turn around and wonder,
"Where is this baby's mother?
Because it absolutely
cannot be me."
♪ Go on and break my heart
But you will love him
so much,
you'll let him sleep on you
anywhere, anytime,
no matter how uncomfortable
you are.
And just one smell of his head
will make you feel like
your heart could explode.
And that is worth so much more
than your fear.
Okay?
You ready to start pushing?
On the count of three.
One, two, three.
Push, push, push, push.
Here's the head.
Good.
Wait, wait, wait.
Niki, stop pushing.
Okay, uh,
shoulder dystocia.
Baby's shoulder is caught
behind the pubic bone.
Okay, Wilson,
what do you do?
Uh, we're doing a McRoberts
maneuver to get the baby out.
Wait. A what?
We've got you, Niki.
♪ Every little heartache,
every little mistake ♪
Alright.
We ready to push again?
Okay.
Alright.
One, two, three.
Go.
Okay, Wilson,
put your hand in and find
the anterior
shoulder, okay?
You got it?
Yep.
Okay.
Now push the back of the baby's
shoulder towards the chest.
Gently.
Okay.
Here he comes.
Oh, my goodness.
You have a boy.
♪♪
Well done, Wilson.
♪ Into a thousand parts
♪♪
Farouk's echo
and cardiac MRI
show constrictive
pericarditis.
Most likely
secondary to the TB.
Hm.
I'm so sorry.
I-I wish it
was better news.
He's already been through
so much,
more than any kid should.
And the hits
just keep coming.
Do you want
to be alone?
I'm sorry.
I don't --
I don't usually do this.
It's your son.
All bets are off.
Mnh.
Uh, okay, so --
so what does this mean?
Is he gonna need surgery or...
I have to consult with cardio,
but I think so, yes.
Most likely
a pericardiectomy.
Oh, God.
I'll admit him,
and we'll go from there.
Oh, Farouk!
Oh, my God!
God, he's so --
he's so good.
I mean,
he's a teenager, but...
God, he's just
always been such a good kid,
despite what this
messed-up world has given him.
He has to be okay.
I will do everything in my power
to make sure that he is.
That's a promise.
Okay.
Do you want me to
call your brother?
I'll tell him,
just not yet.
I...
I-I need
to sit with this by myself
for -for a minute.
Take all the time
you need.
♪♪
So, his lungs had more scarring
than we expected.
It's gonna be
a tough road ahead.
Well, he can handle it.
I know he can.
Thank you.
Honestly, you're
the first doctor I've met
who actually gave a crap,
who's really done anything
for any of us.
Well...I'm sorry
that's the case.
But this is personal
to me, you know?
I am in this with
all of you guys, okay?
W-What's happening?
Dr. Hunt!
Noah, I'm gonna need you
to leave, okay?
I'm not leaving him.
Sergeant, step outside, now!
Now!
Damn it,
his O2 is plummeting.
Noah, you got to go.
Come on, Roy.
V-fib! Paddles!
Sir, you're
not allowed in here.
Sir, you've got to go.
Come on, Roy.
Hang in there!
Okay,
let's charge to 120.
Ready? And clear.
No change.
Push 1 of epi.
Charge to 150.
And...clear!
Come on, Roy.
200!
And clear!
♪♪
Who wants cider?
Congratulations, sweetheart.
Ah.
I know I was skeptical,
but 13 lap choles,
that is something.
Yes.
Even though you did con me
into agreeing this morning.
Con?
Mm-hmm.
Is that what you're
calling it, what we did?
Mm-hmm.
Well, you've set the bar
very high for yourself.
The residents are going to
expect this all the time.
Ohh.
I mean, who knows?
The scrub nurses may walk out.
Ah, well,
everyone will adapt.
They'll have to,
because from now on,
this is gonna be
my primary method of teaching.
To the Webber Method.
Yeah.
Ooh! Rolls off the tongue,
doesn't it?
Mm-hmm.
Ah.
You still
don't like it.
No, I don't.
Look,
Helm clipped that artery
with no attending
in the room.
When I first walked in
and saw all that blood,
even I didn't know
which way was up,
so how was a resident
supposed to?
You know as well as I
that complications
could happened to --
to -to any one of us.
Which is why we owe it
to them and the patients
to be there in the room.
Bailey,
10 years from now,
we are going to be short
tens of thousands of surgeons
if we don't rethink
what we're doing here.
We're a teaching hospital,
and we have a moral imperative
to make sure that people
don't die because
there's no one to
operate on them.
That's what we owe
these patients.
Helm did prove
the system worked.
She asked for help.
She did exactly what
she was supposed to do.
And you were there,
and you helped.
The patient's alive
and stable and in recovery.
It did work.
Oh, yeah.
To the Webber Method.
No. I-I'm sorry.
What, now?
To the Webber Method!
Ah!
♪♪
I'm so sorry, Noah.
We did everything we could.
Roy's lungs
were just...too far gone,
and the damage put
too much stress on his heart.
Noah...
♪♪
I can help you continue
Roy's work, you know,
the data,
the testimonials.
Yeah, I don't
want your help.
I never wanted it in the first
place, but you convinced me.
You convinced me to introduce
you to my friends,
my family,
and look what happened.
You made it
so much worse.
♪♪
You know, I almost left Jake
in the first lockdown,
in the thick of it,
about two months in.
I wasn't even drinking.
I was stone-cold sober.
I just --
God.
They were bickering
about "Game of Thrones,"
and I just
got up off the couch,
got in the car,
and drove.
Drove for about two hours
before I stopped
and even thought to ask myself
what I was doing.
Are you asking
if I'm sure?
I am saying that
when one is in a slight
mental-health crisis,
one might regret the decisions
she makes later.
I didn't leave when I was
thinking about doing drugs.
And I didn't leave
when I was wondering
if Link would ever
really understand me.
I stayed
through all of that
because I thought
I must be crazy,
because who leaves
a really good and decent guy?
But I don't feel crazy now.
And I don't
want to get high.
I just don't want a ring,
and I don't want to have
any more babies.
And -And I didn't
even leave him.
He left me. But...
But I hated the life
that he loved,
and so I think that
the sanest and kindest thing
I could possibly do
is to let him go,
no matter how much
it sometimes aches.
Look at you.
♪♪
Look at me, what?
Look at you, Amelia Shepherd,
all grown up.
♪♪
♪ Pieces of my heart
♪ Scatter like stones
♪ And I'm just trying
to figure it out ♪
Rough day?
Yeah, I had better.
Sorry to hear that.
♪ For every one I find
Hey, I don't want to talk
about it,
but do you want to get
a drink at Joe's?
I think I, um...
I think I need a minute
before I go home
to the wife and the kids.
♪ I'm just trying
to puzzle peace ♪
Yeah, sure.
Sounds good.
♪♪
♪ I'm just trying
to get some sleep ♪
♪♪
♪ But the ocean of my heart
is raging ♪
Hey.
What's up?
♪ I take a breath
and try to breathe ♪
Mm!
♪ I'm just trying
to puzzle peace ♪
♪♪
I-I heard you did two flawless
lap choles today.
I did.
My rock-star boyfriend.
Huh?
Say it again.
My rock-star boy--
I've had to operate
alone before...
♪ Looking for answers
...in circumstances I would
have never thought possible.
♪ But wise words
only get me so far ♪
We'll go home in a minute.
♪ I'd pull it apart
I just need to find
the energy to walk to the car
and get in it...
...which might be tomorrow.
By now, I know what
I'm capable of,
how much I can handle
on my own.
♪ I'm just trying
to get some sleep ♪
And you know what?
I can handle a lot.
♪♪
♪ But the ocean of my heart
is raging ♪
You're playing
the surgery over and over
in your head, right?
When you saw that
bloody field,
you felt numb, but cold,
and sick
to your stomach?
Yeah. How'd you know?
You don't think I ever made
a mistake in the OR before?
♪♪
Or watched Meredith Grey
make a mistake?
♪♪
I feel awful.
You should.
Thanks.
If you didn't, you'd be
in the wrong line of work.
It's that feeling, that --
that -that awfulness --
it sticks with us
so we don't ever make
that same mistake again.
♪♪
It's how
we become great.
♪ I'm just trying
to puzzle peace ♪
Night, Helm.
But that doesn't mean I'm
going to turn down an assist
from another pair
of skilled hands.
♪ Oh-oh
Because at the end of the day,
just because
I can do a surgery alone
doesn't mean I have to.
Hi.
Let me guess --
emergent
kidney transplant.
Uh, liver, actually.
How'd it go?
Good. No bad.
Good.
You're here.
I'm here.
Should we
get some dinner tonight?
Yes.
Okay.
Let's do it.
Go get some rest.
I will.
See you.
♪ I don't really know
what to say ♪
Knowing someone else
has your back?
♪ And I take a breath
and try to breathe ♪
It's everything.
♪♪
♪ I'm just trying
to puzzle peace ♪
♪♪