Previously on The Resident...
Clearly you two are
sleeping together.
She must be amazing
for you to take me on.
- Finally get to go home, Bradley?
- Finally. Yes.
I can't wait to get
home and then sleep.
So, you chose saving money
over patients' safety?
Our CEO needs to be a doctor.
Claire wanted to see me?
- The CEO will see you now.
- Dr. Bell?
You've been with us a long time.
It's difficult for
me to tell you this.
Nic, I heard.
This isn't over yet.
♪ Runnin' through
emergency rooms ♪
♪ Spinning wheels
and ceiling fans ♪
♪ My handshake,
cellophane, landscape ♪
♪ Mannequin fakin'
it the best I can ♪
♪ Cadillac, Cadillac red ♪
♪ No hands on
the steering wheel ♪
♪ I'm crushing this
save-a-ho puppet show ♪
♪ UFO obliterate
the way I feel ♪
♪ Walk with me to the end ♪
♪ Stare with me into the abyss ♪
♪ Nothing is fun ♪
♪ Not like before ♪
♪ You don't get
me high anymore ♪
♪ Nothing is fun ♪
♪ Not like before ♪
♪ You don't get
me high anymore ♪
♪ Anymore ♪
♪ You don't get
me high anymore ♪
♪ Anymore ♪
♪ You don't get
me high anymore. ♪
This better not involve
another grown man's ass.
- I'm serious.
- Don't be ridiculous.
It's a guy with a broken weenie.
I'm paging surgery, but
you need to admit him.
Why? Irving, why?
Because I'm Lennon
and you're not McCartney.
But you could be.
Could be Yoko.
Oh, and it's just too much fun.
Dudes! Fire in the hole.
Aah! I'm dead. What up?
- What's up with you?
- Nothing much.
Just catching my
second wind after another
brutal all-nighter. What
you got there, D-Bear?
Helping Irving with
a broken weenie.
Oh, heck yes. But
what about this, huh?
What about helping me out
with that double date
we were talking about?
Hmm? Pick a night.
I will. Sorry. I've
been slammed.
- You know how it is around here.
- Don't you burn me on this.
- Trying to woo Noni.
- Noni? Our Noni?
- Hot Noni?
- The very same.
I think she might be
the one for all of this.
So I need a wingman
and a wingwoman.
You and Priya would
be perfect. Help me out.
You know I got your back.
Page me right after this, bro.
Speaking of dates,
- you have one with Mr. Berman.
- Okay.
- Mr. Berman.
- Oh.
I'd like you to
meet Dr. Pravesh.
He'll be taking
care of you today.
So cool. Hey.
Now, tell Dr. Pravesh
what you told me.
You know, it just
feels like a hamstring,
but a little bit hi...
Oh. I'm sorry, man.
This looks urgent.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Oh!
- Did I pass out?
- Yep.
Can I get some
drugs for the pain?
Chastain Memorial Hospital.
Incredible things
are happening here
with our cutting-edge
technology,
our groundbreaking research.
We deliver innovative care
to keep your family safe.
Fix your face.
It says, "I'm going
to pounce on Bell."
He fired Nic. What
do you expect?
A verbal, perhaps
physical altercation
resulting in your
immediate termination.
- Guys.
- But then you get to live happily ever after
with Nic under a
bridge somewhere.
Was that your
attempt at sarcasm?
It was not an attempt.
It was a success.
Look, I miss Nic, too, but
she can take care of herself.
So, one more time.
Fix your face.
Don't be an ass.
Hey, guys. Crazy times, right?
It's like, what? What's
even happening?
Hey, quick question
for either of you...
Bradley, I love you like the
little brother I always wanted,
but I can't right now.
Later, though.
You and me, we are
hanging and talking about,
you know...
stuff.
Okay. Yes. I love stuff.
- Um, Mina...
- What he said.
Wait. Wait. Are you
saying that I'm the brother
that you always wanted, too?
Not that part.
It's, like, the main part.
This is the beginning
of a new era.
One defined by The
Chastain Difference.
And, as your new
CEO, I'm grateful.
I'm humble. I'm eager
to work with each of you,
so that, together...
What do you think he's saying?
How sorry he is
he won't have time
to kill any more
people in the OR.
It's Bell.
He'll make time.
You know, there are few
things that keep me up at night.
But surgeons working
overtime to fill the void
I'll be leaving in the
OR is one of them.
And that's why one
of the most gifted
cardiothoracic
surgeons in the country...
AJ Austin... Is
meeting with me today,
and he will choose Chastain.
Why?
Because his CEO
is also a surgeon.
And I can ensure this
hospital is a doctor...
friendly...
environment.
Oh, my God. It's Bradley.
His pulse is thready.
We... just... some help here.
Just carefully. He might
have a C-spine injury.
Oh, God.
Someone page Trauma!
I need a backboard
and a lac tray in here stat.
Watch out, watch out,
watch out. Let me in.
Oh, God.
Holding pressure's not working.
I need that suture kit now!
JT, stabilize that...
that impalement...
What are you doing?
I'll use the cath balloon to
apply pressure from within
to control the bleeding.
That's not how we
control bleeding.
We got to get him into the OR.
It's not how surgeons
like to control the bleeding,
but it's how we
did it in the front
when there's no time
to get someone into surgery.
Okay, we're good.
Load him on the backboard.
Let's go. Move, move, move.
I'm sorry, Bradley, am
I boring you? Wake up.
He just completed
a 30-hour shift.
Bradley, do you need
to go home and rest?
No, sir, Dr. Bell.
♪ ♪
Where's Trauma?
- Page Dr. Nolan.
- I'm here. Talk to me.
- 32-year-old male.
- I know who Bradley is.
Deep neck laceration.
Chest impalement
and fractured tib-fib.
He should have been in
the OR five minutes ago.
We need a full assessment
- before you crack open his chest.
- No time for that.
- Where's Bell?
- Washing blood off his hands.
Oh, my God, Bradley.
How can I help?
- You can't. We're good.
- He's my friend.
I'm not going
anywhere. BP's 107/63.
- Heart rate's 94.
- Vitals are stable.
No output from the
chest tube. We have time.
That metal could be
tamponading a major vessel.
- Could rupture at any moment.
- We need to figure out
what caused Bradley's fall
before we rush off to the OR.
Yeah, great, and
while we discuss that,
- he dies on this gurney.
- Or he dies under anesthesia
from a pre-existing
medical condition.
He took a header off the roof.
It's a suicide attempt.
You hear hoofbeats,
it's a horse, not a zebra.
Stop. I don't think he jumped.
What are you doing?
- The OR is ready for him.
- He's not ready for the OR.
He's a trauma patient.
Trauma attending
makes the call, Conrad.
Take him to the OR.
I'm gonna scrub in.
Let's go.
Wait. Look at his
hands and feet.
He's posturing.
Right pupil's blown.
Send him for a scan
of his brain and chest.
Quickly.
All right, let's go.
Is he even gonna fit
into the CT machine
with that thing in his chest?
Here you go.
Thanks.
It's on me.
Nic. What are you doing?
Don't you love this place?
Wouldn't it be ironic if
we suddenly discovered
we had something in common?
Especially today, of all days.
Okay, I'll play along.
See, I have a way
of never giving up
when I put my mind to something.
The good news is I
have no distractions,
so I get to focus
all of my attention
on one very important task.
You surprise me.
I didn't realize you had
so much fight in you.
Too bad it didn't show up till
the week after you got fired.
Tell me about Nashville.
This conversation's over.
I don't think so, Dr. Derzius.
Oh, sorry, that was
your married name.
It took you a minute to change
back to your maiden name
when you landed in
Atlanta to start over.
Let me give you
a piece of advice.
No, I'm good, thanks.
I'll find out what I need
to know on my own.
All of it.
Don't let it shift.
Did they teach you
this in medical school?
No. You teach yourself on
the red route in Kandahar
after an IED sends shrapnel
into a soldier's
head, neck and chest.
Did he survive?
No, he did not.
We're good. You're up.
How's he doing?
We're about to find out.
But why the hell did he jump?
He didn't. He fell.
We don't know what happened.
We do know he's a
surgeon, and surgeons cut.
But he's been
benched for six weeks.
I was benched for a day,
and I wanted to kill myself.
No. Even after he was benched,
he was asking everyone
else if they needed anything.
This guy is strong.
He's resilient.
He was planning a double
date with me and Priya.
Said Noni might even be the one.
She is not the one.
The point is, he was living
and planning his life.
This was not an
attempted suicide.
Well, this was clearly
an attempted suicide.
And it's not our fault
that the suicide rate
for male physicians is
nearly one and a half times
higher than for the
general male population,
or that it's the
second-leading cause of death
for young doctors.
28% of residents
experience depression,
which, left untreated,
increases the likelihood
of this kind of... catastrophe.
Let's be honest, doctors
don't go to therapy.
Bradley sure didn't, not even
after falling asleep in the OR.
That's tragic, there's no doubt.
But...
this was a personal decision
made by a mentally
unstable resident.
Chastain will not
be held accountable.
Our insurance won't pay a dime.
And...?
And?
And...
I will make it publicly known
that we want to
be a leading voice
and a powerful influence
with an issue that plagues
hospitals nationwide.
You were born to be
a surgeon, Randolph,
but you're a damn good CEO.
- I gotta go.
- Mm-hmm.
I gotta go.
I gotta, I gotta go.
Subarachnoid hemorrhage
with intraventricular extension
and hydrocephalus.
If we would have put
Bradley under anesthesia,
he would have
herniated and died.
His brain is bleeding, so if
you don't get the pressure
down immediately, he still will.
He needs an
extraventricular drain now.
Let's get him to Neuro.
♪ ♪
♪ My heart has been broken ♪
♪ And all of my
love is in vain... ♪
Dr. Austin, I'm glad
you started without me.
I see you're late for
your own recruitment.
Forgive me, this is
a hell of a morning.
There are 3,200
types of bacteria
from 150 species
on the human hand.
Let's spare ourselves
the risk of illness
until we've established
a mutual respect.
Dr. Bell, your
reputation precedes you.
That's a lie. I know
nothing about you.
Though I assume
you are a surgeon
whose passion for cutting
was snuffed out by his fondness
for the good old American green.
Well, in addition to my
expanded responsibilities,
I'll retain the title
of Chief of Surgery.
I still plan to cut.
Why bother?
Passion, love and discipline.
This is good. You
want some of my pie?
You won't shake my
hand, but you're willing
- to share your pie?
- Let me rephrase that.
You can have the rest of
my pie, I'll order another one.
No, thank you.
I'm here to talk about Chastain,
and how much we
want you in our OR.
Let's just do this
as colleagues,
one great surgeon to another.
Yeah, Chastain is on my list.
Buried somewhere in the middle.
But I do like a good
underdog story.
Seabiscuit. You like that movie?
Not so much. A
little vanilla for me.
♪ If I never see your
smiling face again ♪
♪ My mother and
father taught me ♪
- ♪ Always love... ♪
- I'll take the tour.
But I don't like smoke
anywhere near my ass.
Once the cerebrospinal
fluid's drained,
we've got to get
him to an OR stat.
Yep, that's the plan.
So...
Bell is claiming mental illness.
You need to tell me if
there's any truth to that.
I know Bradley was your friend,
- but...
- No.
He was at the end
of a 30-hour shift.
But a depressed doctor who
couldn't handle the pressure
and jumps off a building sounds
better than an overworked doctor
- who collapsed on Bell's watch.
- Okay.
Well, you know what's
great about being an internist?
We get to protect patients.
Which means we're
gonna get to the real reason
behind Bradley's fall, no
matter what story serves
our new CEO best.
Who is it?
Hi, uh, my name's Nic Nevin.
I'm here to speak
with Anthony Ewen.
Yeah, look, I don't
want any solar panels
or whatever you're selling.
And I'm an atheist.
You're a doctor.
No, not anymore.
And I'm not a nurse
practitioner anymore
because of Lane Hunter.
Lily Kendall. 26.
She was my patient.
She died recently.
Because of Lane.
Does Lane know you're here?
No one knows I'm here.
Come on.
Dr. Okafor.
Please, sit down.
I'm about to scrub in to
assist with a mass casualty.
I covered you with
another resident.
Which means
you're now available.
I would like your observations
on a recruiting matter.
I'd like you to give a guest
the grand tour of Chastain Park.
Do I look like a
welcoming committee?
You hear that?
That's the sound of
the keys to this castle
jingling in my pocket.
- Who is the guest?
- AJ Austin.
Top of his class, studied
minimally invasive surgery,
nominated top CT surgeon
by US News & World Report
six times... he won four.
- Fine, but why me?
- Talent recognizes talent,
and his attitude leaves
a lot to be desired.
Mina, uh...
don't forget to smile.
She was my mentor in Nashville.
When rumors started about
her overtreating patients,
I didn't believe it.
Then one of her patients
died of chemo OD.
What did the hospital do?
They let her resign in
exchange for silence.
So she came here
with a clean slate.
Then she offered me
a position at a clinic.
I was loyal.
But then the same thing
started happening again.
This time I asked questions.
Yeah, next thing I knew,
my shifts were reduced.
I was accused of
self-prescribing,
of patient negligence.
Did you ever report her
to the medical board?
Are you crazy?
Who is gonna believe
a disgraced doctor?
By then she was already
building a stellar reputation.
Was anyone at the
clinic on your side?
I mean, what about
Allie? She's a nurse there.
- I mean, if the three of us go together...
- Lady...
there is no "us."
The best advice I
can give you is run.
Run away from Lane Hunter.
- Dr. Austin.
- That is the rumor.
Dr. Bell pulled me
from a mass casualty
to give you the royal treatment.
Is that what this is?
I don't know what this is.
I like you already. You like me?
Early days, but probably not.
Well, I find your
honesty off-putting.
Most do.
Well, let's keep it going, then.
That guy. Go.
Bret Kilborn. Vascular
surgery attending.
- Fifth best at Chastain.
- Out of how many?
Five.
Redhead. Man hips. Go.
Joyce. Orthopedics.
Average at best.
Bitchy.
Why are we doing this?
Well, if I'm gonna
come to Chastain,
I need to know how many
clowns are in the circus.
I'm already accredited here.
- I'm sure you know.
- Are you going to come?
Not likely.
He... Hey. Where you going?
Pre-op on a patient
with a broken penis.
Devon...
what are you doing?
Same as you,
trying to figure out
Bradley's last moments.
What really happened.
What the hell was
he doing up here?
Our lounge sucks. Look around.
This is where a lot
of us interns hang out.
Particularly the ones
addicted to nicotine.
Wait, Bradley smoked?
Every doctor has
some sort of vice
to survive the
pressures, the hours.
This isn't gonna lead to some
weird admission from you, is it?
Look, all I'm saying is I'm
sure you've got a poison,
just like Bradley.
And that's probably
why he was up here.
Yeah, you're right, I do,
but I get my aggressions
out in my own way.
It doesn't end with me
crashing through the skylight.
Wasn't that Bradley's
drink of choice?
Yeah. Anything to stay awake.
Why would he care
about staying awake
if he was planning on
jumping to his own death?
He wouldn't.
Excuse me, ma'am.
I'm sorry, but your
appointment has been cancelled.
Uh, I've been waiting
for over half an hour,
and my appointment was
scheduled on Tuesday.
Denise is a former
colleague of mine.
- She would have
called in advance.
- Something came up.
So sorry she forgot to call.
The way that our
calendar system works,
- it's really hard...
- Denise.
Hey, Denise.
Ma'am? Ma'am!
Unfortunately, we
are booked for the day,
But if you'd like to make
another appointment,
you can call and reschedule.
You do realize I'm not
just here to hang out
and catch up with
old friends, right?
I'm actually here
at the medical board
to report someone who's
putting patients in danger.
You know, the patients? The
ones we're supposed to help?
Do you care at
all about anything?
You know, don't
answer that. I'll be back.
You suck.
Wow. Oh, this is my lucky day.
Wait, is, uh, is that
good news for me?
No. It's a penile fracture.
That baby's broken.
Ow!
But it-it doesn't
even have a bone.
It's a membrane called
the tunica albuguinea.
Look, Doc, this is my thingy
we're talking about here.
Oh, we're not talking
about it anymore.
I'm booking an OR.
Wait, surgery? Whoa.
Look, it's a little crooked.
I can-I can live with that.
"A little."
Steve, tell me how you did this.
- I-I just... not...
- Use your words, Steve.
Well, I had to, uh...
I had a wild night
with a-with a lady.
I mean, uh... a girl.
- But she... It was a woman.
- Steve,
do you really want
to lie to the people
who are going to have sharp
knives next to your thingy?
I thought she was doing
the surgery. Who is this guy?
Hey! Are you gonna
help us help you or not?
I have a tee time.
Okay, that's a lie.
I have a date
with a single malt.
Now, Steve.
Are you going to tell
me what happened,
so we can save the only partner
who seems to want
to have sex with you?
It wasn't from coitus
with a human person.
I'll stay for this.
You did this
yourself, didn't you?
How?
An elliptical machine.
Uh, he asked how.
That is how.
I was working out, and I
was watching pornography.
You did this in public?
No, it was at home.
I mean, I also own a-a
used Pilates reformer
and gravity boots.
Uh, gravity boots?
Yeah, those are new.
What do you have
to live for, Steve?
What makes you rise
and shine in the morning?
What fills your lungs with air?
My... my cats?
I have seven.
I like kitties.
I've always been a cat man.
Dogs like everybody.
But cats are more discerning.
Exactly.
I wanted to know
how you did this
so I could scare you
into never doing
something this stupid again,
because the next time,
you could snap your
neck and not your thingy.
And you will die.
And then, three days later,
guess who's gonna starve and
die right next to your corpse?
My kitties. They...
They're all I have.
That's right.
There's only the eight of you.
Now, we are going
to fix your thingy,
and then we're gonna find
you another, safer fetish.
Yeah.
- Thanks, Doc.
- Don't touch me.
Mr. and Mrs. Jenkins?
Is he in pain?
Uh, he's deeply sedated.
He doesn't feel anything.
Uh, how did this even happen?
Our son would never
try to kill himself.
I don't believe he did.
We're still working on
answering a lot of questions.
But Bradley was a deeply
dedicated member...
You don't need to sugarcoat it.
We know he was struggling.
Bradley was always one of
those kids who had to work
twice as hard as everyone else.
But he would never
- I mean...
- Don't take this the wrong way.
We love our son.
We wanted him to be happy,
but he put a lot of
pressure on himself.
Wanted to be
like his big sister.
She's at the Cleveland clinic.
A natural-born doctor.
Maybe if we told Bradley
how proud we are of
him, no matter what.
He's a good person.
He's got a good heart, you know?
Trust me, we all know that.
If Bradley ends up being okay,
what happens to him?
Is his career over?
I don't know.
Well, if it is,
he'll be just fine.
We'll... help him
get through it.
D-Dr. Okafor?
Promise us that
he's gonna be okay.
Surgeons don't make promises.
But I'll make an exception.
♪ Hey... ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Girl ♪
♪ I think you know what I mean ♪
♪ My little Georgia peach ♪
♪ Hey... ♪
♪ My little Georgia peach. ♪
Timeout is now complete
for Bradley Jenkins.
Let the record show
Dr. AJ Austin observing.
The impalement injured
the left pulmonary vein near
- the bronchus.
- Okay. Let's get him on cardiac bypass.
Whoa. Bypass?
I guess that's the way
a trauma surgeon thinks.
But, you know, you wouldn't
need a bypass if you knew
how to do heart surgery like me.
What'd you just say to me?
- I said kill your resident.
- So you think it's better
to get in there, dig
around without being able
- to see what's going on?
- What do I know?
I'm only a
cardiothoracic surgeon.
Mina, do you have
an opinion on this?
Oh, whoa, whoa, you're asking
your resident for confirmation?
Dawg, you are the attending.
Theoretically, if you
move fast enough,
you don't need bypass.
Ah.
See? Princess Nokia gets it.
Let me show you.
Nurse, headlight.
I said I need a headlight.
I'm sorry,
is English not
your first language?
Or maybe I need to speak slowly.
- I said...
- This is my team.
You will not talk
to them like this.
Fine.
Give him his headlamp.
My apologies to the group.
I don't know what came over me.
No... I really, really shouldn't
have raised my voice.
Thank you.
But it's not like
this is a matter
of life and death!
After you, Doctor.
By all means.
This is only because
you're cardiothoracic.
Yeah, whatever you
have to tell yourself, pal.
Yo, why don't you load up a, uh,
5-0 Prolene on a BV-1 needle?
- Today, Dr. Okafor.
- Listen,
I've treated people
wounded in civil wars
and children dying of AIDS.
None of that scared me.
So you definitely
don't scare me.
Now, speak to me with respect,
dawg.
Fine. Suture.
Now, do you think you
can yank the impalement out
so we can get to work?
He's hemorrhaging.
Retract medially. Suction.
Come on, keep up.
- Keep up!
- He's losing blood.
Pressure's dropping.
Two units, wide open.
Another suture. Now.
Increase my suction.
Come on, come on, come
on, come on, keep up.
Will you look at that?
Bleeding's stopped.
- Vessel's repaired.
- Oh.
Piece of cake.
Wow.
That bleeding was
nothing but a distraction.
Now we can look
for other injuries.
Left ventricle
severely thickened.
He has heart disease.
In his 30s?
Not that we knew of.
The medical board doesn't
make scheduling errors.
And Denise just blew me off.
It was weird. And I think
someone's following me.
- Wait, what?
- There was this car
waiting for me outside
the board, to box me in.
- It freaked me out.
- Okay, I'm done with this whole
"I'll handle Chastain, you
handle the investigation" thing.
Please, don't do anything
else until my shift ends,
and we'll come up
with a game plan.
Rumors travel fast around here.
Nic Nevin?
On the grounds of Chastain.
Ballsy.
She heard about Bradley
and wanted to visit him.
No need to explain to me.
It's not like I'm
gonna call security.
Someone else might, but not me.
So let them.
Have a nice day.
Ventricular hypertrophy?
From what?
Don't know yet.
Combination of cigarettes
and obesity, mixed with
a heavy dose of stress,
would be my educated guess.
Obesity?
I noticed stretch marks
around his gut during surgery.
Telltale signs of a man
who's had gastric bypass.
Um, I'm sorry, I don't
believe we've met.
- Mina, is this...?
- Dr. Austin.
And he is?
Dr. Devon Pravesh.
Top intern at Chastain,
and it's not even close.
Stop smiling.
And don't wink.
Dr. Conrad Hawkins.
I've heard some things.
But it's cool.
I'm sure you've heard
some things about me, too.
I'm Dr. AJ Austin in the flesh.
I assisted in Bradley's surgery.
The plan was to observe,
but I ended up
working with Dr. Okafor,
because the cretin masquerading
as a trauma surgeon really
ought to bury his scalpel,
along with his career,
in an unmarked grave.
Can I borrow you
two for a second?
Toxicology on Bradley's back.
Amphetamines in his system.
And security found
methylphenidate in his locker.
- Uppers.
- Stimulants were his crutch to work in overdrive.
- And it's what damaged his heart.
- Yeah,
but there's no proof that
his heart caused the fall.
Which means Bell will
still sell this as a suicide.
Unless a little controlled
chaos helps us figure out
what actually happened
to Bradley on that roof.
Mm. You're smiling?
Keep me out of it.
You in?
Do I have a choice?
No.
Wait, his rhythm is normal.
Why am I getting
ready to cardiovert him?
I'm pushing isoproterenol
to mimic the cardiac
effects of caffeine.
Wait a second, are you trying
to induce an abnormal rhythm?
- Because that would be...
- Yes.
I am.
I think that energy
drink in Bradley's system
triggered something in
his already damaged heart
and caused him to faint and
crash through that skylight.
And this little experiment
is gonna prove
if I'm right or not.
He's in V tach.
He's gonna crash.
- I'm paging Code Blue.
- Relax.
There's our answer.
Okay? Paddles.
Yeah.
Charge. Clear.
Back in sinus. See?
Controlled chaos
to test our theory.
Exciting, right? Everybody wins.
Except Bell. Proves
that he didn't jump.
Wean him off the vent and
page me when he's awake.
The guy is a gross liability.
He does not belong at Chastain.
Dr. Nolan is just filling me in
- on what happened in the OR.
- You were there.
You saw the way that that
animal treated everybody.
Mostly you, but yes.
Dr. Okafor, you spent the
whole shift with Dr. Austin.
What are your observations?
His bedside
manner is a disaster.
Think about who's saying that.
Sorry.
But in the OR, his
hands, his instincts...
Unlike anything
I've seen before.
And, ultimately, he
saved Bradley's life
without even having to expose
him to the risks of bypass.
He's cardiothoracic, all right?
I put my ego aside
for the patient.
Other surgeons might not
be able to handle Dr. Austin
with that type of modesty.
- Am I done here?
- No.
In your opinion,
would Dr. Austin be
a valuable addition
- to Chastain's surgical staff?
- Absolutely not.
Albert.
Mina.
Even a raptor serves a purpose,
as long as you
know it's a raptor.
Keep Austin away
from conscious patients.
Unconscious ones will love
him because he'll save their lives.
- Raptor.
- We're done.
Hey. Dr. Austin.
- So, how's my, uh...
- Your penis is as good as new.
Oh, thank God.
That's amazing.
Give me your password.
What?
Hey, how'd you get my ph... Why?
6-9-6-9.
There's my kitties.
Take care of your babies, okay?
And I want you
to see this face...
This face right here...
Before you think about
doing something stupid
on a treadmill again.
Do you hear me, Steve?
Yes, sir.
Good.
Can I help you?
Oh. Howdy there.
Um, sorry, I didn't
mean to startle you.
I'm just delivering
your groceries.
Uh, well, I didn't
order any groceries.
You must have the wrong house.
Oh, golly. Really? I'm sorry.
I... No, it...
No, it says this exact
address right here.
Don't want to go wasting
free groceries, now, do we?
Well, now, say thank you.
Excuse me?
Oh, this is the part
where one nice person
says to another nice person,
"Hey, thanks for
the free groceries."
If you don't get off my property
I'm gonna call the police.
Hey, hey, now.
Ain't no need to go turning
something perfectly pleasant
into something else.
How about we just
move on with our lives
and stop looking
to cause trouble?
That way we can both sleep tight
and nobody gets hurt.
You have a good
night, Nicolette Nevin.
I am so sorry, you guys.
I was just trying
to push through.
You know? Just act
like everything was okay.
That's kind of
what we do, right?
We don't put patients in danger.
Or doctors.
Or ourselves.
Okay.
So, is that it then?
Am I done?
Bradley, what do you want?
Everyone in this room
would answer that question
in a split second and
say, "I want to be a doctor."
- But why didn't you?
- No, I do.
I-I do want to be a doctor.
Don't tell me what you
think the right answer is.
Tell me what you want.
I don't know, man.
Look, I...
I never thought that I
would admit this to anyone.
But I thought
about it all the time.
Not falling through the skylight
on Bell's conference
table, per se,
but...
I thought about
stepping off that rooftop.
I just...
wanted to escape the pressure...
anxiety...
the exhaustion...
the fear of...
fear of failing again...
of being a failure.
Even just the thought...
of walking away from medicine...
brings this overwhelming
sense of relief.
It's like a weight
lifted off my shoulders.
Is that weird or what?
- To me it is.
- Incomprehensible.
But for you, it's
not weird at all,
because you don't
love being a doctor,
so go.
Get out of this place
and find what you do love.
Yeah, and...
Well...
I am not going
to miss this place.
But I am definitely...
definitely...
gonna miss you guys.
We're gonna miss you, too, man.
You know where to find us.
Yeah, you guys seriously
never leave this place.
Hey, thumbs up, man.
- Dude, yeah.
- Good, good.
I think this is...
Not one for good-byes?
Love them, actually.
Good-bye.
I'm willing to offer
you a full-time position.
Yeah, what's the number?
Well, more than anyone else
will pay, less than you'll demand.
I'll pass.
Dr. Austin, I know
a great surgeon
when I see one, but...
I also know a desperate man.
You've been a locum
tenens for the last 36 months,
hopping from
hospital to hospital,
searching for something,
maybe running from something.
I only run when being chased.
Okay.
Well, your reputation
outside the OR is catching up.
You know, great hospitals
have a profound aversion to risk,
but I'm willing
to bet two things:
one, on you,
and two, that
your list of suitors
is neither long nor impressive.
You'll have an offer
from me in the morning.
It's a best and final.
Dr. Okafor frightens me
in wonderful ways.
I want her to be my right hand.
My thoughts exactly.
- Hey.
- Did he come back again?
No. Not yet.
How about his license plate?
It was dark. I couldn't see it.
I just ran in the house
and locked the door.
Did you call the police?
And say what? That some
creepy guy gave me groceries?
No, no, no, no, that's okay.
I just, I know what
you're gonna say,
that you're fine and
you don't need my help.
No, I am not fine and
I do need your help.
I'm just starting to realize
how far Lane's willing to go.
Grab your things. You're
staying at my place.
- Just until we figure this out.
- Yeah.
I mean, she
already got me fired.
I thought she was
just trying to ruin me.
But it's not that simple.
Think about it, Conrad.
This isn't just
about Lily or me.
It's bigger than that.
Lane has got
something else to hide.
And we're gonna find
out what it is together.
♪ ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH