♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
I know you're scared.
But it's just 50 days.
It's the best thing
for you.
I'm Amelia Shepherd.
I'm checking in.
Amelia's mom,
she's as good as it gets.
She is as good
as a mother gets.
And it's hard to fathom that
you can do everything right,
and you still can't control
what happens to your kid.
They could still end up
in staggering amount of pain,
in rehab,
fighting for their life.
It's just hard to wrap
your head around
when you think
you might be pregnant.
Your recovery experience...
Is our top priority.
We provide a positive
and a nurturing environment
as you embark
on your addiction treatment.
You'll start in the detox wing,
and then we'll move you
to a regular room,
and you'll be assigned
a therapist
separate from group therapy,
which means every afternoon.
Amelia?
Amelia.
Amelia, can you hear me?
It's gonna get worse
before it gets better.
But I swear,
it gets better.
Okay?
And if you're hiding
any other drugs,
now would be a good time
to hand them over.
They're gonna find them anyway
when you hit the detox bed.
The man I love died.
He died.
Okay, eat.
Morning.
He said "pancake."
Pancake? Really?
Yeah.
Well, it actually sounded
more like "pa-Kay,"
but he was definitely
going for pancake.
Pancake.
Good job, pal.
Yeah.
You heading to--
yeah.
We talk about Lucas.
We're good with Lucas.
We're warm with Lucas.
We're...
We're us with Lucas.
What about you and Sam?
Oh, we're doing great.
Yeah, as long as we don't
talk about pregnancy
or anything baby related.
All right, will you make sure
and tell me as soon as you know
if you're pregnant?
I will.
Okay, and, you know,
if you ever
want someone to complain to,
I'm just--I'm down the hall.
Thank you.
Yay!
Does this hurt?
Ow!
Okay. Sorry.
I know this part's no fun.
How about here?
When did
the stomach pain start?
Just after dinner.
A few hours later,
the night attendant reported
he developed a fever.
All right, Toby.
You're all done.
Let's get you dressed.
Here you go.
Okay, I'm gonna step outside,
talk to Mr. Davies
for a second.
Why didn't you call me, Jim?
I mean, the group home's only
a few miles from my house.
I could've
just come right over.
Come on, Cooper.
I have 43 other kids
just like Toby.
If I called a doctor every time
one of 'em sneezed...
Look...
I wish I could do more.
I've placed him in nine
different foster homes
in those four years.
Nobody wants a sick kid.
Little guy deserves better.
So he was diagnosed
with the lupus four years ago,
and that could explain
the abdominal pain
and the fever,
but I'm gonna have to do some
more tests just to make sure.
Dr. Freedman,
I don't feel too good.
Give me those tissues.
Come here.
Have a seat.
You have a bloody nose, Toby.
Lean forward.
Lean forward. Here.
Okay, just hold that.
This will stop it.
Let me see.
Oh. Okay, okay. You're okay.
You're gonna be okay.
Just say it.
Either way, just say it.
You're not pregnant.
I'm...
Okay.
Look, I, uh, I know
you're a doctor,
but i'm--I'm still going to
give you the speech,
because even though you know
this stuff intellectually,
you need to process it
emotionally.
You don't have to give me
the speech.
I do. So here it goes.
Something like 6%
of women your age
get pregnant using I.V.F.,
okay?
It's a--it's a small number.
But between your commitment
and my experience,
we can--
we can make this happen.
All right? There are
a number of other options.
So when you decide that
you're ready to do this again,
we'll get into it.
It's not over, Addison,
unless you want it to be.
All right?
♪ hey ♪
I want my mom.
I need something to help.
Oh, my god. I want my mommy.
Hey.
Ow.
Hey. Hey, can you hear me?
It hurts.
Yeah, I know.
♪ Sad it has to be like that ♪
What's your name?
Hailey.
I'm Amelia.
I want my mom.
I know. I know.
I want my mom, too.
It hurts.
Aah! Aah!
They're are bugs on me!
Oh, my god.
They're all over me.
Listen to me, Hailey.
There's no bugs.
There's no bugs on you.
Hailey.
Oh, my god.
Hailey, listen,
I'm a doctor
and I promise you,
there's no bugs on you.
There are.
You're just withdrawing
from the drugs.
Oh, my god. Oh, my god.
Oh, my god.
Your nerves are firing
on their own,
and it feels like itchy bugs,
but it's not.
It's just a hallucination.
There's no bugs.
It's not real. Okay?
The pain is gonna stop.
There's no bugs?
No. Look at me, Hailey.
Do you see any bugs
on me?
Because my skin
is crawling, too.
I want to rip my skin off,
it is crawling so bad,
but do you see
any bugs on me?
No.
Okay.
I'm gonna make you a deal.
If I see any bugs on you,
I'm gonna call a nurse.
And if you see them on me,
you do the same.
But if we don't see any,
it is just our nerves...
Healing from all the crap
we shot into them, okay?
And they need--they need
to heal, just like us.
Okay?
Okay.
Ah.
Oh.
♪ Hey, yeah ♪
Can I sit?
That depends.
Did you bring me
one of those?
Thinking about Ryan again?
All the time.
Can't stop.
Don't want to.
Yeah.
Yeah, I had a boyfriend
who died.
And a best friend, too.
The best friend was worse.
You're 18.
Yeah. Why do you think
my parents sent me here?
I miss my best friend
every day.
She was...
Stupid.
We--
we were stupid together.
The boyfriend...
He was a bad influence.
Was Ryan a bad influence?
No. He was...
No, Ryan was...
I think I was
the bad influence.
Amelia.
You have a visitor
at reception.
Dr. Sheldon Wallace.
Could you tell him
that I'm busy?
Of course.
Thanks.
Who's Sheldon?
He's a friend.
Then why won't you
let him in?
I said some things.
I, uh...
I hurt some people.
But they still come
to visit you.
No one comes to visit me.
You should let
your friends in.
You're my friend.
I'm 18.
So?
Hey, is that one of those
h.D... Thingies?
If by "thingie," you mean
supercool camera, then yes.
I'm gonna shoot
Mason's school play.
- Aww.
- Which isn't for three weeks.
Hopefully Spielberg here can get
the camera working by then.
I will figure it out.
You're just going
with the basic equipment?
You're not bringing a tripod
or a boom mic?
Oh.
Boom mic.
Oh, Cooper.
Hold on.
Oh, Cooper. Cooper,
I'm just kidding. Oh.
You know, a lot of women don't
get pregnant the first time.
I know. You have told me
many times.
And I'm gonna keep
telling you that
until you look a little less--
less what?
Miserable? Desperate?
I was gonna say wistful.
Oh.
God.
Yeah, I am.
I am... wistful.
No need for that.
Even if you don't want
to try again yourself,
there are other ways
to make a family.
Hell, maybe you'll get lucky,
find out Sam knocked
someone up ten years ago.
I'm getting used
to the little rug rat.
Mm.
You sound surprised.
Well, it wasn't exactly
how I planned it.
Well, when is life ever?
The point is,
you have choices.
Not all of us
can say that.
So you think you'll do it?
I mean, try again?
I don't know.
Yeah. I think I am--
I am.
You know, Sam...
Had this look of relief
when it didn't take
the first time.
Pete looks relieved
every time I leave the house.
Doesn't stop me
from coming home.
Wow.
That is dark.
Are you aware
of how dark that sounds?
For some reason, I'm vaguely
comfortable with the dark.
Okay.
I'll hold your hand.
If you want to do it,
and Sam doesn't want to,
I will.
Thank you.
So what do you think?
Limited loss of wall function.
Cardiac output is great.
I'm liking what I'm seeing,
Pete.
You sound surprised.
Well, your b.P.'S normal,
no dysrhythmias,
your cognitive skills
post bypass--completely intact.
You are back, Pete.
Back to counting the ten years
I have left. Great.
Oh, no, no.
That's not where you're at.
I mean, there are tons of
bypass patients that live 20,
25 years past surgery.
And with these numbers, I don't
see why you can't either.
Save it, Sam. I'm a doctor.
I've read the literature.
Okay, but as a cardiologist,
I'm telling you,
don't go picking out
headstones.
All right, you've got a second
chance to live a long life.
Live it. All right?
You're lucky.
Thanks.
All right.
I got your message.
How bad is it?
He's a lot worse off
than last week.
His temperature keeps spiking,
and he's showing signs
of liver failure.
What happened?
Um...
I did a blood count,
I did a liver biopsy,
and, um...
The lupus has triggered
a disease called hemophagocytic
lymphohistiocytosis.
What does that mean?
It means that his immune cells
are attacking his own body.
It's very aggressive. He's
gonna need a round of chemo,
he's gonna need
a stem cell transplant,
he's gonna have to stay in
the hospital for several weeks.
A stem cell transplant?
Yeah.
It's very serious,
and he could die.
We need to find a stem cell
match as soon as possible.
This--this is, uh...
Well, okay, if it's
an insurance question,
I've already
contacted medicaid.
But more importantly, Jim,
you need to find this kid
a foster family.
He can't
go through this alone.
We've gone over this, Cooper.
Look, I-I know.
Okay, he needs somebody.
I'm doing everything I can,
okay?
I'll be here
whenever I can.
I need you to sign
some consent forms.
What are you doing?
Uh... I'm just spying
on my woman
and your wife.
What are they doing?
Well, if I had to guess,
I would say that Addison
is talking about doing
another round of I.V.F.
While Violet is...
I'm sorry, man,
but you are screwed.
What? Why?
Violet doesn't
do anything halfway generally.
And both of us are looking
for anything to distract us
from the vast morass
of emptiness
our marriage has become,
so...
My man...
Do you know how dark
you sound right now?
Look, my point is,
filling Addison's uterus
is gonna become like
an extreme sport with Violet.
Good luck with that.
Well, everything
you said makes total sense.
So you think--
yes. I think you sound focused
and positive and energized,
and that means, for you, you're
making the right decision.
Okay.
Do you want me
to go with you?
No, no, i-I'll be okay.
Thank you...
Okay.
For offering.
Hey.
So you're, uh--
on my way to see Jake.
Right.
Okay.
L-arginine increases
blood flow to the uterus,
folic acid, which is obvious,
paba, which is
a b-complex vitamin--
i-i-i know what that is.
I'm no stranger
to vitamin therapies.
But you don't think,
in conjunction with metformin--
we use metformin for
polycystic ovary syndrome.
Yes, but it can also help
with Insulin resistance.
Which there's no evidence
you have.
Okay, but vitamin therapy,
plus metformin,
plus h.G.H. Shots--
equals crazy.
Look, Addison, you don't need to
be doing all of this, all right?
At least not yet.
You have--you have
two frozen embryos left.
No, I want fresh eggs,
fresh sperm.
I'm taking one last shot
at this, Jake,
and I want
the best possible odds.
You want
the best possible odds?
Yes!
Relax.
I am relaxed!
Oh.
Ah!
Okay. Sorry.
Sorry.
Ow!
Done.
Why does this part
never get easier?
Is there anything
I can do to help or--
we're at the end
of the second week, Sam.
You want to help now?
No, I know that you
and Addison
are doing this together.
Well, 'cause you don't
want to, right?
No. I mean, you don't
want to see
or hear or talk about
the most important thing
in her life right now--
Violet.
Why are you mad at me?
Because I think when you're
in a committed relationship,
putting your head in the sand
is complete and utter bull--
Violet.
Sam was just trying
to be nice.
Right.
I'm sorry.
I was projecting my own marriage
on to your love life.
So, uh, you and Pete...
We suck. We just--
we flat-out suck.
And when I think about
how we got here, I wish...
Well, I mean, I wish
a lot of things,
but mostly I wish
that we hadn't let it
get to this place,
because, you know, y--
you're angry
and then you're resentful,
and then things start to change
between the two of you,
and then before you realize it,
you are so far
from the couple
that you used to be,
you don't even know how to get
back there, or if you can.
And that's just...
Yeah, you don't want that.
Violet, have you and Pete
ever tried
going to couples therapy?
Uh, no, no,
because that would require
actually speaking
to one another.
I don't want to leave.
I like it here.
Why can't my parents
be rich doctors
so I can stay here longer?
Or why can't I have
better insurance?
It's safe here.
But it's not real.
I mean, staying sober here
is like...
Feeling happy at Disneyland.
It's easy.
You gotta go out there to see
what you really got here.
You know, for a girl
with all the answers,
you're awfully quiet
about your own crap.
Wow.
Okay.
You want to be mad?
Fine. Be mad.
I'm not mad.
I'm just saying, you do
an awful lot of preaching
and not much sharing.
You know, just 'cause
you're a doctor
doesn't mean
you're not one of us.
Okay.
Whatever.
I think Hailey has
a point, Amelia.
You haven't been
opening up much.
I open up.
Not to us.
You always have an opinion
about our stuff.
Wow. What is this,
a group pile on?
You didn't kill Ryan.
Excuse me?
You didn't kill him.
You might have wrote
the prescriptions,
but he took the drugs
himself.
Shut up, Hailey.
And that guilt?
That's gonna kill you.
That's what killed
my best friend. It was guilt.
Because her mom was so freaked,
she had a breakdown
and her dad left...
Hailey.
So she was...
You don't know what the hell
you're talking about.
You're a child,
and you need to shut up.
Amelia--
you didn't kill him.
Okay?
He took the drugs himself.
You didn't make him take them.
He took them himself.
You gotta get that.
Before I leave here,
you have to get that,
'cause if you don't,
you're not gonna make it.
And I need you to make it.
I know you loved him.
And I know he loved you.
But he took
the drugs himself.
Okay.
Now I can leave.
♪ I try my best
to keep you here ♪
♪ But it's hard to hold
a shadow ♪
Hey.
♪ You said good-bye,
but I couldn't hear ♪
Lucas?
He's napping.
Oh.
♪ To busy praying
for a miracle ♪
♪ and you left me ♪
Well, I'm gonna...
Go jump in the shower.
♪ ...knees ♪
Yep.
♪ Just walked out the door ♪
"Where are you going? Stop."
Keep flying. Keep flying.
That's...
You're a natural.
Okay, you two,
enough rehearsing for today.
You have homework to do.
What if I get nervous and forget
my line to the seagulls?
All you have to do
is look at me,
and it'll feel just like
it does right now,
just the two of us
here together.
What if I can't find you
in the audience?
You'll be able to find me,
because I will be sitting
in the front row.
♪ Mm, mm ♪
♪ boy, I know
you had to hear me ♪
♪ you coulda stopped me then ♪
♪ and told the truth ♪
♪ but instead ♪
Don't use drugs.
♪ ...your head ♪
Let your friends in.
♪ And you left me
on my knees ♪
♪ yeah ♪
♪ you just walked out the door ♪
♪ babe ♪
♪ you didn't even have ♪
♪ the decency to intervene ♪
♪ while I was begging god ♪
I want a baby and Sam doesn't.
It's that simple.
Now we can talk about it,
we can talk around it,
we can say things like,
"we'll deal with it
when the time comes,"
but I don't know how we
get around the simple fact
that I'm in, and Sam's out.
Well, you took the first step
by bringing him here.
Sam, what do you think
about this?
Uh, well...
Honestly, I don't think
this is useful...
For me, at least.
I don't want a baby,
and I don't know,
I've--I've never been
anything but honest about that.
So--
so what?
So this isn't my problem.
It's--no, my problem
is that I feel like
you want to have a baby
so badly
that you're willing
to risk anything for it--
your health, uh, your sanity,
my sanity--
okay, if it had been...
Let--let me--
easier to--
if it had been easier,
if I had gotten pregnant
immediately,
would that have been better?
If...
No, but--
right.
Wait. No.
Listen to me.
I love you.
I love you. I support you.
I want you to be happy.
I want us
to have a life together.
The last thing I want to do
is give up because of a problem
that we don't even have yet.
Yeah, but we are
going to have it, Sam, soon.
There is going to be
a baby,
and even though I'm the one
doing all the feeding
and the waking up
and everything else there
is to do at the beginning,
it doesn't end there.
It starts there.
You know that.
You're a parent.
I--
you have to want to do it.
I do, more than anything.
You don't.
So I-I don't know
how it could work.
I don't know
how we could work.
Well, I want you.
So long as I don't have
a baby.
Well, I want you, Addison.
That's what I want.
♪ I try to my best
to keep you here ♪
♪ but it's hard to hold
a shadow ♪
I'm glad you were willing
to see me.
Why don't you hate me?
After the things I said,
you should hate me.
I don't know how to hate you.
I-I...
I couldn't if I tried,
so...
Where do I go from here?
What do you mean?
I mean, I built this life
with all of you,
with the practice,
and then I burned it down.
So when I have to leave
this place, I...
I don't know
where I go from here.
I know I'm supposed
to try to make amends,
but I'm not there.
I'm not ready.
I don't know how
to face everyone.
And, I mean, honestly, Sheldon,
I can barely even look at you.
There's a sign
in back of you.
That seems
as good an answer
as any I could come up with.
Hey, Charlotte.
Do you have patients
this afternoon?
No. Why?
I need you to go
to Mason's school
and save me a seat
at his play
in--in the front row.
Sorry, Coop.
Can't do it.
Well, you have to. I just
got paged to the hospital.
Coop, I ate pizza with Mason.
I played video games with him.
I even helped the kid with
his long division homework,
but I draw the line
at sitting in the front row
of "James and the giant peach"
with a child
that's not even mine.
I will meet you there.
I promise.
Why can't Erica
save you a seat?
Because she's working
backstage with the kids
on the costumes.
I'm begging you.
My son. First play ever.
Fine.
But you owe me.
Big-time.
Yeah.
Hey.
You look like 10 miles
of bad road.
Charlotte.
You do look a little peaked.
You okay?
I'm fine.
I just skipped breakfast.
Hi. Did you see Amelia?
How's she doing?
She's making
some real progress.
- That's good news.
- It is,
especially since some people
don't respond well to therapy.
Well, I hope all of
you do, because eventually,
she's gonna need us to join her
for a group therapy session.
She needs to make amends
and...
Addison!
Oh, my god.
Addison, what's going on?
All right. Don't move.
Get Jake, Sheldon.
Yeah, yeah. I'll...
Get Jake.
No, I don't want
to do this!
What's going on?
I need to sedate him
before we can
put in the central line
for the stem cell infusion.
Toby hates needles.
Toby, did Dr. Berman explain
to you what she was doing?
Yes, but I'm scared
if she puts me to sleep,
I'll never wake up.
I-I had the same feeling when
I had my appendix taken out.
Okay? I was about your age.
Man, I was--
I don't want to die.
Hey, who said
you were gonna die?
You did.
I heard you tell Jim.
No, I did--
Toby,
I'm sorry you heard that,
but you didn't understand.
You are not gonna die.
Jim was asking me about
some risks and--and...
You are not gonna die.
Will you stay with me?
Well, I-I could. I know,
uh, Jim wants to stay.
He has a million other kids
to take care of.
Um...
Maybe we'll both stay?
Are we ready
to do this now?
Yeah. Okay? We're ready?
Yeah, we're ready.
Sam, what happened?
I heard Addison collapsed.
I don't know. It's some kind of
a side effect with the hormones.
You don't think
you should be in there?
No. There's no room
for me in there.
She doesn't want me
in there.
Violet's...
In there with her.
This is like her--
her project.
Is she planning on raising
the baby with Addison, too?
That'd make my life a lot
easier. I'll just take Lucas...
That's not funny, man.
Dark humor's all I got.
No, it's not.
You got a kid
that you love,
you got a wife
that you love.
You told me
I had another 25 years,
and the first thing
I thought was,
I might actually be able
to dance at my son's wedding.
It made me happy.
And then I thought...
That means I have
another 25 years with Violet.
I don't know
if I want that.
I'm sorry, man.
I won't leave.
I don't have it in me
to leave.
Hey.
Hey. Hey, buddy.
How'd it go?
He was terrific.
Missed his dad, though.
We all did.
Mason, I am...
Really, really sorry.
You promised
you'd be there...
In the front row.
I know.
Something happened at work--
I forgot
my line to the seagull
'cause I couldn't find
your face.
Oh, honey, you covered so well,
nobody even noticed.
Everyone noticed.
They all laughed at me.
Oh.
Oh, buddy.
Should we go get
some pizza?
Just leave me alone,
Cooper.
Oh. It's okay.
I'm sorry.
So my abdomen filled
with fluid...
Secondary to
the fertility treatment?
It's rare, but it--
it does happen.
You can still implant,
though, right?
Well, I need to aspirate
the fluid.
You need to rest
for a couple of days,
but then...
If you're ready to go again--
I will be.
You haven't gone in yet?
Oh, no.
She's still talking to Jake.
He says, uh,
she's gonna be fine
and that it was
a complication.
Well,
complications happen.
Yeah. Yeah.
So you can, uh,
you can talk to her now.
I'll let her get her rest.
She knows I'm here.
Sam--
she knows I'm here.
Addiction impacts
entire families.
Strong families
are essential components
of successful recovery plans.
In this case...
Amelia has named all of you
as her family.
I don't know...
How to apologize.
I don't know how.
I want to take back
everything I said.
I know I can't.
I was sick
and I was scared
and I didn't mean...
I wanted to hurt you.
I was trying to hurt you.
And I think I succeeded.
And if I could change that,
if I could go back
and unsay--
and undo...
The drugs, um,
some people think that
alcohol and drugs,
uh, bring out the truth.
And maybe that's the case
with normal people.
I don't know.
I won't ever know.
But I know that with me...
The drugs bring out lies.
They bring out hate
and they bring our cruelty
and viciousness,
and those things
are not me.
They're not the real me.
The real me is the person that
you knew before the drugs.
The real me is the person
that is sitting here now.
And I hope...
That you believe me...
When I say how sorry I am.
But even if
you don't believe me,
I have to say it anyway,
because...
I want to live.
The man I love died,
and I think that he would be...
I think that he would be
so pissed at me if I died, too,
so I'm saying I'm sorry
and... I'm saying that
I hope you can forgive me.
I hope I can forgive myself.
I can't take it back,
but I'm gonna try
to move forward
and I'm going to try
to do better.
I'm gonna try to never hurt
any of you ever again.
Hey.
Your mom said you were
doing your homework.
You need any help?
I can do it myself.
All right.
Uh, maybe when you're done,
we can go to the batting cages,
take some swings?
This might take a while.
Mason.
I know you're mad at me
because I missed the play.
And I would love to tell you
that I'm never gonna miss
another school play
or a soccer game, but...
I'm a doctor for kids,
you know, like you.
And sometimes,
those kids need me
when they're really sick.
More than me?
Sometimes.
But...
Look...
I know you must have
been scared
up there on that stage,
but I knew you were safe.
I knew you were okay.
But I wasn't so sure
about Toby.
He needed a-a procedure
to save his life,
and unlike you, who's got your
mom and me and your friends,
he doesn't have anybody.
Do you understand?
All right.
I'll let you do your work.
I love you.
Pete and I,
it's just, we...
We just coexist.
And intellectually,
I get it.
There are stages
to Pete's recovery
that--that mirror
the stages of grief,
and that can be very hard
for a couple to get through.
I have walked many patients
through this exact same thing,
and I've seen it shred couples,
shred families.
But?
But I've also seen it
go the other way.
I-I've seen grief
bring families together.
That's the stage that i'm
waiting for...
The stage where we say,
"oh, my god that was hard,
but--but we're better off
for it," you know?
Or we love each other
so much more because we stuck.
That's what I'm waiting for.
But I don't see any sign that
that's what he's hoping for
or working toward.
It's just...
Oh, my god.
Oh, my god. Oh, my god.
What?
I don't want you to do it.
The embryo transfer--
I don't--i don't want you
to try again.
I'm gonna go.
Wait. Are you okay?
Yes, yes. I just need
to talk to Pete.
Hear me out.
Um...
Look, what happened to you,
uh, it really--
it really scared me.
And I know that--that--
that there was a complication
or--or whatever,
but it really--it--
I was really scared.
So for you to try
to do it again,
I...
I love you.
All right?
And I'm asking you, please--
I already did it.
This morning, Jake transferred
two of my frozen embryos.
I was gonna tell you
tonight.
But just so you know,
Sam, this is it.
Okay? No more hormones,
no more I.V.F.,
no more sperm donors.
I'm either pregnant
or I'm not.
Okay.
I don't want to be Anna.
What?
Your wife. Your first wife.
You hated her, but you stuck.
I don't want you to hate me
but stick anyway.
I don't--i don't--
I don't want to be Anna.
And I know we took vows,
and I know you pride yourself
on sticking to your word.
I know you'll stay, Pete.
You'll stay no matter what.
But... I don't want that.
That is no life for me
or for Lucas.
And--and I know you are
more comfortable sticking
than being the guy
who leaves,
so, um...
So I'll--I'll leave you.
If you can't do it
but that's really
what you want,
if you don't love me...
If you don't love me anymore,
then ask me to leave...
And I will.
I'll do that for you,
for us.
And we'll...
We'll figure out
how to make it okay for Lucas.
I do love you.
I still love you.
But I don't want this
for us.
So think about it.
Take a week.
Take--take your time.
But... know that I mean it.
I'll let you out.
I'll be the one
who leaves.
Okay?
Can you nod if it's okay?
Okay.
Sorry to bother you.
It's no bother.
Mason was hoping
to find Cooper.
Ah, Cooper's at the hospital
right now.
He's there a lot.
Well, he helps
a lot of kids there.
Come on.
I was just heading over.
I bet we could find him
together.
Say thank you.
Thank you, Charlotte.
You bet.
Did you think about it?
I'm so sorry, Violet.
Okay.
Hey. Hey, Toby.
How you feelin'?
I'm tired,
but less than yesterday.
Getting stronger every day,
though, right, buddy?
Okay. So this is great.
Your t-cell count
is returning to normal.
Hey.
Mason, come in.
I want to introduce you
to my son.
Mason, this is Toby.
Toby, this is Mason.
Hi.
Do you like pokemon?
'Cause I brought my cards
in case you wanted to play.
I've never played.
Well, they're really cool.
Here, I'll show you.
There's simisage,
cottonee, simipour,
pikachu, scraggy.
You'll be better soon,
'cause my dad fixed you.
There's scraggy,
suicune, seadra,
eevee.
♪♪♪
So he's asleep.
I'm gonna go to the hotel,
but I'll be back in the morning
in time for breakfast.
I'll make him his pancakes.
You can go for your run.
We'll set him up
with the nanny, and, uh...
We'll make it normal
for him,
as normal as it can be.
And, uh, I feel--
I-I think
that we should still
go together to, um,
Addison's
for Thanksgiving tomorrow,
'cause... that's what
we were planning to do,
so for Lucas,
it'll be, you know...
♪♪♪
We should do it for Lucas.
And then we'll talk.
We'll talk about how we're
gonna make it work now.
♪♪♪
♪ It's gonna be
a long, long journey ♪
♪ it's gonna be
an uphill climb ♪
♪ it's gonna be ♪
Don't do drugs.
♪ It's gonna be
some lonely nights ♪
♪ but I'm ready ♪
The first time I got sober,
I was about your age.
And I just 'cause I slipped,
it doesn't mean that...
I became a doctor,
and I've saved
a lot of lives,
and I am gonna save more
if I stay clean.
And if you stay clean,
you can do and be
anything you want.
All right?
You're beautiful.
Inside and out,
you are beautiful.
You are smart
and you are capable
and you can do and be
whatever you want.
And I'll help.
Okay? I'm your family now,
and I will help.
♪ You can't deny the truth ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm the living proof ♪
♪ so many don't survive ♪
♪ they just don't
make it through ♪
♪ but look at me, ohh ♪
♪ I'm the living proof ♪
♪ Oh, yes, I am ♪
♪ thinking back,
life's been painful ♪
♪ yes, it was ♪
That's Mason.
Fix that one.
Mm.
It meant a lot to Cooper
to have Mason here
for Thanksgiving.
Yeah.
Thank you. Shall we?
Oh. This one?
Yeah.
♪ ...about the storm ♪
Seems just like a minute ago,
I was playing with Maya
like that.
Well, with any luck,
Addison will get to experience
the same thing, right?
♪ I got a few scars
that's showing ♪
♪ hey ♪
This is nice,
being here,
everyone all together.
♪ That's the way that I'll win ♪
Are there assigned seats,
or, uh--
oh, anywhere's fine.
Anywhere's fine.
Where would you
like to sit?
Across from you.
All right. Here you go.
♪ Everything you do ♪
♪ you can't deny the truth ♪
Is there room at the table
for one more?
♪ 'Cause I'm the living proof,
ohh ♪
We'll make room.
Absolutely.
There's an open seat
right next to me.
Yeah,
you're just in time.
Dinner is ready.
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ I'm the living ♪
Wait.
Wh-where's Addison?
♪ Proof ♪
♪ nothing about
my life's been easy ♪
♪ No ♪
♪ but nothing's
gonna keep me down ♪
♪ oh, no ♪
♪ so I'm ready ♪
♪ to carry on ♪
♪ oh, lordy ♪
♪ mm ♪