Previously on ER:
- Dr. Pratt.
- Olivia Evans.
- I should move out.
- Why?
I think we both know why.
Cops brought in a friend of mine a
while ago for a blood-alcohol level.
I drew my own blood.
Switched the tubes.
There's little doubt they'll
suspend your license.
- You're going on a vacation.
- What?
I was offering you the job. You
and Alex would be welcome...
- to come live with me.
- Excuse me?
- Good morning, Samantha.
- Hi.
Uh, I was just gonna wake Alex.
He'll sleep for a week if I let him.
Ha-ha. My boys
were the same way.
Not Kelly though.
I used to tease her
about being part rooster.
Three must've been a handful.
Yeah, but kids are
great, you know?
Especially when they're young.
They haven't turned
on you yet, right?
- Your wife is beautiful.
- Mm.
No idea what she
was doing with me.
Cancer.
Even towards the
end though, she was...
something else.
I've got meetings
in the city all day.
I'll be back by 6.
I'm entertaining guests.
- Yeah, you gonna sing for them?
- Ha-ha.
No, no, just a dinner for
the old board of directors...
and their snooty wives.
- Well, I should check your crit.
- Yeah, no, we'll do it tonight.
- I'm feeling fine.
- At least a urine sample.
Listen, my pee right now
is a lovely shade of salmon.
- The chelation's working.
- Like watercolors in my toilet.
- An ounce of prevention...
- Oh, listen. Come on.
There is no cure for MDS.
You can stick me with your
needles after I'm done entertaining.
You know, you should
use the car today.
- That's okay. We can take the 'L'.
- No, I insist.
And I'll have Mrs. Harrison whip
you and Alex up some breakfast.
It's the most important
meal of the day.
They raised Gallant, he turned
out okay. They can't be that bad.
They're great, it's
just they're strangers.
What are they doing in town?
Family wedding.
- You gonna go?
- I wouldn't know a soul.
Besides, I'm sure I'm more dirty
little secret than daughter-in-law.
Well, look who it is. Back
with the commoners, are we?
Good Lord, what is that?
- What?
- That smell.
It's really bad.
It smells like ass.
You do realize how
close we are to the ER?
I think it's you, Morris.
That patient we just transferred
threw her colostomy bag at him.
- I changed my clothes though.
- Well, I would recommend a shower.
- Oh, somebody's got a sugar daddy.
- You jealous?
Guys.
Chemo boy pulled his central
line. He's bleeding all over Curtain 4.
Chop, chop, Rasgotra, we
earn our money down here.
I better go before
stinky gets mad.
Hey, uh, I've been
trading e-mails with Carter.
Really? Did you
tell him about us?
No, no. Uh, he needs help.
In Sudan.
And he asked me if,
uh, I would join him.
- In Africa.
- I'd be back before the baby's born.
Oh, okay.
Okay. I mean, were you, um,
planning on talking to me about this?
I am talking to you. If
you don't want me to go...
You don't need my
permission to go.
The people need help there.
In his camp alone, there are
over 60,000 IDPs being cared for...
by just a handful of
doctors and nurses.
- Problems like clean water...
- I know.
Believe me, between
you and Carter, I know.
If this is something you really feel like
you have to do, then you should do it.
Greg?
All right, I'm coming,
I'm coming. Damn.
Are you there?
Greg.
- Hey, baby, what are you doing here?
- Hey. Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm... What time is it?
I was worried. I tried your cell
phone. I left a message at the hospital.
Yeah, I'm sick. Um,
turned my phone off.
I tried here too.
Well, what do you want me to do?
I'm sick. Don't stress me out about it.
Can I, um, come in?
I'll make you some tea.
No, no, I'm cool. Uh...
Look, now is not a good time.
- But I will be at work later.
- Okay.
Maybe we can talk
then, okay? Olivia.
- That's it right there. S600.
- Yep, sure is.
- A hundred-thousand-dollar car.
- Probably more with the chauffeur.
- Chauffeur? Get out of here.
- The Daimler-Benz company...
was a vital cog in the
Nazi war machine, right?
- Hey, so who is he?
- Who's who?
Your new whale, Daddy Warbucks.
Spill it, you little gold digger.
Go kill another patient, Morris.
What, 97-year-old lung
cancer guy? Yeah, all my fault.
Dr. Rasgotra, phone call.
Hi, this is Dr. Rasgotra.
Oh, hi, you're here. I'll come and get
you. It's easy to get lost. See you soon.
- Hey.
- Got a second?
- Not really. Michael's parents are here.
- I haven't seen you around.
- Well, I've been crazed.
- I wanted to... Ha.
- Was there something you wanted...?
- I'm sorry.
- No, go ahead.
Okay. Um... I was just thinking
about this whole roomie situation thing.
I just wanted to make
sure everything was cool.
- Yeah, as far as I know. Yeah.
- Okay.
- So if we needed to work on anything...?
- No, no. You know...
I'm married now, and I should be past
sharing a bathroom with your mates...
and your not-so-occasional
one-night stands.
I've been inconsiderate when
it comes to having people over.
- Well, it's not just that.
- No, no.
My clothes are
everywhere, dirty dishes...
- It's both of us. I'm a mess too.
- Sure, but you're not nearly as bad as me.
I've already started
looking for a new place, Ray.
Oh.
- Neela. Ha-ha.
- Colonel Gallant.
- What did I tell you the last time?
- Right. Dad, Mom.
- Hello, Neela.
- This is my colleague...
Oh, he was just here.
Seventeen-year-old restrained driver.
Auto versus parked SUV at high velocity.
He lost it taking a turn too fast.
Why do they think they can get away?
- You were chasing him?
- A stolen car.
Found a girl in the back.
Must have jacked her.
- How you doing, Deshawn?
- He's altered. BP, 130/75. Pulse, 110.
- What do we have?
- Blunt head, good vitals.
- Passenger coming.
- Go, I'll take this.
Jane Doe found
unresponsive in the back seat.
- Multiple abrasions and contusions.
- Okay. Hello, can you hear me?
Neela, we might
need a hand here.
I'm sorry. I'll have someone show you to
a seating area. I'll get you when I'm done.
Actually, I wouldn't
mind observing your SOP.
Oh, of course.
No, I'll leave the gore to
old blood and guts there.
Where can I get a coffee?
- The cafeteria, 6th floor.
- Thanks.
- Sinus tach on the scope.
- Pupils, 4 millimeters and reactive.
Abby, this is Colonel
Gallant, Michael's father.
- Nice to meet you.
- Likewise.
You were a medic in
Vietnam, weren't you?
- First Air Cavalry, '68 to '72.
- Four tours. Wow.
Let's see what we've got here.
Is a systematic approach to
the trauma patient called ATLS.
Advanced trauma life support.
It ensures resuscitation and stabilization
in even the most critical of patients.
Trauma panel, C-spine,
chest and pelvis.
Ah, Chicago's finest.
Dr. Morris, chief resident.
Settle down, Deshawn.
We're trying to help you, okay?
Guy must be on
meth or something.
Deformity to the fifth metacarpal.
- A boxer's fracture.
- A real fighter?
- Took a swing at me.
- Need me to check that?
- I'm good.
Okay, liter of NS.
Throw in a second IV.
- BP's good, 125/80. Pulse ox, 99.
- Calm down, man.
- Head CT and a tox screen.
- Tenderness to the left mandible.
- Looks broken.
- Add a jaw series.
- Airway's patent. Is the trachea midline?
- Yes.
- Any JVD? Muffled heart tones?
- No. No.
Where are we, ladies?
Assessing the nine most
life-threatening injuries.
Inadequate airway protection...
tension pneumothorax,
flail chest with hypoxia...
I'm sure you were a big
hit at surgical grand rounds.
Dr. Morris, Colonel
Gallant, Michael's father.
Ah. It's a great
honor to meet you.
- You in the service, Dr. Morris?
- Uh, no. Flatfeet.
- Guys, I don't think she's breathing.
- Pulse ox, 88.
Ambu-bag, intubation tray,
20 of etomidate, 100 of sux.
Dr. Morris, provide inline
stabilization of the neck.
- Sats are dropping. NEELA:
Oh, it's hard to bag her.
Take a look, Neela.
I can't. She's completely
clamped down.
- Did you push sux?
- Yeah.
- Is that a good IV?
- It went right through.
She's completely spasmed
shut. I can't bag her.
Okay. Throw in
two nasal trumpets.
Start a second line. Push another
150 of sux from a different vial.
We're taking you off this
board to make you comfortable.
Lie still. Lie still,
you son of a bitch.
- Let's get him on hard restraints.
- Can I give him some morphine?
- I don't want him to stop breathing.
- He's got a broken jaw. He's in pain.
- I'll splint him.
- He won't lay still for the head CT.
He will if you tape his head
down. I don't know what he's on.
- He could have a real head injury.
- Yeah. Hence the CT.
If it's normal, then he can spend
the time in a jail cell and sober up.
Okay, two of Versed.
- You said his air bag deployed.
- Yeah.
Kind of hard to break
your jaw on an air bag.
One-fifty of sux
going in the second IV.
- Got your flush.
- She should be relaxing.
Damn, it's worse. Her
masseter's in spasm, it's like a vise.
- How about Valium?
- It's too late. Abby, bag her.
- I'll prep the neck. Crike tray.
- Wait, wait, wait. Maybe it's the sux.
- What?
- Pavulon.
Six of Pavulon.
If sux isn't working...
It's a paralytic...
When I was a nurse, we had a
patient that went to the O.R. for TOA...
who had the exact same response
to sux. Her jaws were like steel.
- Betadine and a Steri-Drape.
- Give the Pavulon a chance.
- Eleven blade.
- Neela, do not cut.
- Sats are down to 82.
- We should get Kovac.
If we wait, she'll have
anoxic brain injury.
Jaw is slack.
- Suction. Let's go.
- Abby Lockhart with the save.
We were about to crike her
when the Pavulon kicked in.
Masseter spasm after sux.
There was a case
report in JEM last fall.
- Good catch.
- Thank you.
Head CT on your carjack girl.
- Morris, films on your carjacking.
- Thank you.
No bleed, no fracture, completely
normal. Why did she stop breathing?
Hard to say. Could
be drugs, alcohol.
We need to get her into an ICU
bed, monitor her for hyperthermia.
- Police ID'd her yet?
- No, they're still working on it.
Hello.
Hey. Can you open your eyes?
Still paralyzed from the
Pavulon. Give her an hour.
All right. Can you call RT?
Tell them to lower the Fl02 to 50.
- Sure.
Have you made a decision yet?
About what?
- If you don't want me to go...
- No, I know.
You said that already. I don't understand
why you're putting this all on me.
- I told you, it's only for a few weeks.
- You don't know that.
The last time you went,
we thought you died.
Instead, you came
back with malaria.
Dr. Kovac, paramedics are bringing
in a chest pain with ST elevation.
Page Cards and put the cath
lab on hold. I'll be right there.
Okay.
- Can we talk about this later?
- Yeah, sure.
Fifth metacarpal fracture,
30 degrees of angulation.
Non-displaced mandible
fracture. No need for surgery.
Hey, easy, man.
You broke your jaw.
- Versed must be wearing off.
- Tox screen negative, blood alcohol, 0.
- He's combative from his concussion.
- Stop eyeballing me, jack-off.
What?
- You worried about her?
- You better be.
She dies, we got your
ass on felony murder.
That's 25 to life you get
to spend with your homeys.
You've got a hell of a
unit in there. Good people.
Especially that Lockhart.
Worked her way up from a nurse?
You can learn a lot under her.
- Actually, Abby and I...
- All right.
- Thank you.
- Yeah, she's excellent.
You're lucky. Good
leadership, half the battle.
So I was thinking, if we hurry,
we can do Michigan Avenue...
and still have time for
Field's down on State.
Can't go two days without
swiping that credit card.
We need to get you
something nice for the house.
Sheets. Michael loves soft
sheets. When he was a little boy...
we used to have to
drag him out of bed...
That's not necessary.
I'm looking for a new place.
Michael and I got everything
we needed after the wedding.
Oh, don't be silly. We'll
find you something at Field's.
I can always find something
at Field's. It'll be fun.
For who?
You don't have to go with.
Neela and I can get
along just fine without you.
Maybe the girl
doesn't wanna shop.
Our son deserves
something nice for the house.
- The boy isn't in the house, Glo.
- And why is that, James?
Why don't you explain why
he's not here with his wife?
Jim Coker, 82, assault victim.
Multiple contusions
to the arms and torso.
- A and O, BP, 165/100.
- Nasty bruises.
- What'd you get hit with, sir?
- It felt like a brick.
Did they get the attacker?
Meet Fredna Nasse, 80.
Lacerations to the right palm.
- You attacked him?
- Damn right.
Cheating bastard.
What did you hit
him with, ma'am?
An urn.
I would have hit him again,
but the damn thing broke...
and cut my hand, and spilled
Wally's ashes all over everything.
- Who's Wally?
- My husband.
- God rest his soul.
- Can you wiggle your fingers?
Okay, order a hand series.
Where does it hurt, sir?
All over. Mostly my chest.
- What's this scar?
- Uh...
They put a pig valve in
my heart 10 years ago.
You've got a pig head too.
Philanderer.
Come on, open your eyes.
Yankauer.
BP's sky high, 190/122.
- Okay, amp of atropine. Morris.
- 195/120.
- Mix up Nipride. Have you seen Neela?
- I gave her a few hours off.
- She's out with the Gallants. What's up?
- Hypertension and bradycardia.
Cushing reflex. Increased
pressure in the brain.
No, the CT was clear.
Right pupil's slightly bigger.
- Her fundi?
Yeah, disc margins are blurry.
- Elevated ICP.
- Is it a brain bleed?
- I told you, CT was clear.
- Maybe you should repeat it.
I doubt she bled in
the last five minutes.
I'll call Neurosurg
for an ICP monitor.
- Where's Luka?
- I think he's in Exam 3.
Okay, 50 of mannitol, dial up
the Nipride, and I'll be right back.
Chest is clear,
heart looks good.
- He doesn't have a heart.
- Oh, for God's sake, Fredna.
- Give it a rest, will you?
- I'm not the one who needs a rest.
I'm gone two days, and you
can't keep it in your pants?
Did I crack a rib
or something, doc?
The pain's getting worse.
It's awful hard to breathe.
- Both lungs are up.
- BP's dropping, 90/50.
Okay, repeat EKG and
chest, 500 cc saline bolus.
Not gonna die, is he?
- No. No, I don't think so.
- Well, if he is, let him.
You sure you two aren't married?
Can you take another
look at our carjacking girl?
- Not now. I'm sorry.
- Systolic's only 80.
She's got elevated
ICP and a normal scan.
- Put him in Trendelenburg.
- Should I repeat the CT?
Anything pertinent
in the history?
I didn't get history, she's
intubated, paralyzed.
Okay, try to talk to the
guy they brought her in with.
- The carjacker?
- Yeah.
ICP rises with cocaine
and amphetamine.
She may need phentolamine
or a beta-blocker.
Repeat EKG. Sats only 82.
Uh, try to get a history.
I'll be in as soon as I can.
Set up for BiPAP, get an ultrasound,
and let's see if there's any free resident.
He's really not
okay, is he, doc?
- What's his name?
- Deshawn Liberty.
Deshawn, the girl in the car, does
she have any medical conditions?
He's not the helpful type.
Did she take any drugs?
Coke, meth, anything?
- What are you doing?
- I'm trying to get a history.
- He can't talk with a broken jaw.
- Well, okay, fine, then he can write.
- Not with a busted hand.
- Well, he can use his good hand.
- Can you take these off?
- I don't think so.
- Fine. I'll take off the hard restraints.
- Are you crazy? He's dangerous.
You know, he's
not going anywhere.
Deshawn, did she take any drugs?
Kid knows something.
- Like?
- Anything. Take the cuffs off.
He hit a police officer.
Let them do their
jobs, we will do ours.
I'm trying to do...
Do you sign?
That girl needs help. Now.
- Hey, what are you doing?
- He's deaf, okay?
Do you read lips?
Good. Um...
The girl in the car,
did she take drugs?
Damn it. I don't
know what that is.
Oh, right.
Here.
X? All right. Ecstasy?
Did she take ecstasy?
G. GHB.
All right. That girl's been
frying her brain for 20 minutes.
Brook Sawyer.
We didn't know.
Well, maybe if you guys
weren't so busy beating on him...
That's eight of Ativan.
- Systolic's up.
- Head CT ready.
- Might not need that.
Her brain's seizing, but the
Pavulon has her paralyzed.
- Subclinical seizure.
- Ativan should take care of that.
- She's gonna need a CT.
- Five hundred of Dilantin.
- Keep going, 50 mgs a minute.
- I'm calling Neurosurgery.
- Give it five minutes. It's not a bleed.
- Abby, if it is, we don't have five.
- It's not a bleed.
- This is Dr. Morris from the ER.
Pressure's coming down, 130/85.
- Pulse normalizing, 84.
- Hang up, Morris.
- Uh, wrong number.
- Nice call.
- What do you think happened?
- I don't know.
Dr. Morris, broken-arm
kid's mom is packing up to go.
- You guys good here?
- We got it.
Jerry, can you ask Frank
where our sign interpreter is?
Right here.
- What? I'm trilingual.
- I hate this thing!
It's only for six weeks, then
you'll be as good as new.
- Six weeks? That's forever.
- Dickie, quiet down.
- All right. Can I check your cast here?
- No! I hate you!
Stop it. Now.
You suck.
- Any pain in your fingers, buddy?
- No.
- Can you feel this?
- Yeah. Can you feel this?
Ow!
Dr. Morris, Jordan Prior,
Ladokern Pharmaceuticals.
If I could just steal a
moment of your time.
Systolic's down to 75.
- Damn it.
- What's happening?
- Heard you need a hand. Blood in belly?
- No, it's clear.
- In the heart? SAM:
No cardiac effusion.
All right, let's try
it with the Doppler.
Please, I didn't
mean to hurt him.
- Not like this.
- You did this?
Yes. SAM: Lover's spat.
Mitral regurgitation
through his porcine valve.
He blew it out.
Hypertensive when he came in.
- Stress raised his BP, damaged the valve.
- Page Cardiothoracic and hold an O.R.
- He's not gonna make it to the O.R.
- Afterload reduction?
- Dopamine at 10 mics.
- All right, 1.25 of enalapril.
Ma'am, were gonna fix
him right up. Don't worry.
They were at an after-hours
party. And he couldn't wake her up...
so he grabbed her and threw
her in the car and brought her here.
That car was stolen.
No, that car was her parents'.
And she snuck out.
Well, why didn't he
stop for the police?
He knew that Brook needed
help, and he needed to get her here.
He figured he'd explain
everything when they got here.
Why did he fight with them?
What...? Oh, he
was fighting back.
Trying to protect himself.
Cops don't sign.
And Brook, she's gotten
drunk before, but never like this.
He doesn't even drink.
He's an athlete.
- He wants to know if she'll be okay.
- We hope so.
You probably saved her life.
Thank you.
So you're sticking
with surgery, then?
I'm not sure yet.
It's a big decision.
Well, sounds good. You'll
be able to find work anywhere.
- I was hoping to stay at County, actually.
- You like working there.
I never thought I'd
say this, but, yes, I do.
I've grown quite fond
of Chicago as well.
Well, don't get your heart set.
I've got a Residency set up
for Mike when he gets back.
Muskogee VA, Oklahoma.
Perhaps Michael will
decide to settle here.
Don't worry, first time's the
hardest. You'll get used to it.
- To what?
- Relocating.
Soldier's gotta go
where they tell him to.
The upside is you
get to see the world.
Bismarck, North Dakota.
Barstow, California.
Christmas in Anchorage.
And my all-time favorite,
Indian Springs, Nevada.
Gorgeous in July.
Guess you don't remember when
Mike learned to sail on Lake Como.
How Val's face lit up when
she saw her first ballet in Paris.
We've had a good life, Gloria.
So, uh...
You two talk about kids yet?
Um...
No.
Not yet.
Abby, your carjacking
girl's waking up.
- Did you check the NIF?
- Yeah, it's 30.
- Tidal volume is 700.
- Oh, oh, oh.
Don't do that, don't do
that. Look at me, look at me.
I'm Dr. Lockhart, okay?
Wiggle your fingers for me.
All right. Give me a thumbs-up sign.
Do you want me to take that tube out?
All right. Hold
on just a second.
All right, deep breath in.
And blow it out.
Oh, my head hurts.
A thousand of acetaminophen.
- You got it.
Do you remember what happened?
We were at a party.
You got in a car accident...
and you stopped breathing.
We had to put you on a ventilator.
And the ecstasy that you took
caused you to have a seizure.
And we had to treat
you with anticonvulsants.
Oh, my God.
Yeah, you were very lucky.
He likes to feel my heartbeat.
Yeah, it's funny.
He's the only person in my whole
life who actually listens to me.
You would serve on
the advisory board...
be responsible for recruiting
doctors to participate in clinical trials.
And with your Residency ending in
July, this could be a real opportunity...
to advance the practice of
medicine, as well as your career.
Okay, you know
what? Ow. I don't know.
You know, I'm really not
that much of a salesman.
- Expense account?
- A generous one.
And this isn't a sales position
we're offering you, Dr. Morris.
Your official title would be
director of physician relations.
- Hmm. It's got a nice ring to it.
- Anything broken?
Thankfully, no. It's just a
sprain. Please continue. Aah.
There are meetings and presentations
at medical centers across the country.
Um... First-class air travel?
Of course. And quarterly meetings
at some very desirable resorts.
Best of all, no nights, no weekends,
and no exposure to bodily fluids.
Salary?
Somewhere in the neighborhood
of 300,000 a year. Plus bonuses.
- My kind of neighborhood.
- Hmm.
Huh.
Are you sure you wanna
wait? It's a four-hour surgery.
Oh, yes. Somebody has to
be with him when he wakes up.
Let me give you some
sound medical advice...
please, do not
make her mad again.
I can't help it, I'm a ladies'
man. Always have been.
Well, just take it easy, okay?
Thank you, doctors.
Pretty nice save, huh?
Yep, timely diagnosis of a
rare condition. Good work.
Looks like Dr. Pratt is back.
Well, that's something I
wanna talk to you about.
What?
Your status here.
My status? I thought
my suspension was over.
That was time off so you
could think about what you did.
And so I could think
about what to do about it.
- I was talking to Dr. Carter recently.
- Yeah, okay.
He wants me to come
to help him in Sudan.
- Oh, you're leaving?
- No.
But I thought you could
use a change of perspective.
- No, I think my perspective is just fine.
- Greg, you'll be an Attending next year.
That means all the
decisions fall on your head.
You're a good doctor. A month
there will only make you better.
- What?
- Get your shots.
Make sure your
passport is current...
and get your hat. It
can get really hot there.
Wait a minute. Wait,
you're sending me to Africa?
Yeah, I am.
And what if my answer's no?
It's not a request.
That's about it. I'm sorry
it's not much of a tour.
So when do you plan on moving?
I've been looking for a place.
It's been a bit of a challenge with
my schedule and Michael being gone.
Only one bathroom, huh?
Must get hard with the roommate.
Oh, we manage. We work
different shifts most of the time.
- Mm. So he's not really here much?
- Cut it out. They're just roommates.
- It's not her. I don't know the boy.
- I need to use the phone.
- You can use the phone in my room.
- Thank you.
Neela, I feel I should apologize
for the way we've been acting.
Oh, no. There's no
need. Couples bicker.
Pssh. We passed
bicker years ago.
Oh, it's nothing, really.
You should hear my parents.
Is there, uh, anything
I can get you?
Gloria and I are separating.
Oh. Does Michael know?
No. Nobody does.
We decided to come to the wedding,
put on a good show for the family...
before we dropped the bomb.
We'd like to tell
Mike ourselves.
So if you don't mind,
keep it in the vault.
Uh, yes, of course.
36-year-old with epididymitis. No
need for ultrasound, it's not torsion.
- Any STD risk?
- Of course, he's male.
- You give him levofloxacin?
- I wrote a scrip.
Okay. Fine.
- That's all. Thank you.
- Abby, we need to finish our talk.
No, we don't, actually, because
you know what? I understand.
- No. No, you don't.
- No, I do.
- Listen...
- No, you listen. I mean...
Sorry, I just... You know, I
know that we're not married...
and, um, we don't
live together...
and we haven't really defined
our relationship, and that's mostly...
Probably all, uh, because of me.
But you looked at me and said
that we were gonna do this together.
And I know that you'll be
back before the baby's born...
but I just hate
that you wanna go.
And I hate that I hate
But I'm just a little
bit scared, Luka...
and, um, I don't
wanna do this by myself.
But if I have to,
I can, and I will.
I'm sending Pratt.
To help me with the baby?
To Darfur.
He volunteered.
Long story.
- So you're staying?
- Mm-hm.
Oh, good. That's good.
- Well, I'll see you tonight.
- Yeah.
- Hey, man.
- Hey.
What's up with the
suit? Getting married?
It's my new school uniform.
How do you like it?
It's school.
But our new house is sweet.
- Oh, you moved?
- Yeah, Kenilworth.
Man, you should see it, Luka.
It's like a museum it's so big.
Uh... When did that happen?
When my mom started
working for Mr. Elliot.
It's his house, but he's got an
indoor pool and a movie theater.
- You ready, kiddo?
- I didn't know you guys moved.
Yeah, uh, my boss needs
chelation therapy every night...
so room and board's
part of the deal.
Hey.
See you later, Luka.
So, uh, do you
guys live there now?
- Yeah.
- Wow. That's a big change.
It was either that or
double up on my shifts here.
And even then, it wouldn't
have been as much money.
Is this part of the deal too?
I guess.
We're good, Luka.
Really.
Mrs. Gallant?
Is everything okay?
Are you all right?
Can I get you anything?
No, thank you.
He told you, didn't he?
I'm very sorry.
So am I.
You're a very sweet girl, Neela.
And I see why Michael
fell in love with you.
- I can tell you love him too.
- I do.
- Very much.
- And that's good.
I just wish that love
was always enough.
God knows I love that
man in the other room.
- But here I am.
- You know...
Michael always talked about
what great parents you were.
Maybe there's still
a chance to work...
Have you any idea why
Michael went back to Iraq?
- Not exactly.
- Mm.
I guess he felt like
he was needed there.
- He has a strong sense of duty.
- Ah!
Duty.
For years, I have sacrificed
and compromised...
moving from one sorry
little town to the next.
All because of duty.
The boy's his father's son.
They're soldiers.
And no matter how
much you love them...
there's always another war.
I'm not quite sure what
you're trying to tell me.
What I'm trying to tell you...
is that a strong marriage
is about two people.
Now, Michael's a good man.
Michael is kind. He is
loving, he is generous.
Just like his father.
But if staying here at
County, in Chicago...
is something that you want to
do, then that's what you should do.
Never let anybody or anything
make you ever forget who you are.
Miss Taggart,
please, come quickly.
Mr. Elliot, you're awake.
- I couldn't get him to open his eyes.
- I'm fine.
Go make sure they
don't ruin the duck.
- Mr. Elliot...
- Regina, I've got 20 people waiting here.
- Please, go.
- Yes, sir.
You might wanna think
about canceling your dinner.
Transfusion's supposed
to last three weeks.
- Well, not this time. You need blood.
- Yeah, right. It'll take three hours.
- I got guests.
- Let's get you on some oxygen at least.
Out of the question.
How will I be able to sing,
huh? With a tube up my nose?
This is serious. You're
obviously anemic right now.
Really?
Well, I'll be done by 9.
You can transfuse me then.
You hired me to
take care of you.
If you'll not let me do my job, I
don't know what I'm doing here.
What you're doing here, now,
Samantha, is you're working for me.
Maybe I shouldn't
be working for you.
Maybe not.
Rents are signing some
paperwork for your transfer.
I guess they want you at the
highfalutin hospital in the suburbs.
Yeah, that sounds like them.
We were able to get ahold of your father,
Deshawn. He should be here pretty soon.
We called Dr. Christiano. He's
going to meet us at Saint Helen's.
So we checked it out.
Guess the parents were all out of
town, and they came home early...
saw the car gone,
and called it in.
They thought the daughter
was at a friend's house.
Um...
My guys here have something
they wanna say to you.
Uh... Ahem.
We just wanted to apologize
for the misunderstanding.
We thought you were
flashing gang signs at us.
Yeah, um, we had no
idea you were, um...
We're...
We're really sorry.
He says that he has a
special sign for you guys.
I think that requires
no translation.
Yeah.
And Gyn has a bed, but they
can't take the PID for two hours.
- You get a chance to meet the Gallants?
- No, I must have missed them.
Yeah. Probably better that way.
- Would've been weird.
- Why's that?
Why do you think?
Hey, to tell you the truth...
- I don't know how you do it, my man.
- What?
Every girl I slept with won't
give me the time of day.
Neither one of
them? I'm shocked.
Ooh. I bet it was really
freaky being at her wedding.
Dude, what are
you talking about?
You know, you and Neela.
The whole, uh,
roommate-with-benefits thing.
You think I slept with Neela?
- You didn't?
- No.
Huh. Uh...
- I just assumed.
- Everybody did.
- Everybody did?
- Pretty much.
Hey, but, you know, don't
sweat it. It's just a rumor.
Pratt, Kovac left this for you.
- What is it?
- You're headed back to the motherland.
You better be careful,
I'm having a very bad day.
Maybe you woke up on
the wrong side of the bed.
- Hey, we should go talk somewhere.
- Oh, really? About what, Greg?
- What about? About us.
- That's a short conversation.
- Olivia, come on.
- Who was she?
Nobody.
Look, I'm sorry. I
really am. Come on.
- What? I just said I'm sorry.
- I heard you. I... You know...
Explain to me why you did it.
We never talked about
being monogamous.
We never said anything
about not being monogamous.
All you had to do was
be straight with me.
- I never meant to hurt you, I...
- You what?
You played me, Greg. You acted like
we were in this committed relationship.
And if you thought that it
was cool to sleep around...
you wouldn't have had your
sorry ass at the door playing sick.
Olivia, listen, I like you. I
never was trying to mislead you.
- I just thought...
- No, you didn't think...
Pratt, I got a phone call
from L'Alliance de Medecins.
- They got your number from Kovac.
- Yeah, just tell them to hold on, okay?
Listen, I really cannot
do this right now.
Why not?
Because my boss is making
me go to Africa, that's why.
- You just don't stop, do you?
- Stop what?
- Right.
- Olivia.
Wait a minute.
I'm not lying to you.
You know, you're right, Samantha.
I feel much better with the oxygen.
Did it affect your
singing voice?
Well, I didn't wear
it for the party.
I just stayed in my
chair and never got up.
Just did much more
listening than talking.
Wow. I was beginning to think
you didn't know how to do that.
Anyway, if you're ready,
I'll take my blood now.
- Yo, Neela.
- I'm in here.
Hey, I brought you a peace
offering. Extra anchovies.
And I promise, no
more dirty dishes, okay?
I'm gonna go and stay
at Abby's for a while.
Uh, she's at Luka's
most of the time, so...
So, what, are you
moving out, like, tonight?
I'll get to the post office when
I can, get my mail forwarded.
Do you wanna at least wait
until you find a new place?
I don't think that's
such a good idea.
Yeah, you're probably right.
Hey, um...
All good things, right?
Sure had a lot of fun though.
Well, maybe the next guy
won't drink all my tequila, huh?
- Uh... You need a hand with anything?
- Uh, no, thanks.
- Pizza?
- Oh, I better get going.
Okay.
I've been looking for
this for, like, a month.
I rather liked sleeping in it.
I'll, uh, get the rest tomorrow.
Neela.
Look, just...
Would you just wait
one second, please?
I wish I didn't feel how I feel.
But you...
You're the best
friend I've ever had.
Keep this.