You hit me once I hit you back
You gave a kick I gave a slap
You smashed a plate over my head
Then I set fire to our bed
Oh-oh-oh
My black eye casts no shadow
Your red eye sees nothing
Your slaps don't stick
Your kicks don't hit
So we remain the same
Love sticks, sweat drips
Break the lock if it don't fit
A kick in the teeth
is good for some
A kiss with a fist
is better than none
Whoa-oh
A kiss with a fist
is better than none
I broke your jaw once before
I spilled your
blood upon the floor
You broke my leg in retur...
Holy crap! Shaun!
- You're a good dancer.
- No, I'm not, so don't be a lurker.
You've got to
give a girl warning
before she makes a
total fool out of herself.
- I'm sorry.
- Why are you even up?
You've just gone through hell.
You should be sleeping till noon,
then go out for a Bloody Mary brunch,
and a credit-crashing shopping spree.
Those are all unhealthy
ways to cope with stress.
Fine.
But whatever you choose to do
to decompress on your day off,
it can't start before 9:00.
And it absolutely cannot
involve you sitting around all day
reading medical journals.
You've got to get
out and do something.
I'm so sorry for pushing
you, but you know I am right.
Ugh...
How can you investigate a
response that's not even over yet?
We just began
the terminal clean.
The governor believes
an immediate DIS review
is essential to restore
public confidence.
The CDC confirmed the
virus originated in Malaysia,
and there was nothing
my staff could've done
to prevent the three
deaths or Dr. Lim's infection.
I'm going to need access
to every patient record
and all staff communication
from the moment the first
outbreak patient arrived.
Look at you,
already back at work.
It's either that or
watch the news.
I'd rather be back on
ECMO with a rusty cannula.
Anything you need?
- Thanks, but not necessary.
- You sure?
Magazines, a book,
maple bacon doughnut?
Neil, you don't have to
play "supportive friend"
just because we slept together.
I'm not playing, I'm being nice.
Which I've done for people I haven't
slept with many times in my life.
No doubt.
But until we did, you were
always more interested
in competing than supporting,
and that's how I prefer it.
Okay. I'm not sure
that's true, or fair.
I'm also exhausted,
unshowered and constipated,
so if you could shut the
door on your way out,
I'd really appreciate it.
Will do.
Wake up, Maggie
I think I got
something to say to you
It's late September and I
really should be back at school
I know I keep you amused...
- Hello.
- You up for mimosas?
I was just about to
head out to Hollander's,
and thought you may wanna join.
You thought I might
wanna join you for mimosas?
Why not?
Because we don't
like each other?
We don't really know each other.
Hollander's has the absolute
best brunch in San Jose.
I'll drive, I'll buy.
Morgan, how about you just
cut to what it is you really want.
What else are you gonna do?
Sit around, play guitar
and sing into your phone?
- How did you know what I was doing?
- I didn't.
But that's what your profile
on a certain dating app
says you like to do on days off.
Are you stalking me?
One mimosa and I'll tell you
the fake profile I use
for oppo research.
The guy I use for
my pic is gorgeous.
You really wanna risk
swiping right on me?
- I'll drive myself.
- It'll be fun. Meet you in an hour.
Call me every night.
- I already said I would.
- Okay.
- Thanks for letting me stop by.
- No problem.
Okay.
Well... Bye.
Bye.
- Bye.
- Okay.
Bye.
Mia, wait.
Why don't you stay and fly
back with Kellan on Sunday?
I know it's crazy,
but it's been so long since
we've all been together.
Like old times.
I think that virus may
have affected your memory.
Come on, hang with us a bit.
Just take a break for a few
days. I'm sure you could use one.
It does sound nice, but I can't.
Okay.
Have a safe flight.
But I could take a
later flight out tonight.
Perfect.
- What are you doing?
- I am buttoning my shirt.
The procedure was a
success, the CSF leak was fixed.
What are you doing here? I
thought this was your day off.
Lea said I'm not allowed
to read medical journals,
and Dr. Blaize said you can't
be discharged for two days.
Ah, yes, And yet the US Constitution
says I can leave whenever I want.
I am sick and
tired of being sick.
I'm sick and tired of
being around sick people,
surgery, and radiation,
and blood draws, CTs, MRIs.
I've had it. I need a break.
If you delay the chemotherapy,
you will weaken its effectiveness...
- It'll be fine.
- You can't quit.
I'm not quitting, Shaun!
I'm just...
Oh, my God.
I appreciate your concern,
but you just have no idea.
It hasn't had time to heal.
If it leaks, it would be bad.
You could develop a
subdural hematoma...
And yet, if I stay one more minute
in this place, I will lose my mind.
- Where are you going?
- Anywhere I don't smell iodoform.
- I'm coming with you.
- You don't have to come with me.
I don't like that smell either.
But where are we going?
Are we friends?
- Yes.
- Why?
'Cause I helped you
through school, and get a job?
Or is it because neither one
of us have any other friends?
- You have lots of friends.
- Who?
And if I did, why did I have somebody
drive me around who I barely know,
and who I don't
really like very much?
And by the way, why doesn't she
have any other friends besides you?
She does. She goes out
with people all the time.
And yet she slept on
your floor for a month.
So, unless the people she
goes out with are homeless...
Hello, Lea.
- You better not be studying.
- I'm not.
Good. You wanna come
have lunch with me?
Lea wants us to
have lunch with her.
Wait, "us"?
- Who are you with?
- Dr. Glassman.
Fine. Glassy can come, too.
Glassy never said
he wanted to come.
Tell him the food at
my office is amazing.
Okay.
- She says that the food...
- I'm not hungry!
Go. You just go.
- I can't come.
- Come on, Shaun, please.
I'm having a really crappy day
and you're, like, my only friend.
You know what? I
changed my mind.
I would love to come and
have lunch with your friend Lea.
Yes!
Okay, I will text you
guys the address.
Diego Luis.
My pseudonym. I think
Latin names are sexy.
You might wanna pace yourself.
We don't even have the menu yet.
I'll be fine.
I'm really sorry about that EMT.
Tyler, right? I heard you
guys were kind of close.
Well, you heard wrong.
I barely even knew him.
Okay.
As long as I'm here,
if you wanna talk...
I don't.
I wanted a brunch
partner, not a shrink.
I'm not trying to be a shrink,
I'm trying to be a
decent human being.
Of course you are.
Saint Claire to the rescue.
What is your problem?
You literally blackmailed
me to be here,
and now you have the nerve
to act like I am the one...
I'm gonna take this outside.
If you wanna just get the
check, that's fine with me.
DR. Ho! MIA: Yeah!
Damn, I'm gonna have to wear
a helmet next time I pitch to you.
Yeah! DR. PARK: There you go!
You seeing anyone?
- Sorry, I don't mean to interrogate.
- It's all right.
And no, I'm not. What about you?
Yeah, but it's nothing serious.
- It's okay if it is.
- I'd tell you if it was.
You don't have to tell me
anything. It's none of my business.
Could you imagine us
ever getting back together?
Yeah, sure.
The same way I could imagine
what it's like to walk
across hot coals,
or to be waterboarded, or
attacked by a great white.
All right, I get it. Very funny.
Dr. Andrews, can I help you?
Just wanted to make sure
you have everything you need.
Yes, we do. Thank you.
Any update? Anything
I should know?
It's best if we wait until
the investigation is complete
before discussing any findings.
You already have findings?
- None that I am prepared to discuss.
- Okay.
Although I was a
bit surprised to learn
that you have a
part-time chief of surgery.
What are you saying? I
was here around the clock.
In your role as chief of surgery,
or as the hospital's president?
My dual role was a benefit.
It sped up decision-making,
and ensured that there
was no miscommunication
between administration
and the surgical staff.
Not to mention, this is
none of your business.
DPH has no oversight of
our management structure.
If it adversely
affects patient care.
Oh, it didn't.
And it never has.
You bureaucrats have no
idea how a hospital runs,
or what doctors and nurses
have to do on a daily basis
to provide optimum
care for patients.
And you can tell
that to the governor.
I have to go.
Mimosas, plural. That was the deal.
I've had one, you've had one quarter.
Well, my mom is getting evicted.
Fine. I'll come along.
I'm not lying. I have
to help her move.
- I could use the exercise.
- No.
- Two cars are better than one.
- Stop! What is going on?
You were right.
Tyler's death was upsetting.
I can carry a lot and
I'm great with moms.
Okay.
She doesn't think I can be both
president and chief of surgery.
Really?
You agree with her?
I never was a fan of your staying
on as chief after your promotion.
You really think anything
would've been different
if someone else was
chief during the outbreak?
You used to have more time
to manage scheduling issues.
And staffing shortage did
complicate our response.
Every hospital in this country
is facing a nursing shortage.
I'm not gonna reverse
my decision now.
I'd look like an
indecisive fool.
Or like someone who has
realized they've made a mistake,
and reconsidered.
Welcome.
Wow. How are you
not all 300 pounds?
We also have an amazing gym,
a basketball court and an ice rink.
- You have a very generous boss.
- And idiot investors.
The founder's from Minnesota.
He's obsessed with hockey,
so there's pickup at lunch
and a beer league after work.
- No flying glass elevators?
- Get anything you want.
There's also a pasta bar and
a deli, Spanish tapas next door,
and then we'll meet back
out in the atrium for our feast?
Any of your co-workers
gonna be joining us?
Why?
I don't know. I'm just
trying to be social.
You didn't wanna come,
then you did. What changed?
She always this suspicious?
Hmm.
I am in the mood
for Thai. Shaun?
- No, thank you.
- Sherlock?
- No.
- Okay, so I'll see you two in a few.
By the way, the lobster
rolls are amazing.
Thank you.
And, uh...
Since when do you eat bratwurst?
Oh, thought I'd
try something new.
- You a Bulls fan, Breeze?
- Bulls?
Oh, no. That's from when I
played South By Southwest
with Danny Attie's band.
That was Austin. The
Bulls are from Chicago.
Mom, who else is living here?
It's someone else's mug,
but he is not living here.
He just dropped you off after
a date and left his coffee mug
and bratwurst behind by mistake?
What do you guys care, okay?
I am not a child. It's
my damn apartment.
Yeah, and it was my money that
was supposed to be paying for it.
What was it this time?
You guys were gonna
start a new record label?
A restaurant? What?
I didn't rip you off,
and he didn't rip me off.
I was just a little late.
So, you're getting evicted
because your landlord's a
stickler for prompt payments?
It's the truth.
Mom, why the hell do you
have to get out of here so fast?
There is no way it's
because of a mean landlord.
Because he beat my ass,
and I'm terrified that
he's gonna do it again.
And I am not going to the cops.
I just wanna the hell get out of
this apartment and never come back.
That's it.
Putting's all about process.
Apparently not.
Front nine's for posers.
Back nine's for closers.
You just know I hate that movie
and you're trying to
get me off my game.
- But it's not gonna work.
- Nice.
So, what's she do, this
woman you're not serious about?
- Come on. You started it.
- And it was a mistake.
All right, what about work?
Kellan said one of the
other residents has autism.
Yeah. Dr. Murphy.
So, what's he like?
He's a bit immature, but nice.
Wow,
I feel like I totally
know him now.
Sorry, I just don't
wanna talk about work.
Or your personal life.
But I would like to
talk about something
other than your putting process.
What's going on in your life?
- How are you doing?
- Doing great. Everything's fine.
Come on, Mia, I'm just
trying to relax, have some fun.
This is exactly why we broke up.
That's not how I remember it.
I made a mistake, but we
were broken long before that.
Because I didn't like
to talk about work?
You decided to leave the
police force and become a doctor,
and the first I heard of it is when
you told me you got into med school.
Most people would think
that's a step up, be supportive.
How could I support
a man I never saw?
And when I did see
you, we didn't talk.
It's like everything in your
life can only be divulged
on a need-to-know basis.
And I never needed to know.
Found this in the trash. An
old pay stub for Carnell Hunter.
- I say we pay him a visit.
- And do what?
Give him a stern lecture that'll
teach him to respect women?
We need to make it
clear that abusing, stalking
or in any way bothering
your mom ever again
will be more trouble
than it's worth.
You're a bit out of
your element here.
We're not dealing with some
frat boy or creepy surgeon.
Guys my mom dates are psychos.
So you wanna do nothing?
Let him get away with it?
If she doesn't want
to involve the police,
there's nothing
we can do about it.
Let's just help her get out of
this mess and be done with it.
No. I'm not as
clueless as you think.
I had a stalker in med
school. The guy was scary.
Which is why now I never
go anywhere without this.
What the hell?
Don't worry, it's
legal. I have a CCW.
So, what are you gonna
do? Pop a cap in his ass?
No. We just need to
send him a message.
And studies have shown that men
are more likely to be visual learners.
Give me your key.
- Why?
- I wanna lock this.
We're leaving the car together.
How am I gonna I get it?
Key?
You're the one who insisted
the guy was so dangerous.
I'm sure he is, but you with a
gun is even more frightening.
Here. Go ahead.
How come you're Saint Claire
with everyone but your mom?
Stop calling me Saint Claire.
And you don't know my mom.
I know it's not her
fault she's bipolar.
- Feeling any better?
- Actually, I am.
Nothing like a good BM to
turn a frown upside-down.
I've been thinking about
what you said this morning,
about how competitive
I always am.
And the more I think
about it, the angrier I get.
All I was trying to say...
I have been nothing
but professional with you.
And for the record, you're the
one who invited me out for drinks.
You wanted to go
back to my apartment.
And now you're the one
who's acting differently
just because we had sex.
You need to project more.
Use your diaphragm if you really
want the entire hospital to hear you.
Definitely won't go out of my
way to be nice to you again.
He doesn't trust
me. I mean, why?
Is he that way with
everybody, or just me?
Can you help me convince him to
start his chemotherapy on schedule?
You want me to
convince a brain surgeon,
who doesn't like me, that I know
the best way to treat his tumor?
Yes.
Maybe just be supportive, Shaun.
- He just wants some time.
- No.
He doesn't have time.
You don't understand.
Actually, I do understand.
And I'm getting really tired of
people treating me like I don't.
- I know how you feel.
- Where's your food?
Too many options.
I got confused.
You find out why no
one wants to eat with me?
Still snooping.
Hmm.
Okay, we all need
to do something fun.
Either of you need a refill?
- No, thanks.
- I'm good.
Neither do I,
but I'm gonna get one anyways.
I'll be in the arcade
when you two
are done with whatever
you need to deal with.
Regretting your invite now?
No, it's just, um...
Maybe we should think about
trying to get back together.
Are you insane?
We can't even spend half a
day together without a fight.
Mia, I'm sorry. I
do respect you.
Which is exactly why I
need you back in my life,
to remind me who I can be.
Come on, Alex, you've just been
through a traumatic experience.
You're exhausted and lonely.
But...
I love you.
Just tell me what I
need to do and I'll do it.
Thank you.
I know how hard it
is for you to open up.
I love you, too.
But I think it's best if we just
keep moving forward with our lives.
- Carnell Hunter?
- Yeah?
We need to talk.
Yeah, well, I need to do my job.
So, unless you got a
badge, I ain't interested.
Time for a break.
Because we need
to tell you something,
and we wanna make
sure you're listening.
I'd get out of my
face if I were you.
- Or what? You gonna beat my ass?
- Who the hell are you?
Breeze Brown is my mom.
She's moving out of
the apartment today
and she never wants
to see you again.
What are you talking about?
You're a disgusting,
pathetically weak coward.
You know it, and every woman
you've ever been with knows it, too.
I don't know what
you're talking about,
but I would never lay
my hands on a woman.
Especially Breeze.
She's the best thing
that's ever happened to me.
I love her.
You guys all memorize
the same speech, don't you?
Why do you think I
asked her to marry me?
What, she didn't tell you?
What did she tell you?
You had no right to butt in.
The poor guy was
almost in tears.
Which is exactly why I
couldn't tell him to his face.
He's just... He's so darn
sensitive about everything.
So you thought
disappearing into the night
would make it easier for him?
I know. You're
right. It's just...
I don't wanna marry him.
So tell him you're not ready.
You want to take things slower.
He's one of the sweetest
men I've ever met.
So why are you
trying to ghost him?
I don't know.
Mom.
Dr. Andrews?
- We have some findings.
- I'm excited to hear them.
And I just wanted to say, with
regard to the staffing issue...
I wouldn't worry
about that anymore.
Dr. Audrey Lim
nonconsensually dosed a man
who was not even
a patient with Haldol,
which is not only
unethical, it's a crime.
And Dr. Neil Melendez ignored a
written DNR, which is also a crime.
And I've just reviewed a video
showing Dr. Shaun Murphy
curled up on the ER
floor in the fetal position.
Dr. Murphy has autism,
which on extremely rare
occasions impacts his...
Ability to provide the
proper standard of care?
I'll be recommending all
three to the state medical board
for licence suspension.
Bumper cars? I'd
rather go ice-skating.
I don't want to do either.
All right, these aren't
bumper cars, smart-ass.
They're electric sprint-karts.
NASCAR drivers train in them.
We use them to test our device
prototypes, and they haul ass.
This is a very bad idea.
If the skull base
repair doesn't hold...
I could get a subdural hematoma.
Yes, we've established that.
I don't know what that means,
but I do know both of you
drove on the freeway to get here.
If it's safe, why do
we have to wear...
Enough negativity, both of you.
You didn't blow off Blaize just to
go out for a walk or a nice lunch.
It's time to crank up the
volume on this day off.
I don't want to drive a go-kart.
I don't believe you. I think
you do wanna drive a go-kart,
you just don't want
me to drive a go-kart.
You know what? I'm in.
Okay.
I live my life in the city
There's no easy way out
The day's moving
just too fast for me
I need some time in the sunshine
I've got to slow it right down
The day's moving
just too fast for me
I live my life for
the stars that shine
People say it's
just a waste of time
Then they said I
should feed my head
That to me was just a day in bed
I'll take my car
and drive real far
They're not concerned
about the way we are
In my mind, my dreams are real
Now you're concerned
about the way I feel
Tonight
I'm a rock 'n' roll star
You're not down with who I am
Look at you now You're
all in my hands tonight
Tonight
I'm a rock 'n' roll star
It's just rock 'n' roll
That was awesome!
I still beat your ass, but you
improved your time every lap.
- Thank you.
- You did too, Shaun.
Whoo!
Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- Are you sure?
You look a little
glassy-eyed, Glassy.
No, I think I just have
something in my eye.
Do you have any
dizziness, or a metallic taste?
I'm fine, Shaun. I'm
actually fine. I'm...
You know what? I'm
better than fine. I'm good.
He's good.
Yes!
Come on, Shaun.
I was wrong.
From the moment we met, my
defensiveness was unprofessional,
and my subsequent
behavior even worse.
I was not aware Dr. Lim
dosed a hospital visitor,
or that Dr. Melendez
violated a DNR.
But that's my fault.
Neither of them made any
attempt to hide their actions,
because they both are totally
committed to doing whatever it takes
to provide the utmost
care for their patients.
Practicing medicine requires
doctors to make judgments,
not just follow rules.
Two human beings, who
would otherwise be dead,
are alive because of rules
broken by Lim and Melendez.
They were doing their jobs.
They shouldn't be punished for
that, they should be applauded.
I'll be notifying the state
board of our findings.
It'll then be up to
those doctors to decide.
They'll leave us
bureaucrats out of it.
See you at the hearing.
- I screwed up.
- No.
You did the right
thing. We both did.
I wasn't talking about
this stupid investigation.
I was talking about us.
Ever since my divorce,
I can't help but think...
No matter how real
this feels, it's not.
I have feelings for you.
I have for a long
time, and it scares me.
But I don't want the night we
spent together to be our last.
I feel the same way.
But I'm not sure
it's a good idea.
Especially now, since we're
both gonna be under a microscope.
Yeah, that is true.
Of course, if, for
the time being,
we just made sure that Andrews
and everyone else doesn't know...
Interesting idea.
- Good night, Neil.
- Good night, Audrey.
Thank you.
I'm glad you were
here. It helped.
No problem.
And also, um...
You're not clueless. I am.
You carry a gun,
and you practically dared
that guy to take a swing at you.
I volunteered at a battered
women's shelter in med school,
and I am not an expert,
and I am definitely
not trying to be a shrink,
but if you ever need
someone to talk to,
about anything...
Thank you.
It was a good day.
I need to return the favor,
have you meet my mom.
It's a date.
I decided not to
postpone the chemo.
That's a good idea.
In fact, I'm gonna speed it up.
I'm gonna go for a much
more aggressive regimen.
But Dr. Blaize said...
Dr. Blaize will have to
agree, or I'll get another doctor.
I wanna get this over with. I
wanna have more days like today.
- And you should do the same.
- I don't have cancer.
Exactly. You have no excuse.
Lea's okay, huh? She gets you?
Yes. I get her, too.
She's a good friend.
You think she'll ever
be more than that?
She only wants to be my
friend. She made that very clear.
Hmm.
You're a good man, you
know? Deserve to be happy.
Well, thanks again for staying.
It was nice.
It was.
Well, bye.
- You forget something?
- No.
Maybe you're right.
We could try to slowly and
cautiously test the waters.
I would love that.
Maybe in a couple of weeks I
could come back for a weekend?
- On my own?
- Definitely.
I'll call you.
Shaun?
I thought you were gonna
hang with Glassy tonight.
I did, but he got tired.
Is there any more
beer? I'd like to try one.
Yeah, there's some
more in the fridge.
How many beers have you drunk?
Just this one. Why?
Oh, no. Um...
That's Jake's.
Jake, meet my totally
cool roomie, Shaun Murphy.
- Shaun, meet Jake.
- Hello.
It's nice to meet you. Lea's
told me a lot about you.
He's such a sweetheart.
Well, we gotta run.
Jake's taking me to
Death Cab for Cutie.
Take it easy, Shaun.
And don't wait up. We're
probably gonna be out late.
We've seen the holy,
the lonely, the sinners and
Been to the promise,
the garden, the wasteland
Oh, the truth of it all
We rise and we fall We hold on
We hold on
When we fight When we lie
When the weakness shows
When we laugh When we cry
When it's all exposed
The truth of it all
We rise and we fall
We hold on
Hold on
Oh, love, we hold on together
We scream like sisters
and brothers Drew hard lines
We love like star crossed,
blind eyes seeing light
The truth of it all
We rise and we fall
We hold on
Hold on
Oh, love, we hold on together
When we fight, when we lie
When the weakness shows
When we laugh When we cry
When it's all exposed
The truth of it all
We rise and we fall
We hold on