Glioma, fibroma, blastoma.
Whatever the tumor,
people assume you
approach it the same way.
You find its hiding
place in the body,
then open the patient up...
Miranda. Miranda, what
are you doing? It's 4:00 a.m.
There's a smell.
Something rotting.
I smell nothing.
I know my son. Before
leaving for his dad's,
he left a piece of
food somewhere.
Hey, let's go back to
bed, get some sleep.
Tomorrow's a big day.
You're going back
to your old job.
Can't you do that in your sleep?
You want me to help you look?
How can you help if you
can't even smell the smell?
And you cut it the hell out.
But you're not just
fighting the one tumor.
Dude, you're Jago.
Counter with a wind
kick. It'll take him down.
I can't concentrate
when you watch me.
What are you even doing awake?
Are you worried about
your surgery tomorrow?
Nope.
Can't sleep because of
the crying baby next door.
And the frog and the monkey
picture kind of freak me out.
Hey, is this level seven?
Yep. What about you?
Shouldn't you be resting
before you and Dr. Grey
operate on me tomorrow?
Video games are good for
surgical practice. Give me that.
I'll show you how
to beat Sabrewulf.
You're actually at war
with over a billion cells.
Combo!
Nice. Told you.
Dr. Grey?
Huh?
You wanted me to
wake you if, um...
How is it?
It's starting to have a shape.
Come look.
So there we were, hour
four into this messy trauma,
when I say, "That's not an
adhesion, that's the ureter."
You guys... Shh!
I'm telling a story here.
Um... Oh, uh, creamer.
You said it to the attending?
Yeah, he blew me off. He
didn't stop what he was doing
until the chief resident
invoked the two-challenge rule.
You guys...
It comes from aviation.
Say I'm the pilot,
and you're my co-pilot.
You disagree with
how I'm flying the plane.
Okay, you say something,
and I fly the plane
the same way.
Someone else says something,
and I don't acknowledge it,
I lose. I have to
give up control.
The two-challenge rule.
I mean, the doctors
adopted it to the OR.
Edwards, what?
We're 30 minutes away.
Finish your rounds.
You're gonna wanna be in the
front row when your life changes.
Yeah. I'm ready.
Dr. Webber, you
want to come with us?
Dr. Grey says you're
supposed to be up and walking.
Uh, no, you go on down.
Uh, but come back,
'cause you're gonna wanna
hear the end of this story.
Everyone knows
the end of the story,
because you've already told it!
Maybe you shouldn't be
listening in on conversations
that take place in other
people's rooms, C.J.
Not my fault that
you work for a hospital
with crap-thin walls!
Yeah, go take a lap!
I will if you do!
Hey, guys!
Hey! Hey!
So I have the results
of your compatibility test.
I'm sure we did great.
If we didn't do great,
we'll just take it again.
I took my boards twice,
so it'll be fine, right?
April, I'm sure we did fine.
I mean, we did fine, right?
If I hadn't known
you two already,
I would have
thought you cheated.
90%. We crushed it!
Ow! Mmm.
Yes! She likes to win.
Yeah, no, that's
good. That's good.
Let me get your
exercises for this week.
So...
Listen, um...
There is one problem that
we really haven't discussed.
What?
Well, come on, I
mean, we're compatible
but we're certainly not equal.
Oh, that. Yeah.
I wasn't sure if that
really bothered you.
Of course it really bothers me.
Well, then we
should just fix it.
Now...
Before we're married?
Yeah. I mean, the
solution's simple.
Yeah, we just have sex.
Get a joint checking account.
Sharky, rundown.
I've pre-rounded on
all of your post-ops
and uploaded yesterday's notes.
Mrs. Ott, my
aortic ulcer patient?
Uh, echo shows an
improving EF of 65%.
Nathan Glazier, my HLHS baby?
Uh... Sats fell to 67.
Now in the PICU.
Mr. Wu, valve repair?
There is no Mr. Wu
with a valve repair.
Very good. Here you go.
What's this for?
Well, you stayed up all night
keeping my patients awake
while I got a good night's rest.
So, coffee.
Are you headed downstairs?
Dr. Grey's presenting
the 3D printer.
You know what? I'm
gonna look at it later.
I want to check on the
Glazier baby's numbers.
PICU, one hour.
So is that my tumor?
Yes, and this is your esophagus,
which we will remove.
And then we'll replace it
with a section of your
colon from down here.
And part of my ass
will now be my throat.
Your colon is actually
your large intestine,
and again we're only
gonna take a piece of it.
Well, honey, now when
you give a restaurant
a bad review,
people can truly say,
"You're talking
out of your ass."
Ugh!
When I eat their food,
I can truly say, "It
tastes like crap."
The food will not
taste like crap.
Hey, I'm still mad
at you for Zane's.
I ate there for 10 years
until you ruined it for me.
Oh, please, they
over-salt everything.
Uh-huh.
Well, barring complications,
you'll soon be back
to bossing us all around
about where we eat.
Get another enema.
But he already had one.
Which is why I said, "Another."
Look, we're dealing with the
most contaminated part of the body.
Mmm. Oh! Can I do it
after Dr. Grey's presentation?
I don't care when you do it
as long as you deliver
Duncan to the OR
with a squeaky clean colon.
So when an opening came
up for maternal/fetal surgeon,
I thought of you first. So I
pitched you to the board.
And they just want one of us to
sit down with you to interview you.
You'll be meeting
with Dr. Torres.
Her resume really
speaks for itself.
This is more of a formality.
Well, and maybe an
opportunity to learn
a little more about the
woman you're dating.
Not necessary at all.
So, anything you can
tell me about Dr. Torres?
Um, she's great. I
mean, she's my ex...
So she's not that great.
Look, I'm sure she's
probably not an ax murderer,
but if there's something
there, I will give you a heads-up.
Please don't. ARIZONA:
Just be yourself.
Hey. Hi! Um, this is
Dr. Emma Marling.
Dr. Callie Torres.
Good to meet you.
Let's do this.
Dr. Avery, Mrs. Maddox is
here to get her drain removed,
and I'll do it after
the presentation.
I'll do it myself,
Murphy. Really?
Because I know the case...
Nah, I prefer to do it myself.
Thanks.
What, did I miss it?
You didn't miss it. Do you
think they made a heart?
Steph won't say, but I think
a heart's too complicated.
Hey.
A bladder?
Come on. What'd you guys print?
I'm not saying.
But your minds will
be freakin' blown.
Hey, how'd the
drop-off at day care go?
Tear-free. How's your new toy?
Well, you'll have to wait
and see like everybody else.
Good morning, everyone.
Morning.
Grey-Sloan Memorial has always
valued innovation as a top priority.
And today, the leader
of this charge is Dr. Grey.
We should all follow her
in pushing the boundaries,
moving medicine forward, finding
new ways to innovate. Dr. Grey?
3D printing will allow
us to customize treatment
for an individual's
specific needs.
Instead of ordering and
waiting for an implant...
Do you see that?
The printer, yeah, it's cool.
No, no, the guy next to her
with the eye twitch.
Eventually, even
using a patient's
own cells to prevent rejection.
Hmm. Welcome to the age
of personalized medicine.
A fork? MAN 1: Oh, no.
Well, at least it isn't a spork.
You guys, we just got
the printer yesterday.
We're testing it
out. Forks today...
Tomorrow, portal
veins for actual people.
You guys!
Oh, if your mother
could see you now.
She'd take issue with my hair.
She'd be proud.
Did I ever tell you the
story about how I chose
my first research project?
Many times. You
know, it's looking
a little too comfy in here.
Are you getting your laps in?
You can get one in now. You
can walk me to the elevator.
I have a patient to see.
Go change the face of medicine.
You need to be doing your laps.
You need to be walking.
Another captive runs screaming
from your theater of boredom.
Move along, C.J.
Oh, you know you
need some new material?
I know your entire
repertoire by heart.
They're good stories.
You see? Even Dr. Kepner's
heard them multiple times.
You should come take a
walk with me. Come on.
I'll tell you some
really good stories.
You get a head
start. I'll catch up.
And close your gown. I
can see your underwear.
I'm not wearing any.
Uh, Harvey? Yes, can I help you?
No, but I think I can help you.
I can fix that. It'll
take about 30 minutes.
Fix what?
Twitch.
I don't know who
you are, but frankly,
this is none of your business.
It's not a twitch, it's
a... Hemifacial spasm.
See, I can decompress the nerve.
It's minimally invasive.
It's barely even a surgery.
Who the hell are you?
He's Derek Shepherd, one
of the best neurosurgeons
in the country. I really
think you should let him fix it.
And who are you? Jackson
Avery, plastics, ENT.
I would really love to
observe, if that's cool with you.
No, that's not cool.
Now if you'll excuse me,
I haven't had a thing
to eat all morning.
If you don't eat,
I can do it today.
Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm.
Did you hear Mer just
revolutionized the world of cutlery?
No, I did not.
Working on a liver
model. It's printing up now.
That's great.
It is great.
What the hell's the
matter with you...
Stay out of it.
Okay.
Thanks for letting me pick up
a few shifts. I appreciate that.
Absolutely. It's good
to have you back.
Uh, that's wrong.
My esophagectomy is
supposed to be in OR two.
Sorry, trauma
came in this morning,
and now you're in OR three.
But I planned for OR two.
It was set up exactly the way
I needed it for my procedure.
OR three is identical to OR two.
Good to have you back, Ben.
Um...
What's wrong with OR three?
Is there a smell in there, too?
There is a smell in Tuck's room,
and I'm gonna find it.
Mr. and Mrs. Glazier.
Did you figure out why
Nathan's not getting any better?
The left side of
your son's heart
can't effectively pump
blood to the rest of his body.
So, last week we
inserted something
to help divert the blood
flow to the right side.
Right, you put in the conduit.
Is it not working or something?
The conduit is synthetic.
So, in some cases, the
body refuses to accept it.
We believe Nathan is in the
beginning stages of rejection.
We're running more
tests to be sure.
And what happens
if he's rejecting it?
Well, first we treat
it with medication.
But worst-case scenario,
we take it out and
put in a new one.
With another synthetic one,
but won't he just
reject that one, too?
Let's not get ahead
of ourselves just yet.
We'll let you know as soon
as we have more information.
You said you have answers,
but you really don't, do you?
Okay, so then, um,
after UW you went
to the Cleveland clinic.
That's impressive. Mmm-hmm.
Under Lacy.
And the focus there was
on congenital heart disorders.
Oh, but then you
left after only a year?
Yeah, there were so many
great opportunities out here
in Seattle.
Really?
And there were some
personal elements at play, too.
I was going through a divorce.
And we both
worked at the clinic,
and that became untenable,
it was affecting my work,
so I made a move.
Oh.
No, right, yeah, no, I get that.
So then you moved
to Seattle Pres?
Yes. A year as an attending,
and then running the
maternal/fetal department
for the last year.
My research... Was
that hard for you?
To give up your job?
Well, your city, to your ex?
Uh...
I've been trying to wake him.
Come on, buddy.
We've let you sleep
in long enough.
Good morning, Will.
My big day started
out as a nightmare
when a clown came in at dawn,
asking me if I wanted
a balloon animal.
Clowns are a ped's floor hazard.
Are you still going to try to
remove all of the tumors today?
It just seems like it's
a lot to do all at once.
Will's cancer is a very
aggressive sarcoma.
It's an all-or-nothing approach.
We've come up with a
plan to remove all of them,
starting with number one.
Some will be a snap, but
there are a few tricky ones,
like tumor number eight.
It's deep in the liver, but
we'll do our best to get it.
We'll get it.
We'll try.
Um, it's sort of like
trying to get past level six.
You know, there are
some, uh, fighters,
but we need to
be really precise.
We will eat all those dots
and kill all those ghosts.
She doesn't play video games.
We'll see you in the OR.
What are you doing here?
Oh, I switched with Knox.
Uh, Ben Warren. I don't
know if we met before I left.
Oh, oh. I was actually
at your wedding.
I got you that pizza stone.
We have a pizza stone?
Yeah, I got you a
circular clay stone
about 15 inches in diameter.
It's kind of my standard gift.
Yeah, I just always used
your typical cookie sheet
and poked holes in the foil.
Oh, well, then this
will change your life.
The crust that always sticks
to the edges never gets burned.
You really can
tell the difference?
You broke scrub.
I'm sorry?
Your left hand dropped
below the sterile field.
Go re-scrub.
I didn't move my hand... Yes.
It did. I saw it.
You want to call me a liar,
you need to go re-scrub now.
Miranda, you need a minute?
I need a quiet OR
so we can begin.
10 blade.
Right this way.
Well, your EMG did confirm
that it is a hemifacial spasm.
So, we'll just get you
started on some pre-op tests.
Wait, I know I signed the form,
but how do I know
this is gonna work?
I mean, I've already tried
Botox, muscle relaxers and...
Well, you know, you sell
more than just 3D printers.
Correct. I also
sell ink cartridges.
No, no, what I mean is
that you sell inspiration.
You are the future
face of medicine.
Don't you want that
face to be twitch-free?
The surgery will work.
See? You should listen to him.
He's a guy in a bathrobe.
I'm Dr. Richard Webber.
I basically trained these two.
You're in good hands.
Right this way.
Dr. Avery...
I know you said you
removed Mrs. Maddox's drain,
but I'm worried about a seroma.
Should I go ahead and...
No, no, don't do anything.
I'll do it myself after surgery.
Hey, Murphy!
Get in here.
You didn't hear the
end of my story. Come.
I go to his house,
we eat dinner,
we talk, we watch TV, we talk,
we kiss, we... Other
stuff, and then we stop.
I go home, and
it's hard, you know,
because it's not like I
don't know what I'm missing.
I know what I'm missing.
What do I do?
Hmm? Well, okay, hold on.
What exactly are you asking me?
Well... How do I resist?
Remember when
you had that flirtation
with intern Murphy,
and then you decided not
to take it any further?
Oh. Yeah. Um, I
took that further.
You had sex? Yeah.
Was it... Awesome.
This is not... You're not...
I have to go away from you now.
Ready with tumor number one.
Okay, you see that?
Already going great. One down...
Fourteen to go. I wish we
had gotten to him sooner.
He was diagnosed
already stage four.
Typical teenager.
He ignored his symptoms, didn't
want to ask for help from anyone,
and now he's got an abdomen
completely covered with tumors.
Well, you're right. He
is a typical teenager,
which means he can beat this.
He's strong, able to
fight. And what's better?
What? He's in my OR.
In the OR of someone standing on
the forefront of medicine.
You should print a spoon next.
That way we'll be able to
reach tumor number two.
It is an anatomically correct
liver model with a portal vein.
It's a plastic
blob. I'm starving.
Can they print
food or just utensils?
When will the model be done?
Ten, maybe 12 hours.
That long?
It's life-saving
technology, Shane.
If you want it faster, page God.
It's a fake organ. How
long for functional items?
Like an actual vascular graft?
Like a pretzel.
Here it is.
"Biodegradable polymers."
What are you looking for?
Nothing. It's just interesting.
Printing's the future.
What's a typical
Saturday like for you?
Oh, well, listen,
I know that the newest
attendings pull the most calls.
So I have no problem
working weekends.
Oh, yeah, no. I'm just, I'm
wondering what you do for fun.
What feeds your soul?
I, uh, read.
I like to cook. I like movies.
I have a German
shepherd mix named Lila.
But no kids from your
previous marriage?
Well, previous marriage?
No, I'm just...
I'm just sayin',
is kids something you see
down the line in your future?
Do you want kids?
I'm sorry. I don't think
you can ask me this legally
in a job interview.
Oh, of course not.
Of course not. No. You
know what? Forget I asked.
I haven't given
much thought to kids.
Please, never mind.
But if I do, or when I do,
I imagine girls, two.
I know that they'll
be hell in junior high,
but I grew up with sisters.
Aw. Nice.
Yeah.
Just a few more questions.
More?
Hey, how's it all going?
It's great.
Yeah, we're making progress.
Good. Yeah.
In Japan, they're
making conduits
and seeding them
with the patient's cells
before implanting them,
taking away the risk of rejection.
Uh-huh. Yay, Japan.
Why can't we do that?
Why can't we use a
3D printer to create
a conduit that Nathan's body
would recognize as his own?
He wouldn't need
surgery after surgery
to keep replacing the
failed synthetic one.
It's brilliant, but the
research alone...
I thought you would say that.
Here are the Japanese studies.
We would need extensive imaging
to see if Nathan's
even a candidate.
Also covered.
I've scheduled a
cardiac CT and MRI.
It's too experimental.
We'd have to file a
compassionate release
with the FDA, get approval.
These things take time
that Nathan may not have.
If I start the groundwork
with the FDA,
will you consider it?
Sure.
Can we talk?
Hi. Yes, can we?
I want our wedding
night to be amazing.
So do I. And I want
our first time to be...
And that's the thing.
It will be the first time.
For me.
I just, I want it to be right.
Before we have sex, I want
us to commit to one another
in the presence of God and...
Shh.
April...
I love you.
Yeah.
And I am going to love
you the rest of my life.
And I think that God knows that.
I think he knows how we feel.
Or she.
Well...
Reverend Drew did say
that we should support
one another.
So, if this is really
important to you.
It is really, really
important to me.
Really?
Okay.
Okay? Mmm-hmm.
Hey, those adhesions
are stuck to the intestines.
So, make sure you're on
the right plane of dissection.
Think I'm finally
getting through...
Dah! Careful!
Wilson, if you cut the bowel
instead of the adhesion,
there'll be spillage
all over the man's
abdominal cavity.
Right.
You know, just let me do it.
Dr. Bailey!
I need to feel
the tissue myself.
Dr. Bailey!
What? Spillage.
Irrigation.
Dr. Bailey.
Miranda.
More irrigation.
Dr. Bailey!
Miranda.
Irrigation, now.
We need to completely
wash out the abdomen.
Did you completely wash it out?
I have, several times. I don't
see any stool or contamination.
And we need to
get it closed ASAP.
The hole can cause sepsis,
which could drop blood pressure.
Vitals are steady, we're fine.
We still have all
the anastomoses.
Just concentrate on
one thing at a time.
We fix the hole. Then we
move on to the next step.
Routine complication.
It happens.
Everything's under
control. We're good.
You good, Miranda?
3-0 Vicryl.
Hi.
Hey.
Are all the materials
biocompatible?
Depends on the cartridge.
What happens if you, like...
You know, pause it?
Start something else?
You'd be stuck
with a hunk of junk.
And then Dr. Grey
would have to start over,
sending her back a
whole day in her research,
resulting in her
desire to murder me.
Hmm.
Great.
Vertebral artery is tortuous.
See, it's compressing
the facial nerve
which is the
source of the twitch.
Yeah.
You wanna do the decompression?
Hell, yeah.
Dr. Avery, trauma's
asking if we can take a look
at a huge facial lac in the ICU.
Should I do the sutures?
No, definitely not.
I can handle it. Seriously.
Seriously, I'll be
there in an hour.
Thank you.
Murphy's not bad, you know.
Oh, I know.
It's just that I'm better.
Can I have a pledget, please?
Thank you.
Put it to the left, dumbass.
What? Are you a half-wit?
I said place it
to the left, idiot.
Those are things
Mark Sloan used to say
when he thought he
was better than you.
Are we taking a walk
down memory lane now?
You know, I convinced
him to start teaching you.
You're a full-wit.
Now you have to start
teaching the residents,
hand them the keys.
And let them take it on
a joyride? I don't think so.
Well, pretty soon they're gonna
be 18 and have their own cars.
Let's teach 'em
before they get there.
All right, securing the
pad with fibrin glue.
You're gonna need
a lot of that, asshat.
All right, I get it. Point made.
I know. It's just so fun.
There she is. Number eight.
Right smack in the
middle of the liver.
Let's skip it. Skip it?
Why would we do that?
We'll come back to it.
No, we planned this
surgery in an order.
We should stick to it.
Alex, if we remove
the other ones first,
we'll have better exposure.
Let's just come back to it.
It's the hardest one.
If it turns out we
can't remove it,
what's the point of even
going for the easy ones?
Look, we should try...
I hear what you're saying,
but I'm the lead
surgeon on this,
and I'm making the call.
Let's go to number nine.
Dr. Yang! PICU just paged.
Nathan's definitely
in full-blown rejection.
I did it. Did what?
I spoke to the FDA, filled out the
release, I just need you to sign it
before they can
start reviewing it.
Ross.
We're not gonna
do it. Call them back.
You said you'd consider it
if I covered the obstacles.
There are other
options. Safer options.
We can increase his IV steroids,
start prograf...
No!
None of those are as
good as a biological conduit.
I have all the information.
We have the printer.
Ross.
It's not our printer.
It's Dr. Grey's printer and
she is using it to print now.
So we can't do it.
I'm sorry.
Then, I pan-sear
them for a few minutes
on both sides
until they're brown.
And?
And that's how I make
my famous meatballs.
That's not a story,
that's a recipe.
At least it got you to shut
your yap for a hot minute.
Eh, it's useful.
Uh, you know, uh, besides,
it's better than you
speaking about...
C.J.?
Okay.
C.J...
C.J.!
C.J. I need some help!
C.J.! Dr. Webber?
Let me take over...
Okay, okay, I got this.
Kepner, get a crash cart.
Okay, get me one of epi
and 300 of amiodarone, now!
On it.
Code blue, third floor.
Come on, C.J.
Callie loved you.
She's very nice. Very
thorough, but very nice.
How long have you
two been divorced?
Um, well, I don't
think that we are.
We're sort of
separated, I guess.
Ah, you still have the ring.
But you're seeing
other people, obviously.
Um, yeah, we are.
I'm so sorry. That
was way too personal.
I just got out of a job
interview that was more intimate
than most rectal exams.
I'm just not used to it.
Uh, we don't do things
like this at Seattle Pres.
Well, then, come work here.
Because we do way too
personal on a daily basis.
We'll isolate the
vessels, then take
the tumor out
under direct vision.
I can do it. ALEX: I don't
know if you can, Mer.
It might be better
just to close him.
Well, if we don't resect it,
the cancer will only spread,
and it'll eliminate his
chances of beating this thing.
How do you get it without
taking the entire liver?
Dr. Grey, I just wanted to show
you the latest on the liver model.
Not now.
Edwards, scrub in. We're
gonna need your help retracting.
Alex, he's 15.
I think we need to be as
aggressive as we can. Clamp.
That's the last of the
reconstruction, right?
That's right. Ben, can we
get a methylene blue test?
Coming right up. MIRANDA:
Wilson, watch closely.
If there's blue...
There's a leak, on it.
No blue.
Nice work, you guys.
Let's also get a bubble test.
Do we need both?
We need to be absolutely
sure that there's no leak.
If there's a breakdown
somewhere in the anastomosis,
then bacteria can seep
through, going God knows where,
causing a potential
fatal infection.
Is that what you want
for the patient, Wilson?
No, ma'am.
You know, bubble test
only takes a second.
So, Wilson, as I inject
air into the NG tube,
submerge his chest with saline.
Okay.
No bubble. Should
we start to close?
We're not closing.
There's a leak.
There's a leak. I see a small
bubble, so there's a leak.
We'll patch it. JO: A bubble?
I don't see anything.
It's there.
Dr. Warren?
Um...
You know,
I didn't have a very good
angle from over here,
but I trust Dr. Bailey
if she saw a bubble.
Might as well put a
patch on to be safe.
We'll oversew it and
cover it with a muscle flap.
Suction. Scissors.
Uh, Harvey, are you okay?
I'm waiting for it to twitch.
It's twitched for 20 years.
You can wait all you
want, but it's gone.
We got it.
Thank you.
Who do you wanna see first?
The facial lac or Mrs. Maddox?
I'll take 'em both.
Okay, I will take Mrs. Maddox,
and you can take the facial lac.
You know what? Why
don't you take 'em both?
Dr. Avery, I will
not disappoint you.
How you holding up?
I'm exhausted.
You should've let me do the CPR.
No, no, it's a good exhausted.
I've been stuck in this bed,
reminiscing about my old life,
trying to feel
like myself again.
And now I wanna be myself again.
Ready to get back to my feet and
be the doctor I used to be.
I lost myself there
for a while, Kepner.
Now I'm ready to
get myself back.
He's in florid heart failure.
His EF is falling precipitously.
It's the hospital's printer.
You taught me to take
what I need for my patient.
We can't. Not this time.
I looked at Dr. Grey's research.
She still has months to go
before printing a portal
vein that will actually go
into a human patient.
But this? Building a
scaffold seeded with cells,
we can do this.
This baby can be saved today.
I know, Shane. You
think I don't know this?
Now set up for a
pericardiocentesis
and do a repeat echo in an hour.
Mer, you have to stop now.
I'm about to do the
trisegmentectomy...
Any further, you're
gonna move into
segment two and three.
And it will be fine!
There won't be enough
functioning liver to support this kid.
I think it will, and I will
stop before I'm too deep.
You print one damn
fork, and now you think
you're Moses or something.
Alex, I am in the middle
of dividing this kid's liver.
And I need this
conversation to be over!
Oh, you gonna pull
rank on me again?
Is that how the decision's made?
You could
two-challenge rule. What?
Dr. Webber told us about
the two-challenge rule
where two surgeons who
agree can force a third surgeon
to stand down from
a course of action.
Okay, fine. So, Dr. Edwards,
you and I challenge
Dr. Karev to relax
and let me finish.
No, I'm challenging you, Mer.
I'm asking you to
stop what you're doing.
Edwards?
Dr. Grey, I think
you're amazing.
And you made a beautiful fork,
and I am so grateful to
have been a part of that.
But, right now, I do
think you're pushing it.
And I have to second
Dr. Karev's challenge.
Dr. Karev, you can close.
So, Robbins says
everybody loves you.
I can't work here.
What?
These people are great.
They're incredibly nice,
and overly kind and
a little nosy, but great.
But they're your people,
and they love you.
And they care about you.
And they'll close
ranks around you.
They'll...
Uh, look, I worked
with my husband,
and when our
marriage fell apart...
If something happens to us,
if we broke up, they
would all choose you.
And they'd want my
blood.
I would just be the bitch
that broke your heart.
Are you...
Are you planning
to break my heart?
No, but...
So don't do it.
Take the job.
Owen, I can't.
I can't risk it.
Hey, you don't do it either.
Do what?
Break my heart.
So, what does that
mean? Another surgery?
More chemo and radiation?
It means more time
on the peds floor.
Yeah, it sucks. Um...
But, you know,
while you're here,
we'll get some things from home.
You know, extend visiting hours
so, uh, your friends
can hang out.
And, uh, I'll make sure
that no one rounds
on you before 11:00.
No more peds stuff.
Deal?
Deal.
Sorry about what
happened in the OR,
but we made the right decision.
I could've gotten that tumor.
Nobody could've gotten
that tumor. I could have.
Mer, I need to talk to you.
I need a minute. It's
about a patient of mine.
Well, I'm talking about a
patient of mine right now,
so I need a minute.
I need the printer.
It's my printer,
Cristina. No, it's not.
It's the hospital's
printer, and...
Which I got for them for
my research, for my grant.
Which is important
research, but at this point,
it's research, Meredith.
And what I'm talking
about could save a life.
I can't stop it in the middle.
It will completely
destroy the model.
Just because I printed a fork
does not mean my
research is a joke.
No one said it was a joke.
But see, I could
print a scaffolding
and make a biological conduit
for a baby's heart.
They're not even doing that yet.
They are in Japan.
So, if I get
compassionate release...
I don't have time to argue.
Submit a proposal to the board
if you wanna use the printer.
It's time-sensitive, Meredith.
Well, then you
better get to work.
So that's what it
was about in there?
You and Yang?
She calls you a lousy doctor,
and suddenly you have
something to prove?
That is not what this is about.
Oh, so you take it
out on my patient.
I did not take it
out on your patient.
Look, you need to
be told you're good?
Fine, Mer, you're good.
But Yang was right. You
were a lousy doctor today.
Torres!
Hmm?
Come walk with me.
Looking good, sir.
Feeling good.
You hear I saved the patient
in the room next door to me?
I heard there was a
code. That was you?
Let me tell you all about it.
I was talking to a patient...
Hi.
Uh, come in.
I love you, Matthew.
I love you, too.
I lost myself last year.
And I worked really hard
to get back to who I was.
The fact that I
stumbled in my faith...
It matters to me.
But it just, it feels so good
to be back to who I was
and to have found someone
who shares that faith.
And, Matthew, I love you,
and I respect you too much
for you to let that go.
And...
It's still gonna be
a first time for me,
because it's gonna be
my first time with you.
Oh, it's gonna be amazing.
If we have sex tonight,
the only thing that will change
is that you will have
broken a promise,
and I know how that feels.
So...
We're waiting.
You know, we can lean
on each other for support.
Hmm. Mmm-hmm.
Okay.
All right, but, uh, maybe we
shouldn't actually lean on each other.
Ah.
You coming in here?
Yeah, in, uh, one minute.
So, how do you beat the odds
when it's one against a billion?
I changed our plan on you.
And it'll take time to
figure out our new plan.
But, Miranda, I'm glad I'm home,
because something's
clearly going on.
Between the checking and
re-checking the drawers,
and pulling at your fingertips?
You need help.
What happened
today in that OR...
You and I both know
that there was no bubble.
Uh...
There was a smell.
Look, apple slices.
Probably with peanut
butter on them at one point.
I found them in
Tuck's soccer bag,
and he hasn't been
to soccer in weeks.
So, you know, God knows how
long they've been rotting in there.
Miranda, I...
Everything's fine.
You stand strong,
keep pushing yourself
past all rational limits.
And never let yourself give up.
Hey, how did the surgery go?
I could have
gotten number eight.
Would you believe
me if I told you that
I could have gotten
number eight?
Of course. You wouldn't
say you could if you couldn't.
Now, would it cheer
you up if I told you
I changed the face of
the face of the 3D printer?
No, because I'll
miss his twitch.
You know what this is?
Yes, it's a fork.
No, it's the future.
Go watch your liver model.
I'm gonna put the kids down.
But the truth of
the matter is...
What the hell are you doing?
Despite how hard you try
and fight to stay in control,
when it's all said and done,
sometimes you're
just outnumbered.