Previously on ER:
Got a letter from your dad.
Steve's writing that he got
some new job in Colorado.
Sam, you've got
to tell Alex the truth.
Alex!
It's all gonna be okay.
- He's 12. MAN: When's
the last time you saw him?
Around 8:30.
So four and a half hours ago?
Friends, relatives,
anyone he might be with?
We've been calling and
driving around. There's nothing.
- Any fights, school problems?
- We had an argument.
I went upstairs to take a
shower and get ready for bed...
and about an hour later, Visa
called for an authorization on my card.
He'd gone to the bus station
and tried to buy a ticket.
- Ticket to where?
- Colorado.
- Why Colorado?
- His dad is there.
What about his home situation?
Is it stable? Drugs? Violence?
Alex has a good home.
What about Dad, you let him know
Alex might be on his way or calling?
He's not that easy
to get ahold of.
Why's that?
He's in prison.
Alex doesn't know
that his dad is in jail.
He's been asking me if
he can go live with him...
I'm sorry, shouldn't we be
calling Amtrak or the airlines?
No, they won't board a
minor without parental consent.
- You got a recent photo?
- This happens all the time.
Nine times out of 10, they're
back home in 24 hours or less.
Alex doesn't have 24
hours. He's diabetic.
He could be in a coma by this time
tomorrow if he doesn't get his insulin.
Sam. Sam. SAM: We
gotta go by Shelley's...
- Union Station, the park...
- Sam, the car's...
He likes Navy Pier,
maybe he went over there.
And then we'll circle back to the school,
and, uh, the... The arcade on Lincoln...
We should be at
home when he calls.
We'll check Denny's
and McDonald's.
Open the door.
- Sam, he's not...
- Please, open the door.
Sam, when he calls, he'll call
home. They said we should be there.
He knows how to monitor
his carbs, stay hydrated.
He's too smart.
He's stubborn and
resourceful and smart.
He's not coming back.
Oh. The day shift.
- There is a God.
- Ew.
- Hard night?
- Okay. Everybody's here. Good.
It's 8:02. Time for
rounds. Curtain Number 1.
Wait. Ray, you're on. - Huh?
You're an R-2 now,
R-2s run the board.
Okay. Well... Okay.
Curtain 1, foreign
body in the eye.
Sanding his boat without eye
gear. Shard of glass under the lid.
- Corneal abrasion?
- Didn't get a chance to check.
Okay. Jane, he's yours.
Fluorescein, slit-lamp exam, home.
Curtain 3, we have
an altered 19-year-old.
Drank a gallon of antifreeze.
Responding to fomepizole,
waiting on psych and an ICU bed.
- Great. Moving on.
- Whoa. Good teaching case.
Yeah. Take a minute and
tell us all about fomepizole.
Uh, well, it's pretty new.
Yeah? What does it do?
Lowers the
ethylene glycol level?
Tell them how.
Increases renal excretion.
- Anyone else?
- Does it inhibit alcohol dehydrogenase?
I think it might prevent
formation of acidic metabolites.
Get it in early and
you avoid dialysis.
I'm gonna read about
this and make a handout.
R-2s have to do the
reading before rounds.
- How? I just got here.
- Get here early.
Teaching should be
spontaneous, off-the-cuff.
Excuse me. Is there somewhere
private I can go breastfeed?
We've been here three
hours. My kid needs to eat.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, there's a,
uh, family room down the hallway.
Mom, I'm starving.
Uh, all the way on your left.
- How old is that kid?
- He's gotta be 6.
That is a little freaky.
Sam? Hey.
- What?
- It's okay.
- Did they call?
- No.
It's his picture on the TV.
- How long was I asleep for?
- Um, about an hour.
All right, we gotta start
calling everybody again.
We already called everybody.
They're gonna call us if... Sam.
Hi, Debbie.
Yeah. Nope.
No, huh? Okay. Yeah,
yeah. As soon as... Of course.
- As soon as I hear anything.
- Hi, yes. This is Luka Kovac again.
Hello. LEWIS: What is it?
Altered traffic collision.
GCS, eight. Systolic's
100. Let's bag her.
What's your plan, Ray?
- All right.
Intubation, FAST
exam and a head CT.
- Okay. I'll be in Curtain 2.
- Dr. Lewis?
- Call me if you need me.
- I guess she trusts you.
Uh, yeah, 20 of etomidate, 100 of
sux. Portable C-spine and chest to follow.
- Get that SonoSite ready. Come here.
- Mind if I intubate?
Might wanna observe one first.
Why do we use etomidate?
- We need a sedative with a paralytic.
- No, I know that.
But isn't it true that ketamine
causes less respiratory depression?
Uh, maybe.
Well, does it have a more
favorable hemodynamic profile?
If you're concerned about
interabdominal hemorrhaging, then it...
Jane, we use etomidate
because it's a good drug.
- Okay, let me take a look.
- Sats up to 92.
All right, pull the handle at 45 degrees
and never rock back against the teeth.
Shouldn't you give
a dose of Pavulon?
- Sometimes we do, yeah.
- Is sux okay in crush injuries?
- Uh-huh. Cricoid pressure.
- What about hyperkalemia?
Look, never seen it happen.
The 8-0, it won't pull through. All
right. We need a smaller tube. Bag her.
Is sux okay in burn patients?
More observation and less conversation.
We tube her and then we can chat, okay?
- Seven and a half.
- Okay. Thank you.
Sergeant Parker wouldn't
tell us what this was about.
We haven't found your son yet.
Twelve thousand fliers went out.
Precincts, hospitals,
state police.
We notified the
folks in Colorado...
and we're getting some
play on local television.
Please, have a seat.
We canvassed the airline ticket
counters, Union Station, buses.
Nobody recognized your son.
Hey. Thanks for
coming back down.
Still nothing from Alex?
No, no. You know, I'm sorry.
Why didn't you tell us
this over the phone?
Why did you want us
to come down here?
We got a report of an
unidentified diabetic kid in a coma.
It matches your son's
general description.
- Where is he?
- In all likelihood, it's not him.
We're waiting for them
to fax a photo, but the...
They're still working
on him at the hospital.
- Where is he?
- Iowa. Davenport, Iowa.
- It's 200 miles.
- I'll drive.
They'll know if it's him
or not before we get there.
- If it's him, we'll be closer.
- If not, we'll be farther away.
I can't just sit at the house
waiting for someone to call...
to tell me they've found Alex in a
ditch somewhere or a Dumpster.
I can't! Okay? I can't.
Tell Dubenko the second
HemoCue was 12.1.
- Going to the O.R.?
- FAST was positive, needs an ex-lap.
- How'd it go, Haleh?
- It was a little rough.
Do you wanna give
Dr. Barnett some feedback?
There wasn't much teaching.
You seemed distracted by
questions from the interns.
- Well, they wouldn't shut up.
- Ray.
His frustration prevented the
team from working together.
There was tension in the room.
Could have caused a delay
in diagnosing a splenic lac.
- Oh, please.
- Thank you, Haleh.
Thank you. Thanks.
What was that about?
Improving your skills. Making
you a better teacher, a better leader.
Since when do nurses
evaluate the Residents?
- Haleh's been here longer. She knows.
- I needed to treat this patient.
You also need to create
a positive learning climate.
Are you torturing all
the R-2s, or is it just me?
Ray. Resolving TIA?
Go.
We must have missed it.
They said it's over a mile from
the interstate. We've only gone...
Ah! That's it.
Hello? Anybody here?
Excuse me.
There's a button.
Over there.
Hold your horses, I'm coming.
Hi, you have a boy in DKA?
Security guard found him down behind
Penney's at the mall, didn't have any ID.
His blood sugar was
764, pH 7.10, GCS eight.
Ketones were
positive at one to 64.
He's on IV saline,
insulin and potassium.
He just started opening
his eyes on command.
You just missed Dr. Hahn.
He went home to get his digital camera
so we could send a picture to Chicago.
No. No, it wasn't him.
Right. Thanks.
- Anything?
- No, not yet.
God! Damn it, Alex!
Uhh!
Erica's fine to stay at the
apartment till we get back.
He's not coming home, Luka.
You have the keys?
Where are we going?
Colorado.
- No infiltrate.
- Like I said, fever without source.
- Everything okay?
- Well, he doesn't have pneumonia.
- Urine?
- All clear.
- Rapid strep?
- No clinical indication.
Okay. Mason, can you
open up your mouth for me?
- I don't like that.
- Come on, you're a big boy.
I already did it.
Okay. Real quick, huh? Ah.
- A little bigger.
- Uh.
- Any rash?
- No.
He looks good. Can you
remove his pajamas for me?
- Dr. Babinski had him in a gown.
- I don't wanna take off my clothes again.
Look, I'm sorry, but
it's important. Okay?
You said we can go home.
- I want to go home.
- Mason.
Mason. WOMAN: Okay.
- I want to go home now!
- Mason, come on.
Ray? WOMAN: Two seconds.
- No!
- Excuse me. Be right back.
No! WOMAN: Come on, Mason.
- No! JIM: Come on,
Mason. One more time.
How's it going in there?
Just looking for a fever source.
Babinski said there wasn't one.
You know how it is with interns.
You gotta check up on them.
But not for 20 minutes.
The interns are doctors.
You have to trust their skills.
But they were students last
week, don't know what they're doing.
You're micromanaging
every case. That's not good.
We were caught up. We've got
six to be seen and 20 in the rack.
And that's my fault?
I liked you better when
you were the closer.
Still no service.
We're about 30 miles from Omaha,
so we'll probably get service soon.
- Where in Colorado?
- Huh?
Where's Steve?
Cañon City.
- Where's that?
- In the mountains somewhere, I think.
Never been.
What?
Colorado. Always wanted
to go. I hear it's beautiful.
Yeah.
What were you and Alex fighting
about? Last night, before he left?
The usual.
Me?
Us.
I should have just
told him the truth.
- Well, he knew we were having trouble.
- No.
The truth about his father.
After the Attending leaves you alone
in Trauma, you'll be critiqued by a nurse.
That's weird.
Even if the patient's crashing, make
nice with the newbies or you'll be dinged.
Ray, can I give another four
of morphine to McKenzie?
- You think he needs it?
- No, I just want him to stop breathing.
Fine.
You're responsible for
everything the intern does...
but question the history,
they get testy on you.
- Sounds like you had a great day.
- Yeah.
You ready, Neela? Tonight's
all about you and me.
- And me. Teddy Marsh, new intern.
- Hello.
First shift. An
overnight. Awesome.
This is Neela. She's
the R-2. She's in charge.
Your mission, clear
that board by morning.
I'm so screwed.
Antifreeze overdose has been
here all night waiting on ICU.
Let's step it up. The day
shift wants to get out of here.
Fomepizole's an alcohol
dehydrogenase inhibitor. You'll be fine.
What?
Neela, you're running
rounds. Let's start.
It's about nine hours to Denver.
I think we can make it by dawn.
- You try to sleep. I'll drive.
- No, I'm okay.
No, no. I'm awake. I'm not sure
I will be in the next four hours.
Shoot. My cell-phone battery's almost
dead. I should have brought my charger.
Hey, Luka.
Thank you.
The calculated osmolality
is approximated...
by multiplying the
sodium concentration...
by two and adding glucose
divided by 18 and the BUN, over 2.8.
Anyone have the numbers handy?
That's okay. We'll make some up.
Let's say he's measured...
What does this have to
do with a fractured rib?
Absolutely nothing.
- I have a date.
- Go. We could be here all night.
- Thank you.
- Divided by 2.8.
Twenty minutes and we're
only on the second patient.
Stay focused on the clinically
relevant teaching points.
It is. There's an osmolar gap.
Interns need to know what that means.
- Not right now.
- Stab wound. Need some help here.
Neela, take it with Marsh. Pratt,
Morris, finish running the board.
- Ready?
- My first trauma as a doc. All right.
Single stab to the right chest,
agonal resps, sats 84 on 15 liters.
All right, Trauma 1, let's go.
Now enter the thoracic
cavity through the intercostal.
Okay. I felt a pop.
Okay, insert finger, feel lung tissue,
pass the tube on a curved clamp.
Pretty cool. My first
night, my first chest tube.
The key is to avoid the neurovascular
bundle at the inferior margin of the rib.
The tube won't pass.
All right, let me try.
I can't find the tract.
Sometimes you need to
check again with a finger.
There is no tract. Did you
enter the thoracic cavity?
I thought I did.
Did you feel lung tissue?
It was warm and soft.
Lung tissue expands and
contracts with ventilation.
Right.
Now we're into the pleura.
I'm sorry. I thought I was in.
- I'll do better next time.
- How you doing?
Finishing up a chest tube.
Can you start a central line?
- I got a cue ball versus cheek to sew up.
- Trauma patient takes priority. 0-silk.
Pulse is 98, BP is stable,
what's the big deal?
My guy needs a three-layer closure
on a complex stellate facial lac.
- That could take two hours.
- Yeah.
Let Plastics do it. Someone
needs to keep an eye on the board.
Don't worry. I told the nurses to
send off labs and x-rays on everyone.
Morris!
Looks like everything's
under control.
- Is that a vertical mattress?
- No, it's horizontal.
What are you doing?
Bugs. It's difficult to see.
Where are we?
Uh, we passed Grand
Island about an hour ago.
- We should get to a phone, call Chicago.
- Okay.
What time is it?
One-thirty.
I was dreaming about Alex.
He was 2 or 3.
And I needed a bathing suit...
so I was looking through the
racks at some department store.
And when I looked
back, Alex was gone.
He just vanished.
I guess you don't have to be
Freud to figure that one out.
I lost my son at the ocean.
Daniella didn't want me
to take him, but I insisted.
I was mad that she
didn't trust me, so, uh...
We had a big fight,
and she let us go.
What happened?
It was a very hot day, so
everyone had come to the beach.
You have beaches in Croatia?
Beautiful beaches.
Miles of them.
Anyway, so, uh, we found
about an inch of sand...
that wasn't already taken,
and we went down to the water.
He wanted to build
a sand castle...
so I went back up to pick
up his little shovel and bucket.
And when I came
back, he was gone.
I looked everywhere...
ran up and down the beach to the
shops by the road, into the water.
I couldn't find him.
How long was he missing?
Two hours.
Where was he?
Some boy had a dog.
The police found him wandering.
He knew his name, so they called
our house and Daniella answered.
When I got home, he was
sitting in a bathtub with his sister...
having a wonderful time.
I went to the kitchen and I cried
by the sink, with the water running.
What was his name?
Marco.
Alex is gonna be all right, Sam.
We're gonna find him
and he's gonna be all right.
It's 3 a.m. Shouldn't this
be slowing down by now?
You've got a dark cloud,
Neela. Always have.
Twelve more out there
triaging as we speak.
Neurosurg is coming to see the
subdural, he'll need a unit bed.
I'm gonna lie down for
a couple hours. Cool?
We've got three intubated
patients and a full board.
You are more than capable of
managing whatever comes in.
What? That's the fun
of being the big R-2.
You get to be queen
of the night shift.
Don't wanna be. I wanna get the
board cleared before day shift comes.
Can I get a copy of your schedule?
I'm trying to avoid nights that you're on.
Are you going to bed and
leaving me alone with this mess?
- You're not alone. You have him.
- Busy? I wanna present my guy.
Wake me only if it's
really, really important.
- He's going to bed?
- Yup. It's you and me against the world.
Chuny had me correct your fentanyl
order. It's micrograms, not milligrams.
Oh, God. That could have
led to a really serious mistake.
- It was caught in time, no harm done.
- I'm so sorry. Thanks for fixing it.
It's okay. You gotta learn
somehow. What you got?
A 37-year-old with
a deltoid abscess.
Never done an I&D, thought
you might wanna supervise me.
- Any other history?
- Chronic IV drug use, that's about it.
Physical?
Four-by-five fluctuant lesion on
the lateral aspect of the upper arm.
Remainder of the exam
was entirely normal.
Hey, doc. You ready to
slice open this bad boy?
This is Dr. Rasgotra.
She's my supervisor.
Just wanna take a quick listen.
It's so satisfying when
you guys cut it open...
and all that pus
comes pouring out.
Ten blade, saline,
swabs, packing gauze.
Anything else?
- Mr...?
- Kingsley.
Uh, we'll be, uh, back
in a minute. Okay?
- Did you listen to his heart?
- Of course I did.
So when you said his
exam was entirely normal...
were you just forgetting
to mention his murmur?
- He has a murmur?
- Four over six at the left sternal border.
- He has a thrill. It's not subtle.
- Wow. Big miss. I'll listen again.
You can't miss a
murmur in an IV drug user.
Could be endocarditis.
He needs an echo and
antibiotics before the I&D.
I heard you were smart, but I had no
idea you were such an awesome teacher.
Thanks for saving my ass.
What was that?
I don't know.
Oh, God.
Wait here.
What is it?
A deer, I think.
Is it dead?
No.
I don't think so.
I don't know.
You folks need help?
- I didn't... I didn't see it.
- Antelope.
Did a real number to your car.
- You both all right?
- Yeah.
I got a rifle in the truck.
Sam. SAM: We gotta keep going.
Sam, the car's wrecked.
The radiator's leaking.
The windshield's shattered.
You won't be able to see.
Come on.
Come on!
Our syphilis guy's had over
50 partners in the last 90 days.
Wants to know if they
can come for treatment.
As long as they wait till sunrise.
Pen G, 2.4 million units IM.
Neela! Your COPD'er
isn't looking so good.
Sats dropped to 87 on room air.
Can hardly catch my breath.
He was fine when I saw
him, he wasn't wheezing.
You can't wheeze if
you're not moving air.
We'll give you medicine to help.
Albuterol, 5 migs with 500 of Atrovent.
Sure that's a good idea? His
theophylline's 53, he's throwing PVCs.
What? You didn't bother
mentioning a toxic theophylline level?
I didn't know. I hadn't checked.
Didn't think we'd have
the level back till tomorrow.
Breathing's been bad.
I took some extra pills.
A hundred of lidocaine
and move him to Trauma.
Hold off on the albuterol until
we stabilize his arrhythmia.
You got it.
We'll be right
back, Mr. Canberra.
Whoa, you were great in
there. You really took control.
- Teddy, listen...
- I'm sorry about the theophylline thing.
- I'll have to thank Chuny for fixing it...
- Just listen, okay?
You wanna know a secret?
You don't have to be that
smart to be a good doctor.
You just have to be thorough,
systematic and meticulous.
- I'm trying.
- Not hard enough.
You've missed glaring physical
findings, overlooked critical labs...
and I've been correcting
your med orders all night.
It's my first shift.
I realize that, but you're
responsible for real people here...
and I can't watch
your every move.
I know that. And I
wanna thank you...
And your attitude...
It's just so contrite
and appreciative.
It's just weird.
I...
I guess I just don't get it.
- Wait...
- I'm getting some coffee. Need anything?
Teddy, wait!
We'll do a head-to-toe
H & P together.
Might help identify where
some of your deficiencies are.
Bollocks.
They're gonna send a
truck to tow the car in.
Did you call Chicago?
The guy inside gets off at 7.
Offered us a ride back to North Platte.
From there, we can catch a bus
to Denver, or maybe rent a car.
North Platte's an hour east?
What are you doing?
Sam?
Sam.
Sam!
- What are you doing?
- What does it look like?
- You gonna hitchhike?
- He's been off his insulin for two days.
He's out there dying.
Hey!
- How'd it go?
- Not well.
Will you take a look at this board?
It's not 8 a.m. and the day sucks.
- Morning.
- You should've called me.
I hate leaving a
mess for the day shift.
Most of them are
waiting for beds.
This is ridiculous. Antifreeze overdose
has been here since yesterday morning.
Case in point.
What have you
been doing all night?
Taking a bubble bath
and eating bonbons.
- Lewis will make you run the board.
- I know.
Just remember that fomepizole's
an alcohol dehydrogenase inhibitor.
Hey, come on, come on.
Present this thing already.
Okay, let's get the night
shift home. You are...?
- Lana Clemons, new intern.
- You've met Dr. Sackowitz.
Pratt's the senior and
Dr. Lewis is our Attending.
- Neela, where's your intern?
- Sent him home a bit early.
Okay, day shift, let's go.
Curtain Number 1, 22-year-old
with myelomeningocele. What's that?
- Spina bifida?
- Excellent.
Most common congenital
neurologic deficit compatible with life.
How does it happen?
Neural tube doesn't
close in utero.
Uh-huh. Most likely due to an interaction
of genetic and environmental factors.
Ladies, remember
to take your folate.
On to why the patient is here. Rule out
shunt obstruction, common ER complaint.
- What's your approach?
- Shunt series?
- Before that?
- Tap the reservoir.
Guys. Before you do
anything? Take a history.
Classic symptoms of shunt obstruction:
headache, nausea, vomiting, lethargy.
I'm like a bad trailer-park
version of myself.
What are you doing here, Luka?
Sam, I care about Alex.
But you can't
replace his father.
I know that.
I'm just not ready for this
to be all there is in my life.
I can't bring your kids back.
I have a child of my own, and if
it's a choice between you and Alex...
I am always going
to choose Alex.
- I'm not asking you to choose.
- Of course you are.
I don't want what happened to
my family to be the end of my story.
I was a good father. I
can be a good father again.
And what if it's
not what I want?
Why don't you wanna
have children with me?
It's not about you.
I don't wanna
have any more kids.
I'm done.
I want my life back.
They can stop the run, but the
secondary is suspect, Champ or no Champ.
I tell you what, they make the
playoffs again, Colts will eat them up.
My brother and I got tickets.
Raiders. Should be able
to beat up on those jokers.
What's this idiot doing?
You wanna ticket him?
- Hang on. I'll be right back.
- What do you got?
Alex Taggart?
Hey. Alex?
Are you Alex Taggart?
- I'm Samantha Taggart.
- Dr. Collins.
How is he?
He was lethargic when
they brought him in here.
Glucose was 375.
It's not too critical.
After a little insulin and
saline, he's doing much better.
Can you give us
a minute, please?
Damn it, Alex.
I'm okay. I drank lots of water.
- You were lucky.
- I know how to monitor my sugar.
You're 12 years old and diabetic.
What the hell are you thinking?
I couldn't find him.
What?
Dad.
I looked in the phone
books, I called Information...
a bunch of different
rafting companies.
He's not here.
How we doing?
I'm losing the battle, and
we're knee-deep in triage.
- Well, I'm going as fast as I can.
- More than I can say for your interns.
Well, say no more.
- Dr. Sackowitz. SACKOWITZ:
Four-centimeter scalp lac.
After copious irrigation...
I'm using a 4-0 nylon interrupted,
the wound's edges are...
Abby.
Cosmetic repair is not
an issue at the scalp.
- I've never used a skin stapler.
- You'll do it next time.
Just point and shoot.
Grab another two patients.
There's a guy with
abdominal pain in distress.
I sent off a CBC, Chem-20, ordered an
abdominal series and a Surgical consult.
- Hello. George, how are you feeling?
- I can't get comfortable.
Okay, tell me, does it
feel worse when I do this?
Okay. All right. You
have a kidney stone.
- How'd you know that?
- I just do.
- Four plus blood.
- Okay, 30 of IV Toradol and 10 of MS.
Get a CT urogram and
cancel all the other orders.
- Got it.
- Ten minutes, you'll be feeling no pain.
Thank you.
Should I see if the
analgesics take effect?
No, you should pick
up another chart.
You sure? Because
you don't have to.
I'm sorry, Alex.
I wish that this
wasn't your life.
I can't tell you how
much I wish that.
It's okay, Mom. I wanna go.
Here?
Here? How about here?
Ah!
- Okay, 3 cc's, 1 percent lidocaine.
- Lidocaine?
You have a knot in your muscle,
which this shot should help.
Ah!
Okay. All right. Be right back.
Okay.
Right-lower-quadrant
tenderness, low-grade fever.
- No white count, anorexia or rebound.
- All right. Can you stand up for me?
- Do you think it's appendicitis?
- I'll tell you in a minute.
Okay. Can you do this?
- Yeah.
- Let's see.
Can you do it again?
Okay. Excellent. It's not an appy.
Clear liquids, recheck in the a.m.
- How's your headache?
- Completely gone. Thank you, doctor.
I'm about to clear the rack.
Oh, yeah?
If I saw all the patients
myself, we wouldn't get behind.
Bet you're feeling
pretty good about that.
Mm-hm. I can't believe it
took me so long to figure it out.
- You haven't.
- What?
You didn't show
Sackowitz how to staple.
You didn't teach Clemons about
your approach to kidney stones.
You did a trigger point, a jump test
and completely ignored your interns.
They were moving like
slugs. You told me to step it up.
Yeah, but your job isn't to just move
the meat. You're a Resident now.
The lady in Exam
3 spiked to 104.
Guess I better go.
Nice job on the board, Abby.
- What's the matter with her?
- She's a new R-2.
- It's gonna be a long year.
- She'll catch on.
But she's not supervising,
she's not teaching.
She's doing everything herself.
You know, that reminds me
of someone I used to know.
How is he?
Full of crap, like always.
I meant Alex.
He's okay.
He wants to spend some
time alone with his dad, so...
There's only 10 more
minutes of visiting hours, so...
I figure Steve can't screw
him up that bad in 10 minutes.
God knows, I'm sure he'll try.
Alex is a good kid.
He'll figure it out.
Goddamn it, that bastard. He
couldn't care less about us...
but that little boy loves him anyway.
What the hell is right about that?
- Thank you.
- For what?
Coming.
Now what?
Home, I guess. I don't...
Luka, you cannot possibly
want this for your life.
- Want what?
- This! This mess.
Isn't that something I
get to decide for myself?
No. If it were just me?
Maybe.
I'd better go in
and check on him.
Steve's in prison.
You don't have to run anymore.
I'm not running.
I just don't want what you want.