All right, Caroline,
we'll have your infusion
ready in just a minute.
If you feel nauseous,
just let us know
and we'll get you
some Zofran.
Okay.
Think maybe we could just
give her some preemptively?
She got nauseous
the first three infusions.
I'm fine.
Danny, I can ask for
my own meds, thank you.
Of course you can, I'm just...
I'm just trying to...
Wait. Wait a second.
Don't start
the infusion yet.
Heather? Heather, sorry.
Um, I'm just curious,
is nausea a side effect
of the drug?
No, it's an effect
of the infusion process
in general.
Well, what kind of
side effects
are you seeing
from patients
who are getting the drug
as opposed to those
who are getting the placebo?
This is a blinded trial.
You know I can't disclose
that kind of information.
Of course.
Of course you can't.
I mean, not that
I'd ever tell her.
I just wanna be able to manage
her expectations, that's all.
Dan, I'm not gonna tell you
whether she's on
drug or placebo.
What are you doing?
Trying to take care
of my wife... My ex-wife.
I know that you're
worried about CeCe,
but this is exactly what
got you into trouble
when you were married.
Okay, look, I'm just gonna
go get her a glass of water.
Hey, we got a patient in Two.
Cystic fibrosis, temp 103.
Third time he's been in
in the last month.
That doesn't sound good.
Uh, here.
Been meaning to
give you that back.
Hi, Ben,
I'm Dr. Halstead.
This is Dr. Manning.
Hi.
How long have you
had the fever?
Started last night.
Do you know what antibiotics
usually work for you?
Not many.
The last few times they went
straight to Imipenem.
Okay.
Get me 500 of
Imipenem, CBC, BMP,
cultures times three,
chest x-ray,
PA, and a lateral.
I'm sorry, one second.
That's okay.
Hey.
I just parked.
I'm walking. I love you.
I love you, too.
It's my girlfriend.
Aw.
Lisa.
She can come in
if she wants.
Actually, she can't.
She has cystic
fibrosis too.
Ah.
Well, CF isn't contagious.
But CF patients carry
many different strains
of drug-resistant bacteria.
The fear's that
by sharing the same air,
they'll cross-infect
each other.
So you've never been
in the same room?
We met in an online
support group.
Lots of video chatting.
Um, but that's
all gonna change once
we each get new lungs.
You have to tell them
you're status 1A.
I'm status 1A.
This is why she makes me
bring her everywhere.
Glad to hear
you're 1A.
Three severe infections
in a month,
you're gonna need those
lungs sooner than later.
All right, well,
I'll call over
to the transplant coordinator,
and in the meantime
hopefully the antibiotics
will help get
your fever down, okay?
Poor kids.
So in love, and they
can't even be together.
April, are you taking
Mr. Lane in Six?
Going now.
Awesome.
Don?
Yeah?
I have some stretchers
in the ambo bay.
Can you take care of that?
Yeah, I'll get them.
Thank you so much.
Hey.
Hey, Ava.
Robin.
So, I heard you rounded
on my mom this morning.
How's her
new valve doing?
She is looking great.
I don't foresee
any problems.
Good.
Oh, and did you see the
vertical farming exhibit
at the Smart
I told you about?
I'm telling you,
the future is
aeroponics.
We get 120 days
of rain a year.
I don't see us
running out of water.
It's not about
the water.
It's about feeding 130 million
new babies a year.
Okay.
Have you seen it?
Uh, no, but I'll
make a point to.
Thank you.
Obviously, it is over
some people's heads.
That's a vertical
farming joke.
No.
Yeah.
Nope, nope, nope.
Anyway, I know
my mom's scheduled
for an echo tomorrow,
so once you get
the results...
Oh, my God, help me!
Please, help me!
Get me out!
Help!
Hey, hey, hey, don't move!
April, give me a hand!
Robin, go call Goodwin!
Sir, sir?
Can you hear me, sir?
It's locked!
I got an idea!
Don!
Don?
Hang on, Don!
Use this!
Clear!
I'll go call CFD!
Kill the engine.
Stay with him!
Got it.
What do we got?
Hey, hey.
It's okay, we got you.
What hurts the most, Don?
My leg!
He's bleeding really bad.
Yeah.
It's too much blood.
Am I gonna die?
Don't talk like that.
We're gonna get you
out of here.
Something cut his thigh.
It looks like it must
have been the artery.
I can't reach it.
Hey, give me an 18-gauge
IV catheter with an EJ line
and four units of O-neg
on the rapid transfuser.
Got it.
April!
April, you can't
go under there!
It's okay, I got it!
It hurts so bad, it hurts!
Definitely arterial blood.
Maybe femoral.
Can you get
a tourniquet above it?
It's too high.
It's too high to clamp, too.
If I can just pinch
my fingers around it...
Okay, I got it.
I pinched it off.
Hey, hey,
be careful up there!
Please, please.
Don't let anything
happen to me.
April, you gotta
get out of there.
I'm not letting
his artery go.
She is the only thing that's
keeping him alive right now.
CFD's gonna be here soon.
Hold on.
Sir?
Sir, can you tell me
your name?
He's got a loud
diastolic rumble.
It could be
an embolic stroke.
Which would mean
he passed out while driving.
We need to get him
up to CT!
Okay, let's move him!
Get the gurney in here!
Clear out, folks.
All right!
All right, let's move him!
Come on!
On my count.
One, two, three...
All right,
all right,
all right.
Let's go. There we go.
Ethan, page me when you're
ready to move Don, okay?
Yeah!
All right,
let's go, let's go!
Curry, we've
got ambulances
lining up outside
of the lobby!
Go help them!
Absolutely.
I got you.
This is Sandy Glenn
and her husband, Drew.
Passed out in her home
this morning.
GCS 15, vitals stable.
I'm Elsa Curry,
third-year medical student.
Uh, can you tell me
what happened?
I was just making some tea,
then suddenly I saw stars.
I found her on the floor.
Has this ever happened before?
No.
But she does have
multiple sclerosis.
Relapsing/remitting.
Could it be the start
of a new episode?
Yeah, it's possible.
Any other symptoms?
Visual disturbances,
pain, incontinence?
Uh, no, nothing like that.
Okay, uh, transfer
on my count.
One, two, three...
Okay. Yeah,
you've also got
some dry skin,
marked pallor,
and some peripheral edema.
Have you been
losing any weight?
Maybe a little,
but not much.
All right, then my attending
and I are gonna order
a full set of labs
and have Neuro
come down to take a look.
I'll be back in a little bit.
April!
Hey!
We got here
as fast as we could.
Kelly?
April, you hit?
No, no, no,
I'm fine. It's Don.
We gotta get him out of here.
Just hold tight.
We got it.
Cruz, how's it look?
His leg's stuck
in the wheel well.
Kelly, how long
till we get him out?
Well, we have to stabilize
the car with airbags
and secure it with cribbing
before we can even attempt
to remove that leg.
We move too quick, whole thing
will come down on top of him.
All right,
keep me posted.
Yeah.
Hey, Don?
Hey, you hang
in there, okay?
I'll try my best.
Good.
We're working on a way
to get you out soon.
Hey, come on.
I'll take over from here.
No, don't leave me.
Don't leave me.
No, it's fine.
You're not gonna fit
under here, anyways.
Look, April, I can
squeeze my way in.
I said I'm fine.
Dr. Choi.
How's he doing?
He's lost a lot of blood.
April's pinching off
his femoral artery,
but he's still bleeding
into his pelvis.
We've got him
on the rapid transfuser.
I'm gonna have Dr. Lanik
take over from here.
What, why?
April's in danger.
We need someone in charge
who's not as close to her.
Ms. Goodwin, I hear
what you're saying,
but April and I,
we're just coworkers.
It's fine.
Okay.
Mr. Nichols,
I'm Dr. Rhodes.
This is Dr. Bekker.
How are you feeling?
Sore, but okay.
I'm so sorry
about what happened.
I was getting
so numb and dizzy,
and I just wanted
to get here, and...
You passed out
while you were driving.
Mr. Nichols, your scans show
that you have a tumor
growing in your heart.
It's called a "myxoma."
Now, it is
most likely benign,
which means
that it won't spread to
the rest of your body,
but it is large enough that
pieces are breaking off
and causing you
to have small strokes.
So how do you fix it?
Normally we'd remove it
surgically,
but yours has grown
extremely large.
We would like to put you
on the transplant list.
Find you a new,
healthy heart.
Couldn't that take a while?
What if I have
another stroke?
I could die.
Removing the tumor
is a very difficult procedure.
If we try
and are unsuccessful,
your body won't be able
to tolerate
a transplant later on.
But it's possible
you could get it all?
It's possible.
Then let's do it.
Mr. Nichols, I appreciate
how eager you are
to take care of this,
but I, and we, would really
advise against that.
This thing
almost killed me today.
Just please, take it out.
Well, the risks
are significant,
but if you'd prefer
to take them,
of course, we'll do everything
we can to fix this.
Yes.
Thank you.
Okay.
All right, then.
Ava, you realize what we are
committing ourselves to?
I do.
We get one shot
at opening him up.
If we do it, and we don't
succeed, he's gonna die.
We can do it.
Hi, Ben.
So, good news.
A new pair of lungs
have become available.
Really?
Oh, my God, Ben!
That's amazing!
Yeah, they're flying in now.
Should be here
in a couple of hours.
So I'm getting them today?
I'll call surgery now.
Hey, you here
for your check-up?
That we are.
Hi, Sophie.
I think she's waking up.
I hope the, um...
The doctors will warm
his fingers up.
I heard
they charge extra for that.
That'd be great. Thanks.
But maybe I can
put in a good word.
I'll call surgery for Ben.
Thanks. Why don't I
take you guys up?
Great, yeah.
Everything's all right.
All right.
Dr. Choi!
Don needs you right now.
I can't breathe.
What happened?
He just started wheezing
a minute or two ago.
It's just getting worse.
I can't breathe.
He's having
a transfusion reaction.
We gotta stop the blood.
Give me 50 milligrams
of diphenhydramine, stat.
What's happening to me?
Am I gonna be okay?
You're having
an allergic reaction.
They're gonna have to
stop the blood.
But I'm still bleeding, right?
All right.
Cruz!
Yeah?
How close are you?
Leg's almost free,
but there's a lot of
jagged metal down here.
We gotta move
this whole thing
at least eight inches,
stabilize it before
we can move anybody.
It's gonna be awhile.
I can't give him
any more blood.
How long is "a while"?
What can I tell you?
We're working.
April?
Just let me
switch out with you.
Ethan, I am not leaving him.
Okay, so, anemic,
hypoglycemic.
Low vitamin B12
and calcium.
EKG changes...
Hmm. It ain't good,
but it doesn't look like
an exacerbation of her MS.
No, it looks like anorexia,
but she's not underweight.
Which doesn't necessarily
exclude the disorder.
Let's go say hi.
I'm Dr. Charles.
Ms. Curry wanted me to...
To say a quick hello.
Were my test results bad?
We're worried about
your nutrition.
Have you been experiencing
any digestive issues
or decreased appetite?
No.
No? Okay, that's good.
Are you concerned about
your weight at all, or...
Or even, say,
your appearance
in general?
I'm not anorexic.
I have a tapeworm.
A tapeworm?
Yes, I infected myself
on purpose for my MS.
There's this thing called
"helminthic therapy"...
Yeah, for autoimmune diseases.
It's really cutting-edge.
You've heard of it?
Yes.
Basically, the hypothesis
is that a worm infestation
can activate
your immune system
to fight against
certain conditions.
You know, there's actually
quite a few centers
that are doing
clinical trials.
She couldn't get in to
any of them.
Have you discussed this
with your neurologist?
'Cause there are several
new therapies for MS.
And, you know, modulators...
Steroids, Cytoxan.
I tried everything.
But since I started this,
I haven't had an episode
in three months.
Really?
Okay, what is your normal
remission rate?
Because anything longer than
two standard deviations,
and we could probably
publish a case study.
Um, could you
excuse us for a second?
Ms. Curry.
Ms. Curry, I appreciate
your enthusiasm,
but these trials
are held under strict
medical supervision.
She's doing it on her own.
I know, but this is
the front line
of immunotherapy.
I mean, we could find
a positive result.
That woman passed out today
from malnourishment.
That's what
we're treating here.
Or we can work with her.
We can modify her diet,
we can give her
higher calorie foods...
The patient has a parasite,
and it is clearly undermining
her health.
Dr. Charles, I really...
Let's start with
400 milligrams
of Albendazole
and hang a liter of D5W.
Thanks.
Mmm-hmm.
Looks like things
between you and Phillip
are going well.
He's still having
a tough time,
but it's slowly
getting better.
He's lucky to have you.
Dr. Halstead, Dr. Manning,
Ben's sats are dropping.
Please, help him.
Sats are down to 82.
No breath sounds on the left.
It's likely a pneumothorax.
I'll get a chest tube kit.
Wait.
Do you know
how many chest tubes
you've had before?
Four.
His lungs are likely
scarred as is.
Another chest tube will
only jeopardize his ability
to receive a transplant.
But the new lungs are
still an hour out.
I don't think
he'll make it like this.
I can make it.
We can give him steroids
and put him on a mask.
It's worth a try.
Okay. Let's give him
60 milligrams
of methylprednisolone,
and up the O2 to 10 liters.
Hang in there, Ben.
We're gonna send you up
to prep for surgery soon.
Hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey. Ethan?
He is losing consciousness.
We gotta get him out of here.
Hey, Don?
Don, can you hear me?
I'm so tired.
Stay with me, Don.
Kelly, you guys
ready to go yet?
The back wheels
are still too unstable.
We need a little bit
more time.
We don't have time.
Don's lost too much blood.
We're not moving anyone
until it's safe.
No, Ethan...
I'm sorry, April.
Kelly!
He's dying. We have
to move him now.
Dr. Choi, is that true?
How unstable is the car?
It's not where we'd like it.
If we move now,
can't promise you
it won't collapse.
Kelly!
Do it!
You start pressors,
I'll up his fluids.
No.
Keep working.
We're waiting
till it's safe.
Ethan!
We're waiting.
What's going on?
Turned into a tension pneumo.
We have to needle it.
His sats aren't coming up.
It's not working.
The new lungs are
still 15 minutes away.
He's not gonna
make it that long.
We have to do a chest tube.
If we do it, he may not be
able to get a transplant.
We have to do this.
Get the chest tube kit.
No, wait!
I'm sorry.
Sats are down to 71.
What about his transplant?
We don't have a choice.
Okay, making the incision.
I'm in.
Sats back up to 80.
Eighty-three.
All right, tell radiology
he needs a stat chest CT
before he goes to the OR.
Mmm-hmm.
I can't get an angle on this.
Reflect the atrium.
That's as far back
as it's gonna go.
I can't get around it.
Damn it.
The tumor's extended too far
into the auricle.
And into the valve
and the SA node.
I don't see how we're ever
gonna get the margins clear.
We may have to
close him back up.
But we can't
He's never gonna survive
another procedure.
We need to fix this today.
Let me try it from here.
Reflect the atrium.
Yes, sir. Forceps.
Right here.
Dr. Rhodes?
They're ready
to extract the patient
from under the car.
Okay.
Keep dissecting.
It's the only option we have.
Go grab a board.
Ethan.
Hey, team's in place.
Soon as he's out,
Maggie and I will
bind the pelvis
while you clamp off
the artery.
Why isn't he
on the rapid
transfuser?
He had a reaction
to the blood.
We had to take him off.
And he's been
down there
this long?
Yeah.
He's lost too much blood
and his pressure's
in the toilet.
Even if we are
perfect on this,
it might not be enough.
I know.
Man, I know
that this is delicate,
but is Don an organ donor?
I don't know.
The driver.
He needs a new heart.
God.
Yeah.
Don? Don, it's time
to get you out of here.
You have lost
a lot of blood.
I know.
Your condition is
extremely serious,
and you know that
in cases like this,
we'd like to
have a plan.
You wanna know
if I'm an organ donor.
You're a healthcare
worker, Don, you understand.
You said you were
gonna save me.
I know. We are, Don.
Don, we're gonna do everything
that we possibly can...
I don't want to die.
Stop, guys,
you're scaring him.
April, please.
Get me out.
Just get me out.
Don, Don?
Kelly, we gotta go now.
Let's go!
Ready?
Up on blue!
Copy that.
Up on blue.
Let's get it in.
Okay, ready? Kelly?
Yep.
One, two, three.
There we go.
Gonna roll him!
Yep!
Roll!
You're good.
Clamp?
Clamp!
All right, April.
Yep!
Faster, let's go!
He's gonna bleed out!
Clamps are on!
Heart rate's 140!
Sats are dropping!
Let's go, let's move!
All right,
on my count!
One, two, three!
Let's go! Come on,
let's move, people.
He's crashing.
All right, let's move!
Move, move!
Whoa! What's going on?
Dr. Latham called
the transplant off.
What do you mean?
The new lungs
are ready to go.
The chest tube caused
a hemothorax, and that's
on top of the damage
from all his
previous procedures.
He'd bleed out
before we even got
the new lungs in.
Nothing we've tried has
touched his infection.
If he doesn't get
this transplant,
he's going to die.
Dr. Latham says his lungs
are completely fused
to his chest wall.
It's just not possible.
I'm sorry.
Oh, God!
Oh, God. Here.
Oh, God.
You okay?
Oh, God. Yeah, I'm okay.
Hang a bag of Zofran.
No, I don't want
any Zofran.
Honey, you're nauseous.
It'll make you feel
so much better.
Go get the Zofran.
No, I don't want any Zofran.
I take the Zofran,
I get tired.
When I get tired, I nap,
and then I can't sleep
at night.
I don't want any Zofran.
Okay, well, we can get you
something to help you sleep.
Ask Dr. Singh to write
an order for, uh...
Will you stop it, please?
Okay, will you leave, please?
I want you to get out.
Okay. Okay.
I'll be back
in a little while,
20, 30 minutes, just to see if
you're still feeling nauseous.
No! Don't come back.
I want you out!
How's Don?
His pelvis is
completely shattered.
It's still touch and go.
What?
If he doesn't make it,
that's a heart wasted.
He was terrified, Ethan.
It was wrong of you
to ask him.
How could we not?
He wanted us to save him.
And we are! We're doing
everything we can.
You did not do
everything you could.
You should have gotten
Don out sooner.
That car
could have collapsed.
I wanted to make sure
he was safe.
No, you wanted
to make sure I was safe!
But I wasn't
your patient, Ethan.
He was.
Okay, so, um,
if you email me
the details,
I'll follow up
with you in a week
and we can
take it from there.
Ms. Curry?
What are you doing?
She wanted to be discharged.
She's severely anemic.
She could pass out before
she gets to the parking lot.
I mean, I scheduled
a visit with a nutritionist
and I'm gonna
monitor her closely.
Ms. Glenn?
You're aware
that this worm
puts you at risk
of pancreatitis,
heart disease,
arrhythmia...
I know, but it's
the only thing
that's helped my MS.
Trust me, correlation
is not necessarily causation.
What does that mean?
He doesn't think
that the absence
of MS symptoms
is related to
the tapeworm.
Not what I said.
Whether it's helping you
or not, the side effects
are seriously
endangering your health.
I don't agree.
I know how I feel,
and I'm going home.
Well, then, I'm sorry,
you leave me no choice
but to put you
on a psych hold.
What?
You can't
make her stay here!
I'm afraid I can.
Right now, your wife is
a danger to herself.
My job is to protect her.
Earl, back in Four.
No... Dr. Charles,
what are you doing?
Come with me, ma'am.
Let go of me!
Hey, what are you doing?
You can't keep me here!
Dr. Charles!
Get off of her!
Oh, hey. Uh, my mom,
she was feeling some tightness
in her chest before, so...
Yeah, of course.
I'll check on her
as soon as I can.
Okay, thank... Hey.
What's the matter?
Ah. Tough case.
We allowed this patient
to talk us into removing
his cardiac myxoma when we
should have done a transplant
and now... Well, he's
probably gonna die.
Why can't you remove it?
Well, it's too extensive.
We'd never get it all.
Could you get it all
with an autotransplant?
You're talking about
completely removing his heart
from his body.
I mean, we could get
at the whole tumor,
but the damage
is so extensive,
the odds
of reimplantation
are minuscule.
That might not be true.
The chief of CT
back at my hospital,
he did a 12-patient trial
on reimplantation
after ice-bath dissection.
He hasn't published yet
but he got good results.
What kind of results?
Greater than 50%.
"Greater than 50%,"
you're sure?
Yeah. I can get you
the details on the procedure.
Do it, fast.
I'm gonna be back
in the OR.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Okay.
Mmm-hmm.
I gotta go.
Hey.
Four months ago,
we were getting
married.
Today I gave her
her house key back.
I know.
What do I do?
Come on.
Let's get back to work.
Don's still in surgery.
It's not going well.
If he dies, I accept
full responsibility.
I looked at the notes,
spoke with CFD.
Lieutenant Severide said
you were faced with
some tough decisions,
especially regarding April.
You tried to warn me.
Being responsible
for people's lives
is never easy, Dr. Choi.
Let's all just hope that
things work out for the best.
Yes, ma'am.
The antibiotics
aren't working,
are they?
No, they're not.
Lisa...
I spoke with
the transplant
coordinator.
No one ahead of you
on the list can get here
before the donor
lungs expire,
which means
you're up next.
To get a transplant?
Yes.
I can't.
Not if he's going to die.
He's septic.
He has a DNR...
There's nothing
you can do.
I can be here with him.
I have to be here.
He's amazing.
Never complains.
Most people born with
something like this
would say, "Why me?"
But Ben, he's always
saying, "Why not me?"
He taught me
to be grateful
for what I have.
And I am.
I understand.
But you need
these lungs, too.
I still have time.
Another pair will come up.
Lisa...
No.
I'm sorry.
Mind if I come in?
Not at all.
You okay?
What, you mean
that whole thing
down there?
I mean, I wish it hadn't
come to that, but, uh...
Yeah, I'm fine.
Didn't look
that way to me.
Now, we've worked together
a long time, Daniel.
You usually
empower your patients
to make their own choices.
Putting that woman
on a psych hold?
Sharon, I made
a clinical decision
for her own well-being.
Don't know
what to tell you.
Look, I know watching CeCe
go through treatment
has been very hard on you.
It's making you
feel a little helpless.
But...
Bringing your emotions
to work?
I really don't like this.
You have a better idea?
You don't know
how you're going
to restart his heart.
Robin's on the
phone right now.
She'll have answers
for us soon.
Robin.
Not a cardiothoracic
surgeon,
not even an amiable
country doctor.
I trust her.
Why isn't Lisa in surgery?
You told her
she was next up.
She won't leave Ben.
Not while he's still alive.
Lisa, you and Ben have never
been able to be together.
But what if
there was a way
you could be?
Not through
a pane of glass.
We could?
Yes.
It could only be
for a minute, though,
because you'd have to agree
to take the new lungs.
No.
I can't.
Don't you think Ben would
want you to have them?
I can't leave him now.
It wouldn't be leaving him.
It'd be giving him
what you both have
always wanted.
Lisa, this is the memory
you'll have for the rest
of your life.
The one moment
you were truly together.
Okay.
Lisa, no.
It's okay.
I promise, Ben.
I love you, Ben.
I love you.
It's outrageous, I...
What recourse do we have?
My husband's talking
to our lawyer.
We're going to sue you.
That won't be necessary.
I'm releasing
the psych hold.
You can go home.
What?
I'm discharging you.
You're free to go.
Okay.
Well, good luck.
Hope you feel better.
Follow up with
her neurologist.
Stay on top of
those labs, and, um...
Keep me updated
as to her progress.
Of course.
Thank you.
You know there's
no published data
on intracardiac pacemaker use
in reimplanted hearts?
I am aware.
So do you have a plan
for what to do
if it doesn't catch?
No.
Great.
All right, here we go.
Well, will you
look at that?
All right, we still have
a lot of work to do.
Let's get him off bypass.
Yes, Doctor.
V-fib.
He's DNR.
Nothing more
we can do.
Time of death, 19:42.
They were able
to set his pelvis.
They actually think
he'll make a full recovery.
Are you all right?
I was worried
about you today.
Did it cloud my judgment...
Maybe.
But either way,
there's no place
for that here.
Thank you.
For caring.
Lisa, I'm so sorry.
But Ben has passed.
Natalie!
Yeah?
You and I...
We have some good memories.
Don't we?
Yes, we do.