*** amount of fear,
Unbearable pain.
Cruel injustice.
♪ I see trees of green ♪
♪ Red roses, too ♪
♪ I see them bloom for... ♪
As surgeons, we are
faced with it every day.
♪ ...me and you ♪
♪ And I think to myself ♪
♪ What a wonderful world ♪
Impossible diagnosis.
♪
♪ I see skies of blue ♪
♪ And clouds of white ♪
♪ The bright, blessed day ♪
Family tragedy.
♪ Dark, sacred night ♪
♪ And I think to myself ♪
♪ Oh, what a wonderful world ♪
Looming mortality.
♪
♪ The colors of the rainbow
so pretty in the sky ♪
♪ Are also on the faces... ♪
We face yours while we face our own.
♪ ...of people going by ♪
♪ I see friends shaking hands ♪
♪ Saying, "How do you do?" ♪
And some days, in the thick of it,
in the worst of it...
♪ What they're really saying is,
"I love you" ♪
♪
...we feel just as lost as you do.
[HORN BLARES]
- Somebody, help me!
- Aah! Get me out of here!
- [SCREAMING]
- Are you okay?
[TIRES SCREECHING, CRASHING]
MAN: Something's wrong. I can't get out!
[GLASS SHATTERS]
[HORNS BLARING]
- [CRYING] Aah!
- Somebody, help me!
- [TIRES SCREECH, CRASHING]
- OWEN: Stay in your car, sir.
- [CAR ALARM BLARES, HORN HONKS]
- WOMAN: Are you okay?
Stay by your cars.
- [TIRES SCREECH, CRASHING]
- MAN #2: People aren't stopping!
[HORNS BLARING]
WOMAN #2: I can't see anything!
[TIRES SCREECH, CRASHING]
- Whoa!
- [SCREAMS]
- [TIRES SCREECH, CRASHING]
- [INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
MEREDITH: I have to go.
I have to get out of here.
I can't let him go tank his whole career.
I can't decompress the chamber.
We get the bends if we decompress
too fast, and Gus could die.
- I'm not doing it.
- Is there a phone in here?
Yeah, it calls those tech guys out there.
You want to tell them how your
boyfriend's going to jail for you
and you still haven't said "I love you"?
Is that what you're gonna do?
You're gonna judge me?
Now?
No.
Just...
♪
What can we do for Gus?
How can we help him?
Nothing.
We just wait.
We... We... We let the oxygen do its job,
and we hope they get the blood
here in time.
So while we're stuck here,
you want to tell me
what the hell is going on with my wife?
♪
- [LEO COOING]
- AMELIA: Thanks, Bailey.
We'll be in soon.
Okay.
Babysitter's on the way.
Bailey is expecting us.
[VOICE BREAKING] I want my mom.
[BREATHES SHARPLY]
Oh, uh... okay.
Can I...
Should I call her?
She died a long time ago.
Uh... okay.
What would she say?
If she were here, what would she say?
S-She was a planner.
She made lists,
so she'd be so angry with me.
'Cause I don't even have a nursery yet.
And I didn't ever make it
to the birthing classes.
And Owen and I haven't even
talked about baby names.
And there's a really good man
back at my apartment
putting together a changing table,
and he's not even the baby's father,
so she would be so mad at me.
[INHALES DEEPLY]
But still, she would
rub my back, and she would say,
"Baby girl, I am always on your side,
no matter how wrong I think you are."
[BREATHES SHARPLY] Mm. She'd...
[GROANING] Oh!
Whoa, God!
Oh, God!
Okay. First contraction.
Holy... Ow!
Oh!
[PANTING] What are you doing?
Why don't you call...
just call... call an ambulance?!
If the next one comes
in under three minutes,
we'll call an ambulance.
If not, we are fine to drive.
[GROANING] Oh, God. Ohh, God!
Hiiiii.
My mom said you wanted me
- to come watch Leo.
- [DOOR CLOSES]
No!
♪
Um...
what are we, like, doing?
♪
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
[CONVERSATIONS CONTINUE]
[DOOR CREAKS LIGHTLY]
Um, Chief, can I speak
to you for a second?
Are you back?
Um...
We're getting calls
about a pileup on the freeway
and my head of trauma is in labor.
My other trauma surgeon
is on some rescue mission,
and one of my best residents
was just arrested.
Who got arrested?
Look, I-I know that
you're going through...
something.
But if you feel you can work...?
Yes.
Yes, I can work.
[SIGHS DEEPLY]
Okay, if I wasn't so mad
about all the other things,
I'd dance for joy.
Put on some scrubs and head to the pit.
♪
[SIGHS] Thank you.
[SIRENS WAIL]
[HORNS HONKING]
WOMAN: No!
Okay, let me help you!
FRANCES: Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
We're gonna die.
- It's okay.
- [BREATHING HEAVILY]
- [SCREAMS]
- Somebody, call 911!
[HORNS HONKING]
♪ Shalom rav al Yisrael amcha ♪
- [SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE]
- ♪ Tasim I'olam ♪
- [WOMAN SCREAMING IN DISTANCE]
- [WHIMPERS]
♪ Ki atah hu Melech Adon ♪
- ♪ L'chol Hashalom ♪
- [MAN SHOUTS IN DISTANCE]
[HORN BLARING IN DISTANCE]
[BREATHING SLOWS]
- [VOICE BREAKING]
- That's beautiful.
My mom used to sing it
when I couldn't fall asleep.
[WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY IN DISTANCE]
Okay. Looks like a truck crashed,
and then all the cars crashed
into the truck
- and then each other.
- [SIRENS APPROACHING]
Okay, Frances?
You hear that?
The sirens growing closer?
That is our ride.
We're gonna have to get out.
Okay, Frances?
So, I'm gonna carry you
just like before, okay?
You are so very brave, and I am not.
Frances, Gus is still alive.
And you're still the only one
who can save him.
Now, I get that this was scary.
I know. I got scared, too.
But it was a miracle
that we didn't get hurt.
So let's not waste it.
Let's go save a life, okay?
[SIRENS APPROACH]
I got you. Come on.
[RADIO CHATTER]
OWEN: I got you. I got you.
LEVI: It's okay. Got you.
FRANCES: [WHIMPERING]
People are hurt.
Should we see if we can help?
We're the only ones who can help Gus,
and that is our mission.
He maketh me down to lie
in pastures green.
He... leadeth me to something waters by.
- [HORN BLARING]
- You a churchgoer back home, Frances?
I might be if I left my flat.
Yeah, of course.
Probably will be after this.
Okay, this way. Let's go.
TEDDY: Oh, my God!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Ow, ow, ow! This is not normal!
I-I think it probably is.
[STRAINING] Shut up. It's not! Mnh!
Okay.
[HORNS HONKING]
[GROANING] I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry I said "shut up."
- That is okay.
- [BREATHING HEAVILY]
- That is what women in normal labor do.
- [HORNS HONKING]
- Oh, my God.
What is this traffic?!
Well, it looks like
the freeway is closed.
What?!
[BEEPING]
There is a multi-car pileup
that has shut down the freeway.
Wow, and half the city is
sucked in in fog.
Are we thinking maybe we
should've called an ambulance?!
- [SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE]
- [GROANS]
- [SEAT BELT CLICKS]
- What are you doing?
Where are you going?!
Stay here!
Where would I possibly go?!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
I don't want to have this baby
in your car!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Aah! [GROANING]
Yeah, we got a lot
of pissed-off people back here.
Come on.
WOMAN: What's going on here?
Doesn't look like it's letting up at all.
MAN: we've gotten lots of
calls about the situation...
Officer?
You want to get back in your car, Miss?
This is not safe.
Yes, I know. I will.
Uh, but, also, there is a big baby
trying to come out
of a small place in my car.
- So...
- You can back up.
...could you help us
get to the hospital, please?
- No.
- Back up.
Her father raped her mother?
And, apparently, Jo looks just like him.
And her mother...
wants nothing to do with her.
And her father...
I'll kill him.
Well [INHALES DEEPLY] he's already dead.
[SIGHS]
She's agreed to talk to Bailey
and take a leave of absence
a-and get some help.
[SIGHS]
I keep thinking about the day
she told me she was going to Pittsburgh.
She was laughing. She was excited.
And I said, "No." I said I was worried.
She said, "Alex, the worst thing
that could happen
is I find her,
and she's not happy about it.
Then I come home to you,
and at least I know.
At least I get to stop wondering."
[SIGHS]
I should've stopped her.
You couldn't have stopped her.
She's... She's Jo.
No, she's not. She's not Jo anymore.
She's a ghost.
I know. She needs help.
I tried.
She won't let me.
She needs more help
than you and I can give her.
♪
WOMAN ON P.A.: Dr. Jensen to Oncology.
Dr. Jensen to Oncology.
Nico, you have a new job.
Kari Donnelly. Her finger twitched.
It was probably just a muscle spasm,
but, uh, who knows?
I'd like you to keep an eye on her.
What? Do you want me
to babysit a quadriplegic?
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
[TELEPHONE RINGS IN DISTANCE]
I was gonna say
witness a potential miracle.
[SCOFFS]
Maybe it'll help.
Yeah? Help with what?
Help you not fail your fellowship.
I've been defending you,
but you're turning into someone
no one wants to work with.
So, go. Sit with my patient.
Who's on the cusp of a
life-changing medical breakthrough.
And try as hard as you can to care.
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
[TELEPHONE RINGING IN DISTANCE]
WOMAN ON P.A.: Wendy Bliss to Admitting.
Wendy Bliss to Admitting.
[CONVERSATIONS CONTINUE]
Hey.
Bailey said it was slammed in here,
- so I came to help, but where...
- The fog is so thick,
no ambulance can get through yet.
[SIGHS] We're just... waiting.
[SIGHS]
How you doing?
Um...
All right. Listen to me.
- You listening?
- Yes.
20 minutes east of here,
the fog is so thick,
no one can drive through.
But here, right outside,
it's sunny.
So...
So, I'm saying...
the sun is gonna shine again.
You just got to get...
20 minutes east of wherever you are.
[ELEVATOR BELL DINGS IN DISTANCE]
Yeah, you're right. That was bad.
- Horrible.
- I'm embarrassed.
Oh, my God. You should be. [CHUCKLES]
WOMAN ON P.A.: ...to Radiology.
Dr. Kelly to Radiology.
- [DOOR CREAKS]
- Uh, Luis.
- Hi.
- Hi, I'm Dr. Bailey.
And this is Dr. Fox.
- Hi.
- Hello.
We have some good news.
All right, Gabby's
test results came back,
and her cancer is only Stage 2.
That's good news?
Oh, absolutely.
Non-Hodgkin's lymphoma
is a very treatable cancer.
And when it's found early, like hers was,
the survival rate is quite high.
And she will require further treatment,
but I want to assure you
that my foundation
will cover all the costs.
Thank you.
[VOICE BREAKING] I just, uh...
my gordita has cancer.
What if something happens
before Gabby's mamá can get here?
Sir... I want you to look at me.
I am living with a more advanced version
of a far less treatable cancer right now.
And I'm here, I'm working,
and I am very much alive.
And so is Gabby.
And we're gonna work really hard
to keep her that way.
♪
WOMAN ON P.A.: Dr. Worden to Peds ICU.
Dr. Judy Worden to Peds ICU.
Hey, uh, uh, w...
wait a... wait a minute, everyone.
- What's going on here?
- Dr. Webber, don't.
No. W-W-Why are you in handcuffs?
Why is my star resident in handcuffs?
- Sir, I need you to step aside.
- DeLuca?
Look, I-I committed fraud, okay?
I'm sorry, all right?
I'm sorry, Dr. Webber.
♪
What the hell did he do?
BAILEY: He put little Ellis Grey's name
on another child's records.
I know. I'm sick over it, too.
[SIGHS] And we're needed in the pit.
♪
[SCOFFS]
- [SIREN WAILING, HORNS HONKING]
- Frances, I'm gonna set you down
beside an ambulance.
I want you to slowly open your eyes
and try to stay calm, okay?
All right, folks,
please stay with your car.
I'm Owen Hunt,
head of trauma at Grey-Sloan.
Oh, thank God. Truck driver's critical...
hypertensive with a rapid
and thready pulse,
decreased breath sounds on the left.
We got to move him now.
I'll come with you, and I'll help out,
but these two need a ride, too.
- No, we don't have room.
- Well, make room.
A kid's life depends on it. Let's move.
- Let's go.
- Okay, big step, big step.
Okay, go, go, go.
- [INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
- [SIRENS WAIL IN DISTANCE]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
MAGGIE: The GPS says
we're supposed to be going... east.
We're going north.
No, we don't need the GPS, all right?
- Just follow the trail.
- What trail?
This is just a mudslide
waiting to happen.
Will you just trust, please?
- Trust what?
- Me.
Trust the ground underneath your feet.
It's really hard to trust the road
when you can't see it.
Yeah, well, sometimes you got to
trust things you can't see.
All right, now we just want to take
one step at a time,
and then we'll just...
[THUD] Jackson!
- Jackson!
- [GROANS]
You fell into a river.
You could have broken your neck.
[SIGHING] It's a creek.
It's less than a foot deep. I'm fine.
You said to trust the road.
Ah, it... it's just
a little bit of water.
You said to trust you and come camping,
and now there's a child dying,
and there's nobody there
to operate on him.
Okay.
- Oh, you're mad at me now?
- No, I'm not even mad.
I just don't feel like
talking about this.
I want to focus,
just focus on getting the hell
out of these woods.
These beautiful, pristine, sacred woods
that you're just
so damn determined to hate.
I don't hate them.
It's just a stressful situation.
It doesn't have to be!
This could just be a muddy situation
that we both go through together!
But, no. You want to assign blame.
More specifically,
you want to assign blame to me
when all I did was ask you
to come explore something that I love.
I'm the one that's soaked.
Am I blaming you for that?
Kinda.
You're yelling at me.
Well, I don't want to talk!
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
[GROANS]
[SIREN WAILS]
TEDDY: You are some kinda
genius. I mean it.
I-I-I really think, in another life,
that you and I could be friends.
Well, then [SIGHS]
why don't we just decide
to be friends in this one?
I mean, I'm in Leo's life.
I'm not gonna let that change.
And we've basically been through
a police chase together.
I mean, think how
we could laugh about that
if we were friends.
Seriously, you would
just have to overcome
most of your disdain for me.
But I really think that
you could do that if you tried.
Well, I don't disdain you, Amelia.
Um, okay, I did. Last year.
But there was a whole brain tumor
that explained the things
that I didn't like.
Thank you.
Because, you know, I really think people
don't give that tumor
the credit it deserved.
[CHUCKLES]
[WAILING CONTINUES]
Are you still in love with Owen?
I mean...
maybe a little.
But I fall in love easily and quickly.
I mean, I could very well be in
love [CHUCKLING] with someone else
by the time your baby comes.
I'm a little in love
with this cop here right now.
Seriously. I'm very easily attracted.
You know, the last time
Owen and I broke up,
I walked in on him and Carina,
and I was more jealous of him
because I had a little crush on her,
which is [CHUCKLES] like, the reason
I masturbated for her in that study
which lead to my brain tumor
being diagnosed.
Owen and Carina?
Like, my O.B., Carina?
Ohhhhh, no.
[WAILING CONTINUES]
Aaaaaaaaah!
Oh, boy.
Oof.
Ohhhhhh, God!
[KEYS CLACKING]
[CLICKS, STATIC CRACKLES]
Meredith?
They took DeLuca.
I know! I couldn't go after
him because I'm stuck in here.
I need you to go to the police
and tell them it was all me.
I am not gonna tell a lie to the police.
It's not a lie! It was me.
I mean, sure, a few of you
followed my lead,
but Andrew had nothing to do with it.
His career won't recover from this.
You know who else won't recover?
Your children when
they watch their mother
get locked away.
Meredith, you could lose everything...
- your career, your family.
- I won't.
I'll hire a great lawyer, plead my case.
I'm a well-established,
award-winning surgeon.
This is my first offense.
I am not doing anything
until you're out of there,
and we think all of this through!
[MONITOR BEEPING RAPIDLY]
- Damn it, he's coding.
- MEREDITH: Start the decompression.
Got it.
Come on. Let's start decompression now!
[BEEPING CONTINUES]
[CLICKS, STATIC CRACKLES]
What can I do?
Call Hunt. Tell him we need him now!
[AIR HISSES]
[SIREN WAILING]
♪
That is a very large needle.
He has a tension pneumo.
I'm gonna need to decompress his chest.
You definitely want
to close your eyes for this.
Okay. Here we go.
- [AIR RUSHING]
- Oh! That is just demented.
- [CELLPHONE RINGS]
- Schmitt, get that.
It's clearing. We're out of the fog.
MAN: Hold on.
- [TIRES SCREECH]
- [ALL GRUNT]
Hey, Dr. Webber. It's Dr. Webber.
- Tell him we're close!
- How close?
- 7 minutes, uh...
- 20 minutes to extract the blood.
Uh, okay. We'll be at the hospital in 7.
[TIRES SCREECH]
♪
Come on, Mom. You can do this.
Come on.
[MONITOR BEEPING]
This is a depressing room
to be in, I know.
No, ma'am. You should keep at it.
I think we both know I shouldn't.
Mom.
Honey.
I think it's time to accept
the twitch for what it was...
a twitch.
The final spasm of a dying muscle.
It's awful. And I hate it.
But I love you and...
[GASPS] She just squeezed my hand!
Mom, Mom, you just...
you just squeezed my hand!
- No, I didn't.
- You did, too.
You... You squeezed my hand!
You did, I saw it!
I-I have to...
I'll get Link. Wait, Shepherd.
I'll get them all! Yeah!
[LAUGHING] Oh!
♪
[SIREN WAILING, HORN BLARES]
So, you're feeling better? Really?
Uh, can we save a life first
and talk after?
Deal.
[WAILING CONTINUES]
[BRAKES SQUEAL, SIREN CHIRPS]
- [RADIO CHATTER]
- All right, 40-something driver.
Left tension pneumo
decompressed in the field.
He's hypotensive and tachycardic.
He's bleeding in there somewhere.
Okay, trauma one.
- Frances, let's go.
- Who's Frances?
- Ohh!
- This is Frances.
She needs somewhere quiet
to donate blood.
Oh, oh! You're the golden blood lady!
- I suppose I am, yes.
- I can take you!
- Let me... Can I take her?
- Yes.
- Karev, you can take her.
- Hooray, more needles.
- [SIREN CHIRPS]
- AMELIA: Dr. Bailey!
Shepherd? What the hell?
TEDDY: Okay, open the door.
Okay. I need help.
- Okay. Okay.
- [BREATHING SHARPLY]
You dated my O.B.,
- and you didn't think to mention it?!
- What?
- I am so sorry.
- Oh, that's complex.
Listen, we didn't exactly date.
We were more just...
- Oh, God!
- Why are you in a police...
- Owen... Owen, she is in labor.
- Okay.
- Okay, oh... oh, my God. Okay, don't...
- Get your hands off of me.
Don't touch me. Don't touch me.
[MONITOR BEEPING RAPIDLY]
♪
Alex, we should...
No, I'm not stopping
till that blood arrives.
This kid deserves to live.
He deserves to build towers
of every building in this damn world
and play tee-ball and hug his parents.
His good, kind parents
who have always been there
and done everything for him.
So, no. No, I'm not stopping.
I'm not asking you to stop.
I'm asking you to
just switch off for a minute.
Just take a break.
You're not alone in here.
The hell I'm not.
You're gonna trade places with DeLuca
and go to jail.
And Jo... [PANTING]
Look, you're gonna disappear,
and Jo's already disappeared,
and I'm gonna be here all alone.
Well, you're not alone yet,
and you're getting tired,
so just let me help!
Let's go! Come on, switch.
One, two, three.
[BEEPING CONTINUES]
♪
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
I didn't ask you to change.
I'm asking you to expand.
- That's just a fancy word for change.
- [SIGHS]
I am a grown woman.
I know what I like and what I don't like.
Okay, Maggie. But do you, really?
I mean, you constantly talk about
how you had to race through
high school, college, med school.
Those are all formative years. You know?
You were buried in books
basically from birth.
You don't think it's possible
you missed out on some aspects of life
that you could come to love
with some encouragement?
Do you hear yourself?
Do you hear how patronizing that sounds?
[SIGHS LIGHTLY]
I don't think that we are in this mess
because I missed out
on my formative years
due to my genius.
I think that we are in this mess
because you missed out on the opportunity
to learn consequences
due to your privilege.
But your mom and her money
can't get us to our car
and help me save my dying patient,
so this is on you.
This is what consequences feel like.
You really think that?
That's what you think of me?
I'm saying...
maybe I missed out on summer camp,
- but you missed out on a summer job.
- What?
And filling out financial aid forms
and worrying if your family
could even afford college.
Work-study and student loans
and hoping that
you find a job after college
that can pay off your student loans.
Life stuff...
stuff that comes
from not being Mr. Monopoly.
[CHIRPING CONTINUES]
Mr. Monopoly?
- Wow.
- [SIGHS]
[SCOFFS]
So you just kinda don't have
any respect for me.
And you just kinda don't like me.
Maggie, I love you.
I know.
But you don't like me.
Not the way I am.
You want me to expand.
[CHIRPING CONTINUES]
[WIND RUSHING]
- Teddy, I'm sorry, really.
- [SCOFFS]
It honestly never even occurred to me.
It never occurred to you?! Ohh!
It never occurred to you to mention to me
that you slept with my O.B.?!
[CHUCKLES] Okay. Hello.
[GROANING]
For what it's worth,
the affair meant very little to me.
Okay.
Can you spread your legs for me?
Hmm.
Okay.
Ugh.
Okay, you're gonna feel a little pinch.
Just tell me when it's over.
And... it's over.
- That's it?
- [LAUGHING] That's it.
And what happens now?
And now you get...
Oh, well, now you get cookies
and you get juice.
[CHUCKLES]
What will I feel when my blood is gone?
Woozy, sick, empty?
How much extra or food might I need?
I, um... [LAUGHS]
Frances, you have about
10 units of blood in your body,
and you can live on about 6 units.
And I'm only taking two,
so you should feel just fine.
In fact, you should feel better than fine
because, as you sit here,
eating your cookie,
you are saving a little boy's life.
[CHUCKLES]
This has been
the single most terrifying day
of my life.
I heard that you don't like to travel.
A-Also, there was a pileup.
It was legitimately terrifying.
This morning, if you'd asked me
to list my fears of what might happen,
I would've made quite a long one.
But sitting there,
listening to vehicle after vehicle,
the crunching sounds, the blinding fog,
the screaming...
even I couldn't have imagined that.
And yet, here I am,
with a frightening stench of flop sweat.
[LAUGHS] But other than that,
unscathed, sipping juice.
[CHUCKLES]
There's something about walking
through your fears...
actually going through the worst thing
you could imagine happening to you...
that is oddly freeing.
♪
[CHUCKLES]
BAILEY: I... give them supervision.
I offer guidance.
I praise them.
I steer them on the right path
when they stumble,
like they were my own children.
And what do I get in return?
A big, fat felony covered
in bureaucratic mess.
Lap pads.
[LIQUID SUCTIONING]
Well, maybe DeLuca didn't understand
what he was doing.
DeLuca was number two in his class.
He understands.
Uh, the bleeding's coming
from the mesentery.
Got it. Right angle.
[MONITOR BEEPING]
I'm just saying that there could be
another explanation.
Um, I've been working a lot
with DeLuca lately,
and he is smart, talented,
and excellent bedside manner.
And his medical license is
as good as trash.
Not to mention, he put that
asylum-seeking family at risk
and jeopardized
every hospital employee's
insurance policy.
And I don't think he did it alone.
Hmm.
Meredith Grey's name was on that chart.
I think she participated
and DeLuca's covering for her.
♪
- Really? Hmm?
- Really.
You wouldn't know anything
about that, would you?
Um, let's run the bowel again,
check for other injuries.
[LIQUID SUCTIONING]
[CLEARS THROAT]
What do we, uh... Is it...
Is it somebody's birthday?
Are we singing, huh?
♪ Mi, mi, mi, mi, mi ♪
AMELIA: Tom, be quiet, please.
What?
Mom, you can do this.
You did it once... you can do it again.
I'm tired.
So...
pretend it's me.
Pretend you're fighting for me
instead of for yourself
because you have never once gotten tired
when you've been fighting for me.
Look.
♪
Oh, my God!
Did I do that? A-Am I doing that?!
Can... Can somebody tilt me down?
Kari, point to me.
Tom, I don't think
she can take direction.
♪
Oh, my God.
[GASPS]
I did that!
[LAUGHTER]
Oh!
I knew you could do it.
I bet you want me to sing now.
[LAUGHS]
You moved my finger.
You can sing whatever you want!
♪ Way down upon the Swanee River, fa... ♪
[TABLET BEEPS]
[LAUGHS]
♪
[MONITOR BEEPING RAPIDLY]
- Hey! Hey!
- [AIR RUSHING]
I'm here, I'm here, I'm here, I'm here!
- Let her through!
- Move out of the way!
Sorry! Sorry that it took so long.
We had to extract the blood,
process, and test it.
Okay. Okay.
♪
Just squeeze the bag to make it go.
I know, go faster. I get it.
Are we too late? Is there enough?
Come on, Gus. Come on. Come on.
Come on, come on!
- [MONITOR BEEPING RAPIDLY]
- Come on, come on! Come on.
♪
[MONITOR BEEPING RHYTHMICALLY]
Hey, we got a rhythm.
Yes!
- Yeah.
- We got a pulse.
I'll hang another unit of LR
and keep giving him fluids.
♪
Hey.
[GROANS]
Hey, buddy. Hey, it's Alex.
Remember me?
Now, your chest
is gonna feel really sore,
but that's normal.
You're not in your regular room
right now.
We had to bring you in here for a minute.
But it's like a medical spaceship.
It's pretty cool.
Where...
Where are my LEGO bricks?
[LAUGHS]
Let's go get them.
♪
[METAL CLANKS]
[WHEELS SQUEAKING LIGHTLY]
♪
Jo.
I'm not okay.
I know how to rise...
when I need to.
And I know how to take care
of other patients, but...
I'm not okay.
I love you, and I'm sorry.
It's okay. We'll figure it out.
We'll... We'll talk to Bailey.
Karev.
Can we talk?
It's about Meredith.
♪
[SCREAMING] God! Ow, ow, ow!
Something's wrong! What's wrong?!
Something's wrong! Ow! Nothing's wrong.
Nothing is wrong, Dr. Altman.
You're crowning.
- ! Oh, God!
- What? Already?
Sometimes mothers
with geriatric pregnancies
- tend to have...
- Did you just say "geriatric"?!
I-It's just the term.
I know the term!
I'm just saying,
try not to add to my pain!
What you're feeling right now
is called the ring of fire.
[GROANS] Do I keep pushing?
No. You wait until the next contraction.
[GROANING] Oh, God, come on!
If you like to masturbate,
it can alleviate the...
- What?!
- No!
Okay. Then... just wait.
Oh, God, come on.
- Oh, my God, ow!
- Teddy.
- Ow, ow, ow, ow!
Our daughter is coming out now.
I know this is supposed to be...
a really beautiful moment,
but it hurts like a mother!
Oh, my God!
I got to see this. I got...
- No, no way.
- Whoa, whoa.
Whatever's happening down there
is not pretty.
- [CHUCKLING] Okay.
- [GROANING]
Listen, Teddy, I have seen men
ripped limb from limb.
I know, but you will not see
the war between my legs.
You'll thank me later. No more PTSD.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Okay, here's another one. [SCREAMING] Ow!
- Teddy, push, push, push, push, push!
- Oh, my God!
- You got this, Major.
Push, push, push, push, push, push!
[GROANING]
- [INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
- [SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE]
Hey.
I have had a day from hell.
I miss you.
I know I can be annoying.
I spent the day with a woman
who imagines the worst.
And she was annoying.
Right up until the part
where she was a hero.
Levi, I...
I get that my feelings can be big
and my fears can be big,
and I can be annoying.
But I am also a pretty great guy.
I care about the world.
I sing with people who are scared,
and I help deliver blood
to dying children,
and I care.
And if you love me,
I deserve better than
what you've been giving me.
I know you do.
[REGINA PRICE'S
"HANGING ON THE EDGE" PLAYS]
[SIGHS] And I don't think
you're annoying.
I just...
[SIGHING] I don't know.
- ♪ It's all about feeling ♪
- I just get... jealous.
- ♪ And that's what I'm feeling ♪
- J... [SCOFFS]
Jealous of what?
- ♪ It starts to well up ♪
- Since my patient died,
since I... killed him...
- ♪ But I'm tired of what I
already know ♪ - [INHALES DEEPLY]
- ...the only thing I feel is angry.
- ♪ Oooo, the hours ♪
I just witnessed
a medical miracle in there.
And people are crying
and... and laughing...
- ...and still, all I feel is this...
- ♪ If I don't go now... ♪
- ...anger.
- ♪ I'll never make it out ♪
- I don't know how to do what you do...
- ♪ Hanging on the edge ♪
...but I want to.
♪ I think I'm gonna let go ♪
Well, I can help with that.
♪ Hanging on the edge ♪
- ♪ Chasing what I don't know ♪
- MAGGIE: Oh, oh.
The donor arrived!
- Gus got his transfusion! Oh, my...
- ♪ Chasing what I don't know ♪
- Oh, this is good.
- ♪ Find myself again ♪
[GEARSHIFT CLICKS]
What... What is... What is this?
What is going on?
It's fog, Maggie.
We have it in the city, too.
- I know what fog is.
- ♪ Ooooo, ooo ♪
But this... this is...
We can't drive in this.
- Yeah, that's...
- [EMERGENCY BRAKE CLACKS]
...why I stopped the car.
- [SIGHS]
- ♪ Starting to trust what I cannot see ♪
- [CLICKS]
- I'm gonna check out the situation.
You can't see anything.
[CLICKS]
That's why I've got a flashlight.
- Got a little bit of faith.
- [SEAT BELT CLICKS]
You can stay here
and be safe and sound...
...and knowing exactly
at's going to happen
for the next 10 minutes, all right?
♪ Oooo, the hours ♪
[CAR DOOR CLOSES]
- Patronizing.
- ♪ Years hanging on ♪
♪ If I don't go now,
I'll never make it out ♪
[SCREAMS]
Good!
So, her head is halfway out.
Just one more gentle push
on the next contraction.
- I have to push now.
- You wait or you tear.
- 30 seconds. Breathe.
- ♪ I think I'm gonna let go ♪
But it hurts. I can't keep doing this.
Please tell me something to distract me.
[BREATHES DEEPLY] Okay.
♪ Hanging on the edge ♪
I'm in love with you...
...and I've been in love with
you since the day I met you.
- [CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
- ♪ Chasing what I don't know ♪
[SIGHS] And I didn't understand
- that I was allowed to be happy.
- ♪ Find myself again ♪
- I was afraid.
- ♪ Ooooo ♪
I was afraid that
the way that I feel around you
- was... unsafe...
- ♪ Where it all begins ♪
...unsafe because it feels so good.
You make me feel so good
that I would sabotage it...
...before life would come in
and do it for me.
- But I get that now.
- ♪ Ooo, oooo, ooo, oooo ♪
And I'm done with that now.
[SIGHS]
- Teddy...
- ♪ Hanging on the edge ♪
- [GROANS]
- ...I want to spend the rest of my life
proving to you
that I'm worthy of your love.
- ♪ Ooo, oooo ♪
- If you'll let me.
♪ Ooo, oooo ♪
- Another one's coming.
Here it is, it's coming! It's coming!
- Push! Push, push, push! Push, push!
- [SCREAMS]
- Oh, my God!
- ♪ Ooooo, ooo ♪
DeLuca was not involved.
He had no prior knowledge.
I will go on record.
I take full responsibility
for my behavior.
[DOOR CREAKS LIGHTLY]
No, no, no, no. You two have to wait.
You need to hear
what we have to say, okay?
Richard, not now.
Y-Y-Yes, now.
- It was me.
- No, it wasn't.
I forged the name on Gabby's paperwork.
- No, no, no.
- Yeah.
It was not... It was not. It was me.
- No, it was me. I forged it.
- It was me. Alex, stop that!
No! It was not... It was me!
Are all of you kidding me right now?
This is not a game!
This is not an... an LVAD wire,
and you're not interns.
This is criminal behavior.
So stop this nonsense.
Bailey, it was all of us.
Meredith may have done it,
but I knew about it, and I didn't report.
Same. It was all of us.
The only person it wasn't
was Andrew DeLuca.
- Yeah.
- Richard. You got to be kidding me.
You are a part of this?!
[SIGHS]
Look, I'm sorry, Catherine.
I know we got it wrong.
It was an emotional decision
and a bad one.
But we just couldn't see
putting that father...
that family... through any more of this.
Bailey, it was all of us.
What do you want to do?
What do I want to do? W... I-I'm... I...
[SIGHS]
My God.
I mean, what... what can I do?
You're fired.
What?
Who's fired?
All three of you.
You're all fired!
♪
Catherine.
[CLICKS TONGUE] Oh, my God.
[SIGHS]
[INSECTS CHIRPING]
[SLEEPING AT LAST'S
"BREATHE AGAIN" PLAYS]
♪ Car is parked, bags are packed ♪
♪ But what kind of heart
doesn't look back ♪
♪ At the comfortable glow
from the porch ♪
♪ The one I will still call yours? ♪
- ♪ All those words came undone ♪
- [CRYING]
Thank you.
♪ And now I'm not the only one ♪
- [SCREAMS]
- Push, push, push, push! Push, push!
Yeah!
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
- ♪ Facing the ghosts that decide ♪
- ♪ If the fire inside ♪
- [BABY CRIES]
Got it.
♪ Still burns ♪
♪ All I have, all I need ♪
- Oh, lookit.
- Oh, my God!
♪ He's the air I would kill to breathe ♪
- Hey. Hey.
- ♪ Holds my love... ♪
- [BABY COUGHS, CRYING]
- I know.
♪ ...in his hands ♪
- Yeah.
- ♪ Still, I'm searching for something ♪
What's her name?
- Allison.
♪
- ♪ Out of breath, I am left ♪
- [CRYING]
♪ Hoping someday I'll breathe again ♪
♪
♪ I'll breathe again ♪
Hm.
♪
♪ I'll breathe again ♪
How long will you be gone?
Oh, just a little while.
But where are you going?
Well...
I have to go take care
of something very important.
Okay? But I'll be back.
- All right?
- Okay.
And Auntie Amelia will be here
and Auntie Maggie and Uncle Alex.
♪ Comes in full view ♪
♪ Hang my head, break my heart ♪
♪ Built from all I have torn apart ♪
There you go.
♪ And my burden to bear ♪
♪ Is a love I can't carry anymore ♪
♪
- ♪ All I have ♪
- You are... pretty wonderful.
♪ All I need ♪
- ♪ He's the air I would kill to
breathe ♪ - I hear a "but" coming.
- But I, um...
- ♪ Holds my love in his hands ♪
...jumped in to you really fast.
On the heels of Owen, and, um...
...the life that I
thought I was building.
- I'm a rebound.
- ♪ Out of breath ♪
You definitely were.
♪ I am left hoping someday
I'll breathe again ♪
I don't know if you still are.
- ♪ Oh, it hurts to be here ♪
- [SIGHS]
So, you're saying...?
I'm saying I'm...
- ♪ I only wanted love from you ♪
- ...open to possibilities.
And that could include you.
- ♪ Yeah, it hurts to be here ♪
- If you don't need me to decide anything
too permanent right now.
♪ What am I gonna do? ♪
I, um...
I need time...
to figure out who I am outside of Owen.
♪ I'll breathe again ♪
Okay.
♪
♪ I'll breathe again ♪
VADA: ...go tree climbing, Thomas J.?
LEVI: [CRIES] Oh. His face hurts.
And where is his glasses?
He can't see without his glasses.
MYRNA: I heard "My Girl" playing.
- Made you some soup.
- [LAUGHS]
- Ohh!
- Oh, tough week?
- Aww.
- Thanks, Mom.
Yeah. Who's your friend?
This is Nico.
- Hi, Nico.
- Hi.
He's actually my boyfriend.
[TV PLAYS INDISTINCTLY]
And he's the one
who's had the tough week.
W-We'll talk more later then.
- Yes.
- All right, then.
Nico, do you like chicken noodle soup?
Yes, ma'am.
Well, then, this is for you.
Oh! Thank you so much.
All right. You enjoy.
Okay.
MAN ON TELEVISION: You all right?
[BEACON'S "DON'T GO LOOKING" PLAYS]
[SIGHS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
♪
You're amazing.
[SIGHS]
[SNIFFLES]
[BREATHES DEEPLY]
♪
MEREDITH: When there's no clear path...
all we can do is put one foot
in front of the other.
♪
[DOOR CREAKS LIGHTLY]
Dr. Karev, are you ready?
♪ So, don't you go looking... ♪
- Love you.
- I love you, too.
♪ ...for me ♪
♪
♪ When I'm exactly where I should be ♪
She'll be okay.
She'll need medication and therapy,
but she will be okay.
How do you know?
She's depressed.
It's scary and it's hard,
but it's treatable.
[SIGHS HEAVILY]
Bailey, am I really fired?
Alex Karev.
♪ When it's in front of me ♪
I hate it more than you do.
[SIGHS]
[DOOR BUZZES]
All we can do is the next right thing.
♪
And then the next.
[BUZZER]
♪
This was so stupid.
- [CHUCKLING] Well...
- [DOOR THUMPS SHUT IN DISTANCE]
Were you expecting a thank you?
Your career won't survive this.
You're going to lose your license.
Meredith, what was I supposed to do? Huh?
They called me into a room
and asked me for details.
Was I supposed to turn you in?
Would that have been more noble somehow?
- Well, if we're gonna be together...
- ♪ In chemicals and waterfalls too deep ♪
...you need to develop some instincts
for self-preservation.
All I'm saying is,
let me clean up my own messes
and live in my own truth.
Because what I did was wrong.
But what I was trying to remedy
was so much more wrong.
- ♪ I caught you now, trying to sleep ♪
- And I stand by that.
You think a judge will buy that?
I don't know.
Either way, I have to turn myself in
- and get you out of here.
- ♪ If I'm drowning... ♪
Meredith, don't do that.
Andrew, as stupid as this was...
- ♪ ...you're the air I want to breathe ♪
- [SIGHS]
...and as much as this terrifies me...
I love you, too.
♪ And I'm waiting on you to see ♪
[RECEIVER CLICKS IN CRADLE]
♪
♪ That you know where to find me ♪
[DOOR BUZZES]
♪ Me, me ♪
♪ And you know where to find me ♪
[CLOSING DOOR ECHOES]
[VOCALIZING]
In the darkness, in the fog,
all we can do is feel our way through.
♪
Jackson!
And try to trust that somehow
we will come out on the other side.
- ♪ So, don't you go looking... ♪
- Jackson!
♪ ...for me ♪
[PANTING] Jackson!