Ask most surgeons why
they became surgeons
and they usually tell
you the same thing:
It was for the high. The rush.
The thrill that comes
from cutting someone open
and saving their life.
For me, it was different.
Take care of yourself.
Maybe because I grew up
in a house with four sisters.
No, definitely because
I grew up in a house
with four sisters.
Because it was the quiet
that drew me to surgery.
- How you doing?
- Fine.
- Did Meredith say something
to you?
- She mentioned you're down
about the merger,
lack of a Cardio God.
Your wife is dead, as soon
as her liver grows back.
Be glad she did. That's
why I put you on my service.
You need a God.
Neuro God, right here.
Godly? Your entire day consists
of putting shunts in people.
- Today, temporal lobectomy.
- Hmm.
Our schedule for months now.
Hospitals across the country
have reported
substantial savings...
- How bad is it today?
- The chief's implementing
a computer model for scheduling
our surgeries from now on.
Something about
efficiency and progress.
To make sure this was the right
decision, I have enlisted one of our own
to do a trial run for the
last month. Dr. Sloan?
I know what you're all
thinking. "It's a machine.
It doesn't know me,
doesn't know what I like."
But after using this new
system for the past month,
I gotta say, people,
I'm a convert.
This computer knows
me better than I know me.
Chief, this thing's rearranged
my schedule for the week.
I mean, haven't we had
enough change here already?
Change is good, everyone.
Embrace it.
You two need to stop
bickering. It's unattractive.
The operating room is
a quiet place. Peaceful.
It has to be in order
for us to stay alert,
anticipate complications.
- Your ass is in my way.
- I was in the OR all night
sewing a hang glider's
intestines together.
- I'm kinda sore.
- I kinda don't care.
Move.
Hey. I just got a call
from Swender's office.
Izzie has an IL-2
treatment this week
that she hasn't
called back to confirm.
- And?
- And...
she's your wife. Who could die.
She'll show up. She's a crappy
wife, but she's not an idiot.
OK, well, it's Thursday
at 10:00. So you know.
Don't worry, being
ditched by cancer wife
won't change my mind.
You're still a douche.
When you stand in the OR,
your patient open on the table,
all the world's noise, all the
worry that it brings, disappears.
Dr. Shepherd?
Isaac, if you don't stop
calling me Dr. Shepherd,
- I'm gonna have to cut you off.
- Right, forgot. Derek.
- Thanks.
- I have the scans.
- I didn't order any.
- They're for consult.
- But I can come back
if you're busy.
- No, it's OK.
A calm settles over you...
time passing without thought.
For that moment, you
feel completely at peace.
It's a tumor in the spinal cord.
Possibly a hemangioblastoma.
- You've seen them before?
- Not this big.
You see how the tumor's
worked its way up the spine?
- It's taken over
the blood supply.
- Hmm.
Perfect tumor. Do you know
if the patient has leg function?
- Yes.
- Incredible.
He shouldn't be walking,
should be paralyzed. Dead.
You'd have to operate
quickly to take the tumor out?
I'd love to operate
on this. But no.
You'd have to cut the
cord, paralyze the patient,
to kill the tumor. Who's
the doctor on this one?
- You.
- I'm sorry?
These are my scans.
The tumor's mine.
I'd like you to take it out.
I'd like you to try.
One doctor said it was bad
circulation, a pinched nerve.
When the pain started
to interfere with work,
I decided to run
an MRI on myself.
Isaac, had I known
this was your scan,
- I wouldn't...
- I have been to every doctor,
Derek.
Every time, it's the same thing.
They look at the tumor and
they're defeated. But not you.
You were inspired.
That's why I know I was
right to come and work here.
- I needed to meet you.
- You got a job here to meet me?
I have researched every
neurosurgeon in this country.
I know their statistics, I know
who wins the most prizes.
But I also know... who
takes the most risks.
That's you.
Isaac, I know you believe
I can take this tumor out.
I wish I could. But
this surgery will kill you.
Take the scans, look them over.
But stop your mind before
the part where it gets to "No".
Think "yes," yes?
Shepherd, I've been paging
you. Shunt patient, OR Two.
Screw the shunt,
let's operate on that.
You know what
this is about, right?
You're no longer
Daddy's favorite,
so you've gone in search of a
crazy-ass tumor to get his love back.
Actually, it's about my patient.
Haven't made up my
mind yet. I'm just looking.
- Isaac has a cord tumor?
- It's awesome, look.
Awesome in a bad way.
It's eaten five
levels of his spine.
Wait, you're not seriously
considering trying to take it out?
Of course he is! He's Shepherd.
It's a bad case of
telephone, right?
Isaac's got a bone spur
or herniated disc not a...
He diagnosed an osteosarcoma
case for me a month ago.
I thought it was a shadow,
but it was a tiny
lesion on an x-ray.
That says more about
you than it does him.
I'm sorry. Do you even
know who Isaac is?
- No idea.
- What's everyone...?
A spinal tumor?
I read about a case at Mayo
where the surgery took 17 hours.
The head surgeon had
four rotating assistants,
one of whom just
administered fluids.
You know what, don't try to
Lexopedia your way on this.
This is my tumor.
What happened to
the patient at Mayo?
He died. That's why
it only took 17 hours.
Isaac has an inoperable tumor?
- It's Isaac's tumor?
- OK, yeah, boo-hoo. OK?
- Who says it's inoperable?
- Cristina.
Come on, it's all
the way up to T2.
You need three
or four assistants...
Why aren't you all
at your surgeries?
Go, get to your ORs.
Don't screw with my
schedule on day one.
- I haven't made a decision.
- No rush. I'm a patient man.
Everyone said you'd found
the great white of tumors,
but I just had to
see it for myself.
And now that you have?
You want my fellow
attending answer
or my fellow surgeon answer?
Fellow surgeon.
This tumor is dangerous,
complicated, smart, beautiful.
This tumor is the reason I got
into medicine in the first place.
To successfully take out this
tumor would be an achievement
you could hang your hat
on for the rest of your career.
You could retire on this tumor.
I wouldn't go
near it. It's a beast.
It's a malpractice
suit waiting to happen.
Even if we could get
his insurance to cover it.
Did I mention he
was an employee?
Our pro bono budget can't
cover high-risk surgeries
for every employee.
- We're not a charity.
- What happened to you?
- Excuse me?
- There was a time
you'd have convinced
me to do this.
Now, your first instinct is no?
- What happened to you?
- You came to me
as chief of surgery,
and I said no.
As for my medical
opinion, it is still no.
There is such a thing
as an inoperable tumor.
- What if it's not? I get in there...
- There is no way!
Anything other than cutting
the cord would kill this man!
How many times
you want me to say it?
You're not operating
on an inoperable tumor!
It's a tough job, Derek.
You sure you still want it?
So what did you do?
I scheduled the surgery.
I'm taking out the tumor.
Microsurgery is about precision.
The microscope changes
perspective radically.
Hand-eye coordination
can be learned,
but right now, I need naturals.
Each one of you will get
a chance to guide this pen
through the hole in the cup,
making a mark closest
to the president's nose
and doesn't hit the side
of the cup gets to scrub in.
Who wants to go first?
Take your time.
Oh, wow.
- Do-over?
- No do-overs.
- Way to go, Two.
- - Concentrate, take your time.
Next. Here you go.
Just take your time,
we've got nothing but time.
No, next. Somebody,
please. Well off the mark.
How'd you get into this program?
Mr. Confident.
Next. Next. Next. Next.
Next. Disappointed.
So disappointed.
Ooh... Here we go.
Nicely done.
Somebody improves
on that, I'll be out of a job.
Well, guess you might
need to retire then.
OK.
Dr. Avery, you'll
be scrubbing in.
I'll check and see what
they have available.
Word on the OR floor is
that you've gone rogue.
I'm doing a surgery
I fully believe in.
To piss off the chief.
When did Richard
become your BFF?
He's not my BFF. He's the chief.
For now.
You going rogue?
I'm doing a
surgery I believe in.
Against the chief's
orders. He'll freak.
There's a computer schedule
saying I'm doing craniotomies all day.
- He is not gonna find out.
- No. Shh. Don't say any more.
'Cause me, the chief, secrets...
Hey, I think it is bad-ass.
Come on, let's go.
Should I be offended?
I've been trying to come
up with a good reason
why you paged every
resident to the skills lab but me,
me, your sister.
- Your sister, Derek.
- You're on my service.
Little Grey, I didn't page you
because I have
another job for you.
You gave me the idea, actually.
I need somebody in the OR
whose gonna remind
me to take breaks.
Bend my legs, to drink water.
I will be your
patient, essentially.
- You want me to be your doctor?
- If Dr. Sloan's OK with you
giving up his
service, of course.
You love me.
This is a once in
a lifetime tumor.
Go get your rogue on.
You're nervous about
being in there that long?
- Me, too.
- What do you have
to be nervous about?
Shepherd didn't
even let you compete.
No, that's because he needs me
to maintain his care
while we're in there.
- I'm his doctor, basically.
- Wow.
So you fell for that.
It sounds... sounds
more like you're his bitch.
What?
No, I'm... That is... I'm not...
You're gonna need to
take a break eventually.
And you're gonna
need to stretch.
You're gonna need to pee.
And when you do, I'll
be there to take over.
Yeah, I don't take breaks.
You seriously think you're
gonna last all day in there?
I've done it before. Yeah.
But that's because
I know to stop
taking fluids before a long
surgery. Have fun playing nurse.
It sounds neat.
I don't know. I think
Izzie had it right.
Get fired, run away, die.
Mer, I'll call you back.
- Is that what I think it is?
- What? No. No, no.
No. No!
Gimme...
- A diaper?
- It's for the surgery.
Please don't tell
anybody about this.
Genius. You never
have to leave the OR,
you can hydrate all you want.
You're mocking
me. Fine. Whatever.
It's not like I
was gonna use it.
Of course you are.
This is the definition
of hardcore.
You're like an astronaut.
This is surgery, NASA-style.
Put it on. Right now.
I'll guard the door.
Anybody opens their
mouth and they're fired.
You, too.
Dr. Shepherd, I was just
describing our new schedule
to some of our board
members. This must be...
Mrs. Taylor. She's
undergoing a craniotomy.
It's Mr. Taylor, chief.
We're still working
out a few kinks, clearly.
We should go. Keep the trains
running on time. Nice meeting you all.
- Mm-hmm.
Isaac, if I get in there and it
looks too dangerous to remove,
the responsible thing
is to close you back up.
No, don't close me up.
If you get in, if it's too
complicated, cut the cord.
Paralyze me if you must.
I survived a war.
Did you know that?
I survived a war where they
put bodies into mass graves
where there's once a playground.
I survived the
death of my family,
my parents, my
brothers and sisters.
Then I survived the
death of my wife and child
when they starved to
death in a refugee camp.
I survived the
loss of my country,
of hearing my
mother tongue spoken,
of knowing what it feels like
to have a place to call home.
I survived. And I will
survive the loss of my legs.
If I have to, I'll survive it.
OK?
- But, Derek...
- Yes?
There is always a way.
When things look like
there's no way, there's a way.
To do the impossible.
To survive the unsurvivable.
There's always a way.
And you... You and I
have this in common.
We're inspired.
In the face of the
impossible, we're inspired.
So if I can offer
one piece of advice
to the world's foremost
neuro-surgeon...
today, if you become frightened,
instead become inspired.
Mmm? OK, I'm ready now.
Put me to sleep.
One hour, 13 minutes
on the surgical clock.
The dura's opened.
Let's get our first
look at the tumor.
Wow. That's, um...
Wow.
The vessels are more
intricate than the MRI showed.
There's no way to get to the
tumor out without rupturing one
- and killing the cord.
- So what do we do?
I think if we start at
T-2, I could avoid hitting
the feeding vessels, so
maybe I should go in lower.
OK, there's less
vascularity around T7,
so that does seem better, no?
It does seem better.
And he'd only get function
loss below the chest.
I run the risk of rupturing
the anterior spinal artery there.
Probably. The
tumor tapers off there.
Higher is better maybe?
Either way I risk sending him
into hemodynamic collapse...
- He's not talking to us, is he?
- Not at all.
T2 shows less
potential for bleeding,
at T3 the vessels...
increased.
- I'm sorry about the contest.
- Who told you about that?
No one. Well, I overheard
people talking in the pit.
- It sounded hard.
- It wasn't hard.
It was a moment of...
You know what? We
don't have to discuss it.
Watching Lexie in a diaper
is punishment enough.
What? Lexie is wearing what?
Well, that... that is a
reason you should be glad
you're not down there.
No, that is the reason I
want to be down there.
- What?
- Lexie gets to pee in a diaper,
- and I don't.
- You want to pee in a diaper?
Oh, God. No. I want to
have to pee in a diaper.
To be in a surgery
so difficult and so long
that my only option is to
put on a diaper and pee in it.
Are they just gonna let him
stare at that thing all day?
He hasn't made a single cut.
If I clip the draining veins
without getting the feeders,
they'll burst...
Dr. Shepherd, I
really think it's time
for you to take a break.
It's been over eight hours.
I could go into the tumor,
here, but I might cut the artery.
Dr. Shepherd.
Dude, if you need
a break, take one.
I don't need one. I'm hardcore.
- Are you wearing a diaper?
- Shut up.
At least bend your legs.
You can't bring
yourself to use it.
Shut up! Shut the hell up!
I don't need a break.
If you do, take one.
Either of you open your mouths
again, you're out of the OR.
Bathroom break!
- Um, Dr. Shepherd?
- What?
OK. I'm sure this is a
completely authorized surgery,
but I thought you
might like to know
that the chief is scheduled
to do a surgery across
the hall in OR 3 shortly.
So if you're planning on
doing something, anything,
you might want to do it soon.
Thank you, Dr. Bailey.
Stevens. Izzie Stevens.
I know she's not at home.
You have to try her cell.
Fine, just... No.
Tomorrow at 10:00. Don't
cancel it. She'll be there.
What?
You missed the
contest this morning.
- The one you tanked?
- Whatever.
Shepherd has
assigned us to round
on his cancelled craniotomies.
And, as much as I'd rather watch
his super-secret
surgery from the gallery,
I can handle it myself
if you wanna, you know,
deal with your Izzie stuff.
I respected you more when
you called her cancer wife.
- At least it was honest.
- I'm trying to be human.
You think if I'm not there
you might get to do some
big bad neuro and tell
Shepherd you did it solo.
Which, by the way,
makes you the douche.
You know what? I tried. Go
ahead, throw away your marriage.
- I will be rounding.
- I'll be rounding.
This is why you don't go rogue.
Look at him.
He's cracked.
I coulda told you this
was gonna happen.
Don't be smug. This is one
of our people's lives at stake.
This is so depressing.
Ten hours staring into a spine,
he can't figure out what to do.
What did you just say?
What? No, I didn't... Did I...?
Robbins!
Dr. Shepherd.
Dr. Shepherd, am I to understand
that you cancelled
your surgeries today
to operate on a
spinal cord tumor?
Dr. Shepherd!
The rate of infection
for this patient
is increasing every
second you keep him open,
not to mention the thousands
of dollars you're wasting
standing here doing nothing.
So I am demanding that
you close this man up.
Close him up and
relinquish the OR.
Right now, Derek.
OK.
That's it. Let's close him up.
No way of taking it out
without risking your life.
And to cut the cord,
at this point, I
just won't do it.
You're still walking, Isaac.
Let's reassess in a few months.
I understand. You worked
hard today. You're tired.
- I'm sorry.
- You'll try again tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
No, I can't try again.
The tumor is inoperable.
I can't fix this.
Go home. Sleep on it.
We'll talk more tomorrow.
- I don't understand.
- There's nothing to understand.
I stood there for
ten hours, staring.
In the OR? You stood for
ten hours and did nothing?
Yeah. OK. Let's
talk about you now.
- How was your day?
- My day?
Oh, my day was...
You know, I slept and I
ate an entire box of cereal.
I left three
voicemails for Izzie.
I'm sure she won't
return any of them.
I started and gave up on
Anna Karenina for the 15th time.
- You want to talk
about the tumor.
- I do.
Admit it, I'm a surgery junkie.
It was more vascular
than the MRI showed.
But you were able to
do the decompression?
- Yes.
- But you weren't able to find
- a plane to dissect?
- No plane, nothing.
It was just...
- No path. Nothing distinct.
- Why?
Because it was just... It...
You know what?
What are you doing?
Just watch and learn.
OK.
The tumor... is here.
Now you've completely
lost your mind.
T7 goes all the way up to T2.
You're drawing on the wall!
I opened the posterior
column, it's chaos.
I didn't know what vessel
was connected to the tumor
or to the cord.
So what I did was...
Start here and the anterior
spinal artery could rupture...
cord could die.
Here, you risk catching
the radicular artery
under the tumor, cord dies.
But why not cut
the draining veins,
at the top, expose the arteries.
The draining
veins are very thin.
You slip up, they burst. He
leaves my OR a quadriplegic.
- I might as well cut the cord.
- Which you didn't do.
- No.
- Even though Isaac said
you could.
You knew it would save his life.
He still has
function in his legs.
No, but what I mean is
you didn't cut the cord.
You stood in the
OR for ten hours.
You knew the chief
would stop you.
Anybody else would
have. And you didn't.
So there must be a reason why.
This patient understands
what cutting the cord means?
The loss of function in both
legs, and possibly more?
We have to cut the
cord to kill the tumor.
- There's no other way.
- OK.
That'll only take an hour
or two. You can have OR 1.
Hunt needs it right after,
so you'll have enough time.
- Thank you.
- Good luck.
- We're not cutting the cord.
- We're not?
Mm-mm. The mistake I made
yesterday was that I wanted a plan.
There can be no plan. I just
have to pick a point and cut.
But what you said yesterday,
if you cut an artery
or hit the cord...
Isaac wants us to take the risk.
He wants a cure.
And it's our job to try.
See you in the OR.
This is bad. This
is really, really bad.
Are you kidding? No one at
Mercy West was this bad-ass.
This isn't bad-ass! This is...
You saw him yesterday.
He was spinning
himself in circles,
mumbling like some crazy
psych patient. And he was mean.
Well, he's your psych patient
now. Deal with it, diaper genie.
Hey, I wore a diaper yesterday,
yes. And I will wear one today.
If it helps get Dr. Shepherd
through this surgery,
I will wear a diaper.
My diaper is awesome.
My diaper is hardcore.
You wish you had the
balls to wear my diaper.
I'm gonna wear it, and
I'm gonna wear it with pride.
And if I have to
pee in it, oh, I'll pee.
Because I am a
surgeon. This is America.
And I will do what
needs to be done.
So you can kiss my
hardcore diaper-wearing ass.
You woke me from a
nap. This better be good.
Napping during the day?
That's good. You'll need the rest.
A redo retroperitoneal sarcoma?
- That's like a 12-hour surgery.
- Fifteen, if things get ugly.
Go! Gear up!
- Ah! Dr. Hunt. I need a favor.
- Yeah?
Cristina...
- No. No!
- Shepherd needs the OR.
I put on a diaper.
OK. I've gotten the plane.
Ready to make our first cut.
I heard you needed some support.
You need people to talk
to. Experienced surgeons.
You can't say no
because I'm in charge,
and this is what
I'm prescribing.
Thank you, Dr. Grey. OK.
Let's start.
Making the first cut.
- What, did you paralyze him?
- No.
One vessel down.
Settle in. We have
many more to go.
I still hear some wheezing.
Let's start you on another
breathing treatment.
Dr. Karev, can I
see you for a minute?
I'm a little busy.
Dr. Karev, it's important.
You need to go. It's past ten.
You're checking your
watch every five seconds.
You're distracted.
- Just go, I'll finish up here.
- Shut the hell up.
Alex, come here.
You don't know me. Why are
you all up in my face about this?
Because there's a girl sitting
down there on the third floor
waiting for her guy.
She doesn't want to see me, OK?
She bailed. She didn't even
tell me to my face. She left a note.
So stop acting like you
know anything about it
and let me get back to my job!
- OK?
- If you're sure about that,
then fine.
Don't go. But you better
be 100 percent sure
she's not hoping you show up.
Because right now, you
are making a choice. You.
Not her.
So you better be
at peace with that.
I've cleared a path at T-5.
If I continue
along this plane...
MEP losing amplitude.
What just happened?
Vessel burst, might
be connected...
- If there's not enough blood...
- I could've paralyzed
a patient.
Suction, please. Suction.
- Oh, no.
- What? Cristina, what is it?
Easy. Careful!
- More suction.
- Too much blood.
- We're losing him.
- I should've cut the cord.
- This is too risky.
- Wait, it's back. Amplitude's up.
The cord didn't stroke out?
You didn't paralyze him?
Vessel was
connected to the tumor.
We're OK.
- Nice work, Derek.
- Thanks.
- Dr. Shepherd?
- Take off my mask.
- What?
Take off my mask!
Get in there. Take a
breath and get back in there.
- You can do this.
- You really should
drink something.
- I'm fine.
- You're not fine.
You're dehydrated and
stressed. Drink something.
- I said I'm fine.
- Drink the water.
I said drink it!
- Dr. Hunt?
- Chief.
- Shouldn't you be in OR 1?
- Yes, actually,
but I swapped with Torres. She
has an emergency laparotomy.
Dr. Torres is doing
a laparotomy?
What am I doing?
What? I just heard my name.
- Chief...
- He didn't cut the cord.
Bailey'll stop him at the door.
She's in the OR with Shepherd.
Then who's at the
door? Oh, my God.
- No. Whoa...
- Move.
- No.
- Dr. Robbins.
I said no.
Dr. Shepherd is operating inside
a man's spinal cord right now.
Even the most minor disturbance
could cause him to make
a mistake on that patient.
A patient who works here
and whose life I would like
to see Dr. Shepherd save.
So no. You don't get to
go in there and be a bully.
Not today, chief.
Not on my watch.
OK, I totally thought that
was gonna end different.
Yeah, more like that.
Dr. Bailey, care to fill us in?
No, I would not.
Because anything outside
of this OR is not your concern.
Your only concern
is this patient.
Now, keep going.
- Damn it.
- What is it?
I can't tell which one of
these vessels feeds the cord
and which one feeds the tumor.
- I have to do a blind cut.
- Like a trip wire?
I cut the wrong one, the
entire cord strokes out.
We'll come back to this later.
Later? You could
finish the surgery
only to cut the wrong one?
This will have been for nothing?
Exactly. Thanks
for pointing that out.
How many inches left?
Oh, less than two.
So if I do my math, we've
got four to five more hours.
Crap. Oh, crap, oh, crap.
- What is it?
- It's my hand.
It's cramping. Dammit.
Don't move. Don't move...
BP's dropping!
OK, we're touching the cord.
If we disturb it
any more we run...
- Pulse is down to 52.
- It's getting worse, guys.
Easy, easy, easy, don't...
OK. It's OK. Just stay still.
I'm gonna reach in.
Hey, close your
eyes and breathe.
- OK? It's just a spasm.
- BP's back up
100 over 68.
Have you had anything
to drink today, Dr. Avery?
What?
Muscle cramps are
a sign of dehydration.
You went without fluids so
Dr. Grey couldn't get her hands
on the retractor,
isn't that right?
Yeah.
Sorry.
Don't apologize. Just step
aside. Dr. Grey, take over.
Easy.
- Good. OK.
- Easy.
Hmm. A or B? Dr. Grey?
- A or B?
- You're done?
- You got it all out?
- Except for the blind cut.
Just have to pick one
and we're good to go.
A or B?
- You're kidding.
- You're stalling. Dr. Avery?
I don't like to gamble.
Dr. Sloan?
So you can blame it on
me for the rest of your life?
This is all you.
Right. My call. Great.
He's deciding which one to cut.
Guessing which one.
No logical way
to make that call.
I can't look. I...
Oh, my God, Mer,
this is so good.
Eeny, meeny, miney, moe,
catch a tiger by its toe...
Are you playing Eeny
Meeny Miney Moe?
- Yeah.
- No.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's a bad idea?
We'll see.
OK.
Ask most surgeons why
they became surgeons.
They usually tell
you the same thing.
The high, the rush,
the thrill of the cut.
For me, it was the quiet.
- Come on, Shepherd.
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
Please don't be wrong.
OK...
He cut! He made the cut!
Cristina, was it the right one?
Cristina!
Tell me! Cristina!
Oh, no. No.
Oh, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no...
- No...
- Isaac, what is it?
I can...
I can move my toes.
It didn't work, did it?
- You couldn't do it.
- No, no.
We got the tumor. It's gone.
- But I can move my toes.
- Because we saved the cord.
It was a successful surgery.
You're gonna be fine.
I knew you would try, but...
- I'm going to be OK?
- Yes.
I'm actually going to be OK?
Yes.
You're a good man, Derek.
You're a very good man.
Peace isn't a permanent state.
It exists in moments.
Fleeting.
Gone before we
even knew it was there.
Shepherd finished the surgery.
And I took care of all the
pre-ops, so we're good to go.
She didn't show.
She can't be this stupid.
I mean, it saved her life.
The IL-2 saved her life.
And she didn't show up.
She...
She didn't show up.
Who doesn't show up?
We can experience
it at any time.
In a stranger's act of kindness.
A task that requires
complete focus.
You're standing too close.
- No, I'm not.
- Yes, you are.
- I'll show you.
- You?
Look at your hands.
They're hams.
Mine are tiny little geniuses.
It's not about the hands.
It's about the body.
You know, your stance.
Tilt your head. Here.
Then...
- Your eye-line.
- Uh-huh.
You stand too close, you
throw everything else off.
Good. Go again.
Or simply the comfort
of an old routine.
We can't keep
doing this, Richard.
I'm tired of fighting you.
Let's try and put this
behind us and move on.
I can, if you can.
You're fired.
Immediately.
Get the hell out of my hospital.
Go home.
Sleep on it.
We'll talk more tomorrow.
Every day, we all experience
these moments of peace.
The trick is to know
when they're happening
so that we can embrace them.
Live in them.
OK. So I've heard almost
everything from Cristina,
but I want to hear your version.
So start from the beginning
and tell me everything.
Derek? Derek?
And finally, let them go.