Damn it!
What's going on?
I put too much damn salt
on the rub.
I got to get it out.
Honey, it's 4:30
in the morning.
Yeah, and if the meat
loses its juices,
it's gonna be all dry
and burnt.
Sweetie, I... I...
I feel like this might be one
of those anxiety attacks
that Dr. Reese
said you might have.
It's not because
of my condition.
It's because I put
too much damn salt...
Whoa! Okay, okay, okay.
Let me help you.
Why don't you start
measuring out another rub?
Excuse me.
Yeah... Ah, whoa.
Dr. Rhodes, you're late.
I know. I am sorry.
I understand you're under
additional stress
at home lately, but please try
not to make this a habit.
I assure you
I will not.
Dr. Rhodes,
your CT patient's here.
You're going to 1.
Jerry Willis, 54, called 911
with shortness of breath
and tachycardia.
BP 110 over 60, rate 120,
satting at 89%
on five liters 0-2.
Mr. Willis, what are you
doing back here so soon?
I've been having trouble
breathing.
It started a few days
after I left.
What trouble are
we talking about?
Coughing. He's wheezing.
It's been getting worse.
All right, let's move him
on my count.
All right.
And one, two, three.
I replaced his aortic valve
two weeks ago.
Any intraoperative
difficulties?
None.
Cardiac comorbidities?
Nothing notable, no.
Austin Flint murmur.
The valve is leaking.
That's impossible.
Maybe you're hearing, uh,
tricuspid stenosis
or a subclinical MI.
Is it possible you
misoriented the valve?
Obstructed
one of the leaflets?
No. I remember it
very clearly.
Surgery went off
without a hitch.
We should order an echo?
What?
What's wrong?
Aortic insufficiency.
The valve is
definitely leaking.
But you just replaced it.
How could it leak?
I don't know.
It doesn't make any sense.
I...
Maybe Dr. Rhodes
made a mistake.
Morning.
Good morning.
Hi.
Whoa. Is that
what you're planning
on wearing tonight?
It's a brand-new Chiara Boni.
I mean... Nah, I mean
it's probably fine.
I mean, if you think
it's fancy enough
for the corner table
at Alinea.
Are you kidding?
That's like the toughest
reservation in town.
GQ says 97%
of relationships
are decided on the first date.
Oh, now you're getting
your dating advice from GQ?
Natalie, these are
hard numbers.
Mmm.
I'm just citing the research.
I honestly don't know
what happened.
Go back over your notes.
Try to learn from your error.
I will, and I'll get him
preop'd for a re-do.
That will not be necessary.
Between the adhesions and
further procedural stress,
reopening his heart
is simply too risky.
We'll manage him
with medications instead.
But if we don't fix
the valve,
his quality of life
is gonna suffer.
I understand,
but at this point,
it's our best option.
Any plans tonight?
Still got that chili.
You want to join?
No way.
Is the sushi place
on the corner still open?
Why can't you just be nice?
Oh, I can be nice.
Hold that thought.
Daniel. You're looking
more rested.
Doing my best.
What's the word?
The board is deciding
whether to put metal detectors
at all the hospital entrances.
So I have to go prepare
my recommendation.
Which way you leaning?
Toward yes.
Really?
Doesn't that kind of fly
in the face
of being a trusted
community institution?
You know, putting up barriers
between us and the people
that we're trying to help?
One of those people shot you
in the gut, Daniel.
Yeah, outside the hospital.
What kind of detector's
gonna stop that?
Dr. Reese.
Dr. Charles.
So, Nurse Sexton,
who do we got next?
Henry Lee.
He's a sweetheart,
comes in every month
for his heart failure meds.
Mr. Lee, I'm Dr. Choi.
How are you doing today?
A lot better now
that my girl's here.
She does have
that effect on people.
Any new complaints?
Nope. Just got
to get my meds.
Take a deep breath.
One more.
How much Lasix
does he usually get?
40 IV.
That sounds good.
But I'm also hearing some
dullness near your lung base.
I'd like to send you
for an X-ray.
Thanks, Doc, but
if it's all the same,
I'd rather just get
my meds and go.
Mr. Lee, I hear
what you're saying,
but I prefer
to be thorough.
Nah, let's just stick
to the usual.
Hey, can you do the IV
in my left hand today?
I got a good puffy one.
She never misses.
You got it.
I really would like
that X-ray.
I bet he'd listen to you.
Why? You think there's
something else going on?
I don't know. Probably not,
but it's impossible to say.
Okay, I'll try.
Thank you.
So I've got a 43-year-old
woman who passed out
at a Starbucks
from hypoglycemia.
Mmm-hmm.
Now, that's normal, right?
But then her blood came back
showing insulin
with a high C-peptide count.
So she gave herself
too much insulin.
Right, but here's the thing.
She is not diabetic.
Wait... So wait a minute.
She somehow got her hands
on insulin,
then injected it
into herself?
Why would she do that?
I don't know.
That's why I called you.
Okay, I'll try to find out.
All right, cool, thank you.
Oh, actually, um...
Okay, so you know how
I've been hounding you
about getting a drink
one night after work?
I'm familiar with it, yes.
Okay, well, I promise
it's all going to stop.
Right after you get a drink
with me tonight.
Oh, come on, Noah,
couldn't we just stick
to being colleagues?
Sure.
A drink as colleagues.
Okay.
Ms. Lake, I'm Dr. Reese
from Psychiatry.
Of course you are.
It's nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Uh, I understand that you may
have injected yourself
with insulin today.
I did.
Can you tell me why?
Today's the court hearing.
For my divorce.
Oh.
It just snuck up on me.
I mean, I've been dreading it
for months, but
when I woke up today and
realized that this is it...
Did you try
to harm yourself?
Oh, no, no, no.
I don't want to die.
I just couldn't face the day.
So let me understand.
You made yourself
pass out on purpose?
I panicked.
I did something stupid.
And now I'm wasting your time.
I'm sorry.
Speaking of which, could you
write a note for the judge?
Just something saying
I had a medical emergency.
Ah, I am sorry,
but I can't do that.
It doesn't have
to be anything big.
Handwritten
on a letterhead is fine.
The thing is, you didn't
have an emergency.
You caused it.
So it would be disingenuous
for me to say otherwise.
I'd like to speak
with your supervisor.
Excuse me?
I'm seeing a doctor,
now I need a doctor's note.
And if you can't do that,
then get me your supervisor.
Um... Okay.
You look like you need this
more than I do.
I'm fine.
Sure.
Hair's a mess,
bags under your eyes.
You look great.
Don't be so hard on yourself.
You work our schedule
then go home
to a girlfriend who's
basically your patient too.
Something like this
was bound to happen.
Really? Is that so?
At least it hasn't affected
your sunny disposition.
Keep up the good work.
Dr. Halstead,
You're going to 3.
Doris.
Talk to me, Chout.
Julie Dutra, 34, pregnant,
para one gravita zero,
fainted in a yoga class,
in A-fib at 150,
BP 90 over 60.
Hi, Julie, I'm Dr. Manning.
This is Dr. Halstead.
I told them
I don't want to be here.
Hopefully this
won't take long.
On my count.
One, two, three.
Julie. Are you okay?
I'm fine, just call Mira.
Our midwife.
I think Julie would be more
comfortable at home with her.
Uh, sir, your wife's
in a dangerous arrhythmia.
We can't let her go until
we get it under control.
Do you have any history
of heart disease?
No, I don't eat red meat,
and I keep
a high antioxidant profile
to minimize inflammation.
Okay, good.
Um... Let's get an EKG,
cardiac labs, CBC, CMP,
coags and a U/A, and let's
start 5 of verapamil IV, okay?
No, no medications.
This one's safe
for pregnancy.
If we don't control
your arrhythmia, it could
put the baby in danger.
Is that true?
Scott.
What?
We don't want anything
bad to happen.
Okay, fine,
but then we're leaving.
Thank you. All right.
Let me ask you
a few more questions.
Wait, what are you doing?
Just a quick
fetal ultrasound.
No, get that thing off me.
Acoustic radiation
impairs neurodevelopment.
That's not actually true.
Note that the fetus measures
normal size and weight
for five months.
Wait, what did you say?
That this looks like
a normal five-month pregnancy.
Measure it again.
I'm sure of the numbers.
Well, you're wrong.
Measure it again.
See?
Totally normal
for five months.
Except I'm not
five months pregnant.
I'm eight.
Julie's labs.
Anemia, vitamin deficiencies,
all the signs
of early kidney failure.
And no family history
of troubled pregnancies
or genetic conditions.
Maybe a malabsorption
syndrome?
Ms. Dutra.
Have you ever had any
gastrointestinal issues?
Crohn's, ulcerative colitis?
I used to have leaky gut.
At first, we thought
it was just lactose,
but of course it was
more complicated than that.
I see, and were you seeing
someone for this?
My nutritionist.
She got me off lecithin
and phytic acid.
It helped some,
but then once I got pregnant
I had to give up all GMOs
and anything that wasn't
locally sourced, too.
So what do you eat?
Certain strains
of Swiss chard, broccoli.
Sometimes I'll have
a cup of adzuki beans.
But she supplements a lot.
Selenium, coenzyme Q.
You eat three meals a day?
More? Less?
I do portion control
to manage the baby's glucose.
Seven hundred to 800 calories
a day. Why?
We suspect the difficulties
with this pregnancy
are being caused by your diet.
That can't be.
I only eat organic.
But you're not getting
enough protein or iron.
And we're seeing the effects
it's having on your baby.
We need to start aggressive
IV nutrition to help it grow
as much as possible
before you deliver.
If we admit you
to Obstetrics now, we...
No.
I understand that
you don't want to be here,
but at this point it is...
No.
You're not giving me IV food.
Your baby is severely
malnourished.
No, my baby is getting
healthy farm-to-table
nutrients.
You're not gonna pump him
full of toxins and chemicals.
Ms. Dutra...
I said no.
Your arrhythmia
hasn't resolved yet.
We'll be back in a minute
to check on you.
She's starving
that baby to death.
We need to talk to Goodwin.
Mr. Lee, we got
your X-ray results back.
Great. So I can get
out of here?
Actually, they show
bilateral pleural effusions,
fluid surrounding your lungs.
Is that bad?
It's hard to say.
It could just be
from your heart failure.
Either way, it's not making
your breathing any easier.
I'd like to have Radiology
remove it
with a needle aspiration.
You want to stick
a needle in my lung?
Yes.
But I'm breathing fine now.
I'd rather just go.
I understand, but doing this
will let you go longer
between treatments.
I think it's a good idea.
Don't you agree?
I don't know. Um...
The effusions are
pretty small.
True, but it also wouldn't
hurt to send the fluid
out for analysis,
just to be sure, right?
I suppose.
So, Henry, what do you say?
You really think
this is a good idea?
Okay.
We'll get you over there
right away.
Are you sure you want
to be this aggressive?
I want to cover
all the bases, yeah.
Henry's not
a very healthy man.
He doesn't do so well
with procedures.
I hear you, but medically,
it's the best course
of action.
I don't think it is.
I'm sorry you feel that way.
What you should be sorry
about is thinking
that I would agree
with you in there
just because we're
sleeping together.
That has nothing
to do with it.
I thought you'd agree because
that's my medical opinion.
Well, you were wrong.
The next time
you want to put me
on the spot in front
of my patient, think again.
Hey.
April.
You want to feed a patient
against her will.
A pregnant mother
who's killing her baby.
We believe she has
something called orthorexia,
an obsession with healthy
living that has limited
her diet so severely
that it's become dangerous.
And has led to
a pathologic distrust
of the entire medical system.
She won't let us do anything.
Well, is she delusional?
Can she make decisions
on her own?
No, she's very clear
about what she wants
and what she does not want.
Well, then we can't prove
incompetence,
and we can't force her
to do anything
to her body she doesn't want.
The law sides with her.
But there are
two patients here.
Yeah, one of whom
has no control
over what's being done
to it.
This is child abuse.
Well, I can convene
an emergency ethics committee.
It's possible
they may find grounds
to override her decision.
And in the meantime?
See if you can find a way
to help her trust us.
Dr. Latham.
We should do the surgery.
Dr. Rhodes...
No, I...
I looked over all my notes.
Okay? Mr. Willis' anatomy
is good.
We owe him a chance
to get this right.
We owe him
our best clinical judgment.
Yes, I was inside
of his heart.
He's got more than enough
healthy muscle
and vasculature.
I'm telling you
he can handle it.
Have you had more
than four hours' sleep
this last several weeks?
I am a cardiothoracic fellow.
Sleep deprivation
is part of the job.
I understand that.
But you have a lot
on your plate.
Dr. Bekker and I will take
the case from here.
No, Dr. Latham,
that's not necessary...
Dr. Rhodes,
you have a phone call.
Tell them
I'll call them back.
I'm sorry.
It's your landlord.
He says it's an emergency.
Excuse me.
Hey. Thank you.
Robin. Robin.
Hey, are you okay?
I forgot the brisket
in the oven when I went
to the store, and then
all the alarms went off.
I'm just such an idiot.
Come here.
Hey, Otis, when are we
gonna get that
thing shut down?
Yeah. Thank you.
Don't worry.
It could happen to anybody.
Shouldn't be more
than a half hour.
I'm sorry you had
to deal with that.
No need to be sorry.
You know what I mean.
The more time
you spend with her,
the less we have to see people
who actually need our help.
I don't know.
I'm not quite sure we're...
We're done with Ms. Lake yet.
Why? She just wants
to use us to game the system.
Well, so do a lot
of patients.
We're not gonna let her.
But the question is,
why is she doing it?
Wait, you still think
this is a psych case?
Why wouldn't I?
I mean, she exhibited some
pretty extreme behavior
this morning, didn't she?
To get out of a court date.
Well, perhaps,
but until we figure out
what's behind the behavior,
we haven't really
done our job,
have we?
I guess.
Good.
Keep me in the loop.
Your heart isn't responding
to the meds.
If things keep going
in this direction,
we may need to consider
an emergency C-section
to take the extra load
off your heart.
Drug me up then cut me open?
No way.
That's not what
we want either,
but we do need to protect
you and your baby.
That's why in the meantime,
if you allow us to give you
some IV nutrition...
No way.
Those bags off-gas BPAs.
Look, you don't get it.
This baby is being formed
from every single molecule
that enters my body.
It is my job to keep it
absolutely pure.
That is how I'm protecting it.
They understand that.
No, they don't.
Uh, excuse us.
Please tell me you have
some good news.
I'm afraid not.
The committee ruled
that we can't intervene
against her wishes, not even
for the sake of the baby.
So that's it?
We just have to watch
as she lets the baby die?
If that's
what she chooses to do.
But that's not
what she wants.
She wants to help her baby.
She's just confused
about how to do it.
I'm sorry.
Our hands are tied.
What happened?
Sats are at 78
and dropping.
He's in pulmonary edema.
Get him on BiPAP
and 40 of Lasix.
He's my patient.
Sublingual nitro,
IV nitroprusside
and ready an intra-aortic
balloon pump.
What's happening?
The leak in your valve
is causing fluid to back up
into your lungs.
BiPAP's at 100%.
Balloon pump is here.
What's that?
It's a pump that we can
implant directly
into his aorta to take
the strain off of his heart.
Meds are in.
Still satting at 78.
So, then he's hooked up
to a machine forever?
Possibly if his heart doesn't
respond to the medications.
Oh, my God.
Betadine.
Hold on.
Dr. Rhodes...
Give the meds
a minute to work.
We may not have a minute.
Look.
Your sats are coming up.
We'll hold off for now.
Give him 1.25 of enalapril IV
and another 40 of Lasix.
Mr. Dutra. Hi.
I need you to talk
to your wife.
She won't listen to me.
But you do understand
this has gotten out of hand.
Of course I do.
I mean, all she thinks
about is how
uric acid and compromised soil
are infecting
everything we eat.
What do I say to that?
Well, how did you handle it
in the past?
It wasn't this bad before.
I mean, she's always struggled
with anxiety
and control issues.
But when she got pregnant,
it's like she turned the dial
straight to 11.
Nothing's pure enough anymore.
Everything looks
like baby poison.
But there has to be
something you can say
to get her to let us help.
I am so scared my wife
and my baby are gonna die.
Can't you do something?
So you think I avoid conflict
to protect myself?
I think it is a possibility.
And you think
that's a pattern.
Yes. A destructive one,
from the sounds of it.
I can't believe
I didn't see it.
I will get your discharge
paperwork started.
Looks like you had
a little breakthrough.
I... I think she sees
that she has some issues
and that it will be worthwhile
for her to seek
some long-term therapy.
Sounds like a good start.
I, um...
I was wrong about her,
Dr. Charles.
Thank you for making me
stick with her.
Dr. Choi.
Pulse ox is down to 82.
No breath sounds
on the left.
He's got pneumothorax.
Get a chest tube, 26 French.
I can't breathe.
I'm afraid
your lung's collapsed.
Radiology must've nicked it
during the tap.
You're kidding me.
I'm so sorry, Henry.
I need to insert a tube
between your ribs
to reinflate your lung.
Do you understand, Mr. Lee?
Lidocaine.
Henry, I'm just
gonna lift your arm.
You're gonna feel a sting.
Just breathe.
It's okay. We're gonna
get you through this.
All I wanted was
my damn medicine.
I know.
Then why'd you let him
do this to me?
I was fine.
Oh, God.
It feels like
you're stabbing me
with a knife.
Breathe.
Put him on suction,
get a portable chest X-ray,
gram of cefazolin,
a milligram of morphine
and dress it with xeroform.
At this point I'm gonna have
to admit you, Mr. Lee.
Probably for several days.
I'm very sorry.
I'll check back on him soon.
I'm sorry.
What the hell are you
trying to do me?
Please, Ms. Dutra,
let me explain...
I told you no food!
Just one second.
What's going on?
I need you to calm down,
okay? Please.
She put this in my IV
behind my back.
Ms. Dutra, wait.
Glucose, amino acids.
You did this?
Ms. Dutra.
Julie.
Ms. Dutra, just relax.
Julie!
Ms. Dutra, we need
to get you back into bed.
Get her away from me.
Get her away from me!
I need some help here.
All right, easy.
Relax, I have her.
Let's get her back up.
Dr. Reese.
Your patient in 1's waiting
for his prescription.
Okay.
Hey, have you seen my pad?
Uh-uh.
Huh.
Have you seen
my prescription pad?
No.
No?
I couldn't have lost it.
I always put it back
in my pocket, always...
Hey, do you still need
that note for the judge?
Oh, no, it's fine, my lawyer
actually took care of it.
Oh, good. Could you please
open your purse?
I'm sorry?
I can't find
my prescription pad.
I want to check your purse.
I don't know why you think
it'd be in there.
Because you decided
to forge the judge a note
and you took it from my pocket
when you hugged me.
I have no idea
what you're
talking about.
Hey! Give me that!
So what's this?
You have no right.
You're gonna pay for this!
Ma'am!
I am gonna make you pay!
Hey! Hey.
Ma'am, step away now!
She assaulted me.
She... She put
that in my purse.
Okay, everybody calm down.
Dr. Reese.
What happened in there?
She stole my pad.
That's a felony.
She has been lying to us
from the start.
Of course she has.
Lying, manipulating.
Behaving recklessly with no
regard for herself or others.
Exactly.
No.
Not exactly.
Look, off the top of my head,
probably a sociopath,
but that makes your job
exploring that
and trying to help her.
Not punishing her.
But all she did from
the moment she got here
was try to manipulate us
and waste our time.
Because she's mentally ill.
No. No, it's because people
like you let her.
People like me?
Yes.
Yes, you enable
and you make excuses
and you give out
psychiatric diagnoses
so that no one has to be held
accountable for their actions
just like you did
with the guy that shot you.
You feeling any better?
A little bit.
Good.
If there's anything
that you need,
Dr. Latham
and Dr. Bekker
are gonna be
taking care of you
from here on out, okay?
Dr. Rhodes.
Am I gonna be
like this forever?
Things will get better once
they optimize your meds.
But I'll always be
coming back here
for something, right?
There's no way to go back
to how I was?
It is possible to redo
your valve surgery.
It comes
with significant risks.
You could end up with an even
worse leak than before.
You could even die.
But it could work.
I could go back to normal?
Dr. Latham is the best
this hospital's got.
I promise he's gonna take
great care of you.
This is why I didn't want
to do the lung test.
Still the right call.
No, you don't know that.
You don't know him...
But I know
what heart failure looks like,
and this just seems
like something else.
I've been treating
Henry for years.
This is what he looks like.
I'm not asking
for a second opinion.
You don't want my opinion.
Just because I don't have
an MD after my name
doesn't mean I don't know
what's best for my patient.
April, as the doctor,
I'm responsible.
I have to do
what I think is right.
Both of you, in there. Now.
This has to stop.
Do you need another nurse
on your case, Dr. Choi?
No.
Uh, excuse me.
Why didn't you ask me
if I need a new doctor?
April.
He's just as much my patient
as he is Dr. Choi's.
I don't know what's going on
between the two of you,
but if you don't stop
disturbing my ED,
I'm gonna separate you
for good.
Do you understand?
Clear.
Good.
Carry on.
You're very lucky
her husband convinced her
not to pursue action
against you or the hospital.
Ms. Goodwin, I'm sorry.
I expect better from you,
Dr. Manning.
Nat, wait.
Hi.
I'm sorry.
I'm really not interested.
I understand.
You didn't trust us before.
You certainly have no reason
to trust us now.
Then we finally agree
on something.
Julie.
Fearing for your baby's safety
is the most natural thing
in the world.
When I was pregnant,
I lost my husband.
I was afraid
of a lot of things.
And then one day,
after I had my son,
I was up in a high-rise
building on the balcony
and suddenly had this
vivid image of myself
falling over the railing.
And my first thought was,
what would happen to my son
if I wasn't here for him?
And the craziest part is,
my favorite thing in the world
had always been Ferris wheels
and roller coasters
and being up in the air.
But from that day on,
I had this totally irrational
fear of heights.
It is really scary
being solely responsible
for that tiny, defenseless
person inside of you.
But you are letting
your fear win.
And it's gonna end badly.
Anyway...
I am sorry.
I just got the analysis
of Henry's lung tap.
Non-small-cell lung cancer?
You were right to do the tap.
That's not important.
What matters now is that
he needs to be told,
and I think it would be best
if he hears it from you.
You've treated him longer
than anyone here.
You know him better
Why is Mr. Willis
insisting on surgery
despite my explicit
recommendation
to the contrary?
Dr. Latham, I...
Did you go behind my back?
No, he asked
if he had options.
So I told him.
I in no way suggested...
You've shown extremely poor
decision-making today.
From this point on,
you are not
to set foot in the OR
until I deem you
ready to return.
Do you understand?
You're benching me?
For the foreseeable
future. Yes.
Dr. Halstead.
Her heart rate's too high
and her pressure's dropping.
Baby's heart rate's
down to 90.
My chest hurts.
Your arrhythmia is
escalating out of control.
Push ten milligrams
of diltiazem stat
and up her 0-2 to 6 liters.
We need to do a C-section.
We have to get the baby out.
No.
Julie, I know you
don't trust me,
but your baby is
in real danger.
84.
Julie, let them do it.
I can't.
Julie, if you don't
let us do this,
your baby is going to die.
Okay, do it.
Thank you.
Call OB and tell them
we're coming up
for a crash C-section, now!
You heard her.
Let's move.
I'm not seeing
any cause for the leak.
Pickups.
Are any of the leaflets
impinged in the ventricle?
No,
they're opening freely, and
the orientation is correct.
So what do we do?
Re-suture the valve.
Won't give us
much room to work,
but I don't see where
we have a choice.
It's the valve.
Dr. Rhodes, no one asked
for your opinion.
It's a brand-new valve.
That's ridiculous.
The leaflets
must be asymmetrical.
That would cause
a large enough
opening for the blood
to keep leaking back through.
It does seem that they're
not closing properly.
Really? They gave us
a bad valve?
It appears so.
Dr. Rhodes,
go change your clothes.
I'd like you to scrub in for
the remainder of the surgery.
How are you feeling?
I'm okay.
What are they putting in him?
Proteins,
carbohydrates, fats.
He needs them to grow.
You paged about a consult?
Yeah. Yeah.
Um...
Fifty-something guy,
post-op after
getting shot by a patient.
Is this a joke?
No. I'm serious.
Give me your clinical
evaluation of my recovery.
No residual anger or fear.
Mmm-hmm.
Normal intellectual
and emotional functioning.
You seem like
you have moved on.
Yeah.
And you should too.
Excuse me?
I'm just wondering if today
was less about your patient
and more about lingering fears
for our safety.
It is certainly true
that a very few patients
can be dangerous.
But the overwhelming
majority are
harmless and in fact
very grateful for our help.
Only they can't get that help
if you come to work scared.
I'm not scared.
This is not an accusation,
Doctor.
I just want you to know
that every psychiatrist
goes through this
at some point or another.
And then it passes.
And it'll pass for you, too.
Seems the hospital
changed valve manufacturers
several weeks ago.
This particular company
didn't bother
to conduct any
human testing.
And they can do that?
All they have to do is prove
that it performs the same
function as a previous device.
Unbelievable.
Well...
Good night, Dr. Latham.
When surgeons burn out,
it always starts with stress.
Then a call goes
the wrong way,
an unlucky result.
And they get
in their own heads,
and that's when
the hesitation starts,
the unsteady hands.
And once you're there,
it's a very hard road back.
Are you okay, Dr. Rhodes?
Yes. I am.
Then you continue to have
my full confidence.
Good night.
I'm sorry.
Me too.
This isn't gonna be easy,
is it?
No, it's not.
Though you know
what would help?
Big pot of chili.
Sushi?
I'll see you later.
Yeah.
Hey.
How'd that metal detector
thing turn out?
I changed my mind.
Really?
Yeah.
I saw a woman today
who almost killed her baby
because she didn't trust us.
And I thought,
"How can we encourage people
to trust us more
"if we don't show them
trust first?"
Couldn't agree more.
Well, uh, good night.
All right, see you tomorrow.
Dr. Reese, Dr. Sexton.
Check it out.
Someone slashed her tires.
You still think patients
are harmless?
She did this.
Yes, I'm still here.
I'm sorry you don't
even get a real meal
after the day you have had.
Oh, a little vegetarian
living never hurt anybody.
Well, I'm sorry that
you have to put up with
all of this.
I promise it will
be better soon.
I know.
It's almost 9:00.
Aren't we gonna miss
our reservation?
Maybe.
So then what
are we doing here?
What?
No. No, no, no. No way.
Mmm-mmm.
Hey, you're not gonna
let fear win, are you?
Uh, yes.
Yes, I am.
Aw, come on.
Just one ride.
Oh, Will, no.
Natalie, I'm gonna be
next to you the whole time.
Trust me.