You never told me
you were in an accident.
I know how it looks.
How am I supposed
to believe you?
We've had
a couple very pleasant
coffees together.
How about we, I don't know,
advance to dinner?
My apartment. 8:00.
Did I hear
something about an inmate
from Cook County?
Yeah.
Shanked in the neck.
His last name's Archer.
Dad.
It's gonna be okay,
my boy.
Sean, what is the matter?
What's wrong? Are you hurt?
Are you in trouble?
Dad, take a breath.
I'm getting
all these calls...
Well, something's come up.
Huh?
I'm getting out.
You're getting out?
It... What... Really?
When?
Tomorrow.
And, uh, it's a done deal?
You got 14 months left
on your sentence.
I know.
I guess good behavior,
compassionate release,
overcrowding...
Who cares?
You're getting out.
So what's the...
What's next?
You going back to school?
Or you gonna get a job?
Right now, I just wanna
get to tomorrow.
Well, I'm happy for you.
Liliana? Fantastic cook.
Man, she made me
this dish last night.
Kluski slaskie?
Kluski slaskie.
You can't pronounce it.
I don't have a clue.
I can't pronounce any of
the dishes she's made for me.
Wait, "dishes"? Plural?
I've been over to her house
twice for dinner now.
Third one's on the books.
That's wonderful, Daniel.
I'm so happy for you.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
How are you doing? How's biz?
There's still a few
supply snags here and there,
but no major headaches.
And I probably
just jinxed it.
Uh-oh.
You know.
If it's quiet today,
doesn't mean
it's quiet tomorrow.
Tell me about it.
Keep up the good work.
Bye.
Oh, Maggie.
Oh, good morning.
Morning. I have an idea.
Came to me on the train
on the way in.
Balderdash.
Balder-what?
Dash. It's a party game.
For the next, game night
at your place.
It's been a while
since you've had one.
Yeah, not sure
when there'll
be another one, though.
No worries.
Just putting in
the request now.
Hoping to level out
the playing field.
Ah.
Balderdash is a solo game,
so you and Ben
can't join forces
and destroy the rest of us
like you did in Heads Up!
You got this.
Keep working the beta.
Flow through the moves.
I have no idea
what any of that means.
Okay.
I think I'm stuck.
No, you're good.
Right leg up
on the next hold.
Okay.
Left hand
up and over.
There we go.
That's right, Asher.
Send it.
Wow, nice reach.
5.13. Nice job, Omar.
What do you say?
Give it another try?
I got close.
Makes it all the more
worth it when you ring
that summit bell.
Omar? You good, man?
No one on belay.
Omar, you clipped in?
Is he okay?
I don't think so.
Clip in, Omar!
Omar, clip in!
Oh, my God.
I'll call 911.
Stay with me, man.
Stay with me.
Hi. This is
Dr. Hannah Asher.
I need an ambulance at the
rock climbing gym off Morgan.
Courtney, what've we got?
Omar Thomas, 34.
Long fall while indoor
rock climbing.
Landed on his heels
with axial load.
No loss of consciousness.
Heart rate 120. BP 140/90.
Gave him 4 of morphine
in the ambo,
but he's still in pain.
He a friend of yours?
Gym buddy.
All right.
Omar, we're gonna
take good care of you.
Okay, buddy?
Nice and easy.
On my count, all right?
One, two, three.
Give me 100 of fentanyl
for the pain.
Lungs are clear.
Belly's soft.
Smelling alcohol
on his breath.
Yeah, we smelled that too.
Think it's beer.
He wasn't clipped in.
No one on belay.
I don't see him making
those kinds of rookie mistakes
without being impaired.
Okay, Kathleen,
X-rays of his chest, pelvis,
hips, knees, and ankles.
Mindy, CT head,
CTLS abdomen and pelvis,
standard trauma labs
and type and screen.
Let me see your hands.
Ooh.
That's a gnarly rope burn.
Yeah. I'll be fine.
Dr. Asher, Leah's asking
for you in the waiting room.
All right.
Let me change first.
Cool water and aloe
on those hands.
And keep me updated
on him, okay?
Thank you.
You got it.
Hey, Leah. You needed me?
Name's Jodie Dunner.
Says she's having
an endometriosis flare-up.
She's been crying
since she signed in.
Okay. Thank you.
Ms. Dunner,
I'm Dr. Asher.
I hurt so bad.
Endometriosis is...
it's cruel.
I'm a yoga teacher.
I practice patience
for a living,
but this pain, it's...
Come on.
Let me help you
to an exam room.
Uh... Is it my turn?
Triage system.
Your pain's bumping you
to the front of the line.
Here.
Hook him up.
I'll be right there.
Hey.
How's Omar?
Bilateral tibiotalar
dislocations.
No broken spine
or pelvis.
No fractured femurs.
Liver and spleen
are still intact.
I figured you'd agree
that that's good news.
It is.
It's just Omar's BAC
was only .04.
What's that, two beers?
He wasn't drunk,
so why'd he fall?
Maybe he just
made a mistake.
Dr. Marcel, Dr. Lieu,
something's not right
with Mr. Thomas.
Mr. Thomas?
What happened to my legs?
Justin?
Yeah, Omar, it's me.
You were in an accident
at the gym this morning,
and you fell.
Dislocated both
your ankles.
What? I did?
Where am I?
What happened to my legs?
You had an accident,
Mr. Thomas.
You fell,
injured your ankles.
Justin?
All right, hang in there
for me, Mr. Thomas.
Dr. Lieu, doors.
Some sort of memory loop?
Maybe a whiplash injury,
concussion?
I literally caught him
when he hit the ground.
He didn't hit his head.
The summit bell.
He kept ringing it.
Same sort of loop
like he's doing now.
But it was before the fall.
All right,
first things first.
Let's reduce his dislocation.
Soon as that's done,
let's pull in
Dr. Charles, okay?
Just so you know, I've never
officially been diagnosed
with endometriosis.
Yeah, I noticed
that in your chart.
My sister, though,
she has it.
We're so alike.
Tender?
Yeah.
In my back.
Your back? Really?
Endo pain is primarily focused
in the pelvic area.
I don't know.
I guess it's radiating.
About to start my period.
Maybe that's why.
All right, well,
I'd like to run some tests,
do a bimanual exam,
then an ultrasound.
Sure. Yeah, anything.
I just want to feel better.
Do you think I could
get something now, though?
For the pain?
How about Tylenol?
Okay. If you think
it'll help.
One thousand milligrams
acetaminophen.
That's it?
For this degree of pain?
Yeah, I want to hold off
on anything stronger for now.
Okay.
Dr. Halstead,
you're going to five.
Cesar, talk to me.
Aaron Curtis, 22.
Severe abdominal pain.
He doubled over at work
while stocking shelves.
BP 133/86. Heart rate 99.
Sats 100%.
Two of morphine
given in the ambo.
All this ain't necessary.
Maybe, but you're here now,
so let us check you out.
Okay, on my count.
One, two three.
Thank you.
Look, my manager
at the grocery store,
that's who called
the ambulance. He's just
overreacting. That's all.
Sorry we can't take
your word for it.
Hey, Aaron,
your stomach pain,
did it just start
this morning, or you been
feeling it a while?
I don't know. Couple days.
Can you describe it?
Dull? Sharp? In between?
Ooh...
Okay. Sharp.
KUB.
We're gonna grab some X-rays,
see what's going on.
I know it's uncomfortable,
but stay still, okay, Aaron?
Please,
just let me up out of here.
X-ray up. Clear.
That's a bullet, Aaron.
You were shot?
Okay, let's turn him.
Nice and easy.
There you are.
Partially healed entry wound
in the left flank.
I'd guess
it's a few days old.
What happened, Aaron?
Aaron?
Triple contrast CT.
Maybe it'll tell us
something.
Were you able to get anything
out of him?
Nope.
He won't share
the what, when,
or why of his gunshot.
Yeah, something sketchy
went down.
So, Aaron, here's where
we are, okay?
The bullet is resting
just above the neck
of your pancreas.
Do I need an operation?
Trauma surgeon
doesn't think so.
Then I could bounce?
The pancreas is very
unforgiving.
Just because you're stable now
doesn't mean you're
out of the woods.
There's one more thing.
By law, gunshot wounds have
to be reported to the police.
Aaron...
If you're in trouble,
maybe we can help you.
You just gotta talk to us.
It doesn't matter what I say.
Hmm.
Vegan portabella
mushroom jerky.
Yeah, low in sodium.
Lower on taste.
Your kidneys thank you.
Well, they better.
What's up?
Ah, OpioHealth,
that new AI program
that the hospital's
testing out
to assess
a patient's risk
of opioid abuse?
Yeah, it's one of those
new technologies
designed to sniff out
doctor shoppers, yeah?
Yeah, well, I ran
my endometriosis
patient's name
through it,
Jodie Dunner.
She was red-flagged.
Well, I can see why.
That's a lengthy
prescription history.
Opioids, benzos,
barbiturates.
Yeah, reads like
a classic pill-seeker.
And given that her primary
complaint was back pain,
I thought so too.
But now,
I'm not so sure.
Okay. What do you need?
Second opinion.
The AI program tagged her
as high-risk.
That means if it is endo,
I'm locked out
of prescribing
her meds, but...
As chief of the ED,
I can override
the OpioHealth program.
Yes.
Dean, you know my past.
It takes one to know one,
but Jodie...
I'm just not getting
that vibe from her.
Maggie?
Maggie.
Oh, I'm sorry.
What do you need?
Treatment seven is cleared
and turned over.
Everything good?
Yeah, of course.
Okay.
Hey, they're done.
So he tell you
what happened?
No, he probably doesn't want
to dig his hole any deeper.
And what does
that mean?
Area South Robbery-Homicide's
working a case off 91s
from last week.
Mini-mart got stuck up.
Clerk pulled a gun,
tried to protect himself.
Took one to the chest.
Didn't make it.
And you think Aaron's
your guy?
The description we got
on the offender,
male, Black, average height,
medium build, hoodie.
Clerk fired off a round
before he went down.
Separate blood on the scene
shows he hit someone.
Detective working the case
is on his way over.
We're gonna sit on the room
until he gets here.
All right. Thanks, guys.
Be advised...
I know these guys are
just chasing leads, but...
Male, Black,
average height,
medium build?
That could be
a lot of people, Will.
Yeah, and getting shot
doesn't mean
you're a criminal.
I mean,
the way that Aaron
took my hand at the intake,
the way he looked
into my eyes...
I felt it too.
I mean, I don't know
if he did it or not,
but I'm certain that they've
already made up their minds.
So I fell while
I was climbing...
I dislocated both my ankles,
and they're set now.
And that's what
these casts are for.
Exactly.
And we were talking
about next steps.
Can you remember
what we said?
Right.
Yeah, you said that...
You said...
Damn it!
I don't... I don't know.
Omar, you had a big fall.
It's not okay.
Why can't I remember?
What is happening to me?
Omar, your blood pressure
is getting a little high,
so we're gonna give you
some medicine
to bring it back down.
Just breathe in
through your nose.
Out through the mouth.
In through the nose,
and out through the mouth.
Okay. You know
what, buddy?
I'm gonna let you rest
a little bit, but I want
you to be assured
we're gonna figure this out.
In the meantime,
can I get you
another sandwich?
You kind of mangled that one.
No? All right.
I will, uh,
check back in a bit.
Clearly, he's got some kind
of short-term memory issue,
which is understandably
stressing him out
a little bit.
I mean,
you know Omar, right?
Can you tell me
a little bit about him?
He's only been climbing
a few years,
but he's a star at the gym.
He trains hard.
Disciplined. Driven.
All right.
So more of a type A?
You thinking
he had a mental break
from pushing himself
too hard?
Well, memory loss
can be a result
of a number of
psychiatric conditions,
but it can also be
neurologic.
You know what
I want to do? I want to
get a nutrition panel.
See what we get,
go from there?
Okay.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Any discomfort?
Kind of.
Hmm? Can you be
more specific?
How does this feel?
Um...
I guess pressure.
Pressure, like
I'm pressing on your abdomen?
Yeah. Sorry. It's just
hard to describe.
Okay. Pressing farther up now,
near your diaphragm.
How does this feel?
Same, I guess.
Okay.
Not sharp, stabbing?
No, just, like, pressure.
Okay, Jodie, I don't think
this is endometriosis.
But to be sure,
I'm gonna run
some tests.
CT, MRI, diagnostic lap.
Lap? What's that?
Laparoscopy.
We insert a scope
into your abdomen,
check out what's going on.
Surgery?
Yeah.
And unfortunately,
we won't be able to give you
pain meds beforehand,
'cause it might interfere
with the results.
Okay. I get it.
Hey, it'll be all right.
Pupils practically pinpoint.
Overall listlessness.
Yeah, all signs
she's high.
Her tox screen was likely
a false negative.
She probably loaded up
on water before coming in,
knew it could dilute
her urine sample.
Yeah, doubt she saw a mountain
of tests coming her way,
and I didn't get the sense
that she knew
that they were phony.
No, my guess
is that right now,
she's planning her escape
before any social workers
become involved.
I believed her,
or I don't know, maybe
I just wanted to believe her.
Look, you thought Jodie
was in pain, okay?
You didn't care what kind.
You just wanted to help.
How long has the detective
been with Aaron?
About ten minutes.
He's not talking
to him either.
He was sitting there,
and then his eyes rolled back.
And he just slumped.
Aaron?
Aaron? Bag him.
BP's a mess.
88/50 and falling.
Roll him.
Huge melanotic stool.
He's bleeding
into his GI tract.
Two units of blood
on the rapid transfuser.
Already on it.
Watch your step.
All right, we're moving.
CT. Let's go.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
You said I didn't
need surgery.
Well, that was before.
Your condition
has deteriorated.
The bullet has eroded
into the, uh, the neck
of the pancreas.
That means
it's touching the organ,
making it bleed into the tube
that drains your intestines.
It won't stop on its own?
It may or it may not.
The safest option
is to go in,
take out the bullet,
and remove the damaged area
of the pancreas.
No. No surgery. No.
Look, Aaron, your
blood pressure's unstable.
You've lost a lot of blood.
Opening me up means
he gets the bullet.
I know how it works.
He gonna use it
to tie me to the robbery.
Are you saying
that you were there?
I was there,
but I didn't
rob nobody.
Definitely didn't
shoot nobody.
I was getting a sandwich
on my way to work.
Went to the counter to pay,
and next thing I know,
a guy's jacking the place.
I mean, he got a gun.
Clerk got a gun.
They firing.
I ran.
I felt getting hit, but...
I just kept running.
It's been
a week, though.
Why didn't you come forward,
tell the police, us,
when you first came in?
Because trust
has to go both ways.
Look, I grew up bouncing
house to house in foster care.
Spent time living on
the street too.
People like me,
it don't matter
what really happened.
We gonna get blamed for it.
I ain't the guy.
I swear.
Look, Aaron
your pancreas is bleeding,
and without surgery,
your life could be at stake.
And if I get it,
my life could be over.
I seen people get convicted
and sent away forever.
They were innocent too.
I'm gonna take my chance
the bleeding stops on its own
rather than put my fate
in his hands.
No surgery.
Okay.
She's seizing.
Four milligrams of Ativan.
Naloxone on standby.
Overdose?
It looks like it.
Thought you
had eyes on her.
I did.
I was watching her like a hawk
so she couldn't bolt
before the addiction counselor
came down.
So she hasn't
used at all recently?
Not a chance.
Okay.
So if not an OD,
maybe withdrawal?
Yeah, doubt it.
She's missing
all the telltale symptoms.
Agitation, runny nose,
watery eyes, dilated pupils.
Well, endometriosis
doesn't trigger seizures.
So if not an OD
and not withdrawal,
what is it?
Let's get
a CT head and chest,
this time for real.
Hey, so I...
I got Omar's
nutrition panel back.
Serious B1 deficiency.
Body can't generate B1.
We only get it from food.
This low a level means
Omar's not eating enough.
Probably been malnourished
for a while now.
Eating disorders
aren't uncommon
in the rock climbing
community.
Really?
You're fighting gravity
with only fingertips
and toes,
so lighter's better.
What do you say we
hang some IV nutrients?
Those memory issues
should resolve pretty quick.
Yeah.
Will, he's here.
Thanks for coming.
Uh-huh.
So I, looked
at the security video
from the mini-mart.
Yeah.
Crap footage
and bad angles.
You can tell something's
going on, but you don't
know who's doing what.
Eyewitness statements?
All over the place.
So no proof that Aaron's
the offender, but no proof
that he's not either.
No. I spoke with the manager
at the grocery store where
he stocks shelves.
Said he always
comes in early.
Leaves late.
"Aaron's a great guy.
Wish I had more like him."
His words.
He ever been
in trouble before?
No run-ins with the police.
No criminal record.
No contact card.
No gang affiliation.
So what do you
think, Kevin?
I mean, it's not
my case, Maggie.
Hey, look, I know
we're asking you
to speak out of turn,
but Aaron's passing
on a surgery
he desperately needs
over this.
Well, you know,
I like to say
that there's always a why
before there's a who.
There is no why for Aaron
in this robbery.
I mean, I don't believe
that he's good for it,
but that's the way I see it.
I mean, the state's attorney
is hungry.
With an election coming up,
he might see it differently.
Right.
All right. Thanks, man.
Yeah. I'll be here
if you need me.
Good seeing you.
Mmm-hmm.
So, Jodie,
we've got an answer.
Okay.
Your back pain is not
from endometriosis.
It is from a Pancoast tumor.
Uh, a tumor?
Yes.
It's a rare lung cancer.
Your body's response to it
caused pinpoint pupils
and ultimately
your seizure.
So it's right here.
Oh, God.
That's in me?
It is, but it doesn't appear
to have metastasized.
Do you know what
that means, metastasized?
Um...
I'm not sure.
It means that the cancer
hasn't spread.
So it'll make it easier
to treat. The tumor can be
removed surgically.
It's called resection.
Do you understand?
I think so.
Okay, Jodie,
Dr. Archer and I
are gonna step outside.
We'll be right back, okay?
That was not
an informed consent.
Postictal confusion
from the seizure?
Could be,
or it could be another
complication from the tumor.
There were some glimmers
of recognition, though.
Yeah. I'll call psych,
get their take.
Okay.
Sixty-five, 58, 51.
Keep going?
No, it's good stuff.
How about that
word sequence I gave you?
Let's give that a shot.
Um, San Antonio.
Bubblegum.
Shoelace, ice skate,
stapler.
Excellent.
Well, looks like your memory's
certainly coming back.
Justin, man...
I'm sorry for putting you
through all this.
I have a tendency
to overdo things.
Actually, wondering
if we could talk to you
about that.
Maybe discuss
your eating habits.
Oh, yeah.
I can see how that looks now.
Right after
the world shut down
'cause of COVID,
I started getting
these headaches.
And I read online
if you drink two pints
of beer a day,
it helps,
so I started drinking
two pints a day.
But it didn't work,
so I added exercise.
Rock climbing was perfect,
'cause it was...
It was outside,
socially distant,
challenging,
but now I was...
I was sporting
this beer belly,
so I started dieting.
And I noticed that you...
You only ate the tomato
and the lettuce
out of your sandwich,
so I'm assuming vegetarian?
Uh, and keto.
And keto?
Yeah.
Wow, okay.
So you mentioned that this...
This all started
with headaches, right?
Are you still getting those?
Actually, yeah.
Yeah, I do.
Okay.
I want you to do something
for me. I want you
to look at my finger.
Follow my finger with
just your eyes, without moving
your head, okay?
Mmm-hmm.
What the hell?
I can't move my eyes.
It's okay.
No, I can't move my eyes.
No, it's all right.
Just close 'em.
No, but what's wrong?
I can't move my eyes!
Close your eyes,
all right?
Close your eyes.
Okay.
Okay, order an MRI.
I'm scared.
I'm really scared.
It's all right, Omar.
Keep 'em closed,
all right?
Keep 'em closed.
Any progress?
No.
Well, we'll just have
to keep hanging blood
and hope for the best.
Dr. Halstead.
Ms. Lockwood.
We've positively
matched blood
from pads discarded
in Aaron's treatment room
to blood at the crime scene.
Pads?
The melanotic stool.
We rushed him to CT.
Anything tossed
on the floor is detritus,
fair game for evidence.
Blood links Aaron
to the crime scene,
and that bullet inside him
is gonna link him
to the clerk.
Which only proves
that the clerk shot Aaron,
not that he's the offender.
That isn't my distinction
to make.
It's my understanding
that Aaron requires surgery.
This is a warrant for
the bullet once it's removed.
You're out of luck.
He declined the procedure.
And by law, the state
can't force him to have it.
True, but Aaron's a minor.
ID he's been using to get
a job, rent an apartment,
it's fake.
Turns out, a few months ago,
he ran away from
his latest foster family.
Been pretending to be of age
to cover his trail.
Aaron's DCFS paperwork.
He's only 17, so yes,
the state can compel surgery,
and we'd like that bullet
in the process.
Been asking myself how Omar
didn't realize
he was moving his whole head
instead of just his eyes.
And then I remembered
this avalanche victim.
By the time we got there,
he had dug himself free.
His hands were jet black
with frostbite,
but he didn't realize it
until we pointed it out.
It's crazy, right,
how the brain
recognizes problems
long before we do
and instinctively compensates?
Image up.
Oh, okay. Look.
Right here.
Wait, Gene, can you...
Can you blow
that section up?
Mmm-hmm.
So we got microadenoma
pressing against
the pituitary gland.
Not that big either, which is
probably why CT didn't
pick it up this morning.
Well, the brain lesion
explains Omar's headaches,
but the eye lock?
Well, you see this sort of
diffusion right around here?
I'm pretty sure
that's a bleed,
which would definitely,
you know,
put pressure on
the cranial nerves
and could cause a lock.
Omar's headaches started
almost three years ago.
Eye lock only set in
30 minutes ago,
which means the bleed had to
have started just before then.
I think it might've happened
this morning
when I was first
talking to him.
The BP spike?
Yeah.
A jolt of hypertension
like that, it'd absolutely
trigger a bleed.
So the lesion is the root
of all of Omar's issues.
How do we fix it?
Well, we don't.
Neurosurgery does.
So there's a slowness
to Jodie's thought process
that's evident,
but she grasped
that she's ill,
that there's a tumor present,
that we recommend
it be resected,
and the consequences
if she doesn't have surgery.
Okay, four for four.
Sounds like she's capable
of consent.
So I'll get it, and then
I'll get her up to the OR.
Okay.
The hospital's new AI
pegged Jodie as a drug-seeker.
We almost let her walk
because of an algorithm.
Opiates are a problem.
I get building tools
to help solve it.
Yeah, except patients are
falling through the cracks.
Well, luckily, not today.
No...
But I'm worried
about tomorrow.
I mean, it's a warrant.
Do we even have a move?
Well, perhaps.
Legally, Med only
has to operate
if Aaron's life
is at stake, so is it?
BP's in the toilet.
He's still bleeding.
Without surgery,
it only gets worse.
Okay,
there's no projectile
to hand over
if it never comes out,
so, Dr. Marcel,
is there a way to operate
and stop Aaron's bleeding
without removing the bullet?
That's what
I've been debating.
The bullet is in
a terrible position,
right on the neck
of the pancreas.
All the damage is...
It's directly below it.
So it's gotta come out, then.
I didn't say that.
Well, I'm confused.
How do you get to the damaged
area of the pancreas if
the bullet's in the way?
I'm just gonna have to
slip in around it.
I am all for helping
to curb opiate abuse,
but this OpioHealth AI
is flawed.
The program has bugs,
and Med shouldn't
use it.
Look, analytics
that help identify
a patient's risk for misusing
opioids protect our liability.
This is a program Med
should absolutely
be using.
Liability is
the driving force?
What about patient care?
You know that's not
what I'm saying.
Plus, OpioHealth,
it's not meant to supplant
a doctor's diagnosis.
But it does! It sows
seeds of distrust.
My patient today, the scrips
in her file, the ones
that got her red-flagged,
they were for her aging cat.
Veterinarian put it
in her name.
And I'm sorry about that,
but if you look hard enough
into any AI program,
you are gonna find
outlier cases.
The night shift
had a patient
a few weeks ago
who got flagged for filling
scrips in multiple states.
Turns out he was a pilot.
His pharmacies depend
on what route he's flying.
Yes, there are some
growing pains,
but algorithms
are not the enemy.
They can help predict
which patient
is most likely to benefit
from a particular treatment,
estimate ICU probabilities,
whether a patient's
gonna deteriorate or die
after being discharged.
Peter, we get it.
You're a believer.
But Dr. Asher's problem
is less with AI
and more with this
specific program.
And frankly, I share
her concerns.
As soon as the board approved
testing OpioHealth,
I reached out
to the parent company
for clarity on how they amass
and interpret their data.
They have yet to share
any information,
and they claim that it
would infringe
upon their proprietary
algorithm.
Look.
If OpioHealth
isn't comfortable
sharing how
their program works,
I'm just not comfortable
using it.
And given the growing number
of errant cases,
I'm going to petition
the board to remove
the program hospital-wide.
You're gonna be
picking a fight,
and not just with the board
but with Jack Dayton.
So be it.
Okay.
There's the papilla.
Gonna cannulate.
Moving into
the pancreatic duct.
2.0, visualize the neck
of the pancreas.
Loading.
Clear view of the bullet.
It's right on the duct.
Uh-huh.
Slipping around it.
Okay. Deploy the stent.
Looking good.
The bullet is fully excluded
by the stent.
It is no longer eroding
into the duct.
Yeah.
That should stop the bleed.
Okay.
Hey, Omar.
How you feeling?
Uh...
My eyes are moving.
My headache's gone,
so that's a win.
I'm pretty embarrassed
over my comedy of errors.
Don't be.
Stuff like this happens,
you know?
Ugh. Anyway, I promise,
this is... This is never
gonna happen again.
I'm gonna rehab my legs.
I'm gonna get on a new diet.
And I'm gonna add
yoga, meditation.
I'm gonna add a new
sleep regimen.
Woah, woah, woah.
Easy, Omar. You know
what they say.
Mountains have
a way of dealing
with overconfidence.
Get better first.
Then I'll see you at the gym.
"Mountains have
a way of dealing
with overconfidence."
You know,
I kind of like that.
I am no mountain climber
and I cannot see
any rock walls in my future,
so I guess I'm wondering,
if I were to kind of use that
every now and then,
would that be considered
stolen valor?
Not in my book.
Applies to everybody.
Ah, there she is.
Pit bull.
I heard you
stuck it to legal
while I was in surgery.
Nice.
Goodbye, OpioHealth.
But that's
only here at Med.
Program's still in hospitals
all over the country.
You know, a lot of other
patients could be
unfairly labeled.
Might even be me one day.
Entered my name
into the system.
Yeah?
Was immediately red-flagged.
So it doesn't...
Doesn't matter how long
I've been sober.
That algorithm
has branded me forever.
The capabilities
are endless.
I'm telling you.
Yeah.
Give me ten minutes
to change,
and I'll meet you
in post-op.
Yeah.
Hey.
You two saved
Aaron's life today,
in more ways than one.
Nine years of R&D.
Never imagined that 2.0
could be used as a tool
for medicine
and social justice.
It's a good day.
Hey, Dean.
Rumor is that you keep
a bottle in your desk drawer.
Who told you that?
Shut the door.
So, uh...
Sean's being paroled tomorrow.
That's great.
Yeah...
Isn't it?
Yeah.
Yeah, I just want him
to have a fair shot.
That's all.
Well, why wouldn't he?
You know, these days,
we're all just, data points
for AI to analyze, you know?
This patient of mine today,
she was just defined
by her...
Her prescription history,
right?
And tomorrow, someone could be
defined by their medical
records, you know,
their banking information,
their...
Their criminal
background, right?
It's supposed to be,
work hard enough,
you can be anything
you want,
but if Sean gets out,
he's just a...
A rating some
computer program
spits out.
I mean, all I can say is,
in my book, character counts,
you know?
I can't believe
I'm the only one
who still thinks that way.
Well, sure hope not.
There you are.
Hey.
So PD arrested someone
in connection with
the robbery-homicide.
Aaron's not
their prime suspect
anymore.
Yeah, I spoke to Kevin.
Said he's gonna be cleared.
Heading towards
a happy ending.
Thankfully.
And despite the truth,
Aaron almost lost everything.
Mmm.
Mags, you okay?
Ben and I are separated.
And I don't know if
we're on a path
to getting back together or...
Divorce.
Oh, Mags.
I'm so sorry.
I love Ben
with all my heart,
and despite that truth, I...
I might lose everything.
I was thinking about
our talk yesterday,
about what's next.
Yes.
Yes to school. Yes to a job.
Yes to everything.
I want to do it right
this time, Dad.
Will you help me?
Yeah.
Us against the world, son.
Us against the world.