Nobody's memory
is perfect or complete.
We jumble things up.
Richard. YOUNG
RICHARD: I'm sorry. I can't.
We lose track of time.
Richard!
We are in one place...
You believe that your career
is more important
than mine. It is!
Then another.
I gave it up for
you. I don't want it.
And it all feels like one
long, inescapable moment.
I raised you to be an
extraordinary human being.
So imagine my disappointment
when I wake up after five years
and discover that you're
no more than ordinary.
It's just like my
mother used to say.
"The carousel
never stops turning."
You asked for a consult. This
is my... That's not the point.
I have to control the
infection. Surgery first.
She has an abscess...
If I don't operate,
she will die...
Let's have one conversation.
Meredith, what do you
need? Pierce paged me.
Yeah, I need a general
consult on her chest.
What about Webber?
I paged Dr. Grey.
Pierce, make your case.
I respect
Dr. Shepherd's opinion,
but I need to go in first
to debride the infection
before it shuts down her heart,
her lungs, all of her organs.
And she is my patient. I
paged you for a consult.
I'm sorry, but if the ventricle
ruptures, it could be catastrophic.
I can't sit back
and let that happen.
If you go in first, she
will die on your table.
If you do, she could come
out a brain-dead patient.
Owen, will you
look at the scans?
The abscess is up
against the ventricle.
It could cause significant brain
edema and severe meningitis.
So, basically, you're both
racing the clock on this girl.
If the time hasn't
run out already.
We'll know if her heart stops.
Grey, what do you
think? I agree with Pierce.
I think we get to the neck
and the mediastinum first.
Look at the head CT. I
did. I still think Pierce is right.
No, no, no, let me show you. I
know how to read a brain scan, Derek.
I learned from the
best, remember?
All right, enough. I know
what we're gonna do.
Let's go and
talk to the patient.
I'd had a root canal.
Last week, and it's
hurt for like a week.
But I figured,
it's a root canal.
It's supposed to hurt, right?
Yeah, well, you
should have told me.
Anyway, she passed
out at work yesterday,
and she's run a
fever ever since.
Holly, you got an infection
from the dental procedure
called descending
necrotizing mediastinitis.
It spread quickly into your neck
and down into your mediastinum,
which is the space between
your lungs that houses your heart.
And the fever is caused from
the sepsis from the infection.
Holly, in addition
to the sepsis,
I found a lesion in your brain,
and I think we
should start there first.
Are you telling me that my
daughter needs brain surgery?
Yes, immediately.
She needs chest debridement
as soon as possible.
What are you saying? Here
is what we're going to do.
You've not responded
to the IV antibiotics,
so I would like to run a
chest CT with contrast
to determine which
infection is most urgent.
We will have a decision
very soon, okay?
Edwards? Hi.
What are you doing here?
I am interested
in fetal surgery,
and Dr. Webber said that I could
do some OB ultrasounds so...
So, you're doing my ultrasound?
Unless you don't want
me to. No, no, no, it's fine.
You got to learn.
On me. I mean, it's
fine with me either way.
No, it's all good.
We just don't wanna know
the sex, so I'm not gonna look.
I will do all of the looking.
All right, so, there are
the feet and the toes.
He's breech, sitting
cross-legged like a little Buddha.
Yeah, he does that.
Oh, my God. What?
You said, "He." No, I didn't.
Yeah, you did.
You said, "He." No.
You said, "He." Oh. Oh, God!
I just said I didn't
want to know the sex!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. It
was a rookie mistake.
How's it looking in... Hey.
Stephanie. Hi.
Why... I'm practicing.
Okay. Yeah. Mmm-hmm.
Yeah. Um...
All right, just don't
let her know the sex.
Oh, no.
No, she says the baby's sitting
like a little Buddha,
just like last time.
Last time? Hey,
there, little thing, you.
All right, well, I got
surgeries most of the day,
so I'm gonna miss
our lunch. Sorry.
Torres might get one
of our guys back up
on his feet today, and
I'm gonna miss that, too.
Oh, but, yay, you
guys. Good luck.
All right.
And I just lied to my husband.
That's a great way to
start parenthood. Lying.
Awesome. Thanks, Edwards.
I'm really sorry,
but we're not done.
Oh, we're done.
Whoa, Rick, you're
pulling way ahead.
All right, you got to do
better than that, Jordan,
if you want to beat
Rick's numbers.
Oh. Have we started?
See, I thought this
was still the warm-up.
Oh! Gloves are off.
You don't want
a tie, right, guys?
Don't get his hopes up,
Dr. T., he can't touch my scores.
Oh, bite me. I'm getting
up on that leg first.
Ooh, you gonna take that?
What was it you said
my scores were earlier?
"Phenomenal."
Guys, you're doing fine.
You're both gonna
get the leg eventually.
This is not a contest.
Where's the fun in that, sir?
Yeah.
You're pitting these
guys against each other?
I just spent the morning
refereeing the surgeons.
I don't need this.
This is not a good idea.
They came up with this.
The one to master the
virtual-reality leg first
gets to try the real leg first.
It's just a little
friendly competition.
I'm just saying don't push them.
Hey, we are this close, Owen.
We're gonna have
someone walking today.
Whoo! Yes! Smoked you,
Schultz! Congrats, man.
See, that's the thing
about soldiers, Hunt.
I don't have to push them.
They come wired that way.
All right, Carter, you
ready to take a walk?
It's a pretty
straightforward procedure.
I'll do the initial approach.
Robbins, you can do the cutting.
God, this is good.
Did you ever try this?
Banana Clambake?
I haven't, and certainly
not before 8:00 a.m.
Does it have actual clams?
You're very perky today.
Why not? Life is short.
And at this point, I can eat
whatever the hell I want for breakfast.
Right, Robbins?
Right. You've earned it.
I just wish I could do that
and stay as trim as you do.
Shut up, Graham.
I'll finish prep.
See you in there.
God, that was worth it.
I'm trying to get through
every flavor they have
before I cash in.
Please don't say that.
Why? Why be so serious?
Because we're about to
operate on a pregnant woman,
and I have no idea if
you're in any condition...
I told you... You
told me nothing!
You told me you
have a brain tumor,
but I don't know
anything else about you.
I don't know if you're married.
That's not the deal. You
get access to my knowledge.
It doesn't give you
access to my life.
I'm talking about next of kin.
Like if something should
happen to you, who do I call?
God, you are so annoying!
Divorced, no kids.
Marry the work, Robbins.
It's always there for you.
So, um, no family?
I have work and you and Graham.
God, that's the saddest
thing I've ever said.
What kind of
tumor is it? Enough.
I need to know
if this could affect
your motor skills
or your cognition.
You don't need to know
anything that I haven't...
I need to know if I'm
helping you treat patients
with a time bomb in your head!
Robbins, I have a
team of neurosurgeons
who are far more
experienced than you are,
so your input at this point
is nothing more than an
invasion of my privacy.
Stop. Drop it.
So it's inoperable.
Who says? That's it.
You're done. You can't focus.
You're off the surgery.
Graham can do it.
Go do consults. Fine.
Dr. Shepherd, do
you have a minute?
I'm afraid I don't.
I'm Deborah Curzon. I was
asked to come talk to you.
Deborah, I'm really
sorry, but I don't have time.
Dr. Shepherd, I was
asked by the President.
We didn't get a chance to meet
when you were in Washington.
I'm the special assistant to the
President of the United States.
He asked you to talk to me?
About leadership of the
brain mapping initiative.
We had that conversation.
Oh, I remember.
You told him no.
Confidentially, he
doesn't love being told no.
He thought another conversation
was the least you could do for him.
Those were the
words of the President.
We couldn't have had this
conversation through an e-mail?
I know you're busy. I can
wait for you. I'll be here.
You already
started on her chest.
The sooner I see a head CT...
We got here first. I will wait.
Okay, easy. Easy.
Whoa. It's way harder
than the simulator.
Yeah. That's all
right. That's all right.
You'll get it back.
Just concentrate.
Yeah. How does it feel?
It's amazing. Yeah?
Friggin' hard.
If I had a dollar for every time
you said that about something,
I'd buy a whole
robot leg factory.
Suck it, Schultz. He's jealous.
You'll see, man.
You just wait.
I got it. I got it.
Let me go.
You got it.
Don't fall, now. Schultz.
Sweet!
Can I do the stairs?
That's enough for one day.
They don't think you can.
I got this. No. No.
Seriously, don't.
No!
Jordan!
We're gonna need neuro now!
Could be just a concussion,
but it's acting like a bleed.
I've already called CT.
He's gonna be okay, right?
Sir, he's my best friend.
He's got to make it.
We're gonna take care of him.
I'll meet you in the OR?
No. Stay with Rick.
You've done enough.
Is it my fault?
Did I push him too hard?
Can I get a 3D vascular
reconstruction, too?
Do you need that? We need
the images that we need.
In your opinion.
I'll be right back.
Derek, why are you
pushing back on this?
Pierce and I both agree...
I'm sorry, but I
think you're wrong,
and she called
me for an opinion.
She called me for an opinion,
as well. Of course she did.
She probably thought
you could talk me down.
I need a 3D pericardial
reconstruction, please.
Hey.
Look at this. No. Look at that.
He doesn't even
eat with me anymore.
Grey is in my bed
and my bathroom.
I used to eat with my
boyfriend at that table.
Am I being weird?
So, I did an ultrasound
on April Kepner today.
Okay, that's
weirder, way weirder.
It could have been your baby.
Jo, don't talk.
I'm really bad at these,
and I'm pretty sure I'm wrong,
but I think something's wrong
with Jackson and April's baby.
Man, your husband
can really dig in his heels.
You shouldn't have called me. He's
digging in his heels to piss me off.
Or maybe it's a
you thing. Stop it.
I'm just saying, you got
heels, too. You dig. I've seen it.
She agreed with
me to piss him off?
Takes two to tango.
I agreed with you
because you're right.
But you shouldn't
have called me,
not if you think I
can sweet-talk Derek.
I called you because
you're the best surgeon.
Why would you say that?
See? It is a you thing.
What's the matter
with you? Nothing.
I have a patient who got hurt,
and Hunt thinks it's my fault.
I'm divorced again, and
Arizona thinks it's my fault.
And basically I destroy
whatever I touch.
So, by "nothing," you
meant "everything."
Scans are ready.
You gonna pull a muscle.
What are you talking about?
Yuck. Trying to pretend
you're not staring at Pierce.
Your left eye is gonna
pop out of your head.
Ugh! I don't know
what else to do.
I apologized, which
she seemed to hear.
But the next move is hers.
At this point, I just have to sit
here and wait for her to come to me.
Oh, good idea.
Just sit still and
stare like a creep.
That'll get you nothing
more than hardened arteries
and a restraining order.
What is that?
And why on earth do
you keep drinking it?
It's a kale smoothie.
It's healthy.
Kale's a superfood.
It looks like bile.
Doesn't taste much better.
I'm just gonna stay
out of Pierce's way.
Hey, uh, Richard, do
you have a moment?
Yeah, I might. Can I have
you look at something?
How's he look?
CT showed a multifocal
hemorrhage with some edema.
I'll know more
once I'm in there,
but he's gonna need
a full craniotomy.
All right. Page me
when you're out, okay?
I feel like I owe
you an explanation.
About what you heard last week.
You don't need...
I had a pill
problem. I got clean.
Two years ago, I relapsed,
and for a brief
time, I got into oxy
and then shooting oxy.
I lost someone. Um...
That was rock bottom, and I
have been clean ever since.
Listen, Derek told me everything
I need, so you don't have...
I work for you and I
respect you and I like you,
so if it's all right,
I don't care to hang my
professional relationships
on Derek Shepherd's reputation.
I needed you to hear it from me.
I know it's a choice,
keeping me on.
I know I'm a risk.
We're all a risk.
We all have something.
I mean, I have my own version.
And it was different.
It took a different toll.
It still does, and I
push through every day.
And I'm assuming you're
doing the same thing,
unless I see otherwise.
Okay? Okay.
Look at how the air is tracking
through the fascial planes.
We'll have to
debride the neck, too.
We should have
been in there already.
You're scrubbing
in with me, right?
Of course.
Any word from your husband?
No, but when he sees
these, he'll come around.
Pierce, is this your
mediastinitis girl?
That is a massive infection.
This is just in a week?
Yeah, that thing
moves like a track star.
Have you seen the repeat brain
scans yet? Any increase there?
No, but it's already
invading the pericardium.
Yeah, but it's tricky, though.
We should wait until we talk
to Derek, see what they found.
Sorry. "We"? Wait.
Why are you here?
Derek asked me to have a look.
Why? He wanted a second opinion.
Of course. Any opinion but mine.
Just do it. I don't think I can.
It's bad, and I'm not
good at doing bad stuff.
Will you do it? What am I doing?
I can't tell you. It's so bad.
Then what am I doing here?
You know what? I
don't want to know.
Whatever it is, you can do it.
Just do it. Okay. Okay.
Hi. Um, this is Dr. Robbins.
I'm Amelia Shepherd's
fellow at Grey-Sloan.
Um, yeah. I'm calling about
a patient of Dr. Weaver's.
Nicole Herman?
Yep. Uh-huh. No. I'll wait.
She is? Oh, great, great.
Um, Dr. Herman is requesting
that her neuro records
be sent to Dr. Shepherd.
Yeah, yeah,
histories, scans, CTs.
You know what? Actually,
could you send it all?
Yeah. Care of Robbins.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Oh... Thanks for
taking the time.
Yeah, I don't
have a lot of time.
Then I'll cut to the chase.
I was told not to come back
to DC without a "yes" from you.
And I have a dog who's gonna
starve, so I have to get back.
Help me out.
What kind of dog do you
have? Springer spaniel.
Damn it. That's a good dog.
Deborah, I'd like to
help you out, I would,
but turning down this post was
the hardest decision
I ever had to make.
And I made that
choice for my family.
I know he will understand that.
Yes.
He's just a hard
man to say no to.
I know, but I did it, and
I know it can be done.
Good luck.
Hi. Did you get
anything messengered
for, um, Dr. Shepherd? A chart?
It might have been
addressed to Dr. Robbins.
Mmm... I don't...
Looking for this?
Yeah. Yeah.
Thanks.
Is this our Nicole Herman?
Dr. Herman?
What's going on?
It's bad, right?
It's spectacular, a big, bad
mother of an astrocytoma.
See how it ignores
the anatomical borders?
It's like a perfect butterfly.
Look, it starts
in the subfrontal
and extends practically
into the hypothalamus.
That is a thing of beauty.
Is she showing symptoms?
No. No, but she's...
Wait. What kind of
symptoms would they be?
Oh, God. With this, it
could be almost anything
from dizziness, headaches,
uh, vision loss,
inappropriate sexual behavior,
impulse control
stuff, fatigue...
Fatigue?
Uh...
She texted me earlier to say that
she needed to lie down for a while.
Arizona, who else knows about
this? People know about this, right?
Yeah, everybody who
needs to know knows.
But she'd prefer
discretion, you know.
If you could just
keep it to yourself...
Of course. I'm a locked box.
Thanks. See you.
Based on the information we have,
we'd like to take Holly to surgery now
to get out as much of the
chest infection as possible.
Wait. Wasn't there talk
about brain surgery?
We feel we can't
wait any longer.
My throat hurts.
Can we get her some water?
Not before surgery.
Mom, I just want to go
home. Please take me home.
Whatever you think is best.
Just tell us what to do. We'll listen.
Dr. Pierce's approach
is the way to go.
Let's take care of
that chest infection,
and then we'll do
the brain surgery.
Holly? Holly?
What's happening to her?
Step out of the way, please.
Holly.
Her airway's completely closed,
and she's too
swollen to intubate.
I need a crash cart
and a crike tray now!
Right away!
Shepherd said he's
in a coma. Yeah.
Early signs of herniation.
It's impossible to tell
how deep the damage is,
and there's no signs
of him coming around.
I told you.
Hey, I didn't push him.
I know you think I did, but
they pushed each other.
You should have stopped
them. Owen, they're...
You know these guys. There's...
You don't know the
first thing about them.
You don't know what
risk means to them.
Jordan is a 22-year-old kid
who's asked to defuse bombs
left in a supermarket
filled with families.
That's risk to them.
These guys have to
decide in an instant
whether the person
they're about to shoot
is an insurgent with a pistol
or a school kid
with a cellphone.
That's risk.
So, no, they don't see the
danger in stepping up on a stair.
You should have stopped him.
Dr. Herman?
Dr. Herman...
Robbins. Occupied.
Sorry.
Trach tube and dilator.
We got you. We got you.
What happened?
We lost her airway,
so Pierce criked her.
This is what I
was worried about.
This is why I'm
taking her to surgery.
Pierce, I think Derek's right.
What are you even doing here?
Pierce, the steroids you gave
her may have ruptured her abscess.
There's no evidence of
that, and she is hypotensive.
Pierce, with respect, I have
been here longer than you.
You asked for my
advice. You ignored it.
We're doing this. It's done.
You take over.
Book an OR.
As soon as she is
stable, I am taking her up.
Excuse me. Derek,
you cannot just...
Meredith, I am begging you.
This is not about you and me.
This is about this
girl. If we don't do this,
her mother is gonna be bathing
and feeding her for the rest of her life.
I am sure of this. And as
sure as you are, I am, too.
You are pulling rank
here. Meredith, listen.
And you don't have rank to
pull. From what I saw on the...
I mean, can we all agree that
this is Dr. Pierce's patient here?
She is the department
head, and Derek is not,
so if there's any
rank to pull, it's hers.
So, what would you
like to do, Dr. Pierce?
Let's take her up.
How long has that
been happening?
None of your business.
How long? Was it
sudden? Was it just today?
It's happened more than once.
You're jealous.
Okay. It stops now. No more.
You're taking advantage of her.
I beg your pardon.
She's the one in the
power position here.
She suggested it.
I'm just scoring points.
Oh, God, shut up.
Dr. Robbins?
You could try. She's
pretty open to ideas.
Go away. Go away, Graham.
Dr. Robbins, I just need
you to look at this ultrasound.
Yeah. Oh... Sure.
Is it what I think it is?
I mean, it's not, right?
Yeah, it could be,
type II or III maybe.
Oh, God. What's the matter?
I shouldn't say.
Or maybe I should.
I don't know. Tell
me what to do.
This is April Kepner's baby. I
haven't told her. I haven't told Jackson.
I didn't know what to do. I
just wanted us to be sure.
Don't mention it
to either of them.
I'll, uh... I'll ask Herman.
Because maybe we're wrong?
I hope so.
So, what happens now?
Well, listen, take some time.
And we'll get you up
as soon as you're ready.
I'll be ready when
Jordan's awake.
He's going first.
How long till he can walk?
We're not sure
when he'll wake up.
It could be days, months.
I'm not just gonna
give up on him.
Oh, that's if we're lucky.
Look, I know. I know
how bad you feel.
I do.
But it doesn't mean that you
should give up on the possibility
of walking yourself.
I'm sure that Jordan
wouldn't want you to.
Yeah? You know what he wants?
See, he's my best friend.
Oh, no, no, no. I
didn't mean it like that.
See, when I got
shipped home to rehab,
I was ready to give up.
I wanted to quit every day.
But Jordan...
he had this stupid
plastic football
that he'd just throw at
me every time I'd complain.
At my face, hard.
And every day, I
got a little bit better
just so I could
throw it back at him.
He saved my life.
He's gonna wake up.
And when he does, he's
not gonna see that I...
That I stole what's
his, what he earned.
I am so sorry, but we
just... We don't know how...
What are we to you?
What are we, trash?
He broke, so you just throw him
away, move on to the next one?
Screw that.
He's gonna wake up. Rick. Rick.
Are you okay?
Uh...
I will be. I will be.
Could... Could we just pretend
that everything between
you and I is okay,
just for a little bit?
I could use that.
Yeah.
I feel like everything is going wrong,
and I have no idea what to do about it.
I feel...
like every single thing
I am doing is wrong.
You will figure
it out. You will.
You will, too.
Thanks.
Do you miss me at all?
Of course.
Just not enough.
This infection is a lot
deeper than the CT showed.
How are you doing? Okay.
It's really adhered to
her ascending aorta.
Be careful. I'm coming
across a lot of adhesions.
I think this would
be a lot easier
without those two
breathing down our necks.
Welcome to my life.
That girl's brain could
be herniating right now.
She thinks I've been
working against her.
And to be truthful,
I have given her plenty
of reason to believe that.
But that is not the case
right here. I swear it.
Yeah, I know.
And I know how
frustrating it can be
when someone chooses
only to see you one way.
They're both so
much like their mother.
You really screwed
me here, with Pierce.
First the dinner, now
this. You know that, right?
Yeah. Sorry about that.
She's bradying.
Constrictive pericarditis.
I'm gonna have to strip
the entire pericardium.
Grey. I'm here.
Dry laps and a 15 blade, please.
Are they still watching?
You can count on it.
Hey, um, Dr. Edwards and I would
like you to look at an ultrasound.
Have to be later.
Got paged for an
emergency C. You'll assist.
Uh, will you excuse us, please?
Come find me later.
You spoke to Graham?
You spoke to
Graham? I was worried.
Robbins, I don't know how
many orgasms I have left in life,
but it may be fewer
than flavors of ice cream,
so I can't spare any.
Stop stealing my orgasms.
I didn't try... And stop
invading my privacy.
I was worried about you.
It's not your business to be
worried. I'm a doctor. It's my nature.
And you're sick.
And I want to help.
I want to keep you and
our patients out of danger,
and I just found you having
a quickie with Graham.
Graham, okay?
And I have a hard time believing
that that's not a symptom,
and also, it's
against hospital rules.
Robbins, when you have an
expiration date of five months,
it's amazing how many rules
you don't give a damn about.
Graham is a nominal surgeon,
and he's a complete tool,
but he's young, he's attractive,
and he's very physically fit.
What you saw was not
a symptom of a tumor.
It was a symptom of dying soon.
So I'm gonna screw as
many Grahams as I can.
And I totally support that.
C-section. Let's go.
You paged me 911?
Is it a me thing?
Is what a you thing?
God, can you keep something
in your head for like two seconds?
Me and Derek and this patient.
Am I just digging
in because it's him?
911 for this?
I was telling a mom her 5-year-old
has a spinal malformation.
I need two minutes.
Two minutes.
And promise me you won't
crash in my bed tonight.
Because we saved this
patient from organ failure,
but now she could wake
up with brain damage.
What if you were right?
What if he wasn't being a
stubborn, pig-faced jackass?
What if it is me? Take
Shepherd out of the equation.
If it was another doctor you were
going up against, if it was me or...
Someone who was
really good, like Bailey?
Would you have made the
same decision for your patient
if it wasn't him?
Thank you. Sure. And bite me.
I ended up taking a
stand against Pierce.
That doesn't sound like
staying out of her way.
Ah, I didn't know what I
was getting myself into.
I thought it was just a consult.
Shepherd screwed me again.
I don't care for the
way that sounds.
Where are you going?
Up. I got my wrist thingy on.
I've got to get my
billion steps a day.
I feel like I'm making a bunch
of steps in the wrong direction.
Maybe I should
apologize to Pierce.
Apologize?
Haven't you apologized
enough already?
You are a good
man, a great surgeon.
You shouldn't be turning yourself
inside out for her or anybody else.
You deserve better.
And if she can't see that,
she doesn't deserve you.
I'm just afraid I've undone
the progress I've already made.
Okay. Now I'm bored,
bored with kale smoothies
and walking up stairs
and listening to you
talk about Pierce.
You sound like a broken record.
Sorry.
Kale rage talking.
But I'm not wrong.
Do not follow me.
Shepherd, you were
looking for us? Yes.
Uh, Jordan's awake.
He came around.
Thank God. That's great.
Wait. He is awake
but unresponsive.
There's no new or
recurrent hemorrhage,
but it's too soon to know
how much function he'll regain
or if there will be
deficits. I'm sorry.
Does he have people,
besides his friend?
His parents are in Florida.
They're on their way.
Hunt, can I talk to you outside?
Sure.
You have people, right?
What do you mean?
I just mean... I mean,
you're not trying to...
It's hard to deal with
all this stuff on your own.
But you have Meredith
and Derek, so...
Yeah.
And meetings.
I'm pushing through.
That's what we do.
Right.
Do you?
Have people? I'm... That's...
Um, I'm fine. No, I know.
But you're right there,
living in that little tin box
on my brother's back lawn.
I mean, I keep saying
I'm gonna move out,
but I'm still up at the
house, watching them
glare at each other.
Let me know if you, you
know, if you need people.
I'm around. Thanks.
And thanks for the update.
I don't think I can do this. I
think I need to take a step back.
What do you mean? The
program, the vets. I'm...
You were right, Owen.
I don't know these guys.
I'm trying to help them.
I'm ruining their lives.
It was an accident.
I know I was angry,
but you can't just stop.
Rick says he won't move
forward until Jordan's all right.
Callie, that is... Jordan
might not be all right.
And I'm not just gonna throw Rick
aside and move on to someone else.
I can't do that.
So you're gonna just stop
'cause things got hard?
'Cause you're hurt?
That is not acceptable.
You push through it.
You're not gonna give up
on the program or on Rick.
Get him back here.
Owen, for what?
Get him back here, and... I
don't want to give him false hope.
Then give him real hope.
Okay. Okay. I get it.
Stop throwing the
football at my face.
What?
Nothing. It worked.
Okay, Claire, I need
to do a neuro check.
I thought you said the
surgery was successful.
We just have to make sure there
was no problem with the brain abscess.
She could have brain
damage? He's just making sure.
Can you follow this?
Can you give me a good squeeze?
Try and squeeze.
Is she okay?
Dr. Shepherd?
From what I can see...
You know, actually,
why don't we ask her?
Holly, how are you feeling?
Her second surgery for the
brain abscess will be tomorrow,
but I don't foresee
any problems.
Thank you so much.
Mmm-hmm.
Doctors.
Nice work delivering
the placenta.
Your sutures need
improvement, which is surprising.
Now? Yes. Um...
We need to show
you an ultrasound.
Uh, I... I don't trust myself,
and Robbins thinks
we might be wrong.
Robbins, a fetal surgeon
who can't read an ultrasound
is like a chef who
can't boil water.
Just tell me what
I'm looking at.
What do you think
it is? I'm asking you.
I want to know what
you think you know.
I'm concerned that it's
osteogenesis imperfecta.
Define it, please. A
congenital birth defect
in which the child
has fragile bones
that are easily broken
and for no reason.
With the more fatal cases,
sometimes you can
see the fractures in utero.
I assume that we're
wrong. I mean, it's so rare.
What makes you suspect it?
Size and mineralization
of the head,
no movement in the fetus,
short femurs that haven't grown.
Prognosis?
That's what I'm asking you.
It's very sad.
If it is, indeed, type II and
the infant survives birth,
they don't usually live more
than a couple of days or weeks.
Robbins, someone you know?
A friend.
I'm very, very sorry.
There's got to be
something we can do.
I mean, what can I do?
Be there for her.
Oh! Uh, Edwards!
I forgive you. You... Why?
For spilling the beans
about our little Buddha boy.
It was an honest mistake,
and I was a total jerk.
I'm honestly kind
of glad to know.
I'm gonna tell
Jackson tonight. Okay.
Um, well...
I'm sorry.
Uh... Like I said,
it's really okay.
You're really committing
to this thing, aren't you?
Got to get my steps in.
Dr. Webber! Ooh, look
who's coming around.
Do not apologize.
You sided with
Shepherd today. I did.
I want to know why.
Pierce, it was a coin toss.
Could have gone either way.
But, uh, I'm glad it went yours.
I'm not asking for
an "attaboy" here.
You really didn't think the lesions in
her chest warranted immediate care?
Absolutely. But
it was a catch-22,
so I did a quick
risk/benefit analysis,
outcome measurements,
adverse effects.
It makes quite a
quantitative list.
Really?
It's not infallible, obviously,
but it's right most of the time.
May I see it? No.
I do it in my head.
All of... All of that?
Well, uh, I had lots
of years of practice.
I'd be very interested in going over
that list with you if you have time.
Um...
You know, now's
not a great time,
but, you know, maybe I could
catch up with you in the morning
or we could grab coffee.
I would appreciate
that. Thank you.
Can you hurry up?
Hang on. It's Meredith.
She and Shepherd
are having a thing.
Oh, do you want to wait for her?
We could give her
a ride to our place,
save her the trouble
of coming over later.
You could tuck her in, leave
a little mint on her pillow.
Come on. She's
not there that much.
She's always in our bed.
And now Arizona
is in our shower.
I actually feel like I'm
part of a commune.
Shut up. Look, I told
you it's your house, too.
Yeah, apparently, you
say that to all the girls.
Listen, that house
was always open.
Even when Mer hated
me, I could be there.
People went through their
crap, they needed a place to be,
they came there.
You should understand
that more than anybody.
And as long as I'm the...
It stays open, all right?
All right.
And come on.
You in my bed and
Meredith in my bed
are two really different things.
They better be. What,
you need me to prove it?
Uh-huh.
Where are you going?
I think I need more convincing.
Come on!
Can I?
Go for it.
Hey.
There you are.
Listen, I think...
I got your page. Why
are you down here?
Wait. What are you doing?
You told me to be
discreet, so I set up in here.
Nobody comes down here.
No. No. Take them down.
Why? Give it back.
Just give it all back.
If she finds me with
these, she will kill me.
Just... You know what?
Forget that I ever told you.
I thought you said that everybody
who needed to know knew.
Yeah, and that's
her and that's me,
and she doesn't know
that I know all of this, okay?
She cannot find out that
I stole these. Arizona...
I thought that she was
dangerous and reckless,
and it turns out
that she's just dying.
And she's alone and she's smart
and she's funny and horny
and lonely. Arizona, listen...
And she deserves to
die however she wants to.
And I know what to look
for now, and I can watch her.
And she deserves to die with
whatever dignity she can possibly...
Arizona, shut up
and listen to me!
I think I can remove this
tumor. I think I can save her life.
Dr. Herman?
Can I just ask you
about these scans again?
Oh, yes. Good catch,
by the way. Sharp eye.
Is there really nothing
to help their baby?
I mean, if anyone knows
some way to help them, it's you.
Edwards, I wish I
could tell you there was,
but it wouldn't
serve you or them.
Cases like this are
usually hopeless.
This baby would have a very
short, painful life. I'm sorry.
So cute, sitting
like a little Buddha.
What was that about?
I can get the kids if you
want to just go home.
Did you remember Zola's
coat? You forgot it yesterday.
I remembered the coat.
She can't keep going out in the
cold if she doesn't have a coat.
She has the coat.
Yesterday you forgot it.
I remembered the damn
coat. Why don't you trust me?
For God's sakes, Meredith,
of course I trust you.
Why did you call Richard
today for a second opinion?
If that had been
any other surgeon,
Dr. Bailey, would
you have done it?
It was a surgical consult.
It doesn't matter whether
it's a surgical consult or a coat.
You don't trust me, and all
you want to do is fight me.
I don't want to fight with you,
but I'm not gonna
compromise myself, Meredith,
just because you think I...
You've already done that.
You've already compromised
yourself and diminished yourself for me.
I feel that, your pissiness
and your resentment, Derek.
You know why? Do you
know why I resent you?
Because you've never
had my back on this,
not since the day I
told you I would stay.
I told you that you and the
kids were more important.
You have been determined
to prove me wrong,
that this is the wrong choice.
I have proven it, because
you can't be happy here.
You diminish everyone
around you. I did this for you.
I gave up everything for you.
There it is. Everything.
You gave up everything.
That was everything to you?
Where are you going?
Nobody's memory
is perfect or complete.
We jumble things up.
We lose track of time.
Derek, slow down. No. I'm done.
I'm not gonna do this
anymore, this constant battling.
I'm not battling, but I just
am not gonna let you just...
Yes. Yes, you think
I'm some sort of tyrant
determined to keep you down.
You keep you down,
and now I'm paying for it.
And I don't know how to fix it.
You should have just gone to DC.
Is that what you want?
Because that door is wide open.
That's what you want!
Meredith, they offered
me the job again today.
I could take this job right now.
We are in one place...
Derek. MEREDITH: Derek.
Right. Meredith.
Then another.
You should. Take it.
Deborah, it's Dr. Shepherd.
Glad I could catch you.
It was great that
you came by today.
Please tell the President I would
be thrilled to accept the post.
Yes, absolutely.
We can talk more then.
I look forward to it.
I will see you soon.
Good. Go. Oh, I'm going.
No. I mean it. Go now.
And it all feels like one
long, inescapable moment.
Go.
So, what does it mean?
Richard!
What do we take away?
Which pieces will haunt us?
And I was jealous.
So I ruined it.
Hurt us?
Richard!
End us?
Inspire us?
He's very dreamy.
But he is not the sun.
You are.
It's just like my
mother used to say.
"The carousel
never stops turning.
"You can't get off."