We are having a baby.
Morning, Shaun.
- Were you watching me sleep?
- Yes.
We are having a baby.
That baby is making me feel
like I ate three-month-old sushi.
Good morning, berry.
Why are you making
Mommy feel this way?
Are we naming it Berry?
For now, because he's
the size of a blueberry.
I can just picture your face on
a little blueberry-sized baby...
At week seven,
the fetus has developed
webbed hands and feet.
And you have started
to form a mucus plug...
Your breath is
killing me, Shaun.
I brushed my teeth. Twice.
Because I thought
we might have sex.
The mint from the...
The toothpaste is... It's...
Mm-mm.
Stop smirking like
you're picturing me naked.
Don't have to picture
it. Saw it already.
You're running a little late. Did I
keep you up too long last night?
Don't flatter yourself. I'm
not late and it wasn't that long.
What are you doing?
Shielding us from the rain?
What do you think
this is, The Notebook?
It's raining and I
shared my umbrella.
Having sex doesn't
make us a thing.
We need to make
clear boundaries.
I don't need romantic
gestures from you.
I shared my umbrella, I didn't propose.
But I hear your message, loud and clear.
You hate me. I hate you.
See you tonight?
Can I help you?
Hello, Claire.
My name is Miles Browne. I'm...
your father.
- What are you doing here?
- I've owed you a lot of answers
- for a long time, and...
- Go home.
Um... Oh.
I just, uh...
What I... Well, I
wish I was a better...
Um...
I don't want you to... hate...
Can you lift your arms?
Keep them up.
Okay. Repeat after me,
"Don't cry over spilled milk."
Don't... F... Fry...
We need to get you to the hospital.
I think you're having a stroke.
The quickstep is my nemesis.
I lost my footing and
landed on a 90-year-old judge
with very sharp elbows.
And he insisted I come
in even though I'm fine.
Just a little sore.
Yeah, but Maya's "a little sore"
is a normal person's excruciating.
Take the compliment, babe.
You're shivering.
The abdomen is tense and
distended. She's hypotensive.
We need to do an ultrasound to
check for acute abdominal injury.
I'm fine.
When did you start
feeling lightheaded?
About an hour ago.
There is significant pressure
on the abdominal contents.
- What does that mean?
- She has a retroperitoneal bleed.
We need to get you
into surgery right away.
Hi, Mr. Browne. I'm
Dr. Allen, this is Dr. Park.
- How are you feeling?
- Much better.
I see where Claire
gets her good looks.
BP looks good. 124 over 83. Have
you had these symptoms before?
Happens sometimes
when I get migraines.
Yeah. Migraines come
when I'm stressed.
Don't cry over spilled milk.
Look. I don't want to take
up too much of your time,
but is it possible we can go
somewhere quiet and talk?
Maybe we could grab
a coffee or dessert.
You know, you used to
love Rocky Road ice cream.
Is that still your favorite?
You just had a major
neurological event.
We need to run some CT
scans to identify the cause.
Found the bleeder. Clamp.
We need to open up the
retroperitoneal space and pack.
BP's still dropping.
It's not clotting. She have any history
of hemophilia or bleeding disorder?
- No.
- Push FFP, TXA, and fibrinogen.
Pack more lap pads and
evacuate the hematoma.
Pressure's rising.
This young lady almost died
from a collision with an elbow.
There must be something
else going on here.
Find out what it is.
We'll start by scanning your
abdomen. I'll help you up on the bed.
You were right.
It wasn't a migraine.
I have terminal cancer.
His oncologist started him
on chemo, it shrunk the tumor,
but Miles didn't finish it.
The location of the metastases
still likely leaves it inoperable.
I don't know. If we use transcatheter
hepatic artery chemoembolization,
we might be able to attack
the tumor and spare his liver.
Claire, what do you think?
It's the patient's decision.
You should take it to him.
Let him decide.
You have abnormally
large platelets.
It's a rare condition called
Bernard-Soulier syndrome,
which makes it difficult
for your blood to clot.
It's why you almost
bled out during surgery.
Is it treatable?
Will she be okay?
There's no cure,
but it is manageable.
Keep an eye out for pain or bruising or
any other symptoms that don't go away.
That could be a sign
of a larger problem.
- It's just a pulled muscle.
- You don't know that.
My left leg has been
bothering me for a few weeks.
Months.
I'm not overreacting.
We'll need to run CTs
of your hip and femur
to rule out osteoarthritis
or an occult fracture.
- How does that feel?
- Weird.
- Better?
- Sure.
Why do I need this?
Back pain is a common symptom
of pregnancy. It's preventative.
You should take these twice a day,
with food or milk. Preferably food.
I already have
prenatal vitamins.
You have the chewable gummy
kind. Tablets are better for the fetus.
Okay, please stop
calling it a fetus.
- It is a fetus.
- It's our baby.
Okay, I don't need you
to do any of this, Shaun.
What do you need me to do?
Just... be the
dad, not the doctor.
Do you think I'm going
to drink this? What's in it?
Urine? Saliva? A tropical fish?
Coffee.
Dr. Park, I need to talk
to you about our patient.
Let's do an additional
split-thickness skin graft.
That's a long,
complicated procedure.
If you're going to scrub
in, you'll need the caffeine.
I hear you've been keeping
some pretty late nights.
Too much caffeine before
surgery leads to unsteady hands.
I can assure you I am well
rested. I don't need the coffee.
Your father refused surgery.
His slurred speech was
a side effect of chemo.
Treatment almost took him
out. He doesn't want to try again.
Thanks for letting me know.
I know a lot of girls who
didn't have their fathers.
But yours did
something theirs didn't...
he came back.
He came back to
absolve himself of guilt.
That's a gift I'm not giving
him. That's his burden to carry.
Forgiveness isn't for
the one you're forgiving.
It's for you.
It's Miles. His
liver's bleeding.
Go.
They seem like a
very nice couple.
Very... connected.
I wish I knew
how to be like that.
They're not a couple.
Leo's gay.
Can gay people really
detect other gay people?
You can if you check
out their Instagram.
Dr. Murphy...
I don't think she has arthritis,
but I don't know what this is.
Her disorder caused blood-filled
pseudotumors in her leg.
The blood ate away her bone.
Your liver was bleeding because
your tumor exceeded its blood supply.
It puts you at risk for
serious complications...
even a fatal one.
Please reconsider the surgery.
Yeah, I'm not afraid of dying.
Where's my daughter? Why isn't
she here telling me any of this?
I think it's time
for me to go home.
What about 3D
printed scaffolding?
We could recreate the shape
of the bone, graft new stem cells,
and allograft onto it to
generate new growth.
Her underlying disorder
would eat away the new bone.
Everything I do upsets Lea
and makes her mad at me.
Oh, that's what I'm
doing here, I'm guessing?
Mm-hm. Yes. You're both here
because I have two questions.
When I tell my patient her
femur bone is destroyed,
she is going to ask if I can save her
leg and I don't have an answer to that.
Lea and I are in love.
We're going to have a baby.
We should feel
very happy right now,
but I feel like I'm living with a stranger
who doesn't want me to breathe on them.
We could do an expandable
Osseo integrated limb replacement.
- Too risky.
- Too many surgeries, yeah.
Well, you're going to have
a kid, Shaun, and you...
You can't expect
everything to be the same.
Lea's going through
a whole lot of changes.
You both are.
- No. I'm the same.
- Well, maybe that's the problem, Shaun.
You're in a relationship
with three people now.
You're going to have
to make adjustments.
Both of you.
Okay.
We could use
high-density polyethylene
on the distal femoral segment
to anchor it to the tendons.
I don't like adjusting.
You wanted to see me.
If we discharge
him, he's going to die.
I don't expect you would feel
anything but contempt for Miles.
He was supposed to take
care of you and he didn't.
And now I'm asking you to do
for him what he never did for you.
Oh, he did take care
of me. He just quit.
He used to pick me up
every day after school.
And then one day he just...
stopped showing up.
And for years after,
I would come home,
I'd make sure the
curtains were open...
and I'd wait.
If a car slowed down
in front of the house,
I'd imagine it was him coming
to grab me up and rescue me.
And I thought if I wanted
it enough, he'd come back.
So I just had to want
it more, you know?
And finally, I gave up. I
stopped looking out the window.
I grieved and buried my father
a long time ago, and I'm just...
I'm not interested in getting to know
him just to grieve him all over again.
But he's still your father.
And you're still you.
Someday you'll hate yourself
if you turn your back on him.
We would secure the titanium
prosthetic to the hip socket and tibia
using cement augmentation
for stability and support.
You would have full
flexibility and range of motion.
And with physical therapy, you
should be able to dance again.
If you survive the surgery.
- I could die?
- Yes.
There is a 10 to 15 percent
chance. Approximately.
Femur replacement is a
very complicated procedure
made even riskier by
your underlying condition.
The safest route is to amputate.
Very little chance of major
complication during surgery.
And there have been great
advancements in prosthetics.
My dance career would be over.
Most likely. But you
would still have your life.
My life is dance.
Do whatever it
takes to save the leg.
Oh, Maya. It's too big a risk.
But you know what
this means to me.
But if there's a chance
I could die tomorrow,
there's something
I have to do first.
♪ I played my cards wrong ♪
♪ Oh, just a little bit wrong ♪
♪ Baby I apologize for it ♪
♪ I could fall, or I could
fly Here in your aeroplane ♪
♪ And I could live, I could die
Hanging on the words you say ♪
♪ And I've been
known to give my all ♪
♪ Sitting back Looking at
every mess that I made ♪
♪ So don't call me baby ♪
♪ Unless you mean it... ♪
It is very hard to believe
these two are not having sex.
♪ If you don't believe it ♪
♪ Let me know the truth
Before I dive right into you ♪
♪ Before I dive right into you ♪
You should come over tonight...
unless you need to rest up
for your franken-penis surgery.
You embarrassed me
in front of a superior.
Did you get fired? Did you
get pulled off the surgery?
I was just getting you back
for giving me that rancid coffee.
It was coffee.
Plain coffee with one
cream and one sugar.
The exact coffee I've seen you
have every day for the last three years.
I was being nice.
The same reason I put an
umbrella over your gigantic head.
I was being a
decent human being.
When did we start doing that?
How was I supposed to know
that you didn't dose my coffee?
Because I'm not an emotionally
stunted person. You are.
Anything that resembles
intimacy freaks you out
and you start throwing
blows. Low ones.
And if hooking up causes you
to cross boundaries like that,
it's better to go back
to the way things were.
Barely friends. No benefits.
You're in love with him...
aren't you?
Is that why you're
having the surgery?
You're afraid that if you
lose dance, you lose him?
You're risking your life
to save something that...
isn't real.
Leo and I share a life together.
We're partners in every
sense of the word...
except one.
My best friend growing up was...
a girl named Rachel.
She and I lived in a
very religious community
so it was kind of
assumed we'd get married.
Which was fine with me
because Rachel was...
beautiful and smart and funny...
and I loved her.
But then I fell in love with
the boy down the street.
He never knew, nothing
ever happened between us...
but it's like all of a sudden...
the world...
lit up.
And I realized...
Rachel and I wasn't enough.
I had been lying
to myself, and...
to her.
She deserved to be loved...
and wanted in a way that...
lit up someone's world.
And she spent years loving
someone who could never give her that.
You need to tell
Leo how you feel.
We share our
secrets... our pain.
He listens to me when
I've had a bad day.
He holds me when I'm scared.
I don't want anything
to change between us.
♪ I swear to God,
when I come home ♪
♪ I'm gonna hold you so close ♪
♪ I swear to God, when I
come home I'll never let go ♪
Would you like me to spin you?
Okay. Yeah.
Okay.
Ow.
Okay, the swaying is making
me feel really pukey right now.
Could we try this
at another time?
♪ We're fallin' like the
stars Fallin' in love ♪
I feel...
disconnected from you.
And... the baby, which...
yes, you are very connected to
already. But I don't feel anything.
Because it is not a baby yet.
It is a fetus, and...
it is making my girlfriend sick
and mad at me.
And I feel very...
alone.
You are being so...
selfish.
I'm growing your baby, Shaun.
And reading books and
making appointments
and taking vitamins the size of
my face and working a full-time job.
And on top of that,
you just dropped on me
that you don't feel
anything for our baby?
And expect me to make you
feel love and connected and...
No. You know...
Dr. Lim suggested
I come talk to you.
I know you deserve
better than me.
You deserved a father, and I failed
you. And I can't make up for that.
Breeze and I were
high school sweethearts.
We thought we were going
to take over the world together.
We were young
and naive and stupid.
And we got pregnant
before graduation.
I had a scholarship to Howard,
but it didn't cover family housing.
So I gave it up because
I wanted to be there...
Yet you left the family
you gave it up for.
- You should've taken the scholarship.
- And we got married
and we gave it a go for a while.
But I could not handle
Breeze's mental illness.
When we broke up, she
made it hard to see you...
Don't blame her for
what you didn't do.
I am not blaming her.
- I was immature...
- At least she was there.
At least she stuck around,
drunk and sick and
out of her mind...
I... I waited for you
and I loved you and you left.
Claire, I've always loved you.
Nothing could change that.
- I thought about you every single day.
- You know, I don't care.
Thinking about me wasn't enough.
It didn't do anything for me at all.
You...
You could have fought for me.
You could have
come back before now.
I ran away. I was a coward.
And I stayed away
because I was running
from my own guilt.
Whether I'm in your life or
not, you should get the surgery.
Because if you don't...
then you're still a coward.
I feel scared too.
What are you scared of?
Everything.
And I don't want to
go through this alone.
I don't want to go
through nine months
knowing you view this
baby as a medical condition
you don't feel anything for.
I'll resent you.
And that scares me
more than anything.
And I want to help
you feel connected.
Oh, no, sorry. We're
not having sex right now.
I realize that was
misleading. I...
I want you to put your head
on my belly and talk to Berry.
- About what?
- Anything.
Hello...
Berry.
My patient is a
26-year-old ballroom dancer
with Bernard-Soulier syndrome.
She presented with
a retroperitoneal bleed
but now needs a total
femur replacement.
It is a very risky surgery.
I am your father,
and I am a surgeon.
Did that make you feel
better, to talk to him?
No.
The fetus can't hear any
sounds until 18 weeks.
And we don't
know if it's a him yet
because it doesn't have
fully formed genitals.
I will see you at your
appointment later.
I don't think you should come.
There is a chance it's too
early to hear a heartbeat,
which will make me
feel sad and scared.
And if I can hear
it, I will feel happy.
And either way, you
will probably feel...
nothing.
And that'll make me feel
more alone than I already do.
So you should just not come.
Okay.
Isn't it possible Leo loves
Maya as much as she loves him?
Does it matter that he doesn't
want to have sex with her?
Sex isn't just about sex.
It's about intimacy, and desire,
and a deep, mutual,
physical connection.
And she thinks she has that.
That's the last of
the proximal femur.
Let's get the distal end out.
Maybe Maya and Leo have
such a strong relationship
because it's based entirely
on an emotional connection.
She's hypotensive.
There are secretions
around her breathing tube
and oxygen levels are dropping.
She's rejecting the platelets.
Stop the transfusion.
Increase her oxygen
and respiratory support.
Start dopamine and epinephrine.
BP is 87 over 52.
She's stabilizing.
But without the transfusions, her
risk of bleeding out goes way up.
Are we going to move
forward or amputate?
Her partner's her proxy, right?
He's got a decision to make.
Oh, my God.
She trusts me to protect her
wishes, and she wants to dance.
You should try to save her leg.
Maya's in love with you.
That's why she's
having the surgery.
She thinks if she loses dance,
your relationship will end.
And only you
know if she's right.
If she is, if losing her leg means
losing the two things she loves most,
then maybe you
should honor her wishes.
But if she's wrong,
if you do love her and will
stay with her no matter what,
then you should do whatever
it takes to save her life.
Of course I love her.
There's no question
that I love her.
So the only question is...
how much?
Miles is stable.
But we found a
significant polyp burden
not detected on his CT
and we sent to biopsies.
His cancer was caused by
familial adenomatous polyposis.
That's genetic.
Fifty percent chance of carrying the
gene if you have an affected parent.
You need to get a genetic test.
Even if you have the gene,
with regular colonoscopies
- we'll be able catch it as...
- Thank you.
- What's this?
- Male, late 20s,
needs bilateral carpal
tunnel release surgery
that he got playing in the
United States Chess Federation.
You like to play chess with
Kellan. Your game sucks.
Figured you might
learn something.
This is you being
a decent human?
Maybe sometimes
it's not terrible.
This is... delightful.
- I can give it to someone else.
- Thanks.
Are you glad you went to
see your father before he died?
No. My father hurt me.
He was a bad man who did
bad things. I already knew that.
My father hurt me too...
by leaving me.
He didn't even try
to be a good dad.
How can you be sure he didn't?
Maybe he did try
and he couldn't.
Well, if something is important
to you, you make it happen.
But what if you can't?
What if you are trying to
connect with your child and it...
just doesn't work?
It is difficult to feel something
for someone you don't know yet.
Do you want to know what
kind of man your father is?
Why would you do this to me?
I told you I was
willing to take the risk.
I wasn't.
I love you. I couldn't
risk your life. I'm so sorry.
But I'm here.
I'm not going anywhere.
You're not going to lose me.
We're going to get
through this, My.
We'll be okay.
I sleep all the time,
and I'm still tired.
- When was your last bowel movement?
- I don't know, a couple days.
Shaun, what are you doing here?
- Smile.
- Uh, what?
- There's something in your teeth.
- Shaun.
Do you eat a lot
of black licorice?
- Uh, yes.
- You should stop.
Eating too much black
licorice can lower potassium
which causes fatigue
and constipation.
Stop eating it.
- That's it?
- Yes.
Lea doesn't want me at
her OB-GYN appointment.
There's a woman in the waiting
room with a very interesting mole.
The year Maddie was born, I
took on twice as many surgeries.
I... I hid at the hospital.
I was afraid that I was
going to piss off my wife.
Sound familiar?
Upset my daughter.
- I thought you liked being a dad.
- I did. I...
I just didn't think I
was very good at it. I...
It didn't come naturally to me.
Not like... Not
like brain surgery.
I missed a lot.
Sometimes I think if I had
been there for the swaddling
and for the changing
of the diapers and...
see her first steps, you know...
Shaun, do yourself a favor,
and be there for as many
moments as you can.
Taking the scenic route?
Car needs brakes and
Uber was taking forever.
Chess guy is super cool.
He's going to teach me
Petrov's Defense while he heals.
I didn't mean to take things
so far in front of Andrews.
I guess I had a
tiny overreaction.
It's okay for us to be nice
to each other... sometimes.
Headed home?
I wouldn't mind some
company if you're up for it.
See? Nice is good.
Sometimes.
I'll see you at your place.
Where's Leo?
I don't know.
I asked him if this
could be enough.
If I could be...
He loves me, I knew that,
but not enough.
I suppose I knew that too.
As long as he was here,
I would never make
room for anyone else...
so I asked him to go.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
I'm sure there are
a ton of great guys
who'd want to be with a one-legged,
unemployed former dancer
with chronic nosebleeds.
I've been mad at
you for so long...
that I couldn't feel any
other emotion, just anger.
Angry at you...
angry at myself for secretly wishing
you would turn up on my doorstep
my entire life.
I thought I'd outgrown it.
But when you went
into surgery today...
I didn't feel anger, I felt...
fear.
You get some rest.
When you feel better, you...
You can take me for Rocky Road.
It is still my favorite.
I love you.
- Are you ready?
- Mm-hm.
You came.
Hello. I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
I'm the dad.
Nice to meet you, Dad.
We just got started.
- Where did you go to medical school?
- Shaun.
Her diploma is not on the
wall. I would like to know.
Just be the dad. Sit
there. Be quiet. Do nothing.
Is that the...?
That's the heartbeat.
Right there.
We're having a baby.