Surgery is a solo act.
Are you sure you don't
want help with that?
I got it.
Come on. Come on.
We step up to the table
with a scalpel in our hand,
and we go it alone.
You written your speech yet?
Uh, no, not yet. Mer and I
are going out for drinks tonight,
and she's gonna help me.
The isolation can
start to define you.
Because even though
you're surrounded by a team...
So, vodka is writing your
Harper Avery acceptance speech?
Tequila.
What it really comes down to
is your training, your choices,
your wits, your
hands, your stitch.
I'm coming.
To Joe's? You're working.
No, to Boston. Tomorrow.
We can make a
night of it, you know?
Champagne. Room service.
I'm flying out in the morning,
I'm going to the ceremony, and
then flying back on the red-eye.
I'll be gone less than 24 hours.
Cristina, this is the
biggest day of your life.
Did you get a haircut?
Uh, you're changing the subject.
Yep.
It comes down to just you.
It's been two full weeks
of the night shift, Alex.
How long can you
keep doing this?
Well, I haven't dropped yet.
Well, when you
gonna tell Robbins?
When do I have a chance?
I'm doing surgery 24 hours a day
with a dozen 20-minute
naps in between.
You're like a double agent.
It's actually pretty sexy.
Hey, Robbins.
Uh, back away,
Karev. She's off duty.
I was gonna say you
look nice, but whatever.
Aw, thank you. It's date night.
Yeah, listen, we've been on
opposite schedules for weeks,
so if we don't take the time to
sit down and eat a meal together
and remember why
we chose to be married,
we will kill each other.
No sweat. I've got
everything handled.
Enjoy your night. Thank you.
Thank you so much.
You're amazing.
She has no idea
how amazing I am.
Well, I hear we have
a dog bite over here.
This is Jill and her
parents, Kyle and Nicole.
Hi. I'm Dr. Avery.
She says, "It's
nice to meet you."
Now, your dog bit you, huh?
That doesn't seem very nice.
Jill is deaf, too.
Okay.
Well, luckily,
it's not too deep.
And since it's her face, I can
go ahead and stitch it right up.
Nothing to worry about.
He says, "Don't worry."
That's good. Right here, okay?
We are not getting rid of the
dog. She was pulling his tail.
He growled to let her
know he didn't like it.
I know she can't hear.
Excuse me. Kyle, have you and Nicole
considered a cochlear implant for Jill at all?
Yeah, we've talked about
it. We're not interested.
She's the perfect candidate.
She's the right
age, she's healthy,
and now is the time where
she would get the most benefit.
Yes, I told him
"no." It's a "no."
We feel very
strongly about that.
Okay.
See? Now you made her yell.
He didn't say anything
about her being diseased.
You're overreacting.
Oh, no, no. I
apologize. I'm sorry.
We understand and
completely respect your decision.
Let's just get your little
girl all stitched up, okay?
This is a common
complication of gastric bypass.
The connections that your
previous surgeon created widened,
so your stomach pouch and
intestines have stretched out.
So, basically, it's as if I never
had the surgery done at all.
Well, Dr. Grey and
I are confident that
we were able to
restore the anatomy
of the gastric-bypass procedure
back to the way it was
prior to stretching out.
Is anyone here with you?
No.
I had my wife drop me off.
She was there the first time, so I
told her she could sit this one out.
I can handle a couple of
nights in the hospital on my own.
Well, you won't be alone.
There will be someone here to
monitor you throughout the night.
Now, you just get
some rest, okay?
Um...
Given his comorbidities,
he's a high risk for
post-op complications,
which means one of us is gonna
have to stay here with him tonight.
Um...
This is where
you offer to do it.
I kind of have plans.
Ah, the all-nighter, Grey.
It's the experience
that tests you the most,
teaches you the most.
And when you look back on your
career, you remember it most fondly.
I know that because I
did one last Monday night.
That means you're
well-rested. Perfect.
Good night.
- Oh, thank you.
- Kathleen.
Would you find Dr. Shepherd and ask
him to pick up the children at daycare?
I thought we'd take the
lead on gene receptors.
We do gene receptors.
Sir?
Gene receptors are
our bread and butter.
You tell Claesson that if he...
Even when I understand
him, I don't understand him.
You pushed Nova Jenkins'
hippocampectomy again?
Yeah, I had to. I got to take
these calls on Gdansk time.
You referred three cases to
the Cleveland Clinic last week.
This is not okay, Derek.
People come here for you.
You still work here.
You're the one who talked me
into this project in the first place.
Webber tells me that
you canceled your lecture.
That's the fourth time you
canceled on the residents this month.
I know that
something has to give.
But not surgery, and it
can't be teaching either.
I'll handle it. I've
got it handled.
Hello? Dr. Shepherd?
Yeah. Hold on a second.
The lectures will happen,
and just put Nova Jenkins' surgery
back on the boards for tonight,
and I'll handle it.
Okay.
Dr. Shepherd?
Dr. Shepherd? DEREK: Yeah.
Dr. Grey wanted me to remind you
to pick up the kids at daycare tonight.
Yes, got it. Got it handled.
Excuse me, Dr. Shepherd.
Are you there?
Yeah, hi. Sorry.
Hello? Dr. Shepherd?
Braden's bone marrow
extraction went very well,
um, but he's gonna be
in some pain for a while.
Hey, you did great,
Braden. We're almost there.
Mmm. Cool.
Can you explain it to
us one more time? Yeah.
Because it still sounds like
you're gonna give our son HIV.
No. Um, it's gene therapy.
Braden lacks the ADA enzyme.
Without it, he has no immunity.
So in order to get it into him,
I'm going to deliver it
on a fast-replicating virus.
The HIV virus.
Yes, which will disseminate the
enzyme until it grows on its own.
You want to inject him with HIV?
No, not per se.
Um, for the past two weeks,
I've been working to
genetically disable an HIV virus.
Okay, the HIV is
like a hat, okay?
The virus is what matters.
I've taken off the HIV hat, and I'm
gonna make it wear an enzyme hat.
I know. It sounds
counterintuitive and scary.
But I think this
is his best shot.
We trust you.
Okay.
Hey, we're gonna go, champ.
You gonna be okay?
He's probably gonna
sleep for the rest of the night.
Well, sweet dreams, Brady bug.
Hey, dream about
replicating genes.
Or bunnies.
Thank you.
Hey. Why aren't you dressed?
Whoa. I, uh,
can't... I can't go.
I have to babysit
my bypass patient.
Oh, come on. Tomorrow,
everything changes.
I won't have
time to talk to you.
I'll be too busy
being better than you.
Good thing it's not
gonna go to your head.
Oh.
The speech.
Uh, thank people and be
funny because people love funny.
There's nothing funny
about babies with HLHS.
You're no help to me.
Alex, tonight is
your lucky night
because I will go
drinking with you.
Can't. Working.
Kepner. Yeah?
Never mind.
Okay.
Hey, I just wanted to
check in before I go.
Kids, Dr. Yang's
here. Say hello.
Hi.
I'm sorry.
Jon bought them these tablets,
and it's destroying their brains.
I'm always the bad guy.
It was a joke, Jon. JON: Uh-huh.
Oh, I'm just gonna
be gone for 24 hours,
so you can call
Dr. Hunt if you have
any questions or problems, okay?
Enjoy it. Okay.
What? What did I
say now? Nothing, Jon.
Don't "nothing." What? Nothing.
You get to go
every day. To work.
Still, you get a break.
And then I'm here every
night, Sabine, after I work,
then check on the house,
run our errands, do the laundry.
I come here to play with the
kids so you can get a break.
You play with the kids? Really?
You hand them tablets,
and then you watch sports.
We're basically
living in a hospital.
I can't exactly go out and toss
a ball around in the backyard.
Mom, Dad. - You can go, Sabine.
I have to go. Okay.
You can go anytime I'm
here, but you don't dare
because you're the only
decent parent. I never said that.
You never say
anything! You jab at me!
You guys, you're
giving me a headache.
And then you back away
and act like nothing happened.
Jon, cut it out! Okay, you
guys need to just bring it...
No. Damn it, Jon. Just
go. If you want to, go!
We can't go anywhere!
Okay, Sabine, sit down.
Jon, you need to leave.
Where am I supposed to...
I don't care, but you
need to go right now.
But that's not fair.
Karaoke's my thing. Now,
you can't go without me.
Wait. This is a karaoke bar?
It's a regular bar that
happens to have karaoke.
How is that different?
It's totally different,
and that's something I know
because karaoke's kind of my thing.
If it makes you feel any better,
I'm also gonna be missing out.
I'm just coming
off a 32-hour run.
All I really want is a hot
bath and a soft pillow.
Aw! Gramps, how about
a glass of warm milk, too?
See? You mock. But
actually, that sounds fantastic.
Okay, everybody, get out of
your streets and into your scrubs.
I'm gonna teach you
everything there is
to know about a hippocampectomy.
But you canceled that lecture.
Yes, I did, and I
did you a disservice.
Not only is it a rare procedure,
it's one of the most delicate and
elegant a neurosurgeon can perform,
which you will see later tonight
when you scrub in with me.
Tonight?
Unless you have
something else better to do
than to cure a young girl of her
debilitating seizures, Dr. Warren.
No.
Hmm.
Hey, Miranda.
Hey, come look at my virus.
I can't. I thought I
was going home.
But Shepherd's got
us pulling an all-nighter.
Oh. Um...
What are you doing?
Watching my virus chill.
Hmm. That's, um... That's crazy.
I just removed stem cells
from Braden's bone marrow
and injected them
into this disabled virus.
I just pulled a 32-hour shift.
You see, I should be
sleeping, but I'm working.
And you are here
and have no work.
You should go home
and sleep. For me. Hmm?
I'm just gonna
watch. Go to sleep!
"Boundaries are only
there to be pushed.
"I am grateful for the
opportunity to have pushed.
"I'm also grateful
for the recognition."
How's that?
It's nice.
It's kind of braggy.
Well, it's supposed to be braggy.
I'm winning an award. My turn?
Mmm-hmm.
Wow.
Yes, I have very steady hands.
Braggy.
What are you still doing
here? Oh, hey, um...
Well, a bunch of stuff happened.
Ivy, your head okay?
Yeah, it's just a
headache. It's getting better.
Jon and Sabine had
a complete meltdown.
I kicked him out, and she's
downstairs getting coffee.
I am trying to
distract the kids.
My drinking buddy is
stuck at the hospital,
and I still have to
write my speech.
So will you help me?
Hey, Frankie. I can't sleep.
Want to play hide-and-seek?
Can I? 15 minutes.
Wait, uh.
You paged me to
listen to your speech?
Maybe.
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, come on. You
can't be that busy.
There he is. You
ought to be ashamed.
Chelsea, don't yell at
him. He's doing his best.
No. Nova, you're sweet.
But you're a pushover, and
you won't say this, so I will.
She's sick, and you
keep jerking her around,
scheduling her surgery, then
canceling it, scheduling and canceling.
She hasn't eaten in two days and has
had three seizures in the last six hours.
You're absolutely right.
I'm sorry it's
been so difficult,
but we are going
to do the surgery.
When? Tonight.
The OR is available at 1:30,
so, technically, it's the morning.
Really? Really.
Finally.
Mmm-hmm.
Well, there you go.
See what a little
backbone will get you?
1:30 a.m. That's
still hours away.
Well, don't worry, Dr. Warren.
I just got a page from the ER.
We'll have plenty to do
before then. Come along.
Aw, poor Gramps. I'm fine.
What happened?
His blood pressure is dropping,
and his heart rate is in the 130s.
NG tube lavage is clear.
He's got a GI bleed, either from
the remnant or
the JJ staple line.
Activate the massive
transfusion protocol.
Call the OR and let
them know we're coming.
Get me a second-year resident.
I'm gonna need extra hands in there.
None of the second years are
available. They're all with Dr. Shepherd.
Dr. Shepherd isn't
even in the hospital.
He is. He has surgery scheduled.
Then where the hell are my kids?
And it's not like I'm insensitive
to deaf culture or anything.
I just don't...
I don't get how, as parents,
you don't want your kid to
experience hearing, if they could.
What? You disagree?
They're her parents,
Jackson, not us.
Yeah, well, if that was our kid, she'd
be fitted for an implant three years ago.
Really?
Yeah.
Just like that?
What if I felt
differently about it?
Do you?
Yeah.
Oh, okay.
Don't do that.
Don't dismiss how I
feel. My opinion matters.
I am one half of
this relationship.
It's my kid, too, and it's not
getting a cochlear implant.
All right. It's important that
we immerse them in the deaf
community, who consider deafness,
by the way, to be a
blessing and not a disability,
instead of just opting
for an elective surgery.
I'm sorry. A blessing?
What happened?
Ivy spiked a fever,
and she's experiencing
some shortness of breath.
Mom, is everything okay?
Not now, honey.
Can I keep playing?
Uh, yeah. Sure,
sure. Just stay close.
I'm going to book an OR
and do a biopsy right away.
You should call Jon
and get him back here.
Why? What's going
on? What's wrong?
I think Ivy is
rejecting her heart.
This remnant is
completely distended.
Try his cell again.
All right, I'm performing a gastrotomy
to remove this intraluminal blood.
Keep transfusing until I
get the bleeding controlled.
Suction. Lap pad.
More suction.
Hi, you've reached Dr. Shepherd.
Please leave a message,
and I will return your call.
Derek, the daycare is closed,
the babysitters have
not heard from you,
and no one is answering at home.
Where are our children, Derek?
Now, a ring fracture almost
always causes the dura to tear.
You need to take care
not to make it worse.
Murphy, get in here
and help her retract.
You need to see where
you're going as you extract.
Dr. Shepherd, this man
flatlined five minutes ago.
Yeah, that's true,
but this is a great
opportunity to learn
on an actual brain.
It does seem a little strange.
If by "strange," you
mean "awesome."
Dr. Shepherd? DEREK: Yes.
Dr. Grey's in OR 3 and needs
to speak to you right away.
Right. Okay, where's my phone?
Where did I put my lab coat?
Thirty seconds.
Just 30 seconds.
Oh, wow, you just spit
up all over my pretty dress,
didn't you, Bailey?
Okay, I canceled
the reservation.
Shepherd owes us big time.
He said he owes us, right?
Yes. Something about
taking Sofia for the weekend
so we could have a getaway,
and I'm holding him to it.
Um, Callie, can you hold
him? 'Cause it's dribbling.
Yeah. Oh, here.
Hi! Look at that, Bailey.
Yes, hi. Hello. Yes, hi.
Look at that.
Oh, my gosh.
You forget what it's like
to have one this small.
How did we do it before?
Oh, well, we had Mark.
God, I miss Mark.
Yeah, I miss him, too.
And three's a lot.
Makes me think we
should stop after I
have this next one.
What do you mean after
you have the next one?
Oh, well, I meant "we."
I was just saying "I" 'cause
I'm gonna, you know, have it.
Oh, you're gonna
have the next one?
I didn't know that
we decided that.
I didn't know there
was anything to decide.
Amazing.
Fantastic.
Disgusting! Edwards.
I'm sorry, Dr. Shepherd.
Yeah, don't apologize to me.
Apologize to Mr. Quaid.
I'm sorry, Mr. Quaid.
It's cool.
It's gross. Super gross.
Hey, Doc. Hmm?
Figure out how you're gonna get
these bastards out of my noggin?
Yes. It will be a very
careful, very precise yank.
Oh, me! Me, me, me!
Do I have to do that thing where
I acknowledge the losers?
'Cause I have like five minutes.
I don't want to waste it on
people I don't even know.
Mmm. It is a courtesy.
You're nervous.
You know, I know you
think that I'm too busy,
but I can make it work, if
you don't want to be alone.
But I do.
Wait, you think
you're gonna lose?
Let me go alone.
I'll update the family.
Uh...
Come on. Don't be such a weenie.
I'm not being a weenie.
You're kind of being a weenie.
Murphy, the shears
have only hit areas
of non-eloquent brain function.
The risk of further
damage is minimal.
So go ahead. Pull it out.
Wait.
Okay, vessels intact. Go ahead.
Oh, for God's sake,
she's not going anywhere.
Dr. Shepherd, permission
to step in. Mmm-hmm.
Thank you.
Okay.
Well, that was a little much.
Way to go, Lady Hulk.
Get ready for a big bleeder
and a crash-dive craniotomy.
In your face!
Not you, Dr. Shepherd.
Um, irrigation.
Nova Jenkins is prepped
and ready for surgery.
Okay, great. I've got a little bit
more to do with Mr. Quaid here.
But, guys, go eat and hydrate.
I'll see you in the OR in
about eight minutes. Hustle.
Derek.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Where the hell are my kids?
Don't do that!
Don't walk away from me when
I'm in the middle of a sentence.
Can we just go to bed, please?
I can't sleep now,
not when you're willfully
ignoring my wishes, my beliefs...
About what? Our fictitious
child? It's irrelevant.
You know how slim the
chances are of our kid being deaf?
That is not the point!
What is the point?
You think they're stupid.
You think that they
are being bad parents
because they want to raise
their kid differently than you would.
Come on. I never said
that. You are judging them!
You think they're ridiculous.
Why are we arguing about this?
Because it means you
think I'm ridiculous, too!
Wait a second. What?
Replace "cochlear implant"
with the word "christening,"
"Bible study,"
"prayer."
Now tell me this has
nothing to do with us.
Come on. Pick
up, pick up, pick up.
Jon, where are you?
They just took Ivy up to the OR.
They think that she's rejecting her heart.
I can't find Frankie.
She disappeared.
You just have to get back here.
Call me as soon as you get this.
What do you mean
you can't find Frankie?
Don't you know where she is?
Whoa.
What?
Watch out.
Well, she usually hides
somewhere over here.
Gotcha.
Bam! Gotcha, Frankie!
Wake up.
Wake up. Frankie, wake up!
Wait, hold on, Braden. Back up.
Left, left, left. Hold it.
Back up. Back up.
Right. Right, right.
Hold it. Back up. Back up.
Oh! Oh, crap.
Frankie!
Do you know where she is?
No, crappy camera couldn't
zoom in on a room number.
She's in a linen storage.
Well, which one? I don't know.
That one.
Pulse is faint.
Let's get her on a
bed and on a monitor.
Ivy's biopsy sample's
on its way to path.
Frankie's in heart failure.
Karev and I ran an EKG.
It's not her pacemaker.
She needs an LVAD.
Crap. These kids are like surgical
dominos. Okay, let's get her ready.
Karev's prepping her in OR
4. What time's your flight?
It doesn't matter.
Three hours?
For three hours, Derek, I had
no idea where our children were.
I had my hand inside
a guy's stomach,
and all I could think was...
I told you I had it handled.
You told me you had them.
I thought I did. I had a
surgery. I had to teach.
Hunt and Webber accused
me of dropping the ball.
You dropped this ball.
If you put our kids somewhere,
Derek, you have to tell me.
Let's just step
back for a second
and take a look that
the kids are fine, okay?
I just forgot to make
a phone call, okay?
Now I've got a
surgery to get to.
Mmm-hmm. No, they're
fine. Zola's asleep.
And Bailey was out like a light.
No, I don't. I don't know
why Derek didn't tell you.
Yeah.
No, not a problem. Anytime.
Okay. Bye.
Mmm.
I never would have just assumed
you didn't want
to carry our child.
Mmm-hmm.
You said, "I can't take
another loss. It's too hard."
I took that as a "no."
And I was afraid that if I asked
you again, it would make you too sad.
Okay, that was a year ago,
and there was a lot going on,
and maybe I changed my mind.
Have you? I don't know. Maybe.
Arizona, if it would make you
happy, it would make me happy.
Yeah, Yeah. But do
you think I should?
Now, with this approach, we go straight
down the barrel to the hippocampus.
Questions?
Stop. Okay, hold it.
Here. Let's just slow down.
Here's what we're gonna do.
I'm gonna have each one of you
take a turn next to
me at the microscope.
Whoever is at the microscope
will ask one question.
Ross, you go first.
Where's Gramps?
Who cares? More
microscope time for us.
Good point.
Okay, I think you're
blowing this out of proportion.
Am I? Because this is who I am.
At my core, this defines me.
And I know that.
I love you still.
Oh, well, thank you. Thank you
so much for loving me anyway,
despite my beliefs,
despite my faith,
which I happen to hold
above everything else.
You're twisting my words. It's
not... And you're ignoring mine!
You don't accept who
I am or what I believe.
You tolerate it. You judge it.
You judge my faith
because you don't have any.
I have faith. I have
faith in medicine.
I have faith in helping people.
That's not faith! Faith is
believing in what you can't see.
Will you just admit it, Jackson?
You think what I
believe is ridiculous.
Yes, because it is! Yes!
Your God is like our
hypothetical deaf child, April.
It's not real.
Look, all right, I'm sorry.
It doesn't mean I don't
respect you. It's just...
God, I just feel...
I just feel sorry for you.
You don't know how
to believe in something
you can't touch
or feel, and that...
is so sad.
So you pity me.
I do.
I really do.
We should go to sleep.
Looks like Frankie's
LVAD has good flow.
I agree. Passing the cannulas.
Got it.
Thioproline. Start
protamine, please.
Alex, you're still here?
Night shift. You're still here?
Yes, we're all still
here, obviously.
Did you finish your speech?
Nah, I'm just gonna wing it.
It's weird. They've
made their decision.
Your name is typed on a
piece of paper in an envelope.
I know. I always
figured I'd read
about you winning
the Harper Avery.
I didn't think I'd be operating with
you the night before you won it.
When is the last time we all
pulled an all-nighter together?
Third year?
Oh, God. Look at us
now. You've got two kids.
I mean, you're about to win
a Harper Avery. And Alex...
Oh.
Sad.
Shut up. I got my own stuff.
What stuff?
Oh, lying. Sadder.
A private practice is interested in
me, and I think I'm gonna take it.
A private practice? Is
this the butthole guy?
I've been moonlighting
over there, taking some shifts,
just to see if I get
along with his partner.
Don't tell Robbins.
And I'm killing it. Oh.
And I'm killing
it here at night.
I'm killing it 24 hours a
day, and I can't tell anyone.
Private practice? Why in the
world would you want that?
Because my fellowship is ending,
and it's a crapload of money.
And I didn't come from
a rich family like you,
and I'm probably not gonna
win a Harper Avery anytime soon.
Hmm, that's true. Screw you.
She might.
Might? Screw you.
You don't think this is silly?
No!
Okay, 'cause we're not
picking a movie or takeout.
This is... It's a bigger deal.
Yeah, this feels right.
Okay.
I mean, flipping a
coin feels right. Okay.
It feels decisive. It's done.
Okay, great. Fine. Fine, fine, fine.
Okay, heads,
I will get pregnant
and carry our child,
and tails,
I get pregnant
and carry our child.
Okay?
And however it lands...
That's what we
do. Right? All right.
Okay. Right.
No! You know what? You do it!
I'm sorry.
I don't want to.
And you did it last time,
and it was so beautiful.
Just I don't want to. I
want you to. I want you to.
Is that bad? Am I terrible?
No, you're not terrible.
Will you do it? Please?
Okay, wait, now hold on.
Do you want to?
I would love to. Oh!
Oh.
I'll flip you for it.
All three of them are
on the transplant list?
I'm afraid so.
Ivy's biopsy results confirm that
she is, in fact, rejecting her heart.
But we are treating her
with anti-rejection medication.
Frankie went into heart failure.
I put in an LVAD to
help her heart function.
We've called UNOS
and put both Ivy
and Frankie on
the transplant list.
With Link. God.
We started the day with
one on the list, but three?
Do you want us
to call Jon for you?
He hasn't picked up
the phone once tonight,
and I've already filled his
mailbox with voicemails.
They say this breaks
couples apart, sick kids.
And we talked about that, but
we didn't think it'd happen to us.
But then we didn't think
any of this would happen,
happen to us.
Is this what it looks like?
Is he gone?
This is when
visibility gets difficult.
So why don't we use a
self-retaining retractor?
You can't with a
keyhole incision.
You risk damaging the
anterior choroidal arteries,
which could result in what?
Infarction of the internal capsule
and adjacent basal ganglia.
Edwards, step
back. Wilson, step up.
Man.
How can we tell if the patient
has suffered a PCA infarct?
We wouldn't know until
after she'd woken up.
Okay, good. And
what symptoms would
we look for with a
lesion in this area?
Contralateral hemiplegia,
superior quadrantanopia,
and amnesia.
Okay, Wilson, you're
out. Murphy, you're up.
I was right. Well,
yes. You were.
But nobody likes a know-it-all.
We have a bleeder.
I need visibility
in there, Murphy.
Oh, no, no, no! Not the clamp!
Murphy, what did I say?
I'm sorry. It's just...
It was just instinct. My
hand just went there.
Take a step back.
I'm sorry. Is she gonna be okay?
Just quiet, please.
Dr. Shepherd... I said be quiet!
Do they know where we are?
I was very specific.
Well, I hope this cab doesn't
make you miss your flight.
Oh, God.
My bypass patient's
in V-fib. I got to...
Go, go, go. Save a life.
Okay. Good luck. Okay, thanks.
You know, maybe we should just
call the cab company and make sure...
You know, Owen, it'll be fine.
There's no traffic this
early. I'm not checking a bag.
I've got time.
Oh.
You got to go, too.
No, no. I can wait a second.
MVC pileup on the freeway.
You don't want to ignore that.
I want to see you off.
I'll be gone all of 24 hours.
This isn't some
glamorous goodbye.
I'm catching a cab. I know
how to send myself off.
You sure?
Owen.
Go, go.
Okay, all right.
Knock them dead. Okay.
Nurse's station. Yeah.
Dr. Warren,
we have an on-call
room for this.
Hmm?
I heard Dr. Shepherd had you on
an all-night surgery. How did it go?
Crap!
Kids.
Nova, can you hear me?
Why isn't she answering?
Nova?
Now, if you can
understand me, blink.
Nova.
Is...
it...
okay if I just say "yes"?
Or is the blinking
medically necessary?
That works for me.
I can absolutely blink, too.
It's really no trouble.
So, everything's good here.
Now, Dr. Murphy will be in
charge of your post-op care,
and she will be in every hour
to give you a neuro check.
All you have to do
right now is just rest.
Sounds good to me. Okay, good.
Murphy, doctors
don't cry in hallways.
We have stairwells for that.
I'm sorry. I'm just so relieved.
Yeah, you got lucky today.
Nothing bad happened,
but it could have.
And if it had, it would
have been on you.
So remember that
feeling, that "what if?"
Not the relief.
It'll keep you from
making that mistake again.
Yes, sir.
What did I miss?
Sabine?
Honey.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I fell asleep. I
was right outside.
I went to sit in the
car and cool off,
and I fell asleep, and my phone
died, and I never should have left.
I should have
been here with you.
You shouldn't have been alone.
I'm sorry.
I love you. I love you so much.
I'm so sorry.
I don't know how you do it.
I don't know how you
can be a double agent.
I come off of even
one all-nighter,
and I feel hollow, jangly.
Do you ever get that?
The hollow janglies?
Alex.
I'm good.
No, we're good on
magnetic resonance.
We don't need any more of the
groups on magnetic resonance.
UCLA's got that.
Hey, let me call you back.
I'm sorry.
I should have called you.
I dropped the ball.
This ball can't get dropped.
I know. Nothing catastrophic
has happened yet, but it could.
We're juggling too much.
Something has to change.
Are you saying it has to be
me? I'm not saying that, Meredith.
I'm just saying that
something's got to change.
I know. I know. I just...
I don't know what to do.
Oh, neither do I.
But I do know that
I need you to
take the kids today.
Can you do that for
me? Of course, yes,
and I will update you
on our position hourly.
You don't have
to do that. I just...
No, but I will.
Okay. All right.
Who's here?
April?
Can I stay here
for a little while?
You were right!
I got a good night's
sleep. I slept like a log.
Got up this morning.
I made some homemade
French toast with bacon.
Candied bacon, if
you want to know.
I even had time
to read the paper.
Now I'm gonna go
check on my virus,
which also got a good
night's sleep, thanks to you.
And now you can go
and get some sleep.
I left your favorite
tea on the counter.
Well, actually, I managed
to squeeze in a power nap.
So I'm feeling all right. Hmm.
I'm gonna scrub in on a shoulder
replacement with Torres in a few.
Well, aren't you Superman?
Thank you so much.
Excuse me. Dr. Yang?
Dr. Robert Bonocore.
Cleveland Clinic?
Oh, yes, the epilepsy
neurostimulator. It's so nice to meet...
I am a big fan. Huge, really.
I have read all of your
work on the conduits.
It's just fascinating. Truly.
Thank you. Thank you.
You're Cristina Yang. Yes.
Where are you with phase two?
We're all waiting to see
if we can get our
hands on it. Oh.
Okay, I understand you're
still a cardiothoracic fellow.
Yes. When do you finish up?
I imagine everyone's
asking you that.
You must be thrilled to be
nominated so early in your career.
Any relation to Dr. Tara Yang?
She was my roommate at
UPenn. She was so funny.
Oh, I'm unfortunately...
Oh, looks like it's time. - Oh.
Well, congratulations.
I'll see you in there.
Thank you. Very
nice to meet you.
Oh, uh, excuse me.
Okay, great.
Cristina? Mer, I made a mistake.
I don't want to be here
alone. You should be here.
And we should be drunk.
Why aren't we drunk?
And I want Owen
here. He could, like,
hold my purse
and tell me things...
Oh, my God. And tell
me to wear deodorant.
I forgot to wear deodorant,
and now I stink and...
Where are you? Are you at
the table? You know what?
Forget it. I'm... I'm fine.
Surgeons are
trained to go it alone,
to be solo artists,
to be mavericks, both
in and out of the OR.
But the truth is,
we are never alone.
What?
Owen.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
Thanks.
I finished my speech.
I have it right here.
It took me six hours in a middle seat
with a mini bottle of overpriced tequila,
but it's gracious
and not braggy.
I think you'll like it.
We stand on the shoulders of
those who came before us.
Surgery is the boldest and
most fearless of the healing arts.
We stand side by side with the
colleagues who have supported us,
prepared us...
The Harper Avery
award celebrates
those who have
destroyed the obstacles,
altered the direction,
and invented the future
of how we are to live
and heal and thrive.
The surgeons in this room
are redefining medicine
for generations to come.
For the moment that
every surgeon lives for...
And so I am very
pleased to announce
this year's winner.
When it all comes down to
your training, your choices,
your wits, your
hands, your stitch...
The Harper Avery
award goes to...
when it all comes down to you.
Dr. Ronald Myers,
Johns Hopkins Hospital.