The human heart
is a giant muscle
squeezing or contracting
over 60 times each minute.
That's 3,600...
At this point, your
blood is a deep purple
because it's just finished
dropping off oxygen
for all the parts of your body.
Come on, follow me.
Come on.
Ian.
I have a question, and I
need to go to the bathroom.
Which would you
like to do first?
The question.
Okay. Where's the bathroom?
Who knows where the bathroom is?
I do.
Go with Ian to the bathroom.
I don't have to go.
We're not at school, nobody
goes anywhere by themselves.
Why? In case you get lost.
Or in case somebody kidnaps us.
If somebody kidnaps
Ian, they'll kidnap me, too.
I want to stay with the class.
Michael, go with Ian...
Do you need help?
I need you to find a grown-up.
Is the baby coming?
Who should I take
with me? You're fine.
Go to the front desk
or find a security guard.
I really have to pee.
Oh, God.
Is the baby coming? I
don't know how to do this.
Are you okay, Ian?
Yeah. Sure.
I don't think you are.
You're bleeding.
Help!
$20. Call.
You'll call anything.
My stack is bigger
than your stack.
You in or out?
You know that
relative to their size,
gorillas have smaller
testicles than humans.
Well, then you'd probably have an
edge over a gorilla, but not over me.
Reason is, primate testes' size
inversely corresponds to
the fidelity of our females.
You think there might be a better
time to annoy me about my wife?
I'm talking about poker. Right.
Women are evil, you're
right to drive them away.
Call, fold or raise.
Story time can wait.
We're smaller and
better than chimps,
bigger and worse than gorillas.
For all our rationality,
our supposed trust and
fealty to a higher power,
our ability to create a
system of rules and laws,
our baser drives are more
powerful than any of that.
We want to control our
emotions, but we can't.
If we're happy,
things don't annoy us.
If, on the other hand, we're
sitting on crappy hole cards,
little tiny things annoy
us a whole lot more.
I raise.
So, are you gonna tell me an
annoying story every time I raise?
God, that would be annoying.
I call.
Dr. Cuddy, I got one of
your patients in the ER.
Ian Alston, six-years-old.
Oh, I know him. What's
the problem? I'm all in.
Bloody diarrhea.
Hemodynamically stable,
but he's been developing
some coordination problems.
It sounds like gastroenteritis
and dehydration.
Order fluids and I'll
take it on my service.
Bet's to you, House.
They scan his head?
No, why would they scan...
Don't play games.
You gonna call?
How's the heart rate? Stable.
I'm sorry. House, it's gastroenteritis.
I'm not going anywhere.
Put the order in,
and have someone tell Alan and
Sarah that I'll be up when I'm done.
You in or out?
I'm out.
Stone cold bluff.
You might want to spend a little
more time paying attention to your cards
and a little less time
staring at my breasts.
They don't match either.
I'm gonna take some air.
Follow my finger with your eyes.
How much longer
will Dr. Cuddy be?
Well, given the number of Mojitos
she's knocking back at the party,
I'd say it's gonna be at least three
hours before she's even conscious.
Weren't you at the same party?
I don't drink.
I want you to reach
out and grab my cane.
What's wrong?
Your son's brain is losing
control of his muscles.
Dr. Cuddy's message said it
was just dehydration from diarrhea.
She's wrong.
Is he gonna be all right?
I don't know.
So, were you in
one of those cages?
No. No, no, no, no. No,
those are for tourists.
You were in the water
with the great white?
Sure, it's no big deal. You just
have to keep an eye on them.
If they get too close,
punch them in the nose.
Send them on their way.
I had you going.
You are mean.
Hey. How's that anal fissure?
Did it heal yet? Or
is it still draining?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't realize you'd
come back for seconds.
I figured that after that girl in the
stairwell you'd be done for the night.
He's joking.
No Adam's apple, small hands.
It's no surprises this time.
I'll see you later.
Got a case.
Well, you could've
just said that.
You didn't have
to screw with me.
Yeah, if I didn't
screw with you,
you'd spent the whole night
thinking you might get laid,
which means you'd be useless.
Better to extinguish all hope.
Get Foreman and Cameron
and meet me upstairs. Stat.
What's so urgent?
Two cases, same symptoms.
What do six-year-olds and
70-year-olds have in common?
Their immune systems
don't work as well.
Could be listeria. I
already checked for that.
Leukemia has a higher
prevalence in both young and old.
- So does asthma.
- No, no, no.
They can both get diabetes.
No!
The nearly dead
and the newly bred
have more in common with each
other than with people in the middle.
It's weird. It's kind
of a circle of life thing.
This kid doesn't have
kidney failure. He will.
Based on this file, the
kid just ate some bad food.
Was the old man...
They were nowhere near each
other in any of the four dimensions.
This case is 12 years old. Yep.
And this case is Cuddy's.
She assigned it to me.
She agrees with you that this is
something more than gastroenteritis?
She wouldn't have assigned it
to me if she didn't, would she?
What were we talking about?
Two patients with two
symptoms in common.
And five symptoms not in common.
While you were all wearing
your "Frankie Says Relax" t-shirts,
I was treating a
73-year-old woman
who went through this
progression of symptoms.
The last of which was...
And in case any of you
missed that class in med school,
that one's untreatable.
Kid's got the first two.
It took Ester an hour and 20
minutes to go from two to three.
And less than a day to make
it all the way to the rear exit.
This is all because a child
has some blood in his diarrhea?
He's got a tummy ache.
If there was any reason to
think it was anything worse,
Cuddy would be all over it.
Great. Do a colonoscopy.
On a six-year-old kid who probably has
nothing worse than some food poisoning?
And if you happen to
find any purple papules,
do me a favor and grab a slice.
I wanna check for
Erdheim-Chester.
A disease that there have been,
what, maybe 200 reported cases of ever?
If Ester's family had let me
do an autopsy, there'd be 201.
See anything?
No, and I don't expect to.
House usually avoids cases.
If he's actually stealing a case
from Cuddy, there's gotta be a reason.
It's not the first time
I've seen this file.
About a month before
Cameron was hired,
some trucker came in
here with these symptoms.
House decided he was dying.
Two days and a spinal tap,
bone marrow extraction,
and three colonoscopies later,
we send the guy home
with a bunch of painkillers
and a diagnosis of a
bad cheese sandwich.
One of the guys who
worked here before me
said House tried to cure
Ester at least three other times.
You know how people see the
Virgin Mary in danishes and stuff?
Someone died 12 years ago
and House doesn't know why.
House sees that case
now in paint peeling,
in clouds, and
now in this poor kid.
Erdheim-Chester is an abnormal growth
of some of the cells that fight infection.
Is that cancer? 'Cause
he seems okay now.
The other doctor kind
of scared us about that.
He shouldn't have. We're just
testing. It'll probably be negative.
I don't understand.
You don't think that's what it is but
you want to do this thing to him anyway?
We need to be sure.
Isn't there any other way?
It shouldn't take long.
All right.
Those ridges look a
lot like purple papules.
They're not purple. They're
red. Probably just blood blisters.
Give me the biopsy needle.
How long is this gonna
take? Forget it, Chase.
Your punching out the shark story's
good, but she's not waiting for you.
So?
We couldn't confirm the
source of the bleeding,
but we did biopsy
some... Blood blisters.
You mean papules.
Come on, Cameron. Who's right?
Chase is. Negative
for Erdheim-Chester.
Let me see.
If it's not Erdheim-Chester...
It's exactly what we said before, a
garden-variety viral gastroenteritis.
Can we go back to the party?
Do a kidney biopsy.
Ester's shut down in exactly...
This kid is not Ester.
You screwed up.
She died. I'm sorry.
But that does not mean
this kid is dying as well.
Jeez, you're testy when you
don't get any fuzz. Come on.
What'd the test say?
Colonoscopy was clean.
And the biopsy was
negative for Erdheim-Chester.
So Ian's going to be all right?
It was just some sort of virus.
What's that?
Urine.
Yeah, but it's brown.
Ian's kidneys are shutting down.
Still think it's not
the same case?
So, what can cause
bloody diarrhea,
ataxia and kidney failure?
I'll go do a biopsy. Forget it!
That battle's over.
His rising creatinine is
his kidneys' way of saying,
"Go on without me."
What explains everything?
E. coli HO-157
causes bloody diarrhea
and leads to
Hemolytic-uremic Syndrome.
Toxins from the bacteria
cause his kidneys to shut down.
We should start him
on plasmapheresis.
Clear, concise, and
completely plausible.
And exactly what I did
last time. Didn't work.
What else?
Goodpasture's Syndrome.
Circulating antibodies cause
kidney failure and bleeding.
But not the purple papules.
If you throw in Ester's next symptom,
brain, makes me think heavy metal toxicity.
His hematocrit would
have to be low. It's at 44,
and Ester's never
dropped below... 42.
You have the file memorized?
It's my lucky number.
What about lymphoma?
Causes kidney failure, GI bleed,
and can infiltrate the base of the brain.
You check Ester for that?
She never showed any signs of...
If he has lymphoma
this far advanced,
we should be able to see
it in his blood and brain.
Chase, run a blood smear
and immunochemistries.
Foreman, get an MRI.
I'll page Cuddy. No, you won't.
She thinks the kid
has a stomachache.
Then she'll come right up
here and do one of two things.
If she agrees with
me, I don't need her.
If she disagrees,
I don't want her.
You can't handle people
disagreeing with you?
She might have a
different take on this.
Subordinates can disagree
with me all they want. It's healthy.
People who can shut me
down on the other hand...
Forget Cuddy. I'll have
Wilson keep her busy.
Keep your answers short and
discreet. Is Cuddy still playing?
The chicken is still
in Piccadilly Square.
Brilliant. She'll never suspect
that Normandy is our target.
Is that House?
Tell him that the blinds just went to
20-40 and he's running out of chips.
How's she doing?
What's going on?
The way you took off,
something's obviously...
Love to chat but got a game
to play. How's she doing?
The patient is on life support.
We're about to pull the plug.
Are you talking about me?
What've you got?
Those sounds like
high-dose cardio meds.
Two hearts.
You got the flush?
Still waiting on the final labs.
Is she drinking her seltzer?
No, hydration is not a problem.
She's bluffing.
Push your all in.
Call.
Two pair. Show me your hearts.
Seven of clubs.
Oh, dear. Sounds
like I messed up.
You're gonna be stuck
with her for a while.
Talk to you soon.
Oh, yes!
Why are you taking
a picture of his head?
We're looking for
lymphoma but...
So, it's not Erdheim-something
and it's not his kidneys,
but his kidneys are failing.
Where's Dr. Cuddy?
Dr. House mentioned
another case.
Is there another patient with
the same thing that Ian has?
Not exactly. What
does that mean?
Dr. House had a
patient a while back
who exhibited the same
symptoms as your son.
Then you know what's wrong? No.
So what do you know?
We know the likely
course the disease will take.
Which is?
She had multiple
system failures affecting...
What happened to her?
She died 24 hours
after her admission.
Mr. or Mrs. Alston, would
you mind giving me a hand?
He's having
trouble sitting still.
It's impossible to get
the detail we need.
So I figured he might feel more
comfortable hearing your voices.
Ian, honey.
Just sit still. They'll be done in
a moment. We're here with you.
I'm scared.
It's okay, honey. It's...
It's only a big camera. It's
gonna take a picture of your head.
You love it when I take your
picture at home, don't you?
Yeah.
And you have to hold
still for that, too, right?
But this isn't like that.
I know it's scary,
Ian, but you can do it.
You're getting to
be so grown-up.
So just hold perfectly
still, just for a little bit.
Mommy, are you crying?
No. No, honey, I'm just tired.
Okay. I'll try.
The base of his brain's been
infiltrated by a small mass. We think...
Pituitary? Looks that way.
Explains the low blood pressure.
And pretty much
confirms the lymphoma.
If we'd started Ester
on prednisone...
Did anyone see the lymphoma?
No, we saw a mass. The
location is consistent with...
Didn't see any in
the blood either.
White blood cells show no
spindling or abnormal nuclei.
Nothing on immunochemistries
either. It's not lymphoma.
House!
It's a train.
We don't know what kind of
train... Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
I'm thirsty. It's closed.
It's not now.
We got one advantage. We
know where the tracks are going.
The fact that the end of the
line is death is an advantage?
The fact that we
know is an advantage.
It means maybe we
can get ahead of it.
Next station is the liver.
We got about 90 minutes
before it gets there.
Maybe we can cut down a tree
across the line just outside of town.
I'll do an ultrasound.
No, treatment will
tell us more, faster.
How can we start treatment if we
have no idea what we're treating for?
Treat him for everything.
Give him acetylcysteine,
and interferon, and silymarin,
and whatever else you can
think of to protect the liver.
What's going on?
Oh, just catching up on
some TV. How're you doing?
Well, thanks to your last consult,
the patient has improved dramatically.
Tell House the patient
is about to kill the doctor.
She says the patient... I heard.
What've you got? Well,
Cuddy just raised and...
You're paired. What?
Nines.
How do you know?
Anything lower, you
wouldn't sound so excited.
Jacks or higher,
your voice sounds like Debbie
from accounting is sitting in your lap.
Ask Cuddy if she can
beat a pair of threes.
Wait. What's going on? If
you're gonna mess with me,
wouldn't it be more
fun to do it in person?
Yes, it would.
Can you beat a pair of threes?
What'd she do?
I left orders for
PO fluids, Doctor.
Enough with the codes.
She obviously knows it's me.
She's drinking her seltzer.
Did she stop?
Yes. Go all in.
But... Just do it.
You couldn't care less
about this charity event.
You claim not to
be messing with me.
Obviously, you're either
trying to keep me... Shut up.
Look, last time I wanted
the game to go on. I still do.
It means that this
time you get to win.
Hold on.
I fold.
House, are you sure you're okay?
Meds seem to be working.
Liver's holding its own.
Good.
But the platelets are
dropping. Even better.
Why? It means
he's getting sicker.
It's new. New is good.
Because old ended in death.
I can't breathe.
Chase!
What's happening?
Ian, come on.
Honey, just relax.
Ian, breathe. Come
on, honey. Please.
Please, honey.
We had to put
him on a ventilator.
He's back on Ester's path
and we managed to make
the train skip a few stations.
Which means that instead of 12
hours, he's probably got less than two.
Which begs the question,
why? What did we do?
Acetylcysteine could
mess with the lungs.
Mess with them, not shut
them down in 20 minutes.
Interferon modulates
the immune system.
It could affect a cancer of the
blood, like one of the leukemias.
It doesn't speed them
up. It slows them down.
It slows down all 500 of them?
Anybody know where we can
find an oncologist at this hour?
What effects would
interferon have on leukemia?
Depends on what type. Could
make it better. Could make it worse.
A four-year
fellowship to learn that.
Tell House if he
wants to play cards,
he can get his ass
back down here and play.
You hear that. She
wants me off the phone.
Means she's
vulnerable. Go all in.
But the party's over in
less than three hours.
It's over in less
than two hours,
which means you either have
three of a kind or just threes.
I'm guessing threes.
I bet $500.
Go all in.
You obviously want to bust me.
Why would you...
Either you go all in,
or I tell everybody in the building
that you wear toenail polish.
I'm all in.
I'll call.
I'm betting you
have a pair of threes,
but even if you have three,
it's not gonna beat trip nines.
Oh! Oh! Oh, no!
Oh, no! Oh! Oh,
that's gotta hurt.
What happened? I just killed
two birds with one straight.
Goodbye.
Fine, keep playing.
But I need you to
recommend a good oncologist
because if I don't get one up
here in the next few minutes,
I got a dead six-year-old.
If you need help, ask.
These games are insane.
The games have a
higher success rate.
Well, I don't see anything
that looks like leukemia.
You do a bone marrow
biopsy? No time.
Even if there is an
occult blood cancer,
you wouldn't expect
interferon to make it worse.
Certainly not this fast.
What would move this fast?
Autoimmune diseases.
If his body's own
defenses are attacking him,
then beefing them up is
just gonna put fuel on the fire.
Sarcoidosis could be
in his brain and lungs.
No. No enlarged hilar lymph
nodes on his chest x-ray.
The systemic nature suggests
Juvenile Rheumatoid Arthritis.
Or Kawasaki's Disease.
Can't be Kawasaki's.
That doesn't affect the elderly.
This is a kid's x-ray?
House had another patient.
Who may or may not
have had Kawasaki's.
This kid on the other hand,
he makes antibodies that are
eating the inside of his arteries,
choking off blood to his
major organs, one by one.
First the GI tract, then the kidneys,
then the brain, now the lungs.
Can anyone think of a reason why
Kawasaki's can't affect the elderly,
other than that it doesn't?
Nice. FOREMAN: We
can confirm with blood work.
We need an ANA, sed rate...
Labs will take two hours.
What was the old
lady's sed rate?
Elevated, 98.
You can't use another patient's
labs to diagnosis Kawasaki's disease.
Is that like a dare
or something?
You don't have time to be wrong.
Fine. We'll look for
Kawasaki where he lives,
Ian's coronary arteries.
This other patient,
the old lady, Ester?
Have you read Moby Dick?
It was a book?
It was ten years ago. Twelve.
Obsession is dangerous.
Only if you're on a wooden ship,
and your obsession is a whale.
I think I'm in the clear.
You do realize it's a metaphor.
You do realize that the point of metaphors
is to scare people from doing things
by telling them that something
much scarier is gonna happen
than what will really happen.
God, I wish I had a
metaphor to explain that better.
Go back to the game. Don't worry,
I'm not gonna get eaten by witches.
Coronary arteries
clear. No aneurysms.
Flip the mode.
Let's see the flow.
How did that other woman die?
She went into
respiratory distress.
Her heart and liver
were already... No.
Did she suffer?
Was she in pain?
I don't know.
Laminar flow. No blood
clots, no ragged edges.
Damn. Shut it down.
We're just wasting time.
Look at the right atrium.
That's not Kawasaki's. No.
It's small, but it's there.
Ester didn't have
a mass in her heart.
Ian's younger. He can
take more of a pounding.
Ester died before the
disease reached her heart.
The disease made a
mass and made it fast.
Could be bacteria. Muscle.
Connective tissue.
The kid can't take
any more theories.
Only thing we know is
that whatever that mass is,
that's what he's got.
We need a piece of
it. I'm doing a biopsy.
I'll shut the blinds.
No, let them watch.
I do my best work
on the big stage.
Passing through the
superior vena cava.
You're in the atrium. Pull back.
You've hit the
wall of the heart.
These procedures
would be so much simpler
if you could do them
on healthy people.
And out again.
V-fib. Cardiac arrest.
Call a code.
Come on, paddles!
Come on. Charge.
Clear!
Code blue, ISO room.
And again.
Nothing. Again.
You got a clock on this?
How much longer you
gonna keep doing this?
Clear.
Wait. I've got something.
He's back.
What are you doing? I'm
doing what we came here to do.
It almost killed him. I
know. I was right here.
I need a Vacutainer.
His brain's been oxygen
deprived for over eight minutes.
There might be nothing left.
He might... Tell the parents.
Where the hell is
that Vacutainer?
So, what's he got? Brain damage.
Good chance. I was
talking about before that.
You're not worried about...
Things I can't do
anything about?
I try not to. Yeah.
Things just roll off you
like water off a duck.
Histiocytosis.
Very unlikely in a 73-year-old.
Whatever this is,
it's very unlikely.
Come on. More
ideas. Let's go, people.
Genetic disorders could
cause masses everywhere.
Tuberous sclerosis.
If it's genetic, he's
had it all his life.
Why now? I don't know.
It sure fits nice enough.
We haven't ruled
out leukemia yet.
Or sarcoma. He could have
multiple soft tissue tumors.
Or sarcoidosis.
Multiple neurofibromatosis.
Chondrocytomas.
How's it going? You win?
I got called away by the
angry parents of a patient.
There are three of you here.
None of you had the sense to stop
him, to pick up a phone and call me.
I told them you'd signed off.
The parents are mad
because their kid is dying.
It's understandable.
But if he doesn't die, they
won't be mad anymore.
Well, if he's brain damaged,
they might still be a little ticked.
Had to do it to save him.
You had to do it
to diagnose Ester.
You may have
killed a six-year-old
because you're obsessed with a
woman who's been dead for 12 years.
Sometimes you lose,
House! You're not God!
He's not dead yet.
No, but you're done with him.
It's my case now. Go home.
Go ride your motorcycle.
Go brood in a dark room.
Just don't go near Ian again.
So, anything else or
is it just these seven?
Drop it, House. She's right.
No, she's not!
You know she's not. We
should have called her.
I'm surprised you didn't.
You're gonna have to
find a way to let this go.
We can't go near Ian.
We don't need to go near him.
We have his tumor.
Well, Cuddy may be right
that we screwed up the protocol.
She may be right about
my screwed up obsession.
But I'm right
about the medicine.
How many tests
can we do with that?
Look, we cure the kid, we
solve everybody's problems.
How many?
Maybe two good pieces.
How many okay pieces?
Three would be pushing it.
Three tests, seven choices.
Okay, what's first?
Sarcoidosis seems most likely.
Yeah. So likely that Cuddy's
gonna think of that all on her own.
She's got the kid's whole body
to play with. Let her do that test.
What's next?
It's moving too
fast to be spreading.
It has to be growing from
something that's already there.
Genetic disorder.
Tuberous sclerosis.
Or it's his immune
system. Histiocytosis.
Well, there are more documented
cases of Histio amongst older people
than tuberous sclerosis.
Let's start with that.
Wing or drumstick?
Gonna need a
little more than that.
A little more is
more than a third.
If we have to repeat this test
because you didn't cut us enough...
I'm adding one micro liter
of the immunoperoxidase.
Make it two. I don't want
House biting off our heads
because we weren't
sure if it turned red or not.
That's definitely not red.
The problem could still
be an abnormal cell growth
but a different
cell line. Sarcoma?
Muscle cells are
throughout his body.
It would explain the geography.
Genetic disorder is far more likely
in a six-year-old. Tuberous sclerosis.
Pretty unlikely to
cause a GI bleed.
The time course fits.
Mr. Foreman, you agree with
both of them? Thanks for playing.
If we have enough tissue
for two tests, why not do both?
Then we don't have
to think as hard.
Taking the pressure off the choice
makes us less likely to think critically.
Sarcoma is more likely
to hit a six and 70-year-old.
Tuberous sclerosis, it is.
You think sarcoma
is less likely?
It's more likely.
The test for it, on the
other hand, is less reliable.
Test is negative.
Well, that's okay.
If the tumor cells haven't matured, the
Ki-67 protein wouldn't have turned off.
What happens if we
don't solve this? Kid dies.
I mean for the next 12 years.
Ki-67's negative.
And PCH antigen is negative.
Mighty Casey's
down to his last strike.
Mighty Casey struck out.
Thanks a lot. I was gonna
read that this weekend.
Chondrocytoma.
Connective tissue's been in all
the places we've been looking.
The kid is too sick for that. We're
better off testing for sarcoma.
We would've seen signs of that
when we tested for tuberous sclerosis.
The tumor cells looked like
muscle under the microscope.
No, they didn't.
They looked like fat.
I vote for neurofibromatosis.
Why? Because the
other choices suck worse.
Give me a minute.
You want me out of here?
You come up with anything?
No.
Hey. We can talk
about it tomorrow.
I won the poker tournament.
I totally played this guy,
Berman, from business affairs.
I got great cards. But I
don't bet. Just call, no raises.
Berman pairs his
king on the flop.
I keep calling, the river turns,
I check. He can't stand it.
He goes all in.
He's sure he's won.
I call, I flip them.
Pocket aces.
I nailed his ass.
The aces were hiding all along.
Test him for
Erdheim-Chester disease.
Erdheim-Chester?
That's not even on the list.
Because we already
did it. He tested negative.
So did Ester. The disease lied.
Yeah, the tumor's got it in
for you. Diseases don't lie.
Fine, it didn't lie.
It slow played us.
We biopsied the colon, it
hadn't reached the GI tract yet.
It's there now. It's
in his liver, his lungs.
You want it to be there.
Because then you didn't
screw up 12 years ago.
We can't waste our one test on
the one disease we know it's not.
Run the test.
You sure about this?
Wait. Let me think about
that. Don't pressure me.
Just run the damn test.
Cells look like macrophages.
That's a good start.
Take your time, and say it loud.
CD 68 positive.
Start the treatment.
So, Ester can rest
peaceful now, huh?
Yeah.
$40.
You got lucky.
You gonna call?
What I do
is not just based
on the flip of a card.
You guessed. You got lucky.
It fit.
It could just as easily have been
sarcoma or tuberous sclerosis.
No, not just as easily.
Maybe not. But it
wasn't impossible.
Are you gonna call?
You know, relative to its size,
the barnacle has the
largest penis of any animal.