Your new chief
is Dr. Ethan Choi.
We're running a trial
at Med for an oral
heart failure medication.
Dr. Virani,
would you be willing
to talk about that offer?
Talking about myself
is not really my thing.
I consider myself
more of a stoic.
Big on hiding emotion.
That you?
Mom's moving us to Arizona.
Hasn't happened yet.
We'll figure it out.
I know your heart's
in this COVID battle,
but you can't go it alone.
They are sick,
and they are alone.
I'm not abandoning them.
I don't know what I'm
gonna do at lunch every day,
without talking to
your kids on FaceTime.
Oh, don't you worry.
I'll make sure Annie
still sends you her recipes.
Good.
You take care of
yourself, Mr. Booker.
You, too
Thank you so much
for everything.
Hey.
Dr. Manning.
You look so...
What's the word?
"Decontaminated."
Oh, why, thank you!
And I'm sensing
a temperature
on you of, what?
98.4? 98.5?
Oh, as a matter of fact,
you're wrong. 98.7.
Oh.
Yes, I tend to run
a little hot.
Oh, I'm sure you do.
And what was that?
With Crockett? Nothing.
Oh, no.
Hmm.
Ben and I have never
exchanged temperatures.
Stop it.
Grab your earbuds.
You are on Telemedicine.
What? No.
Sorry, everybody's
gotta clock in their hours.
Ugh, I hate working through
a computer screen.
It's so impersonal.
Well, just break the ice.
Ask them
for their temperature.
Oh, my God.
Dr. Choi, I just got off
with the Board.
They're concerned
about your projections
for next month.
I understand, but with Norris
shutting its ED,
we had to ramp up
for the influx of patients.
And I'm sure you're
doing everything you can,
but with the losses
we sustained
from treating COVID,
they're watching every penny.
I get it.
I can try to reassess some
protocols, maybe find
a few more beds.
Maybe you should
look at how you're
allocating your staff.
Look,
I know this isn't easy,
but if Norris' ED
can go under,
it could happen to us.
Yes, ma'am.
Hey.
Anna got her
algebra test back.
A-minus.
Wow, great.
I know.
Why does that sound like
a lead into something
much less pleasant?
The, uh, transfer to Arizona
came through.
I start in a month.
You already took it? I thought
we were gonna talk about this.
I can't pass this up.
You can't just take Anna
a thousand miles away
without discussing it with me.
There's a direct flight.
You can come see her
on the weekends.
Susan, it's a direct violation
of our divorce agreement.
We really want to end up
in court over this?
I know this is hard
and you guys have gotten
so close, but...
Look, I'm sorry,
but they need me
down in the ED.
We're just gonna have
to pick this up later, okay?
But I just...
Hey, what's so important?
I'm sorry to do this,
but I have to bring you
back down to the ED.
Is this about
my safety again?
That's part of it.
You've been
in the COVID ward
for over a month,
and we've had
a couple nurses
test positive.
All the more reason
for me to stay here.
It isn't just that.
I have to balance my staff
between wards.
Please,
I need you downstairs.
You know how important
this is to me.
Of course, I do.
We just discharged another
patient this morning.
I am helping people
get through this.
I understand,
and it isn't forever.
You can't do this.
I can, and I have to.
I expect you down there
in an hour.
Dr. Choi? Patients are
backing up into the lobby.
What do you want me to do?
Get Doris to double up
on room turnover.
April.
Dr. Charles,
I have a young woman in 6
who needs IV antibiotics,
but is a little anxious
about needles,
and I need
to move things along.
Think you and April
could give it a try?
Yeah, sure.
Whatever you say, Chief.
Thanks.
Everything all right?
No. Ethan yanked me off
the COVID ward.
Huh.
Despite knowing how I feel.
You, um,
want to talk about it?
There's nothing
to talk about.
Hi, I'm April.
I'm gonna start your IV.
How are you doing?
I'm Dr. Charles.
You must be Lisa.
Yes. Very nice
to meet you, sir.
That is quite an infection
you have there...
Listen, you don't
need to worry.
Everybody in here has been
tested negative for COVID,
just like you. Okay?
You mind if I have a seat?
Okay.
So...
In my experience,
the trick to this
whole business is
to talk about movies.
My favorite movie
happens to be Amadeus.
How about you?
Uh... I don't know.
Okay, um...
Well, then, how about books?
You been reading anything
good recently?
Uh...
I don't really read.
I work as a babysitter.
So, you must like kids, then?
Just breathe.
Yes, I take care of a boy
and a girl, Tommy and Bridget.
They're brother and sister,
ages eight and ten.
Got it.
So, is that "Bridget"
with a, uh, D or a T?
'Cause, you know, the Irish,
they spell it kinda weird.
Is it in?
Yep, all done.
Lisa,
somebody's gonna be back
to, uh, check up on you
in a second, okay?
Nice to meet you, Lisa.
That was odd.
It was odd.
But, I mean, come on.
Hospitals can be scary places,
especially, these days.
But I tell you what,
give me a heads-up
when her labs come in, okay?
Mmm-hmm.
I might want to
talk to her again.
Okay.
Thank you.
We see a lot of
heart failure here.
With some hard work,
I think we could
fill this trial
in a matter of weeks,
not months.
I like your enthusiasm.
I mean, I saw
the phase 2 results.
Ejection fraction
is up an average of 40%?
This drug could
be a game changer.
Morning, Mags.
Morning.
Uh, we're starting
the clinical trial today.
Okay.
Let me know if we get
any heart failure patients.
Oh, you're in luck.
We got one in 5 right now.
I'll let you know
how it goes.
Great.
Mags, I'd like you
with me on this one.
All right.
Mr. Esquivel?
Am I saying that right?
Si.
I'm Dr. Halstead.
How're you feeling?
Hard to breathe. Tired.
Mmm-hmm.
Yeah, he's got a right-sided
effusion. Gonna need a tap.
Sir, it says you've been here
before, for heart failure.
I have?
Yes.
And looks like
it's gotten a bit worse.
Are you taking
your medication?
Blue ones, white ones.
Good.
But they may not be
working well enough.
Here's the thing.
I'm actually involved
in testing a brand-new
heart failure drug,
and based on what I'm seeing,
I think you could be
an excellent candidate.
More pills?
Just one.
And it would help
your heart pump better.
Now, it is experimental,
and we don't have
a ton of data on it,
but what we do have
is extremely encouraging.
It will make me better?
I can't make any promises,
but in this trial,
three out of the four patients
get the medication.
As long as you are
one of them, we should
see results pretty quickly.
Uh, what do you say?
Wanna give it a try?
Okay.
Yeah?
I just want to make sure
you understand
what I'm proposing.
Whatever you say, Doc.
All right.
I'll be back in a minute
with the paperwork,
and we'll get you going.
Set him up
for a thoracentesis,
and I'll get you the list
of labs for the trial.
Yeah, but are you sure
he understood?
He didn't seem all there.
He seemed
cognizant enough to me.
I asked him twice.
Yeah, but you
said it yourself,
it's possible that he gets
into the control group.
He might not even
get the drug.
Right.
But the control group
gets the standard
of care regardless,
and after 12 weeks, everyone
gets put on the drug anyways.
He's making a good choice.
Baghdad?
Got a 28-year-old female
paramedic with a knife wound
in the right flank.
123/70, heart rate 82,
respiration's 26.
COVID negative.
Lanik, Marcel,
you're up. Doris?
Yep.
I'll help.
Just keep doing it
that way, okay?
Check her belly for fluid.
Megan? What happened?
I was on call, and a guy
jumped out of nowhere.
Okay. All right,
we're gonna help you out.
Here we go, on my count.
One, two, three.
Okay, let's have a look.
How bad is it?
I've seen worse.
You two know each other?
Yeah, we've crossed paths.
Usually over a Sazerac.
Or three.
If you really wanted
to see me again,
you could have just called.
Don't.
Easy.
It hurts.
He always
could make me laugh.
Mmm. He's a funny guy.
Okay, no free fluid. Good.
Doris, type and cross
for 6 and 6.
Hang two uncrossed units
and call up for an abdomen CT.
Uh-huh.
Am I gonna need surgery?
It depends if it
got the kidney.
We'll see what the scans say.
Uh, If you can do it
without surgery...
My wedding's in two weeks.
You're getting married?
That's fantastic.
I'm happy for you.
Yeah.
Yeah, no, it is.
Could have been this one
if he wasn't so hard to land.
Well, all right.
We're gonna take good care
of you, all right?
Okay.
In the meantime,
lay off the street fighting.
I'll draw up some labs.
That's okay, Trauma's got it.
You don't get out of
Telemedicine that easy.
You two seem to know
each other pretty well.
Yeah, we had
some good times.
Lucky for her, she was
smart enough to get away.
Tell me, are there
any women in Chicago you have
not had a Sazerac with?
There's still a few
on my list.
Hmm.
Is this done yet?
Almost. Before you go,
Dr. Choi would like
to give you a supplement.
Why?
Your lab work
revealed you have
an extreme
vitamin D deficiency.
We get our
vitamin D from the sun.
You not been leaving
the house too much?
I do, to play
with the kids I babysit.
Right, of course.
Thomas and, uh, Brittany?
Yes.
Or is it Bridget?
Bridget. Yeah, Bridget.
Right, of course.
So, you got a nice park
you take 'em to?
Where do you go?
Different places.
Can you do this fast?
I need to get back soon.
Yeah,
of course we can.
You got a long drive today?
Where do you live,
just if you don't
mind me asking?
I don't know.
Just hang in there, Lisa.
We'll get you
out of here soon.
That poor girl is so scared.
It doesn't seem like
just a needle phobia.
Did she have any ID
when she came in,
or emergency contact info?
Nope.
What are you thinking?
She is extremely fearful,
but also, she repeats
her backstory
like she's on some kind
of robotic tape loop.
What do you mean?
Look, she doesn't
spend a lot of time
outside, clearly.
She could have
been abducted.
Maybe.
Or she could have
just been in quarantine
and scared of hospitals.
Well, you could be right,
but I really do think
we should look into it.
Okay.
Do what you can,
but she wants to leave,
so as soon as her bag runs,
I gotta let her go.
Ethan...
You're talking about
getting PD down here,
interviewing her,
checking out her story.
Then we could take a picture.
Have them run it through
the missing persons registry.
It's not ethical
to take a picture of her
without her consent.
I'll figure it out.
But if taking
a picture could save
this woman's life,
that's what I'm gonna do.
Okay, so, tell me,
how long have you been
feeling nauseous for?
A few days,
but it's getting worse,
and my heart's
been beating really fast.
Do you have any history
of diabetes,
heart or stomach issues?
I don't think so,
but I haven't
seen a doctor
since Dr. Kelson retired.
So, have you ever had
these symptoms before?
A few times.
My cousin thinks
I have an ulcer.
What do you think?
I don't really want
to speculate based
on such limited history,
so I do think
it's best that you come in
for some blood work.
Oh, I can't do that.
We're still in a pandemic.
The hospital is actually
very safe. We're taking
every precaution.
I'm sure,
but I'm of an age that...
I understand,
but with your symptoms,
I really do think
it's best that you come in.
I can't. I'm so sorry.
Okay, uh, you know what?
I will write you up some
anti-nausea medication
for the pharmacy
to deliver to you,
um, but in the meantime,
if your symptoms
do get worse,
I really need you
to call me back
immediately, okay?
Oh, I will.
All right, thank you. Bye.
Any luck?
PD ran Lisa's photo,
and they didn't get a match.
It is possible it never got
reported, which happens
more than you think.
What I don't get is
if she was
being held captive,
why would they let her
come here alone?
Her captor might believe
that she's been
so well-conditioned,
that she'd just
come right back.
Like brainwashed?
Yeah, think about it.
If your only reality is
what the people who are
controlling you say it is,
you wouldn't dream
of defying it.
Lisa's IV is finished,
and she's asking to leave.
Ethan, she might be
in trouble. We can't just
send her back out there.
Did PD make an ID?
She's not in the system.
Then I can't leave her here.
Hey, I gotta
tell you, I just...
My gut's telling me
that's not
the right move yet.
Can I go now?
We are done
with your medical
treatment, but...
The hospital is a safe place,
and it's our job
to protect you,
which means that if you
are feeling harmed or...
I want to leave.
Lisa, if anybody
is holding you
against your will...
Just let me go!
Okay.
Here's your
discharge paperwork.
Just sign at the bottom.
What do I do with this?
Why don't you, um, let us
print that out for you, okay?
Be right back.
Okay, look.
iPad's been around
for how long?
What, like, ten years?
Something like that.
Yeah. She had no idea
what this was.
Listen, we've been
looking all along
for a missing adult,
and maybe what we
should have been looking for
is a missing child.
Wait, what are you
talking about?
What if she was abducted
years ago?
When she was a kid?
It'd be
totally possible.
She hasn't indicated
that she's in trouble,
and she's not asking
for our help.
We have no grounds
to keep her.
She could be in danger.
I don't understand
why you just...
I'm sorry.
Buddy. I understand
the kind of pressure
you're under.
Really, I do.
But are you sure this is how
you want to run your ED?
Give us an hour.
Okay, all set.
Good.
Dad?
Are you okay?
Mari?
What happened?
Hi, I'm Dr. Halstead.
Your father just had a flare
of pulmonary edema.
Caused him
some trouble breathing,
but he's doing okay now.
Oh, God, it keeps
getting worse.
Yeah, fortunately,
I was able to sign him up
for a brand-new
clinical trial.
I think it's really
gonna help.
What, like an experiment?
I wouldn't characterize it
like that.
It's an opportunity
for a new medication,
and he said he wants it.
He can't make
a decision like that.
There's not much
to decide, really.
He takes a pill a day
and comes in twice a week,
so we can check his blood...
Twice a week?
I'm his sole caretaker,
and I work. There's no way.
His cardiologist said
he should be evaluated
for something called an LVAD.
That's a surgical procedure.
Given his age and
ventricular insufficiency,
I do not think
he'd be a good candidate.
He's already taken
the first dose of medication.
If we can just give it
a little time...
I'm sorry,
we're not interested.
If you could please
call someone down
and have him evaluated for
the LVAD, I'd appreciate it.
Ms. Esquivel, please...
Doctor.
That's what we want.
Okay, I will
give them a call.
Megan's still here.
Does that mean her kidney
wasn't involved?
There's a laceration
on the inferior pole,
but IR was able
to embolize it.
The blush
looks pretty large.
You sure
that'll cover it?
I, uh, think it will.
And you got Lanik
to agree not to operate?
It took a little convincing.
By someone working
very hard to carry out
his special friend's wishes?
You nailed me.
I'm a helpless
pushover, man.
Mmm. Really, though,
don't you think you're being
a little conservative?
If her pressure drops,
then you'll be taking an
unstable patient into surgery.
I'm sorry, have we met?
'Cause Dr. Natalie Manning
doesn't usually advocate
for surgery.
But thank you.
Always appreciate
a colleague's input.
Anytime.
Always.
This is impossible.
We're never
gonna find her.
Ethan should never have
taken me off the COVID ward.
At least there, I felt like
I was doing something,
having an impact.
You felt, uh...
Felt a real purpose.
Yeah.
I can see how that
would be hard,
leaving that behind.
But, um, I've known you
for a long time,
and it seems to me,
you make yourself pretty damn
useful wherever you are.
Yeah, but this was different.
I felt like I was finally...
I don't know,
I found myself.
Who I am.
Yeah.
And Ethan took
that away from me.
Have you found a match?
It's tricky, as we have
no idea what she looked like
when she was a kid.
Send me her pic.
I found a face app
that can de-age it.
If she was abducted,
it might help us
find a match.
It's a long shot, but...
She looks familiar.
Wait.
That's Kelly, um...
Kelly Bissett.
From Wheaton.
Disappeared
a bunch of years ago.
It was all over the news.
Wait.
Kelly Bissett.
Wheaton, Illinois.
That's her.
April, make sure
she doesn't leave.
I'll call PD.
Dr. Marcel?
Yeah?
Her pressure's dropping.
Hey, how are you feeling?
I'm kind of lightheaded.
Let's have a look.
It's a problem.
What is it?
Got blood in her Foley.
Call upstairs. We gotta
get her up to the OR now.
Wait. What's going on?
Hey.
Your kidney's still bleeding.
There could be serious damage.
What are you gonna do?
We might have
to remove it.
I'm sorry, Megan.
Okay. Do whatever
you have to do.
Miss Webb.
Dr. Manning. How are you?
I'm fine. But how are you?
You told me to call
if I had more symptoms.
Right.
My hands are kind of tingly
and numb. And it feels
weird moving my arms.
How long has this
been going on for?
About an hour.
Is it something bad?
I don't know.
But I do really
need you to come in now.
No, please.
Uh, can you just ask me
a few more questions?
I'm gonna need more
information than that.
Run tests.
This is an odd combination
of symptoms.
I wanna make sure
I'm not missing anything.
Maybe, if we just give it
a little more time?
Why don't I do some more
research on this,
and I will give you
a call back. Okay?
But if this gets worse,
I need you to promise me
that you'll come in.
But you'll definitely
call me back?
Absolutely. Okay?
Thank you.
Of course, bye.
Good news. Your father's sats
are looking better.
Okay, but cardiology
still hasn't come by.
Have you heard anything?
Yeah, I apprised them
of the situation,
but I did tell them
to hold off on coming down.
Wait. What? Why?
I wanted to see if he would
improve, and he did.
His ejection fraction
is up four percent.
His heart...
I made it very clear
what I wanted.
I know. I wanted to
get his echo results in...
How much do they
pay him for this trial?
Maria...
Forget it. I'm calling
his cardiologist.
No, no, no. Please. Hey,
you're making a big mistake...
Dr. Halstead.
Trini, come here.
Miss Esquivel?
Please, just...
Dr. Halstead?
What are you doing?
She was very clear
about what she wants.
She doesn't understand.
If an LVAD goes poorly,
he could end up stranded
on ECMO. That's a death
sentence, Maggie.
Are you sure that this trial's
not clouding your judgment?
Yes. This trial
is the best shot we have
at saving Ruben's life.
Dr. Halstead?
No, no, no! Stop!
He needs to stay in bed.
I'm taking him
to see Dr. Foster.
Papa!
Maria, get out of here.
He's in arrest.
Code Blue. Pulseless V-tach.
Oh, my God.
Paddles.
Charging to 200.
This is your fault!
Charged. Clear!
Papa!
Pulse rate?
No pulse.
Compressions.
Charging to 200.
Please, Papa.
Charged, clear.
Pulse is back.
Is he alive?
Yes.
He's stable,
but unconscious.
At this point,
we're gonna
have to intubate
and then move him
up to the ICU.
Maria!
It's okay.
Hey, we're trying
to help him. We are.
Claims she's not
the missing girl.
She's adamant.
Not surprising.
She's been terrorized
over the last 12 years
into completely erasing
her former identity.
It's not gonna be so easy
to just break
right through that.
Just look at her eyes.
It's her. You can see that.
It could be.
But without a statement
or physical evidence,
the detectives will
have to get a warrant
to check her DNA.
It's gonna take a while.
Thanks.
So, now, what do we do?
We gotta find her family.
And then what?
Lisa!
I've been here too long.
I have to go.
No, no, no. Lisa.
We can help you.
No, no, no. No.
I have to go.
Get out of my way!
Security!
She's on a hold.
Miss?
What? No.
What's going on?
Please.
I have to go. No! No!
Take it easy!
Please!
Lisa? It's gonna be okay.
No! No!
Miss Bissett?
I'm Dan Charles.
You're the doctor who called?
Yes.
And this is April Sexton.
Hello.
I just want you to know
that we get tested
at the hospital every day.
And we're both negative.
It's all right.
I'm tested weekly myself.
And I work from home.
It's so cold.
Please. Come in.
Thank you.
I don't know why
I've agreed to see you.
My daughter's gone.
Whoever's in your
hospital isn't her.
How can you be so sure?
Because I've been
dealing with them for years,
these imposters.
Some want money,
some want attention.
Actually, she's not even
claiming to be your daughter.
What? Then why
are you even here?
She does present
as somebody who has been
in captivity for many years.
So just some crazy person?
Not really.
Um, and there's a photo
we'd like to show you.
I don't want to see
any more pictures.
Please, just take a look.
Please.
That's not Kelly.
My Kelly had birthmarks.
She had a scar on her hand,
where she had a bike accident.
It would be so helpful
if you came with us
to the hospital,
and saw her
with your own eyes.
I'm not doing this again.
I can't take it.
My daughter is gone.
May I?
The pictures have faded...
Miss Bissett, I wish
you'd reconsider.
We know how painful this
must be for you, which is
why we wouldn't be here...
No.
I'm done chasing ghosts.
We're sorry to have
bothered you.
Will. You cannot go in there.
Ruben still has runs
of V-tach.
Has a cardiologist
seen him?
No. They're backed up.
He needs a stellate
ganglion block
right now.
Will!
Ruben's daughter had you
taken off the case.
Miss Esquivel...
Will...
You are not
his doctor anymore.
I understand.
But this is an emergency.
Your father's
in a dangerous arrhythmia.
I want to do what's called
a stellate ganglion block.
Inject a small anesthetic
into nerves in his neck.
Is this a part
of your trial?
No, it's not.
But if it works, it will help
convert his heart back
into a safe rhythm.
It would save his life.
I don't trust you.
No.
Maria.
Dr. Halstead is one
of the best doctors
that we have here.
Please, don't.
I've had enough.
Maria, if he thinks
this is the best treatment
for your father,
so do I.
Do you really trust him?
I do.
Fine. Do it.
Okay.
Thank you.
When I inject, you need
to stay completely still.
If I'm even a millimeter off,
I could hit the carotid.
All right.
There's the carotid.
Okay.
Let's go.
Can you see anything?
Not yet.
Angle it a little down.
A little more.
What is that?
He's having a run of V-tach.
Do you want the amiodarone?
No, we got this. Keep going.
What's happening?
Dr. Halstead...
Angle it up.
Ay, Papa.
He's in V-tach.
He's gonna arrest.
No! Keep going.
A little more.
Pressure's dropping.
Do something! Save him!
Okay, Maria.
Almost there. Keep going
a little more.
Stop right there.
I'm going in.
Do not move.
Got it. Pushing bupivacaine.
Don't move. All in.
Normal sinus rhythm.
Okay, coming out.
Don't move.
Out.
How'd it go with the mom?
We struck out.
Poor thing could barely
look at the picture.
Please, you have to
let me go.
Someone took you
from your home.
They took your family,
your childhood.
Everything you had.
But what no one
can ever take from you
is who you are.
This is yours, isn't it?
Are you Kelly Bissett?
It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's so nice to hear
from you, Dr. Manning.
I have been searching
for possible diagnoses.
But without being able to
examine you, I just can't
narrow it down.
I'm sorry. Even if I
wanted to come in,
I couldn't.
My son used to drive me,
but he moved to Colorado
a few months ago.
He barely calls,
and never Zooms.
I understand. If anything
changes or gets worse, I...
Oh, actually,
there is one more symptom.
My urine is red. I mean,
it's really red.
Like the color of wine.
Hang on one second.
Miss Webb, have you
ever heard of something
called ALAD porphyria?
I don't think so.
It's a very rare
genetic disease,
only ten cases reported ever.
And your symptoms
match the diagnosis.
Really?
To a T.
But if you actually had it,
you would look a lot more ill.
Oh.
"Urine the color of wine."
That's exactly how it's
described in the literature.
I'm sorry to do this,
but I have to ask.
Do you really
have these symptoms?
Or are you just reading
about porphyria online?
The nausea was real.
But I tried to call
my son to ask him,
but he didn't have time.
So, I started looking up
possible causes, and...
No. I don't have
the symptoms.
I'm sorry I wasted your time.
Miss Webb?
Yes?
I miss my son, too.
He's five.
I had to move out
because of the pandemic.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
What's his name?
Owen. You wanna see
a picture of him?
Yes, I do.
Here he is.
He's adorable.
Mmm-hmm.
Mine is named Richard.
He goes by Rick...
Mr. Esquivel,
how are you feeling?
Good.
Great. Yeah,
your rhythm is stable
and your pressure's up.
Hopefully, you won't have
to stay with us much longer.
Take care.
Dr. Halstead?
I appreciate everything
you've done.
So, if you think
your clinical trial is
the best thing for my father,
I'd like to keep him in it.
Thank you.
And I wish he could.
But the ganglion block
disqualified him.
Maybe down the road,
we can revisit it again.
But for now, I'm just glad
he's doing better.
You knew all along
the block was gonna
disqualify him?
It's what he needed.
But here's the sad irony.
All his numbers were up.
Yeah.
Ejection fraction,
heart function. Maggie,
I think this drug works.
Yeah. I shouldn't have
questioned you today.
Yeah.
My bad.
It's okay.
You happy?
Yeah. Yeah, I am.
Good.
So, uh, you think I'll be able
to walk down the aisle?
Oh, yeah. Just promise me
no big dips during
your first dance, yeah?
Okay.
Megan!
I got the first flight back.
Hi...
Are you okay?
Sweetie. I'm fine.
I was crazy worried.
Oh, God.
I'm so glad you're here.
Me, too.
I'm okay.
I just gotta take it slow...
Nice work.
Thanks.
She's right through here.
And you're sure
it's really her?
Absolutely positive.
Mom?
April, I, um...
Good work today.
Thanks.
Hey.
Tell me something.
Why do you do it?
The one-night stands.
They all end up the same.
How's that?
With you alone.
Or maybe that's the point.