Previously on Grey's Anatomy...
Zola was our baby,
and she's gone and I
don't want another baby.
You and I broke up.
You basically told
me to wait for you.
What the hell happened?
That's the screw that I
just pulled out of her heart.
I supervised you inserting
pedicle screws and a plate.
She's half dead.
Dr. Altman's repairing
her heart right now.
So who's gonna
be operating on me?
Cristina.
It's her mentor's husband.
Cristina doesn't have
to know that it's Henry.
Meredith and Alex are
trapped in an ambulance
in the middle of the
highway. We think they got hit.
They're sitting in a powder keg.
We gotta get outta here
before this thing blows.
It's not right.
If she finds out that I waited,
she will never forgive me.
Her husband just died in our OR.
She'll never forgive any of us.
Victims of a sudden impact
are some of the
hardest to treat.
It's not just the collision
that injures them.
It's everything after.
The centrifugal force
keeps them moving,
tossing them from vehicles,
throwing them
through windshields,
slamming their internal
organs into the skeleton.
Their bodies are injured
over and over again.
So there's no way to know how
much damage has actually been done.
Until they stop.
Sir? Can you move?
We need to get
you off this road.
Honey.
Jessica.
Answer me.
Mom?
Mom. Mom, wake up.
Mom, wake up!
Sorry.
Help them, please.
You have to help!
My mom, my dad,
the van, and I just
stepped in blood.
- I just stepped in blood.
- Hey, what's your name?
Lilly. Okay, Lilly, I
need you to calm down
and take the baby.
Hold the baby.
I don't even babysit.
I can't hold a baby.
Lilly, do you want me to
help your family or not?
Hold the baby.
Okay, I need you to
squeeze. One, two, squeeze.
What if I mess up?
You're not gonna mess
up, Lilly. One, two, squeeze.
Count out loud
so I can hear you.
Okay, one, two, squeeze.
One, two, squeeze.
No matter what you
do, don't stop squeezing.
One, two, squeeze.
Yeah.
Ma'am, ma'am, I'm a
doctor. Can you hear me?
I don't know. Three
or four hours, I think.
Yeah, you know what? Hang
on a second. The doctor's back.
This is Laura's mom.
She wants to know how
long the surgery should take.
That depends.
Dr. Altman is working
on the repair right now.
Did you hear that?
Um, he says
Dr. Altman's still...
No, Altman.
No, for the heart.
You know, can you talk to her?
Yeah. Hi, this is Dr. Avery.
She's a cardiothoracic surgeon.
No, no, this is the heart.
No, it's really hard
to tell at this point.
Oh, no. This is cruel.
Her husband is dead,
and she has no idea.
She's sewing a woman's
heart back together.
Come on. There's gotta be
a better way to handle this.
There's no good way
to handle it, Bailey.
This is an impossible decision.
So you land on the side of
what is best for the patient,
the one who's still alive.
Teddy will understand.
You think so?
You got any tape in there? I
have to do an adhesive dressing.
Probably. I just
grabbed whatever.
Is my mom okay? Mom?
Lilly, keep counting.
Why isn't she talking?
Lilly!
One, two, squeeze.
How's she doing?
Not good. I may
have to intubate.
Don't you have to do
a pressure dressing?
Ugh. I see gray matter.
Brains are on the ground.
Wait. That's Nana. That's my...
There's nothing we can do.
Oh, crap.
This kid's got a shard
of glass in her eye.
She's unconscious.
Her pulse is low.
That's my sister.
That's Abby. Lilly...
Just see the blinker on the van?
Just watch that blinker
and keep counting.
One, two, squeeze.
Lilly. The kids. The kids.
Your girls are okay, all right?
I just helped one and the
other one's right over there.
And Michael?
What about Michael?
There's another kid?
Oh, crap.
There's no pulse. Michael?
Dad! Dad!
Lilly, keep counting!
One, two, squeeze.
Michael? Help.
Help. Michael? Michael?
Help. Help.
Okay. I'm gonna
check your pulse.
Pulse is a little weak.
All right. I'm gonna try
to free your legs, okay?
One, two, squeeze.
Meredith, there's a car coming!
Oh, crap.
Can you feel your legs?
You gotta get outta there!
- Michael!
He's trapped. I have
to get his legs free!
There's not time! Oh, my God!
Kid, just keep
counting. Meredith!
Oh, my God. You
gotta get off the road!
Come on.
Come on! Oh, my God.
Help me. Meredith!
Squeeze. No, don't leave me.
What the hell are you...
They're not even gonna see you!
Meredith, what are you doing?
Stop! Please!
Son of a...
It's okay. You're okay.
All right? Just breathe.
Just breathe. Help is here.
Help is here.
One, two, squeeze.
BP's down and she's tachycardic.
We gotta get her up to the NICU.
Units of LR.
13-year-old female,
intubated in the field.
Multiple facial fractures.
Foreign body to the eye.
You're bleeding,
you need stitches.
No, I'll be okay. I'm
gonna take care of it.
Take the mom to trauma two.
And we need to staff as
many ORs upstairs as possible.
I'll take care of
it later, I promise.
Go. We'll talk later.
What do we got?
14-year-old male,
trapped under the van.
Abdominal pain. Last vitals
show a BP of 100 over 80
and a pulse of 120.
Grey, you need someone
to take a look at that?
It's fine. Where do you want me?
Bailey needs hands on bed four.
Wait. Is that my mom?
Could you get her back in
the bed? But that's my mom.
She needs to be checked out.
Dr. Hunt, how can I help?
What are you doing here?
Is Altman out of surgery?
Almost. She's about
to take her off bypass,
but our pagers kept going off,
so she figured, maybe
you need some extra help.
Dr. Webber, I could use
you on this. You, too, Hunt.
Okay.
Okay, go back into
Altman's surgery
and tell her that
I didn't need you.
I was really hoping to log
some more trauma hours.
Kepner...
Altman's husband
died in surgery,
and she doesn't know,
so I need you in the OR.
And page me the
moment that she's...
Wait, wait. I'm sorry. What?
Kepner. Kepner. Henry's...
Can you handle this?
Yeah, yes.
No. No, no, no. You can't
go into her surgery like that.
So go to the gallery and
watch the surgery from there.
Okay?
She went about two
hours with no antibiotics
and an unknown amount of
fluids 'cause we didn't have a pump.
All right. Careful
with that suction.
We weren't able to
suction for a while.
Her pneumonia
may be getting worse.
She probably
needs another X-ray.
Well, that's great.
You did extraordinary
work tonight, Karev.
I've got it from
here. No. What? No.
Yes. You were in
a major accident.
You need to go get
yourself checked out.
Take a breath. You're
gonna sit this one out.
I'm not sitting anything out.
Yes, you are.
Goodbye.
Okay, what do we got?
His pelvis is dust.
Must be massive
internal bleeding.
Can't keep his
systolic above 68.
Okay, there's definitely
free fluid in his abdomen.
It's just hard to define where
the bleeding's coming from.
Where do you want to start?
Pelvis. Abdomen.
Abby couldn't wait
to sleep in a tent.
Sir, I'm Dr. Hunt.
BP's still dropping.
We're gonna be taking
you up to surgery.
Lilly didn't even want to come.
Okay, if we don't
stabilize this pelvis,
there won't be any surgery.
There's no time for fixators.
She wanted to spend
her birthday with friends,
not camping with us.
I said no.
I made her come. Oh, my
God, I did this to them. I did this.
You didn't harm your family.
You didn't mean
for this to happen.
You didn't do this.
Okay, sir, I am really sorry,
but even with the
painkillers, this is gonna hurt.
That should hold for now.
Okay, let's get him to surgery.
Okay.
Altman paged. 9-1-1.
Is everything okay?
Uh, we got this. Go.
Scrub in when you can.
You paged?
Yeah, the patient's
got a flail mitral valve.
The sutures for the patch caught
on the valve when
we went on bypass.
What can I do?
You can tell me
where Cristina is.
I've been paging her,
but she won't answer.
Damn it. Why won't this hold?
Okay, you need a resident?
I'll get you a resident.
No, not a resident. Yang.
This is... I need another me,
and she is the closest thing.
Don't tell her I said that.
She just got out of
surgery. She's exhausted.
All right, well,
splash some water
on her face and get her in here.
She can handle it.
All right, sponge stick.
Damn it.
Let's get an irrigation tray
and start cleaning this up.
Craniofacial lac?
It's worse than that.
We're gonna need a
retinal-vitreous surgeon.
Yeah. I've got Lexie calling
around for one right now.
Parker isn't answering, and Waldman
is gonna be at least another hour.
Try Jassy.
Jassy?
No, I got someone who
will run circles around Jassy.
Hey, babe.
Your girlfriend? Hold on, Julia.
She's great. You'll love her.
Um, you know, it's gonna
take at least 45 minutes
to get here from Seattle Pres.
She's not at Seattle
Pres. She's at my place.
It's five minutes away.
Hey, how'd you like to operate
with me and Derek tonight?
It hurts. My
stomach really hurts.
Okay, Michael, we gave
you something for the pain.
It should kick in in a minute.
Abdomen feels rigid.
Yep.
Free fluid in the
right upper quadrant.
So that could be a liver
lac. We should order a CT.
No, keep trying! That's my mom!
Okay, Michael, I need
you to stay still, please.
What's going on?
You can't just give up.
You have to keep trying.
She already watched
the grandmother die.
Yeah, go, go.
How long you been going?
What have you given her, and
what have her rhythms been?
She's been coding
for 30 minutes.
She's already gotten lidocaine
and amiodarone.
Okay, her kid's outside
the window watching.
We need to go again.
Charge to 360. Clear.
Push another of epi.
Let's charge again. Please.
Please.
Dr. Grey.
Damn it.
Charge again.
Clear.
Damn it. Come on. Come on.
Mom.
Time of death, 2:27.
Hand me the ultrasound
and get me a kit.
We're doing a
bedside gastrostomy.
What do you think you're doing?
We need to
decompress her stomach
so she doesn't get more
reflux into her trachea.
Karev, you're not on this case.
Look, I've been with
this baby since yesterday.
Okay? She almost
died. I almost died.
I didn't go through hell
with this kid to just back off.
Then slow down.
Okay? We don't need
to rush through this.
Yeah, I know. Just,
suction, please.
Cristina, just stop
for one minute
and listen to what I have to...
No. I said no.
I know you're exhausted.
This is a mitral valve...
I am not operating now!
She requested you. Now,
if you don't go in there...
Teddy requested me?
Oh, my God. You
haven't told her.
You haven't told her yet?
What are you... No, no.
No, I am not...
No, I'm not going in.
Cristina, if that patient
dies on the table,
this will all have been
for nothing. This has...
This has to be worth something.
Saving a life is
worth something.
I can't.
I can't. I can't. I can't do it.
You have no choice.
She's waiting.
So go.
How much trauma has
your girlfriend done?
A lot.
She's told me about
a bunch of her cases.
So we're just going
off your pillow talk?
If I get a hint that your
girlfriend is in over her head,
I'm gonna boot her out of my OR.
You know what your problem is?
You don't think anyone
who sleeps with me
can be talented or
have half a brain.
That is not true.
It's mostly true.
Yeah. Yeah, it's mostly true.
Your ex-wife is brilliant,
and she slept with me.
Well, I'm not trying
to start a fight.
I'm just sayin'.
Ah! Dr. Canner,
thank you very much for
showing up on such short notice.
No problem.
Fastball here just updated
me about your patient.
Again, I'm really sorry
for hitting you in the...
I'm fine. My breast
made a quick recovery.
It did.
Okay, Mark.
The glass penetrated the
globe through to the orbit.
So she's gonna lose the eye?
Normally, yes.
I was thinking, if you
used a temporal approach
to expose the orbit and
decompress the eye,
we could save it.
Well, if you do that,
there's more risk of bleeding.
That's true.
I could get control of
the blood supply first,
then enucleate the eye.
But I think the
eye is salvageable.
Either way, it's your call.
Let's save the eye.
Agreed.
Lilly.
I'm so sorry about your mom.
Yeah.
Your dad and your
sister are in surgery.
And I'm about to
take your brother up
to repair a tear in his liver.
Okay.
Do you know if
anyone in your family
is on any medications?
I don't know.
What about allergies?
Has anyone had surgery?
I don't think so.
Do you remember your
parents talking about
what they would do if
someone got really sick?
Would they want
extraordinary measures taken?
I'm sorry. I know it's
a difficult question,
but anything you
could tell us would help.
No. We don't talk
about stuff like that.
We just talk about
normal things,
so I don't...
I don't know anything.
Well, is there
anyone we can call?
Who takes care of you when
your parents go out of town?
My grandma.
But she's dead now, so...
Okay, I've got the
bleeding under control.
It's your turn, Dr. Canner.
All right, pull up my
microscope, please.
Dr. Shepherd.
Okay, 4 by 4.
Okay.
Speculum. Saline.
Dr. Shepherd. 4-0 silk.
Thank you.
Damn it.
Did you just push
the glass in deeper?
You must have speared a
branch of the ophthalmic artery.
Cautery.
All right. Let me get in there.
It's kind of hard right
now. My hand is in her eye.
Forceps. Canner.
Hold on.
There.
Bone fragment.
Thank you. I'll be needing that.
A little bleeding is
natural, Dr. Shepherd.
I'm not gonna find any more
little presents in there, am I?
Okay, everyone, here
comes the fun part.
Clamp.
All right.
Looks like a grade 4 liver lac.
Grey, do you want to do
an omental pedicle repair?
Absolutely. Okay.
Heard you lost one of your clinical
trial patients today, Dr. Bailey.
I'm sorry to hear...
It wasn't my trial
that killed him.
The man suffered
from Von-Hippel Lindau.
That's what killed him.
Well, I wasn't
implying that your trial...
Let's focus on the living patients
and not the dead ones, okay?
What'd you do?
Nothing. I'm just irrigating.
His temp spiked. CO2
levels are through the roof.
Well, what's the
problem? He's tachycardic.
Increased heart rate.
Patient's burning up.
I didn't use sux, but I
did use sevoflurane.
Ice. We need ice.
Wait. Now, this is my patient.
Run. Get ice, now.
Right away, Doctor.
Kid's about to go
into organ failure.
I'm pushing dantrolene.
Let's get some cooling blankets.
- On it.
And turn the thermostat
down in here as low as it will go.
Right away, Doctor.
Oh, my God.
Malignant hyperthermia.
Where's that ice?
What do we got? Oh, good.
I got a flail mitral valve
when I took her off bypass.
Just put her back on
and cooled her down again.
I need your hands. Okay.
Oh, and, um,
thank you
for Henry.
I am so sorry that
we had to lie to you,
but you were the only
one that I trusted to do it.
You get it, right?
Right.
You're not mad at me?
No. No.
Good. Okay.
Go get scrubbed.
Gown me.
What did Altman
want? How's the patient?
She'll be fine.
Now that I put
Cristina in there.
You...
You what? You put Yang
in the same OR with Teddy
with my patient on the table?
What the hell made you
think that was a good idea?
I believe it was your
mistake that put everyone
in this position
in the first place,
so you're really not one
to point fingers right now.
Catch me up.
I can't get visualization
of the mitral valve.
The left atrium's too small.
What about superior
pulmonary vein exposure?
Yes, good. Let's
do that. Scissors.
What is she doing up there?
Sorry?
Kepner. She's been sitting
up there like a gargoyle.
I thought there
was a big trauma.
Oh, yeah. I don't know.
Did you get a chance to
check on Henry post-op
before I pulled you in here?
I bet no one wanted her.
What?
Kepner.
Probably because her
voice can peel paint off walls.
Charge to 200.
Clear!
I mean, a trauma
is stressful enough.
Who needs that?
You're horrible.
Push 100 of lidocaine.
Am I wrong?
I'm right. Would you stop?
- Stop it.
- Kind of.
You agree with me. I can tell...
- Would you stop?
- By your eyes.
Okay, stop.
She's obviously
from the Midwest.
How are they doing?
Please stop it.
Still trying to
repair the valve.
Well, and making fun of me.
What?
Cristina doesn't want to
talk about Henry's surgery,
so instead she's
making fun of me.
I'll turn off the intercom.
No, it's...
I have to know
everything that's going on.
It's okay.
I can handle it.
Still bad visualization.
There is a lot of
unexpected fibrosis.
We're just increasing our
chances of rupturing her heart.
We can't get in there. There's
too much tension on the walls.
All right.
We need to do this right.
We're gonna do an ex vivo.
You want to take the
heart out? Can we try to...
Come on, Yang.
A cardiac autotransplantation
for an ex vivo valve
reconstruction?
If that's not on your
bucket list, it should be.
Are you up for this?
You bet.
Great. Okay.
We're gonna start with
the atria to explant the heart.
And let's get some
music in here.
What do you want
to listen to? You pick.
Let's get another
cooling blanket in here.
Grey, let's repack this liver.
Gelfoam. What's next?
We gave him dantrolene
to relax his muscles
and lidocaine to calm his heart.
He's on ice inside and out.
Only thing left
to do now is wait.
All right. Well, settle in.
Could be a while.
Dr. Warren,
isn't malignant
hyperthermia genetic?
You gotta go warn them...
Already on it.
How's she doing?
She's a little full of
herself, if you ask me,
but she's getting
the job done, I guess.
No, the kid. Abby.
You gotta watch her temp
if you gave her any sux
or inhalation anesthetics,
because our kid had a reaction.
Meredith, did you
get your stitches?
I will. Fill them in.
Pelvic stabilization's
not holding.
Get me more lap pads. More.
Do it. Yeah. I got that.
You need something?
You haven't used any sux or
inhalation anesthetic, have you?
'Cause our kid had a reaction.
Damn it. This
hematoma's expanding.
I'll occlude the internal iliac.
Try and get some
temporary control.
All right. I need more
lap sponges here.
Just watch his temp.
We got it, Grey.
Thank you. Hemoclip.
Yeah, hold it right over there.
Yep. Okay, one more. Come on.
Let's pack it.
His heart rate's coming down.
His temperature's
starting to stabilize.
Usually about the time you
realize it's malignant hyperthermia,
it's too late.
That's a nice catch.
You probably
saved this kid's life.
Figured you didn't need another
patient dying on you today.
So you did it for me?
Oh, yeah.
Any other doctor, I probably
wouldn't have said anything.
It's freezing in here.
Well, why don't you
jump up and down?
That'll warm you up.
I think I'll repair the liver.
That'll warm me up. Suction.
We have to go back in. What?
On the baby. I forgot to place
the tension-free anastomosis.
Do you hear me?
I forgot to place it.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa. Look at me.
You did the anastomosis.
I watched you do it.
You used the
double-layer technique.
You remember?
Okay. You need to sit down.
You need to sit down.
You are overtired
and probably experiencing
some residual shock.
And you're gonna
take a break this time,
for real. Yeah, but...
No. Don't argue with me, Karev.
Deep breath.
Beautiful.
Nice work.
All right. Let's prepare
for re-implantation.
You know, you're
gonna think that I'm crazy,
but there is this thing
that we used to do in med school
to try and stay awake.
And after this many
hours of surgery,
you need to stay awake.
I'm pretty awake, actually.
Whoo!
Give me a "whoo!"
Whoo.
Oh, come on. Give me a "whoo!"
Whoo!
That's not good. Come
on. You gotta wake up.
Whoo!
Okay, that's a little better.
Whoo! Whoo! Whoo!
They still going?
What the hell are they doing?
Come on.
I think they're having fun.
Whoo!
You gotta be okay.
'Cause we need you right now.
So if you can hear me,
I'm sorry for being such
a jerk on the camping trip.
I'll try to be better.
Just please wake up. You
gotta wake up, and I'll be nicer.
I'll help Michael with his
homework, and I'll babysit.
You won't even
have to pay me. Just...
Please, Dad, just
open your eyes.
Lilly,
I just came to tell you that
your brother is out of surgery,
and he's doing okay.
And so is your sister.
Okay. Okay?
Can you
make sure that nobody else
tells them about my mom?
I should be the
one to tell them.
Of course. Of course.
He's coding!
Push one of epi,
one of atropine.
Charge paddles to 200.
Charging.
Charged.
Clear.
Cardio tech, trauma one.
They're almost finished.
Now, they did have to take
her heart out of her body
to repair the valve, but the
procedure went smoothly.
It's over. They're putting
the heart back in right now.
It's good.
It's good?
My wife's body is in
pieces on some OR table,
and you're telling
me that it's good?
What is wrong
with you? I'm sorry.
I didn't... Dad?
Hey, my man. I'm here.
Go back to sleep. Okay, buddy?
Ow!
I thought peds surgeons
were supposed to be gentle.
Yeah. You look like
hell. You should go home.
Me? You smell bad. You go home.
How's the baby?
Good. Actually, really good.
How are the other kids?
Well, the oldest
daughter, I mean,
she watched her mother die,
now her father keeps coding,
and she won't leave his side.
Daddy? Daddy!
Dad, please.
Lilly, I'm sorry.
You can't be in here.
Wait. Wait.
Charge the paddles to
300. WOMAN: Charging.
Charged.
Clear.
I was paged. Code blue?
He keeps going into V-fib.
Okay, let's start compressions.
Lilly, you can't be in here.
She can't see this again.
Come on. Let's go.
No, I'm not leaving.
I'm not gonna leave.
Meredith. Lilly, please.
Stop it! It's my dad. Please.
I have a right to be here,
and I'm not gonna leave him.
Charge again. Clear.
Come on.
All right. That's
the last suture.
In that case, gentlemen,
I am all done.
Nice work, Dr. Canner.
It was a pleasure, Dr. Shepherd.
All right. I can trust
you two to finish this?
You're not gonna ruin all
the good work I just did?
Well, I wouldn't bet on it.
Follow me out, Dr. Grey.
I need to talk to
you for a second.
Me? Why?
I mean, of course, if you...
Don't worry. I'm not
gonna throw a ball at you.
It's about her
post-op instructions.
Her eye needs to
be covered 24/7.
She can watch TV all she wants,
but she can't read a book
for the first three days.
Whoa!
Okay.
Oh, thank God that is over.
Did I seem nervous in there?
Just be honest with me.
You seemed more than okay.
That is Derek Shepherd in there,
one of the best
neurosurgeons in the country
and Mark's best friend.
And the whole time I was in
there, all I could think about
was my high school
cross-country team.
Coach would always
say, "Don't look back,
"never look back, because if
the kid behind you sees that,
"he knows you're weak,
and he will run you down."
The whole surgery, that's
all I was thinking about.
Don't look back.
Well, you didn't.
Thanks.
Yeah.
Thank you, Dr. Grey.
Damn it.
Now I like her.
That's, like, the fourth time
you've had to revive him today.
Is that normal?
His body has been through a lot.
What are those tubes for?
His body is filling with fluid,
and those tubes are draining it.
And that thing
that's making noise?
It's a ventilator. It's
breathing for him.
Is he gonna wake up?
You can tell me. I can take it.
I have no way to know that.
What do you know?
I know that we haven't been able
to take him off
of the life support.
And I know that it's
very hard on his body
every time we
try and revive him,
and that it's taking longer
and longer each time we try.
And his kidney
tests are elevated.
Which means what?
Which means that
his organs are starting
to fail, one by one.
You asked me about
extraordinary measures before,
if my parents ever
talked to me about them.
What you're doing
to my dad, are those...
They are.
I think you should stop.
It's not that simple.
And it's not your call.
You're his child.
I'm not a child, not anymore.
I turned 18 four hours ago.
Today is my birthday.
And I've watched you
torture my dad for the past six.
So I'm the head
of the family now,
and it's my job.
If you take him off the machines
and he lives, then he lives.
But if you don't,
then at least we
let him go in peace.
You gotta stop.
Please.
Okay, time to close.
Would you like to do the honors?
Kepner can close.
What?
Kepner, can you close?
Uh, I can, but... Yang.
Kepner, close.
Cristina...
Can I speak to you
privately, please?
What's up? You okay?
When we brought your
husband into the OR,
we originally thought
we could go in
with a bronchoscope and a laser,
however, there
was a lot of bleeding,
so we had to open him up.
Wait. You... Wait.
No. Owen said that...
When we opened him up,
we saw that his tumor had
eroded his pulmonary artery.
Dr. Webber and I both used
extraordinary measures...
No. But we...
No, no. No.
We used extraordinary measures,
but his heart could not
tolerate the excessive bleeding.
No.
He did not survive
the surgery. I'm sorry.
You're saying...
You're saying he's dead.
Yes.
Say it.
Teddy...
When you inform the
family, you have to say it
so that they know that
it's really happening.
It's the first thing
that you're taught.
I never really
thought about it...
But now I get it, and...
Cristina,
I need you...
I need you to say it.
Henry is dead.
Thank you.
Where's Teddy?
I don't know.
Wait.
You told her?
Of course I did.
You should have let me.
I should've been the one.
Oh, my God. This is not about
you. Who cares who told her?
Okay, I told her,
because you made me
stand there and talk and joke
and lie to her for hours,
for hours.
I am sorry. I had to.
No, I know, I don't wanna...
I don't wanna hear it.
And neither will she.
Give me the chart.
Uh...
Just give me the chart.
Thank you.
Get out.
I'll give you your privacy.
So what happens now?
His heart rate will slow down,
and that's gonna
make the alarm sound,
but I can turn the sound off.
And then his breathing is
going to get slower and slower.
And then his
organs will start to fail
because they need
oxygen to survive.
And then when there's
no breathing and no pulse,
that's when he's gone.
Is this it?
This is it, sweetie.
I'll wait outside.
No, please.
Please wait.
Okay, okay.
I really should be
taking the fall for this.
I agree.
All right. Well, then I'm
just gonna walk in there
and I'm gonna tell him.
Look, let me spell
it out for you, Avery.
This is on me.
Yes, it was your mistake,
and, yes, you
should feel like crap,
but I'm your attending,
you're a fifth year,
which means that I'm responsible
for what happens in my OR,
and you get a free ride.
Well, I don't want a free ride.
Well, I don't want to
give it to you, but I will,
because you're still
young and inexperienced,
and hopefully, you'll
learn something here.
You'll start
double-checking your work,
and the work of your
residents when the time comes,
because otherwise, you'll be me,
walking in to apologize
to a family that hates me
almost as much as I
hate myself right now.
Dr. Torres, there you are.
I need to talk to you.
I know. I know, Mr. Lewis.
I want to talk, too.
Yeah, you owe me an explanation.
Okay? A real explanation.
What happened to Laura,
this is totally unacceptable.
I understand.
I was rude to you before
when you mentioned Henry.
I'm used to it.
It's kinda your thing.
Look, when bad things
happen to you, you lash out.
You want space.
That's why I'm sitting way
over here at my own table.
I'm giving you space.
I didn't just lose
a patient today.
I lost a friend.
I'm sorry.
I wouldn't mind if
you didn't give me
quite so much space.
Canner did a good job.
Yeah, she did.
Don't screw this
one up. I like her.
She's a keeper.
I'll be close by if you need me.
You can't prepare
for a sudden impact.
You can't brace yourself.
It just hits you
out of nowhere.
And suddenly
the life you knew before
is over
forever.
Oh!
What's wrong? There's
no food, and I'm hungry.
I just ordered pizza.
For breakfast?
We've been up for
39 straight hours.
It's dinner. It's a
very, very late dinner.
That cheese is old.
I'm hungry. I might die.
Don't eat the old cheese.
Come and sit down by me.
Put your head down.
I'd like to put a little salt
on your nose and eat a bite.
The pizza will be
here any minute.
Mmm-hmm.
We'll be okay.
If it's just the two of us.
If that's what you want.
I love you.
Pizza.
Don't start eating
that pizza without me.
Meredith?
Derek.
Yes?
Is that our baby?
Yes.
Yes, it is.
She's yours.
Hi. Hi, come here.
Hi.