Hey.
Yeah?
Can we get a laugh?
Come on, Luna.
How about a giggle?
No? Nothing?
- Maybe try your dance moves.
- You wanna see some moves?
Okay.
Okay, yeah.
- ♪ Oh, whoo!
♪ Say it now!
- ♪ Get up off of that thing
♪ And dance
until you feel better ♪
- Oh, yeah.
- ♪ Get up off of that thing
♪ And dance until you,
sing it now! ♪
♪ Get up off of that thing
Spin move.
Nothing.
Yeah? Is this--
Okay, okay, okay.
I'm sorry.
That was bad.
I know.
I deserve that.
- You know she'll laugh
when she's ready.
Aww, baby.
You know,
Mommy used to dance--
yeah, not better than Daddy.
She used to float on the air
like this.
She was luminous.
- Stop.
- You were.
She was.
And this is for you.
- Thanks.
- No.
I'm not just
giving you a dollar.
This is also to ensure
doctor-patient confidentiality.
- Okay, but you know my rates
are considerably higher
than that, right?
- Remember I told you that
I am going to be a grandfather?
- Mm-hmm.
- I was not supposed
to tell you that.
- Why, because it's
the first trimester?
- No, because Ella
may not keep it.
- Uh, what--what?
Okay.
How do you feel about that?
Like--
- Helpless?
- Yes.
- Yeah.
- And I don't like it.
I'm going to talk to her.
- What? No.
No, no, no, no, you can't--
you can't talk to her.
Ella's about to make
a profoundly personal decision,
one that is only hers to make.
- Yeah, but--
- Ah-ah, no "buts."
No meddling, no prying.
You can't even ask.
- So,
what can I do?
- Whatever you need to do
to not talk to her about it,
you should do that.
- There you are.
- Sorry I didn't call you back.
It's been a crazy morning.
- Seems like
all your mornings are crazy.
- How Memorial thought
that they can restructure
their entire legal department
in just two months is...
- Hey, well, in two days,
you get to walk away from it
and I get to have you
back home in my arms
while we plan
our wedding together.
- Can't wait.
- Well, sounds like you can.
- No.
I'm sorry.
I just really want to leave
the team in good shape,
and we're pretty far from that.
You've got this.
Babe, I--I gotta go.
- Love you.
- Don't look so worried, Paz.
You're just here
for your routine scan
to check on the progress
of your tumor.
Did your sister tell you
how promising
her last PET scan was?
- That's not why she's upset.
Sorry, but you should tell her.
- Paz?
- As you know...
when uterine cancer
threw a wrench
into my IVF plan, I mean,
Jasmine stepped up
to be my surrogate.
And she did months of testing
and hormone injections...
- I was going to be implanted
next week.
- But our insurance company
suddenly changed the rule.
Now they won't cover surrogacy
of any kind.
- That's insane.
When did they change the rules?
Three weeks ago, Max.
They basically stopped
covering surrogacy overnight.
- Even though both sisters
are with the same company.
- Barcroft,
who will cover Jasmine
if she wants to have a baby
and Paz if she could
have a baby,
but they won't cover Jasmine if
she wants to have Paz's baby.
I mean, it's not as if Paz's
embryo inside Jasmine's womb
is gonna cost them
any more money.
- Right, but having no baby
saves them a lot of money.
- Adoption agencies
aren't exactly queuing up
to give kids to women
with cancer, so what now?
I mean, Paz waits three years
to see if her uterus
is still "hospitable"
after all the radiation?
That's her only shot
of becoming a mother?
- Helen, if Barcroft
changed the rule overnight,
then let's get them
to change it right back.
- Dr. Ligon isn't back yet?
- Not only is he
still on vacation,
he is also the kind of person
who turns his phone off
while on vacation.
Who does that to an addict?
- Use someone else already.
I heard great things
about Dr. Parsons.
- Seven-year-old
accidental choking victim.
Got caught in window blinds.
Heart rate 118.
BP 110 over 78.
18 respirations per minute.
Setting 98% on nasal cannula.
- Okay, let's get him
to trauma one.
We're gonna take
good care of you, okay?
- That's our son.
- Yeah, you can see him
once the doctors get him
stabilized, okay?
But let me show you
where the waiting room...
- It's gonna be okay.
- Hey, hey, come with me.
- Sweetie, come on.
- Look straight ahead.
That's it, Calvin.
Good job.
Can you tell me what kind
of blinds you got caught in?
- I don't know.
Let's get Iggy and
Child Services down here now.
- What do you think?
- Let's just hope I'm wrong.
- I was, uh, cooking breakfast.
Calvin was in his room playing,
and it was quiet.
It's never quiet,
so I went to check in on him
and I saw a cord, uh,
wrapped around his little neck.
And I tried to rip it off,
but it was all knotted up,
so I started screaming
for Alana.
- I turned the house
upside down
trying to find scissors.
By the time I got them,
Calvin was turning blue.
He was thrashing,
so Ethan had to hold him still.
You know, I--I was
scared I was gonna cut him.
But I got them off
and we called 911.
- Now, if the police were
to come to your home--
- The police?
- Yeah, the police.
If they were to come
to your home, they would see
a piece of cord
lying on the floor
where your wife cut it, right?
- You know,
I think I threw it away.
- You threw it away?
- Yes, after we got him loose.
- But the rest of the cord
would still be dangling there,
severed.
That's what the police
would see.
- And--and they would also see
the scissors
lying on the floor.
And the drawers that
Alana looked through,
they would all be open.
And the breakfast
that you were cooking
would still be...
on the stove.
- Th-there were no scissors.
Um, there was no cord.
It was, uh...
Just me.
But I swear,
it'll never happen again.
Please don't--
please don't take him away.
- So what are you saying,
that I'm lying?
- The marks on Calvin's neck
aren't abrasions.
They're bruises.
A cord didn't do it.
Hands did.
It was me.
He was having a tantrum.
I just snapped.
I didn't know I was choking him.
I just wanted him to stop.
- Ethan, I don't think
that your son
was choked by a man.
The wounds on his neck
were far too small.
- May I see your hands?
- A person who chokes someone
often has defensive wounds
on their hands
from the fingernails
of the person they're choking.
You don't.
- What happened
to your brother, Juliet?
- I wanted his phone,
so I took it.
- Thank you for choosing
Barcroft insurance.
This is Jonathan, how can I
be of service to you today?
- Uh, Jonathan, hi.
This is, uh, Dr. Max Goodwin,
uh, calling about
a recent policy change.
No, no, I don't need billing.
Operator.
- I'm sorry.
I didn't catch that.
- Operator!
- This is regarding
account number 42118?
- No, it's regarding Paz Aquino.
She's not a number.
She's a person.
I know this is
the wrong department, Frank,
but it seems to be
the only department
populated by people.
- Our call center's
in Bangalore.
- Bangalore, wow.
Uh, is there any way
you could connect me
to someone a little closer
to this side of the Earth?
- Good afternoon.
- Mm, is it?
you don't happen to be located
anywhere in the
Western Hemisphere, do you?
- I'm in Kuala Lumpur.
- Kuala Lumpur.
Um, forgive my ignorance.
Is that closer to New York City
than Bangalore?
- Please hold.
Let me check on that.
Happy to.
- How do you think Calvin felt
when you hurt him?
- Well, you know,
if I had to take a guess--
which I don't,
but I'm going to--
I would say that
he was probably afraid.
- I don't know.
- Hey, I am going
to say a sentence,
and then you tell me
if it describes you.
Can we do that?
Okay, cool.
"I think that
most other people are stupid."
- I don't think that.
- All right,
what about this one.
"I manipulate people
to get what I want."
- No.
- Juliet, come on.
It's okay.
It's just me and you in here.
Right?
I've seen tons of kids
come through here.
It's obvious to me that
you are, like, mega smart.
I'll bet you're the best
at manipulating people.
- I'm really good at it.
- Why?
Why do you think
you're so good at it?
- It's--it's kind of like
when I draw.
- You mean manipulating people
makes you feel in control?
- No.
I mean, it's just really easy.
- Mackenzie Adams?
- Yeah, hi.
- Hi.
- This is my husband, John.
Hi.
- I'm Dr. Reynolds,
cardiothoracic surgery.
- Cardio?
- Uh, we came here because
my wife, uh,
lost control of her bladder.
- I'm sure it's just a UTI.
- Well, no.
The urologist said that all of
your tests came back negative,
so cardio's the next step
in the workup.
- Well, my heart is fine.
- Well, heart issues
can affect bladder control,
so we'll just do an EKG to
measure your heart's activity.
- We're not even from New York.
We're just visiting.
- It's a simple test,
Mrs. Adams.
- Colonel Adams.
She's an astronaut.
- Oh.
- I'm scheduled to fly out
on Expedition 64
to the
International Space Station
in 58 weeks.
I've been working toward this
my entire life.
This is my first space mission,
so nothing can be wrong
with my heart.
Uh, what are you doing?
- Mm.
- Earth to Vijay.
- I am meditating.
- Okay.
Why?
- To control
the chaos in my mind.
Because I cannot
talk to someone
I desperately want to talk to.
- Well, that sounds
completely pointless,
but you know what?
I am desperate,
so I'm gonna give it a go.
Come on, help me up here.
- Okay, now fold your legs.
Sorry.
Close your eyes and breathe.
- I'm sorry, do you have
to breathe so loud?
- Mm!
- Hello, this is Aneel.
- Aneel Jay who works
in the East 34th offices
of Barcroft Insurance?
- Uh, yes.
- Who works
in the appeals department
on the seventh floor?
- Can I help you
with something?
- Yeah, uh, could you remind me
of your office number?
- 728.
What is this regarding?
Hold on.
Yeah?
- Hey, it's regarding the
extremely impersonal practice
of trying to help someone
over the phone.
I just think nothing
really gets done
until you sit down with someone
face to face.
You know what I mean?
- I was just leaving for lunch.
- Were you?
I know a great place.
The honey yogurt's really good
if you want to try it.
- Look, it was
an abrupt change, I know,
but last year,
Barcroft hemorrhaged
an unprecedented $80 million
in surrogacy coverage.
- Sure, but how many babies did
you help bring into the world?
- We don't track
that kind of data.
- Mm.
That's why I brought you here.
Your company gives you data.
You get case numbers
instead of stories.
You get account numbers
instead of people.
- What is this?
- This is account number 42118.
- Her name is Paz Aquino.
- Excuse me.
- Hey, Aneel?
- And people say
insurance companies are cruel?
- I'm just trying to show you--
- Human suffering?
Thanks,
but I hear heartbreaking
stories every day.
Along with the carpal tunnel
and the crappy paycheck,
it comes with the job.
- Then why don't you help me
do something about it?
- I may have a title
that sounds effectual,
but I have absolutely no power.
I can't help you do anything.
- "I think that tears
are a sign of weakness."
- Agree.
- "I think that other people's
feelings are not important."
- Agree.
- "I think about
hurting my family."
- Agree.
- Just your brother?
Who else?
- My mom and dad.
- Why do you want to hurt them?
- Because I can.
- You know, I mean, it's early,
and one session
is a small sample, but, uh,
Juliet does present
as callous-unemotional.
- You're saying
she's a psychopath.
- She's been to dozens
of doctors.
We've heard schizophrenia,
ADHD, RAD.
No one's ever said "psychopath."
- Callous-unemotional.
It's, um--it's not a diagnosis
that doctors really
like to give because,
historically speaking,
there is no cure.
- Then what do we do?
- Well...
- She'll go into
an inpatient facility
run by
the corrections department.
- Jail?
She's 11.
- Hold on, hold on, hold on.
There is one other possibility.
Um, punishment bounces off
of callous-unemotional kids
because they can't feel shame,
but there has been some very
promising behavioral therapy
based on a reward system.
I'm sure you've noticed
Juliet's reward drive
is extremely high.
That's why she takes
whatever she wants.
So if I can demonstrate
some progress with Juliet,
we can admit her here.
She could be an inpatient
at New Amsterdam.
- Dr. Frome?
- Yeah.
- Have you ever had success
with a child like Juliet?
- No.
- You okay?
- Sex.
I just replaced pills with sex.
I would say that
I make the worst decisions,
but you know what?
I'm not even sure
that I make decisions.
I just do things.
- Why is that bad?
If all of your instincts
tell you to do something,
why shouldn't you do that?
My instincts told me
to bang my physical therapist,
and it is not going well.
I thought I was
distracting myself
from the pain,
but you know, actually,
I think I was distracting
myself from being sober.
You know what?
Enough is enough.
God, it is time
to face reality--
to stop avoiding
and start making decisions
that are actually good for me,
like go to an NA meeting.
- You just got
all of that from meditating?
- Yeah.
That is how it works, right?
Yeah?
No.
- Not here to harass you.
I'm just here to apologize.
- You are?
- Yes.
And to find out
what office your boss is in.
- You can't be serious.
- Face to face.
It's gotta be worth something.
- Tenth floor, 1021.
- 1021?
- Mm-hmm.
- Thank you.
So at New Amsterdam,
we run into
arcane policy inconsistencies
all the time.
For example, Frances--
may I call you Frances?
- I'd rather you didn't.
- Okay, sure.
For example, there is
a very expensive spinal surgery
that is covered
by your base policy,
yet there is another procedure
that is less expensive
and less invasive that is not.
And that means that
Barcroft is, in turn,
shelling out more money
than it has to.
My patient, Paz Aquino--
- Account number?
- It's 42118.
- Her claim was denied
because Barcroft
no longer covers surrogacy.
- So I've heard,
but Barcroft will cover
a uterus transplant for her,
which is a procedure
that will cost ten times more.
So, uh,
I guess what I'm saying is,
if Barcroft doesn't want to
reverse its policy on surrogacy,
then I am gonna have
to advise all of my patients
to consider
uterine transplants instead.
And how do you think that's
gonna affect your bottom line?
- That's a good point.
Maybe we should stop covering
uterine transplants
starting now.
Hm.
- No, it is not covered--
- Hi, so sorry.
Can you tell me who her boss is?
- You have a condition called
supraventricular tachycardia.
It's an atypically fast
heartbeat that develops when
the heart's normal electrical
impulses are disrupted,
and the frequency
of the palpitations
forced your kidneys
into overdrive,
which overwhelmed your bladder.
- How do we fix it?
- Well, I can do
a catheter ablation.
It'll destroy the source
of the problem.
It's non-surgical.
You won't even have
to be put under.
- NASA has run
hundreds of tests on me.
How did they miss this?
- It might be the first time
it happened.
- Will it happen again?
- It's hard to tell.
It might.
- It won't.
We came here last-minute
for family.
I just need to get back
to Houston, back to training.
- Mack.
- NASA said I'm fine,
so I'm fine.
- Um, Mackenzie,
the attack you had today
probably lasted a few seconds,
but a serious one
could last a few minutes,
maybe even hours.
And instead of losing control
of your bladder,
you could lose consciousness.
If that happens
while you're in space,
your whole mission
could be compromised.
You could risk the lives
of your crew.
- I would never do that.
- Then don't walk out of here.
- If I do this procedure,
will I still be cleared to fly?
- If it's successful,
this will take care
of the problem permanently.
After a period of observation,
I don't see a reason why
you'd be grounded.
- You got this.
- Paz, I have your scan results
from this morning.
Your tumor has stopped
responding to the chemo.
To prevent it from spreading,
you'll need to have
a full hysterectomy.
Once we remove the cancer
from your body,
you will enter remission faster
and you will survive.
- But...
Then there--there's no way....
I'm never gonna have a baby.
- Hey, look at me.
We will find a way.
Sorry.
I know that there are more
important things than--
but I always dreamed
of having a child.
Yeah, I know that sounds
old-fashioned and--
- No, no, no.
No, it doesn't.
It sounds human.
- Okay, let's play a game.
I will set a task,
and if you complete it,
you win.
- What do I win?
- I am gonna give you
Iggy Bucks.
- Those look lame.
- Well, I'm not done.
Iggy Bucks are how you get
to the real prize.
50 of these earns one hour
with this bad boy.
All right?
It just so happens that
this first task can earn you
all 50 Iggy Bucks in one go.
- What's the task?
- You apologize to your brother.
- No.
- Why not?
- He deserved it.
- Juliet, I know that
you don't feel sorry,
and I know that you may
never feel sorry,
but hurting Calvin
was a big deal.
And a big deal
means a big apology,
but it also means
a big reward.
You in?
- If a big apology
means a big reward...
what about a small apology?
- Yeah, sure, okay.
We'll start small.
One small apology,
10 Iggy Bucks.
- What's that?
- Oh, um, that's something
that one of my kids made me.
- It's ugly.
Is your kid stupid?
I'm--I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it.
Small apology.
10 bucks.
- Oh, okay.
Um, that is not--wow.
I--I didn't, um--
- Okay, golly gee.
Wow, hoop-dee-doo.
- Is that supposed to be me?
- I'm so sorry.
20 bucks.
- All right, I didn't say
that I was playing.
- You never said
you weren't, Fat Face.
Were you fat as a kid?
Did other kids make fun of you
because you were fat?
I'm so sorry.
30 bucks.
- Okay, Juliet, why don't we
go over the rules of the game--
- You sweat.
You're sweaty.
You have sweat stains
under your arms.
That's gross.
I'm sorry.
40 bucks.
- Okay, I'm not playing.
I--
Dr. Frome,
I'm really sorry.
50 bucks.
I win.
- Okay, take it easy, man.
I'm just trying to help out.
Aneel? Aneel?
- Come on.
- Hey, this is my friend Aneel.
He's gonna explain everything.
Could you explain to them that
we're just trying...
- Come on.
- To help people?
That we're trying
to do the right thing?
Aneel?
- Ella?
I have been trying to fight
my instinct the whole day
and I have finally decided
to come to you.
For a cup of coffee.
- Coffee.
- I do not want to discuss
your personal matters,
but I...
I do want...
Yes, I do want cream and sugar.
Okay.
- I do not want to pry, meddle,
or counsel you in any way.
So from now on,
for my cup of coffee,
I will go
to the other coffee shop
so no unintentional or
misconstrued advice slips out.
But for now...
I do want a croissant.
No.
Chocolate one, please.
- Dr. Bloom.
Dr. Ligon is back tomorrow
and can see you
at the usual time.
- No, actually, I would like
to book an appointment
with Dr. Parsons
for tomorrow morning.
- Mm, Dr. Parsons'
all booked up tomorrow morning,
but Dr. Ligon is free.
- What about tomorrow afternoon?
- Dr. Ligon
has an opening at noon.
- Parsons.
- I'll squeeze you right in.
- Thank you.
- I see the aberrant pathway.
Hmm.
Well, there's a second pathway.
- What does that mean?
- All right, if do more
than one ablation,
it could weaken your heart
and increase the chance
of recurrence.
- I'm sorry, Mackenzie.
You need surgery.
- That will ground me.
- Well, so will a fragile heart.
When I was little,
I used to sneak out of the house
when everyone was asleep.
I would lie in the yard
and feel the dark all around me,
and I would look up
at the stars and I knew...
that someday,
I would be up there with them.
I really
thought I would get there.
All right, I don't like it,
but I can do two ablations.
It will destroy
all the damage, but...
after the procedure,
you have to let me
put your heart through
a stress test.
- Is that dangerous?
- Well, if the ablations
are insufficient,
it could push Mackenzie
into cardiac arrest.
You could die.
- I won't.
I won't.
- So, Mackenzie's resting.
We'll do the stress test
in the morning.
Thank you.
- Can I ask you something?
- How can I be
married to someone
who loves space
more than she loves me?
- Well, I wasn't gonna
put it like that.
- I love Mackenzie
the way she loves the stars.
She loves me more
than anything on Earth.
Can't ask for more than that.
- Could ask her to stay.
- Uh, you think
John Glenn's wife
ever asked him to stay?
- I wouldn't blame her
if she had.
You know what
the Kármán line is?
It's the boundary
where Earth ends
and space begins.
Loving Mack means
helping her cross that line,
even if she's leaving me
on the other side of it.
- I really thought
that face to face...
How could they say no?
- But it's so unfair.
- Yeah.
- I mean, even without
the financial issues,
IVF is--
it's so fraught.
It's just so filled with hope
and with...
despair, and--
and blame.
- Helen?
Did you...
- After the accident,
everything just seemed so....
fragile.
I don't really know
what I was waiting for.
It's what I've always wanted,
so I just went
and I made it happen.
And the minute that I did it,
I knew that I'd made a mistake.
Because I want to be a mum,
but I realized that
I don't want to do it alone.
And luckily, it didn't take.
- We can't let Paz lose.
- Juliet, grab a seat.
So, you were really
very good at my game.
- Your game was easy.
- Yeah, you kicked my butt good.
But I'm not so sure
if you're ready
for the harder version.
Expert level.
- I'm great at games.
- You are.
Yeah, you're great at games
because you like winning,
but also because
you like making
other people lose.
You made me lose emotionally.
You made Calvin lose physically.
Whenever you win,
someone else has to lose.
- That's how winning works.
- Yes, but not in expert level.
In expert level,
you have to win
without the other person
ever knowing that they lost.
You make somebody angry,
you upset them, that's it.
Game over.
You lose.
- What do I get if I win?
- Calvin's phone.
- So...
when do we start?
- Right now.
- All right, Mackenzie,
I'm going to inject your IV
with enough adrenaline
to simulate
the stress of launch
and reentry, all right?
Now, it's going to be
extremely intense, all right?
It's gonna feel like
your heart's pounding
right out of your chest,
but the first sign of trouble,
I'm gonna stop the test
and intervene.
Okay.
- Now, the target
is 195 beats per minute.
If you can achieve that
without any cardiac event,
you should be clear to fly.
Ready when you are.
Faster.
Breathe.
Mackenzie? Mackenzie?
- Come on back.
- Congratulations.
You passed.
You did it.
- We did it?
Oh...
- Hey, sweetie.
- Hey, Dad.
Hey, Cal.
Hey.
- I'm sorry I hurt you
for a stupid phone.
I really didn't mean to...
and I'm...
really sorry.
- Okay.
- Can I--can I play
with your phone?
- I'm not done.
- But I apologized.
Here.
Trade.
- No.
- I want it.
I apologized.
- Juliet--
- I think we're done here.
- I want it!
I want it!
I want it! I want it!
Shh.
I don't know why
I get so angry,
and I wish I did,
because everyone thinks
I don't care about anyone,
but I do!
I care about you.
And I want your phone because
when we play the same games,
that's the only way
I know how to be close to you.
- I thought you hated me.
- I hate that I'm...
different from you.
Thank you.
- You call that progress?
That was terrifying.
She manipulated them.
- Okay, yeah.
I mean, I'll give you
that it wasn't exactly
a Hallmark moment, but come on.
We all operate on
a reward system of some kind.
You know, you do good in school,
you get good grades,
your parents buy you a car.
You hold down a job
and you get money.
We'll spend the next few years
shifting Juliet's prizes
from phones to real-world things
and then who knows?
If she can learn to always
play on expert level,
maybe she'll win the big prize--
a normal life.
- But...
there will always be something
missing with her.
- Yes, empathy.
She'll never have it,
so we have to have it for her.
- Thank you for choosing
Marcos Insurance.
This is Melissa.
How can I be of service
to you today?
- Hi, Melissa,
I'm just calling to see
if your company provides
coverage for surrogacy.
- Well, I'm sorry, sir.
Unfortunately,
Marcos Insurance
does not cover surrogacy
of any--
- I wanted to be a doctor.
- You did?
- I did a year of med school,
but I couldn't cut it,
and I've spent
the last ten years
kind of numb
because instead
of helping people,
I ended up doing
the exact opposite.
Until today.
- Trustee exemption?
- Anyone on
the board of trustees
can override a policy claim
without changing
the policy itself.
- Then you found a trustee
and got them to make
an exception for 42118?
- No.
I got them to make an exception
for Paz Aquino.
She and her sister
can proceed with IVF.
- Aneel?
- No.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- How did you pull this off?
- I talked to someone
at the top, face to face.
- Yes.
Thank you.
- ♪ I was never ready
♪ To face myself
♪ Gamble
♪ Everything's in shambles
♪ It took me two full years
♪ To make it right
♪ Hoo
- How's it going?
- Good, good.
There's still a ton to do,
so I doubt I'll get to sleep
before landing
in New York, but--
- But you love it, right?
- I do love it.
- Hey, how much time
would you need
to finish out there?
- Six weeks.
But I don't expect you to--
- Then I'll see you
in six weeks.
- ♪ The same mistake
- Um,
I don't know what
that was earlier...
- ♪ Twisted through
a gas light ♪
- But if I want to talk
to someone in the future,
I would like to talk to you.
- Ella.
- Whatever you decide...
We will always be family.
- Oh, Max.
Join me to celebrate
Paz and Jasmine.
- Yeah, well, I would love to,
but we actually, uh,
already ordered bottle service.
So, think we're good.
Oh.
Luna...
Was that your first laugh?
Oh, my God.
We gotta show Mommy that laugh.
I didn't mean to--
- No, of course.
- Think things come out, uh--
- I know.
- We have a, uh,
picture of Georgia
that we talk to sometimes.
- You don't have to explain.
- That was her
saying good night.
Okay.