Cancer is a biological bully,
always picking a fight,
and it'll sneak up on you.
Can we just stay in bed all day?
I could be into that.
You are not making
this any easier.
Okay, okay, 15 minutes.
I have 15 minutes until I absolutely
have to get up and get going.
All right, well, then let's make
the most of the next 15 minutes!
It'll wait until the
body feels safe,
until it feels
healthy and strong...
I can't believe I'm dating a
man who lives in a tin can.
A tin can on wheels.
You ever think of moving
to a place that can't roll away?
I haven't given it much thought.
Mmm. Not that I
don't love the trailer
and the roughing it in nature.
It's like camping.
Wait. Wait. You hate camping.
I hate camping. I do. Yeah.
Yeah.
Well, maybe we
should look at getting
a bigger place... Together.
I thought you hadn't
given it much thought.
I just did. I'm a fast thinker.
What do you think?
I think that's a good idea.
I'm a fast thinker, too.
That's when cancer
will move on in
and get bigger and bigger.
What do you think, the
blue or the, uh, burgundy?
The blue makes you
look too handsome.
Oh.
You don't want the
president to be distracted
by those piercing blue eyes.
Oh, you want me to get the job.
I want neurosurgeon
Dr. Shepherd to get the job.
I don't want my husband
That's complicated.
Yes, well, I'm complicated.
I'm gonna take a shower now.
So am I.
No. It's been three weeks.
You went back on your promise.
I can't sleep with a
man who's a lying liar.
What if I put on the blue tie?
Nope.
You're having fun.
You delight in my pain.
I just took off my robe.
Now I'm soaping myself up.
Oh, my goodness.
The body never
even sees it coming...
Callie, come on. We got to go.
Well, we said we'd
each do a box a day.
I'm doing mine,
so come do yours.
No, no, no. Sofia's ready to go.
Come on, it'll
just take a minute.
Callie... Unpack this box!
You know, the whole
world is not going to end
if I don't open this box...
Open it.
Because cancer is
the master of surprises.
I inscribed the band
with the date we
moved into this house.
Our new start.
Calliope Iphegenia Torres...
Put it on!
Take it off!
Take it off! Your ring. - Oh.
Take off your ring.
Thank you, Dr. Avery.
I am, um... I'm glad you agree
that a microvascular free
flap is called for in this...
Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
Particular scenario.
Well, you are not getting
your security deposit back.
Glad I never gave you one.
You guys are really serious.
Yes, we are.
What did I miss?
Owen and Emma
are moving in together.
He holds a meeting for that?
Thank you all for coming.
I know you're all busy,
so this won't take long.
The board has just approved
a new non-fraternization policy.
This hospital has to be
a safe work environment
where our focus remains
clearly on providing
the best patient care possible.
Moving forward,
all relationships
with co-workers
will be discouraged.
And all relationships between
superiors and subordinates
is strictly prohibited.
You will all receive a
copy of the new rules.
Your supervisors will arrange
meetings to go over the details.
And that's it. Let's
get back to work.
So you're the panty police now?
I know there will
be some feelings,
and I know you've established
good relationships
with the residents,
so I'd like you to
take them today
and make sure that they
understand the policy.
So you want me to
be the panty police.
All due respect, nuts to that.
Dr. Hunt, we have some
questions about the policy.
Dr. Webber can answer
all of your questions.
Radiology.
Hey, Rory. How you doing?
Besides the fact that I
have bone cancer, I'm great.
Seriously. Look at this polish.
It's called "bad to the bone."
Mm! We saw it at the drugstore,
and it was like God
ordered us to buy it.
Hey, I don't take any
orders from any god
who gives me cancer twice.
Dude, your stupid brain
cancer got us a puppy,
and your stupid bone cancer
is getting us
both out of finals.
You're right.
Yay, God.
Take a deep breath.
All right, so today's
gonna be a piece of cake.
We're gonna stage
the tumor, do a biopsy,
and then we'll come
up with a treatment plan.
This isn't a brain
tumor coming back?
I mean, it was six
years ago, but...
No, I looked at Dr. Shepherd's
notes and his follow-up scans,
and I really think
that you beat that.
I think this is a totally
separate cancer.
Are you having any
trouble breathing?
No.
She has decreased breath sounds.
Let's add a contrast
study to that staging CT.
Why? What do you think it is?
Uh, the contrast just gives
us more of a detailed look.
Um, yeah, you know,
and it'll give your toes
a chance to dry
before the biopsy.
Perfect. CALLIE: Yeah.
Coming through!
What do we got?
Lisa Campbell, 32, found
in apartment trash chute.
Compactor tore her leg up
pretty good before it jammed.
Lost a lot of
blood in the field,
but vitals are stable.
Why was she in a trash...
Foraging for food, probably.
How many times
do I have to tell you?
I'm not homeless.
I don't forage.
I have a PhD.
On my count. One, two, three.
Okay, start her on
one gram of Cefazolin.
We need to clean
this out. Page plastics.
I'll do it. All right, Lisa,
is there anyone you'd
like for us to call?
My boyfriend.
I was in that trash
chute for two days.
He's probably worried sick.
His name is Ted.
If his wife answers,
hang up and try
again in an hour.
- This can't be legal.
- It is.
The hospital is allowed
to create any policy
regarding co-workers
dating that they see fit.
Shepherd met Grey
while she was an intern.
And what about
Warren and Bailey?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
We're married, so just...
If dating co-workers
is frowned upon,
how are they supposed
to meet anyone?
I'm good. You don't
have to worry about me.
You spend half
your life here, Shane.
This is your dating pool.
Why am I the only one
who thinks this is ridiculous?
They shouldn't be
able to do this to us.
Nobody's doing anything to you.
This is being done for you.
One of your own
didn't feel safe at work
and lodged an
anonymous complaint.
One of our own?
You realize you just made
my relationship illegal.
Pretty sure he just
said it was anonymous.
Yeah, right.
That's a giant mass.
Could be a met.
She had brain
cancer six years ago,
and Torres is doing a biopsy
on a possible osteosarcoma.
Three cancers by
the ripe, old age of 16.
That's bad luck or
something genetic.
Bailey's gonna test for a link.
What do you think?
Highly invasive.
I don't think you can remove it
without shrinking it first.
What if she doesn't
respond to chemo?
Then we still need to figure out
a surgical approach
that won't just kill her.
We need to be as
aggressive as this cancer.
Mm. Okay.
All right, folks.
You're gonna study
her case files,
look at the scans.
I want you to come up with
a surgical treatment plan.
The board did you a
favor with this new rule.
You're gonna take all that
brain power you used to
devote to penises and vaginas
and put it to some good use.
Um, can we, uh, use
other doctors as resources?
What, like your wife?
Yes, you should, and you can.
Work as a team.
Bounce ideas off of one another.
You come up with
something, I'm all ears.
So, uh, you guys want to start
throwing some ideas around or...
I'm good on my own.
My flight leaves
at 9:00 tonight.
The cab's gonna pick me up here.
The kids are in daycare.
The laundry is clean and folded,
and the kitchen
is fully stocked.
It's one last interview.
You've said that before
the last two interviews.
I know. I will see
you before I leave.
Where you going?
Uh, actually, I have another
interview with the White House.
Oh, show-off.
Hey, do you want to sleep over?
You can help me
try and figure out
why my research
isn't working. Aw.
And you can help
me with the kids.
Mnh-mnh. Sounds
like fraternization.
We could talk about
Owen and Emma.
Oh, what's there to talk about?
They're moving in. Whatever.
I have wine.
I'll be there.
Yeah. Figured.
For you.
So, we're supposed to fill
this whole thing up with spit?
No. To the line.
How?
Think about dill pickles.
Oh, my God. It works.
Every time.
And this is going to tell you...
If there's a genetic reason
why you all keep getting cancer.
Well, it's got to be
in my wife's side.
There's been a couple of breast,
a pancreas, a lung, and a butt.
Oh, and Billy's balls.
But we keep surviving.
We beat cancer.
Yep.
That's what we do.
Go ahead and alert the OR.
I have a debride leg repair.
Right away, Doctor.
God, Lisa.
I told you not to
come to the party.
I also told you not
to have a secret affair
with the head of the sociology
department, by the way.
I know. I know. You're right.
But, you know, I
wasn't going to go,
but then everyone from
the department was going.
It would have looked
strange if I wasn't there.
Really? You don't think
getting stuck in his trash chute
with a piece of
fish in your hair
looks more strange
than not going to a party?
Mnh-mnh.
How did this happen?
Well, you know, he
ignored me all night,
which maybe I'm used to
because that's
how we are in public.
But after a while, I just...
I couldn't take it anymore.
So, I grabbed my coat and
made a break for the door,
but just as I was
about to leave,
he called my name,
and I stopped because...
finally.
But all he did
was ask if I'd mind
throwing out the
trash on my way out.
And I didn't know what to say,
so I took the bag, the
big, smelly trash bag,
and I tossed it in the chute.
But I was so mortified
because I didn't realize
I had thrown my
purse along with it.
So, you jumped in after it?
Oh, I clearly make
excellent choices.
Does Ted know what happened?
No. I didn't tell him.
I was trying to
preserve your dignity.
Thank you.
I didn't realize there was
nothing left to preserve.
Um, well, I certainly can't do
anything about your dignity,
but if we're gonna
preserve this leg,
we need to get you
right up to the OR.
Is that a shrimp tail?
Oh, no, that's a prawn.
Ted's wife prepared them.
They were actually really good.
Oh, my God.
Well, the prelim path report
looks like high-grade
osteosarcoma.
But we'll need another
day to get the final report.
We still need to figure out
what's going on in her chest.
Yeah.
Hey! Did you show Kepner?
No, no, no, she's
working with Avery all day,
so I didn't want to brag.
Ah, good call. Yeah.
But then we had
coffee, and it sparkled,
so I ended up, you know,
showing it off, anyway.
There were squeals.
Hey, Karev, do you notice
anything different about me?
No.
Callie gave it to me.
We're trying to
unpack a box a day.
So, this morning, Callie was...
Hey, you know, most
people at least pretend
to like this story, so...
Alex, you can't keep
ignoring my pages.
We really need to talk.
Not now. If not now, when?
We can't sneak off to
have a private conversation.
It's forbidden!
Oh, will you stop?
It's just a stupid rule.
Nobody's taking it seriously.
I'm taking it seriously.
You don't have to worry about
it because you have seniority,
but I'm a resident.
This is my reputation we're
talking about, my career.
I know that you
think the rule is crap,
but we can't just
ignore it at my expense.
You're overreacting!
No, I'm not!
Oh, so, what, you're
just gonna roll over
and let the hospital tell
you who you can be with?
There isn't a choice.
There's always a choice!
You can choose to make
the best out of a bad situation.
You can choose
to act like an adult.
not to pick a fight
in front of the entire hospital.
You want to walk around here
and pretend like we don't
mean anything to each other?
Fine. I'll make it easy for you.
We don't mean
anything to each other,
not anymore, 'cause we're done!
That is not what I want. Alex!
Are you okay?
Hmm.
Hey. How was that?
Alarmingly convincing.
Just stop freaking out, okay?
Now I will.
Thanks for doing that for me.
I'll see you tonight.
You know, I appreciate
the dinner date,
but I thought Webber told
you people to work together.
We're not gonna get
anywhere that way.
I know this
non-fraternization policy
is gonna be beneficial
in the long run,
but for now, it just
gives those kids
one more reason to shut me out.
Um, just who are you
trying to fraternize with?
Um, my wife.
They're mad at me
because I get to be happy.
Mm.
Seems hardly fair.
I agree.
But, uh, you know, they're
gonna hate me anyway.
So might as well get
something out of it, right?
Ben Warren, we are at work.
Mmm-hmm.
But you can lock that door.
Oh, my God.
Already?
I haven't even
gotten started yet.
No, uh, there's a
mutation in the P53 gene.
What does that mean?
Emma probably keeps a nice home,
has window treatments,
uses place mats.
Oh, place mats are overrated.
I want him to be happy.
I'm enjoying torturing Derek.
Does that make
me a terrible person?
Mnh-mnh. Mnh-mnh.
Mm. It's weird, though.
It's really over.
I'm empty.
Yep.
That window is closing.
She is gonna give him babies,
and then he's gonna
be somebody's daddy.
And then it's really over.
But you guys are divorced
and seeing other people.
Doesn't that mean it's
really over, anyway?
Oh, come on. You should
know better than anyone
that that is not true.
But somebody's daddy?
You kind of can't
get between that.
You're supposed
to be on a plane.
They called me before I
even left to go to the airport
and canceled the interview.
Well, what does that mean?
The president dumped him.
Shh! Oh.
You know, I'm out. I'm out.
You guys, uh, have,
uh, a good night.
I'm catching a cab.
Bye, bye, bye.
Kiss to the girls.
I think I'm gonna turn in.
You don't know that it's over.
What did they say?
I better turn in.
Congratulations!
I heard you're moving...
In with Emma!
Um, yeah.
We might, yeah.
Yeah, so I brought
you some wine!
Whoa, what...
Wait. This is a very
nice bottle of wine.
Yeah, I know.
Uh, uh, I swiped it
from Derek's collection.
It looked really expensive.
So, enjoy!
The both of you.
Oh, no, Emma's...
She's not here.
Oh.
So, what's the plan now?
Should I start sneaking
in your bedroom window?
You do live with one
of the board members.
I told you, she's at Mer's.
Yeah, I'm not just
talking about tonight.
Look. Things will blow over.
I'll work on Mer and
Cristina. This will all go away.
Until then, yeah,
maybe you sneak in
my bedroom window.
But Yang's supposed
to be out all night tonight.
Yeah. You want to go upstairs?
I would, but upstairs
is just so far away.
Hi.
I got so many compliments
on my ring today.
Ooh.
It's so sad, though,
about Alex and Wilson.
Oh, yeah. Mmm.
It's not fair, right, that
we get to be so happy
and other people have
to be so miserable?
Yeah, like April...
Just out in the cold.
I feel terrible.
Awful.
Mmm.
Who am I gonna sleep with?
The hospital is my dating pool.
Mm-hmm.
You... You are
making it impossible
for me to get laid.
Well, I don't think that
has ever been a problem.
Yeah, well...
Mmm.
Were you sad
there weren't any window
treatments at the firehouse?
What?
You know, drapes and, uh,
the thing that
goes on top of it.
Uh... What are they called?
It's a curtain rod?
Mnh-mnh. No.
I mean, yes, obviously
you need that,
but there's that other thing.
I should know this.
My mother is an
interior decorator.
I spent my childhood
listening to her talk
about these things.
Who are you... Are you...
Mom? Hey, it's me.
Yes. Yeah, I know it's late.
No, I'm fine.
Listen, uh, what do you call,
uh, those things that are
on top of your windows?
No, the other thing.
Valance! Yes!
Thank you. Okay, good night.
Valance.
Were you... Were you sad
we never had valances?
No.
No. A little bit?
No. No.
I'm not sad...
That we didn't have valances.
It never occurred
to me, you know,
to get window treatments.
I know.
I'll input them for you.
Great. Thank you.
Hey, sorry I couldn't
come by last night.
Oh, no, no, it's fine.
I had three surgeries,
including an emergency
C. At 28 weeks.
Baby's fine.
Oh, that's great.
Yeah, it is. It was.
And so are you.
And I wanted to say
something in person,
um, but I'm...
Okay, I'm just nervous,
so I'm just gonna say it.
So, we're gonna look at houses,
and there's gonna be
that awkward conversation
about how many bedrooms we need,
awkward because
this is kind of new
and we haven't really
talked about kids,
and houses have bedrooms,
and kids go in bedrooms.
So, um, okay, I'm just gonna...
I would like two
kids, maybe three,
and I plan on not working
until they're in school
and being the kind of mom
that walks them to school,
so I need a good
school district.
I'm freaking you out.
Um... Crap.
When I went
over this in the car,
uh, it didn't sound so "marry
me and sire my children."
It was reasonable.
No, it...
It is.
You should be
talking about this stuff.
Good.
Hmm. I'm not crazy.
Mnh-mnh, no, you're not crazy.
Okay, then.
So, I'll meet you
back here tonight,
and we'll go to the
real-estate agent.
Yeah. Okay.
Bye.
It's time to rethink the plan.
Hey. What did you find?
Oh, Rory has
Li-Fraumeni Syndrome.
Li for what? Never
even heard of it.
Neither had I.
It's an extremely
rare genetic condition
due to a mutation
in the P53 gene
that suppresses the ability
to regulate cell growth.
The poor kid can't
fight off tumors.
So, as soon as you cure one
cancer, another one pops up.
Yeah. That's awesome.
Now, I'm meeting
with the family today.
I'd like to be able to tell them
we have some sort of
plan in place for Rory.
Okay, so, that chest tumor
might not even be a met
from the osteosarcoma.
That makes chemo that
much more complicated.
Okay, the tumor in
her leg should respond
to doxorubicin, plus cisplatin.
Radiation's out.
It would make her too
susceptible to new tumors.
The chest tumor's so vascular,
even a biopsy would
be pushing our luck.
How rare is this?
Only a few hundred families
are reported in the literature.
We need those case studies,
but, I mean, that
could take awhile.
Not if I get those
residents on it.
Sorry I'm late. I'm
doing scut for Hunt.
Well, it'll get handled.
This is more important.
All right, listen up.
Your assignment's changed.
Rory has Li-Fraumeni Syndrome.
It's rare.
Dig up every case
of it you can find.
Find out what
worked, what didn't.
I want one of you
to look for Dr. Karev.
He's with the oncologist.
I will.
Are you sure?
Yeah. Got to face him sometime.
Now, you can't rely
solely on the Internet.
Hit the library.
Now.
Uh, Ross, a word?
You've been quiet.
I don't know what's
going on in your head,
but if it's too soon to
come back full time,
we can talk. No.
Just trying to keep my
head down and work, sir.
Well, if you feel like you
have something to say,
speak up, son.
Keeping it inside won't
help you or anyone else.
The last time I spoke
up, a patient nearly died.
That was grief and
exhaustion talking.
I'd like to hear you talk.
Thank you. Of course.
You should put me
back in OR rotation.
Start clipping aneurysms again.
Derek. Hey.
Dr. Hunt.
Well, it would be
good to have you back.
It used to be all
I wanted to do.
I'm grateful that they
approached me for the project
and that you
pushed me towards it.
It wasn't about Washington
or the accolades.
They're looking for answers
to questions I've been
asking my whole career.
And to know that that
project is out there...
I mean, how do I go
back to being satisfied
doing neurosurgery again?
Yeah.
Your standards have changed.
My standards have changed.
We were able to
clean it out in surgery,
and now we're gonna let this
vacuum dressing work its magic
and start the healing process.
Oh, my God, those are beautiful.
Did Ted send them?
No.
They're from your mom.
Oh, damn it, Lisa. Really?
No, it's not Ted.
I mean, it is Ted.
You're right. I'm insane.
This whole thing has
made me certifiably crazy.
I am a college professor.
I'm supposed to
be, you know, smart,
but instead I'm
jumping into trash chutes
and bursting into tears
because I'm heartbroken
that my mom cares about
me more than some jerk
who won't even
talk to me in public!
What is that?
Can you hand me my phone?
I just want to call my mom
and thank her for the flowers.
Sure.
You're gonna call
Ted, aren't you?
I'm a monster.
Oh, my God.
Hey, hey, hey.
Oh, my God, we need to go
public with this thing, okay?
I can't keep track
of when and where
I can put my arms
on my own wife.
Look. I know it's hard.
But the whispers and the
stares after the wedding
have just started to die down.
As soon as we tell people,
they're just gonna start up again.
Yeah.
Plus, I like our secret,
little marriage bubble.
Sneaking around is kind of sexy.
I am so proud
that you're my wife.
I am married to a brilliant,
gorgeous trauma surgeon,
and I just don't want to
hide it anymore, you know?
Okay, that's even sexier.
So, what do we do?
I think we should
start telling people.
In a more controlled setting.
Just... Doctor.
Well, it looks like
we're gonna get you
started on chemo soon.
I saw Mom talking to Dr. Bailey.
There were tears.
Oh, wow.
Thanks for the
cancer genes, Mom.
If you have it, I have it.
Oh, you haven't been
sick a day in your life.
You have Dad's nice, safe genes.
Maybe not.
We'll find out after the test.
You know, you don't have
to find out if you don't want to.
Knowledge sucks.
Your face sucks.
Oh, come on. I'm not kidding.
I know we like to act
like this isn't a big deal
and we're the family
that beats cancer,
but we're not actually
beating anything.
I mean, like, I can handle
one cancer at a time,
but it's all I see now...
Just cancer after
cancer until I'm dead.
And I wish I could go
back and un-know that.
She can say no, right?
It's her decision.
Not according to Mom and Dad.
They say I need to know
because it'll determine
whether I take an aspirin
or get a brain scan
for a headache.
And if I'm gonna have
kids, I need to know...
Kids? You're a kid.
I'm just saying, all right?
Mom and Dad are freaking out,
and they're calling
the whole damn family
and wanting
everyone to get a test
and wanting to
start a foundation
and change the world
and be like the family
that fights Li-Fraumeni.
Who cares what they
want? What do you want?
I can really decide for myself?
Even though I'm only 16
and my parents
say that I have to?
I can say no? I can
make the decision?
It's your life.
Nobody can make you do
anything you don't want to do.
Hey. I need the
oncology report on Rory.
They said we should
add methotrexate
for the osteosarcoma.
Okay, thanks. Look...
Hey, what are you doing?
I'm done sneaking around.
They can't tell us what
to do or what to feel.
If they want to fire me, fine.
We had a plan. What happened?
Look. It's a stupid plan.
We're adults. We
love each other.
They can go screw themselves.
What was that?
Is somebody in there?
Hey, guys.
You want to just
hand me my shirt?
Mine, too.
Hi. Appreciate it.
Ugh.
Come on. Let's get out of here.
No! Oh!
Dr. Webber. This
isn't what it looks like.
Well, I'm fired.
We're not fired.
You're not. You're an attending.
I'm an expendable resident.
The rules are just a
dumb thing on paper
to cover the board's ass.
No one actually cares.
Well, speaking
as the hypocritical board
member in the room,
the board cares.
Since when are
you two still doing it?
Since the wedding.
Nice.
What?
I'm deciding whether
this makes me
hate you more or less.
More.
Hey, well, um, since
we have you guys here,
there's something that
we wanted to... Oh, no.
Think he's still out there?
There's only one
way to find out.
You guys want to close the...
No?
Hey.
Hey. I need a consult.
Okay.
So, my project
is at a standstill
unless I hand it
over to a bioengineer.
Okay.
What's your pitch?
Become a bioengineer.
I can't give Derek
the satisfaction
of lightening my workload
because his guilt is
my only ray of sunshine.
Well, he doesn't think
he's gonna get the job,
if that makes you
feel any better.
I know. I actually feel
kind of bad for him.
But I feel worse for
me. I hate quitting.
Don't think of it as quitting.
You're waiting for science
to catch up to your brilliance.
Think of it as...
As letting someone else
take your project out for a spin.
You just step back, see
what else is out there,
so when you come back to your
project, you'll have fresh eyes.
It'll be better than ever,
just like coming home.
You slept with Owen.
Yes, I did.
Don't.
Karev, talk to me.
She was hypertensive
and unresponsive,
with absent breath sounds over
her left chest when I got here.
I needled for a tension pneumo.
Okay, we'll have
to get her intubated.
Okay.
Aah!
Ariel, I need you to
go find your parents.
I couldn't wake her up
when the machine
started beeping.
I tried, but... Look,
this is not your fault.
We're gonna help
your sister, okay?
Go find your parents. Go! Now!
Where the hell did all
this blood come from?
Her tumor could have ruptured.
We've got to get her to an OR.
Guys, I just found a case
of Li-Fraumeni in Chicago.
The guy has almost the exact
same types of cancers as Rory.
Uh, they tried neoadjuvant
chemo to shrink it,
then surgery, and then, uh...
And?
And then he died.
I'm really sorry for
what I'm about to say,
and I want you to know
that I'm not trying to be mean,
but I think that you
should hear it from me.
Okay.
Jackson and April
are still together.
What?
Webber just walked in on
Alex, me, and them in a closet.
I'm confused.
You know, I know that you
were trying to punish them
when you made your
complaint, but they're fine, Steph.
They're great.
The only one who's
being punished is me!
This is gonna force
Alex and me apart!
Didn't you guys just break up?
No, we faked it.
I'm so confused.
You know what you do
when your little heart
gets broken, Steph?
You talk about it
with your friends.
You don't file a complaint!
I don't know how many
times I have to tell you this.
It was an...
An anonymous
complaint, which you file
because you're afraid if
people find out it was you,
they'd treat you like crap
instead of understanding
or even trying to understand
that it wasn't some
frivolous thing you did
because your little
heart got broken,
but a decision you
made because you felt
like your medical education
had been compromised.
God, I don't even
know why I bothered.
I should have just
signed my name.
Oh!
This job is a
privilege and a gift,
and we are squandering it.
I almost lost my
place in this program
because I got
distracted with Dr. Yang.
And you are all
letting distractions
get in the way of our work.
We have a chance here
to actually save this girl.
And I have an idea.
Look.
You slept with Yang?
The anatomy's all messed up.
The tumor's stuck
to everything in here.
Okay.
Let's try clamping the aorta.
That may temporarily
help curb the bleeding.
Now I just have to find it.
This patient survived
six types of cancers.
They were onto something.
Yeah, but then he died
from a surgical complication.
So, if we combined
radiofrequency ablation
with an anterior-approach
en bloc resection...
Yes.
V-fib. Starting cardiac massage.
Charge the paddles to 10.
No, no, no.
Look. Look. Look.
This gives us
good local control.
So we can treat the tumor
without compromising
the healthy lung tissue.
Exactly.
Okay, charge to 20.
Clear.
All right. We got a rhythm.
It's weak, but it'll do.
Okay, let's get in there
and find the source.
And we can get a
biopsy while we're in there
to customize the chemo
to her specific tumor.
This will work, guys.
Yeah.
Let's go tell Webber.
We got it! We figured it out!
You start with
radiofrequency ablation.
Then you take the
remainder out en bloc.
And the healthy
tissue remains healthy.
Guys...
But here's a twist,
you can do a biopsy.
Which will customize her chemo.
That's not gonna work.
It might have.
It's a worthy pitch,
but Rory bled out
into her chest tonight.
It looks like it
tore into her aorta.
We did everything we could.
She died?
She died.
We tried everything.
No.
Oh, my God.
We're so sorry.
Oh! Oh!
Do I have it?
The gene... I want
to know if I have it.
No, honey. Now is not the time.
No, now is the time, Mom.
I want to know.
You know.
Dr. Bailey told you.
Ariel.
Do I have it?
Yeah.
It's okay. It's okay, Mom.
I always wanted to be
like her, and now I am.
I'm just like Rory.
Shh.
Really? Webber told on us?
None of us want
to be here, Karev.
Then why are we?
You're having a relationship
with a subordinate,
and that is against policy.
Can we not talk
about my personal life?
I'd love to not
talk about it, Alex,
but you are making me.
Now, I realize that we cannot
legislate for romantic feelings.
Okay, obviously, what you do
at home is your own business.
Look, we're just
asking that, at work,
things remain
strictly professional.
Oh, that's crap! Alex.
Oh, it's okay for
you all to flaunt
your relationships
and your rings
and your happy, little lives
just because you're married?
Karev, just sit down. No!
I'm not gonna let a
bunch of hypocrites
tell me to keep my
pants on at work
when this place
was built on all of you
feeling each other
up in our on-call room!
I'm done! Punish me! Whatever!
Okay, so, this is not how we
wanted to tell you guys this,
because it could look like
we're trying to
get off the hook,
which we are not.
But we...
We are married.
What?
Yes, April is my wife.
So, our supply-closet
activity breaks no rules.
Since when?
Since the wedding.
My other wedding.
Kepner, you continue
to surprise me.
Mm-hmm.
Um, Congratulations.
Thank you.
Okay.
So, I should probably go.
I'm so sorry. Good luck.
Filing that complaint
really took balls,
balls I didn't have.
Jo's gonna be so
pissed at me, isn't she?
Oh, yeah, she is.
Hide at the bar?
Yes, please.
All right.
Shane, we're
drinking. You're coming.
You can try to
hide from a bully.
But hiding won't work for long.
You're gonna send her
flowers, you're gonna apologize,
and then you are never
going to see her again.
Oh, I'll take this outside.
Okay.
Oh, uh, tell him he
kisses like a turtle's butt.
Is she breaking
up with him for you?
I can't be trusted
to do it. I'm crazy.
But the first step is admitting
you have a problem, right?
No more secret romances,
no more married men.
Hey.
What are you doing this weekend?
You're beautiful.
And you've already
seen me naked.
So, you might as
well buy me dinner.
Well, I actually already
have plans with my wife, so...
Stuck in a trash chute, check.
Prawn stuck in my leg, check.
Embarrass myself in front of
my surgeons, double check.
Yeah. That about
sounds right. I can die now.
You know, he really
should wear a ring.
It's not fair,
going around looking
like that without one.
Totally agree.
There's really only
one way to win.
It's an interesting idea.
Mm-hmm.
I wish we'd had a
chance to give it a try.
You know, but maybe
we'll be ahead of the game
for her sister.
It was a team effort.
I don't want to get ahead of
myself, but I think I'm starting
to make some
headway with those kids.
Oh.
Warren!
Dr. Bailey, we're
gonna go to Joe's.
You mind? Can Ben come?
Go on.
Go play with your friends.
But don't stay out too late.
Sure you want to come? Mmm.
Just rub that in our faces.
I'm gonna come out.
Believe me... I'm
gonna get home tonight.
You have to fight back.
I don't understand.
This morning, we were making
plans to see houses together,
and now you want to break up.
I thought I knew what I wanted.
What, the house,
the kids, or me?
Emma, I am so sorry.
Don't.
I don't need an apology.
I want an explanation
because the last time I
checked, which was this morning,
we were on the exact same
page, and now we're not.
What changed?
I want to come home
to someone at night
who is equally as
passionate about their work...
I am.
Emma, you...
You would give up surgery
in exchange for a family.
That's a problem?
No. No, it's amazing for you.
I want you to have that...
house with the
bedrooms and the kids.
It is a beautiful future.
But I want to come home at night
and exchange OR stories.
We want different things.
So it's me.
Emma, come on.
Please. Just please let me go.
Emma, Emma...
I'm gonna call a cab.
Will you wait a few minutes
so that I'm gone
before you leave?
And if you're lucky
enough to get out alive,
take just a moment
to celebrate...
The White House called.
You got it?
No, it's much bigger than that.
That's why the interview
process was so exhaustive.
They want me on
the advisory board.
They want me to run the thing.
You're mad.
No.
I'm not mad.
I just... I'm happy for you.
But there isn't room
for me to take my
career to the next level
and for you to run the thing.
Derek, that's frustrating.
Mm-hmm.
Come here.
What are you doing?
I'm gonna have sex
with my husband... Oh.
Because three weeks is too long.
And I guess I do find
presidential
appointments very sexy.
Mmm.
And then we can
fight more later.
Good. All right.
Before you put
your guard back up,
ready to fight the next one.