.
- I want another doctor.
You're done working on my son.
- Carmen and I started a thing,
then we broke up.
- Then he got her
on the rebound, right?
- There's more to it.
- Stay away from my family.
- We're getting hammered
by the press.
Donors are fleeing.
Doctors are getting poached
by other hospitals.
- Why are you here, Mr. Shentu?
- Reputational management.
- I'm not opposed to you
wearing your heart
on your sleeve.
But you and I are strongest
when we work together.
- I like you too.
- You okay?
- It's paperwork
for my divorce.
- Didn't know you were married.
- It's over.
He's just dragging it out.
- I need an MRI.
- It'll set him back months.
You should never
have allowed Ethan
to push himself like that.
If they can't say when,
you're supposed to.
♪
See you tomorrow.
- Ethan.
- Daniel.
What are you doing here?
- I know.
Me in a gym, crazy right?
Buddy, been meaning
to give you a call.
I heard the last surgery was
a big success.
- Yeah.
Doctor says I should be able
to return to work
in six to eight weeks.
- You wanna grab
some breakfast or something?
I--I got the day off.
- Yeah.
Let's do it.
Uh, one sec.
It's my dad.
Hello? Mm, okay.
Yeah.
All right.
- How's Pop?
- Uh, it wasn't him, actually.
I guess he got
an in-home nurse, Felicia.
She's concerned that...
I didn't even know he was sick.
- Huh.
- Yeah. I need to go see him.
- But you're not cleared
to drive yet though, are you?
- No, no.
I'll just order a car.
- Let me give you a ride.
- No, no, no.
You don't have to do that.
- Buddy.
You'd be doing me
a big favor, okay?
I was gonna be paying bills
all day.
Five minutes,
let me jump in the shower.
- Thanks.
- I thought
all this was finalized.
No, I don't want to speak
to my husband directly.
That's why I hired a lawyer.
Listen, I'm at work.
I'm gonna have
to call you back later, okay?
Okay.
- Guess that was, uh,
about your divorce?
- We already agreed that
Andrew would keep the house
in Grosse Point.
Now, suddenly,
he wants to sell it
and give me half the proceeds.
- That's a good thing, right?
- No, he's up to something.
He's trying to lure me in.
It's a control thing.
Sorry, this must be so boring.
- No, it's fascinating.
I'm riveted.
- Sure. What's in the bag?
- My suit.
Remember, we're going
to the gala tonight?
- Yes, of course.
- But, uh, if you've got
too much on your plate--
- No.
We're gonna do this.
- Excuse me, Dr. Hammer?
Treatment room five.
- Okay.
Let's firm all this up later,
okay?
- Yeah.
- Lisa Backman, 37 years old,
34 weeks pregnant.
Vitals all stable.
- Collapsed on the floor
and lost consciousness
for 30 seconds.
Husband called 911.
He was right behind us.
- Thanks.
- Hi, Lisa, I'm Dr. Hammer.
How you feeling?
- Fine.
I just got
a little lightheaded.
It's not a big deal.
- Let's take a quick look,
okay?
Let's get the ultrasound.
- Do we really need to do that?
- We just want to make sure
that everything looks okay
in there.
I mean,
you're here already, right?
- I just want to get out
as fast as possible.
- I understand.
- Hi, Lisa,
your husband's here.
- Is she okay?
- I told you already,
I'm fine, Jonah.
This is a complete
waste of time.
- Well,
the placenta appears normal,
which is a good sign.
But your baby's breech.
You might be having it
sooner than you think.
- See? I told you something
was going on.
- Has she told you yet
that she's anemic?
- No, but good to know.
Okay, let's get
a CBC, PTT, a KB,
and a fingerstick
for blood glucose.
- I--I don't need all of that.
- They're just lab tests
to make sure that you're okay.
- Yeah, if you give me
the name of your OB,
I can contact him
for you if you like.
- I'm no longer seeing my OB.
- Go ahead, tell them why.
- Okay, don't do this, Jonah.
- Fine. I'll tell them.
Because her OB had
the audacity to suggest
that Lisa get vaccinated,
but she didn't want to.
- Enough, okay?
That's my decision
as a mother to make.
No one else's.
And I don't appreciate you
trying to recruit
more soldiers to your cause.
I feel isolated enough already.
- This has been going on
for months.
- Okay, stop!
What is she doing?
- She's drawing some blood.
- No.
I--I just wanna go back home
and get ready
for the home birth
with my doula as planned.
- Hey, Lisa, you know, anemia
can greatly increase the risk
of adverse events
during delivery.
- I know that already.
We can manage.
- Damn it, Lisa, stop messing
around with our baby's health.
Listen to the doctors.
- It's really best to be sure.
- Fine.
Run your test.
- Oh, good.
You're finally listening
to medical advice.
- I've had it.
I want you out of here.
- This is my baby too.
- I said get out.
Do I need to have you
call security?
- Why don't you come with me?
There's a waiting area
right outside.
- Thank you.
♪
.
- Here's hoping we avoid
any hiccups with this surgery.
Dry cleaner closes at 6:00,
and they got my dress.
- Oh, I take it that means
you're going to
the fundraising gala tonight?
- Oh, I have received
many enthusiastic emails
from Dr. Shentu suggesting
that my attendance is--
thank you--mandatory.
- Well, it makes sense.
The hospital wants
to parade around its stars.
- I'm not complaining.
It's actually
kind of refreshing
to get out every now and again.
- Good.
Well, why don't you meet up
with me before hand?
Let me buy you a drink.
- Oh, um...
Can't imagine
I'll find the time.
Today's the day, Dorothy.
How you feeling?
- Ooh, ready to meet
my new liver.
Chad and I couldn't get here
fast enough when you called.
- Mom and I are pretty stoked.
- Yeah, well, after all
the time you've been waiting,
I believe it.
Your labs are showing
that your blood sugar's at 240.
- Mm, it's always a roller
coaster with my diabetes.
- Yes,
but your white blood cell count
is also elevated to 18,000.
Numbers like this usually
indicate that your body
is fighting
some sort of infection.
Have you been feeling
worse than normal?
- It's hard to know
what normal is anymore.
I been feeling so crummy
this last year.
- Dorothy,
you mind if I examine you?
- Sure.
- Okay.
You feeling cold?
- No more than usual.
- Do you mind
if I remove the jacket?
Ooh.
- I was trying to warm my feet
by the radiator
the other night,
and I guess I got too close.
- Uh-huh.
- Didn't even feel it
for some reason.
- That's the neuropathy
from the diabetes.
- Let's have a look.
- Yeah, burned yourself
pretty bad there.
It's definitely infected.
- Okay, we are gonna need
IV antibiotics for that.
So excuse us while we go
flag down a nurse.
- Yeah, let's leave this open
for air.
Keep it off, okay?
- Okay.
- What do you think?
- We can't give her steroids
or put her
on immunosuppressants
with an infection like that.
- There's no way, right?
- Feel terrible for her.
- So what do you wanna do now--
- Is this gonna be a problem?
- Unfortunately,
your mother's infection
presents potential
complications for her surgery.
So we're gonna have to postpone
it for a later date.
- What about the liver?
- It'll go
to another recipient.
♪
That's not fair.
- I understand
your disappointment.
But trying to transplant
a liver
when your mother has
an infection
is just too dangerous.
- My mom's been waiting
for this liver
for almost a year now.
We'll take the risk.
- Unfortunately,
I'm obligated to ensure
that the organ is transplanted
under the most optimal
conditions possible.
- That's your concern?
The liver, not my mom?
- Of course I'm concerned
for your mother.
But as you well know,
these livers are
in short supply.
- Stop.
Here's how this is gonna go.
You're gonna go back in there
and you're gonna prep
my mom for surgery--
- Whoa, walk away.
Walk away.
Or I call security and have
you removed from the hospital.
♪
You okay?
- Can you please go find me
a nurse?
- Dr. Shentu.
- Ms. Goodwin.
Glad I caught you. Um.
How's your speech for
tonight's gala coming along?
- Fine.
- Okay, I'm asking
all of tonight's speakers
for a copy of their speech.
Just so I can ensure
they stay on-message.
- And what message is that?
- Reflecting the hospital
in a positive light.
Some donors are still shaken up
in the wake
of the, uh, FBI investigation.
- Well,
don't you worry about me.
It's not my first rodeo.
- Okay.
I guess I'll be surprised.
- Sharon, there's an issue in
the ED you need to be aware of.
- Okay.
- This is from who?
- From the lawyer
representing Jonah Backman
demanding
that his client retain
all decision-making rights
for his wife Lisa
and their presently
unborn baby,
citing, now, and I quote,
"Her inability to comprehend
comparative risk
"and her wanton disregard
for the health
of her unborn child."
- Let me see that.
- What's the status
of the patient?
- Stable.
- Well,
this is clearly an overstep.
Lisa might be distrustful
of doctors,
but she obviously has capacity.
I'm not gonna disregard
my patient's wishes.
- We're not asking you to.
- Yeah,
unless a judge issues a stay,
the hospital's gonna
continue to honor
Lisa's personal autonomy.
- Mr. Backman will be kept away
from his wife
unless she says otherwise.
I'll have security assign
a dedicated guard
just to make sure.
- Thank you, Ms. Goodwin.
- Dr. Scott.
- Uh, hey, D-man. What's up?
I heard you were here.
I just wanted to see
how you were feeling.
- Well, he's doing much better.
But we're good here.
- I asked him to stop by,
Terrell.
- Good to see you...
Dr. Scott.
- You okay?
Huh? Having trouble breathing?
- Hey, let me, uh, talk to you
for a second.
- We'll be right back, sweetie,
okay?
Hold on.
- Uh, I thought I told you
to stay away from my family?
- It's okay, Terrell.
- Look, man, uh,
I'm just trying to help.
- Then leave.
♪
- When I tried to wake
your father up this morning,
he was difficult to rouse.
I thought he might have
had a stroke.
- Was he slurring his speech?
Does he have
any motor deficits?
- He had a little facial droop,
but it's better now.
Tried to convince him
to see a doctor,
but he refused.
- Yeah.
- He was, um, very upset
when I told him I called you.
- Hey, no.
You did the right thing,
Felicia, thank you.
- Your dad served in Vietnam?
- Yeah, Seventh Fleet.
Lieutenant commander.
- Joon-Kung Choi?
- He goes by Patrick now.
- Thought I heard
a familiar voice.
- Hey, Dad.
- Hey, son.
What, you thought
you needed backup
to deal with your old man?
- This is my friend,
Dr. Charles.
- Dan. Nice to meet you.
- If you came here to give him
a second opinion,
wasted a trip.
I don't need a doctor.
Never mind two.
- I'm just a chauffeur today.
- Mm.
Well, Felicia here
jumped the gun.
- I'm sorry, Patrick.
- Well, we're here now.
Might as well take
a look at you.
You look like
you lost some weight.
- Still in fighting shape,
thank you very much.
Go on.
Pop me and see.
Come on.
- How about we just start
with your eyes?
Take a seat, Pops.
So, uh...
Felicia tells me
you're on some anticonvulsant.
What's that for?
- I just take whatever the doc
at Kenosha prescribes me.
I don't ask questions.
- You brought in a nurse
for a reason.
- Maybe I got tired
of the sound of my own voice.
- Right. Squeeze my fingers.
Harder.
Is that as hard as you can?
- At least I can still
walk around without a cane.
Mm?
In case you're, uh, thinking
of going a round or two, eh?
- Just humor me.
Let me take you
to the hospital,
run a couple tests.
- Why? I'm fine.
Now, watch me go to the kitchen
to make myself a sandwich.
Can I get one for you too,
Daniel?
- You know what?
I am in fact feeling
a little peckish, thank you.
♪
- Did you go see Darius?
And how is he?
- Ah, he's a tough kid.
I think he'll be all right.
- Yeah?
- Ah, Carmen.
- Hey, uh, Terrell just took
Darius to the car,
and I had to finish
some paperwork,
and I wanted to swing by,
say thank you.
- Yeah, well, uh,
you know,
if you ever need anything
you can call me any time.
- I don't know how well
that will go over with Terrell.
And I'm sorry about the way
he's been acting.
- Yeah, well, he's still mad
at me for that arrest.
- I know.
But it wasn't your fault.
He shouldn't have been hanging
with those guys.
- Yeah.
Carmen, um...
I didn't do right
by you either.
- I--I should go.
- Your hemoglobin is
lower than we'd like,
- So I'm still anemic?
- Yes.
We're also seeing
a concerning tracing
on the fetal monitor.
- Your baby's heartrate is
dipping intermittently.
- We suspect there's been
a subclinical abruption
meaning that
your placenta is separating.
- But you told me
it looked normal.
- The transabdominal ultrasound
can't always pick things up
to that detail.
- Dr. Patchefsky
from obstetrics
is recommending
an urgent C-section.
- No, I wanna deliver
her naturally.
- Lisa, a vaginal delivery
would be very dangerous
for both you and the baby.
And the risk
of hemorrhage is high.
- Extra problematic
because of your anemia.
- Even if you found
an OB willing to try,
you would need blood
during or after.
- Perhaps you'd like to discuss
options with your husband?
- No, he stays outside.
Tell me something, if--
if I needed a transfusion,
could you guarantee
that the donor
was unvaccinated?
- I'm pretty sure the hospital
doesn't screen donors
for that criterium, so no.
- Well, you should.
That spike protein
that the vaccine
makes your body produce
is a toxin.
- You do realize
if you go into labor,
it will be very precarious
for you to refuse
a blood transfusion.
- I don't care.
No way I'm going
to allow that poison
to be put in my
or my baby's bloodstream.
- Lisa.
You could die.
- Yeah.
Keep up with the scare tactics.
Like all you doctors have since
the beginning of this pandemic.
You know what?
Where's my phone?
I wanna speak with my doula.
- Still think she should be
making her own decisions?
♪
.
- Sorry about Dad's tuna fish.
Kimchi's an acquired taste.
- Are you kidding me?
It was worth the whole trip.
He's so damn stubborn.
He's feeling worse than
he's letting on, I know it.
- Look, still, I think
it's great that you came up.
Really.
Spend a little quality time.
- Sincerely doubt that.
- Ethan, quick!
♪
- Dad?
Dad!
Hey, Dad, can you hear me?
Hey, talk to me. Talk to me.
- Calling an ambulance.
- Hey.
Everything okay with Carmen?
- Yeah, we were just saying hi.
- That's it?
I saw a look.
- What look?
- Don't play with me, Dylan.
What's the deal?
- Uh, Carmen and I used
to go together back in the day,
but got a little messy.
- I was a young cop, you know?
Wearing that uniform,
you get a lot of interest
from the ladies.
It wasn't my finest hour.
- So you cheated on her.
- Grown a lot since then.
You know?
- And what about the look?
- Mags, it--it was nothing.
I mean, so much has changed
since then.
She's with Terrell.
They have a kid.
Ancient history.
- Mr. Abbott?
- Dr. Marcell.
- Hey.
Boy, I'm glad to see you.
- Finally getting that liver,
huh?
- Guess I'll see you
on the other side.
- You bet. See you there.
- So I just saw Henry Abbott.
- Yeah, he was the next name
down on the transplant list.
- Uh-huh.
- Same blood type
as the donor liver.
- Great.
When were you planning
on telling me?
- Actually, I thought it was
a good opportunity
for another surgeon
to get some experience.
- Oh, another surgeon?
- But you're more than welcome
to watch
from the observation booth
if you like.
- Uh-huh.
♪
You're mad at me, aren't you?
For what happened this morning.
- I'm not mad at you.
- Something's up.
- Okay, well,
since you mentioned it...
I can fight my own battles.
And I can buy my own drinks.
♪
- Mr. Backman?
- Finally, some information.
How's my wife doing?
- I'm sorry, legally, I can't
disclose any information
about Lisa's condition.
But I wanted to ask,
are you a viable blood donor
for your wife?
- We're the same type,
but I'm vaccinated.
So, no.
- I see.
- Does she need blood?
- I'm sorry. I can't.
- This is our baby. I--
I just wanna help Lisa,
but I can't get through to her.
I--that's why I went
to the lawyer.
I didn't know what else to do.
- Pregnancy can bring out
a lot of stress
in expectant mothers.
I bet things will get better
once your baby's born.
- I hope you're right.
- Ah!
- Dr. Hammer.
- What's going on?
- Fetal heartrate's dipping
again.
Lisa, we are out of options,
okay?
You need a C-section right now.
- No!
- Lisa.
We need your consent.
- Fine. Do it.
But remember what I said
about the blood.
- We will inform OB.
Let's get her to L and D.
- Tubes in.
Okay to...
- You okay, Marty?
- Marty. Marty! Hey, doc--
hey, what--hey!
Pamela!
No, no, no, no! Don't come in!
♪
.
- So what's the plan here?
- Evacuate this whole floor.
- Gonna need you two
to vacate the area.
- No, I'm not going anywhere
until we help
Dr. Blake and her team.
Talk to me, Capp,
what are you thinking?
- Look, if there's sarin gas
in that room
and this is
some kind of terrorist attack,
opening that door will put
everyone out here at risk.
- Look, I get
the OR's positive pressurized,
there's risk involved
in opening that door,
but somebody's gotta go
in there and get them out, man.
- You guys have
any more of those suits?
- Come on, I mean, we're on
a ticking clock here, guys.
- We're talking to an engineer
about shutting down
the ventilation system.
Once that happens,
the halls are cleared,
and we're suited up,
we'll go inside.
- That'll take too long.
They could die by then.
- We have no choice.
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Bedard, are you all right?
- Hey, watch out. Move.
Move, move, move, move.
Hey, hey.
Easy, buddy. Hold your breath.
- Let's move him
down to the ED.
- It's the masks.
Hey, hey!
Dr. Marcel.
- She's got a pulse.
Check the others.
- All right,
I'll check this one over here.
- Hey, Pamela?
Pamela, can you hear me?
Hey.
I got you.
Pamela, can you hear me?
Pamela, I got you.
Let's get you upstairs.
- I wish there was more
we could do.
- I'd have donated blood
myself, but--
- You're vaccinated, yeah.
Me too.
- You seeing this?
- Crisis in the OR?
- Marty, can you hear me,
buddy?
Marty. Hey, take over for me.
You got it?
- Got it.
- How's she doing?
- Pulse is still thready.
Hey, this looks like
classic opioid toxicity.
- You think so?
- I've seen a lot.
Pinpoint pupils,
hypoventilation.
- Hey, you got Narcan?
Get that?
Let's try it.
Here we go.
♪
Hey. Pamela?
It worked.
We need Narcan. Narcan!
- Get us Narcan!
- Let's go.
- Hey. Hey. I got you.
- Dylan.
Take her to treatment four.
- Thanks. More on their way.
- Goodwin just activated
the internal disaster plan.
What's going on up there?
We're not certain.
But it appears that Dr. Blake's
entire transplant team
has been poisoned.
- What?
Is everyone okay?
- I don't know.
But nobody's dead.
- Carmen's back.
- Help, Dylan.
- What happened?
- His breathing's
getting worse.
- D-man, can you talk to me?
- It's cold.
- Oh, God.
- All right,
let's go to trauma four.
Come with me. Come on.
- What do I do?
What do I do? All right.
Okay.
- Stay right here.
Get on the bed, sweetie.
- Careful.
- Let's take you up.
- Mommy's here.
- 102.
Acetaminophen?
- Yeah.
His lungs sound junky.
- I need an x-ray in here.
- Why is this happening?
The chemo?
- Not sure.
- What do you mean?
Okay.
Don't be scared, okay?
- Everyone stay back.
- Infiltrates in the lungs.
He's got pneumonia.
Let's get a mask on him.
- Oh, my God.
- Hey, D-man. You with me?
Maggie's gonna put
a face-breathing mask
over your nose and your mouth,
okay?
It's gonna help you out
for now.
- Okay, honey. Okay.
- Let's get a CBC, CMP, UA,
blood and sputum cultures,
all right?
Where's Terrell?
- He's at a job interview.
I gotta call him.
He's--he's gonna freak out.
♪
- Are you Patrick's son
Dr. Choi?
- I am.
- I'm Dr. Jahan
from neurosurgery.
I wanted to show you
the CT we just did.
You can see a couple of small
intraparenchymal bleeds
here and here.
There're probably the result
of the fall.
But it's hard to tell because
of the increasing size of this.
- Brain tumor.
- Yes.
If you compare it to the scan
we took six months ago,
you can see how fast
it's grown.
And it also looks like
he has Metz to the skull,
the spine, and lungs.
It's a miracle
he's still alive, really.
- I'm assuming it's inoperable.
- Well, at this point, yes.
I discussed surgery
with your father months ago.
He didn't tell you?
- No.
- I'm sorry, I--
I'm afraid the only thing
to offer is palliative care.
- I see.
- I can prescribe
some morphine for the pain
and put you in touch
with hospice care
if you'd prefer.
- Thank you, Dr. Jahan.
Thank you.
♪
- Take him to OR three.
I'm behind you.
- A janitor found
a wadded up pair of masks
in the men's bathroom trash
as well as a vial
of some unknown substance.
We sent it,
along with the tampered masks,
to our crime lab.
I suspect they're linked.
Hopefully,
we'll know something soon.
- Everyone on the surgical team
has been resuscitated
and transferred to the ED
for further treatment.
- Good. Please let me know
when they'll be available
to be interviewed.
- Will do.
- Oh, by the way, Henry Abbott
remains in stable condition.
I had him moved
to another OR for surgery.
- Okay, no, we can't risk
doing the transplant.
If that goes south
with a criminal investigation
still underway, the hospital
could be held negligent.
- And what about Henry Abbott?
- Well, when he wakes up,
he'll go right back
to the top
of the transplant list.
- Oh.
Not that he hasn't been waiting
on that list
for months already.
Plus that liver's got, what?
About four hours
till it's no longer usable?
So by all means, you tell me.
- You have my approval to move
forward with the transplant
as long as
you can assemble a team
that can safely assist you.
- Yeah.
- I'm sorry to do this.
I really am.
But with Dr. Blake's team down,
you're one nurse short.
- No, we aren't.
You didn't count me.
I spent more than a few years
working as an OR nurse.
I will circulate for you,
Dr. Marcel.
- Yeah?
- Absolutely.
- Uh...
Ms. Goodwin,
I don't recommend this.
- The clock is ticking.
♪
.
- The fundus is firm.
That's a good sign.
And your bleeding
appeared normal.
- It's a good thing you didn't
need a transfusion.
- Yeah.
- Well,
say hello to your baby girl.
- Oh!
Baby girl.
- Have you named her yet?
- I have an idea,
but I'm gonna wait and see
how her father feels
about it first.
Who do I need to talk to so
Jonah can come see the baby?
- We'll take care of that.
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
- Catch that grunting?
- Yeah.
- What--what is it?
- Yeah, I'm just gonna take
a quick listen here.
- Okay.
♪
- I am hearing
a slight irregularity
in her breathing pattern.
- Is she okay?
- It's probably
nothing serious,
but considering
she was a bit premature--
- It's best to just
take her to the NICU
for some further observation.
- Can--can I come?
- We'll bring you over as soon
as she gets situated.
- What--
- Hey,
this is very common, Lisa.
Just try and stay calm, okay?
Try not to worry.
♪
- Thanks, Felicia.
So, uh...
Dr. Jahan said you've known
about this since last summer.
- What was I gonna say?
There's nothing
anyone could do about it.
- Well, I'm a doctor, Dad.
Coulda helped.
- Yeah.
You're a field medic, son.
Not a brain surgeon.
What could you have done?
- Could have at least spent
some more time together.
- Ah, come on.
- Listen, Dad, I, uh...
♪
I know it hasn't really been
our thing to talk about stuff.
And I'm not putting that
on you, I, um...
I could have been more open.
There's just so much between us
that goes unsaid.
And, um--
- Yeah.
Okay, I get it.
You know what I'm thinking?
- What's that?
- I forgot to put
the snow tires on.
There's a storm coming in.
Need to get that done.
- What are you talking about?
- Take my car
to the garage on Wilmot.
They should have them on sale.
- Dad,
it can wait till tomorrow.
- No, it can't.
I need you to do it now.
- Come on, what are--
what are you doing?
- Damn it, Ethan!
Just--
If you can't help me out here,
what the hell
are you doing here?
♪
- Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Snow tires?
- Yeah, there's a garage
a couple miles from here.
- And that's gotta happen now?
- Yeah.
- Well,
why don't you let me do it?
- No, no, no, no,
he wanted me to.
- Ethan, what does it matter
who puts the tires on the car?
Hang out with your dad.
- No!
I'm going
and that's all there is to it.
Damn it!
- Buddy,
at least let me drive you.
- Okay.
Just finished
the arterial anastomosis.
- BP's dropping.
- Okay, we'll give him
some more blood.
- I'm using all three ports
of the triple lumen.
Two for pressors,
one for blood.
- Okay.
- But we need a large bore PIV
to more rapidly transfuse.
- I'll start a new line.
- Okay,
let's kick it into gear.
BP's down to 70. Let's go.
- Just one more second.
- Let me try.
I'm in.
- Very nice.
- Got a 16 gauge in the AC.
- Blood pressure's coming
back up.
Okay, heck of a job, team.
All right, let's go.
- His sats have improved. 92%.
- That's good, right?
- Means he's getting
the oxygen he needs.
- Thank God.
- I think
his weakened immune system
made him more susceptible
to the infection.
I'll call his oncologist
and bring her up to speed.
Once Terrell gets here,
we'll page her over
so you all can discuss
any necessary adjustments
to his chemo regimen
moving forward.
- Okay.
- Hang in there.
Both of you.
- Dylan. Dylan, hey. Hey.
That's my baby.
- I know.
- So I need you
to take care of him.
- I know.
- You gotta promise me he's--
- It's gonna be okay.
- I can't--
- Okay?
- I can't.
- It's gonna be all right.
- I know.
- Told you to stay away
from my family, man.
- Terrell, Terrell, come on.
No, no, no, no.
- Yo, Terrell, calm down, bro.
- Why are you talking to him?
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Let go of me!
Just let me, really.
- Relax.
- Let go of me.
- Let me go.
- Relax.
- I'm good.
- I'm sorry.
- Let's go outside. Come on.
- Come on.
- Let's go for a walk.
- Yo.
- It's okay.
- Take a breath. Let's go.
- Come on, man.
♪
- Carmen--
- I can't.
You okay, honey? Mommy's here.
It's okay. It's okay.
- Well, I'm not hearing
anything too concerning.
Her sats are holding up well.
We'll draw some labs,
but, overall,
I'd say she's looking good.
- Thank you, doctor.
- Lisa asked to see you.
She wants to talk baby names.
- She wants to see me?
You did say everything would
be better after the baby came.
Maybe we can get
past this after all.
- Hey, what is it?
- It's Lisa.
- She's hemorrhaging.
- BP's dropping 70/43
and falling.
- Did you insert a balloon
to tamponade the bleed?
- Already did.
All uterotonics and TXA
are on board,
but it hasn't stopped
the bleeding.
- What's going on?
- We need to get her
to the OR now.
- I don't have a pulse.
- PEA on the monitor.
Starting compressions.
Someone start bagging.
One of epi.
- Why aren't you taking her
to the OR?
- We need her heart beating
first.
- Epi's in.
- Any pulse yet?
- Nothing.
- Another of epi.
- Why isn't anyone
giving her blood?
- We can't.
Your wife forbade it.
- Sats at 80.
- Pulse check.
- Nothing.
- Asystole on the monitor.
We need to call it.
- What?
Do something!
- I'm sorry.
- Lisa.
♪
.
- Our crime lab determined
the substance
in that vial we found,
carfentanil,
was sprinkled
on the masks in the scrub room.
Traces of the drug were also
pulled off
the discarded scrubs.
It all came together when we
found security camera footage
of Mr. McCoy moving about
the surgical floor in scrubs.
- So he poisoned the masks.
- Yeah, he was pretty thrown
when we cancelled
his mom's transplant
this morning.
- Eventually, I'll need
statements from you both.
- Of course.
- Got it.
- Listen, I'm gonna go check
on Dr. Blake, okay?
- Dr. Marcel.
- Yeah.
- Good job today.
- You too.
I'll see you.
- What am I supposed to do now?
- I'm so sorry.
- You know,
Lisa wasn't always like that.
I left home
for a month for work,
and when I got back
it was like she was
a different person.
- Different how?
- She'd gotten sucked in
to that conspiracy stuff.
She was in her own world.
Online all the time. I--
I tried to get through to her,
but...
I couldn't, I--
Every time, we just
ended up fighting.
- Hey.
You tried.
You can't blame yourself.
- I should've tried harder.
♪
- Hey.
- Hi.
- How you feeling?
- Lousy.
- Yeah, I'm sure.
- I hear you've been busy.
- Well, I had big shoes
to fill.
- Come in. Keep me company.
- Sure.
- I never should have
benched you today.
But it turns out it was
a good thing I did.
- Water under the bridge.
- I here they're gonna
discharge me soon.
Pretty sure I'm not gonna
make it to that gala though.
- Yeah, I'll probably
skip it myself.
- Hmm.
Well, in that case, could I
ask you to take me home?
- Absolutely.
- Thank you.
♪
- Will, I'm sorry.
- Yeah, I'm, uh, not sure
I'm in the mood either.
- No, I booked a flight
to Detroit tonight.
To go finalize my divorce.
- Okay.
- When I decided I didn't want
to be married
to Andrew anymore, I kinda
just picked up and moved.
Left my lawyer
to clean up after me.
At the time, it felt like
that's what I needed to do.
You know, for my own wellbeing.
But looking back,
I wasn't exactly fair to him.
He thought we were
in it together.
I owe him an explanation.
- Sure.
I get it.
- I'll see you when I get back.
- All right.
- Wish me luck.
♪
- You mind taking this?
- Hello?
Okay.
Thanks.
Uh...
Buddy, I am so sorry to have
to tell you this, but, um,
your dad just passed away.
- He didn't want me
to see him die.
♪