Research suggests
that up to 40% of our day
is spent acting out
existing habits...
Smells amazing.
What are you making?
Celebratory arrabbiata for your
last day as a general surgeon.
...rather than
making new decisions.
Mmm. It's so good.
The kids are gonna love it.
Mmm. Well, they'll
have to love it tomorrow
'cause they've already been fed,
bathed and put to bed.
It's just you and me?
It's just you and me.
From sleep to personal
hygiene to diet and exercise.
So this is
my curriculum description
of my
Bleeding Intervention Program.
I wanna show it to every
chief of trauma surgery
in the country.
Yeah, it's good.
Clear.
So, hey, um, you had a chance
to look at the budget, or...
Some of our habits
serve us well.
Come here.
Hmm? Oh.
Okay.
Others can be more complicated.
You want to change a habit?
Behavioral scientists suggest
starting small.
Incoming.
-Hey.
Do you wanna go grab a bite?
I wish, but I'm waiting on labs.
It'll go faster if you go
down there and ask in person.
You have your way, I have mine.
Fair.
I'm gonna go
grab something to eat.
-See you tomorrow?
-Yeah, definitely.
Make one minor
adjustment over time.
Time of death: 2024.
We're still in a rough patch,
but we talked
and we're gonna keep trying.
Well, you know,
she is right.
If you go down there yourself,
it'll be much faster.
Great.
It creates
a domino effect
that helps us make
bigger changes down the line.
Dr. Fox.
Uh, what brings you to my
little corner of the hospital?
Natasha here is just taking me
on a little tour.
I wish I'd known. I would
have prepared a presentation.
You don't have to
put on a show for me.
I just like to pop in
from time to time
and see where my money's going.
Well, uh, if you have
any questions, I'm--
Ah. I think I've seen
everything I needed to see.
Good night, Dr. Shepherd.
Make a radical change,
and you've set yourself up
for failure.
We have a problem.
Well, you are a sight
for sore eyes.
-Hi.
-Hey.
Oh...
You came all the way back here
for one patient?
You are some doctor,
Maggie Pierce.
Well, I've been with him
for a long time
and he's getting bad news today,
so thought it should
come from me.
Hi. How are you?
Good.
How was your flight?
Bumpy, and there
weren't any snacks.
But I made it here,
so I guess it did its job.
Guess it did, yeah.
-Well, I gotta prep
for a surgery, so...
-Of course.
-We'll catch up later.
-Yeah, all right.
Dr. Altman.
Yes. Please, uh, come in.
Have a seat.
Thanks.
Dr. Adams,
we would like to follow up
on the investigation
of Sam Sutton's death.
The family has decided to settle
with the hospital.
And our GME Council
is recommending
that you remediate
your intern year.
Wait, I have to start over?
The Council just
gave a recommendation.
Catherine Fox will make
the final decision.
Her office will be reaching out
to set a meeting with you.
Uh, but does
this recommendation say
what I should have done instead?
While I had
a patient bleeding out
and there was
no attending in the room?
That was a unique situation,
and I am sorry that my medical
crisis left you alone in the OR.
But after the investigation,
the Council is not confident
that you will be ready
to move forward
with your surgical training.
I wasn't the only intern
who operated on him.
But it was your decision to cut.
Your judgment is in question,
not your skills.
Look, I know repeating
your intern year
sounds like a big price to pay--
Adams.
Thanks for letting me know.
I'm not giving you
my grandmother's
banana bread recipe.
- Good morning.
- I gave you my car.
Yes, because the judge made you.
All right. Time-out.
We need to make this quick.
I have an important surgery
to prepare for.
Sorry, Dr. Ndugu.
Just give me the recipe.
-Not happening.
-Dr. Griffith.
Mason Peterson, 16 years old
with idiopathic
pulmonary hypertension.
Admitted for new onset
congestive heart failure.
Do you have any
big plans for today?
What do you think?
Thought I'd run a marathon.
Go for a swim after.
Lift some weights.
I think you're gonna
need new lungs for all that.
-Did she say...
-He's getting new lungs?
And a heart.
We just got the call.
Oh, my God. Baby.
I'm gonna go with the team
to procure the organs,
and Dr. Ndugu here
will get you prepped
for the operating room, okay?
Oh, baby.
Schmitt, who's on my service?
What multiverse are we in?
Adams, you're with me.
Oh, he's actually in the pit.
She doesn't care.
Dr. Pierce. I can't
believe you came.
Always.
-Dr. Adams, this is Brady--
-Brady Hauser. Forty-two,
had a heart transplant
four years ago.
Readmitted last week
after an MI IVUS
shows chronic cardiac
graft vasculopathy.
He's on IV steroids
and antithymocyte globulin.
Uh, I skimmed his chart
as fast as I could.
Mm-hmm.
Brady was one of my
first patients in Seattle.
And you must be Ian.
I've heard so much about you.
I mean, not so much about you.
I don't know your
Social Security number
or anything like that.
But I know that you're a
history teacher and you guys met
when you accidentally picked up
his matcha latte
at the coffee shop. Yeah.
-Ian. Right? It's Ian?
-Yeah, it's okay.
He knows I'm madly
in love with him.
Better be. We just
moved in together.
Yeah. I wanna spend as much time
together as we can
in case, um...
Don't go there.
So it's bad, right?
I mean, you wouldn't come all
the way out here to say hello.
Chronic rejection
is causing your heart to fail.
We need to put you back on
the transplant list.
We should plant
the tulips that you want
and see the Space Needle.
You've never done that.
Should we get married?
We should get married, right?
-Brady.
-No. No, you're right.
That was a terrible proposal.
I take it back.
How long can I make
it with this heart?
With medications, a few months.
But Ian is right.
Don't go there.
We're gonna talk to UNOS.
Don't lose hope.
I can't find my gloves.
-Oh, uh, buddy,
they're in your hands.
-Not these ones.
He wants the ones
with the stripes
'cause Mia said they're cool.
Well, if Mia said they're cool,
go look in your basketball bag.
Is this how you hold a 10 blade?
Keep it at a 45-degree angle.
Yeah. And let it glide.
Hold it strong.
There you go.
So there's this house
that just came in the market
in Chestnut Hill.
It's four bedrooms.
It's got a big yard.
I mean, I don't know.
We could get a dog.
-Can we? Please.
-Don't listen to him.
-How-- Did you hear that?
-Dog.
The dog's negotiable.
What do you think?
Who is that?
Amelia.
Amelia? You didn't tell me
she was coming.
I would have rearranged my day.
You made good time.
How long are you staying?
I brought hard drives,
papers, everything.
I couldn't risk leaving them
there. Catherine's all over us.
Dorian has requested
orange Jell-O.
Turns out he's
a Cleveland fan. Yeah!
Well, he passed
his swallow study,
so we can finally advance him
from full liquids
to a soft food diet.
Look, his white count
is elevated again.
It's barely above
the normal range.
He doesn't show any signs
of wound infection
or peritonitis or nothing.
-How are his CRP and PCT?
-Normal.
His progress is remarkable.
Yeah, we should still order
additional labs, cultures,
and a chest X-ray
just to rule out infection.
I heard about Adams.
Uh-- Let me know
when the labs are back.
I don't know if
Catherine knows about us,
or if she is just
sniffing around everyone's labs.
But either way, it is not good.
We need more time.
Can you stall?
Catherine has access
to the hospital finances,
so if she doesn't know by now
it's just a matter of time.
Wait, you didn't cook the books?
I'm funding research,
not a mafia hit.
If Catherine
pulls the plug,
no one will fund us off of
a hunch and some raw data.
We need time to finish
analyzing everything.
-All right.
How much time do you need?
-A few weeks.
A few weeks? You've had months.
We're trying to find
a cure for Alzheimer's.
Did you think that was gonna
happen in a couple of months?
I mean,
this is a cross-sectional
observational study
with just the two of us.
We don't have analysts,
coordinators,
techs, assistants, nothing.
And this is Catherine Fox.
You better find a way
to speed it up.
If we powered through
and didn't take any breaks,
it would still take four days.
Who's on your service today?
Kwan and Millin.
Do we trust them?
Oh. Sorry.
I can go somewhere else if
you're trying to get some rest.
Brady Hauser's back on
the transplant list.
I'm sorry.
I really missed this couch.
It's a great couch.
Do you still have
that hideous recliner?
Why do you have to be like that?
It's a great chair.
It's definitely a chair.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Is there any chance
you could assist on
a heart-lung transplant?
Altman was supposed to do it,
but she got pulled into
some chief emergency.
It's an old patient of ours,
Mason Peterson.
Oh, my God.
-Mason's getting
a new heart and lungs.
-Yeah.
That's amazing.
I would love to scrub in.
Thank you for asking.
All right. Um... Yeah.
I'll put us on the board.
Uh, I'm-- I'm sorry that I
haven't signed the papers yet.
I meant to, but--
No, it's okay. It's no rush.
I mean, my lawyers wanted
them, like, a month ago,
but I told them, "You'll
get them when you get them."
-Well, sure you did.
-What's that supposed to mean?
Well, just that, you know,
sometimes you can be a little--
Careful now.
Direct. Some might say bossy.
You said you
loved that about me.
Because I didn't wanna have to
sleep on this couch.
I'll see you in the OR.
Are we working on
vascular anastomosis today?
I need help with
a very important,
highly confidential project.
Nobody can know
what you're working on.
Can I trust you?
-Of course.
-Absolutely.
These are
gut microbiome sequences.
I need you to enter them
into the database.
So the very important project
is data entry?
Can you handle this?
-Absolutely.
-Great.
Thank you.
We're just allowed back
in the OR
and now we have to code
literal crap?
You wanna fight the chief,
be my guest.
I'm gonna get to work.
Have you guys seen Adams?
He's not answering my texts.
-Haven't seen him.
-Nope.
-What are you doing in here?
-Give me your spot on
the heart-lung transplant
and I'll tell you.
I don't care that much.
What? She said no.
Hey, Link. Link.
Link, do you have a minute?
I just got scans back
for one of my OB patients.
She's 17 weeks.
Her prenatal ultrasound showed
a cystic mass behind the uterus,
but I say we just
watch it closely, right?
About ten centimeters.
You see that, Yasuda?
A tailgut cyst.
It is benign,
but it carries the risk
of malignant transformation,
so I'd recommend removing it.
That makes sense.
But the chances of it becoming
malignant are extremely rare,
and she's asymptomatic,
so I say we just watch and wait.
-That also makes sense.
-Right.
-It's a decent-sized tumor.
-It's an incidental finding.
-You asked my opinion.
-If we operate,
one misstep,
she could lose her pregnancy,
she could lose the function
of her leg, her bladder.
And if it becomes malignant,
she could die.
But you're right.
Transformation is unlikely,
-so we could watch and wait.
-Right.
But watch it carefully. An MRI
every two months at least.
Great. Thank you
for the consult.
Is everything okay?
Um...
You know how Brady
casually dropped marriage?
Funny story.
I had already
been thinking about that,
and I have my grandpa's ring.
But I didn't know
if it would fit,
so I put it on him
when he fell asleep,
which was a really bad idea.
His heart failure
is causing his hands to swell.
Let's see.
Let's try this.
Thank you.
When are you gonna propose?
Uh, haven't decided yet.
You probably think I'm crazy.
He has congestive heart failure,
and I'm planning a wedding.
I think you two
love each other a lot.
What's that? What's happening?
-Out of the way.
-Oh, my God, Brady.
Code blue. Fourth floor.
Cardiac arrhythmia.
Oh, please, help.
Code blue. Fourth floor.
Cardiac Care Unit.
Page Dr. Pierce!
- Charge to 180. Clear.
- Charged.
Why isn't it working?
Somebody get him out of the ICU.
Two hundred. Clear.
Give him one of epi.
-And charge to 250. Clear.
-Charged.
What's happening?
We got a rhythm,
but the HemoSphere is showing
his ejection fraction is 15.
All right. We need to get him
on ECMO immediately.
Update UNOS.
They need to know that
he is in critical condition.
- This upload
is taking forever.
- Shut up.
Is this a group project where
I do all of the work
and you do none--
This is a group project in which
you will do none of the work
because I have written a code
that will do the work for us.
It'll even send
the file when it's done.
-You know how to write code?
-Yeah.
-I taught myself in high school.
-And you did this for fun?
No, I did it for survival.
I mean, if I needed
a Reiki session,
my parents had me covered,
but real-life survival stuff?
I was on my own.
So, I learned how to code
so I could rig
online sweepstakes.
That's diabolical.
I got a Jacuzzi once,
but we had nowhere to put it.
So, now you can enjoy a hot soak
if you're ever near
the spiritual center
of the desert.
Unlikely.
Could you optimize
my dating apps?
It's kinda like a contest.
I am not writing code
so you can get laid.
Too hard? Can't figure it out?
-All right.
-Too hard.
Give me your phone.
Hey. I'm on my way
to assist in the OR,
but I wanna know
how your meeting went.
Can't talk right now.
Trying to help Dr. Pierce.
Do you wanna come over
to the house after work?
You know what's going on?
They're making me
repeat intern year
because of what happened
with Sam Sutton.
I told the lawyers
I wouldn't have operated
if you weren't there.
-This is my fault.
-No, it's not your fault.
It was my decision.
I made the cut.
I will talk to Dr. Fox.
I will request a hearing
with the board.
-We were all there.
We can defend you.
-And then what?
Just let it go, Simone.
Could I get
the MRN for Ms. Patel?
No. Why?
Dr. Lincoln asked me
to schedule her procedure,
so I need to
order her pre-op labs.
We decided we weren't
doing the surgery.
You were there.
I was, and we did.
But then Lincoln
talked to DeLuca about it,
and now the patient decided
to remove the cyst.
Why wasn't I told about this?
All due respect,
that is way above my pay grade.
And yours too, apparently.
So sorry.
My filter's broken today.
I don't believe this.
So the pre-op labs. Could--
Tell Dr. Lincoln to take
his pre-op labs and shove it.
Yeah,
I'm not doing that.
Where's Pierce?
She had to put
a patient on ECMO.
They're finishing up
the organ procurement.
I know
he needs a new heart
so he can adapt
to the new lungs,
but isn't Mason's heart
technically fine
for somebody else?
Why won't UNOS
accept it as a donor?
Well, it's adapted to Mason's
pulmonary hypertension.
So to work for someone else,
it would not only
have to be a match
but also have similar
physiological conditioning.
Hey, page Schmitt.
He can cover for you in the OR.
-I need you to check
on something for me.
-Okay.
Things seem good here.
The kids look happy,
you seem settled.
Yes.
-What are you fishing for?
-Nick moved in yet?
No.
Hand me that dataset.
Well, whatever we find in
the data, I hope it is strong
so that when we present it
to Catherine,
she can't turn it down.
We're not
presenting it to Catherine.
We're sticking to
the original plan.
We're publishing an abstract
based on our findings.
We've already gone behind her
back once. If we do it again--
We can't risk her
pulling the plug on us.
We need independent funding.
What if I say no?
Meredith, you might not care
about your relationship
with the Fox Foundation,
but I do.
They are still
funding my other research.
They are
the majority stakeholder
at the hospital where I work.
I can't lose my job, Meredith.
No one's talking
about that happening.
We are erasing him.
Derek.
And if we are right about this,
it makes his work obsolete.
No one is gonna read it.
No one is gonna
reference it ever again.
Why are you doing this now?
I thought that I would have
more time to process.
And now you're talking about
being days away
from his entire contribution
to this field just disappearing.
And he would understand that
because new discoveries
replace existing theories
every single day.
I'm not saying
that it's rational,
but it doesn't change the fact
that when we do this,
we are burying my brother
deeper in the ground.
And I would think that
you of all people
would understand that.
I do understand that.
I also think I've come too far
to throw the towel in.
And I seriously hope
you feel the same way.
Okay.
Being on ECMO is not ideal,
but it buys us some time.
Well, can I go sit with him?
Yeah, of course.
I gotta go check on
some patients in Chicago
and then I'll come back--
-We might have a heart
for Brady.
-UNOS called with a match?
Dr. Ndugu's preserving
he cardiac graft
from a heart-lung
transplantation.
The heart is salvageable,
and it's a match.
-It was only failing
because of pulmon--
-Pulmonary hypertension.
Okay. I don't wanna get
the boyfriend's hopes up.
This is Mason's heart.
What about screening
for infectious diseases?
-All negative.
-Valvular function?
Good for transplantation.
You found one?
A heart for Brady?
-I have to get back to surgery.
-Okay.
There is another
transplant patient
whose heart might be a match,
but we don't wanna
get ahead of ourselves.
This is not
something we do regularly.
A lot of stars have to align
for this to work.
But they-- they could, right?
Okay. Let me check with UNOS,
put eyes on the heart,
and then we'll go from there.
Come on.
-Hey.
-What's going on?
I need to talk to you.
Chief to former chief.
That doesn't not turn me on.
Okay. So remember
when I was promoted
and I wanted to get those shoes
that said, "I'm in charge"?
Yeah. The ones that
I told you not to buy
'cause we had a mountain
of legal debt and you secretly
bought them anyway
with our emergency savings.
Ahem. How can I help?
I used discretionary budget
to fund Meredith's Alzheimer's
research
after Catherine shut it down,
and I think she's onto me.
What made you think
that was a good idea?
Because it's a potential cure
for Alzheimer's disease.
And it's not like
I stole something.
And regardless,
Catherine has 30 hospitals.
I didn't think that
she would notice
one small line item.
Listen...
I didn't wanna
keep pestering you
about funding my Bleed Program,
so I went to Catherine.
And she said that she'd
look into your budget.
You went behind my back?
Owen, I told you
I was working on it.
You're accusing me,
and you're the one
who's misappropriating funds?
Like you have never
bent the rules around here.
-I'm trying to help you.
-Oh, God.
Okay. Okay.
Okay, listen.
Go to Catherine.
Tell her the truth.
Better to come clean
than to get caught.
She will respect you
for doing the hard thing,
and then you can
figure it out together.
Okay. I can do that.
I can do the hard thing.
-Okay. Yeah.
-Thank you.
All right.
Aortic anastomosis is complete.
-Let's get this heart beating.
Schmitt?
-Coming off bypass.
- Where's the heart?
- Back table.
Glove me, please.
Have you done a domino
heart transplant before?
-No, never.
-Sounds like we should all
buy lottery tickets today.
If this works, it's huge.
But it doesn't change the fact
that I've got four patients
on the floor right now
who might not make
it through the week.
So, yeah, miracles are great,
but we wouldn't need them if
more people were organ donors.
Come on, Mason.
Come on. Come on.
Starting
cardiac massage.
Come on.
Come on, Mason.
Come on. Come on.
- All right. Internal paddles.
- Yeah.
How's it looking
back there, Pierce?
- The heart is healthy, but...
- Clear.
...the SVC-- it's too narrow.
Won't fit.
Can we stent it?
It's a good thought,
but it won't be enough.
Clear.
Come on, Mason.
Again. Clear.
It's incredible.
Yeah, never gets old.
You good to close?
-Yeah. Go ahead. We got you.
-All right.
How's it looking?
So Brady's SVC
is scarred from prior surgeries.
We need a bigger diameter
to allow for proper blood flow.
We can get
a bigger diameter if we
excise the fibrotic area.
The scarring's too extensive.
There won't be enough tissue
to make it work.
Okay. Then we reconstruct
the SVC
with a bovine pericardial patch.
Come on. We've done difficult
reconstructions before.
We've even done
a partial heart transplant.
We can handle some scar tissue.
All right.
I'm gonna need a pair of loops.
What is it that
you're looking for?
Do you want, like, casual dating
or a relationship or sex?
No one uses apps
for relationships.
I met my
ex-girlfriend on an app.
Were you looking for
a relationship
or were you looking for sex?
What about her?
She's a financial
security analyst.
I don't know what that means.
You are just like
every other guy.
You just want
a dumb trophy wife.
Oh, you're jealous.
-You are sorely mistaken.
-Oh, really?
Because I'm pretty sure
you told me that you loved me.
Okay. That was
a moment of weakness.
-That doesn't sound like
a denial.
-Ooh!
Fine. I have
a tiny crush on you.
But you know what? I'm hot,
I'm single. I'm a damn doctor.
You're--
You're like a cold.
I have it, I'll get over it
and then it'll be like
it never happened.
Hey, what's up? What's going on?
Catherine may have found out
about everything,
so we just need to move
up the timeline to publish.
I thought you said you
and Amelia were careful.
We were very careful,
but Catherine does have
access to Teddy's budget,
so we just need to move
a lot faster.
If Catherine knows, that's it.
It's done. You cannot publish.
I can't afford not to. You're
the one who said, "Find a way."
-Yeah, and you got caught.
-So what should I do?
Just throw everything
I've done away?
Okay.
When you get fired from
the Fox Foundation,
what happens then?
-I will continue the work
somewhere else.
-You think I'm fine with that?
I mean, you can't expect me
to keep uprooting my life.
I-- I moved to Seattle.
I followed you to Boston.
Now you're back
and forth to Seattle.
I'm living in
a glorified dorm room.
But I said I wanted
to move in with you.
Yeah, months ago. And I don't
pay lip service here, okay?
When I say I wanna move
in with you, I mean it.
I want family dinners
every night
and camping trips with the kids.
And I wanna take care of you
when you're sick and lift
you up when you're sad.
I mean, my God, you don't get
it. I wanna marry you, Meredith.
-You do?
-I do.
And you can't even be bothered
to ask if I'm on board
before you burn it
all to the ground.
I thought we were
watching and waiting.
I know, but I had reservations.
So you went over
my head to my boss?
I was working with
DeLuca on another case.
-I just brought it up.
-Not your place.
I brought you in.
You should have paged me.
There wasn't time. DeLuca
got paged to deliver a baby.
-That's convenient.
-It's the truth.
Maybe, but clearly he
didn't care what I had to say.
The patient seemed
pretty worried about
the cyst growing bigger.
I should have been consulted.
Jo, I value your opinion,
but you're a resident.
It was a rare tumor. I wanted
to talk with somebody who had
more experience. That's it.
Open. Open. Open.
Can we talk about this later?
-I have patients to check on.
-You're an attending.
Just have your resident do it.
This tissue
is more dense than I thought.
-Can you help me
clean out these edges?
-I can give you some traction.
If this doesn't work,
what happens to Brady?
He stays on ECMO,
and we wait for another donor.
- Could take months.
- He's got a lot to live for.
I have to believe
that he will hang on.
-How's Mason?
-He's doing great.
Dr. Schmitt did an excellent job
placing the sternal wires.
- Can I get a ray tech?
-  -What sutures are you gonna use
to attach the pericardial patch?
-4-0 GORE-TEX?
-Exactly.
Well, unless you're Dr. Pierce.
She uses a 5-0
with the eyelid retractor.
-You remember that.
-Oh, I remember.
-We don't.
-Well, I find that I have more
control with a smaller suture,
but it is not the norm.
So I normally don't have
a resident assist me
when I'm placing a patch.
I don't wanna teach bad habits.
But sometimes you get
an overachiever
who insists on being
in the OR with you
and learning all your secrets.
All right.
I hit healthy tissue.
All right. Dr. Pierce,
what do you think?
I think...
...we still got it.
-Brady's getting a new heart.
-All right.
Let's prep the patient
for transplant.
I won a trip
to the Bahamas once.
Sounds fun.
Yeah, it was right after
my mom got cancer.
I moved back home, and there was
this townie bar near her place.
They had this promotion where
for every drink you bought,
you got an entry to win
a trip for two to the Bahamas.
And I was there more
than I care to admit.
Racked up a bunch of entries,
and I won.
So, you abandoned your mom
to go on vacation?
The opposite.
I convinced them
to extend the deadline
so I could bring her.
She really wanted to go.
I thought we would go
after she got better,
but that is obviously
not what happened.
She died,
and I needed an escape.
So my girlfriend
and I went instead.
-Well, how was it?
-She got sun poisoning
and I broke my arm.
It sounds like you need a redo.
Uh, we should get out of here
before someone tries to come in.
Uh, what I said earlier--
- This Isn't-- Like, we aren't--
- Uh, no, I--
I just don't think
it's the right time...
-Oh, no.
-...to get in a relation--
Stop.
I don't want you
to have the satisfaction
of being the one
to cut this off.
So, I'm good.
We're-- We're good.
Just a cold, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, just a cold.
Hey. I'm just
headed to the airport.
Had to grab my stuff.
Do you have a minute?
Millin and Kwan just uploaded
their last dataset.
Wait, does that say--
95% confidence.
There is a definite correlation
between gut microbiomes
and Alzheimer's
disease progression.
Even before
patients have symptoms.
I mean, this might mean
that people could be diagnosed
before they're symptomatic.
And if we could
alter the gut microbiome,
maybe we could prevent
the disease altogether.
Oh, my God.
I thought about Derek.
But mostly I've thought
about my mother.
This disease robbed her
of her entire identity.
I know how personal
it is for you.
I just didn't want
the world to forget him.
This is as much your research
as it is mine,
so if you don't wanna publish,
we can find another way.
I mean, they would want us to
push through no matter the cost.
That is how we honor them.
Well, then I guess
we have an abstract to write.
Oh, my God.
He did great.
-Can we see him?
-He's being transferred
to the CCU now,
but once he's settled, you can.
I have to head
back into surgery,
but we'll check in tomorrow,
and we'll talk about
plans for recovery.
What about the person
who got his heart?
-Are they okay?
-Unfortunately,
we can't share any information
about the recipient.
Um, excuse me?
I'm sorry, but did your son
donate a heart today?
Yes, he did.
Thank you.
Adams.
Impressive work today.
It was a rush.
Yeah, we got really lucky.
Yeah.
Do you like it here?
Does anyone like
being an intern?
We have a categorical position
at the Heart Center.
You would train
at the University of Chicago
and do your research with us.
I think you should consider it.
I think you'd do
really well there.
I always thought I'd do neuro.
Why? Because you're a Shepherd?
There are worse things
than being a neurosurgeon,
but cardio is pretty great.
Just think about it.
I can't believe you remember me
teaching you
pericardial patches.
That was, like,
a million years ago.
Yeah. Donna Barton.
We did her transplant
my second year of residency.
Same complications, same fix,
but not exactly
outside her body.
-No.
-I remember everything
that you taught me.
Oh, my God. Um--
I'm--
I'm-- I'm so sorry.
Yeah, no. It's okay. Um--
You make an amazing save
in the OR,
and then celebrating after.
It's what we do.
What we did.
Right.
Yeah.
I think it's time
for us to let go.
I signed 'em.
Yeah.
Until the next
miraculous surgery.
Goodbye, Maggie Pierce.
Pierce offered me a position
at her hospital.
In Chicago?
Yeah. I'd be a designated
cardiothoracic resident.
Working on groundbreaking
surgeries like we did today.
Every day.
Sounds like a great opportunity.
Yeah.
And I'm considering it.
Dorian's repeat labs
and scans are all normal. Hmm.
He's been through it more
so than most, but he's okay.
He made it.
Okay. Thank you
for double-checking.
The ABSITE results come
in tomorrow, don't they?
I asked Millin how it went,
and her answer was,
"I think I finished."
- What-- I mean,
Yasuda said it was easy.
Kwan gave a half groan,
half laugh.
I learned not to ask.
I mean, they've come really far
in the last few months.
They're finally
where I need them to be.
And if any of the rest of them
have to start over--
You've come to care for them.
They're interns.
They're your interns.
There will come a moment
when their pain is your pain.
Their success is your success.
Trust me. I get it.
Hey.
Did you finish
Lincoln's post-op orders?
I can't do this anymore.
What?
You're breaking up with me?
Here?
You know, you are one of
the most incredible people
I've ever known.
-Don't patronize me.
-I'm-- I'm not.
When I-- I first met you,
I was so stressed
because I had no money.
I mean, I was
working all the time.
I didn't even sleep.
I barely ate.
And then one day,
I walked into a bar,
and you smiled at me.
And for a moment,
everything was okay.
But now you are my boss.
You literally get paid
to tell me what to do.
And as much as I wish that
I could just put that aside,
I-- I don't think
that either of us
have strong enough feelings
to prioritize
this relationship
over everything else.
So you're choosing work.
Wouldn't you?
I used
my discretionary budget
for Meredith Grey's
Alzheimer's research project.
There is no excuse
for going behind your back.
It was disrespectful,
and I am sorry.
Dr. Altman, we all make
mistakes at every level,
but not everyone
is honest about it.
That takes courage.
Tells me you're a woman
of great principle.
Thank you.
I knew that you
would understand.
I didn't say I understand.
Hey, can I get a beer, please?
One for him too.
We're celebrating.
We saved two lives today.
Ah. Yeah, right.
You say that like
it happens all the time.
Well, technically,
it is our job.
Technically, things don't always
go our way.
Unless they do for you.
In which case,
this beer is also mine.
Cheers.
I'm sorry.
I could have handled
everything better today.
I'm sorry too.
Going back to being a resident
is harder than I thought
it would be,
and I took it out on you.
The principle
of the domino effect
is a double-edge sword...
Then tell me
what I can do.
I think that we should keep work
and home separate,
and only work together
when absolutely necessary.
And just keep it professional.
-Okay.
And under this new arrangement,
can I do this at work?
That would be
highly inappropriate.
- Mm-hmm.
- What about this?
...it can help us
build healthy habits,
but it can lead to
destructive tendencies as well.
Wait, you--
you got on the gurney with him?
-I didn't know what else to do.
-Oh, my gosh.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
Maybe it's not that funny.
No, sorry. I, um...
I signed divorce papers today.
Oh, God.
I'm not-- I'm--
I'm laughing with you.
I'm not laughing at you.
-I'm not laughing.
-No, no.
It's just-- I just
got divorced too.
And we rented doves.
-When you got divorced?
-No, no, no, no.
When we got married.
We should have rented 'em
for the divorce.
That would have been fun.
I even built a tent, though,
on the be-- on the beach.
Oh, really? We had a live band.
We had custom sand sculptures.
Ew. Why?
Oh, no.
This is gonna suck
for a while, isn't it?
Yeah.
One small misstep
becomes one bad habit.
Of course,
none of us is perfect.
And so much
is out of our control.
-Hey. The kids asleep?
-Yeah. Yeah.
They were exhausted.
I got your favorite.
Where are you going?
I'm gonna go
sleep in my own bed.
You're right. I'm terrible
at being in relationships.
And if it makes you
feel any better,
I've always been this way.
You know, it really--
it really, really doesn't.
You know you're the most
important person in my life
besides my children.
I don't know that
I can marry you.
I did that once before. I don't
know that I can do that again.
But I know I love you so much.
And I love
going to sleep with you,
and waking up
and seeing your face.
I can promise
to love you forever.
Or as long as
I can remember you.
Mer, I love you too. That's
not the issue. You know that.
The issue is that I put
work before you,
and you're right, I do.
But just right now.
That's not forever.
And if you love me,
then you'll support me.
And if you support me,
then I can do this.
Are you in?
You should take that.
All you can do
is make the best choices
available to you...
Teddy. Is everything okay?
Catherine just fired me.
...and hope they don't
come back to bite you.