♪♪
♪ Yesterday's ghost ♪
♪ Should be haunting me ♪
♪ But I've finally woken up
to who I'm supposed to be ♪
"On your deathbed, no
one wishes they'd worked more."
-  ♪ Walking in the golden hue ♪
- Miranda!
♪ I wanna give it back to you ♪
Miranda!
♪ I won't fall ♪
That's the trite,
little phrase people trot out
when they want to play
hooky
or spend too much money
on vacation
or shame working parents
for missing their kid's
soccer game for a board meeting.
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
Mom!
Don't post that!
My tie's not straight!
Oh, ho!
You look fantastic.
- Definitely not that.
- Ahh.
But you know
what matters even more
for your
History Day presentation?
- I'm prepared.
- That's right.
You researched and
practiced.
Hard work is the recipe
for success.
Wh...
What in God's name?
Fart Attack app.
I'm gonna bust it out during
Robbie Uhr's presentation.
No, you will not!
Sabotaging the competition
doesn't make you any better.
Oh, come o...
That's so silly.
Okay. Your dad's
picking you up after school,
so we'll see you on Monday,
okay?
- See you Monday.
- Mm.
- Knock 'em dead.
- Bye.
♪♪
"On your deathbed, no one
wishes they'd worked more."
Tell that to the people
who love their work.
So, today, I'm gonna climb
60 flights of stairs.
All my gear on.
98-degree heat.
But, then again,
I guess
- that's not really that...
- No.
I can't talk to you about
my day?
You cannot.
Because it's not cute.
What you're doing
to my stomach lining.
Not cute.
You're giving me a permanent
case of indigestion.
Miranda,
how long are we gonna do this?
Just pull over right here.
I have a meeting at Seattle Pres.
Since when?
Are you playing calendar
with me now?
You've been living
another life off calendar.
Stop right here.
Okay, look. I'll, uh...
I'll see you at the...
Hello? Hel... Hel...
"60 flights of stairs?
In that heat?
In that gear?!
You are a badass,
Ben Warren."
"Yeah, I know, right?"
Please. Please.
I-I don't think
you're hearing me.
It's not so much a clot in my leg.
It's like a-a pre-clot.
Mr. Nelligan, I cannot
admit you for a pre-clot,
because that's not
a real thing!
- Excuse me. Nurse?
- I can feel it
right under the surface,
like a time bomb
waiting to...
Hello. I need a moment of
your time.
We all need something,
don't we?
Dr. Bailey?
What are you doing here?
My name is Dr. Miranda Bailey.
I am Chief of Surgery
at Grey Sloan Memorial...
- Surgery is upstairs on four.
- Okay,
interrupt me again,
I'm coming over that counter.
My name is Miranda Bailey.
I am Chief of Surgery
at Grey Sloan Memorial,
and I believe that
I am having a heart attack.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 14   Episode 11
Title: "(Don't Fear) The Reaper"
Miranda!
What, I can't talk about my day?
Miranda, how long are
we gonna do this?
Good news, ma'am.
It doesn't look like a heart attack.
May I have that?
I see you are a doctor,
so I'm sure you know that people
can confuse heart attacks
with basic indigestion or reflux...
I'm not confused.
Give me that.
Run a 15-lead EKG.
You could be missing
a posterior infarct.
Well, my cardio chief told me...
I'll be the chief of my own cardio,
and I'm telling you what I need is...
Here.
For a posterior EKG,
you want to put leads here...
and here...
and...
Here. Turn around.
Turn around! Here.
Well, don't just stand there!
Now run it again!
Well?
Nothing.
I'm telling you, Doctor.
The EKG looks fine.
But how about
I take a family history
while we wait for
the cardiac enzymes?
We find out if there's
something else going on.
How about you go away now?
And bring me whomever is in charge?
Miranda!
Miranda Bailey!
You have three seconds
to get inside this house
before I come looking for you!
Three! Two!
One!
Now, what did I say about coming
in before the street lights?
That if I wasn't inside
before the first flicker,
you'd be on me
like white on rice,
on a paper plate,
in a snowstorm, in Antarctica.
And are the lights on?
I'm sorry, but I was just
reading in a tree. I promise.
Stuck up in a tree is no place
for a little girl.
Especially when they have
a perfectly good porch swing
on the front of their house,
where I can see you.
Yes, ma'am.
Yeah, I need you to cover my service.
I'm not feeling well.
I thought I'd stay home
rather than make my sick patients sicker.
"Do no harm" and all that.
Well, what's wrong? Are you...?
Uh, Mrs. Woo is coming in
for a regular screening
colonoscopy.
Everything's in the chart.
And Mr. Izikoff needs an ERCP.
Can you do that?
Dr. Maxwell.
Paging Dr. Larry Maxwell to the ER.
You sure you're okay?
I'm sick!
You want the gory details?
I'm trusting you'll handle it.
Gotta go!
Chief Bailey.
Chief Maxwell.
We here at Seattle Presbyterian
know that you have a choice
when it comes to your health,
and I'm delighted,
with all your Harper Avery wins
and national recognition,
that when you need quality care,
you come to us.
You talk to a woman having
a heart attack this way?
Believe me, if you were having
a heart attack, I would not.
So you're taking your
intern's diagnosis over mine?
I'm taking the H&P, normal EKG,
and negative rapid troponin.
Miranda, we're running
a full cardiac enzyme panel
for good measure,
but trust me... it'll be normal.
My clinical judgment
tells me you're all good.
I most certainly am not "all good."
I have nausea, heartburn.
Any big stressors in your life lately?
Any big changes?
- Do not go down that road with me.
- What road is, uh...
The road where a woman shows up
in the ER with physical symptoms
and you decide that it must be
that she's not able to
handle all her feelings.
No, this is not about anxiety.
My secret heart doesn't need fixing.
My actual heart needs fixing.
Are you sure you're not experiencing
any unusual levels of stress?
- You're fired.
- This man is dead!
Miranda, just get in the car.
I'm gonna take care of myself.
I need $20 million.
I am having a heart attack.
And I'm not going anywhere
until you do a full cardiac
work-up and prove it.
Paging Dr. Anderson
to Labor and Delivery.
Whatcha in for?
Uh, heart attack.
Mm. Whatcha workin' on?
Work.
No wonder you had a heart attack.
Sorry. Too soon?
I am Chief of Surgery
at Grey Sloan Memorial,
and my work doesn't stop
just because...
they want to take their sweet
time with their work-up!
Wow. Chief of Surgery.
Look at you.
Burning it down.
My work ethic sucks.
Drove my parents crazy.
I'm just grateful I had
a temp job when they died.
What are you in for?
Broken femur.
And a nasty road rash.
But, you know,
that what's I get
for... pushing my Kawasaki
to 100 on Route 10.
Needless to say, frequent flyer.
What, you not a fan of hogs?
Life is a gift, one that
I show my appreciation for
by not recklessly speeding
through mountain roads
on hogs or
anything else for that matter.
I wore a helmet!
Now, you want to talk
reckless?
- Skydiving in Costa Rica.
- Ooh.
That's reckless.
Plane almost lost a wing
on the way up.
Hell of a rush, though.
If you say so.
So no interest?
Zero.
Not even...
Not one iota.
Not buying it.
It's human nature.
Everyone has the need to be
a little bit reckless.
Ouch! Dang it!
Miranda!
Oh, my Lord!
Ohh!
I'm okay.
I just scraped my elbow.
Why on Earth weren't you riding
with your training wheels?!
Because I'm in junior high!
And all the other kids pick
on me for using training wheels.
Like they pick on me
for wearing high waters.
Well, I don't want your hem
getting caught up.
And we don't need you tripping,
falling, and busting your head.
I know how to walk.
Come on in here.
We gonna clean this up.
Paging Nurse Alvarez.
You seem agitated.
She's having a heart attack
and you're not helping her.
That's agitating.
Thank you.
Let's discuss diet and exercise.
Any significant changes
lately?
Um...
A few years back, my levels
were a little high.
I got them under control.
They've been steady ever since.
I take my steps,
drink my green drinks...
So no spicy foods or...?
You went to Yale Medical School,
as I recall.
- Mm-hmm.
- Ivy League.
Is there actual ivy there
or is that just a thing?
Dr. Bailey, I would rather
discuss your health
than my education.
But, yes. There is actual ivy.
It's not just a thing.
Oh. Well, then.
I learned something new today.
Which is more than you can say
for your days at Yale.
Because apparently your teachers
didn't get the memo
that women's heart attacks
don't manifest the way
they do in men.
They're not all
chest-clutching, vomiting,
"help, my arm is numb,"
boom... floor drop.
Look. Just... Just give me
a cardiac stress test, Dr. Maxwell.
Dr. Bailey, I can tell y...
Just give her the damn
stress test, Maxwell.
Any medications you take regularly?
Um, other than statins
and anti-depressants
to manage OCD, no.
Hm.
Everything's under control.
We're good.
You good, Miranda?
I put my hands in those
patients, and they died.
I feel so... dirty.
Accept that
you have a disease, Bailey.
Accept help.
Don't do that.
Do what?
I am a sci-fi-loving
African-American woman
in her 40s
with a stubborn husband,
a beautiful son,
and... no pets because
they smell like feet.
And I have a big job
where I do big, lifesaving,
miracle-working things...
where I lead others
so that they can do
their big, lifesaving,
miracle-working thing.
And, yes, I have
obsessive-compulsive disorder.
I am not ashamed of that.
But it's not my story.
It's just one piece.
And if you continue to look
at just that one piece...
if you check the "mental illness" box
and refuse to look at
anything else...
then I'm not gonna live long enough
to finish
the rest of my story.
Give me the cardiac stress test,
Dr. Maxwell.
Miranda, you do not need
a stress test.
Okay, then I want a second opinion.
If you're not happy with your
care here, you're free to leave.
Oh, and drop dead
in the parking lot?
No. That is not how my story ends.
Second opinion.
Please.
And preferably not a Yale grad!
All that ivy seems to
have poisoned your brain!
Ha! You tell 'im!
If something happens to me,
do not let them hook me up to
anything.
And if something happens to me,
hook me up.
I want extraordinary measures.
The more extraordinary,
the better.
Seriously.
- Seriously.
- Seriously?
Dr. Bailey. I'm Dr. Gregory.
Finally! I've been waiting
for the stress test
and cardiac consult
for the last half-hour.
Well, I am here for a consult,
but I'm not a cardiologist.
I am a psychiatrist,
and I was hoping that we could talk.
♪♪
Dr. Bailey?
Yeah, I need you
to meet me in the pit.
I'm on my way. Not our pit.
The pit at Seattle Presbyterian.
- Seattle Presbyt...
- Sh... No, no. Don't say it out loud.
And don't tell anyone
you're coming.
Just get here.
Fast. That's an order.
Also a request.
I'll be right there.
Let's talk about your home life.
You have a husband, yes?
Yes.
A husband who is a doctor.
Was a doctor. Now he's a firefighter.
It's not easy to be the wife
of a first responder,
knowing your loved ones
run into situations
that most run away from.
He is not the reason
I'm having a heart attack.
But is that the reason
that he's not here?
'Cause he's fighting fires, or...?
Okay, Dr. Gregory,
with all due respect
to your field of medicine,
I need you to understand
that every second we waste,
I'm losing heart muscle.
My vessels are constricting.
My heart is being damaged.
I'm a doctor. You should, at the
very least, acknowledge that.
Fair enough, Dr. Bailey.
Well, then, if you'll humor me,
I'd like to ask you for a consult.
I have a patient...
a-a woman who has a big job
with big responsibilities.
Manages life-and-death
scenarios on the daily.
She also has a history of
mental illness.
And I have assessed
limited coping skills.
I see no data to support
her self-diagnosis
despite repeated tests.
And on top of that,
I see no support system in place.
No friends or family in sight.
Dr. Bailey,
if you were this woman's doctor
and you were looking
at her chart,
what would you think?
63% of women who die suddenly
from coronary heart disease
had no previous symptoms,
and women of color are
at a far greater risk.
So if I were consulting
on the patient your describe,
I would take into
consideration statistics
that would never even occur
to people who look like you.
And I do have a support system.
And a beautiful child
who had a history presentation
this morning
and who is now
on his mid-morning break.
So if you'll excuse me,
we're done here.
What's wrong?! Are you hurt?!
- I got in! I got in!
- Full scholarship to Wellesley!
Blue pride, baby!
Congratulations, honey.
6 hours and 40 minutes away!
Are you sure
it's your first choice?
Mom, are you serious?
Harriet Stratemeyer Adams.
Cokie Roberts. Nora Ephron.
Hillary Rodham Clinton!
I'm going to a school of
the greats.
But it's near Boston.
Can you be happy for me?
For once?
Hi, honey. Hey, how'd it go?
Because I'm your mom and I get
to know all the things. Go.
Wha...
A standing ovation from all the teachers?
Ohh.
I am so proud of you, Tuck.
I'm so very proud.
Because I'm your mother
and I get to say it
as many times as I want to.
Y... Yeah. No. Hey, go to class!
Okay. Hey, and be good
for your dad this weekend.
I love y...
♪♪
Please. Please.
I need some help in here!
Well, this is a s-surprise.
Yeah, I, um...
I-I'm here for a consult.
Another doctor called me.
For a consult.
Well, I-I'm a following up
on something for a colleague.
Oh, another surgeon?
Excuse me. The family waiting
area is down that hall.
We're doctors.
Yeah, uh, following up on
calls we got from your ER.
Then can I help you find
someone?
- Dr. Bailey.
- Miranda Bailey.
I don't see a Dr. Bailey
working here today.
Uh, check patient records.
I can't share that information.
HIPAA and all.
But I'm sure you knew that, Doctors.
Mm. She's my mom.
Uh, Miranda Bailey is my mother.
You're her husband?
Uh, no.
Um, but s-she's my daughter.
B-But he's married to my mom,
Miranda Bailey.
That's right.
Bed number three.
- Thank you.
Probably should have led
with husband, huh?
Okay. Just don't mention that
you called her your mother.
No, she had me
very, very young.
Call a code blue!
Hey! Uh...
- Crash cart coming in!
- She's coding!
She had a broken femur!
May have thrown a clot!
All right. Hold on. Hold on.
Hold on, Morgan. Hold on.
V fib. Charge to 120.
- 120.
- Clear!
Charge to 200.
- Charged.
- Clear!
We got her back.
Oh, my God, Miranda.
Ohh! Damn. I'm glad to see you.
Bailey!
Hey! Miranda?
Miranda!
- Bailey.
- Miranda?
If you didn't tell him,
then how the hell
did he figure out where...
I figured it out because
I have never known you
to take a sick day, ever.
And because I heard them page
Dr. Maxwell when you called me.
And none of that matters.
What matters now is that you
are being hooked up to an EKG
with cardiac symptoms
in someone else's hospital.
- The hell's going on here?
- Dr. Maggie Pierce,
Chief of Cardiothoracic
Surgery at Grey Sloan,
and I'm saving your patient's life.
Look at this EKG! Elevated STs...
I know what an MI looks like.
Clearly, you don't, because she has
been sitting here for hours
and you completely missed it.
Dr. Bailey, you know as well as I do
that your previous EKGs
did not show these changes.
Webber. Glad to see the Grey
Sloan team decided to join us.
Dr. Pierce needs to get
Dr. Bailey to cath lab STAT.
I need to open up the blockage
before it's too late.
Let's load her with Plavix.
You don't have privileges here.
Now get out of the way
so I can help your friend.
Let's go.
♪♪
- 60 damn years.
- Do you have it in you?
When I said I do,
I meant I do.
Even though I know what you're
gonna be like in 60 years.
And what am I going to
be like, Dr. Warren?
Bossy.
Ah. Like you're gonna be
some walk in the park.
What is it?
Are you feeling any...
Why is it that men only listen
to women
after they've done
something wrong?
Let's just hold still
so we can get this done.
You have a wife?
I have access to the LAD.
Y'all. Don't. Listen.
Princess Leia knows
what I'm talking about.
When they went on that planet
with the... the... Ewoks!
Yeah.
And if Han and Luke
had listened to Leia,
they could've avoided a lot of misery.
I'm just sayin'.
And... we're... done.
Ewok.
You're welcome, Dr. Bailey.
♪♪
I know she'll be fine.
She's Bailey.
She's unstoppable.
You can't slow her down.
I'd like you to slow down.
Maybe have a seat.
I checked her charts, and her first
troponin levels were normal,
so this hasn't been
going on for very long.
Long enough for us to have noticed.
Between this and Amelia, I...
I mean, we're always so busy
running around taking care
of everyone else.
Maybe we're not checking in
on each other enough.
Oh, God.
Are you dying, too?
No. No one's dying.
Right. I... Right. Okay.
Where's Ben?
If Bailey wanted him here,
he'd be here.
Are you okay?
Me?
I'll be fine when she's fine.
So we're gonna sit here
with you wearing that
terrified look on your face,
for a respectable amount of time,
so that Dr. Baylow
and her friends can assume
you're having your behind
handed to you on a platter!
You're gonna make a hell
of a surgeon, Dr. Bailey.
Lose the smile.
Okay, you're stable.
The cath procedure went well.
They stented your LAD.
And as soon as you're up for it,
we want to transfer you
to Grey Sloan
and admit you to Maggie's service.
No, no.
I'm not being transferred.
No. Everyone knows me
at Grey Sloan.
They'll make too big a deal.
A heart attack is a big deal, Bailey!
When was the last time
you called in to work sick?
I have, on occasion,
when necessary.
Mm-hmm. Pierce?
Never. Perfect-attendance award
since fourth grade.
- I'm not about to blow that now.
- Exactly.
Pierce is the youngest
female cardio chief.
I am the first woman
to become Chief of Surgery.
We didn't get to where we are
by calling in sick
or showing our bellies
or admitting weakness.
No one is gonna think any
less of you.
Okay, when you came back
from being electrocuted,
it was All Hail the Conquering Hero.
Nobody doubted your ability
to come back.
- Miranda, this is not...
- No, do not "Miranda" me.
This is a battle
you've never had to fight.
It's taken me way too long
to feel tall there.
And I'll be damned if
I'm gonna let a blocked artery
take me down a peg.
Will you at least let us call Ben?
Let him know you're all right?
Is this really something
you want to keep a secret?
Your mother isn't trying
to hold you back.
She's trying to keep you safe.
She's trying to keep you alive,
the way she couldn't
keep your sister alive.
I had a sister?
It was before
you were even born.
Her name was Danielle.
She lived two months.
Sids.
We felt helpless.
Took me a long time
to understand it wasn't our fault.
To forgive myself.
But your mother never could.
So when you were born,
she swore she'd never let
anything bad happen to you.
Every single day, she lives
with the fear of losing you.
Hmnh. No transferring.
And no calling my husband.
I'll be fine.
I will rest and recover and
be back to work by tomorrow.
So if you think you're
keeping me out that contest,
you got another thing coming.
- Dr. Bailey...
- No. I-I've made up my mind!
What happens at Seattle Pres
stays at Sea...
Her pressure's dropping.
I need an intra-aortic
balloon pump tray STAT!
Okay. Someone page Maxwell! Now!
Ohh.
Okay. Just breathe.
Breathe normal.
Miranda. Breathe normal.
Relax.
Hold on, Dr. Bailey.
Start dopamine at five mikes
per kig per minute.
She could have a coronary
dissection.
Maybe. Her artery was
extremely torturous.
Maybe if you had diagnosed her
before she was actively
having a heart attack,
you could've taken your time
with the procedure
instead of having to rush through it!
I followed the protocol
for ischemic heart disease.
Did you do a cardiac stress test?
If you had, you would've seen this
long before it became emergent.
Now not only has your stent failed,
but we have to get her
up to the O.R. immediately.
We?
They're talking about doing
an emergency C-section.
They can talk all they want.
I'm not going to Mercy West.
This baby is not coming out.
- I need a ride.
- You could lose it. You know this.
- Things just happen.
- No! The world just doesn't happen!
Okay? It's not on God!
It's on me!
Stop it! Stop it.
Okay, you're right.
Cars are not safe for children.
Okay? Neither are bookcases or squirrels.
They're all gonna get your baby.
You feel this way
because you are a parent.
It'll pass. Mostly.
Some of it never will.
No! Oh, no! No, no! No!
The elevators aren't working!
Turn the elevators back on!
Turn them back on!
Oh! Damn it!
No, no, no.
Keep breathing.
The IABP will get you stabilized, okay?
Get her straight to the O.R.
Prep her for a repeat angio
and sternotomy.
A sternotomy?! N-No. No way.
Dr. Pierce, she's likely
going to need a CABG.
Not in two days or two hours, but now.
If you open up her chest, you will be
putting her through hell for no reason.
Angioplasty is no longer an option.
Do the graft via keyhole procedure.
It's far less invasive.
It's a 3-inch incision, max.
You can't. You don't know how.
A conventional approach is the safest.
Says the man who ignored
his patient for half the day,
insisted that she was wrong, and
now put her in this position,
which she should've never been
in, in the first place.
So please step aside
and give me privileges.
Huh.
Larry, we've known
each other for a long time,
so you can trust me.
If you give Dr. Pierce privileges,
you will be extremely happy
that you did.
For old time's sake?
Then in a few days,
we can laugh
about the whole thing
on the golf course.
My treat.
Fine. I'll do this for you, Richard.
- But I'm there the whole time.
- Okay, let's go.
- Let's go, everybody.
- Need some help.
Come on.
- It's okay.
- It's gonna be okay.
It's okay.
Mom, we've been through this.
You can't become a surgeon
unless you go to medical school.
I'm saying... speech pathology.
It's still a helping profession.
Plus, you can make your own hours,
which is no small thing
when starting a family.
Speech pathology is boring.
And what's the matter with boring?
Being a surgeon
is the highest-stress job
you could have.
And I don't want you
killing yourself
driving home
after a 100-hour week.
That's just no way to live.
It's not healthy.
It's not safe.
I'm not Danielle!
William...
I...
I'm so sorry, Mom.
Surgery makes me happy.
I need you to get happy
for me.
Look at me.
Look at the Mandy Bailey
that you've raised.
Look. I know
I'm not Danielle.
And I know you miss her,
and I know you're scared.
But I'm not.
I'm happy.
And I'm not afraid.
Please let me live the life that
I know I'm supposed to live.
Bailey?
Bailey, you all right?
Let's get her intubated STAT.
I'm gonna go scrub.
Dr. Pierce!
Call Ben. Call Ben.
I need my husband.
Call my husband.
♪♪
You know what?
Uh, better make it two.
Rough morning?
60 flights of stairs carrying 50 pounds.
I'm tired, and I'm hungry.
Four more hours to go.
- You got it?
- Uh, yeah.
Next.
Dr. Webber.
♪♪
I've dissected
the internal mammary.
Now I'm going...
I'm Chief of Surgery,
bot an intern you have to
walk through the procedure.
- Wow.
- Wow?
Yeah. Wow.
Wow. You are infuriating.
Wow. You are arrogant.
Wow. Dr. Bailey deserved
so much better than you.
You'd rather cut someone open
stem to stern
than be bothered
to learn something new.
Dr. Pierce, I understand
you're upset, but this is...
I'm not upset. I am furious.
And I am grateful.
I am grateful that Dr. Bailey
fought for herself
like she does for her patients
every single day.
And I am furious that
she even had to.
- She's in V-fib.
- Damn it! Internal paddles.
Clear.
- Excuse me. Pardon me.
- Whoa!
- Excuse me.
- Hey!
♪♪
Where is she?
Oh. She's in the O.R.
Pierce is doing a keyhole CABG
to fix the damage.
How much damage?
We don't know
until she's done.
There's nothing
we can do but wait.
She said it was indigestion!
♪♪
No concern
we'll end up just friends?
That what you're looking for?
No.
Me neither.
I'm dating Dr. Bailey.
I know the drill.
I know you.
Oh, maybe it's a phrase.
"My question to you." Anybody?
- How many letters?
- 13.
No. It's 14. Count again.
I just counted.
What, you have X-ray vision
from across the room?
"Will you marry me"
is "my question to you."
And the reason why that it's so easy
is because I made the crossword.
The phrase has 14 letters.
"Will," 4, "you," 7, "marry," 12, "me."
You know, Miranda is one
of the most stubborn,
pigheaded women I know.
Amen.
Brilliant mind. Terrible cook.
Double Amen.
But also the strongest
person I've ever met.
Damn straight.
That feeling you're having
right now?
The waiting, wondering whether
she's gonna make it?
The not knowing eating
at your insides?
That's what
you're asking her to do
every morning
you walk out your door.
How is she?
Oh, well, w-we're still waiting.
What's... What's all this?
Ohh.
Wagyu beef brisket sandwiches.
- Garlic mashed potatoes.
- Wow.
Mm-hmm. Oh, I will not have you
drinking that swill.
I can't believe
you made all this.
Child, please.
I had my driver pick it up.
Well, come on, fellas.
Feed your faces.
Come on, honey.
Mwah.
You don't get to make
decisions on your own
without a heads-up anymore.
You don't say, "Maybe
I'll apply to be an intern.
We'll see how it goes.
But for now, it's my little
secret between me and me."
That's not your life
anymore.
When you're sharing
your life with a person,
you talk to them.
You think with them.
You make decisions with them.
You are loyal to them.
You are not a free agent anymore.
Do you understand me?
Does this mean we're
still getting married?
How you feeling?
Fine. Do I know you?
Oh. I-I'm sorry. No.
Uh, I'm Miranda Bailey's friend.
She'll want to know how you're doing.
I feel like I got charged
by an angry rhino.
That actually happened
to me once. In Namibia.
Huh.
Doctors said, uh,
your friend saved my life.
She did.
She should seriously work
on that addiction of hers.
Addiction?
Never stops working.
Ah.
Bad for the heart.
Indeed.
Tell her I said so.
Hold up.
A-Am I allowed to ask
how she's doing?
Seeing as
how she saved my life and all.
You're awake.
Good. You look good.
Well, not good-good, but...
Um, I was able to bypass
the LAD with a graft.
You'll be back to bossing us
around in no time.
Thank you, Dr. Pierce.
♪
I thought I lost you.
Not a chance.
You call me.
- I know.
- No, you...
Call me.
♪ Well, you almost had me fooled ♪
Um...
Talked to my boss
down at the fire station.
Told him I'm done.
- ♪ Nothing without you ♪
- I'm done, Miranda.
Mm. Benjamin Warren.
♪ I can thank you for
how strong I have become ♪
- Call him back.
- I'm sorry?
♪ 'Cause you brought the flames
and you put me through hell ♪
You fighting fires terrifies me.
Life is... terrifying.
But I could die of a heart attack
and you could die
crossing the street tomorrow.
♪ Prayin' ♪
Life is too precious
to waste doing anything less
than what makes us happy.
♪ I hope you find your peace ♪
You get to be happy.
Just promise me one thing.
♪ Prayin' ♪
Hm?
Anything.
Mm. Build me a tree house.
I'm guessing those
- pain meds are working.
- Steal yourself one of those
fancy fireman's ladders
and build me
a tree house I can read in.
A girl needs some peace
to read a good book.
♪ And you said that I was done ♪
Highest tree you can find.
♪ Well, you were wrong, and now
the best is yet to come ♪
Highest tree
I can find.
It's not about
whether you spend your life
in a board room, your bedroom,
or on a beach
with a Mai Tai in Maui.
When you look back on your life,
the only thing that matters is...
Did you spend it doing what you love?
With the people you love?
Hello?
Were you happy?
Mom.
Mandy! I was just
about to call you.
You know Shari-Lynn down
on Dogwood Road?
She and her daughter went
to Memphis on a road trip,
for God knows what,
and stayed in a terrible hotel.
Car broken into.
Room broken into.
Oh, it was an awful mess.
And for what?
For Graceland?
Tell me you aren't having delusions
about a road trip with Tuck
any time soon.
Mandy? Are you still there?
Miranda, what's wrong?
I'm hurt, Mom.
I-I got hurt.
I had a heart attack.
♪♪
And it was scary.
But I'm okay.
♪♪
I had surgery.
And I'm going to be okay.
I know.
I know you are.
You are my Mandy.
- ♪ I hope you're somewhere prayin' ♪
- Mm-hmm.
Did you make the most of this beautiful,
terrifying, messed-up life?
♪ I hope your soul is changin' ♪
Did you let go of all the
things that held you back?
♪ Changin' ♪
♪ I hope you find your peace ♪
So you can hold on to
what matters most?
♪ Falling on your knees ♪
♪ Prayin' ♪
♪♪