Hello.
Get the door!
Need some help! Watch out!
She's cyanotic.
Let's get her to Trauma One.
I don't care if it's closed.
We can't take...
No. No, look, Jesus,
I'm telling you...
Jesus... Jesus, are you deaf?
Move out M.I. Moving to five.
What the hell is going on?
Mercy's closed to trauma,
and Lakeside's power is out.
That makes us it.
Hi.
Jen went to Milwaukee
to find an apartment.
Why is it so hot in here?
Air conditioning's out.
Ah! Great. Hottest
day in October.
Isn't this your
day off? Hi, Rach.
Tommy missed his plane
coming back from
his brother's wedding.
The joys of being
chief resident.
Dr. Ross, there's
a five-year old
with some kind of heart
problem in Trauma One.
Okay.
Bye, Rach.
Bye.
Our baby-sitter's
not going to be here
for a couple of hours.
Is there anybody who
can watch Rachel?
Uh... Joanna's off in ten.
What are all those
wires sticking out?
That's so
we can give him medicine
to make him better.
Is he sick?
Actually, he's...
uh...
What's he doing out here?
Paramedics brought him in D.O.A.
from some nursing home.
The heat got him.
City's supposed to
come pick him up.
Come on, Rachel. I'll show
you where the TV is, okay?
I thought Tommy was back today.
He's supposed to be.
Doug needs you in One.
I got to take Rachel
into the lounge.
I got her.
Come on, Rach.
I'm not even changed.
Let's see what's
in the fridge, huh?
What do you got, Doug?
Okay, Mark, we
have a five-year-old
with known
coarctation of the aorta.
She had a sudden onset
of severe respiratory
distress about an hour ago.
You worried about
congestive heart failure?
Yeah. Resp's 40, B.P.'S 180/100.
She's tachycardic.
Her rate is 180.
You get blood
gasses? Chest film?
Yeah.
Mid-systolic murmur.
Bolus her with 20 milligrams
of Lasix.
What's her name?
Kanesha.
Hi, Kanesha.
I'm Dr. Greene.
You know, I have
a daughter your age
and she came with
me to work today.
When you're feeling better,
how about I bring her in here,
and she can meet you, okay?
Okay.
Get a cardiologist down here.
I'm going to go check on Rachel.
I'll be back in a
couple of minutes.
You just stop it!
I told you!
That's all!
Indian summer.
It gets this hot,
people just sort
of lose their heads.
Supposed to be 102 today.
Hoo!
Dr. Greene, a pizza
delivery guy got stabbed.
He's driving himself in.
How soon?
Only a couple of blocks away.
Where's Benton?
Jerry.
Somebody order a pizza?
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.
Do you have any
pain in your head? No.
In your neck? No.
What about your chest?
Jerry, would you call Security?
Somebody's in my parking space.
Ba-da-bum!
Where's Rachel?
Joanna's keeping an eye on her.
Cardiology been down yet?
Yeah. Kayson's finishing
up an angiogram right now.
Should be here in
about 20 minutes.
Anyhow, now she's
got a fever of 102.
A fever?
How you doing, kiddo?
Her rhythm's changed.
Ventricular tachyrhythmia.
Tachyrhythmia?
20 Milligrams of
Lidocaine, I.V. push.
Could be secondary
to the congestive heart failure.
Has she had any
surgeries recently?
No. Her family's
in the waiting room.
I'll see what I can find out.
They stabbed me!
Mr. Etker, does your neck hurt?
No!
Pressure's 210/120.
Squeeze my hand.
Press down with your foot.
I'm dying!
Does your chest hurt?
They stabbed me!
Where?
My side.
There. There!
You want me to prep
for a peritoneal lavage?
No. I want you to get some
Bactine and a Band-Aid.
What's wrong?
Why aren't you helping me?
It's just a scratch, Mr. Etker.
A... a scratch?
It was a really big knife.
Jerry, can we at least get this
D.O.A. into an empty room?
Well, there aren't any.
Then take him down to Pathology.
Uh-huh.
So?
Five on 300.
I'm in. 350.
I got 375.
Wendy?
I never win.
Oh, come on.
It's only five bucks.
Okay. Um...
200.
200? Man, you can play anytime.
200 it is, Wendy.
Lydia?
Hey, she's smelling.
She's not allowed
to smell, is she?
465.
Uh... Dr. Lewis,
want to get a piece
of today's blood alcohol pool?
Oh. Who's today's victim?
Arthur.
Ooh. Well, anything
under 400's a sucker bet.
550.
Ooh. Ooh.
Ahh.
Oh, Dr. Lewis?
Your sister's looking for you.
She's in the lounge.
Hi, Chloe.
Hi, little sis!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Look at you!
Wow. Stethoscope and everything.
Even a little badge.
Man, look at that picture.
It's worse than the D.M.V.
Is that a push-up bra?
No.
You've got sugar on your chin.
I was eating doughnuts.
Are they yours?
No. They were in the fridge.
I thought they
were for everybody.
Well, they're not.
I'll replace them later.
You sure? Okay.
Eeeehhh!
Aahh! Chloe, I'm working!
Oh, hey, is this your locker?
Chloe...
Wow. Must be cool to
have your own locker.
Sort of like back in school.
Chloe, I really have
to get back to work.
I'll call you tomorrow, okay?
Uh... I lost my apartment.
What happened to
the money I sent you?
It wasn't enough.
$500?
I can't do this right now.
No, please.
No, Chloe. Not this time!
Mom won't let me
stay at the house.
I can't. Really.
It's just for a couple of weeks.
Weeks?
Days then, okay?
I promise, this time,
I won't screw up.
I won't.
Please, Susie.
Please?
I don't have
anyplace else to go.
Don't let the cat out.
And none of your friends
can come over, ever.
You hear me? All right?
Understand?
It'll be okay. I promise.
Good. I know it will be.
I got to go.
Thanks.
No friends.
Was surgery ever scheduled
to correct the malformation?
They found it when
Kanesha was a baby,
but they said I had until
she was six or seven
to have it taken care of.
She was doing so well, there
didn't seem to be any hurry.
Normally, that'd be true,
but her condition
clearly worsened today.
Dr. Kayson is going to
examine her in a few minutes.
He's an excellent cardiologist.
Can I have 75 cents for a soda?
Shandra.
Doe she have a cardiologist?
We've got a pediatrician.
I should probably call him.
Her. Ellen Mathias.
Her. Sorry. I'll
call Dr. Mathias
and get Kanesha's records
over here right away,
and I'll be back as
soon as Dr. Kayson's
had a chance to examine her.
How's she doing?
Lytes came back normal.
Damn it.
She's hypertensive... 180/100.
Hypertension, agitation.
Fever, ventricular
tachyrhythmia.
Poisoning?
Let's get a tox screen
going right now.
Sweetheart, did
you take anything...
Anything your dad
told you not to touch?
Anything in the sink,
in the bathroom, in
the garage, anything?
Peter, it's your
liquor store guy again.
Ivan? Oh, God. What now?
Shots were fired.
The paramedics say it looks bad.
Multiple gunshot wounds.
Pulse 150, thready. B.P. 50.
We got two large-bore
I.V.s wide open,
but his pressure's
still crashing.
Where's Ivan? Ivan Gregor?
I thought that's who
you were bringing in.
Over here, Doc. I
thought you were shot.
That's the one... The
one who shoot me.
Now I shoot him.
Dr. Benton?
Get six units O-neg now.
Now I shot you, huh?
See how it feels,
huh, you little bastard!
Now you see!
Oh, no. What...?
Is she okay?
Your daughter's fine, sir.
Oh, thank Jesus.
Thank you, Doctor.
Thank you.
I'd like to see her now.
I'm Dr. Ross. Sir, your
daughter wasn't suffering
from congestive heart failure.
She wasn't?
This is Mrs. McGillis,
from the Department of
Child and Family Services.
She'd like to ask
you some questions.
Your legal name and address?
What the hell's going on here?
I need your legal
name and address.
Where's Kanesha?
I want to see her, now.
Your five-year-old daughter
overdosed on
cocaine, Mr. Freeman.
No palpable B.P.
Capillary refill's bad.
All right, he's bleeding.
Let's get that blood
in a pressure bag.
He needs a bilateral
chest tube now.
How old is he?
14, tops. Let's roll him.
Here we go.
Oh, God, Ivan. What
did you use, a cannon?
The kid's got no exit wounds.
Move, Carter.
Exit wounds?
He was shot in the back.
Call the O.R...
See who's available.
Get them down here, and
get them down here now.
All right, here we go.
He had a seizure
in the waiting room?
Yeah. He slammed his head
against the corner
of the admitting desk.
Says his name is Monte,
and that he's HIV positive.
Are you on any
medications, Monte?
AZT, DDI, Bactrim?
Uh... AZT and some
white and red ones.
Dilantin? Have you
been taking them?
Sometimes I forget.
Have you been drinking, Monte?
You can't mix
alcohol and Dilantin.
It's very dangerous.
Do you understand?
I try to get to the clinic,
but they won't let me on the bus
because I don't have any money.
Get a C.T. tox screen,
CBC, a Chem seven, Dilantin,
and blood alcohol levels.
Decreased breath
sounds bilaterally.
Carter, get over here and
put a stitch around the tube.
To hold it in. Move!
Here comes the cavalry.
Who is it?
Langworthy.
Great. Just what I need.
What have we got, Peter?
Teenage male with
multiple gunshots in the back.
Bilateral hemothorax.
We've got a lead
out of the left already.
Dr. Benton, that Russian
guy keeps screaming for you.
He says you're the only one
he's going to let
sew up his head.
I don't get a pulse here.
Carter, go take care of Ivan.
I'm putting in the stitch.
Got a bullet in
the right ventricle.
Tamponade. Here we
go. I'll crack his chest.
No, you won't.
He's my patient.
Carter, you still here? Go.
Go. Move. Move.
Thoracotomy tray.
Let's move, let's move.
Come on, come on.
Here we go.
Hi, Kanesha.
This is Rachel.
Hi.
I'll get you a stool, okay?
Is she going to get better?
Yeah, she's
feeling a lot better.
Aren't you, Kanesha?
Yeah, good.
I like your dog.
His name is Schmedley.
I had a dog... a real dog.
His name was Max.
Did he run away?
He was old and he died.
My mom died, but she wasn't old.
My mommy's in Milwaukee.
My daddy's your doctor.
He helped make me better.
That's what doctors do.
I get a real dog
when I'm ten.
My dad says I get to name him.
P.E.A., tachycardic. 140.
Heart's racing with no pressure.
Spreader.
Thank you, Sarah.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Rachel, Rachel, Rachel.
Is he sick?
Yeah.
I think he is.
Did somebody hurt him?
I don't know, darling.
Somebody bad?
Probably somebody very bad.
It was him.
He came in before,
with his friend,
and he shoot me.
You need to stay
still, Mr. Gregor.
Now he just come
in... Like nothing.
He thinks I'm being afraid.
Not this time.
This time he should
be afraid, huh?
What would you do if he come in?
The one who shoot you before.
I don't know.
You shoot, that's what you do.
Just like me.
Any man say he
don't, he is a liar.
A damn liar.
Whoa.
Hey. Hi.
Hi.
I was going to
look for you today.
I have to get to the lab.
Well, I'll walk with you.
Look, I was a jerk showing
up at your place like that.
Uh-huh.
And, so, I owe you an apology.
You're not making this
any easier for me, are you?
Oop!
Hey.
Hi.
Aren't you going up to the lab?
No. I always take the stairs.
Great girl, isn't she?
Yeah.
I don't blame you for
still wanting to be with her.
I know I do.
You know, I was a jerk
going up to Carol's
place like that.
I've done the same
sort of thing myself.
Don't be so tough
on yourself.
Hey.
We'll get you all fixed up now.
You getting off?
Not my floor.
We're on the 12th.
Yeah, I punched the
wrong button there.
Pericardium's full of blood.
Get me a 2-0 suture.
No time.
Make like the Dutch boy
with his finger in the dike.
Hold on tight, everybody.
This is going to be a gusher.
Ready!
O.R.'s been alerted.
Where is it?
Got it.
All right, let's go.
All right, come on.
Coming through.
Clear the way, people.
Clear the way.
Come on, let's go.
Step on it.
Call the O.R.
Tell them they've got a
tamponade coming up.
Tell Cardiology they're
going to need ten units now!
Have O.R. prep for
a heart/lung bypass.
Coming through, people!
Hold the elevator!
Let's go! Come on!
Step on it.
And the winner is...
Aw!
Read it and weep, boys.
.473. Every damn time.
How does she do it?
This is going to be a tough one.
You really going
to clean him up?
Tradition is tradition.
Glad I didn't win.
Come on, Arthur.
You've got an appointment
with some hot water.
Your sitter still hasn't shown?
The car overheated.
When are they going to fix
the air conditioning?
They're working on it.
Jerry, the dead
guy is still here.
What, are we waiting
for him to get ripe?
I'm sorry, Dr. Greene.
I called Pathology.
Why don't you throw a
sheet over him at least?
All right.
Hi.
You must be... "Jerry."
I'm Linda Farrell,
Novell Pharmaceuticals.
Oh, hi.
You like pepperoni pizza, Jerry?
I'm a vegetarian.
I'll eat it.
Is Dr. Greene available?
Um...
He's expecting me.
On his day off?
Uh... he's on the board.
What are you
selling, Miss Farrell?
Are you in a procurement
position, Doctor...?
Lewis. Dr. Greene's
very busy today.
I'll wait.
Could be quite awhile.
Jerry and I will catch
up on old times, then.
Won't we, Jer?
Oh.
Uh...
sure.
I'll tell him you're here.
Where you from, Jerry?
West Town?
Yeah. Ukrainian Village.
I knew it. My grandfather
grew up on West Haddon Avenue.
Huh! Cortez Street.
What do you know about that?
Maybe we're cousins
or something, huh?
Hey, Mr. Kinnett.
Mr. Kinnett?
Has the anesthesia taken hold?
He's out.
Okay.
Up...
you go.
How did he dislocate
his shoulder?
Waterskiing accident.
He's still in love with you.
Doug? He's a little kid.
He always wants
what he can't have.
You ready?
Yeah.
Let's move in together again.
What?
It's been five months.
Got it.
I still have more
than enough room.
I just got a new couch.
So we'll stay
at your place.
Okay. Let's get an X ray
for a postreduction film.
And... at least
think about it, okay?
Okay.
He seems really nice.
He is.
Is it that Doug?
No. It's me.
He says it wasn't him.
That he doesn't know
where Kanesha could
have gotten cocaine.
And you believe him?
Did you call the police?
What for?
Child endangerment.
He's middle class.
He owns a home. He has a job.
I got families of ten
living in '67 Buicks.
He could be a coke dealer.
The Department will
follow up with a field visit.
If anything seems
wrong, we'll pull the kids.
I'm not releasing her
till I think she's ready.
That's your prerogative, Doctor.
"He looked and he looked.
"He could see nothing there
but a small speck of dust
blowing past through the air..."
Hey, Rachel. What
are you reading?
A book.
Horton Hears a Who.
Oh, I remember that one.
Keep going.
Okay. "'I say, '
murmured Horton.
"'I've never heard tell
of a small speck of dust
"'that is able to yell.
"'So you know what I think?
"'Why, I think that
there must be someone
"'on top of that
small speck of dust...
"'some sort of a creature
of very small size,
"'too small to be seen
by an elephant's eyes.
"'Some poor little person
who's shaking with fear
"'that he'll blow in the pool.
"'He has no way to steer.
"'I'll just have to save
him, because, after all,
a person's a person,
no matter how small.'"
So cancel your credit card.
If I report it stolen,
and she tries to use it,
they'll arrest her.
Would that be so bad?
Last time Chloe moved in
with me, she stayed for months.
You could have told her no.
I tried to, but she's...
she's my sister,
and I care about her.
I don't know. Every year,
she seems to get worse.
Would you talk to her?
And say what?
Anything. Just observe her.
Let me know what you think.
Well, I could recommend someone.
We tried. She won't go.
I'll introduce you
as my boyfriend,
and then she'll never know.
Your boyfriend?
Is that what I am?
This is my sister, Div.
Look, it's a bad...
it's a bad idea.
Why?
What if she asks me what I do?
You want me to lie to her?
Damn right.
What if I have to
tell you something
you don't want to hear?
Like what?
Oh, I don't know...
Like your Uncle Bob
molested her as a child.
We don't have an Uncle Bob.
I'm sorry, but this
is just an awful idea,
and I'm not going to allow you
to talk me into it.
Ho! Ho, ho, ho!
Time to feed the animals.
So you're not going to help her?
No. No. No, I'm not.
Fine.
I'll do it on my own.
He went into a systole.
What do you expect?
Yeah, but you
can't anticipate that.
Sure, you can.
I'll see you around.
Yeah. Sure.
How is the boy?
He's in surgery.
Is he going to be okay?
No, Ivan, he's not.
I was very scared.
I stay, see how he do, okay?
Look, Ivan...
yeah.
Yeah.
I'll find you later.
Good.
Good. I wait here.
Huh?
Right here.
Rachel just wanted
to say good-bye to Kanesha.
Did Tommy finally show up?
Yeah. He just
called from O'Hare.
He's on his way in.
Is she okay?
She's sleeping, Rachel.
You, uh... still planning
on admitting her?
Mm-hmm.
For how long, Doug?
I don't know.
She could go home tonight.
No, she can't.
She could live with you, Daddy.
Kanesha's got a family
of her own, Rach.
But she doesn't have a mom.
No, she doesn't.
And you'll be lonely
when we go to Millakey.
"Milwaukee"?
It's hard not to have a mom.
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
Lots of families are that way.
Some families just have moms,
some just have dads,
but it works out okay.
Doug, I need you in seven.
Kid with a bellyache.
Okay. Listen, sweetheart,
will you stay here
till I get back?
I don't want her
to wake up alone.
Okay, Dad?
Sure.
Okay. Thank you.
Hey, Carol.
I'm in a hurry, Doug.
Taglieri and I
had a little talk.
Nothing like that.
He accepted my apology.
Well, he's a bigger
person than I am.
Come on. Slow down here.
Why don't we just agree
to behave like adults
when we're around each other?
"We"?
Mm-hmm. No. Me.
It's me, and I'm sorry.
Want to hit me?
Come on, you know you want to.
Here, hit me. Right here.
It'll make you feel better.
You know you want to.
Just give it your best shot.
You must be Dr. Ross.
Linda Farrell, Novell
Pharmaceuticals.
I understand you handle
emergency pediatrics
around here.
Yes. I do.
Hi. I'm Doug Ross.
Ow!
You're right.
I feel better.
Did I interrupt something?
No. We're done.
Uh...
Who did you say
that you worked for?
Novell.
Have you tried our
new cephalosporin?
It has excellent coverage.
Doug!
I tell you, Miss Farrell,
whatever you're
selling, I'm buying.
It's Miss Farrell?
Is that right?
Call me Linda.
You can call me Doug.
Doc. Hey, Doc.
Oh, hi. How are you feeling?
Okay, you know. Much better.
Good.
Hey, Doc, Doc...
um... I am a screwup.
Always have been.
Uh... I think I need
to get into a program.
Dr. Lewis?
Oh, it's okay, Jerry.
Yeah, sure. I can give
you some referrals.
But I can't be in one
on the South Side.
I got to get out of
the neighborhood.
But it costs money to move...
To set up someplace else?
You got to find
someone to help, to care.
No.
It's just a couple of
hundred bucks. That's all.
I said no.
A hundred bucks...
50!
What are you? Deaf?
I said no!
That's it.
Hey! I wasn't doin' nothin'!
You're out of here, pal!
You bitch! I was only
askin' you for help!
Bitch!
Dr. Ross...
Might as well go
home, Mr. Freeman.
Kanesha's not going
to be released today.
That's because of you, right?
That's right.
Dr. Ross, can I take
my baby home tonight?
Your five-year-old
daughter is recovering
from a cocaine overdose.
I don't know where she got it.
At 6:00 in the morning?
I'll give you a hint.
She got it from your house.
It's because I'm black, right?
Drugs, black man...
Got to be trouble.
Your daughter could have died.
You understand that?
She has a serious
heart condition.
You have no right
to judge me!
Watch me.
Your boy died.
Yeah. I heard.
When did it start raining?
Couple of minutes ago.
Well, maybe it'll cool
things down, huh?
Maybe.
Gather your things up, Rach.
Did you make him all better?
Who?
The boy in the green room.
The gunshot victim.
They tried really
hard, Rachel...
but he died.
Will his mom be sad?
Very sad.
Are you sad?
Yeah.
If you're sad, why
aren't you crying?
I am...
right here.
Dr. Benton, there's a detective
here from Violent Crimes.
Wants to talk to you
about that gunshot kid.
Put all your stuff
away. Okay, hon?
Got a minute?
Mm-hmm.
He's got a point.
Would you feel the same way
if her name was
Stephanie and she lived
on the North Side?
This isn't about race.
Oh, sure it is.
So you think I'm a racist, too?
No.
I think he deserves a chance.
I believed him.
And are you willing
to stake that
child's life on it?
See if he's willing
to take a drug test...
The rest of the family, too...
And find out who else
has been hanging
around the house.
Ta-da!
Arthur?
The very same.
That's incredible!
He looks better
than your last husband.
Here's your old clothes, Arthur.
Take my advice.
Burn them.
What was that?
Ah! The air
conditioning is back on.
Great. Just in time
for me to go home.
Good night.
Bye-bye.
Jerry, if this guy's
here in the morning,
why don't we get some
shovels and bury him
in the parking lot?
Sorry, Dr. Greene.
Good night.
So, when they
brought the boy in,
was he conscious?
Did he say anything?
Ivan had been shot by
the same kid twice before.
Yeah. Oh, is that
what he told you?
Did he tell you that he
shot the kid this time?
Yeah. Look, how
many times was Ivan
supposed to let this
kid attack him? Huh?
All right.
Thanks a lot, Doc.
We'll be in touch if
we need anything else.
Look, Detective...
Ivan's not the kind of
man that belongs in jail.
What? You two friends?
Yeah. Yeah, I guess we are.
Yeah? Well, that
kid was unarmed.
Mr. Gregor chased him
out into the street and shot him
as he ran away.
You know where
Mr. Gregor is, Doctor?
Ivan...
Um...
I'm sorry.
Dr. Benton, they need
you in Trauma Two.
Dr. Benton?
You okay?
Yeah.
Uh... two.
Let's go.
Carter?
Mr. Freeman, the test came back.
It was negative.
Good.
I can have my baby?
Your older daughter
Shandra's drug test
was positive.
You knew that, didn't you?
Do you have kids, Doctor?
One. I have a son.
The year before my wife died...
she and Shandra were
at each other's throats.
Typical adolescent stuff.
They just...
never had a
chance to work it out.
I don't know what to do.
How to reach her.
Sometimes...
I think she's
trying to kill herself.
She needs help.
I can help you get it for her.
Honey, you can
fall asleep in here,
but I'm going to have to put
you in your own bed later, okay?
Okay. Does Mommy
come home tomorrow?
Day after tomorrow.
Now, good night.
I miss her.
Me, too.
Daddy?
Yes?
If I got hurt, would you fix me?
Yes. I would.
You wouldn't let me die?
You are... the most
important thing to me
on this earth,
and I would do everything
to make you better.
Everything.
I love you, Daddy.
And I love you, sweetheart.
Come on, Chloe,
don't do this to me.
Chloe...
What are you...?
Chloe, I told you
not to let the cat out.
Chloe?
Chloe...
Oh, damn it!
Oh, Chloe...
Susan?
The cat was out.
It's going to be all right.
I'll talk to her.
We'll get her some help.
It's going to be okay.
It's okay, it's okay.
Shh, shh, shh.