♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
♪ Ah, ha ha ♪
♪ oh, yeah ♪
"Dr. Turner's story
is at once mesmerizing
"and instructive
and a significant achievement
for a first-time author."
Oh, I love the "chronicle."
We love the "chronicle."
Mommy and daddy are gonna
subscribe to the "chronicle."
Okay, here's the "post." "In her
first book, Violet Turner
"lets us into her life
with admirable candidness.
No scar remains unexposed."
Cute.
"An honest and powerful read."
I can't believe how good
these reviews are.
Are you kidding me?
Oh, yes, she can. Mommy is
not that modest, is she?
Uh-oh.
What? What, vi?
Uh, "what portends to be
an honest, forthright accounting
"of a psychiatrist's
professional and personal life
"ultimately winds up being
too honest.
"Dr. Turner reveals herself
to be more...
"Self-involved
than therapeutically minded.
She lacks all sense
of boundaries."
Who wrote that?
Uh, Marla thomkins
in the "times."
Well, clearly,
she's an idiot.
Well, she's not just a reviewer.
She's also a shrink.
It's one bad review, Violet.
One. I mean...
Yeah. It's one bad review.
♪ Why I work so hard
for you ♪
Uh-oh.
♪ Work to give you money ♪
♪ ooh ♪
You all right?
Do I look okay?
Well, you look like...
Something you ate
last night?
No. I didn't eat anything
last night.
I was mad at you.
And unlike Naomi,
who I know has been very much
on your mind these days,
I do not stress eat.
Okay, Addison.
We're past this.
Now I'm sorry you are...
Whatever you are...
But really,
we're going backwards here.
I told you, nothing happened
with Naomi.
That's the end of it.
Okay? Now can I
get you anything?
No.
I'll see you at work.
♪ Ah ha ah, do do do,
da da da da da ♪
♪ I can't work any harder
than I do ♪
♪ ah ha ah, oh, oh, oh ♪
Does that hurt?
No. Not at all.
How is it possible
that I'm cancer free
and pain free
after all this time?
Good oncologist,
even better pain specialist,
and a pretty good
support group, right?
You guys are amazing.
You're the one who went through
all the painful radiation.
We're just
the cheering section.
You have been positive
from the very beginning.
You've never wavered.
And you...
Apart from the minor detail
of being the surrogate
for our baby...
Well, it's an aunt's dream.
I get to spend quality time with
my niece before anybody else,
including her mommy.
I expect baby pictures.
Oh!
Claudine?
Sit back down, slowly.
Ah.
Is it the baby?
Ooh. I don't know. Um...
I'm gonna go get our o.B.
To take a look at you, okay?
Okay.
I'm gonna go get the lamaze
pillow from the car,
just in case.
Wait, wait.
This could be it.
Anyone hear anything
from Naomi?
Uh, uh, I-I left her
a message, but no.
Maybe she reconsidered
and ran off with fife.
I talked to fife.
He's still here
in a hotel room, waiting.
Where is the damn antacid?
Sorry. I needed it.
I felt the same
before my book party.
That's revisionist history.
If you recall, on his big day,
they made a cake
that looked like Sam,
and he wouldn't let any of us
eat it. He was staring at it
with this smile on his face that
matched the smile on the cake.
Hey, Addison,
can you do a consult?
Sure. Thank you.
No, it's just, uh, you know,
my book comes out, uh, tomorrow,
and, uh, people are
gonna be reading it.
That's what people do
with books.
I-I know. I know.
Violet, if this is about what
that petty little pseudo shrink
wrote in the "times"...
Do you think
I lack boundaries?
I don't lack boundaries.
Cooper?
I'm not an expert, so...
It doesn't take
an expert to realize that first,
you are great at your job,
and second, if everyone else
loves your book except one
petty reviewer, screw 'em.
Yeah. Want me to quote you what
people wrote about my book?
"There is a clear pattern
of narcissism
"in Violet Turner's
brand of therapy.
"She comfortably inhabits
"the role
of emotional seductress,
"taking the vulnerable
to where she wants them
in order to achieve
her own end goals."
Blah, blah, blah.
Like I said, screw 'em.
Yeah, I mean, the review's
not entirely wrong, and...
Right?
Screw you.
No, seriously, Cooper.
I'm putting myself out there.
What have you ever done?
So wh-wh-what time
is the party tonight?
Oh, god. Um,
uh, we were just--
no, please. This is not
the first time we've, uh,
caught a couple kissing.
Addison, uh...
This is claudine...
How do you do?
And Elliot.
Elliot is married
to claudine's sister.
Oh. Oh.
So I get Kyle wasserman
into an arm bar,
and I'm about to end it--
remember, wasserman
has never been pinned.
Then I just got dizzy.
Next thing I remember,
the coaches
are standing over me.
Any dizziness
before that day?
Never.
And how about since?
I was a little light-headed
after practice yesterday.
You're back
at practice already?
Oh, not at school.
Coach won't let me.
Just at home with my dad.
Conference finals
are tomorrow, Dr. Freedman.
Place is going to be packed
with scouts.
And after the wasserman match,
Tyler has to perform.
Yeah, we need a full ride,
division I.
Okay.
Tyler's been wrestling
for years with no problem.
He's a healthy kid.
Okay, I do hear
a slight heart murmur.
So I would be more comfortable
if our cardiac specialist,
Dr. Bennett,
took a look at him.
Can we do this today?
It's just--we have to make sure
Ty wrestles this week.
His scholarship--everything
depends on him being there and--
okay, we need you
to sign this.
Coach Patterson won't let him
compete without it.
Well, look, I know
how important this is to you.
If Dr. Bennett says
his heart is fine,
I will sign it.
This isn't some tawdry thing.
It's--
crazy. I'm--even if
it makes sense to you,
you--you're cheating
on your wife with her sister--
her sister who is carrying
your child.
W-Wait. That baby is--
no, no.
We did in vitro with my sperm
and claudine's egg
before any of this happened.
Well, Elliot, I don't know
what I can say.
H-How do you think
this is gonna turn out?
I don't expect you
to get it.
I mean,
before Lorraine was sick,
things weren't great
between us.
And we tried to work it out,
but then the cancer came on.
And claudine and I,
we took care of her.
Spent a lot of time together,
talking and...
Trying to laugh through
how scared we were.
And claudine, she--
she understood me.
Those feelings,
they kept getting stronger
until one night--
and now you're here. Fine.
But... Lorraine deserves
to know.
You get that, right?
Sh-she'll know. She'll know.
After the baby's born...
I'm gonna leave Lorraine
to be with claudine.
Hey.
What was that about?
What?
In the kitchen.
You mad at Violet?
No.
Are you jealous
of Violet?
Why would I
be jealous?
Well, you tell me.
Violet is a great shrink,
and now
she's a published author.
Naomi builds hospitals
all around the world
in addition to performing
miracles at a fertility clinic.
And Pete,
he's already saved lives
in basically every country
Naomi's going to, not to mention
being an E.R. doc
and an expert in critical care
and infectious diseases.
And you're one of the youngest
chiefs of staffs in the country,
and everyone is doing
something special--
everyone except for me.
Grow up, Cooper.
You look like crap.
Ugh. Thank you.
Flu?
You don't feel warm.
Did you eat anything weird?
No.
So what's wrong
other than, you know,
you lookin' like--
I don't know.
Amelia, I just don't
feel well. Okay?
I'm exhausted.
I feel nauseous.
I just... I don't know.
Maybe it's just some sort
of... delayed reaction
to the bizzy stress.
Maybe.
Have you gained any weight?
Okay, now you're
just being mean.
Are you peeing a lot?
Your boobs--are they tender?
Okay, you are a neurosurgeon.
I am a gynecologist.
All right, if I were,
I would know, and I'm not.
Okay? I can't be.
Do you and Sam
use protection?
Amelia, I'm telling you,
I can't--
are you late?
Yes.
But I can't be.
I mean, I don't think--
you're preggers!
This is awesome.
Auntie Amelia.
Even though you divorced
my brother,
I'm still gonna be
your kid's aunt, right?
Amelia,
for me to get pregnant,
it would take a miracle.
A miracle that I am
going to spoil rotten.
I think I'm gonna take her
to Paris for her 13th birthday.
You want to come?
You are out of your mind.
I am not pregnant.
If only there was
some way to know for sure.
Wait. Wait.
I was out shopping,
and I saw these tests--
knock it off.
Just pee on a stick.
I'm busy.
You are stalling.
You like the idea.
Admit it. Admit it.
I am not gonna go away
until you admit that--
go!
See that?
That slight thickening
of the septal wall
and an elevated flow
across the l.V. Outflow tract.
Looks like
hypertrophic cardiomyopathy.
It's borderline.
Does that put Tyler
at risk for an arrhythmia?
Well, he may never have
a problem.
There are cases, rare,
but they happen,
when the most
seemingly healthy kid
could just die suddenly.
Is there any way to know?
Well, we could start
with an m.R.I., watch him
over the next few months.
In two days, it won't matter.
I mean, this kid has a chance
to change his life.
He can get a scholarship
to college.
I don't think
he can afford it otherwise.
But he has to compete
in the conference finals,
and given the circumstances--
well, I'm not saying
he can't wrestle.
You said he could drop dead
if he does.
Is there a chance? Yes.
But is it greater
than the chance he could get
into an automobile accident
on the way to the meet?
Given that his only symptoms
are a little dizziness,
probably not.
So you'd let him wrestle?
I mean, if his whole future
depends on it,
it's--it's a calculated risk.
Well, I mean,
you never take risks
with kids' lives, Sam, ever.
Well, that's not
the way it works.
You don't think I wanted
to lock Maya in the house
and not let her ride a bike
or drive a car or ski?
No, you can't do that.
You can't eliminate
all risk in life.
And given what you're telling me
this kid has at stake...
I don't understand.
Lorraine and Elliot have been
married for what, eight years?
You understand it.
You just don't like it.
Yeah. It's just--life isn't
a cheap romance novel, you know?
It's supposed to be about making
a commitment and honoring it.
Sometimes. And other times,
for other people,
it's about passion.
You think passion
is enough?
You don't?
To make an adult relationship
work, you need more.
Come on. You're talking
about claudine and Elliot
like they're
some insubstantial fling.
I mean, they're both grown-ups
who are taking a risk--
a huge risk--
because they found each other
and fell in love.
Just because a risk is big
doesn't make it worthwhile.
I feel for Lorraine.
Of course I do.
But on some level, I mean,
don't you think it's brave,
what Elliot and claudine
want to do?
Mm. Mnh-mnh. Stop looking
at me like that, Pete.
This is not about
Sam and me.
Of course it is.
Sam and I told Naomi
that we were in a relationship.
Okay.
Who's gonna tell Lorraine?
Okay, claudine.
You're in the very early stages
of labor.
You're just
3 centimeters dilated.
So you're
gonna be here a while.
I will call your regular
ob-gyn.
No, my o.B.'S gone all week.
And I don't know the woman
who's on call for her.
Can't you do it?
Okay, but--
and maybe you could
call Lorraine.
She's so excited.
No.
I think
that you should call Lorraine.
If you mean we should
tell her, I can't.
We can't. Not--not yet.
Don't you think that she
has a right to know?
You know I love Lorraine,
right?
And I'd do anything for her.
I mean, I am.
I'm doing this.
Ever since we were little,
Lorraine wanted to be a mom.
She just... she knew.
I never did.
Maybe it was too many
Princess movies growing up,
but me?
I only
wanted to fall in love.
Which is probably
why it never happened for me.
And then there was Elliot.
At first, he was just
my big sister's boyfriend,
who... I mostly resented
for taking her away from me.
But once my sister got sick
and we really
got to know each other,
something happened,
something... amazing.
And the more we tried
to hold back,
the harder it got,
until...
I love Lorraine,
Dr. Montgomery.
I do,
and I always will,
but now, especially since
I'm carrying Elliot's baby--
okay, stop, claudine.
All right?
Just think about that,
all right?
You're pregnant. Your hormones
are all over the place.
They can overwhelm you,
and--
no, that's not what it is.
I mean, I wish it was.
Believe me.
But... real love
can't be confused
with anything else.
Then tell your sister that.
I understand that
you can't choose
who you fall in love with.
But you can choose
to be honest.
I reviewed your scan
with a heart specialist,
and as much as I would like
for you to compete and to win,
- I can't let you take that risk.
- But I-I feel fine.
I can wrestle.
I have to wrestle.
It's just, Tyler has worked
so hard, and this is his dream.
We're talking about
a potentially
fatal problem here.
What are the odds
that something bad happens to
Tyler--10 to 1, 100 to 1, what?
I can't give you odds.
Then why should we listen
to you?
Look,
I know my own body.
I haven't been feeling dizzy.
I'm--I'm feeling great.
I can make weight.
You're way out of line here.
We're his parents,
and we say what he can
or can't do, not you.
Except that you need
my signature
on Tyler's
medical release form.
We'll get another doctor.
Randy.
I'm saying Tyler could die.
What about that
don't you understand?
I'm sorry, but finals aren't
gonna happen for you, Tyler.
Let's go. Now, Tyler.
Dr. Freedman.
Hey, Tyler.
Come in.
Is everything okay?
Nothing is okay.
Uh...
My mom got laid off
last year.
My dad is working double shifts
just to pay the rent.
I have a part-time job
on the weekends--
yeah, I understand. I do.
No, you don't.
Look, I'm the only one
in my family
with the opportunity
to go to college.
Without a scholarship,
I'm just gonna end up
doing the same thing
my parents are.
You don't know that.
Just like you don't know
something bad will happen to me
if I wrestle tomorrow.
I can't let you
take that risk.
But that's my decision.
Sometimes, when you are
so close to a situation...
You can't see it--
you can't see it clearly.
And I'm telling you--
stop. Just stop
telling me things
a-and just help me.
I think I am, even if it doesn't
seem like it to you.
You're not.
But i-i-th--i think I am,
okay?
You're not.
I made a cardiac m.R.I.
Appointment for you tomorrow,
and I left word
for your folks,
I expect to see you there.
It's the first step.
You're scared to take a risk.
I'm not.
But you are.
And that's why
you're doing this.
♪ I got a way of finding
all the wrong places to go ♪
♪ being everywhere
I ain't supposed to be ♪
Tell me
you're not drinking.
It's ginger ale.
It's a small
price to pay for a b-a-b-y.
Shh.
Hey, everybody, I want
to propose a toast
to our favorite new author.
Uh, here's hoping
that your book outsells mine.
And that someone very handsome
plays me
in the movie they make
from it.
Cheers.
Great. Thanks. Hey.
Hey, what'd I miss?
Not much.
You--will you excuse us
for just one minute?
♪ Whatever you don't want ♪
♪ Promise to give more ♪
All of your friends are here,
your book is coming out,
and you're sulking.
It's not right.
What if Marla thomkins
is right?
What if I am too familiar
with my patients?
I mean, their success is my--
my success, so, you know,
where are the boundaries?
I tell them things
about myself
in the hopes
that they'll open up,
but maybe I am doing it
to make myself feel better.
I mean, i--yes, I don't
sleep with them, but, you know,
seduction is, uh, it's
complicated, it's ethereal.
And I can be disarming
and charming.
You know, you've--you've always
said that therapy is a process
that can't be
cleanly deconstructed,
and that ultimately,
your patients get better,
and that's all that matters.
If that's the case,
then no reviewer,
shrink or not,
can criticize your methods.
Well--
Violet, this is your night.
You've earned this.
After everything
you've been through,
after all you've accomplished,
you've earned this.
Come on. Don't let
anyone ruin it for you.
♪ I'm your life ♪
My book launch
was half this size.
Hmm.
♪ Whatever you don't want ♪
Why don't you stop leering
and just head over there?
I was thinking about it,
but everybody's walking up,
talking to her,
and I hate crowds.
I thought
you were supposed to be
some kind of a lady slayer.
Usually I am.
Uh, I have a weakness
for tall blondes.
A-And did you notice
how she fills out those pearls?
Hi.
I'm Marla thomkins.
♪ I'm your life, yeah ♪
Oh, my god.
That's Marla thomkins.
Sheldon is talking
to Marla thomkins.
What's that face
he's making?
He's mad.
Oh, 'cause she's pointing
at him.
Oh, what a bitch. I bet he's
telling her off right now.
You gave that lecture
at u.C.L.A. Last month
on the psychology
of the male sex addict.
It was fascinating.
Well... thank you.
Your conclusions
were ridiculous, of course,
but I assume you were just
trying to be provocative.
Oh, an inveterate critic.
Oh, it's what I do.
Are you interested
in anything
but tearing apart
other people's ideas?
I'm interested
in all sorts of things.
♪ I can't be your friend,
my friend ♪
♪ no ♪
Hey.
Thanks for having my back.
Oh, of course.
Thanks, man.
You made her night.
Thank you.
Yeah, sure, sure.
♪ I'm just your life ♪
♪ yeah, I'm your life ♪
Hey.
You feeling any better?
Oh, I'm fine.
Addison, it's been two days.
You need to go home
and get better.
I can't.
I have to see how a patient's
labor is progressing.
What?
No, it's just, you--
you've been exhausted
and nauseous
and, no offense,
hormonal--
no, don't even say it,
Sam, okay?
'Cause we both... know that
that is not the case.
Okay.
Oh. I have to go.
You were up
and out early.
You know me--always trying
to grab life by the balls.
Thank you.
What are you working on?
Nothing.
Come on.
Graduate child psychology
courses. Really, Coop?
Exactly why
I don't tell you.
Get out.
Come on.
I'm not being critical.
Why is it so hard for you
to understand
that I may
want something more?
Well, aren't I enough?
Okay, I'm serious, Charlotte.
This is important to me.
Relax, Cooper.
I don't want to relax.
I just want you
to take me seriously.
If you can't do that,
leave me alone.
What's going on?
Late decels on the monitor.
What does that mean?
It hurts.
The baby is in distress.
I need to do a c-section now.
Why does it hurt so much?
Listen to me. Listen to me.
It's gonna be okay.
I'm gonna be right here
with you the whole time,
just like you've been for me.
Ah!
It's okay, baby.
It's okay.
Okay.
It's gonna be okay, baby.
Elliot?
E-Elliot, are--are you
and claudine--
I'm not sure
now is the time--
tell her we're sorry. Please.
Need to clear the field.
Dr. Montgomery,
her pressure's dropping.
Almost got her. Suction.
♪♪♪
♪ strong yet ♪
Okay.
There's a posterior tear.
0 vicryl and a ct-1.
Can't hold her b.P.
Something's wrong.
Yeah, you think?
She's still bleeding,
and I can't localize the source.
Suction.
Damn it. She lacerated
her uterine artery.
Betty, get over here and hold
pressure on the bleeder.
♪ ...deepest part ♪
Sorry I'm late.
Uh, this place is a maze.
Uh, this is Dr. Bennett.
I'm glad you came in.
Yeah, we talked about it
in the car
on the way home yesterday--
argued, really.
But what you said about Tyler's
life being in danger--
you're doing the right thing.
Where is Tyler?
Didn't Stacy bring him in?
She called me at work and told
me they were on their way.
Westside traffic?
No, I talked to her
over an hour ago.
♪ This time ♪
Finals?
Oh, god. They start
in ten minutes.
♪ Don't fight ♪
All I'm saying is,
you were harsh,
Violet's a friend,
and you hurt her feelings.
It's cute,
you're so protective of her.
Well,
I hate being called cute.
No man
likes to be called cute.
I could think
of worse things to call you.
What kind of therapist
specializes in insults?
The kind who spends her weekends
reading and reviewing
the endless stream of
self-indulgent pop psych books
that the not-busy-enough
members of our profession
continue to vomit up.
Then--
then why do you do it?
It gives me flexibility
to do other things.
In the last couple of years,
I've hiked machu picchu,
I taught a semester
at Oxford,
and studied
at the cordon bleu.
Oh, well,
I love to eat.
How can this you
be the same person
who wrote a review
that skewered my friend?
Look, Violet wrote
what she wrote.
I have an opinion about it.
It's not personal.
Yeah, but you're wrong
about her.
She has a pattern
of seductive manipulation.
She gets people
to do what she wants.
She strong-arms a male patient
into leaving his wife,
she allowed a schizophrenic
to stop taking her meds,
she told an agoraphobe
she was pregnant
before she told
either potential father.
Oh.
Oh, wait.
That was you, wasn't it?
♪♪♪
Oh.
Well, obviously I don't need
to argue my point
since clearly, you, too,
were seduced.
You're tough.
But fair.
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
And you like it,
don't you?
♪♪♪
How's the baby?
The baby's doing just fine.
But there was a complication
with your delivery.
Yeah, Elliot said that
there was some bleeding.
You had to do a c-section.
Your uterus ruptured
during labor,
and unfortunately, I couldn't
control the hemorrhaging.
I had to perform
an emergency hysterectomy.
Wait. That means that...
Claudine won't be able
to have any more children.
Um...
I didn't think...
I never thought
I wanted to be a mom, but...
But after I had
this baby--
Lorraine's baby.
It's not just Lorraine's baby.
It's my baby, too,
and claudine's--
it's her egg.
But you promised
your sister--
things are different now.
Claudine,
you're a surrogate.
Regardless of what's happening
between you and Elliot,
you promised Lorraine
a baby.
Can I really never have
a baby?
You know,
with all due respect,
if claudine and I want
to keep this baby,
you can't stop us.
Now I want to see my child.
♪ I'm catching my second wind ♪
♪♪♪
Coach. Coach Patterson,
I'm Cooper Freedman.
I'm Tyler's doctor.
Not--not right now.
Use your legs, Ty!
You need to stop
this match, coach.
No, no. His med consent form
was signed.
Reverse him, Ty!
Reverse him!
I didn't sign
a consent form.
What the hell did you do?
Stop the match.
Roll him, Ty!
You got him! Roll him, Ty!
You got him!
Hold on, Ty!
You got him, Ty.
♪♪♪
I guess I was wrong.
I mean, I almost took this
away from him,
from all of them.
No, you made the right call.
No matter what happened,
you made the right call.
Dr. Freedman!
Ty!
Ty. Ty, wake up, baby.
Ty.
- No pulse.
- What's happening?
It's a cardiac arrest.
Please. You have to save him.
Ty.
You take over?
Yeah, I got it.
Ty. Ty, baby.
Wake up, honey.
Wake up.
Ty.
Wake up. Ty!
Come on, buddy.
How is he?
We got his heart started.
Oh, thank god.
He was deprived of oxygen for
an extended period of time.
So we've had to put him
in a medically induced coma
to give his brain
a chance to recover.
So he's gonna be okay?
We don't know.
All we can do now is wait.
He came to me.
He told me how much
he wanted this...
Not just for him,
for us, too.
How could I say no to him?
All those
early morning workouts,
the weekends traveling
to meets,
everything Ty worked for,
that we worked for...
This was
his chance for something better.
Look at where we're at.
How is this better?
Blaming each other is not
gonna help Tyler. Um...
They won't let me hold
my baby, Dr. Wilder.
Why won't they
let me hold her?
There were complications
during the delivery,
and Dr. Montgomery had to
perform a hysterectomy.
Claudine won't be able
to have any more children.
Oh, my god.
Is claudine...
Claudine will be fine,
but...
She and Elliot
want to keep the baby.
♪ hold on to what makes sense ♪
No.
I--you're not alone here,
Lorraine.
Do you know how many times
I've imagined
what this day would be like--
a beautiful, healthy baby?
I've been carrying around
this--this onesie
to take her home in
and I've learned all the words
to "lullaby and goodnight,"
and... what am I
supposed to do now?
You're gonna
take a deep breath,
pull yourself together,
and you're gonna fight.
I'm scared, Dr. Wilder.
I've lost my husband,
my sister.
I have nothing left.
You need to dig deeper,
Lorraine...
For your daughter.
You wanted to be a mother,
and now you are one.
If you believe
that you can be a good parent
to that little girl,
then you will be,
but you need to believe it.
You need to be willing to do
anything to protect her,
because parenthood
is a fight.
You have to be willing
to get in it.
♪ Running in circles again ♪
♪ miss previously loved ♪
Can I date Marla thomkins?
That's the woman
that trashed Violet?
She's beautiful and smart,
and I want to date her.
Yeah, you can't do it.
You're right.
Is there any way--
nope.
You seem sure.
I'm not an expert
on many things, Sheldon.
That's become pretty clear
to me, but I know Violet.
And if you want to be
her friend, you can't do it.
♪♪♪
Thanks for bringing her.
You said you wanted
to see her.
So...
I brought her by
for a visit.
Oh.
She's incredible.
She is.
They won't let your sister
hold her.
Is Lorraine...
How is she?
How do you think she is?
♪ Put a smile
on your face ♪
I know how horrible
this looks.
♪ Hold on
to what makes sense ♪
But it doesn't change
how I feel.
If this were you
and you were in love
and there was this baby,
and you knew you could
never have another one...
What would you do?
♪ Miss previously loved ♪
I've done some things
that I'm not proud of.
I've chosen... myself
and paid the consequences.
But Lorraine is your sister,
and you made her a promise.
You wanted love,
and she wanted to be a mother,
and you said you'd help her,
but now you're--
oh.
♪♪♪
♪ time will pull through ♪
If you are asking me...
You can have Elliot
or you can have the baby,
but you can't have both.
♪♪♪
You were gonna leave
without talking to Lorraine?
What is there to say?
To start with,
I want my baby.
Lorraine...
This isn't your baby.
It takes more than an egg
and sperm and nine months
to make a mother, Claude.
You know that.
She's right, claudine.
You know what? You guys can't
come in here and bully us.
Okay, no one is trying
to bully anyone, Elliot.
Look, this is our baby.
And if we went to court--
You want to do that,
go to court?
Because I've done that,
and I'll tell you,
the person that loses the most
is the child.
Come on, claudine, we don't
have to listen to this.
Stop! Elliot, please.
Just... stop.
This baby...
Is not mine.
It's yours.
Claudine--
it's always...
Been your baby.
I could try to explain
how all this happened,
but... could you ever
forgive us?
I'd like to say yes, b--
but I'd be lying.
So that's it?
So we're...
We aren't family anymore?
You and me will never be
what we were.
But... now you have a chance
with her.
Be a good aunt.
You're gonna be
a great mother.
This came in the mail
this morning...
From u.C.L.A.
They had already decided
to take him
before the finals.
He didn't even
have to compete.
Full scholarship.
The first in our family.
My son
was going to college.
He could be okay.
I talked to Dr. Bennett.
There's a chance...
(Ry cuming's
"Always remember me" playing)
Well?
Addie?
♪ Two by two, lovers stand ♪
You're killing me.
♪ Santa Monica ♪
♪ Pretty eyes ♪
♪ long hair ♪
♪ smelled so sweet,
like summer in the air ♪
♪ watch me as I fall ♪
♪ to the water calling ♪
♪ Watch me as I sink ♪
Tyler hatcher almost died.
He might not wake up.
You did the best you could.
Yeah, and I still have
a 17 year old in a coma
at St. ambrose.
♪ Ooh ♪
If you want to believe
that's your failure,
then you are worse off
than I thought.
Cooper,
you are a great doctor.
I see it every day--
how hard
you work for your kids,
how much you care,
what you'll do for 'em,
even if everyone else is trying
to make it impossible.
Title before your name,
letters after your name, books--
that's...
That's all just commentary.
When it comes down to it,
what we all want to be
is doctors...
♪ Watch me as I fall ♪
Who help people.
Really, truly... help people.
♪ To the water calling ♪
No one...
No one, Cooper,
does that better than you.
♪ Into the sea and always ♪
♪ remember ♪
♪ Lovers stand ♪
♪ on the beach
in Santa Monica ♪
I was in the neighborhood.
♪ Pretty eyes, long hair ♪
♪ smelled so sweet
like summer in the air ♪
♪ watch me as I fall ♪
I do.
I want people to like me.
I need people to like me,
and I get them to...
Because I charm them,
knowing that
they're gonna need me.
And, you know, with patients,
with friends,
with everyone, Pete,
I don't do it for them.
I do it for me.
I do
emotionally seduce people.
Well, you didn't seduce me,
emotionally or otherwise.
I chose you.
Well, that's what
I led you to believe.
No, Violet. I--
look, listen--look...
♪ Ooh ♪
We both went into this
with our eyes wide open.
Now did we play games?
Yeah, maybe.
Well, not that much more
than any person
trying to figure out
if something can work.
And you know what? We work.
I know--
we work. Whatever you brought
to this relationship,
whatever I brought,
we have proven that we work.
I--Pete, I'm not talking
just about our relationship.
I'm talking about
as a therapist and as--
I don't care. I don't care
what Marla thomkins says
or anyone else.
You are a brave, honest,
amazing therapist
and wife and mother and--
stop talking.
♪ Watch me as I fall ♪
♪ to the water calling ♪
♪ watch me as I sink ♪
I'm not pregnant.
Yeah. You told me yesterday.
Yesterday I wasn't sure,
but I took a test,
♪ remember ♪
Now I'm sure.
Guess it was just
the flu.
I see.
And you're sad.
♪ Ooh ♪
And you're not.
We talked about this.
Yeah, you said that
you needed more time.
I said I'd give it to you,
but I didn't ask how much.
Three months? Six months?
A year?
Well, I-I can't quantify--
well,
then how will you know?
♪ ...calling ♪
I will know when I know.
♪ Into the sea and always ♪
I think maybe...
When people say
they need more time,
it means
they're not committed.
And that doesn't really
work for me anymore, Sam.
I've made up my mind.
I want a child.
So I need to know...
Are you in
or are you out?
♪ Me ♪