Knight F six.
Then you've got mate in three.
Well done.
I don't spend all day
playing games.
Sabeena,
there's a restaurant in my
neighborhood opening up.
You wanna
check it out?
I'd like that.
Michael, I can't have
my medical reps upselling
during a procedure.
I can't welcome him
back to my OR.
Would it be too much
to ask for you to back
me up just a little?
I'm thinking
about reconnecting
with my daughter.
There's a program
that helps parents
track down the children
they put up for adoption.
It's been over 20 years.
She may not want
to reconnect.
Oh, hey. Good morning.
Hey.
Somebody woke up
on the right side of the bed.
Somebody got a sitter
for tonight.
Oh.
And that means she's gonna
bring food to your house.
What do you wanna eat?
Oh, whatever you want.
It's all good with me.
You always say that.
I wanna know what you like.
I like Thai, Indian,
pizza, burgers. I like it all.
You know, we have
been dating now, for,
I don't know how long,
and I still know
so little about you.
You know I like
Thai, Indian...
Oh, get out of here.
...pizza, burgers...
Go away.
Then he looked
at me and said,
"You know so much
about endoscopy,
"why don't you just
rep the line yourself?"
So, you're gonna be
in charge
of a whole new series
of devices?
That's right. And I'm telling
you, Ma, they're awesome.
Increased success rates
on embolization,
sclerotherapy,
stent and valve placement.
Really gonna help
a lot of people.
Oh, that's fabulous, Michael.
Good for you.
Thank you. But to be honest,
I am on the clock.
Can't waste any more time
talking to you.
Well, have at it.
All right.
Hey, Maggie.
Hey, Sharon.
You okay?
Mmm-hmm.
It's here.
About my daughter.
Wow. You tracked her down.
What are you gonna do?
I'm not ready
to open it.
Well, if you need me,
call, okay?
I have to admit,
I thought I had you
when I took
your king's knight.
Which is why
I let you take it.
What?
I knew you were
about to play
the Mecking Variation.
Because it's subtle
but brilliant?
Because you always play
the Mecking Variation.
Oh, all right.
I'm gonna need
a rematch tonight.
See if I can come up
with some surprises.
I'll see. I have two more
trial patient exams
and a status
report due.
Oh, my God! Mom!
Get a gurney!
What happened?
She's been
having palpitations,
but she wouldn't let me
bring her in until today.
Okay. Hi, I'm a doctor, too.
Does your mom have
any cardiac conditions?
Not that I know of.
But she's pregnant.
All right. We're gonna
get you up to the ED
and check you out, okay?
Is there anyone
you'd like us to call?
Her husband?
No. Gary's passed.
Anyone else?
The baby's father?
No. The baby's mine,
and my husband's.
Yours?
My mother's
carrying our baby.
Hello again.
Where are we at?
Miss Daniels is a 22-week
pregnant surrogate
for her daughter.
And I am seeing signs
of atrial fibrillation.
Okay. Do you mind me asking
how old you are?
Fifty-four.
I know
that's pretty old
to carry a baby,
but when Katie asked me,
I just couldn't...
He's busy, Mom.
I'm sure he just wants you
to answer the questions.
Uh, so, has this ever
happened before?
No.
And any other medical history
we should know about?
Uh, I'm allergic to shellfish.
And I had
a kidney stone once...
She's an alcoholic.
I'm sorry, Mom, it's true.
Recovering alcoholic.
I haven't had a drink
in two years, six months.
Do you think
that's why this is happening?
My husband and I,
we knew there might be
medical issues.
We couldn't afford
a professional surrogate.
Okay. Let us do
a few tests,
and we'll figure out
exactly what's going on.
And in the meantime,
we'll try to get
your heart back into
a normal rhythm, okay?
Excuse us.
What do you think?
She's unstable.
We need to cardiovert.
Mags, order an echo and
100 milligrams of flecainide.
We'll see how she does
over the next hour.
Hold up.
All right.
If this is alcoholic
cardiomyopathy,
we may want to
do it electrically.
But we don't want to affect
the baby's rhythm.
Meds would be safer.
But less effective.
The longer this goes on,
the worse it could get.
So, what do you
want me to do?
Flecainide is standard
of care. We'll go with that.
What've we got?
I've got Arash Mehti,
shot in the leg.
Two of morphine
in the field, vitals stable.
Okay, Mr. Mehti,
I'm Dr. Marcel.
We're gonna take
good care of you, okay?
I don't want to be here.
Okay, we're just gonna take
a look at you, all right?
Let's get an X-ray in here.
Okay, here we go, guys.
On my count.
Nice and easy.
One, two, three.
No, please.
Whoa.
I can't afford this.
I'll go somewhere else.
Bring his head up.
Yep.
Okay. Listen to me,
Mr. Mehti, you need
to be in a hospital.
I don't want your leg moving
any more than it has to.
So, please stay calm.
Okay? Nice and still.
Let's move back.
Okay, Mr. Mehti,
looks like the bullet hit
one of your large vessels.
I need to operate in order
to stop the bleeding
and remove the bullet.
Is that okay?
Operate?
Yes.
No.
Dad, I don't
think you have a choice.
Mr. Mehti, your son's right.
You're still bleeding.
If we wait much longer,
you'll lose too much blood.
You will die.
Dad, just let him fix you.
Uh...
Please.
Mr. Mehti?
Fine.
Okay. Call the blood bank,
let OR know we're coming up.
You got it.
I'll see you soon. Okay?
Hi, Emily, I'm Dr. Manning.
What happened today?
I was on my way to the gym
and I got mugged.
Oh, my God.
I'm so sorry to hear that.
It's okay.
You mind if I just...
But he threw me pretty hard.
All right. Yeah,
it appears to be broken,
but I do want to do
an X-ray to confirm.
Thanks. And could she get
something for the pain?
She's trying
to be brave, but...
I'm sorry,
this is Brian, my husband.
Nice to meet you. And yes,
we can get you something.
Did you make
a police report?
No. The guy got away
so fast.
You should think
about filing one.
You'd be surprised
at how often
they find the suspect.
Nah, it's fine. I didn't even
get a good look at him.
Come on, Em.
If we're just
sitting here anyway,
we might as well.
My head hurts,
and it seems like such a pain.
Sweetie, the guy
broke your arm.
Okay.
Great. I'll send
someone in.
And in the meantime,
we will get you those meds.
Okay?
Mmm.
Hey.
Um, I have a patient in 3
who was just mugged,
and she seems like
she's in a little bit
of denial.
Would you mind talking
to her for a minute?
Just make sure
she's all right?
Not at all.
Thanks.
I've been
on hold for a while.
Where are you guys?
He's bleeding bad.
Can I help?
Are you a doctor?
No. I'm a nurse.
Good enough. Come on.
Sheet metal got his leg.
We tried to tie
a belt around it,
but it just keeps slipping.
Hey, my name is April.
I'm gonna try
to help you, okay?
Hey, April. I'm Russell.
Hey, Russell.
Just hang in there.
Thank you. All right. Hey.
Oh, that's too high
for a tourniquet.
You gotta press right here.
Yeah. And press
down hard. Harder.
Okay. What's in
that toolbox?
Hang on, Russell.
Okay, let me see.
Does that first aid kit
have any alcohol in it?
Yeah. Here you go.
All right.
This is gonna hurt,
okay? Get ready.
Okay.
I know, I know. Okay.
God!
Hang in there.
Press down harder.
Use all your weight, okay?
Can you hold his legs,
so, he doesn't kick?
Yeah.
I know, Russell.
I gotta clamp your artery.
Just keep pressing.
Yeah. Got it.
Ease up, slowly.
Is he gonna be okay?
I think so.
What do we got?
Russell Byrd, 26,
lacerated femoral artery
with significant blood loss.
BP 90/55,
heart rate 115.
Got a liter
of saline en route.
What? Were you
repiping his sink?
We were
at a construction site.
I had no choice.
Serrated teeth,
no less.
Ugh. The whole artery
wall's ground beef.
Okay, go get
yourself cleaned off.
No, it's okay. I got it.
Look, you've done enough.
Okay? Nancy?
Sorry.
And tell the OR to hang vanc
and gent when we get there.
And hopefully,
this guy's still got a leg
when he gets out.
So, I talked with
your patient, Miss Norris.
And there could be a little
residual shock there.
But I don't know, I just...
Something's not adding up.
You know, I can't escape
the feeling we're not
getting the whole story.
How so?
Hey, guys.
Station checked
all the cameras
in a three-block area.
Said they couldn't find
any footage of an attack.
Oh. Thanks.
Mmm.
OR's ready
to plate her arm.
Okay. Um, I just have
a couple of questions.
Um, so, you said
you were attacked
at 6:00 a.m.
Yeah?
Give or take, yeah.
And you were
on a sidewalk?
Not in an alley
or anywhere else?
Is there something wrong?
Because the cop asked
these same questions.
No, they're just having
a hard time finding video
of the incident. That's all.
See, I told ya,
this was a waste of time.
They just want to help.
I know. But I'm cold,
and hurt,
and I just want this
to be over with already.
Let's get her a blanket.
No, it's okay. Here.
We're gonna get you
through this
and go home. Okay?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hey. You want us
to dress those for you?
Oh. Uh, I'm fine.
Those look like
fingernail scratches, yeah?
Yeah, they did.
Maybe I need to
have a little chat
with Mr. Norris.
We never did get
that coffee this morning.
After an hour
of trial questionnaires,
I'm sure you could use it.
Miss Daniels
is still in a-fib.
Saw that.
I think we should switch
to electrocardioversion.
I'd rather stick to meds
and up the dose.
Okay if I observe?
I'm invested.
Yeah, of course.
Ethan, her heart rate's
only getting worse.
I really think we should
change course.
Okay.
All right, Miss Daniels,
we're putting a little
sedative into your IV,
so you should only
feel a small jolt.
And this won't
hurt the baby, right?
Mom, just let them
do their job.
Mary?
We'll be very careful.
Kate, please.
Okay, here we go.
Right here.
Charging to 50.
And one, two, three.
Nothing.
Miss Daniels, you okay?
Good. Fifty again.
And one, two, three.
It's not working.
Let's increase her meds.
No, let's go to 100.
And one, two, three.
She's in v-fib.
No pulse.
Charging to 200.
What's going on?
The current flipped her
into a more
serious arrhythmia.
We have to shock
her out of it.
Clear.
Oh, my God.
Still no pulse.
Push a milligram of epi!
Charging to 200 again.
Epi's in.
Clear.
Sinus rhythm.
Pulse is back.
Mary?
What happened?
Your, uh, heart issue
is still not under control.
And I'm sorry,
but at this point,
we have to be prepared
for this to happen again.
Get another 12-lead.
Call me
if anything changes.
Yeah.
All right.
Vessel's repaired,
clamp's coming off.
Just gotta grab that bullet,
and take this thing home.
Help me pull
the artery over.
It's over
as far as it'll go.
Huh. Try the other way.
Dr. Marcel?
I can't find the bullet.
It was right here
in the X-ray.
All right,
somebody check his bed,
make sure it didn't fall out.
On it.
You sure you read it right?
Leg film, easy to turn
upside-down.
No, Marty,
it wasn't upside-down.
The bullet's
not in here anywhere.
Bed's clean.
Okay. Did anybody
touch his leg
between the ED and here?
Because if it didn't
fall out, I don't know
where else it could be.
All right. Get me
an X-ray here, stat.
Move.
Yes, Doctor.
So, I heard
you're thinking of doing
an interposition graft?
What are you doing?
Scrubbing in. I spoke
with the charge nurse.
I got a team. Thanks.
I understand.
But I came in
with this patient,
and I'd like to
see it through.
April, I appreciate
your enthusiasm.
But you're an ED nurse.
I'm sure you could be of help
to someone down there.
Mr. Norris?
Hey.
There you are.
Will she have her phone
when she gets out
of surgery?
I like to send her
little messages.
Oh. What, from the watch?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's cool.
I had this thing for years.
I still haven't gotten around
to figuring that part out.
Yeah, absolutely.
We can make sure
she has it
when she wakes up.
So, look,
um, your wife gets attacked
on the street this morning.
What do you think
she does next?
Does she call you up?
Or does she just
walk home? Or...
She might've called.
I don't know.
Uh, truth is,
it would take a marching band
to wake me up in the morning.
Oh. Bit of a night owl?
No, I just can't seem
to get good sleep lately.
Why do you think,
you got stress at work,
or something?
No, I'm actually retired.
Really?
Yeah.
From what?
Army.
173rd Special Troops,
Afghanistan.
Oh.
Been back three months.
Wow. Huh. Afghanistan.
That... Was that rough?
Oh, it wasn't so bad.
Anyway, you're not
getting sleep. That's when
you have accidents, right?
How did you say
you did that again?
I don't know.
Uh, maybe yard work.
Hmm.
I have no idea.
Anyway, Emily should be
getting out soon.
Can I go wait for her
in Recovery?
Yeah. I'll totally
arrange that.
These things can also
help you figure out what's
going on with your sleep, too.
You know that?
Yeah.
I think Emily might
have put one of those apps
on here for me.
Oh.
Let's have a look.
Hey. So, get this.
Mr. Norris
is ex-military.
Just back from Afghanistan
three months ago.
And we all know how
complicated those transitions
back to civilian life can be.
But for what it's worth,
he's not throwing off
an abusive profile for me.
Take a look at this.
Those are
her medical records
from East Mercy.
She's been there twice
in the last month
for bruising
on her rib cage
and a bloody nose.
She's being abused.
Third time
she's coded in an hour.
The fetus is putting
too much strain
on her heart.
But we can't deliver,
she's only 22 weeks.
We have to stick
with the playbook and hope
the higher dose
of meds works.
Or we try
something else.
Now, what?
Tetracaine.
Are you kidding?
You give it
as an infusion,
block her sodium channels
and reset her rhythm.
That's only been tried
in a handful of cases.
There's no hard data.
Yes, it's cutting-edge,
but it could be a home run.
Or it could cause asystole
and kill her.
I understand,
but we can't keep
going like this.
Each shock we give her,
increases the chance
of fatal arrhythmia.
I want to protect
the fetus as well,
but our duty is
to our patient first.
Ethan...
You've already done
enough damage as it is.
We're sticking
with the meds.
I know.
I'm such a klutz.
One time, I tripped
at the gym and landed
on some weights.
And the other time,
I ran into a door.
Did Brian go to
the ED with you?
I didn't tell him.
I was embarrassed.
Huh. You guys, you seem
so close. I don't get why
you'd be embarrassed.
What is going on?
Look, Emily,
if there is anything
you want to tell us...
Wait, you're not
suggesting that he had
anything to do with this?
All three injuries
have happened since Brian's
been back from deployment.
Look, Brian is a good man.
He's a good man
who went through combat.
And as I'm sure you know,
people can...
They can come back
with issues.
It wasn't easy for him,
what he saw there.
But what matters now,
is that he's back
and we're together.
Okay. But no matter
what happened
to him over there,
it is not okay
if he's hurting you.
You don't know
what you're talking about.
Emily,
please, we're just...
I think that you should leave.
Look, I... Okay.
She's protecting him.
It's classic
battered woman syndrome.
You know, very possibly.
But I don't know,
something's still...
It's just not adding up.
All of these ER visits,
all these injuries
are taking place
very early in the morning.
Okay. So, they fight
in the morning.
But what if he's not
fighting her at all?
What if he's fighting with
something else and she just
happened to be there?
Nat, no wonder
he can't remember where
these scratches come from.
I think that this
might all be happening
when he's asleep.
How do you prove that?
I have an idea.
You lost a bullet?
We didn't lose it.
It's called
a bullet embolism.
It got pulled through
the hole in your vein
and traveled up to the liver.
It's lodged
inside the vessel there.
Look, Mr. Mehti,
this is not what we wanted,
but we're gonna get
this taken care of, okay?
However,
since you've already been
put to sleep today,
I do want to wait
two days before
opening you back up again.
Two days?
Yeah.
I'll give you guys
some space.
Hey, uh, Dr. Marcel?
Yeah?
Look, I'm sorry
about my father.
No, it's okay.
If it helps,
his anger is actually
directed at me.
Don't worry about it.
He gave up everything
to come to America.
To give me opportunities.
What do I do?
I insist on being
a musician.
He says I'll never
earn a living.
He hates my music.
His disappointment's
over a lot more
than a bullet.
I understand it.
And you don't have
to worry about my feelings.
Let's just get your
father fixed up. Okay?
Yeah.
All right.
Dr. Marcel?
Yeah.
I don't mean to butt in,
but I overheard you talking
and I think
there's a way you could
avoid another surgery.
How's that?
I've got this new
endoscopic device
to deploy artificial
heart valves.
It extends mechanical fingers
to release the valve.
You're thinking it
could work in reverse?
Exactly.
Just grab the bullet.
But it's not
approved for that.
This would have
to be off-label, right?
It would.
But if you're
trying to avoid
an open surgery...
Right.
It's actually
a pretty good idea.
All right, let's do it.
Maggie's just wondering
if you need someone
to cover for you.
Um, no, I'll be down
in a minute.
Hey, you okay?
What if I cost this man
his leg, or worse?
April, don't get
caught up in that.
I'm sure you did
everything possible.
How's she doing?
Still in and out of v-tach.
Ethan's giving her
the standard meds,
which maybe is for the best.
But you have something
better in mind.
Tetracaine.
It's risky
and may not even work,
but how do we sit here
with an ace up our sleeve
and not even try?
I'm with you.
When I practiced
medicine in India,
every time I looked
a patient in the eye,
knowing their life
was on the line,
I couldn't stop till I knew
I did everything I could.
Anyway,
easy for me to talk.
It's a medicine
that's unproven, but could
reset your rhythm for good.
Now, the problem is,
there's also a small chance
it could stop
your heart completely.
Oh, my.
I know.
And that's why I'm not
pushing you to do it.
But I'm not sure how many
more rounds of defibrillation
your heart can handle.
So, if this sounds
like something you want
to know more about...
If my heart stopped,
what would happen
to the baby?
It's too small, so,
it wouldn't be able
to live outside of you.
I see.
But if I don't make it,
is there a way to keep
the baby alive inside?
Ms. Daniels,
let's not go there yet.
No. I've read about this.
Some kind of machine
you hook me up to,
so the baby
can keep growing?
Yeah, we could.
But it's a complicated issue.
Maybe you wanna wait
for your daughter.
No.
This is my decision.
I was never there for Kate.
I was too drunk.
Her dad traveled for work,
so, she had to walk herself
to school,
find her own dinner,
put herself to bed.
And I know I can never
make up for that.
But now,
she wants a child
more than anything.
To finally
have a family.
And if this medicine
is my best chance
to give her that,
then I want it.
Mary.
This is a big decision.
You sure you don't
wanna take some time
to think about it?
Thank you, Maggie.
But I know my answer.
I'm not gonna let
my daughter down again.
Okay. I'll set it up.
Will? Will.
Shouldn't we wait
for Kate to be part
of this decision?
You heard her. Okay?
She's trying so hard
to make up for the past,
not being there
for her daughter.
Let's give her that chance.
Will. You talked her
into this infusion
behind my back?
I didn't talk her
into anything.
It's what she wants.
What is wrong with you?
You needed to
come to me first.
Hey, I tried. You're too
stuck on a treatment
that isn't working.
So, you're just
gonna risk her life?
No, I'm doing what both I
and our patient think is best.
Mom, this is crazy.
There's no way.
I've made my decision.
No. This is stupid
and reckless.
I have to do something.
Every time they shock me,
it puts the baby in danger.
I don't care.
Of course you care.
This baby means everything.
No, it doesn't.
Kate...
You've been waiting
for this forever.
Mom...
This baby doesn't mean
as much as you do.
Ms. Daniels,
you're starting to
throw irregular beats.
What do you want us to do?
Please, let me do this.
Mom, no.
I love you, sweetheart.
I'm ready.
Start the infusion.
How is he?
There was enough artery
left to repair,
and he's perfusing well,
so, I think
he's gonna be fine.
Thank God.
Hey, April.
He lost a lot more blood
out there than I realized.
So, you didn't just
save his leg.
You saved his life.
Pretty good for a nurse.
You should've gone
to med school.
Is there a reason
why we're still here?
The orthopedist said she's
medically cleared to leave.
Yes, but we would like
to speak with you first.
Brian, I think that
you are suffering
from a form of PTSD.
What?
Okay, this is enough.
He's not even
the patient here.
Please, just bear with us
for a moment.
I think that you're
experiencing something
called "PTSD nightmares."
Now, the word "nightmares"
is misleading.
They're actually much more
like sleep terrors.
The difference being,
people often
don't remember them.
But your body
still very much
experiences them.
To the point that
on certain nights,
the intensity leads you
to literally act them out,
physically.
In this case, on Emily.
No.
She has been
to the hospital for injuries
twice before today.
What?
It's nothing. It's fine.
Please, we're just
trying to get him
the help that he needs.
No, You're trying to report
this as domestic abuse
and get
the police involved.
Listen, we are legally
obligated to report this.
But I guarantee you,
because of the specifics
of this case,
that Brian, he's not
gonna be prosecuted.
He'd still end up
with it on his record.
And then what?
A mental health diagnosis?
These things
follow you your whole life.
Em, maybe we should
talk about this.
No.
The Army, the hospital...
They won't protect you.
I am the only one
who will protect you.
Okay.
Emily, Brian and I
were discussing his sleep.
Do you mind
bringing up that app again?
Yeah.
The watch tracks
his sleep patterns.
Most people have
a sleep efficiency
of around 85%.
That means a lot
of deep sleep.
Very little movement. Okay?
As you can see,
Brian's sleep efficiency,
it averages around 50%.
And on the days that
you went to the hospital,
it was down to 10%.
So, what?
You see right here,
early in the morning?
All that movement?
Those are night terrors.
Emily, did I do this?
No.
Emily,
you came in here today
with a broken arm.
Next time,
it could be far worse.
Em, tell me the truth.
Brian...
Have I hurt you?
Honey, please,
I couldn't live
with myself.
You didn't mean to.
Oh, my God.
I'm so sorry.
I know. I know.
No. It's okay.
It's not your fault.
We can help you.
I'll do whatever
it takes.
Starting infusion.
Her rhythm's erratic.
It's not gonna
hold for long.
Are you okay, Mom?
BP is falling.
She's having runs of v-tach.
We need to cardiovert.
No.
The baby...
Ma'am...
Give the medicine
a chance.
Your pressure's
dangerously low.
Mary?
Mom?
Come on,
let them do it!
Let's give it a minute.
Ms. Daniels,
we're running out of time.
Ms. Daniels?
Mom?
Don't let her die!
She's in v-tach.
Charging 200.
Ethan.
Charge, clear.
Mags, clear.
Mags.
Clear!
Maggie.
Sinus rhythm.
It worked.
Thank you.
This is where
we deployed the device.
But as you can see,
when we tried to
grasp the bullet,
it slipped away.
Which dislodged it
from the vessel wall
and into the current.
Yeah, we tried to go
after it again, but the
blood flow was too strong.
It got swept away.
Swept away?
So, where is it now?
It's in the right atrium
of the heart.
They're finishing up
the echo now.
Using a device off-label?
What were you thinking?
I was trying to avoid
another open surgery.
Look, while the outcome
wasn't ideal,
the bullet is safe.
So, we'll go in tomorrow,
same as we would have done.
Promoting your products
for unapproved uses?
It made sense.
It could have worked.
Ms. Goodwin,
I'm the surgeon of record.
It's not his fault.
This is far beyond
the bounds of
professional conduct.
Dr. Marcel?
Yeah.
You need to see this.
Excuse me.
What is it?
He's got
a ventricular-septal defect.
A hole between
the two sides of his heart.
Didn't you know
about this?
No. Nobody did.
Wasn't in his history.
What does that mean
for the patient?
If the bullet
passes through it
from the right side
into the left,
it could shoot up
into his brain and cause
a massive stroke.
Gotta get him
into the OR, now.
How's it looking?
Got some
high line pressures.
He's getting coagulogenic.
Better move it along.
Yeah,
right side's empty.
Bullet must've passed
through the defect
after X-ray.
Let's open up the left.
Hang on.
Sats are down to 92.
What's going on?
Oxygenator line
is clotted off.
Giving heparin.
Let's get out of here.
Nope, not yet.
Eighty-four.
If it's not there,
we have to go.
he's got bigger problems
than his sats.
Shut it off.
We're down to 79.
Shut it off!
Come on.
Dr. Marcel...
Hold on.
One last place.
Under the valve.
There you are.
There it is.
Yes!
All right,
let's close him up.
5-0 Prolene.
Is that the baby's heart?
Yes, it is.
It looks very strong
and healthy.
It's beautiful.
I have already talked
to the state's attorney,
and he assured me
that not only will Brian
not face any charges,
he won't even
have a record. Okay?
And as for the arrest,
I'm sorry.
It's just pro forma.
And the psychiatric facility
they're sending him to,
for how long?
It's hard to say.
Maybe a couple weeks,
a few months.
You know, there are some
cutting-edge new therapies
involving medications
like MDMA, ketamine,
that could shrink
that time considerably.
And then he'll be
my Brian again?
I think
there's an excellent chance
of that, really. I do.
I love you, Em.
I love you.
Going behind my back,
throwing up Hail Marys.
We got the win today,
but you and I
have a problem.
Hi. Mr. Mehti,
how are you feeling?
He's doing well.
But he has something
he wants to tell you.
Okay.
Doctor.
Yeah.
I want to apologize
and thank you.
It's okay.
Thank you, Doctor.
My pleasure.
I'll check on you
in a bit, okay?
Okay.
I don't know
what you said,
but whatever it was,
it seemed to make him
feel better.
Yeah.
Yeah, I told him
he had a good kid,
he should give him a chance.
Hey, you ready?
Mmm-hmm.
Mmm. You need
to order every time because
this rice is amazing.
So good.
Mmm-hmm.
So, annoyingly enough,
properly cooked, it's rice.
Mmm-hmm.
And you burn it,
get it crispy
at the bottom...
Tahdig.
Yeah. Look at you.
Mmm. Good to know.
Yeah.
Um, so...
Your name,
Crockett Marcel...
Mmm-hmm.
...doesn't sound very Persian.
Yeah.
My birth name is Darioush.
Darioush Jahanbani.
Darioush.
My parents
changed me and my sister's
names to make it easier
on us in school.
Yeah, they picked Marcel
'cause it was popular
in New Orleans.
Hmm. And "Crockett"?
Where does that come from?
My pops was a big fan
of Miami Vice.
Sonny Crockett.
Oh.
True story.
Mmm-hmm.
You want some more tahdig?
Ah. Yes, please.
Absolutely.
Yum. Thank you.
You're welcome.