Hey! Get off of her!
Punk bitch.
They were jumping me in.
Gang initiation.
What if you found
somewhere else to stay?
Thank you.
Is this what I think it is?
Fertility chart.
Just seeing
the chart is like...
You can get
a little overzealous.
Okay, my lips
are still tingling.
I'm Ben.
Maggie.
You know, I should
probably eat
an actual lunch after this.
I don't like to eat alone.
This is Ben, my date.
What're you
doing here?
Hey.
A patient told me
about a peppermint
and ginger aromatherapy,
it's supposed to help
with the nausea.
Oh, thank you.
I'm sorry you're having such
a hard time with the chemo.
I'd say it's been a bit more
tolerable now that
I have my sidekick.
So, you're the one who's been
stealing my lunch companion?
Guilty as charged. I'm Ben.
Natalie. Nice to...
Ben?
You all right?
I'm okay, I'm okay.
You look flushed. Maybe you're
coming down with something.
They got me on
a new chemo regimen.
I'm always coming
down with something.
You know, why don't you
pop into the ED
once you're done here?
I'll just give you
a quick exam.
Thanks, but I'm fine, really.
Don't be stubborn.
I'll make sure he gets there.
All right. See you soon.
Thanks, Nat.
Dr. Sexton.
Wait for me outside.
Hey, Dr. Marcel.
Our distended belly
in Two is non-surgical.
Sign her over to GI.
Yeah. You know, I hate to ask,
but you mind putting
in the order?
I just... I gotta run
a quick errand.
Oh, is she your errand?
Looks familiar.
Wasn't she here
a few weeks ago
with those gang guys?
Uh, she's not
with them anymore.
It's true. She's turning
her life around.
Oh. Is that why she's wearing
your Blackhawks jacket?
Please tell me that she's not
shacking up with you.
No. No, no, no.
It's not what
you think. It's, um...
She's crashing
in my guest room
for a couple of days
just until she can
get back on her feet.
If you say so.
Okay. I'll be right back.
I'm just gonna take her home.
Would you do me a solid
and just keep this
between us?
I don't want April to...
Kick your ass, maybe?
Yeah.
Measles?
Nat, are you sure?
The lesions in your mouth,
the elevated fever,
the conjunctivitis,
these are all
very strong indicators.
I don't understand.
I was vaccinated as a kid.
You've also been on chemo
for six months now.
It's likely wiped out
your vaccine antibodies
and left your immune system
too weak to protect itself.
So, do I need to suspend chemo
while we treat this?
I'd like to speak
with your oncologist.
But my guess is yes.
Will I be okay? I mean, people
get over measles all the time.
Yes, they do. I mean,
we can manage this, right?
Put him on bedrest,
make sure he doesn't develop
any secondary infections.
Ideally, yes.
But?
I did hear congestion
in your lungs.
Which means that, most likely,
you've already
developed pneumonia.
So, what happens next?
With your weakened
immune system,
I'm afraid it's only
a matter of time
before the virus starts
attacking your other organs.
Wait, are you saying
this is gonna kill me?
Measles are gonna kill me?
I'm so sorry, Ben.
Nat, there has
to be something...
How long am I looking at?
Months?
Weeks?
Days?
If what I suspect is true,
I'm afraid so.
Morning, Daniel.
Morning.
I haven't seen CeCe
in a couple of days,
how's she doing?
You know, not too thrilled
that I keep on leaving
my dishes in the sink
but other than that,
hanging in there.
You think she'd be up
for a drink tonight?
Just the four of us?
The four of us?
Yeah.
Turns out, Bert and I
met a few times.
Just for a couple of drinks,
don't get too excited.
He still has a lot
of explaining to do.
Okay.
And I just figured that maybe
CeCe would get a kick out
of all of us getting together.
Are you kidding me?
She'd love it.
I'm just warning you,
you're gonna get
a big "I told you so."
Yeah, well. I'm looking
forward to that.
And that one.
Mmm.
Oh, and it's Trini's
first day at Med,
I was supposed to get her
oriented, but...
Don't worry,
I can answer
all her questions.
Okay.
Hey, I'm April.
Nice to meet you.
We got a nose bleed
in Treatment Five,
why don't you start there?
Thanks.
I'm good.
Maggie, go be with Ben.
Thank you.
Hey. Have you seen my brother?
I thought he was
on your service today.
He stepped out.
Where?
Said something
about an errand.
I got him covered.
Hey, listen, about
the other night
that move on my part...
Let's just
forget it,
okay? It's...
April...
Look, we were
sippin' Sazeracs,
having a nice time,
I guess I misread
the situation.
Yeah, just...
Let's blame it
on the Sazeracs.
Dr. Halstead, we got
an ambo landing,
you're going
to Trauma One.
Elsa, you're with me.
Lori Shelton, 16 years old,
BP 118 over 82,
heart rate 112,
collapsed on a jog
this morning.
We told her not to push it,
but she just won't listen.
Dad, I'm fine. I skipped
breakfast before my run.
That's why I was dizzy.
Lori, I'm Dr. Halstead,
this is Student Doctor Curry.
Try to relax, we're gonna
get you checked out.
On my count. One, two, three.
Please tell me
her kidney is okay.
Kidney?
She had nephrotic syndrome,
finally got a transplant
about six weeks ago.
Congratulations.
Is it okay if I take a look
at your incision site?
Incision looks good.
No edema
in the lower extremities.
Great.
Lori, you had any fever,
night sweats, chills
over the past few days?
No. Since I got the kidney,
I feel great.
Okay. I did hear
a little congestion.
Honey, tell them
about your cough.
Dad, I'm fine.
Well, it is possible
you developed an infection
in your lungs.
An infection?
Yeah, it's a common
post-op complication.
Curry, what do you think?
We should probably start
with a CBC,
BMP, chest X-ray,
and give 500 milligrams
empiric azithromycin.
And a full transplant panel,
make sure her kidney's okay.
Lori, you just try
to take it easy,
we'll be back
to check on you in a bit.
Hey. Good morning,
I'm Dr. Choi.
You must be Dennis.
Yeah, the one and only.
And this is my girlfriend
and partner, Aviva.
Say hi to Dr. Choi,
you guys.
Excuse me?
You're live in front
of 800,000 people, huh?
Say hello!
Uh, mind if we do this
without the camera?
Sorry, Doc, but we keep
our stream live 24/7.
Hey, I don't really
think this is the place.
Oh, anything you need
to say to me,
you can say in front of
our loyal followers.
All right. Mind taking a seat
so I can examine you?
Well, I don't know,
can I take a seat?
I'm not following.
Not you, Dr. Choi,
he's talking to our followers.
They're voting.
Sorry, dude, they voted no.
Looks like I'll be
standing, Dr. Choi.
You're not serious?
It... It's in the name.
UrTheJudge.com.
Our followers vote
on all of Dennis' decisions.
Look. If you won't
let me treat you properly,
you should see
another doctor.
Oh, I don't mean
any disrespect, Doc. Oh.
It's just that,
I make my living
honoring the vote.
Please don't send me back
to the waiting room,
my stomach is killing me.
Abdominal pain?
It's definitely
food poisoning.
They made me eat a ton
of discount sushi last night.
Ow! Easy, man.
You're warm
and your belly's
obviously tender.
I'd like to get a CT scan
to rule out anything serious.
I'll be back to check
on you soon.
Wait, Doc. They're voting.
Okay, good. Yes.
It's a yes to that scan.
Hey. What are you doing?
Oh, April's
covering for me.
You can't go in there.
You're immunocompromised.
A little credit, Nat.
I know how to take
the necessary precautions.
If you catch this virus,
you might not be
able to fight it off.
I'm willing to
take that risk.
Maggie.
Nat, I'm not about to
abandon him now.
Hey, Doris? Can you get
the leg fracture
in Trauma Two
admitted to Ortho?
Help! We need some help!
Hey. Give me a hand over here!
Noah? Oh, my God!
Noah?
What?
What happened?
Don't know.
I found him
on the sidewalk like this.
Get him to Baghdad.
I got C-Spine.
Let's roll!
Easy, easy. Easy.
All right.
On my count, everybody ready?
One, two, three.
Noah, I'm right here.
Come on, come on.
Okay? I'm right here.
Hang in there.
Set up for an X-ray!
Hey, let's get him
on the monitors. Noah?
Hey buddy, do you know
where you are?
Me... Med?
Good, Noah, that's good.
Breath sounds
present bilaterally.
Multiple abrasions
on his face, neck, left flank,
some broken ribs.
Did he get hit by a car?
No. Injuries like this,
looks more like a beating.
Did anyone see
where he was going?
He just said he was
meeting a friend.
I thought you said
he was running an errand.
BP's down to 92.
Hang a unit of O negative.
X-rays. Everybody, clear!
Massive hemopneumothorax
on the left side.
We need a chest tube.
Push five of morphine.
Chest tube. Give it to me!
BP's down to 70.
I'm in.
Pressure's better,
but his heart rate's still up.
He's still losing blood.
Call CT,
tell them we're bringing
him up to do
a pan-scan now.
Don't worry, buddy.
We got you.
April, how is he?
Stable for now.
Still trying to find
the source of the bleed.
Can I have a word with you
and Dr. Choi, please?
I want Dr. Lanik
running point on this.
Miss Goodwin...
You know as well as I do,
you're too close
to Dr. Sexton.
I can separate
my personal feelings
from him...
No.
Dr. Lanik will keep
you updated.
And you're needed in the ED.
Yes, ma'am.
I'll check back
as soon as I can, okay?
Hey, we get the scans yet?
No.
Hey. What were
you saying earlier?
About Noah meeting a friend?
Just said he had to
help someone.
Who?
Scans are up.
He's got a grade III
splenic laceration
with a central blush,
he's bleeding
into his abdomen.
I'll call the OR, tell them
we're bringing him up.
No, pressure's stable.
No reason why we can't
embolize the bleed.
But if the
pressure drops...
Well, we can worry about that
when the time comes.
IR is less invasive.
I agree with Dr. Lanik.
I don't want to cut
my brother open
unless it's
absolutely necessary.
It's not really your call.
No. It's mine.
We're going to IR.
Let's move.
I just checked
on Lori Shelton's blood work,
uh, the lab should
have it up soon.
Great. Thanks.
Yeah.
Did you know that Fibonacci
is performing tonight?
The mathematician?
Hasn't he been dead
for about a thousand years?
Uh... It's a...
It's a rock band.
They write all of their songs
using Fibonacci's sequence,
so, every note
is the sum total
of the two notes before it.
And their music
is actually quite elegant.
That sounds interesting.
There are still
tickets available...
If you're asking if you can
take off early, go ahead.
Oh, okay. Okay,
thank you. Thanks.
Help!
We need help in here!
It's okay, baby. It's...
Watch out, Dad.
My stomach. It hurts so bad.
Ultrasound.
I got it.
What is it?
What's wrong?
We're gonna
find out.
There's a clot blocking
blood flow out of the kidney,
that's likely what made her
collapse this morning.
I thought it was an infection.
Kidney dysfunction can mimic
signs of an infection.
So, what do we do?
There's a drug called tPA
that should break up the clot,
but we'll need a CT first
to pinpoint its location.
Tell radiology
we're bringing her up.
No, wait.
You cannot give her a CT scan,
she's allergic
to the contrast.
You're sure she's allergic?
She had a CT scan
before her transplant
and had a really
bad reaction.
It almost killed her.
The transplant center
must have not put
that in her chart.
You have the ultrasound,
can't you use that
to locate the clot?
Ultrasound doesn't
give us it detailed enough.
We can't inject the medication
without a precise location
on CT.
Please, make it stop.
Isn't there something
else you can do?
We could try to get
a CT by using
a high dose of steroids
to suppress her allergy.
Yeah, but she could go
into anaphylactic shock.
No. I'm not putting her
through that again.
Do we have
an alternative?
All right.
We'll put her on heparin,
wait to see if the clot
resolves on its own.
At this point,
it's our best option.
Bolus 1,000 units of heparin,
50 mics of fentanyl
for the pain
and repeat her labs.
Lori, hang in there,
we're gonna get you
through this.
Hey. Your scans came back.
Turns out you
didn't have food poisoning,
you have an appendicitis.
I told you guys
this pain was real!
Luckily, we caught it in time.
We can get you up
to an operating room
to remove it before it bursts.
@Mew-buddar is asking,
is there an alternative
to surgery?
In some cases,
it can be managed
with antibiotics,
but surgery is the standard.
Babe, the chat is all
worked up over the pros
and cons of surgery.
Give me the camera.
All right team,
this is a big one,
so, don't do me dirty,
'cause my side
is literally killing me.
Will you let me have surgery?
This is no way
to determine treatment.
You heard him, peeps.
I'm setting up a vote.
Surgery versus
antibiotics. Go!
This is ridiculous.
Votes are tallying...
Okay, the votes are in...
Oh, babe, uh,
surgery's a no-go.
It's a serious
medical decision.
You can't let strangers
on the Internet
make it for you.
If your appendix ruptures,
there's a good chance
you'll die.
I'm sorry,
the decision's been made.
We're going with
the antibiotics.
Doris, order
one gram ceftriaxone
and 500 milligrams Flagyl
for my patient in Four,
and page Dr. Charles.
Maggie, I'm sorry
to hear about Ben.
Thanks, Sharon.
He just wants to go home.
I'm afraid that's not
gonna be possible.
What do you mean?
We need to keep Ben here,
under quarantine.
Why? Hospital protocol
is if a patient has measles,
that they can self-quarantine
as long as they don't take
public transportation.
Yes. Under
normal circumstances.
But there's
a citywide outbreak.
The county health officer has
issued a mandatory quarantine
for all hospitalized patients.
Ben will have to
remain here until he's
no longer contagious.
That's five days.
That could be
all the time he has left.
I'm sorry.
Sharon?
Yes.
Please,
he just wants to go home,
and die in his own bed.
Maggie, you know,
I understand,
but my hands are tied.
It's the law.
How you doing?
I'm Dr. Charles.
Dr. Choi showed me
your website, it's pretty...
Pretty interesting stuff.
His name tag legit says,
"Chief of Psychiatry."
I'm gonna get thrown
in the loony bin
if y'all keep
punking me with these votes.
Dude, we're getting mad love
in the tip jar today.
Definitely gonna top
naked skydiving.
So, Dr. Choi and I just wanna
make sure you understand
that by opting out
of the surgery, that you are
putting your life in danger.
We never go against the vote.
Those are the rules.
No chance of even
a one-time exception?
No can do.
A year ago, we were
living in our car.
Now, we've got
a condo on the lake.
Our followers buy
our merchandise
and watch our ads
for one simple reason,
I always obey the vote.
As soon as I break
that pact, it's over.
Okay. Well, really nice
to meet you both.
So?
He clearly understands
the decision he's making.
Yeah. But he's not
making the decision.
True, but, he's willingly
allowing other people
to do that for him.
He's denying surgery
to boost his online following,
how can we say he doesn't
pose a risk to himself?
Well, just 'cause
he's reckless, doesn't mean
he's suicidal. You know?
So that's it, hmm?
If the antibiotics don't take,
we just watch him die?
Ethan, I don't
like it either.
But we can't lock
a patient up
just because he wants
to be Internet famous.
We spoke to a few
witnesses who were
at the scene
and they confirm
Noah was jumped.
By who?
They weren't able to ID
any suspects except that
they looked Latino.
The guy that
brought Noah in,
he said that there was
a young woman with him.
She helped Noah
into the car.
That friend he was meeting,
could it have been
this young woman?
Dr. Marcel, if there's
something that can help us...
I did see him leave
with a young woman.
What?
The one that you
and Noah found,
getting jumped in
by that gang.
Said he was taking her home.
You saw him leave with Jacinta
and you didn't tell me?
Do you have a last name
for this Jacinta?
Uh, yes. Nieves.
Jacinta Nieves.
Okay, we'll run
with that.
Listen, we're all thinking
about your brother.
Thank you, Jay.
You didn't think
it was important to tell me
that my brother ran off
with some kind of gangbanger?
He asked me not to.
He is fighting
for his life.
He's a big boy, April.
He makes his own decisions.
I was told to get
a quick blood draw.
Just leave it.
I'll do it.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
Okay, okay. Okay.
You're okay.
Do you want some water?
Yeah.
There you go.
Okay.
I had finally fallen asleep.
Yeah.
And the hospital can't do
anything for you,
and here you are,
getting poked and prodded
every other minute.
I should never have
brought you here.
Mmm-mmm.
I'm so sorry.
The folks at group
say surrendering...
Isn't weakness.
It just means that you've
accepted your future...
As it comes.
No, Ben.
I won't let you spend any more
of your precious time here.
Do you have any idea
what you're asking me?
I know that it's
technically illegal...
And unethical to have me
change his charts and say
he's post-infectious...
Yeah, but you
and I both know
that I can keep
one measles patient
from infecting the public.
Please, Nat, I...
Please, let me honor
the only wish he has left.
How many times
have I had your back?
This is not about
what I owe you.
This is about what
we owe the public.
And I am sorry, Maggie,
but I can't discharge him.
Maggie, I...
We just got Lori's
latest set of labs back.
Her creatinine
has risen dramatically.
What does that mean?
The heparin isn't working.
Lori, I'm sorry, your kidney
is in serious distress.
No.
Since we're unable
to get the CT needed
to inject the tPA,
I'm afraid there's not
much more we can do
to save your kidney.
Oh, God...
There's still dialysis
and you can go back
on the transplant list...
No, I can't
go through
that again.
Please, there has
to be another way.
I wish there was, but...
What about the thing
you were saying earlier?
About suppressing my allergy?
Well, there
is a chance
we could prevent
an allergic reaction
to the CT contrast
by loading you up
with a high enough
dose of steroids.
That would be
extremely risky.
I wanna do it.
You could... You could go
into anaphylactic shock.
I spent too much time
on the transplant list.
The pain, and the fever,
and the sleepless nights.
I can't go through that again.
But honey...
I can't go back on dialysis.
Lori, I would need
your parents' consent.
Please, I... I can't lose
this kidney.
Lori.
Okay.
Dad?
You have our consent.
All right.
Hey. You can't do this.
She could die in the scanner.
Elsa, I understand the risk,
but we have to try.
Why? I mean, even if
she loses her kidney,
she can still
survive on dialysis until
a new organ is available.
She could also spend years
suffering on dialysis
and still die before getting
another transplant.
This is what Lori wants,
we have parental consent.
Heart rate's up to 140.
When was the last time
he had pain meds?
Two, maybe
three minutes ago.
We need to get him
to the OR now.
He's gonna crash.
What are you talking about?
His vitals are stable.
Not for long.
Pulse pressure's narrowing,
heart rate's climbing
and his lips are turning blue.
I've seen this before.
Means a crash is coming.
No. We almost have
control of the bleed.
If we wait until
his pressure drops,
it'll be too late.
It's Dr. Lanik's call.
Dr. Marcel!
We gotta stop this.
I'm almost there.
Dr. Marcel, you need
to back off.
He needs the OR!
Stay away
from my brother.
Pressure's falling!
Now can we move him?
Let's get him
ready for the OR!
Doris, what's the word
on Noah.
They just rushed him
to the OR.
It's touch and go.
Dr. Choi, I need some help!
What's happening to him?
Ultrasound?
Give him
some room, Aviva.
Breathe in
and out, buddy.
In through the nose,
out through the mouth.
All right. Your appendix
has nearly perforated.
We need to get you
into surgery now.
Babe?
It won't take long
until your
appendix bursts.
No, no.
When that happens,
it may be too late
to save you.
Group chat's saying
you should put him
on a medicine called Cialis?
They have no idea
what they're talking about!
Dennis, what do you say
we give the surgery a shot?
Live to fight another day?
Babe! We just hit
a million followers!
We're going viral!
Oh, my God. We did it!
Dennis, think this through.
Babe, our ad revenue
is going to double.
The antibiotics could
still work, right?
It's highly unlikely.
But is it possible?
Technically, yes, but the odds
are highly against it.
Then we're still going
with the vote.
Show me some love, people.
Buy our merch
and smash that subscribe
button below!
Get him up to two grams
of ceftriaxone.
Still think
this guy is sane?
All right, Lori, we're gonna
give you the injection
of steroids
before we administer
the CT contrast, okay?
I'm ready.
All right.
And now the contrast.
All good?
Great. Let's get her
into the scanner.
Hey, Mags.
Oh, hey, Eddy.
Dr. Manning's order didn't
mention this was a transfer.
Oh, it's not.
We're taking him home.
Hospice care.
Oh, the discharge.
Yes.
Dr. Manning's signature.
All right.
Let's load him up.
Yeah.
Are you sure about this?
It's time to get you home.
There we go.
Sats are dropping.
We close?
Doing the best I can.
We have to get her
out of there!
No, she can tolerate it.
Sats are down to 87.
How much longer?
I just need another minute.
She doesn't have
another minute.
All right, we need to
get in there.
All right, Lori,
just relax. Okay?
I gotta intubate.
Twenty etomidate, 100 of sux.
Okay, Lori.
Sats are down to 72.
Damn it.
Airway's totally
clamped down.
I might have to trach her.
Sats are down to 70.
Wait. I'm in. Bag her.
Let's move her back through.
Gurney!
Sats are climbing.
What about the scan?
We got it.
All right, let's get her
to IR now, and clear
the obstruction.
Give me
another lap pad.
There must be
two liters in there.
Why'd you wait
so long to bring him up?
Great question.
Curved six.
Pressure's in the toilet.
Please tell me this isn't
gonna take long.
Clamp's on.
Spleen's coming out.
I need an O silk tie
on a pass.
BP's down to 100.
Okay, tying off
the vessel now.
Clamp's coming off.
There, that should do it.
Pressure's dropping.
He's still losing blood,
we have to find the source.
Aviva, I was hoping
to get just a quick word.
One sec.
Our suppliers can't keep up
with our merchandise orders.
Wow.
Gotta say, very impressive
what the two of you
have created here.
Yeah, no joke.
Yeah. It'd be such
a shame to lose it all.
I just mean, you know,
if something happened
to Dennis,
I gotta imagine that's
gonna impact your livelihood.
It's not just about
the money, Dr. Charles.
You don't understand.
In high school,
Dennis was a ghost.
Nobody knew
he was there.
Hmm.
But when I got to know him,
I realized just how
incredible he was.
So, I convinced him
to start live streaming.
Now the world
gets to see what I see.
That's what this is about.
But what happens when he goes
into septic shock, though?
We'll ask our followers
for another vote.
They'll let him do
the surgery for sure.
Yeah, but what if they don't?
They're not trolls,
they're our homies.
Well, but then why won't they
let him have the surgery
when his appendix
could rupture at any time?
They're pranking us.
Oh.
But I know our followers
and if things get worse,
they'll do what's right.
I gotta get back to the show.
Dennis' fever just spiked,
he's septic.
Dr. Manning, radiology
just called, they're ready
for Ben's chest X-ray.
Good. Let's get him upstairs.
Did they take him already?
Looks like he was discharged.
Discharged? By who?
You, Dr. Manning.
Uh...
What are we doing up here?
I figured out how we can
double your followers
in an instant.
I don't think
you get how this works.
It took us over a year
to get to a million.
I think I know exactly
how this works,
which is why I want you
to ask your followers
a very simple question...
Should you jump off
this roof right now?
Woah!
This is not cool, man.
Wait. Is that a no?
I thought that they made
all the decisions.
Wait, isn't this, like,
against the rules?
You said your followers
love you, right?
They don't wanna see anything
bad happen to Dennis.
You got nothing
to worry about.
Babe, the chat's blowing up.
They wanna vote.
What do we do?
All right, guys,
this is for reals.
Look at the drop.
All right, team.
Should I jump off this roof?
They're voting.
Oh, man...
No...
What's it gonna be, man,
what are we doing?
Oh.
I'm not jumping.
Oh, my God. They're all
unfollowing us.
Hold on, you guys. That wasn't
even a fair question.
It doesn't count.
You can still be the judge.
What do you say, Dennis?
Can we get you into surgery?
Yeah.
How is she?
They were able to successfully
break up the clot.
And her kidney?
Function's improving.
We expect Lori
to make a full recovery.
Thank you.
Thank you for saving
our little girl.
I'll have someone grab you
as soon as they get
her settled into recovery.
Thank you again.
Dr. Halstead, thank you again.
You take care.
That was amazing.
Yeah, we had
a good save, didn't we?
No, you had a good save.
I should never
have doubted you.
You know, Elsa, I've been
a doctor for ten years.
After a while, you develop
a kind of intuition.
You just get better
at guessing when it's
right to take a risk.
Thank you.
As soon as we're inside,
we'll get you a nice
warm bath,
and a neb treatment.
There you go.
Maggie.
It's okay.
Let's go back.
I found it.
The short gastrics
are still bleeding.
I don't have the angle,
can you clamp them
from your side?
Yes, sir. Hemostat.
Better hustle,
I can't keep
his pressure up.
Don't rush me, Marty.
Got it. Two-oh silk stitch.
Pressure's improving.
Nice work, Crockett.
Let's tie
this off and close.
Get him quarantined, now.
You forged my signature?
I'm sorry, Nat.
I didn't know
what else to do. I...
I couldn't turn
my back on him.
That doesn't give you
the right to endanger
the public.
I realized that as soon
as I stepped outside but...
I can't believe
you did this, Maggie.
I'm sorry.
Go, be with him.
How's he doing?
The appendectomy went well.
The surgeon expects him
to make a full recovery.
Great.
Daniel, what's going on?
Can you please explain to me
why there's a video showing
my chief of psychiatry
asking a patient
to jump off the roof?
I realize that the optics
aren't good.
You're supposed to be
mitigating psychiatric crises,
not creating them.
What if he had tried to jump?
First of all, Sharon,
there was never any danger
of that happening.
But if it had, I would've put
him on a psych hold
and mandated the surgery.
This video's going viral.
What happens if
the Tribune picks it up?
Wouldn't be good.
No.
I'll see you tonight.
Hey, you're Elsa, right?
Uh, these concert tickets
just came off the printer.
Your name is on 'em.
Thanks. I was just
about to grab 'em.
How was your first day?
Um...
Great.
Everyone was so helpful.
Uh, excuse me.
Um, Will...
Sorry. Dr. Halstead,
I was just wondering
if maybe you...
There you are!
Somebody promised me
a Stoli Up, extra dirty.
Ready to go?
Definitely.
Juliette, this is Elsa,
fourth year med student.
Juliette's one of our
new paramedics.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
Mmm-hmm.
Yeah, did you need something?
No, no, no.
Uh, it's nothing important.
I'll see you tomorrow.
All right, you bet.
Good night.
Let's go.
All right.
Hank, do you call this
a decent pillow?
It's all that was left
in central supply.
Then you go to plastics
and you find me some silicone.
I don't care
how you do it.
Let's make
this patient comfortable.
Hey, Daniel.
Hey. Where's CeCe?
You cannot imagine
how excited she was
when I told her about tonight.
But she just wasn't up to it.
Did, however,
absolutely insist
that I join you.
So, how about a quick drink?
Sounds good.
Good to see you.
Please get this young man
whatever he's drinking.
Hey, hey.
You're gonna be okay.
Hey, April?
I'm here.
I'm right here.
Just get some rest, okay?
I'll check back in a while.
Hey, Crockett.
Thank you.
I'm just glad he's okay.