(INDISTINCT TALKING)
(SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE)
(SNIFFLES)
There's a social worker
out there with my kids.
If this takes a while...
We've got them. Don't worry.
I just need the papers.
(SIGHS)
We're gonna begin now.
You can sit next to him.
(RESPIRATOR HISSING)
(MONITORS BEEPING)
(BEEPING STOPS)
Wait.
Ma'am... Just wait!
Derek.
ELLIS: He was
the love of my life.
He was.
I doubt I'll ever love another
man the way I loved him.
I'm certain I won't.
How could I?
But he's gone. That's
the point, isn't it?
He's gone, and
I'm here, and, uh...
I'm here.
(YOUNG ELLIS SOBBING)
Are you okay?
YOUNG ELLIS: Richard...
Hey, Torres, I need help
on a hip disarticulation today.
You want in? Ooh. Maybe.
Uh, wait, you have
to finish your story.
So, you actually had
to break his knee?
No. So, I had to shove the
rod back in there even harder,
and it wound up
cracking the tibial plateau.
Can I help you? ALEX:
You're hogging the pot.
ELLIS: Everything
looks different now.
It feels so...
Different.
Maybe ask nicely, like
a civilized human being.
Callie? May I have the
carafe, please? Hmm?
Oh! Mmm-hmm.
See? It's quite easy, actually.
Really?
Hey, Mer, I heard there
was weather near Dulles.
Derek's flight got
delayed, didn't it?
MAGGIE: I hate that airport.
Pierce, my gallbladder guy's
pacemaker keeps misfiring.
You think you can
take a look at it?
MAGGIE: Yeah, I could do
it right now. CALLIE: Hmm.
Derek is dead.
No, you can't. No, I need
you to place an IVC filter
on my laminectomy patient.
Okay, right. Um, I could
swing by in about 20.
MEREDITH: Derek is dead.
What was that?
Derek is dead.
ELLIS: I don't know what to do.
I mean, I do...
I know what I should do, but...
I don't know.
ALEX: Meredith...
OWEN: Meredith...
RICHARD: He's not dead. OWEN:
Meredith, what do you mean?
Meredith? CALLIE:
What do you mean?
CALLIE: Meredith? Meredith?
MAGGIE: What do you...
MAGGIE: No!
ELLIS: I've lost him.
Everything changed,
and now it's...
It's hard to accept it, I guess.
He's gone.
He's just gone.
And there's no getting him back.
WOMAN ON PA: Dr. Eisenberg,
4673. Dr. Eisenberg...
(CRYING)
Y-you can't go in there.
What? Not until
you've stopped crying.
(SOBBING) Right.
(CRYING)
Okay, okay. I know.
Hey, how is she?
She's all right.
She's dehydrated.
How's Amelia holding up?
What, she doesn't know?
She's in surgery.
You know the protocol.
(SIGHS) Yeah. I
know the protocol.
(SNIFFLING)
STEPHANIE: Cervical
spine is fractured.
So are both legs.
Right foot has no pulse.
AMELIA: We're gonna
need to stabilize his spine.
What did they say he was? A cop?
STEPHANIE: Yeah,
he fell off a building
under construction
during a chase.
CALLIE: Sorry it
took me so long.
I was, um... AMELIA: It's fine.
We brought him straight
in from the helipad.
Central line is in. Transfuse
him with two units of blood.
Torres, you should
look at his leg.
Torres?
CALLIE: Yes. The leg.
STEPHANIE: All right, sir,
I need you to follow
my light with your eyes.
All right, good.
AMELIA: Do you
know where you are?
Do you know your name?
CALLIE: Dan.
Pruitt. That's his
name. Dan Pruitt.
I, uh, treated him
a few months back.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
STEPHANIE: Pressure's dropping.
AMELIA: Let's start him on a
dopamine drip and page general surgery.
Let's get moving! Put him under!
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
(SIGHS)
Can we have the room, please?
Did you need something?
Maybe we should have
this conversation in my office.
Look, I don't have time for...
Who died?
Amelia...
I know the face.
I've been here before.
Everyone thinks they are
the first person in the world
to ever look at a human
being like that, but...
It's always the same face.
Who is dead? Derek.
It's Derek.
I'm so, so sorry.
It was an MVC accident,
and he wanted to help.
I don't need the
details. Dead is dead.
I am so, so sorry.
I wish there was something
I could... Thank you.
For telling me.
Amelia, if there's
anything I can... I'm good.
I've done this
before. I know the drill.
It's not a big deal.
(WATER RUNNING)
(SNIFFLES)
Oh, my God.
MAN: This is a day for us to
celebrate Derek Shepherd's life
and for each of us
to say our goodbyes.
Every day we celebrate
him in some way,
as a father, as a husband,
as a brother, as a friend.
It was a nice service.
I liked your poem.
(SIGHS)
If something happens to me,
do not let them
hook me up to anything.
Nothing. Understand?
Just donate my organs
and let me go.
If that's what you want...
Okay. Okay.
(SIGHS)
But if something happens to me,
hook me up to everything
and never let them unplug me.
Ever. Ben, I'm not
joking about this.
Neither am I. I want to live.
I want extraordinary measures.
The more
extraordinary, the better.
Seriously.
Seriously?
No running ever.
MEREDITH: That we'll
take care of each other
even when we're old and smelly.
DEREK: Tumor is here.
MEREDITH: Now you've
completely lost your mind.
"You're like coming
up for fresh air."
It's you. It's always been you.
They offered me the job again.
MEREDITH: Take it.
Someone doesn't want
to put her shoes on.
Look, she's just so happy.
You don't have any idea
what's gonna happen, do you?
MEREDITH: Derek?
Derek?
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
ELLIS: Richard,
you can't leave me!
Richard, Richard!
MEREDITH: I was swimming...
And I let go.
I stopped fighting.
ELLIS: Meredith, get up.
Zozo, honey, wake up.
ELLIS: Put these
on. (UNZIPS BAG)
Okay. You ready?
Where are we going?
Away, sweetie. We're going away.
Come on, sweetheart, let's go.
It's just so strange that
she left with no warning.
She left a note.
Uh, "The kids and I are
safe"? Yeah, that's helpful.
ALEX: I called Yang again, but she
hasn't heard from Mer since the funeral.
Are you serious?
That was weeks ago.
Wha... Okay, I just
don't understand.
I don't understand. I do
not understand how you...
You want to go to
a meeting after this?
I'm good. Thanks.
Are you?
MIRANDA: "So long,
I'll see you later" or...
You're basically
living at the hospital.
MIRANDA: "trouble due
to the fact that I am all..."
I'm fine, Richard, really...
MIRANDA: "world right now."
I mean, she just dropped
everything. Her patients, her surgeries.
Look, maybe it's time
we hire a detective,
make sure she's really safe.
Yeah, I think we
should call the police.
CALLIE: Mmm-hmm.
RICHARD: Okay,
that's... That's enough.
Meredith Grey is not a missing
person. She... She left a note.
She's not jeopardizing her kids.
She's not an
irresponsible person.
If she's gone, she's gone
because she wants to be gone.
She's doing what
she knows how to do.
Same as her mother.
Ellis Grey left Seattle
and never looked back.
So, that's it? That...
We just let her go?
(LINE RINGING)
You've reached
Dr. Meredith Grey. (SIGHS)
(LINE RINGING)
You've reached
Dr. Meredith Grey. (SIGHS)
OWEN: And time isn't
the same over there.
Hours don't exist. There's
only minutes, seconds.
It's visceral and exciting.
But you're chief.
Well, not for the
next few months.
Webber is stepping
in as interim chief.
The work I'll get to
do is raw and urgent.
Kepner, you just feel
so useful and good
at the end of every day,
and after everything
that's happened here, I...
I'm ready.
I'm ready for this kind of
change. I just need to feel...
Useful.
And good.
Yeah.
I don't care how
sick the kids are.
I'm not doing this next year.
(LAUGHS)
Our patient has 60%
surface area burns.
She was pulled from a
house fire this morning.
Are you even listening?
JO: I'm... I'm sorry. I just...
You need to prepare yourself.
Burns like this are...
Difficult.
This will not be easy.
Hi, Anne.
Dr. Wilson and I are here to
start your first dressing changes.
(SIGHS) I'm so cold.
I can't stop shaking.
I mean, isn't
that weird, that...
That I got burned and I'm cold?
Well, your skin and your nerves
have experienced severe damage.
You are unable to retain heat
or feel surface pain.
Dr. Wilson, do you want
to walk Anne through
what we're gonna be doing today?
We'll debride the
burns layer by layer
until we expose healthy tissue
to help new skin grow.
JJ: And it hurts like hell,
so you might want to
grab onto something.
The bed rails work really well.
Who's that?
That... That's
your neighbor, JJ.
She was admitted
a couple weeks ago.
Hello, JJ. JJ: Oh, and
do yourself a favor,
grab something to bite down on.
That's not... Thank you, JJ.
Is she serious?
We've got you under sedation.
JJ: Barely works!
JACKSON: Really, JJ?
We are going to do this as
quickly as possible, okay, Anne?
Um, is my husband out there?
Oh, um, I don't see him,
but we can track him down.
S-should I... JACKSON:
Uh, sure, yeah.
Just... Just be quick,
okay? Ready to get started?
Okay. You ready?
(GASPS) JACKSON: Okay.
Ow. Ow!
Ow, that... That hurts! I know.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SCREAMING)
JJ: Okay, you see, that's why
you want to get
something to bite down on!
(CRYING)
(CHUCKLES) I... I never... I
never said you were boring.
Don't deny it.
I got the whole story
out of a resident.
You thought I was boring.
That's why we never
had a second date.
(CLEARS THROAT) And, uh...
Which resident told you this?
(CHUCKLES)
I'm not gonna put my CI at risk.
Um...
That's a confidential
informant. It's cop talk.
I'd elaborate, but
you might think
it's a little too boring.
(CHUCKLES)
Relax, I'm just
messing with you.
(LAUGHS)
(GROANS)
Oh, okay, all
right. Take it easy.
That graft we used to close
your abdomen is breaking down,
and you're gonna need
another series of surgeries
just to complete the closure,
let alone to complete
your spinal fusion.
What about my leg?
I know it's in pretty rough
shape, but I'm gonna need it back
if I'm gonna go back to chasing
crooks and leaping over rooftops,
you know, all that
super-boring cop stuff.
(CHUCKLES) Come on.
Don't make it that
easy. Give a little back.
I can take it, you know?
Dan, I can't make you any
promises about your leg.
I'm gonna do
everything that I can,
but I am not confident
that we'll be able to save it.
There's a very, very
long road ahead.
Wow.
When you sling it back,
you don't mess around.
But silver lining,
this means you'll have that much
more time to fall
in love with me.
(LAUGHS)
Ow.
Your face... Priceless.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Yeah.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
How is what you're doing any
different than Meredith Grey?
We've been over this.
Because my husband didn't die,
because I'm not running
away from anything,
because this is an
incredible opportunity for me
to learn surgical techniques
that I've never even dreamed of.
Jackson, it's only three months.
You could at least
pretend to be happy for me.
Why? I don't like it.
(SIGHS) I don't. It's dangerous.
I'm not gonna be fighting!
I'm gonna be doing surgery.
I'm gonna be teaching, helping.
These are all things that
you do here every day.
It makes me excited.
Happy.
Please... I need this.
I want it.
It's three months.
WOMAN ON PA: Flight
721 to Los Angeles...
My flight's about to board. I...
Well, I can't leave if we're like this.
Will you at least
kiss me goodbye?
Ready? One, two...
You do know what you're doing?
I'm a surgeon.
Gonna ruin my day at the
lake, poking a hornet's nest.
You know, that's a saying.
People do not actually
poke the hornet's nest.
I didn't do it on...
Ow! What's... What?
(CHUCKLES) You baby.
And you want to
be kept alive forever.
You can't deal with a
pair of sharp tweezers.
You want to be intubated,
catheterized, multiple IVs,
central lines in
the neck and groin,
and bed sores all because
you can't get it together,
let Jesus take the wheel.
What?
Look, look, if I am
lying in a hospital bed
in such bad shape that
it has reached that point
that some doctor is talking to
you about extraordinary measures,
I am not gonna let Jesus
take the wheel. Oh!
No, you know when Jesus
should've taken the wheel,
when he should've been flipping
his turn signals
a-and shifting gears?
When whatever bad
thing that happened
to make me suffer a traumatic
brain injury was happening,
but instead, Jesus was clearly
out joyriding with someone else
because there I
am gorked in a bed.
So, no, I'm not gonna
let Jesus take the wheel.
I'm not gonna let Jesus
anywhere near my damn car!
I'm driving!
No, science is driving.
I did not stab him in the
neck with these tweezers.
I want that noted.
Hey. Anything today?
No. You? Nothing.
(LINE RINGING)
Still no word at all?
She doesn't reply to e-mails.
Or her freakin' phone.
DR. DREYFUSS: Two hours... Two.
For a routine neuro consult.
I get we're down a
guy, but I'm sorry,
the board needs
to get off their asses
and hire a new
neurosurgeon already.
Don't make a scene.
It's not worth it.
I know.
DR. DREYFUSS: Well,
it's irresponsible, is what it is.
It's bad management.
How hard is it to find more...
(THUDS)
Really? Really?
You think that we need
to just get off our asses?
We should do you that solid
because the loss of
our colleague and friend
is all about your
needs, your schedule?
You think that we should
be sensitive to that?
How about you take a minute
to think about the person,
the talent, the life that we lost?
How about you think
before you start complaining
that Derek Shepherd's death
has been inconvenient for you?
(INDISTINCT MURMURS)
WOMAN: What just happened?
(SIGHS)
I made a scene.
AMELIA: Okay, these are
hypertrophic bone spurs.
We just need to bite
them off, and we'll be set.
STEPHANIE: So, no foraminotomy?
AMELIA: I really
don't think we need it.
CALLIE: Oh, really?
Because I'm not having
any success with his leg.
He's probably gonna lose it
and Dan and I were hoping
he's a viable candidate
for a bionic prosthesis,
so if he's in chronic pain
or in a c-collar for too long
and that delays rehab, which...
I realize this isn't the method my
dear, dead brother would have used.
His method would
actually be clunkier
and offer less
support than mine,
so let's do it my way.
I don't think Derek will mind,
on account of he is dead.
Cool? CALLIE: Sure.
Totally, totally cool.
AMELIA: Great. Rongeur, please.
ANNE: Ohh!
(GROANING IN PAIN)
No, it hurts more!
Honey, honey,
you're doing great.
I know that it's painful, but that
just means that you're healing,
and then the more you heal...
(JJ SPEAKING ALONG)
the more your nerves regrow.
Yeah, isn't that a bitch? The
better you get, the more it hurts.
And then they send
Dr. Wilson in here.
What, all the ugly
doctors are busy
so they got to enlist Snow White
to come and peel
us like a grape?
JJ, you're not helping!
No, no, actually,
that's... That's funny!
She is... (SCREAMING)
(CRYING)
JJ: I know.
I mean, seriously, they're
sending in a Disney Princess,
so what does that
make us? (CRYING)
The Seven Dwarves?
(CRYING) JJ: Two
of them, anyway.
Okay, I'm, um... I'll be Burny,
and you can be Screamy.
(CHUCKLES)
And... And, you
know, there... There's...
There's that guy down the
hall who just lost a leg and...
And that woman who's in
the trauma room next to me.
And she was, like, dying,
but she wouldn't
stop complaining
about the service
she was getting.
(CHUCKLES)
They can be dwarves, too.
Stumpy and Bitchy.
(LAUGHS) Stumpy and Bitchy.
Yeah. Yeah.
Okay, I'm gonna
go again. (LAUGHS)
(SCREAMING)
I'm right here. I got you.
It's okay. You're okay.
It's okay.
You know who they
should've sent in here
was Mary friggin' Poppins.
I bet she had some morphine
in that bag of crap she
carried around with her.
(CRYING)
JJ: Okay, so we got, um, Burny,
Screamy, Stumpy,
Bitchy. Who else?
For God's sake, shut up!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Lance...
Okay, we're gonna
take five, okay?
ANNE: Lance?
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
He's just scared.
(SIGHS)
This is scary for him.
JJ: Then, um,
he fits in perfectly.
Okay, we've got...
(CLEARS THROAT)
We've got Burny, Screamy,
Stumpy, Bitchy, and Scaredy.
Yeah.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
MAGGIE: We
should try to find her.
She's not a rogue agent.
She's not on the lam.
She's a single
mother with two kids.
How hard could it be?
Really freakin' hard.
I called anyone
I could think of...
(SIGHS)
Cristina, her father.
And then I thought
maybe Webber was right,
maybe she followed
in Ellis' footsteps.
So, I started calling
hospitals in Boston
and asking for Dr. Grey just
to see if anyone would answer.
(FIREWORKS EXPLODING)
MAGGIE: Oh. Wow.
(CHEERING IN DISTANCE)
ALEX: Yeah, here we go.
This isn't why I
came to Seattle.
Ooh.
I didn't know exactly
why I was coming, but...
I knew it had to do with
finding out about my family,
and I found Meredith.
And then she...
(GASPS) (CHEERING CONTINUES)
(FIREWORKS CONTINUE)
I never felt abandoned
by my birth mother.
My parents never let
me, not for a second.
We were meant to be a
family. I believe that. I know that.
But...
(GASPS)
(SIGHS)
But I think this is
how I would've felt...
If I had.
(LINE RINGING)
You've reached
Dr. Meredith Grey.
(BEEPS)
Look, cut it out. It's
not fair to any of us.
Just tell me that you're
okay and that you're safe.
That's all. Just do that.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hey. APRIL: Hey.
Why haven't you
been picking up today?
I... I've been working.
Okay, well, now I've only
got a couple mikes, so...
Who's... Who's Mike? What?
(STAMMERS) Mikes. Minutes.
I just... I... I have to hurry.
Oh, okay, well, only a
couple more days of this, right?
Pretty soon, you'll be back here
and we'll be both on
the same crazy schedule.
Yeah, right, that's
what I have to...
Oh, I have a confession
to make. Um...
So do I. We have a new couch.
There was an
accident involving mole
and a really exciting National
League playoff game, actually,
and, um, couldn't get
the stain out, so just...
New couch.
I'm not coming home next week.
(STATIC)
What? I just...
I can't... Apr...
teaching people
these techniques.
We've barely started.
I mean, the level
of need here is so...
(STATIC)
children.
I mean, Jackson,
if you were here,
you'd know what
I'm talking about.
It's just... Just, I don't
feel like I'm done yet.
Understand?
I do.
And I don't. I mean, are you...
Are you telling me
that's your decision
or you want to talk
about this now, or...
Well, now, uh...
(STATIC)
No, I... I can't... I can't now.
Um, can I try you
back at 1300 hours?
I'll be sleeping.
That's like 3:00 a.m.
All right, so, when are you
saying you can be home?
(STATIC) April?
Jackson... April?
(STATIC)
(BEEPING)
This is such a lovely
meal. Really nice.
More than nice.
(SIGHS)
You keep me on my
toes, Catherine Avery.
(CHUCKLES)
You make me very happy.
(CLEARS THROAT)
CATHERINE: Richard Webber,
if you are about to do what
I believe you're about to do,
you should stop.
Catherine... (SIGHS)
No, please, please.
You should not be asking this
question without knowing my answer.
Well, I thought I did.
We are not new to this.
We know better
than to get caught up
in some grand, romantic gesture.
We know what marriage
really is. It's a merger, a contract.
No one should enter
a binding contract
without careful, lengthy,
practical consideration.
Sounds so romantic.
No, and it shouldn't be.
You know what? Yes, it should.
You know, I pulled back
on the romance tonight
because I knew...
If I could, I'd fill
this room with roses.
I'd have invited
all of our friends.
I would've hired a
quartet or a soloist
or a damn mariachi band to start
playing the minute you said yes,
because a proposal
should be romantic.
It's... That's how I see it.
It's not a hollow gesture.
It's me telling you
how much I love you.
But, um...
Clearly, we disagree.
(CATHERINE SIGHS)
(RICHARD SIGHS)
I take it we're
splitting the check?
(MAN SCREAMING ON TV)
Oh. (GIGGLES)
All right, where's the remote?
MAN: Splash on over to...
You know, people wake up.
Statistically, people
don't wake up.
Well, who's to say I
couldn't defy the odds
and... And be a miracle man?
There you go with
the miracles again.
You believe in Jesus but
you don't believe in miracles?
Um, Jesus didn't hook you
up to a bunch of machines.
Jesus isn't an idiot.
(CHUCKLES) Okay, you know what?
You and all your
little snide comments,
you can take them and you can...
Oh, it's back on. Mmm.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Okay, see, she's about to die.
Oh, she's definitely gonna die.
Look at this guy's
spinal abscess.
Sloppy.
Who was the primary? Dr. Nelson.
Oh, it figures.
If Derek saw this, he
would roll over in his grave.
Can you actually do
that? Roll over in a grave?
I mean, a casket's pretty snug.
There's not a lot of
room to move in there.
More like shake.
If Derek saw this, he
would shake in his grave.
Shimmy, maybe. Please stop.
Stop what?
You've been making a lot of
jokes and comments about...
My dead brother?
Yeah, which...
No judgment. It just makes
me very uncomfortable.
Why? It's the truth.
He's my brother, and he's dead.
There are some...
I checked, and there are
some grief groups that meet,
and I just thought,
look, I can go with you.
My grandmother passed last year.
It would be really
good for me, too.
Edwards, I have a morbid
sense of humor, but I'm fine.
I don't need a group.
But thank you. It's
very thoughtful of you.
Okay? Okay.
Let's just put it to rest.
Like my brother.
Ha!
(GROANS IN PAIN)
(SIGHS)
JACKSON: You're doing great,
Anne. (BREATHING HEAVILY)
It's okay. Just keep going.
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
Okay. Tell me more about
how you're gonna fix me.
Okay, well, our next surgery is to
remove skin from around your hips
and graft onto these cheek
scars here and then here.
So, you're gonna chop
off my love handles?
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Did you hear that, JJ? I'm gonna
get a smaller waist out of this.
They can take whatever
they want off my ass.
(ALL CHUCKLE)
When do we get started?
Well, I just need to get that
infection in your nose under control
before we start the
grafting procedures.
I see.
Yeah.
So, where's husband
of the year today?
He was here this
morning. Brought bagels.
She doesn't need bagels.
She needs a hand to hold.
So, um...
So, it's still gonna
be a little while
before we really get
going with the grafts, huh?
Okay. Yeah, that's okay.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Excuse me.
(CONTINUES RINGING)
(BEEPS)
Sorry about that.
No, no, no, no, that's dessert!
I am sorry, but that
turkey is three hours away.
I didn't know it was
gonna take all day.
Didn't your mother ever
teach you how to roast a turk...
No, 'cause I never had a mother
and I didn't have
an oven in my car.
Point taken. (DOOR OPENS)
Doesn't help the
fact that I'm starving.
ALEX: I have food.
Oh, my God, thank you!
Damn it, Alex.
ALEX: Hey, it was a good effort,
but the only thing that bird is
stuffed with is food poisoning.
Oh, my God, I'm so
frickin' hungry! Ah.
There. Mmm. Mmm-hmm.
(RINGING)
(BEEPS)
Hey. Hey, you're alive!
Alex, listen... I'm
fine. The kids are fine.
We're okay. I'm fine.
Please stop calling.
DAN: So, my partner says,
"Who's gonna play Santa
at the holiday party?"
And I say, "I don't
know. I'm stumped." Oh.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Please, that's the easiest
amputation joke in the book.
Yeah.
You have plans for the holidays?
Um, yeah, my ex and I are
splitting Christmas with our daughter,
so I get Christmas
Eve this year,
and she gets Christmas Day.
DAN: Dr. Torres... Well...
Callie... I need
to say something.
Dan... Mmm. No, please, just...
Let me say this. (SIGHS)
I think that I was...
I was meant to meet
you. No, Dan, Dan.
Dan, Dan, Dan, let me say this.
When... When a
doctor cares for a patient
for an extended period of time,
that care can often feel
to the patient like, um...
(CLEARS THROAT) affection.
What? What? (CHUCKLES)
I meant as my doctor,
but please keep going.
This is great.
Oh. Oh, my God!
(CLEARS THROAT) Um,
look, that first date, it sucked.
Mmm-hmm. I get it.
But it got me to you, and I
think I needed you for this.
Like...
(CHUCKLES)
I couldn't have
survived this without you.
So, thank you.
Merry Christmas, Dr. Torres.
(LAUGHS)
Merry Christmas.
Tuck must've been not
even slightly naughty.
Do not mock
divorced-mother guilt.
Oh, hand me that bow.
What if I met Idris Elba?
What?
Well, you're hooked
up to endless machines,
having the time of your brain-dead
life with extraordinary measures,
and since you are
technically alive,
well, then I'm not
single, I am not a widow.
Years pass, and, uh... Okay,
I'm not the kind of woman who...
Okay, there are people who
think that sex isn't cheating,
there are people out there
who think that an
emotional affair isn't cheating.
Well, I'm not either kind
of person. It's all cheating.
Even though my
husband is an idiot
who thinks that he will have
that one-in-a-zillion chance...
No, look, there are
documented cases
of people waking
up after years of...
There are documented
cases of people
who've seen the Loch
Ness monster, too.
So what?
I will be locked
up like some nun,
withering and wasting
away lonely and alone
all because you're mad at
Jesus, so I don't get to have Idris.
You're taking away
my Idris chance.
(LAUGHS) What? Idris Elba!
He could come to Seattle, witness
an accident, save a child's life,
carry that child in his
arms, bare-chested,
into my trauma
room. You don't know.
So, you're gonna
pull the plug on me
so you can have your
way with Idris Elba?
It's Idris Elba!
Oh, I ate too much
pizza. (CLEARS THROAT)
Second batch.
Deck your halls, y'all!
I always hated eggnog.
Why is yours so good?
Mine's mostly hooch.
It's basically a
bourbon milkshake.
Cheers to that.
Karev, that is definitely the
saddest tree I've ever seen.
ALEX: Tell Robbins.
No, it's better than no tree.
Alex was like, "Why bother?"
And I said, "You have to
have a tree at Christmas."
Otherwise, your soul is just
curdled and you've given up on joy,
so I got a tree.
I started decorating it, and then
some woman went into labor,
so I gave up.
"To Zola, from Sofia."
(SIGHS)
Sofia keeps asking,
"Mommy, maybe at
Christmas, we'll see Zola.
"Shouldn't we
get her a present?"
And I don't... I don't
know what to say.
I mean, I don't know if
they're ever coming back.
Hmm. I know the feeling.
So, I caved. I got a gift, just in
case. (DOORBELL RINGING)
That's the spirit.
Hey, merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas! You came!
Oh, I invited Richard 'cause he
seemed a little sad and lonely.
Is that okay? Yeah.
(RINGING) RICHARD:
I brought a Yule Log!
MAGGIE: Yum!
ARIZONA: Oh, here.
Put it here. Or over there.
Move the dip.
Hey. APRIL: Hey.
How's Karev's
Christmas-not-Christmas thing?
Uh, it's okay. Karev
scraped together some pizza.
(SIGHS)
I miss you. I wish
you were here.
I'm sorry. I... I tried...
Really?
You've extended this "tour of
duty" thing three times already.
What does that make
you, colonel now?
Jackson...
April...
It's Christmas. I know that.
Don't you think I wish I
could be there with you?
You could, actually.
You haven't been drafted.
You should be here.
We're supposed to be a...
We're supposed to have a child.
We were supposed
to be celebrating
Christmas together,
the three of us.
And every time I
think about that, I just...
OWEN: Kepner, we got
to pack up and bug out.
What's going on? Um...
No, it's fine. It's just some
insurgents that have
been... (EXPLODES)
What is happening?
Um, I... I got to go!
April? Hold on, April?
(BEEPING)
(CELL PHONE CLATTERS)
(ANNE CRYING)
He's not worth it.
He's not good enough!
If he can't make it
with you through this,
then he's not good
enough for you!
(ALARM BEEPS)
JJ: Finally! Anne.
Where does it hurt?
Are you in pain? (CRYING)
Her son-of-a-bitch
husband shows up,
brings her that
Christmas present,
and told her that this was
not what he signed up for,
and walked out on her!
(CRYING) Okay, okay,
deep breaths. Okay.
I'm gonna... I'm gonna get
you something to help you relax.
He's an ass, sweetie!
Oh, yeah, he is an ass.
Shh.
Deep breaths,
okay? Deep breaths.
You're okay.
But he's right. He
didn't sign up for this.
(SOBBING)
Who would?
I mean, I've been here
six months or seven.
I... I've lost count, and...
And look at me.
I'm disgusting!
He's married to burnt toast!
Who would want to
be married to this?
Who would love this?
Anne, honey...
If this had happened to
him, would you have left him?
Would you have loved him?
He's not good enough
for you! He's not right!
This is the best Christmas
gift you could've gotten,
knowing that he is
not the man for you.
And you don't have to
spend one more minute
with someone who is
less than you deserve!
You get to start over.
It's a gift.
We're starting over.
Like it's our first
Christmas, okay?
Right?
(CRIES)
(CHUCKLES)
You know what we need?
We need a little holiday
cheer up in here, right?
Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
(SINGING CHRISTMAS SONG)
Oh, really? Really? Songs
about roasting things?
(ALL LAUGHING)
That was an unfortunate choice.
Uh, all right.
(SINGS DIFFERENT CHRISTMAS SONG)
No. No noses.
No noses and no fires. (LAUGHS)
Okay, um, how about,
I'll Be Home for Christmas?
(SINGING)
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
(SIGHS) (BEEPING)
I know you're not sleepy,
but you have to close your
eyes or else he won't come.
Will he bring me some toys?
If you go to sleep.
Will he bring me a baby sister?
(LAUGHS)
Not tonight.
I wish Daddy were here.
Night-night,
sweetie. Sleep tight.
I'm just not sure of
anything anymore.
I keep going over it round
and round, over and over again.
Like any other choice I
make, might change things.
But no. This is the
right place for me to be.
This is the right
thing for me to do.
I know that. I just didn't expect
that it would hurt quite this much.
Sweetie, don't go too far!
MEREDITH: Mommy.
ELLIS: Meredith.
You grew up.
I did.
(CHUCKLES) It's a shame.
It's awful being a grown-up.
But the carousel
never stops turning.
DEREK: And I want
more. Of this, of us, of...
(EXHALES)
I want to have more.
Another baby? Sure.
Uh, seriously?
DEREK: Listen, I love
you, and you love me, and...
Whatever happens, I don't care.
No more doctors, no more labs,
and you and I, we
have a lot of sex.
Maybe we can make
a baby, maybe not.
Maybe you get Alzheimer's,
maybe not, but this...
I am calling Post-it.
Zola and Bailey
and tumors on the walls
and ferry boat scrub caps.
You're everything.
Meredith, I can't
live without you.
I don't want to
And I'm gonna do everything
in my power to prove it.
AMELIA: You've never
lost the love of your life.
You have never cried
over the body of the person
you love most in this world.
You...
You don't know how
that messes a person up.
You've never had to claw
your way back from that.
MEREDITH: I can
live without you.
But I don't want to.
I don't ever want to.
ELLIS: The carousel
never stops turning.
You can't get off.
Sir, I hear you saying
that you have no answers,
but I need you to have
some damn answers!
That...
(SLAMS RECEIVER)
Hey. (SIGHS)
Is everything okay?
No, everything's not okay.
She should never have gone.
April should never have gone
to a freaking combat zone.
I know. I know it's hard.
It's not just hard.
It's... (SIGHS)
Just... She lost a leg.
You know, with everything
that happened this past year
with you and your baby, she...
She lost a leg.
And she's learning how
to walk again, and you...
You have to let her do that.
Why? Why should I do that?
Why does she get to go
off and put herself in danger
and just leave me here to...
If she lost a leg,
then I lost a leg, too.
But guess what? I still
get up every morning.
I face every day.
I don't get to jump on a plane and
fly halfway across the damn world
so that all that
April has left of me
is some crappy memory of me
yelling at her from a picture on a phone!
Wait, what happened?
(SIGHS)
We were talking,
and then there was
gunfire, a lot of it,
and the call got cut off.
And I have not been able
to get ahold of her since.
I don't know where she is.
I don't even know where she is.
MIRANDA: All I'm saying is,
I just don't understand how you
can know a man and love a man
and not see eye-to-eye with him
on such a basic,
fundamental thing.
CATHERINE: Exactly.
Richard wants to propose
by drowning me in flowers
and chocolate-covered
rose petals.
You'd think a man
would be grateful
for a woman who allows him
to avoid that kind of nonsense.
MAGGIE: Or maybe
it's just not about you.
CATHERINE: I beg your pardon?
MAGGIE: Nothing. Sorry,
none of my business.
CATHERINE: Well, you seem to have
made it your business, so elaborate.
Please.
MAGGIE: Maybe it just
makes him feel good.
Maybe it's easier just to
accept a bunch of dumb roses
than to ask a man to
fundamentally change who he is
or do what makes him feel good,
when what makes him feel good
is telling you how
good you make him feel.
Maybe by not letting
him give you that,
you're actually taking
something away from him.
Sorry.
CATHERINE: No, it's...
You're protecting
him. I understand.
Happy New Year!
How are we feeling...
(ANNE SHUSHING)
Good. (CHUCKLES)
Sorry, we were up all night,
and I know, I know that's bad,
but we wanted to
watch the ball drop,
and then we started talking
and we couldn't shut up.
So, I told her that I would
take the first torture shift today.
Okay. Just let her sleep.
I feel like I fell asleep
10 minutes ago.
Did you know that JJ
was a volunteer firefighter?
And then she gets burned at a...
At a tailgate party
for a Seahawks game.
(ANNE LAUGHS)
We sort of died
laughing at the irony,
and then we cried about it.
Then we laughed again.
(SNIFFLES AND BREATHES DEEPLY)
I'm just gonna go grab
something really quick.
Wait, stop. What's going on?
What's wrong?
Is it JJ?
Wait, I know something's
wrong. (BANGING ON WINDOW)
Anne, you have to
lay back. JJ? JJ? JJ?
You have to lay back. No,
no, no, no, no! (SCREAMS)
You'll tear your skin.
(CRYING) No! No!
I'm so sorry. I'm so
sorry. She's gone.
(CRYING)
No, she can't be! She can't!
I can't do this without her!
I can't do it alone!
ELLIS: I raised you to be an
extraordinary human being,
so imagine my disappointment
when I wake up after five years
and discover that you're
no more than ordinary!
What happened to you?
DEREK: You're ignoring me.
Um, trying to. You
shouldn't ignore me.
Why not?
Because I'm someone you
need to get to know to love.
Really? Oh, yes.
So, if I know
you, I'll love you.
Oh, yes.
You really like yourself, huh?
Just hiding my pain.
(BOTH LAUGH)
So, what's your story?
My mother tried to kill
herself when I was a kid
after the love of
her life disappeared.
I never told
anybody that before.
(SNIFFLES)
So, you think I'm broken?
Is there a reason for this?
Because if you can think of
a reason, any reason at all,
why the universe is so screwed
up and random and mean,
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(DOOR OPENS)
now would be an amazingly
good time to tell me
because I really
need some answers.
I know. I know
you do. Come here.
(CRYING) I don't...
I can't! I can't!
I don't...
Slow, deep breaths, slow, deep
breaths. (BREATHING HEAVILY)
Here. Take this.
Slow down, slow down.
Just breathe in. Take
a deep breath. Go.
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
MEREDITH: You can
say anything to me.
I want to marry you.
I want to have kids with you.
I want to build us a house.
I want to settle down
and grow old with you.
I want to die when
I'm 110 years old
in your arms.
I don't want 48
uninterrupted hours.
I want a lifetime.
MEREDITH: He's gone,
and I know he's gone.
And the bed feels lonely.
It's like I don't know
how to sleep alone.
I miss you.
MEREDITH: I believe that we
can be extraordinary together
rather than ordinary
apart, and I want to be...
(CHUCKLES)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Okay, now, go slow, okay?
Go slow, concentrate, okay?
(MECHANICAL LEG WHIRS)
(CHUCKLES)
You ready? Yeah.
(WHIRRING)
DAN: Holy crap!
(CHUCKLES)
It's moving. (LAUGHS)
That's great. Great.
(WHIRRING)
CALLIE: That's great!
One more. Yeah.
(WHIRRING)
Yes, it's great!
(LAUGHS)
That was the best first run
of any patient I've ever had!
You did it! No, you did it.
I would never have
done this without you.
(CRIES)
Um, okay, I take it back. I
take it back. It was all me.
No, no, no.
It was you. It was you,
and it was me, and...
(SIGHS) The
reason that your brain
can tell your new
leg what to do is, um...
It all started
because of these...
These, uh, badass little sensors
(VOICE BREAKING) made by
an amazing neurosurgeon who...
(SIGHS)
You're right.
We don't know why we meet
the people that we meet, but...
I wouldn't be here without him.
He was a brilliant surgeon,
and he was a good friend.
And, uh...
And he would've loved this.
He would've... He
would've loved it.
(SNIFFLES)
Okay, anyway...
You want to go again?
Absolutely, yeah. Okay.
All right.
Hi, Laura.
I'm here to start your first
dressing change, okay?
Now we're gonna debride
the burns layer by layer.
That'll expose healthy tissue in
order to help new skin to grow, okay?
ANNE: You're gonna want
something to hold on to.
Bed railings work pretty
well. This is gonna hurt.
Who is that?
That is your neighbor, Anne.
ANNE: Oh, and
do yourself a favor,
find something to bite down on.
JO: Thank you, Anne.
ANNE: I know
the drill. Tell her.
Yeah, thank you, Anne.
I'm gonna get started now,
okay? (WHIMPERING) Mmm-hmm.
(SCREAMING)
It's okay. (CRYING)
It's okay.
(CONTINUES CRYING)
You're gonna be okay.
APRIL: Hey.
Sorry, I should've called.
They ordered us out really
suddenly, and I was hopping planes,
and then I thought
maybe I'd surprise you,
but I can see by the look
on your face that... (GASPS)
Oh, Amelia, hey, got
time for a cup of coffee?
(SIGHS) Sorry, busy day. Yeah.
Haven't seen you at
a meeting in a while.
A long while.
Like I said, really busy.
Edwards mentioned
something about you...
Really? What else
is Edwards saying?
(CHUCKLES)
I'm not accusing you.
I'm checking in. You
know, I get to check in.
That's the kind
of friends we are.
I do not have time for coffee.
I do not have time for meetings.
I don't... My job is not to
make you feel better about me.
My job is to make
my patients get better.
Do you know what can happen
in the hour or two I
would be wasting with you?
An hour or two matters!
They matter to me.
They should matter to you.
They matter to my patients.
If I leave and my patient
dies, it's not me who will suffer,
it is his mother, his
sisters, his friends, his wife,
and they will hate me.
With everything inside them,
they will hate me and
you and everyone here
because they won't
understand why he is gone,
why people always leave,
why everyone you give
a crap about walks away
or is ripped from your world
without warning, without reason,
in convenience stores
and plane crashes
and podunk hospitals
with podunk doctors
who don't do what
they are supposed to do,
which is save people!
(SIGHS)
(WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY)
OWEN: Hey.
It's good to see you.
Hey.
Feels like I've been away
forever, but I see nothing's changed,
except they chopped
down that old tree.
Yeah.
Okay, I'll...
I'll see you around.
I have a baggie full of
black-market Oxy in my coat pocket,
and I'm trying to decide
whether or not to take it.
(SNIFFLES)
I've got the Dead-Derek
thing completely managed.
I know people were worried.
Since he died, everybody's
been looking at me,
waiting for me to
fall apart or freak out
or just... (IMITATES EXPLOSION)
become a mess.
Like some bomb everyone
thinks is supposed to go off.
My mother was calling
three, four times a day.
Addison was calling... Everyone.
It makes sense.
It's natural.
Every man I've ever loved
has died.
Including my baby.
Thank you, universe.
So, I should be, like...
Greek tragedy, turned to stone,
bat-crap crazy, but I'm good.
I got this. I am fine. I'm
telling you, I'm amazing.
I am saving lives
left and right.
I am putting butts in the
seats in that O.R. Gallery.
I mean, people are
fighting to hear me lecture.
I am entertaining.
Joke, joke, joke!
I'm funny! I'm fun! I'm a
party! I'm doing... I'm great!
I'm handling the
Dead-Derek thing really well.
Okay.
Except today, I
yelled at Richard,
who was only trying
to invite me for coffee,
and then I went and scored
Oxy from this junkie doctor.
But you haven't taken any?
Not yet.
(SIGHS)
But I might.
That's the thing.
I really actually might.
I have been sober
for 1,321 days, Owen.
I was fine. It was managed.
But I might.
All this stuff
you're managing...
You're not supposed
to be managing it.
You're supposed to be
feeling it, grief, loss, pain.
It is normal.
It's not normal.
It is. It is normal.
It's not normal to you
'cause you've never done it.
Instead of feeling it,
feeling the grief and the pain,
you've shoved it all down
and you do drugs instead.
Instead of moving through
the pain, you run from it.
You...
(SIGHS)
Instead of dealing with
being hurt and alone
and afraid that this horrible,
empty feeling is all there is,
I run from it.
(SCOFFS)
I run off, and I sign up for
another tour of active duty.
(SIGHS)
We do these things.
We run off, and we...
And we medicate.
We do whatever it takes to
cover it up and dull the sensation,
but it's not normal.
We're supposed to feel.
We're supposed to love,
and hate, and hurt,
and grieve, and break,
and be destroyed
and rebuild ourselves
to be destroyed again.
That is human. That is
humanity. That's... That's...
That's being alive.
That's the point.
That's the entire point.
Don't... Don't avoid it.
Don't
extinguish it.
Derek died.
(VOICE BREAKING) He died.
I don't want to feel it.
I... I don't think I can.
I don't think I even want to...
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I can't. I can't.
I can't do this.
You have to. If you don't...
No, I can't. Shh! I can't
do this! You... You have to.
If you don't, that bag of
Oxy's not gonna be your last.
(SNIFFLES)
(CRYING)
You're gonna be okay. You're
gonna survive this, okay?
(CRYING) Everybody does.
(SIGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
It's perfectly normal.
It's boring, even.
(CRYING)
It's so normal.
Okay, Zozo, here's your
snack, cheese, bananas,
and a little...
(GRUNTS) Damn it.
ELLIS: It doesn't matter
if I'm hurting, does it?
It doesn't matter if I'm
alone. Where do I sign?
WOMAN: Ms. Grey, it's important
you fully understand, by signing these,
you sign away all
rights to your daughter,
now and in the future.
ELLIS: And I'm all alone.
Now I have to raise
my daughter alone.
(VOICE BREAKING) How
am I expected to do that?
Mom...
WOMAN: I understand.
It's okay if you need more time.
More time? More time?
I needed more time with him,
but it just keeps going
forward faster and faster,
and there is no more time.
You can't go back.
You can't press "pause."
The carousel never
stops turning. It...
(SIGHS)
I don't need any more
time. Where do I sign?
(INHALES SHARPLY) Damn it.
(MOANS)
Actually, you know, Zo, I
think maybe we'll take that, huh?
We'll put it in a
baggie, and we'll...
(GROANS IN PAIN)
Mommy!
It's okay, Zola. It's okay.
You're bleeding. There's blood!
YOUNG ELLIS:
Blood. It's just blood.
Mommy, should I call 911?
ELLIS: Not yet. Wait.
Yes. Call. ELLIS: Meredith,
don't be afraid.
Don't be afraid.
(LINE RINGING)
WOMAN: 911, what's
your emergency?
My mother tried to kill herself.
My mommy needs help.
(SIREN WAILING)
Are you the smart girl
who knew how to call 911?
DOCTOR: You might've
saved your mother's life.
Dr. Grey, we're just
about ready to start.
My kids? Where are my kids?
ELLIS: Stop it! (SHOUTS)
She shouldn't be
in here. No, wait.
ELLIS: Don't touch me!
MEREDITH: Derek! Derek!
Derek!
DEREK: I don't
want you to be alone.
If anything should happen
to me, I don't want it to...
Just be you.
We would make pretty babies.
So, you're thinking
about it, then?
Oh, I'm thinking about it.
MEREDITH: Wait.
Dr. Grey? Dr. Grey?
Your husband is here.
Hey.
Apparently, I'm your
emergency contact.
I had a baby.
I know.
Derek is dead.
MEREDITH: Derek?
(SIGHS)
Derek?
DEREK: If there's a
crisis (BABY COOING)
you don't freeze.
You move forward.
You get the rest of
us to move forward.
Because you've seen worse.
You've survived worse.
It's okay.
You go.
DEREK: And you
know we'll survive, too.
(BABY GURGLING)
(BABY CRYING)
Hey.
(CRYING CONTINUES)
Okay, sweetie. Okay.
Hey. Hey. It's okay.
It's all right.
Shh.
Baby's name is
Ellis. Did you see her?
(CHUCKLES)
She's beautiful.
Bet she looks just like you.
(CHUCKLES)
I didn't think I could do it.
Part of me thought, "What if I
have this baby and just die?"
And then she arrived,
and I saw her face,
and I saw him in her.
She's beautiful.
(SIGHS)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(LAUGHS)
Happy Valentine's Day.
Happy everybody's day!
Oh, my child is with
his dad in Disney World.
He's in the happiest
place on earth. Mmm-hmm.
I'm with you.
Naked, in this house.
That's a whole different
kind of happy place.
(LAUGHS)
(LAUGHING) Now
everybody's happy!
Well, then, this is
a very good time
to give you a present.
(GASPS)
Ben! Is this the
plane tickets to Paris?
Oh, 'cause if this is the
plane tickets to Paris.
It's my living will. (CHUCKLES)
It gives you full permission to
pull my plug whenever you see fit.
No extraordinary
measures, witnessed
and notarized.
Miranda? So, um, before,
you wanted to be kept alive.
Before, you wanted
extraordinary measures
because you had this stupid idea
that you were gonna
be a miracle man
and wake up and come
back to me, but now
you signed the papers?
Well... Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
I mean, that's what you wanted.
We've been going 'round
and 'round about it for months,
and, I just got tired of arguing,
so I decided to go ahead
and sign the papers.
Miranda?
Well, this was the meanest
thing you've ever done.
What?
You no longer love me
enough to hope for a miracle?
Oh, are you kidding me?
(COUGHS)
From the beginning, you were
shouting, "Unplug me! Unplug me!"
Yeah, but you weren't
supposed to do it.
I mean, you were, but you
weren't supposed to want to.
Now you want to?
Miranda, why are you
being so crazy about this?
What's going on?
Hey... What is going
on? (FIRE CRACKLING)
I love you too much!
It's too much.
(BREATHES RAGGEDLY)
Okay, my first husband...
Okay, if he left...
A piece of me always
knew that I would be okay,
and when he did
leave, I was, but you...
Ever since Derek died,
I sit up in the middle of the
night, gasping for air, terrified.
I've been having these dreams
that something happened to you.
So, if something happened...
I love you too much.
Like, you are a piece of me.
I love you.
So...
I need a plan. I need rules.
I need some order,
and I had just gotten used to
your dumb miracle-man idea,
and now you're telling me
you want me to pull the plug,
and I can't deal with that.
I... Mmm, just order
and, uh, some rules
and a plan and some
order in the middle of this,
'cause if I have to think
about what could happen,
it's too much.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I promise... I promise
that I will let you die first.
(CHUCKLES)
That
is so wrong!
I love you too much, too.
Here, let's not think about
this anymore, all right?
(SIGHS)
We can't plan. We don't know.
So let's ignore it
and just stay here in
our bubble, all right?
Here, together.
(CHUCKLES)
In the happiest place on earth.
(SIREN WAILING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
CATHERINE: Richard Webber!
Catherine?
I'm mad at you!
I'm doing something
I swore I never would.
I'm asking a question
when I don't know the answer
because you... What's going on?
(SHUSHING)
Because you're worth me
standing here like a fool,
announcing how I feel
in front of the entire hospital!
(ALL MURMURING)
I love you, Richard Webber!
I love you.
And I would very much like
for you to be my husband.
That is, of course, if
you would like it, too.
(MURMURING CONTINUES)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Well, about damn time.
(LAUGHS) (CHEERING
AND APPLAUDING)
(WHISTLING)
(ELLIS COOING)
Come on, Zo, let's get Bailey
and your little sister settled in.
(SIGHS)
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(LAUGHTER)
Now, wait, hang on. Alex
hosted a Christmas party?
Mmm. "Hosted" is a bit
of an exaggeration, right?
Whatever. There was a tree.
Yeah, there was a
sad, sad tree, God.
ELLIS: I have to
believe there's a way.
There has to be a way
to step off the carousel,
to start again, to start fresh.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
ELLIS: There has to be a way
to leave all my ghosts behind.
I'll see you around.
You're anything but
ordinary, Meredith.
It's a choice.
It's a choice I'm making.
To move forward.
To move past this.
I can do that.
MIRANDA: You ready for this?
MEREDITH: I am.
10 blade.
All I have to do is begin.