Who do I gotta screw to get
some health care around here?
Well, honey?
Try an intern. They're
always hard up.
- Come on, Jeremy. I'll take you back.
- Where?
To see the doctor.
- My dad here yet?
- No. He's on his way.
Did I give my ticket to you?
Just a little longer, sir.
Don't make me late. My
baggage went through.
Right. Come on, Jeremy.
Eleven-year-old
boy with multiple lacs.
Hey, how you doing, little man?
TV fell on him. Kids
were home alone.
Okay. We'll get
to him real soon.
- Standard of care is primary...
- Standard of care is for rookies.
Get him started, Jane.
Dr. Pratt will be right there.
And I got a real winner for you:
Belly pain with
combustible breath.
- That creepy homeless guy?
- I don't think he's homeless.
How about we wait till he sobers
up? I'll be home in bed by then.
- He needs to be examined, Pratt.
- I'll take care of it.
- How long has he been here?
- Oh, about two hours.
He thinks he's in an airport.
He's altered? - A little.
You ask me, we need one
line for legitimate patients...
- another for the rest.
- Good thing nobody asked.
UTI, dislocated shoulder, and rapid
hair loss all need to be signed out.
I haven't been this starved
since the last Burning Man festival.
- Who wants some 'za?
- You just had a burger.
- Fast metabolism.
- Pratt.
Wheezing guy was
driving insomnia lady crazy.
- So I moved him into Exam 3.
- Okay, beautiful.
Okay. Who's the lucky bastard
that gets to take my blood?
- I need CBC, LFTs and amylase.
- I'll do it.
- Is this about your needle stick?
- Yeah.
Well, you gotta do what
you gotta do, right? Heh.
This is Dr. Barnett from County.
I'll take six... No,
make that seven.
Two pepperoni, two sausage and pepper,
two Hawaiian and one with the works.
It's, let's see, 11:23 right now,
so we'll get that at 12:03, right?
All right, man. Cool.
Seven pies? What was that about?
Guaranteed delivery within
40 minutes or there's no charge.
What the guy doesn't know is Wacker's
closed and The Loop is a parking lot.
There is such a
thing as a free lunch.
Luka, belly-pain
guy's going down.
Somebody bring a gurney.
Sir? Open your eyes, sir.
Hey, doctor. No way.
Uh-uh. I was here before him.
Vitals were normal
when I triaged him.
That nurse told me I was next!
Diaphoretic. Carotid's
weak and thready.
- Seventy systolic.
- Is that what it takes?
Flopping around on
the floor like I'm dying?
Yeah, don't push me! Watch me!
- Hey! Watch! Okay, here we go!
- Get him on O2 right away.
Hey! Look at me!
- Look! See me?
- My bag.
My bag. I want my bag.
- I got it!
Start the EKG in
case he's having an MI.
What about me, huh?
I might have an MI too!
- Any history of hepatitis?
- Huh?
Abby, can you give us a hand?
- What about my blood draw?
- I'll write you a note.
- What are you doing?
- Get a 12-lead going.
- Where am I?
- Sam, got the IV?
- What are you doing?
- Okay.
- Hey, Pratt, can you spare Jane?
- Definitely.
Document everything
we do and the time.
- Isn't that usually a nurse's job?
- There's a nurses' shortage.
- Haven't you heard?
- What are you doing? Stop!
I may not know what to write.
- I'll tell you.
Start with two
liters of O2 at 11:25.
- Pulse ox, 98.
- Ow.
That's my bag. Give
me my bag back.
- I'll give you your bag back...
- Get your hands off of me!
- Calm down.
- Knock it off!
Okay? We're here to help you.
We can try the nice way
or we can try other options.
- This is how you help?
- Yeah, that's right, sir.
JVD is 10 centimeters.
The EEG is printing.
- Chart it.
- Eleven twenty-six.
Got your line. What
do you want sent?
- Abby?
- CBC, Chem-20, PT/PTT...
troponin, type and hold.
And add a serum ammonia.
EKG looks good. There's
no ischemic changes.
- Mm-hm.
- Excuse me. Excuse me.
Hey. Hey!
Hey. My name is
Charlie Metcalf, okay?
- Okay?
- Okay.
Ouch! Don't! PRATT: Okay.
I'm not gonna hurt you, okay?
- Dr. Kovac.
- Okay, let's get him gowned.
We need you to work with us,
Mr. Metcalf. This will be much easier.
- What's the trouble?
- Possible extensive tendon lac.
Okay. Can you move
your toes up and down?
- How did that happen?
- My sister pulled the television down.
It was an accident.
I guess it's true then, huh?
TV really is bad for kids.
- Where were your parents?
- My dad was at work.
- Babysitter?
- We can't afford one.
I watch after Steffie.
Can't afford a babysitter
but they got a TV.
Luka? KOVAC:
Somebody call the dad?
The neighbor who brought him in.
Get him cleaned up
and send for x-rays.
We have three TVs.
- That IV making you feel better?
- Yeah. Yeah, look.
Before... I'm sorry.
- I just was getting a little...
- Shh, shh.
Eleven twenty-seven,
300 cc bolus is in.
Pulse down to 110.
No murmur, rubs or gallops.
Multiple spider angiomas
on the chest wall.
Watch my stomach. Watch...
- Have you seen a doctor lately?
- Um, it's been a couple of years.
- Do you have a primary-care physician?
- No. Not at the present time.
- I need a 5-0 nylon.
- Oh.
Over there.
Who were you seeing
a couple of years ago?
I don't remember the guy's
name. Some doctor in Taylorville.
Taylorville?
- You live there?
- Yeah.
- There's a prison there, right?
It's a correctional facility.
What's the big deal?
I knew somebody who spent time there.
- Yeah, small world.
Positive fluid
wave. Liver is small.
- Ascites?
- Yeah.
What's that?
It means you have
fluid in your belly.
So, what were you in for?
- A mistake.
What you mean?
You weren't framed?
Spleen's enlarged.
Chart a BP, 100/70 at 11:28.
KOVAC: Caput medusae.
What kind of mistake?
I killed a guy.
Palmar erythema
and muscle atrophy.
- Oh, yeah? For what?
- For asking too many damn questions.
HemoCue is 7.2. KOVAC: Yeah.
- My dad here yet?
- No, not yet.
- Hey, kid.
- Don't look at him. Just look this way.
- Hey, pally.
- Don't worry about him.
- Mr. Metcalf.
- What?
Mr. Metcalf, you're very anemic and
you could be losing blood from an ulcer.
You a drinker?
Yeah.
- Drinking in jail?
- Yeah.
Not gonna rat me
to my parole board?
Important we know
what you've been taking.
Pruno. Breakfast of felons.
Now I drink wine, beer, I don't
know, anything I can get my hands on.
- Pruno?
- Yeah.
It's fruit...
Fruit and bread
from the cafeteria.
You put it in a garbage bag with
toilet water and then you let it ferment.
Ow, ow, ow, ow.
- Ferment where?
- Under the bed.
You strain it through your
socks and then you're ready to go.
If you're desperate,
it tastes like a martini.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah. You don't know
what it's like to need a drink.
I can imagine. METCALF: Yeah.
To check for blood loss, we're
gonna have to do a rectal exam.
A what? No, no, no.
I spent the last nine
years avoiding rectals. No.
It's the only way
for me to know...
You gonna stick
your finger up my ass?
- My gloved and lubricated finger, yeah.
- No. No.
It's smaller than your
bowel movements.
Listen, boss. Exit
only, you understand?
Exit only.
If you're bleeding internally,
it could be life-threatening.
Okay, fine.
Can I...? Maybe we can
cover me up or something? Ow!
- I don't want it!
- Hey, would I hurt you?
No! I don't want it!
I'm not gonna hurt you, okay?
I want my dad. - Don't worry.
- Where's my dad?
- Look at me. I'm not gonna hurt you.
I want my dad!
- I don't wanna get a shot. PRATT:
I'm not gonna hurt you, okay?
Pally?
- What's your name?
- Jeremy.
Jeremy, you know, the way
I see it, doctors are mean.
They wanna make us
cry. But you know what?
If you don't, I won't.
What do you say?
Let's show them.
Let's both not cry.
Okay, kid?
Okay, Jeremy.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's all right. See?
That's it. Don't worry.
It's okay. There it is.
Good job. That's it.
See? Hey, that
wasn't bad, was it?
We have to put a
tube down your nose...
into your stomach to figure
out what's causing the bleeding.
No, the docs in the joint gave
me one of those for my pancreatitis.
We're gonna numb it
up so it won't be so bad.
We won't keep the tube in any
longer than necessary, okay?
Sit him up.
Ohh.
- You know I used to be an artist?
- Open.
Pressure's up to 110/76.
- What kind of artist?
- I did some painting.
A mural for my wife's church.
You know, mostly I earned
my living as a contractor...
a carpenter, that sort of
thing. Fixing old places up.
Y'all could use my
help around here.
If you swallow it while we
pass it, it will go down easier.
All right, all right, all right.
Okay.
It's going down.
Keep swallowing. It's
going down. That's good.
Very good.
All set. Relax.
Okay. Hook it up to low suction.
I was mixed up before.
I get confused in my head.
But I'm better now.
Like you think
you're going on a trip?
In the waiting room, you kept
asking me what time your flight was.
Sometimes it's a train or a bus.
Sometimes it's a boat.
One time I was getting
ready to parachute.
Is that what the
suitcase is all about?
No, I always have that.
You leave anything at the flop, it
won't be there when you get back.
Those scumbags steal it.
NG output is one liter at 11:32.
Looks too dark for an ulcer.
- Varices?
- What's that?
That's when the elevated
pressure in your liver backs up.
The veins of the esophagus
become engorged...
and can bleed a lot.
Sometimes uncontrollably.
Emesis basin.
You made me worse.
- Get it out of me.
- No, no.
- That has to stay in.
- Get it out of me!
Okay, soft restraints!
- Get the tube out.
- Pressure's dropping, 82/66.
- Tachy at 130.
- Two units of type-specific.
- And call GI down here now!
- He needs a room.
No, no, no. Don't, don't.
Trauma 1 is open.
Okay, Mr. Metcalf, is there
anyone we can call for you?
- You mentioned you had a wife.
- No.
- Children? Siblings or anyone?
- Nobody that will come.
Let's get him to X-ray.
You stay with him, okay?
- I'll see you in an hour.
- Pratt, with us.
Make it four
units, type-specific.
Take too long. Get
O-neg out of the cooler.
Get these off me. Don't tie me
down. You can't keep tying me down!
Let's go. Prime
the rapid infuser.
Subclavian on the right?
- Prep the chest.
Let's go. Prime the rapid infuser.
- Subclavian on the right?
- Okay, prepping the chest.
- O-neg here.
Squeeze in the first unit.
Sam, second on the infuser.
- Pratt...
- Push the octreotide.
- Been paying attention, huh?
- Need me to do something?
Yes. Cycle the
dynamap when it's ready.
A little Sandostatin's not gonna
make his chances any better.
- It will diminish blood flow.
- But what's the point?
- The odds of him making it are what?
- Another 200 cc's out the NG tube.
He's that sick even
though he was just lucid?
He's on the edge.
All he needs is a push.
You know what? We
got a lot of hands in here.
- You don't wanna help...
- You're an Attending now?
No one wants to be a nurse anymore?
- Pratt, come on.
- Prick.
- That's enough!
- Heart rate's up to 140.
- Is he taking any meds?
Check his bag. He said
all his stuff was in there.
- First unit's up.
- Eleven thirty-five.
- Pushing 50 mics of octreotide.
- All right.
Guide wire's passing.
Yo, hair of the dog.
- A hundred and fifty-one proof.
- This guy's a class act.
- Ready with your extension tubing.
- What's your problem?
We're killing ourselves for
a non-compliant, alcoholic...
- ex-con with end-stage liver failure.
- You wanna get out? Get out.
You know what? It's Friday.
I don't do lost causes on
Friday. It's a religious thing.
Second unit's going in.
Anything else in that bag
we need to know about?
No, but there's a picture. It looks
like him and his wife and a kid.
Here's a bunch
of letters, a journal.
Pressure's 98/62 at 11:37.
And I don't know,
some kind of painting.
- Where's my passport?
- Where's your what?
Give me my passport.
- I can't go without my shoes.
- Go where, Mr...? Ho, ho. ho.
- Let me go. Let me go.
- Okay.
- Head up to 20 degrees.
- Let me go.
- And check on GI again.
- Let me go. Thank you.
- I'll be right back.
- Get them off. Get them off.
Do you have a problem with me?
- No.
- With Sam?
- I was out of line.
- Okay. Let's go.
The guy's a waste, dying from
something that he's doing to himself.
Last time I checked,
alcoholism was a disease.
So was suicide. He should
catch that and save us the trouble.
- We get ones like this every day.
- Then maybe I need a day off.
- It's personal?
- I guess.
Good. Then we don't
have to talk about it.
- You like riding me?
- I don't think I do.
No. Ever since I was an
intern, you've been on my back.
- Maybe a couple of times.
- Why?
You're good, Pratt. But I
think you could be better.
There's a number
you wrote with a name.
Bobby? Should we
call him, Charlie?
No. No. Don't call him, please.
I don't want anybody to call him.
- Okay.
- Okay? You understand? No calling.
- I don't want to see him.
- GI's on their way.
Mr. Metcalf, the veins at the end of
your esophagus are bleeding a lot.
This is a result
of your cirrhosis.
That also means you have less
than a 50-percent chance of surviving.
Less than surviving for
how long? A few months?
"Months" months? What...? What?
Not that long.
What we need to know is, if you
stop breathing or your heart gives out...
do you want us to
use heroic measures?
Do heroic what?
Do you want us to do
CPR, shock your heart...
- or put you on a breathing machine?
- Wait, wait, wait.
You're saying now?
You're... You're saying
now? You mean, like, today?
No, no, no. Look, no. I have
a lot of things that I have to do.
- Okay.
- I'm just not ready. I'm not ready.
- I'm...
- Okay. Okay. The man wants it all.
Okay.
I'm Adler from GI. How bad? Hmm?
About two and a
half liters of output.
Pre-load the scope with
a Saeed Six-Shooter.
What? What's a Six-Shooter?
We're going to look
down your esophagus...
and try to bend the
veins to stop the bleeding.
- What's the deal with your suction?
- Turn it up.
- I did. SAM:
Nothing's coming out.
- Great. KOVAC:
Check in 2, Abby.
Jane, get on the
phone about a portable.
- You guys have suction in here?
- Last time I checked.
- What time is it?
- Eleven forty. Why?
They got 23 minutes
or we eat for free.
- Hey, is your patient stable?
- Smoke inhalation with wheezing.
- Okay. We need the room.
- You into pepperoni, Abby?
- You have ADD? Come on, let's go.
- Give us two minutes to finish.
- We need it now. We're good here.
- The guy just needs to be tubed.
- This guy might need to be pronounced.
- Hope you're not a veggie...
- because I got meat on everything.
- See you later.
- Cetacaine and bite block.
- Little more numbing spray, Charlie?
Okay, push two of Versed.
All right, Charlie.
Once we're ready to start
you're gonna have to keep this...
between your teeth. It stops you
from biting the fiber-optic scope.
- Check the monitor.
- Is this Bobby?
- Charlie? Is that your son?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- And your wife?
- Uh-huh. Evelyn.
Pretty. You want me to call her?
No. No. She's gone.
It's been a long time.
Well, what about Bobby? He
must be all grown-up by now.
Yeah. He's 19. He's gonna be
20 next month. He's in college.
Well, let's try to
reach him, okay?
Heh. I haven't talked to
him since he was little.
His aunt gave me that number
when I got out of prison, but I...
Well, that's all the more
reason to use it now.
Let's pull the NG.
Okay, Charlie. Here we go.
- How's pressure?
- 108/58.
Okay, ready to go. SAM: Hi.
I'm looking for Bobby Metcalf.
Okay. Yeah. You know what? Can
you actually wake him up for me?
Hi, Bobby? My name
is Samantha Taggart.
I'm a nurse at the County
General in Chicago.
- Grade-two varices?
- Grade three.
Yeah. We have
your father here and...
Yeah. And he's pretty sick.
Four columns, two hemorrhagic.
Two bands at each bleeding
site, one at the others.
No... He's out. Well,
he's out of jail, yeah...
I don't know. For a while, I think.
- Systolic's down to 90.
Is there any way you can
come here and be with him?
Probably the Versed.
Five-hundred cc saline bolus.
No. You know what? He can't talk
right now because he's in a procedure.
Sucking the varix into the cap.
Wait... Okay, hold on.
He wants to talk to you.
Sorry, that needs to stay in.
And...
firing.
Mm. Okay, let's talk.
Okay, guys. I'm gonna put Mr. Metcalf's
son on the phone for a minute, okay?
Bobby?
- Dad? Is it you?
- Yeah.
- It's me.
- So you're sick, huh? You dying?
- No, no, no.
- Nurse, is he dying?
He's very sick.
What am I supposed to say?
Huh, Dad?
It's been a long time.
So many things I...
- Yeah.
- I don't know. I...
- Hey, Dad.
- Yeah?
Nice knowing you.
I told you, you
shouldn't call him.
Firing. Good.
Turn up my suction.
- Can you band it?
- Not if I can't see it.
Mr. Metcalf?
- BP 68/32.
- Mr. Metcalf?
I can't even feel a pulse.
- Bobby.
Bobby.
- Bobby! PRATT:
He's bleeding out.
Okay, turn him over.
Another two units on
the infuser. Ambu-bag.
Come on in. The water's warm.
Try the femoral. ABBY:
Get another four units here.
FFP after these two.
Hey. Hey, you
dumb son of a bitch.
Hey, you dumb son of a bitch.
Thought we lost you
there for a second.
- Bobby?
- We had him on the phone.
Is he coming?
No. No, he's not coming, man.
BP's 86/42 at 11:44.
Want the FFP?
Yeah. Another
unit of packed cells.
Dr. Kovac.
How long have you been out
of touch with him? Your son?
A long time. Since
I went to prison.
Well, even in prison,
he's still your kid.
Blood's here.
You don't know what it's like.
If I had a kid, I'd do everything
I could to stay with him.
Need a Linton tube, a
Kelly, and a 60-cc syringe.
You think you
know, but you don't.
How it could all switch on you.
Life could turn on a dime.
Gets broke and you can't...
You can't see a way to fix it.
Mr. Metcalf, the specialist thinks we
can't control the bleeding with the scope.
So you want a Linton tube?
- What?
We pass a large
balloon into your stomach.
So it helps us keep
pressure on your veins.
All right. What's there to lose?
I'll test the balloon.
It was April 10th, 1992.
When Bobby was turning 8.
My wife asked me to go
get some stuff for the party.
But I stayed so I could finish
putting together this robot for him.
You know, so I made her go.
From the street I hear a thud.
This scream.
And I go to the
window to look out.
And she's lying there like
she's asleep on the street.
And ice-cream cake...
Ice-cream cake was all
around her on the pavement.
Five syringes.
So there I am. There I am
with this little boy to raise.
And what do I do?
I start drinking.
I get high.
I can't keep it together.
Then I stab some guy at a bar.
Just for... Just for nothing.
For nothing. Because
he looked at me wrong.
This one's good.
We can go up to
750 for hemostasis.
Okay. Ready, Mr. Metcalf?
Uh...
Oh, oh. KOVAC: Where
was your son after that?
With my wife's folks.
Listen for bowel sounds.
At first they would bring
him by on visiting days...
but after a while that stopped.
Then the letters started
coming back unopened.
You know what? I don't feel
good. Something's wrong.
Something's wrong.
BUN, 74. Creatinine, 8.2.
Okay. Call Renal
and throw in a Foley.
Hey. We should think about TIPS.
What's that?
TIPS stands for Transjugular
Intrahepatic Portosystemic Shunt.
It... Uh...
We put a catheter from
your neck to your belly.
By bridging the two vessels, we bypass
the liver and slow down the bleeding.
- How much time would that give me?
- It's hard to say.
- No urine output. ABBY:
Hepatorenal syndrome.
- Your kidneys are not working.
- He needs dialysis.
I'll make the call.
Okay. GSW to the belly.
- Not here, Chuny.
There's nowhere else. - Okay.
Move him over and keep
traction on the Linton.
Hold on. Okay, go ahead.
Okay, let's transfer
him. One, two, three.
No meds, no allergies,
no past history.
NG, Foley, and a portable chest.
- Bastard shot me for stealing my spliff.
- I need another nurse.
Said it was his, but it was
mine. Rolled it this morning.
- What's going on?
- They need to stabilize him.
I want my own damn room!
Get the hell out of here, man.
- Screw you, jerk-off. KOVAC:
Okay. Doctors only talking now.
Damn, that's hard.
Even a gunshot in the belly
don't buy a man some privacy. Ow!
Okay. Two grams of
cefoxitin, IV piggyback.
It's a house we
rented one summer.
There's a lake nearby. I
took Bobby fishing there.
Periumbilical GSW
with intestinal prolapse.
- What about the on-deck batter?
- We're waiting for a TIPS and IR.
That sounds bad. Let's
get him up for an ex-lap.
Portable monitor. Let's go.
- What about x-rays?
- Get them upstairs.
T minus 11 minutes
on those pizzas.
IR's already on the
floor. Renal's on the way.
Luka, he's getting tremulous.
I haven't had a
drink since last night.
- It's alcohol withdrawal.
- Dr. Pratt?
- Yeah, that would be me.
- Hey. Ramirez, Nephrology.
- Who's this guy? RAMIREZ:
We'll need central access.
He's got a subclavian. - Great.
- Let's consent him and start the run.
- What? What is he talking about?
He's here for the
dialysis that we discussed.
I never discussed it.
You discussed it. I
never discussed it.
- Alfonso, how are you?
- Is this a TIPS patient?
Yeah. And we should go first.
- What are you talking about?
- That's what's gonna prolong his life.
Without the dialysis he'll bleed
out the minute you spike his liver.
What? What...? Spike my liver?
Will his pressure even tolerate
dialysis if the varices bleed?
- I don't understand. What...?
- I can support his pressure.
The Linton is
supporting his pressure.
- What are you talking about?
- Dr. Kovac?
Well, he's gonna need
dialysis three times a week.
- Oh, yeah. For the rest of his life.
- TIPS is not a cure.
- It's a bridge to a liver transplant.
- We know that's not gonna happen.
Hey, hey, hey. I'm right here.
- Yeah.
- Talk to me.
Sorry.
Now, you can't fix my kidneys?
You're gonna need
dialysis three times a week.
And what about my liver
problem and the bleeding?
- The TIPS is a temporary measure.
- Your best hope is for a liver transplant.
I don't understand.
What are the odds of that?
Based on your history
of drinking, not good.
Is there any chance that I'm
gonna be walking out of here?
With the dialysis
and the TIPS...
I mean, today.
What are the chances that I'm
gonna walk out of here today?
None.
I don't want it.
I don't want anything, then.
If you don't have the TIPS
procedure, we can't control the bleeding.
- You'll die.
- Yeah, I get it. I get it.
Just stop everything.
- No blood transfusions? No breathing...?
- No, it's over.
No CPR? METCALF: No.
I need it to be
very clear, Charlie.
If we don't continue with the treatment,
do you understand what could happen?
Yeah.
Okay. Mr. Metcalf is a DNR.
Eleven fifty-seven.
Wait. Wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Hey, hey, he's not
competent. Come on.
That's what he wants, Pratt.
Can you...?
Can you do something for this?
Hey, could we put
him on an alcohol drip?
- You're gonna get me drunk?
- Just enough to stop tremors, Charlie.
Charlie, let us do the procedure.
You don't have to do this.
Call...
Try Bobby again.
Try my boy. Get
him on the phone.
If he knows it's
really over, he'll come.
Okay? He'll come.
Okay.
Hey, Bobby Metcalf?
Oh, yeah. It's the
hospital calling again.
Yeah. Do you think
you could do that?
Okay. Thank you.
- What happened?
- He went to class.
His roommate's gonna
see if he can find him.
Can you take this
out? It's uncomfortable.
- The tube's keeping you alive.
- It's uncomfortable. Please.
Okay.
Is there...? Is there a window?
Can you open a window and get
some fresh air in here? Please?
Sam. METCALF: Please.
All right. Here we go.
- What is that? Lincoln Street?
- Harrison.
I've worked here over a year.
Never thought about what was outside.
I worked here for six.
Uh... Oh.
It's from the tube. I'll take care of it.
Ten percent ethanol at 100 cc's an hour.
You know, your booze works fast.
Mad Dog IV, just for you.
All this stuff, you know...
it's just blinders.
It's just a screen.
I don't want anything separating
me from what's happening.
I'm not gonna run
and hide from this.
Pulse ox and
dynamap can come off.
Last sats, 92.
My brother Lou died
when we were kids.
My mom, she said...
Ohh...
She said, "Charlie, Lou's
gone away on a long trip."
Don't you just leave me here.
I wanna see a doctor now.
Last sats, 92.
When is my turn, huh?
When is it going
to be my turn, huh?
People? When is it?
When is my turn?
Pulse, 104.
Resps, 18.
Temp, 98.2.
Ninety-two.
91/60.
One-oh-four.
One-seventy. Ninety-one.
- What are you saying?
- It's your vitals.
- Is it starting?
- What, Charlie?
Am I going?
It's starting.
Don't you people have a system?
Isn't there any method at all?
Don't worry. You won't be alone.
Good. That's good.
Someone will stay with you.
Sam, you get this?
Could you touch me?
Sorry?
My face?
Please?
Uh...
Maybe we should anchor.
- What?
- Do you think we should keep going?
I don't know, Charlie.
Well, what about him?
What do you think he wants?
I don't know. I
don't think he knows.
Is it too late?
Not if you don't
want it to be, Charlie.
Watch it!
Oh, no. Oh, no.
Oh, no.
I feel drunk again.
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
Sure.
Okay, Mr. Metcalf. We're
gonna keep a heart monitor on...
- and the alcohol drip for comfort.
- Okay.
I wanna take you off
the octreotide now...
which is the last
support measure.
Okay.
- Shouldn't be long now.
- Okay.
I never believed in God.
That might bite me
in the ass now, huh?
God will get over it.
Do you need this?
- Can I take it?
- Take it.
Take it.
What?
- What can I take?
- No, never mind. Never mind.
What's it gonna be like there?
Peaceful.
No.
- Come back.
- Charlie.
Charlie.
Get all my stuff?
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Make sure he gets it.
I will.
And give this to him.
You never knew your dad.
No.
That's too bad.
I don't let it bother me.
I bet it bothers him.
Bobby.
Let me in.
Open up.
Charlie, can you hear me?
Hey, pally.
You made it.
How do I look?
You look okay.
I'm so sorry.
Don't think about that.
Okay?
Just take it easy.
It's okay, son.
It's...
Um...
Twelve-oh-four.
I'll take that.
Can someone just tell me that?
How much longer?
Ma'am, you need to
wait in the room. Let's go.
It's about time. Been with the
same patient for almost 45 minutes.
Whatever happened to
"treat them and street them"?
Do as I say, not as I do.
All right. The TV
kid's back from X-ray.
He's in Triage with
his dad and his sister.
Things go south?
He was a nice guy.
Just a drunk.
There's pizzas over
here if you get hungry.
Got you one with anchovies.
Oh, and the delivery guy got here
at 12:04. You know what that means?
It means he didn't
make it on time.
Means lunch is on
the house, my friend.
Hey, Jeremy, little man.
Back so soon?
Hello, I'm Dr. Pratt.
I'm the one who
treated your son.