Clear.
Go again. Clear!
Still in V-fib. Been
down 28 minutes.
Hey, Carter! Hey, Dave.
Hey, man. Good to see
you. It's good to see you too.
Yeah? You miss me?
What happened to your hair?
The chief's training me
on the sternal saw today.
Hopefully we get a GSW
who needs his chest cracked.
I'll keep my fingers
crossed for you.
And, uh... Uh, this
jerk cut us off. Carter.
And then I rear-ended him.
And then the air bags went off.
That's disgusting.
Hi, Carter. Hi, Chuny.
I'm glad you're back.
She drinks anything... No!
She can get her hands on.
Probably psychogenic polydipsia.
You want to, uh, check her lytes
and then call for a
Psych consult. Agua.
Hey, Carter. Hey,
Lily. How are you?
Chuny... Weaver needs
somebody to make a blood run.
Weaver needs to get a
couple more nurses down here.
Can you tell we're short nurses?
Ha-ha.
Congratulations. John...
welcome back.
Hey, Carter! I got a live
one waiting in Exam 3.
Freak tore off all her toenails
with a pair of pliers.
What about me? I
need medical attention!
The only thing
you need is a bath.
I'll be there in
a minute, Lydia.
Can I get a doctor? Any doctor?
Hey, you. Where do
you think you're going?
Oh. I, uh... I work here.
No, that's an old ID.
Well, I've been away.
Dr. Weaver. Does
this one belong to you?
Yes, he does.
He'll need to get a
new ID from Personnel.
You can get it after your shift.
Sorry, doc.
Why not Christmas?
Next Christmas.
No, this Christmas.
Are you mad? It takes
months to plan a wedding.
Hey, Carter. Carter.
We got engaged.
We bought a house.
Wow.
Congratulations
on both accounts.
Boy, I go away for
a couple weeks...
you guys get engaged...
Chen's pregnant,
Malucci's blond, Admin
looks totally different,
and I can't seem to remember
my locker combination.
Oh. You know, the,
uh, state medical board
made us clean it out.
I'm sorry.
Where's my stuff? Uh...
Listen, I'll look into, uh,
getting your locker back.
But you can use mine until then.
Uh, look, I better run.
Listen, there's a
surgical conference today.
We're short-staffed.
Please don't let
your residents call
for any unnecessary consults.
Good luck, Carter. Thank you.
We'll talk dates later.
You ready to rock 'n' roll?
Yeah, I guess so.
Listen, if you
need anything, uh...
Talk about a case or
a patient or anything
just come find me.
I'll do that.
I will.
Hey, you got anything good?
Got a chest pain
in 2 hooked up...
I think Dr. Greene
is free. Thanks, Lily.
Sorry, Carter, but in order
to facilitate your return,
we need to
implement a few rules.
Uh-huh. Such as?
You're to do only minor
medical, no trauma.
No suturing. No
needles. No narcotics.
And absolutely no
surgical procedures.
Uh, that leaves me with...?
The chance to practice
medicine again. Okay...
Let me go! Settle
down, Mr. DiBattista!
Settle down! Let go of me!
Give me some four-by-fours!
I think I know this
guy. Stabilize his neck!
Leave me alone,
bitch! All right, that's it!
Once you get back
in the swing of things...
you can resume a normal schedule
and do procedures again.
But until then, it's baby steps.
Why don't you start with...
Mr. Griffis?
Gluteal rash.
Nothing worse than a
chapped ass. Or so I'm told.
Dr. Carter. When
did you get out?
A couple weeks ago.
Well, I got a patient.
Go forth and heal.
So who's watching
the drugstore cowboy?
I'm head of the ER.
That makes Carter
my responsibility.
Correct me if I'm wrong, but
didn't he develop drug addiction
under your eye? Is there
something you need?
Do I need to have a reason
to come down and say hello?
But now that I'm down
here, perhaps you can tell me
who replaced all the candy
bars in the vending machines
with raisins and rice cakes?
You're here because
you need a sugar fix?
We're a hospital. We're
setting a good example
by offering healthy snacks.
So, what are you,
the nutrition Nazi?
America's poor eating habits
help keep us in business.
Did you even take
the Hippocratic oath?
I had my fingers crossed.
Oh... Dr. Romano? Dr. Chen.
Well... I guess I
don't have to ask
what you've been up to.
Look, um, I... I need a favor.
Well, if it's about taking
time off, talk to Weaver.
Maternity leave is a topic
for those bearing ovaries.
No. It's about my parents.
I figured you'd run into
them today at the conference.
I'll say hello. Well, actually,
um, I haven't told them
that I'm pregnant yet,
and... I'd really appreciate
your not saying anything.
Um... I-I want to surprise them.
How? By going into
labor at Sunday dinner?
"Mom's" the word.
Just a little longer.
I've already been
here three hours.
How long is this gonna take?
Abby, what are you doing
here? Looking for Weaver.
She's under the impression
I'm her own personal temp.
She's next door. Thanks.
Is somebody gonna dig
this wood out of my butt
before it sprouts roots or what?
Would you mind, before you
go, removing some splinters?
Can't you do it?
Weaver won't let me
use any instruments.
Oh. Okay. Sure. Just a minute.
You need an ortho surgeon
for a closed reduction.
I've been paging them every
five minutes for half an hour.
Call the attending, tell
them you're Weaver.
That usually will
scare somebody down.
Excuse me. Dr. Greene?
Uh, I've got a 9-year-old
boy who got hit in the larynx
with his skateboard.
He's pretty hoarse.
Uh-huh. Any sub-Q emphysema?
No. Uh, everything's okay.
No stridor, good sats, and
he's handling secretions.
- He woke up with pain.
- Visualize his cords?
Well, our scope
is being serviced.
I paged Head and
Neck to bring one down,
but I've been
waiting three hours.
Yes. Yes. It's moved to the
lower right quadrant. Yes.
Yup, we're gonna have to
scope him. Call the attending.
Well, I tried. But, uh,
they're either in surgery
or at some damn conference.
He's too sick for a jump test!
Hold on one second.
Dave, you have a problem?
Stewart here has had two
days of vomiting and diarrhea.
Corday says it's not a
good story for an appy.
Maybe, maybe not. But
now he's got classic signs,
including guarding and
rebound tenderness.
Did you tell her that? Yeah.
But she won't come down.
She wants me to
make this poor guy
get up and jump around!
Thanks, Elizabeth.
Follow me.
Where are we going?
Dr. Weaver, did you page me?
Yes, Abby. Hi. Hi.
We need those in Exam
4. Wh... Why am I here?
We're short on nurses.
I am an OB nurse.
Are you planning on
going back to med school?
Yes. Okay. Then
you might as well work
as a nurse in the ER.
You'll see more medicine
here than upstairs.
Right. But I... I... Okay, look.
I'm offering you a
learning opportunity
that'll put you way ahead when
you come back as a student.
Which should only take
me about two more years.
It's really not so bad
down here, Abby.
Oh, yeah? Compared to what?
Excuse me.
I'm having trouble
with my card key.
What's the name?
Dr. Peter Benton.
You're not on the list.
Oh.
I just became a
surgical attending.
Gonna have to
park on the street.
I'll just park in
the visitors' area.
No, you won't. You
said you work here,
and employees can't
park in visitor spaces.
Well, if I'm an employee,
then you have to let me in.
I can't. You're not on the list.
Uh...
You've got a corneal abrasion.
Don't you mean pinkeye? Uh.
No. You've got a
scratch on your eyeball.
Probably some dirt got trapped
under the eyelid there.
Well, how on earth
would that happen? Mm.
I don't know. Maybe,
uh, the wind blew it in.
Well, the last
time I was in here,
they said I had pinkeye.
Ooh!
And crabs.
I think I might have them again.
Mm-hm. Okay.
Well, why don't we
treat one thing at a time?
I'm gonna go get
some antibiotics...
put them in your eye,
so it doesn't get infected.
Oh, will...? Will it
stop the hurting?
We'll get you
something for the pain.
Am I gonna get a patch?
I'll see what I can do.
Hello. Elizabeth.
Have you gone downstairs
to see that ruptured appy yet?
Rupture? I thought
it was a rule-out.
Well, that was 10 minutes
ago. I'm sure it's ruptured by now.
Look, I told you there's
a surgical conference,
at Rush today, and we're jammed.
If Dr. Malucci fails to give
me a good enough story...
Hey, hey, hey, hey. I gave
you a great story for an appy.
When we call for a consult,
we need you to do just that.
Well, thank you
for the clarification.
What's this?
Uh, it's just some things
we need downstairs.
Well, these "things"
belong to the OR.
Well, the surgeons
can bring them back
once they've come down
to the ER to use them.
Hello. I'm Dr. Chen.
So, Willie,
it says here that
you're having earaches.
Yeah.
Could you, uh, take off
your hat so I can have a look?
Oh.
Gee, what happened?
I couldn't stop
the bleeding. Huh.
Who did this to you?
I did.
With what?
Kitchen shears.
On purpose?
Didn't it hurt?
What do you think?
I tried to numb it with ice,
but they're still pretty sore.
Yeah, I bet.
Now, why would you give
yourself Doberman ears?
They're Vulcan.
Is that like a Shih Tzu?
Uh, no. I think he
means like Mr. Spock.
On Star Trek.
Oh. Oh, right. Right.
Okay, um...
we'll irrigate the wounds,
wrap them in saline gauze,
um, give him a DT and
run in a gram of Ancef.
Okay. Psych consult?
Yes. And I'll call Plastics.
Psych? W... Wait a second.
But I'm not... I'm not crazy.
You mutilated yourself
with kitchen shears.
How long is it gonna take?
The sci-fi convention's today.
I'm running pretty late.
We're moving at warp
speed here, Willie.
Hey. I got a present for you.
What?
One fiber-optic laryngoscope,
compliments of the OR.
Where did you get this?
Ah, you're better
off not knowing.
So you pick out
a name for the...
little bambino yet?
No. Oh, well...
Uh, let me get that.
You, uh, planning
on something Chinese
or a little bit more Western?
I haven't really
given it much thought.
Hey, you got a minute? Oh. Sure.
I got a corneal abrasion
that needs some Vicodin,
and I'm not allowed
to write for narcotics.
Yeah, I'll take it.
Uh, there's an otitis in
Exam 2 you can have.
All right. He
presented as pinkeye.
But all he needs
is the meds. Okay...
And wear this mask,
because he's pretty rank,
and he's got crabs.
Are you going
soft on me, Carter?
Uh, it looks like I
missed a few things
while I was away, huh?
Yeah.
So how far along are
you? Twenty-four weeks.
Was this planned, or...
No. Not particularly. Mm-hm.
You know, I gotta run.
Sit still so the doctor
can look at your hand.
It hurts.
We'll give you medicine
to make it better,
but you have to let us
clean out the germs first.
Abby, irrigate the wound
and start him on Augmentin.
Gloria, this looks
like a human bite.
Mm, his Uncle Charlie bit him.
Did you call Social Services?
That's Uncle Charlie.
Uh, Albert's my
grandson. Charlie's mine.
Oh. You're, uh, babysitting?
24/7 for the past two years,
if you call that babysitting.
Her daughter got involved with
someone with a drug problem.
She got pregnant. I got Albert.
How long have you
had that cough, Gloria?
Couple months. Okay.
It comes and goes. Here we go.
Do you smoke? Yeah.
But I go outside. I don't
light up around the kids.
Okay. I'd like to
get a chest x-ray.
No, I'm fine. I just need
you to look at Albert's hand.
It'll only take a few minutes.
What about Albert and Charlie?
I can take them to Daycare.
You don't have to do that.
It's not a problem. Let's go.
Let's go to the playroom.
Okay, I'll get a PA and
a lateral chest on Gloria.
Okay. Let's go.
Thanks.
Ow!
Grandma! Grandma!
Uncle Charlie bit the nurse!
Is everything gone
crazy down here?
I can't even log on
to the damn system.
Forget your password?
Uh, Dr. Romano. Here.
Peter, you're still here.
I had problems getting
into the parking garage.
Now I can't get
onto the computer.
You didn't get my
letter? What letter?
Your privileges have
been revoked. What?
Yeah, you remember that,
um, dialysis patient of yours?
Um... Uh, Fletcher.
That's right.
Well, your, uh, tattletaling
to the inspector general
cost me a $50,000 fine which,
uh, my insurance doesn't cover.
Look, I was just looking
out for my patient.
You also cost the hospital
a substantial EMTALA fine.
Now, I had to recoup those
monies from somewhere,
so I was forced to eliminate
the attending position.
It's all in the letter.
Hold on, hold on.
I mean, we can't talk
about this in private?
Why, Peter? You didn't
seem to feel the need
to talk in private
about our problem.
You just decided to
go off on your own.
So now you are.
So, what is my position here?
You have no
position here, Peter.
You're firing me?
No. No, no, no.
You fired yourself.
Hey, Cleo.
How are you at getting
insects out of little boys' ears?
Keep him still. I'll
get to him in a minute.
I brought her to the
doctor's with a sore throat.
That was three weeks ago.
She's still not getting any better.
Where are we?
I see tonsillar exudates.
What's that? Excuse me.
It's, uh, pus.
Gross.
Yeah, it looks like strep.
Did you take all the medication
the doctor prescribed last time?
Yes. She can't miss
any more school.
I'm going to order
a couple of tests
to rule out other
infections. Abby?
Rapid strep, mono spot,
Gram's stain and culture?
That'll do it. Thanks. Yep.
Abby...
can you find a room
for Mr. Duncan here?
Uh, sure.
Excuse me.
Ah, I need you to
suture a head lac, Abby.
I... I can't do that
now. I'm a nurse.
Oh, I forgot. Oh, can
you clean it up for me?
Sure. In a minute.
Abby... Abby. Just the
person I wanted to see.
Ah. Ooh, bear attack.
Listen. Um, I've got a trio of
businessmen with food poisoning.
Shoot them up with Compazine
and plug them into IV's.
And, oh, you might want to call
Housekeeping for some buckets.
Buckets?
It was an all-you-
can-eat buffet.
Hey. Anybody else need
anything? Bring it on.
If I'm being arrested,
I get a phone call.
You'll get it. There's
a phone upstairs.
Why are you letting
them move him?
The man's wanted for murder.
Lucky I recognized him.
Once a cop, always a cop.
This is not a police department.
Yeah, they can observe
him in the jail ward.
If people don't feel safe here,
they'll stop coming in when
they need medical attention.
- Only the criminals.
- I'm not talking to you.
I think we're done here.
I was still observing him.
Freaking liberal
foreigners. Uh...
It's my decision
to transfer or not.
Yeah, he's a threat to
the patients and the staff.
He needs to be in custody.
And that is my decision.
Hey, it's not so bad down here.
I'm gonna give you
some antibiotics.
But the next time that you
want to pierce your nipples,
I suggest you go to
a professional, okay?
You almost finished?
I need the bed.
Yeah.
Oh. Hey. How's it going?
Oh, great. Actually, it sucks.
I'm not allowed to do anything.
Uh, well...
Easy does it?
You might want to give
yourself a little bit of time.
Time and scut. I
got plenty of both.
It could be worse. How's that?
Did you have to pluck maggots
out of anybody's crotch today?
Ooh. I had a guy with crabs.
Ah. That's not even close.
Anything interesting
on the big board?
A UTI in Exam 2.
I was hoping for something
more than a bladder infection.
There are no small
patients, Carter.
What about dwarves?
So, Carter, you've known
Jing-Mei for a while, huh?
I knew her before
she was Jing-Mei.
So do you know
who got her pregnant?
Even if I did know that,
Dave, I don't know if I'd tell you.
That's not a definitive no.
You two haven't been...
Yeah. Uh-huh.
Sometimes this medicine
can give you muscle spasms.
Ooh!
Don't worry. That's easily
reversed with Benadryl.
And I'm sure you'll
all feel much better
after you're rehydrated, okay?
Abby. You need a hand in here?
Everything's under control.
How did you become paralyzed?
I was... I was hit by a car.
Um... on my bike.
And I would've been killed
if I wasn't wearing a helmet.
You were lucky, huh?
You know, I didn't
used to think so,
but... now I come
to the hospital,
and I see kids way
worse off than me.
It says on your chart that
you think you might have
a urinary tract infection.
Does it burn when you pee?
I don't know. I don't...
I don't feel much...
I don't feel much
below my waist.
But I can feel pressure
on my stomach...
you know, when I need to go
and, um, that's when I
know to catheterize myself.
And how often do you do that?
About every six to eight hours.
Uh, but lately I've... I've
been having to do it more,
which is usually a
sign I have an infection.
You put in your own catheters?
My grandmother used
to help me, you know.
She passed away
in... In February.
Who takes care of you now?
I live in a retirement home.
Um... you know,
it used to be me
and my grandmother,
and, you know, now it's
just me. I know that sounds...
really lame,
but it's across the
street from my school,
and some of the old
folks don't get a lot of visits
from their families, so
they like having me around.
It's kind of like having
20 grandparents, huh?
Ye... Yeah, it is.
Okay. You might
need some antibiotics.
And I'm gonna have
a nurse come in...
and get a urine sample.
Um. That's okay. I
can... I can do it myself.
I'm used to doing
stuff like that myself.
I'm gonna have a nurse
come in and help. Okay?
I seem to be a magnet
for the weird ones today.
Why? What's up with this guy?
Whoa! Oh!
Where did this water come from?
Oh. Mr. Kamatovik,
what did I tell you?
I found him soaking
his blanket in the sink.
I'm sorry. I didn't
mean to make a mess.
Mr. Kamatovik, why
is your blanket wet?
I was afraid I was gonna burn.
I have a family history of
spontaneous human combustion.
Really? Yeah.
I... I... I gotta stay wet,
or I'm gonna go up
like a Roman candle.
Oh, get that oxygen
away from me... Hey!
Unless you want this
whole place to explode!
Mr. Kamatovik,
please just sit and relax.
I'll... I'll turn off the
oxygen in the hall, okay?
Dr. Chen, let's get
Mr. Kamatovik started
on a flame-retardant saline
and get somebody down
here from the special burn unit.
Yes. Okay.
Don't worry, Mr. Kamatovik.
We've got you covered. Okay?
Hey, chief!
Woah!
Oh!
You okay? Yeah.
There's... There's a
multi-trauma coming in.
A causeway collapsed at a
sci-fi convention. I'm good.
Spin a crit, dip a urine.
C-spine, chest and
pelvis. I'll be right there.
You okay, Cleo? So far, so good.
There were so many
we had to double up.
First one's a forearm
fracture from falling concrete.
Open or closed? Closed.
Neuro-circ is intact.
Got a 10-centimeter
scalp lac. No LOC.
Olbes got a bad one in 43.
What's this?
Looks like a
dislocated shoulder.
Neck pain with
midline tenderness.
BP 125/78. Pulse 90.
You got it? Yeah.
Where do you need me?
Triage the most critical
patients to the beds.
You got it.
23-year-old man, crushed
pelvis, fell at least 20 feet.
Danny. Danny. Where is he?
Who's Danny?
He's my brother. He
was standing next to me.
I think Morales got him.
He didn't want to go today.
I made him. Danny.
Looks like a bad tib-fib.
Please, don't let him die.
Let's take care of you
first, sir. What's your name?
Sir?
Sir, open your eyes.
Losing the pulse.
Okay, let's go.
Blunt chest trauma,
tachy at 120.
Decreased breath
sounds on the left. Abby?
I said we could
handle one major.
They've got 30 critical
patients on scene, Kerry.
I told them we could take
three major and 10 minor.
How can we handle criticals if
we don't have any surgeons?
We can stabilize and triage
them to surgery one at a time.
I hope that we can, Mark.
Frank. Page the surgeons.
They're all at the
conference. Page them.
Hey, can I help? No.
Looks like you're slammed.
All the more reason for you
to take the minor
medicals. No trauma.
We need you in Trauma 1.
Let's take him
to Curtain Area 2.
Give me the
greatest hits, Morales.
32-year-old male. Walkway fell.
This guy crushed his
right foot under a girder.
- What's wrong?
- Open fracture.
- Bleeding through the perineum.
- Pressure's down to 60.
I'll put in a central line.
How's the other patient?
They're putting in a chest tube.
Elizabeth, you should
go check on him.
I can't leave this
patient. Where's Peter?
Didn't Romano fire him?
What?!
No, I saw him earlier.
Try paging him.
Go on. I can handle this.
Kerry, he needs a
MAST suit inflated,
a suprapubic Foley, and
either a pelvic embolization
or application of
the external fixator.
You can't possibly
do all of that at once.
And I'm not leaving
him until he's stable.
And the other patient
has blunt chest trauma.
He might be bleeding out.
If he is, I'm sure
Dr. Kovac will come get me.
Get me a 3-0 nylon
and an OpSite.
Got it.
Tell Mark Greene we
are closed to trauma!
Urine dip is negative for
blood. Hemoglobin's 11.6.
Get him a unit
bed. Working on it.
Third liter of
saline up at 15:10.
Pressure's down
to 60. Tachy at 130.
I have some breath
sounds on the left.
20 of etomidate, 10 of Norcuron.
I'll intubate. Abby, prep
for a chest tube on the left.
Suction.
Open a Steri-Drape.
Too much edema.
I need the fiber-optic scope.
Abby... put in the chest tube.
I can't. I'm a nurse.
This guy needs a chest tube.
You're gonna have to do it.
It's a tough intubation.
You know how.
Go!
Ten blade.
Hey, hey! Get back in
bed, Mr. Kamatovik. I...
You're not supposed to be here.
Are you feeling better?
There was probably a lot of dust
when the causeway collapsed.
It aggravated your asthma.
All right. 60 of prednisone.
Repeat nebs in 30
minutes. Sorry about that.
It's like Mars Attacks in here.
Got a 23-year-old
male with hip pain.
BP's 130/85, pulse 110.
There's no obvious deformity.
Ah! Okay.
Let's cut this off, please.
No! Don't cut my costume, man!
I need to take a
look at your hip.
The zipper's in the back.
Fine. Unzip Zontar here.
Titrate 10 of morphine.
Get a AP pelvis
and a right hip film.
Where the hell is
Benton? I think he quit.
We got a bad tib-fib fracture,
and he's losing foot pulses.
We gotta get him to the OR
now. We're short surgeons.
I thought we were
closing to traumas.
It's a little late for that
now. I'll get Corday.
Liver and spleen look good.
Excellent. Bleeding must
be limited to the pelvis.
We've a patient with probable
compartment syndrome.
Do your best to stabilize him.
I'll be there as soon as I can.
And we need the digital Stryker.
Call upstairs. No,
it's under the sink.
Dr. Greene borrowed
it from the OR.
Oh, stole it, more like.
Never mind. Let him use it.
Just tell him I want the
results of the readings.
Systolics are down to 70.
Another two units
of packed cells.
Oh, Dr. Weaver. Cops are coming
to arrest your pneumonia
mom, Gloria. For what?
Frank said for
writing bad checks.
Oh. Elizabeth, you
okay for a minute?
Yeah. Go.
Hey, did somebody get hurt?
Uh, yeah.
Hey, did that nurse come in yet
and get the urine sample?
No. What happened?
A, uh, walkway collapsed
over at the Tarver Center.
Run two units O-neg
on the rapid infuser.
Type and cross for four more.
A lot of people got
hurt, huh? Yeah.
That's too bad. I bet
they never saw it coming.
I sure didn't.
Okay. Let's get
you up here, huh?
Oh.
Uh.
I'm sorry. I... I didn't
know I had to go.
I would've cathed myself,
but I was waiting for the nurse.
It's okay. No big deal, Dennis.
Oh, uh, I'll get to him
in a minute, Carter.
Oh, that's all right.
I got this, Lydia.
They need you in
the trauma rooms.
Are you sure? Yeah. Go.
You know...
most doctors don't
like to do this stuff.
All right, let's get you...
out of those wet clothes.
BP's stable at 140/90 in
all three compartments.
His leg is cool.
He's losing
circulation to the foot.
Gloria. This is the Zithromax.
Take two tomorrow,
then one a day for
the next four days.
Is something wrong?
Yes. The police are on
their way to pick you up.
What?
They have a warrant
out for your arrest.
You know, sometimes I have to
bounce a check to buy some time.
But I... I... I usually pay
everything off in time.
I just... You know
what? I've got two jobs.
I understand. Here
we go. Right this way.
Daycare... Hey... Hey... Hey...
Day... Woah... Day... Honey,
Daycare is up this way.
The fourth floor!
Thanks for everything!
Kerry.
Oh. Tell me that
you're here to help out.
No. But I will take
Mr. Kamatovik up to Psych
once we get a bed available.
Yeah, I appreciate that,
but we could really use an
extra pair of hands down here.
Sorry. We've got our
own problems up there.
Tonight's the full moon.
Stop by... later, if you want.
It'll be like Mardi Gras.
Anterior compartment
pressure is 68.
That's not good.
Normal is 30. He
needs a fasciotomy now.
You're gonna do this?
I did one in med school...
on a cadaver.
Well, you can't do it down here.
If we don't do this now, he's
gonna need an amputation.
Get Corday on the intercom.
Dr. Corday? What is it?
We've got the pressures.
An average reading: 65.
I have to open the compartments.
Yeah, well, we're ready.
This guy's bleeding
from his pelvis.
You're gonna have to wait.
Can't wait. We've
lost foot pulses.
Look, could you get
another surgeon?
No one's here.
You're gonna have
to talk me through this.
Well, I don't think I can.
You're gonna have
to do this, Elizabeth.
Another oh-silk, please.
What are you doing?
Sewing in a chest tube.
When I said you'd get more
medical experience down here,
this is not what I meant.
Nurses do not
sew in chest tubes.
Do they, Dr. Kovac?
She knows how. Of course.
But our malpractice
insurance no longer covers her
doing anything outside the
scope of normal nursing practices.
We were short-handed.
The patient could have
died if she hadn't put it in.
You let her put
in the chest tube?
It's your responsibility
if anything goes wrong.
- She did a great job.
- That's not the point.
You should've called me.
You were busy. Step back, Abby.
I... I'm really almost done.
You know... Step back!
Get Corday some Pavulon.
I need some Pavulon.
How's it going in there?
I'll live.
Hey, do you know if we have
any extra-small scrubs in here?
Sure they'll fit you?
Ha, I got a paraplegic kid
with a UTI who just wet himself.
I want to give him something to
change into, and these are huge.
Well, don't ask me.
I didn't even know I was
working here till today.
I swear, I can't
win with Weaver.
Well, who can?
Here, she drags me down
here claiming it's for my benefit,
so I can get more experience,
but not too much experience.
Talk to your nurse
manager. Right.
And then Weaver
completely hates me
if I ever come back
as a med student.
Oh, you'll come back.
I don't know I want to.
This place is a freak show.
This place grows on
you. So does foot fungus.
Abby, get Mr. Palmer a
CBC, urine dip, myoglobin,
put in a Foley.
Uh, which one's Palmer?
Three-hundred-pounder
with blue skin.
Oh, excellent. Fat
and colorful. Here.
Hey. Well, at least you
got something to do.
I'll trade you Jabba
the Hutt for the UTI.
I said I was bored,
not desperate.
Abby. Corday's still
waiting on that Pavulon.
Right.
Your self-diagnosis
was right on!
You got a urinary
tract infection.
Hey, are these for me?
Well, you think like a doctor.
So you might as
well dress like one.
I will help you put those
on when I get back.
I'm writing you a
prescription for some Bactrim.
If you follow all the directions
and take all the pills,
you'll be better in no time.
Oh, and, uh...
think I could get some extra
catheters while I'm here?
Sometimes they forget
to order them for me.
I think we can manage that.
Really? Sure.
Thanks. Here, I
made this for you.
Hey, thanks. That's very cool.
Well, now, it's supposed
to look like an F-22 Raptor.
Oh, you like jets?
Yeah. I wanted to be a pilot.
Now I make paper
airplanes, but...
Will it fly?
Yeah.
Here. Check it out.
Frank?
Where is Frank?
Grow up, Malucci!
What did I do? You
got patients to treat.
Lydia said you
needed more Versed?
Yeah. Try another two.
There's a lot of masseter spasm.
So...
when are we gonna meet Daddy?
Huh?
The father... of your baby.
Everybody's kind of curious.
How's he doing?
He's out.
You know, my pregnancy...
is none of your business.
In fact...
nothing remotely concerned
with my personal life
is anybody's business.
I... I just wanted to
meet the lucky guy.
You do know who
the father is, right?
Hey, I'm... I'm... I'm sorry.
I can't help myself sometimes.
There's something
about seeing you this way
that I find very sexy.
I'm gonna order a
post-reduction film.
Whoa... Whoa.
Conscious-sedation protocol.
Somebody's gotta babysit
this guy till he wakes up.
Yeah? Well, I guess
that would be your job...
Dave.
Thank you.
Oh, crap. What's wrong?
Got a 16-year-old with
gonorrhea in her throat.
Her mom brought her. Now
I gotta find a way to tell her
without her mom
finding out. I'll take that.
No, that's okay. Come
on. Your hands are full.
Carter, I've got it.
Lateral incision.
Start three finger breadths
below the fibular head
and carry it down to
above the lateral malleolus.
How deep?
First incision...
just through the skin and sub-Q.
Got it.
Is there anything I can do?
Yeah. Get Elizabeth out here.
What's next?!
Now, carefully,
extend the incision through
the deep fascia of the anterior
and lateral compartment.
What about the
anterior tibial nerve?
You should be okay.
Don't cut too deep, and
you'll stay superficial to it.
How's he doing?
Who? Mark or my patient?
I'm gonna need
more type-specific.
Hey, Moira. Where's your mom?
She went to find you.
She was getting really
pissed off waiting around.
Well, it's good she's not here.
Why?
You have a sexually
transmitted disease.
What?
You contracted gonorrhea.
Wait. But that's impossible.
I... I've never even
had sex. I'm a virgin.
What about oral sex?
That doesn't count.
Oh, God.
You and your boyfriend both
need to be treated with antibiotics.
He gave me
gonorrhea in my throat?
Have you had any more partners?
I'm not a slut.
I didn't even want to
do it in the first place.
Then don't.
You're not gonna
tell my mom, right?
No. But you have to promise me
you're going to
practice safe sex.
I thought I was.
All right.
Yes.
Hello? Hey, it's me.
Peter?
What are you doing home?
There was a surgical conference,
so all elective surgery
was canceled today.
I figured I'd come home
and hang out with Reese.
Oh. Being an attending
has its privileges.
Hey, man.
Hey. Reese. How are you?
What's happening?
Hey. What's this?
What you playing with, huh?
Playing with your fire
truck? Want to be a fireman?
Huh? What's that?
Horse, huh? You
want to be a cowboy?
Looks like I'm gonna have
two doctors in the family.
How much longer am
I gonna have to wait?
Have a seat. Someone
will see you in a minute.
I've been seen. She disappeared.
Who's that? I don't
know. Some black woman.
She came into the room,
looked at my daughter's
throat three hours ago!
What's your daughter's name?
Garvey. This is ridiculous!
Mrs. Garvey. Oh, there she is.
Where have you been? At lunch?
I'm sorry. I had some
traumas come in.
I gave Moira her shot.
She's ready to go home.
Three hours to get a needle.
I'll be right there
to discharge her.
What did you say
to her? Nothing.
I don't even know
who... Who she is.
BP 110, pulse 95.
Tell them I'll be
up in a little while
to put in a suprapubic catheter.
Tell the blood bank to send
the other two units upstairs.
Hey. How's he doing?
Pulses are bounding.
May I take a look?
Did you get your guy's
pressure back up?
Oh, yeah. After eight
units of packed cells.
That's not bad for a first time.
Piece of cake when
you follow directions.
Yes. Funny how I
can talk you through
a complicated fasciotomy,
but when I tell you to pick up
your socks, you just ignore me.
I'm sorry, did you
just say something?
Dr. Dave: 14. Death: Zero.
Nice job on triage, Dr. Malucci.
Ah, thanks a lot,
chief. I still can't believe
we didn't get one penetrating
chest trauma, you know?
Hey! We got another
one. Greg Fulton, Exam 5.
Wanted for assault, battery
and indecent exposure.
Hey! Sorry, Frank.
This isn't working.
What are you saying?
We made two arrests.
It would've been three if
that mother hadn't escaped.
And between you and me, I think
someone on staff tipped her off.
No more record
checks on patients.
What did you do with my patient?
Mr. Kamatovik? I got him a bed,
but he's gone AWOL.
Well, he can't
have gotten too far.
You look pretty good in scrubs.
Uh, can I keep them?
Uh... sure. Hey, I'll
be right back, okay?
Hey, Cleo.
Was that your
gonorrhea patient? Yep.
Did you manage to treat
her without Mom finding out?
Yep.
Listen, I wasn't trying
to step on your toes.
When I offered to take the case,
I was just trying to help.
I know.
Hey, Cleo.
Do you, uh...
have a problem
with me being here?
Course not.
I told you. He's disappeared.
What is this?
Alcohol wipes.
He says he has to stay cool to
avoid spontaneous combustion.
Yeah. He begged me to
give him a Popsicle enema.
We settled for ice chips.
Mr. Kamatovik. Are you in there?
Yes!
All right. Come out
so we can help you.
I can't!
I'm burning up. I
need wet blankets.
We can get you some upstairs.
You want me to
bring him out, chief?
Please.
Mr. Kamatovik, open up.
Somebody call the burn unit!
Get a gurney!
This is a modified version
of Ken Blackburn's
1998 world-record design.
Sure you want to launch it?
Piece of folded
paper until you let it fly.
All right, let it fly.
All right.
Wow.
That looks like it
could go on forever.
Mm, theoretically, it could,
if the wind kept blowing,
and it kept finding up currents.
This is really cool. I've never
been up this high before.
Looks like your ride is here.
I'm out of airplanes anyway.
Oh.
Thanks for bringing
me up here, Dr. Carter.
Well, you make
some more airplanes,
and we can do it again sometime.
I'd like that.
Hey. Hey.
You were popular today, huh?
I know.
What's that about?
I'm everybody's favorite nurse.
Oh. But that's the problem,
because as a med student,
I screwed up everything.
Everything. Things I could
do even with my eyes closed.
I think it's all in... here.
The...
You are a good nurse, Abby.
But you could be a great doctor.
Just need a little confidence.
Oh, my God. I'm sorry.
I can't believe I did that.
Abby. Yeah?
You got a code
brown with Mr. Pozoni.
Again? Jeez. How
much can that guy eat?
I gotta go.
Yeah.
I'll see you later.
Bye. Bye.
Peter, are you here?
I've been calling.
Why didn't you pick up?
I didn't feel like talking.
I went up during my break.
Shirley said you'd been fired.
Hm.
I guess the whole hospital
knows by now, huh?
Why didn't you tell me?
Peter, I was worried
about you. I called Jackie.
She said you had
been gone for hours.
What did you tell her?
I didn't tell her anything...
except I didn't have
any idea where you were.
What happened?
Peter?
You can tell me.
Ah, Romano got hit
with a big EMTALA fine
over the Fletcher case.
Good. He deserves it.
Yeah. Well, now he's
taking it out on me.
Maybe he's just
blowing off steam.
No. I've seen him do that.
This time he's serious.
Talk to somebody.
Call Anspaugh.
Tell him what?
Tell him Romano is a
racist, sexist, elitist jackass.
Cleo, he knows that.
You're an excellent
surgeon, Peter.
And you're a good man.
And we'll work it out.
How's it going, Carter?
Good. My day got better. You?
Yeah. Think so.
Hey... Heck, no.
It was like, rrooh, the
guy just went up in flames.
You should have seen it.
Hey, Carter. You ever see
spontaneous human combustion?
Uh, no, Dave. It doesn't exist.
Ah. I was there. I saw it.
No lighter, no
matches, no nothing.
He's right. I went on a
missing-persons call once.
All we found was
this old gal's legs.
The rest of her
burned to a crisp.
But that chair she was
sitting in, barely singed.
So, Carter, how was
your first day back?
It was good. A little slow.
Glad to hear it. Finished up?
Yeah. I am
officially out of here.
Just one last thing to do.
Sure.
You coming with me?
That's the rules.
Sorry, Carter, I have to
witness the entire process.
Trust me. It's no
treat for me either.
Seen any good movies lately?
No.
You want me to run
some water or something?