Previously on ER:
I saw Charlie Pratt at CeaseFire.
He said he stopped by here last week.
- How did it go?
- Quick.
Did the oncologist you spoke with mention
anything about prophylactic surgery?
You mean having
my breasts removed?
There have been advances in
reconstructive surgery. Protect yourself.
You promise giving up my
breasts would protect me?
I had my annual PSA screening.
Needle biopsy showed a moderately
differentiated prostate cancer.
- I'm so sorry.
- Does this hurt, Blaire?
She's in a coma, Inez.
- Not anymore.
- What's the last thing you remember?
- We had an accident.
The reason I'm calling, Dr. Clemente,
is that you were supposed to start today.
So unless your plane went
down or you got hit by a bus...
you'd better get in here as
soon as you get this message.
Luka, I need you to wait.
Pratt's running behind.
The new Attending is a no-show.
Think he'd wanna
make a good impression.
- You never did.
- Page me if he doesn't show.
Morris, run through
the moonlighting list.
See if we can find
someone to come in.
- Whoa. Where are you rushing off to?
- Upstairs.
Why? Uh... Never mind.
Last time I reached out to someone,
Dubenko tried to make me his concubine.
Hello, my people.
- You're late.
- Not according to me.
According to me, I got
20 patients on the rack.
Chest pain, I need
a monitored bed.
Don't have one.
12-lead in the hallway.
- Is Dr. Lewis coming in?
- Dr. Lewis is never coming in again.
She took a tenured
track position in Iowa City.
- Just like that?
- Just like that.
That's why Dr. Clemente
is supposed to be here now.
Who's this Clemente guy, anyway?
He was residency director at Jacobi in
the Bronx and he did a stint in Newark.
Is he gonna be the
new department chief?
We're forming a
search committee.
The guy must be
angling for it, right?
Abby, vomiting blood.
- My favorite.
Ray, nosebleed.
Sorry, I'm on my tox elective.
I was just rolling down here to
remind everybody about my gig.
- Oh... Pogo Lounge.
- Isn't that a strip club?
It's behind the Lava Lounge,
which used to be the Aqua Lounge.
Roomie, are you gonna come?
That's why I wake
up in the morning.
Okay, med students. Burning
urination, seafood allergy.
- We're not really doctors.
- That never stopped Morris.
Roswell and Marshall are premed.
They're working for my grant
tracking patient throughput time.
If we don't start moving the
meat, they'll be unemployed.
You want me to supervise everyone
and take on three new patients?
You're an R-4, stop whining.
- Where are you going?
- To the Weaver Lounge.
To work on my presentation. Anything
short of a meteor crash, don't bug me.
Pratt.
EKG looks good.
All right.
Where's your pain, sir?
It's not a pain. I just
feel something right here.
- BP 124 over 78.
- What's it feel like?
It feels really heavy, like a
boulder. I can't breathe, doc.
Say no more. Sir, would you
do me a favor and open up?
No, no. I did two
lines of coke last night.
- What?
- Yeah, and a bottle of tequila.
- You did?
- Yeah, not to mention three Viagra.
- Why didn't you say something?
- Aren't you supposed to take my history?
- Who are you?
- Victor Clemente. Your new Attending.
And congratulations,
doc. You just killed me.
Usually, Dr. Pratt
is very thorough.
We're getting slammed.
It's okay, death becomes me.
I've got a Q&A upstairs, but
maybe I should stay down here.
No, go ahead, take it. Dr. Kevorkian
and I will hold down the fort.
Hey, Jerry.
You know where to find me?
- Mm-hm.
You know how to
make an entrance.
I was just trying to
get the lay of the land.
You take it too far.
You should have seen me at St.
Mary's. I took it all the way to a rectal.
She was cuter than you, though.
Look at that. You guys
still using x-ray film?
I thought everybody
was digital by now.
- Oh, hey. Nice job shaving my chest hair.
- No problem.
Now, it took 24 minutes to get
my vitals. Twenty-four minutes.
Come on. I know we
can all do better than that.
Yes, we can. Yes, we
can. It's totally what I think.
Archie Morris, chief resident.
It usually takes me about 10 minutes
to figure out who the kiss-ass is.
At least we're breaking
records somewhere, huh?
Now, the EKG was prompt, but
the resident's evaluation was sloppy.
You know we were busy.
It's always busy, it's always
chaos, always out of control.
I know you don't have enough
hours to spend with every patient.
But our job is efficiency and
excellence. We're marksmen.
We hone in on what's important, hit
our target with one shot and move on.
We should call
Psych on this guy.
And who are you?
Abby Lockhart. R-2.
Oh, yeah. Weaver was
talking to me about you.
I'd like to say it was
all good, but it wasn't.
- Can we start by clearing this stuff?
- Okay, in Trauma 1, we have...
Grease board? God, I haven't seen one of
these since the '80s. That's pretty cool.
Look, unless anybody has any
objections, I prefer walking rounds.
We all learn. Okay? Let's go.
He's kind of hot.
- I thought you had a boyfriend.
- He's at war, and so are my hormones.
Come in.
How are you?
This toothbrush feels like
a hundred-pound weight.
Well, it's normal after
such prolonged bed rest.
Please tell me you brought
rocky road and a cheeseburger.
I just came by to test
your muscle tone again.
So no fries?
Well, at least you're
not Dr. Schulansky.
He brings tours here like I'm a
freak from the wild animal park.
He's excited that you're awake.
She's alive. She's alive.
Squeeze my hand.
Okay. That feels a little
stronger than last week.
Try to lift up your leg.
That's good. Very good.
Ugh.
Well, it's more than you
could do the last time.
That's thanks to three hours a day
with Helga, the therapist from hell.
Well, I see you
had some visitors.
Yeah, that was my
best friend from college.
I haven't seen her
since graduation.
I asked her for a joint and
she brought me a teddy bear.
Good for her. The last thing you need
is anything interfering with your recovery.
I need, heh, to
take the edge off.
Waking up and finding out that
your mom's dead, your fiancé's MIA...
and you've literally slept through
your 20s, it's just a little stressful.
Has Dr. Schulansky said
anything about the accident?
All I know is you and
your mom were driving...
and there was some
kind of traffic collision.
Yeah, that much I remember.
We were on our way for my
final fitting for my wedding dress.
It was strapless
with a tulle skirt.
I wouldn't even
let Jason see it.
- Your fiancé?
- Mm-hm.
Have you spoken to him?
Oh. That would fall
under the heading...
of "Scared as hell, don't
know how to do that one."
Lowered tidal volume
of 6 cc's per kilo...
decreased mortality from
40 percent to 31 percent.
You twirl a knob,
you're gonna save a life.
Okay? All right, let's go.
Those are cool shoes,
man. Are they Adidas?
Get laid, Morris.
Boris Nadinovitz, presenting with
fever, lymphadenopathy and night sweats.
No obvious source.
Ya bolen, doctor.
So, what's your
diagnostic approach?
Skin test for TB
and cocci histo?
Good, good, good.
Dorsey Watson.
Greg Pratt.
Man, what's it
been, like five years?
Six. I was in second
year when you graduated.
- Wow. What are you doing here?
- I work here. What's your excuse?
I heard you were in Winnetka
doing lipo on rich chicks.
Still am, man. Still am.
But one of my patients got a half-price
tummy tuck from a hack, landed upstairs.
Hey, killer, come on.
We got patients
to clear. Let's go.
- I gotta roll, man.
- Hey, do your thing.
- I'll holler at you before I go.
- Definitely.
Be relaxed. Try to sound calm.
It will be weird
for him at first.
You think?
- It's ringing.
- Okay, take a deep breath.
What's going on?
Oh! Hi. Is this
Jason Clark's house?
She's calling her fiancé.
Blaire Collins. I'm an old
friend of his from the Art Institute.
- She's doing great.
- I'm amazed by her progress.
I've been trying to help her for over
four years and all of a sudden, this.
Yeah, it's really me.
What were you treating her with?
Most recently, an
experimental cocktail.
Fluoxetine, Sinemet
and dextroamphetamine.
- Is she still on them?
- Not anymore.
I know. It's weird.
She's asked me about what
happened, how she got hurt.
Um... I think it's better not
to talk to her about it yet.
Is there something
she shouldn't know?
The accident was
violent, to say the least.
Blaire and her mother were
carjacked. Her mom was raped.
And shot?
Blaire tried to fight
and was pistol-whipped.
They would have killed
her, but someone pulled up.
Still, she has
the right to know.
She's in a fragile state.
Telling her could set her back.
Let's get her healthy first.
She needs to hear this
from someone close to her.
- She has no family.
- She'll be told, doctor.
All in good time.
A 22-year-old female presenting
with recurring headaches.
- No history of migraine...
- Right.
But there is a history of
idiopathic intracranial hypertension.
They usually take out
a bunch of spinal fluid.
We don't do that anymore.
- We don't?
- No.
Now that we know that IIH is
caused by sagittal sinus thrombosis...
resulting in a decreased CSF
reabsorption at the arachnoid sinuses.
I didn't know that.
- Heparin is the treatment of choice.
- Here you go, doc.
I'm just gonna place a
drop in your eye. Lean back.
She still needs an
LP for diagnosis.
Hey, hey, not so
fast, not so fast.
Annals of Emergency
Medicine, May 2000.
- 2000...?
- Five?
- Nope.
- Three?
- Four?
Ten points for the winner.
Intraocular pressure correlates
with intracranial pressure.
Fifty-four. Diagnosis made,
and you don't get a spinal tap.
Abby, Oncology's on the phone.
If you ever say he's hot
again, I'll kneecap you.
Some patient of
yours is freaking out.
- In Oncology?
- Mm-hm.
- Who is it?
- Stephanie Lowenstein.
She's upset because we
couldn't do the reconstruction.
- Why not?
- They found an enlarged lymph node.
We told her pathology
isn't back, she won't listen.
She says it's all your fault.
She smashed the mirror.
- Stephanie.
- I don't want you here.
I just wanna help.
You call this helping?
This is not helping.
- Okay, I understand how you feel.
- You have no idea how I feel.
Miss Lowenstein, wait.
You just have to let the doctors
get the results back from the tests.
We'll figure out how to proceed.
To do what? To cut me up some
more? To hell with your damn tests.
Stephanie, listen to
me, please. Just listen.
- You ruined me.
- I know you're scared.
Is that what I am?
Just because they found a node
doesn't mean you have cancer.
I need a cab. Where's a cab?
You need to come
inside and let us treat you.
I have money. Where's
my stupid book?
- Oh!
- Listen.
Everything you're
feeling right now is normal.
- It's just gonna take time.
- I don't have time.
That's not true.
Who's gonna marry someone
who could need chemo for 10 years?
Someone who could die before
the kid goes to high school?
If they had trouble making a
diagnosis, it may not be cancer.
And if it is, because you had
the surgery, they caught it early.
- I don't believe you.
- It's the truth.
You did what you had to do
and it was incredibly brave.
- Then why do I feel like this?
- Because it's scary.
It's scary, but you don't
have to go through this alone.
- Get the hell away from me.
- Stephanie, please.
Just let me take care of those
cuts. Just come inside with me and...
Stephanie, please.
I've tried all the
Internet dating sites.
I rewrote my profile so many times,
you would have thought it was my thesis.
What happened to Lou?
- I liked Lou.
- Ah.
I don't think he
could handle this.
He said he would come
back after the surgery, but...
I never liked Lou.
Guy's a jerk. It's a good
thing you found out early.
I don't wanna freeze my
eggs or buy milk on the Internet.
I wanted to breastfeed.
This is a little
bit of Neosporin.
Aren't you afraid you'll
wind up the auntie?
Be forced to adopt
some kid from Cambodia?
I think Cambodian kids are cute.
You know what I meant.
Stephanie, if all goes well,
you'll get the reconstruction.
You'll have an uneventful
recovery and a perfectly normal life.
That's doctor talk.
You don't get it.
My mother's sister
died of breast cancer.
So did my grandmother.
And you?
I have never even
had a mammogram.
Tony Dejesus, single stab wound to
the neck, vitals stable, good airway.
Having trouble breathing? - No.
Time of arrival, 1442.
- This gang-related? TONY:
My old lady stabbed me.
- Why did she do that?
- Because she's a psycho bitch.
Where are my residents? This
is a great case. Get my residents.
Hey, who are these clowns? We
are not putting on a show for you.
What the hell is wrong with
you? Get the hell out of here.
The woman who answered
Jason's phone was his wife.
Six years is a long time.
Ha. You know, the thing
that's so hard about all of this...
is that everything has
just gone on and I still feel...
like Jason and I were just
finalizing our wedding list yesterday.
I'm sure he stayed by
you as long as he could.
He came by twice.
Schulansky told me.
No wonder he wanted
us to write our own vows.
He probably planned on omitting the
whole "in sickness and in health" part.
Did you want him to spend the
rest of his life hoping for something...
everyone said wouldn't happen?
Maybe I can be his mistress.
Which anatomic landmarks
define zone two of the neck?
The cricoid cartilage to
the angle of the mandible.
Very, very, very good.
Because management of zone
two injuries is very controversial.
Actually, some people advocate
surgical exploration for everything.
I'm pretty sure surgeons
would not wanna explore...
an asymptomatic patient
with a superficial wound.
Can you guys hurry up? My
old lady's gonna burn my truck.
Maybe next time, you won't
double dip at your mom's-in-law.
You seen my wife's mother?
- Then don't criticize.
- My bad.
I'm sure you guys are aware of all the
indications for immediate exploration.
Right, Dr. Morris?
Airway compromise, severe
hemorrhage or expanding hematoma.
- He has none of those.
- Good, so then let me go.
Right, but we can always
learn from every case, Dr. Pratt.
Talk to me about
management with neck injuries.
- What?
- Brother, keep it short.
Don't go Al Sharpton on his ass.
Duplex scan, endoscopy,
gastrograffin swallow...
which you would only
do if he had symptoms.
Well, slow your roll, bro...
because what proportion of zone
two vascular injuries are asymptomatic?
Dr. Rasgotra?
With a significant injury, he might
have signs of bleeding or a hematoma.
- The guy is stable.
- Maybe, maybe.
But nine in a hundred times,
asymptomatic patients...
have lesions that
require surgical repair.
How about that, Dr. Pratt?
How about that? Talk to me now.
You know what? How about I go
check on my asthma patient in Curtain 2?
There's no asthma
patient in Curtain 2.
Yeah, well, maybe he
went out for a smoke.
I'll go find him.
Yes, Eve, I did. I
put up the sanitizer.
No, I didn't hand out pens.
I am putting up the
poster as we speak.
Yes, that special tape
that won't ruin the walls.
Okay, bye-bye.
Don't tell me. Eve?
It's her day off
and she still calls in.
Here. She wants everyone's hands to
be sanitized before they touch a patient.
"Scrub or rub"? It sounds kinky.
- We should be so lucky.
- Heh-heh.
I was thinking we could
get something to eat.
You know, maybe catch
a movie or something.
No, I haven't seen that one yet.
All right, cool. I'll
meet you out front.
Hey. How are you doing, Greg?
What, you're stalking me now?
No. I'm here for...
A sick friend.
Sure you don't have another
illegitimate kid up in there?
We need to talk. What
are you doing after work?
I've got a date.
With Olivia Evans?
Nice girl. I've known her
since she was in high school.
That's great.
What about tomorrow?
Maybe we can have dinner.
You like gumbo? I know a
great place on King Drive.
And down the street,
there's a cat with a pool hall...
Listen, we're not eating any
gumbo together or playing pool.
All right?
Then what would you like to do?
I would like for you
to leave me alone.
For real. We're done.
Okay. You don't wanna
have anything to do with me.
- What about your little brother?
- Don't use him like that.
- He'd like to get to know you, Greg.
- He just met me.
I don't know what your
mother told you about me.
But I have an idea
it wasn't everything.
- Come on, man.
- I could explain...
- but only if you give me the time.
- I do not have the time.
I'm trying here.
Then stop.
Fine.
If you wanna drop it
forever, that's your call.
But you'll have to live with it.
Your choice.
I never got the whole
marriage talk from my mom.
But the moment that I told her that
Jason proposed, she pulled out this trunk.
She had every detail
of my wedding planned.
It was crazy.
Oh, my God. Stop, stop.
She wasn't gonna pressure you.
Yeah.
She wanted it to be special.
Which way is Lake Michigan?
That way. You can see it from
the other side of the hospital.
- Can we go?
- I shouldn't even have you out.
- Please?
- No.
Come on.
What does a girl have to
do to get a break with you?
I hope Clemente doesn't
become chief of the department.
- You liked him.
- I did until I had to present.
Patient doesn't have
flesh-eating bacteria now...
but what symptoms might he have?
Is that muscle spasm in
the jaw? Acute tetanus?
I'm all for teaching, but
this guy doesn't stop.
Yeah, he's annoying.
You said you liked his
bloody shoes, you wanker.
Just because he's annoying,
doesn't mean I can't like his shoes.
- Are you going to Ray's gig?
- To hell with Ray.
He's upstairs having a blast.
Jerry, it's Ray. Save
me. I'm bored stiff.
Try picturing every woman up there
naked. That always works for me.
Oh, come on. Are there
any drug cases down there?
Couple of traumas rolling in.
Lola Simon, 7-year-old
with crush injury. BP 70 palp.
- What crushed her?
- Your next patient.
Seven-year-old
girl, no sign of drugs.
Yeah! I'm king of the world!
Looks like you
forgot how to fly, king.
Tommy Bonetti, stood up on the
Tilt-A-Whirl at the St. Ignatius fair.
- Is he on drugs?
- He might have just hit his head.
Sounds like drugs.
I'm on my way down.
- Move away from the light.
- We're trying to take care of you, man.
You look like an
alien. Don't probe me.
Please sedate him.
I have to assess
his neural status first.
Taking the HemoCue.
Gaaah!
Process the spinal films
before you take the rest.
- Hey, I'm rolling out, man.
- What, you scared of a little blood?
- Squeeze my hand.
- Systolic's 65.
All right, no fluid in the
abdomen. Pericardium is clear.
Looks like spinal shock
with a high thoracic injury.
Am I right?
I'm way out of my league, man.
Don't you remember Bartlett's
lecture on blunt trauma?
Sweetie, listen, I'm gonna poke
you. Tell me when you feel this.
Start dopamine at 5 mics,
900 of methylprednisolone.
Ow!
Sensory level at T4.
How you doing, Lola?
- That's a big bug.
- You just killed our mascot.
- Here she goes.
- Log roll. Keep her on the backboard.
Suction.
Look, some of the old U of I crew's
are hooking up at Cherry Red tonight.
You got plans?
- Pratt, we need you in here.
- I'm gonna try to roll through.
- Pratt, now.
- Go see what's up. I'll intubate.
You don't stay still, I'll put
this needle through your heart.
- Can we sedate and paralyze?
- He took his IV out.
Since when did Alfred E.
Neuman become a doctor?
- What about I.M. Versed?
- Gave him five. It's not touching him.
- What did he take?
- Maybe ice, coke. Tracheal 140.
- What the hell are you on?
- Her in a minute.
I can't find the vein.
- How about Haldol?
- No, he could seize.
Morris, let me try the line.
Dr. Pratt. PRATT: Go
ahead, push the sux.
This guy's unstable as
hell. We can't get a line.
- I'm tied up.
- We need help.
You gotta get Clemente.
- Is there another Attending on?
- Clemente's the only one.
No, we can handle this
ourselves. I'll do a femoral cutdown.
- Are you serious?
- He needs access.
Pulse keeps going up.
Mix up esmolol,
slow down his rate.
- Ten blade.
- We got sugar in here?
Oh, wow, we got a
trauma. I didn't know.
Pager's probably not working.
No, my pager's working.
Twenty-foot fall complicated
by unknown intoxication.
- What are you guys doing?
- A femoral cutdown.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
everybody take a deep breath.
Take a deep breath.
Get my briefcase under admit.
- Banana cheese.
- What did he take?
- He won't say.
Tachy with mydriasis. My
guess is sympathomimetic.
Bad, bad guess.
Skin and membranes are dry.
It's an anticholinergic.
Electrolytes back yet?
Right here.
Hyperchloremia. Anion gap is
minus four. How could that be?
Skittles, people, skittles. Very
popular with the kids these days.
It's cold pills with
dextromethorphan hydrogen bromide.
The lab analyzer thinks
bromide is chloride.
- You get a reversal of the gap.
- Aaah!
Anything to calm him down?
- Two mics of I.M. physostigmine.
- He still needs access.
- Here you go.
- I'm Rick James, bitch.
Close your eyes. Go to
your happy place, son.
What time did the
chem panel come back?
He's got weird anatomy. We
couldn't find the subclavian.
There it is, there
it is. Right there.
See, the probe allows us to cannulate
the vein under direct visualization.
That's very cool.
- You carry that with you all the time?
- It's just a demo.
I ran the phase-three trials.
- Beautiful, beautiful.
- It's like shooting fish in a barrel.
Heart rate's down to 80.
I guess we didn't need
the beta blockers, did we?
I trust you guys can
finish without me.
No problem, boss.
Hey. Even if you think
I'm a pain in the ass...
it should never get in
the way of patient care.
You with me?
Good.
Dr. Lockhart?
Hey.
What's up?
Well, everything. And
almost twice a day.
Congratulations. I hear
you're getting out today.
If you thought it stunk to
work here, try being a patient.
By the way, thanks for the date.
- She told you?
- I had to pay her.
- It was supposed to be a freebie.
- Just the first time.
Initially, it kind of turned me off when
I learned that she was a professional.
But then when I thought
about it, it turned me on.
We're both professionals.
So you didn't need me after all.
Well, I guess not.
Hey. I don't remember your name.
Abby. And you're
a little late, Lou.
I came to see how
Stephanie was doing.
She had her breasts removed.
Pick up a pink ribbon on your way out.
- What? She did?
- Yeah, she did.
What are you talking about?
Stephanie says you
disappeared on her.
She told the nurse
not to let me in.
And every time I called, she
wouldn't say why she was here...
and kept going on about...
how she couldn't handle
dating anyone right now.
- Why would she do that?
- I don't know.
All I know is I can't
stop thinking about her.
And I'm a little worried.
Come on, come
on. Do it, do it, do it.
Dr. Clemente.
- Oh, damn it.
- Do you have a moment?
You should really consider
getting one of these.
It might keep you from
hacking up the patients.
I'm sorry I didn't call you in
earlier. Bonetti's gone up to the ICU.
We've got to consider
preemptive orders.
It was really
unprofessional of me.
Nurses transporting patients?
What a waste of resources.
- Are you listening to me?
- Actually, no.
I lost. Okay, look.
A femoral cutdown has to be a
last-ditch effort in a peri-arrest patient.
- And skittles boy wasn't quite there yet.
- Well, I thought he was.
Oh, you thought he was.
Look, I know. I was a resident too, I
thought I had the keys to the kingdom.
But the great thing is that we can
always learn. That's why I'm here.
Well, sometimes you
wanna do it yourself.
Sometimes your ego does, but
the patient would rather that I do it.
- Believe me.
- You're right.
You know what? It's
not about being right.
Okay, look, I consider you, Pratt, Morris,
every resident, every student here...
an investment in the future.
My dividend comes when something that
I've taught you saves a life. That's it.
You should really consider
surgery as an elective.
Well, why do you say that?
Because you're quick to cut and you
like to use a scalpel more than your brain.
Come in.
- Hi.
- Hey.
I brought you some company.
Lou.
I heard what happened.
Hi.
Come in. Sit down.
Chocolate.
Hi. I'd like to schedule an
outpatient mammogram.
Sure. Patient's name?
Abby Lockhart.
First you missed
morning rounds...
and now they tell me you're
avoiding Poison Control.
No, I got stuck with a consult.
Look, a bunch of Zen monks made
tea from this plant in their garden.
Now they have
vomiting, diarrhea.
Some are tachycardic, some bradycardic,
some hypotensive, some hypertensive.
Not a clear toxidrome.
I haven't identified
this on the Internet.
I even sent digital photos to
the Botany Department, but...
It's not jimsonweed, not
foxglove, not oleander.
Well, maybe it's tabaco gigante.
You know something?
You may be right.
I saw this once in
Mexico. It's a tobacco plant.
Your patients have
nicotine toxicity.
- Oh.
- Good call.
Thank you.
Dr. Clemente.
Why are my research assistants
sitting in the waiting area?
The parking garage is too cold?
They're collecting data for me.
The looky-loos were
getting in the way of the work.
Then you just tell
them to step back.
I didn't wanna overstep. Maybe
that should come from you.
Overstep? You pulled
the plug on my study.
Look. I meant it as more
as a time-out kind of thing.
You told them that
my study was useless.
Look, I know what
happened in Newark.
And I really do not want
a repeat here, okay?
All right, look. Bottom line, you hired
me to make this place more efficient.
And that's what I am trying to
do. And if and when we start...
bedside registration is
gonna make your study...
I don't know, irrelevant?
I've got a $100,000 grant
that says that it won't.
You've got $100,000,
why don't we go digital?
Listen, I run this hospital.
If we start bedside registration,
that goes through me.
If you put my students on a
time-out, that goes through me.
If you wanna wash the floors
differently, that goes through me.
Do I make myself clear?
I got one more question for you.
Does my answer go through you?
My mom loved seeing the lake.
Look at the water.
At least some
things stay the same.
We should really get back.
Have you always
been such a worrier?
I've always had
things to worry about.
Do you think this was God?
What?
Me waking up.
I don't know.
You think it was
science, don't you?
I've seen deeply religious
people come into the hospital.
Prayer did nothing for them.
And then I've seen
plenty of skeptics...
experience
miraculous recoveries.
So you think it was fate?
I think...
I'm glad we're both here
able to wonder about it.
Yeah.
How you gonna punk me like that?
What's up, little man?
You know where Olivia is?
- Yeah, she's down the hall.
- Thanks.
I hear you, fellows.
But you sound like a
bunch of knuckleheads.
Hey, all I'm saying is, you can't
feel nothing with no jimmy on.
Get used to them.
There's no alternative.
Getting a girl pregnant
is 18 years of lockdown.
Half your check
going to Uncle Sam.
- The other half going to your kid and...?
- The baby's mama?
And what happens if you
miss a child support payment?
Who's gonna be
blowing up your pager?
My baby's mama.
Having a kid at your age...
ain't what you wanna do.
Trust me.
Do you miss Croatia?
I have family there.
But there are more
opportunities for me here.
I like Chicago.
Except the winter sucks.
Yeah, you can always
go inside and warm up.
You know how I keep
asking you about the accident?
It's because I keep having
these flashes that don't add up.
What kind of flashes?
I remember being scared.
We had just gotten coffee and I
remember seeing my mom's face.
Her eyes were petrified.
And I hear her screams, but her
screams are muffled by the radio...
and there's blood and laughter.
Lots of laughter, and at first I
thought it was just a dream...
but the images are so vivid.
- They're so clear.
- Sit down.
Sit down.
Something else
happened that night.
And not knowing
what it is is killing me.
But I need the truth.
- Blaire.
- I want to be out...
- Figure it...
- Blaire?
Come on, Blaire. Stay with me.
Hey, I need a monitored bed.
- Trauma 1. What's going on?
- Page Schulansky in Neurology.
Hey, I'm Dr. Clemente.
So, what's the problem?
She's not talking.
Get me an Accu-Chek, a
HemoCue and a pulse ox.
- She doesn't need that.
- Can we have her friend wait outside?
- I'm not her friend.
- This is Dr. Kovac, one of our Attendings.
Hey, doc. I'm
sorry, I had no clue.
- Ma'am? Ma'am, can you hear me?
- Her name's Blaire.
- Can you hear me? MALIK:
Schulansky's at the VA.
Damn it. Gaze is
fixed to the right.
I need a CBC, chem
panel and a head CT.
No, she needs fluoxetine,
Sinemet and dextroamphetamine.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Abby, run up to the
pharmacy and get the meds.
There's an approach dealing
with altered mental status.
This is not a standard patient.
She's been on experimental cocktail.
Abby, fluoxetine, Sinemet
and dextroamphetamine.
Abby, please go.
Hey, hey. I need some help.
Hey.
What's up?
Fluoxetine, Sinemet,
dextroamphetamine.
Yeah, write it up. Hey,
what are you doing?
Are you crazy? You
can't go back here.
Crit's fine. Sodium
and potassium normal.
- I told you that.
- CT is ready.
Okay, let's move her now.
- She needs the meds.
We could be missing a
brain bleed or a mass effect.
- I know.
- We don't have time to screw around.
The meds woke her
up from the coma.
If they did, we'd have coma
patients waking up everywhere.
- All I know is they worked for her.
- Got them.
You're not gonna
actually let him do this?
Are you confident these
meds are gonna work?
If not, there's gonna be
a tall guy in a cheap suit...
from the state asking questions.
It's worth a try, Kerry.
Right. Hold the scanner.
I'll give him five minutes.
You know what? Don't sweat it.
Dr. Kovac, you're the
physician of record.
I'm not on the chart
when the family sues.
Well, I'm in luck.
There is no family.
And fluoxetine in at 2019.
Let's get her up to CT.
As soon as I get
a portable monitor.
Blaire? Blaire?
Eyes opening to pain.
- Incomprehensible verbal activity.
- You got a GCS of 2, 2, 4.
Check her gag. WEAVER: Whoa.
She's seizing. Two
mics of Ativan now.
One hundred percent
oxygen, non-rebreather.
- She has a history of seizures?
- No.
Well, any of the meds you
pushed could have caused this.
So could falling drug
levels, so could withdrawal.
Another round of Ativan.
Heh. I really liked
that last one. Is it new?
Yeah. It's called "Blood Wine."
Oh, "Blood Wine." How
did you think of that?
I cut my finger opening
a bottle of merlot.
So you and your
friend headed home?
I don't know what she's doing.
Do you know what you're doing?
- Yeah, I know what I'd like to do.
- Hold that thought.
I'll settle with the boys. I'll be back.
- Yo, Ray.
You guys are late. We
were the opening act.
Clemente had us pull journal articles
to justify the treatment of every patient.
You wanna get something to eat?
- I have plans.
- Do your plans have friends?
Let's see.
- Zoe.
- Yes?
- This is my boy, Archie.
- What up, ladies?
- You guys hungry?
- We wanna meet the band.
I play drums.
Heh.
Yeah, I'm serious. Like:
That's my marching band.
We won the nationals.
Turning into pooh,
pooh, pooh, and then we...
Guys? Ray!
Blaire?
Blaire, open your eyes.
Maybe she's postictal.
Or the Ativan didn't wear off.
Or I shouldn't have
pushed the meds.
You don't know why
she had a seizure.
Maybe we overloaded her sinuses.
Luka, there is no way to
know why she fell back into this.
Yeah.
I have to go. Are you okay?
The state conservator agreed
to admit Blaire to the hospital...
for two days to see if
there's any improvement.
If not, she'll go back
to the nursing home.
I could have been a
doctor But why poetry?
Why I? Why me? Why I?
I could have been a
lawyer But why poetry?
Poetry. Why?
Poetry.
Thank you.
- Where's our waitress?
- To hell with her. What do you want?
Uh... Light beer.
Lipo doctor's scared
of getting handles.
Don't hate. I look good.
I'll be back.
Excuse me.
Hey, what's up, bro? I'll
get two beers, one light.
- You want something?
- A conversation would be cool.
- You haven't said anything to me.
- We can barely hear.
You could hear everyone
just fine. What did I do, Greg?
- Tell me what I did.
- You should've told me he was in there.
- You want me to survey the building?
- Yes, I do.
Look, he's down there
helping those kids.
And who sews up those kids
once they leave your place?
Your father tries to help
them before they get to you.
I see. Charlie Pratt
may be a lot of things.
But he's not my father,
my dad or my pops.
He's just a guy who
got my mom pregnant.
So basically, he made the same
mistake he's warning those kids about.
Greg, wait. Uh...
You wanna hate him, I can't
stop you, but Charlie's a good guy.
Twenty hours a week with the
kids, runs a basketball league...
- rehab houses for poor people.
- Yeah, see, that's the problem.
I've waited my whole life
to spit in my old man's face.
He's not lying in the gutter...
- People change, Greg...
- He's building houses for people for free.
- No. No.
- Greg.
Ah!
Blaire, I hope you can hear me.
On that night, you and
your mom were driving.
You stopped at a red light.
Another car pulled
up next to you.
There were three men inside.
They pulled a gun...
and dragged your mom...