Previously on The Resident...
I just signed with the
hottest music agent
- in Atlanta.
- You can't be a musician.
You're a princess.
Your time here will
be coming to an end.
Yo, Pravesh!
Rupa is one of my goddaughters.
Her son has a
very rare condition.
His heart is growing
outside his body.
I worked hard all my life
to be seen like my dad.
He was a good man.
We're getting hitched, baby!
Nicolette Nevin, will
you do me the honor?
Yes.
Everything okay up there?
I just dropped something!
You could slow down.
If we don't hurry, we're
not gonna get a table.
You're the one who
wanted to shake things up.
Uh, I meant like skydiving
or hiking Stone Mountain,
but, hey, if this is what
you want to do, I am all in.
Too much?
Wow!
Does it go with these?
Oh, my God!
That's so sweet.
I love them!
You're wearing the ring.
Aren't we still keeping
that on the DL?
For now, yes.
We should let Jessica and
Irving have their moment.
I was ready to shout
it from the rooftops.
I like having our
sweet little secret.
For now, anyway.
But today we celebrate
our engagement.
We got to go.
♪ Yeah, two doors down ♪
♪ They're laughing and
drinking and having a party ♪
♪ And two doors down they're
not aware that I'm around ♪
♪ But here I am
crying my heart out... ♪
- Okay.
- Right?
Okay.
- This is fun.
- Oh, my God.
I told you it's packed!
This is the coolest
thing I've ever seen.
We have to bring
everyone we know.
Bell and Cain don't
have the right pumps.
Ezra, what are you doing here?
- I'm a regular.
- What?
Pro tip... the chicken
and waffles are divine.
Skip the biscuits and gravy.
- Good to know.
- Mm-hmm.
- You got it.
- Uh-oh!
Who do we have here?
Oh, hello.
- Me? Me?
- Yes, you, Mr. Handsome.
Hello.
I love this. I love...
I love this.
Thank you, thank you.
Oh, my God.
Oh, guys?
My friends and I
have a table up front
if you want to come join us.
- Yes.
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- Wait until you see
the headliner, Doll E. Wood.
She is a-mazing.
♪ I can't believe
I'm standing here ♪
♪ Dry-eyed, all
smiles and talking ♪
♪ Making conversation ♪
♪ With the new
love I have found... ♪
Are you ready, Doll E.?
I'm a little under
the weather, but...
you can't keep a Tennessee
mountain girl down, honey.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome to the stage
our very special entertainer,
all the way from Locust
Ridge, Tennessee
to our humble house
of pancake makeup.
The one and only, Doll E. Wood!
Oh, it's a glorious Sunday to be
who you always wanted to be.
Boy, you sound
like a partying crowd.
- Do you like to party?
- Yeah!
Well, that's a good thing,
'cause I hear there's one
happening two doors
down, and we are all invited.
♪ Two doors down, they're
laughing and drinking ♪
♪ And having a party
and two doors down ♪
♪ We're not aware
that they're around ♪
♪ Here we end ♪
♪ Feeling everything but sorry ♪
♪ We're having our own party ♪
♪ Two doors down, yeah ♪
♪ Two doors down... ♪
This is my favorite bit.
The James Brown interlude.
Yeah.
♪ Two doors down ♪
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
This wasn't in the act before.
Doll? Doll, are you okay?
Oh, my God.
Still breathing.
Pulse is weak.
Call 911, we need an ambulance.
♪ ♪
Take her to Bay Seven.
Give me the bullet.
We were at this
amazing drag brunch.
I start on surgery tomorrow,
so I needed to decompress,
- you know?
- Bullet, Ezra, not life story.
This is Joseph Kinney,
aka the amazing Doll E. Wood.
Ezra, want to take
another shot at that bullet?
Acute onset abdominal
pain with syncope.
- Hypotension...
- One, two, three.
Hypotension improved
with two liters normal
saline en route.
Y'all are too kind, all y'all.
I'm so embarrassed,
causing all this fuss.
No need to be embarrassed...
This is what we do.
We want to help.
Let's get you into a gown,
so we can do a
full exam... Ezra?
You have pain like this before?
Off and on.
I just ignored it.
With all the
acrobatics, the dancing,
the cinching and the tucking.
I threw my back out.
I even had kidney stones.
I'm used to hurting.
Let's, uh, get an
EKG as well as a CBC
and a CMP to start.
Doll, we're just
covering all the bases.
- We're gonna take
good care of you.
- Okay.
Dr. Feldman and I are gonna
get you some pain meds right now.
Got your gown here.
Oh, a gown... Oh.
I don't know... White
is really not my color.
I'm more of an autumn.
Would you be a doll and
shut that curtain for me?
You got it.
I don't need the
world to see this show.
Tell Rupa and Salman that
the baby is stable for now.
Mm, she said she's scared.
She really wants to hold him.
Tell them that Baby Farhad has
a combination of four
heart abnormalities,
known as Tetralogy of Fallot.
He's going to need
two surgeries today.
The first to repair the defects,
and the second is to put
the heart back in the chest.
Two surgeries in one
day on a newborn?
There's only been a handful of
successful surgeries worldwide.
We're going to do everything
we can to save Farhad.
Where are we with
the prostaglandins?
They're maxed out.
Well, it's not working.
I did an echo ten minutes ago.
His ductus arteriosus
has gotten smaller.
This baby needs surgery
in the next few hours.
So, it has to
happen at Chastain.
All you.
This is way beyond
even my exceptional abilities.
This surgery has maybe a
five percent success rate.
No, it's got to be done by
a pediatric cardiac surgeon,
who has experience
in this procedure.
They want to take Baby Farhad
to Boston Children's immediately.
He won't survive
the transport, Nadine.
But we are not
fully prepared here.
Now, Atlanta General has
a dedicated pediatric
cardiac center
and doctors who are trained
- in this particular procedure.
- He's too unstable for transfer,
- even there.
- I know, I know.
Torres.
You worked at
Atlanta General, right?
- Yeah.
- Is there a world-class
pediatric cardiac
surgeon we could call in?
I know just the person.
Dr. Judith Brown.
Call her.
You got it.
Hey there, pretty lady. Look,
I know everybody's real busy,
but would y'all mind
taking a look at my fiancée?
We've been here for a long
time; she's in a lot of pain.
Technically, it's my day off.
I have an incoming
trauma, could... you?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
- I'll take a look.
- Thank you.
You're the best.
Yvette, hi. I'm Nic.
I'm a nurse practitioner here.
Um, it says here
you're 23 years old.
- Is that true?
- Mm-hmm.
And, uh, and you're
experiencing some stomach pain.
- When did that start?
- Just today.
It wasn't too bad before.
On a scale from one to ten,
how would you rate your pain?
It's pretty bad...
I'd say a ten.
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna need Yvette to answer.
It really hurts.
I don't know, maybe...
maybe a ten.
Do you have any other symptoms?
A little bleeding.
Down there.
You didn't... tell me that.
All right, I'm gonna
have to do a pelvic exam.
- Do you mind stepping out?
- Oh, uh...
I'll stay.
I'd like him to stay.
There you go.
I can't leave Rupa and
Salman alone for too long.
I know, the NICU will let us
know when they need you back.
How are you doing?
You must be exhausted.
It was a long night.
Well, a trip to the
hospital is not the best way
to end a birthday party,
and in the middle of all of this,
you have a big decision to make.
Devon?
My father wants me to...
leave Atlanta and
return home tomorrow.
He's not just my
father, he's... my king.
There is no decision to be made.
Well... is this what you want?
It doesn't matter what I want.
I can't put my own wishes
before my obligation
to my people.
And with everything that
Rupa and Salman are facing,
it seems selfish to even
think about it right now.
Wow.
So... this is our
last day together.
I guess it is.
Dr. Brown is here.
How long did you two work
together at Atlanta General?
Throughout fellowship.
She's excellent...
she's mastered
techniques used for
operating on neonatal hearts.
And since we worked together,
she's asked me to assist.
His murmur has gotten
softer in the last hour.
He's also gotten more cyanotic.
Dr. Brown's gonna have
to create a shunt surgically.
I know we tolerate
lower O2 sats in infants,
but his have
dropped into the 50s.
He's not getting enough
oxygen in his blood.
This baby needs surgery now.
Pravesh, you seen Dr. Brown?
She's not answering her page.
- No.
- I thought she was with you.
Rupa and Salman
want to meet her.
Maybe later.
We need to find her
and have her scrub in
immediately.
Looking for Dr. Brown?
She's in the lab.
I'll get her.
You guys prep Farhad for the OR.
Take Salman and
Rupa back to L&D.
♪ ♪
Dr. Brown?
Mm, yes?
You're needed in
OR Two immediately.
Feel a bit of a cold coming on.
This isn't a day
to call in sick,
so I am just giving myself
some hydration and O2.
You can tell 'em
I'll be right there.
- You doctors are
miracle workers.
- Ah, all we did was
run some tests and give
you fluids and pain meds.
The real miracle is how
you somehow managed
to grab your makeup bag
and bring it in the ambulance.
Well, when a girl
feels her worst,
that's when she
must look her best.
Spoken like a true icon.
- Indeed.
- So I'm free to leave?
No, not yet.
We need to figure out
why your calcium is so high,
and then treat it.
Want to explain further?
Hypercalcemia could be
causing all your symptoms.
- Belly pain, weak muscles,
even kidney stones.
- High calcium.
My uncle and my
daddy both had that.
- Did their doctors know why?
- No.
They both got pancreatic cancer.
Passed away when
I was in high school.
Excuse me.
I heard that Dolly Parton had
collapsed onstage,
and I just thought...
The next best thing
is right here, honey.
She's the person I
always wanted to be.
You know what Dolly always said.
"Don't rent it, don't
lease it, own it."
I'm... sorry for intruding.
I see you're in very
good hands, so...
Hold on, handsome.
I will serenade
you with Dolly's hit,
"Kiss It And
Make It All Better."
Um... maybe later.
- We're gonna order some more
tests, and we'll be right back.
- Okay.
Dr. Bell, a moment, please?
I need to do genetic
tests and scans,
but I suspect Joseph
may have MEN 1.
Multiple Endocrine Neoplasia.
Would that explain
his family history
of high levels of calcium
and pancreatic tumors?
- Yes.
- If he has MEN 1,
he could have a tumor
in any of his endocrine glands.
I'm thinking parathyroids.
Which is where you
would come in, because...
- if I'm right,
he would need surgery.
- Yeah, okay.
Let me know what you find.
All right, go ahead
and put in the orders.
Hey.
Everything okay?
See the couple in Bay Four?
She has pelvic inflammatory
disease from gonorrhea.
Says she's 23, but I'm
not even sure she's 18.
We've been here all day.
And he hovers.
Doesn't leave her
side for a second.
He says they're
from out of town,
but she's already been in our ER
for an STD a few months ago.
- Listen to me. Listen...
- Just stop.
You think she's
being trafficked.
I need your help
getting her alone
so that I can find
out if she's safe.
Okay.
Yvette, Marcus,
this is Dr. Hawkins.
I brought him in to
consult. He also agrees
that a round of antibiotics
should clear your symptoms.
Great. We'll swing by the
pharmacy on our way out.
- Call in a prescription?
- Nic did.
But before you go, I'll
need to give you an exam.
Can't you just write
me a prescription, too?
Not without an
examination. Nic, why don't
you take Yvette to the
pharmacy while I give Marcus...
No, no, no, you ain't
treating me, okay?
You're treating her, and
we're taking off. Let's go.
But before you do any of
that, there's something else
I wanted to take a look at.
Do you mind if Dr. Hawkins
listens to your heart?
I heard a little abnormality
when I was
listening to it earlier.
This'll just take a second.
Yeah, I hear it, too. She
could have endocarditis.
It's a life-threatening
condition and result of her STD.
And can cause sudden death.
Bacteria travels
through the bloodstream
and enters into your
heart. We absolutely have to
- do a cardiac ultrasound.
- No.
Doctors make up stuff all
the time to get more tests.
- Come on, Yvette, let's go.
- Endocarditis is very real,
I promise you.
We can do the echo right now.
If it's negative,
you go on your way.
I just... know you
want Yvette to be safe.
I'll do it.
I don't want to die.
Then we'll go right
now. Thank you.
How long is this gonna take?
It won't take long at all.
We'll just be right back.
I'm going with her.
Only patients are
allowed in the echo suite.
Sorry about that. It's just
hospital rules, not mine.
- Dr. Brown, we are ready for
the Blalock-Taussig shunt.
- Great.
Let's have that graft on hand.
Time to dissect out the...
uh... uh...
The pulmonary artery?
Cautery, please.
Is it me, or is
she a little off?
This is not the surgical
star Torres led us to expect.
I saw her hooked to IVs earlier,
giving herself
supplemental oxygen.
She said she had a cold.
Laps.
Suction. Clamps to Dr. Brown.
She just lacerated
the pulmonary artery.
Dr. Brown.
- Judith!
- She's definitely swaying.
Dude, she may be intoxicated.
Dr. Brown, I'm tagging you out.
- No, you aren't. This is under control.
- You are impaired.
- Torres, talk to me.
- He's exsanguinating.
- I need help stopping
the bleeding.
- I will stop the bleed.
You've only made it worse.
His artery is turning further.
My patient, my surgery.
You are not fit to operate.
Clamps to me... now.
- Everything okay?
- Yeah, we stabilized the baby.
You commandeered my surgery.
Never, in all of my
years of operating,
have I had something so out...
so outrageous happen.
You should be stripped
of your privileges.
You tore this baby's
pulmonary artery.
You been drinking?
That was a typical
perioperative complication.
- Then submit to a blood test.
- Absolutely not.
You can't refuse, Dr. Brown.
It's in every surgeon's contract
at Chastain.
If you say no, we will alert
the hospital admin and
medical board that you refused.
What are you hiding, Dr. Brown?
Nothing.
Then prove it.
Do the blood draw.
Right here, right now,
so everybody can see it.
So Conrad's
hypothesis was correct.
This is likely MEN
1-related abnormal growth
of Doll E.'s... or should I
say Joseph's parathyroids.
That's why his
calcium is so high.
Yeah, it looks like
four-gland hyperplasia
causing the elevated calcium,
so they'll need to be removed.
This is a delicate
surgery just to avoid
- the critical nerves
in that region.
- Correct me if I'm wrong,
but damaging those nerves
could destroy Joseph's voice.
Yes. But I'll do
everything possible
to make sure that
doesn't happen.
And we'll monitor nerve
function throughout the case.
"We"? So I can assist?
I start on surgery tomorrow.
- I've been practicing
my two-handed ties.
- It was more of a...
it was a royal "we."
Oh.
But sure, you can scrub in.
My very existence
as Doll E. Wood
depends on my voice.
Well, you could still lip-synch.
Of course, but that's
not all that's involved.
Dolly Parton talks, a lot.
She has an intimate
rapport with her audience.
Doll E. Wood has
to have a voice.
She must talk to her
audience. She must.
Keeping your abnormal
parathyroids in place
could cause a
hypercalcemic crisis.
That's what happened today.
Next time you could die.
You said "could"
cause a fatal
"hyperhoozamajiggy" crisis.
- So it's not certain.
- No.
But it's a risk that
you shouldn't take.
When I found my inner Doll,
my whole life went
from black and white
to all the colors
of the rainbow.
"If-if you want the
rainbow, you got
"to put up with the rain.
Storms make trees
take deeper roots."
Oh, this boy's a gem.
He's quoting Dolly.
"If you don't like the
road you're walking,
"start paving another one.
We cannot direct the wind,
but we can adjust the sails."
Okay, I-I think we get the gist.
Everything possible
to preserve your voice.
Shall we schedule the surgery?
No.
Okay.
What about the ultrasound?
You don't actually need it.
There's nothing
wrong with your heart.
We just wanted to have a
private conversation with you.
What did I do?
Oh, nothing. You didn't...
You didn't do anything.
You tricked me.
Marcus was right.
I can't trust you.
You know, sometimes, um,
in the hospital, we see
people who we think
might be in a
situation that isn't safe.
So, um...
we just wanted to make sure
that you're not one of them.
I'm fine.
Marcus is my fiancé. We're in
love and we're getting married.
I want to go now.
Look, Marcus doesn't need
to know about any of this.
It's your choice. I mean,
we're not gonna force you
to do or say
anything. We just...
We want you to
know that you can.
Yvette?
You're safe, okay?
You're totally in control here.
Okay?
Okay.
Okay. We understand now.
It's okay. It's okay.
You're safe. You're
safe. We're here for you.
♪ ♪
- They're all coming out
to see you, Doll.
- Oh, stop it.
I wish you'd reconsider.
You're a dear.
But I will take
whatever time I have left
as the full and complete Doll E.
If I die young like my
daddy, well, so be it.
Can I have... just
have a minute?
You know, my dad raised
me on the Queen of Country.
- Get out.
- Yeah.
My daddy took me
straight to Dollywood
the minute I could
hold up my head.
I was practically
baptized there.
So, were the two of you close?
We were.
My daddy was a pastor.
I was supposed
to be next in line,
till he realized what was what.
He knew I wasn't
the son he expected.
I believe that broke his heart.
He talked for a while
about conversion therapy,
but he saw how I felt
about that and he gave it up.
When I was bullied or attacked,
he was the first one
in line to defend me.
'Cause he was a good
man, a loving man,
who walked the
walk of a Christian.
Judge not lest ye be judged.
He gave me the best gift of all.
Acceptance.
You know, I'm thinking that
maybe you're a lot like him.
Too much, as it turns out.
Well...
if your dad could
have had the surgery,
and it cost him his voice,
so he couldn't preach,
but you still had your dad,
would that have
been better than...
I see where you're
headed. Very clever.
You don't have to share
the same fate as your father.
We found this in
time to save you.
And you may wake up
with your voice intact.
There's a decent chance.
But if not...
"I can see the light of
a clear blue morning..."
"I can see the light
of a brand-new day."
You know.
"Everything's gonna be okay."
Oh...
You better give me some sugar.
So we'll schedule the surgery?
Okay.
How did you meet Marcus?
I was 16 and fighting
with my mom a lot.
So I started to text with a man
named Luis that I met on an app.
He told me that he'd
help me run away.
And after a while, I
began to like that idea.
So, one day I climbed
out my bedroom window.
He had a car waiting.
There was another
man in the car.
They blindfolded me
and they drove away.
They drove for a long time.
Most likely across state lines.
Uh, they took me to a motel.
Marcus was there.
He said he had a
client waiting for me.
I had no idea what
he meant, but...
But then he took
me to a motel room
and he left me with that man
and he did what he wanted to me.
My old life ended right there.
After that, Marcus said
that I was now ruined,
and that I belonged to him.
I could never go home again.
He said that no one would
ever love me except him.
You know that none
of that is true, right?
And you are not ruined.
And you're safe now. You
don't have to do that anymore.
I hate it.
I hate all of it, but he
said that he'd kill me.
He'd kill my whole family
if I ever told anyone.
We're gonna make sure
that doesn't happen. Nic?
We'll be back in
two seconds, okay?
Okay.
I've notified social services.
They'll take over, find
her a safe place to stay.
I'll go check on him.
I'll stay with her.
Where the hell is she?
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
It's okay, we're
safe. They've got him.
It's okay.
My work is my life.
I've performed the
most complex surgeries.
The Norwood, the
Glenn, the Bentall.
Sometimes back-to-back.
Patients came from
all over the world.
Dr. Brown, you have
an alcohol problem.
You almost killed a baby today.
That baby still needs surgery.
He needs it right
now, and fortunately,
I am the only one capable
of doing it, so let's just
- go back to the OR...
- We are taking
Baby Farhad back to the OR,
but Torres and I will operate.
- No, I can do it.
- No, you cannot.
That's not because I'm
drunk. I'm in withdrawal.
Just get me a drink.
I'll be ready to go.
We'll treat you with benzos
and you can guide us.
But you are not
cutting. That is final.
With benzos, I would be
too drowsy to guide you.
Without a drink, my
symptoms will only escalate.
You've seen what happens.
These shakes will get worse,
I'll vomit, maybe hallucinate.
Even seize... I know
what you're thinking.
You're thinking that I'm just
an addict making up a line
to get her fix,
but you also know
that what I'm saying
is medically accurate.
The fact is, unless
you let me drink,
I will not be able to
help you with the surgery.
We got to get her a drink.
- No way.
- There is no other option,
Pravesh.
Can you count
backwards from ten?
I'd rather sing, since it
might be for the last time.
♪ It's been a long, dark night ♪
♪ And I've been
waitin' for the morning ♪
♪ It's been a long, hard fight ♪
♪ But I see a brand-new day ♪
♪ A dawning ♪
♪ And I can't s... ♪
Okay.
Time to scrub in.
One more shot.
Last one, right?
Mm-hmm.
Ready.
All right. Let's make it happen.
Baby Farhad's
parents want updates.
Are you gonna tell
them about Dr. Brown?
We usually don't if there are no
adverse outcomes to the patient.
This is unacceptable.
You know my dad would
never approve of this.
How can giving
Dr. Brown a drink be okay?
It's not right.
And I know that alcohol is
considered haram, and forbidden.
But we've exhausted all options.
This is the only
possible solution.
Farhad needs surgery,
and he needs it now.
What if she gets drunk?
She knows how much
to drink to function
and not get drunk.
I promise you, she will
never touch Farhad again.
Let's start by freeing
the skin from the heart
by tracing along
the transition zone.
Scalpel to me.
Retractors to Torres.
All right, be careful
not to pinch the P.A.
- Chest is open. Let's
rotate the heart in.
Hmm, it won't fit.
The heart is too big.
What if we take
down the diaphragm?
Still not enough space.
You have to do a
partial lung resection.
Removing the right lower lobe
should give us enough room.
That would compromise
his lung function.
He could end up
in respiratory failure.
Well, partial lung
resection is our only option.
We have to take the risk.
This is the first parathyroid.
Normally the size
of a grain of rice,
and here, it is enlarged.
And right next to it is the
recurrent laryngeal nerve.
Incredible. This morning
I heard him perform,
and now I see
what lets him sing.
So we are gonna save
half this parathyroid.
And reimplant it into his arm.
That way he has enough
remaining gland function
so his calcium doesn't plummet.
You came prepared.
Would you like to assist
me in removing the next one?
I have to admit, I
am a bit nervous.
We're working so
close to the nerve.
Well, he has very
challenging anatomy,
but if we're careful...
We lost the nerve signal.
- What the hell did you do?
- Nothing. I didn't
touch anything.
Give me that. Steady.
The nerve may have been damaged.
Dr. Bell, if he
loses his voice...
Stop talking.
Where's Marcus?
He's been arrested, Yvette.
We don't want him
to hurt other women.
You'll be safe,
where you're going.
They have plenty of resources.
They'll take care of you.
For a while.
Then what?
I never finished high school. I
have no way to make a living.
I can't undo the
mistakes I've made.
You were a child,
and you are blameless
for what happened to you.
Go take your life back.
It's not gonna be
easy, but I promise
you can do it.
I've been in and out of
hospitals a bunch of times.
And no one has
ever taken the time
to try and help me.
So thank you.
Come here.
You let us know if you
need anything, okay?
Okay.
Bye.
♪ ♪
Partial lung resection complete.
Now place the
heart into his chest.
Ah... the heart is back in.
Let's align the breast bone
and chest wall, then close.
Sutures and wires
to me, por favor.
I'm impressed.
You should consider adding
pediatric cardiac surgery
to your triple board rolodex.
I'm grateful for your
help, Dr. Brown.
But surgeon to surgeon,
I really hope you
seek help yourself.
I don't have to tell you
that alcoholism is a disease.
But there are treatment
programs for doctors.
I know our system looks away.
We live in a culture that
discourages asking for help
or speaking up.
It makes it very
easy to self-destruct.
But you have a gift.
And you have
patients who need you.
Let's bring the
chest wall together.
BP is 40/20.
Heart rate is 200.
He's about to code!
Max out pressors.
- His heart is too fragile.
- No, he's too swollen.
She's right.
Closing the chest is
constricting the heart,
preventing it from
pumping effectively.
We need to keep the chest open.
Cutters.
Oh, this is too horrible.
They'll try to close
his chest later.
But if they can't...
All right, the
swelling's gone down.
It's time to close his chest.
Back to the OR?
No.
We're gonna do it right here.
Bringing the chest wall
and sternum together.
Pressure and
heart rate are stable.
Heart is pumping effectively.
He'll need more
surgeries in the future
to reconstruct his chest,
but at least for now,
he has a chance to thrive.
One last thing...
Little man needs his armor.
Hey.
Just got off the
phone with my dad.
He's really happy to hear
Farhad's doing so well.
Yeah, he beat the odds.
Chastain came through.
And we got lucky.
There's more, Devon.
My dad said if you wanted
to continue seeing me,
you could come be a
doctor in my country.
He would get you a great
spot in our finest hospital.
Wow.
That's lovely.
But this is my home.
Please, just think about it.
The offer stands.
Things don't have
to end between us.
When's your flight home?
Tomorrow morning.
- You done with your shift?
- Yeah.
Yeah?
Good.
Not here.
♪ ♪
Red gurney to
surgical waiting area...
Joseph.
Good to see you awake.
Surgery went well. Your
calcium levels are stable.
- Can we hear your voice?
- That's premature.
It'll take him a little
while to recover.
It's okay, I...
It... it doesn't sound good.
Well, that is to be expected.
You're going to be hoarse
after being intubated.
It's normal.
It'll get better. Soon.
Will it be like before?
I hope so.
Thank you both.
It's in God's hands.
What are we doing next Sunday?
Let's go back to brunch.
We did not get
the full experience,
not by a long shot.
I can't believe that
was this morning.
Ah, just another
day at the office.
- So...
- Hmm.
So we're gonna start telling
everyone we're engaged, huh?
Let's shout it
from the rooftops.
Oh, and in the
spirit of being open,
I have a confession.
I, um, may or may not
have eaten the chocolates
that you hid in
your sock drawer.
- You didn't.
- I did.
Aw...
- Well, I have
nothing to confess.
- Oh, really? Nothing?
Fine.
That diamond on your ring
is fake. It's cubic zirconium.
- Really?
- Yes.
Huh, it looks so real.
Well, in that case,
you want it back?
- Wait...
- I mean, if it's fake...
- What?
- We don't have to get married.
- Honestly.
- No. No, no, no, no, no.
I'm kidding, I'm
kidding, I'm kidding.
I love it.
♪ ♪
This isn't over.
I know.
♪ It's been a long, dark night ♪
♪ And I've been
waiting for the morning ♪
♪ It's been a long, hard fight ♪
♪ But I see a
brand-new day dawning ♪
♪ I've been looking
for the sunshine ♪
- ♪ You know I ain't seen it ♪
- Mom.
♪ In so long... ♪
♪ But everything's
gonna work out just fine ♪
♪ And everything's
gonna be all right ♪
♪ That's been all wrong ♪
♪ 'Cause I can see the light ♪
♪ Of a clear blue morning ♪
♪ I can see the light ♪
♪ Of a brand-new day... ♪
♪ Of a clear blue morning ♪
♪ Oh, and everything's
gonna be all right ♪
♪ It's gonna be okay ♪
♪ I can see the light ♪
♪ Of a clear blue morning ♪
♪ Oh, and everything's
gonna be all right ♪
♪ Everything's
♪ It's gonna be okay ♪
♪ 'Cause I can... ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH