A crane collapsed
in downtown Trenton.
Don't care.
My great-grandfather.
No, it's just a book he wrote.
Open it up.
Seriously? You're
giving this to us?
It's a big step you're taking.
I wanted to congratulate you.
I understand that's
the adult thing to do.
How did you know?
I've known for a while.
The fact that you decided to
cohabitate is not exactly a spoiler.
Unless my intel is wrong.
Trouble in paradise?
We have to get to Trenton.
Somebody, help me.
Can you hear me?
Hmm.
Did that sound like a "yes"?
Sir, we have to get you to the
OR. You have a bad wound,
but we're gonna pack it and
transport you as fast as we can.
Skull fracture. Glasgow Coma
score of 11. She's immediate.
Move on. This guy's dead.
His wounds aren't so...
Forget the wound,
look at his toes.
Atherosclerotic emboli. He'll
never survive the surgery.
Maybe his shoes were too tight.
It's not the shoes, skin
shows smoker's facies.
He's not gonna
make it to morning.
He'll just take up
an ambulance ride,
surgeons' time and an ICU bed.
He's expectant. Leave him.
I only nodded off for a second.
I lost control of the
load. I'm so sorry.
Don't worry. We're
gonna get you out of here.
I'm sorry.
He's secure. McCREANEY: Ready?
Three, two, one.
Crane operator. He made
it through amazingly well.
Lucid and responsive,
stable fracture, right humerus.
Haven't gotten to
his lower half yet.
Tell me when something hurts.
I fell asleep, killed
all those people.
Something other
than your conscience.
Is that a pill in your pocket
or are you just happy to
have a tiny, pill-shaped penis?
Caffeine pills.
You fell asleep taking these?
I drank two cups of coffee, too.
Is that normal for you?
No, I hate coffee.
I'm working on no sleep.
My daughter has the flu.
This much caffeine
for a coffee virgin...
There's no way he fell
asleep. He passed out.
Which means a
neurological disorder
caused the crash, not fatigue.
Hey!
We're taking the crane
operator back to Princeton.
They said he was
barely hurt, he can wait.
Steal an ambulance
and call the team.
Tell them we've got a case.
House, no. I need you here.
But he needs me there, and
he moans louder than you do.
There were over 100
people in that building,
only 76 have been accounted for.
Foreman and your team can
handle the crane operator for now.
Having fun down there?
Lots!
Every time Cuddy
leans over a patient,
it's another opportunity
for a downblouse nipslip.
What's going on
between her and Lucas?
Besides them moving in together?
That's not enough for you?
I gave her the
housewarming gift earlier,
and she paused
for a split second,
like she was hiding something.
It's probably her moral
revulsion at housewarming gifts.
Or maybe she didn't
want to accept a gift
for something she
wasn't gonna do.
You actually think they're
not moving in together?
What was that? You okay?
Yeah.
Vending machine collapsed.
She still using your
ex-wife as her realtor?
As far as I know.
Well, know a little farther,
will you? Look into it.
Hey!
Somebody down here!
If you can hear me, tap
three times or call out.
Is anyone there?
I'm not getting anything.
I heard something. There's
got to be a void down there.
There's a million voids down
there, it was the parking garage.
But our equipment hasn't
picked up any movement,
dogs haven't
picked up any scent.
There's smashed cars down there,
you don't think that gasoline
could throw off their scent?
We gotta get back to work, okay?
We'll get to this area
soon. Excuse me.
Anybody hear me?
Hey! Can anybody hear me?
Help me.
What's your name?
Please...
My husband's gift...
I was supposed to pick it
up at the framers. It's on Elm.
You should have told me earlier,
I could've picked
it up on the way.
What's your name?
It's a picture from our
Tortola trip for his birthday.
I'm not asking your name
because I wanna become friends.
I'm trying to gauge
your mental state.
Hanna.
Okay, that's a start.
What day of the week is it?
Tuesday.
Better still.
What happened?
You know that giant
construction crane next door?
It's kind of on top
of you right now.
Okay, I'm gonna
try to pull you out.
Ow! My leg!
Okay. Okay.
I really need to get help.
No. Stay.
Someone else will come.
No one knows I'm down here.
Please! Stay with me!
Don't leave me in the dark!
I'll be right back.
No! Don't leave me in the dark!
Please stay!
He's still in the ER, House.
We haven't had time
to start a differential.
Perfect, we'll start right
now. Put me on speaker.
What causes syncope?
Your guy's stable. The
two dozen other patients...
Don't need to be diagnosed,
they just need to be bandaged.
What causes syncope?
Vasovagal reaction.
Meningioma, sick
sinus syndrome...
Or you're wrong and
he just fell asleep.
How's he gonna sleep
with 50 cups of coffee
going through his veins?
Were you never a
medical resident?
I hear Ten, Eleven and
Twelve. Where's Thirteen?
She's not here.
And answer to your
next question is,
"I don't know where she is."
Do you have the answer
to my question after that?
A space-occupying lesion
in his brain is most likely.
MRI will prove I'm right.
Or it'll just prove he suffered
head trauma from the crash.
Which we'd want to find anyway.
Two birds with one scan. Do it.
Having trouble finding
a vein for Hanna's IV.
Is she getting weaker? Paler?
No, no, she's stable.
That means her blood loss is
minimal. It buys us some time.
Get the IV into her tibia.
It's almost hollow, feeds
into the venous system.
Which they, obviously, don't
teach you in EMT school.
This side's still leaning pretty
bad, got to shore up this beam.
What do you got?
We need six 4X4s...
Told you I'd be back.
Heard you might be thirsty.
I assume that bodes
well for the rescue.
Structural beam, high-compression
concrete. I can't break it up.
You can't get me out of here?
No. Just means
we're gonna move on
to a different
piece of equipment.
I got airbags coming
in that'll lift 70 tons.
What's your name?
You testing my mental state?
If I'm gonna be stuck
down here for a while,
I'd like somebody to talk to.
Look, the guy who just left
is the one who's gonna be
holding your hand through all this.
You can talk to him.
Little pinch.
Ow! Ow!
Okay. Big pinch.
I got to call my husband.
Can I use your phone?
No bars down here.
L'chaim.
Where're you going? Don't worry.
Fire Marshal Bill
will be back soon.
So, I hope I didn't weird
you out, giving you that gift.
Can we talk about this later?
Of course.
Is now later?
Maybe things aren't
going so well with Lucas?
If so, I'm sorry. I didn't
mean to step into anything.
There's no problems. We're
doing just great. Thank you.
So why the weirdness?
Can you help?
When I opened it, I didn't
think it was a housewarming gift,
I thought it was an
engagement present.
It just happened last night.
No wonder you'd
wanna hide this from me,
since I'm such
a delicate flower.
I didn't know what to say,
and I've been
slightly distracted.
That might make sense, except
you're not wearing the ring.
So you are hiding it,
which begs the question...
House, it's in my office drawer
because I knew I
was coming here.
It's not weird,
there's no mystery.
I'm just getting married.
Excuse me.
How much longer?
Less than a minute.
Are you in any pain?
Nothing new. Just a
little claustrophobic.
Shouldn't you be taking
care of those other people?
The ones that I hurt?
Everything checks out okay.
My nose is bleeding.
It's expected, given the
trauma you've sustained.
That's not expected.
The way things fell,
this support beam
is now holding up a
giant pile of rubble.
We can't lift it without
jeopardizing everyone down here.
So it's time to
discuss amputation.
No.
Please listen to me. You've
been down here almost two hours.
By the time they
clear away the rubble...
We're not cutting off her leg.
You don't have to rush to
this to make his job easier.
You kidding me?
We leave the leg pinned,
we're risking crush syndrome.
What's that?
Your leg isn't getting
enough circulation.
The longer it's pinned,
the more the muscle dies.
So what does that
mean, like a limp?
Dying muscles release poisons.
We free your leg, the poisons
rush back into your system.
It could stop your heart.
So could cheeseburgers.
Just get your lazy friends
to start moving that pile.
She's got two more hours before
crush syndrome could possibly set in.
McCREANEY: We're
digging up there by hand.
I can't guarantee
I can get 10 tons
of debris pulled
off in two hours.
Well, you need to try.
It's my leg.
McCREANEY: It's not just crush
syndrome you got to worry about, okay?
There's gas leaks, there's fire,
we can never rule out
secondary collapses,
no matter how much
we shore this thing up.
You think chopping
off someone's limb
inside a pile of
dirty rocks is safe?
Sepsis, fat embolism,
hemorrhage...
Those risks are nothing compared
to the risk of this thing
coming down again.
Captain, he's a jerk, but
that's what the patient wants.
Can we please just give
it a couple more hours?
Yeah.
I got to get up to triage.
Thank you, Doctor.
House.
You don't need to thank
me. It just makes sense.
Just promise me you
won't let them cut off my leg.
I promise.
Does that make you feel better?
For some reason, it does.
Your phone is working down here.
Switched carriers, better
rollover minutes. Talk.
MRI was clean, but afterwards
he started bleeding
out of his eyes and nose.
So there was something
wrong before the collapse.
Unless it's just conjunctive
coagulopathy from the trauma.
Yeah, yeah, you don't think
he was sick before, we get it.
You're wrong.
Brain infection?
Sorry I'm late.
- Where were you?
- Physical therapy.
I left my phone in my locker.
The infection causes
neurological symptoms,
goes systemic, and
DIC causes the bleed.
Good theory.
Except for the part
that there's no fever.
Get an X-ray venogram.
See if you can find a
reason for your existence.
Also look for venous
sinus thrombosis.
We would've seen it on the MRI.
Not if you were too
busy not looking for it.
We should X-ray for
a facial fracture first,
this could all be simple trauma.
Just do what I tell you.
I'll be back in 10 minutes.
You're leaving?
There's a dozen people
here who can save you.
I'm apparently the only one
who can save this other guy.
Wait.
Don't go.
Hanna's freaking out.
She's having a panic
attack, she can't breathe,
she's gonna rip out all her IVs.
So calm her down.
She wants you.
I'm flattered. Give her oxygen.
They won't let O2 down
there, fear of explosion.
You have to go back.
She needs you, House.
You only came back
because I freaked out, right?
Not at all. I just realized
how big and scary the world is,
and how cozy and
safe this little place is.
Thank you. I'm
sorry I needed you.
Here. Call your husband.
Charlie?
I'm here in...
They called you?
They're helping me.
Are you coming?
I don't know how this
could've happened.
It's your birthday.
I'm so sorry.
See, this is why I
lied about the phone.
Your BP is spiking, so you're
bleeding faster from your leg wound,
and we'll have less
time to save it. Hang up.
Okay. Okay, they're
telling me I have to go.
That was stupid of me.
It was nice.
I don't see that
as a contradiction.
He was already on his way.
He was in Baltimore and
they all saw it on the news.
How many people were hurt?
What did I tell you about not
raising your blood pressure?
Can I ask what's
wrong with your leg?
Crane fell on it.
Small world.
You could've just said no.
I'll remember that for
my next human contact.
Would you pray with me?
No.
I'm not in the habit of encouraging
my patients' superstitions.
How's that a habit?
You plan on getting trapped
under a building again?
I don't believe in God.
I don't either.
Please.
I always thought
if I did the right thing,
if I treated people right,
then good things
would happen to me.
Do you think
that's how it works?
I didn't use to.
Then recently I tried.
Now I don't know.
McCREANEY: Good news.
Advancing catheter
through interior jugular vein.
You told House
you were at therapy.
Did you transcribe
the entire meeting?
Entering the cavernous sinus.
Your therapy's on Thursdays.
It got rescheduled.
Injecting dye.
Really?
I'm not gonna rat
you out, we're friends.
I just wanna make
sure you're okay.
No filling defects.
Don't worry. I'm okay.
Do you think we could be
friends when I get out of here?
Yeah.
We'll catch a ball game or a
group sex show or something.
Put it in there.
Okay, when the beam starts
lifting, you're gonna feel pain.
It's gonna be like your foot's
gone to sleep times a billion.
You'll notice that I'm
waiting till now to tell you.
We're ready.
Lifting.
I'm feeling the pain already.
That's good. Means
the pressure's coming off.
Closer to getting out of here.
Come on. Help me pull her out.
Come on.
It's moving!
Hanna!
What the hell happened?
McCREANEY: I think the adjacent
beam snapped during the lift.
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday!
We got a secondary collapse.
We're all right,
how are you guys?
Rescue 1, copy the mayday.
Main tunnel looks fine.
Red Team is on the way.
Lift this up.
One, two...
The kit. Give me the kit.
McCREANEY: All right.
No breath sounds on the left
side. Tension pneumothorax.
Hey, Hanna.
One of your lungs has collapsed.
I'm gonna have
to reinflate it, okay?
Hey, you better get back up top,
make sure you
didn't nick an artery.
I'm gonna have to go.
McCREANEY: It's
okay. You're all right.
You're lucky this isn't worse.
You know who's even luckier?
You and just about every other
human being who wasn't down there.
What did the venogram say?
Clean. Now the guy is
starting to spike a fever.
Subarachnoid bleed.
Meningitis?
He didn't say his neck was sore.
That's because
everything's sore.
He just took a 15-story swan
dive into concrete. Do an LP.
We also have to
consider other infections.
So you're suggesting
we do an LP?
I guess I am.
Genius.
Hey, bad news.
Because of the collapse,
we can't try the airbag again
until we get
everything off the top.
Be five, six hours, at least.
Then we have to amputate. No.
It's been four hours already.
It used to be a long
shot, now it's crazy.
Crush syndrome is basically
a build up of potassium.
If we remove potassium...
We're already treating
with sodium bicarbonate.
Not with glucose and insulin.
We got glucose in the kit, there's
got to be a diabetic here somewhere.
You want to dose
the insulin here?
In a non-hospital
setting? That is insane.
It's not worth it. Really?
Because I think I'm
the only one here
who knows what a leg is worth.
And fortunately, you're not
the one who's in charge, he is.
And he knows that
I'd testify against him
if Hanna sues
for cutting off a leg
without exhausting every option.
Give us a minute?
I know you're angry,
but please don't put her life
at risk just to get back at me.
Really? Wow.
So this is all about you now?
You took her side against me
right after you heard
about my engagement.
Yeah, that must be it. It's not
that you're a pathetic narcissist.
I don't love you.
So just accept it and
move on with your life
instead of making
everyone miserable.
That's great.
A life lesson from a
middle-aged single mom
who's dating a man-child.
Screw you.
I'm sick of making
excuses for you.
I'm sick of other people
having to tiptoe around you
and make their own lives worse
while they try to keep
you from collapsing.
I'm done.
Fantastic. Just stay
away from my patient.
What are you clinging to, House?
You're gonna risk her
life just to save her leg?
It really worked out
well for you, didn't it?
What do you have in
your life? Honestly, tell me.
I'm moving on.
Wilson is moving on.
And you? You've got
nothing, House. Nothing.
I'm going down there,
and I'm gonna convince
her to let me cut her leg off.
If you have any decency
left, you'll stay out of it.
No.
Dr. House promised.
If there was any other way...
It doesn't hurt right
now. I can wait.
Dr. House,
tell her.
Hanna,
we have to amputate your leg.
No. You said that
there was time.
There was. And it's run out.
No.
You asked me how
I had hurt my leg.
I had a blood clot, and
the muscle was dying.
And I had all these doctors
telling me I should amputate.
And I said no. And they did this
very risky operation.
I almost died.
But you saved your leg.
I wish I hadn't.
They cut out a chunk of
muscle about the size of my fist.
They left me with this
mutilated, useless thing.
And I'm in pain every day.
And it changed me.
It made me a harder person.
A worse person.
And now...
Now I'm alone.
You don't wanna be like me.
You got a husband who loves you.
You have friends,
you can start a family.
You have a life.
And this is just a leg.
Okay.
I got it.
I can't put you out 'cause it could
depress your respiration too much.
This should take
away some of the pain.
Will it be quick?
I'll use the scalpel to slice
through the skin, muscle and fat.
That should go pretty fast.
Then I'll switch over to the
electric saw when I get to the bone.
It's two bones about as
thick as a broom stick,
and takes about as
long to get through.
I'm gonna cut as close
to the concrete as I can.
Save as much of
your limb as possible.
Then the orthopedic surgeons
back at the hospital
will clean you up,
have you fitted
for a prosthetic.
You'll be running circles
around me in no time.
How bad will it hurt?
Like nothing you've
ever felt before.
Hanna.
Baby, I'm so sorry.
Shut up. It's all right.
You always loved my legs.
Baby, I don't care
about your legs.
Baby, I love you.
I love you.
What?
He's fallen into a coma.
LP was clean, but...
What are his vitals?
Excuse me, Officer.
What do you mean "Officer"?
How long has there
been a cop there?
I don't know, 10 minutes.
He was being questioned
when he fell into the coma.
Was anything else making him nervous
or worried before his other symptoms?
He was claustrophobic
right before the bleed.
And before the
fever, we told him
that he probably
did fall asleep.
It's his BP spiking.
But that didn't cause
his first symptom.
Yeah, it did. All the caffeine.
We thought the
problem was in his toilet,
and by that, of course,
I mean his head,
which distracted
us from the fact that
it could've been just a
clog in his sewer pipe,
and by that, of course, I
mean his spinal cord and...
Blah, blah, blah,
blah. You get the idea.
An arachnoid cyst on his lower
spine, that's why we missed it.
He's been sitting
10 hours a day,
spiked his spinal
fluid pressure.
Run a CT...
BP 72 over 42.
Hanna?
Hanna? I can't breathe.
I can't breathe.
Breath sounds bilaterally.
It's not another pneumothorax.
Neck veins flat, no tamponade.
Damn it. I waited too long.
Hanna, you've got a clot in
your lungs. I'm gonna fix this.
IV streptokinase.
What's happening?
What's going on?
Her body won't get any oxygen
unless we can bust the clot.
This is a blood thinner.
Is she gonna be all right?
It'll make her bleed more,
we'll take care of that next.
It's not busting the clot.
Maybe it's the heart.
What? It's not a clot.
It's a fat embolism
from the amputation.
Okay. So what can we do?
Come on.
Do something. Please.
Please, do something.
Come on, guys, do
something. Come on.
Please, come on, do something.
Come on, do
something! Do something!
There's no way to
prevent a fat embolism.
Even if you'd
done this in an OR,
you couldn't have saved her.
You can't blame
yourself for her death.
This wasn't your fault.
That's the point!
I did everything right.
She died anyway.
Why the hell did you think that
would make me feel any better?
You shouldn't be
alone right now.
You're bleeding.
I'm gonna give you a
task, as an employee.
Get out of my way.
What's that?
I'm asking for some time off.
What's wrong?
Are you okay?
Obviously not.
You're gonna leap
across the room
and grab them out of my hand?
No.
It's your choice if you
wanna go back on drugs.
Okay.
Just so you know, I'm finding
it hard to see the downside.
You need to rebandage
your shoulder.
Is that why you're
here? Foreman sent you?
No.
Here to yell at me again?
Well, I'm running out of ideas.
Lucas...
Oh, great.
You're feeling
uncomfortable again.
Probably means you just got back
for some quickie
wedding in Vegas,
or you're already pregnant...
I ended it.
What?
I'm stuck, House.
I keep wanting to move forward,
I keep wanting to
move on, and I can't.
I'm in my new house
with my new fiancé,
and all I can
think about is you.
I just need to know
if you and I can work.
You think I can fix myself?
I don't know.
'Cause I am the most
screwed up person in the world.
I know.
I love you.
I wish I didn't.
But I can't help it.
How do I know I'm
not hallucinating?
Did you take the Vicodin?
Nope.
Then I think we're okay.
Yeah.