Crockett, it's okay.
What happened
is in the past.
Can't remember
what it was.
Now we just have to
set up the nursery,
but in the meantime,
how about that date?
You won't turn yourself in.
I can't let this go on.
I thought we had
an understanding.
You can't possibly know
what it's like.
Every day I say
I'm gonna quit.
I will turn myself in.
I can go with you.
Yeah, I'd like that.
Come to my place?
Hey.
Mmm, breakfast?
There's a spot on the corner
with excellent French press.
Um, what time is it?
No, sorry.
I gotta get to work.
My shift starts soon.
Mmm...
Listen,
what we talked
about last night,
this doesn't
change anything,
does it?
You mean my
reporting myself?
Do you think
I slept with you
just to get out of it?
No.
I just wanna make sure
that's still the plan.
It is.
I just need to round
on a few patients
so I can hand them off,
then I talk
to Ms. Goodwin.
I'll come with you.
Yeah, I want you to.
Hannah,
you're so smart.
And tough.
You're so much more
than this addiction.
I know you're
gonna beat it.
Hi, Mr. Sher.
Oh, please, call me Lewis.
This is my
ex-wife, Elaine.
Hi.
And my daughter Harper.
I'm Dr. Manning.
So, I see you're experiencing
some abdominal pain.
His tummy started hurting
as soon as he got off
the airplane today.
Oh, really? And where
did he fly in from?
Daddy lives in Geneva.
It's 2:20 in the afternoon
there right now.
Oh.
Harper, sweetie,
just let the doctor
do her work, okay?
It's okay.
I'm just impressed
you know so much
about Geneva.
My daddy works
in a laboratory there.
He's a chemical scientist.
Wow.
A polymer engineer.
You mind?
Harper,
honey, come here.
Does your job require
you to handle
any toxic materials?
I work with a lot
of heavy metals,
but I always take proper
precautions. Why?
I am hearing
some congestion
in your chest.
As well as
a slight discoloration
in your eyes.
It could be due
to some kind
of toxic exposure.
Let's get a tox screen,
and a CBC, BMP and a UA.
Okay.
Is my daddy
gonna be okay?
I promise, I am
gonna take very good
care of your dad.
Okay?
I'll be back
to check on you soon.
Give me one sec.
Dr. Manning?
Yeah?
There's something
he's not telling you,
and I'm worried
if you don't know it,
it will be a problem
in treating him.
Absolutely.
What is it?
Well, everything
he just said in there,
it's not true.
I'm sorry?
Lewis is not
a polymer engineer
in Geneva.
His real name
is Derek Jordan,
and he's an actor
from New York.
An actor?
Yes.
It's a long story,
but I hired him
to play this role.
I don't understand.
What role?
The role of my
daughter's father.
One, two.
Harper, sweetie,
let's go get a snack
so the doctor can
talk to your father.
Be right back, Daddy.
Okay, sweetie.
Elaine filled me in
on your arrangement.
I understand you want
to keep pretending
for Harper's sake,
but since we're alone,
I do need to gather some
real information from you.
So, your initial
tox screen was negative,
and your hemoglobin
is low.
Have you ever had
any blood disorders
or iron deficiencies
in your past?
I don't think so.
Okay, why don't you
give me your
doctor's information,
and I'll have your
medical records sent
over from New York.
As my daughter told you,
I live in Geneva.
Mr. Jordan, if I'm gonna
treat you properly,
I'm gonna need your
medical history,
not your character's.
My name is Lewis Sher,
and I don't know
what you're talking about.
Hey, Doris, will you
add a liver panel to
my patient in Three?
And also page
Dr. Charles.
This guy is nuts.
Thanks.
Hey, how's your
hormone therapy going?
It feels
like my skin is
crawling with ants.
But other than that,
I'm holding up.
Hang in there.
Hopefully your numbers
will level out soon.
Yeah.
Need some
help over here.
Okay. Hold this.
Siana Fredericks,
seven months pregnant.
I just paged her OB.
Okay, let's take her
to Treatment Four.
I'm Dr. Halstead.
This is Nurse Lockwood.
You having contractions?
I'm not in labor.
I'm having a pain crisis.
Are you talking about
a sickle cell crisis?
Yes.
Have you had any
flare-ups recently?
Not since
I've been pregnant.
My OB has me on
a special diet
that's been helping.
Is there anyone
we can call?
I already spoke
to my husband.
He's stuck
in Minneapolis.
When did the pain start?
Yesterday morning.
Let's get her on oxygen,
hang a liter of saline,
and push two milligrams
of morphine.
No!
No morphine.
Siana, 24 hours
is a long time.
We have to get your
crisis under control.
You don't understand.
I've been through
three rounds of IVF.
I'm finally
carrying an embryo
that doesn't have
this awful disease.
I'm gonna make sure
everything is perfect
for this baby.
Please call
my OB, Dr. Asher.
Hannah Asher?
Yes.
She's been helping
with my birth plan.
She'll know what to do.
Okay. Yeah, we'll contact
Dr. Asher, order some labs.
I'll be back to check
on you soon.
Okay.
You're calling OB?
I'll try Asher's cell.
We're friends.
Going straight
to voicemail.
OB must be backed up
this morning.
I'll run up and find her.
All right.
How'd it go?
He wouldn't break
character for me either.
Break character?
This isn't a play.
Yeah, I mean,
I've been doing
this for 30 years.
This is a new one.
And this poor little girl
growing up with this lie?
Okay, but she's
not sick. He is.
So what do we do?
I had fun last night.
Me, too.
How about we do it
again tonight?
Wow.
Absolutely.
April. With me.
Noah.
Paramedics just called.
I got a guy over
on Chicago Avenue
with some sort
of cardiac event.
All my attendings
are tied up.
Was hoping that you
two could handle it.
How long until
they land?
They're not.
I need you two
to get over there.
Guy's refusing
to get in the ambo.
So, you think that
he's really sick?
Yes, his symptoms
are all over the place.
But he refuses
to cooperate.
God.
We can't make a diagnosis
without an accurate history.
Do you think that
you could talk to him?
Get him to drop
the performance?
I wish that I could,
but that is how he is.
When I first met Derek,
he was playing
a paraplegic on Broadway.
He would go home every night
in his wheelchair.
Okay, I think
this is getting
out of hand.
I'm sorry, but we might have
to call Child Services.
No.
I'm sorry,
but we are
very concerned
about Harper.
No, no, no.
Don't do that.
This is all about Harper.
That is why I did this.
I grew up
without a father.
I couldn't stand
the thought of that
happening to her.
But, I mean,
hiring an actor?
I mean, you didn't have
any male friends
or relatives
who could serve
as role models?
No.
When Harper's real father
abandoned us,
there was nobody.
And when I hired Lewis,
it was just supposed
to be one time, okay?
It was father-daughter
day at her preschool,
and the thing is,
she just fell
in love with him.
And it made her
so happy.
So you did it again.
And again.
Look, I know what
I did was wrong,
but I am putting
an end to it.
I told Derek
this is the last time.
Lewis is gonna
go back to Europe.
He's going to get
busy with work.
He'll lose touch with Harper,
and after a few months,
I'm gonna tell her
that he died
in a work accident.
And that will be
the end of it.
But Harper's
eight years old.
I mean, don't you think
that killing off her father
would be pretty
traumatic for her?
Not as traumatic
as the truth.
Harper's real father
has zero interest in
being a part of her life.
Please, just try
to figure out
what's going on
with Derek, okay?
So, we're right
back where we started?
Well, maybe not.
I mean, if Derek knows
that his character
is gonna die,
is it really just
a coincidence
that he's ended up
in a hospital?
Hannah?
Can I help you?
Yeah.
I'm looking for Dr. Asher.
She hasn't come in yet.
We had to cancel
her first appointment.
Okay. Thanks.
Hey, Courtney.
What's going on?
Hey. Got here about
a half-hour ago.
He refused to get
in the ambo.
His name's Larry Simpson.
Cardiologist put him
on digoxin.
He mixed up his
meds this morning.
Took a triple dose.
All right,
we'll take it
from here.
Stand by.
Hey, Larry.
I'm April.
This is Dr. Sexton.
Thank God.
Please help me.
Tell us
what happened.
I started feeling faint
on my way into work.
I called
my cardiologist.
He said to find a way
to keep my heart
rate up and call 911.
Okay.
Hey, you thinking
what I'm thinking?
A milligram of epi.
Guys.
All right, Larry,
we're gonna give you
some meds to keep
your heart rate up
while we get you
to the hospital,
all right?
Do what you have to.
I can't keep this up.
Yeah.
All the way up.
All right.
You're gonna feel
a little pinch.
Okay.
All right.
Now, slow it down.
Wait.
Oh, Noah!
Whoa, whoa.
Hey, hey.
His heart rate
must be dropping.
Hey, Larry.
Larry, Larry.
All right,
you have to keep
moving, okay?
Okay.
Keep moving.
Okay, okay, okay.
It's gonna be eight hours
until his body
metabolizes the digoxin.
Till that happens,
he has to keep running.
We gotta pace his heart.
While he's running.
Hey, guys,
you gotta do something.
I got an idea.
Here we go.
Hey, what do we got?
Name's Walter Hobbs.
50-year-old prison
transfer from Indiana.
Vitals are stable,
but there's something
wrong with his arm.
What happened?
Not sure.
Okay, hang in
there, Walter.
Trainee, start an IV,
and get him
on the monitors.
Easy, buddy.
We're gonna do
a sheet transfer
on my count.
Nice and easy, folks.
Watch the shackles,
everybody.
Okay, ready?
One, two, three.
Easy, buddy, easy.
You're all right,
you're all right.
Scissors.
Start him on O2.
Belly's soft.
Lungs are clear.
Walter, can you
tell us what happened?
Arm's hard as a rock.
Okay, all right. He's got
compartment syndrome.
Needs a fasciotomy
to relieve the pressure.
Let's get
the Hybrid OR ready.
Any idea
what caused this?
Fellas?
Drugs, fight,
what are we
working with here?
Hey, Indiana sent him
to the closest level-one
trauma center
because his wounds
are severe.
We can't treat him
if you don't tell us
what happened.
Walter's been on Indiana
death row for 10 years.
The creep killed
a family of five
at a home invasion.
He was scheduled
to be executed today,
but something went wrong,
didn't kill him.
You mean,
you gave this man
a lethal injection?
Yeah, except
it wasn't lethal.
Well, I was able to
open up his arm and
relieve the pressure,
but he's still
in bad shape.
And the corrections
officers insist
they don't know what was
in the lethal cocktail.
Well, I'm not surprised.
Pharmaceutical companies
are no longer permitting
the use of their drugs
for executions.
Odds are these guys
used something
without their authorization.
Fools missed
his vein completely.
Drugs are trapped
in his muscle,
slowly leeching
into his bloodstream.
We need to know
what they gave him.
Well, I'll call
the warden,
and see if I can
coax him into telling me
what they used.
Meantime, see what
else you can do
to flush his system.
Yes, ma'am.
They really did
a number on him.
Let's just treat the guy
and get him out of here.
Amen to that.
Where's Dr. Asher?
I'm afraid
she's not available
right now.
Good news is I went
ahead and paged
Dr. Patchefsky.
I don't want
another doctor.
She's more than qualified.
No way.
I've had too many doctors
accuse me of using my pain
as an excuse to get high.
Dr. Asher's the only one
who understands
my situation.
Siana, your labs show
that you're anemic.
If you won't see another OB,
at least let me give you
some blood.
A transfusion?
Yes.
I don't know.
Siana,
the last thing Dr. Asher
would want is for this
to evolve into something
that could harm the baby.
Let us help you.
You need this transfusion.
Okay.
Type and cross her
for two units.
Start the first unit
as soon as it's up.
Got it.
Hang in there.
You're gonna
feel better soon.
Mmm-hmm.
Hannah, where are you?
You should've been
here hours ago.
You have a patient
who needs you.
Listen, whatever
your situation is,
just call me. Please.
Just let me know
you're okay.
Can't keep this up
for much longer.
We're almost set.
So, what is this?
Defibrillator.
Now that you're
staying in place,
we can send
a continuous charge
to your chest, okay?
It'll steady
your heart rate
long enough
for us to get you
to the hospital.
We're good.
All right, Larry.
Here we go.
Okay.
Turning it on.
Whoa. Hey!
Whoa, whoa.
Give me a hand!
Oh, God!
What happened?
We need you to get
back on the treadmill.
What? No, no.
Yeah.
Your heart rate is still
dangerously low.
You have to keep
running to keep it up.
I can't.
Hey, Larry.
You have no choice.
Come on. Larry,
come on! Come on!
Okay, okay.
Just stop slapping me.
All right, now,
come on.
Give me a hand.
There you go.
Take it up to a five.
Five?
The pads couldn't make
good contact with the skin
because of the sweat.
It was not your fault.
I gotta call Med,
get an attending.
"Derek Jordan
"doesn't simply
inhabit Richard III,
"he embodies
the psychopathic king
"with every molecule
of his being."
The New York Times,
no less.
So, for an actor
who approaches his work
on a molecular level,
I would imagine
that every
aspect of Lewis
has been carefully
researched, crafted,
to give Harper an incredibly
real and loving father.
And that's the role
of a lifetime.
Right? I mean,
no wonder you're having
a hard time giving it up.
The character dies, okay?
But not like that.
How do you mean?
Elaine wants
Lewis to disappear.
He would never do that.
No?
No way.
Lose contact
with his daughter?
Lewis loves her too much.
So you have...
You have a different
ending in mind?
I'm gonna stay true
to the character.
Right. And how are you
planning on doing that?
Wait, you're not...
You're not planning on dying
in front of Harper, are you?
Oh, my God.
What do you think
that will do?
Give her the closure
she deserves.
You poisoned yourself,
didn't you?
You would do that
to this little girl?
What did you take?
Tell us what
you took right now,
or we'll tell Harper
who you really are
and put an end
to all of this.
Dr. Manning.
You're not allowed
to do that.
That's protected
information, Doctor.
Dr. Manning, a moment.
What is wrong with him?
Look, I googled him, okay?
He hasn't worked
in six years,
just lost his wife
to cancer.
So he's suicidal.
You can put him
on a psych hold.
We can't afford
to antagonize him.
If we're gonna
save his life,
we have to get him
to tell us what
poison he took.
Then we have to get Elaine
to tell her daughter
the truth.
Where am I?
Chicago Med.
We fixed your arm.
Now we're giving you
a drug to flush the toxins
from your system.
Don't. Just let me die.
Easy, buddy, easy.
I... I could feel everything.
My whole body was on fire.
Hey.
I couldn't move,
I couldn't talk.
Easy.
I know I deserve to die,
but not like that.
How's the patient?
Stable and recovering.
In that case,
the warden would like him
transferred back
as soon as possible.
We should still
monitor him for any
post-op complications.
Prison medical unit
will take it from here.
The death warrant
was extended.
They just rescheduled
his execution.
How about that?
First time I ever
patched up a guy
just so some other guys
could kill him.
Walter Hobbs is
a ward of the state,
so as long as
he's stable, we comply
with their demands.
Hey, I'm not one to fuss
about capital punishment,
but those bozos
don't have a clue
what they're doing.
That's not our problem.
Our job is to treat him
regardless of what happens
when we're done.
Oh.
Know what?
I think that's
what they call
compartmentalizing.
Yeah, I called
10 minutes ago.
When is he gonna
get here?
Try to hurry it up.
It's gonna be an hour
until an attending
gets here.
What if you paced him
internally?
Push a wire
into a man's heart
while he's running
on a treadmill?
Are you insane?
You serious?
Do you have
a better idea?
If I push the wire too far,
it'll puncture his heart.
Kill him
on the spot. No.
No, the best option
is to wait for backup.
Noah, look at him.
We do not have time.
You need to
pace him internally.
April...
Come on.
You can do this.
I'll help you.
O2's at 88.
Stop the transfusion,
get her on a mask.
Got it.
What's happening?
You're having
an inflammatory
reaction to the blood.
What? Why?
There's always
a risk of complications.
Sats are down to 79.
The baby's not getting
enough oxygen.
Siana, you need
an emergency C-section.
She's only seven months.
It's too early.
I know. I'm sorry.
We don't have a choice.
You just have to trust me.
I told you,
I want Dr. Asher!
Siana, she's not here.
Please, listen
to Dr. Halstead.
We have to get you
up to surgery now.
Don't lay another
finger on me!
Okay.
Start her on racemic epi,
a gram of Tylenol,
and push 50
milligrams of Benadryl.
Should buy us some time.
Where are you going?
I think I know where
to find Dr. Asher.
Why's it taking so long?
He's threading
a little wire
into your heart.
It's a delicate process.
God.
Just try not to tense up.
Uh, there's something
moving in my arm.
You mean your chest?
No, my arm, my left arm.
Okay, you must
have overshot
the vena cava.
You have to
retract the wire
and start again.
What? Start again?
No, no, no.
I can't do this anymore.
Larry, just hang
in there, okay?
I can't, I can't, I can't.
You gotta keep
running, Larry.
No, no, no! Larry!
Larry, hang in there
for a minute.
No, no, no, no.
Don't do this, Larry!
Finally!
Hey, help me out, man.
All right, bag him.
All right, I'll get
on his chest.
Heart rate's 30.
He's not circulating.
Come on.
Retract the wire,
start over.
He poisoned himself?
All his labs and symptoms
indicate that he has.
He believes
Lewis needs to die
in the presence
of his daughter,
so that Harper
can say goodbye
and get closure.
Look, you need
to tell your daughter
the truth.
I can't. No.
If you end it now,
Derek will have no reason
to play this all out.
But if Harper finds out
that I lied to her,
she will never
trust me again.
Elaine,
if you don't stop this,
Derek is going to die.
Harper can handle
the truth. Trust me.
I'm not saying
it's gonna be easy,
but eventually,
she'll understand
and she will forgive you.
All right.
But only if he agrees.
Harper will never believe
that Derek is not her dad
unless he is the one
that tells her.
Okay. Go and talk to him.
Please.
We can ask a nurse
to take Harper
to the cafeteria.
Okay.
Connie.
I couldn't get Sean
on the phone.
He's not in today.
Can I help?
I'm looking for a woman.
She's a regular.
She calls herself Val.
Oh. Yeah.
Have you
seen her today?
No.
Is everything okay?
He's been down too long.
You gotta hurry.
Yeah, I'm...
I'm stuck in his neck,
and I... I can't
advance the wire
to his heart.
Heart rate's
down to 20.
Steve, take over for me.
Okay, I can
feel the wire.
It is stuck.
Okay, I'm gonna
turn his head
and see if that expands
the opening,
and when I do,
see if you can push
the wire forward, okay?
Okay.
All right.
One, two, three.
Hold compressions.
I see PVCs. We're in.
Pacing him now.
Come on.
Nothing.
Take it up to 100.
Hundred.
I don't understand.
It won't capture.
Come on, come on.
Pressure's climbing.
What happened?
Just breathe, Larry.
We're taking you
to the hospital.
Let's get him
on the gurney.
Okay. Yeah.
Prison transport
is standing by.
Well, I'll let
the warden know
he's on his way.
Dr. Choi, Dr. Marcel.
My arm!
Push 50 mics Fentanyl,
get him on oxygen.
Okay, okay, okay,
all right.
All right.
Arm's dead
and necrotic.
Lethal injection drugs
constricted blood supply.
We need to amputate.
Get the Hybrid OR ready.
Dr. Choi, can I...
There's no point
amputating a man's arm
who's just gonna
get executed.
Look, we're here
to treat him,
and right now that means
amputating his arm.
Arm's already
dead and gone.
Won't be long
before he's septic.
I say we load him up
with pain meds,
let nature take its course.
We're doctors,
not executioners.
Hybrid OR's ready.
Okay.
Let's move.
Siana?
You and your baby
are not getting
enough oxygen.
You need a C-section
right now.
You're just gonna
make things worse.
I know you
don't trust me,
and I get it.
But you can't rely
on Dr. Asher
today, either.
She's not coming.
No.
No!
Siana, listen to me.
In a few minutes,
you're gonna go
into respiratory failure.
You'll suffocate and die,
at which point
we'll rush you upstairs
for a C-section
and deliver your daughter.
Siana, you said you
wanted everything to
be perfect for your baby.
That means making sure
she grows up with her mother.
Please.
Will you let us
help you?
Mmm-hmm.
Open intubation tray.
Call OB, tell them
we're on our way.
Almost there.
Okay, bone's cut.
Just need to release
the posterior muscle.
Okay.
Here we go.
All right, let's go ahead
and tie off the vessels.
Wait a second.
The skin on his
shoulder's dusky.
Hand me a scalpel.
Whoa!
Sorry, Doc.
The necrosis has spread
all the way into the
shoulders and chest.
We gotta keep going.
Okay,
I'm gonna get help.
He won't do it!
He wouldn't
even discuss it!
Now he's getting
really sick!
He's in bronchospasm.
Push 0.3 milligrams
sub-q epi.
On it.
Tell us what you took.
Sats are coming up.
Your kidneys are starting
to shut down.
Tell us what you took.
Do you have any idea
what it looks like
when a human being
goes into organ failure?
It's gruesome.
Horribly painful,
it's violent.
Are you sure
that that's...
That's the kind of closure
that you wanna
give to Harper?
What if we can
figure out a way
to give you what you want
and save your life?
How?
By staging your death.
Okay?
You give your daughter
a final farewell,
and then you
drift off to sleep.
What? No.
It has to be perfect.
It has to be real
for Harper.
Real, but peaceful.
You go to sleep,
she leaves the room.
All right?
Tell us what you took.
I will.
Afterwards.
Dr. Charles.
You can't do this.
What's the alternative?
Sit there
while the guy dies?
Just do nothing
while he kills himself?
There has to be
another option.
Look, unfortunately,
one way or the other,
Harper's gonna experience
her father's death. Right?
But this way,
hopefully, it'll be
less traumatic for her,
and maybe we can
save the guy's life.
Decay's
infiltrated all the way
into his chest cavity.
Pressure's dropping.
Axillary
artery's torn and
retracted into his chest.
I can't pinch it off.
Pressure's down to 80.
Come on.
I need to clamp it.
I can't reach it.
He's peri-arrest.
I can't get control
of the vessel.
He's bradying.
Heart rate's 20.
Doing
the best I can.
He's arresting.
Lost his pulse.
You need to
start compressions.
Circulate what?
He's right.
His blood's
already on the table.
Time of death, 16:22.
Daddy?
Hey, sweetheart.
Daddy's really sick.
But you're gonna
get better, right?
I don't think
they can fix me,
honeybear.
But I want you to know
that I'm so proud of you.
And remember,
Daddy loves you
more than anything.
I love you too, Daddy.
I think, uh, we should
let your daddy get some rest.
Okay, baby.
Come on. Come on.
You're gonna get better.
You're gonna
get better, okay?
We're gonna do
all the things
you talked about.
You're gonna take me
to Geneva, and Paris,
and we'll see
the Eiffel Tower
and the Mona Lisa
and that really
big museum.
You can't die, Daddy!
You can't die!
Daddy?
I can't do this to you.
I'm so sorry.
You're okay?
I am, sweetie.
I'm right here.
Don't let me die,
for her sake.
It was cyanide.
Grab a cyano kit
from the Pyxis
and hang
the hydroxocobalamin now.
Is my daddy really
gonna be okay?
Is he?
Yeah. Yeah, he is.
Come on, honey,
let's let the doctors
work on him, okay?
Okay, come on.
It's gonna be
okay, Daddy.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
Go.
Almost there.
Baby girl.
Premature but healthy.
All right, let's get her
to the NICU.
How's Mom?
Sats and pressure
are holding steady.
Should be fine.
Hey. How are Siana
and the baby?
They're fine.
Oh, thank God.
Now?
I just, uh,... My phone
crashed on me.
I had to get it fixed,
and I caught a flat,
it was just...
It was like
the perfect storm.
I just could not
get in here today.
Your patient
and her baby
almost died today
while you were off
somewhere getting high.
High?
I told you,
I caught a flat.
You expect me
to believe that?
You didn't seem
to have a problem last night.
Yeah, that was a mistake.
A mistake?
Yeah, and it was a mistake
thinking you'd turn
yourself in today.
You know what?
You think whatever
you want to.
I need to go
check on Siana.
A few hours ago,
you were ready
to discharge him.
Now you're telling us
he's dead?
The doctors encountered
complications in surgery.
Bleeding,
to be specific.
Ultimately, we weren't able
to get it under control.
They did everything
they could.
You can explain
all that to the AG.
That man belonged
to the state of Indiana,
and he died on your watch.
Let's go.
Is there anything
I need to know
about what happened
in there?
Ms. Goodwin...
I assure you,
Dr. Marcel and I
did all we could.
Mmm-hmm.
I'm glad to hear that.
How's he doing?
Dr. Latham was able
to implant a permanent
pacemaker.
He should make
a full recovery.
Thank God.
He also said that
given the circumstances,
it was a very
impressive save.
I don't understand.
My daddy's
not my daddy?
But he is.
You know,
Harper, it really is
kind of confusing.
And it might take a while
for you to understand.
But all you really
need to know
is that he loves you
very, very much.
I know that.
Can I go see him now?
Okay.
Yeah, of course.
We can go see him.
Hey. You ready?
Yeah.
Listen,
I know we had
plans tonight,
but I was wondering
if maybe we could
grab a drink
with Crockett first.
With Crockett?
I know you don't think
the world of the guy,
but we had
a really rough day
on the case today.
Oh. Okay.
Why don't you go ahead...
Forget it.
I can do it another time.
You sure?
Yeah.
Come on.
Let's go home.
We got a date
tonight, right?
Yeah. Okay.
Hey, Earl.
You got a minute?
What do you need,
Dr. Halstead?
A favor.
Seek. Seek.
You were right.