Wow.
Yeah.
Come back to bed.
Give me a minute.
You get 20 seconds.
Hey. What are you...
Female, late 20s,
tonic-clonic seizure.
Duration of the seizure?
A little over three minutes.
Does your friend have
a history of epilepsy?
She never said.
My name is Dr. Cameron.
You're in a hospital.
We're gonna take care of you.
What's her name? I don't know.
House?
I have a case I think
you might be interested in.
Not now.
Twenty-six-year-old woman
had a tonic-clonic seizure.
What about me speeding
away says to you "let's chat"?
History of fatigue, and two years
ago she had a retinal vein occlusion.
She's diabetic.
No, she's not, and she has
no history of hypertension.
It can wait.
I knew I should have set up
the video camera. Stay there.
Oh, my goodness, I played a
practical joke on my best friend,
and he's badly injured.
Wish I'd learnt this
valuable lesson earlier.
I was waiting by my window
for an hour. Why are you late?
I had a breakfast
meeting at Mickey's Diner
with the Mercy
people to tell them
I'm coming back to work here.
Sorry if it interfered with
your plan to maim me.
Donut's a nice touch.
That's just my way of
saying welcome back.
The seizure could be the result of
dehydration or something neurological.
Or the Ecstasy you
found in her system.
According to Dr. Hadley,
the patient took the drugs
about five hours
before the seizure, so...
How does Thirteen know about it?
Apparently, she was
with the patient last night.
At 3:00 a.m.?
Oh, yeah.
Penthouse Forum
meets medical mystery.
Maybe there is a God.
Empty, transient sex?
I've been waiting for
you to spiral out of control
ever since you got your
Huntington's diagnosis,
but this is more
than I dared hope for.
The patient's seizure
resulted from dehydration,
which resulted from a
cocktail of alcohol and ecstasy.
Mystery solved.
Wait, were you doing drugs?
Not diagnostically relevant.
That's what we're
trying to diagnose.
It's how steep of
a spiral you're on.
Our patient hemorrhaged
into her eye two years ago.
Also not
diagnostically relevant.
Retinal vein
occlusion was fixed.
Her doctor said it
was a venous anomaly.
Is he in this room? Because if
he's not, I don't care what he thinks.
Unless he's a she, and
she was there last night, too,
in which case, I
care very deeply.
What if the eye problem wasn't
with her vein, but with her blood?
It would explain why she
seized, why she's always tired.
She parties until 3:00 a.m.,
that's why she's always tired.
Yet, you seem fine.
She's visited four other
doctors in the past year,
none of them found anything.
She's a hypochondriac
who drank too much.
Blood clots could
explain everything.
Makes sense. Bone marrow's in
overdrive, too many platelets. Sorry.
Thirteen, go stick a needle
in your girlfriend's pelvis.
And, no, that one
wasn't a metaphor.
Suck out some
marrow. That one was.
I like to watch.
I can handle this alone.
You've already handled it,
that's why you need a chaperone.
Of course, I'm a very permissive,
understanding chaperone,
so feel free to ignore me,
you know, if you're in the mood to
start kissing or groping or showering...
You'll have to excuse Dr. House,
he mistakes immaturity for edginess.
You're Dr. House?
I assume my name came up
last night in the form of a moan.
You had sex, then a seizure.
Could be a particular
position or activity that set it off.
That sounds like a valid
medical theory, doesn't it?
I'm really sorry,
just ignore him.
Whatever you think we
did, we did. And then some.
Lights on or off?
You got a medical
rationalization for that one?
Light sensitivity could... On.
Huh! Figured she had
more shame than that.
She talk dirty, or make you
rely on vague hand signals?
She's pretty direct
about what she wants.
I'm learning so much.
Okay, score the score,
scale of one to 10.
Don't answer.
Seven.
Finally get one right.
You want to investigate
him because he ate a donut?
He claimed he had a morning
meeting at Mickey's Diner.
Wilson loves Mickey's Diner.
He has the French Toast Tower
whenever he sets foot in the door.
There's no way he would have
come to work wanting more carbs.
He lied to me. I
need to know why.
What do you think
you'll find out?
I'm worried that
he might be a spy.
He's been gone four months. You're
worried the friendship has changed.
I'm just not sure if
he's working for Hirohito
or the New England Patriots.
You played a practical
joke on him, he didn't laugh...
I need something
to lord over him, a lie.
He didn't try to
retaliate, he moralized.
He always moralized.
And he always
moralized and got even.
He hasn't fired back.
Things always change.
And that sucks.
Yeah. Find out where he was.
I should've known it wasn't a
coincidence. I found your letters.
You recognized House's name,
and you're the first patient I've seen
who actually enjoyed
being accosted by him.
I would've told you, but...
What exactly would
you have told me?
That you slept with
me to get to House?
That you've been trying to get him
to take your case for over a year?
I'm sick, no one
even wrote back.
You used me.
My motives were clear.
You might've figured out my motives
faster if you had bothered to ask my name.
I followed you to that bar
because I wanted to talk to you,
see if you'd help
me get to House.
I didn't expect you
to be so aggressive.
Was that seizure even real?
Why would I fake a symptom?
It would just make it harder
for House to diagnose me.
There's nothing to diagnose.
Your biopsy results are negative.
Then it's something else.
Get dressed. I'm
discharging you.
House admitted me.
He obviously thinks...
House is using you as an excuse
to stick his nose in my personal life.
I'm tired all the time.
Some nights I fall asleep at 10:00
and wake up at noon, still tired.
Every doctor I see, tells
me there's nothing wrong.
And that proves what, exactly?
That they're wrong
or that you're wrong?
Come on, you
expect me to believe...
Sit back, deep
breaths. Try and relax.
Get the paddles,
she's gonna crash.
Damn.
We had to use paddles to
stabilize the patient's heart.
Eye issue, brain issue,
now a heart issue,
sounds like a real case to me.
Yeah, I get it. I was
wrong. Can we move on?
You're just upset because the
whole time she was with you,
she was thinking about my
huge, throbbing diagnostic skills.
Drugs would explain everything.
This morning you rejected drugs.
That's when I thought
that Thirteen was right
and I was just
jerking her around.
Cardiac arrest means
she could be a serious user.
Great. What?
That means that something
she did at my place set this off,
either she brought drugs in
or she grabbed something
from my medicine cabinet.
And that means my place
needs to be searched.
Now, I'd be happy
to do that myself,
but unfortunately, that would
be far less titillating for House,
so he's about to come up with
some convoluted medical reason
why I have to stay here
while he goes through my stuff.
Patient's dad had
bypass surgery,
means she's a candidate for
atherosclerosis, she needs an ultrasound.
That was much less convoluted
than what you just said.
I'm not giving you my keys.
If you want to
do this, I'm going.
Who can pick a lock?
I'll go. Make sure he
doesn't steal any underwear.
You're a disgrace to your
stereotype. Move over.
Think you can pick a
lock faster than me?
No need to pick.
Nice. Steal from your employees.
Never.
I had my dick make keys when
I hired him to dick up the team.
I always imagined she'd have
a sex swing in the living room.
Give me my key.
Don't have your key.
You expect me to believe
that you hired Lucas
to investigate
everyone except for me?
Waste of money.
I already know
everything about you.
Thirteen had her purse,
that's gotta be the patient's.
Check it for drugs.
I call shotgun on her bedroom.
You know that I stole a
car when I was a teenager.
You know that my
mom has Alzheimer's.
You know nothing else.
Want me to have you investigated?
When did you get so needy?
I'm not needy, I
just don't buy it.
You always want more
information about people.
Look where we
are. Purse is clean.
Last night wasn't the first time that
Thirteen brought home some strange.
If you found her
diary... No toys.
When you sleep with the
same person over and over,
that's when you
need accessories.
First time is plenty
exciting on its own. Unless...
You think an asthma inhaler
could be used as a sex toy?
There are ways of getting to know
people without committing felonies.
People interest me.
Conversations don't.
Because conversations
go both ways.
Like Thirteen. Like Thirteen.
Brown recluse, found
it at your apartment.
Their venom can cause
seizures and heart problems.
Unless the ultrasound
showed anything.
No.
What room did you find it in?
Bathroom.
Nice bidet, by the
way. Very refreshing.
I don't have a bidet.
Oh.
Spider's not the only
interesting thing I found.
Yeah, my inhaler is fascinating.
It's got its own
extensive online following.
You have asthma?
When I was a kid.
It started acting up again
when I moved into my new place.
You moved? Who cares?
He doesn't. He's just
surprised he didn't know.
You withhold things other
people would never bother to.
A move, a little wheeze,
whatever you thought was in
my pocket instead of your inhaler.
Maybe I should make a
return trip to your place.
A spider bite doesn't
explain anything
unless the patient was
actually bitten by a spider.
I'll do the exam.
Don't be ridiculous,
that'd be inappropriate.
It'd be better if a
woman gropes her.
There's no sexual
tension that way.
I need you to stand up
and take off your gown.
I think I would've
felt a spider biting me.
Not necessarily.
You really need those after
everything we did the other night?
The other night I
wasn't your doctor.
How long are you
going to stay mad at me?
going to be here?
Okay, then.
Look,
I really had no intention
of ever seeing you again.
So, having me end up here is
a little less than ideal. I get it.
But we just met. How did you know
you didn't want to see me again?
It's nothing personal.
I'm just really not that
into repeat performances.
I figured I wasn't the
first girl you cruised.
Why is that?
You're awfully good at it.
You'd think with all that experience
that I'd be better than a seven.
We just met, we were both drunk.
Not like there wasn't potential.
A little more practice
for the both of us,
I'd say we're looking
at a nine, easy.
But that would require
a repeat performance.
You didn't have
to move your hand.
I didn't.
My hand's on your
hip, you don't feel that?
No. What does that mean?
It means it's not a spider bite.
Blood test confirms
low potassium levels,
explains the
numbness in her hip.
It's not good, but I
think we've got time
for at least one or two
comments about my personal life.
Which you just wasted with that
comment about my comments.
Low potassium means her heart
problem is a symptom of a kidney problem.
What caused the kidney problem?
Could be lgA nephropathy.
Not without blood in the urine.
PSAGN?
Not with normal blood pressure.
Renal tubular acidosis?
Her kidneys don't filter
acid out of the blood,
excess acid drives down potassium,
causes kidney calcifications.
If it's RTA, all she needs is
sodium bicarbonate for the acid
and surgery to remove the
calcifications. CT her kidneys.
If you find calcifications,
we have our diagnosis.
What's he doing now?
Mmm-mmm. He's playing
that carjacking video game.
He'd get a lot farther if he
didn't stop at all the red lights.
Maybe he was doing something
he thinks I'll mock him for.
Like just about anything.
You don't think it's that.
I don't think it's "just
about anything"?
You don't think it's
about anything trivial.
If you weren't worried, you
wouldn't be sitting in my car.
Maybe he's seeing a shrink.
That does not look
like a pizza delivery.
Doesn't matter if it isn't,
Wilson doesn't buy his pizza.
Eight units in this building,
there's gotta be a pervert like
me living in at least one of them.
Yes, because you represent
one out of every eight people
living in this country.
Well, apparently, he has
developed a taste for pizza.
Things change.
CT shows one more calcification
near the superior
pyramid on the left kidney.
See it.
That thing you were hoping
House didn't find at your place.
I found it.
You did the CAG
test two weeks ago.
A number this high means you
have less time than you thought.
It's understandable
you'd be upset.
It doesn't mean you
have to self-destruct.
It's not noble for you to
protect me from House
if you're just going to judge.
There are things
you should be doing,
working out, improving
balance and coordination...
Yeah, that sounds like a blast.
I'm having fun, cramming as
much life into my life as I can.
You're doing drugs, staying up
all night, having sex with strangers.
It sounds fun to me.
Good night.
Close the incisions.
She won't even have a scar.
Her O2 Sats are dropping.
Did you nick something?
The procedure was
clean, BP's strong.
Well, she's not breathing.
We need to intubate.
The breathing problem started
after we fixed her kidney problem,
means the RTA isn't
the underlying cause.
Where's Thirteen?
Traffic's bad, she's
probably just...
Not here.
It's not her lungs. No
masses, no infiltrates.
Her lungs are working,
but she still can't breathe.
Distribution plant
can't distribute
if it's not getting deliveries.
If her lungs are fine, maybe
the problem's in the supply line,
airway collapse.
That could signal autoimmune or some
kind of dystrophy as the underlying cause.
There's only way to find out if her
airway failed. Make it happen again.
Stick Thirteen's carpet cleaner on
a treadmill, methacholine challenge.
And someone find the carpet.
Exam going on, 15 minutes.
Morning, Dr. Hadley.
Just spoke to my brother.
And by brother you mean...
I mean, my parents' other son.
Wow, same dad.
He got a call last
week from your PI.
You lied. You did
have me investigated.
You've been taunting the
team with what you've learnt,
but you never came after me.
Means you couldn't
find anything.
You're right.
That's because you
haven't done anything stupid,
spontaneous, or even vaguely
interesting since you were 17.
And that's just sad.
I found her in the clinic
giving herself IV fluids.
At least you could've let
her finish. She looks terrible.
She has a fresh nightclub
stamp on her wrist.
She's in no
condition to practice.
Unless this is a prelude
to an actual spanking,
there's no reason
for me to be...
I want her to take a drug test.
You can't make me do that.
But I can suspend
you until you do.
Because she went to a
nightclub in her free time?
Or because she had
sex in her free time?
The patient was undergoing
a routine surgery for RTA.
I didn't need
Thirteen here for that,
and I don't need you making my
employees punch a clock or pee in a cup.
Let's go. Come on.
Thank you.
By the way, the
surgery was not routine,
the patient stopped breathing,
and you missed a differential.
You're fired.
What? You just defended me.
No, I just prevented you from getting a
drug test, probably saved your career.
I'm already taking responsibility
for one doctor with a drug habit.
I don't have a drug habit.
The slutty party girl is fun
till she pukes on your shoes,
then she's just a pain in the ass.
I haven't sat on this couch for four
months. It remembers my cheeks.
I've missed this.
Me, too.
Me trying to work,
you interrupting.
Come on, your patients can wait
five minutes, get me caught up.
Come on. What
did you do? Travel?
Did you get a new hobby?
Did you meet someone?
Actually, yes, I sort of
started dating someone.
Great.
What does she do?
Is she an actress?
No. Why would you think that?
I just figured you'd want
something a little more exciting...
She's not...
You're gonna find out anyway
because you're gonna meet her.
She's a prostitute.
Used to be. She
made some mistakes.
Single mom, had
some drug issues,
but she's so smart.
She wants to go to law school,
and I told her I'd
help her with tuition.
How long have you known her?
I knew you'd be like this.
I asked a question.
House, you are a drug addict,
you go to prostitutes,
you can't be judgmental.
And yet...
Please, don't do this to me.
I was hurting, and I
wanted to feel good.
I didn't expect
it to go this way.
Amber said that she
wanted me to move on,
that she wanted me to be happy,
and Debbie makes me happy.
If you're happy, I'm...
I heard.
Yeah. I'm looking
for my ticket back.
I'm sorry if I upset you. I didn't
want to invade your privacy...
It wasn't your fault. Can
you get me caught up?
You think you're going to
find something we didn't?
It's good for the
patient, good for me.
Films are clean, we
ruled out hypertension,
the guys have her on a treadmill
running a methacholine challenge.
And I still think you've
been acting like an idiot.
I know. Did you talk about whether
this lung field looks a little dark?
It's probably just overexposed.
Or her diaphragm's
a little flat.
Could be a sign
of hyperinflation.
Suggests a
pulmonary obstruction.
Lung cysts, they wouldn't
show up on an X-ray.
The treadmill test isn't gonna close
her airway, it'll make her lungs explode.
Her throat's fine.
We made her airway
collapse, but it's not collapsed.
You ruptured a cyst,
her lung collapsed.
Breath sounds on both sides.
Move.
Trachea's deviating to the left.
Nice.
Chest CT confirmed
multiple lung cysts,
one of which burst
during the treadmill test.
Luckily, Thirteen
figured out the problem
and was there to
re-inflate her lung.
Lung cysts plus all her other
symptoms, could be amyloidosis,
which we can manage, or
pulmonary fibrosis, which...
Thank you.
My employees can
take care of it from here.
We need to biopsy the cysts.
You fired me
because I screwed up.
I just proved I
can pull my weight.
All you proved is you know
how to make an entrance.
House, she deserves
another shot.
She found the cysts,
saved the patient...
Who wouldn't have needed saving
if Thirteen had shown up to
the differential in the first place.
Give her job back, House.
Or what? You're gonna quit?
Go do the biopsy.
I'm sorry.
How much clearer
do I need to make this?
What does it even
mean, dating a hooker?
He's an idiot with
a messiah complex,
savior to all who need saving.
That's why his first
wife had a wooden leg,
his second wife was Canadian.
He's the one who
needs to be saved.
From you or the ho?
The ho's just using
him for his money.
Wait, it was a bad example.
Normally, in these
situations, I'd follow the girl,
find out something embarrassing
about her to show him.
But since that's our
starting position...
We proceed directly
to the leg breaking.
I'm not breaking her legs,
she probably has a pimp,
or at least an older brother,
or younger brother, or
overprotective sister...
Find her. Find her family.
Find client number 9.
Just get me something I can
use to force her to back off.
Sorry to interrupt
your meeting, Mannix.
Here's the result
from the lung biopsy.
Why not men?
You're bisexual.
If you were just
being self-destructive,
you'd be having
random sex with men.
Better chance of getting
assaulted, catching a disease.
If this were just
about getting laid,
it'd be a lot easier to
pick up men or ugly girls.
This woman's hot, which means
you like the challenge, the conquest.
It's the control
that gets you off.
And controlling women
is as close as you can get
to controlling what's
going to happen to you.
Here I thought I
was just into boobs.
Instead of getting
sweaty with a stranger,
why don't you try
taking it to the next level?
Play God.
Tell a girl that she's
got 10 years to live.
She has LAM.
Okay.
This is not a test.
You're not getting your
job back if you can...
I know what it's
like to get this news,
and no one should
have to get it from you.
Hey.
The biopsy of your lung cyst
showed smooth muscle cells.
That's indicative of a
disease called LAM.
What do you do for that?
Surgery to remove the cysts,
but they'll come back.
Little by little, the
cysts replace healthy
lung tissue until your
lungs stop working.
I'm going to die.
Yes.
I'm so sorry.
They removed all
the cysts they could.
That should help
you breathe better.
How long until the
cysts come back?
We don't know
exactly. I'm sorry.
Stop saying you're sorry.
I know you're scared.
I don't know what I feel.
You're going to be
numb for a few more days.
Then you'll go home
and cry for a few weeks.
And then you get angry, start telling
yourself nothing matters anymore.
You start doing stupid things.
Maybe you go out to bars
and pick up a bunch of women.
You're...
How long do you have?
Maybe a little more than
you, maybe a little less.
I'll race you.
I was thinking maybe
I'd come back later?
Sounds good.
Oh, God. What's going on?
All her blood counts are down.
It's a new symptom,
aplastic anemia.
Does the word "fired" have some whole
other definition that I'm not aware of?
I don't work for you.
Fine, don't pay me.
Just let me finish
out this case.
So you like her
now that she's dying.
What happens if she stops dying?
There's no danger
of that right now.
If we don't figure out what's wrong
with her, she's got days, not years.
Aplastic anemia
takes LAM off the table.
Unfortunately, none of our
other choices are any better.
PNH with some sort
of respiratory infection...
Best case gives her 12 years.
Or fast-moving
Langerhans. Few months.
Or mastocytosis, which can cause
systemic shock and kill her in days.
Go. Test for
everything. Not you.
You're just a visitor.
How's your patient?
She doesn't have Langerhans.
That's good.
Actually, a cancer diagnosis
would be good news right now.
Do you think I'm boring?
Yes.
You're saying that
just to screw with me.
Yeah. Why would you
expect anything else?
I expect House
to pull my strings,
I expect Cameron to
make me feel better,
I expect the new
team to kiss my ass,
and I expect you to be honest
'cause you don't give a crap.
Yes, you're boring.
That speech was boring.
Thanks so much.
You don't let other
people's problems affect you.
You don't let your own
problems affect you.
And it's the screw-ups
that make us interesting.
You're never out of control,
which is good and boring.
Never losing control also means
you're never putting yourself out there,
never pushing your limits.
On the other hand, you do have
a tattoo, so maybe I'm wrong.
I'm glad you're here.
She needs a bone
marrow transplant.
Test results are back?
What's she positive for?
Nothing. But we've
got a donor match.
Jumping to a transplant
when we don't know what she...
I know she has a blood disorder.
Could be PNH. She needs
a bone marrow transplant.
Or leukemia. She needs
Or thalassemia. She
needs a bone marrow...
Yeah, I get it.
But she'll never survive
total body irradiation.
So we don't radiate her.
Her marrow's nearly wiped
out already, count is almost zero.
"Almost" being the key word. The
new marrow would attack the old marrow.
She'll die from
graft-versus-host.
You got a better idea?
She trusts you.
Go get her consent.
Sometimes I find out
things you'd rather not know.
This was in his trash.
He's using.
You're back.
Genius.
Damn, I knew the fake
works was too much.
Well, you had no choice.
Where were you gonna go
after fake-hooker-girlfriend?
How did you know he was outside?
Cane prints.
I'm actually kind of insulted.
No way I'm a drug addict
but you completely buy that
I fell in love with a prostitute?
You played to your strengths.
By which I mean you
played to your weaknesses.
Oh, my God.
You invoked your dead
girlfriend's name to sell me.
You're my hero.
Best $30 I ever spent.
Thirty? Did you keep her number?
Unfortunately, I killed her
and buried her in the basement.
Shame. Hungry?
Yeah.
So, seriously, where were
you the other morning?
Oh, don't make me do this again.
It has nothing to do with you.
Then tell me.
We're going bowling on Monday.
I'm coming over to play poker
this weekend. Nothing's changed.
You have to trust that.
Okay.
You're gonna keep
following me, aren't you?
It's what we do.
Be outside my
apartment at 8:00 tonight.
She said yes to the transplant.
Good.
You're in a downward
spiral of destruction.
I can stop.
You're gonna keep spiraling,
keep screwing around,
keep slashing away at
every person who tries to help
until no one tries
to help anymore,
until you hit bottom,
until you're dead.
But until then, I can use you.
You're hiring me back?
You did good work.
I did good work yesterday, and
I was still fired. What changed?
You wanted me to
spend time with her,
see if I could still
make a connection.
You connected with the
diagnosis, not with her.
You're trying to save
me, trying to control me.
You're doing exactly
what you think I'm...
Cracks.
Your lips are cracked.
Been using your inhaler lately?
Allergies. Don't deflect,
you always deflect.
Did she cry?
When you told her that she
was going to die, did she cry?
She got upset, she...
Were there tears?
No.
Chopping an onion
releases a mist
of Syn-propanethial-S-oxide.
A chemical irritant which causes
people to have a very predictable reaction.
She has no tears.
It was either this or
put on Brian's Song,
but I didn't have time
to stop by Wilson's.
She has Sjögren's, that attacks the
glands that produce tears and saliva.
It also, by the way,
causes lung cysts and RTA.
It doesn't cause bleeding.
It's like you and men.
Just because you usually
don't doesn't mean you can't.
And it doesn't cause
cracked lips in other people.
Lack of spit makes her mouth a
breeding ground for a fungus like Candida.
Her asthma inhaler
did the same for you,
wiped out your
mouth's immune system.
So, she's got what I've got.
Just the opportunistic infection,
not the underlying condition.
Another life saved
by girl-on-girl action.
I'm gonna be okay?
You're gonna be okay.
Methylprednisolone to get
the Sjögren's under control,
and some artificial tears to maximize
the visual impact of this moment.
Spencer's gonna be fine,
and I hear you
got your job back.
I'm gonna keep standing
here until you say something.
I feel alone,
and she hasn't gone anywhere.
She gets to live.
I'm gonna go home. I'm tired.
What do you think?
Oh, my God.
You guys shop here, too?
Best nipples in Princeton.
Why are you here?
Because he ate the donut.
I'm so sorry. He must
have followed me.
I'm sure.
You're clearly not pregnant.
So either you're
buying this as a gift
or this is some kind of weird "if
you build it, they will come" moment.
I'm adopting a baby.
She asked me to be
a character reference.
That's where I was
the other morning.
I'm sorry, I couldn't
betray her confidence.
I didn't want anyone else to
know in case I didn't get approved.
Today, I did.
Are you going to
congratulate me?
If you're happy, I'm...