.
♪
- You know,
you were so right.
The light on this side
of the room, way better.
- I've been right about quite
a few things since you left.
- I wanna give you a choice
between two doors.
- Well, by all means.
And you have
until security gets here
to give me
as many choices as you like.
Oh, this is gonna be fun.
What's behind door number one?
- Resign.
Collect your golden parachute
or whatever it is
they promised you,
and leave this hospital
in the hands
of any of the dedicated and
passionate department chairs
who love this place
with their entire being
and will run it
with dignity and grace.
- Okay, let's just skip ahead
to door number two.
- Okay, door number two,
you cling to a job
that I know you don't like,
don't want,
only took for money,
and I stay here in New York,
away from the woman
that I love,
the life that I love,
and rip you from this hospital
by the roots.
And believe me,
you will be begging for mercy
once I unleash the full--
- ♪ Got that yummy-yum
- ♪ That yummy-yummy
- Excuse me.
- ♪ Yeah, you got
that yummy-yum ♪
- Hi, baby.
- So I was just walking
into work,
and I passed that gazebo.
Do you remember?
When it was raining
and one thing led to another--
- Yes, yes, I do.
I would very much love
to relive
wet-clothes-gazebo-day,
but I'm right in the middle
of giving Veronica
that ultimatum--
- Oh. Go, go, go.
Yes, give her the full
Mad Max.
Love you, bye.
- Yeah. Bye-bye.
Yeah, so rip you from the--
Sorry, where was I?
- You're gonna take me down,
nothing's gonna stand
in your way, whatever it takes.
- Whatever it takes
to make sure that you,
Veronica Fuentes,
are going--
Ow, ow!
Guys, okay, I'm going.
You win. Hey, take it easy.
- Sorry about this,
Dr. Goodwin.
- No, no, don't be, Joe.
Everything went exactly
as planned.
- Did you find it?
- I literally had my hand
in a drawer
when Veronica walked in,
but Yahtzee.
- Oh, thank God.
- Yeah.
Now, start scouring, okay?
We're looking for anything
that says "deal points."
- How did you even come up
with this?
- Well, the only way
to oust Veronica
is with a seat on the board.
And the only way
to get back on the board
is to be employed
at the hospital.
And right now, I can't even
get past the front doors
without security
kicking me out.
So I figured,
let's get creative.
- Urgent Medicine Incorporated?
- UMI, they're a bargain-rate
trauma clinic
that Veronica franchised out
to a third party.
And technically, they remain
a separate entity
fully outside
of Veronica's purview.
- We're gonna need
more than that.
- How's this for more?
According to this deal,
UMI negotiated exactly one seat
on the board of New Amsterdam.
- Hey.
♪
- Do you remember
the Nick's Grocery Massacre?
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
From the news.
The shooting a few years back.
- Six years ago...
and five months,
four days.
But who's counting, right?
- You were there?
- I worked at Nick's
after school.
I was a stocker.
- Okay.
And what do you remember?
- I was--
I was working
with this guy Marco
in the cereal aisle.
He was doing impressions
of the different characters
on the boxes.
And then I heard the bang,
and I looked back, and...
Marco was bleeding.
His chest.
I don't know
where it came from.
I tried to help him,
but the wound was so big,
and he died really fast.
And I was kind of
in shock, I guess.
- Yeah.
- Then I heard the screams,
and I knew
the shooter was coming,
so I got on the floor,
and I pulled Marco's body
on top of me
and pretended I was dead too.
He came right up to us.
And I thought, "This is it."
Then he just walked away,
shot everyone else, and...
here I am.
- I gotta say, it sounds like
you're processing that day
about as well
as can be expected.
- Yeah,
that's not why we're here.
- Oh.
Okay, well,
then why don't you--
what brings you in?
- Tell him.
- I wanna help you. I do.
But I don't think this is--
- Just tell him, Dad.
- Dr. Frome,
Nick's Grocery
was a false flag operation.
The so-called shooting...
it never happened.
♪
- Teyarnie?
- Yeah. Who are you?
- I'm Dr. Reynolds.
- What happened
to the spine doctor?
- Well, we got the results
from your scans
and the source
of your back pain.
Unfortunately, it is a tumor
on your pancreas.
-  A tumor?
- I'm afraid so.
- I've been driving long haul
16 years.
Backaches come
with the 18-wheeler.
Are you sure?
- I am.
And it needs to be removed,
or it could prove fatal.
- Okay.
Well, let's get on it, then.
- There's the challenge.
This is an extremely
specialized procedure
that requires
an endocrine surgeon,
and currently,
we don't have one.
- Well, can you bring one in?
- Well, that's the plan.
You know, I've got word out
to every hospital
in the tristate area,
but these specialists, they...
are almost as rare
as your tumor.
- Dr. Reynolds?
- One sec. Okay.
- We can schedule
Teyarnie's surgery today
at New Amsterdam.
- Wait, how?
- Turns out, we do have
an endocrine surgeon on staff.
- Who?
- I completed
my Endocrine Surgery Fellowship
at the Icahn School of Medicine
at Mount Sinai.
Made me who I am today.
♪
.
- Hey.
- Hey, hon.
- So it is raining cats
and dogs,
and we are thoroughly soaked.
Wet clothes are clinging
to every curve of your body.
- I'm gonna stop you
right there.
- I'm sorry, you wanna stop me
before the part
where we cracked
the gazebo banister
with our entangled bodies?
- Only because now might not be
the ideal moment
to recount us vandalizing
a local heritage site.
- I'd like to hear it.
- Oh. Hello...everyone.
- Let me give you
a call later, okay?
- Mm-hmm. Yeah.
My apologies to...everyone.
♪
Hello?
- I'm busy.
- Oh, busy?
There's nobody here.
- Not enough docs.
- Well, that's perfect,
actually,
'cause I'm here
for a job interview.
- I sure do love
that idea, sweetie.
- I knew you would, Dad.
Oh! My doctor's here, hon.
Say hello.
- Thank you for taking care
of my dad.
- My pleasure.
- Okay.
I'll call you later.
Love you.
- Love you too.
- Your daughter
seems very sweet.
- She just played me the song
for our father-daughter dance.
One of my favorites.
- How are we feeling?
Has your pain level
decreased at all?
- No.
Still a pressure always there.
But let's hear it
for consistency, right?
Ooh.
- Mr. Aronova,
late-stage osteosarcoma
is an incredibly painful and--
- Lewis, please.
I mean, you're getting me
to that wedding after all, huh?
- Of course, Lewis.
- Mm.
- But there is only so much
that we can do.
- I promised Marissa I would
walk her down that aisle.
My body just needs to hold on
three more months.
- I can look
into upping your dosage
and possibly a spinal infusion,
but you should know
that the only guarantee
we can give you
for these treatments
is that your pain
will increase.
- I just need...
three more months.
♪
- So Teyarnie Jordan's
been moved to pre-op.
You just have
to pick out an OR.
- Oh, okay, okay.
Slow down, cowboy.
I won't even consider operating
until I've run every MRI,
every CAT scan,
every blood lab.
- No, no, no,
that could take days.
Teyarnie Jordan
needs surgery now.
- May I remind you
that only one of us
is a specialist in this field?
And in order to do my job,
I need to be 100% certain
that this tumor
is even amenable to resection.
- It doesn't take an expert
to know
that Teyarnie Jordan's tumor
is a time bomb.
She could have a GI bleed
at any second.
Your hesitation could kill her.
- Dr. Reynolds, I am not
hacking into a woman's torso
without sufficient preparation.
- You know, Dr. Fuentes,
we all know surgeons
who try to get back in the game
after some time away.
Doctors who became
administrators
who, at one point, wanted
to step back up to the table
but, once they got there,
realized they're not
doctors anymore.
- Is that what you think
this is?
- I think that Teyarnie Jordan
shouldn't have to risk her life
for us to find out.
- Excuse me,
where are you going?
- I'm transferring Ms. Jordan
to another hospital.
- So this is Romero Willis,
who I presented at rounds.
- Pancreatic neuroendocrine
tumor.
- Yeah, that's right.
And if you concur,
I plan on going in
with a chevron incision
and resecting the pancreas,
leaving margins
approximately here and here.
- Do you see
this dark spot here, Veronica,
on the wall of the stomach?
The tumor is not confined
to the pancreas.
If you start cutting,
you're gonna be compelled
to keep cutting.
You'll take out the stomach
and then half the liver,
and you may even have to resect
the entire diaphragm.
If you pull this thread,
it will cost this hospital
$750,000
with no guarantee this patient
can even survive post-op.
- So basically,
what you're saying is,
it's just too expensive
to save this man's life?
No, I wanna hear you say it.
- The answer is no,
Dr. Fuentes.
The surgery is not approved.
♪
- All right, so tell me,
was it always like this?
- No.
No, we used to be really close.
Every summer, we'd go to
Oak Island, just the two of us.
- The island with no roads,
no power?
That is some intense, rugged
father-son bonding right there.
- Yes, sir.
Anything you want
on Oak Island,
you gotta build yourself.
- Mm.
- Nobody can build like my dad.
I always looked up to him.
- Yeah.
Okay, so tell me
about when it changed.
- A few years
after the shooting,
I'm home from college
for Thanksgiving,
and I go to use
my dad's laptop,
and I see that on his browser,
he has this video about
how 9/11 was an inside job.
I mean, I thought
it was "The Onion,"
but then I see
he's got, like, 60 tabs open.
Lots about Nick's Grocery,
about how it was a false flag.
I mean, he's cooking
the turkey,
and I'm looking
at a photo of my friend
dying on the ground
with arrows pointed at him
saying, "Blood isn't this red!
#InOnIt."
- Did you confront him?
- Yeah.
But it's like
he was brainwashed.
Like he wasn't
even my dad anymore.
- Hmm.
- Shrinks can help people
get out of cults, right?
- Yes, but this isn't a cult,
not like we've known.
But, you know,
cults have one leader.
They have a physical location
that you can actually leave.
That's not the case here.
This internet-fueled delusion
is still very new,
but from what doctors
are seeing,
cult deprogramming tactics
don't work.
- So what does?
- Nothing.
- I mean, he's not just
some rando
who clicked on the wrong
social media post
about mass shootings.
I'm his son.
I was there.
He picked me up,
and I was covered in blood.
He knew it was real.
He's still in there.
Help me get my dad back,
please.
- You've certainly been
in and out
of some highly esteemed
institutions.
- Thank you.
- So I'll do you the favor
of not bringing you
into this one.
- Not...
What?
- Something stinks.
The ex-medical director
begging to work here?
I don't buy it.
You want something.
So what's your game?
- Very good, Antonio.
You got me, okay?
You're very astute.
- So they say.
- I need your seat
on the New Amsterdam board.
- Mm.
Very stirring.
As you can see,
we're not exactly
busting at the seams here.
Sixth floor
isn't the best spot,
as you might notice,
for an urgent care.
Corporate doesn't seem to care,
but I know it's gonna
land on me somehow.
You find a way to triple
our patient volume,
increase our revenues,
and that seat's yours.
- You want me to triple
your pat--that's impossible.
- They say anything's possible,
you want it badly enough.
- Okay.
All right, you give me
hiring privileges, and...
you got yourself a deal.
- Welcome
to Urgent Medicine Inc.
.
- Hello.
- So there I was,
licking every inch
of your body.
- Mr. Twickham, I'm gonna have
to call you back.
- Oh, role-playing? Kinky.
I like it.
So where were we?
Oh, right,
the gazebo was a-rocking,
so don't come a-knocking.
- Wrong number!
- Hello? Hello?
Broken.
- Welcome.
- Hey, you got a minute
for a consult?
- Yeah, always.
- So I have a patient
who is losing his battle
with late-stage bone cancer.
His only wish is to live
long enough
to attend
his daughter's wedding.
It's only three months away,
but I don't think
he's going to make it
that long.
- That's heartbreaking.
- Well, I was hoping that you
might have a way to--
you know, with--
to extend his life
with the means and methods
that maybe are outside of
the realms of scientific study.
- You've come
to the right place.
I was just putting together
this elixir.
It's from the springs
of the Loxahatchee River
where, in 1513,
Ponce de León searched
for the Fountain of Youth.
- Oh.
- Wait, seriously?
- Of course not.
This is Dijon vinaigrette
for my arugula salad.
I am a medical practitioner.
I don't make magic potions.
I'm a healer. I'm like you.
I can't just wave a magic wand
and heal your patient,
even though I wish I could.
- I'm sorry.
- Sorry.
- Enjoy your salad.
- I have heard what Drew
has to say about that day.
But what about you, Robert?
- You think
it's gonna help him?
- I do.
- Drew and I don't see
eye to eye on Nick's Grocery,
and I don't wanna
keep upsetting him.
- That day was hard
for everyone, okay?
But I think what Drew
needs to hear
is what it was like
for you in your words.
- I was at work.
My wife called
and said she saw
Drew's store on the news.
Brought Drew home.
- Okay, well, what was that
like, getting that call?
- Bad news, your heart drops,
you know?
I could hear panic
in her voice,
but she was talking so fast.
It took me a sec to get what
she was seeing on the news,
but when I did...
When I did...
I did, like, 90
out of that parking lot.
I had this image of you...
shot,
dying, wanting me with you
when you went...
and not being with you.
But then I come
around the corner...
and there you are.
My boy.
Alive.
- You both experienced
a trauma that day.
It's not the fear
or the pain that casts
a shadow over your life.
It's the,
"Why did this happen? Why?"
You ask God,
you ask the universe, and...
you don't get
an answer, ever.
And that is so hard.
And in that void, we turn
to whatever we can find.
We turn to anything that looks
like it might tell us why,
no matter
how far-fetched it may be.
But some things
can't be explained.
Sometimes "why"
doesn't have an answer.
- Hmm.
You're right.
All I wanna know is,
how did they get to my son
and get him
to say those things?
- Jesus!
- If you would just let me,
I could show you
how it was all rigged--
- I was there, Dad! You saw me!
Why the hell
would I make that up?
- I'm not saying you're lying.
- Maybe we can just--
we can take a step back here.
- I can't believe I thought
this would actually work.
- Drew, hang on.
- Where's Teyarnie Jordan?
- Dr. Fuentes had her
transferred up to the OR,
like, 20 minutes ago.
- What in God's name
do you think you're doing?
- This middle school teacher
needs our help
to get back to work.
- This surgery
was not approved.
- Yet we're starting
with a chevron incision.
Scalpel.
- As chief of medicine,
I will make certain
that anyone doing procedures
behind my back
will never find work in
another health-care facility.
- Noted.
Now, get out of my OR.
Scalpel.
Need a little more light
on the field, please.
- Why wasn't I notified
of my own patient's surgery?
- Need I remind you of our
last exchange, Dr. Reynolds?
Retractor.
You refused to run labs
and order scans
that I deemed relevant.
You tried to push through
a surgical procedure
before it was even clear
that surgery
was the best course of action.
Lap pad.
So I ran those labs myself,
and I really didn't feel
compelled to include you
in that decision.
But if you're gonna
stick around,
I suggest you
make yourself useful.
Scrub in.
♪
- It's called
Urgent Medicine Incorporated.
And I know, it sounds like
a front for the Serbian mob,
and honestly, it might be,
but we're gonna turn
this place around, okay?
And this job is gonna
be way more hours
with a lot less money.
- How do you think your pitch
is going so far?
- What you're trying to do
sounds amazing, Max.
- Right? And that's why
I'd love to have you on board.
- I would love to,
but my hands are full.
My patient load is crazy
now that I'm no longer a chair.
- So you expect
the former chair of surgery
at the largest public hospital
in the country to join you
working part-time at some
rinky-dink walk-in clinic?
- Well, no, Claude,
I never said, "Rinky-dink."
Gladys, please.
- It's just a case
of supply and demand.
- Uh-huh.
- You know, there's
a nationwide nursing shortage.
And my level of skills
is in very high demand.
- Well, I can see that.
- I can even make my own hours.
- That's great! Then you can
totally fit Urgent Medicine
right into your schedule.
- Oh, Max,
you couldn't afford me.
- Sandra Fall, me and you
back together again
like Thelma and Louise!
- They drove off a cliff.
- Oh, yeah.
What about--excuse me--
Butch and Sundance?
- Died in a hail of bullets
in Bolivia.
- Oh. Well, how about
peanut butter and--
- Tall mocha latte for Tanya!
Max, for over a year, I've been
trying not to work for you,
and I've finally succeeded.
- But--
- My answer is no.
- No.
- Hell no.
- How can you say that?
How can everybody say that?
We're talking
about New Amsterdam.
There's no place
in the world like it.
How can nobody
wanna fight for it?
- 'Cause we all lost our jobs
'cause of you, Max.
And now you want us
covering your six
like you're some kind
of Joan of Arc?
Listen, I'm sorry, Max,
all right,
but you're just
gonna leave again.
You're gonna leave
New Amsterdam in the hands
of some other bureaucrat.
You tell me
you're sticking around,
you're not going
back to London,
I'll come with you right now,
and so will everyone else.
Can you do that?
- I--
- Yeah. I didn't think so.
- ♪ Got that yummy-yum
♪ That yummy-yum,
that yummy-yummy ♪
♪ Yeah, you got
that yummy-yum ♪
♪ That yum
.
- Dad, I so wish
you were here.
Oh, the walk was amazing,
but this view,
it's everything we imagined.
- I can see that.
♪
- I know it's hard for people
trained in Western medicine
to understand what I do.
- Look, I swear
I was not trying
to ridicule your specialty.
- I know.
You're struggling
with the limitations
of your power
to care for this man,
and you came to me for help,
and I whiffed it.
- I just know that I have used
every single tool
in my toolbox.
♪
- I might have one left
in mine.
♪
- Do you see
what I'm dealing with?
- I do. I do. I do.
- He's so lost in this,
but his heart's still there.
- Yes. Yes, it is. It is.
- So what do we do?
How do we help him change?
- He can't change.
He won't.
So you have to.
- But he's the one who's wrong.
He's the one who believes
things that aren't true.
- Exactly.
You are able to tell
what's real and what is not.
The burden falls to you
to do what he can't,
what he isn't doing.
- No. No, no, he's just
lost contact with reality,
and if we can figure out why,
then we can bring him back.
- We'll never know why.
Even if we did,
it wouldn't matter.
It wouldn't change anything
because the reason
doesn't matter.
- Of course it matters.
Conspiracy theories
aren't harmless.
They're the reason why millions
of people won't get a vaccine
that could save their lives.
They're why global warming
might actually kill
every person on the planet.
- Right.
- Mass shootings like Nick's
happen so often,
it isn't even news anymore,
and I'm supposed to just
put my head in the sand?
- Yes.
If you want a relationship
with your father,
that is the price tag,
accepting his reality.
- But how am I supposed
to have a relationship
with somebody who insists
on calling me a liar?
- He's not insisting on that,
is he?
He didn't wanna
discuss the topic.
He didn't share
his beliefs with you.
The only reason you found out
is because
you borrowed his laptop.
The person who keeps insisting
that you talk about this
is you.
- Because it happened...
to me.
- Yes, it did happen.
But now you have a choice.
You can be right,
or you can have your father,
but you can't have both.
♪
- And that is the last
of the primary tumor.
- Negative for hypothermia.
- Yeah, Mr. Willis should get
a Medal of Honor.
Sponge and lap pad.
Can you imagine being
a middle school teacher?
Ugh, brutal work.
Janice, no stories from you?
You're usually so chatty.
♪
Dr. Palpa said
if we helped you,
we'd all lose our jobs.
- Well, that is not happening.
I will protect you.
I will protect
every single one of you.
Helping this man was my call,
and it is the right call.
He needs us today,
and we're gonna do
whatever it takes
to help him, understood?
I got you.
♪
And that is the last
of the primary tumor.
Moving on to expose
the stomach wall.
Forceps.
Damn it.
- What you got?
- Right there.
- I don't see anything.
- It's that tiny spot.
Teyarnie's tumor has invaded
her stomach wall.
- Ooh. Okay.
- Close her up.
- Close her up?
No, we just resect
the stomach wall.
- That's just the beginning,
Dr. Reynolds.
And then we'd have to perform
a radical resection,
remove half of her liver
or more.
- Yeah, so we do it.
To not do it
is a death sentence.
Scalpel.
- Dr. Reynolds, I want you
to think this through.
If we keep resecting,
what awaits Teyarnie
when she wakes up?
She's gonna need a kidney
transplant, a liver transplant,
an islet cell transplantation
of the pancreas.
And if she survives, she'll
never drive a big rig again.
Following down this path
is simply not worth it.
- This is her only chance!
- Dr. Reynolds, I said stop!
You're done!
- I'm not done, actually.
- Step away from the table,
and get out of my OR now!
- This is not how we do things
around here!
♪
- Get out.
All right, let's get to it.
Let's close her up.
♪
- Oh, sorry.
I just came out
to clear my head, but I can--
- No, no, just--
don't worry about it.
I'm just leaving.
- I did what I did
for the sake of the hospital.
- How's that working out
for you?
- Hey, man,
you're the one who left.
- Yeah, because I thought
the people who stayed
would keep fighting.
- Yeah, but how long?
Max, how long should we keep
risking our careers,
our livelihood,
our reputations?
For six months, a year?
How long
should we keep fighting
to make it easier for you?
- Easier for--
you think this is easy?
I'm dragging Luna
back and forth across an ocean.
I'm leaving behind the life
I'm just getting started.
- So what?
So we should be grateful
for your presence?
We should be thankful
that you came back to save us?
- I just came back to help.
And today, when I asked
all my friends to join me,
they all said no.
♪
- You didn't ask me.
- No. I didn't.
♪
.
- This is why I didn't wanna
come here today.
- Yes, today has been
very hard.
But Drew and I have spoken,
and he has something
he'd like to say to you.
- You remember Oak Island?
Remember how nothing mattered
except the essentials?
Pumping water, starting a fire,
getting the generator to work.
- I didn't think you cared
about that place that much.
- I didn't.
But it's the only place
I had you to myself.
Like the rest of the world...
didn't exist.
- Go on. Tell him.
♪
- I've been, you know,
thinking about making
a coffee table
for the house.
I just--
I don't know
how to make a dovetail joint.
Oh.
Well...
your wood
has to be planed true.
Otherwise,
the cuts won't line up.
♪
- Maybe you can show me.
But if you don't have time--
- I'd be happy to.
I'd be happy to.
- All right, we could just
go back to the house
and focus on the basics.
♪
- Lewis, these are
Tibetan singing bowls.
They're used in traditional
Buddhist practices,
and their sounds
are known to be very healing.
- Well, at this point,
I'll try just about anything.
Can you take
a deep breath for me?
- Good.
And another.
So far, better than chemo.
- I'm curious,
where is your daughter
getting married?
- In the country,
an old hotel in Connecticut.
- You got your tux all ready?
- Oh, yeah.
- I bet that it's beautiful
up there this time of year.
- Do you have a live band?
- I, uh--
- Tell me about her dress.
♪
- Her dress?
- Yeah, the wedding dress.
What's it look like?
♪
- ♪ Helplessly hoping
- It's cream...
long.
Nothing fancy, but beautiful.
♪
- ♪ Heartlessly
- My little girl
is so, so beautiful.
- ♪ To her bad dreams
♪ He worries
♪ Did he hear a goodbye
♪ Or even
♪ Hello
♪ They are one person
♪ They are two alone
♪ They are three together
♪ They are for
♪ Each other
♪
♪ Stand by the stairway
♪ You'll see something
certain to tell you ♪
♪ Confusion has its cost
♪ Love isn't lying
♪ It's loose in a lady
♪ Who lingers
♪ Saying she is lost
♪ And choking
♪ On hello
♪ They are one
- Is he...
- ♪ They are two alone
♪ They are three together
- But you got him
to his daughter's wedding.
- ♪ Each other
♪
ER physician to three, stat.
- We failed our patient today.
- I know.
- Dr. Fuentes,
you are incredibly,
incredibly gifted...
- Dr. Reynolds,
you are easily
one of the best surgeons
I've ever seen.
And I want you to know
that I have stood exactly where
you're standing right now.
- But I want you to ask
yourself a hard question.
How can you do the most good
with those talents?
Today you gave
a middle school teacher
two, maybe three more years,
but you took away those years
from a patient
that we'll have to turn away
tomorrow.
- That is what so few people
in our profession
are willing to admit,
much less understand.
- That the greater good
is simply too expensive.
Sacrifices must always
be made.
- Now, the doctors who do
understand these hard truths...
they're the ones
who keep this system afloat.
- They're the ones who become
great leaders, who become...
- Medical directors.
- Dr. Fuentes, right now,
you've got two doors
in front of you.
- Behind that first door,
you're just another cog
in the system.
You're just another
nice guy, right?
- And behind that second door
is the opportunity to fix...
- The system,
to decide what resources
are best spent where and to...
- Heal as many people
as possible...
- With what you've got.
- The choice...
- Is yours.
♪
- Sydney Tsimbaris?
- Sandra Fall from billing.
- I'm as surprised as you are.
- We're backed up, boss.
You mind pitching in?
♪
- Didn't think
you had it in you.
- You still can't afford me,
but I'm here.
- What--what happened?
What changed your minds?
- Reynolds called me.
- Me too.
- I don't even know
how he got my number.
- He called me too.
♪
How can I help?
Hello.
- Hey.
Sorry to call so late.
- It's okay.
I was just getting up...
mm, in three hours.
- Probably not a good time
to talk about all the things
we did in that gazebo, huh?
- No.
No, I don't think it is.
- Well, if we can't
talk about old memories,
then...
maybe we could make
some new ones.
- Hmm.
I'd love to, but how?
How when we're oceans apart?
What new memories
are we gonna make?
- Well, close your eyes.
Well, that will be easy.
- Now...
imagine me next to you...
- ♪ Wishing well
- My arms wrapping around you.
Can you feel that?
- Max.
Just...
just try.
♪
- ♪ Is it real
- Can you feel me touching you?
- Yes.
- 'Cause I can feel you.
My fingers just--
just graze your neck
and slide down your chest...
♪
Your stomach.
I can feel the heat
coming off your skin.
And I can smell you.
It's that mixture
of sun and jasmine.
- Where are your hands now?
- Where do you want them?
- I think you know.
- I'm kissing
every part of you.
You try to kiss me back,
but I don't let you.
This is all for you.
- Then what?
- I work my way
down your body,
stopping at each...little spot.
I take my time,
and I don't stop
until our bodies
find their rhythm...
- ♪ Feel alive
- And it's like I'm there,
Like there's no space
between us,
no ocean apart,
just you and me,
and we fit together.
- ♪ Is it real
♪ Just to feel alive
- You still--you still there?
♪
What are you thinking?
- ♪ Have you heard
it's a wild world ♪
- I'm thinking...
hmm...
that we're gonna be just fine.
- ♪ Have you heard
it's a wild world ♪
♪