Oh!
We can't both shower
at the same time, Lea.
One of us would block the
stream of water for the other.
Oh, Shaun, this is not for
the purpose of cleanliness.
This is for the purpose
of having sex with you.
Oh.
No. No, it would be
inconvenient, possibly dangerous.
Soap might get
into difficult places.
If we leaned against
the shower handle,
we could scald ourselves,
bottles could be disarranged.
It was just a thought.
It was a bad thought.
I'm surprised, you're
such an intelligent person.
I'll reset your alarm.
It's a three-day
weekend and a full moon.
People are gonna
do stupid things,
so I'm asking everyone to take
an extra trauma call in the E.R.
Make yourselves available
if you're needed. Questions?
- How'd you get the bruise?
- First casualty of the full moon.
I smacked my head when I
was reaching for my coffee mug.
Any other questions?
Why is there a Subaru
in your parking space?
Because it's my car.
You have a car?
You're gonna be seeing
a lot of it. I sold the Ducati.
What? No.
- It just wasn't practical.
- Is it already gone? Because...
A guy from Craigslist
snatched it up.
Any other questions,
not dealing with the bike?
It wasn't that
much of a bruise, -
but the doctor at the ski resort
told us I might develop a hematoma.
It's not unusual, but
it'll need to be drained.
I see you were treated
for melanoma six years ago
and more recently,
breast cancer.
Hence, this ski trip. A
celebration. One year cancer-free.
Also, five years cancer-free.
I don't suppose a long
needle will be involved in this?
Your hematoma extends pretty
deep, so the needle will have to be long.
But it's over quickly.
I have to intervene
before this deal goes south.
You don't mind if I step out?
Would you like us to wait for
your husband to come back?
No. Let's go ahead.
How do you get
frostbite in San Jose?
Cryotherapy accident.
I stayed in the
booth a little too long.
I was gonna stand outside
for the full three minutes,
- but he said...
- I said no need.
I'd set the stopwatch
on my phone,
after which my thoughts
immediately drifted and...
I came back to find
him frozen in carbonite.
You know, I'm more
worried about the fever.
Was the cryotherapy
meant to treat something?
No, routine self-care.
We've made life extension
part of our health regime.
Supplements,
meditation, exercise.
Three of my gaming
apps have gone viral.
I'm lucky enough to afford
basically whatever I want,
so I spend it on my health.
Now, I figure fever
must be an infection.
Mm. I know that frostbite can
make you vulnerable. It just...
It didn't seem
severe enough to...
I'm sorry, I feel
a little queasy.
Wyatt.
I need a medical
transport team, STAT.
Perforated bowel, he
needs immediate surgery.
No. No! Why do
people hate wind farms?
Everyone thinks they're noisy.
This could make a
turbine sound as quiet
as a page turning in a library.
That's not worth our investing
in? Did you even look... Hold on.
Anything I need to know?
Hematoma's drained.
We sent the sample
to Pathology, routine.
- Should have it back sometime tomorrow.
- Thank you.
I couldn't help overhearing a
little. Are you a venture capitalist?
The only people who
ask me if I'm a VC
are people who want a
VC to invest in their project.
Maybe after we get your wife
healthy again, we could talk.
Call whenever you're ready,
my life is listening to ideas.
If it's good, I'll run it by my
two partners. If it's really good,
we'll take a 30 percent equity
position in your company.
Yeah, yeah. You're the one
who wanted to get us
into clean technology.
I think I've been
asked out on a date.
Nice.
No, I work with him.
- Hasn't stopped you before.
- I supervise him.
- Schedules can be changed.
- He's polyamorous.
Unless he also texted
you a ring, it's just a date.
And you need to get out more.
So do I.
You wanna take down
the splenocolic ligament,
just don't nick the
inferior mesenteric artery.
I feel the IMA under my finger.
Placing the stapler and cutting.
I voted approve.
Disapprove.
No opinion.
There's a poll?
Yes. About shower sex.
I know it's wrong to
discuss shower sex at work,
so I did a poll instead.
Much better.
Dr. Murphy, do you really want people
knowing the details of your personal life?
You don't think they took
it as an abstract question?
No, we all take it as something
that happened between you and Lea.
And that there was a fight.
Sometime before 8 a.m. today,
which was when the poll was sent out.
You are very astute.
I'm seeing diffuse dilatation
of the large bowel here.
Is that normal?
Some calcified
lesions. Wall's thin too.
Hirschsprung's?
I thought Hirschsprung's was a disease
only babies and young children got.
It is, but he has it.
We treated the Hirschsprung's
by removing the
dilated part of your colon.
It won't impact your life, but
we would like an explanation.
Dr. Murphy doesn't mean we
expect you to be a diagnostician.
It's just... this was
kind of singular,
so if you have any thoughts...
Did anyone in your family
suddenly develop these symptoms?
I did something singular to
myself about six months ago.
I modified my genetic code.
I did a CRISPR procedure
under the guidance
of some researchers I know
in China through my work.
They put together a series of
cocktails, they FedEx'd them to me,
and Sophie helped me inject
them into my bone marrow.
Why? If you know
anything about CRISPR,
you know how risky it is
to tinker with your genome.
You have no idea what
problems you might let loose.
I needed to optimize
my telomerase activity.
It's the enzyme responsible for
correcting cell replication errors.
Essentially, the cause of aging.
You can't stop aging through
changing your telomerase activity.
You might extend your life a little,
but exercise, it does the same thing.
Much less risky. Your
decision makes no sense.
Extending my life by a few
years is only my short-term goal.
Look, you know how
fast medicine is moving.
The day isn't that far away
when cloning will make transplants
as easy as switching
out a light socket.
AI will start to make breakthroughs
that we can't predict or understand.
Medical knowledge
will rise exponentially.
There are babies born
now who could live to see it,
could live to be a
thousand years old.
Maybe more, maybe forever.
Or at least as long as they want to.
So our plan is to give
my CRISPR a year
to make sure the telomerase
change works, and then we'll do her.
We'll aspirate a sample
of your bone marrow.
See if we can figure
out what the hell you did.
Hey. Um, I don't think
coffee is a good idea.
Entire civilizations rely on it,
but I don't think you're
referring to the beverage itself.
No, I don't think it's a good idea for
first years and fourth years to go out.
I am bound to supervise
you at some point in the future
and it'd get complicated
trying to change dates out and...
The fact is, seeing somebody
you work with rarely ends happily,
so I appreciate you
thinking of me, but I...
Oh, you... thought
it was a date.
I'm still new here, and I
thought it was a good opportunity
to get to know each other.
Well, coffee's perfect
because you're asking
the least amount of commitment
from another human being.
It's not even lunch.
If it's still a no,
it's still a no.
But I'll let you
re-think your answer?
What?
He only claimed it
wasn't a date to save face.
Or maybe I just assumed.
But why did I assume?
I don't think I'm
some kind of narcissist
who thinks every man
wants to get close to me. I...
Or we both assumed it's
a date because it's a date.
This is fun. I like
being your bestie.
Slumber party?
I made a poll to test the
popularity of shower sex.
I heard. I fielded some
questions about that.
Approve has won, but
don't get too excited, Lea.
It's only 58-38 with several
- complicated non-committals...
- Okay.
So clearly my
attitude is reasonable.
We don't have room
for a skier exercise thing.
I'm only putting it together
so I can take a picture
and sell it online.
Why do you have it
if you don't want it?
My ex sent it.
Ex?
Husband.
I left this thing in the attic
until I got settled somewhere
with enough space,
and, okay, that was ten years
ago, but it's not like it was in his way.
We got married. Not for
long, right out of high school.
Literally the boy next
door. We grew up together,
people expected it.
It was a big mistake.
We both realized
it pretty quickly.
Why would you even
wanna live forever?
You'd be bored out of your mind.
The person I am now is miles
away from the person I was at 14.
I only get more
distant every year.
You learn to understand...
love books that you once hated.
Sometimes people you once hated.
Music that you didn't get
the point of becomes magical.
A thousand new doors will open.
I look forward to the adventure.
Sorry.
Adventure's not
always gonna be fun.
I figure it takes 40 or 50 years
just to get over the
things your parents did.
If only we lived long enough,
the human race might finally
have a chance to grow up.
What size shoes do you wear?
Seven and a half.
Dr. Allen's Walking
on Clouds inserts.
Putting "doctor" in names is
always a good marketing strategy.
They're designed to
reduce inflammation
that could lead
to plantar fasciitis,
calluses, arthritis, and
they feel damn good.
Does this have anything to do with
our patient's venture capitalist husband?
I need testimonials.
Labs and Path for Hannah Palmer.
Aren't we all busy enough
learning how to be surgeons?
Do you really wanna divide
your focus onto something trivial?
Because wanting to make
money taints the purity of medicine?
I have five brothers. I've been
taking care of people my whole life.
Someone got hurt, they
came to me to patch them up.
I became a doctor so
I could get paid for it.
But also because I'm good
at taking care of people.
It's possible to do something
for more than one reason.
The news is bad.
There's an abnormally
healthy population
of Hematopoietic
progenitor stem cells.
He did it?
It's significant.
He's succeeded in optimizing
enough telomerase activity
to potentially add ten
years to his natural life.
Well, assuming he
doesn't subtract about 50.
There's already an autoimmune
reaction that mimics Hirschsprung's.
Who knows what else he did?
What if this is the opposite
of an autoimmune condition?
What if he's done something that
lowers his resistance to infection?
Then we'd be seeing
more opportunistic infections
of the lungs and skin.
If you lived another 1000 years,
would you be with the same
person at the end as at the beginning?
No.
No, if you assume monogamy.
That puts too much
strain on a relationship.
Is one person supposed
to be everything to another
all the time for 1000 years?
Yeah, apparently Jesus agrees.
On monogamy. He said that in
heaven there'll be no more marriages.
I guess humans can't
sustain a relationship that long.
You read the New Testament too?
And the Qur'an,
and other things.
Like you're a stalker, like you and
God had an acrimonious divorce.
What if he caused
neurofibromatosis?
Microscopic tumors
forming on the nerve sheath?
Possible, but there'd
have been some evidence
of Schwann cell
growth around his colon.
Would you still love your
wife in a thousand years?
You have three answers,
that should be enough.
Park's marriage
failed in far less time
and Enrique doesn't even try,
Asher is a... unknown quantity.
You're committed.
You've made promises.
I've made promises based on an
understood human lifespan, Murphy.
Most likely diagnosis is
autoimmune polyneuropathy.
It damaged the enteric ganglion
nerve and led to the perforation.
Start him on steroids
and immunosuppressants.
Dr. Andrews?
So you wouldn't have gotten married
if you thought it would be forever.
You expect all
relationships to fail over time.
It's just a question
of how long.
I love her now.
I intend to love
her as long as I live.
But eventually,
everything breaks.
I always go back to comfort
reading when I'm in the hospital.
Cozy mysteries and
little English villages
where nothing bad
happens to anyone we like.
We've gotten your results back.
- When will your husband be...
- Is it cancer?
Yes.
Thyroid carcinoma.
We're gonna do a
complete imaging series
- to pinpoint just how advanced...
- Treatment?
Surgery to remove
some or all of your thyroid
is usually the first
line of defense.
Sometimes we can wait,
but given the hematoma
was probably caused by the
tumor invading nearby vasculatures,
we should probably do
it in the next few days.
Later, there'll be
radioactive iodine treatment.
Panic attack?
Her trachea is
deviated to the right.
The tumor's compressing
it. We're doing surgery now.
What happened? The nurse just
said surgery. Was it the hematoma?
It's more serious.
It... It's not cancer again?
Thyroid carcinoma.
We've removed her thyroid.
She's doing well.
We're looking into potential
causes. Genetic, environmental.
There may be a deeper issue
that we can find and address.
I can't do this.
You've done it before.
You'll do it this time.
You know what it's like?
To wake up every morning
and know your wife might
not be here next year?
All those
treatments, they all...
They all have this little
tag attached to them
that says, "because
she might die."
And you see them put those gloves
on before they hook up the chemo.
You know why they do that?
It's because it's poison.
And you sit there...
and you watch them shove
poison into the person you love.
And why? Because she might die.
We're killing her
because she might die.
Go for a run, go punch a wall.
You need to release
some endorphins.
My release is my job,
and that's why I love it.
My work requires total focus,
and every minute I'm working
is a minute I'm not
thinking about... losing her.
I have to go.
Your pain and weakness are
consistent with polyneuropathy,
treatable with steroids
and immunosuppressants.
If you live 1000 years,
will you still love Sophie?
Yes.
How can you be sure? People
change. You expect to change.
Sophie and I will
change together.
We'll go through the same
adventures and learn the same lessons.
What if you go through
the same adventures
and learn different lessons?
Even if we did, whoever,
whatever we become,
Sophie will always be beautiful.
I mean, she could turn into
a machine or a set of pixels
or a giant purple flower,
she'll still be beautiful
because it's part of
her essential nature.
But if you don't know
how you'll change,
- you don't know how you'll change.
- Shaun.
We'll let you get some rest.
The steroids should
make you feel a lot better.
Why didn't you ever mention
you had an ex-husband?
Shaun, I've barely
thought about him in years.
I didn't mention him
because he's not important.
I know, that's the problem.
At one time, you felt he
was important enough
to your life to marry him, and
now you barely think of him.
You make long-term plans,
you have expectations,
and then something
happens to you,
and suddenly you're
a different person.
I know you don't like
change, but it's not all bad.
After all, you are working to
change yourself all the time.
I'm working to be a better
surgeon, a better boyfriend,
better at the things
I've chosen, but this...
other change,
it's unpredictable.
You don't choose it.
It just comes at you.
It's like hurricanes before 1873
when the Army Signal Corps
first put up flags to warn
people storms were coming.
Before that, houses were
flattened, lives destroyed,
and there was no way to
see it was heading for you.
Shaun, our relationship will
not end in natural disaster.
It did begin in one.
I'm going to look
in on my patient.
Okay.
Blood and saliva will tell
us if there is a genetic cause,
and the samples we
take from your house
will tell us if there is
something environmental.
I know it's stupid,
I've almost felt
guilty for my cancer,
like I arbitrarily decided
to be sick and burdensome.
Do the people you're close to
ever act like you're
a burden to them?
You mean Alan.
He's scared.
He takes the exit he's got
and he turns to his work.
You're okay with that?
I accept this compromise.
That's not the hard part.
The hard part is... not knowing.
Each new thing that happens,
I worry, "Is this it? Is
this where I lose him?
Is this where he breaks?"
So this is boiled coffee.
Some people call it Turkish coffee,
or Greek coffee, or Egyptian coffee.
Because we need to take
ownership and put things in categories.
Yeah.
Do you actually live in this thing?
In the hospital parking garage?
Why not? Convenient for work.
When I wanna spend a
few days off the beaten track,
convenient for that too.
Mm. I'm gonna get
three sips in this.
But three really great sips.
That's how I try
to live my life.
Try to appreciate,
savor, not pass by.
That what the
polyamory is about?
Does it really work?
Or is it one of those theories
about life that people regret later?
- No regrets so far.
- Mm-hm. No, I guess not.
Not while you're
young and having fun.
It is fun. But not for the
reasons that you're thinking.
It isn't about sex. It's
about commitment.
Emotional connection.
The joy I'm sure you get out of
a relationship, I get a little more.
Also, have to give a little
more. But that's meaningful too.
Hmm.
You mind if I ask you something,
since we're getting personal?
Sure.
What's your favorite
misheard song lyric?
This is nice.
I'm glad it's not a date.
Me too. I don't believe
in those categories.
He reported widespread
bilateral pain, then he keeled over.
BP dropped to 80 over palp.
- I'll order a vasopressor.
- Already did.
Good. We need an EKG,
CBC, and chest images,
and a new diagnosis.
Whatever he caused with
CRISPR, it's not just neuropathy.
Something else is killing him.
What if he's caused something
that mimics carcinomatous
autonomic neuropathy?
Explains the BP and bowel issue.
That doesn't explain the sensory
issue that led to the frostbite.
A connective tissue disorder?
That would've shown up on the
scans. His chest looks normal.
Maybe we can't think of the
answer because there is no answer.
We keep trying to jam
it into these categories
and diseases that we know.
But this never existed before.
He created a new
combination of genetic code,
that means a new
combination of symptoms.
We shouldn't be looking
at what fits the picture
but at what's
closest to the picture
so we can figure
out a treatment.
And what it's closest
to is amyloidosis.
This isn't an
autoimmune neuropathy,
so the nerves must be under
attack by something else.
Something like amyloid disease
could leave deposits along the nerves,
causing the symptoms we've seen.
Where do we look
for those deposits?
In the spleen.
Drink all eight ounces.
We talked, we had a few laughs.
Oh, sounds date-y to me.
I don't think
Enrique's a player.
No, he's kind of the
opposite of a player.
With him, emotional
connection is the point.
He's trying to live
some idealistic fantasy
where everyone is nice
and no one is jealous.
I am so staying away.
Well, of course. Once I
heard "emotional connection,"
I knew the game was over.
What does that mean?
I'm against emotion?
I'm not the one with
"cold-hearted bitch"
as my social media hashtag.
She's an excellent doctor.
Every time you've
loved somebody,
it's ended in disappointment
or death. Sometimes both.
It's like a reflex now.
You just expect that everything
ends badly, so why start?
So despite the many practical
reasons not to go out with a first-year,
this is all about me.
Is that a diamond ring?
I mean, it's pretty.
The patient caught
her fiancé cheating,
big fight, he demanded
the ring back,
she swallowed it.
I did.
You don't even know if this is
going out, and that's the point.
It doesn't matter what Enrique's offering,
whether it's friendship or romance,
you're not investing.
You're risk-averse.
Your portfolio right now is
entirely in T-bills and money market.
I have no idea what that means.
It's too bad. A guy that
can make you laugh
might be just what
you need right now.
It's regressed to
your large intestine.
Here's a plastic bag.
Put it over the toilet seat.
You'll have every opportunity
to recover your property.
Don't run away from
a chance at love.
It's a date.
Maybe. I don't know. Oh.
Their house is full of TCE.
Side effect from chipmaking
back in Silicon Valley's early days.
So they move away
from their toxic home
- and hopefully things get a little better.
- Probably not much.
She also has a
genetic predisposition.
It's both?
She shouldn't go
outside in a rainstorm.
How do you tell a woman
that her third cancer
likely won't be
close to her last?
Unfortunately, this
is a teaching moment.
Dr. Allen! After
12 hours on duty,
I can report that your
inserts came through.
Check your e-mail,
you'll find my testimonial.
Claire. Olivia.
And if you're right,
what will you do?
We'll treat the symptoms
with targeted drug therapies.
There really isn't a disease
as such that we can address.
- The pain shifted?
- Yeah.
- Oh!
- Never mind about the ultrasound.
It'll be easier to check for deposits
after the organ's been removed.
- After it's...
- Yeah.
His spleen's about to
rupture. Call the transport team.
It's called Li-Fraumeni
syndrome, LFS.
An inherited predisposition to
developing a wide range of cancers.
Yes, there was a toxin
in your environment
that likely played
a role in this,
but there will be other
triggers in the future.
Your body is super sensitive
and will respond with
tumors for the rest of your life.
I know that's a shock. But
here's what you should know.
Most cancers are treatable
if found early enough.
We know the most
common associated with LFS
and we can do surveillance.
Nip anything in the bud
before it becomes a problem.
It may not seem this
way now, but this is good.
We know what we're dealing with.
We're warned, and we'll be ready.
He won't be able to handle this.
Liver, pancreas, other
organs look normal.
But there are calcified
lesions along these nerves.
He'll be in pain like
this for the rest of his life.
No, there is a reasonable chance
it'll get worse as time goes on.
I need my sharp-blunt
curve scissors.
What if we use CRISPR
to reverse CRISPR?
Researchers have identified
a protein in certain bacteria
that inhibits CRISPR.
What if we insert the DNA
that makes that protein
into our patient's genome?
That would deactivate
the CRISPR gene.
So, CRISPR messed
him up permanently
and you think we
should do more of it?
Well, our patient
is a risk-taker.
We need a delivery mechanism,
the code would have to be
introduced through a virus.
A virus that specifically
targets nerves.
- Well, polio targets nerves.
- Because this isn't risky enough.
Polio is such a dangerous virus
because it's so good at penetrating
the nervous system.
Dr. Murphy?
She's going to be
this way... forever?
She'll have good
periods and bad periods,
but she will always
have to be on her guard.
Is she always gonna have to
be on guard against you too?
What does that mean?
Chronic illness puts
strain on relationships.
Statistically, it is more often
the man who can't handle it.
Our marriage is
none of your business.
No, her health is my business.
And your behavior adds to her stress.
You look at her and
you imagine she's gone,
and that is hard, I get it.
But she thinks the same
thing when she looks at you.
I never complain to her.
I know it's nobody's fault.
You don't think she knows
you have trouble with all this?
Every time something
new happens, she wonders,
"Is this the straw that is
going to break your marriage?"
You've got her living in a
constant state of uncertainty.
That is practically
the definition of stress.
So this is the "straighten
up and fly right" lecture.
No.
I am...
I'm telling you to consider
how best to time your divorce.
There are gonna be a lot of
new issues dropping on Hannah,
and if you're gonna
end up leaving anyway,
- you should start planning now.
- I don't wanna leave my wife.
My best advice...
help her through this
next round of treatment
as best you can...
and then get out.
It's hard living with
someone who needs so much.
I know you feel there is a point
where you have nothing left,
where you're ready to break.
Just don't break when
she needs you most.
Get out before that happens.
Reading an article
that's five years old?
Dr. Glassman was once
involved in an experimental attempt
to treat Parkinson's with
CRISPR technology. It failed.
So it's both old,
and it didn't work.
Dr. Glassman likes his
failures to be informative,
that's why his
articles are longer.
Do you worry about
losing the people you love?
Because we can't stop
ourselves from changing,
which means we might
stop loving someone
or they might stop loving
us. It is a very bad thing.
It is.
So no one can ever feel safe.
How can you keep going
if you never feel safe?
Well, sometimes not
changing is just as dangerous.
So how do you know
when to do what?
If you find the answer
to that, let me know.
- I have it.
- You do?
Dr. Glassman used
varicella-zoster virus
as the delivery mechanism,
which didn't work.
His first choice
was herpes simplex,
but the technology was not up to
putting their DNA package into it.
The technology has
improved. It can be done.
Using conventional treatments,
there's nothing more
we can do for you.
The pain will be permanent
and it could get worse.
Well, I've not been one to
be limited by the conventional.
We think we can
reverse the CRISPR.
You want to reverse what I
did? My telomerase change?
- No. They want to stop your pain.
- Soph, it's temporary.
And what is it, 40
years? That's nothing.
Our real lives are
ahead of us, okay?
Look, as long as
this doesn't kill me,
I've made the right choice
no matter how bad things get.
No.
I was willing to exercise for
hours, and fast, to give up all sugar
and alcohol, and
do all the other things
that we needed to
do to get to a future
that I knew might never come.
But now you're asking me to watch
you suffer for the rest of your life?
You're the one who
embraces change.
So change to the person
who can be happy with me...
here and now.
Doctors, would you
mind waiting outside?
Why did she want us to leave?
I think she's
delivering an ultimatum.
♪ The last time... ♪
Are you sure about this?
Seems there's always something
else that I have to give up.
But this isn't like
sugar or cigarettes.
You won't get
over this in a hurry.
No... not in a thousand years.
♪ And the way we
talked last night... ♪
Are you gonna be okay?
I'm fine. Alan's at work, but
there should be a taxi waiting.
I won't say goodbye, Dr. Brown,
'cause I'll probably be
seeing you again pretty soon.
I sent your cab away.
I'm sorry I wasn't here sooner.
I had to present a
proposal to my partners...
♪ Just give me a
little more time ♪
♪ Give me a little
bit of warning... ♪
I'm selling them my
share of the business.
Is there something
else you wanna do?
Yes.
I wanna be your husband.
♪ Don't be cruel... ♪
I realized I was so afraid
of losing you in the future...
I was losing you now.
♪ Give me one more
second To dry my eyes ♪
♪ Give me one
more day to realize ♪
♪ Smoke's in our eyes
Or in the distance ♪
♪ Either way, we're
gonna miss it ♪
♪ Give me one more
year To get back on track ♪
life To win you back ♪
♪ Smoke's in our eyes
Or in the distance ♪
♪ Either way, we're
gonna miss it... ♪
Sorry. I hear your VC contact
decided to quit the business.
He did the right thing.
You know...
my feet are killing me.
♪ If it ain't me, come on ♪
♪ Just give me a
little more time ♪
♪ Give me a little
bit of warning ♪
♪ Baby, I'm gonna be fine ♪
♪ When I figure out where ♪
♪ Give me one more
second To dry my eyes ♪
♪ Give me one
more day to realize ♪
♪ Smoke's in our eyes... ♪
I'm open to being friends.
That's great. I'm open
too, to wherever this goes.
It's going to friendship.
Understood. But
life is about change,
which means one day you
might change your mind,
and if you did, I'd
be open to that too.
It's not gonna happen.
Okay.
♪ When it's gone ♪
First, there should
be no soap involved.
Also, we need to stay
at one end of the shower
so we don't accidentally knock
into the temperature control.
What changed your mind?
I've been thinking
about change over time.
I spoke with people and also
graphed several possibilities for us,
using time as the horizontal
axis and change as the vertical.
I realized that the
problem isn't really change,
it's whether two people
change in the same direction.
We want to keep our
coordinates close to each other
for the rest of our lives.
We certainly do. But people
do sometimes drift apart.
Yes. You need a warning
when you and your partner
might be starting to veer off
so you can both
change course a little.
You don't want a surprise
realization when it's too late.
Surprises are awful.
The U.S. Army Signal Corps
used flags to warn of hurricanes,
I brought us this.
A cowbell?
If you see us heading
in different directions,
you ring it.
Do we really need a
bell? Can't I just tell you?
I mean...
Oh! When you ring it, I'll pay
attention. I really hate the sound.
Only in emergencies.
I've already moved
the shampoo bottles.
What?
Oh, you mean now?
♪ Smoke's in our eyes
Or in the distance... ♪
Don't worry about putting
the bottles back, I'll do it later.
I love you.
It's no trouble, I remember
where they all go.
♪ Either way, we're
gonna miss it ♪
♪ Give me one more
second To dry my eyes ♪
♪ Give me one
more day to realize ♪
♪ Smoke's in our eyes
Or in the distance ♪
♪ Either way, we're
gonna miss it ♪
♪ Give me one more
year To get back on track ♪
life To win you back ♪
♪ Smoke's in our eyes
Or in the distance ♪
♪ Either way, we're
gonna miss it ♪
♪ When it's gone ♪