- Sign in.
- Actually...
- Where are our T-sheets?
- I'm a new med student.
Congratulations.
You said that yesterday.
- Check in with the docs.
- Okay, thanks.
- Do you guys have a lost-and-found box?
- Somebody stole it.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Are you Dr. Carter?
Lewis. I don't think he's in yet. And
I'm not old enough to be a ma'am.
- I'm supposed to meet him around 8.
- You're a tad early.
Yeah, it's my first day. I
guess I was a little excited.
You'll get over it.
So Mr. Hopper, what
seems to be the problem?
I can't eat. I can't sleep. I
just don't feel like myself.
- How long has this been going on?
- A few weeks.
Any stress? Family? Work?
All my problems started when I
met this girl at an after-hours bar.
- She bit me.
- She bit you where?
In the alley outside the club...
- No, where on your body?
- My neck.
I'm pretty sure
she was a vampire.
That's a hickey.
- Is that a zygoma fracture?
- Maybe.
- Are you Dr. Carter?
- Nope, Greene.
I'm Michael Gallant. I'm
supposed to be meeting Dr. Carter.
You found the ER.
That's half the battle.
- You called for surgical consult!
- I changed my mind.
- After I got down here.
- He has rectal pain. Probably prostatitis.
That's why I need
to examine him.
If it is an appy, he's probably
going to need surgery.
Need a second opinion? - Nope.
Yes! He has a 22-year-old
male with right-sided tenderness.
Who also says it
burns when he pees.
What's his urine and white count?
- Still waiting.
Usually you won't even
come till labs are back.
Fine. When it bursts,
you can operate.
- Hey, Dr. Carter?
- Kovac.
- Dr. Kovac. GREENE:
Hold on. Elizabeth!
- What's going on?
- Isn't it obvious?
- No.
- He calls for a surgical consult...
then changes his mind
the moment he sees it's me!
That's a bit egocentric,
don't you think?
- They're afraid to have me treat patients.
- You're being paranoid.
Am I?
Excuse me. Excuse me. Do
you know where Dr. Carter is?
He should be here
in a few minutes.
If you say where he
is, I could find him.
I don't know. Sorry.
How come there aren't any doughnuts?
- No petty cash.
There was 50 bucks
in there yesterday.
I need a psych consult. My
patient thinks he's a vampire.
Count Fred? Where is he?
- Exam 2.
- Is there a nurse in with him?
- No, why?
- He's a vampire.
- What do you mean?
- I mean, he drinks people's blood.
You're kidding, right?
That's nasty.
But I volunteered to drive to the
Royal Botanical Gardens fundraiser.
I'm sorry, but there's just
not much I can do about it.
You can stop lying to me.
- Good morning.
- Dr. Carter.
- Did I miss something?
- Yes, breakfast.
Your grandmother's upset
because the Jaguar's being serviced.
For a week!
- What's wrong with it?
- Yes, Alger. What's wrong with it?
- They're waiting for a part.
- What part?
- The ignition coil.
- Liar. He's holding me hostage.
- What's the matter with the Town Car?
- I don't drive the Town Car.
You shouldn't be driving
anyway. That's why we have Alger.
Having a driver was
your grandfather's idea.
Now that he's gone, it seems
an unnecessary expense.
- He's just trying to look out for you.
- I'm a big girl. I don't need a chaperone.
Oh, John, are you still
planning to come with me to...?
Gamma! Gamma?
- Nurses do most of the triaging, right?
- Right.
So maybe you could
sneak me some minor cases.
Maybe you could sit down...
read your orientation
kit, and wait for Dr. Carter.
- What's going on?
- Teaching Nicole to take blood pressure.
- Why?
- It's part of her training.
- What training?
- I'm learning to be a nurse's aide.
Really? KOVAC: Abby?
No helmet. Alert at
the scene. GCS-14.
- Any blood loss or seizure?
- No.
Okay, let's get him in
Trauma 1. Nicole, come on.
- Me?
- Yeah, it'll be good for you to watch.
Must've taken a header
off the skateboard.
Bad scalp lac, hematoma,
right peritemporal.
Abby, show Nicole
how to take a pulse ox.
Uh, put some gloves on.
- Can I watch?
- Why don't we sell tickets?
- You a med student?
- Michael Gallant.
- Dr. Finch.
- Nice to meet you.
- Road rash all the way down the chest.
- Big abdominal bruise.
- Unh!
- BP's 90 over 60. Pulse, 115.
Full trauma panel, lateral
C-spine, chest and pelvis.
Jeremy, do you
remember what happened?
Right pupil is sluggish,
slightly larger than the left.
18 gauge in the right AC.
- What's his pulse ox?
- I can't get it.
Abby?
Make sure the fingernail
has contact with that red light.
No CSF or blood from the ears.
100 of fentanyl and page
Benton and Neurosurg.
Read the number
off of this monitor.
Decreased breath
sounds on the right.
- 78.
- What?
Pulse ox is 78 on 15 liters.
Okay. Good job.
- What do you think?
- Hyper-resonant on the right.
Decreased breath sounds,
low sats, hypotension.
Tension pneumothorax, right?
Yeah.
I had a fainting spell,
John. It happens.
But it shouldn't happen.
In my day, it was quite
acceptable for a lady to swoon.
- There's a med student looking for you.
- I'm a little busy.
- Oh, hello, Mrs. Carter.
- Hello.
Hi, Evan. Your mother's on her way.
She found your inhaler in the laundry.
Gam, will you sit up for me, put
your legs over the end of the bed?
Yes, John.
You're not gonna make
me do pushups, are...?
Gam? Gamma? Gamma?
Susan. Gamma, can you hear me?
John?
Okay. You're okay.
I need to step out for a
minute. I'll be right back.
- Checking orthostatics?
- Yeah.
- Is she anemic?
- I don't know.
I'm sending her
up for a tilt test.
She might be dehydrated,
it's probably nothing.
- Can I intubate?
- Maybe next time.
What am I looking at?
Teenage skateboarder, tension
pneumo on the left, with a head injury.
Needs a central line.
He's anterior. I can
see the cords. I'm in.
Okay, bag him, Nicole.
Come on. One,
two, three, squeeze.
He did this on a skateboard?
Trying a crazy stunt, no doubt.
- Good breath sounds.
Probably has a
depressed skull fracture.
That's what they used to
call a ping-pong fracture?
- Neurosurg is on the way.
- Pressure's dropping.
He's bleeding somewhere.
How much out in the chest tube?
Less than a liter.
First HemoCue is nine.
Let's hang the O-neg. Get
him to O.R. Has he had Dilantin?
Yeah. And 70 grams of mannitol.
What about his head?
- Who are you?
- Michael Gallant. You a trauma surgeon?
- You a med student?
- Yes, sir.
Why don't you find something to do, all
right? Let's get him ready to go. I'm in.
- I'll learn more here.
- You'll learn more with your eyes open...
- and your mouth shut, okay?
- He's got a point.
What about his head?
Won't make a difference if he bleeds
out in his chest first. Okay, let's move.
- You did good.
- Really? I was so scared.
- You get used to it.
- I don't know.
- You saved his life.
- Yeah, I hope so.
Me too. I better go back
to work. I'll see you later.
Okay.
What are you doing?
- What?
This morning she was learning to
take a BP, now she's in a trauma?
- Yeah, she's learning.
- To be an aide, not a nurse.
- I know you don't like her, but...
- That has nothing to do with this.
- It's inappropriate that she be in trauma.
- I just asked you to help her.
That's not my job, Luka.
Do you even realize
what I do in there?
You're not the only one
trying to save that kid's life.
- I'm gonna and scrub in.
- I'll page Neurosurg again.
- Dr. Benton?
- Yeah?
- Yeah, are you Peter Benton?
- Yeah.
Consider yourself
served. Have a nice day.
What was that about? Peter?
- I'm being subpoenaed.
- For what case?
Reece. Roger's
suing for custody.
So how extensive do you
think his brain injury is?
- It's too early to tell.
- How is he?
The skateboarder.
Is he gonna be okay?
- Are you his father?
- No. I'm David Hilliker. I called 911.
Did you see what happened?
Screwing around in the mall with
buddies. Looked like he hit his head.
- Yeah. He wasn't wearing a helmet.
- Wouldn't be cool. Don't need helmets...
to drive a motorcycle in
this state. Why a skateboard?
- You got a little limp.
- Oh, yeah.
I twisted it chasing him
and his buddy out of the mall.
You should let us
look at it. Come on.
Ice pack and a couple
beers, I'll be fine.
Sit down.
- We just need to change the dressing.
- But Dr. Carter usually does that.
I'm aware of that, but
Dr. Carter's not here right now.
- We'll wait.
- I don't know when he'll be in.
- I'm very patient.
- Look, Sister.
Helen.
- The sooner I change the bandage...
- I'm Monica.
The sooner you guys can get out of
here and get back to doing your stuff.
And, quite frankly,
I need the bed.
Perhaps if you told
Dr. Carter we were here?
- Your fans are getting restless.
- What is it with you and nuns, Carter?
It's almost kinky.
Can you take care of them?
- They want you.
My grandmother had a...
She passed out this morning.
Having Cardiology work her up.
- Is she okay?
- I don't know.
- Are you?
- Me? I'm fine.
- Just wanna see she gets settled.
- I'll take care of it.
- Thank you.
- Come on, ladies.
Tequila Willie is still in Exam 1,
covered in puke and assorted body fluids.
- He's making this whole place reek.
- This place always reeks.
- Yeah. And it's Abby's turn.
- Oh, come on.
I did him last time. You're up.
Fine.
- Nicole.
- You need something?
Yeah, grab some gloves. I'm gonna
show you how to bathe a patient.
Oh.
Robert!
I was scrubbing in when I
discovered Dale's doing my Whipple.
He's an ass, but he's
a decent surgeon.
- I was back on service today.
- No, not yet.
Why not? I've complied with
every insulting, demeaning request.
- Even volunteered for a lie detector test.
- We have to wait for the CDC...
to finish with their bug hunt. But the
criminal investigation is essentially over.
- Couldn't find anything.
- What's that mean?
"We think you're killing your
patients, we just can't prove it."
If it makes you feel better,
this has nothing to do with you.
Then why am I not in surgery?
I'm sorry. I know this is frustrating. But
what choice does either one of us have?
Take the opportunity to
catch up with your dictation.
Spend time with your
baby. Enjoy the downtime.
- What are you doing?
- Excuse me?
- That's my patient.
- Drawing blood.
You were injecting
something into her central line.
I couldn't get a
draw. It's clogged.
- What did you inject?
- I didn't.
- Don't lie to me! I saw you!
- Is there a problem here?
- No, I was...
- Yes. She was injecting my patient.
- Urokinase to bust the clot in her line.
- Let me see it.
Where's the vial?
Elizabeth.
Sorry.
Excuse me.
Twenty-six years with the Chicago
P.D. Never fired my gun once.
That's good.
These are different times.
Try and stay off your
ankle and keep it elevated.
- Dr. Kovac, Jeremy's mother's here.
- Okay.
I'll have one of the nurses give
you a lesson on using the crutches.
Mrs. Norris?
Hi. I'm Dr. Kovac. I was the
first doctor to treat your son.
- How is he?
- He suffered a hemothorax.
That's when blood collects in the
chest cavity and collapses a lung.
- But it's been repaired.
- Can I see him?
- He's been taken up to the O.R.
- But he's gonna be okay.
There was evidence
of a head injury.
Is he in a coma?
I'm afraid we won't know until he's out
of surgery and the anesthesia wears off.
There's the idiot who was
chasing him, right there.
- Are you the boy's mother?
- What did you do?
- Nothing. I'm sorry...
- He threw his stick at him.
- What?
- You should get back in bed.
No, he's the one who
made Jeremy wipe out.
Your boy was riding in the
mall. I asked him to leave.
- You knocked him off his skateboard!
- I didn't!
You attacked my son? - No!
- You did! KOVAC: Can
you put him in the room?
- What'd you do?
- Nothing!
- I called the ambulance!
- Where is it?
Last door on the right.
- He hurt my son?
- I don't know, ma'am.
He's the reason Jeremy's here.
He should be arrested or something!
I just wanna see Jeremy. I
just wanna be with my son.
I'll get an update and find out
when you can go to see him, okay?
- I think he's having a heart attack!
- Good!
He started hyperventilating
and complaining of chest pain.
- What's going on, Mr. Hilliker?
- I don't feel so good.
- Chest hurts?
- Yeah. Head is spinning.
Okay, put him on oxygen,
aspirin and let's get an EKG.
I didn't mean to upset the mother. I
was just trying to offer my condolences.
Just relax.
He rode by me. He stole my hat.
He was tossing it back and forth,
threatening to throw it in the fountain.
- They were terrorizing the mall.
- Did you throw your nightstick at him?
Okay. Okay. Just relax.
- Dr. Zogoiby.
- Dr. Corday.
I've been reviewing charts...
and I have a question about a
patient you worked on with me.
- Yes?
- It was a few weeks ago. A Mrs. Taylor?
I'm having a little difficulty
reading your notes.
- You put in a central line.
- No, I was called away.
That was the day my son fell
off the monkey bars at school.
The on-call anesthesiologist
stepped in for me.
- And who was that?
- Babcock.
Babcock.
Hope this wasn't a waste of
time. Think this kid'll ever wake up?
I don't know.
You're scaring me. You're
not your usual jolly self today.
Haven't developed a drug addiction
or drinking problem like your buddies...
- in the ER, have you?
- No.
Give it time.
Jeremy's mother is in the waiting room.
- Great.
Jacy, have you tracked
down my sister yet?
- I left another message.
- All right. Thanks.
- You want me to talk to her?
- No.
Good.
Mrs. Norris.
Hi. I'm Dr. Benton. I'm one of
the surgeons that was with Jeremy.
- How is he?
- We tied off the bleeding vessels...
in the chest, but there's swelling in
the brain. He's with a neuro team now.
With an injury like
this, it becomes a...
- A waiting game.
- Waiting? To see if he wakes up?
Waiting to see if he's
a vegetable? What?
All of that.
They've got to be
able to do something.
He's all I've got.
Yeah.
- Ever gotten an erythropoietic porphyria?
- No.
- What about porphyria cutanea tarda?
The most unusual medical
case you've ever seen?
I had a guy with a live
bullfrog in his ass once.
Ever seen a patient scratch
through the skin into the bone?
- Are you serious?
- Figure he'll hit gray matter by spring.
Mr. Eldon, could you show a
young med student your itch?
Ooh.
- Save me.
- What?
I have a med student
who is in need of a home.
- Oh. No, thanks. But he seems nice.
- Oh, yeah. Of course he does.
That's how they all start, till they grow
up to become Residents like Carter.
I wish.
- What?
- "I wish"?
He turned into a good doctor.
- Uh-huh.
- He is.
- You and Carter...?
Dr. Greene, can I ask you
something? I'm sorry, am I interrupting?
Not at all.
You don't mind me asking
all these questions, do you?
No, of course not. This is a teaching
hospital. This is how you learn.
Bye.
Oh, hi. I was just talking about you.
How's your grandmother? What is it?
- Looks like Shy-Drager.
- I'm sorry.
They've been having a lot of success
with fludrocortisone and desmopressin.
- How'd she take it?
- I haven't told her yet.
They're still
running some tests.
- Anything I can do?
- I don't think so.
- Let me know.
- I will.
Carter! Dr. John Carter, this is
your new med student, Michael...
Gallant. CARTER: Hi.
Go get the orientation package,
when you're finished just come find me.
I did that while I was
waiting. I try to keep busy.
- Yeah. I had a family emergency.
- Nothing serious, I hope.
You wanna talk about it?
Okay. Well, I watched a trauma already
and helped Dr. Kovac with a possible MI.
Both of which were
very interesting.
But I was hoping that once you
got here I could start working up...
some of my own cases.
- He stepped into the men's room.
- Oh.
His grandmother's sick.
Do you want to see if we can
go find you a case to work up?
Yeah.
Kit.
I want to apologize for my behavior
earlier. It was completely unprofessional.
I know it's not an excuse, but I
have been under a lot of stress lately.
I understand.
That said, I also have a couple of
questions about some recent cases.
- Do you remember a Mr. Durning?
- Diverticulitis?
No, he was an elderly gentleman, came
in for a hemicolectomy for colon cancer.
- With all the faded Navy tattoos.
- Yes, yes.
You took out his central
line on October the 16th.
Yes. Well, no. It came out on the
16th. But we didn't do it. Babcock did.
Babcock?
- Why Babcock?
- I don't know. He just did.
Sometimes he likes to pull his own lines.
In fact, occasionally he insists on it.
So Mrs. Reynolds, how
long have you had the spots?
- About a week.
- I gave her some penicillin.
- Oh, for what?
- I got a cold.
Cough, sore throat, headaches.
Hmm. Yeah,
antibiotics won't help.
- I told you.
- Where'd you get the penicillin?
The medicine cabinet. Left
over from an ear infection.
Oh, yeah, you should
never share prescriptions.
If you're given one,
try to use all of it.
What's wrong?
She's experiencing hypersensitivity
vasculitis. It's from the antibiotics.
Thank you, Dr. Kevorkian.
- Is it treatable?
- Absolutely.
We'll get some medicine for you
and have you feeling as good as new.
- You might wanna get a CBC.
- I beg your pardon?
Her history. It could be indicative
of undiagnosed thrombocytopenia.
- You know, low platelets.
- And you are...?
Grace. I'm a
second-year med student.
Ask if she has any unusual
bleeding when she brushes her teeth.
- Are you a med student at this hospital?
- No.
I'd appreciate it if you kept
your comments to yourself.
Hello.
- Is he your student?
- Excuse me?
She's a second-year med student
who thinks she can diagnose my patients.
He takes a lousy history.
I will bet your lunch money
she's got thrombocytopenia.
She's right. Low platelets.
Needs additional labs,
head CT and admission.
I'll take care of it.
You're welcome.
So do you do self-diagnosis too?
As a matter of fact, I do. I've
let myself get a little rundown...
and I can feel the flu coming
on. I can't afford to be sick now.
I was hoping you'd get me
a little Relenza or Tamiflu.
We can manage that.
What school are you in?
Western and Binville. I'm getting
my law degree simultaneously.
- Really?
- Mm-hm.
My parents didn't want
me to go to med school.
I know that feeling.
Excuse me. Can you get a head
CT for Mrs. Reynolds in Curtain 2?
I'm not a nurse. I'm
just training. I'm sorry.
That's okay. I'm sort
of in training myself.
- I'm a new med student, Michael.
- Nicole.
- How are you doing?
- Oh, okay.
- Everybody helping you?
- Abby showed me how to bathe...
- a homeless man. It was a little...
- She's busy. Stick with Malik and Haleh.
- Is this Mr. Hilliker's 12-lead?
- Yeah.
- Did he have an MI?
- No.
Probably an anxiety attack.
Want to give him the news?
- Can I?
- Yeah. I've got a trauma coming in.
We're gonna need some IV
saline. It's in the suture room.
Okay.
- It can get a little crazy here.
- Yeah, I know. It's only my first day.
- Are you liking it?
- So far, so good.
Oh.
- Oh, my God.
- Go! Go and get somebody!
Take a breath, Mr. Hilliker.
Somebody help me!
Hang on. Hang on.
Hey, Gam. Sorry
this is taking so long.
- Did you get some lunch?
- No. I didn't get anything.
That cardiologist has
never been back to see me.
Yeah. It's because I
asked to speak to you first.
Why?
It's the least I can do, since
you've been stuck here all day.
John, don't beat
around the bush.
You have what's called
Shy-Drager Syndrome.
It's a progressive disease that
affects your blood pressure...
and could put you at a greater
risk for a heart attack or stroke.
Is it gonna kill me?
Most people die within 10 years.
Ten years? I'm not even sure I
want to be around 10 more years.
Ten days, now, that might
have put a kink in my plans.
- Gam...
- Can I go home?
- I think they want you to stay overnight.
- John, I want to go home.
- You on a break?
- No.
- Can I get you a coffee?
- No, thanks.
Do you want to talk?
Is he going to die?
The guy that hung himself? No.
Well, not today. He's lucky you
and that med student walked in.
Try not to let it
upset you too much.
Once in a while some freak
tries to off himself in the hospital.
I wish they would
just do it at home.
My father hung
himself. I was only eight.
He'd lost another job. I
found him in the kitchen.
I was too little to do anything.
- Oh, God. I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
- Does Luka know this?
- No. I never told him.
I never told anyone. I
don't think I can do this.
- Well, it's not always this bad.
- Look at me. I'm crying like a baby.
We've all cried. Sometimes
it's the only thing you can do.
I went through my charts. I
found another commonality...
- to all my post-op infection mortalities.
- What am I looking for?
- I highlighted his name.
- Babcock?
Yeah. He was in every
case. I only missed it before...
because he stepped in for Dr. Zogoiby,
whose handwriting is illegible.
Dr. Babcock is gonna have a date with
your friend from the health department.
- Phone call, Dr. Greene.
- Take a message.
He knew I was being investigated. Why
didn't he step forward, say something?
Maybe he didn't want to be probed
or forced to give stool samples.
I'm being serious. Who knows
what he's working with in his lab.
I'm sorry. That's Rachel's school.
They need you to pick her up.
- Is she all right?
- She got suspended.
- For what?
- I don't know. That's not my business.
- Suspended?
- It must be some kind of mistake.
- Probably drug-related.
- You better go. I'll deal with this.
- How's he doing?
- Pulse ox is 98 on 50 percent.
Good. Mr. Hilliker, we had to put a
tube down your throat to help you breathe.
I'm gonna take it out now, okay?
I want you to take
some deep breaths.
When I say blow, I want you to blow
as hard as you can. Ready? Okay, blow.
I'm sorry.
Try not to speak, Mr. Hilliker.
Take some deep breaths.
- Tell him.
- Okay, Mr. Hilliker. Just relax.
Just relax.
He doesn't want us to tell the police.
He's still got buddies on the force.
I'm afraid we have to.
It's gonna be okay,
Mr. Hilliker. It's gonna be okay.
His wife died last year. - What?
Breast cancer.
He was a respected and
decorated police officer.
Only reason he took the job at the mall
was so that he could still help people.
- Why are you telling me this?
- I just thought you should know.
Keep an eye on his vitals
and call for a psych consult.
- 100.8.
- Feels like 108.
BP is 140 over 80. And your white
count is 14,000. You're a little anemic.
40 percent of menstruating
women are anemic.
My diagnosis is you're a little
rundown. Maybe it's time to pick a career.
Medicine beats law any day.
My parents will only pay for med
school if I graduate law school.
If your parents are both attorneys,
why don't you have any health insurance?
I have a sad and complicated relationship
with them that you couldn't understand.
I might surprise you.
You need to take better
care of yourself, Grace.
You need to eat right, get plenty
of sleep and lay off the caffeine...
I would if I could. I haven't
had eight hours' sleep in months.
Do you think you could
get me some Halcion?
- I don't think so.
- Just one dose. I mean...
Today is shot for me. If I could
just go home and crash. Please?
I diagnosed your
student's patient.
This is a one-time
special treatment...
and only if you promise to do
the other things we talked about.
Cross my heart.
What are the EKG
findings for hyperkalemia?
Peaked T waves, prolonged
PR and short QT intervals.
- You're good.
- Mm-hm.
- Hey. Your day getting any better?
- Not yet.
- You talk to your grandmother?
- Mm-hm.
How did she take it?
It didn't bother her.
She went home.
- You let her drive?
- No. Her driver picked her up.
- You have to notify the DMV.
- I didn't tell her that.
Dying's one thing. Not
driving is another story.
- You have to mail in the notice.
- I didn't see her as an ER patient.
- I brought her in.
- It's the law.
- I can't rat out my own grandmother.
- You want me to? She doesn't like me.
Carter! Your patient went down.
- What happened?
- She must have vagalled.
All right. Let's get the gurney.
Whoa...
All right, come on.
- I need to talk.
- Somebody took target practice...
on a crossing guard.
I gotta plug her up.
- It's rather important. ROMANO:
Well, give me the Cliff Notes.
I'm listening.
- I'd prefer to have your full attention.
- Suit yourself.
Are you joining us, Elizabeth?
No. I'm afraid not.
If you could have your assistant
page me when you're done, please?
- Hey. Thanks for coming.
- Want something to eat?
No, no. So, what did he say?
Well, I talked to Mitch and Sophie,
my friend that works in the courthouse.
- And?
- They said the worst thing to do is fight.
- I can fight it if I want to?
- It looks like you got something to hide.
What if I'm just offended
by the whole principle?
Peter, you go in.
You get swabbed.
They run the DNA. And you can prove
once and for all that Reece is your son.
- What if he's not, Jackie?
- Is that really a possibility?
Ooh.
- What are you doing?
- You're out of surgery.
The patient coded before we even got
started. What are you doing down here?
I wanted to ask you
about a couple of cases.
Uh...
You know, it doesn't matter anyway.
It'll have to wait. I've just been paged.
Elizabeth.
Aren't you forgetting something?
I believe those are mine.
Thank you.
I must be dehydrated. All I've had is
coffee and a muffin since last night.
You want to tell
us about the scars?
I used to be a cutter.
My parents fought a lot when I
was a kid, and I was a geek in school.
I developed an eating disorder. It
was my way of dealing with stress.
Did you ever see
anybody about it?
The only people who seemed to
care were the doctors and nurses.
- Probably why I'm in med school.
- What about now? Are you still cutting?
No.
- Show me your arm.
- You don't believe me?
You have a fever and
a borderline white count.
Maybe from an infection,
or using a dirty blade.
- I told you I haven't eaten.
- So the eating disorder continues?
- No. I've just been cramming.
- Pull up your skirt.
- Pardon me?
- Let me see your thigh.
I don't think so.
- You ass!
- You're still cutting.
- We just want to help you.
- Okay, hold on. Grace.
- I have a pathology final.
- If you don't stay...
- I'll put you on psych hold.
- On what grounds?
- Danger to self.
- That's not true.
- Grace, Grace. Wait.
- Stop!
You're blowing this
way out of proportion!
- Why are you doing this?
- I know what it's like to need help...
- when you least want it.
- Please.
- Please just leave me alone.
- I can't.
What are you staring at? You couldn't
even diagnose thrombocytopenia.
- Get five of droperidol.
- No! No, stop! Stop! I don't need that!
- Okay. Get back into bed now.
- Don't touch me! Don't touch me!
Please. Please. Please.
- Take it easy. It's okay.
- You'll ruin everything.
Please, you'll ruin everything.
No, please, stop. Don't. No, don't...
Don't, please. Can't you just...?
- I had to get a doctor to cover for me.
- I'm sorry.
- Scissors, Rachel?
- It's not like they said.
Did you threaten this girl?
It was Natalie. I threatened to
cut her dreadlocks, not stab her.
Why?
She tried to steal Andrew away from
me. She keeps on sending notes in class...
- and asking him over to study.
- This is over a boy.
- It's no big deal, Dad.
- Then why aren't you in gym class now?
Maybe because they stopped
teaching gym in the '70s.
Don't get smart.
This is serious.
You've been suspended. Next
time you will be expelled permanently.
- There won't be a next time.
- Right. Because now we have new rules.
- Like what?
- No more rides to school...
unless it's with Elizabeth or me.
No more going out on weeknights...
or weekends for that
matter, for at least a month.
Why don't you send
me to a convent?
I would. But I need you around
the house to do all your chores.
- I have chores now?
- Yep. Think of yourself as Cinderella...
- and I'm your evil stepmother.
- I've already got one of those.
Keep it up. You'll find
yourself back in St. Louis.
- Why are you doing this to me?
- Don't know. Maybe because I love you?
- Oh, really?
- Yes, really.
Do you know how many
messed-up teenagers I see?
Drug addicts, suicides, 10-year-old
homeless girls who've been raped...
because nobody gave a damn about
them? Well, I give a damn about you.
You may not like it now.
Hell, you may never like it.
This is how it's gonna be.
Get in.
- Need any help?
- Hey. Did you page me?
No, but I figured I might find you
in here. Hi, Reece. How are you?
Good.
Did you talk to Jackie?
Yeah. She thinks I
should take the test.
So, what happens if
you're not a genetic match?
Well, I guess it makes it easier
for Roger to fight me for custody.
Nothing's changed, Peter.
You're still his father.
So what are you
two doing for dinner?
Why don't you come to my place?
I have those fish sticks
in the freezer Reece likes.
Hey, hey! Take it easy.
- Someone's getting a little frustrated.
- He's tired. He wants to go home.
Daddy can't take you
home. I have to work.
What's he saying?
He wants his other daddy
to come take him home.
Gamma, because you cannot
drive. Because you could black out.
No, I'm... Hey, I'm sorry.
No, I'm not. No, I am not.
- She won't stop driving?
- She's calling from the car.
She's been driving around for
two hours just to prove me wrong.
It's not funny. She could
hurt herself or somebody else.
- What are you gonna do?
- What am I gonna do?
What am I gonna do? Call
the cops on my grandmother?
- You already made me call the DMV.
- Me? Don't make me the bad guy.
- I should go home, wait for her.
- I can wait with you.
- Yeah?
- I mean, yeah, if you want.
Enter!
Ah, I was just about to
page you. Have a seat.
So, Elizabeth.
Dr. Babcock says that you
were trespassing in his office...
and his research
area. Care to elaborate?
- I wanted to talk to him.
- You knew I was in surgery.
He's worked on every one of my cases
that died from a post-operative infection.
- Is this true?
- Yes. It's true.
- And I have evidence to prove it.
- So what?
You have made it clear on
more than one occasion...
- you are not opposed to euthanasia.
- I can't imagine a humane doctor who is.
- I have four bodies in the morgue!
- That's not my fault.
You need to take responsibility
for your gross misjudgment!
- Time out! BABCOCK:
This is a load of crap.
You allow her to operate on elderly
lost souls who should never be in surgery.
And then when they die,
which they inevitably will...
she comes looking
for someone to blame!
They didn't die from surgery.
They died from post-op infection.
- The key word there being
"post-op." ROMANO: Okay.
- If you hadn't operated, they'd be alive.
- Okay! Enough!
This whole thing has
gotten out of hand.
The health department has
yet to conclude its investigation.
Until they do, neither one
of you is in the O.R. Happy?
- No.
- That's not a solution.
It works for me.
- I'm not doing another case with her.
- You certainly aren't.
Get out, both of you. You're
giving me a headache. Go.
God is love.
You can go home,
Gallant. Carter signed out.
Oh, yeah, I know. I think
I'm gonna stay and study.
- Here?
- Maybe I'll pick up stuff by osmosis.
You'll pick up something.
Hi. Feeling better?
What do you want?
I heard you talking about
your pathology exam.
I thought you might like
to take a look at Robbins.
Thanks.
I'm sorry about some
of the crap I said to you.
- I think I was just a little stressed.
- I know what that's like.
So you obviously
know your vasculitidies.
How are you with your
glycogen-storage diseases?
- Not so good.
- Yeah. Me neither.
Mr. Benton? I am Asha.
You're here for a DNA test?
Yeah.
Okay. Don't
worry, it's painless.
I'm just gonna use this swab to
wipe the inside of your cheek. Okay?
Yeah. ASHA: Say "ah."
Ah.
Okay, all done.
That wasn't so bad, now, was it?
- I can't believe it.
- I didn't believe it either.
Fentanyl.
If you're gonna abuse
drugs, abuse a good one.
- Wow.
- I've been clean and sober for a year.
You got it out of your system.
I wouldn't say that.
What?
Nothing.
- Disappointed in me?
- No! No. I'm just...
You were stabbed.
Twice. I don't recommend it.
- Can I see your scar?
- What?
- Show me your scar.
- No.
- Why not?
- Why?
- Don't be bashful.
- Get your own.
Why do I feel like a
school kid sitting out here?
Must be the adolescent
sexual tension.
Mm.
That's it.
You know, I used to
have a crush on you.
- Used to?
- It's all coming back to me now.
- I used to have a crush on you too.
- Liar.
I did! You were cute.
- Real cute. But...
- But?
Well, you were a med
student, I was a Resident...
I'm a Resident now.
- Chief Resident.
- That's right.
Glad you came back.
Me too.
Gamma's home.