♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
♪♪♪
Are you gonna be home
late tonight?
Uh, well, I have
a baby to deliver.
But mom
will tuck you in, okay?
She does it wrong.
I want you.
Okay, I tell you what,
you get into bed,
and when I get home,
I'll tuck you in. I promise.
Love you.
♪♪♪
You came.
I was summoned.
"Future hunters,"
14 down--
no.
Now, Addison--
if you want to
tell me something,
tell me why she's coming.
You can ask her yourself.
Where are you going?
Just wanted to make sure
you showed up.
Now that you're here...
W--captain,
you can't just...
Bizzy's here.
What is going on?
Ask your mother.
You cut your hair.
Yes. Uh, I wanted, uh,
something different.
Hmm.
So, um...
The captain was here,
but he left us
to chat, bizzy.
It was a dreadful flight--
dreadful staff,
dreadful food.
I'm gonna make a complaint
to Wilson.
Right.
I cannot believe
you moved to this place,
but here I am,
yes, about that.
I was surprised that you
actually came to visit. Uh--
Addison, don't push.
You know, short hair
isn't for everyone.
Some people look older
with it.
And the geraniums bloomed.
They're absolutely gorgeous.
I think we'll win first place
this year at new haven.
The silvermans' tulips
were...
You could cut
the tension with a knife,
but they're smiling,
they're drinking,
they're chatting
about flowers.
Hmm. Trust me, they are not
chatting about flowers.
They are speaking wasp.
We learn it
at an early age.
What are they saying?
See? Now that's the thing.
Usually I know,
but this time,
I have no idea.
Maybe I'm crazy. I mean,
maybe everything is fine,
which would be creepy
because nothing is ever fine.
Oh, here she comes.
Ah, Mrs. Montgomery.
Now, Samuel, how many times
have I told you
to call me bizzy?
Yes, Mrs. Montgom--
bizzy. Ma'am.
What is that?
Milo. I've decided to
give up men and get a cat.
Don't say that.
That's so sad.
People will believe you.
And you'll have to
lock it up or something.
Well, if your father and I
are gonna be staying here...
Stay here?
Let me just
get that for you.
So, bizzy, uh, what brings
you here to L.A.?
Excuse me.
Huh.
Yes.
Sam?
It's Dell.
Dell,
what happened?
I-I don't know. The house,
it just exploded.
It had to have been a gas leak.
I don't know.
It's okay.
24-year-old female,
extensive second-
and third-degree burns,
possible inhalation injury.
B.p.'s 100 over 60.
Pulse 130.
- Let's go.
On my count. Ready?
One, two, three.
I need high-flow 0-2.
I'm gonna need a blood gas
and a carboxyhemoglobin.
We're on it, Cooper.
I-I tried to get 'em
both out, but--but the flames--
I could hear Heather screaming,
but I couldn't see anything,
so I got Betsey. By the time
I got to Heather, she...
I-I could--i-i couldn't
get them both.
Dell, you did
all the right things.
Let's get a liter
of lactated ringers.
Hey, do you mind? You're
interfering with our protocol.
Okay, guys.
You have to let my team work.
- They do this every day.
- It's not Dell every day.
I know that.
Now step back, both of you.
I-I need to be
with both of them.
What do i--
Pete, go with Heather.
You go with your daughter.
Okay, let's move.
I'll get you an update as soon
as I can, Dell. Let's go.
Please don't let her die.
Get out of the way now.
Let's go,
let's go, let's go!
Okay, Heather.
No! Betsey!
Heather, you're--
where's Betsey?!
You need to keep
the mask on.
No!
Heather, you need
to keep the mask on.
Where's Betsey?!
Betsey is alive.
She's unconscious.
Aah!
She's in the E.R.
Cooper is working on her.
Dell is with her. Now you need
to keep the mask on.
She's got second-
and third-degree burns
over 60% of her body.
Her lungs have sustained
severe inhalation injuries.
We should have
an ecmo unit standing by.
I've already ordered it.
Let's give her morphine.
Do you know her well?
I used to work
with her husband.
What's the prognosis?
In my experience,
30% chance of survival.
Dell, I'm so sorry.
Is there anything--
anything we can do?
I--I'm supposed to deliver
the Higgins baby.
They're gonna
be waiting for me.
I-I already
took care of it.
The on-call doctor
is gonna deliver. It's fine.
Okay.
Did I give my insurance card?
They're gonna--
they're gonna need it.
Dell, I'll--I'll make sure they
have all the information, okay?
Hey.
Hey, Dell, I took a look
at Betsey's C.T. scan.
She has a moderate
brain contusion
and she also has
carbon monoxide poisoning.
Now most people
wake up in a few hours,
but because she's so small,
it's gonna take a little longer.
Heather--how is she?
I don't have an update
on Heather from Pete yet.
But they know
what caused the explosion.
Okay.
Maybe we should go outside.
Just say it.
Um...
Heather was cooking meth.
They think it was ether.
Dell, we've got Heather
stabilized.
She's asking for you. I know
you don't want to leave Betsey,
but it...
Heather.
Don't try to speak.
Can you hear me?
Can you understand me?
Good.
I hope you die, bitch.
You almost killed
my daughter.
I hope you die
a miserable...
Painful, agonizing death.
You're almost there,
Heather. Almost there.
After this, we're gonna
test your lung function.
Help us decide
our next move, okay?
He hates me. He wants me to die.
Just let me die.
Heather, listen to me.
You can't give up.
Dell doesn't want you to die.
He's upset
and he's worried about Betsey.
But you gotta fight, okay?
You gotta fight.
Give me more drugs. Please.
Just make it stop!
Okay, Heather.
Oh!
- He said that?
- He's upset.
It's his way of dealing
with a tragic situation.
To tell somebody
who's fighting for their life
you want them to die?
I don't care what she did.
That's crossing a line.
He couldn't have meant it.
Do you guys think he knew that
Heather was doing drugs again?
I got you all coffee.
I'm gonna go check
on Heather.
I didn't know about the drugs.
I wouldn't have put Betsey
in danger like that if I knew...
Since you
were all wondering.
Dell, no o--
no one thought--
it's cold in here.
She hates the cold.
You know, she's always asking
for more blankets at night.
She needs another blanket.
Okay, you know what, Dell?
Why don't--we're gonna go
and talk to a nurse
and see if we can
get some more, okay?
God, can you believe
all this?
I know.
I feel terrible.
I-I feel like I really
should've pushed him harder.
I should've made him
really think
about letting Heather
back into their lives.
Nai, there's nothing
you could've done differently,
nothing anyone
could've done differently.
Well, maybe you're right.
I don't know.
Hey, wait. Let--let--let's just
have a 1-minute mental break.
Sure. Maya?
Same--hating me and loving
pink or rink or dink.
Whatever his name is.
Bizzy?
The same--
cocktails, cold smiles--
you know, maternal.
Something's going on, but--
Bizzy.
Yes.
I will pick up some more
on the way home.
Bye.
Crisis?
More gin.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Me, too.
Addie.
Susan? What...
Oh, what are you doing here?
Hi.
Oh, my god. You look great.
You look...
How long has it been?
You look exactly the same.
Oh, about eight years,
and I look a mess.
You have your mother's skin.
Oh.
So how is it?
She's driving me crazy.
Mm.
He is driving me crazy. I don't
know how you work for them.
Remember to breathe
and many cocktails.
What are you doing here?
You know bizzy's rule--
wherever she goes, I go.
Susan, why is she here?
I have no idea.
She didn't tell you?
You really don't know?
Let's go face the dragon?
Breathe. Many cocktails.
Mm.
Hey.
Look who I found.
Susan.
I brought the documents
for the Houston charity ball.
Hello, captain.
Who wants... a drink?
Excuse me.
You're turning down drinks?
Good night, Addison.
Did something happen
with Dell?
No, no.
Susan--she runs the family
office. Do you remember her?
I like her. I mean, she's close
in age to me, you know,
and she would
do things for me.
She would deal
with my mother for me.
A-A-Anyway, she's been working
for us for 20 years.
She's like one of the family.
She shows up here and...
And what is it?
I think the captain's
sleeping with her.
I think that's why
he sent for bizzy,
because anywhere bizzy goes,
Susan goes, too.
He invited his wife out
so that she would bring
his mistress?
That's my father.
And my mother trusts her.
I mean,
she lives on the estate.
You know,
and now he does this? Ugh.
I mean,
right under bizzy's nose.
And now they're here in
my house. Uh, I need a drink.
No, no, no, you don't.
Oh, I do.
What you need to--you need to
tell those people to leave
instead of putting up
with their lies.
Just kick 'em out
before your liver drowns in gin.
Sam, I can't tell the captain
and bizzy to leave.
They're the captain...
And bizzy.
You are Addison adrianne
Forbes Montgomery.
You have more names
than anybody else I know.
Tell them to leave.
I can do it.
I could...
Tell them to leave.
Tell 'em to leave.
Good girl.
Everything's
gonna be okay.
Don't worry.
I love you.
Susan?
Oh, captain.
Bizzy's right down the hall.
Captain...
Addison?
How'd it go?
What was bizzy's face like...
What happened?
I can't--i-i can't.
I just--i-i...
Do you mind if I spend
the night here?
I-I promise I'll, um, I'll stay
on my side of the bed.
Yeah, sure.
♪♪♪
Morning.
You're short.
I mean,
usually you're in heels,
very high heels.
♪♪♪
I hope you don't take that
as a criticism.
It's a nice change.
♪♪♪
You okay?
14 down.
I'm stumped on 14 down.
I'm sorry.
I was working
a crossword puzzle yesterday,
and I couldn't figure out
14 down--"future hunters."
Future hunters is a clue?
Yes. Do you know the answer?
I don't--
"future hunters." I know
I know the answer to that.
It's just not coming
to me right now.
If I could just figure out
the answer...
And I-I know how I sound.
I know.
I know that if I look at you,
you'll like...
Think I'm some sort
of crazy woman or something.
I--but trust me, you want me
to be thinking about 14 down.
If I don't think about 14 down,
then I'm just gonna have
a nervous breakdown
in this elevator,
- and I can't do that right now.
- I can't.
Why don't I ride up with you
the rest of the way?
♪♪♪
You want to come
to my office?
♪♪♪
Do you believe
that people are owed?
I sometimes believe
that you're owed, you know?
And I think Betsey's owed one.
She's just had
such a tough life--
you know, teenage parents
and a mom on drugs.
And I'll never know
what this has done to her.
But I figured
she's owed, right?
She's had it so bad,
that this can't be her end,
'cause then
what was her life for...
Just suffering?
That would be cruel.
That would be
just beyond cruel.
Mm.
Dell.
Betsey, hey. Betsey.
Uh, get it out, Naomi.
Just get it out.
Okay, okay, okay.
Just relax.
I'm gonna count to three,
and then I want you to blow out.
One, two, three.
It's okay.
There you go. Good girl.
Okay, good job, kiddo.
You're okay.
I'm gonna go get Cooper.
Okay, okay. Hey, hey,
it's okay.
It's gonna be okay.
Where's mommy?
Where's Betsey?
Heather, your potassium
is too high from tissue damage.
It's affecting your
heart rhythm. You need oxygen.
Okay. What do we got?
She's having runs of v-tach.
Lido 75 I.V. Push.
I need that calcium.
V-fib. Charge to 200.
Everybody off.
Clear.
Is she dead?
No.
Heather crashed.
We got her heart started,
but she's dying,
and she knows it.
Dell, I know you're angry,
but Heather is going to die.
You can choose not to see her,
but she wants to see
her daughter.
No.
Dell, it's her mother.
No, a mother is someone
who--who loves her,
who wouldn't have
done this to her,
someone she's supposed
to have good memories about.
She should not have memories
of her mother burnt to a crisp
because she didn't give enough
of a damn about her daughter
or me or anyone else
to stay off drugs.
No, Pete. I'm not gonna let
my daughter's last view
of her mother be this.
Just no.
I hate him so much.
You hate your father for...
For breaking her heart...
For forcing her to do this.
He cheated on her for 40 years.
She had no one.
She had no one to talk to,
no one to comfort her.
Of course she turned to Susan.
Is it possible that this
relationship with Susan
is your mother's choice?
I know what it's like,
okay...
To be rejected,
to have your heart broken,
to... be lonely.
Is that how you feel now?
Okay, we're not talking about
me. We're talking about her.
Actually, we're not talking
about her.
We're talking about your father,
which is interesting.
You had
this traumatic experience
involving your mother--
it wasn't traumatic.
Okay.
You suck as a therapist.
Why am I here?
I don't know why I'm here.
Uh, maybe because
I'm a stranger.
You can talk to me,
tell me... your feelings.
I'm neutral. I'm Switzerland.
I'm just here to listen.
It wasn't traumatic.
Addison,
I'm here to help you...
And to talk
and to let you talk,
but I'm not sure you're focusing
on the right things here.
And I'm sure that I am.
Then why didn't you
get off the elevator
when you saw your mother?
You might be right about
your mother and your father.
And far be it from me
to question
what should make you angry.
But... you haven't talked
to either one of them.
And your point is?
Well, maybe you need
to get off the elevator.
Are you sure it's okay
for her to have ice cream?
Yeah. Wouldn't hurt for you
to get some food, too.
I just want
to start over.
I just want to get as far away
from this day as possible.
Get her home,
not that we have a home.
Come stay with me.
My home is yours.
You know that.
As long as you need.
You guys, good news.
Betsey's neurological exam
is completely normal.
She shows no evidence of
any kind of ongoing problems.
7 year olds
are resilient as hell.
So I would like to keep her
another day to monitor her,
just as a precaution, but she's
officially out of the woods.
That is great,
which means you can eat.
So I'm gonna go
to the cafeteria.
I'm gonna get you some food,
and no arguments.
Okay. Thank you.
You're welcome.
Uh, w-where's my daughter?
She's with Dr. Wilder.
Betsey, I want you
to be prepared.
Your mom is all bandaged up
to keep her wounds clean.
So don't be scared, okay?
You ready?
Betsey.
Dell.
- Unh-unh!
- Betsey?
Daddy!
Betsey.
Bring her back.
Oh, Mrs. Montgomery.
What are you doing here?
I'm waiting for Addison.
Addison is not here
this morning.
She actually, uh, went to--
she's here.
She knows I'm here.
Oh.
Have you talked with her?
Not yet.
Have you?
No, no.
I have not talked with her.
Hey, Sam. I'm--I'm sorry
to interrupt.
I'm gonna go back
to the hospital now.
Violet,
this is Addison's mother--
Mrs. Montgomery.
Hello.
I'm sorry.
I have to go now.
And what do you do here at my
daughter's practice, Violet?
I-i--I'm a psychiatrist.
Interesting.
Yeah.
Have you met my husband--
the captain?
Um... I...
Yeah, uh, once or twice.
Did you meet him once
or did you meet him twice?
Twice.
Yes, I believe twice.
I was hoping
we could do some shopping today
and then have lunch.
What are you doing?
What's going on?
Okay, that was a mistake.
Mother, I'm just...
I'm so sorry
about what happened,
about what he did to you.
Who did what to me?
Look, I know, I know.
We don't talk.
We chat about, uh, flowers
and pretend that
he's not... cheating on you.
But let's not do that anymore.
Let's face it.
I'll face it with you.
You've gotta be lonely
and--and alone and--
Addison,
this is not your concern.
It's not my...
You're my mother.
Exactly.
Let's not discuss
these things.
No, we have to.
You're wrong...
About your father.
I'm wrong. Bizzy, don't...
He drove you
to kiss another woman.
Susan... has been with me
for 20 years.
Yes, I know.
She's worked with us for ages,
which is why it's--
Susan has been with me
for 20 years.
So, uh...
Shopping and then lunch?
Mother...
Sit down.
There was one girl
in boarding school
when I was 14.
And then there was the one
in Switzerland on holiday
when I was 17,
but those don't count.
It was cold,
and we were girls.
But...
Then I met Susan.
And the captain?
What about him?
Does he know?
We don't discuss it,
but, yes, he knows.
I think he's always known.
Did you ever love him?
Oh, my... bizzy,
why did you marry him?
We're from Connecticut.
My father
is a Bradford Forbes.
Okay, so...
Let me get this straight.
You were the cheating whore,
not dad?
I'm gonna go.
If you're gonna talk like that,
I'll go.
You have no idea
how difficult it was.
Oh, come on, bizzy.
How hard could it have been?
I mean,
nothing was expected of you.
All you had to was
order the housekeeper around,
run your charities
and screw your husband
every Wednesday night.
How complicated is that?
You have no idea.
You don't know me.
You don't know anything.
You don't know
one single thing about me.
I could have done things.
I could have... been things.
But I'm a Forbes.
So I got married because that
was what I was supposed to do.
And I chose your father
because he asked
and he was nice
and he seemed like
he wouldn't suffocate me.
And by the time I realized
my mistake, I had children.
So I made a life.
I did what I could
with what I had.
And I may not have been
in love with your father,
but I loved him.
I do love him.
And I loved you
and your brother.
And so instead of doing
what I wanted to,
which was run
or slit my wrists,
I threw birthday parties
and I smiled
and I kept my mouth shut.
And I raised you
and your brother,
and you both
turned out brilliantly.
Susan was for me.
Susan was the one thing
that was for me.
My children
took everything else.
And I'm sorry,
but until you have a child,
you have no idea
what it's like to be a mother.
You have no idea
the sacrifices a woman makes
when she has children.
So don't you dare judge me.
What the hell
were you thinking?
Naomi had to call me
to calm Dell down.
He can decide
whatever he wants for himself,
but that little girl
wants her mother.
That is not yours to say.
You made it worse and--
don't you dare lecture me
about making things worse.
- You don't get to lecture me.
- Dell... stop!
Dell!
You want to hit me? Fine.
Get off!
But there's a woman in there
who you loved,
the mother of your child,
her child,
who desperately
wants to see her.
Yeah, you're pissed.
You have a right to be pissed.
But if you don't make peace
with this, Dell,
if you don't make peace
with it now,
you're never gonna get another
chance, and it will eat at you.
Get off!
Dell, let Betsey see
her mother before she dies.
Stay away from me!
Just stay the hell
away from my family!
You want to tell me
this isn't personal?
You know,
maybe you can condone
keeping a child
away from their mother,
maybe that makes sense to you.
Not to me.
Heather made a mistake,
but if that child
doesn't get to say good-bye,
you tell me what it does
to that kid.
Drink before you speak.
She's very upset.
Is she? I'm sorry.
That's so sad.
Drink some more.
Just give me
one good reason
why my entire childhood
was a lie--one good reason.
We were trying to protect
you and Archer.
Really? Because I'm a cheater,
Archer's a cheater.
We're all
these awesome cheaters.
So, you know, that's a bunch
of crap--protecting us.
I want a good reason.
She's the love of my life.
We've been married
for 40 years--
40 years.
My entire adult life,
she has been at my side.
I love her.
She's my best friend.
She's my... everything.
It's not her fault,
you know? She didn't know.
We didn't know.
And when we did...
She's the love of my life.
It's complicated.
Love is complicated.
Being a lesbian
is not a choice.
She's not going to change
her mind.
Hell, she's practically screwing
Susan right under your nose.
The mouth on you...
You know...
She sleeps with one woman.
I sleep with all the rest.
So what?!
And that's good enough
for you?
My entire life,
I thought she was
this poor, pathetic woman.
I thought it was my job
to cover for you.
And it made me hate you.
I mean,
don't you understand?
I hated the wrong parent.
I--my cheating? I thought
I got it from you.
But now I know that you're
the poor, pathetic one,
because you love her,
and she loves someone else.
But you stay.
This is like some pathetic,
sad, afterschool special,
which is just awful,
because now--
now I hate you both.
Eaglets.
What?
14 down. "Future hunters."
It's eaglets.
♪ And when our mouths
are filled ♪
♪ with uninvited tongues
of others ♪
♪ and the strays are pining ♪
♪ for their unrequited... ♪
Thought I heard you
come in.
Betsey woke up.
Got the call.
That's great news.
Yeah, and then Pete
took Betsey to see her mom,
and Dell punched Pete.
We're one big happy family.
Everything's bad now,
I know...
Stop talking.
But you have to give me
another chance.
I said stop talking!
Just--I'm tired of talking
and I'm tired of thinking.
Could you just stop talking?
♪ Spears and scepters
and squirming sacks ♪
♪ scribes and tangles
between their ears ♪
You gonna tell me
what happened?
♪ ...charcoal smears ♪
Addison.
♪ Oh, dear ♪
Hey.
♪ The thickets
thick with mold ♪
Talk to me.
♪ The bracken and the briar ♪
Tell me--tell me...
♪ Catchweed into the fold ♪
Wait, wait. Wait.
Not like this.
Please.
Addison, no, no.
Sam--
no, no. No.
♪ When our mouths are filled ♪
♪ with uninvited tongues
of others ♪
♪ and the strays are pining ♪
♪ for their unrequited mothers ♪
♪ milk that sours
is promptly spat ♪
♪ the light will fill
our eyes ♪
♪ like cats ♪
I'm sorry.
Shh.
Don't be sorry.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
You people need to leave.
Leave this house.
Leave this city. Go home.
Samuel, you have no right
to interfere in this.
It--it--it's okay.
No, it is not okay.
Addison is over at my house
right now,
and I don't know what happened,
but you people did it.
Sam. I don't think
I've seen you since you--
you were an awkward
med student.
All due respect,
this isn't about you.
No, it's about them.
It's their family.
I'm sure you care about Addison,
but so do I, so do they.
They're not just gonna run out
because Addison is--is upset.
And I will not let...
This destroy them.
Well, she's my family, too.
And I think I know her
better right now.
So I'm not asking. I'm telling
you, you need to leave.
Now if Addison wants to
make things right,
then that's up to her.
But you are not
going to push her.
Sam--
look...
If you care about Addison,
and I believe that you do,
leave.
Come back to bed, Coop.
I gotta get back
to the hospital.
You shouldn't be embarrassed.
Things have been
really stressful lately.
Dell's family--
oh, is it time
for the sexology advice?
"Impotence happens to all men.
It's usually just stress.
Maybe we can cuddle instead."
Cooper...
You neglected to tell me
that you were married before.
That's the problem.
Cooper--
oh, shut up, okay?
Shut up.
I hate you!
She's just upset right now.
Well, I'm upset, too, okay?
She hates me.
I'm--I'm not the one who
almost killed her, you know.
I'm tired, Violet.
I'm exhausted.
I'm just trying
to protect her.
And you are protecting her.
I know that.
You're protecting her from
seeing something horrible.
But maybe you're protecting her
from the wrong things, Dell.
I mean, my life is a mess.
You know that.
And--and you're--
you're probably right.
I don't always make
the best choices.
But, um, you know, I've
always made them with, uh...
With Lucas...
With Lucas in mind,
to protect him.
And, you know, maybe I'm right,
but maybe...
I-I just know that if Heather
could, she would take away
all the hurt that she has
caused you and Betsey,
every last bit of it, Dell.
I found a pipe last night--
last night--
and I confronted her about it.
And she said it wasn't hers,
that she had a friend over.
You know,
and I knew she was lying.
I mean,
I knew she was lying.
But I wanted and I needed
to believe
that she wasn't using again,
that she wouldn't do that
to me or to Betsey,
that she loved us enough
to stay clean.
So I walked out of the house,
and I left my daughter.
I left Betsey.
And she must have been
so scared when it happened.
I did that to her--me.
So I can't let it happen again.
Hey...
Dell
Heather is going to die.
So you might want to allow her
a little bit of mercy.
Just for one moment.
♪ I hear ♪
Dell.
♪ The sound of sleep ♪
♪ I hear the moonlight creep ♪
Dell, you came.
Heather,
Dell is not here.
That's the morphine talking.
I'm sorry for lying to you.
I'm sorry.
♪ And you're dreaming deep ♪
♪ I hear the sound of sleep ♪
I forgive you.
♪ Last night's tea... ♪
I'm sorry for hurting you.
And i'm... sorry
for hurting our little girl.
♪ Hear yesterday's rain... ♪
Tell her...
Tell her that I love her
so much.
Tell her that mommy
made a mistake.
I love her so much.
Will you tell her, Dell?
I'll tell her.
I wanted to be a good mom.
I wanted to.
I forgive you.
It's okay.
I love you
and I forgive you.
And our baby's gonna be okay.
So don't worry.
♪ ...down and head on home ♪
♪ when they let you leave
is when you lose ♪
You just go ahead
and go.
You can go ahead and go.
♪♪♪
Just go.
♪ Now on tiptoes ♪
♪ the gray light creeps ♪
♪ I still hear the sound ♪
Heather.
♪ I hear the sound of sleep ♪
I'm sorry.
♪ I hear the sound of sleep,
the sound of sleep ♪
Addison.
We're leaving, all of us.
Bizzy never meant
to hurt you.
I tried to get her to leave.
I was the selfish one.
I wanted more.
But she wouldn't leave
her children.
That should count
for something.
We're flying out at 11:00.
Heather died.
So I'm going to the hospital.
Wait, Addison.
I'm coming with you.
♪ Hold onto hope, love ♪
Dell, i'm... I'm sorry.
♪ ...high and low for you ♪
I have to...
Go in there
and tell her that Heather's...
♪ Each day gets closer ♪
Betsey's gonna want
to know everything.
She's gonna ask me questions
about everything that happened.
What do I say?
♪ And you ♪
♪ someday soon ♪
You tell her the truth.
♪ I'll find you ♪
As painful and horrible as it
is, you tell her the truth.
♪ ...you, oh ♪
♪ yeah, oh ♪
Hey.
Mommy didn't make it.
Is she...
Yeah.
No!
Come here. Come here.
It's okay.
♪ So hold onto hope, love ♪
♪ I've searched... ♪
I kept something from you
that I shouldn't have.
I lied.
And I lied because I didn't
want you looking at me
the way you're
looking at me now...
The way you're
not looking at me.
I'm sorry.
I'll keep saying it
until it's enough,
until you forgive me.
Okay?
♪ I'll find you ♪
♪ someday soon ♪
Heather's dead.
♪ I'll know you ♪
♪ someday ♪
♪ you, oh ♪
♪ yeah, oh ♪
♪♪♪
♪ Someday soon ♪
♪ I'll find you ♪
♪ someday soon ♪
♪ I'll know... ♪
Did you call Wilson
to complain
about the service
on your flight out?
No.
I'll call. I can call,
make some noise.
They won't want to lose
your business.
That would be nice.
♪ ...high and low for you ♪
Thank you.
♪ For you ♪
♪ each day gets closer ♪
♪ so hold on stronger ♪
♪ to me ♪
♪ and you ♪