Previously on ER:
- How's your dad doing?
- Okay. Got a nurse for him 16 hours a day.
Then from 11 to 7 it's just me.
What happened there,
doctor? That was your patient.
No, it's a trauma. No medical
record number yet. Thanks.
Don't say thank you to the blood
bank and don't let the boys bully you.
- I... I wasn't letting the boys...
- You play with your hair when nervous.
Wanna get some dinner?
Thanks, I have plans
already. Not with anyone...
- if that's what you're wondering.
- Not a problem.
- You abandoned that kid.
- My shift was over.
- He was counting on you.
- I had a gig.
Screw your gig,
medicine isn't a day job!
Jing-Mei.
- Come when I call you.
- Why do you do this?
Please.
Papa, I can't.
Jing-Mei.
Okay. Okay.
I promise.
Why's your brother here?
Your parents live in Winnetka.
Ben's in the Peace Corps and
they bug him to get a real job.
That sounds familiar.
- If I get this sofa bed...
- They're checking the stock.
All right, thanks.
- You the youngest?
- Oldest. Ben and my little sister, Tess.
She's a junior partner
in my dad's firm.
- I wonder who the favorite is.
- Hmm.
- You have siblings?
- My brother died when I was 11.
- I'm sorry.
- We have the sofa bed in stock...
but only in moss
green, not black.
- Green's fine. Can you deliver it today?
- On Christmas Eve?
Mm.
- Could tie it to the roof of the car.
- You think?
Pfft. That's why you brought
me along, isn't it? A little brawn?
- We'll take it. I'll go pay.
- I'll go find some rope.
- Meet you at the checkout.
- All right, thanks.
Can you say
anything? Can you talk?
Okay, you're choking. So I'm
gonna do this really hard, okay?
Mom!
Oh, no. It's okay. I was actually helping
her. She was choking on a piece of...
He grabbed my daughter.
I'm a doc... I think we
should get out of here.
- What happened?
- I saved that little girl's life.
- What's he saying?
- Uh, "thanks"?
We did it when I was a kid.
No way. Gifts get opened
on Christmas morning.
- Tell Dr. Lewis we'll be back for more.
- Where are you taking them?
Washington Library on State Street.
- The library?
They keep opening up public
buildings until everybody's in.
If Alex opens a gift tonight...
It's cheating to open
a gift the night before.
Then he won't be so
desperate to get up...
which means he'll sleep in,
which means we get to sleep in.
- Oh, okay.
- Plus, it's just fun.
Is that a trick so you
can open your gift tonight?
Robert Sanders, 42.
Syncopal episode at home.
- Hit his head on a chair on the way.
- Mr. Sanders, I'm Dr. Kovac.
190/100, 110 and
30. Glucose, 125.
- I can't get a sat.
- It's too cold to read.
- Do you guys need some help?
- So it seems.
Increased work breathing,
crackles bilaterally.
- Wife's behind us.
- Gonna be below 10 degrees soon.
Merry Christmas.
Excuse us. Keep
this pathway clear.
- Get a history? ZADRO:
Read it and weep.
- Okay.
- Okay, out of the way.
Okay, out of the
way. Now. Come on.
Systemic lupus, erythematosis.
- Diagnosed 20 years ago.
- Dialysis-dependent, renal failure.
- Dialyzed yesterday, two hours.
- Coronary artery disease.
Yeah, come on. Okay, let's go.
- Hypertension, hepatitis C.
- And a partridge in a pear tree.
- Sorry, I'm a handful.
- Morris. Stop eating.
- We got a hundred people waiting.
- Lewis already loaded me up.
Pratt, is your CVA
out of Trauma 1?
ICU just called for him.
- Sats correlating at 89.
- Okay, crank up the O2.
- Abby, I have six charts for you.
- I haven't even taken my coat off yet.
Oh, Carter, stay on with DHS. You have
to pound them to pick up the homeless.
- Right. Squeaky wheel.
- Yeah. It'll calm down soon enough.
They're not in by
midnight, they'll freeze.
Susan, you around tomorrow?
Well, I'm on at 3 but we'll be
hanging out till then. Bring Henry by.
Oh, I will. I got something for Cosmo. I
want you to see Henry in his Santa suit.
- You got a headache?
- No, I got a backache.
I was helping move a
couch. Who is on with me?
- Chen, but she's running a little late.
- Becoming a habit. Merry Christmas.
Oh, my God. Did you just
re-gift right in front of me?
Yep. I'm your
secret Santa. Enjoy.
Established rheumatology
patient seen by Doctor Scheer.
Spear, not Scheer. I'm the
wife, Carol Shoup-Sanders.
- It's Jared Spear.
- Sorry. That's Spear. Dr. Spear.
Can you touch your
chin to your chest?
I have his medical history here.
He's tachypneic,
pulse ox is borderline.
- We can order records.
- You'll prefer mine. Concise.
- Honey, let them work. KOVAC:
Tilt your head all the way back.
You need my help.
They just don't know it yet.
- No. He needs to be admitted.
- Okay, let's sit him up.
Gonna make you more
comfortable, Mr. Sanders.
Robert.
Okay, how long
was he unconscious?
Forty-seven seconds.
- What happened before that?
- I stood up from the dinner table.
- He felt short of breath, dizzy.
- Chest pain?
- No.
- Rheum's not coming in.
- Dr. Spear?
- He was unavailable.
The primary complaint sounded cardiac.
We'll give him nitrates, call Cardiology.
We have a great cardiologist,
Dr. Knauth. K-N-A-U-T-H.
Well, shouldn't somebody
be writing this down?
Another shelter van's here.
Let's go. I'll take the first 20 people.
Male, 62, lives under a bridge,
says he's having chest pain.
Register him. Check a
12-lead, pulse ox, chest film.
Diagnosis: hunger, cold.
Aftercare: food, warmth.
Hey, Jake Scanlon, fourth
year, transferred from Creighton.
Hey, Jake. This guy knows
if he says chest pain...
he'll be here 16 hours and get a
tray of food. So let me do you a favor.
Listen up, everyone. The vans are
here to take you all to the Holiday Inn.
- Ray.
- That is right. Thank the mayor.
There'll be plenty of food. Remember,
it's all good at the Holiday Inn.
- Liar.
- It works. Only the sick ones are staying.
Don't give him any credit.
Very good. Trick the needy.
It's a holiday. And it's someplace
like an inn. All right, get in the van.
- Ready? Gotta get Alex in 20 minutes.
- Yeah.
Abby, is that our
Cardiology on Mr. Sanders?
I'm on hold. But go. I'll
present to Carter or Chen.
- Thanks, Abby.
- You sure?
You've been on since 7 this morning.
Somebody should have Christmas.
- Yeah, Alex is pretty excited.
- Alex or you?
- Go ahead. We're fine. We're fine.
- Thanks.
- Hi. I'm calling about Robert Sanders.
- Abby, is Kovac still here?
Admit. Yeah. Cardiomegaly
and pulmonary edema.
- Luka.
- Hey, I have a lupus patient for you...
- in Trauma 1. Sanders.
- No, no. I can't stay.
I'm just here to pick
up meds for my dad.
Uh, look, I know it's a lot to
ask, but can you cover my shift?
- It's Christmas Eve.
- I know. I'll do New Year's.
Ready, Freddy?
I'm sorry. I can't
cover for you.
It's a family emergency.
I wouldn't ask otherwise.
Are you serious?
For tonight? Come on.
It's my first Christmas
with Sam and Alex.
I can't help you
this time. I'm sorry.
Dr. Chen, this is Margaret. She'll
be temp-clerking this evening.
- Hi.
- Yeah. Nice to meet you.
- Not a big fan of the Yuletide.
- Is Lewis still here?
Headed towards the exit,
as am I. Merry Christmas.
- Yeah. Merry Christmas.
- What does that mean, exactly?
What? "Merry Christmas"?
You could at least examine
him before you blow me off...
Okay, BNP, fine. Happy
holidays to you too.
Never get sick on Christmas.
Hey, did you call Psych?
- Yes. I suggested they bring kibble.
- Okay. And you can go home.
- Students don't have to work holidays.
- I volunteered.
That's twisted. Next year, I'm inventing
a family so I won't work on Christmas.
- What did Dr. Knauth say?
- Cardiology thinks it's a kidney problem.
- How's the breathing, Mr. Sanders?
- Hanging in there.
- Dr. MacPherson's our kidney guy.
- Right. He's on call tonight.
Thought I told you to go home.
BP, 195/105. Heart rate,
115. Resps, 30. Sats, 93.
CBC, troponin, chem-7,
and Card suggested BNP.
- What the hell is that?
- B-type natriuretic peptide.
I will double check that
dosage. Get started on the rest.
Get me a suture kit for the head lac.
- You got it.
- What did you say your name was?
- Jake.
Jing-Mei, I am sorry
about your dad. I really am.
- But I keep cutting you breaks.
- I know, and I appreciate it.
- This'll be the last time.
- Oh, man.
There is no way I can get anyone
to cover tonight. It's impossible.
- Susan, please.
- I hate to be hard-core, but I can't.
Look, can you stay?
I have a baby. And a guy
who's been watching him 24/7.
And I just worked a
14-hour shift. No, I can't.
Well, maybe Carter can handle
it. He's got Abby and Morris.
We're inundated with
homeless from the city roundup.
- I know.
- We're already understaffed.
Jing-Mei, please. You
have to understand.
- I do. It's okay.
- Good. Thank you.
I'm sorry, Susan. I quit.
And so the holiday begins.
Happy, happy, joy, joy, everyone.
Nine-year-old, auto vs. ped.
Transient, LOC, hit-and-run.
- Mom? MRS. PRICE:
Right here, honey.
- Confused and agitated.
- What's his name?
- Harry.
- Hey, Harry. I'm Dr. Carter.
- We'll take good care of you.
- I'll get Neela. My shift's over.
She's busy.
- I got a plane to catch.
- I'm not asking!
One, two, three.
Okay. Large-bore IV...
500 of saline, open.
What happened?
- Car hit him.
- Came out of nowhere.
- Weak femoral. Was he thrown?
- Diffused ecchymosis on the chest.
- He was outside.
- I parked the car. He was getting out.
- Harry flew up in the air.
- Mattie.
Systolic's 77.
You guys are okay?
You're not hurt?
- We're okay. They checked us.
- Tenderness, crepitus over the chest wall.
- What's that mean? CARTER:
He has multiple rib fractures.
- Mom, it hurts.
- Baby, I'm here.
Okay, CBC, type and cross
for forehead, chest and belly...
CT, trauma panel,
and a femoral line.
- Pulse is up to 138.
- Okay, rush the blood bank.
He could be anxious or bleeding out.
- Bleeding out?
- It's okay, Mattie. RAY:
We'll take care of him.
- Why don't we take Mattie for a walk?
- I wanna stay here. Can I stay here?
I'll set her up in the Family
Room. Come on, Mattie. Let's go.
Dr. MacPherson, this is
Lockhart again in the ER.
I'm calling about
Robert Sanders.
I know his wife can be a pain in
the ass but tonight he has a real...
Problem. And he needs
dialysis. And call me back.
Abby, take this thyromegaly and be well.
As you can see, I have a party to attend.
- Where are you going?
- Not that you'd know...
but it's the Players Ball at
The Peninsula. Kanye West...
- Twista, the whole Roc-A-Fella... Hello.
- Hi, I'm looking for a doctor.
Well, that would be
me. How can I help you?
- I'm looking for Dr. Morris.
- Morris. No, see, what you need is...
- somebody with more experience in...
- Hey, hey. Hi. Glad you could make it.
Come on. I'll show you around.
- Bye.
- Bye. She's with Morris.
- Chen just quit. Where's Carter?
- Quit what?
- The hospital. Where's Carter?
- Trauma 2, I think.
- Quit for good?
- Is she all right?
She's burnt out. We're
screwed. I can't believe it.
Chen.
- Your secret Santa gift.
- From you?
No. It was in the lounge with
your name. What's with Chen?
- I don't know. She's not answering.
- "Rats, Lice, and History"?
Ooh. That's a good one. Someone
really likes you. I got a Pez dispenser.
- See y'all later. NEELA:
Happy Christmas.
Hey, I got a 39-year-old
IV-DU, narcotic withdrawal.
- I'm dying.
- This guy needs detox.
- Get him 2.1 of clonidine.
- Hey, what are you doing?
This is a publicly-funded hospital,
and this is an illegal religious artifact.
- Well, it's Christmas.
- So?
So...
put it back.
- Sharps back. Pericardiocentesis needle.
- Systolic's 82 on one liter.
Carter, Chen just quit.
Harry, you're gonna
feel a little pressure.
- She quit? RAY:
Heart rate's trending up.
Yeah. That's the tamponade
limiting contractions.
- Gotta up the rate to compensate.
- What's that mean?
There's blood around
his heart. We'll relieve it.
- PVCs.
- Yeah, I'm in but not getting anything.
- Lift up his head a bit.
- Chuny, close to trauma...
- and refuse any more homeless.
- Good idea. Did you smell Triage?
How can people stink
so much in cold weather?
Oil of wintergreen on a mask
or breathe through your mouth.
You're not staying?
There's blood in there. But it's
either clotted or it's
collecting posteriorly.
- Can't get it with a needle. Page CT surg.
- Oh, I'll get Neela.
If I leave now, I can
still make my plane.
Forget about your plane.
- I promised my mother.
- Your mother?
- Look, somebody's gotta stay.
- I'll page Surgery.
Ask for an echo-guided
pericardial window.
- Hey, Carter, do you have a minute?
- Yeah.
Titrate the dopamine
to a systolic of 90.
Keep paging CT surg.
All right, Harry's stable.
And Dr. Barnett is here.
Apparently.
My lupus patient. Pulmonary
edema's worse and his pressure sucks.
- Can you take a look?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
- So Chen quit? What was it? Her dad?
Yeah. I'll go home, have
dinner with Chuck and Cosmo...
sing some carols, come back.
- Chuck's been cooking, my dad's there.
- All right, go home.
If we're busy, I'll
call. Otherwise, stay.
Thank you. You're
amazing. Thank you.
Come be amazing over here.
- I'll check in later.
- Did you call his primaries?
- Rheum says he's too sick for them...
call Cardiology. Card says call
Renal. Renal says he just had dialysis...
it's not their problem.
- BP is dropping, 88/59.
- Stop that BNP drip, lower his head.
Yeah, I tried that. He desats.
- Hard to breathe. Carol? JAKE:
She's gonna come right back.
Abby, you gave
nitropaste and BNP drip?
Give two vasodilators and
his pressure bottoms out.
You try getting hold of three
specialists on Christmas Eve.
You're his doctor.
Now he's got crackles in the apices.
Is Renal coming to take off the fluid?
- No.
- What do you mean, no?
He was dialyzed yesterday, so Renal
thinks there's another explanation.
- What do you think it is?
- He got half his usual dialysis time...
because of the holidays, ate
salty food, flooded his lungs.
- So...
- I'm waiting to hear from MacPherson...
the Renal Attending.
- Dr. Agbo from Surgery's here.
- Agbo? I've never heard of him.
- Junior fella, sweaty palms.
- See? Nobody wants to be here tonight.
- Including me.
- Okay. Why don't you call...
Dr. Mac-What's-His-Name again.
Remember, nobody knows what your
patient needs now better than you do.
- Sats only 88.
- Uh, put him on a nonrebreather.
That should help. I'll
be right back, okay?
These are Robert's
medical records.
- Listen. Um, about today on the phone...
- Pain in the ass that I am...
I got them from Records myself.
Otherwise, you'd have them tomorrow.
Now will you look at my file?
- Hey.
- What are you doing here?
Heard a crazy story about
you quitting. Can I come in?
You know, thanks, Greg, but
I'm fine. Thanks for coming by.
Hey, you need some help?
Yeah, get me
some Ativan, please.
- How much?
- Two milligrams.
- What happened at work today?
- Sometimes he's cooperative and lucid.
- Sometimes he's like this.
- Sundowning.
Sundowning? That's
too nice a word for it.
- Give me my pants, please.
- You know, you got a lot of Ativan here.
Potassium too.
Jing-Mei, what are you doing?
Talk to me. What's going on?
I'll relieve the blood
accumulating around the heart.
- Is that the pericardium?
- 10 blade and pickups to me.
Watch over my boy.
Keep him safe in your arms.
McAlpin catheter,
60-cc syringe. Quickly.
- Whoa, a hundred cc's right there.
- Keep him safe, I beg you.
- Another 60-cc syringe, quickly.
- Hey, man.
- Dr. Agbo? MRS.
- God be with you.
- Maybe I nicked the vessel.
- Give me some sterile eights.
- Jesus, I call on you.
- PVCs. Bigeminy.
Pull that catheter back.
- I can get it.
It's my fault. Sorry. I didn't mean to...
- Shut up, Mattie!
- Hey!
- Mrs. Price, take your daughter outside.
- No. I wanna stay with my son.
- I said pull that catheter back.
- The blood will just reaccumulate.
- Get out of the way. Out of the way.
- V-tach. Crash cart.
- Catheter is out.
- Charged to 100. Clear.
- Just wait. Just wait.
Normal sinus.
All right. 3-0 and
a needle driver.
That's good. Right? That's good?
- Dr. Carter?
- Take this girl to the Family Room...
page Social Services, and
stay with her until they get here.
No.
Feeling better?
A little.
Don't lie. He's not
better. Look at him.
BP's stabilized, 119/85.
Pulse down to 115.
He's had lupus cerebritis?
Two years ago. It calmed
down after a steroid burst.
Okay. I'd like to get a head scan to
make sure the cerebritis isn't back...
and there's no
internal bleeding.
I have a discharge
and then I'll take you.
I could take him.
- Do you know where it is?
- Mm-hm. Can his wife come with us?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
Put him on a portable monitor and O2,
and call me if you have any questions.
Okay?
Mm-hm. ABBY: Okay.
Would you like to color?
Are you excited about
Santa coming tonight?
- Why not?
- Santa's not coming for me.
Mattie, that's not true.
- Hey.
- I thought you had a plane to catch.
Hey, Mattie. How you doing?
You know, when I was a kid, I used
to fight with my brother all the time.
Did he get hurt?
Yeah, he got hurt. I got hurt. Kids
get hurt sometimes, by accident.
I was mad at him for
not playing with me.
So I threw his book out. And
he went to get it, and got hit.
Mattie, it's not your
fault Harry got hurt.
It is. I tried to help
him but I couldn't.
- I had to go get my mom.
- Your mom wasn't there?
She was at work.
- You and Harry were alone in the car?
- We live in the car.
Don't tell my mom. I'm
not supposed to say that.
My father's a doctor. He
knows what he's asking.
Without the G-tube and IV,
he would've died weeks ago.
Oh, so now lifesaving
technology is bad?
- If someone doesn't want it.
- How do you know he doesn't?
- He's not even in his right mind.
- After he sleeps, he's lucid.
Each time, every day,
he begs me to help him.
Removing the
support's not enough.
It would take him days to die of
dehydration and he'd be in misery.
- Put him in a nursing home.
- So he can be somebody else's problem?
- Who doesn't know or love him?
- He won't even know that he's there.
You're not Chinese.
Oh. So it's Chinese to
euthanize your elders.
It's Chinese to respect them.
Here you go.
You should go.
I don't want you here.
You've been through a hell of a
lot this last year. You need a break.
Put him in a home for a month
so you can catch your breath.
I can't.
We fight to save
lives every day.
You know, we literally bust our asses
to give people a few more hours of living.
You're a doctor, you can't just
cross that line like it's nothing.
Quality of life is the only
measure that matters.
My proud father is
lying in his own feces.
He can't eat without
vomiting, can't sleep.
He knows what he's asking for and
he knows he can get that from me.
If you weren't a physician,
you couldn't do this.
But I am and I can.
Why haven't you
done it up till now?
If he's been asking so much?
Because you know,
deep down inside...
it would haunt you
for the rest of your life.
Why haven't you done it yet?
Maybe I don't have the courage.
It's over. Christ is born.
It's only midnight? Feels
like 4 in the morning.
Margaret, if you turn off
these lights one more time...
- I'll beat you to death with a fruitcake.
- This is totally loser's Christmas.
Give that back, you little minx.
Okay.
Rudolfo, can you blow like you're
blowing out candles on a birthday cake?
- Too many cold.
- Does it hurt to breathe in?
Lockhart, your lupus
patient's coding in the scanner.
All right. Neela,
chest film and O2.
Got it. RAY: Hey.
Hey. It was cool what
you did with that little girl.
- Telling her about your brother.
- Yeah. I think it helped.
Although I don't actually
have any siblings.
Why does that not surprise me?
Social Work's got Mattie,
Carter says I can go.
Can I sign out Harry to you?
- I thought you missed your flight.
- I'll go standby.
Don't want to disappoint
Mom on Christmas.
- Do something.
- BP's 83/50.
- Cycle the dynamap.
- What happened?
Central line got
caught and it pulled out.
Bleeding won't stop.
- Not with lupus-associated coagulopathy.
- Heart rate's dropping.
Okay, 8-0 and a mac tube now.
Ma'am, please step back.
Let us help your husband.
Put pressure right here.
Don't check it. Don't let go.
- Sats, 68.
- Yeah, he's hypoxic. I get it, thanks.
- Oh, God. Please don't let it be tonight.
- I'm sorry.
- Tube.
- Pulse, 64.
I'm not ready for him to die.
- I'm in.
- Sats coming up.
- Run, don't walk, to the blood bank.
Four units of O-neg.
Work on type-specific.
- I'll meet you in the Trauma Room.
- He's stable?
He needs blood. We're
gonna start a central line.
- Can an Attending do it?
- I put in lines all the time.
He's been through enough.
I want a surgical Attending.
He's moving in
the right direction.
He's gonna spend the night in
here until an ICU bed opens up.
You were at work
when this happened?
We've been living in the car since
I left my husband three weeks ago.
It wasn't bad when the
kids were in school...
but since Christmas
vacation started...
You left them in the car?
I gotta work.
It's okay, Mama.
Can their dad help?
He's a violent guy.
I could take it, but he was
starting in on Harry. So I...
Yeah. We're a little concerned about the
amount of strain that you've been under.
I didn't want Mattie
saying how it was...
because I don't want
anyone taking my kids.
We're not homeless people.
I got a job. This
is just temporary.
I can help you find a place to
stay until you get on your feet.
We tried the shelter.
It isn't safe for the kids.
No, this isn't a shelter.
It's a house for families
fleeing domestic violence.
It's safe.
Thank you.
I'm sorry that I
yelled at you, honey.
Don't be scared of me, okay?
- I'm sorry, Mom.
- Oh, no.
You didn't do anything wrong.
Come here.
So, what do you think?
I think the bad guy's the driver,
not the mother. Lady needs a break.
Cafeteria's serving up a
feast. Better get up there.
Hey, Morris.
Ew.
Burgers probably
would've been safer.
Speaking of, I'm hungry.
Wanna get something to eat?
- Just lost my appetite.
- Dr. Carter.
Phone call from Africa.
It's Kem somebody.
Catch you later.
Hello? KEM: John.
- Hi.
- What are you doing?
Uh, I'm not doing
anything. I'm just working.
No. It's too cold to snow
here. Maybe tomorrow.
Shh. It's okay.
It's okay.
No, no. It's okay.
Calm down. Don't worry.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
- Bring more Ativan!
- I add five of Haldol when he's like this.
Okay, calm down.
- What is he saying?
- To let him go.
Shh. Shh.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Papa.
Okay, now squeeze. Hold on.
No, no. Both hands. Both
hands. Let go of my hand.
- Let go... RAPHAELLA:
Hee-hee-hee!
- Squeeze the trigger.
- My hands are shaking.
Hey!
- Hi.
Um, Neela, Raphaella Greenberg.
Are you a medical student?
I'm his girlfriend.
- HIPAA? Patient privacy?
- Stapling, it's nothing.
- This guy's totally out of it.
- This is so wrong.
Well, I'll staple. You watch.
Security! Security!
Somebody get Security!
Give me a reason!
- Give me a reason!
- Stop it!
- Whose patient is this?
- Mine. Mr. Beidermeier.
- I need help!
- Get Security to cuff him to a bed, huh?
Get him on monitor until
we figure out what he took.
- Should've let him OD!
- Come on. Up, up.
- That's the Christmas spirit.
- Yeah.
Back to bed, Mr. Beidermeier.
At least have him arrested.
- What's your name again?
- Margaret.
Margaret, we're good here.
Crap.
Got a flash. Guide wire.
Didn't you come because
the wife wants you?
Not her call. I like to make a
small nick with an 11 blade.
She's afraid Abby
might kill her husband.
I don't think she will.
Okay. Catheter.
Tachy at 110. BP,
94/79. Sats, 86.
That's as good as he's
gonna get until he's dialyzed.
His lungs are swimming in fluid.
Nice. Threading easily. Good.
Thank you for coming in.
It's my job.
You want to admit him to your service?
All those other docs are blowing me off.
Santa Claus is coming to town.
Okay, removing the
introducer, 10-cc syringe.
Legally and morally they have to come
when you call or lose staff privileges.
- Don't think they heard about my power.
- They're aware.
They take advantage...
- of submissive interns.
- I'm not submissive.
- Nice return.
- I know.
Like many interns and,
well, many females...
you incline yourself toward
popularity and equate it with success.
Well, when an ER doc is
popular, someone's losing out.
And it's usually the patient.
- All this guy has is you.
- Infusing well. Needle driver.
All right. Well, good job.
Really good job, Abby.
I'll finish up.
Yeah, go. Go out there
and do what you have to do.
By the by, did you,
um, get the book?
Rats, Lice, and History?
You're my secret Santa?
Yeah, I'm quite excited
to discuss it with you.
The chapter on the influence
of vermin epidemics...
on political and military history, and
the relative unimportance of generals...
is outrageous.
Oh, 4-0 silk.
- Submissive.
- Not a word I would use to describe you.
Okay. Time to get unpopular.
Look, I take full responsibility
for what happened with Sanders.
You didn't do it, the tech did. I
shouldn't have sent a student to CT.
I want you to send me, okay?
It won't happen again.
So, what did you
learn from all this?
Always go home when you tell me.
Hi. Is this the dialysis tech?
- It's kind of late.
Yeah, I know. It's 2 a.m.
I'm sorry to wake you.
What did he say?
He thanked me.
Said I was a good daughter.
You are.
You want me to do it?
Lab called on Vivadi Sanito.
- The coags were QNS.
- Okay.
And Betty Muldoon was
admitted to Medicine.
Can I get a cab voucher? Huh?
I don't think we're quite ready
to discharge you, Mr. Claus.
Dialysis for patient Sanders.
- Do you want me to...?
- No, no. I got it. Thank you.
Hi. Thanks for coming in.
Double overtime on holidays. But I
just did Robert Sanders yesterday.
Yeah. He's... His
fluid overloaded.
- MacPherson call in orders?
- I spoke to him on the phone.
- What did he want?
- The usual, standard run.
2K bath, 35 bicarb,
pull off a couple liters.
- Two or four hours?
- I'm not sure about that.
- I'll give him a call.
- Well, actually...
Dr. MacPherson very specifically
said he did not wanna be disturbed.
He wouldn't come in.
- He wouldn't come in.
- Ha-ha.
What a prick. But I need orders.
Okay. Okay, well, do you think you
could get started and then call him?
- Sure.
- Thank you.
- All right.
You're welcome.
- MacPherson ordered dialysis?
- Uh...
No. I did.
You? You can't order...
Thank you.
Merry Christmas.
- Hm. MARQUEZ:
Tetanus is up to date.
I was putting a sled together and I
sliced myself on the metal runners.
It doesn't look too
bad to me, Mr. Rotolo.
Santa's gotta get home,
doc. Know what I mean?
Me and Mrs. Claus have things to
take care of before the kids wake up.
- Won't take long. You feel that?
- Yeah.
- Feel that?
Excuse me, Dr. Carter.
When you have a minute?
Sure. Um...
Irrigate, open up a
suture kit. I'll be right back.
I have something for you.
- But I haven't wrapped it, it's at home...
- Liar. But my birthday's in two weeks.
- "Mildred"?
- Oh, sorry. Mildred didn't show.
I was giving out
a bunch of these.
Just a little something.
So how was your phone call?
It's good. She's good.
Oh, yeah. Very handy.
- For hooking up the VCR.
- Right. Yeah.
Oh. Yeah. You look like
an old-fashioned doctor.
I am an old-fashioned doctor.
- Okay.
Okay. Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas.
Ho, ho, ho. Merry Christmas.
- We got sliders.
- Yes!
You will never be more loved
than you are at this moment.
Oh, I could eat about
three dozen of these.
- Hi.
So is this the little
homeless boy?
Should we treat as inpatient?
- Is he hypoxic?
- No.
- Tolerating POs?
- Yeah.
Then he only
needs PO antibiotics.
- And a warm bed.
- I'll call the Pedes team.
Hi, Rudolfo.
Hello, doctors.
- Hi.
- You got a chimney?
I'm sorry, honey. What?
How's Santa Claus gonna find
me if you don't got a chimney?
We don't need a chimney. Santa
sees everything. He'll find you.
But you'll have to go to sleep
before he comes, all right?
Good night.
Do you think Dad has
a present for his son?
Doubt Dad's got
enough for their breakfast.
Santa Claus better
come up with something.
- Jumbo Mart?
- Do you have any cash on you?
No.
Jing-Mei...
it's been over an hour.
You okay?
I'll call the mortuary
in the morning.
What are you
gonna do after that?
Well, I have to go to China and
bury my father next to my mom.
Deal with his
estate. Bum around.
Visit the village where they were
born. Meet some relatives. I don't know.
I'm pretty tired.
Well, you know...
if there's anything I can
do. I mean it. Anything.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you for...
That's okay. Come here.
Where are we going?
Ho, ho, ho, and
a jolly old soul.
- Sikhs don't have Christmas.
- Grew up in England.
Old King Wenceslas, Boxing Day and a
family tradition of anonymous kindness.
- Where'd you get that key?
- Wendall from Social Work.
- I have a plan.
- A sly and cunning plan?
We give these toys and books
to the homeless kids in the ER.
Ahh.
Stealing from the bad
off to give to the worse off.
We buy new stuff tomorrow
in the after-Christmas sales.
- Belated gift for Child Life Department.
- Do we have ribbons or paper?
We can steal bows from the
decorations in the cafeteria.
- What's up?
- I thought you'd be in Miami by now.
O'Hare's a mess. No
seats until tomorrow.
Miami? I thought your
mother was in Philadelphia.
Hey, it's snowing. Come on.
Hey, if it's snowing, that
means it's warming up.
You knew he was in Miami?
He's got a girlfriend
that lives there.
I worked his shift because he gave
me some sob story about his mother.
Barnett, you back already?
I can't stay away.
I love it!
- Does snow get polluted?
MacPHERSON: Where's Lockhart?
Dr. MacPherson?
I didn't authorize dialysis for Sanders.
You started it without my approval.
- I wanna speak to your Attending.
- Uh...
Your patient was drowning.
He needed dialysis.
You're an Attending
on-call. I covered your ass.
You can't just deceive
Attendings when you don't agree.
You report me for working the system,
I report you for abandoning your patient.
Go, Abby.
See you inside.
- Oh!
- Miami?
Come on. Let's get back to work.
This is Jing-Mei Chen.
I woke up this morning and found
my father had passed away in the night.
Yes. He's been very ill.
Well, actually, his physician is
here. He can sign the death certificate.
Thank you.
It's 2753 West Cedar Drive.