Previously on Grey's Anatomy...
There is a fundamental flaw
in how we are
teaching our residents.
And we have got to fix this.
- Who is Dr. Eliza Minnick?
- Minnick's kind of a legend.
You'll just be observing
the first few days anyway,
getting a sense of how it works.
I thought you two
were working together.
Bailey, who's running this
program, me or Eliza Minnick?
She thinks she's the
new Residency Director,
like she is Richard
Webber's boss.
You don't want to hear my
opinions about a program that I built,
- that I trained you in.
- I made a decision
about what is best for the
hospital moving forward.
Look at that hand.
This is assault.
A pediatric surgeon
walking around this hospital.
Do you realize what happens
if you're convicted of a felony?
Mer, the trial's tomorrow.
It could be our last chance
for, like, eight, ten years.
Jo Wilson isn't my real name.
That's why I couldn't marry you.
It might all come out
at the court tomorrow.
Karev, what are you about to do?
I'm going to the district
attorney's tonight,
and I'm gonna take the plea.
- He's going to prison.
- When?
It's just us now. There were
five of us, and it can't be just me.
Mr. Karev? He'll see you now.
We all have heroes...
So, this website's saying that
we need a case record number.
The other one said that I
needed his arrest-record number.
- Are those the same thing?
- I don't know.
People we look up to, people we
aspire to be, who teach us how to be
greater than we are because
they're greater than we are.
- Did you find it?
- I'm looking.
They're great if we
don't look too closely.
I can't get any information about
his case without that number.
Alex sent me an e-mail one time
with an arraignment
number on it or something...
- Try the "search" box.
- I'm searching.
Oh, maybe this. Okay, "Locate
current defendant using his..."
Yeah, no. Still need the number.
- Okay, I found it. You ready?
- Yes.
"RDH4467A239."
'Cause if we get too close...
There it is, there's his case.
We realize, heroes
are just regular people.
Thirty years to life.
He's gonna die in prison.
Wait, that's not even his case!
- I said "A" not "8".
- Thank God.
- Do you need me to take over?
- No, no, I got it.
Criminal case, blah, blah, blah.
- "Disposition."
- Deposition.
That's good. That means
he's giving testimony.
So that means
that he's in court,
and he didn't take the
plea, and he's not in prison.
At least, not yet.
"Disposition".
Oh. Okay. On it.
And regular people can fail us.
Looks like criminal proceedings
have been concluded,
and indefinitely postponed.
So that means the
trial's been cancelled.
Which means that Alex took a plea,
which means that Alex is in prison.
This doesn't make any sense to
me. Does this make sense to you?
No. You declared
war on Eliza Minnick.
We're ready to throw down,
and now you're just calling
a truce before we even start?
Okay...
- Occupied!
- Come back later!
It's me!
- Richard doesn't want to fight.
- What? Why?
- That is not what I said at all.
- You know what?
I'm just gonna call a board
meeting, or I'll loop in the Foundation.
We'll just go over her
head. I'll get her fired.
That doesn't sound
like nepotism to you
since Catherine's my
wife and your mother?
Wrongful termination.
Look, I'm not suggesting
we back down.
I'm saying that we
need to be smart.
Strategic, organized. You
just don't rush into battle.
That's what gets people killed.
I mean, think about Yorktown.
Look, we need to make her
want to leave because she's failing.
Robbins? You with
us? What, rough night?
Yeah. Have you heard from Alex?
No. Nothing.
We tried, but we can't
figure out where they put him.
Go away!
It's Murphy. I need Dr. Robbins.
There's a laboring
mom on her way.
Tell me if you hear
anything, okay?
- Uh, what?
- You guys haven't heard
about Karev?
Hey, Wilson.
I'm sorry.
What?
About Karev. You
know, I just thought...
Why are you sorry?
You didn't put
him in prison. I did.
Morning, Dr. Minnick.
First day. Exciting.
I love first days.
Such a feeling of...
Yeah, this isn't gonna work.
No, no. No, don't...
The valve replacement and
the neuroblastoma debulking
are happening
around the same time,
but I need to see both,
so I'm moving one.
- Okay.
- And this amputation's got
to go...
No, you don't want to do that.
- What is wrong with you?
- Okay.
No one touches the
board except Chief Bailey.
If Chief Bailey even
sees you lay a finger on it,
she will take that finger,
and she will kill you.
And you can't take my career
to the next level if you're dead.
- Ma'am.
- Dr. Minnick.
- You rearranged.
- I hope you don't mind.
One less thing for me
to do. Make it happen.
- She touched the...
- Edwards, excuse us.
I thought we should
gather the attendings,
let them know you're
officially starting.
No, no. I'm good. I
do this real slowly.
I win their hearts and minds,
OR by OR, attending by attending.
I teach the technique, they
start spreading the word,
and then, suddenly,
they realize,
I'm the best thing that
ever happened to them.
Uh, some may need more
convincing than others.
Chief, there is a
Dr. Webber everywhere I go.
I know how to deal
with a Dr. Webber.
Good morning, doctors! Chief.
And welcome to you, Dr. Minnick.
Thank you, really,
but I don't do caffeine.
I don't need it.
Noted.
Okay, well, let's make it a
good morning, everyone.
She's on her way
here now, in a taxi.
Contractions are less
than three minutes apart.
Her doctor's out of
town. I've set up a whole...
Page, Portman, 'cause
I've been up all night.
- Portman's on call.
- Portman is in a delivery,
and the driver thinks this
woman is having a baby right now.
So how are you
talking to the driver?
Oh, he's VideoChatting...
You're okay. Hello?
- Hi. It's Dr. Robbins.
- Hey, yeah,
we're about eight blocks
away from you guys.
About how far apart are
your contractions now?
Okay, I don't know
that. All I know is,
this lady is super
having a baby right now...
and we're coming in hot, okay?
- I only have a few minutes.
- Okay.
The battle has begun.
All right, guys, I've been
working on this petition
from all of the attendings.
We can read it if you want...
No, no, we're past that, okay?
- I did some recon.
- And?
I think Minnick's plan
is to go into the ORs
and turn each
attending, one by one.
- Okay.
- We never let her in the OR.
We isolate the enemy, cut off
her supply lines, starve her out.
- Great.
- Genius.
What?
It's Dr. Bailey, who
I respect and like.
Look, she is the first
black woman chief
we've had at this hospital.
I'm not exactly excited
to undermine her like this.
Jackson, no one
wants this less than I do.
This isn't about Bailey.
This is about correcting a
mistake that threatens our hospital.
This is not a Bailey problem.
This is an Eliza
Minnick problem.
- So we lock her out.
- Okay.
- Hi.
- Is she here?
- Who?
- Amelia. She left last night.
She left a note. She's not here?
- No.
- Meredith...
No, I don't know.
- Where do you think she'd...
- I can't find her.
You have to find her. Alex
is in jail. I have to find him.
You have Amelia,
I have Alex. Okay?
Let me know when you know.
It was already bad
when I first picked her up.
I tried to talk her through
the breathing and everything,
but she just yells.
- That's okay. Are you guys close?
- Like, two blocks.
- See, that was her.
- Yeah, we got that.
Steve... It's Steve, right?
Hey, it's gonna be okay.
I'm gonna talk to
Mindy for a second.
Okay.
Mindy, it's Dr. Robbins.
- Has your water broken?
- Yeah,
I trashed this poor guy's car.
Hey, it's fine.
I am gonna divorce my husband.
No, I'm gonna
kill that son of a...
Big inhale.
That jerk is out shopping right
now. Shopping! Can you believe it?
I'm about to give
birth in a freaking taxi!
No, no, no, no, no!
We're almost there!
Mindy, hang on.
I feel like I'm
crushing the baby.
I think I'm sitting on her head.
You're feeling the baby
descend into the canal,
so just lay back, scoot
your butt up, put your feet up,
and we'll be waiting for
you in the parking lot, okay?
- Yeah.
- You're almost here, right?
Yeah. Fire up an epidural.
- Where do I go? Here?
- Straight! Straight!
Mindy?
Excuse me!
All right, so you just need
to look straight ahead.
We're gonna put this
collar on, stabilize your neck.
Just look right
here, lean forward.
No, I'm fine, really.
It's more my head
than anything else.
But is she okay?
I told her I was gonna get
her here before her baby came.
Mindy?
- Mindy? Mindy?
- Tell me what you need.
Mindy Wallace, at term,
in labor at time of impact.
Her ABCs intact, but
she's unresponsive.
Responsive to pain.
All right, come on, Mindy,
wake up for me, okay?
Possible head injuries,
bilateral hip dislocations.
She must have had her
legs up on the dashboard.
What? Why?
The way her legs are
shattered. Airbag deployed...
And the force shoved her legs
into her chest and abdomen.
Moving to the E.R.
- Hey, how's your pregnant lady?
- She's bad.
Yeah. Guy who hit them
barely has a scratch on him.
- Oh, God. Let me up!
- Hey, sir!
- Please!
- Lay him down.
- Mindy!
- Please lay back.
- You know her?
- That's my wife!
She's having our baby!
Oh, God, I hit my wife!
- Mindy!
- Just get him inside.
As soon as I'm done with
this, hang two more units.
- Murphy, where's my art line?
- I'm in.
All right, bandage,
and get me a blood gas.
Mindy? Mindy, it's
Dr. Robbins. Can you talk to me?
Ow. Ow. What's happening?
You were in a car accident
and you were pretty badly injured,
- but we're checking you out now.
- My baby. Is my baby...
Okay, all right.
There's the heartbeat.
It sounds really, really good.
Is my husband here?
Okay, breathe, breathe, breathe.
The baby's coming, but
you're not fully dilated.
Films coming up.
Pelvic fracture along with
bilateral hip dislocations.
Is that the femoral
head inside the pelvis?
The pelvis is broken,
trapping the baby's head.
Oh, my God.
Mindy, we're gonna take
you for some CT scans.
I want to check for other
internal injuries, okay?
I'll meet you there. If she
starts to decompensate...
I will head right to the OR.
- What do we got?
- Bryan Wallace, 36,
conscious status, post T-bone
MVC, G.C.S. 15, minor lacs.
- C-spine clear.
- Did you see my wife?
We're having a baby
right now, literally right now,
- and I need to know
if she's okay.
- Bryan, I'm Dr. Robbins.
- Is Mindy okay?
- Mindy's still in labor.
Her injuries are pretty severe,
so we're taking her up for scans,
but I'm taking care
of her, both of them.
- I'm doing everything I can.
- Thank you.
Okay, I'll get a lac kit, and
you order a head CT, please?
- All right. Bryan,
can you feel this?
- Yeah.
- Edwards, you're on neuro today?
- Yes.
Is Shepherd here?
No. She said she was
taking a few days' leave.
- But you spoke to her.
- No, I got an e-mail.
I'll need an ultrasound.
Let me know if you
hear from her, okay?
- Anything.
- All right.
Hey, Dr. Riggs.
I am here and stoked to scrub
in on your valve replacement.
Oh, that's unfortunate. That
was my valve replacement.
- What?
- Yeah. It went great.
I don't understand.
It was scheduled for
right now, the next surgery.
- Oh, maybe you
misread the board.
- I wrote it on the board.
Well, maybe you mis-wrote it.
Look, I would open
him up again for you,
but, you know, that kind of
thing could get me arrested, so...
Cheers!
He's not there?
Nobody? Somebody
has to know something.
Okay. Good luck.
Was that Meredith?
She can't find Alex?
He's not in King County
lockup or Tri-County.
I was there last night, and I
wouldn't wish that on anybody.
There. Looks like a
grade-2 splenic lac,
and she's bleeding from
her common iliac artery.
- How is that baby okay?
- Okay, so we need
to do a C-section
- and then repair
all those bleeders.
- Yeah, absolutely.
Okay, Murphy, can you let
the OR know we're coming?
Yes.
Any pain when I press down here?
No. But my head
still hurts, though.
Yeah, we're gonna
take a look at that, too.
Man, it was crazy. I was
driving like a bat out of hell.
How is that lady? Is she
gonna be able to have her baby?
- Is the baby okay?
- That's hard to say.
Right, yeah.
You probably can't tell
me anything, anyway.
I mean, who am I?
I'm not her family,
just a taxi driver.
That's cool. I get it.
Just kind of got invested.
We almost made it. Almost.
Listen, I'm gonna
order a head CT for you.
And I'll see what
I can find out.
Gonna order a head CT.
Is Minnick starting today? I
think I saw her on the OR floor.
I know what you
know. Less, actually.
I didn't even know
she was here today.
You're the Chief's husband,
and you don't know anything?
- No.
- What does that get you?
Hey, can we get some help
over here? Dude needs some help.
Started a fight in
the third period.
'Cause you high-sticked
me in the throat, you jag!
'Cause you got in the way of me
scoring, asswipe. I had a clean shot.
Look, let me take
a look at it, all right?
Oh, oh!
That's from a hit to the throat?
He went down, and I stepped
on his face with my skate.
Accidentally!
- Idiots.
- I think we'll page plastics.
Okay, we're gonna do
a C-section right away.
- Oh, God. Wait. Is the baby...
- No,
but you're bleeding internally,
and that's not good
for either of you.
So we'll need to
repair the bleeding,
and then you'll need surgery
to repair the hip fractures.
Okay. And I'll be
unconscious the whole time?
- Yes, of course.
- No, but can Bryan be there?
For the baby? When she's born?
- Mindy, your injuries are
too severe.
- Please. Please?
He was supposed to
be here to cut the cord,
and her mom will be out
cold. She'll just be alone.
- I'm afraid...
- Of course he can.
Thank you.
- He cannot be in that room.
- He'll just be there for the C,
and then he'll go,
before we do repairs,
just like a regular delivery.
- It's not a regular delivery.
- It's the only one
that they get,
- and I made this happen.
- What?
I told her to put her
feet on the dashboard,
and I made this so
much worse for them.
Look, please let me
make this one thing better.
Just for the birth.
Your labs look good. Just
waiting on your head-CT results.
Any word on the
lady and her baby?
Jury's still out. Sorry.
You know, today
started out so good.
I pulled up, she was
huffing and puffing.
I told her, "Sit in
front, sit in front."
you know, so she could recline?
And I said, "Imma get
you there. I got you."
I figured, either I get
her to the hospital,
or she's having
this baby in my car.
Either way, I was gonna
go home and tell my kids,
"Your daddy was a hero today."
How'd it get from that to,
like, everybody's dying?
Yeah. It happens.
Yeah. Sucks, is what it does.
That's not the point, genius.
Your little testosterone
game could've cost him his life!
Is that what you wanted? To
kill someone over a stupid game?
Excuse me.
- Is there a problem here?
- No problem.
Wait here for your studies.
You think I could
get her number?
Shut up.
- You sure you're okay?
- I'm awesome.
Have you heard anything else?
About Karev? About
how long he's gonna be...
- Why would I know that?
- I don't... I just...
Listen, if you need anything,
if there's anything I can do...
I need to finish
working up my patient.
Right.
You should go on the website.
I have been on the website.
I've been all over the website.
That's why I came here to
talk to someone in person.
Can you please help me?
- Please?
- Give me the info.
It's Karev.
- Where's the Social?
- I'm sorry?
The Social Security
Number. It's not on here.
I don't have that.
Next in line.
- Wait. Is there any other...
- Yeah. Go on the website.
Next in line.
We need to get
that baby out, ASAP.
No problem. I've
actually assisted on
- several emergency C-sections.
- You'll take my lead.
Sounds like the perfect
reason to let Murphy jump in.
Dr. Minnick, hi.
I heard about your trauma.
I'm gonna pop in there, okay?
- That would be amazing.
- No, thanks.
And, apparently, we need to
hire a new Peds Surgery Chief.
Seems ours went up the river.
Murphy, can you go make sure
that Mindy is set up in the scanner?
You're not welcome on my case.
I'm not actually
asking. It's my job.
I'm actually telling
you. It's my patient.
And your patient is
my student's classroom.
That seems like a
very distasteful way
of referring to a woman who
just suffered a medical trauma
giving birth to a baby. Whose
name is Mindy, by the way.
And Richard Webber,
he's a friend of mine,
so you can stay the
hell away from my OR.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Aren't those Bryan
Wallace's head CTs?
Yeah. Yeah. I
can't tell if this is
a subtle intraventricular
hemorrhage or artifact,
so thought I'd run it
up to the third floor,
see if I can get a
neuro consult on the fly.
- Right.
- Shouldn't take long.
So, if you can't find
me, that's where I am.
Barely missed his eye.
Could've even
severed his parotid duct.
We'll see more
once we get in there.
Dr. Avery, how are you?
Dr. Minnick. First day?
Officially. I'm just going to
tour the ORs to get my feet wet.
This the hockey kid
that got the worst of it?
Yeah, yeah. He took
a stick to the neck
and a skate to the face.
Full facial deglovement.
Wow. Dr. Warren, right?
Have you ever had
one of those before?
- No.
- But I bet you've done a hand.
The method we're using now,
we can teach Warren
how to build on the skills
that he has already
learned, and he'll go faster...
- It's not a hand.
- I know.
- I think she means...
- It's a face. It's his face.
This is this young man's
future we're talking about,
his entrance into the
room, his hello to this world.
It's his first impression
on employers,
his glance across a crowded
bar at his future spouse.
I am saving the thing
his mother loves the most.
- Wow. You're fancy.
- And you just want to waltz
in here
and have our young
surgeons practice on all of that?
Because what?
'Cause he did a hand?
- Are you kidding?
- Then when will he learn?
On another surgery,
or two, or three maybe.
Not on this one.
You know what, Warren?
Why don't you just cover the pit?
I'll have Mitchell assist.
Does anyone ever
get taught around here?
We'll say hi, and then you'll
go out before they intubate her.
How do I tell her?
How do I tell her
this is all my fault?
You don't. Not now. You
wait till you get your baby
and Mindy's safely out of surgery,
and then we take it from there.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
Yeah. Thank you.
- Hey, you.
- Hey.
- This is not how we
pictured, huh? No.
- Nope.
- There's gonna be blood.
- I know.
- Okay. Don't faint.
He's squeamish, in a big way.
I'm... I'll be fine.
Say hi to her for me,
okay? Oh, honey, your face.
What happened?
I'm so sorry.
- What? Why?
- It was me.
In the other car. I hit you.
- What?
- It's all my fault.
- Okay, Bryan,
we need to get started.
- No, wait, wait...
Mindy, you're gonna
feel a little drowsy...
Mindy, I'm so sorry.
I love you so much.
It was you?
Okay. Let's have a baby.
- Dr. Webber, how are you?
- Ah, there she is.
How's that first day?
I'm actually having trouble,
finding my way into ORs.
Everyone seems
to have full tables
or patients so dire, they
can't afford extra people.
Dr. Robbins,
Dr. Riggs, Dr. Inaba...
Tough breaks.
Was there a problem
with the way I arranged
the board this morning?
You used lower-case letters.
So? It's still legible.
It's a little passive-aggressive,
don't you think?
We prefer caps.
Chief Bailey told me to handle
the OR board as I see fit today.
- Is that right?
- It is.
Then, I'll leave you to it.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
He took the pen.
Oh, man.
It's all right, Bryan.
Get ready to meet your girl,
because here she comes.
- No. No, no.
- I got to get in there. Robbins?
- Pack her uterus. Metz?
- Bryan, you need to go.
Baby looks a little
cyanotic. Can you put her
under the warmer and
see if she perks up?
Why isn't she crying?
Get him out of here! Right angle.
Robbins, pass me the vessel loop.
- What is it?
- Bryan, your baby's
having a little trouble
breathing, but it's okay.
And we need to control your
wife's bleeding from the trauma.
If you can't ventilate, then
you need to get her intubated,
get her up to the NICU,
and get a full work-up.
Mosquito. Hang two more units.
- Oh, God. Oh, God!
- Somebody get him out of here!
Hey! I'm here for
about two minutes.
Here are the scans
that you asked for.
You know...
You said you were taking a
leave. You can actually take a leave.
- These are the dad's?
- Yeah. Closed-head trauma.
CT looked clear,
but then I saw this.
Yeah, I see what you mean. How
is his family? Is the baby okay?
God! They just wanted a happy
ending, and boom, ran into each other.
No, this is just
artifact. CT's clear.
Good. And this is the driver's.
- You had the yogurt?
- Yeah, I was hungry.
He's good, too.
I think Dr. Hunt knows.
I had to lie to him,
and that feels...
I'm sorry. I will go to a hotel.
This is unfair. I know.
It's a terrible imposition.
No, it's fine. You... Hmm.
It's not a big deal. You
are welcome. It's just...
That was my last yogurt.
- I will go to a hotel.
- Just go to a store.
He looks miserable and
he's scared to death for you,
and I don't want to lie to
your husband anymore,
so can I just tell him
something, please?
- No.
- What?
Because he will try to
fix it. And it can't be fixed.
Okay. Okay.
Thank you.
Give me the PTFE
graft and 5-0 prolene.
That is exactly what
I was talking about.
- Mayos.
- I could've told you
exactly how that would play out.
I know, I was here.
I didn't think you could make
it any worse for that poor guy...
Just stop it, Pierce, please!
DeBakey pickups.
Dr. Robbins, chest X-rays show
their baby has a
diaphragmatic hernia.
All right, is she intubated?
Yeah, but still de-satting.
All right, let's put her on
ECMO. Have a 5-0 ready.
Go, Murphy.
- You're not coming?
- No.
I have to make sure
that this baby's mother
- doesn't bleed to death.
- I've never put a baby on ECMO.
Call the peds surgeon that's
on call and get help, figure it out.
You can do this, okay? Go!
Scissors?
Hey. Hey, buddy.
I haven't heard anything
about your pregnant lady yet.
Cool, yeah, thanks, but, this
dude, is this guy breathing funny?
Damn it.
Damn it!
He dropped a lung. Can
I get a nurse over here?
I need an X-ray
and chest-tube tray!
And set up for intubation!
Has anybody seen Wilson?
Is the baby on ECMO?
Did you get help?
I found someone to help
me, but she's still unstable.
There's too much pressure
on the mediastinum.
She's not oxygenating
or perfusing well
despite the heart-lung bypass.
And she's still... Hang on.
- Another clamp.
- Hang more FFP. Right angle.
Dr. Robbins, this
baby's tanking.
I think we need to
get her into the OR.
Who's with you?
Barton.
Barton's no good for this.
- You should go.
- I need to be here.
No, you don't.
Hey, you didn't do this.
A car did this.
I need to be two
people. I need Alex.
Alex isn't here.
Go. I've got this.
- I'm ready to go.
- Hey! Hey, hey! Hey, hey, stop!
We thought we'd
get her ready to go.
We've tried everything.
She's just too sick.
Yeah, you're right
about that one.
- All right, should we move?
- No, we don't have time.
Betadine and drape her. All
right, start prepping the room!
Let's get some gowns
and gloves in here!
- What are you doing?
- You're right.
She's too sick to move. I need a
surgical tray right here, right now!
It's Karev, K-A-R-E-V.
Nope. He's not in the
computer. I don't have him.
Okay, so, can we call
around to some other jails?
Sure. Because this
is Saks Fifth Avenue.
Okay. Right.
Okay, thanks.
Sterilization team
to OR Recovery.
Hey.
Hey, Bryan Wallace's head
CT is clear. I just discharged him.
- Who'd you find
to take a look at it?
- Dr. Morton.
Oh.
Bryan asked me for an
update on his wife and baby,
- so I'm heading up there now.
- Okay.
- Hey, how about the cab driver?
- Yeah, she cleared him, too.
She? I thought you
said it was Morton.
He, I mean.
Anyway, cab driver's
clear. I told Warren.
Find me when you get the update.
We'll go talk to Bryan together.
- Yep.
- Yeah.
What happened?
Rib fractures must've
punctured a lung.
Anything more
from the chest tube?
Bleeding slowed down.
Only 400 cc's in the pleurovac.
Yeah, we'll need
to stabilize his ribs.
In the OR I'll join you.
And before you tell me no,
I spent all day rearranging
my schedule, thanks to you.
I was hired here to do a
job, and I think it's time...
I would love to have you.
- What?
- Warren, book an OR.
Okay, you see here, Warren?
This rib punctured the lung.
Why doesn't hockey
just ban the fighting?
Are you kidding? It's part
of the game, the good part.
You got to shake up the other
team or get your own team going.
Garth is the enforcer.
Now, his job is to go in,
take out the skills player,
upset the other team.
- Seems he's pretty good at it.
- Fights can be strategic, too.
A fight can change momentum,
clear the air, break a stalemate.
It also rallies the team
against a common enemy.
Well, this is fascinating.
And I thought, I was just
gonna learn about surgery.
No, Dr. Warren, it's me
who's being schooled tonight.
Isn't that why you
allowed me into an OR?
I just wanted to see how
you "deal with a Dr. Webber."
You don't want to
have this fight, sir.
Someone always tries to,
and they always get on
board or get left behind.
You said fighting is
the good part, right?
Well, I hope you meant it.
Hey, how goes the battle
for hearts and minds?
Well, change doesn't
happen overnight.
Well, that sounds like someone
who's won no hearts or minds.
It's always hard at
first. They push back.
Eventually, everyone
gets on the same page.
That's not how it works in
my hospital. I'll call a meeting.
Dr. Bailey, you're only
going to make this harder...
This is not a fight you
should be having, Dr. Minnick.
I'll call a meeting.
You do this a lot? Get a
10 French chest tube ready.
Major surgery on a
newborn, right here?
The baby would die on the elevator.
And the mom might already be...
So we need to go, all right?
Let's just... Let's do this.
Scalpel.
Murphy, you gonna
assist or what?
Dr. Pierce was able to stop
Mindy's internal bleeding.
She's closing her right now.
What does that mean?
When can I see her? Is she...
When will she wake up?
- Will she wake up?
- We don't know.
- We have to see
how she responds.
- Oh, God!
And the baby?
Dr. Robbins has
asked me to tell you...
- your baby is in surgery.
- Surgery?
- Is she okay?
- As soon as we know anything...
I was in a baby store
when I got the call.
Isn't that weird?
I just bought her
this tiny little hat.
It was the first thing I
ever picked out for her.
It's like, this morning, I knew
what my future was, you know?
And, now...
I might not have
a baby. Or a wife.
Or what if she wakes up
and doesn't forgive me?
What if she never
wants to see me again?
Is she okay? Is she
sober? Just tell me that.
She's safe.
You don't have to worry.
Tell her to come home.
Tell her it'll be
fine, and we'll be...
Just tell her to come home.
She's onto us.
- Already?
- Yeah.
Damn it! We have
to escalate the plan.
Hey, you guys get this
e-mail from the Chief?
What?
- "Emergency meeting"?
- Yeah, it's to all the
attendings.
Except me.
What's our next step?
I have an idea.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
She's gonna be okay? Really?
Yeah. It was a good
repair, and I do a lot of them.
Thank God!
Thank God, she's okay.
Bryan...
Mindy's injuries were much
worse than they could have been
because her feet were
up on the dashboard, and...
Yeah, they said, the airbag...
I told her to put them up there.
The baby was coming,
and she was in a lot of pain,
and... And I asked her to put
her feet up on the dashboard
to relieve the
pressure. But I didn't...
I didn't mean to make it
worse. I did not mean to hurt her.
You didn't. You were
just trying to help.
You didn't hurt her. I did.
You were trying to get to her, to
get to them both. You were just...
You were trying to get here.
Okay?
Okay.
They're just...
ten minutes late.
But all of them?
- Where are they?
- I have no idea.
Operating, teaching, molding
the surgeons of tomorrow.
Or maybe just sending a message.
Oh, they've been sending
their message all day.
Dr. Minnick, will you excuse us?
No, please. I'll
see you tomorrow.
Okay.
- So, this is mutiny.
- Call it what you want.
Why are you doing this?
You yourself said you
like Minnick's approach.
It's not what you're doing.
It's how you've done it.
It's too abrupt. The
program suffers.
Butt-hurt.
- I beg your pardon?
- You're butt-hurt.
That's what Tuck
calls it when you get
all bent out of shape and mopey
over something you shouldn't
because you're embarrassed.
You're forcing a change
nobody asked for.
This is not about my butt.
- You really want to do this?
- I haven't done anything...
You really want
to do this to me?
- Look, Bailey, it's not just me.
- It's not just you.
People are angry about
your treatment of me,
about your direction of this
program. It was a bad call.
And you can walk it back.
People also felt the need
for change and adaptation.
People recognized that,
the way we've always done it,
isn't always the best way,
and that a fresh perspective
doesn't have to be a threat!
So, I'm gonna walk on!
"People", huh? Who?
It's not just me.
Sir, I signed your
discharge papers.
- You're good to go.
- Oh, yeah. No, I...
I just kind of wanted to know
how that family made out.
'Cause I can't just go home
and wonder, you know?
- It's still a question mark. Sorry.
- Oh. Damn.
- Okay. Thanks. Night.
- Night.
Hey! Sir? Sir.
That kid in the bed next to you,
the one who couldn't breathe?
The hockey player?
Yeah. Yeah, well, it turns out,
that he had internal bleeding.
Would've killed him
if you hadn't caught it.
You saved that kid's life.
- For real?
- For real.
Woo-hoo!
Our heroes aren't
special. They're just people.
They're like us. They're
just trying to survive.
Uh... Hunt wants
you to come home.
- How'd that family turn out?
- Good.
She's not out of
the woods yet, but...
everyone's still alive.
Good. That's good.
Good. I'm gonna
turn in, if that's all right.
Good night.
They're trying to be happy.
Trying to do better,
be better, feel better.
Hey, Dr. Robbins, wait up.
Hey, Dr. Minnick,
I've been awake for more
than 48 hours, so I'm gonna...
This'll just take a second.
- I wanted to thank you.
- What?
Murphy told me you let her run
with that baby from the trauma.
That's the spirit. That's really
putting my method to work.
Good to have you on board.
Good night.
Heroes aren't more special, more
courageous than the rest of us.
After all, they're only human.
You're not okay.
- What?
- That hockey kid today?
He dropped a lung.
We had to take him up to
the OR. Where were you?
I was in Path. I was
getting a culture.
Come on. You've been
in your head all day.
It's fine, 'cause I covered
for you, but talk to someone.
- Work it out.
- What do you need, Warren?
Do you need me to be fragile?
Do you need me to fall apart?
- Come on, now.
- Would that help you?
Because you keep looking
at me with your eyes all soft
like you want to help me, you
want to make me feel better.
I don't need to feel better. I
don't need your sympathy.
Stuff like this happens,
and I am built for it.
I'm fine. Leave me alone.
They hurt, they
break, they bleed.
Hey.
You okay?
- Is it a patient?
- No.
But, yeah. Yeah, that, too.
- Do you want to talk about it?
- I can't.
It's nothing that you
wanna hear about.
Okay.
I miss Alex.
And I know that that's not
fair to say to you, but it's true.
I hate that he's
gone. I just... I hate it.
But sometimes,
every once in a while...
What?
When it matters,
they get it right,
and that changes everything.
Hey. Anything?
Three counties, four jails,
nothing. No one will tell me anything.
Maybe, they're
still processing him?
You'll find out tomorrow
what happened.
I know what happened. He's
gone. That's what happened.
A hero is only human,
but that's the point.
If they can do it, so can you.
- Did Owen find Amelia?
- Amelia?
Where's Amelia?
Where is everybody?
I'm dirty. I stink. I need
to wash off this day.
So, you keep going.
You don't give up.
You stand tall. You fight.
- What the hell, Mer?
- Alex? Alex?
You always show
up to save the day.
Oh.
Wait. I've been
looking for you all day.
I've been here.
I've been sleeping.
- All day?
- All day.