Hey, we're going to 152.
On the right.
Got it.
Okay, Craig,
you take over the bagging.
Got it.
Lacerated forehead,
possible crushed airway.
Jeff, dispatch said
mass casualty.
Only been on site
a few minutes,
but it's at least
a dozen vehicles,
maybe more.
We need help
over here!
Here, here, here,
come here, come here.
My teeth.
Come here. Gauze!
I've lost my teeth!
Here you go.
Okay, bite down, bite down.
Hold the pressure.
All right, here.
Let's move over here.
There you go.
Lay down.
Casey has just
radioed in.
They're popping
the windshield
on a minivan.
Need medical on site.
Red, 30 yards in,
eye of the pileup.
We're on it.
Go.
Jeff.
I'm with you.
Yo,
bag that strip in, got it?
Got it.
Choi, got a family of four
trapped inside.
Lot of intrusion
on the vehicle.
All polytrauma.
All right, we're on it.
Adam...
I got it.
My son. Save him.
My son.
All right,
we're gonna get you all
out of here, all right?
Help my boys. Please.
Help them, please.
Bleeding head lac.
Transected his
temporal artery.
Give me two hemostats.
I've gotta clamp it off.
Copy.
All right,
I'm on the boys.
Hang in there, guys.
Almost there, guys.
Help my boys, please.
Help... Help my...
Hey, Adam, EVC collar.
You're gonna be okay.
Jeff, what do you got?
I got some
serious leg damage.
Possible abdominal injuries.
Let's give them
some morphine.
Can you get a read
on body weight?
I don't know,
60, 65 pounds each.
Push 4 milligrams IM.
I got it.
All right,
just take it easy.
Just take it easy.
Bleeding's under control.
Let's get him out of here.
Got it.
Hang in there, guys.
I'm gonna give you something
to make you feel better,
all right?
Place two 16-gauges
on the right,
and let them know
he's red-tagged.
Jeff, stay with the kids!
I got you!
Clear!
All right. Back up!
All right.
He needs oxygen!
Need a backboard!
All right, sir, we're gonna
get you out of here.
Sir, can you hear me?
Try to stay calm, okay?
One, two, three.
Pick him up.
All right,
you're doing really good...
Oh, God.
Hey, I need
a little help over here!
Pregnant woman!
Hey, you there?
Hey, a little help
over here! Hey!
Okay, everyone, listen up.
Glad you made it in.
It wasn't easy.
We've got
a predawn pileup.
Multiple traumas
en route.
White-out conditions,
staff snowed in at home,
no supplies coming in.
We need to make do
with who
and what we've
got on hand.
All right, Dr. Manning
and Halstead,
let's decompress the ED.
Anyone who's stable
kicks back into
the waiting area.
Copy.
Dr. Wheeler,
be ready to glove up.
Got it.
April, we need
every room we've got.
Let's clear the hallways,
supply rooms,
anywhere we can fit a bed.
Let's go, people.
On it.
Uh, Doris, put out
a hospital-wide alert,
and page the triage team.
Okay.
Back to the waiting room?
I've already waited an hour.
I apologize, Mr. Kellogg,
but we'll get to you
as soon as we can,
all right?
What is the only
indication for AVR
in an asymptomatic patient
with severe stenosis?
Left ventricular
systolic dysfunction.
Correct, Dr. Bardovi.
This patient is stable.
Close his incision.
Why?
We are expecting an influx
of trauma patients.
Per emergency protocol,
you and I will be
in charge of triage.
We need to ensure that
operating rooms are available
to the most
critical patients.
This man is not
one of them.
Close him up.
Yes, Doctor.
All right, look alive!
Here we go! Incoming!
Thirty-eight-year-old male.
Pulled from his minivan.
Mom and two kids
are on the way.
Here's the triage team.
GCS 12, hypotensive.
Clamped his temporal artery,
belly's distended.
All right, he's surgical.
Stabilize him,
and get him up to the OR.
Dr. Manning?
Got it.
All right. Dr. Choi.
Forty-year-old male, GCS 15,
satting 90% on a face mask.
Dr. Halstead?
Got it.
No, I got this one.
Severe burn.
Make him warm, comfortable,
and move on.
There's nothing more
you can do.
Naïma?
Sixty-three-year-old female.
Went through the windshield.
Triple zeros,
down for nearly 20 minutes.
Stand down.
Coming from a vehicle with
a high-deceleration injury.
Most likely a torn aorta.
We can't be sure.
Regardless,
asystole for 20 minutes.
This is not
a survivable injury.
Hold compressions.
Wait, let's
warm her up first.
Dr. Rhodes,
understand that today
we need to focus
our efforts on patients
with the best chance
of survival.
Please.
I need Helene. My wife.
Mr. Winter, we'll find her.
Just try to relax.
He needs an IO.
Mr. Winter,
I'm gonna have trouble
finding a vein.
I need to put
an IV in your leg.
It'll only take a second.
Dr. Choi,
what are you doing?
Putting in an IO.
Can I speak
with you?
Hang on one second.
I'm almost...
Now.
I'm in.
He's 95% TBSA.
Calculate his fluid
based on Parkland,
and run everything
through the warmer.
Copy.
I thought I told you
to make him comfortable
and move on.
Dr. Latham, standing by
while a patient dies
is not in my
job description.
He has full thickness burns
over 90% of his body.
There is no chance
of recovery.
He's awake, talking,
lucid, not in any pain.
As you well know,
he's not in pain,
because his cutaneous nerves
have been destroyed
by the burn.
Very soon, his organs
will begin to shut down.
He is going to die.
And treating him
will only take
resources away
from patients who have
a chance of survival.
Maggie!
Jeffrey.
Twenty-six-year-old female,
found passed out in the snow.
Thirty-five weeks pregnant.
Vitals stable.
Dr. Wheeler,
you're going to
Treatment Two.
Got it.
Stop.
Green is not
the proper designation.
An expectant mother
always takes priority.
Is my baby gonna be okay?
Don't worry, we're gonna
make sure both of you
are taken care of.
Okay.
I'll get some blankets.
On my count.
One, two, three.
They said you lost
consciousness.
Do you know
what happened?
I don't remember.
It all happened so fast.
I saw a cut on my arm,
and I went for help.
Next thing I know,
they're bringing me here.
Oh, your vitals look good.
What about my baby?
I'm checking now.
Baby's heartbeat
is strong.
Dr. Wheeler,
traumas are coming in hot.
You done here?
Uh, let's get her undressed,
and put her on
a fetal monitor.
Everything looks good.
I'll be back soon.
Pulled from the minivan.
This is Mom, Susan,
38 years old, GCS 15.
Right arm fracture,
complaining of back pain.
Son and nephew
are coming in behind us.
My husband, Blake.
How is he?
We've sent him up
to the OR already.
Belly's clear.
Get her to CT for
head and TLS spine.
Make sure there are
no vertebral fractures.
Take care of the boys.
We will.
Nine-year-old nephew, Josh.
GCS 15, vitals stable.
Got pinned in the backseat.
Bilateral femoral fractures,
one open.
His parents are
traveling abroad.
He's been staying
with his aunt and uncle.
All right, Dr. Manning?
Yep.
Hi, I'm Dr. Manning.
I'm gonna take
good care of you, okay?
Mmm-hmm.
I'm gonna give her
a hand.
All right, you're
going to Treatment Five.
Yep.
Talk to me.
Benjamin,
10-year-old son, GCS 15.
Abdominal pain,
mildly hypotensive
from possible blood loss.
Systolic, 100 over palp.
Dr. Halstead, red tag.
April.
You're going to
Treatment Four.
My hips! My hips!
Hang in there, champ.
We're gonna get you fixed up.
Four. Here.
Okay.
Okay, on my count.
One, two, three.
Thank you, gentlemen.
Breath sounds clear
and present bilaterally.
Hang another liter of saline
on the level one.
Yep.
How'd you get
to be so strong?
You're doing great.
Chest and belly clear.
Okay, honey.
BP 86 over 47.
Heart rate 135.
I know, I know.
Okay, okay, that's it,
just breathe.
Unstable pelvis
and hypotensive.
Close it down to
stop the bleeding?
Yeah, grab a sheet.
I need some help in here!
What do you need?
This might hurt.
Give him 25 mics
of fentanyl.
Copy.
Okay, honey. Okay.
All right, all right.
Okay,
make sure it's tight.
Okay. Fine.
Heart rate's coming down.
Bleeding's temporized
for now.
Let's get X-rays.
Chest and pelvis.
Let me know the second
there's an opening in
interventional radiology.
We need to embolize
the bleed.
Got it.
Chest and abdomen
are clear.
Cold foot. I can't get
a pulse on this leg.
Fracture's probably kinking
the femoral artery.
We've gotta
reduce this now.
Let's push
2 milligrams of Versed
and 25 mics fentanyl.
Okay, Josh,
we're gonna have to do
something right now,
and I need you to be
so brave for me.
Can you do that?
Yeah?
Uh-huh.
Are you ready?
All right,
one, two, three.
It's all done. That's it.
It's over. Great job.
All right. Get
a post-mold splint on him.
Page Ortho. He's gonna
need surgery to wash out
and ex-fix that fracture
as soon as
we can get an OR.
Are you all right?
Okay, can you keep
being brave like that?
Dr. Rhodes.
You are so brave.
So brave.
What happened?
I don't know.
She was alert and talking
a few minutes ago.
No pulse.
All right,
Clarke, intubate her.
April,
a milligram of epi.
On it.
Wheeler, get on
her chest now.
She's hemorrhaging.
Abruption from
the trauma?
That might explain
just a vaginal bleed,
but not this.
She's bleeding
around her IV.
Dr. Rhodes.
All right, likely
an amniotic
fluid embolism.
Impact from
the accident forced
amniotic fluid
into her bloodstream,
disrupted her
clotting factors.
Trigger the MTP.
We need to get
this baby out now.
Page OB?
No, there's no time.
We've got about four
minutes to deliver,
or we're gonna
lose her and the baby.
Tube's in.
Take over bagging.
Yes, Doctor.
All right,
splash prep her abdomen.
Give me the knife.
Clarke, pull.
There we go.
It's a girl.
April, cut the cord.
Clarke, start packing
her abdomen.
On it.
Got it.
Okay.
The baby looks good.
April,
let's get her up
to the NICU.
On my way.
Okay.
All right, Wheeler,
hold compressions.
She's in v-fib.
Paddles.
Charge to 200.
Charge.
No.
Charge again.
Charge.
Clear.
Sinus tach, BP 70 over 33,
heart rate 130, oxygen 95%.
Set up a neo drip
at a 100 mics.
100 mics.
She looks like she's lost
about three liters.
How much have we given her?
Two packed red blood cells,
one FFP, two cryo.
Second batch is on its way
with more blood and cryo.
All right.
She's still bleeding.
Tell the blood bank
to keep sending us O-neg.
We'll finish
packing her here,
and then
we'll send her up to OB,
so they can close her.
Right.
Hey, Mr. Winter.
How are you feeling?
Cold.
That's to be expected.
The damage to your skin
caused you to lose heat.
We have another warmer
coming in for you.
Mr. Winter.
You're in burn shock.
Your organs are gonna
shut down soon.
I'm...
I'm dying?
Yes.
Keep me alive till
my wife gets here.
I wanna say goodbye.
We'll do everything we can.
Mr. Winter, your airways
are starting to swell.
We need to intubate you,
put you on a ventilator.
But I won't be able...
To talk.
When your wife gets here,
I'll remove the tube,
and you'll be...
And you'll be able
to say goodbye.
Twenty of etomidate
and 15 of rocuronium.
All right,
now for waiting room drama.
His name is Jack Kellogg.
Came in for
a Xanax refill.
How long you have
to wait around here?
Got bumped from
his treatment room.
Doesn't seem like
an emergency to me.
He's fine...
Might just be
hunting for drugs.
But if you think differently,
I'll send him upstairs.
Did he threaten to hurt
anybody or himself?
No. He's just
a pain in the ass.
I'll talk to him.
All right.
Mr. Kellogg.
I'm Dr. Charles.
I've been waiting
for over two hours.
Nobody cares.
I'm just a number.
I'm very sorry.
We have a major pileup
on the highway, and we're
in a triage situation...
It's not my problem.
Okay. Well, what seems
to be the trouble?
Cut the crap, all right?
"Blah, blah, blah."
I'm out of my meds.
Did you call your doctor?
He's out.
Why else would I be here?
How hard is it for you
to write me a prescription?
Well, we wanna make sure
you get the right medication,
the proper dosage.
Dr. Charles...
Could you hold on
a second?
I'm sorry,
but there's an emergency
in the psych ward.
A patient attacked a nurse.
They need you.
Mr. Kellogg,
I'm very sorry.
We are gonna take
excellent care of you,
but you're gonna have
to wait a little bit longer.
Oh, for God's sake.
I will be right back,
and I'm gonna make you one
of our first priorities.
"First priority."
Yeah, sure.
Look at me!
I'm a human being.
I'm a human being!
A human being!
Should we put him
on a psych hold?
No, he's not dangerous,
just pissed off.
Daniel, we're slammed
and short personnel.
I need to pull
Dr. Reese off your service
and put her to work here.
Go to it.
Reese, with me.
Okay.
Heart rate's 150,
BP 70 over 40.
What are his injuries?
Femoral fractures
in both legs.
Lots of soft tissue
injuries.
Looks like bilateral
thigh hematomas.
So, blood's
accumulating in his legs.
We need to transfuse him.
Yes, but first let's get
a liter of lactated ringers,
dopamine at 10,
titrate to
systolic BP of 90.
Maggie, need
some help in here!
Coming!
Blood pressure's
coming up, 80 over 50.
90 over 60.
He's stable for now.
Call up to the blood bank,
and tell them
we need two units of
O-negative for this boy.
I need the same
for his cousin
in the next room.
Okay, hold on.
You're both gonna have to talk
to Ms. Goodwin about this.
Because of
emergency surgeries,
and a pregnant mother's
serious bleeding disorder,
we have used almost
all of our O-negative.
We can either treat
Benjamin or Josh,
but not both.
Benjamin needs an angio
embolization more urgently
than Josh needs surgery.
How can you say that?
Josh isn't compensating
for his blood loss as well.
He's in worse shape.
I understand you're trying
to protect your patient,
but you're being
emotional.
"Emotional"?
And what are you being?
Our recommendation
needs to be based solely
on clinical criteria.
So I'm handing it over
to the triage team.
Dr. Rhodes,
your opinion?
I have to agree
with Dr. Halstead
that Benjamin needs
angio embolization
more urgently than
Josh needs surgery.
Not the issue.
We're here to decide
who has the best chance
of survival, so...
Unfortunately,
even if Benjamin gets
the embolization,
there's only a 15% chance
that the bleeding in
his pelvis will stop.
Exactly.
Whereas with
Dr. Manning's patient,
as the pressure in
his thighs builds,
the bleeding will
eventually slow.
Worst case,
Josh loses a leg,
but there is no question
he has the best chance of
survival.
I don't understand.
We're very sorry.
But it's up
to you to decide which of
the boys gets the blood.
Decide who gets the blood?
The doctors have
their opinion,
but it is a decision
you and your husband
should make,
and he's still in surgery.
But, without blood,
is one of them gonna die?
It is a possibility,
but we are gonna do
whatever we can to
prevent that.
And you want me to
decide between my son
and my sister's?
But how?
Our recommendation
is to give the blood
to your nephew, Josh.
Josh? Why?
Because he has
the greater chance
of survival.
That means Ben...
We are gonna do
our best to keep him alive
until we have more blood.
How can you make me
do this?
I can't.
If you'd prefer,
we can make the decision
on your behalf.
Mrs. Porter, I assure you,
we will do what's medically
and ethically correct.
You'll be all right.
No, no, stay still.
Dr. Rhodes, I hear
we're running
out of O-neg.
No, we have
run out of O-neg.
Wait.
Is this because of
the woman with the
amniotic fluid embolism?
Partly, yes.
Dr. Rhodes!
She didn't present with
any of the symptoms.
No hypotension,
shortness of
breath, chills...
Wheeler,
nobody's blaming you.
I understand.
We're going to do
all we can.
Leah, there was
a fella out here before,
a Mr. Kellogg?
That guy.
Yeah, did you see
what happened to him?
Stormed out. Said
he was tired of waiting.
You should've
heard the language.
I don't appreciate being
talked to like that.
Yeah.
His color's
already improving.
Heart rate's down to 119.
BP's up, 118 over 84.
Albumin and platelets
aren't gonna cut it.
That kid needs blood.
I know.
Hey.
We've contacted
Mr. Winter's wife.
She's doing her best
to get here.
Mr. Winter,
did you hear that?
BP's down to 80 over 40.
Hey. Hey.
Hang in there.
Hey.
How's Mr. Winter?
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
And I'm sorry
to have to tell you this,
but we're out of ventilators.
No.
We've got emergency cases
who are coming out of
surgery who need them.
The only choice we've got
is to take them from
our terminal patients.
I can't.
That ventilator's not
gonna save his life, Ethan.
You know that.
All he wants is
to stay alive long enough
to say goodbye to his wife.
She's trying to get here.
Man, I understand.
Look, in the field,
so many times,
a wounded soldier will
call out for a loved one,
a mother, a wife.
There's nothing
I could do.
Come on, man.
Let's give this man
his dying wish.
I'm sorry, man.
I can do it for you.
I can take him off
the ventilator myself.
No.
He's my patient.
I will.
Mr. Winter.
As you know,
your condition is going
to continue to deteriorate.
I'm sorry,
but the hospital is in
an emergency situation,
and I've just been informed
that I need to disconnect
you from this ventilator.
It's needed for other
patients who have a better
chance of surviving.
I know.
Here's what I can do.
I can help you
breathe manually,
until your wife
gets here, all right?
April, pull the ventilator.
Yeah.
I'll bag him myself.
Thank you, Doris.
I just told Dr. Choi
to take his patient
off the ventilator.
Hmm. Right.
Dr. Latham,
don't you feel anything?
Do you mean, am I empathetic?
Do I feel what others feel?
Dr. Rhodes,
one can lack empathy,
but still feel compassion.
Sarah.
You liking psychiatry?
Uh, parts of it.
Yeah.
I'm thinking
about psychiatry.
I'm not sure the ED
is the best fit.
Um, let me ask you
something.
Day's got me
a little stressed.
Could you write me
a prescription for
KlonoPlN?
Um...
Don't you have
your own doctor?
Actually, no. Uh,
I never felt the need.
I only want a few pills.
You know, take the edge off.
Jason, I'm sorry, but
I'd have to ask Dr. Charles.
Really?
Hey, you know what,
never mind.
I didn't mean to
put you on the spot.
It's no big deal.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I'll be fine.
Forget I asked.
Uh-huh.
Uh-huh. Wait, do you wanna
talk to his resident?
Wait, he's right here.
Dr. Charles,
the brother of the patient
that you saw in
the waiting room.
The one who left?
Oh, Jack Kellogg, great.
Mmm-hmm.
This is Dr. Charles.
Please tell your
brother that I'm...
What?
I am...
I'm so very...
Uh...
Is there anything
that we can...
Hello?
Jack Kellogg shot himself.
He's dead.
Dr. Charles?
I changed lanes.
Next thing I know,
we were hit.
Truck came
out of nowhere.
I'm just glad
you're okay.
What about the boys?
They're both at the hospital
and receiving treatment.
Thank God.
Josh broke his legs,
and Benjamin suffered
a pelvic fracture.
Pelvis?
You can fix that, right?
I'm afraid it's
a bit more complicated
than that, Mr. Porter.
Both boys lost a lot
of blood, and both
needed transfusions.
However, the accident
combined with the storm
created a shortage.
We only had enough
for one.
For one?
Honey, please... It was
an impossible choice.
I don't understand.
What are you saying?
You gave the blood to Josh?
She didn't.
We did.
We decided that Josh had
the best chance of survival.
"Survival"?
What about Benny?
We are doing
everything that we can,
but he needs blood.
Okay, I'll donate.
I'm sorry, sir.
But neither you nor
your wife are a match.
You must've
approved this.
I...
I can't believe it.
You should've made them
give the blood to Ben.
Josh, he's my sister's son.
How could I just...
So you're okay with
letting our own son die?
What kind of mother are you?
I cannot imagine
the difficulty this must
be for the two of you,
but again, we are doing
everything that we can.
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
Sixteen critical,
twenty-four stable,
seven treated and released.
All remaining have
been accounted for
and assigned their
proper designation.
Thank you, Dr. Latham.
Ms. Goodwin, if Benjamin
doesn't get blood soon,
he's not gonna make it.
Dr. Manning,
we discussed this.
I know,
but I have an idea.
So, let's adjust her
Ativan to Q2-hours,
and with Q4-hour vitals.
See if that doesn't
calm her down.
Yes, Doctor.
Dr. Charles.
Um, about what happened
with that patient...
Yeah, that
was unfortunate.
No, what I mean, um,
is there was no way
you could've known.
It's emergency medicine,
Dr. Reese.
We make
these evaluations
very quickly,
and these kind
of things happen.
Of course.
I was just concerned
because of your history.
Oh.
Look, I have lost patients
to suicide before, and
I undoubtedly will again.
I appreciate your concern,
but it's just the cost
of doing business.
Oh.
Okay.
Thank you.
Good.
Okay.
Hey.
Came as soon as I could.
Yeah. Replenishing the bank,
and hoping to find
a match for your patient.
Dr. Halstead jumps to
the front of the line.
Done.
Thank you, Maggie.
Don't thank me.
Thank her.
It was her idea.
Paramedics just brought
in a hemothorax.
Dr. Rhodes needs you
to put in a chest tube.
What about his wife?
Have we heard anything?
She's stuck in the storm,
still trying to get here.
Then ask Dr. Rhodes to have
one of the other residents
do it.
Dr. Choi...
He just needs
a little more time.
I'm so sorry.
Time of death, 15:37.
BP's down,
heart rate's up to 152.
We could add
another presser.
He's peri-arrest.
His heart's working
to compensate.
We've tried every
stopgap we have.
Without oxygen-rich
red blood cells,
I'm afraid
there's nothing more
we can do for him.
Ms. Goodwin, we typed
a few universal donors
in the doctors' lounge.
What is taking so long?
Everything has to go
through the lab.
If we transfuse blood
that hasn't been screened
for HIV and hepatitis,
we are in direct violation
of FDA guidelines.
We'll just have to wait.
Now, hold on,
I'm O-negative. I'm screened
routinely by the Navy.
I don't know
if military testing
meets our standards.
Please. If this could
save my boy...
Heart rate's up to 160.
Connect me to a bag now.
We can push whole
blood directly through
the rapid transfuser.
Ms. Goodwin?
Okay. Do it.
I've put him
in room P-Ten.
Earl, I got your text.
What's the emergency?
Yeah, found
this guy holed up
in a patient room.
Not even registered.
Had his feet up,
watching TV like
he owns the place.
Said he was
Dr. Charles' patient,
so I brought him here.
But your brother
called and said...
It wasn't my brother.
It was me.
Dr. Charles
thought you were dead.
Well, maybe I finally
got through to him.
Think he'll see me now?
Mr. Kellogg.
I am so grateful that
you're still alive.
And that I get
to treat you.
I just want my meds.
Yeah.
It doesn't really
work that way.
You see, your behavior
indicates a pretty profound
personality disorder.
Off the cuff,
among other things,
I'd say you're probably
a malignant narcissist with
overt sadistic impulses.
You've got no right
to talk to me...
Shut your mouth.
Dr. Charles.
Maybe I should just go.
No, no, no.
I'm so sorry,
but I gotta put you on
a 72-hour psychiatric hold
for your own good.
What? Seventy-two hours?
You wanted my attention,
and now you have it.
BP's coming up.
Heart rate's going down.
Thank you, Ethan.
Of course.
Good news.
We should be able to get
him up to interventional
radiology soon.
Susan?
His father was right.
I was willing
to let him die.
No.
No, we made the decision
to give Josh the blood.
But that doesn't mean
we ever gave up on your son.
I'm his mother.
I should've fought for him.
What will he think
when he finds out?
Hi, uh, I'm looking
for my husband.
They said he was burned
in the accident.
His name is Rod Winter.
Oh, his doctor is not
available right now,
but if you can wait
in the waiting room...
Mrs. Winter.
Uh, hi, I'm Dr. Rhodes.
Uh, I can speak with you
about your husband.
Please.
Blood finally arrived.
Good.
Hey,
I'm sorry for calling you
"emotional" earlier.
You know,
you spend a lot of time
apologizing to me.
Well, there are
a very few people
I care more about.
Good night, Will.
Night, Natalie.
Snow's letting up.
Supplies are
coming in finally.
Rough day.
I was glad to be
back in the ED.
You can fix people's bodies,
but their minds...
I envied you today.
Making those decisions
clinically,
not letting
your emotions interfere.
Dr. Rhodes,
are you saying
you envy my autism?
A little bit, yeah.