Why is light given
to those in misery?
And life to the bitter of soul?
To those who long for
death that does not come?
Who search for it more
than for hidden treasure?
Who are filled with gladness and
rejoice when they reach the grave?
For sighing comes
to me instead of food.
My groans pour out like water.
What I feared has come upon me.
What I dreaded
has happened to me.
I have no peace.
No quietness.
I have no rest,
but only turmoil.
Faithlessness is the
only natural disaster.
Sugar is evil. Cast
away that pop.
Safe haven, right?
That's what you said? Well, I left my
baby here and now I want him back!
I was next. WOMAN 1:
Call this a safe haven?
Dr. Lockhart! Purdy can't sleep.
Give me my baby!
Okay, I'll be with you in
a minute, Mrs. Gaines.
Thank you. MAN 3: How
much longer I gotta wait?
Come on, sir, I'm taking you in.
I've been here two hours.
Paul Traylor, 34,
GSW to the chest.
- Shot by intruder in his apartment.
- Okay, I'm Dr. Lockhart.
Some dumb kids. Made a mistake.
Tachy at 120, BP's good.
- Hold up, hold up.
- Sats down to 89.
It's getting harder to breathe.
- Okay, hemostat.
- What?
- Give me the clamp.
Repent sin lest ye be stricken.
- Now is the time of fire and brimstone.
- Reidy, you gotta know...
that covering a penetrating chest
wound creates a one-way valve.
Causing a tension pneumo.
- Today...
the reckoning will commence.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
Welcome to the end of the world.
Today everything changes.
Today? Really? I thought
that was next week.
On my count. One, two, three.
Can you call St.
David's Academy?
- No exit wound.
- I won't be coming in.
- On it.
- Nothing below the waist.
- What do you do?
- Tutor.
- I run the sports program.
- Axilla's clear.
Okay, get him
back down. Gates...
- start on chest tube.
- Got it.
Haleh, can you call for
C-spine, chest and belly films?
- Uh-huh.
- I'll do that.
I'm supposed to do grunt
work while you supervise.
- Oh, that's true.
- So how'd this happen?
Stayed at my
girlfriend's last night.
- Got back, a bunch of kids were there.
- In your place?
They were partying or something.
I told them to leave.
Things got out of hand.
- One of them had a gun.
- How'd they get in?
- I don't know. GATES:
All right, little pinch.
Being the new
attending feel different?
No, not really.
Well, yeah, a little bit.
Guys, I got hung up with the
intussusception kid. What do you got?
GSW to the chest, no
exit. BP and Sats are good.
All right, slight pressure here.
- Two hundred cc's on the floor.
- That's my blood?
That's normal for
a gunshot wound.
- Type and cross for 6.
- Morris, excuse me.
- We have an attending here.
- Right. Of course.
Told them family only, they
wouldn't take no for an answer.
- Coach, you okay?
- How'd this happen?
Thanks for showing up, guys.
But you got morning
drills and school.
We ain't practicing without you.
Call me when you get
the films back. Excuse me.
You okay?
Had a run of double shifts.
- Why don't you take a couple days off?
- He won't stop working.
Yeah, the interns are
all in procedure lab...
and we're already
stretched thin without Greg.
Have you met the
new, uh, chief yet?
- Banfield?
- No. Not yet.
Soon enough, she's on today.
Dr. Morris. I got two kids
here with possible gastro.
I'll take it. Why don't
you take a break?
This is Mrs. Weddington
with her sons, Larry and Curly.
Where's Moe?
No Moe. Okay.
Uh, Larry?
- That's Curly.
- Right. Right.
Up all night vomiting, but
they seem to be better now.
Probably had too much cake.
We were at a bowling
party all day yesterday.
Sam, I thought
you went upstairs.
Eh, they said it might take a
while, so I might as well work.
They're making her go in
front of some disciplinary board.
- How come?
- She left a Hep-Lock in a patient.
Okay, fluid
challenge these guys.
Give them some
popsicles, see how they do.
Oh, excuse me. Um,
I was wondering, um...
My boys are
getting to the age...
where they need to know
about certain things...
and I'm sure they
have questions.
- Oh, sex, drugs, rock 'n' roll.
- Yeah.
Could you maybe talk to them?
Uh, yeah. Sure.
Oh, great. Thank you so much.
Sure. I'll be back
here in a little while.
Okay, I'll just
catch up with them.
- Great.
- Okay.
You look pretty.
Are you stoned?
- So I just, uh, heard a rumor. Is it true?
- This kid's here to see his coach.
Yeah, he's, uh... He's
right through there.
Some of your friends
are already with him.
What's the rumor?
That you got a job
at Mass General.
That you're moving to Boston.
Who told you that?
A girl who works in
HR told a scrub nurse.
The same girl that said Chuny was
pregnant with Crenshaw's love child?
Hey.
I'm happy for you, I really am. I'm
happy for you and Luka and Joe.
Even if it kills me to think that
you won't be working here anymore.
That you'll be living far away.
I wish you would have told me.
Well, what for? What?
So you could plan some
embarrassing party?
Because I'm your friend.
Well, we're still gonna
be friends, aren't we?
Well, first shift as an
attending, last shift at County.
- That's quite a day.
- Yeah.
- How soon are you leaving?
- Tonight.
Tonight?
- Abby!
- I'm sorry. I know...
can you not tell anybody?
Because it's just...
It's too weird and I'll...
I'll figure out a
way to do it, later.
Rule of today: No crying. Right?
Hey.
I got two guys coming
in. Fight at a synagogue.
- Oy vey. A couple of feisty Jews, huh?
- Hm?
I don't know. The
gloves are off today.
What the hell is this?
Frank's learning to tango for
his 30th wedding anniversary.
Promised Connie that I would
dance with her at the party.
Keep your head up, Frank.
I can't, then I can't see
where to put my damn feet.
Thirty-two-year-old male,
lip versus fist, vitals stable.
You're not a mohel,
you're a butcher.
The baby is fine, Sheldon.
A little blood is normal.
You were sloppy! Sloppy
with my baby's penis!
- End of conversation.
- Crazy.
I'm done with brises.
Who needs the aggravation?
- Hey, do I know you?
- I don't know. Do you?
I performed your
wedding ceremony.
It's Abigail, right?
Um, yeah. Abby,
actually. It's Abby.
So how's your first year
of married life been?
Oh, well, you know.
Got its ups and its downs.
What? He's a slob?
Leaves the toilet seat
up, never does the dishes?
Something like that, yeah.
Listen, the ceremony
was meshuga.
Those are the ones that last.
Here.
Keep this on it.
- It was nice to see you again.
- Don't worry, it'll get easier.
Shalom to that.
You guys, where's your mom?
Okay, uh... Here we go.
I sometimes talk to kids
about, you know, stuff.
So why don't we
just go right over here.
And if you have any
questions about...
sex, or drugs or alcohol,
you can just shoot.
I know it's hard for kids your age
to talk about this stuff, but I think...
- We can ask you anything?
- Yes.
Is it true if you sneeze with
your eyes open, they pop out?
- Can vampires get AIDS?
- Put a penny on El track, will it crash?
Why can't we wear
pajamas in daytime?
Our brother got a girl
pregnant, he won't marry.
- Why do you think he won't?
- Okay, am I...? Am I being punk'd?
Crit's dropping in 2.
You guys, stay right there.
- How do blimps fly?
- What about chest and belly films?
- Haven't done it.
- What's taking so long?
- Processor's down.
- That's ridiculous.
550 out of the chest tube,
hemoglobin's dropped to 11.
All right, hang O-neg, call for
type specific, platelets and FFP.
- This is Lily.
- His fiancée.
- He's gonna be okay?
- That's the plan.
Sat's only 83. ABBY: All right.
Deep breaths for me.
A non-rebreather and
set up to intubation.
Etomidate and sux. Eight-oh.
Paul, we're gonna have
to put another tube in.
- You're not gonna be able to speak.
- Right.
Zeke.
It's not your fault. Okay?
I don't blame you.
Hear me?
Say you hear me.
I hear you.
Pushing the meds.
All the bulbs are out.
Okay, folks, give
it to me straight.
GSW to the chest.
- First unit's up.
- First unit? That's all?
Hemodynamically
stable five minutes ago.
Okay. Get this crowd out of here.
- This is his girlfriend.
All right, just
the Globetrotters.
You're gonna have to step
out while we work, okay?
- No way.
- We're not gonna leave till...
Hey, Meadowlark, did you
hear what the lady said?
I prefer to give blood
before the vitals take a dive.
- It works out much better that way.
- I don't transfuse without a reason.
Oh, like being
shot in the chest?
Where's the bullet?
I ordered plain films,
the processor's down.
What's the CT show?
- CT takes an hour.
- Oh, please.
Our patients don't need radiation and
a $1000 bill for an unnecessary scan.
Oh, yes, the victim complex.
It's all so hard here at County.
Boo-hoo. Takes so long, nothing works.
You think this is tough, kiddies,
try a cinderblock hut in Malaysia.
I'll call Radiology again.
I know you're Tsunami
Mary or something...
but we don't need
war stories right now.
I don't think we've been
properly introduced.
I'm Cate Banfield.
- Abby Lockhart.
- You're a baby attending, flying blind.
Take help if you wanna stick
around. Otherwise, the door.
And I'm talking about the big
picture. So there are your options.
I'll keep that in mind.
Who wants to intubate?
Guidewire.
Hemoglobin's stable, 11.1.
That might be a sign that
bleeding is slowing down.
Not necessarily.
- Hang another unit.
- Introducer.
Let Gates finish that, I
need you to run the board.
- Call me when the films are ready.
- All right.
He said they were
from the neighborhood.
What? You didn't hear
what coach told the cops?
- I don't know who they are.
- Settle down.
- Stay out of the way. HILO:
They live in your building.
Dr. Lockhart, she's so blue,
can you give her something?
I'm not a vet, and cats
aren't allowed in the ER.
- Is there anything else I can do for you?
- My water pill. I need a refill, please.
You know what? This has gotta stop.
You have to get yourself a real doctor.
You're not a real doctor?
Mrs. Gaines, you
know what I mean.
I'm not gonna be here forever.
You have such a
dark perspective.
I'm drawn to you,
dear. So sue me.
Can you hang on?
I'll be right back.
Hey! At least you
don't sneeze anymore.
Yeah, I take antihistamines
when I see you coming.
What are you doing? I
thought you were taking a break.
Ever been at a crossroads?
Who do you think
you're talking to?
That's how I feel.
Like something's changing,
but I don't know what it is.
It gets easier once
you get used to it.
I keep thinking
about what he said.
The last words of Greg Pratt
were, "Don't screw it up, Morris."
You won't.
If I were in trouble,
Archie, I would call for you.
I would.
I would trust you with anything.
And I didn't always feel
that way, but I do now.
Actually, why don't you get up
and come with me for a minute.
Can you die from eating
Pop Rocks and soda?
If I hold in a fart,
will I explode?
Why don't you try to find your
mom? Check the front desk.
Dr. Morris. This is
Roxanne Gaines.
She's on captopril, Lasix,
Ambien, and glyburide.
She comes in once
a month for refills...
sometimes more when she
shares meds with her cat.
Yeah, Purdy has insomnia.
You can do this at
your primary physician's.
No, wait, Morris. Please, just...
Can you just do this for me?
- What?
- If I'm ever not here, Roxanne...
- ask for Dr. Morris.
- Abby.
Look, just do it.
- I'm trusting you.
- Got films on your guy in 2.
Maybe you guys should
chat. Get to know each other.
A little kooky, but I love her.
Yeah, join the club.
Hm. Oh...
What's going on
with the Hep-Lock?
I got duped, the
guy used it to OD.
That's a calculated
risk, we've all done it.
Are they gonna put
a letter in your file?
Nursing supervisor called
me, said to be prepared.
What, ha, ha, are
they gonna fire you?
Screw them.
I can always find another job.
Oh, come on, you don't
really want that, do you?
No, I don't.
Got your films.
Blood gas looks good.
All right. Dial down
the oxygen, please.
- Where's Cruella de Ville?
- Covering for you, we hear.
And real happy about it.
Bullet's in the
belly. Call Surgery.
And you threaded the
subclavian into the neck.
- Crap.
- Yeah.
How's the board look, doctor?
Um...
Clear with a white
frame, lots of writing on it.
If you put pressure on
the clavicular fossa...
as you're threading subclavian,
it prevents it going in the jugular.
- Know what that's called?
- The finger in the fossa trick.
Points to the new lady
for stealing the punch line.
Nice pickup.
Go next door, see
what's going on.
As much as I enjoy
being your bitch, I...
Dr. Gates has been duly
schooled, we'll take it from here.
Get set up to fix your line.
We raided your boys too. - Hey.
- Hey, hey, hey!
- It's your fault!
- Can I get some help here?
- Why? Why you have to do it?
- Knock it off.
- Our father!
Come on, guys. Come
on. HILO: You did this!
It's his fault! He got
coach messed up!
Let's go. Come on. Let's go.
It's his fault coach is in here.
- Outside.
- Here.
- Get off me. Get off me!
Hey! I'm trying to help you.
Come here.
Sit down. Sit down.
- Hold this on it.
- What for?
Just do it.
Is coach okay?
He's gonna be.
It's not my fault.
Why would it be your fault?
I just said it's not.
I didn't even think
he'd be there.
Where? His apartment?
Coach knows how it is.
He's been through
his own rough times.
And got past it. That's
what he teaches us.
That's a good thing to teach.
I think you're gonna
need some stitches.
Zeke.
Why?
It's... It's not like they say.
He would give you anything
you needed. You know that.
I'm sorry.
- Ow!
- Lily, you're gonna have to step out.
- Come on, here we go.
- You know that!
Bring her back in there.
I'm gonna need 4.0 Prolene...
and 1 percent lido. - Okay.
- Abby.
- Have you seen a kid running around...
- he's about 15, yay high?
- No. Not that I noticed.
You working at a surgi-center?
- Well, I wa...
- Haleh, you seen that kid, Zeke?
Not since you have.
- I'm getting lido.
- Thanks.
I told myself, you know, I could
walk away and never think twice, but...
If you see my basketball kids
roaming around, let me know.
- Okey-dokey.
- This is County.
- Is, um...? Is Frank dancing?
- Keep your head up, Frank.
Well, it turns out I can't
imagine working anyplace else.
- You can't?
- No, I can't. Can you?
Well...
it wouldn't be easy, but
for the right reasons, yeah.
Is there something...
- you're not telling me?
- No.
- Come on.
- Yeah.
Luka and I are moving to
Boston. Don't tell anyone.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Ab...
- Can't go there.
- It'll get me started. Thanks.
- There's your lido.
- Then, uh, no problem.
- Yeah.
- So I have to go find this kid. All right.
- Okay. We'll talk later, then.
- Why do monkeys love bananas?
- What's a douche bag?
- Where the hell's their mother?
- I want to talk to you.
You know what? I'm not the right
person, because I'm a short-timer.
- You are? How short?
- Yeah. Really short.
Today is my last
shift, don't tell anybody.
I was just about to say what a
great mentor you've been and ask...
- I find this pretty upsetting.
- You're good.
You don't need me anymore.
Abby! He's on the roof.
Zeke?
Hey, Zeke, I didn't get a
chance to finish dressing your cut.
Don't come over here.
Hey, you know, these
things, they don't...
Don't usually work out the
way we think they're going to.
Because it's, uh...
you know, it's the
middle of the day.
It's a crowded street and
you'll probably end up...
End up landing on
a bunch of tourists.
Hey, what are we doing up here?
After Jamal got shot...
out in Tinley...
coach told us if we ever
needed a place to go...
like to be safe or just chill...
He left his key in one of those little
magnet boxes behind the radiator.
Those kids hassle me...
all the time.
I told them I could
take them to a place...
where we could just party...
hang out, do whatever
we wanted there.
After coach came in,
everything got crazy.
I couldn't stop them.
I promise I'm gonna fix up
your coach if you'll just please...
Just come back
away from there, okay?
All right, listen. Hey.
I'm gonna...
Look at this. Come here.
Look at this. Just look at this.
All right? You take it.
I don't live up to my end...
you inject that into your vein
and your heart will stop beating.
- I'm not stupid.
- I'm not kidding.
It's called a fatal arrhythmia.
If I don't live up
to my part, take it...
and you can do
whatever you want.
Are you nuts or something?
I just know what it's
like to be out on a ledge.
And yeah, I'm nuts.
So why don't you just please...
Just please come back here, okay?
Come on.
Come on, Zeke.
Come here. Come on.
Just easy.
It's okay.
Listen to me, we have
a man bleeding out.
The rapid infuser.
We're bringing the GSW.
- Switch to portable, we're going.
- Someone tell me what's going on.
Losing blood faster
than it's replaced.
Surgeons need to
get in there and repair.
Seems too red.
- Run of six.
- All right.
- Let's roll.
- He's got a pulse.
Send him with a crappy BP
and intermittent V-tach he'll arrest.
Longer we argue,
the greater the chance.
- She's right.
- We're more equipped to handle...
a code down here, trust me.
Abby. HALEH: He's in V-tach.
- All right, lost pulse.
- Thoracotomy tray.
- Starting compressions.
- Charge to 360.
Sterile 7s, a 10 blade.
- What are you doing?
We have to open his chest.
- Abby, look at this.
- Not now, Grady. Clear.
No change.
- Resume compressions, 360, again.
- Look at the left hemi-diaphragm.
Yeah, it's a hemothorax.
It happens. Clear.
Still in V-tach.
All right. Haleh,
prep the chest.
You slowed us down enough.
Three-sixty again.
Stand by with epi.
The chest tube went through?
You see the tip of the
tube right there. Clear.
Maybe it only looks like the tip.
The end is obscured by blood.
- Back in sinus.
- Strong radial pulse.
All right. Let's
get him to the O.R.
All right.
- Wait.
- No.
Grady's right.
Chest tube followed
the bullet, in the spleen.
Listen, that is highly unlikely,
and we can't prove it here.
We could see it with the
ultrasound. Let me see.
- We did an ultrasound.
- But it's easy to miss.
A dislodged clot in the
spleen could have caused...
Caused a precipitous arterial
bleed to drain out the chest tube.
Get out of the way.
Yeah, I can't get a
good view. Haleh...
call down to the pharmacy,
have them deliver some fibrin glue.
- Dr. Lockhart.
- Fibrin?
A tissue adhesive, it can be
used for splenic hemostasis.
I think the dose is 2000
units but you better check.
Stop. Enough. We are done.
He is a green resident,
and you're a newbie...
- we ain't messing around on a hunch.
- Wait. Hold on. Hold on.
I know you don't know anything
about me or my clinical judgment.
But it's not really my first day.
It's... I've been here for 10 years.
And I know when
I know something.
And you've been here for a week.
So just... Can you just give me this?
Your five minutes are up.
- Almost there.
- Over a liter out now.
Sorry, we were stuck
with a grade-5 liver.
- Put him in Trendelenberg.
- Okay, here we go.
- How long to clot? ABBY:
How long does what take?
Fibrin glue. Couple
of seconds, I think.
We think the chest
tube's in the spleen.
- You think?
- Yeah. No scan, we can't see anything.
- So how'd you come up with this plan?
- Grady.
He was paying attention.
Seems to have worked.
Oh, God, thank you.
Thank you.
Systolic's up to 90.
Clamp the tube. Let's
get him out of here.
- Can I go with him?
- No, it's better if you wait.
Here we go.
Impressive.
Well, I'm a skilled practitioner
and an excellent teacher.
It's just getting
too hard to deny.
Well, I've never heard of
using fibrin glue this way.
Yeah.
To tell you the truth, I have absolutely
no idea where that came from.
Lodged in there somewhere.
Well, it's a good job it was. And
I see you've met our new chief.
Hm. She's not the chief of me.
- Lucien's waiting for us in O.R. 1.
- Okay.
Zeke, you can't be up here.
Go do your thing. What are you
doing? Where's the nurse I left you with?
He... He looks bad.
He's pale from blood loss, but
the surgeons are gonna fix that.
- If he doesn't make it...
- Hey. Hey.
Now, I kept my end of
the bargain so far, right?
All right, now you
have to keep yours.
Now, just go downstairs
and wait with the nurse.
Zeke, this is
going to be all right.
You just have to keep
telling yourself that.
All right. I'll see you later.
A little more traction. - Coker.
End-tidal looks good.
All right, into the peritoneum.
You guys are gonna bring
this home for me, right?
Capsule's ruptured. - Suction.
Splenic artery's sheared off.
You know, we get
tired of hearing...
how you guys have to come
in, clean up our messes.
We can autotransfuse what's
left back in the splenic vein.
But the fact is,
sometimes you do.
VBG's 7.38. NEELA: Pickups.
So let's make this one
more for the road, huh?
Here's our bullet.
- Second liter's up.
- Curved clamp to Neela.
Splenorenal ligament
is isolated and...
And cut. Excellent.
Looking up, Abby.
Great.
That is great.
Bovie. Watch out for the...
Gastroepiploic artery. See it.
Okay, bullet completely
spared the stomach and liver.
You guys are so good at this.
I mean, just
really, really good.
Systolic's holding at 98.
DUBENKO & NEELA: Oh-silk.
And I love what
you've done up here.
This new observation
deck is very comfortable.
Nicely lit. Nice big window.
- Way to go. NEELA:
Posterior margin's free.
Mobilize it.
- Curved clamp.
- Clamp to Lucien.
And, you know,
you two are like...
Like yin and yang. Have you
ever thought about, I don't know...
dating?
I mean, why ask what if, right?
I'm gonna go tell them
that he's out of the woods.
- Yeah, why don't you do that?
- Yeah, we're fine here.
And I'm gonna be
punching out soon so...
Thank you for this.
I'll see you sometime.
Be good.
They're almost
done, it's going well.
Good.
His people are in the
family room, I'll update them.
You know, you won't really have
me to beat up on after tonight.
So I understand.
You know, despite some
obvious issues with authority...
I'm wondering
why you're leaving.
For my family.
I have a husband and a little
boy. We just need a fresh start.
- How old is your son?
- A little over 2.
It's a great age.
I love that age.
Well... your
shift's almost over.
Nice knowing you.
Good luck here.
Can you give us a minute?
- Sure.
I want my syringe back.
- He's okay?
- Mm-hm.
And you're gonna have to talk to some
doctors to make sure you're okay too.
I know you think
you're a bad person.
We all think that about ourselves
sometimes. But you're not.
You just did a bad thing.
Don't make the same
mistake again, okay?
You would've never let me
use that thing, would you?
You know what? I really
hadn't thought that far ahead.
See you later.
Dr. Lockhart.
Dr. Lockhart. Dear, you
made me so nervous...
- I had to come back.
- What's the matter, Roxanne?
You're sick, aren't you?
No. Not anymore.
Oh, ha, ha, but the way you were
talking. Is something bad gonna happen?
No. Something good. Hey,
Sam! Are you going up now?
- Dead nurse walking.
- I wanna talk.
- Will I see you next time?
- Ask for Dr. Morris.
You have to do some stupid monkey
dance for a bunch of cheap suits?
To justify how we
navigate a broken system...
which is the problem that
they should be looking at.
You're very articulate today.
I know.
Nurse Taggart, it'll
be a few more minutes.
- Are you kidding me?
- It's okay.
No, it's not okay.
She's working, all right?
She can't keep bouncing up and
down like some registered yo-yo.
Abby.
Hi. Hi, I'm sorry, but don't
you think this is kind of ass?
- Excuse me? Who are you?
- Abby Lockhart.
I used to be a nurse in the ER, I
am now an attending physician.
- You'll have to be on the agenda.
- Let me break it down for you.
What we do is take
care of patients...
that nobody else wants
to deal with, all right?
The homeless alcoholics,
drug addicts, psychotics.
All of us, especially the nurses,
put ourselves at risk every day.
Every day.
When wards don't want to
go over nurse-to-patient ratio...
because they want to follow rules,
guess who sucks up the surplus?
The ER does. And
never mind that means...
having admitted patients parked
on gurneys in the hallway for days...
and our nurses have to cover three
times as many patients as anybody else.
We're the safety net.
We do not have the luxury
of abiding by the rules...
because we don't kick
patients out on the streets.
So we get creative.
And yes, it's against the rules to
send a patient home with an IV.
Worst-case, he'll
do something stupid.
But Sam Taggart is not a
worst-case scenario kind of person.
Well, none of us are.
Because to work down there you have
to have some sort of faith in people...
and in your ability
to help them.
She didn't inject drugs
into the IV, the patient did.
And what would you have her do?
Deny a potentially lifesaving treatment...
because the guy maybe
might do something stupid later?
She's an excellent nurse.
And she did what almost
anybody else would do...
and she should not be punished
because a patient made a bad choice.
I mean, we have so many
things working against us.
Don't be another one of them.
And they all deserve a raise.
Don't make me come back here.
Have you journeyed to
the springs of the sea?
Or walked in the
recesses of the deep?
What are you doing with that?
- Souvenir.
- Mm-hm.
You come with me.
Some we had to put up for them.
Dr. Greene, Greg.
You're the only one
who's ever gotten to do two.
I don't see Carter up there.
He wouldn't do it.
He said it was defacing
government property.
We're gonna miss
you so damn much.
Have the gates of death
been shown to you?
Hey, I was looking for you.
Do I have to go up
there and apologize?
No, um...
I got a week's suspension, no pay,
but it could have been a lot worse.
So thank you.
Nurses gotta stick
together, right?
All right. I got a run to catch.
What is the way to
the abode of light?
And where does darkness reside?
One, two, three, four, five.
Frank. Passion. Intensity.
It's the dance of immigrants,
stuck between two worlds.
Yeah, well, I better get better at
it by Saturday, or I'll be deported.
Is Connie gonna kick you out?
Worse. She'll make me
buy her something expensive.
Hold it, ha-ha. Hold on a
second. Let me show you.
Apilado.
Now, la cadencia.
Five, six, seven, eight.
I've been stumbling
around here all day. What...?
What were you waiting for?
- Where is everybody?
- There's a double run coming in.
I'm taking this.
- I'm not here.
- Me neither.
Hey.
Tell that big Croat to bring
you back for a visit sometime.
Keep your head up, Frank.
I guess I let the cat
out of the bag, huh?
This kind of group thing I
was sort of hoping to avoid...
but, um, Luka's picking me
up and since you're all here...
I just wanna to say,
it's been a great decade.
Excuse me?
- What the hell?
- She's leaving, Archie.
- When?
- Now, you idiot.
What?
You are?
She...? You are?
- You never said anything.
- Well, I just...
- I kind of thought you got the idea.
- I didn't.
I didn't.
I... Well, I'm... Well...
You know, Archie,
it's amazing...
that you've managed to make
my last moment about you.
I love that.
- I love you too.
- Ha-ha-ha.
Okay. ABBY: Okay.
I'm gonna miss you guys.
We'll be thinking about you.
So long.
Bye, Abby.
Have you comprehended
the vast expanses of the Earth?
Tell me if you know all this.