♪ Can't keep my hands to myself ♪
♪ Think I'll dust 'em off
Put 'em back up on the shelf ♪
♪ In case my little baby girl is in need ♪
♪ Am I coming out of left field? ♪
♪ Ooh, woo
I'm a rebel just for kicks, now ♪
♪ I been feeling it since 1966, now ♪
♪ Might be over now ♪
I kind of overcooked the eggs.
Not used to a gas stove, sorry.
Last thing I want is food.
Ah, lightweight.
You know, I outdrank you
two-to-one.
Never mind I was rolling on Molly.
I'm a cheap date.
Take the coffee, though.
♪ Leave her with a babysitter
Mama, call the grave digger ♪
You're a doctor.
♪ Gone with the fallen leaves ♪
♪ Am I coming out of left field? ♪
Well, Dr. Browne,
I had fun last night.
Me too.
And that unenthusiastic response
answers my question...
Wanna meet up again?
♪ Let me kick it like it's 1986, now ♪
♪ Might be over now, but I feel it still ♪
I'll get out of here.
♪ Ooh, woo
I'm a rebel just for kicks, yeah ♪
♪ Your love is an abyss
For my heart to eclipse, now ♪
♪ Might be over now, but I feel it still ♪
♪ Ooh, woo
I'm a rebel just for kicks, now ♪
- Hey, Shaun.
- I have a question for Dr. Glassman.
Uh, he's in the shower.
Do you wanna come on...
- When did his shower begin?
- He just got in.
His showers are at least
nine minutes. I'd be late to work.
I'll wait. This is important.
♪ Am I coming out of left field? ♪
♪ Ooh, woo
I'm a rebel just for kicks, now ♪
♪ I've been feeling it since 1966, now ♪
Something I can help with?
The florist told me
that pink roses express passion
and purple Peruvian lilies
convey devotion.
But I feel both passion and devotion
for Carly.
Give her both.
♪ Start flipping for my enemies ♪
Please ask Dr. Glassman
to text me the answer
- as soon as he's out of the shower.
- What's Carly's favorite color?
Flowers don't really have meaning,
that's just a tactic to boost sales.
Purple.
There you go.
♪ Is it coming back? ♪
Oh.
♪ Ooh, woo
I'm a rebel just for kicks, yeah ♪
♪ Your love is an abyss
For my heart to eclipse, now ♪
♪ Might be over now, but I feel it still ♪
♪ Ooh, woo
I'm a rebel just for kicks, now ♪
♪ I've been feeling it since 1966, now ♪
♪ Might be over now ♪
Hi, Shaun.
I'd like to have sex tonight.
♪ I'm a rebel just for kicks, now ♪
Would you?
Yes.
♪ Ooh, woo
I'm a rebel just for kicks, now ♪
♪ Let me kick it like it's 1986, now ♪
♪ Might be over now, but I feel it still ♪
♪ Might've had your fill
But I feel it still ♪♪
Thirty-nine-year-old male, multi-car
accident. Blunt abdominal injuries,
including ruptured spleen
and lacerated liver.
- What's his GCS?
- Nine.
Free fluid in the right upper quadrant.
We need an OR stat. Page Melendez.
We were at our engagement photo shoot.
I thought it was just a migraine.
I get them sometimes
with the flashing lights.
Then she started slurring words.
I was trying to tell him that
I couldn't feel or move my left side.
The only thing that got me through
was Tony telling me:
"Okay, it will be."
How long before your symptoms
began to subside?
Half an hour. By the time we got here,
all I had was a mild headache.
I think you had
a transient ischemic attack.
- A mini stroke.
- A stroke?
- Mini.
- Jeanie's 25.
Which is why we'll need an MRI,
cardiac echo, and labs
before we know for sure.
Cauterize that bleed.
That's it for the liver.
What's his mean arterial pressure?
Sixty-seven.
What was that place with the
deviled oysters you took Dr. Lim to?
Oh, Mia's in town.
As some of you may be aware,
Dr. Lim and I are no longer together.
It's called Half Shell.
Downtown, off Second.
Remove the packing.
Look at the aorta.
Likely a laceration from the accident.
We'll need to dissect further
to determine the extent of the damage.
- BP's sky-rocketing.
- He's suffered massive blood loss,
he's under anesthesia,
should be hypotensive.
- Pulmonary embolism?
- Push beta-blockers.
That would... kill him.
He's tachycardic and hypothermic.
I think he must be on something.
MDMA mixed with anesthesia?
Give him a low dose of nitroglycerine
and calcium channel blockers.
- BP's dropping, it's working.
- Push the full dose. Close him up.
We're gonna have to wait for the MDMA
to leave his blood stream,
and get a better look
at the aorta by imaging.
Good call.
I need to use the restroom.
Hang in, Jeanie,
just a couple more minutes.
You should ask me
what I'm going to do tonight.
Okay, but just to make it feel
more like an actual conversation...
Nothing much. I've got a yoga class
and a date with Ben and Jerry tonight.
- How about you, Shaun?
- I'm having sex with Carly.
- Whoa.
- It's my first time.
Mazel tov.
It took us 22 days to kiss,
nine more to hold hands,
although, we don't really hold hands
when we hold hands,
and another six to touch
more than one thing at a time.
- But now I'm ready.
- That's a lot of foreplay.
I've been reading
about the four stages of arousal...
Fair warning, the first time
for most people is awful.
Your first time was awful?
Not an appropriate question
to ask a colleague.
Although there's an exception
to every rule.
Which books did your lover read
to prepare?
No clots, no bleeds, no occlusions,
no PFO.
She didn't have a stroke.
She's having a seizure.
Pushing diazepam.
She had to use the restroom.
Her bladder is distended.
Whatever it's pressing against
must be causing these attacks.
CT shows she has two pelvic lesions.
Labs show elevated levels
of catecholamines.
The pain meds we gave her
could've distended her bladder,
which is abutting one of the tumors,
setting off her second attack.
- But what set off the first one?
- Sexual intercourse.
The other tumor appears to be
within her clitoris.
Progressive impact may have
destabilized it over time.
And now she's at risk
of having more seizures.
Sex could kill this woman.
He's stable and the MDMA's
out of his system.
We're good to go back in
and graft the aorta.
We're just getting caught up
with blood loss and fluid resuscitation.
An endovascular stent
is minimally invasive.
- It is a better option than a graft.
- A stent could clot off
because we won't
be able to get blood
thinners. His liver's
still a bleeding risk.
Let's take our chances
with the stent.
We can have him back in the ICU,
where we can focus on his recovery.
I do not want to proceed
without consent.
He won't regain consciousness
for another couple of hours.
We shouldn't wait that long.
Get it from his wife.
She's on her way here now.
We can remove the tumors.
But it means we also have to remove
most of your vagina and clitoris.
You can still have children...
Via C-section.
It won't affect your uterus
or ovaries.
What about sex?
You won't be able to have intercourse
or experience an orgasm.
It doesn't make sense. I've been
sexually active for five years,
never had any attacks.
We suspect the tumor's been dormant
for some time.
What if I don't have the surgery?
What are the odds of another attack?
There are many variables involved,
including frequency,
duration, sexual position,
penis size...
About 2 percent.
- Each time?
- Each time.
On average, couples have sex
52 times per year.
Which means, in the next three years,
your chance of having
a life-threatening attack
is well over 95 percent.
I think we'll take our chances.
You should talk it over
between yourselves.
- Perhaps with a counselor...
- I understand the situation.
I don't want the surgery.
- Hey.
Missed you at the research meeting.
I was in surgery, craniotomy.
Now I have two consults,
a meeting with a donor
and hospital chair meeting.
- Don't forget to eat something.
- Ah, food is for the weak.
So is waiting for this elevator.
- Are we okay?
- Yeah. Sorry, I'm just busy.
We're recommending the stent.
It risks clotting, but it's also
less invasive than the graft.
A graft would be
a more permanent repair,
but there's greater chance
of surgical complications.
I have to trust you, right?
- Is Dad gonna be okay?
- Oh, absolutely, darling.
We're gonna take care
of your dad.
He'll be home
before you know it, okay?
Okay.
Thank you.
If we send her home
without the surgery, she'll die.
We don't know that.
And taking away sex
from a young couple in love?
- That's devastating.
- So is death.
How much time does a couple
spend having sex?
Nineteen minutes per week,
including foreplay.
The rest,
that's the real relationship.
Forget the act itself.
Sex is crucial to the happiness
and satisfaction of a relationship.
Sex is destructive.
It turns people into liars
and cheaters and idiots.
Might start relationships,
but more often than not,
it rips them apart.
She got devastating news
and made an emotional decision
without thinking it through.
The least we can do
is get her counseling.
Was she offered counseling
when you gave the diagnosis?
Briefly. But she was still...
Then it's over. Once she's stable,
discharge her. Thank you.
You got the pink heart
and purple star...
How're you feeling?
Hi, doctor, he's doing great.
Hi, I'm Dr. Browne, you had a tear
in your aorta,
- but we stabilized it with a stent.
- Mm.
Until we can give you blood thinners,
you'll be at risk of a clot,
so we'll be monitoring you closely.
But now, everything is looking
absolutely perfect.
- Aw.
- Gentle.
See, cupcake? It's all good.
Why didn't you come home last night?
Daddy had a sleepover
at Uncle Jeff's.
He got a new turtle,
you can see it next time.
Your blood pressure is responding well
to the alpha-blockers.
We'll run labs, if they're normal,
you can be discharged.
Thank you.
You'll wanna be aware at all times
of where the closest hospital is.
Every time you have intercourse,
you'll be endangering
your fiancé's life.
I'm aware of that. We both are.
But it's Jeanie's body.
It's her decision, I'm just trying
to be supportive.
I don't think you are.
You're being selfish.
She's risking her life,
and you're keeping your mouth shut
so you can keep getting laid.
You do think
I'm making the right decision?
Yes, I do.
Thanks.
He really is gonna be fine.
I know, thank you.
You okay?
I think he's cheating.
His brother lives in Willow Glen.
The other side of the city
from his accident.
What did he say about it?
That he had a breakfast meeting
with a client.
Not unlike the excuse he used
last time he cheated.
Him denying it was the worst part.
Made me doubt myself, you know?
Was I just a paranoid, jealous wife,
throwing out wild accusations?
Your husband has just had
a serious car accident
and you're very stressed.
Right now, all you should be
thinking about is getting him better.
You're right.
- Thank you.
- Not at all.
- Would you like to take my top off?
- Yes.
♪ Boom, boom, boom
Boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ My heart beats boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ Boom, boom, boom
Boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ High speed, go zoom, zoom, zoom
Zoom, zoom, zoom ♪
♪ Zoom, zoom, zoom
Walkin' away from you ♪
Would you like me
to take your shirt off?
No.
I would like to do it myself.
Even better.
♪ With a new attitude ♪
♪ Why would I sing the blues for you? ♪
♪ I said, hey, uh-huh, you can't stop me ♪
♪ If you break ♪
Okay.
I've got it.
♪ My feet go boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ Boom, boom, boom
Boom, boom, boom ♪
- I could...
- Okay.
♪ Zoom, zoom, zoom ♪
♪ My feet go boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ Walkin' away from you ♪♪
Mm.
Do you want to slow down?
Do you wanna stop?
I'd like to go watch some TV.
- So you... You weren't feeling it?
- I was definitely feeling it.
She... I don't know...
I think you're confused.
I think it's emotional and it's hormonal
- and maybe...
- I wasn't confused.
She had a tattoo.
It was half a heart.
I don't understand why someone
would get an incomplete tattoo.
She shouldn't have something
incomplete on her body
that I can see.
You sure it was the tattoo?
Yes. It is a very disturbing tattoo
that makes no sense.
Maybe it's not about the tattoo.
I mean, maybe it's about intimacy?
Letting another person into your life,
that's a big deal, I know, trust me.
There are gonna be things
about her that you love,
and things about her that, heh, you don't.
And there are certain things,
like the tattoo, you can't change.
Because...
Well, it's worth it.
She can get the tattoo removed.
She can't get the tattoo removed,
Shaun.
I don't think it's about the tattoo.
We are backed up.
Sorry, Shaun.
Okay.
Everything looks good.
You could've checked them
on the EMR.
I know. How's it going with Shaun?
He tends to over-share
with co-workers.
Yes, he does.
And he was over-sharing
up until this morning,
so I'm guessing
"the night of a thousand stars"
didn't go as planned?
We're fine. Thanks.
Of course. You waited three weeks
for a kiss, you're a saint.
That didn't sound like a compliment.
I like Shaun,
and I love that he's dating.
But I can't help thinking
the person who'd go out with Shaun
might be seeing him more
as a project than a person.
And I'd rather not see him
get his heart broken.
Last week, two techs called in sick.
I had to diagnose and file
over 200 slides.
But when I told Shaun, he came down
and he helped me get through them
until 3 in the morning.
I am not going out with Shaun
because I have a martyr complex.
I'm going out with him because
he's a great guy who treats me well.
And the condescending notion
that someone needs an ulterior motive
to be interested in him
means you're the one who isn't
seeing him as a person.
Craniotomy ended an hour
before the research meeting.
You didn't miss the meeting because of
surgery, it was because I was there.
I'm busy.
- I can show you my calendar if you'd like.
- You dumped me.
I should be the one avoiding you,
what's going on?
- Are you having second thoughts?
- No, I'm not.
Why are you willing to die for sex?
Sex creates vulnerability.
Lets you be open,
honest with each other,
share your biggest fears.
Sometimes you shouldn't share.
Sometimes you have to
just accept, right?
- Wrong.
- Mm.
What you have to accept,
that's not for anyone else to say.
If you don't tell your partner
everything that you're feeling,
thinking, worrying about,
then you aren't fully connected.
Close your eyes.
Yes, this is one of those
dumb sensory exercises,
but just go with it.
Now tell me one of your
favorite memories with your fiancé.
Last summer, we went camping
in Yosemite.
We decided to rough it by only
packing PB&J sandwiches.
The first night, a bear rips
into our tent and devours them.
And the next night,
we have this hole in our tent
and the mosquitoes just eat us alive.
And the bug spray that we thought
we packed, it was sunscreen.
When it started pouring, we turned
to each other, at the same time,
and we said, "Denny's."
Ha-ha. And that's when I knew
I wanted to marry her.
Great.
That was a memory of something
you got through together.
Not about the time
you had a threesome in Miami.
It was New Orleans.
The threesome was in New Orleans,
not Miami,
and it was way better
than the bear trip.
But I wasn't gonna tell
my fiancée's doctor about it.
Sex makes you real with someone.
Sex makes you stupid.
I had the perfect man.
He was smart and funny...
He squeezed the sponge
after washing the dishes.
And one night, I met some guy,
and I had a few drinks, and...
I got all tingly
and got really stupid.
Never saw him again.
Or my boyfriend.
Sex can make us feel incredibly close
to someone,
honest, vulnerable...
But sex is not the goal.
All the rest of those things are.
She's the love of my life.
And I always thought
that we were strong
and that we could overcome
anything together.
But without sex?
I don't know if we have enough.
Okay.
Then you need to lie to her.
Nurse said you'd be here an hour ago.
Yeah, well,
you're not my only patient.
Look, I get it. This is about
as awkward as it gets.
Yes, it is.
You know, I almost died
in that accident.
When I woke up, all I could think about
was my wife and my little girl.
How much of an ass I've been
and how hurt they'd be.
So why is it once I get out of here,
I'm gonna keep cheating on her?
I can't help it.
No matter how much remorse
or guilt or...
I feel like I always give in.
- Then you should leave them.
- I can't.
I love them.
How messed up is that, right?
But I think you know.
Yeah, well, I don't cheat.
I saw you checking me out in the bar.
My left hand.
Just making sure I was married.
You're just as big a cheater
as me, Dr. Browne.
My, uh, leg, it's... It's cold.
No pulse.
Your stent has formed a clot.
We need an angio, stat!
Everything okay?
You haven't said a word
since "pass the salt."
It's about Shaun, isn't it?
Two weeks ago, you asked me
to give him romantic advice,
which I didn't wanna do.
And then he comes into my office
for romantic advice
- and you kick him out.
- Because you're helping him too much.
- He is completely dependent on you.
- For good reason.
He hasn't spoken to his parents
since he was 14.
The only person he cared about
died right in front of his eyes.
Aaron, I know how much you love him.
How you hate to see him struggle, fail,
get hurt...
But you need to let him,
and it'll be okay.
Because he has someone else
in his life now.
Just like you do.
Placing guide wire
through the needle.
Placing catheter.
How do you know this guy?
You knew he was on MDMA,
been avoiding him since he arrived.
And I checked on his accident.
He was a half-mile from your place.
I was with him the night
before the accident,
but it's not relevant.
It hasn't affected my judgment.
Yes, it has.
If you hadn't been avoiding him,
we could've caught the clot earlier.
I figure you've been going through
something lately?
Something that's really hurt you?
And maybe it's making you
turn to things you normally wouldn't.
But some of the guys you meet
are gonna be trouble, be married...
He took a vow, not me.
That's the exact attitude someone had
when they helped ruin my life.
There's the clot.
Activating angiojet.
- It's too big to bust.
- We have to open him up.
You said accept things I don't like,
but Jeanie said I have to share everything
- and I don't know...
- Shaun, stop, stop, stop.
I have to go home.
I can walk you to your car.
Is it very far?
I think this will take 15 minutes,
so maybe you can drive me?
We have to set boundaries, okay?
We have to set some limits.
You can't just come over 6:30
in the morning for flower advice,
pop into my office any time you want.
- Is this because of Debbie?
- No. Yes.
And I agree with her.
It was different when it was
just the two of us,
but now we have people
in our lives, both of us.
We have to make them the priority.
Does this mean we can't talk anymore?
No, of course we can talk.
It's just there's a time
and a place for everything.
And this is the wrong time and place.
Yeah.
Seven a.m., Tuesday, pancakes.
I liked it better when it was
just the two of us.
One-twenty-five over 78. Looks good.
Nice bug spray. SPF-50.
Not much went right that trip.
But the more things went wrong...
the closer I felt to you.
We'll get through this too.
I don't know.
Sex has always been our language.
Our way of sharing who we are
with each other,
and if we lose that...
What if we don't have enough?
We'll still have...
honesty, intimacy, love,
three kids, two boys and a girl...
I love you more than sex.
I love you more than sex too.
Does this mean
you're getting the surgery?
Yeah.
Ninety minutes without a pulse
in his leg. At high risk for necrosis.
Prosthetic successfully
sutured aorta.
Almost done with
distal right anastomosis.
Careful not to narrow the artery
during suturing.
Blood flow restored.
Good arterial pulse.
Good job catching that clot,
Dr. Browne.
If we waited any longer,
we'd amputate.
Thank you. It was a team effort.
Making incision
at the vaginal wall.
Murphy, develop margins at the lesion.
- Forceps.
- Nicely done.
How you turned your patient around.
It was nice when Tony told
Jeanie he loved her more than sex.
He was lying.
I told him that if he cared about her
at all, he had to.
Maybe it was the truth.
It can be true
without him knowing it's true.
What's wrong?
Dr. Glassman told me
I have to accept things,
but Jeanie said to be open
and honest.
I agree with Jeanie. Whoever she is.
It's your tattoo.
Thank God, I thought
you hated my boobs.
It's incomplete.
Didn't you have enough money
to pay for a full heart?
- I got this in high school.
- It's incomplete.
Not anymore.
I got you.
Shaun...
Dr. Glassman was right.
It's not the tattoo.
We were able to restore blood flow
to his legs. He's gonna be just fine.
Thank you so much.
Now that he's out of the woods,
you don't need to feel guilty
about questioning him.
All the pain, and paranoia
and self-doubt...
You deserve to know the truth.
He's just gonna deny it.
Then you need to insist.
Our relationship was a stupid idea.
Which made ending it a smart idea.
Simple, binary, and naive.
I really underestimated
how hard this would be.
Yes, I've been having
second thoughts.
I'm not saying we should
get back together.
What are you saying?
I don't know.
Good.
It's good to know that it's not easy.
It's good to know that it mattered.
Intimacy isn't about a tattoo.
And it's not about touching,
or kissing
or even sex.
It's about sharing your biggest fears.
Yes.
What are you scared of?
I love being a pathologist.
But every day I walk into the lab,
I am filled with doubt.
Am I smart enough?
Am I capable enough?
Do I really deserve to be here?
How long until someone walks in
and exposes my fraud
and has me removed from the premises?
Eventually, those thoughts retreat.
Until the next morning when they all
come crashing back into my brain.
That, and pigeons.
They freak me out.
Hmm.
My biggest fear...
is that I'll be alone.
If I don't get over this, you'll leave.
We don't have to have sex.
Can we just hold each other
for a little bit?
I think I'd like that.
Shaun?
Sasha. Sash...
You should go.
I don't know, maybe it can wait
until tomorrow morning.
And you were right.
Everything you said was right.
This is different.
Shaun needs you.
Hey.
Your mom called from Wyoming.
Your dad's been diagnosed
with pancreatic cancer.
He may only have a few days left.