All right, hold on. I
got the turn up here.
Oh! How cool was that?
That was way cool!
My turn. Sorry,
that's not allowed.
I just signed 15
pages of forms saying
you gotta ride on the back of that
thing. I don't see any lawyers around.
You know that's
not the point. No.
You just wanna keep
all the fun to yourself.
Come on, Dad!
You go over 15, we're
pulling over, all right? I mean it.
You're the best. All
right, get on there.
Put on your goggles. Okay.
Ready? Got the clutch in?
All right, that's my boy.
Adam, you're going
too fast, slow it down!
I mean it, you're going
too fast. Slow down!
Adam!
Let go of the throttle!
Adam! No!
What've you got?
Sixteen-year-old, status post,
ATV crash, 40%
burns on his body.
Nasotracheal intubation.
Start a bag of lactated
Ringer's, wide open...
Will he be okay? We'll
be with you when we can.
Get him out!
Wait, wait, wait!
I'll start fluids. Let's
go get him hooked up.
Watch the line.
Been looking for you.
Been avoiding you.
Burn Unit can handle it.
If they could handle it, they
wouldn't be asking for you.
Is that a journal?
Friend wrote an article.
In Hindi?
They have a cutting-edge
neuroscience program in India.
It says so right on the cover.
Kid's heart rate's messed.
Tachycardia can be
explained by the burn.
I assume the Burn
Unit knew that.
His potassium's low.
Which can also be
explained by the burn.
Except I'm sure the Burn
Unit's pumping him with fluids
which means his potassium
should be going up, not down.
Could be amphetamines.
Or bacteria
lunching on his heart.
Or cardiomyopathy, or
some other very bad thing.
He needs an EKG.
Okay, no skin, no EKG.
Is he even gonna
survive the burn?
What, you got a
date or something?
Forty percent of his body.
If the Burns Unit can
prevent an infection,
his body will
regenerate maybe 10%,
surgeons will do 20 or so
grafts, six months in this room,
he'll end up with a series of
nasty scars, maybe some pain,
but he'll live.
Unless his heart shuts down
'cause we can't figure out what's
causing the low potassium and tachycardia.
We need help from a
Belgian doc named Einthoven.
He's dead.
While he was alive, he invented a
little dittie called the Galvanometer.
Where do we get one?
Go to any electronics store
that's been open since before 1905.
There's a good chance they've
got one in a corner in the basement.
We need an audio-visual
setup for the lecture hall.
What for? For the lecture.
What lecture?
Dr. Weber's lecture.
Who is Dr. Weber?
A neurologist, I think.
The memo was from you.
Where is my assistant? She left.
When? Wednesday.
Seriously? Well, the temp
agency sent someone,
but she got lost.
Well, when she
gets here, fire her.
Oh, yeah.
Did you issue this
memo? Look at that.
Congratulations.
The patient that has been in a
coma for two years and counting
is still in a coma.
This is not my signature.
I don't know anything
about this guy.
I'm supposed to introduce
him? Have lunch?
The coma patient has a
migraine? Oh, no, no, no.
No, I gave him medication
to prevent a migraine.
That's a migraine.
Increased flow velocity
in his cerebral arteries.
I did subsequently give him
nitroglycerin, which could possibly...
You induced a migraine
headache in a coma patient?
I gave him a little headache, similar
to the one you're giving me now.
Have you even read
an ethical guideline?
Well, it would be wrong to try out a
new migraine prevention medication
on someone who
can actually feel pain.
Did you sign this? Yeah.
We can talk later about
the appropriate discipline.
Because of the burn,
we can't perform any of our
normal tests to see what's wrong.
So we're going to
try a Galvanometer.
It picks up a pulse in
the wrists and the ankles.
Hopefully it'll tell us why
his heart rhythm is abnormal.
What have I done to
him? I... It was an accident.
All right? So...
He's got all these burns
and now there's something
wrong with his heart?
We're trying to figure out if the
two are somehow connected.
Had he been sick
lately? No, nothing.
Anything unusual
with his behavior?
Had he been
tired a lot? Nothing.
He was great, he was happy, he
was just having a great time, and then...
If he was experimenting with
amphetamines or cocaine...
No.
We gave him some pot
about a year ago, to try...
It was just once.
We thought if we took the
mystery out of drugs and alcohol,
the less he'd experiment.
We'll know more after the tests.
It looks like they're
gonna electrocute him.
Plug it in.
You plug it in.
Fine. Give me the cord.
Works.
Prominent U waves.
No inverted T wave. No ischemia.
Q wave normal.
That's not good.
Okay, turn it off. Turn it off!
What's happening? What is that?
The seizure's getting...
Can't you stop that?
Who electrocuted my patient?
He had a seizure. CAMERON:
He wasn't electrocuted.
What does the
seizure tell us? Move.
What are you looking for?
Same as you are, love, acceptance,
solid return on an investment.
Differential diagnosis. Go.
Could be epilepsy
or seizure disorder.
Not with the tachycardia. It
could be a virus in his brain.
Your specificity's impressive.
Adrenoleukodystrophy.
Could be MS.
The seizures could be caused by
plaques and lesions on the brain.
Well, let's find out
which. Get him an MRI.
No nuclear imaging!
He wouldn't survive the move to
Radiology. MRI and CT scan are both out.
Okay, lumbar puncture will tell
us if his proteins are elevated,
at least we can exclude MS.
We can't do a lumbar
puncture either.
You're cramping my exits.
Don't tell me, no
skin on his spine.
We'd be inserting a needle into
an area that's teeming with bacteria.
If he doesn't have a brain infection
already, we'd give him one for sure.
There's no other
way to look at a brain.
Transcranial Doppler Sonography.
She said "brain," not
"pregnant woman's uterus."
They do sound alike. I used
one to look at a brain this morning.
Why didn't you take the patient
to Radiology, get an MRA?
Obviously I was
doing something illegal.
Using nuclear imaging
would have raised questions.
You're not gonna get a
diagnosis of MS from a sonogram.
Not definitively,
but patients with MS
have more reactive neurons
in their occipital cortex.
Okay then.
Thank you for all
coming to today's lecture
by Dr. Phillip Weber,
who is our guest
today at our hospital
to talk about headaches.
Dr. Weber is at the Weber
Center for Pain, that makes sense.
Weber, Weber. So
please welcome Dr. Weber!
Thank you Dr. Cuddy.
I suppose I should tell you
a little bit more about myself.
I went to school in Virginia.
You've never been to one
of these things in your life.
Who is this guy? No idea.
What's with the outfit?
Sudden chills and
light sensitivity.
Inexplicable.
I received my medical degree
at Johns Hopkins University,
where I studied under
Brightman and Gilmar...
Hmm. He must be good.
You went to Hopkins, and studied
under Brightman and Gilmar.
Shh.
Helped me win the Doyle
Internship at the Mayo Clinic.
You were supposed to
get the Doyle Internship.
This guy's Von Lieberman? The guy
who got you thrown out for cheating?
The dean threw me out. Von
Lieberman just ratted on me.
This guy's name is
Weber, not Von Lieberman.
I call Weber Von
Lieberman, way eviler.
Shh.
1D receptors have improved
the acute treatment of migraines,
to this point...
So what's the plan?
You gonna wait until he bends
over and make a fart sound?
I'm not here about the
past. He's a bad scientist.
Well, you cheated off
him, how bad can he be?
He got the answer wrong.
Are they trying to wake him up?
They can't do that, right?
He'll be in too much pain.
Don't worry, he's still under.
But the brain never completely
sleeps, it's always working.
Controlling your heart
rate, breathing, temperature.
The eyes respond
to visual stimuli.
Blood flow increases in
certain areas of the brain
and we can track
that with a sonogram.
With MS, blood vessels are
more reactive, so flow is faster.
If Adam has an infection,
there'd be swelling, which
would constrict the arteries.
And the flow would be slower.
Chase. Near the
subarachnoid space.
Data from control subjects were
analyzed of a two-way ANOVA
with status and side
as within-subject factors.
You stalked this guy for 20 years
just for this shot to humiliate him?
I'm trying to learn.
Vessels without
significant rebound...
He doesn't even
know what that means.
You're gonna interrupt
him, aren't you?
If I have a question.
And what's that
gonna accomplish?
Why can't you just enjoy this?
Why can't you just be happy for me?
You have got to find less debilitating
outlets than humiliating people.
I hear bowling is
more fun than stalking.
But I'm better at this.
If "P" is less
than point-zero...
Blow a ton of money
on a plasma TV.
We found a subarachnoid bleed.
Bleed in the head
isn't causing seizures.
It could be. 10% with damage
to cerebral cortex have a seizure.
Or bacterial meningitis.
Viral encephalitis? There's
no way to tell without...
Shut up!
Excuse me.
Not you.
You know, if my lecture is
interrupting your meeting, I can wait.
As your people say
in India. Appreciate it.
We'll figure out why later.
Fix the bleed or he dies.
Talk to you in a couple hours.
I'm in the subarachnoid space.
Can you get it? Think so.
Put the probe back where
it was so I can see the wire!
We're looking
for the bleed in...
Look when I get there, I'm flying
blind without a contrast CT here!
And with a p-value
of less than 0.001,
we have strong statistical evidence that
this drug prevents migraine headaches
without daily administration.
Excuse me, Doctor.
He knows his field
better than you do.
It's always been my understanding
that, unless you follow a daily regimen,
no drug can prevent a migraine.
That's why they call
it a breakthrough.
That's why you call
No, the pharmaceutical company
sponsoring my clinical trials
also hails it as a breakthrough.
I'm sure your wife
and lawyer do, too.
Is there anybody who doesn't
stand to make a fortune from it
calling it a breakthrough?
Who are you?
Just a lunatic who
desperately needs a hobby.
How exactly do
these studies work?
Do you give this drug
to a bunch of people,
and if they don't get a migraine,
you go, "Voilà, my drug works"?
Excuse me, miss?
Do you have cancer?
Wow! Mango juice
prevents cancer.
Perhaps I should have taken
my medication before this lecture.
We had a very specific control
group, chronic migraine sufferers.
I don't have time to go
through all the math right now,
but the incidence was
dramatically... Sure, in India.
Two plus two equals
five there, right?
Do I know you?
I know your math
skills. They blow.
Touché.
You sound very familiar.
Why did you publish it in
an obscure journal in India?
Why not publish it in really, really
cool head cases of South Philly?
Neuroscience New Delhi
is a respected journal.
Yeah. The guy running Slurp N'
Gulp tells me it's one of the best.
Get a hooker, anything.
See, I'm thinking that publishing
studies is probably the easiest way
to get a pharmaceutical company
to give you a reach-around.
And choosing a journal that no
one can actually read, well, that's...
That's shrewd.
I know I know you.
Sure you do, Dick.
The name's Philip.
My bad. Something
to do with your face.
I always think
your name is Dick.
House? Here.
Medical school was 20 years
ago. Give it a rest. Grow up.
Yeah. You were always the grown-up.
Do the responsible thing, tattletale!
You cheated! I cheated
then, you're cheating now!
Your drug doesn't work.
Oh, yes, you would like to believe that
because it plays right into your fantasy...
I tested it. Oh, really?
What are your parameters?
Where's your study?
Room 2134.
One patient? The coma patient?
You haven't changed a bit.
You took shortcuts in med
school, you're taking shortcuts now.
You cannot test this
on an abnormal brain.
That's so close-minded. He's
not abnormal, he's special.
Cerebral cortex
atrophies in coma patients.
You need live, conscious people.
You don't know
everything, House!
Something that
disrupts brain function.
Plaques are perfect. Interrupt
neuronal communication.
MS? No, MS is complicated.
I think this is more basic. It's
just tachycardia and seizures.
How much longer the Burn Unit
guys gonna keep him in that thing?
Lecture's over, let's
go. House wants to...
Adam's waking up.
Get the anesthesiologist
in here now.
He's in pain.
That's not pain.
Need some help in here!
Adam had an orgasm.
What? You mean,
while he was sedated...
What's wrong?
I'm having a migraine.
Are you okay?
Yes.
I was right.
I'm gonna knock you
out for a couple of hours.
No, I got work to do.
Just give me
sumatriptan for the pain
and verapamil
so it doesn't recur.
I heard the patient had fun
in the hyperbaric chamber.
Yeah.
Gotta schedule me
some time in there.
Weber's meds aren't
even legal in the U.S.
It's legal in India.
I was disoriented.
Moving around is a bad idea.
Hey, if you feel chest pain,
you need to let me know.
Verapamil can cause
congestive heart failure.
Nothing can hurt my heart.
Hey, you're gonna feel some
dizziness. Definitely gonna be constipated.
Differential diagnosis
for getting off.
Is he gonna be okay? No.
Something's seriously wrong with him.
Differential diagnosis
for ejaculation.
Don't make me say it again.
We're not stalling,
we just don't know.
Then guess.
Could pain medication
cause an orgasm? I wish.
Maybe pain caused the orgasm.
You get a tattoo, the brain releases
endorphins which create pleasure.
Most people don't
orgasm from a needle prick.
Well, Chase has a point.
The brain is like a huge
train station, if the switches...
You're the
neurologist, talk for me.
If sensory information got misinterpreted
by the medial forebrain bundle,
it's possible for bad to feel
good, and good to feel bad.
He's a lucky kid. Let's not
fix him until the burns heal.
So what attacks the
medial forebrain bundle?
Infective neuropathies,
vasculitic neuropathies...
Krabbe's disease,
metachromatic leukodystrophy.
All very bad things.
No way to look for any
of them in his condition.
Could be an infection.
I said infection about
eight seconds ago.
You listed some
brain infections.
But what if it's just a regular old
infection festering in the burned skin?
Pus on his arm isn't causing
problems in the forebrain.
He's on 20 different medications
to manage his pain, his heart,
how often he urinates.
His brain is like a waiter
that's got too many...
Hey, hey. I do the metaphors.
The brain is stressed.
An infection elsewhere
could put it over the edge.
So we just wait for his burns
to heal to see if you're right?
If you're wrong, he doesn't
have that kind of time.
Dominic Larrey.
He another dead doctor?
He's Napoleon's
Surgeon in Chief.
Cleaned a lot of battle wounds.
By amputating legs.
And with bugs.
Maggots are implanted
directly into Adam's burns.
Maggots, they eat dead people,
Maggots eat dead
flesh. Only dead flesh.
So they're perfectly
suited to clean wounds.
They also kill the bacteria
that thrive in injured tissues.
Dr. Jekyll, I presume.
They found a half-eaten sheep in the zoo.
The police wanna ask you a few questions.
I need something
to wash it down.
Coffee? Bad idea.
You're better off with
water! Coffee's closer.
Foolproof plan, by the way.
Either his meds would work,
and you'd be in psychic pain
because Von Evil is gonna be rich.
Or they wouldn't, and you
get to be in agony all day.
Perfect lose-lose
situation. Very you.
I had to prove...
You've proved nothing.
Right. This isn't a migraine.
Yeah. "Dear New England
Journal of Medicine,
"I took this guy's drug
and still got a headache.
"Thus, scientifically proving
that my arch enemy is an idiot."
You just wanted the pain.
Meds are supposed
to prevent migraine.
You get distracted by pain.
Leaves less room for the things
you don't wanna think about.
Like the Flyers sucking,
or the price of gas,
or the fact that you pushed the
love of your life out of your life.
God, I wish the
pain would go away.
Next time you need to get your
mind off her, stick a needle in your eye.
It's less annoying to the rest
of us when you can still walk.
Did you sleep here?
Lower.
Do you want a pillow?
Not softer, lower.
Frequency of your
voice is grating.
You should've
been better by now.
I'm super.
Patient?
The maggots did
great for the burn.
But the brain waves
are still all over the map.
Which means your regular old infection
isn't causing his brain dysfunction.
Which means there's
an underlying condition,
which means we've
gotta get inside his head.
Do a lumbar puncture.
We've already established
that we can't get a lumbar...
C2, C3.
No. No. No way.
I only saw a cervical tap once,
and that guy got paralyzed.
Ask the parents if they prefer to
have their son in a wheelchair or dead.
Something's causing
his brain to lose control.
Eventually it'll shut off.
We need to do a lumbar puncture
to get some of the fluid in
his spine so we can test it.
You need us to sign a consent?
I have to warn you.
There's a serious risk
of paralysis or death.
Are you saying we
shouldn't do this?
You have to do this.
Then why are you telling
us what can go wrong?
I just think you should
know... Either you're cruel
or this clipboard is a way
for you to cover your ass,
in case you cripple our
son. This isn't his fault.
No, it's not. It's yours, that's
what you keep telling me.
My son is lying
in there half-dead,
I am just trying to find a
way to get through this.
I'm sorry. Yeah, I know.
Needle.
It's not going
in. Don't force it.
I'm going one space higher.
It's too close to his
brain stem, it'll herniate.
You're gonna paralyze
him. You're not helping.
His blood pressure's
spiking, stop. I can get it.
He's 180 over 120,
he's gonna stroke.
I'm in the space.
Give me the vial.
He doesn't have
MS or an infection.
His proteins aren't elevated?
Wrong protein. lgM, not lgG.
Elevation was probably
caused by the bleed.
What if there was tingling in
his extremities prior to the crash?
How can you still be on
MS? I gotta be on something.
Something's interrupting his
neurons' chitchat, like lesions.
We can't scan for them.
The only test we can do, we
just did and it was negative.
He has no tingling, no numbness.
And you read his history,
parents didn't say anything about...
What about Adam?
We can't look into his brain,
but you want us to read his mind?
Good point.
Yeah, you can finish the
sponge bath in a minute.
They're just re-doing his
dressings. He's out, he's fine.
I didn't page you to put him
out. I paged you to wake him up.
Why are these
lights so damn bright?
Thank you.
Come on, I need to talk to him.
House, you can't wake up a burn
victim to play twenty questions.
It's torture. He won't remember.
He's gonna be in
extraordinary... God, you're good!
You're putting me to sleep.
I know he's gonna be in pain, I
know you disapprove. I'm his attending.
Wake him up.
Oh, my God!
I'm Dr. House. It hurts!
It's gonna get a lot
worse, so answer fast.
Before the accident, did you experience
any numbness or tingling in your fingers?
You got burned, it's
healing, I need an answer.
It really hurts!
Any tingling in
your arms or legs?
You gotta do
something, I can't...
Adam, you gotta listen to
me, did you feel anything?
I pissed in my pants and
then I don't remember...
Was he okay? Get
everyone in my office.
Where you going?
Kid's screaming gave me a
headache. I gotta take an aspirin.
House, you okay? We've
been waiting for you.
I'm hallucinating.
Hallucinations with migraines
are pretty uncommon.
What did you see? I saw music.
Sensory deception
makes no sense.
You took something.
The kid's fighting for his life.
Hey, you find him?
He was hallucinating
in the locker room.
He okay?
He's feeling no pain, he's high.
Vicodin high?
Past that. He's seeing sounds.
Took something.
Why is it so dark in here?
It's a beautiful day outside.
Open the shades,
let the sun shine in.
It's nighttime.
It's still Tuesday,
right? You look better.
I took something.
Mind if I ask what?
Little of this, little of that.
I know what's wrong
with our patient.
He's depressed.
He told you that when
you woke him up? Nope.
He told me he pissed
his pants and blacked out.
That's not diagnostic of depression.
Lack of appetite, isolating yourself.
Uncontrollable urination and blacking
out are good predictors of what?
Seizure.
Which means the seizure he
had when you tested his heart
was at least his second
seizure. So what?
Depression and seizures aren't
correlated. No, but you know what is?
Depression and
anti-depression medicine.
Tox screen was clean.
Yeah, but you know how
much crap he's got in his system
for dealing with those burns.
The guy could have the Spanish
Armada floating through his bloodstream
and we wouldn't know about
it, till they started firing cannons.
Antidepressants have been known to
cause seizures in kids, but not orgasms.
This is a brain in trouble. This is
a brain with too much serotonin.
Serotonin affects mood, appetite, it
doesn't cause the brain to shut down.
Antidepressants fake brains into
thinking they have more serotonin
than they actually do.
Every ten million or so
cases sets off a chain reaction.
Produces too much,
enough to fry itself.
If Adam has Serotonin
Storm, it's deadly.
But treatable. Cyproheptadine.
Unless he doesn't
have Serotonin Storm.
He could just as easily have
too much dopamine as serotonin,
but if it's dopamine, the
cyproheptadine will kill him.
Where are you going? Gonna
talk to the kid again, he seems nice.
You can't.
Why? Did he say
he doesn't like me?
Anesthesiologist told
the parents what you did.
Everyone's a tattletale.
Is your son depressed?
No. Who are you? I'm Dr. House.
Oh, you're the
idiot who thought...
I heard him screaming all
the way down the hallway.
If I didn't wake him up, I wouldn't
have learned what caused the crash.
He had a seizure.
This wasn't my fault?
Well, if he hadn't had the brain
problem, he wouldn't have the burns.
On the other hand, if you
hadn't put him on the ATV,
he also wouldn't have the burns.
You can debate your personal
responsibility after I leave.
I need to wake him up again.
I need to know if he's
taking antidepressants.
He's not.
He's the happiest kid I know.
But you don't know, do you?
He's my son.
That's sort of my point.
At 16, they'll tell anyone
anything, except their parents.
Adam talks to us
about everything.
Yeah, I know about
the pot and the cocaine.
There was never...
Cocaine. What...
Are you sure? Are you
having him followed?
He told us when he
got drunk at a party.
started having sex.
At 16? Way to go.
He told us when he
cheated on a math test.
He told us when his
girlfriend cheated on him.
He doesn't hide anything from
us. But if he was depressed?
He'd tell us.
We don't judge, he's not
depressed, we're sure.
"Bet his life on it" sure?
Just hypothetically.
Yeah.
Okay.
Kid's happy.
Happy, happy, happy.
Then we're back to where
we started. Seizure disorders.
Seizure disorders
aren't causing orgasms.
Vascular malformations?
Would've seen it
on the sonogram.
Hepatic encephalopathy?
Liver enzyme tests were normal.
Where are you
going? Take a leak.
What are you doing?
You can't come in
here, you're not sterile.
Don't touch our
son, we told you...
Seriously, millions of
bacteria, microbes on you.
He'll die of sepsis.
If you go in there...
I think he's gonna
wake him up again.
I know he is.
House, you can't do this.
Oh, if I had a nickel for every
time I've heard that. Relax.
Are they gonna sue us?
If I'm right, I save his life.
If I'm wrong, he's dead
no matter what I do.
Either way, how much
have I really hurt them?
Leave him alone!
You're not sterile. Do
you wanna kill the kid?
Give me the syringe.
No pain, no gain.
Hey, you gotta stop this.
They're right.
- He's not depressed.
- Yeah, sure.
I'm not letting you go till
you give me that syringe.
What's that on his wrist?
A burn.
Why on his wrist?
Why not on his wrist?
His back, his torso, everything's
a mess. His forearms are clean.
Except right there. So what?
It's a perfect circle.
So a drop of burning gasoline fell
on his wrist, a screw from the ATV.
Maybe.
Why are you torturing
him? Does your son smoke?
I'd kill him.
So, he can talk to you about sex,
crack, anything except cigarettes.
He has a cigarette
burn on his wrist.
Also a fading nicotine
stain between two fingers.
Bad news, your son has
a filthy, unhealthy habit.
Good news, he's trying to quit.
Bad news, the
quitting's killing him.
Good news, I can
cure him. Bad news...
Nope, that's the end of it.
Quitting smoking can kill?
No-smoke meds
are antidepressants.
The crappy ones you
get over the Internet
are loaded with whatever
antidepressants they can get cheap.
And since Mommy and Daddy obviously
didn't take him to a pediatrician...
Sorry, I was wrong about
him being depressed.
Treat him.
Hey!
Did you drop acid?
Why would I do
that? To annoy me.
Or maybe because
you're miserable,
or because you
want to self-destruct.
Pick one.
How about because LSD acts
on serotonin receptors in the brain,
which can stop a
migraine in its tracks.
I'm just saying that's
also a possibility.
How did you know about it?
Cameron is worried about you.
I told her that LSD lasts up to 12 hours,
if you were functional, she must be wrong.
Either that or I also took a
whole bunch of antidepressants,
which short-circuited the LSD.
I'm just saying that
would also explain it.
Thank you for ruining
my clinical trials.
Pharmaceutical company's
shutting me down.
You're kidding. Really?
How could that surprise you?
You sent them an email
complaining about my math,
telling them about your stunt.
I didn't know people
actually read emails.
Delete button's so conveniently
located. So what's next?
You gonna follow
me my whole life?
Torture me? Why would I do that?
You waited 20 years to do this.
What's next? Break up my marriage?
No. We're even. Right.
Oh, thanks for setting me up.
Eye for an eye, LSD
and antidepressants.
Everything in balance.
Buddhists call it Karma.
Christians call it the Golden Rule.
Jews call it...
I don't know, Rabbi Hillel
said something poignant.
Universe always
settles the score.
Does it? No.
But it should.
Do you think you'll ever be able
to look at him and not blame me?
Yeah. Will you?
I'm Paula.
Hey, Paula. How you doing?
You work over at the college,
or are you full-time over at the...
I'm looking for a distraction.
You don't need to
talk to do that, do you?