I took this at Lane's clinic.
Look at these dosages.
They are extremely high.
That's an awful accusation.
I get it, she's your mentor.
But you got to trust me.
The chemo was
so strong this time.
I'm worried about Lily.
I don't get your
obsession with this.
There's something else going on.
I'm dying. Please.
Please help me.
Charge to 200.
Clear.
- Ready.
- Charge to 200.
Clear.
We lost her pulse.
♪ ♪
Time of death...
21:58.
Watch where the
hell you're going!
God, what happened to you?
- Nothing.
- You look like you got hit by a truck.
- I'm fine.
- Let me run an X-ray just to make sure...
Sprained tibiofibular ligament.
Twisted ankle. Not necessary.
Put it in an air
stirrup for support...
- I said I'm fine!
- Oh.
Dr. Jacoby.
Oh!
Conrad Hawkins. How wonderful.
You were one of
my favorite students.
- You work here now?
- Third year of my residency.
Internal medicine. I was
just headed up to the floors.
So proud of you.
You're hurt.
I fell. Running.
It's no big deal.
Oh. Exercise.
Myself, I avoid it.
That's good advice. I
could've used that an hour ago.
Are you okay? Why are you here?
I see ghosts.
♪ ♪
I need you to use your
best bedside manner.
Really make him feel welcome.
Have I ever let you down?
The second richest man in
China is a very big get for Chastain.
- Foreign VIPs pay full freight.
- Ted Zhou.
Tumor in the caudate lobe of
his liver. Does he speak English?
He went to Oxford, Dr. Bell.
Well, I never heard of him.
On the cover of Forbes and
all the gossip magazines in Asia.
Sadly, I no longer
subscribe to Chinese gossip...
Well, I'll have security
bring him around to the back.
Guess I'll meet him upstairs.
She was stable last
night when I left my shift.
She was happy.
I...
I don't understand.
It happened so fast.
I went home.
I left her alone. I
should have stayed here.
You were at the
end of a double shift.
You can't be here every
second of every day.
It wouldn't have
made a difference.
She arrested, we
coded her. Too long.
Tried everything.
They should've gotten
rid of this last night.
You were with Lily last night?
New patient. Room
5417. Dr. Eileen Jacoby.
Do we have any
idea why she coded?
Sh-She was a professor
of mine in med school.
I'm just trying to
make sense of it.
Jacoby's important to me.
Lily was my patient, too.
Maybe we should talk about it.
What happened to your ankle?
Another question people
need to stop asking me.
Okay, let's go to an
exam room. I'll wrap it.
- You're not touching my ankle.
- I'm a doctor.
- That's the point. I've seen your work.
- Hey.
Claire Thorpe wants us
in her office in an hour.
Postmortem on Lily's code.
He's punishing himself.
He'll keep walking
on it until it snaps.
Hey. A bottle of Kenalog
rolled off the Mayo stand
and broke. Bed 5124.
Can I grab another?
- Sure, let me check the computer.
- You don't need
to look it up. I just
need 30 milligrams
to do a quick procedure.
Okay.
Here you go.
Is it true that Eileen Jacoby is
here and she is your patient?
Mm-hmm.
When I was nine in Nigeria,
I saw a news story about a
pioneering female neurosurgeon.
Footage of her doing
brain surgery in the 1970s.
All the other doctors were men,
and they tried to keep her out
of the OR, but she was
so good, they couldn't.
She did the first
microscopic AVM resection.
Eileen Jacoby is the reason I
decided to become a surgeon.
- You want to meet her?
- Yes.
And if you introduce me
to her, I won't tell anyone
you were shooting up in here.
Yeah. It was cortisone.
Tell anyone you want.
You know cortisone wears
off pretty quickly, right?
1664.
What kind of room
number is that?
You know, four
means death in China.
1664. is the number,
which sounds like...
which means "one road to death."
No one can survive
in a room like that.
If I walk in there, I'll have
a heart attack on the spot!
Those are just numbers, sir.
I need to get your vitals to...
Oh, don't tell me about
numbers. I run a search engine.
100 server farms
and the world's biggest
e-commerce website in the world.
And why are all the rooms
you're offering me facing south?
Health faces north.
A simple research
on the Internet
about Chinese customs
would tell you that!
Anne Huntington, the VIP wing.
I need help.
Shall we talk about my ghosts?
Okay.
This is a new one for me.
I'll give it a go.
Do you see them often?
All the time.
What do they look like?
Like you and me.
But dead.
They're my patients.
My neurosurgery patients.
The ones I couldn't save.
Jenny McBride.
13 years old.
Ruptured saccular aneurysm.
Rushed her into
surgery on a Friday night,
but it was too late.
She died on the table.
Bill Hodges. 44.
Married. Two children.
Grade IV anaplastic glioma.
I thought I excised
the entire tumor,
but... no.
Dead two months later.
I'd like to run some tests.
Yes. Of course.
Sometimes hallucinations
have a biological basis.
I've considered
that possibility.
But you don't
think it's the case?
What I think, Conrad,
is that I'm losing my mind.
Hey. I ordered you a scooter.
- Did I ask you for a scooter?
- No.
I can get my own damn scooter.
I've had dementia patients
more rational than you.
Well, you're not my
doctor, so stop trying.
Actually, I am.
I admitted you an hour
ago using your hospital ID.
You're patient number 421-78A.
High left ankle
sprain, under my care.
Ah, you think that's cute?
It's not cute.
You're right. It's not.
- It's my job.
- Okay, enough.
Remember, we want the hospital
to push for an investigation.
There's no more hope
for a second opinion
now that Lily's gone,
but an autopsy would prove
if Lane was overdosing
her with chemo.
Okay?
Yes. All right.
Dr. Hawkins,
Dr. Pravesh, Nurse Nevin,
thank you so
much for joining us.
Conrad, I'm so
sorry I wasn't there.
I know you tried to save
her life. I can't tell you
how devastated I am.
Lily Kendall's
death was untimely
and unfortunate, and I know
that everyone in this room
is grieving, but it is
important for the hospital
to understand exactly
what happened.
Her heart failed. That
much we know for certain.
But she was getting
massive chemotherapy, and...
an autopsy will tell us if that
played a role. We need to
make sure the doses she received
were appropriate.
Of course.
I absolutely agree.
An autopsy is 100% warranted.
Great. Then we're all
on the same page.
I'll call Pathology right away.
Claire,
please let me know the
minute you receive the results.
Of course.
Hey, Arthur.
- Randolph. Hey. How are you doing?
- Good.
Listen, I want to talk to you
about my friend with a tremor.
Enough. Let's be
honest with each other.
We both know your friend is you.
Look, it happens
to the best of us.
We get older, our hand shakes.
I'm on your side.
You've tried a
bunch of solutions.
You should consider
the possibility
that it might be stress-induced.
Lot of things coming
at you at once.
Chief of surgery,
face of the hospital.
Not to mention your divorce.
What is it, number four?
Two.
Two. Feels like four.
That's a boatload of pressure.
Yeah, well, what
do I do, Arthur?
Long term? Jog.
Swim. Learn to meditate.
Figure out a way to blow
off some of that anxiety.
Short term? Take a Xanax.
It's a benzo. I've tried those.
Mm. Nah...
This one will take the edge off.
Let you focus on
what really matters.
Come up to my office,
I'll give you a sample.
Works wonders.
Check it out.
And I'm paying for two kids in
college and a kitchen remodel.
This is between us, okay?
We look out for our own.
Full results are gonna
take at least a week,
but I might have a
preliminary cause of death
in less than 24 hours.
Blood drawn before
the code should help.
One question.
Why would Lane
agree to this autopsy?
You paged me?
I need you on the VIP wing.
Are they short-staffed?
New patient.
Ted Zhou, high security.
Driving the nurses nuts.
I'm a nurse practitioner,
I have my own patients.
The VIP wing's
coddling rich people.
That's why I want you up there.
Not a request.
An order.
I want a list of error
rates at every hospital
in the Southeastern
United States.
If Chastain Park can't
accommodate what my needs are...
Mr. Zhou, I hear you're
nervous about your surgery.
Who are you?
There were white
flowers in my room.
Now, in China, white
flowers for dead people.
Details matter.
Cultural sensitivity is a
marker for overall competence.
Everybody gets
anxious in a hospital.
Lack of control, strange place.
I understand, but
you're gonna be fine.
I am a nurse, not an assassin.
If you don't trust us, then
you can leave Chastain.
But if you put your hands on
me again, I will have you arrested.
It's okay.
I like your attitude, Ms...?
- Nevin.
- Ah.
What's a lucky number
in China, Mr. Zhou?
In this instance, three.
Three means "life."
Come with me.
- Better?
- Very clever.
Now, if you worked for me,
I'd promote you immediately.
Well, I can't wait to
discuss my new salary,
after your surgery.
I want to see if the
hallucinations are a result
of encephalitis.
I'd like to think
that having done
a few thousand of these myself
would make it hurt less,
but it doesn't.
No whites, no reds?
Everything's normal?
Dr. Bell, do you still
want me to take over?
Yeah, I was gonna
supervise the anastomosis.
I think I'll finish up.
2-0 silk.
- Mina.
- I know.
I have Dr. Jacoby's
test results.
Tag along if you
want to meet her.
I've prepared a speech.
This is too important of a
meeting to forget a single word.
Fair warning: do you know
why Dr. Jacoby's here?
No.
Let's just say she's
not her old self.
Dr. Jacoby.
I'd like to introduce
you to someone,
our star surgical
resident, Dr. Mina Okafor.
It is a great honor to
meet you, Dr. Jacoby.
I've followed your career,
starting when I was a child.
I used to read about you in
my uncle's medical journals,
I collected a video
library of your surgeries.
I've played them over and
over to learn your technique.
Your retromastoid and
curvilinear incisions are...
remarkable.
Well, I'm honored.
Thank you.
What are you looking at?
Mrs. Hamilton... had
a spinal cord injury.
Compressed fracture
between T7 and T8.
Car accident.
I transgressed the cord
with a titanium screw.
She never walked again.
Your test results... EEG
and spinal tap... They
both came back normal.
So I am losing my mind.
Let's focus on other
possible diagnoses first.
I read in your chart
that you're a vegetarian?
A lifelong vegan.
Vegetarians often suffer
from B12 deficiencies.
A B12 deficiency can
cause people to hallucinate.
In some people; it's rare.
One in 1,000, but it happens,
- so we'll give you...
- High-dose B12 injections.
You really think
that will do the trick?
Honestly, I'm not sure, but
it's a quick and easy gamble,
so why not?
I'll take that gamble.
Time to turn that off. No cell
phones in the operating suite.
I was talking to my lawyer.
Making preparations
in case I die.
You know, I'm gonna
give all my money away.
I don't want to
spoil my children.
- They have to learn to stand on their own.
- Well,
I'm definitely on board with
your parenting, Mr. Zhou,
but you are not going to die.
At least not here, not today.
So nothing bad ever happens
to patients under your care?
Mr. Zhou.
So nice to see you again.
Are we making you feel welcome?
Dr. Bell. The man on the poster.
Nurse Nevin assures me
I'm in good hands here.
The very best.
Alan Wyatt.
It's a craniotomy
and a facial nerve transection.
It was Mass General,
spring of 1983.
I-I should have
cut a little higher.
This is Supervisor
Stevens, fifth floor.
I need extension 43.
What the hell's
he doing in here?
We thought he might have a gun.
Oh, so you just
let him in the OR?
Mm-hmm.
Dr. Butler, can we run
through the checklist, please?
Yes, sir. One, uh,
please confirm the
name of the patient.
- Ted Zhou. Male, 55.
- Confirmed.
Two, please confirm
the procedure.
Caudate lobectomy.
Confirmed.
See the way she neatly accesses
the superior temporal lobe.
Gives you goose
bumps, doesn't it?
Not how I would describe it.
I heard she sees ghosts.
Conrad already found the
biological basis: low B12.
There's no such thing as ghosts.
Not true. I've seen a
ghost right here at Chastain.
Room 1313.
Lot of people died in that room.
Totally haunted.
Don't be an idiot.
I read that ghosts were
big in Nigerian culture.
This is America.
The Garuda Purana says
it takes 13 days for the
soul of a dead person
to transition to the eternal.
If the deceased's
desires aren't satisfied,
they get stuck in limbo.
They become Prayt
Yonee, a ghost.
I was thinking about Lily...
how she didn't die
on her own terms.
Something to say, Dr. Butler?
I'm-I'm sorry. It's just,
it looks like the caudate
lobe is encircling the IVC.
Should we tie off the
small hepatic veins?
In case they bleed when
we excise the tumor.
Not necessary. That's a
backup in case of error.
This is flawless.
Yes, sir.
Where's Dr. Jacoby?
Sent for psych eval.
What? Why?
She was roaming the
halls talking to herself.
So you want me to lie?
They'll keep her in the
psych ward for 72 hours.
She's a frail, old woman.
So, yes, lie.
Just get the point across.
Given your multiple knee
surgeries, you should really...
Did you pull my medical history?
Johnson in Orthopedics
has this boot...
No!
Fine, but I won't quit.
She's grossly psychotic.
We're putting her on a hold.
Conrad. MRI results. Brain
bleed in her frontal lobe.
Well, that could explain
her hallucinations.
She needs surgery.
ASAP.
I have a brain bleed?
I had to tell 'em something.
B12 shots didn't
do a damn thing.
You have not changed.
Not at all.
Sometimes we wish he would.
Who is this handsome young man?
Devon Pravesh, Dr. Jacoby.
I've heard a lot about you.
All scandals, I hope.
Ah, lurid but very enjoyable.
We need to consider
a different diagnosis.
Another test, huh?
A PET scan or MRI?
No, no more tests.
You and I need to discuss
what's really going on.
How you feeling, Mr. Zhou?
Can you hear me?
Dr. Bell's surgery went well?
Well... the patient survived.
Am I missing something? Were
you expecting a different outcome?
Mr. Zhou, can
you look over here?
Get back.
-Hey, out! -BP 70/30.
- I need two units of PRBCs.
- Cycling again.
His pulse is getting weak.
Systolic is down to 50.
Can someone tell me
what's happening, please?
Page Dr. Okafor and Dr. Silva.
Patient needs the OR, stat.
Why Silva and Okafor?
That's Dr. Bell's patient.
He's bleeding internally.
My guess is it's
Dr. Bell's fault.
Now, you can
let him try to fix it,
or would you prefer
Mr. Zhou lives?
Ladies and gentlemen, if I
could have your attention.
I'm Dr. Randolph Bell,
Mr. Zhou's surgeon.
We completed the
operation at about 2:50.
Blood pooling behind the IVC.
Yeah.
Clamps for me and Dr. Okafor.
No one tied off
the hepatic veins.
Who removes the
caudate without...?
Dr. Bell said it was
a waste of time.
He should've known better.
In over his head, as usual.
Okay, infrahepatic
clamp's in place.
- Suturing now?
- What's going on?
Hey, how many people have to die
before you turn in
your scrubs, huh?
It doesn't matter
how great you were,
it's how great you
are, here and now.
You don't have it
anymore. It's time to retire.
How dare you? You
question my ability?
Not in my OR.
Not in my hospital.
I see incompetence, I
call it out. End of story.
And this isn't your hospital.
I've operated on
more patients...
You didn't tie off
the hepatic veins.
You caused a tear in the IVC.
Now, a second-year resident
doesn't make that mistake,
but you did.
Ted Zhou is my patient.
No. Not anymore he's not.
- I wanted you to see this place.
- Mm-hmm.
Have a simple conversation.
- I know it would do me some good.
- Fine. About what?
Ghosts.
You think the ones
you see are real?
Oh. Now, that's a
complicated question.
They...
They're as real as
human regret or guilt.
I keep thinking they
want something.
Are they angry?
Or do they blame me?
Sadly, they can't speak.
So what I want most of all
is to undo the mistakes.
And I can't.
Dr. Jacoby.
Depression is a
very powerful illness,
we both know that.
Would you consider
the possibility
that depression with
psychotic effect could lead to...
Hallucinations. Yeah.
Yes.
Well, I have good
reason to be depressed.
My career is over, my best
years are behind me, and...
You've had a wonderful career.
Broken down barriers.
Trained so many great doctors.
You are an inspiration.
- And you saved so many lives.
- But I lost so many as well.
I carry around a small
cemetery in my brain.
You took on the riskiest cases
and had so many triumphs.
Yeah, well, joy
leaves too quickly
and sorrow rudely overstays.
Over the course of 40 years,
not every outcome
is gonna be perfect.
The only thing any
of us can hope for
is the good we do far
outweighs the harm.
No amount of talk is going
to change the past, Conrad.
There are some
memories you can't escape.
He's still Chief of Surgery.
He could have you fired.
Dr. Bell,
I, uh...
I lost my temper earlier.
Heat of the moment.
We could use a hand.
Maybe you can run
the patient's bowel.
Hey, Dr. Silva, you don't invite
me back into my own surgery.
I'll make that call.
But you're right,
you do need help.
You crossed a line.
Duly noted.
Step aside.
There's an obstructive mass.
We'll have to resect it and
look for other metastasis.
I'll save his life.
Dr. Silva.
Another tour of duty
or another hospital.
That's your future.
The board will be revoking
your privileges at Chastain.
What was that all about?
You know, in 1980 the
Shah of Iran was sick.
Had to have his spleen removed.
They brought in the most
famous doctor in the world,
Michael DeBakey.
Now, DeBakey
was a heart surgeon.
You know, he'd only done
a handful of splenectomies
his entire career.
But operating on the Shah, well,
that was an honor
he just couldn't resist.
He botched the operation,
and ten days later, the
Shah died from complications.
DeBakey never once
admitted his mistake.
That was 40 years ago,
and nothing's changed.
Mina, I need your help.
You tried your best,
and I appreciate it,
but enough is enough.
Dr. Okafor has a favor
to ask before you go.
There is an operating microscope
in OR Three that I
cannot rebalance.
I've tried a dozen times.
They were your specialty.
I was wondering if
you might help me.
Oh. Well, I suppose
I have the time.
Not like they're knocking my
door down to do a TED Talk.
Shall we?
Really?
So the way I see it,
you have two options.
One, you continue to hobble
around here like an ass.
Eventually you'll
completely tear your ligament
and require surgery.
Or two, you pick one of these.
Conrad.
You didn't listen
to Nic about Lane.
I believed her.
You didn't.
I saved Lily once. You lost her.
But you get to be the only
one around here in pain?
Uh-uh.
Don't malign me as a doctor,
keeping me from
treating your foot.
For Lily, I was a better
doctor than you were.
It's been weeks since
anyone's been able to use it.
I tried to rebalance, but the
stabilizer arm won't sit still.
Oh. Ooh.
- That's not good.
- Yeah.
Perhaps you could give it a try?
It's been quite a while. I'm
not sure I remember how.
Well, what harm
could it do, huh?
Okay. No...
- Was it me? Not the machine?
- No, the counterbalance is off.
We have to raise
the arm like so.
And...
And then refocus the optics.
There.
That should help.
Poetry.
Oh, my.
Strange how good this feels.
I always used to be terrified
at the start of an operation.
You know, in neurosurgery,
the margin of error is so slim.
But as soon as I felt
these controls in my hands,
the fear would just disappear.
I'm sorry.
I'm a silly old woman getting
emotional over a machine.
I am very emotional
about machines.
People, not so much.
Thank you.
Oh. Oh, my dear.
Fixing it was nothing.
No. For being my hero.
Mr. Zhou, you came through
the surgery with flying colors.
But there was a complication.
During the course
of removing the tumor
- from your liver...
- Is there something wrong?
I found a single metastatic mass
in your intestine causing an
obstruction, which I removed,
all of it.
Now, we're still waiting
on the pathology,
but you should be in the clear.
You truly are a great
surgeon, Dr. Bell.
A small token of
my appreciation.
Is this...?
It's real, of course.
24 karats.
I would be insulted
if you didn't accept it.
Well, if you insist, I...
I'd like to stay for a
moment if that's all right.
Of course... but I have surgery.
I'll close up the room,
and I'll make sure the
lights are off, I promise.
Okay.
Thanks.
I'm sorry.
I did my best.
How's the patient?
Resting peacefully,
thanks to you.
So, I kind of got
into a bit of a thing
with Bell in the OR earlier.
I know. It's all
anyone's talking about.
Hmm. I'm done at this hospital.
Jude, you're one of the best.
- You'll survive.
- No, not this time.
No, the bridge is
burned... for good.
I just wanted to tell you, um,
how sorry I am about Lily.
Thank you.
I'll see you around, Nic.
See you around, Jude.
You really need to get
that looked at, Conrad.
Spoke to our head of psychiatry.
She offered to start seeing
you herself next week.
Depression needs
to be fought head-on.
The world needs
more doctors like you.
Which is why I've decided
to go back to teaching.
That sounds like a perfect
way to let go of the past.
Live forward with purpose.
And forgive ourselves.
You lost someone as well, hmm?
Recently?
Then you need
to live forward, too.
Come in.
Hey.
So, I, uh, heard
you had a bad day.
Listen, you saved
a man's life today.
You're an incredible
surgeon, Randolph.
People are jealous.
The higher we
rise in this world,
the more the little people
want to bring us down.
But you, my friend,
you can fight it.
I have, believe me.
Could get ten grand
for this... maybe.
You don't need the
money, a man like you.
I sunk two million bucks
into a motel in Conyers,
a million and a half on the
Bell Tool, and the divorce...
That was...
the most recent blow.
Oh, I'm good at a lot of
things. Money isn't one of them.
Unbelievable.
After all the billing
you generate for
Chastain every year.
- None of it in my pocket.
- You know where it ends up.
In the pocket of our CEO.
Claire Thorpe makes
three million dollars a year.
Yeah. She's not even a doctor.
She's a complete
incompetent, if you ask me.
I mean, all that nonsense
about transparency.
Exposes us to lawsuits,
forces us to practice
defensive medicine.
You know, she's
destroying this hospital.
We need to have a
physician running Chastain,
not an MBA.
I mean, you could
do the job, Randolph.
You'd be great at it.
I mean, not that you'd
want to do it, of course.
Let's have that drink.
Cheers.
What?
What are you thinking?
Nothing.
♪ You remember ♪
♪ You remember my love... ♪
Really getting into this, huh?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, it's a good look on you.
You and Bell kiss and make up?
Uh, you ever checked out
Doctors Without Borders?
They send you to hot
spots all over the globe.
Yeah, I know about 'em.
What are you talking about?
Saving lives while
people shoot at you...
It's kind of my speed.
They're doing real
good in the world.
Jude, I'll walk into
Bell's office right now...
No, no, no, no.
I stayed at Chastain
for the wrong reasons.
And I should have
gone with my gut
a long time ago and moved on.
That's the truth.
We both know it.
You said... Nic deserves me.
You said I can give
her what you can't.
Yeah, and?
Lily's death.
She's hurting pretty bad.
You see, I want to
help her, but I can't.
I'm not the guy that's
gonna make it better for her.
Only you can do that.
Hey.
Stay safe.
Brother.
Nic.
You never got X-rays, did you?
I'm not here to
talk about my ankle.
Your ankle's getting worse.
Honestly, it's killing me.
Come on, I'll drive you.
Take you three days to get
home on that stupid scooter.
Been a while since
I've been here.
The stairs were fun.
Well, we made it. Go sit down.
Ice pack's in...
First aid kit's still
on top of the...
Right, you know.
Give me your foot.
I'm not a doctor. I'm
not gonna hurt you.
Oh, my God.
You know, if you would have
let me do this this morning,
it wouldn't have gotten so bad.
But things are never that
simple with you, are they?
Nic?
I should have
listened to you sooner,
believed what you said
about Lane, but I just...
I didn't.
Keep it elevated,
ice it every hour,
take an anti-inflammatory.
You know the drill.
Please.
I don't want to do this.
I just... I can't.
What do you want me to say?
Nothing.
Because it's not your fault.
It's mine.
And Lily's gone.
It's killing me.
But that is no excuse
not to see your pain.
I'm sorry... for everything.
♪ I love the way ♪
♪ You never doubt me ♪
♪ Even though ♪
♪ I'm just a fantasy ♪
♪ I can't see straight ♪
♪ When I'm around you ♪
♪ Hold me down ♪
♪ I'm losing gravity ♪
♪ Don't tell me it's too late ♪
♪ We can work this out for now ♪
♪ I won't run anymore ♪
♪ You know I'll do
whatever you want. ♪
♪ ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH