Previously on "ER.."
What's your
son's name, Dr. Benton?
He doesn't have one.
You got a full arrest,
you call on attending.
You don't play
the hero. You get help.
‐ Let's have a beer.
‐ Okay.
‐ Dr. Benton?
‐ Yeah.
Elizabeth Corday..
...visiting surgical lecturer
and your savior.
You take Dr. Del Amico back.
I'm intimidated enough already.
‐ Anna, please.
‐ Alright, Anna.
If Dr. Minz calls, let
him know I'm on my way out.
‐ Okey‐dokey.
‐ Goodnight.
I have nothing to say, okay.
I agreed to have you follow
me on the job, we can do that
but no more interviews.
'WMAQ 670 news. Good morning,
Chicago. I'm Pat Cassidy.'
'It's hot, too hot. Temperatures
expected to press 100 degrees..'
Son of a bitch! What the hell
do you think you're doing?
Dr. Greene?
I'm sorry.
I thought, that's alright.
You don't have to stop.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
‐ I'm not stopping, I'm parking.
‐ Where, on the street?
Yeah. I don't park
in the garage anymore.
I don't blame you.
Place gives me the creeps too.
Nah, it's alright. It's alright.
It's not even a dent.
It's a nice car.
Good color.
You should use
the crosswalk, Carter.
‐ Right.
‐ You're in early?
Yeah. I wanted to be here
before my med student.
Ah, you're very own scutpuppy.
Somebody to pick up my labs.
Someone to do a patient history.
The occasional
obligatory rectal exam.
‐ And someone to abuse.
‐ No‐no, this is about teaching.
This is completely
about teaching.
‐ The way Benton taught you?
‐ Or even better.
Threat to
parents with children
'who will get sick
this school year.'
'And with more than a 100
viruses floating around..'
Hello?
Dr. Morgenstern?
Come here. Come here, you.
David.
Little guy has a tendency
to get away from you.
‐ Whoop.
‐ Here, let me.
There you go.
Kerry Weaver.
Katie Couric.
Katie Couric, Kerry Weaver.
So, David,
how are you feeling?
Morphine, damn fine stuff.
I talked to Dr. Weintraub today.
She said they're
tapering your lidocaine
echo showed very little damage
to your myocardium.
Uh, I put the nitro patch here.
Just as effective.
Most doc put it
on the patient's chest.
I say, why tear out these little
hairs, if you don't have to?
Uh, you know, I have some
forms that billing sent down
for you to sign the CPT codes
for the attending's
for last month.
They're always
sending me this junk
forms, paper work, duplicates.
Little perforated lines.
"Tear here."
They must not have heard
about your heart attack.
Now, if you want to look
them over, I can send them‐‐
I never look them over.
You just sign them for me
and send them back.
‐ You want me to sign them?
‐ I want you to sign everything.
Send everything back.
You don't mind if I step in
and take over a little bit?
Praise Allah, no.
I don't mind telling you
sometimes I have felt
like a sheriff with no posse.
Like a general with no
...grunts in the field.
Like a lone shepherd,
high up on a hill, no sheep dog.
I completely
understand how you feel.
You know, I'd like to take‐‐
Everywhere you look
there's sheep, sheep, sheep.
Maybe it would be best
if I stepped in and took over
some of
the administrative duties
while you're recuperating.
God bless you, Kerry Weaver.
God bless you.
Doug?
Ketchup or Tabasco
...in your scrambled eggs?
You want, uh, something
some people consider a vegetable
or do you wanna go with
something a little more daring?
You thought I left, didn't you?
‐ No, I didn't.
‐ Yes, you did.
No, really, I didn't.
Okay, yeah, I did. But you, you
kind of did leave, technically.
Well, that doesn't count.
If you'd gotten up
a little bit earlier
you would have seen
me here, sound asleep.
‐ Some habits die hard.
‐ Yeah, like you sleeping in.
Like you not being
there in the morning.
Ah, that's an old habit.
‐ Wow. Thank you.
‐ Mm.
Okay, I got to talk
to you about something.
Oh, Doug, not another
serious conversation.
You used to say we
didn't communicate, so‐‐
I know, but now
you're communicating
a little bit too much.
This is important.
Can I have a drawer?
‐ What?
‐ A drawer.
Something you keep
your clothes in.
Something that
I would keep my clothes in.
You never wanted
a drawer before.
Well..
That's 'cause
I always got up and left.
Now, that I'm staying here..
Hmm?
If I could maybe
just have, um...someplace to..
...well, keep a new shirt.
‐ Yeah?
‐ And a nice pair of socks.
Mm‐hmm.
I'd settle for underwear.
You know..
...you can always just wash
your boxers out in the sink.
They'll be dry by the morning.
‐ Come here.
‐ Mm.
Oh, my.
'So, Morgenstern
asked you to stop by?'
Well, I had some forms
for him to sign
and next thing you know,
he's making me acting chief
of emergency services
while he recuperates.
I think‐I think he's
been under a lot more stress
than any of us realize.
Oh, Mark, can I give Mrs. Crane
another 50 of Demerol?
She is extremely touchy.
Yes, I know and yes, you can.
‐ Convention?
‐ Tour bus.
They're waiting
for their driver.
He ate bad eggs at Pulipski's
and now, he's puking up
his guts in exam room four.
So, maybe we should talk
to Morgenstern's doctor.
‐ Who's taking care of him?
‐ Emma Weintraub.
And actually,
I already talked to her.
No more PVC's,
but intermittent chest pain.
They scheduled angioplasty.
So, in the meantime,
you'll be filling in?
Well, David asked me
to do what I can
to fill in with some
administrative duties
as long as you don't have
a problem with that.
The only problem I'd have,
would be, if I had to do it.
‐ Excellent point
‐ Good morning, everyone.
‐ What is that, a convention?
‐ Tour bus.
‐ No kids, I hope.
‐ It's your lucky day.
Jerry, pull the QA and QI data
for the past three months.
‐ You're kidding?
‐ Now!
‐ Morning.
‐ Good morning, Carol.
‐ Did you sleep well?
‐ I did, yes. Thank you, Doug.
‐ Tour bus?
‐ Bingo.
Mark, I need to attend
the executive committee meeting
for JCAHO's next visit,
and I‐I wanted to know
if you and Carol could
interview the candidates
for the new desk
clerk position.
They should be here
around noon.
‐ It'd be a pleasure.
‐ Great.
Just clear
your selection through me
before you make a final one.
‐ Hey, you going somewhere?
‐ Not that I know of.
'Dr. Mark Greene?'
‐ Yeah.
‐ This is for you.
Wait a minute. Who are you?
Uh, there's a name and number
of an attorney on the inside
if you want to call
for information.
What is this, a subpoena?
Oh, man.
You coming into the clinic
at 4:00, right? Al?
Al! Al.
Yeah. Don't worry.
I'll be there.
As long as I can
come up with another excuse
to leave work early.
I wish you could
just tell Roswell the truth.
That I have AIDS? Come on.
Take him only five
seconds to fire me.
Okay, uh, how about
you have to pick your mother up
from the airport?
I used that one.
One of our kids is sick?
Well, all four
have already had
every childhood
disease known to man.
How about your
grandmother was sick.
You have to swing by
to see how she's doing.
Yeah, well,
poor grandma had a stroke.
Went to her funeral last month.
Al, that's horrible.
I know,
I know, but it worked.
Got me the afternoon off.
I'd better get going.
Yeah, well, just make sure
you get this afternoon off.
'Cause if you miss
your clinic appointment
you could lose your meds.
‐ Yeah, yeah, yeah, okay.
‐ Yeah, yeah, yeah, okay, okay?
Don't worry.
'He's ready
to come off, of the vent'
You wanna extubate him today?
It's been three weeks.
I think he's ready.
What about a trial of C.PAP?
Well, he's almost
at room air, setting at 99.
He says that's good.
No, uh, I know it's good,
Carla, but, uh..
...he‐he could end up
back on a‐a ventilator.
That's very unlikely.
I'll extubate him
this afternoon.
What's wrong with you, Peter?
Why are you so against
hearing good news?
Carla, I just want to be sure.
You haven't even wanted
to give him a name
fix the birth certificate. What?
It's going to be
baby boy Reese forever?
Look, we weren't even sure
if he was going to make it.
But now we are.
But the next ultrasound of
his brain could show bleeding.
And the sky
could be falling, too, Peter.
We need to get on with his life.
The first thing I'm doing
is taking down those bunks.
Don't you even think
about arguing with me.
Alright. He's too smart for
that, aren't you, Skyler?
It was my husband's bright idea.
He had bunks when he was a boy.
Seven brothers, we had bunks all
over the house when I was a kid.
‐ You never fell out?
‐ Uh, no.
But I was pushed
a number of times.
Anna, you got a minute?
Uh, the nurse will be in
with your ortho
referral, Mrs. McClay.
And Skyler, uh, take the bottom
bunk for a while, okay?
Thank you.
‐ Looking over the charts‐‐
‐ Hey, you know what?
In front of the patients
I'd appreciate
if you called me
Dr. Del Amico.
‐ I didn't?
‐ Nope. You called me Anna.
Alright. I didn't mean
anything by it.
I've probably
called Mark Greene
"Mark" in front of his patients.
‐ That would be wrong too.
‐ Okay, I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Um, what about the charts?
Now, you've worked mostly peds
since you started, right?
Hang on.
Did you disagree with my
handling of any of those cases?
No. It's, um, do you want to
talk about this someplace else?
No.
Sometimes it's easier
to go with what we know.
Now, uh, you've done
a peds residency
but you were here
on an emergency residency
and I think you would benefit
by working with more adults.
Well, I appreciate your concern
but I think I can
balance my own caseload.
Well, I don't,
I don't know, you, you‐‐
A‐and y‐you're not
supervising my residency here.
‐ Well, pediatrics, I am.
‐ Okay.
Anna, adults you run
by Dr. Doyle first
then either myself
or Dr. Weaver, okay?
‐ You, too, Carter.
‐ What?
‐ Run my cases by Maggie?
‐ That's right.
Dr. Greene, excuse me,
but I've actually done
quite a few more
ER procedures than she has.
Uh‐huh, and you are what year?
Technically, I'm an intern,
first year and she's second year
but I spent half my surgical
internship teaching her.
‐ No, you didn't.
‐ I taught you!
I taught you how
to tie one‐handed knots.
‐ Big deal.
‐ Okay, look, that's enough.
Is everybody clear about
who runs what by whom?
Yeah?
‐ Where are the students?
‐ Cafeteria.
Doug, Anna was gonna take
these barfing twins in five.
'Peter, you've met
Elizabeth Corday, haven't you?'
‐ Oh, yes, we've met.
‐ Uh, yeah. Hi.
I was wondering if you'd assist
her today, show her the ropes.
Well, I don't know
my surgical schedule.
No, just in trauma.
Penetrating trauma,
gunshot wounds.
‐ That sort of thing.
‐ Yeah, sure. No problem.
I was scheduled to
tag along with Mr. Campbell
but apparently he's
in hospital with a kidney stone.
And seeing as Dr. Carter
isn't taking up any
more of your time..
No problem. You know what, this
is the ER right now, so, uh..
‐ Oh, lovely.
‐ Good.
Ah, which one do you want?
I don't really want
either of them.
I had plenty of students
back at CHOP. You choose.
Let's just go along
gender lines. I'll take the guy.
Hi. I'm John Carter.
This is Anna Del Amico.
‐ Hi. Chasity Lee.
‐ Chastity?
Uh, no, that would be
as in Bono.
No middle "T." Just Chasity.
‐ And I'm George Henry.
‐ Uh, okay.
Uh, you'll be with me.
Looking forward to
finally doing my ER rotation.
My dad's a trauma surgeon.
I know there's gonna be
a lot of scut work
but I'm glad to finally
start seeing some patients.
Oh, uh, uh, John,
I should probably mention
that I'm not actually
all that interested
in working with patients.
‐ Excuse me?
‐ I'm getting my M. D. PhD.
I finished my first
two years of med school.
I've been doing bench research
for the past four years.
Uh, patients just aren't
all that helpful to my research.
Yeah, but you haven't had any
medical training in four years?
You remember anything? About the
path of physiology of disease?
‐ How to do a physical exam?
‐ No, no, not really.
No, I‐I've been doing
brain research.
Studying genetic
markers for Angelman's Syndrome.
Well, you may know it
as "happy puppet's disease."
It, um, causes the afflicted
to laugh inappropriately
and to flap their hands
like a‐a puppet...on a string.
Wow.
'Okay, get x‐ray in here.'
Please, it hurts.
Caught a good one there,
didn't you, Ernesto?
Oh, man.
This is Elizabeth Corday,
new surgical resident.
It's a pleasure. How do you do?
Alright, people,
what do we have?
Uh, GSW to the right chest,
sixth intercostal space.
Got two liters of saline
in the field. BP is 100 over 60.
‐ He's tachy at 120.
‐ Pulse ox 95 on 10 liters.
Alright, this is Dr. Corday's
first gunshot trauma.
So, people, let's run it
by the numbers.
‐ I'm Miss Corday, and you are?
‐ Ernesto Ruiz.
You've a rather nasty hole
right near your nipple, Ernesto.
‐ Somebody call my mom, please.
‐ Forget about it.
You can tell her yourself
what you've been doing.
Alright, primary survey.
Assess the airway
and the respiratory effort.
No sign of tension pneumo
or cardiac tamponade.
Next, auscultation of the heart
and lungs while palpating
the carotid pulse.
Do you by any chance know,
what sort of bullet
you were shot with?
Palpable carotid indicates
a systolic BP of at least 60
no muffled heart sounds.
But we've got diminished
breath sounds on the right.
‐ This guy needs a chest tube.
‐ Alright, 32 French.
‐ Let's move.
‐ Nine millimeter.
I think he was shot
with a nine millimeter.
Is that's one
of the semiautomatics?
'Uh, right, the entrance wound
is pretty typical'
but the exit wound
is a little bigger
because the bullet yards
through 90 degrees.
'Cavity's a little
larger than a 38 special.'
‐ Is that temporary cavitation?
‐ 'Oh, God, no.'
'You need an Ak‐47 for that.'
Nine millimeter's low velocity.
Only 1200 feet per second.
Listen, when we get in there,
just stand back, observe.
Don't do anything.
I don't know how
to do anything.
‐ So you've said.
‐ Wait. W‐why are we going here?
‐ They didn't page us.
‐ Henry.
When you hear there's a good
case you show up, try to help.
They always let you stay.
Just follow my lead, okay?
Horizontal mattress
with "O" silk.
Xeroform here.
And the velocity
with a 45 automatic is?
Oh, about 900
feet per second.
Doesn't deform or yaw.
How do you do?
I'm Miss Corday.
I'm John Carter.
This is my student,
George Henry.
What've we got?
Ah. You can see they just
put in a chest tube.
Probably a hemopneumothorax.
Carter, what are you
doing here?
Just wanted to help out.
'Less than 500cc's of blood.'
That means they won't have to do
an exploratory thoracotomy.
‐ We don't need you.
‐ Didn't page you.
Well, as long as I'm here
if there's something
that you do need‐‐
Carter, take a look around.
There are four doctors here.
‐ Well, yeah, I realize that‐‐
‐ We got it, John.
Why don't you check
with Dr. Greene.
Right.
Okay, Henry, I think
Dr. Greene probably needs us.
Your feet, ma'am.
Let me have your feet.
How much
did you drink, Ethyl?
I don't drink.
I had a good job.
Right. Oh, good timing, Carter.
Who's this?
This is Henry,
my med student.
Well, you get to start
with a good one, Henry.
Cops dropped off Ethyl Hayes,
found down in the park
but of course, she didn't have
a drop to drink.
‐ Have you, Ethyl?
‐ I don't drink.
Henry, teaching point,
she looks like a drunk
she smells like a drunk,
she is a drunk.
Connie, get a CBC,
chem seven, blood alcohol level
and a tox screen.
‐ W‐what do you want us to do?
‐ Carter?
Hydrate her with a banana bag
add folate,
mag sulfate and thiamine
and give her 50 of Librium
for her pending DT's.
Right.
Oh, and, uh, carter,
she's febrile
so, a gram
of Tylenol, rectally.
‐ R‐rectally?
‐ You heard him.
Glove up and dig in.
Why is it so hot in here?
Because it's so hot outside.
Isn't the
air conditioning working?
These new desk clerk candidates
are sweating like lil' piggies.
'Only two left.'
'Yeah, not counting the one
they're in with, now.'
‐ How were the others?
‐ Not a big hit.
Yeah, well, I didn't
put my money on you
when you were
interviewing for desk clerk.
‐ You bet on us?
‐ Sure.
‐ But you didn't bet on me?
‐ Nope.
'Mrs. Styman, you worked
at several other'
uh, Chicago area hospitals?
‐ Nine other hospitals.
‐ If that's what it says.
Why did you move
around so much? Just curious.
Did you ask them why?
No. We just
received your resume now.
Precision, that's why.
Their extraordinary
lack of precision.
‐ Precision?
‐ For example.
This interview
was scheduled for 12:15.
I arrived promptly at 12:10.
However, the interview didn't
actually start until 12:26.
11 minutes late.
Very imprecise.
Well, um, we've
been a little backed up.
I thought so.
Next question?
Estelle Webb, 79.
Fell down her stairs.
I didn't fall down.
Please, please, help me.
‐ What's open, Jerry?
‐ Uh, not much. Try curtain two.
Don't worry, Mrs. Webb I'm going
to take good care of you.
Well, thank you, dear.
Thank you.
Vitals are stable. BP's 130 over
70, pulse 88 regular, resps 16.
‐ Nice and easy.
‐ Oh, please don't!
‐ Oh, it hurts.
‐ Where does it hurt?
Please, don't let
her do it again.
‐ See you later.
‐ Okay, thanks.
Please, don't let
who do what?
My sister, she pushed
me down the stairs.
You just rest. We're going
to check everything out, okay?
‐ Ah, Dr. Corday.
‐ Dr. Benton.
We're going to be operating
today with Dr. Sam Breedlove.
Breedlove, invented the
Breedlove Retractor 1948?
Mm‐hmm. And he's getting
on someone in years.
Quite ancient by now,
I should think.
So I'll be doing
most of the teaching.
‐ Really?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Listen, you might want
to pay a little more attention
in here than you did in
the trauma room, okay?
Well, I'll certainly bear
that in mind, Dr. Benton.
‐ Sam Breedlove.
‐ 'Elizabeth Corday.'
‐ 'How do you do?'
‐ Come again?
I said Elizabeth Corday.
I knew he was old, but I didn't
realize he was so short.
What did you say?
I said, "I knew you were old
but I didn't know
you were so short."
Yes, yes. Always have been.
Salmon Sperm, you say?
Yes. That's what I use
in my research as a carrier.
Obviously because
it's so easy to collect.
Obviously.
Is your student hell
as special as mine?
I drew the blood
of the chest pain down at four
and now, I'm just taking these
urine samples to the lab.
‐ Great.
‐ I guess not.
Carter, I've got
an LOL in curtain two
claims her sister pushed
her down the stairs.
I want to get a social worker
on it. She needs a full H and P.
Meet my student Henry.
No, no, I'm really not
very, uh, capable.
Take her history.
She doesn't have any
orifice‐type needs, does she?
Carter, the labs
on that lady they found
down in the park are back.
Uh, yeah, there's puking
in the air today.
I'm already on
my third scrub top.
Need to move some
patients here, doctors.
‐ We got a 70‐year‐old ALOC.
‐ Sure.
And a seven year old
in respiratory distress.
‐ 'Who do you want?'
‐ I'll take the 70. Thanks.
I guess I'll take the seven.
We don't really
need your resume.
We've got your
job application form.
Really. I know I have it here.
I just, I know I do.
If you want, you can bring it
back in a day or so.
Oh, no, please.
I know what that means.
I'd like to interview now.
Um, my name is Cynthia Hooper
and I'm originally from Joliet.
My whole family's there,
actually although
my parents have both passed on.
Oh, so you have
brothers and sisters?
No. I don't have
any brothers and sisters.
Why don't you tell us
about your job experience.
I mean, something that might
apply to, the job here.
Uh..
...well, I've always been
really good with people.
Uh, everyone's always
said that about me.
When I was the cashier
at the Ford Dealership
Service and Parts, I used to
talk to all the customers
while I was
processing their bills.
Is that what I'd be doing
here is handling the bills?
Uh, we have a separate
department for that.
Oh, okay.
‐ Um, well, I have other skills.
‐ Telemarketing?
Yes. I used to sell
vitamins over the phone.
Tha‐that's kind of in
the health field isn't it?
No, I guess
it's not really, is it?
Well, they didn't
even like me there.
I‐I, uh..
...well, I got fired because I
wouldn't sell the combo vitapak
to the old people that
we were supposed to call.
They didn't need
vitamins, I mean
it was just too late for them.
‐ How long has he been coughing?
‐ No entendemos.
‐ Just a slight fever, 100.3.
‐ I need a translator in here.
‐ I've called twice.
‐ Ayudelo, por favor, eh?
Probably bronchitis
but it might be pneumonia.
Get a CBC and a chest film.
Uh, how long?
Uh...uh..
...uh, cuantos dias?
Oh, casi...casi dos semanas.
Has he had his shots?
‐ Uh, shot, um, injecciones?
‐ 'Oh, si.'
Get me that translator.
Oh, the second
guy wasn't so bad.
No, except he
lied about his age
previous job experience and
where he went to high school.
He can do the job.
Mark, we need
to see more people.
None of the people
we've seen seem to fit in.
They don't
have to fit in.
All they have to do
is answer phones‐‐
Mark, it's a lot more
complicated than that.
Mark?
‐ Heather.
‐ Hi.
What happened?
Another water polo accident?
Yeah, but it's
just a bad sprain.
Looks like we're
twins, let me guess.
‐ Racquetball? Rollerblading?
‐ I wish.
You should have asked
for me when you came in.
I thought about it.
I have occasionally missed you.
So, um, how's your
busy social calendar?
Well, it's not as busy anymore.
‐ Yeah? Mine, too.
‐ Should I just go on?
Uh, I can see
you're busy now, so..
Well, I'm busy
with patients, but..
‐ I'll see ya.
‐ Right. Right.
So...who's my patient?
Laura Quentin,
fainted at the car wash.
‐ I don't want to stay here.
‐ Dr. Greene‐‐
Just a minute, Carter.
Hi. I'm Dr. Greene.
‐ You fainted?
‐ Yeah.
I think it was
probably just the heat.
Has it happened to you before?
No, never.
Um, you don't have to call
my parents or anything, do you?
‐ How old are you?
‐ I'm 18.
Nope, we don't have
to call your parents
but we do have
to run a few tests.
Okay.
Dr. Greene..
Ethyl Hayes is‐‐
Get a CBC, chem 20,
a serum glucose
orthostatics
and a pregnancy test.
Dr. Greene, Ethyl Hayes'
labs are back.
The tox screen was negative
blood alcohol level
was low, .05.
Buff her up.
Let her sleep it off.
Yeah, she's still
slurring a lot
especially for
that low of a BA level.
Well, maybe she
wants a free meal.
I'd like to run
a few more tests.
Carter, we get six
or seven of these a day.
We can't save
them all, okay?
So give her some jell‐o,
let her sleep it off
and move her out.
What if the cords are swollen
from prolonged intubation?
We're standing by
with vaponefrin.
What about apnea
from brain damage?
His ultrasound
was normal.
He's doing really
well, Dr. Benton.
And already up
to four pounds, 10 ounces.
You can hold him if you want.
Yeah, sure.
Go ahead, grab him.
Oh, here we go.
Oh, that's my little one.
You doing better now?
Huh?
Look, he's smiling.
How can you not know where
he is? He's your student.
‐ He keeps disappearing.
‐ I can't believe he did this.
I mean, he said he wasn't
very capable, but please.
I've come to take
him at his word.
Jerry, has that social worker
called back yet on Mrs. Webb?
Mrs. Who?
The woman who was pushed
down her stairs.
Nope, not yet.
Henry.
My, uh, throat's
a little scratchy.
This is the history
you took on Mrs. Webb?
‐ Yes, I wrote everything down.
‐ That's the problem.
You documented
almost 20 complaints.
Back pain,
earache, constipation
bumpiness in her head, I don't
even know what that means.
‐ No, neither did I.
‐ Listen..
You can, you can listen
to multiple complaints
without having
to chart them all.
Yeah, well, now
that you wrote them down
we have to check
them all out.
Just a moment, Mrs. Webb.
Good rule of thumb, if a
patients lists more than
three complaints, odds are that
there's nothing wrong with them.
‐ No, but I wrote them all down.
‐ I'll be right there.
This poor woman will
be stuck here the whole night
having tests she
probably doesn't need.
Th‐th‐this doesn't mean
that I have
to stay here the whole
night, does it?
‐ Very thorough.
‐ Yes, he is very thorough.
Social worker
will be here soon.
Oh, I can't come
back to my sister.
No, they're gonna
try very hard to find
a new place
for you to stay, okay?
You want to smother me
with that pillow, don't you?
She tried that once before, too.
Oh, Mrs. Webb.
How are you doing?
I'm okay.
Your labs came back.
You're dehydrated.
Have you had the flu
or been vomiting?
Uh‐uh.
Is there something
else going on
that you haven't
mentioned to us?
Uh‐uh.
I'm just going to take
one more quick look, okay?
Can you open up for me?
Laura, has your
dentist mentioned
the enamel on your teeth?
I hate dentist.
Yeah, me too.
I don't think
he's bipolar or schizophrenic
but I can't figure him out.
‐ Hmm.
‐ Sure never seen this in a kid.
I'm waiting on the CT, but I
thought you could take a look.
Sure.
This guy thinks
I'm Sidney Poitier
in "Lilies Of The Field."
'See, see, see.'
If you're wearing
a white coat
then you must be
the, uh, butcher.
No, that's not right,
not if you're the pharmacist.
‐ Am I here to pick something..
‐ Um, 70 years old.
Picked up
wandering the street.
‐ BA, and tox screen?
‐ 'Negative.'
He's confabulating and has
complete short‐term memory loss.
Has no idea who I am every
time I walk in the room.
I wore it to a wedding.
Oh, cook! Ooh, I hope
they have lima beans.
Hey, Oliver,
I'm Dr. Del Amico remember?
And this is
Dr. Carter and Mr. Henry
'and you're here
in the hospital.'
I'm in a hospital?
Well, okay, if you say so.
Like Jimmy Stewart
was in "Harvey," huh?
You feeling okay, Oliver?
Sure, sure. I feel fine.
Hey, we'll be back in
a little bit okay, Oliver?
Okay, okay.
Lima beans.
I think you're right
about the psych consult..
...but I would
call them down anyway.
Yeah, I thought
I'd wait on the CT.
See if it reveals anything.
‐ It will.
‐ Henry.
Probably show
a small lesion in
the area
of the mammillary bodies
and the dorsal medial
nucleus of the thalamus
otherwise known as
the mammillothalamic tract.
It's generally associated
with Korsakoff's Syndrome
which causes retrograde
and anterograde amnesia
thus accounting for
the short‐term memory loss
and the confabulation.
Thank God you showed up,
I could have gone
a lifetime without a translator.
Can I put in
for extra pay?
Yeah. Just run it
by Kerry Weaver.
Buenos tardes.
Soy Chuny Marquez.
Estoy aqui para ayudarle
a ustedes y al doctor.
Uh, Mr. and Mrs. Trujillo
uh, Jesus' x‐rays didn't
show anything specific..
los rayos x no
indican nada specifico.
‐ Probably has bronchitis.
‐ Tal vez sea bronquitis.
‐ Is he gonna be okay?
‐ Yeah, he's gonna be fine.
Uh, we're just giving
him some antibiotics.
and we're gonna
check up on him..
‐ Gracias.
‐ Okay?
Mrs. Webb,
this is Thomas Anders.
‐ Department of social services.
‐ Oh. Where is he taking me?
'Thought we could talk a little
on your way to radiology.'
‐ Back to x‐ray?
‐ No. Ultrasound this time.
Ooh, wait. My glasses. Ah.
‐ Here you go.
‐ Thank you.
And we've been trying to
track down your sister.
Ooh, no, please.
It's going
to be okay, Mrs. Webb.
Jeanie, my slippers,
those slippers you gave me.
Well, I don't see them.
Maybe they're
under the bed.
Jeanie, please don't let
them send me back there again.
‐ Okay, I know. I know.
‐ Please, don't let them.
They can't do it.
Let's just get these
slippers on here, okay?
There we go, one more.
Jeanie, please..
Okay, go ahead.
Carol Hathaway filled me in
on the desk clerk interviews.
Yeah, a bunch of crackpots
but we'll break one in.
Well, she felt maybe you
should see some more candidates.
I don't.
Carter.
As long as you feel
confident with that.
‐ Where are you taking her?
‐ Uh, MRI.
‐ She's a drunk.
‐ Yeah, I just want to be sure.
I already did an LP,
And I just think I need an MRI..
‐ Carter‐‐
‐ I ran everything by Dr. Doyle.
She agreed.
Well, at least, let your
student handle the transport.
Henry is collecting
stool samples
on three abdominal pains.
Jerry, could you do me
a favor page Henry again?
‐ I already did twice.
‐ Again.
Mark.
I just checked in
on Laura Quentin.
Yeah, I saw her labs.
Urine specific gravity's low
she's mildly hypokalemic.
She probably got the flu.
Actually, she's bulimic.
I checked her teeth.
The enamel's eroded which is
consistent with the vomiting
and she hasn't had
her period in six months.
Took a lot to get it out of her
but she finally admitted to it.
Let's re‐hydrate her.
Two liters of normal
saline and turf her to psych.
She doesn't want
to go to psych.
her parents to know.
I called the eating disorders
clinic, but
the next available appointment's
not for seven weeks.
Well, there's not
a lot we can do.
Well, I thought maybe
you could talk to her.
Doesn't sound like
it's going to do much good.
Well, can't hurt to try.
Look, I got a lot
of patients, Carol.
Come on, Mark.
‐ She might listen to you.
‐ We're an ER.
We don't manage
chronic problems.
Her condition
is chronic, not acute.
Oh, if you have concerns
about other
desk clerk candidates.
Run them by me first
before you go to Kerry Weaver.
Henry was right.
‐ There it is.
‐ That's the lesion?
‐ It's large.
‐ Yeah.
Come on, Chasity, you're
about to get your first taste
of giving the bad news.
Oh, hi. Well you see, uh,
I don't need a haircut.
Well, you're not
the barber, are you?
Oliver, I'm Dr. Del Amico
and you're in a hospital.
Yeah, well, whatever you say
is fine but I feel just great
uh, just like Jimmy Stewart
was in, uh, "Harvey."
Oliver, listen...I need you
to listen to me for a minute.
We took a picture of your
brain and, unfortunately
you have a tumor
on the right side.
You...you look
like Carole Lombard.
‐ She had a brain tumor.
‐ Oliver, it's very serious.
Serious?
Are you saying I'm gonna die?
Uh, the people upstairs
in surgery are going to do
everything they can
but we can't be sure.
Oh...I'm going to die?
'I'm going to die.'
Oh...God!
'Oh...God.'
Henry, what the hell
are you doing up here?
You're supposed to be
on your ER rotation.
If I don't load
the sequencing gel now
it could ruin
the whole experiment.
Doesn't your ER rotation
mean anything to you?
You mean beyond
it's being a requirement?
Alright,
what's all this stuff?
This is a plasmid control
with ten micrograms
of Salmon Sperm carrier.
Would you like
to see my linkage map?
Wait, wait,
don't‐don't‐don't touch this.
This is‐this is
ethidium bromide.
It can, uh, slip between
your DNA, cause a mutation.
No, no, eh‐eh..
...don't, don't
touch the eppendorf.
Hey, did you feed him yet?
I got stuck in the OR.
No, Tabash says I can't
try until this evening.
Good. I thought I was
going to miss the first time.
Listen, um, I'm on tonight.
Page me and I'll
come straight up.
‐ How's he doing?
‐ He's doing great.
But they're asking for a name.
We gotta get this birth
certificate straightened out.
Yeah, I guess we have
put it off a bit, huh?
"We?"
I had no idea you
could be so superstitious.
‐ Yeah...neither did I.
‐ So, what are we going to do?
Are we going
to flip a coin?
Reese or Benton?
Carla...we talked about it
and we said it was
going to be "Benton."
It's easier
for the insurance.
We already talked about
it, but we definitely
did not agree on it, Peter
And that insurance
reason is an excuse.
You know you just want your boy
to have his daddy's last name.
So what's wrong with that?
What's wrong with him
having his mama's name?
I'm the one that's going to get
up in the middle of the night.
Feed him, change him,
rock him back to sleep.
Carla, I can do that, too.
So you're just going
to move into my apartment now?
Look, I know we
haven't talked about it..
No, we haven't because
you kept acting like
this day was
never going to come.
He needs a family.
‐ Is that what you think we are?
‐ Look, I mean, you know..
We don't have
to formalize things.
If there wasn't
a baby in the picture
would you see
the two of us as a family?
It's okay, Peter.
I don't, either.
22‐year‐old female,
GSW to the left upper chest.
Two IV's of saline in the field,
BP 100 over 60, pulse 110.
O2, 15 liters by mask.
‐ Hey, hey, hey, look out.
‐ Who is that guy?
They're checking
for radioactivity.
God, I love this job.
Okay, let's go.
'One, two, three..'
‐ I'll get her clothes off.
‐ What have we got?
‐ Gunshot wound to the chest.
‐ Two in one day?
Honey, you haven't been
here very long, have you?
‐ I can run it.
‐ Why don't I have a go at it?
Right. The usual investigations.
FBC, electrolytes, type
and cross match four units
and a portable
radiograph of the chest.
‐ FBC?
‐ Full blood count.
Run in a liter of saline
and a gram of cephalexin.
The trachea is midline,
no jugular venous distention.
Strong radial pulse,
subclavian's intact.
Pulse ox is 92
on 15 liters.
BP's 95 palp.
Diminished breath
sounds on the left.
She'll need a tube thoracostomy.
‐ A what?
‐ Chest tube.
Dr. Weaver,
could you intubate, please?
Number eight ET
tube and suction.
And I wonder if everyone
might slow down just a bit.
I think things will
run much more smoothly
if we have a little
more peace and quiet.
Has anyone bleeped Dr. Benton?
Oh, I like that one,
"Bleeping Benton."
Well, perhaps somebody
could just ring him up now.
Page, right?
‐ Let's page Benton?
‐ 'I got it.'
One percent lidocaine.
Alright, I'll get it.
Okay...I'm in.
Let's bag her.
We're out, I'm going
to go get some from supply.
Es mi hijo.
Por favor ayudenos.
‐ Es mi hijo.
‐ Connie, get the lidocaine.
‐ Es mi hijo. Por favor.
‐ Anna, we need your help.
'Esta sangrando.'
Esta sufriendo, por favor!
‐ What is it? What happened?
‐ Por favor, miren.
‐ He's stopped breathing.
‐ Agarenlo!
Pedes laryngoscope
and a number six ET tube.
Chasity, get ready to bag him.
El doctor dijo
que era bronquitis.
‐ Bronquitis, no lo pienso.
‐ Ay, no, por favor, no!
What happened?
Dr. Corday just
stabilized your patient.
GSW to the left upper chest.
Came in with a
pressure of 100 over 60.
Received two liters
of crystalloid.
Spun hematocrit is 34,
gave a gram of cephalexin.
Placed a left thoracostomy tube
with 300cc's of blood.
Missed the great
vessels...lucky girl.
So I guess you
were paying attention.
Always.
‐ Her sister died in 1984?
‐ That's right.
So obviously her sister did
not push her down the stairs.
‐ Not recently.
‐ I'll kill her.
You can't kill her,
she's a borderline.
You can never get
rid of borderlines.
Randi, call psych
for me, I need a consult.
They won't admit her.
Not until medicine's
completed her evaluation.
I'm still waiting
on eight tests.
You know what I've done
for this woman today?
She claims you tried to
suffocate her with the pillow.
She what?
Gratitude.
Have you seen Dr. Carter?
He keeps paging me.
Oh, Henry, come with me, you're
about to do some baby‐sitting.
Come on.
'Hi, Mrs. Webb..'
I asked if the boy
had had his shots.
They didn't realize
you meant vaccines.
They thought you meant
had he ever had any shots.
I didn't think
of whooping cough.
It presents a lot
like bronchitis.
I've missed it myself.
Well, thanks for
stepping in. Thank you.
‐ Oh, God.
‐ What?
Excuse me.
Malik..
He was supposed to be
up in neurology an hour ago.
Yeah, we're on our way up.
Dr. Weaver needed
some labs, stat.
Well, get him up
there now, please.
Well, hi there, you're the
ice cream person, aren't you?
You don't want to
spill on that coat.
No, no, you're
the pharmacist.
See, I already
have my toothpaste.
Hey, Oliver, do you remember
you're in the hospital?
Hospital?
Is something wrong with me?
'Dr. Greene..'
...I just need you to
sign a chart for me.
It's for that woman with
slurred speech, Ethyl Hayes.
Oh, did she finally dry out?
Not exactly,
LP showed pleocytosis
and elevated
gamma globulins.
MRI confirmed she has
multiple sclerosis.
Did you order
a neurology consult?
‐ Yes.
‐ Good.
Hey...I am now officially
having a bad day.
The one non‐puking kid I had
almost died of whooping cough.
‐ Well, I'm ready for a drink.
‐ You want to join me?
Uh, I can't.
What's your bad day?
Remember Chris Law?
Oh, yeah, the, um,
his brother died.
‐ The basketball player, right?
‐ Yeah. Yeah.
Well, that's what the process
server was about this morning.
He and his family are slapping
me with a malpractice suit.
It's a great world, huh?
First, he beats me up,
and then, he sues me.
Chris Law didn't
beat you up, did he?
The police said
he had an airtight alibi.
Ah. That's what
the police said.
But you don't believe them, huh?
I don't know.
So, what happened
with your amnesia patient?
Mm. He kept forgetting
he was dying.
I had to tell him
five different times.
Hmmm.
And after all that, they
give us this humiliation.
Wow, a paycheck.
Alleged paycheck.
So small,
the rich kids at CHOP
would blow the whole thing
on poker the first night.
‐ Didn't think I'd even care.
‐ About getting a paycheck?
Hm? Uh, no, no,
I just meant that, uh..
I didn't think the money
was gonna make that
that much
of a difference.
Well, it won't...
after I pay my landlord
the med school bills,
my phone bill, the gas bill.
That should leave
me about four bucks.
Oh, yeah. Me, too, uh..
‐ See ya.
‐ Hey, Dr. Weaver.
‐ John.
I know I said that
I didn't need to be paid
but it sure feels good, and I
just want to say thank you.
Yeah, I'd hoped to catch you
before you actually got it
but I need to have you endorse
your check back over to County.
What?
Apparently, to cover
disability and malpractice
they issue one
every week and then
you sign it back over to us.
Endorse it back over to County?
‐ Right.
‐ Every week?
That's what we agreed, right?
You didn't
need to be paid?
Right.
Alright, thank you.
Yep...pen.
Been up to any
of the labs recently?
Why do you ask?
‐ Give me your shoes.
‐ What?
I said get me your shoes,
they're radioactive.
You know how much
these things cost?
‐ Did he say radioactive?
‐ Carter, give him your shoes.
‐ I won't.
‐ Yes, you will.
Hey.
‐ He's really doing it, huh?
‐ Oh, yeah.
This boy is really doing it.
Only lasts a couple
of minutes, though.
Then he gets really tired.
Listen, um..
I thought about
what we talked about and, uh..
I don't have any more
claim on his name than you do.
I'd be happy
with the name Reese.
I would.
Well...I thought
about it, too, Peter
and, uh, I'd be
okay with Benton.
So, why don't we name him..
Reese Benton?
‐ Reese Benton.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Sounds a little formal but, uh..
...we'll get used to it.
Reese Benton.
Reese..
Yeah.
Yeah, we will.
'Dr. Greene.'
Hi. Um, I'm sorry
to bother you.
‐ Do you remember me? I..
‐ You're, uh..
‐ Cynthia Hooper.
‐ Yeah, right.
You've been hanging
out here all day?
No. Well, I sat
over at the diner.
Look, I know I'm out
of contention for the job
but I just really
wanted to apologize
for how I was
in the interview.
I‐I just get so nervous
and I never say
the right thing, and..
It happens to all of us.
Yeah, well, at least I
didn't throw up in there
which I actually have
done in an interview.
That probably hurt
the interview.
Is this your
first time in Chicago?
Yeah. Thanks.
I've only been
here for six days
but, um, I'm actually
starting to figure it out.
The lake is..
‐ That way.
Right.
I'm glad you stopped by
'cause I didn't have a chance
to make any phone calls
yet and so I can just
tell you that you got the job.
What?
Oh, you're kidding, right?
No, no. It's yours
if you want it.
Of course I want it. I‐I‐I..
Are you sure
you're not kidding?
You can start next week.
Oh, my God.
I don't know what to say.
Thank you.
You're welcome
‐ Goodnight.
‐ Are they closed?
‐ Closed.
‐ Keep them closed.
‐ I said they're closed.
Okay.
Open them.
Alright.
That was very
delicate, Doug.
What the?
Well, that's a drawer.
You know what?
‐ I love this drawer.
‐ Good.
Come here, you.
Come here.
You know what? I love sitting
out here on the porch with you.
It's..
Something new.
Nice drawer.
It's a good touch,
don't you think?