When we're hurt...
our body send signals
to form blood-clots,
directly at the injury
to help stop
any bleeding
Thanks.
Are you okay?
I lost control, Meredith.
I was angry,
and this bar...
it was just awful.
They're predators.
They're destroying lives.
It's our body's system
of checks and balances.
Yeah, well, this
wind is picking up.
We better get going.
Catherine says
you haven't gotten a new sponsor
since Ollie died,
you're not making meetings,
and now
you're destroying bars.
You need to get
your head right,
get your head in a place
where you can take care
of the people
who depend on you.
It's a system that's
supposed to save our lives.
Aah!
Or so we hope.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 15  Episode 08
Episode Title: "Blowin' in the Wind"
Okay... Ben?
Sorry I woke you,
but I, uh,
I didn't know the rules
about using
my key during our separation.
We are not separated.
We are taking time apart
so that I can focus on
bringing my stress down.
- It's a sabbatical.
- Yeah, I know what you call it.
And even though
I'm not sleeping in this house,
I still want the people
who live here to stay safe.
Wind storm's on the way.
It's supposed
to get pretty ugly. I, uh...
I was gonna board up the
windows before my shift...
Oh.
If that's okay
with you.
Yes, of course.
Just try not to
wake up Tuck.
I will hammer
the nails into the boards
as quietly as possible.
I'll do
Tuck's windows last.
Oh.
- Hey.
- Hi.
There's a...
There's a tree down
over on Madison.
Yeah, I saw.
God, it's crazy out there.
They said it's only gonna
get worse
throughout the day.
So, are we talking
about the weather, Maggie?
That's... our new thing?
- Hey.
- Altman.
Am I gonna like the reason
you're here?
Well, I couldn't
sit in my hotel room today,
and you're gonna be inundated
with patients.
Hey.
Hey,
any update on Betty?
- No.
- Nothing.
I'm gonna take Leo upstairs.
- Yeah. See you, buddy.
- Ohh.
Nobody got much sleep
last night.
Yeah.
How much longer you
in town?
Um, I'm...
I'm not really sure,
but if you need help with
anything,
- just let me know.
- Okay, thanks.
Their kid's been missing
for three days.
I couldn't dump
any more on them.
That's very thoughtful.
Oh, is, uh, Karev around?
His mess is.
Oh, uh,
this is a matter for the chief.
Um,
I'll come back later.
Uh, if you peel that tape,
you'll find my name,
and I'm here, which says
a lot more than Karev,
who seems
to think "interim"
means "sloppy"
and "whenever he feels like it."
So... just say
whatever it is.
Um, well,
I was... close
to Frankie Shavelson.
Oh.
Oh, yeah.
I was so sorry to hear...
Are you all right?
Yesterday, I, um,
went into a bar and...
- Richard, no.
- I didn't drink,
and I didn't hurt anyone.
I lost my temper.
There was
property damage,
and I was arrested.
Well, I'll
need to inform the board,
and there will be
an inquiry.
I... do need
to bench you for today.
You'll get some rest,
catch up on charts.
Just stay away
from patients.
- Can you manage that?
- I can.
Thank you, Bailey.
Where the hell is
Alex Karev?
Mm.
You have pillow marks
on your face.
I haven't slept that hard
since I took that stupid job.
I'm gonna nap for like...
for like five more minutes.
I feel like
I got at least eight hours.
Oh, crap!
Crap!
What?
Okay, breathe in for me,
Cece.
Good.
Oh, Dr. Grey,
I have something
to show you.
I normally don't take pictures,
but I couldn't help it.
I snapped this one
while he wasn't looking.
Cece, save your strength.
He has distinctly
kind eyes
and a playful
sense of humor,
and he's a surgeon
in this hospital.
Dr. Lincoln.
Yeah,
I know who he is.
And?
And, DeLuca,
I'm waiting.
Yes, uh, her respiration's
getting more labored,
she's complaining
of more shortness of breath.
It's probably
the pleural effusions.
Meredith,
I just showed you perfection.
And I don't have
the time.
Have you looked at me?
I'm the one
who doesn't have time.
Okay, so then
I'll make it quick.
Let's prep her for
a pleurocentesis.
Uh, hey, is, uh...
is everything okay?
Just check back
in an hour.
Hey,
did you check the weather?
Do I ever check
the weather?
Uh, it's windy.
That's helpful.
Okay.
Oh, uh.
Well, t-they're telling everyone
to stay off the roads,
that there's
three accidents on the I-5.
The bridge is closed.
I mean, we're screwed.
Yeah, well, if it's that bad,
then the hospital's slammed.
We need to go.
We can't help
if we're dead.
No, no, no, Karev.
Stay there until it's safe.
We'll figure something out.
We always do.
Okay, we got burns,
car-wreck injuries,
and flying debris has given us
a ton of blunt injuries
and several
penetrating traumas.
Wind storms are
my favorite.
Yeah, you're gonna love this.
We're supposed to love this?
Oh, ho, ho.
Impalement-palooza.
Bailey,
I don't think we have room
to treat all these patients,
and Seattle Pres is already
closed to trauma.
Hey!
Uh, hello!
Everyone...
Hey, be quiet!
Listen up.
We will move
all stable patients upstairs
to clear beds.
We will stock
disaster supplies
on all floors.
And we will notify
the blood bank
to have extra units
on standby.
We are staying open
for trauma,
but sheltering
in place.
This is a brick house,
and no amount of huffing and puffing
can blow us down.
Whoo! Whoo!
- Yeah, I still got it.
- Okay, come on. Let's go.
- You need something.
- Come to the OR.
Did you eat
the rest of the chips?
Apparently only
a third of the staff
- can make it into work.
- Oh,
the... the barbecue ones,
the blue bag?
They're sending floor nurses
down to the E.R.
Apparently anesthesia's
- working... triple.
- Ugh! Where are the chips?
- I ate them last night.
- Oh.
I feel like a crappy leader.
I mean, who the hell
abandons the ship
in the middle of a disaster?
Maybe
it's not a disaster.
We've hardly seen each other
since we got married,
and we're stuck here,
so... what if we make this
our second honeymoon?
With no food?
We have jelly
and bread and beer and...
Expired mac-and-cheese.
It's fine,
because
we have a gas stove.
Oh.
When's the last time
we cooked?
Right there.
Trauma one.
- Okay.
- Go, go.
No more trauma rooms.
Next incoming
can go to procedure room 4.
Avery needs me in 1.
Could you...
Go, go.
Schmitt,
I told you trauma 2.
Trauma 2's the...
the selfie stick in the brain, and...
Helm, you got a problem
with brains?
- Love brains.
- Trauma 2.
Schmitt, go to the clinic
with Dr. Kim.
We need to clear the patients
per the protocol.
On it.
I'm not afraid anymore.
Of the s-selfie stick.
- I can do it.
- Too late.
Think about that
on your way to the clinic.
- Bailey.
- Altman.
Uh, cardio consult
in trauma 1.
Oh, I was just about
to ask you for privileges,
- but now I don't need to.
- Go.
You live here now?
Dr. Ford, 3235.
- Dr. Ford, 3235.
- Why did I get a glass door?
Hold tight, Georgia.
We got you.
Qadri, hand me a 4x4.
Dr. Grey.
How was sunny L.A.?
Not so sunny.
Do you think
it violated the fascia?
Uh, not sure.
I am worried about
a thoracoabdominal injury.
I thought you weren't coming
back until tomorrow night.
Plans changed.
Well, if you're home,
maybe I won't drink
a whole bottle of wine
and eat a whole carton
of ice cream by myself.
There's fluid
in the upper-right quadrant.
Missed the liver.
Can you make a fist
for me?
Now open.
That's great.
There's no major damage.
Qadri, clean and stitch.
Good to have you back,
Grey.
So, you said
your plans changed.
Did your VIP patient die?
No, the... just the plans,
they just changed.
Qadri, let's get her up to CT,
please.
I can see it
out of the corner of my eye,
but I can't feel it.
You can't feel it
because your brain
doesn't have
any pain receptors.
I know you're scared,
but I need you
to stop moving around
so much, okay?
I have a selfie stick
in my head.
It's not even mine.
It's some idiot teenager's.
How is
she talking this much?
Adrenaline, maybe?
I don't know.
How we doing?
I told CT you'd be on your way
any minute.
Wh-When are you
taking it out?
You can take it out,
right?
Please take it out.
Phoebe, I am gonna do
everything I can to remove it,
but when I do,
there is a strong possibility
that your brain will bleed
or swell.
I just want to prepare you
in case you want to call
anyone before surgery.
My mom.
Can I call my mom?
The paramedics said
they had my phone.
We'll find it.
Bailey,
I need to... I just...
- Oh, go, go.
- Yeah.
Do you see yourself?
I told you
not to go outside in that mess!
Do you see me?
How about some sympathy?
And stop shouting!
Nobody can hear themselves think
with you in here.
Can someone please
check my ears
for years of damage?
So, you two are married, then.
Decreased breath sounds
on the right.
He's got a small pneumo.
- We were having a fight.
- Which he started.
So I went outside
to get away from her.
Which is all
he ever does.
And I slammed the front door
on her perfectly.
Rivaled the Great Door
Slam of 1987.
And then someone's
mailbox slammed
into our sycamore.
But I couldn't undo that door slam,
so I took a walk.
Like an idiot.
I can't tell if there's
a pericardial effusion.
I'm getting a pulse in the neck,
but I'm worried about
an underlying injury.
So, I'm standing in front
of the Hoffmans' house
when their stupid Christmas
decorations caught the wind,
and, ta-da!
I should be in Santa's workshop.
It isn't even Thanksgiving.
It's enraging.
I wrote a letter to
the neighborhood association.
I write one every year.
- Hah!
- Hm?
Oh, thank God.
Owen.
- You two got this?
- Yeah.
What happened?
I'm okay.
It barely stings.
She walked here from Yesler
and got hit by a tree branch.
So she says,
follow my finger.
She needs a few stitches.
And a CT scan
and a tox screen.
I don't need that.
It's just gonna say I'm high.
I'm sorry.
I know I messed up,
but I want to get clean.
I came back because of you
and Owen and Leo.
I have to go.
I have a surgery. Um...
Just tell the nurses
she's an addict
and don't give her
anything.
I'm so sorry.
Hey,
it's gonna be okay,
okay?
Come on,
come on. Where are you?
What's all that stuff?
Just wedding gifts.
I can't find Bubby!
Is Bubby a security blanket
or a pet rat?
There you are!
This is Bubby.
She gave me hot meals
when I was living in my car.
I didn't have grandparents.
I can't believe the real answer
is sadder than a pet rat.
Trust me
when I say your
mac-and-cheese will
be made with love.
- Oh, no.
- What?
What is it?
- Our marriage license.
- So?
So if you don't mail it in,
it's not official!
Was that my job?
Kinda!
So we're not married?
Hello? Yeah.
What's up, Schmitt?
Uh, Dr. Karev,
Josh Gordon's in the clinic
with abdominal pain
and vomiting and...
Got it. Will do.
Dr. Karev said to put in an NG
tube and admit him to peds.
I'll take Mrs. Aguilar over,
then I'll be back
to handle Josh.
- I've got Josh.
- No, no, no.
His electrolytes are
all over the place,
probably an SBO,
and I have experience
with adminis...
Yeah, I know.
You've got all the experience.
You've had a lot more
patients than I've had.
But I've had patients, too,
many with small bowel
obstructions and NG tubes,
so I've got it.
But if you want to help,
you can walk him
to peds when I'm done.
Mommy,
I don't want you to be worried.
I'm okay.
It happened
on my way to work.
No, work's good.
Helm, we'll keep her
in a sitting position.
C-Could you go by my house
later after the storm
and take over for the dog sitter?
I might be a little longer
than I thought.
And don't forget, he only gets
one treat after dinner.
Thanks, Mom.
You're the best.
You're the very best mom.
I'll call you after?
Be safe.
Love you.
Sorry, I just...
I don't like to scare her.
We understand.
Ready?
She's plenty scared.
- Hey.
Welcome to the North Pole.
Huh. You should've seen
his wife screaming at him
all the way
up to the red line.
Marital bliss.
You take him to CT?
No, there were a dozen patients
up ahead of us in line.
I'm thinking
we cut the top off
and just pull the cane
out from the bottom.
Works for me.
How's Betty?
Oh, um,
she seems
to be mostly okay.
- Thank you, by the way.
- Yeah.
Staying means a lot.
Owen, I...
I need to tell you
something.
- What?
- Not here... later.
Can we grab a cup of coffee
after surgery?
Uh, sure.
We... We...
We need to get in there.
Okay.
- Basin.
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Cottonoid.
And fibrin glue?
Yeah, just a little.
Good.
- Agh, damn it. Suction.
- What happened?
Stick must have been tamponading
her vertebral artery.
Helm, suction.
He said
I don't talk
about my feelings
enough,
that I don't
share enough.
He should do
more surgeries with you.
What?
Okay, it doesn't look like
it damaged the fascia.
Qadri, do you want
to do the honors?
- Pull it out?
- Yes.
Straight up.
Straight.
Good.
♪ Havin' trouble sleepin' ♪
- ♪ with you next to me ♪
- What, am I just supposed to change
- overnight?
- Okay,
let's wash it out
and start the repair.
Irrigation.
Do you think
I'm overreacting?
This woman had 50 pieces
of glass in her.
It could have
killed her.
You and Jackson,
it... it sucks,
but no one's gonna die.
♪ I sink like a stone ♪
♪ Stone in your water ♪
♪ Tell the truth ♪
♪ You know you cannot keep me safe ♪
♪ There's more pain in love
than we could find in hate ♪
Uh, I was calling for
Catherine Fox.
Who is this?
Koracick?
♪ So if you ever leave,
at least it's bittersweet ♪
♪ I dive in you like water ♪
♪ I sink like a stone ♪
Pulse is dropping, and her
pressure's through the roof.
Because she's herniating.
Should we give her mannitol
or start hypertonic saline?
- It won't work.
- What? Why?
Her brain stem is
going dark.
Let's check her pupils.
♪ Be gentle with me ♪
Fixed and dilated.
♪ Have patience... ♪
But she was talking.
She... She talked to us.
She... She talked to her mom.
She was lucid.
The stick was right up
against her artery.
Any attempt
to remove it was a risk
for hemorrhage
and uncontrollable swelling.
She never had a chance.
No.
Can you check
to see if she's a donor?
She is... B negative.
All right, let's, uh,
close her up,
get her up to ICU
until we can call it.
Helm, let's go.
B negative?
Yes, why?
That matches
Cece Colvin.
♪ In your water ♪
What are you doing?
There's no more patients.
Just making sure
you get back okay.
Ready?
Don't worry about me.
I'm waiting it out over here,
and not because
I'm scared or weak
but because it's
the sensible thing to do.
The winds are picking up.
Listen, I'm sorry
if I came off harsh in the elevator.
You were an ass.
This... This is exactly
what I didn't want.
I don't need the drama,
the... the hurt feelings,
the freshly coming out.
I don't need
the shame spiral.
Look, you're really sweet,
but... I can't guide you
out of the closet
like some kind of gay Sherpa,
all right?
I'm not the drama.
You're the drama.
And you're also clueless
if you think it's safe
to cross the ambulance bay
right now.
Ever heard
of the Venturi effect,
Mr. "I'm So Experienced"?
It means wind speeds
can easily double
in between two buildings,
creating a tunnel.
There's a reason they call
Pacific Northwest windstorms
"Big Blows."
This is an extra Big Blow!
See, I-I can't even touch that.
At least stay low
to the ground.
Nico!
Hurry! In there!
Are you okay?
Yeah, I think so.
Ohh! That was...
Dude.
You're welcome.
Okay, ready?
Here we go.
All right, keep going.
There's no injury
to the jugular so far.
Are you even pulling on it?
Listen,
slow and steady.
I don't want him
to bleed out.
We're buying him some time
away from his wife.
We might be doing him
a favor.
So, did something happen,
something bad?
Not now.
Carotid's intact.
Listen, if you're sick or
something, you should just...
Owen.
Wait.
Is this, whatever this is,
why you came back to Seattle
in the first place?
Why didn't you
talk to me before now?
Well, 'cause I didn't want
anyone to... bleed out.
Oh, so it's definitely bad.
Can we just focus
on the surgery?
Great. My field's clear.
I'm officially declaring her.
♪ I know... ♪
Her radionuclide scan shows
no cerebral perfusion.
♪ To breathe... ♪
She's brain dead.
I'll touch base with UNOS
and our transplant coordinator.
- Helm, you'll...
- Tell Dr. Grey?
Yes, right away.
♪ You've lost
the will to fight ♪
♪ Is anybody out there? ♪
- ♪ Can you lead me... ♪
- Hello?
Honey, is that you?
Are you out?
Mrs. Moss, um...
♪ Is anybody... ♪
This is Dr. Shepherd.
I was your daughter's surgeon.
♪ All be all right ♪
- ♪ You are not... ♪
- Just go ahead and yell, okay?
I know you're mad,
and I get it, so...
Thank you.
For coming back.
You can always come back,
okay?
- ♪ Singing you a song ♪
- Please, always come back.
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
Okay.
♪ I will carry you
Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ I will carry you ♪
♪ I know
you can't remember... ♪
What is
so wrong in your life
that you can't listen to
my problems?
Maggie.
No.
Ah, uh!
Did Jackson tell you
what happened?
Because even if he did,
that shouldn't matter.
You're my sister.
You should have my back.
Do you love him?
Do you still love him?
Yeah, of course,
but that's not the point.
No, it is the point!
♪ Is anybody out there? ♪
Catherine has advanced
chondrosarcoma on her spine.
She's my VIP patient.
She's why I went to Los Angeles.
- ♪ Is anybody... ♪
- It's big,
and it's bad,
and he's gonna need you.
So, unless he's revealed himself
to be some sort of sociopath,
just make up with him,
or, at the very least,
be his friend.
Does Jackson know?
Does Richard?
Not yet.
- Meredith.
- I know.
And you broke HIPAA to me
with Teddy, so we're even.
I, uh... I found them.
He didn't.
Found what?
We may have organs
for Cece.
Okay.
Grazed the liver,
missed the colon.
I don't see
any damage to the spleen.
How's the heart?
Well, the cane passed anterior
to the pericardium.
There's only a small hole
in the diaphragm,
and it missed
the heart completely.
Yeah, and the bowel only has
a few serosal tears.
- Irrigation?
- Yeah, I can't believe it.
He's completely unscathed.
Honestly,
I'm kind of disappointed.
♪ You-ooh-ooh are not alone ♪
- Owen.
- Hmm?
♪ I've been here... ♪
I'm pregnant.
♪ Singing you a song ♪
With your baby.
I'm sorry I waited so long.
Dr. Altman, they're asking
for you in the E.R.
- Another cardiac case.
- Yeah.
- ♪ I will... ♪
- I'm on my way.
♪ ...carry you-ooh-ooh... ♪
Congratulations?
♪ I will carry you ♪
♪ Is anybody out there? ♪
Teddy,
are you and Owen finished?
Oh, I'm sorry, what?
With your surgery.
Oh, um,
they were just about to close,
and... and then I got
called out.
Okay, thanks.
I, uh, have to talk to him.
And, um, thank you so much
for your help.
I can't tell you
how much I appreciate it.
Oh, yeah, of course.
- Hey, Altman!
- Excuse me.
Yeah?
Help me out.
Wow.
Where are
all the orderlies?
They're stretched thin,
so maintenance is helping out.
This entire hospital
is stretched thin.
You should shut it down
before someone gets hurt.
- What? You want her to close trauma?
- Yeah, I do.
Every hospital in the area
is shut down, and...
And this is
a brick house.
- Get him to CT.
- Got it.
You know,
for what it's worth,
I was the last one
to find out about Harriet,
and she's the best thing
that ever happened to me.
Could you...
Uh, do you mind talking to...?
Go ahead. Go.
I'll talk to his wife.
So I can get
my transplants today?
Yeah, there's a few more tests
that Dr. Pierce has to run,
but if they check out,
yes.
Who's the donor?
Do they have family?
All I can say is that
it was someone
who was hurt
in the storm.
And the storm's
gotten so bad
that UNOS can't
physically send the organs
anywhere else.
So they're
giving them to me?
Why the face?
You weren't the next person
on the list, Cece.
You were nowhere near
the top
because your body's been
through so much damage,
and with procedures
like these,
you're at risk
for catastrophic bleeding.
You'll be under anesthesia
for hours,
which can only increase
the possibility
that you'll clot
or have a stroke.
There's a chance
it won't work.
There's a chance you might not
make it off Dr. Grey's table.
What's wrong with this one,
again?
He's right.
You don't have
to accept the organs.
We are taking
a huge risk.
If I die today,
I die fighting.
I'll die knowing
I did everything I could,
but, Dr. Grey,
if you don't fight,
if you don't try,
if you don't do your part
and squeeze all the light
and love and joy you can
out of this one life
you've been given,
I'm gonna haunt you
from my grave.
Okay.
Now give me
those organs.
Because I'd much rather
haunt you from above ground.
I will see you upstairs,
Cece.
Okay, so, let's recheck
her potassium
and correct her coagulopathy,
okay?
- Yes.
- Uh, yes to...?
Drinks. I'm assuming
the offer's still standing?
- Really?
- Yeah.
Definitely.
Um,
- you want to try tonight?
- Sure.
I mean, if the bar's
still standing
- after the storm.
- Let's do it.
Someone who knows us
thought we'd want this?
Kepner registered
for us.
Wait, what is the point
of the tiny bowls?
Oh, those are
ramekins.
They're, like, uh, good
for crème brûlée and stuff.
Mm, who are you?
Izzie... Izzie,
she baked a lot.
You know
what I'm thinking?
We shouldn't
talk about our exes
on our honeymoon?
No. Mm, we return
all this crap,
make a fortune,
buy a bigger TV.
I love you.
For your face.
There's some swelling.
What?
What happened
to your glasses?
The band snapped when we were
climbing in the rig.
Can you see?
Yes, I can see.
Just not perfectly.
They're probably
broken on the ground
or blew away into a tree,
which is
all your fault.
You done?
Yes.
No.
No, I'm not done.
You know
what's also your fault?
The fact that you think
I have a shame spiral,
because I don't.
I'm not spiraling.
I'm a nerd.
I'm no more ashamed
of being attracted to guys
than I am of anything else
in my life.
Do you know what I did
almost every night
before I went
to college?
I sat
in my mom's basement
with three other
debate-club kids
playing
"Dungeons & Dragons,"
a-and it's the same basement
I live in now.
Trust me when I say
no one was having sex.
With guys or girls.
Sex was...
Sex was like
the Sunsword.
- ♪ Oh, I, oh, I, oh, ♪
- ♪ am I getting through?♪
- It's a magical weapon in the game
that's really hard
to find.
It's basically like a talking
light saber, but...
Never mind,
doesn't matter.
The point is...
sex wasn't
on the table for us.
So I didn't know
I was gay.
I-I knew that
I had feelings for boys,
but I didn't
understand it.
♪ Could change your mind ♪
Not until
you kissed me.
You kissed me,
and I felt
the opposite of shame.
I felt like I existed,
and everything
fell in place.
For the first time,
it felt like
I was holding the Sunsword,
and I kno...
♪ Oh, maybe I can... ♪
Are... Are... Are...
Are you just kissing me
to get me
to stop talking?
- ♪ But, oh, maybe ♪
- No.
♪ I can change your miiiiind ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Cha-a-a-a-a-nge ♪
♪ Can I change your mind? ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
Hey.
Look, I know...
I probably shouldn't have
said all that to Cece,
and I-I get it if you're mad,
- but I-I had to say...
- It was brave.
Not many doctors
are brave enough
to tell
that kind of truth.
You impress me, DeLuca.
Well, you amaze me,
Dr. Grey.
And while
I'm feeling brave,
I'm not sorry I kissed you
at the wedding.
'Cause it's all I've been able
to think about ever since,
and... I know
you have options,
but... I want you to know
that I'm one of them.
I am your attending.
- No, no, no.
- Don't do that, okay?
This isn't some kind
of abuse of power.
I'm not an intern.
I'm a senior resident.
You dated my sister.
Maggie doesn't care.
Like, deeply doesn't care.
DeLuca.
Meredith.
Andrew.
Look...
I think
there's something here,
and we can keep going through
all the excuses of why not,
but I think
you feel it, too.
I'm having such a week.
I don't trust my thinking.
So I'm gonna walk
out of here, okay?
But I'm gonna think
about what you said...
when I'm able
to think.
Okay?
Okay.
Cheers.
To our second honeymoon.
Mmm.
Ahh.
Beer tastes better
in this.
If we keep
all the gifts,
does that mean we have
to write thank-you notes?
- Not it.
I don't care about the license.
I feel married.
Me, too.
But we should still
mail it in.
Yeah.
Louie's fine?
He... He was an appetizer
on a festive toothpick.
Yes, and, surprisingly,
nothing vital was pierced.
- He needs to rest, okay?
- Ohh.
Stay quiet
for several weeks or so.
I know it sounds like we hate
each other, the way we go at it,
but I have loved him
every day
of the 45 years
we've been together.
But still,
that's 45 years of marriage.
I mean, we would have never
made it without fighting.
Louie... he likes
a dramatic exit,
but he scared me
half to death today,
because...
because, you see,
he always comes back.
No matter the fight,
he would... he would come back.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
I am gonna re-read
this entire thing,
and then I'm gonna
get a new sponsor.
Well, I think that
is an excellent idea.
'Cause I'm pretty sure
my wife is having an affair
with Tom Koracick,
and I'm afraid, if I don't
get a little more serenity
than I already have
right now,
that I'll kill someone
and go back to jail
for good.
Catherine and Koracick?
Well, not everyone
is Bailey and Warren.
Ben and I...
aren't sleeping
in the same house right now.
I asked
for a sabbatical.
You don't take a sabbatical
from a marriage.
You take it from a job.
I worry
every minute of the day
about whether
he was suffocating
from too much
carbon monoxide,
blowing up
in a burning building,
or falling off
a stupid ladder.
I worried
about him dying.
A-And all that stopped just
because you asked him
to leave?
And you're not
worried anymore?
You gave up your job
and your husband.
What's next... Tuck?
Bailey, you're trying to fix
the inside from the outside,
and I know because
my insides are a damn mess.
You need to
get some help, Bailey.
Hi.
You got a minute?
Been thinking
about yesterday.
That was kind of the first big
fight we've ever really had.
Jackson, I-I don't know
how to say this.
No, it's okay.
You don't have to say anything.
Maggie.
Jackson, I'm so sorry.
♪ Ooh ♪
It's your mom.
♪ Oh, child,
when you are weary ♪
♪ Weary deep down in your soul ♪
- Hey, Helm.
- Hey.
You're taking Phoebe up
for the procurement?
Yes. Uh, Dr. Grey's
meeting us in O.R. 2
while Qadri
preps Cece.
♪ I won't ever leave you... ♪
- I'm joining.
- Thanks.
♪ Oh, no, no, no, no ♪
♪ Oh, child,
when you're in darkness ♪
- Hey.
- No!
What? I'm... I'm going
to the O.R.
You're following me.
I'm going to your O.R.
I'm on the case.
Okay, uh, I will
stand over here,
and I will be silent,
and I won't look at you.
♪ Takes some getting lost
to be found ♪
Coming in, careful.
- ♪ Ohhhhh ♪
- Go. Go, go, go.
- Hey.
- Watch it.
Hey.
Hey, hey, hey!
♪ Ain't no grave
gonna hold you now ♪
- Teddy, we need to...
- Owen, I'm...
I'm heading back
into the O.R.
I got this.
Hey, we got this.
- ♪ Ain't no chain gonna hold you down ♪
- ♪ Oh, ho, oh, ho, hoh! ♪
♪ Ain't no grave
gonna hold you now ♪
How could you have
kept this from me?
Don't act like
this should've been easy.
♪ Ain't
it time to bury them bones? ♪
Hey!
I have been looking
for you everywhere
because I had to see you
and tell you that, um...
Whoa... um,
that I want to apply
to be Betty's
official foster mom,
which might mean that Betty and
I have to move out for a while
for bureaucratic whatever,
but, um... I love her.
You know?
Like, we love her, right?
- ♪ Wash me clean in the water ♪
- ♪ Oh, take me down ♪
What?
Did something happen?
Sometimes our body's signals
get messed up...
♪ Ain't no grave
gonna hold you now ♪
♪ Yesterday done came... ♪
and our failsafe
goes haywire.
Instead of making clots,
our body destroys them.
- What is it?
- Amelia, I need to...
We need to...
♪ Wash me clean... ♪
And the thing
that's supposed to help us
only hurts us.
Oh!
- ♪ Wash me clean in the water ♪
- What's happening?
♪ Down to the river ♪
♪ Wash me clean in the water ♪
- ♪ Take me down to the river ♪
- ♪ Oh, ho, ho, ohhh ♪
♪ Wash me clean in the water ♪
- ♪ Take me down... ♪
- We're stuck.
It means we start to bleed...
♪ Wash me clean in the water ♪
♪ Take me down to the river ♪
- ♪ Oh, take me down ♪
- ♪ Wash me clean in the water ♪
- ♪ Take me down...  Take me down... ♪
- ♪ Take me down to the river ♪
♪ Wash me clean in the water ♪
and everything shuts down.
Sync corrections  by  srjanapala