Previously on New Amsterdam...
You're being accused of
forming a nontherapeutic alliance
with your patient, Avi Mantell.
The rules exist for a
reason, and I broke them.
Now the only thing for me to
do is to be a different therapist.
I was actually here to talk to
Max about extending my leave.
Whoa, for how long? Forever.
Max.
Early in the morning
I'll come calling
I'll come calling after you
Darling, if you answer
Oh, we'll wander
Down the garden where it's cool
Later we'd
discover All in colors
Children silent as the stars
Early in the morning
I'll come calling
I'll come calling after you
Though you seldom
answer Still I wonder
What will pass here when you do
Crisp and pressed and blue
Wow. Dora, you really are
as terrifying as Max says.
And I'm going easy
'cause you're new to the
role of medical director.
Deputy medical director.
I'm only taking on Max's
duties while he's recuperating.
Yeah, well, you're 10 minutes
late to your first meeting,
which is a baller move
so soon into your tenure.
I'm on my way.
Could you message this
to Dr. Valentina Castro?
Max's DNA?
Please don't Jurassic Park him.
One Max is more
than I can handle.
It's for a new treatment,
one that will get him back
into the hospital ASAP,
so I no longer have to be...
Sharpe, just the medical
director I was looking for.
Deputy medical
director. How can I help?
Oh, I need ecstasy.
Like, the feeling of bliss?
Like MDMA, like drugs.
Is this a joke?
Am I being hazed?
No, we don't do
that anymore, right?
No, I have a patient who is
exhibiting the most aggressive PTSD
I think I've ever seen.
Kapoor and I've
tried everything.
Nothing makes a dent, so I would like
you to sign my new treatment strategy.
Max thoroughly approved.
Was he high at the time?
No, but he actually made that same
joke when he approved it, so it's cool.
It's a good joke, I think.
Great minds, right?
Listen, I assure you MDMA,
under the proper supervision,
allows a patient to
confront their memories
in a trigger-free
environment, it's amazing.
Yeah, see you later. Mmm-hmm?
It teaches them to remember
a traumatic event
instead of reliving it.
All right, either you sign,
so I can get the pure stuff
from upstairs, or I'm gonna
have to go score from a guy
named Rocket who lives in
his grandmother's basement.
Yeah, just... Okay, fine.
Aces.
Wow.
Signing off on illicit drugs
on your first day. Hmm.
Yeah. Yes, I do.
Oh, my gosh,
that's true, though.
How long have you
all had this tradition?
Oh. How many
Sundays is in forever?
Mom! Hey, Jayden...
No matter how old we
got, Mama has always
made sure we're here every
Sunday eating her food, right?
It's been family tradition
since before I was born.
Sunday means church, family,
and a meal with two meats.
No exceptions.
That's right. Right?
Yep, yep.
My family never did the church
thing, but we're very spiritual.
Hmm. Uh... Which spirit?
Uh, Brandi... - Hmm?
Don't make me bust out
the drill team photos. Oh.
Okay, Foofy.
Ooh!
All right, forget the drill team
photos. I'm busting out prom.
Everybody look right here.
Two words, "sportin' waves."
I'm gonna put you both in the
corner if you can't find your manners.
So, Evie, you're a
lawyer at Floyd's hospital?
Well, I got there
first, actually. Oh.
By one week.
Okay. I did my
undergrad at Yale,
and I went to, I went
to law school at NYU.
So, I did have a
leg up on the city.
Oh, I had the HBCU experience.
Do they have Greeks
at Yale? I pledged AKA.
Oh. Hey, Soror.
No way! Yes.
Oh, my goodness.
Oh, I knew I liked her.
Okay, I hear you. I hear you.
There you go.
Sorry.
Keep in mind, Dr. Kapoor and I
will be here with you the entire time.
Jacob, you don't have
to do this, obviously,
but before you say
no, can I just ask,
when was the last time a
loud noise didn't scare you?
Or when was the last time
you felt safe in a crowded room?
Or slept without nightmares?
You cannot keep going through
life feeling like everyone is a threat.
But they are.
Just turn on the news,
hate crimes, wars,
they put kids in cages,
and no one cares.
It's not PTSD. People are
a threat. People are evil.
Do you know what the
cruelest symptom of PTSD is?
It's a thief.
It robs us of the
ability to see the light.
But that doesn't
mean it's not there.
Do you remember how it
felt when the world had light?
This process is how you
get that light back, Jacob.
Max?
Max.
No, it's not me. It's Georgia.
What happened?
The placenta previa ruptured.
I was about to call 911.
Do it now.
The blood, it happened so fast.
Okay, we need to
get you off the floor.
Max?
No, I was too weak.
I couldn't lift her.
Okay, well, now you
got me. Come on.
Ready? One, two, three.
Max, 911. OPERATOR:
911, what's your emergency?
Any fever? Chills? No.
Any contractions? No.
I need an ambulance
to 42 East 17th Street.
I need paramedics, not EMTs,
and I need you to get here now.
Heart rate up to
180 and thready.
No, no, just get here.
Is that bad? No,
just try to relax, okay?
Max, Max, can I... They're
out there, 12 minutes out.
That's too far away.
Georgia will bleed
out before they arrive.
No, there's time.
Max, she's out of time.
We need to ligate the artery.
Here? And now.
Hey, look at me. I'm right here.
I'm with you, okay?
I'm right here with you.
The fentanyl should
already be working.
Okay, you're gonna
feel a slight heaviness,
and then you're gonna
drift off to sleep. Hmm.
And then we'll
be able to operate
without you feeling a thing.
All these drugs,
they might hurt her.
Will they hurt her?
It's not gonna hurt the baby.
It's not gonna hurt
her? No, I promise, no.
The opiate will slow
Luna's heart rate a little,
but we'll be monitoring
her every step of the way.
Okay.
Hey, it's gonna work.
It's gonna work.
I don't want Luna to have to
take ballet because of me, Max.
No, no, she won't.
I want her to experience
everything. Everything.
Rock climbing and
clarinet and painting.
She will.
No, you have to
encourage her, Max.
You have to help her.
You have to help
her find her own voice.
Her own path.
We can encourage her
together, you and me.
But if I don't...
If I don't, Max...
Stop, stop. No.
No.
I need you to
promise me something.
Promise me that you'll
save her... Save her first.
Promise, I need
you to promise me.
Promise you'll
save our baby girl.
Promise me, no matter what.
Promise me.
Max, it's time.
Let me go! Will you
guys just listen to me?
I have done nothing wrong!
Yeah, that's what all
innocent people scream.
This lunatic... My
name is Wilson Hatch.
This lunatic, Wilson Hatch,
swallowed the biggest balloon
of cocaine I've ever seen.
No, no. We need an X-ray
of his abdomen so we
can get him on intent to sell.
This is... Okay, this
might fly with people
who don't know any better, but I am a
partner at Wyman, Frost, and Handle.
I know my rights. You
guys have nothing on me.
I'm out of here. I'm done.
I'm leaving. CASEY:
Yeah, you're leaving...
You're leaving this floor
and heading up to radiology.
Let's go, buddy. I
don't consent to that.
Ow! Mom. How you
gonna do me like that?
I love you, but you take
food with your bare hands,
I'll put you over my knee.
I can't help it. It's so good,
and I can't live without it,
just like I can't
live without you.
Aw.
Yeah, yeah.
So, she's amazing, right?
She's an exceptional young lady.
Good, I was hoping
you'd say that because
it's time, for me to
use the family ring.
Oh, honey.
What?
Evie seems like
the perfect woman,
just not the perfect
woman for you.
Don't want to pull too hard.
A half hedge will fully
occlude the artery.
That should do it. Bleeding
should be under control.
Huh?
Georgia's having a contraction.
It... It's squeezing the cord.
Heart rate down to 40.
If it goes any lower, it...
We... We need to stop
the contraction. I can't.
It can only pass.
By itself.
Max...
The baby won't
survive another one.
So we have to get her out.
There'll be too much blood loss,
Georgia's lost enough as it is.
No, you did one surgery,
you can do another.
Except this time,
Georgia will die.
Yes, Max, the hospital is still
here, so you can go back to bed.
I need you to listen to me.
911 dispatched an
ambulance to my apartment,
but they don't have
everything that we need.
An ambulance, why?
I need you to call dispatch
and have them go back
to the station, and
they need to pick up
trauma dressing and
surgical gloves and oxygen,
and then I need a
second ambulance
from New Amsterdam
that's fully stocked
with B-positive blood
and mifepristone.
I'm doing it now. Max,
what's happening?
I'm trying to save my family.
We just finished finals.
Third year, never have
to take a test again, so,
we went out to
celebrate. Who's "we"?
I can't remember exactly.
Try.
It's me,
Bobby and Emma.
We're outside the door.
What happened next?
You got a problem?
Perhaps we should wait.
No, no, no.
He's not talking to me.
Hey!
He said...
You got a problem?
Jacob, leave it alone.
This guy just bumps into me.
He's big.
It's all right, Jacob.
We're right here
with you. It's okay.
It's okay. It's
okay, Jacob. Hey.
We're right here
with you, Jacob.
I didn't know it was a pipe
bomb when it happened.
I see Emma. She's...
Emma?
Help!
This piece of stone
is crushing her.
She can't breathe.
I have to get her out,
but it's too heavy.
Please, somebody help me!
If just one person
helps me, I can get it off.
Just one person,
but no one helps.
Not Bobby, not anyone.
Ahh!
Now they're trampling
me, and I can't move.
And she's dying.
No one will help.
They're all running
right over us.
Watch it!
Why would he do that?
It's okay... It's okay, Jacob.
No, why would he do that?
It's okay. It's
okay. Just breathe.
Help me.
Help me, Dr. Frome. Help me.
Please, Dr. Frome, help me.
I'm sorry, Jacob. I need... I
need to... I need something.
Dr. Frome, what's happening?
You're in New
Amsterdam Hospital.
You're in Manhattan.
Where is she?
- What's happening?
- You're safe.
Dr. Frome, where is he?
Take the FDR, anything
else will take too long.
And remember, when
you get there, cut up early.
It's a one-way.
Wait! Wait, I'm coming.
Dr. Sharpe, you cannot leave.
You are the medical director.
And I learned from the best.
Max, we need to talk
about what happens if...
They'll get here.
If Georgia has another contraction,
there's not gonna be time to talk.
I'm gonna have to deliver the
baby, or we're risking both their lives.
But if you open her up
before the blood gets here,
she might not make it.
Which is why we
need to decide who...
No, they'll get
here. They have to.
I've been so selfish.
Thinking that I was the
one who wouldn't survive.
I never even stopped
to think, what if...
Georgia...
And Luna.
You know what? It's
okay. We don't have to...
If you hadn't shown
up when you did,
I don't know what
I would've done.
Thank God you're here.
By the way,
why are you here?
We can talk about that later.
You can't keep ignoring
me. I'm not ignoring you.
We've got guests, and these dishes
are not gonna walk themselves in.
You're always reminding
me how you're saving
the family ring for me, and
now I finally want to use it.
All your adult life you keep
telling me about your plan,
that you want your new
family to look like this one.
Yeah, I still do.
And how's that gonna
happen with Evie?
She doesn't even go to church.
Ma, that doesn't
mean that I can't.
I even noticed that
Evie doesn't cook.
Doesn't cook 'cause she can't.
She works 12 hours a day.
So, is she giving that up
when you have your kids?
Are you? I don't know.
Exactly.
Come back for the
ring when you do know.
Don't say it.
She just wants you to be happy.
No, she wants me to
marry somebody like her.
'Cause that's how you
get a family like this.
No judgment.
That's just the reality.
A life with Evie isn't
gonna look like this.
It's not going to look
like what you planned.
And Mom is smart enough
to see that. Why can't you?
He's calmer now.
Good.
Thank you.
When Jacob started to break
down in there, my instinct was...
Was to hold him.
That seemed like the
appropriate response.
But I can't.
Not after what happened
with Avi. I can't do that.
So I just froze.
This is different than Avi.
No, it's not.
I feel like
the physical contact
is all I have.
It's my crutch, you know?
The only thing I have
in my bag of tricks.
Iggy, sometimes people
need the physical contact
to feel cared for.
But it's not the
only trick you have.
It just heightens
your other gifts.
You can't doubt that.
But I do.
All the time now.
How can I get inside someone
else's head if I can't get out of my own?
You're always the
one who counsels me.
And you have
taught me very well.
So what I'll say to you is this.
That boy needs help,
and you are the only
one who can help him.
Heart rate's fluctuating.
The contractions have
started. I have to cut.
No, wait, wait, wait.
They're close, okay? Max...
No, they're gonna
be close. Just wait.
Hey, hey, tell me you guys will
make it here in the next three minutes.
We're close, Dr. Goodwin.
The other bus is right...
Give it to me. Sure.
Max, it's Helen. Talk to me.
Luna's heart rate is fading
with each contraction.
We could lose her
on the next one.
But if Bloom operates now...
Bloom's there?
Yeah, she saved Georgia's life.
But if she operates and
you are not close enough,
then she could bleed out.
Oh, God.
What? What?
Max, we are not close enough.
Yeah, no, but you...
We're not gonna make it.
Max?
Are you still there?
Yeah.
After everything you have done,
I would jump out of here, and
I would run the blood to you
if I thought that it would help,
but we are not close enough.
I'm...
I'm so sorry.
I have to...
I have to choose
between my wife and my...
No, no. Okay, look.
Hey, listen to me.
This is a decision
that you cannot make,
'cause whatever you decide,
you're gonna be haunted
by it for the rest of your life.
I've seen it, Max.
The guilt, the shame.
The loss.
It'll destroy you, Max.
But I have to.
I'll do it.
I'll decide.
I'll take on the responsibility.
Please, Max, please.
Let me do this for you.
Okay.
Try to cast your mind
back to that night.
What was the last exam you
and your friends had taken?
I don't...
I don't remember.
Jacob.
Jacob, when you
were talking about
being trampled
by people earlier,
you said, "Why
would he do that?"
Okay.
Why would you refer to a
whole crowd of people as "he"?
Person after person
running by you, over you,
and you said, "Why
would he do that?"
That's not what I meant.
I think it was.
Jacob, what really
happened that night?
Don't you think
it's time to find out?
Georgia's pulse?
Steady.
I can't get it.
The cord is crimped.
Can you free it?
I'm trying.
Come on, baby,
come on. Easy, easy.
Easy, easy.
You got it. All right,
you got it. Okay.
Okay, I got it.
Okay.
Easy.
Okay. There you go,
baby. There you go, baby.
There she is.
Hi, Luna.
Oh, my Lord.
It's okay.
Hi, hi.
Hi, Luna.
There you are.
You're a mess.
I'm your dad.
I got ya.
Ready?
Georgia,
she's here.
Georgia.
Yeah, I know.
Georgia, she's here.
Hi, we've been
waiting so long for you.
You came into this
world in a really,
really crazy way,
but now you're here.
Now you're here.
Georgia, she's here.
Georgia.
Max, she needs blood.
Right now.
You have to hang in there.
You need to hang in there.
Because I am not
doing this without you.
This little girl...
This little girl, she
needs her mom.
And so do I.
I wish that I had known
In that first minute we met
The unpayable debt
That I owed you
Because you've been abused
By the bone that refused you
And you hired me
to make up for that
Walking in that room
When you had tubes in your arms
Singing morphine
alarms out of tune
Had you sleeping and eating
And I didn't believe them
When they called you a
hurricane thundercloud
Okay, we got a pulse.
Is she all right?
She's fine.
It's not happening.
It's just a memory.
Say that.
So then look at it.
It's okay to look, Jacob.
Watch it!
I don't want to.
Every single detail is in there.
Just close your eyes and look.
Em...
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay to look somewhere
else, just this once.
Where's your other
friend from the line?
Bobby? Yeah.
I have no idea.
Sure you do.
He's on the dance
floor somewhere.
Facing us?
He's facing away.
Okay. Well, now you
know why he didn't help.
He didn't see us.
No.
What about the big guy, the
guy who bumped into you?
Where's he?
He's on the dance
floor somewhere.
You sure?
You said he
crashed into you later.
So he couldn't be on the dance
floor when the bomb went off.
He must have been...
Why is he over there?
You tell me.
Wait. I hear something.
What is that?
Take a look.
It's a gas pipe.
Is that what the
guy's looking at?
That can't be right.
If that happened, I'd be dead.
So why aren't you?
Watch out!
He saved me.
I wasn't being trampled.
I couldn't move because
he saved me.
He risked his life for me.
Why would he do that?
Because sometimes
the world has light.
Hey.
I have to say, you're the last
person I expected to find here.
Yeah, well, me too.
I actually came to tell Max
that I'm not coming back.
Hell of a last day.
Yeah.
Max would've lost his
family if it wasn't for you.
I am so sorry, Lauren.
I'm so very sorry.
I betrayed your trust.
I ruined our friendship.
You saved my life.
Look, if I did anything good
today, it's because of you.
Let's go.
Trauma team's waiting.
Go.
You coming?
So, in my professional opinion,
that right there
is a giant balloon
full of cocaine in
Wilson Hatch's stomach.
It's at least four ounces.
Okay, so maybe there happens
to be a balloon in my stomach,
but you can't prove what's in it. It
could be something perfectly legal.
So let's see it.
What do you mean,
here? Just now, in the...
Please, man, please.
I'll be disbarred.
My girlfriend will leave me.
My wife will leave me.
Good luck.
No, no, no, no.
Tre, you want to play video games...
- Tre, put your hat on.
When we get home?
Thank y'all for coming.
Evie, you should come
over for dinner every Sunday.
Ah. If I came over every Sunday,
I would never get any work done.
Thank you.
Here.
It's yours, right?
You gonna take it or what?
No.
She's great.
Is that her?
Hey.
You did it.
There's somebody
who is dying to meet you.
Luna, say hi to your mom.
Oh, my God.
Hi.
Honey, you did it.
She's perfect.
Yeah.
There she is.
Your mom is drop-dead gorgeous.
I hope I look half
as good at her age.
Now is when you say, "You'll
look gorgeous at any age, babe."
I'm sorry. I just...
What's up? You haven't said
more than two words since we left.
Couldn't have been that bad.
I couldn't have been that bad.
You know, my whole life I imagined
what my future would look like,
what my family would look like.
I had a plan.
And to be honest,
you don't fit into it.
So I...
I don't know what to do.
For the first time,
I don't know what's
next, and I don't care.
As long as you're there.
As long as you're
right there with me,
I don't need a plan.
Look, I don't have your family's
blessing, and I don't have mine.
I don't have a ring, I
don't have anything.
Will you please,
please say you'll
spend your life with me,
make a family with me,
you'll marry me?
Yes.
Here you go.
Thanks.
So are you back
down on earth yet?
Yeah.
First time on ecstasy
I haven't called an ex.
Jacob.
A joke, all right, man.
So why would my brain do that?
That guy saved my life.
Wouldn't I want
to remember that?
It does seem counterintuitive,
until you realize
how the brain works.
The brain is just...
It's just trying to
make sense of things.
Like, sometimes the world
is so beautiful, you know?
The laughter of a friend.
A newborn baby
gripping your finger.
Life is all so fragile.
You blink, it's
gone, just like that.
In the face of horror,
our minds turn our trauma
into a story to
make sense of it,
even if it doesn't make sense.
So why would your mind tell
you that the world was evil?
Because evil means
that your fear is right.
Evil means that
you can just give up.
But to believe that we all
have the capacity to be heroes,
no matter how evil
the world may seem,
that's harder.
Because that means
when the worst happens,
we can choose to stand
up, we can choose to help.
And that's what, all day,
all around us, people do.
So, is the world dark?
Sure, but there's light.
There's so much light.
You just have to open
your eyes and look.