♪ One, two, three, four, unh! ♪
♪ Whoo-o-o-o ♪
Pharmaceuticals
are designed to mimic
the body's
natural brain chemicals...
The ones
that make you feel good,
make you feel better,
make you feel unstoppable.
♪ Whoohey - whoohey ♪
3-0 tie, please.
♪ In the back of my mind,
I was losing it ♪
How long do you think
it'll take
before I'm ready to do
a 24-hour surgery?
I'm not sure that's
a healthy life goal, Qadri.
Hey.
What's going on?
Mer's doing a pancreas-sparing
total duodenectomy
in a frozen abdomen.
Oh. It got moved
from yesterday?
No, she started it
yesterday.
Five more hours, and she's gonna
break the hospital's record
for the longest surgery.
You think it's gonna take
five more hours?
Well, I mean, with the adhesions
and the scar tissue,
it's taking her longer, so, yeah.
She can beat the record.
- Feel a little better?
- No.
I mean, yeah, she gets awards
and prizes and all that,
but I get to be chief,
so we're good.
They make it in a lab and put
it in a pill for pain relief,
giving you the high
your body creates naturally
anytime you're doing
something you love.
Helm.
You want to tap out?
No, thank you.
- DeLuca?
- No, thank you. I'm good.
Oh! - Oh!
Think he could
use a break, though.
When I said
"breakfast,"
I meant more of a place
where we sit,
someone takes our order,
there's less... lion jaws.
No. Um...
pointed reduction clamp.
I let interns assist on hip
replacements once they're prepared.
I don't dish out
special favors.
At work.
Neck osteotomy's done.
Now we got to get into
the femoral canal.
- What's the next step?
- Okay,
first, I'll do a ream.
And what would you use?
I think
the Christmas Tree Reamer.
Let's do actual breakfast
on Thursday.
I'll make French toast.
Why are you holding
toilet paper?
It's the most important
camping supply.
Oh, God.
Why's your face like that?
I, uh...
O-Our weekend away
is camping?
Yeah. Babe, what did
you think Glen Rock was?
"Sounds fancy,
but I deserve it"?
I mean, of all the campsites
I went to,
yeah, I guess it's the fanciest.
It did have running water.
But no toilet paper,
so no...
Toilets.
Okay, so, right.
- Where do we go...
- packed a small shovel.
And there are these really nice
rocks. They're great.
You just kind of move over them,
kind of, as you...
Look, it's camping,
babe.
We're going camping.
Are we, though?
Ohh!
You're gonna love it!
This is Tom Koracick?
The one who works here?
I was surprised, too.
But it's, you know...
I don't know.
It's new, and it's...
It's just kind of...
amazing.
Look, I definitely
didn't expect to be dating
at 30 weeks pregnant,
but he's kind and fun,
and he's kinda wow.
- Huh.
- I know.
How about you
and Ben, now that he's back home?
Watch out!
Slow down!
This is a hospital!
Get out!
Go, go, go!
- Oh, my...
- Go, go, go, go!
Hey, Bailey,
pinpoint pupils!
Yeah. Get some Narcan,
a crash cart, and some O2.
I think
we got an OD.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 15  Episode 14
Episode Title :
"I Want a New Drugl"
Sync corrections  by  srjanapala
I thought
you'd be in O.R. 3.
I've been busy.
This boy's buddies almost ran me
over in the ambulance bay.
Tossed him
out of the car.
Opioid overdose.
Why? What's going on
in O.R. 3?
Grey's been in surgery
since yesterday.
Quite a crowd.
Bailey,
we got two more.
Two more overdoses?
Mm-hmm. Jerry and Paula.
Regulars.
Always shooting up
in the park down the street.
They usually wake up
with one dose of Narcan
and then
refuse treatment,
but I've already given them
three doses,
and they're not
responding.
There's a bad batch of
something out there.
- Okay.
- Attention, all units.
We've reached
Code Red status.
Any available unit, please
report to Meridien Park
for multiple
suspected overdose events.
Looks like I'll be
seeing a lot of you today.
Okay, listen up.
This is gonna be
an all-hands-on-deck situation.
Let's page on-call personnel.
Let's make sure that we got
all the Narcan from the pharmacy
to reverse the opioids.
We need to be prepared
for secondary injuries
and side effects.
Wait a minute.
Where are all my residents?
Uh, they're in Grey's gallery.
I'll make sure
they get down here.
- Okay.
- What about Hunt?
Um, he's, uh...
He's saying goodbye to Leo.
Betty's parents are taking him.
Oh. Um...
I'm sorry to hear about that,
but this is a mass OD.
Yep. Okay.
We'll page him.
Get your shoe on.
Okay.
Your mom got this for him.
Do you want to keep it or...
No, no.
That's his favorite.
We were gonna... We were gonna
watch him grow up.
We were gonna
teach him so many things.
Well...
Listen.
I, um...
I hope you play soccer.
I hope
you love your life.
Wait, wait. Yours makes mine
sound shallow.
Yeah. You should
probably go again.
Yeah. Um...
Listen.
I'm always gonna be
rooting for you.
Okay.
Ready?
No.
But they're good people, Owen,
and they love him.
He will be loved.
Hey.
Come in.
So, uh... may I?
Oh. Uh, sorry.
Yeah. Here.
Hi!
Ohh!
When he gets fussy like that,
he's usually just hungry.
- We've raised one before.
- It's okay.
Right.
E.R. 911.
All hands on deck.
So, we are, uh...
very grateful to you both.
I have to go.
Owen...
Listen, it's a massive
incoming trauma. I have to go.
I'll just,
um...
Do you want to feed him
while I finish packing him up?
Yeah,
that'd be great.
Whoopsie!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Okay, everybody slow down.
Speak to your team calmly,
get what they need, and handle it.
With this many people,
communication is key.
- What do you got?
- He was responding until
about two minutes ago,
when he started hypoventilating again.
Get him
on a Narcan drip.
Bailey, how's it going?
It's worse outside
than it is in here.
And too many teenagers.
I'm aware that I sound
like my mother,
but is the world going to Hell
in a handbasket?
Uh, 0.4 of Narcan.
All right.
Bailey, you got this?
I'm gonna go
to the ambulance bay
and see if I can get it
under control.
Teddy, I'll do it.
Owen.
Look, I'm sorry.
I-I wasn't
gonna page you, but...
No, no, no.
Better here than at home.
Okay.
Hey.
People are dropping like flies
all over the park.
Never seen anything like it.
How many ODs have been called in?
50 and counting.
Whoa.
Hey, everybody! Listen up!
Here's how this is gonna go.
Three ambulances
are gonna pull up.
When the patients are offloaded,
they're gonna pull out,
and then the next three
are gonna come in.
We're gonna set up
a triage area,
where we're gonna assess
each ambulance
and mark them
with the appropriate tag.
Red tags get priority
for the E.R.
Walking wounded will
be shown to the clinic,
where they're gonna
be evaluated.
Thank you.
Let's go.
Helm, tell me
about the SMA first approach.
You, uh, dissect out
the entire
superior mesenteric artery
to, uh, evaluate for any...
tumor invasion.
Helm, are you in pain?
No.
I, uh...
I just, uh, shouldn't have had
so much coffee.
- Well, then go.
- No. I can hold it.
If you can, I can.
Did she have
her bladder stapled?
That's not
the hard part...
The achy legs,
the sore feet,
the cramping back,
or the bladder.
No, the hard part is that
this surgery doesn't get easier
as it goes on...
It gets harder.
And her eyes and her instincts
will need to be sharper
when she finishes
than when she started.
And that was yesterday.
Do you think
she's part robot?
I can hear you.
I'm... so sorry.
Helm, just go.
Go update the family.
Tell them
that he's doing great.
And then go see
what you can do in the pit.
Thank you!
Sorry. Thank you!
Hey! Dr. Hays wants to know
if he can still do that surgery.
Not if it's elective.
I want those O.R.s free.
Have you ever seen
anything like this?
No. And of course
it happens on a day
that Mer sets
a new surgical record.
I mean, I want to be there
to cheer her on.
She has DeLuca
- Well, that's not a thing.
- Pretty sure that's a thing.
- Truman!
- Truman?
- Ma'am, are you okay?
- My son... Truman.
He's three years old...
He has blond hair, he's wearing
a blue shirt,
- I think...
- All right, we'll call security...
I talked
to the police.
The police are
at the park, looking.
We were at the park,
playing,
and suddenly
there were ambulances
and police cars
everywhere,
and I went to see
what was going on,
and then
when I turned around...
Truman was gone,
and then, uh...
Anyway, the police
are looking in the park,
and so I thought
I would come here
and see if an ambulance person
- or a fireman...
- What's your name?
- Wendy.
- Wendy, look, we're gonna help you.
- Jo, can you take her...
- I'll take her to security,
see if he's here. Do you have
a picture of him?
Yes. Yes.
Okay, I'll make sure
she has a tele bed
to monitor
for arrhythmias.
And I'll be out of town
this weekend,
but I'll have Parker check
for her electrolytes
and cardiac markers,
and you just, you know, call me
if you see anything unusual.
All right.
If calls can
even go through.
I might be
completely off the grid.
You going to the moon?
I'm going camping.
Why?
'Cause Jackson loves camping
and I love Jackson.
I love Ben, but I don't love
fantasy basketball.
Therefore,
I don't participate.
I'm going camping, Bailey,
and I am going to like it.
Are you, though?
All right, Qadri,
so, we're definitely looking
at a shooter's abscess.
I need to you make sure
he's got plenty of antibiotics
and get a full washout
in the O.R.
And look,
I know it smells bad,
but breathe out of your mouth
or something
so you don't look
so overtly disgusted.
Mr. Frazier's prepped
for his hip replacement,
and Schmitt's been crushing
the saw bones sessions,
- so he'll assist.
- That's great,
but Schmitt's
gonna have to wait.
But his technique's flawless,
and I'll be there...
I see the butterflies
floating around between you two,
and that's cool, but try
to see past them long enough
to notice the flood of patients
around you.
I postponed
Mr. Frazier's surgery.
It's all hands on deck
with trauma.
- Got it.
- This unlucky lady not only OD'd,
she broke both of her arms
when she fell.
She needs to go to the O.R.
Schmitt can assist with that.
And tell
the anesthesiologist
she's had four doses
of Narcan.
Thank you so much, sir.
I won't let you down.
I am ready and prepared
and...
Show me,
don't tell me, Schmitt.
Interns.
Am I right?
No offense.
None taken.
Out of your mouth,
please.
Apneic at the scene
with erratic rhythms...
Last BP, 80 over 40.
Got one patient responsive
after two doses of Narcan
and another one
with decreased mentation
but responsive
and talking.
He lost his pulse.
Starting CPR.
Helm, your two sound good
to go to the clinic,
- but keep an eye on them.
- Yes, sir.
Let's get them inside. Come on.
What's happening?
Is s-she gonna be okay?
Get these two
into the clinic.
Is she... Betty!
Betty!
Unh! 5-0.
4-0.
- What happened?
- You did it.
No, I haven't finished
the anastomosis
or the lymphadenectomy.
Suture scissors, Bokhee.
Mered...
Dr. Grey, you just beat
the hospital record
for the longest
single surgery.
Yeah.
I guess I did.
Damn it.
What?
That just means that I'm gonna
want to break it again.
Okay, let's get ready
with some lap pads.
And, uh, Bokhee, someone should
update the family.
Okay. I'm gonna tell them
their son's being saved
by a surgical legend.
Okay, don't do that.
Surgical superhero?
No.
Wonder Woman?
Yeah! Perfect.
Thank you, Bokhee.
Whoo!
You are.
Okay, now observe
the scaphoid carefully.
What's the usual
point of entry?
The distal pole.
But wait.
There's a humpback deformity.
Exactly.
Can you imagine...
wanting something so badly
that you'd be willing to
break both your arms to get it?
Well, she didn't mean
to break her arms.
Yeah, I know.
I'm just...
I broke
both my arms once.
You did?
Couldn't wipe my own butt
all summer. It was the worst.
But the new X-Men comic
was coming out,
and I had to have it.
Like, had to be first in line
because, in my world,
that was the only thing
worth bragging about.
Fell off your bike?
Flipped over the handlebars...
One block from the store.
I got two months in casts,
three months of PT.
And Robbie Freaking Krimefelt
got bragging rights.
So yeah.
I get wanting something so bad
you'd be willing to...
Whoa. You just...
All right.
She's all good.
And with no hands to shoot up
for the next three months,
hopefully, she'll actually
manage to detox.
Dr. Mahoney to the E.R.
Hey.
Tell me
she found that kid.
No.
Security's on it.
I'm worried about her.
Her BP's through the roof.
She is so scared.
Excuse me.
I found him in the park...
Kind of shook up.
Truman!
I'm gonna...
Mommy!
Thank you.
I saw him wandering,
and I thought, well,
everybody's coming here.
Uh... yeah.
Let... Let us get you some food
and some shoes, maybe.
No. Unh-unh.
No, please. We got to
take a look at those feet.
Uh, Qadri, could you help
this gentleman?
Yeah.
So, she's all right, then?
That lady?
Oh, yeah. She's...
She's fine, thanks to you.
She was scared
out of her mind.
No, I mean
from the park.
I saw her passed out
on the bench out there
with the rest
of them junkies.
I want to go.
Can we go?
Can you get our clothes?
Okay, yeah. Sure. I just...
I want to make sure
- you're okay.
- I want to go.
I don't want Amelia
to see me here.
I-I don't want to put her
through that again.
- O-Okay.
- Linus, please, can we...
Hey. Hey!
Hey! Help!
I need help!
Hey. It's okay.
She was just talking.
She wasn't complaining
of anything when she came in.
Well,
she's complaining now.
It hurts!
What did she take?
I need to know.
Meth.
We smoked some meth before
the batch of pills came 'round.
280 over 145.
Okay,
I need a gurney!
Out of my way.
Out of my way!
I got a hypertensive
emergency here.
Took meth and opioids
and whatever
they were laced with.
Clear a trauma room now!
7-0 tube.
Helm said she was stable when
she landed. This just happened.
What's happening?
Is she okay?
Who's that?
No idea. Boyfriend?
Get him out of here.
I've got this.
No! I need to be with Betty,
all right?
I love her. I love her. Please.
Get him out of here!
I need to be with her!
She's afraid to be alone!
Dude, let me help you.
Let them help her.
Go.
How can I help?
She needs to be ruled out
of multi-organ damage,
hypertensive ICH.
I've started her
on a clevidipine drip.
Hunt,
you need to step away.
We need that X-ray
in here now!
Let me do this!
Just... call Amelia.
Tell her
that Betty's back.
We don't need her to
flip her car trying to get here.
Richard, please.
I need to be
with Betty.
No, you need hydration,
and we need to observe...
One of the first nights
at rehab,
Betty was telling me
what she's scared of.
I-I-It was blood,
being home alone in the dark,
falling into
a frozen lake,
a-and she was scared
that for the rest of her life,
she'd have to
tell people
that her dealer
got her pregnant at 15.
And who would
love her then?
But I did.
All right?
And I do.
And I told her that one day,
we'd get a house
and that we could
keep the lights on all the time
and we'd be
nowhere near a lake
and that no matter what,
I would love her.
No matter what.
You have to save her...
Please.
Betty's getting
the help she needs.
I'll... get you an update
as soon as I can.
Okay, Ralph,
I've paged a plastic surgeon
to come take a look
at these skin lesions.
I don't have any shoes,
but I'm getting plastic surgery.
And I'll need
a urine sample.
What for?
We just need to run
a tox screen.
Oh, that's unnecessary.
I don't do drugs
or drink alcohol.
I just make my home
in the park.
I'm not like them.
They're bringing down
the neighborhood, you ask me.
Do you have... anywhere else
that you could stay?
A temporary shelter?
No. They got more people
than they got beds.
They set a limit
on how many nights you can stay.
I maxed out months ago.
I never thought I'd be
calling a park bench my home,
but rent control went out,
and I went out with it.
Qadri,
what do we have?
This is Mr. Tennyson.
He's got ulcerations and eschars
on the dorsums of his feet.
Mr. Tennyson, this is Dr. Avery.
He's our head of plastics.
You don't want to give me
a nose job, do you?
No, sir.
Your nose is perfect.
I would like to take a look
at these feet, though.
Qadri, face.
She's got
a widened mediastinum,
and with the meth
and opioids...
You're worried
about an aortic dissection.
Mm-hmm.
It's a known
complication of meth.
She's got
the classic signs.
Hey. Where is she?
Amelia...
Well, is she hurt or just high?
Richard said...
Listen, I didn't want you
to panic,
but we received some patients
from Meridien Park,
and they all OD'd
from the same drug...
She OD'd?
Is she okay?
You brought them here?
They were still
at the house.
That's Britney.
Britney?
Oh, my God. What happened? Is
she hurt? I need to see her. Move.
You can't go in there.
You can't go...
Oh, my God.
You had to intubate her?
You can't go in there
right now...
That is our daughter!
Yeah, and I'm her doctor,
okay? So...
Okay, everyone calm down
and let Dr. Altman do her work.
You too, Hunt.
Okay, just tell us
what happened.
She, uh, complained
about chest pain,
and it looks like
she's had an aortic dissection.
We're prepping her
for the O.R. right now.
Surgery?
We're gonna call Pierce,
we're gonna meet her there.
- I'm gonna do it.
- No, no. You have an entire E.R...
- Bailey can handle it.
- No. I'm gonna call Pierce...
We don't have time
to wait for Pierce.
Owen, let her do it.
Okay.
Well, I'm gonna go, too.
Uh, Dr. Hunt, now,
you can help out in the pit,
or you can sit in the chair
with the other parents,
but you will not step one foot
in that O.R.
All right, here we go.
All right.
Watch the baby, please.
Here we come.
Thank you.
Hold the elevator!
I don't understand
why you took him. He was fine.
Because he was out of your sight
for a little while,
so we just needed
to check him out.
He'll be back soon.
- You know, let me...
- let me take your blood pressure again.
I'm fine!
And so is he.
We should
just be able to go.
Okay.
Stuart?
Oh, my God!
Honey, they didn't need
to call you.
We just had
a little scare.
Wendy, tell me
what the hell is going on.
I just...
Rita gave me some pills once,
from her back surgery,
- just... to relax me.
- You were in the park to buy drugs?
You took Truman with you
to buy drugs?
I couldn't leave him alone
in the car.
Please, Stuart. I'm sorry.
I love him.
I love him!
You have to forgive me!
Can you take me
to my son, please?
Please.
It's a lot, right?
This is one of those days
where being a doctor is...
It feels futile.
It's, like,
we're in here
doing our damnedest
to save lives, and out there,
people are just
killing themselves or each other
faster than we can
possibly work, so...
what's the point?
Where would you go?
If you just...
gave it all up?
Um...
You know, when it all
seems hopeless,
what's... your secret
fantasy escape hatch?
Went to Barbados once.
It was... a bunch of expats...
Started a Blues bar.
Tiny little shack
but incredible guitar players.
Waves... rum... sand...
quiet.
You?
Right now,
that sounds...
pretty great, actually.
What the...
What's...
Oh, my God.
Son of a bitch!
Oh, my God, no.
Here.
Got to get down here.
I came
as soon as I heard...
Type B dissection?
I'm gonna do an endovascular
stent of the descending aorta.
Webber's on his way up
to join.
Thank you. I know you've been
swamped down in the pit.
I can take it from here.
- No.
- No?
She's so pale, I can see
every capillary under her skin.
That dissection could
cause her aorta to rupture.
You know as well I do
that Amelia may never see
that little girl
open her eyes again.
Teddy...
And if that happens,
let me be the surgeon
to tell Amelia that we lost her.
Because she's gonna need
her sister.
You are so close.
Tell me something.
Okay. What?
Just anything.
Because all I can
think about right now
is how much
my feet and my legs hurt,
so if you tell me something,
I can think about that instead.
Um, okay.
Uh, when I was seven years old,
I broke a world record.
For what?
Most times a minor rode
a roller coaster in one day.
Really? How many times
did you ride it?
12.
I-I didn't really break
a world record,
but for several years,
I believed that I did.
♪ You flood my mind ♪
♪ When I dive in too deep ♪
You're an artist.
And I think
it didn't occur to me
because you're also
a work of art.
Physically.
Like a statue in Rome.
And
when I look at you,
surgery isn't
what springs to mind.
But that...
♪ I don't speak my mind
out loud ♪
In there...
♪ It might not seem like I am
listening ♪ - I want to be that good.
You'll get there.
And you're also
good at a lot of things.
♪ Mmm ♪
So much better
than a comic book.
♪ To feel nothing ♪
♪ I'm hardwired differently ♪
Couldn't get him back.
He was my patient.
I left him sitting in a bed
with an IV in his arm.
Perfectly healthy kid.
Dr. Shepherd?
Are you okay?
Do you want to take a break,
take a walk?
I knew him.
That kid.
He was, uh...
He was a good kid.
He wasn't a bad kid.
I'm gonna have to
call his parents.
I can take care
of that.
No.
No, I'm...
Thank you.
I'm so sorry.
It's... It's okay.
Great work, Qadri.
You want to cut away
all that dead tissue
till we find
healthy bleeding.
Almost done.
So I get to keep 'em?
You do
get to keep them.
Can I talk to you?
Yeah, of course.
I can't go camping
this weekend.
Babe, see,
the thing is you think
you can't go camping
this weekend, okay?
But once
we get out there,
you're gonna find it
breathtaking.
And you will realize all the
things we don't need in life...
Just how much
we don't need, okay?
When you're sitting there
by a fire crackling,
one bowl, one spoon,
you realize
we don't need...
three pairs of ski boots.
You know?
Y... No. And don't... don't
tell me that you don't ski.
I know you don't ski,
because it's outdoors,
but that's probably
because your parents
didn't take you outdoors,
but when I do, you will see.
Okay? Just let me show you,
please? Okay?
Okay.
Backing up...
Mm-hmm.
Betty is
in the hospital.
She OD'd.
Amelia's gonna need help,
so...
So you cannot go camping
this weekend.
My bad.
I'm sorry.
You should still go,
though.
Aw. That's too bad.
Ah, it's okay.
Next time.
Okay, so, we're
almost finished here.
I'll get you
bandaged up.
It's important that you keep
this clean and dry, okay?
That'll be tricky.
Ralph lives in the park.
He brought in
a little missing boy today.
Oh.
The park.
Okay, I hadn't...
realized that.
It's okay.
Makes you realize
all the things you don't need.
Dr. Teller to the E.R.
Mr. Cole.
The police have taken your wife
into custody and...
Good.
The police can have her.
Sir, your wife has a problem.
She needs treatment.
She needs that
more than punishment.
I don't know
what I can do for her.
No, you're right.
Don't worry about her.
Worry about him.
And no matter what she says,
you don't just forgive her.
You don't let her near him
until you know she's clean.
Yes, get her treatment,
but protect your kid.
You got me?
Protect your kid.
Okay, let's shoot the angio.
No endoleaks, stent-grafts
are well-approximated.
Aortic arch is clear.
There's no flow
from the celiac.
Let's shoot
from the femoral.
Dye.
Higher concentration
of dye.
God, I hate
that she did this to herself.
That's addiction...
The thing that's killing you
keeps whispering in your ear
that you need it to survive.
There's no flow
from either end.
Her distal aorta
is blocked.
Which means
there's no blood flow
to the distal
extremities.
Damn it! Damn it!
Altman, if there's
any extraordinary measures
you can use here,
please use them now.
Okay.
Take everything out.
We're gonna have to
open her up
and reconstruct
her distal aorta completely
if we're gonna
save her life.
Let me have a pad.
All right,
let's prep her abdomen!
Let's go. Come on.
Come on, Betty.
Come on.
I can't even stand
to look at you.
That's the last thing I said
to her before she disappeared.
"I can't even stand
to look at you."
Now...
Tell us
that she's gonna be okay.
I mean, you're doctors.
Just...
tell us that she's gonna
get through this.
I wish I could.
I wish
I could tell you that.
♪ Where are you now ♪
♪ When darkness seems to win? ♪
DeLuca, you'll place
the wound vac.
Okay.
Final time...
27 hours and 8 minutes.
That beats the hospital's
old record by over three hours.
Whoo!
Thank you for the assist,
Dr. DeLuca.
♪ I hear you say ♪
♪ "Look up, child" ♪
♪ Mm-hmm, hey, hey ♪
I am going to go put my feet
in medical waste,
so I definitely need
a ride home.
Amelia needs us.
It's Betty.
She's gonna need us.
♪ Where are you now ♪
♪ When darkness seems to win? ♪
Mr. and Mrs. Dickinson?
She's out of surgery.
She's being moved
up to the ICU.
♪ Oh, I ♪
♪ I ♪
♪ I hear you say ♪
♪ "Look up, child" ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ Where are you now ♪
Oh, thank God.
That means...
she made it, right?
Yeah.
I think
that's what that means.
♪ Where are you now ♪
♪ When I can't figure it out? ♪
♪ Oh, I ♪
♪ I ♪
♪ I hear you say ♪
♪ "Look up, child" ♪
Come here.
♪ Hey ♪
♪ "Look up, child" ♪
This world is so scary.
No matter how well
you raise your kids,
no matter
how much give them,
it's a scary,
scary world.
Yeah.
It is.
- But it's beautiful, too.
- Mm.
And if you descend into the fear
and miss the beauty,
that's when you start to go
to a bad place
and need to...
escape.
- ♪ "Look up, child" ♪
- I'm not gonna start using drugs.
Yeah, I know.
But... just...
be in the beauty with me
for a second.
♪ "Look up, child" ♪
♪ I hear you say ♪
♪ Ohh ♪
♪ "Look up, child" ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, hey ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ "Look up, child" ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, hey, look up ♪
And you don't have room
for one... just one more?
He's a 75-year-old m...
His f...
Mm-hmm.
Y... Yeah. I...
No, I understand.
Thank you.
No luck?
It should not be
this difficult
to find a place to stay
for an elderly man.
No, it shouldn't.
I feel awful.
I mean, I was going on and on
about how we
can't decide whether we should
stay inside or outside,
and... I've got too many...
Ski boots.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
And I spent all day
debriding his feet,
and there's no way he can
maintain a follow-up protocol
on a park bench.
I would say just cook his chart
and keep him another night,
but then where is he gonna go
tomorrow night?
Owen took Leo
to daycare
so that you could focus
on Britney.
So, how are we
gonna tell her?
About her... boyfriend?
How are we gonna tell her?
We don't tell her.
What?
No.
We don't tell her.
I'm afraid something like that,
that would kill her.
That kind of... news
could...
It could kill her.
My fiancé died.
Um... years ago.
He died in bed
beside me.
He OD'd.
I thought
it would kill me, too.
But instead,
it saved my life.
Because I decided to live.
I decided to live
because he died.
You can't protect her
from this.
from the pain
that she is going to feel.
But you can hope...
that this is her bottom.
I...
God, I hope this is her bottom.
I hope this gets her clean.
I hope
that she decides to live.
Please decide to live.
Honey,
please decide to live.
♪ How I marveled at your pace ♪
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Yeah, whatever you want.
It's not much, but it's enough
to keep you warm and dry
till you get off the waitlist
for a real place.
Dry socks here, long underwear,
lightweight tent,
a sleeping bag,
a couple raincoats,
and a pair of shoes for you
once the swelling goes down
a bit.
You had all this...
just in the trunk of your car?
Yeah.
Yeah, I did.
♪ And I will bide my time
for you ♪
You were left
in a park, right?
When you were three.
By your junkie dad.
Bar parking lot.
And I was six.
I wish I'd been three.
Then I wouldn't have remembered
that he left me there.
Jo, it's too late
for coffee.
It's hot chocolate.
I am not a kid anymore.
Oh.
I am the chief.
Mmm.
Yeah, that's good.
It's really good.
I love you.
They call it a high
for a reason.
Because the flip side
is really low.
♪ And I thank you
for letting me watch you fall ♪
♪ I thank you
♪ And I will bide my time
for you ♪
♪ And I will bide my time... ♪
Mom?
I'm here.
♪ And I will bide my time
for you ♪
The chemical version
isn't worth what comes after.
♪ And I will bide my time
for you ♪
But the dopamine rush
from a job well done?
That's free.
♪ And I guess I'll let it fly ♪
♪ That you never really
said goodbye ♪
♪ And I will bide my time
for you ♪
♪ And I guess I'll let it fly ♪
♪ That you never really
said goodbye ♪
♪ And I will bide my time
for you ♪
And it's one of the very best
parts of being alive.
Sync corrections by srjanapala