Severe winter weather
advisories have been issued
from Kansas to Western Minnesota.
Severe ice...
Shaun.
There is a severe weather warning
in Minnesota.
You haven't been at work
in three days.
I want to be left alone.
I'm sorry she hurt you.
But you are strong.
You're the most determined man I know.
You're gonna get through this.
I wish I was...
normal.
Everyone wishes
they were normal, Shaun.
You need to get up.
You need to do your exercise routine,
then shower, shave, get to work.
Not because patients need your help,
but because it will make you feel better.
I'm not leaving without you.
Your sleep apnea
is worse than we thought.
You have a condition related
to your pseudoachondroplasia
that is narrowing
the base of your skull
and compressing the part of your brain
that controls your breathing.
People always say I'm too full of myself.
Guess it's actually true.
Finn, this is serious.
Don't worry, I'm gonna be fine.
We can remove bone from your skull
and resect a section of your cerebellum
to reduce brain stem pressure.
You're gonna cut out
a piece of his brain?
It won't affect your intellect,
but it will cause a speech impediment
and some difficulty with balance.
I'd rather you knock a few points
off my IQ.
- Stop it.
- I'm serious.
My gift of gab
is what you love about me.
What's option two?
I'm sorry,
but there is no other option.
I'm a salesman.
I don't hear the word "no."
There's always another way.
You just think outside the box.
We've done that, which is how
we came up with this surgery.
It's the only way to keep you alive,
no choice but to accept it.
Dr. Murphy is being rude and insensitive,
but he's also right.
Finn, please, I love you.
And I will always be here
no matter how you talk or walk.
Listen to your doctors.
I love you too.
Do whatever you think is best.
Let me guess.
I'm gonna need another surgery.
- What's that now, my tenth?
- Eleventh.
And I still can't work the farm,
can't drive a tractor,
pull the combine lever.
I can't even twist open
a bottle of beer.
When we met, you were in an ambulance
and your arms were still
in your harvester.
Today you have sensation
and almost full mobility.
Now we just need to treat
the neuropathy
and improve your strength.
How do we do that?
I'm thinking
a gracilis muscle transfer.
That should improve his grip
and relieve some of the pain,
but there's only one way
to eliminate all of it.
Tyson, have you given any more thought
to amputation
and the osseointegrated
prosthetic arms?
They'd attach directly to the bones
and nerves in your forearm,
and you can control them
like your own hands.
Function would be reduced
in some respects.
Less dexterity, no sensory feedback.
But others, like grip strength,
would be better and you'd be pain free.
I want to be a farmer, not a cyborg.
Okay.
The pain's getting worse.
Probably because I've been crazy busy
in the OR with Murphy out till today.
He's back?
Only because Browne went
to his apartment and dragged his ass in.
She shouldn't have done that.
He's trying to work this out
on his own, that's a good thing.
- The DMARDS aren't working.
- I know.
Which is why I've been thinking
about synovectomy surgery.
You're going to remove
the joint linings in your fingers?
That'll resolve the pain temporarily,
and then what?
It would give me at least 10 years.
Then you're gonna be bone on bone.
Every joint in your hand
will be mangled and deformed.
What's your plan then?
Who knows what treatments
will be available in 10 years?
Have you thought about oncology?
Surgeons do the real work.
They cut out the tumor,
they cure the patient.
Oncologists just sweep up after.
You wanna know an even better job?
Starting pitcher for the Oakland A's.
You wanna know
why I didn't get that job?
Scouts didn't like the way
you wore your hat?
Yeah, that and I was born
with this arm.
You were born with those hands.
What are you gonna do?
Practice surgery for a few more years
and then spend the rest of your life
not being able to pick up a pencil?
You can pursue another specialty,
practice for the rest of your life.
You get rear-ended on the way to work
or you just hate little people?
Neither.
EKG is normal.
So you got dumped.
No, I didn't.
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
We were never even going out.
Finn? I've been worried sick.
Oh.
Take it easy.
I told you to stay home,
there's nothing to worry about.
Stop trying to act so tough.
You shouldn't have
to go through this alone.
Sorry, baby, but you should wait outside.
Let the doctors finish up
and I'll be right out.
He's not going to the OR for a while,
so there will be time to visit
when we're done.
Okay.
I'll be right outside.
Is there any way she and Nathalie
stay in separate waiting rooms
and aren't allowed to visit
at the same time?
No. We're not helping you cheat.
I'm not cheating.
I've always made it clear
I'm not ready to settle down,
but, sometimes,
women make assumptions.
And you don't feel the need
to correct that?
I understand you don't approve,
but all I'm asking is for you
to help me get through brain surgery
without emotional turmoil that I assume
would be harmful to my recovery.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
You seeing the same thing
I'm seeing?
The tendons are encased
in scar tissue.
The gracilis muscle transfer
isn't gonna work.
It still could.
If we attach the muscle further down
the forearm and bypass the scar ball.
It wouldn't hold. There'd be
too much tension on the graft.
We can figure out a way
to work around that.
Wake him up
and put him back in his room,
and pull every paper
on free muscle and nerve transfers.
His only option is double amputation
and osseointegrated prosthetics.
- We don't have a choice.
- Yes, we do.
And as chief of surgery,
I just made it.
He doesn't really look the part.
Ha. He's handsome
with a great sense of humor
and a high-paying job.
He means because women
don't like to be in relationships
- with men who are weird.
- He's not weird, and neither are you.
A week ago you were juggling
two women,
so stop feeling so sorry
for yourself.
Have you ever dated anyone
who wasn't tall,
handsome and neurotypical?
This is not about me.
Talk to me.
He's stopped breathing and I haven't
even administered the paralytics.
What just happened?
Pressure on the medulla
must be getting worse.
He's lucky he didn't wait any longer
to come in.
- Tube him and get to work.
- Wait.
Flex his head
into position again.
Extend his neck.
What's going on?
Flexing the neck offsets
the posterior compression.
That should take the pressure off,
not make it worse.
Doesn't make any sense.
And we're not gonna do
brain surgery on him until it does.
I don't see anything different
in the flexed neck views.
Should his C2 bone be curved inward
like that?
It could exacerbate the narrowing on the
front of his...
It's not significant.
If his apnea's getting worse because
of pressure...
The treatment is the same.
Surgery to create more room
in the skull base.
It's not the same
and stop interrupting me.
If we drill off the C2 in the front
as well as open the back,
we might not have to resect
the cerebellum.
He wouldn't have any speech
impediment or balance issues.
We'd have to approach
through his mouth,
a bacteria-rich environment,
which can't be fully sterilized.
There'd be too high a risk
of a post-op infection.
So we figure out another approach.
There's only one safe way
to access the C2.
Okay, so come up with something
outside the box.
No. That's a stupid expression.
There is no box.
And you are wasting valuable time
just because you want
to be nice to her.
- Murphy...
- We should do the cerebellar surgery
- before he has a fatal apnea...
- Murphy.
I'm not being nice.
I'm using my experience and judgment
to make the call, that's my job.
- You are being nice.
- And you're being a jerk.
You've got the night.
If you two can't come up with
a solution by morning,
we'll proceed with the original plan.
Your patient's in desperate need
of an Oklahoma weather report?
I didn't even want to be here today.
You should try a martial arts class.
Focused distraction is key to dealing
with stress and heartbreaks.
That's just avoiding the problem.
Don't obsess over what you've lost,
focus on what you've gained
from the relationship.
Hate to interrupt group therapy,
but what if we approach
through the side of the neck?
We could transpose
the vertebral artery
and open up the spine laterally
to drill off the C2.
It would leave his spine permanently
unstable and could cause a stroke.
There might be a way
to mitigate stroke risk.
And he'd still have
the instability in his...
Come on, Shaun.
I need help, not criticism.
I've always supported you
trying to come up
with an unconventional option.
You supported me
when you thought I was right.
What do you guys think?
- We gotta go.
- We do?
Remove the scar tissue
and the nerves,
then harvest nerves from his
upper arm to rewire his forearms.
It'll improve his grip,
and with the scar tissue removed,
the pain should decrease too.
It does nothing to solve the blood flow
problem causing the scarring.
I'm sure we can come up
with a solve for that.
- That's what you said last time.
- And I was right. We're making progress.
Would you two give us a moment?
We'll meet you in the Residents'
Lounge when we're done.
Are you so against the prosthetics
because you think it's in Tyson's
best interest or because it's my idea?
You think I care
whose idea anything is?
You're a competitive person
working with the guy who held your job.
I'll admit my competitive drive
may kick up a notch
when we work together.
I'll also admit
that I admire the courage of a guy
who stumbled a half-mile
back to his house
after his arms were ripped off
by a combine.
He opened a door with his mouth
and dialed 911 with his nose,
and as long as he wants to keep fighting,
I'm gonna fight with him,
which has nothing to do with my ego.
Good. That's all I wanted to confirm.
But I'm gonna start prepping
for the amputation
because that's the only
rational choice we have,
which I'm confident
you'll realize soon enough.
Making any progress?
Yeah, I figured out a lateral approach...
but Shaun thinks
it would leave his spine unstable
and increase his risk of stroke.
- I agree.
- Yeah, me too.
- There has to be a way to mitigate...
- Dr. Browne?
These just got delivered.
- Enjoy.
- Thanks.
Dash is a romantic.
I thought you hated romantics.
Yeah, he's teasing me.
I told him I thought guys
who send flowers are lame.
We haven't even kissed yet.
What are you waiting for?
I don't know.
Um, I enjoy being with him.
Actually, I forgot how funny he is.
It just...
hasn't seemed like the right time.
I'm more worried about stroke risk
than spinal instability,
so focus on fixing that.
Okay.
And, Claire, if he's the right guy,
stop holding out for the right time.
Your vitals are stable.
The nurses will monitor you
during the night.
Your problem's simple to solve.
Just ask someone else out.
- Lea was special.
- I'm sure she was.
But there are so many others
just as special.
You just have to get to know them.
- No, I don't want to.
- Yes, you do.
You think I don't know how you feel?
Afraid of being rejected
because you're too different.
Finally I decided "screw it."
I started talking
to every woman I saw.
Street corners, elevators,
grocery stores.
And I learned I'm pretty good at it.
That's my gift.
Everyone has one.
They just have to figure out what it is...
Okay. Code blue!
Code blue!
Murphy and I just inserted
a diaphragmatic pacemaker on Finn.
It'll only trigger shallow breaths,
so he's at high risk for pneumonia.
Got anything?
I was thinking of using
a more inferior transatlas approach.
That would minimize stroke risk.
It won't work.
It would destabilize the C1-2 joint.
You did all you could. Go home.
We'll do the original cerebellar surgery
in the morning.
- So I'll be able to work the farm?
- We still need to increase blood flow.
You should regain most of your grip
and forearm strength.
But you'd still be in some pain.
I can handle it.
Can you? How can you know for sure?
As the years go by
and the pain doesn't stop,
will you change your mind?
Because it'll be too late.
- What's wrong? What are you feeling?
- Like a horse just kicked in my chest.
I need an echo and pulmonary
cath kit! And page Lim, stat!
I think the last time that I was
at an actual punk rock show was, uh...
College?
Patti Smith.
Oh, my God,
I completely forgot about that.
You forgot getting your ass tossed
off-stage by a 60-year-old woman?
- Yeah.
- Remember what you said
- when we picked you up?
- Uh... Oh.
Something about her being thin
but strong?
- "Thin but wiry." Wiry. Ha-ha.
- Wiry!
Okay, well, I, um...
I have an early surgery,
- so I should probably get going.
- Okay.
Okay...
- I had a good night.
- Good night.
I got an idea.
Actually, you had it first.
It was the right approach,
just the wrong route.
We'd go in from the back,
posterior transdural,
gently move your spinal cord
out of the way,
so we can drill off
the misshaped C2.
There is a risk of paralysis,
but we'd be monitoring spinal functions
to help avoid any nerve injuries.
Let's do it. Where do I have to sign?
You shouldn't sign anything.
Consenting to this surgery would be
incredibly short-sighted and reckless.
It is one thing to take your bad mood
out on your colleagues,
but to try and undermine
my surgical advice...
- My opinion's valid.
- Thankfully, he disagrees.
He's risking paralysis
to be charming,
because people expect everyone
to be perfect.
Everyone's opinion is valid
all the way until we go
into the patient room.
We are a team with one opinion.
I...
I don't feel better!
I feel worse!
And doing the wrong surgery
is not going to help anyone.
I don't want to do it,
I'm going home.
You're not walking out
on your patient. Or your team.
I still have two sick days
and 76 hours of unused PTO.
You're not sick,
you're in the middle of a case.
I don't care about the case
or the patient.
I don't care about anything.
I've had my heart broken twice
in the last few years.
You want to know what I did?
I came to work every day
and pretended everything was fine.
Until, eventually,
I wasn't pretending anymore.
That's not helpful at all.
How about this?
Go and help Claire prep Finn
for surgery, or you won't be my resident.
Or anyone else's at St. Bonaventure.
And I know you care about that.
We were able to clear the clot,
but due to the restricted arteries
in your arms,
we're going to need to keep you
on blood thinners, indefinitely.
Okay.
The blood thinners make
the reconstructive surgery impossible.
We have no choice but to amputate.
I'm sorry.
No.
I'm not letting you cut off my arms.
I don't want false limbs.
I don't want to be that guy.
I want to be who I am.
You are the toughest,
most tenacious person I've ever met.
And that is not gonna change
because we replace your hands
with titanium.
It's time to let go.
Okay.
Any way you could draw a skull
with a cobra coming out of its eyes?
Would you settle
for a lame smiley face?
Because that is the only thing
I can draw.
Here's my favorite nurse.
Did you check out that Ethiopian place
I told you about last night?
Actually, I did,
and the kik alicha was delish.
Now if you want
a truly life-changing meal,
you try Lennon's on Sixth.
Is it expensive?
Outrageously. But worth it.
Now, it's all white tablecloths
and candles, so you'll need a date.
How about Dr. Murphy?
You told me yourself
he's a gifted surgeon.
That's pretty high praise.
And he told me you're cute.
- Good luck today.
- Thanks.
I totally teed you up.
All you had to do was take a swing.
I am not interested in her.
If she's not your type,
I'm sure there are plenty of other
cool nurses roaming around here
who can make you feel better
about yourself.
He's miserable because he's had
two relationships blow up.
I don't think jumping
into another one is the answer.
No. No. No!
Finn, you can't exert yourself
like this!
Just take it easy.
I ran into a woman in the cafeteria.
Real nice but seems stressed.
Turns out that her boyfriend
is having spinal surgery too.
Big coincidence, huh?
But get this.
He also has pseudoachondroplasia.
I mean, what are the chances?
Nathalie, don't you dare. Stop!
Just slow down.
You called me the love of your life.
- Aah! Don't say that!
- I do love you.
I don't wanna hear
any more garbage.
Please, you have to listen.
You need to get back to bed
or you'll pass out.
What's up?
What are you doing in here?
Once you get a patient on the table,
there's too much going on
to appreciate what this place is.
Mm, it's nice.
It's perfect.
Time to scrub in.
This will be my last surgery.
Five months ago, I was diagnosed
with rheumatoid arthritis.
I'm not responding to medication.
Why did you do that?
I felt like it.
It didn't change the fact
that he cheated on you.
It won't make your life any better.
You can't control
how you feel about someone...
but you can control
what you do with those feelings.
I ended the relationship on my terms.
More importantly...
it made me feel better.
- A Louisville Slugger to a Porsche?
- It was insane.
I like her.
What is to like?
I don't know. I just do.
A sudden complete loss
of SSEP and MEP signals.
BP and heart rate are tanking.
We injured his cord.
Push high dose steroids and pressors.
Remove that retractor,
to take the pressure off.
That's the last of the vessels
and nerves ligated.
Mayos.
Specimen bag.
We have healthy bone anchor sites.
Same here.
Time to give him functional arms.
Not me. Give it to her.
She's a third-year resident,
a talented one, but...
I'm sure she's read every article
written on osseointegration,
spent countless hours
in the Skills Lab
and could probably do this with one
of her own arms tied behind her back.
- Blindfolded.
- Get to work.
Push another milligram of atropine.
We may have just paralyzed him
trying to avoid a stutter.
We won't know until we wake him up.
- Where's the pressure still coming from?
- Laterally now.
So if we remove the joints
of the C1 and C2 bones,
that should make enough room
to drill off the odontoid.
Replace with screws and rods
to stabilize his spine.
That's...
a good idea.
Yes, it is.
If he's not already paralyzed.
Colleen Brown. Freshman year.
I took her to the roller-skating rink
because I thought
that's what you're supposed to do,
take girls to the roller-skating rink.
I didn't know how to roller skate,
she ended up leaving
with Bobby K's little brother.
Broke me up.
I couldn't go to school for a week.
Convinced my mom that I was sick
for the first three days,
and the last two I spent
in a double feature. All day.
Where's Poppa? and Twelve Chairs.
To this day,
I can quote both films verbatim.
So you think I should have
stayed home two more days?
No, I don't think it would have mattered.
It doesn't make a difference.
And then I made a list of all the things
that annoyed me about her.
The way she chewed gum, the way
she sat in the front row of every class
so that the teacher would call on her
when she raised her hand.
The way she said, "Excuse me,"
instead of just "What?" or "Huh?"
None of it makes any difference.
Then why are you telling me?
Maybe it'll make you feel better to know
that what you're going through,
every other young man in the history
of the world has gone through.
You tried to make it work
with Lea and with Carly
and you're getting beat up,
and that's okay. Join the club.
You're in the mix,
that's a good thing.
I'm proud of you.
You ready?
It's gonna take some getting used to
but they're the same nerves
you used before.
All you have to do is think about
using the arms the way
you normally would.
That's pretty cool.
It's not a beer,
but you've got to start somewhere.
Now pinch your forefinger and thumb
and twist off the cap.
I can't feel a thing.
You'll get used to it. You got this.
Nice.
- You want me to say you were right?
- About the patient, or you?
When you offered me a job,
you said it was to help me
get back on the horse,
but what you really wanted
was a mentor.
Which I'm fine with,
but I think maybe you feel threatened
by that need.
Well, maybe that's true.
But maybe also you enjoy it
a little too much.
Maybe because you're having
a hard time giving up being chief.
Maybe we're both right.
How did it go?
Can you lift your arms for me?
Okay.
I'm gonna push your arm
and I need you to resist.
Good. More.
Stronger. That's great.
- You should make a full recovery.
- Thank you.
How's Nathalie's hand?
There was no nerve or tendon damage.
She'll be fine.
She's a good person.
A little spirited,
but that's what I loved about her.
Are you going to try to win her back?
I'm confident, but not stupid.
Gotta know
when to call it, Dr. Murphy.
There's a whole world
of amazing people out there.
Don't get bogged down
with this notion of a soulmate.
Finn's exam was normal.
But I am not sure
it was worth the risk.
We did a good thing today.
Mostly because of you.
That's kind of you to say.
Your commitment to your patients...
reminds me of why
I got into medicine.
Being around you makes me
a better surgeon.
A better person.
- Well, good night.
- Night.
You did good work today.
And I understand
you're leaving surgery.
And I know that's tough,
but it's the right call.
No, I don't think it is.
I love operating, so I'm gonna keep
doing it as long as I can.
I'm gonna have
the synovectomy surgery.
That's really stupid.
That's incredibly stupid.
Not every dream comes true.
You have other opportunities,
you have another chance.
Not everybody does,
be grateful for that.
Pick another passion and pursue that.
I'm doing the surgery.
Enjoy.
Another, please.
That's one way
to start the night off right.
Hello, Nurse Fletch.
You can call me Julie.
Here alone
or are you meeting someone?
- I'm alone.
- Mm. To us.
You have beautiful eyes.
Thank you.
Or did someone just tell you that
that's a good opening line?
It's right in our backyard
and I've never even been there.
- Have you?
- No.
It's time we unleash
our inner tree hugger.
You're off next weekend,
I think we should go to Yosemite.
- What do you think?
- Yeah, sounds fun.
- I'm gonna get some hiking boots.
- Mm.
- And like a fleece, a beanie...
- Oh. Mm.
I'm rocking the full lumbersexual look.
Because I gotta blend in.
I hear a bear can spot a tourist
a mile away.
- Mm.
- Mm-hm.
You okay?
You're here but, you know, not.
You're right. I'm sorry.
It's just been a long week.
I'm a bit exhausted.
I think I might call it
an early night.
Oh, you sure?
I mean, we don't have to go to the club.
- We can chill here. Watch a movie.
- I'm sorry, I just...
I just think I should go home.
Okay.
Shaun?
I want to smash your car up.
I think that's a bad idea.
I want to hurt you...
the way you hurt me.
- I'm sorry...
- You...
You...
You're...
I can't.
You acted like you cared about me...
but you don't even respect me.
You're flaky.
And...
And you can't keep a boyfriend.
And you can't keep a job.
And no one likes you.
And you're going to
end up alone and you deserve it!
Because you're a superficial,
selfish and prejudiced person!
Ready to tell me
what's on your mind?
Not really.
I think I'm in love with my boss.