Costs us about $2,200
per bed a day just to
keep Chastain open.
Now, that's roughly
$160 million a year.
Have-have you ever experienced
the Serengeti, Randolph?
No, Gordon, but
much more rewarding
than waiting for
the rains in Africa
might be to help
us make it rain here.
Mm-hmm, like funding
your new surgical center?
Well, in order to keep
brilliant, young surgeons
like Dr. Okafor here
happy, we need the...
Is that why you were invited
here tonight, Dr. Okafor?
To, um, help persuade us?
I was invited because I'm black.
Apparently diversity matters.
Ah, look at poor Mina.
I wish we could
throw her a lifeline.
Why don't you go down
there? Help her out?
I'll go if you go.
I'd rather have a colonoscopy.
They're in my ear. Can
you... Can you get them out?
All right, let's
get back to work.
Wait.
Please.
It hurts.
Can you get them
out? It hurts. Please?
Too loud.
They're-they're in my ear.
Please, can you
help me get them out?
Oh, is that right?
Yes, that's... Yeah.
They're in my
head. Get them out.
Excuse me.
They're in my ear. Get 'em out.
- Excuse me.
- Call for help.
How did she get in here?
She's got a pulse,
it's very slow.
Pupils are equal and reactive.
Scattered rhonchi, but
she's moving good air.
Okay, everybody, just
step back, step back, please.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Let's just give these
doctors some room to work.
I need a C-collar
and backboard now.
Okay, well, let's get this-this
poor soul to our ER, and, uh,
just keep me posted
on how she's doing.
It's okay.
She'll be all right.
♪ ♪
They're in here.
- All right, let's get you checked out.
- They're in here.
- What's your name?
- Are you having pain anywhere?
Too loud.
In my head, get
them out. My ear...
Get them out.
Here, I'll take the bags.
- No.
- Ready.
One... two... three.
When I asked you to bring me
something from the fundraiser,
I meant, like, a crab cake.
- What do we got?
- Jane Doe, 20s.
Collapsed from syncopal episode
with blunt head trauma,
multiple abrasions,
and a forehead laceration.
- Plus one hell of an ear infection.
- Not seeing an I.D.
She needs an altered
mental status workup
- and a lac repair.
- Trauma panel, EKG,
- chest X-ray and head CT.
- I'll take care of the lac.
And risk getting blood on
that dress? I'll do the sutures.
It's not that, I-I can't see!
No, I can handle the pain,
I just, I can't see
out of this eye.
Keep working
here. I'll grab that.
- Talk to me.
- Channing Brewster, 25-year-old male.
Ran through a glass
door. Facial lacerations,
multiple small cuts
to his arms and torso,
shards of glass in his left eye.
Two episodes of
vomiting en route.
- I can't see out of this eye.
- Okay, easy, Mr. Brewster.
I'm Dr. Feldman, I'll
be taking care of you.
I just want to take a
look at your eye, okay?
- Okay.
- Everything's gonna be okay.
Let's transfer him
and prepare to irrigate.
Micah, hey. Sorry we had to
change your echo to tonight.
It's been crazy around here.
Yeah, I noticed. I was
rerouted from the front entrance.
How's the new ticker?
That's what I'm
here to find out.
Admit him to the floor
on antibiotics and we'll
take him to the OR tomorrow.
Mm-hmm. Right away.
Wow, Dr. Okafor, I almost
didn't recognize you
all supermodeled up.
In for your 1,000-mile checkup?
A patient who
actually follows up.
Yeah.
I will leave you two to it.
I hear your heart donor's
family wants to meet you.
They reached out through
the recovery program.
Just not sure I'm
ready for that yet.
So don't meet them.
It's your heart now.
No, actually, we'd like to
keep the guest list to 150.
Nonsense.
So few? That would
barely cover my cousins.
Well, it's important
to us that we pay
for half the wedding,
- so we need to stick to our number.
- Yes.
But the groom's family
can also contribute,
- not just the bride's.
- Of course.
We can pay for more than
just flowers and the mithai.
It's okay.
Like I said, we got it covered.
Besides, we want to
keep it small and intimate.
Let's talk about something else.
So, uh, Priya, your father
is a barrister in London, yes?
That's right.
How does he feel
about you marrying
the son of a taxi driver?
- Tejan.
- My parents are very fond
of your son, Mr. Pravesh.
They don't discuss things
like this in their family.
Well, judgments
get passed in silence.
Your occupation
has never come up.
And it is my decision who
I marry, not my father's.
Uh...
- And the check, sir.
- I have to get back.
Do you have to leave now?
The hospital is short-staffed
and they need me.
No more questions,
Dad, and... We got it.
Let me.
We discussed this.
It's okay.
Her head CT and drug and
alcohol screen came back normal.
Thinking she's altered from
an underlying psych disorder.
We need a medical
reason to admit her.
She does have an area
of pneumonia on her X-ray.
Plus the ear infection,
but, technically,
we should just discharge
her on oral antibiotics for that.
- Yeah, no, we can't do that. That's not right.
- Yeah, I know.
Well, admitting her,
I'm just trying to...
I remember her saying
she felt severe chest pain
before she collapsed, don't you?
That'll buy her an admission.
I mean, I'm not sure it's
gonna fly with admin, but...
Yeah, too bad.
We're out of options.
These drops will sting
for a few seconds but
then numb the pain.
- Okay.
- Look down.
Ow.
- Blink. Good.
- Yeah. Thanks.
We'll try irrigating,
and if this doesn't work,
then we'll pull those little
suckers one at a time.
Look down.
Wh-What about the face?
I mean, is it gnarly?
Do I need stitches?
That's a no to the
gnarly and the stitches.
You got lucky.
How in the world did you
run through a glass door?
Occupational hazard.
I was trying to get away
from my client's husband.
Oh, yeah? You, like, a
private eye? Divorce lawyer?
No. Although, in
my line of work,
I definitely run into both.
Uh...
I'm in the, um,
service business.
Oh. Oh!
You're a gigolo?
Well, we prefer "male escort."
Huh.
Pretty. So pretty.
The painting.
Yeah, it is pretty.
Here.
Were you at another hospital?
Huh?
Did you come from
another hospital?
I'm gonna get you something
to eat. I'll be back, all right?
I think our Jane Doe was
dropped off by another hospital.
Hospitals dumping
homeless patients
not only pisses
me off, it's illegal.
We sure she didn't
elope on her own?
It's not likely.
I know exactly what hospital
this EKG lead comes from.
They've done it before, Conrad.
A little overdressed for work.
I was at dinner.
I'd say I'm sorry for
interrupting date night,
but I'd be lying.
It wasn't a date
as much as it was
an interrogation by my father.
You got me confused
with someone who cares.
I need you to head down to
the ER. Irving's short-handed.
Needs help with the gigolo.
Wait.
Did you say "gigolo"?
It's really about
the little details.
Personal touches in
every patient's room.
Personal menus.
We also keep a
full-on staff of nurses,
make sure everyone
has that one-on-one feeling...
Why was this woman admitted?
Just following through on
your promise to the donors
that we'd get her the
best care in the city.
Excuse me. I'll be right back.
Randolph, is
everything all right?
Yup. Everything's fine.
Be with you in one second.
We don't know what's
wrong with our Jane Doe.
We had to admit
her to run more tests.
And before you ask,
she tested negative
for any drugs or alcohol.
Okay, wouldn't she be more
comfortable in the psych ward
on an involuntary hold?
Trent from Psych
already examined her.
He doesn't think
she's mentally ill.
That's why we're
doing more tests.
We're not running
a charity here.
Well, you're the
Chief of Surgery.
You know it's not your call.
I'm the highest-ranking
member of the board
currently on the premises.
And it sure as hell
isn't a resident's call.
Treat her for the bare
minimum and street her.
That makes us no better
than Atlanta General.
Atlanta General?
This lead goes with a new
all-digital EKG machine
from Cardiosure.
Atlanta General has
the only one in town.
I've been trying to get
one here for months.
Yeah, but, Nic, we got that
fancy cappuccino machine
- up in the VIP wing.
- Just call Atlanta General
and tell them to come
and pick up their problem.
Yeah, I'll get right on that.
Well, you know, I just, I
forget who I'm talking to.
I'll do it.
How are you gonna get
Atlanta General to do anything?
No, it's simple.
We just call them,
tell them to come pick
up their responsibility,
unless they want to be the
lead story on the 10:00 news.
"Atlanta General unwilling
to treat homeless patients,
- now dumps them on Chastain's door."
- All right.
They're just going to dump
her on the street again.
- Uh, the one-on-one...
- We can't let that happen.
Very important to us that
patients feel comfortable.
Nice, nicely done.
Sorry, it wasn't my
idea to call you back.
It was Conrad's.
It's okay, he did me a favor.
Not that Priya was thrilled.
Your parents and your
fiancée don't get along?
No, no, no. Priya loves them.
It's just my old man
who's got the issues.
He gets all squirrely and weird
when it comes to
his money and pride.
Has a lot to do with how
he was brought up in India.
Great. So, how's the pain?
It's, uh, great.
As in, I don't feel any.
It sounds like your dad's all
caught up in the caste system.
Is your fiancée in
a different caste?
Is that the-the problem?
What do you know about
the Indian caste system?
It's a paradigmatic,
ethnographic
social stratification
that determines the behavior
of one member of
society over another.
I was an International
Studies major. Yeah.
I took a special interest
in Southeast Asia.
The whole caste
system thing, it's archaic.
So, uh, the whole,
uh, male escort thing,
is that to pay off
student loans?
I don't carry student loans.
Job pays well.
I mean, that could change if I
end up looking like Leatherface.
Nah. Battle wounds.
Gives you character.
Mm, the news is good, Micah.
No sign of rejection,
your EF's up to 54%.
The valves are functioning well,
limited view of the aortic
root from shadowing,
but, overall,
everything looks good.
I knew that. Wasn't
worried at all.
Oh, you're laughing.
That's always a good sign.
We're all done here, Micah.
I'm going to leave you in
Nurse Nevin's capable hands.
- See you next month.
- All right.
- Thanks.
- Mm-hmm.
That has to be a huge relief.
Let's get you out of here.
You know, actually,
my surgical scar's
been a little irritated.
I'm worried it's not
healing properly.
Oh. Looks okay, but
better safe than sorry,
- I'll see if Dr. Peterson can come back.
- It's okay.
Can Dr. Okafor check it out?
I mean, since she's here
and she was on
my surgical team...
I got to go, but I'll
see if she's available.
Okay.
- What happened?
- Found her hypotensive
and coughing up large
clots. Sats are dropping.
I think it's her lungs.
We need pulmonary.
Page Dr. Hoffman.
And activate massive transfusion
protocol with the blood bank.
Paging Dr. Hoffman.
Dr. Hoffman's in the
middle of an ER bronch.
It says he'll be here
in 15 to 20 minutes.
She'll drown in her
own blood in ten.
Then I'll intubate her myself.
Infiltrate's on the left,
that's probably what's
causing the bleeding.
Hurry, her sats are dropping.
Airway's filled with blood.
I need to intubate
just the right lung.
Sats are down to 74%.
Okay, through the cords.
Rotating 90 degrees.
Hoping I can block the
bleeding from the left
and still ventilate her.
No breath sounds on the left.
Blow up the balloon.
Sats are coming back up.
This is just a Band-Aid.
Page Mina.
She needs a
bronchoscopy right away.
Paging Dr. Okafor.
Bleeding has stopped.
The cautery worked.
Let me get a tissue sample
for biopsy while I'm here.
So, this is where the lesion
eroded the bronchus,
causing her to hemorrhage?
Doesn't look like pneumonia.
It can be any number of things,
including cancer.
Got the sample.
We need to start narrowing
down the differential.
Get her to imaging for a CT
and send the
biopsy off to the lab.
That's expensive.
Since when do you care
about the cost of tests?
Not tests. This bag.
This is an Xavier
Mellino original.
It's worth $148,000.
What... How do you know that?
I know stitching. Probably
found it in a Dumpster
or snatched it from the owner.
Nic already looked
for an I.D. in there.
One-of-a-kinds like this
usually have the owner's name
inscribed on the inside.
Sara Ravenscroft.
Her name even sounds rich.
I'm sure she'll be happy to hear
that we found her
$100 grand purse.
Maybe there's a reward.
Maybe.
Or maybe...
our Jane Doe is
Sara Ravenscroft.
She's the daughter
of Lawrence and
Veronica Ravenscroft.
They're wealthy
philanthropists out of Savannah.
How does the daughter
of one of the most
prominent families in Georgia
end up sick and
living on the street?
According to one of the
Savannah gossip blogs,
Sara is estranged
from her family.
She left town a couple
months ago to become an artist.
Is she out of imaging yet?
Was just about to check.
You get that, I'll
check on Sara.
- Mina, you've got something else to deal with.
- What?
Pressing surgery?
A certain lovesick transplantee
has something
wrong with his scar.
This is a waste of my time.
You know his scar is fine.
Mina, you know Micah
has feelings for you.
If you want them to go away,
you've got to deal with them.
Be gentle.
The poor guy just
got a brand-new heart.
I'm always gentle.
A little swelling is normal.
I'll prescribe some
vitamin E ointment
to help with the healing.
I wasn't really
worried about my scar.
I was too embarrassed
to tell anyone
- what I actually wanted to discuss.
- Look, Micah...
It's-it's my heart donor.
Turns out he was a convicted
car thief who was
let out on parole.
- You have a felon's heart?
- Ironic, right?
Me, a minister's son.
Anyway, I went online, right?
And there's this thing
called cellular memory,
where the person who
receives a donor organ
sometimes takes on the
characteristics of the donor.
You know, like their
taste in music and food...
No, I'm serious. Look,
what if I develop a taste
for aggravated assault
or armed robbery?
Okay, calm down, Idi Amin.
I'm sure there are studies
from reputable medical journals
to dispute this nonsense.
I will look into it and get
back to you tomorrow.
Why not tonight? I'm stressed.
- That could be bad for my health.
- My shift is...
I can wait until you're done.
Maybe we can discuss
it over a cup of coffee.
Fine.
One cup, black, to go.
So how long till I can
see out of this eye?
Depends on how quickly
the swelling goes down,
but I'm optimistic.
The injuries seem superficial.
I've paged an ophthalmologist
to take a second look.
And once he gives you
the okay, you can go.
Hmm.
Uh, so your fiancée, is
she Kshatriya or Vaishya?
She's, um, she's Kshatriya.
And, uh, your parents,
they-they immigrated here, right?
Uh, what's your dad do?
He owns a medallion cab
in Queens, and I'm done
- talking about this.
- So you are the successful son
of an honest,
working-class family.
I'm guessing your
family is Vaishya.
As a gigolo, shouldn't you
be a man of action, not words?
Okay. First, male escort.
Second, m-most of my
clients just want to talk.
Look here.
So your fiancée's
in the higher caste,
which probably makes
your dad feel insecure.
Or is it her family
that has issues?
Our families haven't even met.
You're not gonna wait for them
to meet at the wedding, are you?
Ah.
You got to be kidding me.
What are you guys doing here?
Where's-where's Priya?
She dropped us at the hotel.
Our flight leaves early
tomorrow morning.
We were worried that we wouldn't
get a chance to say good-bye.
We barely got to
see you this trip,
so we took a cab over here.
Pleasant driver
from Belize. Nice car.
Little too chatty.
We know you're
busy, we'll just sit.
And whenever you get a coffee
break, you just come and visit.
Is there a gift shop?
Maybe I'll get a book.
The gift shop is
closed and we don't,
we don't have coffee breaks.
Honey, we haven't
seen you in months.
Just watching you
work makes me happy.
You can't watch me work, Mom.
There are rules
about these things.
We'll grab a bite
and wait, then.
The cafe is closed, Dad.
The gift shop is closed.
Everything is closed
but the saving-lives part
of this building, okay?
You should have called first.
Do you not want us to be here?
Do you not want us
meeting your colleagues?
What? No. Okay,
that-that's ridiculous.
Look, I'm sorry. Okay?
You can stay. There's a-a
nice waiting area upstairs
and I will drop by when I can.
But right now I have to go.
I have patients that need me.
All right?
He's under a lot of pressure.
Excuse me.
Where did you get that?
Uh, on the buffet tables.
Oh, my God, you
have to turn that off.
You're making me so nervous.
Hi. Hi. Um, wow.
Uh, I can't believe that
you guys are all here
to see this dream come true.
Painting has been a passion
of mine since I was a child.
So, thank you.
To all of you, to the
Thackery Gallery and, uh,
especially to my parents.
Okay, uh, sorry. That
is enough out of me.
I'm so nervous, I might
actually run the risk
of talking all night.
So, enjoy the show.
Which we know
will be the first of many.
Thank you, Dad. Thank you.
Thank you, Dad. Enjoy the show.
Hello?
Hi, um, my name's,
uh, Nic Nevin.
I'm calling from Chastain Park
Memorial Hospital in Atlanta.
Uh, your daughter, Sara,
is being treated here.
Is she all right?
Well, she's safe, but
I'm-I'm afraid she's quite ill,
- which is why I'm calling.
- Yes...
Uh, I know. She has...
paranoid schizophrenia.
She refused to
take her medication,
and we told her if she was
going to live in this house,
she would have to.
That was the last
time we saw her.
Mrs. Ravenscroft...
I-I assume you're putting
her on a psychiatric hold.
Um, we'll cover
all of her expenses.
Maybe you will have more luck
getting her on anti-psychotics.
Mrs. Ravenscroft, the
doctors don't believe
that she's mentally ill.
Forgive me if I
can't take the word
of some random ER
over the diagnosis of a
world-renowned psychiatrist
that examined her.
Maybe if you just, if you
just came to see Sara.
She's scared and alone.
I-I really think
it would help if...
She's schizophrenic.
She needs to accept it.
Please don't fill her head
with a lot of false hope.
Just give her the
meds that she needs.
Thank you.
- You guys reach her parents?
- Yeah, they're not coming.
Her mom's convinced
Sara's schizophrenic.
We need to figure out
what the real diagnosis is.
Well, that's not gonna happen.
She's getting sent
back to Atlanta General.
They'll just treat her for a
pneumonia she doesn't have,
load her up with olanzapine
and turf her again.
Or worse, banish her
to their psych ward.
Where you going?
- This place feels pricey.
- Mm-hmm.
- Champagne, Dr. Hawkins?
- No, thank you.
Dr. Hawkins, could it be?
H-Himaya, this is
Dr. Conrad Hawkins.
The mentor. So nice to meet you.
I didn't catch a name.
Oh. I'm Tejan,
and this is Himaya.
We're Devon's parents.
Right, yes, you're
in town. Oh, wow.
It's... It's so
nice to meet you.
So nice to meet you, too.
- Thank you for everything you've done for our son.
- Yes.
You should be very
proud of him. Excuse me,
- I have to talk to someone.
- Of course.
- He's so nice.
- Very nice.
Who are they?
Uh, I think I heard
telecom billionaire. I just..
- Oh.
- Yeah.
I have some news.
We just admitted a
VIP, Sara Ravenscroft.
Of the Savannah Ravenscrofts?
The very wealthy
and philanthropic
Savannah Ravenscrofts. Correct.
You put her on the
16th floor, I hope.
That's a good idea. I
should... I'm, I just...
I had her flying coach,
but let's upgrade her
to the VIP wing immediately.
Okay, well, I should go see her.
Well, you've already met her.
She was here at
the fundraiser earlier.
Five-seven, blonde
hair, dark roots.
Carrying a $100,000
Xavier Mellino bag.
I'm not gonna lie, she
could use a shower.
Sara Ravenscroft is...
Well, get her up
on the 16th floor,
and I'll be up
there in a minute.
Sure. But you have to deal
with Atlanta General first.
You did call them to come
get their Jane Doe, right?
Yeah.
I appreciate the call, Randolph.
Listen, I am sorry
about the Jane Doe.
Apparently, she ran off when
personnel just wasn't looking.
Right. And walked three
miles to the closest hospital
despite a severely
compromised sense of direction.
Denying someone proper
treatment when they present
with a clear emergency
medical condition
is a violation of
federal law, Gavin.
Listen.
If one of our people turfed
a homeless patient
to your hospital,
they will be terminated.
Look, the only reason
you're here is because
we threatened to tell the media
Atlanta General
dumps its undesirables.
You're lucky we
didn't call the cops.
Randolph, if you came to
us with the same problem,
we would handle
it with discretion.
Well, unlike your hospital,
we treat everyone who
walks through these doors.
So, what's really at play here?
At play?
You played us, Gavin.
We're done here. You won.
Listen, I promise you, they're
gonna have you back up
dancing the salsa with, um,
what's your
boyfriend's name again?
Joe, but he doesn't dance much.
Oh, I'm telling you right now.
You could teach him
how to dance, right?
How did you get
here from your bed?
Oh, the nurse was nice
enough to help me out.
You see, Mrs. Reed's a little
nervous about
her fractured ankle,
so I'm just keeping her company
till the doctors come back.
- I am better.
- Mm-hmm.
- Thank you. Carry on.
- Mm.
What's up?
- He's working the room pro bono.
- Hey,
you guys save lives,
I save people from loneliness.
It's like my superpower.
Are you all right? Your
voice sounds different.
And his breathing.
My chest feels tight.
Having a hard time breathing.
- Palpable air under the skin.
- Subcutaneous emphysema.
Do you think he
swallowed some glass?
- What's going on?
- Get up. Let's get you up.
Your vomiting en route may
have been forceful enough
to cause an
esophageal perforation.
Air is leaking into your chest.
We need a STAT CT chest,
esophagram, and call the OR.
So, if it's not mental illness
and it's not drugs, what is it?
No definitive answer yet.
How did Sara Ravenscroft
end up like this?
Well, this is her chest CT.
Multiple lesions.
They're too small
to have shown up
on previous X-rays.
Wow, the disease is extensive.
It could be TB, it
could be cancer.
I'm just waiting on
her biopsy results.
Okay, well, I'll call the lab,
see if I can get
them to speed it up.
Thank you.
Let's just wait and see.
Uh, we got a problem.
They've come to take Sara.
- I took care of Atlanta General.
- No, not Atlanta General.
Her parents are here, with
their doctor and their private jet.
Look, we can't
let them take her.
Sara is their daughter.
And since she can't
speak for herself,
they get to decide her course of
treatment and where she has it.
Okay, but they
want to medicate her
and put her in a
psychiatric facility.
That is not what
is best for Sara.
What if you're both wrong?
What if her respiratory
issues and her mental health
are unrelated, and what
if she is schizophrenic?
What if we're right and her
two issues are connected?
All I'm asking for is
a little bit more time.
If we can really figure
out what's wrong with Sara
and cure her,
think about how much
more financially grateful
the Ravenscrofts will be
to Chastain and to you.
Okay.
Okay. I can buy you, I
don't know, maybe an hour.
But the minute they demand it,
I have to discharge her.
Forgive me for the delay.
Um, please take a seat.
We're fine, thank you.
When can we see her, Doctor?
Well, i-in addition to
her mental disorientation,
your daughter had
bleeding in her lungs.
And we've identified the lesion,
which we're
cauterizing as we speak.
So it shouldn't be
too much longer.
The bleeding in her
lungs, is it serious?
For someone her age,
it's probably from a
bronchitis or pneumonia.
Soon as she's back in
Savannah, I'll have a pulmonologist
assess her while we treat her
for the schizophrenia
concurrently.
We will need copies
of all of her records
- and tests from tonight.
- Yeah, of course.
Now, are you...
are you confident
with the schizophrenia
diagnosis?
We've had her diagnosed
by the best in the field.
Would you object to sharing
that physician's name with me?
Do you have any
idea what it's like
to watch the child that
you love just fade away
piece by piece, Dr. Bell?
We're supposed to
protect our children.
It almost killed me that I
couldn't protect her from this.
But now Sara can't
speak for herself.
So we finally have
the legal power
to do something
about her condition.
We've waited a long time
to get her mental
disorder treated.
I'm in no mood
for further delays.
You know, I did some research
- on cellular memory and transplants.
- Uh-huh.
As it turns out, there
is a reason for you
to be concerned
about your heart donor.
I found some studies out
of Singapore showing that
the human heart can
actually store memory
through combinatorial
coding of nerve cells.
- Seriously?
- Mm-hmm.
There was one case, uh,
where an engineer in Iowa
received a murderer's heart
and stabbed his buddy in the head
with an ice pick.
Wait, wait a minute.
Are you sure?
Yeah. In another case, a
God-fearing high school teacher
from Conyers, Georgia
received the heart of a car thief
and suddenly fabricated
medical symptoms
just to get his doctor
to go out with him.
One can only wonder
what perverted intentions
he had in mind.
- So I wanted to go out with you.
- You lied.
Yes, but my brain wanted
to do the right thing.
My criminal heart held
it hostage. I'm sorry.
I like you. All right?
I know you're a good man.
But I don't date patients.
My career is my focus.
Anything else is an
unnecessary distraction.
What you want, I can't give.
I don't believe that.
Believe it.
And if you try to
prove otherwise,
I will guarantee you one thing.
I will break your
brand-new heart.
Oh, I'll risk it. Turns
out they're replaceable.
Good night, Micah.
- Oh, you're weakening.
- I'm not.
Yes, you are. Yes,
you are... Hey, wait.
Hey, oh. My heart
just skipped a beat.
It just skipped another one.
Come on, you're killing me.
You can't just leave me here.
- Any progress?
- I'm missing a puzzle piece.
I just don't know what it is.
What if we can't
diagnose her in time?
Then we go to plan B.
Try to get through to Sara.
Get her lucid enough to make
her own medical decisions.
Sara?
Sara.
Hey. Hey, I brought
you something.
These are tidal
marshes. You painted this.
It has your name right there.
You're very talented, Sara.
Nic has a great eye.
If it weren't for her,
I'd still have Bruce Lee
posters on my walls.
Look, there's this one, too.
See?
Sara?
Blood pressure's dropping.
Give her a 500cc bolus.
There's blood in her urine.
Disorientation, ear infection,
pulmonary bleeding...
Lung lesions, hematuria...
Any skin lesions?
Hey.
I'll call the lab.
How will we know if we're right?
You'll see it in the blood.
Reminder, I'm a
nurse practitioner,
not a histopathologist.
You don't have to be.
You'll see.
Chris, can you put it up?
- Wow.
- See the staining pattern of the granular white cells?
Anti-neutrophil
cytoplasmic antibodies.
Sara has Wegener's.
I've-I've read about it,
I've just never seen it.
The disease attacks blood
vessels in multiple organs.
I've never seen it attack
blood vessels in a brain,
but it makes sense.
It explains the psychosis.
What?
Schizophrenia is not
curable, but this is.
I mean, that's news
any family would pray for.
- We can treat her.
- If she hasn't been discharged.
Sara has a very rare
autoimmune disease
called Wegener's.
It's what caused the bleeding
in her lungs and kidneys.
Which also, likely,
caused her erratic behavior,
making her seem
mentally ill when she wasn't.
You understand how we still
find this news hard to believe.
The biopsy results
confirm the diagnosis, Lawrence.
The doctors are right.
She isn't schizophrenic.
Look, given the lack of research
on Wegener's affecting
the brain this way,
you know, I'm not surprised
Sara was misdiagnosed
at that early stage.
She's being treated
with medication
to stop the body
from attacking itself,
but it may take hours
- before we see any change.
- Dear God.
We almost had her committed.
She could have died.
What if she never forgives us?
The surgery was successful.
Your face is gonna be fine.
It'll heal without a scar.
You seem stressed.
Your parents.
Are they still here?
- It's that obvious, huh?
- Yeah.
Hey, you know what I think?
No, and I know that's not
gonna stop you from telling me.
I think your father's
not the only one
with money and pride issues.
I think it's you, too. Yeah.
I think that you're
anxious that your in-laws
won't think your
family measures up.
- Excuse me?
- Hey, bro, listen, I get it, man, I get it.
I'm-I'm the kid of
immigrants, too, all right?
I-I know how it feels to... to be
embarrassed by your parents.
God...
When I was in high school,
I would just get so frustrated,
you know, they couldn't grasp
- simple Western mores.
- Yeah.
You got it worse than me;
your dad's just a cab driver, so...
Dude, you have no
idea about my dad.
Folks hear the accent
and assume that
he's beneath them.
They have no idea that he
is a self-made entrepreneur.
That he speaks three languages.
Not to mention the courage
and the confidence it took him
to uproot his family and start
all over in another country.
Hey. I don't
think I could do it.
Your parents?
They sound great.
Yeah.
Yeah, they are.
- Okay, get some rest.
- Yeah.
And, uh, for the record, you're
not so bad at talking to people.
You ever consider a
career in psychotherapy?
No, no, no. Too pretty.
You know, but if the
looks fade, maybe.
- Channing.
- Ha.
Ready to get back to work?
I got to go check on my parents.
Is your tuxedo pressed?
Don't tell me they're
at the fundraiser.
Okay. I won't.
But Conrad says they are.
I have to say,
your sari is stunning
and such a breath of fresh air.
This traditional Indian
dress is really very simple.
An untailored length of cloth.
And yet so elegant.
Traditionally, the sari was seen
as a sign of purity,
because cloth, when cut
and pierced with
needles, was impure.
- Fascinating.
- Mm.
You know, I love to travel.
I'll have to put India
on my bucket list.
Uh, I wanted to
thank you personally
for your support of Chastain.
Perhaps I could give you a tour,
let you see where your generous
donation gets put to good work.
- Donation?
- Dr. Hunter,
I'm sorry for the confusion.
- These are my... parents.
- I'm Tejan Pravesh,
and this is my wife Himaya.
- Oh.
- Devon is our son.
Oh, s... I'm so sorry.
I was told that you were
in the telecom business.
I-I'm in... transportation.
My father owns his own cab.
He put me through medical school
working seven days a
week, very long hours,
and I'm very proud of him.
You know, I-I don't have
any children of my own,
but if I did, I would hope
they'd be as proud of me
as Devon is of you.
Really, such a pleasure
to meet you both.
- If you'll excuse me.
- Of course.
I-I'm sorry we couldn't
spend more time together,
but we had a lovely evening.
I hope we weren't
too much in the way.
No, I... I owe you
both an apology.
I was...
I was very dismissive of you
and your feelings at dinner.
No... I was wrong to
ask about Priya's parents.
No, you weren't.
They've wanted to come visit,
and I've been pushing back.
I was...
I was worried about...
I was worried that
they were gonna take
creative control of the wedding.
But it's more than
that; I just didn't know
if you all were gonna get along.
But I think it's important
that we all meet,
and we-we... we honor
family traditions on both sides.
We would like that very much.
Yeah?
- Hmm?
- Good.
♪ It's a ritual... ♪
Dad?
Veronica.
♪ It's a ritual... ♪
Mom?
Sara.
- Baby.
- Honey?
Oh, darling...
- No. No.
- It's okay.
- It's okay. -No.
- No, no. Shh...
- I'm not going.
- No, stop. No, please, stop.
Get away from me!
- Help me, please! I'm not going.
- Sara!
- Sara.
- I'm not going.
- Sara?
- Get away from me.
Sara, it's okay,
I'm Nurse Nevin.
Look at me. You're
fine, you're safe.
They want to put me
away, they think I'm crazy.
No one's gonna
put you away, Sara,
- because you're not mentally ill.
- You hear that?
You're not crazy.
- Huh?
- You have an autoimmune disease
that's been untreated
for a long time.
And the medicine that
they're giving you now,
it's reversing the disease.
You were right, Sara.
We were wrong.
I'm really gonna be okay?
Yes.
♪ It's a ritual... ♪
Oh, honey.
We are so sorry.
We're so very sorry.
It's okay, Mom.
Uh, N-Nurse Nevin?
Um, Doctor?
Thank you both.
I, uh...
Thank you.
Well, we're just happy
you're all together again.
And I better get an invite
to your next opening.
I'll do better than that.
I'll paint something
just for you.
I'd love that.
♪ It's a ritual ♪
♪ It's a ritual... ♪
♪ ♪
Maybe now isn't a good time
to ask them to open
their checkbook.
It's not always about the money.
I'll wait a few days.
A few days?
He'll be back before lunch.
♪ It's a ritual. ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH