Meredith: Every time
a surgeon operates,
it's for the first
time all over again.
Ohh! Wha... What
are you doing?!
Huh? I'm hiding from James.
I just saw his car pull up.
I thought you liked him.
I did. We had sex.
Oh. Twice.
And then I find his
wedding album. To Ryan.
I had sex with Ryan's husband.
- How did I miss this?
- This is not a problem.
He is a man of God who cheats.
I'm pregnant with twins.
Hey. I... I can see you!
Can we talk?
- Whoa!
- Brought you tea!
Oh. I can't hear you!
Ask him if it's caffeinated.
Fine. I'll get
coffee from the cart.
Look, I know this is a lot,
but we'll figure it out.
We're gonna get a night nurse.
My mom can move in for a while.
- Where are we going?
- The other entrance.
Even if you've done hundreds
of kidney resections
or heart transplants,
you've never
resected this kidney
or transplanted this heart.
Past experience usually helps,
but for unique cases,
you fake it first.
No. Sorry.
Then who are those for?
Me. I'm going to put
them in the fridge.
I don't have time
to come back here.
Hope you made time for an EKG
after consuming 400
milligrams of caffeine.
I have taken two of
Yasuda's shifts this week.
Same. She and her sister
really appreciate it.
Well, not enough to share her
mom's cookies she sent her.
I'm just glad that Chloe
seems to be recovering well.
Woman: Excuse me. Have
you registered to vote?
- Already registered.
- Yeah, me too.
Same. Not my thing.
You rehearse on replicas
for hours on end,
and hopefully when the real
patient is on the table,
you know what you're doing.
Lots of people put
sex on the calendar.
Marsha: When you're
juggling two busy schedules,
it's perfectly normal
to schedule intimacy.
Okay. You schedule a haircut.
I do not want to have to
schedule sex with my wife.
Why do you think
this bothers you?
It feels like she's not
trying to fix anything.
You know? We are hemorrhaging,
and she's just reaching
for a Band-Aid.
So if I don't want
to fix our problems
the same way that you do, that - means that I'm not trying?
- No, no, no.
Unfortunately, we have
to stop for today,
but I want you to
see this through.
Have scheduled sex this
week and see how it feels.
It might not be what you
think. For either of you.
Well, I guess I'll see you
at 10:00 tomorrow night.
Um, would this be a
bad time to tell you
that I have to reschedule?
Hey. Haven't seen
you in a while.
I know. Yeah. Sorry.
It's been... busy.
Been meaning to give
this to you. Oh.
Yeah. Left it at
my place, so...
Yeah. Oh!
Mm-hmm. Ha-ha. Yeah.
I guess you have been really
busy. Because this is not mine.
You sure?
Yeah.
It's a really nice
color, though.
She has good taste.
Oh, my God. I'm so sorry.
Hey. You needed a consult?
Uh, I have a patient coming in
from Friday Harbor
with a head injury.
The local hospital's
sending in the scans.
Should I come back? No.
I was just leaving.
I'm gonna go.
Have the nurses page me
when the scans are in. Heh.
Hm.
Ben: Schmitt is with
Dr. Beltran today,
so I've got your assignments.
Let's do a lineup. A lineup.
It's something we did at the fire
station to get the day started right.
Discipline, organization.
Or you can stay exactly where
you are. That works, too.
So, Yasuda's out on PTO today.
But, Adams, you're with
Schmitt on Beltran's service.
Millin, you're
with me and Ndugu.
Griffith, with Lincoln.
Um, you forgot someone.
And you've forgotten
your dictations.
There are over 100 incomplete
records with your name on it.
Have fun staring at a computer
all day playing catch-up.
Woman on P.A.:
Orderly to 6 East.
Any available orderly to 6 East.
Are you lurking?
Okay. Your...
Your evaluation forms
were sent out today.
I know. Ndugu will
be the first one
who will officially assess me.
You know? How do you know?!
Um, you left your laptop open
on the kitchen counter today.
Hey, hey, hey.
You lurk, I snoop.
Okay. Just... Just...
Mnh. Just be yourself!
I've never been
to Friday Harbor.
I went on a field
trip in seventh grade.
We picked apples.
Hey. Today you are
picking up Ofelia Lopez.
She's 10 years old. She
fell off a moving tractor.
Her vitals are
stable, but she's got
a bad leg injury and a TBI,
so she needs a
higher level of care
than her community
hospital can provide.
I would go myself, but I
got a full patient roster.
I don't mind getting
out of the hospital.
- It's a nice drive.
- I'm sure it is.
But you're taking a helicopter.
No! Nice!
Taking an ambulance would
be more cost-efficient,
m-more environmentally friendly.
And it's not up in the sky.
Update me when you arrive!
Morning, Mr. Riley.
No, no. Left, right, left.
The other left, Kenneth. Ugh.
Instructions go in one
ear and out the other
with this kid.
Maybe he's missing
his director, huh?
He's missing something, alright.
Go ahead.
Uh, Darren Riley,
55, presented with
antibiotic-resistant
pneumonia with a concern
for a rapidly progressing
necrotizing infection.
Was intubated but
couldn't oxygenate
despite maximal
ventilation settings.
Placed on VV ECMO and
was extubated last night.
Mr. Riley's X-rays
from this morning.
Left lung's
completely whited out.
Winston: Let's order
him a CT with contrast.
Mr. Riley, I'm gonna change
your cannula dressing.
Well, I can take care of that
as soon as I place this order.
We'll just meet
you in radiology.
That's not necessary. I want
to help with transport anyway.
Oh, but we can handle that.
Moving a patient on
ECMO can be tricky,
so I'd like to be there for it.
Okay. Uh, great.
All risks and benefits
were explained
and patient agreed to
sign informed consent...
Hey. Are you okay?
Yeah. Yeah. Good.
Must have slept funny.
The patient was taken to an
operating room and placed...
Hey. Are you sure you're okay?
I could take a look if you want.
Someone get me a gurney!
Mr. Wheeler, how
are you feeling?
Fit as a fiddle.
Think I'm about ready to go home?
Not quite yet.
I saw some fluid building
around your heart
on this morning's echo.
It's a common complication
after heart surgery.
We might have to do a
procedure to drain it,
in which case we'd have to
keep you a little bit longer.
Oh, no. I can't stay longer.
I have to be home next week.
It's my 40th
wedding anniversary.
Congratulations.
That's a big milestone.
Hey, why don't we watch it and
see if it resolves on its own
before we jump into
a new procedure?
Macie and I got engaged
when we were 19.
She wanted this
big church wedding,
but our parents didn't approve,
so we eloped at city hall.
We know how that goes.
We wanted to get
married in the park,
but we wound up
doing it in a bar.
Every year, we recreate
our wedding dinner...
hot dogs from the
cart on the corner.
You know, we should go to
Joe's for our anniversary.
It's the only place we ever go.
Look, I want to run
another set of coags,
and we will take it from there.
Get her flowers
on your way home.
Works every time.
- Thanks for the tip.
- Yeah.
Woman on P.A.: Dr. Horowitz,
6-2-9-6. Dr. Horowitz...
Thanks for making the
trip. She's got severe
left lower extremity trauma,
extensive soft-tissue damage,
as well as vascular injury.
Suffered some head trauma
with multiple contusions
and lacerations.
- Okay. Hi.
- Hi.
Levi: Her respirations
look a bit labored.
Her sats were in the
80s when she arrived.
The oxygen's helped.
But you didn't intubate?
Our only ventilator's in use,
and we don't have the
resources to manually bag her
if we did RSI.Okay.
Nanette: We rushed her
here as soon as we could.
This doctor said you'll
be able to help her more?
Will her leg be alright? She
loves to play in the fields.
I'm Dr. Schmitt.
This is Dr. Adams.
We'll have a better idea - once we examine her, okay?
- Okay.
We temporized with a
splint and tourniquet.
Ischemia time is
about 45 minutes.
Um...
Hi. I'm Levi.
Your name's Ofelia, right?
My friend Lucas and I are gonna
help make you feel better, okay?
Okay.
Okay. This is my number.
We're gonna get to
Grey-Sloan before you,
so once you get
there, give me a call.
Wait. We can't go with you?
I'm so sorry. There's not
enough room in the helicopter.
But I promise we'll take
excellent care of her, okay?
- Okay.
Jose: We love you, mija.
We're gonna have to amputate the
leg if we don't get back fast,
so let's intubate
for transport ASAP.
Okay.
Back to the helicopter.
Dr. Kwan? Aren't
you supposed to...
Look, I know I'm
behind on charts...
and when I'm behind, it
becomes your problem,
and you don't like problems.
Uh, is that Zayne
from custodial staff?
Yeah, he, uh, collapsed
with a severe
abdominal and hip pain.
Mr. Johnson, I see you took
that whole rack down
with you. You okay?
Pain started way
before that rack fell.
I've been managing it
fine for months now.
Alright, well, we need
to get you to the E.R.
to get you checked
out. Hospital rules.
I'll just take something
once my shift ends.
Let me save you the trouble.
You can fight her on this,
but you will lose. We all do.
Can you make it quick?
I will make it thorough.
Come on. Let's go.
You too, Kwan!
Doctor should be in soon.
Okay.
We are never going to fit
four car seats in
either of our cars.
Are we gonna have
to get a minivan?
You know what's transporting
those babies right now?
Me!
Every horrible pregnancy
symptom, double it!
Twice the... the reflux,
the weight gain, the exhaustion.
And then after all that,
I'm gonna return to work,
delivering other
people's babies,
taking care of not
one, but two newborns.
But, sure, by all means,
you go test-drive minivans.
How can I help?
I wish I could tell
you, but all the energy
that used to go to my brain
is now being diverted
to my uterus.
You know what?
I really need this to
not take a long time.
I have a patient who is 29 weeks
and she's about to
deliver triplets.
Three babies. Hmm?
Could be worse! Heh!
You want three?
A Consult in the E.R.
Just go.
I'm staying for the ultrasound.
It's gonna show the same
as it did yesterday,
and then you're gonna smile
and say, "We've got this."
And right now I really...
I frankly don't...
really don't need that.
Did you play? Marching band?
No.
Cool. Me neither.
Oh, I didn't do sports.
But it's band.
Do they wear uniforms?
Then I didn't do it.
Oh. Damn it.
His lung is completely liquified
from all the necrotic tissue.
What's your recommendation?
Chest tube and change
the antibiotics.
Oh, a chest tube
won't drain this,
and the antibiotics
aren't penetrating,
so we'll need to completely
remove the source.
The source is his lung.
Book an O.R... I'm gonna
get him off the table.
Well, don't you want
us to get him...
Does he normally have to
do everything himself?
Well, he let me sew a patch
graft angioplasty once.
Maybe it's you.
Simone: When you say
it's "not your thing,"
you don't mean like
you never vote, right?
Like it's a recent thing?
What about in 2016?
What do we got?
Uh, Zayne Johnson, 32.
Diffuse pain, greatest in
his abdomen and right hip
after a supply rack fell on him.
We're still working
on his history.
Do you take any medication?
How much room do you
have on that thing?
I take folic acid,
hydroxyurea, ibuprofen,
and tramadol as needed.
- You have sickle cell?
- Yeah.
And I know about that new
gene therapy that cures it,
but my insurance won't cover it
and I don't have $3
million laying around,
so I still got it.
FDA approves a cure, and
nobody can afford to get it.
If I had three mill, I wouldn't
want to spend it on treatments.
I'd buy a boat and
sail around the world.
I was kind of in the middle
of another patient upstairs.
Yeah, I brought you
here for that hip.
The articular surface
is completely destroyed.
Griffith, take him
upstairs for an MRI.
And we should also
get an abdominal CT.
- No, no. I...
- Ah. It won't take long. Okay?
If there's anything you need,
you let these interns know.
Don't be shy.
Pilot: We've hit a
bit of rain and fog.
I'm trying to
steer us out of it.
Think about puppies.
Gravity blankets.
Wizards and adventure.
Well, either somebody died
or you're ghosting someone.
I am ignoring a mistake.
And don't look at my phone.
Is it the guy from the hallway?
So what? Does he hate dogs?
Puts the toilet paper on wrong?
Does he not know how
to cook a real meal?
Do you? I'm just saying.
Just because it's a bad match
doesn't mean it's a mistake.
You're right. It
wasn't a mistake.
It was a giant failure!
Oh, my God.
Her blood pressure spiked.
She might be herniating.
Okay.
Her pupils aren't blown.
Actually, they're pinpoint.
Her heart rate's in the 50s.
- Okay.
- Okay. We got you.
Okay. We got you. We got you.
She's diaphoretic, bradycardic.
Her eyes are tearing up.
We keep having to suction her.
Her parents said that she likes
playing in the fields, right?
The farm probably
uses pesticides.
Are you thinking
organophosphate poisoning?
Yeah. Let's get
her on atropine.
Okay. Oh. She's seizing!
Oh! Oh! Okay.
Damn it. The tourniquet.
Did it come loose?
No. The clasp is broken.
We have to stop this bleeding!
Holding pressure!
Yeah, I got her leg!
Find the atropine!
Hey, uh, Aurelio's
labs are back.
Okay. Great. Thank you.
Can I get an ultrasound and
a pericardiocentesis kit?
I just need to finish
reviewing these scans.
Teddy, it's still
a small effusion.
He's coagulopathic. I
mean, we can either do
the pericardiocentesis now or
we can wait till he crashes
in the middle of the
night and do it then.
We don't know
that's gonna happen.
Didn't you accuse me
of... what was it...
putting a Band-Aid on a
hemorrhage this morning?
What does that have
to do with this?
So now I am trying to
face this problem head on,
and that doesn't seem to
be good enough, either.
I mean, forget about
my years of experience
treating pericardial
effusions. Teddy...
Uh, I was just
getting a cup of tea.
Oh, well, um... Well,
we were just, um...
We were just
discussing a patient.
Look, I can give
it another hour,
but then we're gonna
need another set of scans
and a repeat echo.
Okay.
Oh, you should try
the Moroccan Mint.
It's very, uh...
refreshing. Hm!
Simone: What about
local elections?
State propositions?
Or public surveys?
I send those straight to spam.
Link: Griffith, what
are we looking at?
Studying his abdominal CT.
His hip MRI is about to come up.
You can relax, Zayne.
Pretend you're in
that $3-million boat.
That's not relaxing.
I get seasick.
But you want to sail
around the world?
No, but my son does, and
I'd do anything for him.
Simone: Is that his
spleen? It's so small.
Pretty much nonfunctional
at this point.
Also, those are iron
deposits in his liver.
Should we take care of
his gallstones, too?
The gallbladder wall's
not acutely inflamed.
The sickle cell has
basically ravaged his body,
including... His
hip, which you all
would have seen if you
noticed his MRI was up.
He's got subchondral collapse and
flattening of the femoral head.
We're gonna have to
replace the whole joint.
Oh, he's not gonna like that.
We don't have a choice... if
he wants to stop this joint
from completely degenerating.
Hey. Did you get the films
from my transfer patient?
Schmitt and Adams are
worried about the leg.
My fellow will need to take it.
Okay.
Hey. I took a look
at Ofelia's scans.
Minor subdural. No
swelling, no shift.
I'm not terribly worried, but I
will re-evaluate when they land.
Their ETA is 25 minutes.
Okay. I'm gonna
check on a patient.
Text me if they get here sooner.
Hey. A-About earlier,
it wasn't exactly
what it looked like.
Uh, none of my business.
Okay.
Lucas: The tourniquet's
completely broken.
I can't get it to
hold tight enough.
I'm gonna need another one.
Oh, it looks like
there's an injury
to her superficial
femoral artery.
There's another
tourniquet in this bag.
Hold as much pressure
as you can. Got it.
Here.
Alright.
Once we get a signal, we
need to update Beltran.
Got it.
Damn it.
It's basically beyond repair.
She's gonna need an amputation.
Well, we have I.V. tubing.
What if we make a
temporary shunt,
see if we can reconnect the
femoral artery with the tubing?
If the pilot is re-routing,
it's gonna take us a
lot longer to get back.
The tourniquet's been
on for almost two hours.
The leg looks ischemic.
If we do nothing,
she'll lose it.
Okay. Yeah. I'm in.
Okay. Alright.
So, if you take my lung, I'll
be rid of this thing here?
Unfortunately, due to
your smoking history,
your other lung won't be
able to oxygenate your body
well enough by itself.
You'd have to stay on ECMO
until we can get you
a lung transplant.
Any chance that happens before
the NorthPac Band Review?
Jules: We don't know.
It could be tomorrow.
It could be weeks from now.
There will be
other performances.
I was thinking
about my alto sax.
First instrument
I ever picked up.
Thing was nearly bigger than me.
But once I got the hang
of it, I fell in love.
I haven't been able
to play in weeks.
What if I can't ever play again?
Or, worse...
what if I can't teach?
The band's more
than just my job.
It's my life.
Well, music and teaching,
it's in your bones.
Losing a lung won't change that.
Just might need a little
extra practice after surgery.
That's all.
Let's get you prepped.
Mr. Johnson?
Dr. Bailey and Dr. Lincoln
would like to talk to you.
I have to finish work
so I can get home
for dinner with my son.
Uh, your scans show
something called
avascular necrosis in your hip.
I'll make an appointment
to come back.
My son needs extra attention,
and my sister's had him all day.
Your pain is only
gonna get worse.
The sickled cells
in the joint cut off
the blood supply to the bone,
which is causing it to die.
But we can replace
the joint today,
and your insurance covers it.
And then I won't feel pain?
Well, we can at least help
with the pain in your hip.
So instead of curing my pain,
they're gonna let
every joint and organ
in my body deteriorate and
then they'll pay to fix it?
I know. It doesn't make
sense. And the system sucks.
Maybe I shouldn't
say that, but...
I've been through this before.
I know the frustration of
trying to fight a system
that doesn't care if you suffer
or even if you live or die.
They only see you
as a code or a cost
or some number in
a sea of numbers.
The system couldn't
care less about you.
But if you care about yourself,
you should get the surgery.
Simone: Think about your son.
If you weren't able to walk
or continue to do your job,
it'll be a lot harder
to take care of him.
Okay.
What's next?
I'll go tell Dr. Lincoln.
Don't bother. I'll do it.
Oh. Uh, I'm about to
meet with Balcom Medical.
You know, I've always
had a great relationship
with Ethan Chen,
so if there's anything
the hospital needs,
I'm your man.
Oh. Ethan is retired.
Oh. Well, good for him.
Yeah, the new CFO
is Erika Desai.
She is great.
But her husband Nirav's
also very prominent
on the board,
and he only hears what he wants
to hear, which is himself.
Ooh. It sounds like a
communication issue.
And he often overlooks
how hard I am trying
to make everything work!
And then he insinuates that I only
care about what is best for me,
regardless of what
anyone else wants.
You mean what's best
for the hospital.
This isn't about Balcom, is it?
So... you want
advice or a pep talk?
Is there one that's less
irritating than the other?
You've already been
through a war together.
You can do this.
That's the least
irritating one?!
Winston: Tissue's
very fibrotic.
Millin, suction?
Jules: Got it.
Ben: My mom really wanted
me to learn an instrument.
Then my fourth-grade class
got sent home with recorders.
My brother and I were
learning the accordion
- for a few months.
- Didn't stick with it?
Our teacher didn't want to be
paid in lemons from our yard.
I'm at the hilum.
You need more retraction?
That'd be great.
Harrington, please.
Ben: Oh.
Could you hold that
right there, Warren?
- Uh-huh.
- Thank you, Bokhee.
With all due respect, I
may be on a trial basis,
but I'm coming in as a
fourth year resident.
I'm perfectly
capable of retracting
and prepping patients
for transport
and moving them to the CT.
Hell, I'm capable of
a lot more than that.
Alright. Specimen.
Here we go.
How's he doing?
Simone: Feels like
this could have been
a much less extensive
surgery years ago.
Bailey: Well, seeking treatment
when you have sickle cell
is a minefield of stigmas
and misunderstandings.
That's not on Zayne.
Kwan, careful with the drill!
This bone is like stone!
You know... I'll take over.
Bailey: Oh, let him give
it another try. Go again.
Easy this time.
Put... Put the drill down!
Bailey: If he doesn't try
again, he won't learn.
We're not doing second
chances right now.
This man is in constant,
agonizing pain.
And I'm just talking
literal physical pain,
not the hell of
suffering in silence
because nobody cares
or believes in him.
It's the only way he can get by,
even though it causes more
pain and more suffering!
Damn it!
Someone get me a new drill bit!
Bailey: Are you done?
Yeah. Whatever
you're going through,
go through it on your own time.
We are taking care
of Zayne right now.
I cannot take care of you, too.
Suction, please.
Adams! Suction!
I'm trying!
I just have one more tie.
Oh! Oh, my God! Ohh! Okay.
Whoa!
Let's do this fast. Alright.
Okay.
Ah! Damn it! Can't
get it to stay.
Can you hold it, please?
Yeah.
Okay.
I think that's it. Okay.
Tourniquet coming off.
Okay. Okay.
It's holding.
We did it.
Ohh! What's happening?!
I don't know! I
can't see anything!
Pilot: I can't get
around this storm!
I'm gonna attempt an
emergency landing!
Macie. Macie.
How long has he been like this?
15 minutes. Muffled
heart sounds.
Low BP, JVD.
Cardiac tamponade. This is why I
wanted to do the procedure earlier.
He wasn't - this symptomatic.
- Alright.
We're gonna need to reopen
him and relieve the pressure.
We're doing a needle aspiration
bedside. We're already prepped.
It's much more
controllable in the O.R.
Macie: I'm his wife.
Let me through!
There's blood seeping out
of his incision already.
We don't have time. Scalpel.
I'm right here, dear.
Oh, my God! Whoa!
I need a crash cart! Prepare
for open cardiac massage!
Someone get her out
of here, please!
No!
I feel so... much better now.
- He's alive?!
- Aurelio: Ohh.
Owen: His vitals
have stabilized!
We need to get him
to the O.R. now!
What's happening?!
My husband's okay?!
It was a buildup of pressure
from fluid and blood,
but it was around the
heart, not the heart itself.
We're gonna know more when we get him
in there, but we need to move fast!
Let's go, let's go, let's
go, let's go! Let's go!
What would you do
with $3 million?
Fund voter-registration drives.
How do you think the
system gets fixed?
Well, it's my game. You have
to spend it on yourself.
I'd hire an at-home nurse,
and my granny wouldn't
have to live in a facility.
Pay off my loans.
Start a maternal-health
nonprofit.
Boring!
Let me guess. You'd
buy an obnoxious car.
Oh, for starters,
I'd get my own place
so I don't have to live
with you fools anymore.
I'd travel, and, yes,
buy an obnoxious car.
Mm-hmm.
But if I had a curable
disease, you'd be damn sure
I'd spend every
penny to heal myself.
What's crazy is he
works at a hospital...
and he can't even get the
treatment he needs covered.
And he'd probably be a
great candidate for it.
It's out there.
It's available.
We have everything we need
to cure his sickle cell.
Everything except the money.
Jose: What do you mean
we beat them here?
- It's a three-hour drive.
- When the weather is bad,
they often re-route to
get around the storm.
And how much longer
until they arrive?
And is Ofelia still okay?
This doesn't necessarily
mean anything,
but at the moment, we've
lost contact with them.
No. No.
I'm calling Dr. Schmitt
and Dr. Adams.
We will also keep trying
them until we get through.
We trusted your team
with our daughter.
They promised to take
care of our little baby!
Amelia: I know that
this is terrifying.
We are closely
monitoring the situation.
Dr. Beltran has a whole staff
that is prepared to treat Ofelia
as soon as she arrives.
Come on. Let's go
take a seat. Come on.
Oh. Kwan, Griffith.
Yeah, yeah, sorry to bother
you, but this is important.
It's about a patient,
and it's urgent.
Can you page another attending?
We need you... or Dr. Altman,
but she's headed to
emergent surgery.
Our patient has
sickle cell disease,
and there's a new gene
therapy that could cure him,
but it's expensive and his
insurance won't cover it.
We know the hospital can't
treat everyone pro bono,
but this man works here.
H-He walks the same halls as us
and eats the same
cafeteria food.
How can we look him in the eye
knowing we're not gonna help him
just 'cause some idiot
suit in an insurance office
says we can't?
Doctors, these are
some of our partners
from Balcom Medical.
These are two of our
surgical interns...
who I believe have rounds?
- We... We do.
- Thank you for your time.
His chest tubes are
putting out minimal fluid,
and he's stable on ECMO.
Yeah, he knew he was
sick for a while,
but he's been trying
to work through it.
He said if he's gonna drop,
he'd rather do it around
people than at home by himself.
And all I've done
since he showed up here
is give him bad news, and he's
had to take it all on by himself.
He doesn't have any family.
And his students can't visit.
So my personal interest in
providing Mr. Riley's care
has nothing to do with
anyone's capability.
I just don't want
him to feel alone.
So, um, Millin, put
in the post-op labs.
- Of course.
- Great.
Warren, start to
wean him off sedation
and extubate him when
you think he's ready.
You got it. Alright.
I...
Amelia: Anything new?
Just my increased
blood pressure.
They should've connected
with an ambulance
when they made it down...
if they made it down.
Hello?
This is Grey-Sloan Memorial.
Is there anyone
there? Come in.
I sent them. I specifically
sent Schmitt in my place.
I sent your nephew.
If something happens,
I'm gonna have to
call Schmitt's family
and tell them that I put
him on that helicopter.
And your family.
I-I just had to go to the
worst case scenario in my head,
and it's really hard not to
when they're flying
right now over water
and other things that
could spell disaster.
Well, I've experienced enough
that I always go to the
worst case scenario.
And sometimes you've just
got to accept the situation
at face value...
so you can keep moving forward.
Hello?
His heart exploded, and
now he's completely fine.
That poor wife!
She was covered!
Covered in blood.
It was...
This is terrible! Ohh!
I can still feel it in my socks.
Ohh!
Ohh...
Owen, we don't have
to schedule sex.
Well, technically,
it's now our homework,
and I have always been a
straight-A student, so...
We're gonna get through this.
We have gotten
through a lot worse.
I'm not sure if you're talking
about Iraq or the kids.
Teddy... can I
take you on a date?
Somewhere that's not Joe's.
I'd really like that.
Is it over?
Oh, yes. Your surgery
went very well.
- How do you feel?
- Really tired.
Blue: The paid meds
are still working.
So, is this Zayne Johnson?
Zayne: Either these pain
meds are really strong,
or you're not Dr. Lincoln.
I'm Dr. Webber. I
have some good news.
There's a possibility you could
get sickle-cell gene therapy.
What? H-How?
We're doing it pro bono?
No, my partners and I at
Balcom heard your story,
and we'd like to
open a discussion
about how you can apply
for a grant we have.
I can't believe
this. Thank you.
Thank your advocates. They
really made an impression.
Okay. We're talking
about that later.
Richard: If you get to go-ahead,
we need to get you started soon.
This whole process could
take almost a year.
- A year?
- Well, sometimes as soon as eight months.
You'll get blood transfusions,
then you'll stay in the hospital
to collect your stem cells.
And after gene therapy,
you'll be given chemo
and kept in isolation
for about a month
until your immune
system recovers.
I don't think I could do that.
My son has special needs, and
I can't afford a caretaker
or to be away from
him for that long.
Okay. Um... Well,
you think about it,
and, um, maybe you'll
figure something out.
The system still sucks.
Yeah, if only there was
something we could do about it.
Monica: She's still
in critical condition,
but she should be okay.
And... And her leg?
We were able to save it.
She'll likely need more surgery,
but hopefully with
some physical therapy,
she'll regain function.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you, Doctors.
Dr. Adams will take you in.
Do you think peds
was your calling?
You know I applied
for the fellowship.
I don't mean your interest.
I've heard all
about your interest.
I mean, do you truly believe
that it's what
you're meant to do?
When I was a kid, I was
obsessed with helicopters,
so for my fifth birthday,
my mom splurged on an
aerial tour of Seattle.
Got to take pictures
with the pilot,
put on the cool headphones.
Then we got up in the
air, and I freaked out.
I rode the entire trip
with my eyes closed.
That was my only helicopter
ride until today.
I pretended to nap the
whole way to Friday Harbor,
but on the way back, when
she started to deteriorate,
all I could think
about was Ofelia.
Even when we were going
down in the storm,
I only wanted to keep her safe.
I know peds is my calling...
but I don't know how to
prove that to everyone else.
Well, I've never
been more certain
that a resident belongs in peds.
I want to help.
I think that ship has sailed.
Hm. For now.
But I have a lot of friends
who got their fellowship
after doing research.
And I have a colleague in Texas
who's looking for help
with a clinical trial.
You interested?
Sure. Great.
'Cause I already told him you'd
call him to schedule something.
You know more than
you think, Schmitt.
Trust yourself.
Check on Mr. Riley?
Yeah, he's stable for now.
I asked the nurse to let us
know if anything changes.
Alright. Thanks. If it
does, I'll handle it.
Not because you can't.
I'll just be across the
street at Joe's, so...
Are you meeting folks?
No. Just, uh,
grabbing some dinner.
Maybe watch the game.
I like the noise.
You ready?
I just told Tuck to put
the casserole in the oven
and Pru to clean
up her Play-Doh.
Actually, I think
I'm gonna head over
to Joe's with Ndugu.
Oh, I don't want to go to Joe's.
Well, it's a good thing
you weren't invited.
Have a nice time.
I'll see you at home.
Meredith: The old
saying goes...
fake it till you make it.
Because sometimes pretending
you have confidence
helps you find the real thing.
Okay.
You can go home. I can
stay and monitor Ofelia.
Are you still avoiding that guy?
Just because we shared
a near-death experience
doesn't mean I
have to answer you.
Sure, but he's following us.
- Oh, God.
- Hey, Levi. Hi. Can we talk?
I know about Ryan.
Okay.
I thought what we had was real,
something deep.
I'm sorry I didn't say anything.
I'm sure you are.
It's hard to know
when to tell people
about your dead husband.
What?
Oh, I d... I didn't realize.
I'm so sorry.
It'll be four years this summer.
Um, I just haven't done a
lot of dating since then,
so this is all new to me.
Yeah, yeah.
Wait. Did you think
I was cheating?
No! No.
I m... I mean, may...
maybe a little bit.
I think what we have is real.
Okay? You're kind
of the best thing
that's happened to me
in a really long time.
When it doesn't work,
when life doesn't
give us second chances
or dress rehearsals...
you can walk away...
or you can go all-in.
Hey. Ofelia's vascular
checks look good.
Mm. Nice.
Yeah.
Thanks for your help today.
I just did a neuro exam.
No, I was freaking out,
and you calmed me down.
Oh.
I'm being genuine!
No, I... It's not
you. It's the irony...
that you would see if
you knew me better.
Listen. The thing
with Ndugu...
It's just casual. We were just
going through something similar.
You don't owe me an
explanation. Really.
You and I are good.
Good night.
We tell ourselves we don't care.
Hey! Hey.
Ultrasound showed two
strong heartbeats.
Equal fluid level.
DeLuca saw nothing
to worry about.
Great.
I'm sorry.
I was so freaked out over
one baby, and now it's...
And I'm exhausted.
You know, I worked
20 hours straight last week.
I delivered eight
babies with no caffeine.
I told you you should
rest after that.
Are you mad at me?
You... locked me out of
your car this morning.
You kicked me out of the
ultrasound appointment.
I didn't kick you out. I...
I was overwhelmed and hormonal.
This is a high-risk pregnancy!
The odds of making it full
term with two healthy babies?!
I'm scared!
Yeah, and you think I'm
just worried about cars?
No, I d... I'm scared
out of my mind!
I'm scared for them.
I'm scared about you.
We're supposed to be partners.
If we're falling apart just
thinking about having twins,
what's gonna happen when
we actually have them?
We can try to hide
our doubts and fears.
Or we can accept the unknown...
What's this?
And dive in.
I've had... an
extremely long day.
I just wanted to
end it with you.
And a real meal.
Mm-hmm.
Are you hungry?
Starving.
The real thing is better anyway.
subsync
johnhallgeir