.
I had your van towed.
You took my home.
How could you?!
I gotta go.
Mom, stop! Mom!
I'm a little concerned.
What do you mean?
When capable people
like yourself
feel like they need
a little extra help...
I'm not on anything.
Do you feel like you've been
morally compromised
promoting the Vas-COM?
I don't feel so good.
♪
How about drinks?
I don't think
it's appropriate
for me to date a patient.
You know how to reach me.
You saved me.
Another round of
Arnold Palmers?
Just because I can't drink
doesn't mean
you have to abstain.
Arnold Palmer for me.
Mezcal for the gentleman.
Double shot. Best you got.
You trying to take advantage
of me now?
Oh, no.
I like my prey alert
and engaged.
Oh, I'm sure you do.
Hey, what's up, man?
Hey, Big D.
What was I saying?
Oh, you was telling me
about some knucklehead kid
that busted up his leg
on a skateboard.
He had a bone sticking
through his shin
and then his foot
just was like--
Hey, come on. Stop it.
Hey, Uncle Joe,
I ain't see him in a minute.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
I think it's probably best
to let him be.
He's not in a good place
right now.
Why?
Sergeant Kerry.
Oh, man.
He up to his antics again, huh?
Yeah.
He put him on rubber gun squad.
Desk duty for what?
Some rookie cop was mouthing
off at your uncle
in the parking lot after work,
so Joe had to teach him
how to respect his elders.
Oh, Joe shaped him up?
Joe shaped him up good.
Well, we shouldn't be laughing.
But it was a sight to see.
And he snitched, right?
Yeah.
Because these young guys, what,
they as soft as tissue paper.
They wasn't even on the clock,
but you know Kerry.
I know Kerry.
I think he's just trying to
make an example
out of your uncle.
Oh, excuse me.
You, uh, you mind if I--
Who's hitting you up
at this hour?
Is it another lady friend?
No, it's your mom, actually.
And she wants me to meet her
at Med.
I thought you weren't
on call tonight.
No, I'm not. She knows that.
I, just, um...
Don't want to let her down?
Yeah, just--I wouldn't have
started drinking if I--
Crockett, you're allowed
to have a social life.
Yeah. Right?
Just...let her know
that I'm unavailable,
and, uh, that's that.
And then what do you say
we get out of here,
go back to my place
for a nightcap?
I would, uh,
I would love that.
But I have to be up early.
I'm on in the ED at 7:00.
Do-over tomorrow night?
So I'm thinking about getting
all the guys together, right?
And we're gonna have
a poker night.
I'm standing right here,
and you come in the door
and you knock me
out of the way?
Hey, pal. Why don't you
just go sit down, okay?
I said you cut me off,
old man.
Get out of my face.
Get out of my--
Hey!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Chill out, bro.
Take it easy.
Hey, I hardly touched him.
Uncle Joe, you're bleeding.
Let me look--
Hey, Joe! Joe!
Hey, stop it. Stop.
Enough!
Let's get him out of here.
Come on, man. Come on.
Let's go.
Take it easy.
♪
.
I'll circle back later
after his wife leaves.
So you really think Cooper
was about to come clean?
I'm sure of it.
I'm telling you,
Ms. Goodwin, he was--
Keep me posted.
Hey.
How you doing?
I'm still in shock.
Matt seemed completely fine
at the convention center
and then all of a sudden,
he just--
Yeah. I know.
Do you think it was my fault?
Maybe Matt overheard me
questioning his judgment
on Eleanor Holt's case
and then--
No, no, no, Jessa.
That's not why--
And if that raised his blood
pressure, then maybe--
No, I'm positive.
There were...
extenuating circumstances.
Good. I mean, not good.
The man had a heart attack.
I just--
No, I get you.
Really?
You're one of the few.
Anyway, I should get this.
Yeah.
♪
Hey, Unc. Good morning.
How you feeling?
Just had whiskey
and bumped into some jackass.
You're a peach compared
to the guy
that put that gash
on your head.
Oh, crap.
Not my money maker, D.
Look, I would have
sewn you up myself,
but I figured I'd let Plastics
take a crack at it.
You know?
Give you the VIP treatment.
Thanks, D. You and your pops
are always looking out for me.
Yeah. On that front, uh,
I heard about the incident
with the rookie.
What incident? Come on, huh?
Where we come from,
you pop off, you could get
your ass handed to you.
Kid didn't expect your unc
to make him eat pavement,
that's all.
Well, what about you,
you know?
How are you dealing
with the fallout?
Heard you talked
to somebody internally.
Yeah. They had me sit down
with some pencil-neck shrink
from the department,
cover their asses.
It's not like I'm gonna cry
my guts out to the guy.
That'll give 'em a reason to
put me out to pasture sooner.
Well, um, you know,
we got a guy here.
Dr. Charles,
he's the head of psychiatry.
He's becoming
a really good friend of mine.
Here we go.
Nah, for real.
He's a good guy.
And he has no connections
to the department.
No one will ever know
that you even talked to him.
Are you really gonna turn down
an opportunity
to bitch for an hour?
Ow.
That does sound appealing.
Yeah.
You know, Marsha,
she's been trying to get me
into therapy for years.
It'd make her happy.
Well, you got to wait
on Plastics anyway.
♪
So, uh,
how are you doing this?
You taking steroids, huh?
You cloning yourself, huh?
Because you've seen
more patients this morning
than any other doc in the ED.
Really? I didn't realize.
Not that it should come
as any surprise
seeing as you've learned
from the best.
You referring to yourself?
Hey, you said it, not me.
Hate to break up
the love fest, gentlemen,
but we've got an MVC incoming.
Dr. Choi, you're going
with Dr. Marcel. You good?
Yeah, good.
Damn right you are.
Marcus Clemens,
40-year-old male.
Unrestrained driver,
high-speed MVC.
Suspected chest trauma and
visible bulge in his abdomen.
GCS 12. Vitals are stable.
Gave him 4 of morphine
in the ambo.
It looks like some sort of
incarcerated ab hernia.
Might be traumatic.
It's hard to tell.
I've seen it before when
patients get thrown
against the gearshift.
Hey, Mr. Clemens,
I'm Dr. Marcel.
You were in a car accident.
You're at Chicago Med now.
I'm gonna take
good care of you.
All right guys, here we go.
Whoa, no, no, no, no.
Kayla, cover Dr. Choi for me.
Come on.
Not yet, brother.
Welcome back.
Here we go. On my count.
One, two, three.
Nice and easy.
Ultrasound, please.
All right.
Diminished breath sounds
on the left.
Okay. FAST is negative.
All right. Let's clear.
Mr. Clemens, I need you
to be still for me. Okay?
X-ray's up.
Yep.
Left pneumothorax.
I'll put in a chest tube.
Go ahead and prep.
I'm gonna see if I can reduce
that hernia manually.
Okay, bear with me,
Mr. Clemens.
Might wanna try
the Trendelenburg position.
That's not gonna make
a difference.
Some Brucet to relax him?
No, this thing isn't budging.
I'm concerned it's starting
to strangulate.
Might be the angle.
Give me an abdominal CT.
Let's see what else
is going on.
Mr. Clemens,
you feel this right here?
All right, everyone,
let's simmer down
and let's gather.
Yes. Good morning, everybody.
It's that time of year again.
Wyatt Labs is on site
to do our random drug testing.
Maggie will facilitate,
assigning
each of you a time slot.
And I know y'all are slammed,
but no exceptions.
Everyone must give a sample
before clocking out today.
Uh, Doris,
you're lucky numero uno.
Thank you.
Thank you, y'all.
Okay, well, you have
my number if she turns up.
Yeah. Thanks.
Oh, hey. I was just,
uh...
My mom and I got into a fight
last night and she took off.
I've been up all night calling
shelters, trying to find her.
I'm sorry to hear that,
Stevie.
Yeah, well,
wishful thinking on my part
that she'd turn up
in a shelter.
Any idea where
she might have gone?
Uh, yeah.
In the past when things
have gotten chaotic,
she's turned to drugs.
Anything to numb herself.
So you think she might be
trying to score?
I don't know. I'm gonna see
if I can track down
her friend Misty.
Um, see where people
from the encampment are buying.
Why don't I come with you?
Got a five-hour pharmacy
and therapeutics Zoom
this morning
I'm sure I won't be missed at.
I appreciate the offer, Will,
but it's okay--I'll be fine.
Oh, I don't doubt that.
But everyone can use
a little backup, right?
Even the Hammer.
You call me that again,
I leave you on the curb.
Copy. Let me get dressed.
I'll meet you out front.
Okay.
How you doing?
I'm Dr. Charles.
You must be Uncle Joe.
Yeah.
Well, Dylan here says that
you're a master of your craft.
So that's a ringing
endorsement.
You know, he's enthusiastic,
so we try and look
past his faults.
All right.
I'll let you two comedians
get at it.
What's, um--
what's been going on?
Well, didn't Dylan
tell you already?
You know,
just the broad strokes.
He said that you were having
a rough time at work.
Honestly, Doc,
I was hoping you might
recommend some sort of meds.
Oh, okay.
My wife Marsha--
well, I don't know if she
calls herself that anymore.
She had me move out
when things hit the fan.
Oh, boy.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Anyways, she always thought
that I should be on
some sort of pill, you know?
Help even me out a bit.
Right.
Guess cops are allowed
to take them now
with a doctor's note.
I don't know.
Maybe if she heard
that I was finally listening
to her advice for once,
she might let me move back in.
Okay. Look, we can absolutely
talk about medication.
But I guess I just--I want
to hear a little bit more
about what's going on.
For instance, you say
that your wife thinks
that maybe medication
might even you out.
What do you think
she means by that?
No, no, no, no.
Look, it's not like
I'm some sort of loose cannon.
All right?
It's just what happened
with the rookie,
I know I crossed the line.
I should never have
put hands on him.
I think you're--
you're probably right
about that last part,
but I mean, look, I get it.
I've been doing this
for over 30 years.
I wouldn't want some first year
resident mouthing off of me.
Exactly. These kids
these days, no respect.
Punk got off easy.
Hmm.
Hey.
Is everything okay?
All good.
Vanessa?
Are you all right?
Yeah, yeah. I'm fine.
Food poisoning, I think.
I stopped
by a sketchy food truck
last night after work.
My mistake.
Oh, no. Do you feel
well enough to work?
Actually,
maybe I should go home.
Oh. Sure.
Let me just check
the testing schedule.
You know,
can I just reschedule that
for another day or something?
Unfortunately, no.
They take a real hard line
on these things.
Anyone who misses
is automatically subject
to investigation.
But no worries, I could just
move up your time slot,
and you can go home
right after.
You know what, I, uh,
I think I'll stay.
You sure?
Yeah. Yeah.
I think I probably
actually got the--
the worst out of my system.
Okay, well, try to take it
easy and rest between patients.
Oh, and don't forget
to hydrate.
I got it, Maggie.
Thank you.
Okay.
Hey, morning, Dr. Blake.
Apologies I couldn't scrub
in last night.
You missed
a once-in-a-year case.
Oh, well.
My rule of thumb--
if I wouldn't drive,
I shouldn't operate, right?
Maybe I made
a miscalculation.
I beg your pardon?
I thought you were committed,
serious about the opportunity.
I am very much so.
Just not enough to prioritize
it above drinking and partying?
With all due respect,
Dr. Blake,
I wasn't on call last night.
Okay.
If you want to shadow me,
when opportunity knocks,
consider yourself on call.
Doesn't matter the hour.
And if that doesn't work
for you, you just let me know.
Sooner rather than later.
I don't like having
my time wasted.
.
Hey, Crockett, I just got
Marcus Clemens' CT back.
No solid organ injury
and no free fluid,
but a clear abdominal wall
hernia with incarcerated bowel.
Yeah. Looks like he needs
an emergent laparotomy.
All right,
I'll call the OR now.
Right now?
You think that's a good idea?
He's got a pulmonary contusion.
His sats aren't great.
Well, it's not opportune.
But if we wait,
we risk the bowel dying.
Yeah. This is Dr. Marcel.
Give me scheduling.
What about giving
manual reduction another shot?
I had this old-school surgeon
on my first deployment.
She taught me this method
she swears by.
Hold on for me.
Heat followed by ice
and you kind of corkscrew
the bowel back into place.
I'm telling you, Ethan,
the sucker's stuck.
It's not budging, and the more
we piss off that bowel,
the greater the risk of
strangulation and perforation.
You know that.
Let me give it a shot.
I'm not trying to undermine
your efforts in any way, man.
I just--I saw this work
on the ship dozens of times
when surgery wasn't an option.
Yeah. Let me call you back.
You know manual reduction
is a physically
involved procedure.
Yeah, I know.
I'll be careful.
I understand that.
But with your injury, I mean--
Hey, let me worry about that.
I'm sorry, Ethan,
but when it has the potential
to negatively impact
the patient's outcome,
I can't do that.
I'm gonna book the OR.
Yeah, give me scheduling.
Yeah, laparotomy 2.
Didn't sound to me
like this Sergeant Kerry
has too many fans on the force.
I mean, is he giving
everybody a hard time?
No. No, no.
This guy's had it out for me
ever since he got his stripes.
Listen, get this, every year,
we all get uniform allowance,
right? 1,800 bucks.
This year, mine doesn't
even hit my bank account.
Not a clerical
oversight, huh?
Oh, no. Kerry keeps track
of every penny, where it goes.
He did this on purpose
just to snub me.
I mean,
you should see this prick
sitting up there at his castle
at Mount Greenwood.
Then they're at Mastro's
every Friday night,
dining off the company dime.
Every Friday?
Like clockwork.
And in the meantime,
this jerk's cut me
out of overtime
by taking me off-a patrol.
But I mean, Joe, that's--
that's a decision
you can appeal, right?
And give him the pleasure
of shooting me down, huh?
Humiliating me again?
Forget it.
But I'm gonna tell you what,
if he doesn't put me back
on patrol soon,
I can't say
what's gonna happen.
What--
what do you mean by that?
Joe, what do you--
Listen, Doc, are we going
to do these meds, huh?
I gotta get going here.
Misty saw my mom last night.
Said she was headed
to a pawn shop.
She's trying to hawk
a gold bracelet,
which confirms
she's looking for fast cash.
Where do you think she got
a gold bracelet?
It's mine. Um, she must have
taken it with her.
She's not a thief.
She acts out
when she's desperate.
Anyway,
Misty gave me some addresses.
places where people are buying,
shooting galleries.
I thought we could start there.
Hey, if you want,
I can call my brother Jay,
get help locating her.
Will, if the cops find her
with drugs in her possession,
they'll lock her up.
Look, I don't want this
to sound harsh,
but maybe that's the wakeup
call she needs.
She's already done time.
Served a one year sentence
back in 2003.
I can't put her
through that again.
Whoa, whoa.
Hey, Joe, where are you going?
I thought we were gonna talk
a little bit more.
Buddy, again,
medication is absolutely--
Hey. I'm good. Okay?
Thanks for the help, Doc.
I gotta split.
Hey, let's at least
try and find Dylan.
I--I know that he wanted
to say goodbye to you.
I hassled the kid
enough last night.
I won't bother him
while he's saving lives.
Take care, Doc.
Hey, Marcus.
Techs will be by shortly
to transport you upstairs,
and Dr. Marcel
will meet you in the OR.
Oh, already? Okay.
Were you able to get
in touch with your wife?
Yeah.
She was hoping she could
get here before the surgery,
but I told her not to come.
Elaine's eight months along
with our first
and she's got preeclampsia,
so it's...too risky.
Ah, that's tough.
She could go into labor
at any moment,
and if I'm not there,
she just might not--
Anyways, uh--
not like I got
any other options, right?
Guess surgery is it.
♪
And the patient was referred
by Dr. Scott.
Yeah.
Close family friend, okay?
Calls him uncle.
Mm, Understood.
You said he sounded paranoid?
I mean, maybe even
a little delusional.
Did he make any direct
threats against this sergeant?
Not explicitly. But, I mean,
he's smarter than that.
He did, however,
describe in surprising detail
the habits of the sergeant
and his wife.
I mean, I'm pretty sure
he's stalking him.
Yeah. But without
an explicit, eminent threat,
you can't commit him.
A judge won't allow it.
And that's a conundrum,
right?
I have no way to force him
into treatment,
which leaves one option,
which is to alert the sergeant.
I mean, surely, I have
an ethical responsibility
to notify potential victims
of--of threats.
A duty to warn.
Yeah.
And yet I hate going that way.
There's already so much stigma
around first responders
seeking mental health support.
This is precisely
the kind of situation
makes it that much worse.
I mean,
you think Dylan is ever
gonna send me
a cop in trouble again?
He'll never forgive me.
But if this guy ends up
attacking someone--
Never forgive myself.
Whew, this is a tough one,
Daniel.
I don't envy the position
that you're in.
But just know,
whatever decision you make,
I've got your back.
Vanessa.
Dr. Rush is looking for you.
Sorry.
Um, I just need a moment.
Wait, have you been crying?
No, no, no. I'm fine.
Vanessa.
No, I'm fine, I just need
to go back to work.
Please, just--
Vanessa!
Oh, my God. Okay.
Sit down.
Sit down. Okay.
I just need
to go back to work.
Okay, you're having
a panic attack.
Slow down your breathing.
With me.
In.
Out.
What's going on?
I'm so screwed.
I've been taking Adderall
for the past couple of weeks
to stay on top of work.
And now with this drug test--
If you have a prescription,
he can't penalize you.
No, I--I know. I--
I don't have a prescription.
I know! I know.
It's just because
I've been so tired
and overwhelmed with work
and--and med school.
I know it's no excuse.
But everyone does it, Maggie.
I took a pill this morning,
and as soon as I found out
about the drug test,
I--I threw it up right away.
But--
If you threw it up
immediately,
it wouldn't have metabolized.
So you're fine for the test.
I took one last night.
And the half-life
of an Adderall is ten hours.
It takes a day to...
to clear your system.
I'm not gonna pass this test.
I'm not gonna pass it.
Everything,
everything that I worked for,
I'm just gonna lose.
I'm not gonna pass this test.
I'm not gonna pass
this test, Maggie.
Okay, okay.
Maggie, I'm not gonna
pass this test.
Okay. Look at me.
We're gonna figure this out.
No, no, no. This is on me.
I'm gonna face
the consequences.
Okay.
Have you been guzzling water?
Yes.
Drinking cranberry juice?
Okay, keep it up.
As much as you can handle.
And--and in a few hours,
we're gonna take an
off-the-record drug test,
and we're going to see
where we're at.
Okay?
Okay. Yeah.
But that's the last Adderall
you ever take.
Yeah. Yes.
Okay. Let's get you
out of the cold.
Come on.
.
Excuse me.
Have you seen this woman?
Hey.
Why don't I search upstairs?
Yeah?
♪
Hey. Is your mom
or dad around?
Hey, Stevie,
I didn't see your mom.
Mr. Clemens, what are you
still doing down here?
Marcel.
Dr. Choi made
a very compelling case
to give manual reduction
another go.
I can't believe
you signed off on this.
It's not safe for Dr. Choi,
and if it's not safe
for the doctor,
I assume it's not safe
for the patient.
If anything goes south,
we're both right here.
And if it still doesn't work,
Mr. Clemens
goes straight to surgery.
No harm, no foul.
Oh.
My test result?
Just got the alert.
Let me see.
The Adderall's still present
in your system.
But it has to be a tiny amount
at this point.
It doesn't matter.
It's all over.
I'm gonna lose everything.
Vanessa.
Here.
What's this?
Lasix.
To dilute your urine.
Take it exactly 30 minutes
before you give your sample.
If we're lucky,
it'll make the last traces
of the drug undetectable.
Maggie, I--I can't
thank you enough.
Don't.
If you're just stopping
to pass this drug test--
No, no, no. I'm not.
I'm not.
You have my word.
I'm done with it.
I don't ever want to go through
anything like this ever again.
I'm done.
Oh, my God!
Hey,
just try to relax, Marcus.
Take deep breaths.
Okay. I feel it's starting to
go. I feel it starting to go.
Sorry.
No, no, it's okay. It's okay.
I'm just getting
a bit of resistance.
I need more leverage.
Maybe it's time
to head upstairs.
No, no, no, no.
I just need a better angle.
Whoa, what are you doing?
Too restricting.
Ethan.
I'm good.
♪
There we go.
It's going.
Yes, it's going.
Almost there.
We got it, Marcus.
We got it. We got it.
We got this. Yes. Yes!
Ohh--
That's it.
Hey, good job.
I guess you can
cancel that OR.
We'll give you
a little time to rest,
and then we'll check
back shortly. Okay?
I can't thank you enough,
Dr. Choi.
You take care of your
little one, all right?
Hope it's a smooth delivery.
♪
Gotta hand it to you, man.
Hey, hey, hey.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
You okay, man?
Hey, talk to me.
I'm gonna need an MRI.
Okay.
Oh, that's a big one.
You're gonna feel
a little pinch, okay?
Ow.
Sorry.
Hey. Get away from her.
I'm not hurting her. Promise.
I'm just removing a splinter.
♪
Hey. What do you say
we go get something to eat?
No? Aren't you hungry?
I can't leave Mommy.
Hey. Hey, yo.
We gotta bounce.
Come on, baby.
No, no.
Let me go.
She's not going with you.
Let me go. Mom. Mom.
We don't have time for this.
Just leave her.
Let me go.
Mom! Mom!
Let me go!
I'm sorry.
Mom!
Why the hell did I just get
a call from my father
saying that you've reported
Joe as a threat
to Sergeant Kerry and his wife?
Dylan, I'm really sorry that
I couldn't give you a heads up,
but you know HIPAA.
Do you know
they called him in,
stripped him of his weapons,
and pending an investigation,
he could get
kicked off the job!
And I would feel
absolutely terrible
if that were to happen.
What did he say? Huh?
What the hell did he say
that was so bad
that you had to go
and blow up his life?!
You know
I can't tell you that.
Look, if he was using some
sort of heightened language,
it was all bluster. Okay?
It's a part of cop culture.
Macho talk, you know?
Joe--Joe's rough
around the edges. Yes.
But he's not a danger
to anybody.
But, you know, I got to go
with my instincts.
You need to trust me,
Joe is a powder keg.
And I just couldn't risk
something terrible happening.
I told him
you were gonna help him.
But instead, you destroyed
everything he ever worked for.
♪
.
Thanks again, Rosado.
Yeah.
♪
Police just took her.
They said DCFS already has
a home lined up for tonight.
That's good.
You all right?
Yeah.
I just, uh...
No, I know how that girl feels.
Like this is all her fault.
I shouldn't have left Chicago.
I abandoned my mom.
Hey, this isn't your fault.
It was my job to protect her.
It was my job.
No, that was her job.
She was supposed
to protect you.
Multiple herniated
lumbar discs.
Yeah.
Gonna set him back months.
Poor guy just
can't get a break.
This wasn't some
freak accident.
Katie, would you
excuse us, please?
Say what now?
You should never have
allowed Ethan
to push himself like that.
Navy men are a tough breed.
Sacrifice is second nat--
That's garbage.
As acting chief,
it is your duty
to look out for your doctors.
If they can't say when,
you're supposed to.
Simple as that.
♪
Where you headed now?
Home.
Promise?
Good. I'll see you.
Hey.
I'm glad you were there today.
Did you give your sample?
Yeah.
Well, all we can do
is wait now.
You did everything you could.
It's not in our hands now.
No, wedid everything
we could, Maggie.
Listen, I am so sorry for
how hard I've been on you
these past few months.
For you to put your neck out
for me, it's--
It means a lot. And...
I honestly owe you.
Believe me, Vanessa...
You don't owe me anything.
♪
Mmm. Will.
Hey.
You, uh...
gave me quite the scare.
Yeah.
Yeah. Seemed like you were...
I don't know, looking
for a distraction yesterday.
You got a lot on your mind.
Mm.
Yeah. What is it?
Having a hard time
keeping my eyes open.
Yeah. I should, uh...
let you rest.
Hey, Pop. You heard from Joe?
No. I was gonna ask you
the same thing.
No one's seen him.
He's not picking up
his phone either.
Called him, like,
a dozen times.
Yeah. You stop by
the apartment he's renting?
Just left. Nobody was home.
He took that news
pretty hard, D.
I'm afraid he might
do something to himself.
Yeah. I got you.
Look, I'ma, um, hit a couple
more cop bars, all right?
All right.
I'ma dip out of work.
Stop by Marsha's.
See if she's heard from him.
I love you, son.
Love you too.
Joe, what are you doing?
Sit down. Now.
Hey, hey. Joe.
Joe. No, please.
Now.
Hey, Dad,
Uncle Joe still drive
a '69 Camaro, bright orange?
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up.
Joe,
whatever it is you're feeling,
we can talk it through.
Oh, you want to talk?
You want to talk, huh?
What, like we did this morning?
Huh? You're such a phony.
Do you know that?
You're just like
everybody else,
trying to screw me over!
.
You're gonna
get on your phone.
You're gonna call
the department.
Tell them you messed up,
overreacted, I don't care.
You just get me my life back.
Do you hear me? Hm?
Okay. Okay.
Shh. Shh.
Dr. Charles?
♪
Stop! Stop!
Just stop. Please stop!
I know this isn't
what you were hoping to hear.
No, but it's certainly
not your fault.
Thank you for stopping by,
Dr. Yang.
I'll follow up with my primary.
Okay.
Oh, Dr. Halstead.
I can come back later.
No. It's fine. Come on in.
I just wanted to let you know
that, uh,
my chat with Cooper was a bust.
He was totally out of it.
I didn't make any headway.
Dr. Halstead, I think maybe
we should put this on hold.
Wait. That--that's not what
I was getting at.
I'm fully on board.
No, I know you are.
It's just that I feel
it's taken a toll on us both.
What's going on?
I'm having some trouble
regulating my blood sugar.
We added an oral to my regimen.
But unfortunately,
it hasn't helped.
I'm sorry to hear that.
What are they thinking?
Well, given that my
cortisol levels are high,
they're concerned
that it might be--
Stress?
Yes.
Look, I got it from here.
I'm sorry, Dr. Halstead.
But I'm just not willing
to let you take that risk.
♪
Dr. Marcel.
Does this approach
usually work for you?
Just pushing docs
to their edge, past their edge?
'Cause I saw how it worked
for a colleague today.
And it doesn't.
I'm sorry to hear that.
I want to learn from you,
Dr. Blake. I do.
But not if I have to--
Pay a price?
Give something up?
Oh, you will, absolutely.
But it's the cost of not
giving everything you've got,
of not pushing past that edge,
that's what keeps me
up at night.
And I suspect you and I
are cut from the same cloth.
Check your email. Got a kidney
transplant at 6:00 a.m.
Uh, listen, um...
I apologize
for coming at you earlier, man.
I just never thought that
Uncle Joe was even capable of--
I get it.
You have
a long history with him, right?
And it can be difficult to...
see people you're close to
in a certain light.
You were right to report him.
I talked to Marsha,
and he was making threats
against the sergeant.
I mean, that's partially
why she kicked him out.
Thanks again, by the way,
for not pressing charges.
Hey, that's the last thing
someone going through a mental
health crisis needs, right?
I mean,
I'm just glad it looks like
he's gonna get
the right kind of help now.
Yeah.
Sit down, will ya?
I think that you're
in a tough spot, right?
You're--you're straddling
these two worlds, right?
And you got loyalty to both.
It's--it's just
a tricky tightrope to walk.
You know, back when I was
a cop, all that behavior,
that tough guy stuff,
it was normalized.
Yeah, well, like I said,
I think--I think you should
take it easy on yourself.
Will. Hey.
Hey.
Um, I wanted to ask you
this morning,
but it seemed like
really awkward timing.
I was wondering, there's a tree
lighting happening downtown.
My niece Holly
is singing carols
and I thought, I don't know,
I thought maybe you'd want
to come with me.
Well, it's just you mentioned
that your mom used to
take you to see the lights,
and I thought,
in the spirit, it'd be great.
Yeah.
Let's go cheer Holly on.
Okay. Yeah.
Dr. Choi.
Thank you, Daniel.
I heard about what happened.
Have you talked to Dr. Abrams?
I have. And, uh...
after reviewing
all my options,
I've decided to have
the multilevel spinal fusion.
Oh, wow.
So I'm guessing you'll need
a little longer to recover.
Unfortunately, it'll require
at least two months
of rehab post-op.
Oh, jeez. I'm so sorry.
Don't be. I knew the risks.
It was my decision.
Well, that's
very noble of you.
But you have to
take care of yourself.
So take as much time
as you need.
We'll be thrilled
to welcome you back at Med
whenever you're ready.
Yes?
Yes, ma'am.
All right.
Excuse me.
Ah.
Thank you.
Have a good night,
Ms. Goodwin.
All right.
♪
Mom!
I--I took something of yours.
I just needed enough money
to get the van back.
I'll get you the rest.
I promise.
No, no, Mom, no. It's yours.
Keep it.
No, no. It's yours.
Do you want to come up?
No. I--I gotta go.
Go...
Yeah, I'm heading out
for a few months.
I--I got that itch
to be on the road again.
Mom...
♪
Take care.
I love you, Stevie.
I love you too, Mom.
I'm always here.
♪