Previously on Grey's Anatomy...
Kyle Diaz, diagnosed
with relapsing
and remitting
multiple sclerosis.
You and I are a lot alike.
I told him maybe we would go
out when he got back from touring,
and so we've been texting.
Oh. Guitar Hero?
If Jackson can make a case
that April committed fraud,
he's got a shot at getting
full custody of that baby.
I think Jackson's gonna sue me.
I tried to take the high road.
Apparently, the high road is
paved with restraining orders.
The restraining
order was a mistake.
You were my best friend, April.
We should treat each other
the way we did on this paper.
Bailey gave me the
Preminger Grant.
I'm gonna be
miserable without you.
You can figure it out.
You will. You... You should.
I can totally go with her.
You'll be able to see
Sofia whenever you want.
My ex-wife wants to move across
the country and
take our daughter.
It's a six-month suspension
from the residency program.
I tried to save her.
They know that, right?
I wanted to fire you!
I was talked down!
Well, I am sorry
I disappoint you.
That's all, Dr. Warren.
Surgeons are often evaluated
on speed and efficiency.
Did you brush all of them? Yes.
Let me see.
But that doesn't mean
faster is always better.
Good girl. Keep brushing.
Maggie, where's... Yeah.
We're here. Found them.
Where?
They were under my pillow.
Someone crawled into
bed with me last night.
Who's crawling into whose
bed? Is DeLuca here?
Ha! Definitely not.
It's the wrong foot. Aw!
You jump the gun, you risk
making a wrong diagnosis.
You know, we're
becoming like cat ladies,
and the children are our cats.
I'm not a cat lady just
because I stopped having...
Read the room. Yeah.
S-E-X with DeLuca.
We don't always have the
time to think before we act.
Hey, Mommy. Yes?
Why did Aunt Maggie stop
having S-E-X with DeLuca?
Because he couldn't handle
that she was his B-O-S-S.
Do not ever date a man who
can't handle your P-O-W-E-R.
Okay.
They just pick up everything.
Got 'em all. Good job.
And that's what
gets us in trouble.
I can't stand it, you know.
I mean, the other day, I
was sitting in a coffee place,
and I thought, "Huh.
I can be a barista."
Why not?
I was an
anesthesiologist for years.
Now I just wake
people up for a living.
Feels like a less-than-lateral
move, don't you think?
Well, I got to do something.
I'm going stir crazy.
I'm falling so far behind,
I'm losing so much OR time...
You have more experience
than any of the other residents.
Don't panic. You're
already ahead.
It's funny, actually.
You've been a doctor
longer than any of them.
Been a doctor longer than me.
How is that funny?
It's not.
Yeah, it's really not.
God, that coffee sounds
really good right now, doesn't it?
Yeah.
Oh, hey. WOMAN: Hey, yes.
Did you see what
happened in the paper?
No. But you were right about it.
Hi. Sorry. I'm here, I'm here.
No, no, no, no. Hey,
did you want to order?
No, I'm good. And you
have a consult, right?
Yeah, I do. Yeah. Yeah,
so we should probably just...
Yeah. No. Well, how's it going?
It's good.
Penny and I found a place
near Preminger. It's really nice.
Aww. An apartment? Yeah.
Is it small? It has
two bedrooms,
and it's really close to
some really great schools.
You picked schools?
No, I brought these
so that we could decide,
so that we could talk
about the possibilities.
You picked brochures. It
sounds like you're decided.
Uh, she's going to
school in New York?
Well, I mean, if she does,
she would need to
fill out an application,
which, actually, I meant to
talk to... Um, okay. I'm sorry.
We need to take, um,
a big step backwards.
Somewhere, sometime
you heard me say yes to this.
You heard me say,
"Yes, please, Callie,
"take my daughter
across the country."
But I never said that.
I did not. I said we
could talk about it.
No. Callie, what you said was,
"You'll be able to see
Sofia whenever you want."
Okay, that's not what I meant.
I'll "be able" to see her.
I was just excited about
making this move. That's all.
Go. Be happy. Have your Penny.
You're... You're not taking
my daughter with you.
Please stop saying
"your daughter."
But she is my daughter, and
she's yours, and she lives here.
So I don't know why we're
talking about schools over there
and bedrooms and...
I... Why can't she
come visit you?
'Cause that's not... Okay.
That's why we're here.
That... That's what
we're talking about.
That... We are just
discussing what the options are.
That's not what it sounds like.
How's Hot Rock Star?
Filthy as ever. And creative.
I know, right? I've got to keep
coming up with
new names for his...
Oh, no.
What's wrong?
Kyle is in town, and he
wants to take me out to dinner.
I don't understand your face.
Mmm, no. No, I'm not going.
Uh, why not? Free
food with bonus hot guy?
Well, we're doing very well
right now with our fingers,
so why screw with it?
You mean by actually screwing.
This is fun,
but we don't actually
have anything in common.
You know, do surgeons
even date musicians?
He is very chatty.
No, this is Grey. She
wants labs back on her...
No. No.
What now? No.
I just sent something
very filthy...
Well, isn't that the point?
To Meredith Grey. Oh...
Undo, undo! Undo!
Undo! Undo! Undo!
No! There's no undo!
Thanks.
There you are. I know.
And, Dr. Grey, I'm so sorry.
You should be.
Did you get Sheila's labs?
Dr. Grey. What?
Nothing.
Or thank you. You're
a very classy lady.
Hey, Sheila, good morning. Hey.
This is Dr. Edwards. Hi.
She will be assisting me
in surgery this afternoon.
Uh, Sheila Davis.
5-centimeter hepatic adenoma.
Uh, scheduled for laparoscopic
resection this afternoon.
She's off OCPs for...
Could you hand me my purse?
I think I have a
hairbrush in there.
Sure. Trying to look
good for surgery?
Not for surgery. For him.
James is coming today.
Oh, that's great.
Uh, James? My boyfriend.
Ooh. Sort of.
I mean, "Soul mate" is
gross, but, yes, my boyfriend.
I'm finally meeting him
today, and I look like this.
You haven't met your boyfriend?
Not in person. They met online.
A year ago. Oh.
And it's been the
most amazing year.
Only over texts.
Then I told him
about my surgery,
and he said he had to be
here, canceled everything.
That's really sweet. I
know it sounds crazy.
You can get a
lot done in a text.
What am I doing?
I mean, why would I want
him to meet me like that?
He's going to be
expecting my profile pic,
and I don't really even look
that good on my best day.
Hey, you look fine.
And Dr. Edwards
completely understands.
She has a first date
today, too. A big one.
Huge, apparently.
Really? That's so nice.
No. It's still up in the air.
Oh.
Well, we will be back to
prep you for surgery. Okay?
Let's go, Edwards.
Apparently, you got my text.
Oh, yeah. I got it good.
Obviously, it was
not meant for you.
I hope not, because
it sounds so painful.
It was very unprofessional, and
I should have been more careful.
Edwards, you really
should save your energy,
because you're gonna need it.
Can we skip ahead to the
part where this joke is old?
No. Did you really do this?
I have not.
I've... I've... I
was riffing on...
You... Okay.
I'm sorry. I'm confused.
Your son is here? Yes!
We think so. Hers. Or mine.
They said there was a shooting.
Who said... Who
said that? The police.
When they called, we were...
We were at work,
and... And our sons
are at... At home
with the sitter.
The last names are Green and
Cole. Can you just look it up?
I'm here. APRIL: I'm sorry.
I don't see any record here
for either of those names.
I got paged. Gunshot kid?
They said the ambulance
was coming here.
Wait, "Gunshot kid."
That... Is that our kid?
Karev, let's move.
We have an incoming
GSW. Victim's eight years old.
Oh, my God!
Our sons are both eight
years old. Which one is it?
Which one of our
sons has been shot?
Ma'am, we'll know more
soon. But right now...
Right now, we just
need you to have a seat,
and we'll get back to you
when we know something.
Oh, please, let them both be alive.
- Come with me.
Come with me. Come with me.
Guys, I appreciate
that you want to help,
but all I need
right now are Hunt,
Wilson, and maybe
Cardio and Neuro.
So, the rest of you can go.
Don't! No, we have
to see who it is!
Ma'am, ma'am, please stay back.
Eight-year-old male,
GSW to the abdomen.
Stable after 500cc bolus NS.
Who is it? I can't see him.
We're... We're gonna
take care of him.
It's all right. We're gonna
take care of him, okay?
No! No, it's
Brandon! It's Brandon!
Oh, thank God.
Peter! Peter, there you are.
Get him inside.
Coming through.
Brandon, Mommy's
here! I love you!
Ma'am, we've got
him. We've got him.
ET tube in good position.
Breath sounds clear
and equal bilaterally.
Well, does anyone
know what happened?
Was it a drive-by?
Where the hell
was the babysitter?
Hey, everybody, shush!
A GSW to the right
upper quadrant.
Belly is soft.
Okay. I'm gonna need a...
An ultrasound. OWEN: Mmm-hmm.
You know... You know,
let me get in there.
I'll... I'll... I'll do it.
He's a little tachycardic,
but his pulse is strong.
Shepherd, any reflexes?
Spinal shock. The bullet must
have penetrated the spinal cord.
All right, let's get him to
CT. Everyone clear the room.
All right, you heard him.
Thank you and goodbye.
Okay, ready? JACKSON: Okay.
Call us if you need us.
Ready and... On my
count... One, two, three.
Pierce.
We're good, thanks.
Easy.
Sofia's doing really well. You
know, she loves her dance class,
and why would we take her out
of school in the middle of the year?
No, no, no, no. We
wouldn't move her
until after school's
over for the year.
Well, yeah, no. "We"
wouldn't move her anywhere.
Uh, "we" is you and Penny.
You can't do this. You
don't get to just decide to...
I haven't decided anything.
I'm trying to talk to you.
I'm trying to show you that
I've thought out this choice.
But it's not just your choice.
To completely
disrupt our child's life...
Why is it disrupting her life?
You moved three times a
year when you were a kid.
You turned out pretty
good. Why isn't it just life?
I have a consult.
Do you want to look at these?
No. No, I'm good.
He's so little.
Hey, you still have that, uh,
prenatal appointment tomorrow?
Yeah, uh, at 9:00.
Will you, um...
Just let me know how it goes.
Absolutely. Uh, right after.
All right. Appreciate it.
Of course.
Brandon's injuries are severe.
And we're taking him
up to surgery right now.
The bullet hit his spinal cord,
so at the moment
we are evaluating...
Patty. PATRICIA:
Stacy, are you okay?
Were you shot at? I'm so sorry.
I left the room for
just a few minutes.
Were the boys out front?
Did they find the
person who did it?
No.
The boys found your gun.
They were playing with it.
Your gun?
You have a gun?
Yes, I do. But it's locked.
No.
We were just
playing. It went off.
Did I kill him?
No. Peter, no, you didn't.
Peter, Brandon's alive, okay?
And we're gonna take
care of him right now.
All right?
I'm gonna need to talk to you.
Let's go.
We don't know that. Excuse me?
We told that kid that
he didn't kill his friend.
He didn't.
Except we don't
know that. Not yet.
Hey.
Ooh. You all right?
Yeah, I just... I needed a
second. A little kid got shot.
Oh, God.
Yeah. It's just awful.
Okay.
Time's up. Yeah.
How did everything
go with Arizona?
She's not even open to talking.
It's like she's just saying no.
I'm sorry. That sucks.
Did I jump the gun here?
I'm just trying to get all the
ducks in a row so that we can talk,
but it seems like she really
just wants to fight about this.
Am I wrong? Yeah, I...
I can't help you.
There may come a time when I
get to have a say in Sofia's life,
but that's definitely not now.
I'd just make things worse.
So, all I can say is I'm sorry.
That sucks.
Coags and LFTs are normal.
She's ready when the OR's ready.
Great. How are you feeling?
Sheila, what's wrong?
Nothing. He just texted me.
He's here in the hospital,
and he brought irises.
He remembered I loved irises.
It's just... I was
just freaking out.
Okay, well, let's
try to calm down.
Sheila Davis?
Yes. Is he here?
Um...
Yeah.
Hi.
What? Who are you?
I'm James.
Surprise.
No.
I... I... I know this isn't
what you're expecting.
I'm... I'm really, really
sorry about that, but I just...
Oh, my God.
This isn't how I wanted to
do this at all, but when you...
When you told me you were
sick and you needed surgery,
I just couldn't wait.
You catfished her.
No, I... I just
didn't want to...
Get out. Get out.
Sheila, it's... It's James.
Get out! Get out! We
should call Security.
James, let's go.
James. Get out!
I think we should go outside.
I just...
L1 shattered and left
fragments in the spinal canal.
So, his mom just had
a gun laying around.
She said she had it locked up.
The mom should be locked up.
Well, she might be.
It could be involuntary
manslaughter if...
Don't even say it.
It's not gonna happen.
Do you own a gun?
No. No. No, I fix bullet
holes. I don't make them.
I just mean you're in
the Army. I imagine...
Well, you need one in the
Army. You don't need one here.
Meanwhile, every
day, someone's kid
is in an OR with
a gunshot wound.
Every single day.
When are people gonna
learn? It just makes things worse.
And people always say they
need one for protection. They don't.
Unless they do.
I have a gun.
Yeah, right.
I do. I've had one
for a long time.
You have a gun. - Mmm-hmm.
Why?
Just like you said.
For protection.
Have you used it?
No. I haven't
needed to, thank God.
Thank God you haven't
had it used against you.
All right. Can we stop?
There's a kid down
there scared to death
he might have killed his friend.
There are two lives
on this table right now,
so can we just stop the
chatter and pay attention?
Right angle.
Let me just tell him. Yes.
Thanks for holding.
Who's calling?
What happened?
Right.
Sorry? Well, how did you...
Where were you that they
were able to get a gun?
I was...
I left the room for a minute.
For a minute?
It was so fast.
So, but why? Why?
What?
Did you leave your phone
charger in the car or...
Were you texting
or was it the TV?
No! The police already
asked me all this.
Yeah, why were you
gone long enough
for them to unlock a drawer
or a closet or whatever
and pull out a gun and shoot it?
It was your job
to keep them safe.
It was literally your job.
And I was doing my job.
The boys aren't
babies. They're eight.
They go off and
they play together.
I don't have to watch over
them every single second.
They're good boys.
I... I should be able
to go to the bathroom
or warm them up
some mac and cheese
without them
shooting each other.
Dr. Pierce.
I was just making them food!
This wasn't my fault!
Can I get you to take a
look at something, please?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Did they call someone for you?
Is your mom coming?
Uh, Dr. Pierce.
I spent every day for an
entire year talking to him,
and he's just a liar.
Of course, I'm the
idiot who let it happen.
I mean, I told him that I
loved him before we even met.
Who the hell does that?
Well, you were ready
for something good.
Yeah, plus, sometimes
someone can seem
really, really good onscreen.
True. Sometimes too good.
He was so good onscreen.
I know.
Oh, my God. No, no, no.
What... What is he doing here?
Wait. That's your date?
That's the guy you
were gonna do the...
Please don't. I
mean, I wouldn't.
I'm classy, remember?
Hi. What are you... Hey.
Uh, I'm working. I'll...
I'll... I'll walk with you.
I'm, uh, Kyle Diaz.
Hi, Kyle. I feel
like I know you.
What are you doing here?
You said you couldn't
wait to see me.
I said a lot of things.
She did. SHEILA:
This is my life.
I get James and you get that.
You really need to
leave. I'm working.
You know, Edwards, you can
go and catch up if you need to.
See? We get to catch up.
No, we really... I
don't need to catch up.
Uh, you really need to leave
because I need to go operate.
Ooh, can I watch?
See you do your thing? No.
No? No, it's private, okay?
The OR is a private
place, and you can't watch.
I'm working! This
is an OR elevator.
You can't go in here, either.
The OR is a sterile area.
You are not sterile.
You are very, very dirty.
Robbins.
I've been working on the
resident rotation schedule.
Okay.
Yeah, and losing
Warren and Blake,
I mean, soon enough,
it's gonna have an impact.
Yeah.
Um, would you care if you
lost a resident for a few days
while I get things settled? No.
I'll give you two interns.
No! No! Why is it just me?
Why are you taking
my resident away?
Why am I the one that's just
gonna roll over and take it?
And why don't you go
screw someone else over?
Robbins, you might want
to take it down a notch.
Callie's moving to New York.
What?
And she's trying to
take Sofia with her.
Can she do that?
Hey. What are you doing here?
I'm doing it.
You're doing what?
Something other than literally,
literally watching the
clothes dry at my house.
Slow down.
I'm meeting with Don Heller.
Seriously? Yes. Yes.
Look, I have seven years in
anesthesiology. It's perfect.
I can work, help people, earn
money, and get time in the OR.
Everybody wins.
All right. What does... What
does Bailey think about this?
Well, listen, it might
not even pan out. Right.
I mean, why tell her
until it's a real thing?
That's what I thought.
Just keep it to
ourselves. Until we know.
You realize that's a
terrible idea, right?
It's a great idea.
I wish you luck, sir.
I don't see any
residual bleeding.
Can you get a good look?
Yeah.
Definite CSF leak.
We'll need to remove
the entire vertebral body
to decompress the spinal cord, right?
- Mmm-hmm.
Problem is, I'll need to
dissect more of the aorta.
Risking paralysis?
- Is there another option?
- Put him in a brace.
Then he wouldn't be
completely decompressed.
So, we risk paralyzing
him either way.
What are you gonna do?
Do I have time to
talk to his mom?
Both the brace and the surgery
carry some risk of paralysis.
My recommendation
is the surgery.
It's very delicate,
but I would like to try.
My husband's on his way.
Do I have to decide right now?
I'm afraid we can't wait.
Okay. Okay. Um, then
please do whatever you can.
But he'll survive,
either way, right?
Danielle. We're
working very hard.
He'll pull through.
I know he will.
Danielle, will you shut up?
What?
You better hope
he pulls through.
This is not Peter's fault.
He is a child. But the
gun was locked away.
They shouldn't have been in
my room. This is not the time...
Don't you dare get
righteous with me.
That was your house
and your gun and your kid
that knew about it, not mine.
I sent my child over
to your house to play,
and your kid might have
made him a murderer.
Hey. Hi.
I called the sitter.
The kids are okay.
What's wrong? What happened?
Nothing. Nothing.
I just wanted to make sure
they're okay, and they are.
What's wrong with you?
Oh. Okay, you
guys haven't heard.
An eight-year-old came in today,
GSW, accidentally
shot by his friend.
Oh. Oh. Wow.
Anyway, just wanted
to check in, you know?
Okay. Yeah.
Man, I just...
Kids with guns.
Stop that.
We're not doing
this. It's too sad.
Shake it off. We
can be sad later.
We're not talking juvie
GSW during my surgery.
Richard, she offered me visitation
rights to see my own daughter.
Well, I... I'm sure she didn't
mean it that way, Arizona.
How else would she mean it? My
lawyer says it's an indication that...
Your lawyer?
Yes, I have to protect myself.
I know you feel like you do.
But you and Torres have always
figured out this stuff beautifully.
Just slow down. I just
watched Jackson and April...
Yeah, I know. So
did I. It was a mess.
A mess started with overreactions
and misunderstandings.
So, what? Now I'm overreacting?
I'm saying Sofia's too important
not to ask yourself if you are
before you do something
that can't be undone.
You're right. Of course.
You're right. I know.
Retract more cephalad.
Great.
So, what's your deal?
I'll establish vascular
control, and...
No, I meant about your date,
the one you blew off out there.
There is no deal.
- What's your deal?
- Excuse me.
You're not supposed to tell me
to take my time to go see a guy.
You're supposed to tell
me to hurry up and prep.
Can you please do your job
and make my life miserable?
I'm just saying,
after all those texts,
and then that's the
way you treat him?
'Cause the texts are all it is.
Yeah, it's been a few weeks,
and it's good and hot, but...
I know. It's on my phone.
The expectations are too high.
There can only be
disappointment from here.
You don't know that.
I know I am a very
good "on paper" person.
I mean, I shine. I'm amazing.
But when it comes to being
an "in person" person, I...
You said you wanted
to work and not talk,
so can we focus
on the work, please?
I said I didn't want
to talk about sad stuff.
I'm okay to talk
about this stuff.
Graspers.
Although, this is
its own kind of sad.
Hell. I'm in actual
hell right now.
Well, you said to
make you miserable.
Dr. Shepherd, BP is going down.
How's that bone graft coming?
It's out. Sealing
up with bone wax.
It's in the house?
What?
The gun. Where
is it in the house?
It's in a safe place.
I didn't even know it was
there. I want to know where it is.
It's in a box under the bed.
It's under our bed?
That's where we'd need it.
I don't want a gun in my house.
It's my house, too. It
makes me feel safer.
Does it? JO: Have you
seen our neighborhood?
Because you're not safer.
You're more likely to get hurt
because there's a
freakin' gun around. Alex.
I got shot once. You know that.
BP's 60/40.
Starting him on levo.
Once I decompress the
spinal cord, it should get better.
I just... Just let me work.
- Work faster.
You okay?
Yeah. Just watching.
He's hypotensive now.
You'd make a good cop.
You nearly broke
that babysitter.
I don't know what I was doing.
Why did I do that?
I watch my sister's
kids all the time.
And last week, I turned
away for one second,
and my nephew had dumped
an entire bag of flour
on the kitchen floor.
He's three.
And I thought,
"What if that had been
a pot of boiling water?"
I'm not used to this.
Being scared like
this, worrying like this.
They're not even my kids.
Oh, I get it.
They're family.
Family messes you up.
That part's new for me.
Got a minute?
Ben. What are you...
I just came by to, uh...
You know, I...
I had a nice conversation
with Don Heller just now.
You did? Yeah.
I thought I could pick up some
cases as an anesthesiologist,
and he said he'd be
happy to have me...
No, absolutely not.
I said, "Great.
When can I start?"
Ben, no.
I can't sit around that house
for five more months, Miranda.
You're suspended. Sitting
around is the damn point.
I am suspended from the
surgical residency program.
I won't be operating. And I
can stay current in the OR.
I can earn a living.
Nobody's gonna go hungry.
Look, what's it gonna
look like if the staff sees you
sitting in surgery like
nothing happened?
It's gonna look
like I'm working.
It'll make me look like I'm...
You? You?
See, it's always about your job,
what's gonna make
you look good or bad.
Well, what am I supposed to do?
I don't know, but
you're not doing this.
You run Surgery, not Anesthesia.
You're not chief there.
It's not your department.
It's not your call.
Ben, you can do this.
Oh, I know I can.
But if you do,
you better figure out
where you're gonna sleep.
How you doing?
Micro Penfield 4.
Just a few more...
He's in V-tach, rate of 233.
- Paddles!
- No, no paddles.
His spine is completely
unstable and exposed right now.
- We have to.
- If you shock him,
he will move and
he will be paralyzed.
You'll undo all my work.
We'll try and take
him down with meds.
Uh, push amiodarone,
125 milligrams.
Just give me a minute.
Add vaso on top of his pressors.
V-fib. ALEX: Shepherd,
we have to shock him.
Charge to 50. No! If he
moves, he won't walk.
If he dies, he won't
walk, either. Clear.
Amelia, clear!
Just give me... Damn it!
Clear.
Is Sheila okay?
James, Sheila was very
clear. She wants you to leave.
I love her. I
wasn't trying to lie.
Should I call Security?
We talked online every day.
We understand each
other in a way that...
I've never been seen like that
or loved like that for who I am.
Well, not exactly who you are.
Yes. Who I am, not
just what I look like.
So, when she asked
to see my picture,
I... I looked at myself
in the mirror and...
I got scared.
I knew this could
happen. I'm not stupid.
But then, when she
was dying, I had to risk it.
Well, she wasn't dying.
Her tumor, I mean.
It was a benign tumor.
The chances of it killing
her were very, very low.
Excuse me?
Yeah.
You told me you were dying!
Get out. You said you
had a malignant tumor.
You said you were 6'2".
How could you lie
straight to my face?
It wasn't even
your face, you liar.
You said you were dying!
You said you had hair!
I can't believe I fell for
someone so superficial!
A person does not get
to call me superficial...
Are you calling
Security or am I?
I will, and I will handle
Sheila's post-op.
You're done here.
Pardon me?
Edwards, go. Bite the
bullet. Go on the date.
It's better than being
lonely and crazy like me
or having sex with your
phone in the residents' lounge.
Can you not...
Go. And don't text me from it.
You owe me $500!
You owe me a
year of my life back!
God, I told you I loved
you. Stop yelling at me.
So, you do love me.
No, no. I loved a stranger!
Security.
Hmm? Oh.
What is it, Torres?
No, uh... We had a meeting
scheduled for now, but you're busy.
What's it about?
Um, it can wait.
Not gonna get any
less busy, Torres.
Just tell me. I'd rather...
I'd rather wait.
What is it?
I'm moving to New
York with Penny Blake.
I'm leaving Grey Sloan.
Uh, excuse us, please.
Mmm-hmm. Sure.
When?
Well, Penny starts work
in a couple of months,
so first I need to get
some things squared away.
Like a job?
Uh, I already have an offer from
NYU, and Columbia's been calling,
so there's been a
couple of other...
They offered you
Chief of Ortho? No.
Um, it'll be fewer hours. And
Penny's working a lot, so...
And I'm hoping to
have Sofia there.
Ugh. What?
I mean, your career...
You're a chief.
She's a resident.
So, you're giving up your career
to chase tail across the country?
I just wanted to
give you notice.
And I don't need your judgment.
Arizona's already
got that covered.
Hey. Start her on D-5 half. I'll
be back in about a half an hour.
Okay.
Hi. This is Dr. Robbins.
I'm sorry. From where?
Yes, I am.
Yeah, you bet I have a minute.
There's a chance of some
recovery of movement,
but it's very small.
He'll get physical and
occupational therapy
to help him regain some
function, find some new ways...
But he'll never walk again?
I'm sorry. It's very unlikely.
The gun was locked up.
It was supposed to be
locked in a drawer. It was.
I don't know how they...
Kids watch.
They pick up everything you do.
I'm very sorry
that this happened.
Hey.
Brandon didn't die?
No. He didn't.
But he can't walk?
And he can't ride bikes?
Is he mad at me?
If it had been
Brandon who hurt you,
would you be mad at him?
A little. But it was
just an accident.
Right.
So, I want you to
promise me something.
Whenever you feel bad
about this, I want you to say,
"It was an accident.
"I didn't mean to."
I know that.
But you have to know it, too.
So, you got to promise
me you will say,
"I didn't mean to."
We can go now,
right? We're free to go?
Will you promise me that?
Peter, honey, it's time to go.
Thank you.
Well, Brandon's
doing fine. His BP's...
I lived in my car when
I was 16 years old.
Every night, trying to fall
asleep, I would listen to the voices.
People going by, people
who had nothing going on,
nothing going for
them, nothing to lose,
scared to death that they
would break in and take my stuff,
take me.
This gun made me
feel like I had something,
something on them.
But then, today...
That little boy will
never walk again.
Jo, he's still alive.
Barely.
You know, back then, I...
I didn't value my life
all that much, but...
It's different now.
I've outgrown this.
I don't need it anymore.
I don't want it.
I thought we were
getting drinks.
Your exact words were
"Somewhere special."
Come on.
This is, uh... This
is the holy ground.
Also the dirty ground
with the dirty rugs and...
Have they ever
cleaned any of these?
No, they've never
changed anything in here,
the paint or the
rugs. They don't...
They don't really
want to mess with the...
With the acoustics, you know,
or the, uh... Or the mojo.
Every major musician from
Seattle has recorded here.
Hmm?
And now me.
All I wanted was
just to record here,
right here, this...
This very room.
Huh. You know, this is...
This is where I... I feel
the most like myself.
This is the me
that I like the most.
Yeah, I get that. I get that.
The OR's kind of
that way for me.
You know, the feel
of the scrub brush,
the smell of the
antiseptic, it's just...
The air changes
when you walk in.
It gets cold.
You can feel your mind sharpen
as you step up to the table.
Yeah, it's like... Like
you turn it up a notch.
Or a bunch of notches.
Like you get charged.
Yeah, right.
Okay.
I like it. Okay. Whew!
Thank you. Thank you.
Come on.
What is this? What
is this "come on"?
Aren't you gonna
play something for me?
Oh, you want me to play for you?
Isn't that your move? Don't
you play for all the girls?
Hey, it's my life.
You know, when I'm playing,
it's how I let someone in,
let someone see...
Okay, it's my move, right? Yeah.
It's my move. But it
always works, though.
Yeah, I bet.
You want me to play for you?
Kyle, you don't need moves.
Okay. I'm ready. Let's go.
I just want to go see the kids.
I did something very good today.
I pushed two hearts together.
I forwarded the cause of love.
What's wrong? What's wrong?
I... I don't know
how you do it, Mer.
Do what?
Love your kids like this.
I really love them.
They love you, too.
No, I love them like...
If something happened
to them, I would die.
Like, my heart is so wide
open, and they're so fragile.
I don't know how you
live like this. I don't.
It's awful.
Sometimes, you just
have to push through it,
push the awful aside,
just get through the day.
Hey. Hey.
I think you saved
that boy today.
I paralyzed that boy today.
I was too slow.
No, I meant Peter.
Nathan...
Nathan cheated on my sister.
I know. I, uh... I...
And when she found out,
she called. She told me.
And I said...
I said,
"Just forget about
him. Walk away.
"Just get on a chopper
and come to me."
I told my sister to
get on that helicopter.
I did it.
And
that was the last
thing I ever said to her.
You didn't mean to.
Hey.
Got a late one, huh?
I do.
Everything okay?
I wondered if you wanted to
go in the morning to the OB.
Of course I do. Yeah.
Good.
Baby should know
that you're there.
I will be there.
Uh, 9:00 a.m.? Sure.
Hey, there he is.
Glad to see you, man.
Glad it all worked out.
Yep. Yep, it worked out.
Once we fire that first
shot, we're committed.
God, she was so little.
You remember when
Sofia was in here
and you could... See her
heartbeat in her whole body?
God, how impossibly
tiny she was.
I can't believe our
girl was ever that little.
There's almost no
way to take it back.
I jumped the gun. I'm so sorry.
I was carried away
when I first told you.
And I've done
everything wrong since.
Sofia is our little girl,
and I am not trying to
make plans without you.
Please believe that.
The Barton School called me.
They wanted to talk to
me about her application,
which they loved.
They called you?
So, tell me that part again about
how you're not making plans?
You know how these things
work. There are waiting lists.
It doesn't mean that I
actually tried to make...
We're not talking
about this anymore.
Hey, you don't get to
decide that. I'm going.
I don't want to
leave Sofia behind,
so we have to
work out something.
Yeah, I just mean that you're
not talking to me about it anymore.
The question becomes
do we keep firing back...
You got a lawyer?
Yeah. You can talk to her.
You hired a lawyer.
Yes.
Now who's jumping the gun?
You started this.
All right.
And declare an all-out war?