The best gift I ever got was
for Christmas when I was 10:
My very first suture kit.
I used it until my fingers bled,
and then I tried to use
it to stitch up my fingers.
Thank you for meeting me.
You're the chief of
surgery. If you page I'm here.
It put me on the path
to becoming a surgeon.
I want to say something.
I need to say something
about what happened the other
night. I need you to know it wasn't...
Well, it isn't what you think.
Oh, I don't think anything
about your personal life, sir.
I had a problem,
a long time ago.
I was diagnosed with
alcoholism. Or I diagnosed myself,
and I didn't take a
drink for almost 20 years.
But I think it was
a misdiagnosis.
I'm not saying my drinking
wasn't bad, because it was.
But there is such a thing
as... situational depression,
and I think that's what
I was suffering from,
and it escalated my drinking.
Situational depression?
- Your mother.
- Yes, she escalated
my drinking too.
Have you told anyone what
you saw? Have you told Derek?
No. No.
Since I took a step
back from surgery,
I've had some time to
really look at our residents.
And your work,
your raw talent...
is extraordinary.
A lot like your mother's.
And since I have some
time, some extra time, um...
maybe you would like a mentor.
Maybe I could teach
you some things.
Have you ever done a two-layered
continuous suture for an anastomosis?
My point is,
sometimes the best gifts come
in really surprising packages.
No.
Take a seat.
You're about to.
Wait.
Oh, it's Teddy. I love
it when it's Teddy.
OK.
Don't you think it's strange
he's mentoring you at night
and still not talking to me?
Since the merger, it is
impossible to get OR time.
- And who is
responsible for that?
- That's what I'm saying.
- I need all the help I can get.
- I say he is using you
to get to me.
- He is not!
- Then why now?
Why are you suddenly
seeing so much of him?
I'm done talking about this.
If you want to stay mad, stay mad,
but I'm just gonna be here kissing you.
Oh, my God! That is the biggest
pseudoaneurysm I've ever seen.
It's at the suture line of the
transplant. Her new heart is dying.
- Damn it!
- Poor guy that brought her in,
I think they were
on their third date.
Doesn't look like
a heart anymore.
That's because it's not.
It's a chunk of useless flesh
that has to come out right now.
You're taking the heart out?
What are you gonna replace it with?
I don't know.
We're gonna have to
figure it out as we go.
OK, wait, let me get this
straight. You removed her heart?
- Yes.
- - And she can live that way?
Like, what? Like a vampire?
Usually you'd connect a
ventricular assist device to the heart,
but since she
doesn't have a heart...
Dr. Altman attached
two, um, devices
to her blood vessels.
This machine now pumps
the blood through her body,
which is basically,
um, a miracle.
I really like her... I like her a
lot, but we've only had four dates.
I'm supposed to have Thanksgiving
with my family, you know?
She was gonna join us,
and now she's like a...
She can really
live without a heart?
If you don't want to stay, we have
a great nursing staff, great doctors.
She'll be in good hands.
No, you know? She
doesn't even have a family.
And if it was me, I would want
somebody here, so I'll stay.
OK.
Tucker and Little
Tuck are both fine.
I know, I'm sorry I have to work
today and on Christmas this year.
Yeah, Tucker and I were hoping
to bring him home to visit you.
Mom, um, I have to go.
Happy Thanksgiving, Mom.
You didn't tell your
parents about the divorce?
How long are you
gonna keep that a secret?
When you started dating women,
how long did you keep that secret?
- OK.
- What?
When did the bleeding start?
This morning. He's
had these before.
I just... I've never seen a
nosebleed go on like this.
There's blood on Timmy, Mom.
Mr. and Mrs. Jacobsen,
can I see you?
Go ahead. We'll be fine.
Nicholas has what is called
an arteriovenous malformation.
A cluster of tangled blood vessels in
his brain, what's causing the bleeding.
In order to stop the bleeding,
we need to remove it.
You mean like
brain surgery or...?
I'll do everything I can to protect
the brain tissue and minimize damage.
I'm sorry. I know it's scary,
but we have to go in right away.
Excuse me.
I'm looking for Dr. Mark Sloan.
Um, see the dude who was
burned trying to deep-fry a turkey?
Sloan's the guy making
him scream like a girl.
- Dr. Sloan?
- Yeah.
Hi. Uh, so this is a
little weird, but, um...
my name is Sloan Reilly, and
my mom's Samantha Reilly.
And, um... I'm pretty
sure you're my dad.
Hi. How's it, uh...
going in here?
- Great.
- Fine.
OK. So...
have we broached the
question about the paternity test?
'Cause I brought supplies.
She's 18. That's not very
much younger than me.
It's not that shocking, actually. The
way Mark got around before he met you?
There could be a gaggle of
Sloans. Sloan Jones, Sloan Smith,
Sloan Sloan.
Mean.
Oh, damn it.
Son of a bitch.
I can't access the feeders.
So what does that mean?
It means I can't get at it.
I can do a temporary fix.
But once he starts
bleeding again, which he will,
there won't be
anything we can do.
So we're just gonna
send him home to die?
Happy Thanksgiving,
Jacobsen family.
- Nice day.
- A little chilly.
Yeah.
- It's brisk, though. It's not cold.
- Right.
Look, Teddy...
No. I know.
I don't... I don't understand.
You said that he would
die without the surgery,
and now you're telling us we're
supposed to just take him home?
Well, I've stopped the
bleeding temporarily,
but the only way to remove the
AVM safely is through the sinus.
Why don't you do that?
There are no instruments that
can maneuver through a nasal cavity
this small and get
the appropriate angles.
Why not? Who does that?
Who invents those things?
Mark.
Now might be a good place
for you to say something.
Out loud.
Dude, are you, like,
high or something?
- Sloan...
- Yeah!
- Yes?
- Heh. Mark,
I need you on something.
I have a daughter, Derek,
an 18-year-old daughter.
I am too young to
have an 18-year-old.
It's a nail in my coffin. It's
like death has come to call.
OK, can we put a pin in your
existential crisis for a minute?
No. That's why
they call it a crisis.
Dr. Robbins and I have a
six-year-old with an inoperable AVM.
We need your help
to make it operable.
This is the best
Thanksgiving ever.
No obnoxious relatives,
no stupid traditions.
No going around the table and
saying what you're grateful for.
I think we should do the opposite:
talk about what we're not grateful for.
- The merger.
- The Mercy Westers.
They're like the plague. I
mean, stealing all our surgeries,
eating all that pie
in the nurses station.
- You're doing that wrong.
- I am not.
You are. Can I show you?
Private lessons with the chief.
Man, those daddy
issues are working for you.
I don't have daddy
issues. He's teaching me.
- You're his bitch.
- In that case,
you're Teddy's bitch.
Maybe that's my
problem. I'm nobody's bitch.
You were Izzie's bitch.
- You're the bitch.
- You know what? It's Thanksgiving.
- Can we just have
no name-calling?
- Yeah, please.
Just... Show me
that stitch again.
- Hey!
- Hey.
Hey.
- Hi.
- Hello.
Welcome. Happy
Thanksgiving. Who wants wine?
- I do.
- No, you don't.
Um... Hey, everybody.
Well, the results are in.
It, uh, turns out Sloan was
right about her parentage.
I am her dad.
So here's another
thing to be thankful for.
Lexie, Sloan here is gonna
move in with us for a little while.
- Oh, my God!
- Oh!
Ouch.
Just ease up.
Let the suture do
the work for you.
It's like a dance, you know.
You let the needle be
the man, let it take the lead
and let your hand just follow.
Look at that. I haven't
seen skill like that since...
since your mother. That
woman, she could dance.
You should make up with
Derek. It's Christmas, it's time.
You need to take perpendicular
bites, about a millimeter apart.
- How's it feel? Still tingling?
- Oh, it's fine.
- I pretty much have
full sensation.
- Great. Good.
So... Have you...?
I mean, you think you can ask
her how long she's planning to stay?
Mark, it's been a month,
and you've exchanged
three sentences with her.
Two of them were,
"Pass the cereal."
In the spirit of the holiday,
maybe you can ask her yourself.
She's pretty easy to like
once you get to know her.
Really?
No. She's a vapid, vapid girl,
but she's your daughter, OK?
So try. OK? Try to be her dad.
Go.
What are you looking
at, you old perv?
- Dad!
- Merry Christmas.
- Your mother sent me.
- Oh. You heard.
Your cousin said something to
her husband in front of your niece,
who said something to your younger
niece who said something to your mother.
- I was planning
to put a tree up...
- And where's Tuck?
He's back East with Tucker's family.
He was with me for Thanksgiving.
So it's true. You
are getting a divorce.
It's weird.
No heartbeat.
I used to climb
mountains, you know.
One time I did the Inca Trail.
It's four mountains in three days.
The second day there was this
climb, it's eight hours straight,
and you are so tired and the
air is so thin, you don't even talk.
All you do is climb.
And it's just you
and your breathing
and your heartbeat
pounding in your ears.
It's just hard getting
used to no heartbeat.
And I'm getting tired.
Really tired.
I know.
You know what? You just need
to hang on until New Year's Eve.
There's a lot of drunk drivers, a
lot of brain death. It's organpalooza.
Kelsey, you just
gotta hang on, OK?
You'll hike again, you know?
We'll hike together.
It's such a beautiful
world outside this hospital.
It's snowy and quiet, cold.
And perfect.
So, you know, you just gotta
make it until New Year's Eve.
- I need to go outside.
- What?
I might die, we all know
that. I might die really soon.
But snow is my favorite
thing in the whole wide world.
It's my favorite thing.
Please.
Please, OK?
- I'm sorry, but...
- We can do that.
We can do that.
I wanna bolt. I want to quit, I
want to... go back to New York
or... I don't know, Arkansas.
Somewhere no one
can come looking for me.
I don't know how to talk to her. I
don't know what she wants from me.
It's the guilt, you know?
It's how every time
I look at her I just...
The guilt is like a punch
in the gut every day.
Well, you shouldn't feel
guilty. You didn't know.
I did know.
I knew when her
mom got pregnant.
She told me. I gave her a couple
hundred bucks and I left town.
I never saw her again. I
figured she got an abortion.
Hoped.
But I did know.
Well, you're a different guy
now. You're not 18 anymore.
You've grown up.
You're capable of better.
Nicholas is back in the ER.
He's got a nosebleed, bad.
I've tried to stop
it for an hour.
We can't operate.
We're not ready.
Then I'll admit him and keep
transfusing 'til the equipment's done,
which is gonna be soon, I hope?
Um, hello. Are you Bailey's...
I mean, Miranda's dad?
William Bailey.
You can call me Bill.
OK. Hi, Bill.
I'm Callie Torres,
I'm a friend of Bailey's.
She mentioned that she snuck you
in here, said I should come say hi.
- So what's that
she's doing down there?
- That's a hernia repair.
We get a lot of
hernias at Christmas.
Lots of people lifting trees
or heavy gifts or Santa bags.
It's... We get a lot of broken
bones, too, 'cause of the weather.
Oh, I had this,
uh, this guy earlier,
he got an electric shock
from some Christmas lights.
The shock was so big that
it broke both of his wrists.
- Whoa.
- Yeah.
- Anyway,
I'm dating women, and...
- I'm sorry?
Oh, I'm... I recently
started dating women,
and my family had a really
hard time accepting that.
But, you know, we worked
through it, and, um...
Bailey said that you're having
a hard time with her divorce,
which I totally
understand, but I...
I wanted to say that she didn't
come to that decision lightly.
And she's a good person, and...
Merry Christmas.
Did Hunt ever tell you about
the time that he made snow?
No.
His guys were feeling
the holidays pretty bad,
so Hunt orders one of those
snow makers on Christmas Eve.
He tries to get the thing going, but the
minute the snow hit the sand, it melts.
So Hunt blindfolded his guys
and made them put their faces
right up to the snow blower.
There was this one
kid from Minnesota,
he actually cried and he said it
felt exactly like Christmas at home.
Ooh, Hunt.
Hunt's so delicious when
he's tending to bloody soldiers.
- Love me some Hunt.
- Shut up!
So, how was the view?
I have been a proud father.
Your whole life, I have
been a proud father.
Your mother and I sat in the
front row of every dance class,
every oboe recital,
and we cheered.
We sat in the front
row of every graduation.
I was always the first one on my
feet and the loudest one in the crowd.
I have been a proud father.
And today, Miranda,
I sat in the gallery
and I watched you repair
some fat man's hernia,
and for the first time in my
life I felt ashamed of you.
This is what you
do on Christmas?
For this you traded
your husband?
your child's family?
So you can work all day and
go home alone on Christmas
to an empty house,
without even a tree?
I have been a proud father...
Miranda, but I would be a bad father
today if I didn't look you in the eye
and tell you that you have
made a terrible mistake.
You broke your family,
you set your son up to fail.
And the child I raised...
she was raised better than that.
That's something you
don't see every day.
She could code, or the
monitor could short out.
Teddy's a brilliant surgeon, but I
don't get how she made this call.
I get it. It's patient care.
And Teddy's always been
a sucker for Christmas.
Oh, my God! Kelsey!
From your X-rays and CT, it looks
like part of your bowel has died.
It's a side effect of your poor
circulation, it's why you collapsed.
Just fix her, OK?
She can't have come
this far to... Just fix her.
We're gonna need to repair
this as soon as possible.
The more time we wait,
the more bowel dies.
But how? She's septic,
hypotensive, and she has no heart.
Her pressure's too low for general
anesthesia. She won't survive.
Then... we won't put
her under general.
This goes through the nose,
through the base of the skull,
and then I drill the bone off.
Well, what happens
once you drill the holes?
We put miniature staple
clips on the vessels.
- With what instrument?
- We don't have it. Not yet.
But we will, we will. We're, uh,
still trying to figure out how to build it,
but we're on it.
I would like an invitation to
your home for Christmas dinner.
I know it's very late for me to
be asking for such an invitation
given that it is, in
fact, Christmas Day.
However, I have a
very worried father,
and if I don't look like I have
some sort of life, he'll never leave.
I have a bowel
infarction to repair,
and then after that I'll be
free to come to your home.
- Sounds fine.
- Oh, absolutely.
- Thank you.
- Chief cut off funding
for equipment.
- What?
We're way over budget.
Nicholas is running out of time.
We want our bonuses to go
towards finishing the prototype
- for Nicholas Jacobsen.
- Sorry, you can't do that.
- But it'll be like a donation.
- They're our bonuses.
There are no bonuses,
that's what he's trying to say.
There are no bonuses
this year. I'm sorry.
Merry Christmas.
I'll write a check. How much?
- I'll split it with you.
- Thank you.
I have a teenager. What if
she wants to go to college?
- Have you met her?
- Fine, I'm in.
Thank you. I'll get back
to you with numbers. Shep.
Chief?
I'm sorry I tried to fire you.
And in the spirit of the
holidays, I was, uh...
I'm sorry.
You're not serious. You got
him a snow globe of Seattle?
What? He likes Seattle.
I gave you fifty bucks.
Where's my change?
Um... Ahem. Mark?
Your kids are bickering.
- Have you talked to her yet?
- I'm working on it.
Your sister's got a
ready-made family there.
Don't worry, she didn't forget
about you. She invited you, right?
He's drinking.
Isn't he? Richard?
He's off the wagon.
Well, he's drinking
egg nog. It's Christmas.
Everybody drinks
egg nog at Christmas.
Some people do.
Recovering alcoholics don't.
He's not an alcoholic.
That was a misdiagnosis.
Is that what he's telling you?
Meredith, he is a surgeon
and he is drinking and...
he is an alcoholic.
That could quickly
become catastrophic.
Were you drinking
when I was a kid?
When you left me with my mother and
got another family and never looked back?
No.
No, I didn't start
drinking until much later.
Well then, we can't blame the
world's evils on alcohol, can we?
Oh, yeah!
- It hurts.
- I know.
Surgery with only a local
anesthetic is not ideal.
Hang in there.
OK, you're OK.
It's gonna be OK. I'm
here with you, all right?
Hey, hey! No tears.
No tears at Christmas.
No, it's only, uh, lights...
and snowmen and...
songs. Um...
Come on, now.
- Karev.
- No, thanks.
- Sing, Yang.
- No, I don't... I'm Jewish.
Don't play the race card with
me. Sing or get off my service.
You too, Karev.
The house looks beautiful.
- Thank you.
- Callie?
- Working.
- That's too bad.
- Here, you need some stuffing.
- Thanks.
- How did Kelsey do?
- Well.
- Who's Kelsey?
- Uh, girl with no heart.
I have to do a
laparoscopic bowel repair
while the poor thing
was awake on the table.
Miranda, mind your manners.
Even if surgery
is your whole life,
it doesn't mean you
have to talk about bowels
at the dinner table.
My child is healthy.
- Excuse me?
- He may not be with me tonight,
- but he's healthy
and he's well-loved.
- I didn't say he...
He's a well-loved boy
and he's a happy boy
- and staying in an unhappy marriage...
- Now is not the time or place...
a marriage that I've outgrown,
a marriage full of ultimatums
and numbness and resentment.
- Miranda!
- That is not the kind of life
I want to model for my child!
That is not what I want him
to believe married love is.
Look, I know what's possible,
I know what's out there for
me because you taught me well.
You and Mom showed
me what true love looks like.
So I chose not to settle
and I'm happier for it,
even if I'm alone at Christmas.
My child is healthy
and I'm happy.
You know, part
of my happiness is
the fact that I got to
repair a woman's bowel
and save her life today.
And that's God's work,
which makes this appropriate
Christmas dinner conversation.
I'm happy, and
my child is healthy,
and that's enough for me today.
Dad, that's enough.
- Uh, green beans, anyone?
- Thank you.
Thanks.
OK, here I would
advise a one-hand tie.
- OK, why don't I talk
and you operate?
- Good.
Last night was my last drink.
- The shaking will stop soon.
- Good. Good for you.
That doesn't mean I have to quit
drinking tequila. I really like tequila.
- It's New Year's Eve.
- I know.
She shows no signs of leaving,
no suitcase packed, nothing.
Talk to her right now
or no more sex for you.
So, what you reading?
I can tell you
don't really like me,
and, uh, your girlfriend's,
like, totally freaked out by me
'cause I'm kind of,
like, hotter than her.
But... I'm pregnant. Yeah.
I'm having a baby and, um...
That's why I dropped out of school
and why my mom kicked me out.
Look, I know you
don't owe me anything...
but I can tell you guys
are about to kick me out,
and I... I...
I don't have
anywhere else to go.
Shh! Shh, shh...
It's OK. You're gonna be OK.
OK, he's in hypovolemic
shock. He's lost too much blood.
We're gonna have to put a tube
down his throat to help him breathe.
- Nicholas?
- We need to tube him right now.
Don't tube him. Bag him
until we get to the OR.
- The OR?
- We finished the instruments.
- We did?
- We're gonna operate.
I just need you to
sign the consent form.
- Pretty dramatic timing,
Dr. Shepherd.
- I like to make an entrance.
It's OK.
Her kidneys are shutting down.
We need to find a donor. We
needed to find one yesterday.
It's New Year's Eve, Dr. Yang.
You said I just had to
make it to New Year's Eve.
Drunks all over
the road, so, yeah.
Tonight's our best shot.
- How's it handling?
- It could bend
a little more gently.
Don't be all critical. The
thing cost me a fortune.
At least one more
day to practice.
OK. Inserting the clip applier.
Why don't you try torquing it a
little bit, give it a different angle?
There you go.
OK. There it is.
- They're open.
- OK.
Got it. That's the last clip.
- Oh, my God.
- Ladies and gentlemen, we're done here.
- Nice work. Beautiful.
- Oh, my God,
you did it.
Amazing.
Hang on. Look at the clock.
That's seven, six...
Five... four...
Three... two... one...
Happy New Year!
- Happy New Year!
Happy New Year.
I'm just gonna take a listen.
- We're hitting the final wave.
- I need to talk to you.
- I'm heading into the...
- Now.
- What is wrong with you?
- You.
- Me?
- Yeah, you come over here...
- Why did you tell me this now?
- Why do you even care?
You didn't say a thing all those
times, all those years, so why now?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
What does it matter to you? You
never felt the same way for me.
Of course I did!
Of course I did. I had all those
feelings for you, Teddy, for years,
- but you never
gave me anything.
- You were engaged...
- You never gave me
one damn hint!
You idiot.
I have loved you forever.
I have loved you
when I was coupled up,
when I was single.
I have loved you every
second of every day.
- Teddy...
- I love you. I'm in love with you.
I'm in love with Cristina.
You paged me?
I just confirmed a brain
death on an 18-year-old female
involved in a head-on MVC earlier
this evening. She's a match for Kelsey.
So I called UNOS, and they gave me
the go-ahead for a directed donation.
Dr. Bailey will do the organ
recovery and I set up OR 2 for Kelsey.
That is why New Year's
Eve is my favorite holiday.
Stop it! This is not a
celebration. Come here.
No! No, no, no, not my baby.
Please, not my daughter.
This is not a celebration.
No! No!
Your kidneys have stabilized
and your vitals are stable,
and everything looks great.
Feel.
- Awesome, huh?
- I can only feel your boob.
Hey!
- You want to feel?
- Uh, no, but I will listen.
- Oh, my God! What are you doing?
- What are you doing?
I know it's only been
a couple of months...
And four dates. It's
technically been four dates.
You amaze me every day.
And we went through a war
together, we went through this together,
and we came out the other side.
And I think if we
can get through this,
we can get through anything.
So marry me.
Please.
Yes, of course!
I'm...
insensitive sometimes. Um...
But I'm not oblivious,
and I don't want you to be with me
because you feel like you owe me
because you two
went through war...
I want you. I want you
because I want to be.
I want you because I love you.
Are you sure?
Every day we get
to give the gift of life.
It can be painful,
it can be terrifying.
But in the end, it's worth it.
Every time.
We all have the
opportunity to give.
Maybe the gifts aren't as dramatic as
what happens in the operating room.
- So how was New Year's Eve
at Tucker's?
- It was fine.
I kissed my grandson at midnight
East Coast time and tucked him into bed.
OK. Uh, so you're
headed home today?
- Mom's picking you up
at the airport?
- Yeah.
I, uh...
tucked you in every
night of your childhood.
- Dad...
- I tucked you in,
and I kissed you good night
and I checked under
the bed for bad guys.
And you went and grew up
and got yourself a divorce...
and didn't bother to tell me.
Dad, I didn't know
how to... explain.
I didn't want to disappoint
you. I didn't want to be judged.
I'm your father.
Can you imagine if Little Tuck grew
up and got a divorce and didn't tell you?
Then I'm sorry, Dad.
I'm... I'm so sorry.
Maybe the gift is to try
and make a simple apology.
I'm never judging you.
I'm worrying about you. Your
mother and I worry about you.
That's all.
Little Tuck, he's a
real spitfire, isn't he?
- He is.
- He sure is.
He doesn't seem too
much worse for wear.
Maybe it's to understand
another person's point of view.
Hey. I'm sorry that I paged you.
He's pretty public here,
and I know what that
can do to his career.
I didn't know what else to do.
Maybe it's to hold
a secret for a friend.
The joy supposedly
is in the giving.
Meredith!
Happy New Year.
She's my star pupil, Joe.
She's my little star.
And I'm so proud of her.
I am so very proud.
She will be a brilliant surgeon.
Brilliant.
Just like her mother.
So when the joy is gone...
Get Dr. Grey a
drink, Joe. Tequila!
When the giving starts to feel more
like a burden, that's when you stop.
And, um... I will have
another... club soda.
But if you're like
most people I know...
And it's on me. On me.
You give till it hurts.
And then you give some more.