The harder the hit,
the more it'll sting.
That's usually the case.
So we prescribe.
Meds, ice,
compression, elevation.
Things you do to stop
the immediate pain.
You left early this morning.
Yeah, 'cause I love
it here so much.
I had to open,
plus it looks good.
- Is that what the lawyer said?
- Supposed to establish that
I'm a valuable member
of the community.
You know, to counteract the
fact that I ruined DeLuca's face.
I meet with them
today. Strategy session.
They say it's make or
break, whatever that means.
But you can only dull
the pain for so long,
and when the drugs
start to wear off...
it really hurts.
Thank you for offering to help.
I love you, and I feel for you.
Solidarity and all of
that, but this is scut.
Don't think for one
second you're getting points
for arriving before me.
Things you didn't
do yesterday...
refill the glove dispenser,
check the auxiliary
thermometer batteries,
- stock oral swabs.
- I'm out.
And what, you think
this is a place to...
to hang out with your friends?
You do realize we open in
20, so you gonna sit there
and admire me, or do
you want to get to work?
It's a big thing for
me not to know.
What is? Which one?
The church one...
that you go to church.
You go to AA.
That's a lot of praying.
What are we gonna
tell the children
about God and
the afterlife or...
Wait, the children?
- What children?
- Our children.
So we're having children now?
No! How can we have
children? I barely know you.
You know, I had a thought.
You and I should...
hang out together.
You know, somewhere
that isn't here.
Like, uh...
- A movie?
- No.
Maybe I could
just show up there,
and then you show up,
and hey, look,
we're hanging out.
I don't hang out.
You could.
Come on. We're in the clear.
Pierce asked me out.
I let her down gently.
We could try.
There's no trying.
We are not that type of friends.
All right, well, what
type of friends are we?
I'm leaving.
It's progress.
Sorry I'm late. What do we have?
Jackson...
- Dr. Avery!
- Yeah, I'll get her.
- Hey.
Just, um, catching up.
Tough night with Harriet?
She got up like six times.
- Or maybe seven.
- Ohh.
Does it count if she wakes just
as we're putting her back down?
"We"? What, you and April?
No, you guys... You have
to switch off, take turns.
Yeah, I know. We are, totally.
I mean, kind of.
It's just, you know, she's
recovering from surgery,
so every time it's
her turn, I still get up
and see how she's doing,
which makes her feel guilty,
so then she tries to come
and help when it's my turn,
and I spend that entire
time trying to convince her
that she needs to get
rested up for... for her turn.
Which you then get up for, too.
It's not a perfect system.
But, I'm ready to
work, you know?
I'm just... I'm cranking
away right here.
Yeah, well, um, tell you
what. I'll take point on rounds
by way of the
coffee cart, and...
Or not. Got a trauma
on the helipad.
- You're on your own.
- Yeah, a couple minutes.
Hold that elevator.
Yep. Hey.
You look tired.
Well, I've been up a while
with Amelia talking and talking.
She's yours now. I'm
not taking her back.
I'm good. She's great.
We're... We're great.
You have the rest of
this elevator ride. Go.
You know, she gets
an idea into her head
and she just won't let it go.
She's relentless,
like a... like a shark.
- She just won't put it down.
- Two more floors.
And she asks me a
question and I answer it,
and my answer just
causes more questions,
and suddenly I've forgotten
what we're talking about
and I'm late for work.
And I love her,
and it's exhausting.
- Do you feel better?
- Yeah, a little bit.
Glider plane crashed
near Snoqualmie Falls.
Two passengers, both
conscious at the scene.
Is Polly behind
me? She's my wife.
Is she okay? I need
to see her. Please.
Polly Campbell, 33,
B.P.'s 90 over 40.
Blunt trauma to the
chest and abdomen.
Where's Daniel? Is he okay?
We've got him.
Timir, uh, I wanted
to ask a favor.
Look, I need to leave for
about an hour this afternoon,
but I can be back before close.
I know you consider
this grunt work, Dr. Karev.
It's a far cry from the hallowed
halls of the surgical floor.
I didn't say that.
And I'm sure you're not used
to taking orders from a nurse.
- No, it's fine. I just...
- Oh, is it fine?
Thank you.
This is second Thursday.
Vaccination day.
We're about to get flooded
by hundreds of patients
needing shots on
top of everyone else.
I wouldn't ask if it
wasn't important.
What's important
is our patients.
They can't be rescheduled
like elective surgeries.
They need you here and
so do I. The answer's no.
You figure out your life
on your own schedule.
Clinic's open.
Get the doors.
Pierce, you see this page?
Cardio consult in the pit.
Oh, well, if you're going...
You want to go?
I don't have to go.
No, you... you're already going.
- Why would I go?
- 'Cause you were going.
Well, I'm not,
though, if you are.
- So I'll go.
- And I will not go.
- Excuse me.
- Okay.
Okay...
- I - want to see my husband.
Try and hold still for me.
Is Daniel hurt? Can
you at least tell me that?
He's in the other room
getting checked out.
There's some fluid in the belly.
We're gonna need a
CT. To take a better look.
Was your husband
flying the glider?
It was his first time up
there without an instructor,
and he wanted me to go.
He worked so hard for this.
- SATs are dropping.
- She's gonna need a chest tube.
Please, please tell
me he'll be okay.
I got him, Polly,
but I need to make sure
you can breathe first, okay?
- Okay, how can I help?
- Lido.
Twenty-eight French,
and set up a pleurovac.
Still dropping.
SATs are down to 88.
I've got it. Will you move?
Polly, I'm sorry.
There you go.
- How is he? Superficial
facial lacerations.
But right leg, though.
I'm fine. Please,
go help my wife.
She's asking for you, too.
She's being treated
in the next room.
I'm telling you I'm fine.
I'm gonna need sandbags
and a spinal x-ray.
Okay.
I just want to see Polly.
Daniel, I'm gonna need
to get a spinal x-ray.
- I can't feel my legs.
- Okay, I don't want you
to be alarmed.
No, I mean I haven't
felt them for three years.
I'm paraplegic.
Oh. Well, okay.
Where's Daniel?
I want to see him!
Daniel!
- Owen, stop.
- Sweetie, you there?
Daniel?
I'm here! Are you okay?
- Are you all right?
- Are you okay?
- I'm all right.
- I'm okay, I think.
Polly, I wish I could see you.
- I love you so much.
- I love you, too.
Polly, I'm so sorry!
Polly?
I noticed it a couple weeks ago.
Now it smells kind of funny.
That is one infected abscess.
We're gonna have
to open that up.
What are you doing?
My patient needs an
I&D for his abscess.
Yeah, not by you. Page surgery.
I am surgery.
Not in here you're
not. You do not lance,
you do not drain,
you do not cut.
It'll take five minutes.
You are not authorized to
use a scalpel on anyone.
Page surgery.
I thought you said
you were a surgeon.
I wanted to let you know
that the internal reports
have been completed and filed.
Copies will be mailed to you,
and all your records
have gone to the D.A.
Okay. Thanks.
Uh, one more thing.
While the legal
proceedings are still ongoing,
you are not to
discuss this matter
within the walls
of this hospital.
Don't talk about it to anyone.
- Understood?
- Yeah, I understand.
You know, it won't be
hard not to talk about it
'cause no one talks to me
much now anyways, so...
You know, Dr. Avery's being
called in as an expert, I think.
DeLuca, what'd I just say?
Right. Don't talk to anyone.
Got it.
Pan scan with contrast, please.
How old was I when my dad died?
Sorry?
- Five.
- I was five.
See, you knew that.
But your dad died, too, and
I have no idea when or how.
It hasn't come up.
Well, don't you
think it should have?
Or maybe we didn't
give it enough time to.
We gave ourselves a
two-week engagement.
I think we're okay.
I think I should know how old
you were when your father died.
- It's...
- Almost 10.
He knows?
Hey, sorry.
- What? It's not
a secret, is it?
- No.
- Was that a secret?
- No, no.
It's just she's
worried about stuff
she doesn't need
to be worried about.
Makes it a little more difficult
than it needs to be, right?
Yeah, it's worth it, though.
Definitely.
Scans up?
Nope. Just started.
You're back. I didn't
know you were here.
No, I'm not back.
I'm here early for my
appointment with Dr. Robbins.
Six hours early.
Baby's in the nursery,
so I'm here to finally sleep.
Dibs on the bottom bunk.
Don't you have a bed
of your own at home?
Not my home.
I can't day-nap there
'cause it's cleaning day,
and people are
vacuuming and polishing.
It would feel rude.
You're making very little sense.
You know that
thing they say about
how you're supposed to
sleep when the baby sleeps?
That's a lie!
Babies don't sleep.
- I'd like to sleep.
- At least my baby doesn't.
Except when she does
sleep, then I don't sleep.
- You know why?
- 'Cause you keep
talking to her.
Because I am a guest
in Jackson's house.
And Kepners are perfect guests,
and being a perfect guest...
is a hard job.
Listen, Dr. Kepner, I
empathize, I really do,
but I just spent 16 hours
straight removing a meningioma
and clipping something like a
million back-to-back aneurysms.
And I'm back on Dr. Shepherd's
service in a couple of hours,
so I need my sleep, too,
so I could go cut into
actual human brains, so...
You got to be kidding me.
Well, am I dying?
- No.
- Do I got the cancer?
Good news, Earl. Looks like
you just had beets for dinner.
You're having a natural
reaction called beeturia.
It's where the red pigment
of the beet passes through...
Which means you're fine.
Give this to the
desk on your way out.
This is a clinic, not a hotel.
Bed six... binge drinker.
Her name's Emma.
Frequent flier... in here
once a month. Good luck.
What's the protocol
for underage alcoholics?
Uh, like an adult.
You hydrate her,
give her the pamphlet,
then get her out.
We need the bed.
Finally.
Emma, right? How
you feeling today?
Oh, I'm feeling amazing.
I'm feeling perfect.
Got it all together.
I'm Kendall and Khloé and Kylie
and whatever other
"K" names you got.
Just give me an I.V.
bag, and I'll be on my way.
Headache, nausea,
chills, the spins...
- I.V. bag.
- All right, vitals first
then I decide what
to give you, okay?
Oh, ew... You're new.
Put the I.V. in the left arm.
It's where the good veins are.
Start with a liter of
saline and push it hard.
I'm dehydrated.
And do me a favor.
If you're an intern
or, like, dumb,
get help, because last time,
I was poked about 100 times
and my arm was purple for weeks.
That's good to know.
How are the scans?
Well, it looks like a
grade-3 splenic injury.
- How's the husband?
- He's worried about her.
I'm gonna take
her up for an ex lap.
For that? There's no reason.
There's no active bleeding.
Well, I thought
that, too, but look.
There's stranding and
fullness around the aorta.
If we go in for the spleen,
then we get to have a
better look when we're there.
Right, but there's no
clinical reason for surgery.
Well, there is if we find out
that her aorta is in trouble.
If. That's my point. We
should wait and see.
I can see what you mean,
Hunt, but Grey's right.
I mean, the patient is stable.
Observation just makes
more sense right now.
We do a repeat C.T.
angio in a few hours...
Waiting is definitely
the safer choice.
Well, I disagree.
Oh, so that's it, then?
Two against one? Fine.
She gets checks
every 30 minutes,
and I hope you're both right.
We make quite the team.
I don't need a team.
It's the right call.
This is the wrong call.
You got outvoted by
two smart surgeons.
It happens.
So, why did you join the army?
Okay, why are we doing this?
I feel like I'm in
a job interview.
There's just stuff I don't
know. I mean, it's scary.
We have our whole lives to...
And there's stuff that
you don't know about me.
And what if you don't like it?
What if it's too scary?
How bad could it be?
Hey, hey, really. How bad?
You know what?
Never mind.
It's fine.
When the trocar's
in the amniotic cavity,
that's when we use a
fetoscope. Hey, DeLuca.
Come here.
Freeze.
Tilt your head up.
Chin up. Turn.
Damn. It's beautiful.
You look nice today, too.
Avery did a really great job.
Nice symmetrical eye sockets.
Not even a hint of
residual bruising.
No scars. How are you feeling?
- I'm fine.
- Yeah?
I keep missing you at home.
Avery give you a
clean bill of health?
Yeah, no, I'm good.
And the trial? Any
news of a court date?
- I can't really talk about it.
- You can't talk about it?
- We share a bathroom.
- With anyone.
Okay, it's the Chief's
orders. I'm sorry.
Bed six, Karev.
I have to check on this guy.
Okay, so I have two
more patients' parents
saying they'll be
character witnesses.
Yeah.
I'm trying to get
there. I'll be there.
I'll... I'll try.
Was that your lawyer?
Meeting's supposed to
be at 4:00 if I can get past
Timir the gatekeeper.
- You bring ketchup?
- Ugh, did you wash your hands?
- Why are we here?
- Oh, because Alex is here,
and we want to see
what Alex is up to.
Does Alex have something
he'd like to share with the group?
AA pamphlets?
They're for this
patient, this college kid.
- She's a mess.
- Literature is not
gonna do it.
When you're
addicted to something
and you want it so
badly, a piece of paper is...
It's not gonna
make her stay away.
What would make you stay away?
Say, if you were a
bartender and an alcoholic
and there's alcohol
in front of you
right under your
nose all the time.
Doing cardio surgeries.
Uh, count to five.
If that doesn't work,
get out of there,
remove yourself
from the situation.
So, on a scale
of lots to nothing,
how much would you say
you knew about my brother
when you guys got married?
I'm not getting in
the middle of that.
Why? Did Owen...
I knew Owen would
say something to you.
See? There's something
you know about him.
- Back to my patient.
- Your kid might need an ally.
Someone who's been there,
who can speak the language.
A pamphlet's not gonna
do it. Not that I am offering.
I have my own stuff going on.
Really? This is not
a cafeteria, Karev.
We've got two cases
of strep, your alcoholic.
Your foot guy still
needs his foot done.
- I paged surgery!
- You're in a room
full of surgeons.
One of you guys want to lance
a patient's foot abscess for me?
- Resident's job.
- I'm eating.
I would, but I don't want to.
Yeah. I'm gonna pay for that.
How much longer?
The I.V.'s still almost full,
and I don't have
time to sit here all day.
Hello? I have work.
- Call in sick.
- I can't call in.
Just tell me if I'm looking
at 20 minutes or an hour or...
Oh, my God, I'm
not an alcoholic!
They say you're in here
all the time asking for fluids.
Because I've figured out what
makes my body feel better.
Isn't that what
doctors should want?
I'm making your life easier.
Fine, forget it.
You know what?
You're full of crap.
- Excuse me?
- Look, I may be a doctor,
but that doesn't mean
I never partied before.
- I had one beer.
- Oh, come on.
You're a kid who routinely
comes in here for an I.V.
after a night of partying.
And you're an adult
who routinely uses
"party" as a verb.
- Emma, listen to me.
- You're not listening to me.
- Emma, you keep doing this and
an I.V. isn't your fix anymore.
- Oh, my God.
Because first it's drinking,
then someone gives you a pill.
Next, it's needles.
Before you know it,
you're out on the street
with all the other junkies.
- Is that how
you want it to go?
- No!
On the side of the road
covered in your own puke?
Dr. Karev.
Now, that's enough.
- Okay, listen,
this girl's a drunk.
- No, I'm not!
Step away from that
young woman, right now.
That was good. It was
very good. Very convincing.
Yeah? I think I
was a little harsh.
It was just right.
You were a jerk. She and
I have a common enemy.
- How much time do I have?
- About half an hour.
- I slowed down her I.V. drip.
- Smart.
I'm going in.
Good luck.
Oh, sorry. I didn't
realize... um...
I'll just go to another room.
You don't have
to. I'm almost done.
Okay, great.
Four, five.
Five what?
More minutes.
Yeah. I'll...
You know what? I'll come back.
You don't have to.
So, Polly doesn't need surgery?
Right now, no.
It's a waiting game.
We would like to wait
and see if it resolves itself,
but she's stable and awake.
She'll hate this.
Waiting and seeing.
When I got hurt, we were
engaged, and I gave her an out.
I mean, it only seemed fair.
Her answer was to haul
the chaplain into my room.
We basically
eloped in a hospital.
Nothing gets to her.
I like her.
Except glider planes.
Those are my thing.
She thinks she hides it,
but I know she's not
wild about heights.
Oh, God. I hope she's okay.
I'm gonna let her
know you're here, okay?
Hey, Polly. Someone's
here to see you.
I need some help in here!
What's happening to
her? Abdomen's rigid.
Belly's full of blood.
Hang two units.
I need a 7-0 E.T. tube
and an intubation tray.
Blood's on the
infuser. Coags sent.
Page Hunt and Riggs
and book an O.R. right now.
You said she was stable.
What the hell's going on?
Her spleen ruptured, and
now her aorta's dissecting.
Gown us. We
could've avoided this.
Yeah, well, this
shouldn't have happened.
It wouldn't if you two hadn't
teamed up against me,
if we hadn't waited!
Okay, listen, can we
do this another time,
because if we don't
get to this dissection,
it's gonna take
out her coronaries.
Let's get in here. I
need some hands.
I told that other doctor this
is just what my body does.
I have a beer or
I get dehydrated,
and I get sick.
I know how to fix
it. This is how I fix it.
I totally understand.
You know your own
body better than anyone.
Exactly! And I don't
need some idiot
telling me I have a
problem when I don't.
Okay, you know how to handle
it. You know your own limits.
It's doctors like him
that are the problem.
He thinks I'm some
crazy party girl.
I'm not an alcoholic.
You know, I used
to tell myself that.
Well, actually quite a bit.
We talked a lot
about that in AA.
AA?
Really? What is this?
Are you trying to play good cop,
bad cop with me or something?
Emma, no. All I'm trying to...
- I am not stupid and I won't
stick around for this. Emma,
what are you doing?
Emma, wait a minute.
What did you do?
I just barely touched her.
Emma... Emma, just calm down.
Don't touch me!
Just... Just let me fix it.
Oh, my God.
Oh, what on earth?
So... can I get out of here now?
Who is responsible for this?
Not the clinic.
It's Karev's fault.
He should've discharged her.
Dr. Karev works for the clinic.
Dr. Webber, did you injure
her? Because now it's a liability.
She appears fine. She needs
x-rays to rule out a fracture.
Well, she's back in bed
and not happy about it.
- I'll check on those x-rays.
- Mm-hmm.
Actually, Chief, I
could use a little help.
I have a meeting with
my lawyer this afternoon,
and Timir won't let me out.
I have helped you. I got
you this job. I didn't have to.
What, you need me to
help you do that, too?
Figure it out.
Rush on these, please. Thanks.
So, Bailey told me, too, not
to say anything to anybody.
But, uh...
I don't have anyone else
who understands except you,
and I know that Bailey
said not to say anything,
- but it's like...
- Heads up.
- I...
- I'm gonna go...
Okay.
April grinds the coffee?
And brews it.
Every morning.
Yeah, I don't see the problem.
No matter how late
we are up with Harriet,
she wakes up before
me and makes the coffee.
No matter how badly I need
to leave and go to work or...
But you can't walk away
from a fresh pot of coffee.
And not feel like an ass, no.
So, I drink the coffee
and make the small talk
because that's what
people do, apparently,
but sometimes I don't
want to make the small talk.
What are you laughing at?
Nothing, man. I
just... I remember.
From when you stayed
with me and Miranda.
Yeah, but I wasn't that bad.
Dude.
I was?
No. You... You
should've said something.
Yes, and so should you.
Just talk to April.
Yeah, I... Okay,
you're right. I will.
It wasn't really that bad
with me, though, right?
It might've been
better if you'd have
brewed a brother a cup of
coffee every now and again, but...
I'm so tired.
But I go out of my way to make
coffee every morning to be nice.
So, sleep in. Don't make coffee.
Well, I have to do something.
I was taught to be
a courteous guest.
But you're not a guest.
You're a... You're
a co-habitant.
You're a roommate. He's
your... He's your Andrew.
He's not my Andrew, no.
He's my ex, and we live
together 'cause he's being nice,
so I need to be a good
houseguest even if it kills me,
which it might, unless I
die of lack of sleep first.
I can't handle dying, right now.
So, move out.
- What?
- Your incision is healed.
You can lift as much as you
want, so come back to work,
move out of the house, and
then do whatever you want.
Doctor's orders.
Not only do you get
dumped on me in my clinic,
but then you make
me look incompetent
in front of the Chief?
I didn't do anything.
You pulled a girl's
arm out of her socket.
Yeah, and I put it
back like I always do,
- so when can I go?
- You still need to get x-rays.
- And I didn't even touch her.
- You upset her.
You're the reason
she tried to leave.
Look, my shift
starts really soon.
You have no idea, but
my boss is the biggest jerk.
I have some idea.
All it takes is her
filing one complaint.
I know you don't care 'cause
you have a cushy job to go back to,
but this is my cushy job.
I don't need you
causing trouble.
You paged me?
Can you hear me, Karev?
Are you even paying attention?
I paged surgery. I need a
consult over an abscess.
Okay.
Bed two. Can you do it?
You paged me
here to do your scut?
No, no, that's not...
Then why else do you
need me to lance a boil?
Because I'm not allowed to.
Damn right, you
are not allowed to,
and... and you're not allowed
to go near that girl again either.
Okay, I don't want
you anywhere near her.
Screw it. Screw all this!
There are your patients.
There's your surgical consult.
I have someplace to be.
Hold on! Stop the bus!
I got your message.
What's so urgent?
Check it out.
So, you know how Emma
presented with a hangover
but insisted that wasn't it?
Yeah, even though
she was in the clinic
every couple weeks
for I.V. hydration?
And she said that thing with her
arms has happened to her before.
Well, what's this
have to do with me?
Well, just read the chart.
Look at her list of symptoms.
I mean, there's
something wrong with her,
but she's not an alcoholic.
Dehydration, bruises
easy, joint hyper mobility...
that's for sure.
Fainting spe...
Ehlers-Danlos Syndrome?
You're not as
strong as you think.
I only encountered a
couple cases in my career.
I mean, we'll have to
run tests to confirm it.
But if you're right
and she has this...
Karev, you may have
just saved this girl's life.
- Did you tell her?
- No, that's why I paged you.
You have to tell her, not me.
Look, if I give her
some big diagnosis,
I'm undermining
Timir's authority,
but if you tell her...
No, it doesn't seem right. No.
Look, she needs this way
more than I need a credit.
If we can't catheterize through
the inferior petrosal sinus,
will we go straight to the
superior ophthalmic vein
- or what? What?
- You...
had sickle cell anemia.
Oh, good. This.
Have? Had? Have had?
- Had.
- You had that.
I know that about you.
Nobody knows that
about you, but you told me,
trusted me with the information.
You let me know you.
I know that about you.
I know we are about to go treat
a dural carotid
cavernous fistula.
Owen could've had
it, too. I have no idea.
Unlikely for a
number of reasons.
But I know it about you,
just like I know that
you do not like dogs.
You don't ever go to church.
You do like mushrooms.
And I knew all of those
things before today.
I should've married you.
I'm not sure that would've
worked out for either of us.
That church one is just a guess.
Okay, wait. You're gonna
have to say that all again.
Ellie what-is-it syndrome?
Ehlers-Danlos.
It's extremely hard to diagnose,
but all your symptoms add up.
You did a great job
paying attention to
what your body needs.
This diagnosis is a
good thing, Emma.
We now know better
how to actually help you.
All this time...
So, this means it's real.
I'm not overreacting.
I'm not crazy.
Definitely not.
Thank you, Dr. Webber.
There's no way that
other asshat doctor
would've figured this out.
That's why the
clinic's here, Emma.
We're just happy to help.
Thank you.
While we were in there,
you had a sudden
dissection in your aorta,
which, well, I'm glad
we caught it in time.
- How you feeling?
- I don't know.
I... I guess, like...
like I fell out of the sky in a
plane I never wanted to be in.
- Don't tell Danny
I said that.
- No.
He'll feel so bad. I know him.
He's eating himself
alive over this.
- Can I see him?
- Yeah. I'll find him for you.
Oh, one more thing
that's kind of strange.
I can't feel my legs yet.
When is this anesthesia
gonna wear off?
What?
So, when the aorta dissected,
it compromised
the feeder vessels
to the spinal cord
right around L-4.
And it damaged the cord there.
So, she's paralyzed
from the waist down?
And it's irreversible.
If we'd been in there sooner...
- It wouldn't have made
a difference.
- Yes, if we had gone in...
Owen, it wouldn't
have made a difference!
It dissected right
in front of us!
I couldn't have foreseen
that and neither could you.
This happens.
It's happened to me before.
Okay? It's
unfortunate, but it does.
You couldn't have saved this.
I'll go tell her.
That's the truth, right?
What?
That we couldn't
have seen this coming.
- That's true?
- Why would you ask me that?
Because I need to make
sure that our decision to wait
didn't put this woman
in a wheelchair.
No, it didn't.
You didn't... side
with me because of...
you and I?
Excuse me?
Because we decided
to wait, this falls on us.
If you think I would play
around with a patient's well-being
in order to get into your pants?
That's not what I'm saying.
I'm asking a question.
It's a damned
offensive question!
Did we make the right
decision for the right reason?
I agreed with you
because you were right,
not because you were you.
Now, what happened to
Polly is not to your fault.
And it's certainly not
mine. I'm not that stupid!
You heading home?
I'm not sure I'm at liberty
to disclose that
information at this time.
Right.
Wouldn't be prudent
at this juncture.
Your whereabouts should
remain need-to-know.
Mmm.
Look, if you can't
talk to anyone
and I can't talk to anyone,
no one's gonna know if
we talk to each other, right?
True, yeah.
You hungry?
I better not say.
So, Dr. Hunt says
that she's still groggy
and trying to
process everything,
but she wants to see you.
I can't go in there.
I can't. I'm the one
who did this to her.
She's in the bed because of me.
I can't face her. I can't go in.
You have to.
You're the only one
she needs right now.
She was on the
plane because of me.
And now she's
off and she's alive.
Your wife is alive.
And if there's anyone who
could tell her this isn't the end,
that this isn't the worst
thing that could've happened,
it's you.
Because this isn't
the worst thing.
She's still breathing.
She needs you right now.
She needs you to be strong
and pull it together for her.
Daniel, she's ready for you.
But what... what do I say?
You guys love each other.
You can say anything.
- Shh, she's finally sleeping.
- Okay.
Shouldn't she be in
a crib or something?
You should be happy
she's sleeping at all.
Well, I mean, I was
hoping we could talk.
I just feel like if
I stop doing this,
she's, like, gonna wake up.
Okay. Totally fine.
It can wait. I'll just...
I'll go watch the
game in my room.
Did you want to
watch it in here,
'cause I can try to
move her into her crib.
No. It's totally
fine. Don't be silly.
There's plenty
of TVs. It's fine.
I mean, I'm aware, but
this one's the biggest.
- I said no. Thank you.
- Are you sure? 'Cause If you
want to watch the game, I can...
- April, I said no.
- Okay.
I can't keep doing
this, all right?
I can't keep walking
on egg shells
in my own house, all right?
We have to figure out a
way to freakin' exist together.
I'm sorry. You're
walking on egg shells?
What do you think
it's been like for me?
I don't know. I don't know.
I know this whole
thing is weird.
Yeah, it's weird, and... hard.
Agreed. It's
hard. I don't like it.
- I don't either.
- Well, what do you want to do?
I don't know. Move out, I guess.
What?
Well, Arizona says that I can.
I mean, I'm... I'm healed, so...
I will, like, I guess.
I mean, does that mean, like,
right away, or what do you...
As soon as makes sense.
Right.
Well, uh...
She just slept
right through that.
Yeah, she can be, um...
pretty quiet when
she wants to be.
I don't want you to move out.
I don't want to
move out, either.
I'm scared I may
never sleep again.
She's stronger than I
am. She could defeat me.
There's two of us. We
got her outnumbered.
You two are staying.
- Okay.
She's sleeping. Why
the hell aren't we?
I don't know.
I'm just gonna go set
up the coffee thing...
Please don't. Okay? It's
enough with the coffee.
- No?
- No.
Okay.
- Night.
You know you can
tell me anything.
I know.
Okay.
Night.
There was this man I loved...
very much.
And we loved
taking drugs together,
and one night we took a lot.
And... the next
morning I woke up,
and he had O.D.'d
and aspirated
on his vomit and...
died.
I told you it's bad.
I once...
I once choked Cristina.
I didn't mean to,
but, I was asleep.
I had this ceiling fan.
And in my head,
the blades, it was...
In my head, it was a helicopter.
And I thought I was back there.
And I woke up, and
I was choking her.
We're okay, right?
We're okay.
And our kids will be okay?
Our kids will be amazing.
They will.
I can't wait.
So, let's not, then.
Let's not wait.
I can't do what
we did today again.
Okay.
I can't have another case
where I question my
medical decisions or yours.
I can't do my job
if I'm thinking about what
you're thinking about me.
So, you're thinking about me?
I don't want to be.
Let's just be colleagues.
Nothing more.
Colleagues?
Sounds stuffy.
It's not.
It's...
Colleagues are people who hang
out at work and talk about work.
Still sounds stuffy.
Well, it's what I'm offering.
I don't see why
we can't be friends.
Who can't be friends?
You and me.
I just feel like things
have been a bit strange.
Like I've made you feel
a little uncomfortable.
God, no. No, you didn't.
You di... It's fine.
Of course we can be
friends. We are friends.
All of us, right?
We're all friends.
Great, then.
- I should get going.
- Bye.
Night.
Thank you for talking to him.
- Yeah.
- It's awful, but it's...
It's good to have
it out on the table.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
There's a reason these
fixes are called temporary.
They were never
meant to last forever.
So, what happens when
you're faced with a fix
that's more permanent?
Hey.
You ready to go?
- Give me a minute.
- How was your meeting?
How do the lawyers
feel about your case?
Do you fight it?
Do you try to resist?
I'm going to jail.
God, Alex, don't say that.
Why not?
You're in an awfully good mood
for a guy who thinks
he's going to the slammer.
I caught a one-in-a-million
case today, Mer.
It wasn't so terrible.
Or do you step back and decide
that maybe acceptance...
I'm good.
Okay, let's go.
Is the best fix of all?