Previously on "ER."
We do not need
a pediatric attending here.
Don't worry.
It's not going to happen.
Do you think I have what it
takes to be an attending?
Of course, you do.
‐ You've been a great friend.
‐ But?
‐ But there's this other guy.
‐ Oh, yeah?
We're both adults.
'We enjoy each other.
Why not?'
None of you wants the family
involved in your lives.
He's not going
to break my heart.
Men like him don't change.
Let's start an epinephrine drip.
Why don't we
also give her a heart
transplant while we're at it?
Peter.
Aha.
Sleeping beauty awakes.
Hey.
I was just checking
my messages.
You didn't even stir
when the alarm went off.
‐ Dead to the world.
‐ Ah.
Well, you know...
it's not that often that
I get the chance to sleep in.
Yeah, yeah,
don't rub it in.
Some of us have
to work Sundays.
Oh, please.
You know I've had my share.
Well, you're welcome to stay.
No reason to waste
a warm bed.
'No, no, no.'
Actually, I need
to get going.
There's tea and toast
in the kitchen.
You'll have to boil the kettle
but I think you can manage that.
No.
I've, uh, I've got
to go somewhere.
Umh, not some other
clandestine meeting, I hope.
Reese is getting baptized today.
Protestant or Catholic?
‐ Why?
‐ Just curious.
AME.
Look, I would have
invited you, but‐‐
Ah, don't be silly.
It's a family thing.
We've got time to go
home and change?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Okay.
Well, have
a good time then.
Hey, and could you
lock the door on your way out?
‐ Sure.
‐ Great.
Hey, Peter.
It was really lovely last night.
‐ What are you doing?
‐ I'm hungry.
‐ You can't start without her.
‐ Why not?
I knew this brunch
was a bad idea.
No. She's a little bit late.
We should have met
on neutral territory.
I told you, deep down..
...your mother likes me.
Keep dreaming.
Finally.
There you go.
Hi.
‐ Oh, Hello.
‐ Hello.
What happened
to your front step?
Oh..
Did you get a flat tire or
something? Why are you late?
Javier, this is
my daughter Carol.
‐ Please to meet you.
‐ And her friend Doug.
‐ How are you?
‐ Hey, nice to meet you.
I'm sorry, we're late
but I couldn't get
'your mother out of the house.'
‐ Excuse me?
‐ Well, you know how she can be.
Has to be perfect, right?
‐ Allow me, sweet pea.
‐ No, I'll get this.
Can I get you guys
something to drink?
‐ Well, you have orange juice?
‐ Yes, we do.
Two mimosas, please.
‐ You brought champagne.
‐ Hm‐hmm.
‐ Well, aren't we celebrating?
‐ Two happy couples right?
'Did you see the way he kept
touching her back?'
Ah, wasn't really paying
attention.
Oh, you were too busy
laughing at his stupid jokes.
He was funny.
What was with "Sweet Pea."
If he called her
one more time
I was going to barf.
I thought it was great.
Doug, they met
at the racetrack.
Now, that was
a senior citizen outing.
So? They let anybody
in those groups.
Alright. It's not true.
All I know is that
this is the nicest
your mother's
ever been to me.
And I wanna keep it that way.
You don't understand.
My mother hates men.
Hate's a strong word.
Yeah, but in her case, accurate.
‐ Maybe she's getting some.
‐ Oh, Doug, don't even go there.
‐ How was it?
‐ Ugh, In like flint.
'I'll get it.'
You look like hell.
Oh, you got to love
Saturday nights.
ICU is packed.
Two muggings, three bar fights.
Four gangbanger drop‐offs
and a bad stroganoff
from a wedding reception.
Don't forget the guy
who licked the bottom
of his girlfriend's shoe.
‐ Why's that?
‐ She asked him to.
Had to do a tongue culture.
On that note, anybody hungry?
No. Anna actually brought
Sunday doughnuts.
Oh, so, cake isn't enough?
You have to deep fry it?
That's the point.
‐ How long are you on?
‐ 20 minutes.
Medevac is incoming.
29‐year‐old,
chemical accident.
Bad chemical burn.
Terrific.
Hold the elevator.
‐ Going down?
‐ Uh, up, actually.
Well, up's fine.
Surprised to see you
here on a Sunday.
Ah, well, I'm just
full of surprises.
‐ Covering the ER?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
I've noticed you signed up for a
lot of extra coverage lately.
Well, you know, idle hands.
Yeah,
I know exactly what you mean.
In fact, Lizzy,
I think it's about time
you and I had
a little sit‐down.
‐ Is there a problem?
‐ No. No problem.
Let me buy you lunch.
Is it about
the hemoAid study?
That and the future.
‐ Alright.
‐ Good.
‐ Then, in about an hour?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
‐ You said hydrofluoric acid?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Not hydrochloric?
‐ I don't think so.
‐ Why?
‐ Well some‐‐
I heard we had a fire victim.
Actually, chemical burn.
How bad?
‐ What do you got?
‐ 'Paul Canterna.'
'31‐year‐old security guard.'
Second and third‐degree
chemical burns
to the trunk, right arm
and and both legs.
Doused with hydrofluoric acid.
‐ What happened?
‐ It was stupid.
The vat was leaking.
I tried to tightened the valve.
Alright, sir,
just lie back and relax.
I got in the shower
to rinse it off.
Gave him five of morphine,
two liters normal saline.
You feeling
any more pain now?
‐ It's okay now.
‐ Alright, let's go.
Let's move him.
‐ Morning.
‐ Hey.
Usually, significant
improvement occurs
within the first three months.
Oh, he's still working
on his motor skills.
The fact is, Chase's progress
has slowed considerably.
That's all the more reason
for aggressive therapy.
He can get that at home.
Look, I just want what's
medically best for my cousin.
Gamma, I think
this is a big mistake.
John, it's often wise
to listen to the perspective
of those
not personally involved.
'Chase is getting worse.'
He's lost nearly all function
on his left side.
No, he just favors his right.
You have to force him
to use his left.
I wish it were that simple.
It is. Watch.
John, please.
Hey, Chase.
How you doing?
You, uh, you want to draw?
He was left‐handed.
He was drawing just last week.
You want to draw
something for me?
John, this isn't necessary.
Hmm? Okay?
‐ Okay?
‐ Okay.
'Okay. Why don't you go ahead
and you take the pencil?'
No, no, no.
Other hand.
Come on.
He can do this.
'It's okay. It's okay.'
There you go.
And you're all set.
What do you want
to draw, huh?
‐ You.
‐ Me?
You want to draw me?
Okay, go ahead.
I rushed him.
You can't, you can't rush him.
Alright?
Here we go.
Let's try again.
Yeah.
Needs calcium chloride,
ten percent solution.
‐ Start with five Amps.
‐ Five Amps?
Yeah. And set up an infusion.
One gram every 15 minutes.
So, Mr. Canterna,
feeling any more pain?
It's starting to get numb,
doctor. Is that bad?
Our immediate concern is with
the fluoride in the acid.
‐ Well, like‐like toothpaste?
‐ Not exactly.
The uh, calcium, uh, can be
drawn out of your cells.
So, what does that mean?
Well, it depends how much has
penetrated your skin.
Right now, we're giving you
calcium intravenously
to counteract the effect.
Is there any family
you'd like us to call?
Is there something
you're not telling me, doctor?
Hydrofluoric burns
can be serious.
So, is there any family you'd
like us to call in the area?
Nah, I don't really have
family in Chicago.
Okay. I'll, I'll be right back.
Carol, uh, can, uh,
you keep an eye on him?
Make sure he's comfortable.
‐ And watch his heart rate.
‐ Alright.
Tell me
if his leg gets worse.
It's not his leg
I'm worried about.
‐ Hey.
You look nice.
Thanks. Hey, is,
uh, Carla here yet?
‐ Inside.
‐ Oh.
‐ Hey, Uncle Peter.
‐ Hey.
Where is she?
Who?
Your girlfriend.
‐ Steven.
‐ What?
You said
he had a new girlfriend.
Well, I don't.
Well, dad said he heard grandma
turning over in her grave.
Alright. That's enough.
Both of you go in there
and get a seat.
'Peter.'
Oh, come on.
You remember Roger?
How you doing, man?
Uh, hey, hey.
Uh, Carla, can I talk
to you for a minute?
‐ All set?
‐ Yes.
Uh, we should do
a little rehearsal
before everyone arrives.
Um, um, mom and dad..
Uh, um, I'm‐I'm the father.
Oh, I'm sorry.
‐ Uh, who's holding the baby?
‐ I am.
Okay. Now, l‐listen if you'd
just step back here.
Yeah, come on, everybody.
Just kind of move around
and make way here, please.
Thank you.
No, no, over here.
That's good.
Here you go, little pickle.
Yeah, mom in the middle.
Dad, dad, right here
on the end.
Right here.
Just move back.
Thank you. Okay.
'You know, I wasn't even
supposed to go into work today.'
I was home
restoring my car and..
...the weekend guy
called in sick.
So, I figured I could use
the overtime, you know?
What kind of car do you have?
It's a '63 'vette.
She's an eyesore,
but she's got matching numbers.
I'm going to fix her up.
She's gonna be worth..
It's hurting under my skin.
I'm going to give you
something more for the pain.
How long is this going
to hang me up for?
It's hard to say.
He's already severely
hypocalcemic
and the leg is necrotic.
Any EKG changes?
Prolonged QT.
He's at risk
for an arrhythmia.
What does toxicology say?
Hydrofluoric burns of this
magnitude are always fatal.
There's no new treatment.
His family on the way?
‐ He doesn't have any in town.
‐ Hm.
You might have time
to fly somebody in.
Yep.
‐ Guess I better go tell him.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
This is really starting
to hurt, doctor.
We can do something
about that.
I'll give him
another five of morphine.
You okay? You don't look
so good yourself.
Mr. Canterna, the calcium
we're giving you
can't reverse the chemical
reaction in your body.
W‐what do you mean,
"Chemical reaction"?
The fluoride is binding
to your cellular calcium..
...to form calcium fluoride.
A crystal salt that seeps
into your body tissues.
So‐so, what does that mean?
We're already starting to see
changes in your cardiogram.
So, now, what?
As the calcium level
in your cardiac cells falls..
...your heart's going
to begin to fail.
What? Are you telling me
that I'm going to die?
We're doing everything we can.
Is that a yes?
Yes.
How‐how long?
Days?
Maybe 12 hours.
Is there anybody you'd like us
to call, Mr. Canterna?
Mr. Canterna?
I don't feel that bad.
Well, you let me know
if the pain increases.
It hurts. I just don't feel
like I'm dying or anything.
We're gonna do
everything we can
to keep you as comfortable
as possible.
Maybe he's got it wrong.
Shouldn't you call
a specialist or something?
I feel like you guys
are giving up on me..
We're not giving up
on you, Mr. Canterna.
I promise you that.
We're gonna do
everything we can.
You sure there isn't someone
we can call for you?
It's too late.
Why? How far away are they?
No, I been gone too long.
She won't come.
Who won't?
My daughter.
21 years old.
Complains of neck, back..
Hold up. we're full here.
Next room.
Neck, back and bilateral
ankle pain
following a 75‐foot fall
into the river.
‐ From where?
‐ The Train Bridge.
Sinus rhythm:
A and O times three.
ETOH on breath.
Sensory and motor exam normal.
Okay, CBC, dip a urine cross
table c‐spine
chest and pelvic x rays.
‐ Does that hurt?
‐ A little.
Okay, and lift.
What were you doing
on the bridge?
It's a long story.
‐ How about here?
‐ No.
BP is 120/70.
‐ Pulse is 112.
‐ Is that bad?
No. We're just gonna check
to make sure you're okay.
Good peripheral pulse.
Normal cap refill.
Follow with bilateral
ankle films
and, uh, call psych.
Psych?
Wait, I don't need a shrink.
Relax. Everything's fine.
I didn't jump,
if that's what you think.
‐ Okay.
‐ No, I'm serious.
‐ I didn't jump.
‐ Okay.
‐ Take any drugs?
‐ No.
I‐I was there with my buddies.
We were just fooling around.
How much have you had to drink?
A couple beers.
Well, you also have a couple
of broken ankles.
‐ Throw in a BA.
‐ Where are you going?
We're gonna take care of
everything. Just relax.
Is everything okay in there?
Joker jumps off a bridge
and walks away
with a couple of ankle
fractures.
‐ So to speak.
‐ Yeah. Called psych?
‐ Yeah.
‐ I'll tell Weaver.
‐ Surgical consult?
‐ Uh, Trauma two.
Straight ahead.
Mark, he changed his mind.
He really wants
to see his daughter.
Oh, I thought he didn't have
family in town.
No, he does. He just hasn't seen
her in six years.
‐ How old is she?
‐ Six and a half.
‐ Oh, boy.
‐ Don't worry.
‐ I'll take care of it.
‐ You sure?
Yeah, yeah. You go home.
Get some rest.
No no no. Listen I should
probably stick around.
Mark, there's nothing
else for you to do
except hold his hand,
which is my job.
‐ Go on. Get out of here.
‐ Alright. Thank you.
'And another breath in.'
‐ Got a sec?
‐ Sure. I'll be right back.
CBC, pulse ox, lytes,
ABG and a chest film.
Still waiting
for an ICU bed.
Pulse ox is
falling slowly.
Uh, I didn't talk to him
about a vent yet.
I wanted to let
the news set in and..
...Carol is looking
for the family.
‐ Alright. Have a good Sunday.
‐ Thank you.
‐ Sorry about that.
‐ No. I know you're busy.
I don't usually come to the
emergency room...for the flu.
But I can't seem
to beat this cough.
Hmm. How long you been
feeling fatigued?
‐ A‐about a month.
‐ Any weight loss?
Mmm. I've been so stressed
planning this wedding.
Oh! Congratulations.
Is that a daughter
or a granddaughter?
Why, it's my wedding.
After four years
I told her it was about
time to make a commitment.
Well, good for you.
Gives me less than
a month to get better.
No promises.
‐ You might have pneumonia.
‐ Pneumonia?
We'll know more once
we get a chest X‐ray.
Hey, Anna, are you the one who
had that voodoo woman yesterday?
‐ Oh, She's back?
‐ Yeah. Exam three.
Chief complaint, "Voodoo man
has taken over her body."
Wait a minute,
this isn't the same one.
My voodoo patient
was 60‐something.
I had a voodoo guy last week.
Oh, no.
Voodoo epidemic.
Sorry.
Yeah? Ma'am, your ex‐husband
is in critical condition.
I know you are at work.
He just..
Look, he's going to die tonight.
He just wants to see Molli.
‐ Anybody home?
‐ What have you got?
Pedestrian versus auto.
Head contusion, brief LOC.
Broken arm,
vitals are stable.
‐ What's open, Chuny?
‐ Uh, curtain three.
Curtain three?
‐ Cerebral palsy?
‐ I don't know.
Somebody clipped
his wheelchair.
He couldn't tell us
if he was hurt or not.
No one was with him?
Nope. Just found him
on the street.
Okay. Sir, can you
tell me your name?
No it's not use.
You can't understand him.
He might have
the uh, a subdural
that could impair his speech.
We should get a head CT.
How do you do a neuro exam?
It would help if we
knew his baseline.
Okay.
Sir, can you, can you push in
against my hand?
Alright, let's start
with a c‐spine.
Carter, have you seen Elizabeth?
No.
Wasn't she called down
for a consult?
‐ I just got here.
‐ Anna?
O‐oh, she's right there,
actually.
‐ Hey.
‐ Peter.
I thought you
weren't coming in.
Uh, I wasn't,
but I decided to come in
and do some,
uh, post‐op notes.
You look dapper.
‐ Thank you.
‐ How was the baptism?
‐ Good. It was good.
‐ Nothing afterwards?
Hey listen, you want
to get something to eat?
Oh, I wish. I've got
this thing with Romano.
‐ What thing?
‐ Lunch.
I think it's got something to do
with my fellowship renewal.
Ah.
Did you really come in
for post‐op notes?
Yeah, yeah.
So, I'll see you later?
Oh, yeah. I hope so.
'You should call the military.'
They might have
an antidote or something.
A buddy of mine
says they use stuff like this.
Yeah, it's not really
the same thing.
I just want you to know.
I know.
Did you find her?
Uh, I talked
to your ex‐wife.
What'd she say?
She said that she's
sorry, but, um..
She's not going to bring Molli?
No.
She, um, she knows
what's happening to me?
That's okay.
Hey, it's for
the best, I guess.
I'm sorry.
I was going to make it
up to her, but..
I guess I ran out
of time, you know?
At some point,
you'll have to let us know
if you want to be put
on a ventilator.
Dr. Weaver,
do you have a minute?
Yeah. Uh, what is it?
Auto versus pedestrian,
possible head injury.
‐ What's the problem?
‐ Cerebral palsy.
He's, uh, tough to assess
and we don't want to hurt him.
Alright. Call me
at the first sign of arrhythmia.
Are you sure it's CP?
He might be posturing.
No, he's conscious.
Well, is he on any meds?
I don't know.
He has no family.
We can't understand
a word he's saying.
‐ Did you check‐‐
‐ Wait, hang on.
Let me grab this one quick.
Yo! I need a portable c‐spine.
‐ Oh, X ray, trauma two.
‐ No, Maggie. I got him.
‐ When did you call?
‐ I didn't.
‐ But I need to clear a neck.
‐ So do I.
‐ Well, how bad is yours?
‐ How bad is yours?
'Hey, I need a hand here!'
Carter, grab that gurney.
Is he breathing?
Yeah. I need a C‐collar
and backboard. Let's move.
‐ I got it.
‐ Connie, get Doug.
‐ Why didn't you call 911?
‐ I thought I'd get here faster.
How long has he been
unconscious?
Uh, he was awake in the car.
He just stop crying.
‐ Pulse is weak and thready.
‐ What happened?
Uh, I had him for the weekend.
We were washing the car.
‐ 'I didn't see him.'
‐ We need the room now.
'I only backed up
a couple of feet.'
Get that guy out of here.
We'll roll him. Alright?
Here we go. Hang on.
Roll him.
Did you drive over him?
Yeah, I think so.
I just didn't see him, man.
‐ 'Get radiology over here!'
‐ Okay.
Cap refill is poor.
'What's going on?'
Chuny, get me a crit and type
and cross for six.
Put him on oxygen,
ten liters by mask.
Dip a urine.
Pupils are..
...equal and reactive.
I got a line in.
Alright, saline, 20cc's.
Uh, uh, per kilo bolus.
That's...uh, he's 30,
so, that's 600, right?
BP is 70/30,
pulse is 144.
Abdomen is distended.
‐ No bowel sounds.
‐ Can't wait for a CT.
Alright, let's prep for
a peritoneal lavage.
‐ I'll get a kit.
‐ Pulse ox?
‐ Hey, you okay in there?
‐ 'Yeah, I think so.'
‐ 'Where are the lavage kits?'
‐ Down and to the right.
‐ What's that? Lavage?
‐ What?
Oh, it's a procedure to check
if there's internal bleeding.
That sounds pretty bad.
Well, you never know.
Is it a boy or a girl?
It's, uh, it's a boy.
You could go in there
if you need to 'cause I feel..
No no. No. They got it.
Can I ask you to do
something for me, nurse?
Yeah.
I have a couple of thousand
dollars in my savings account.
Can you make sure
it gets to Molli?
Sure. Do you have
a will or something?
No, I didn't get around to it.
But I just want to make sure
I get her the money.
It's not much,
but I want to give it to her.
I can get a public
notary to arrange it.
I'll take care of it for you.
‐ You promise?
‐ I promise.
Okay. But Don't tell her
that it came from me.
'Cause I don't
want her to think
I'm buying her forgiveness.
Sorry. Hallway's blocked.
‐ 5.5 ET tube.
‐ Got the blood!
Ten unit.
I'll start a second line.
Rapid induction. Point five
of pavulon, 75 of sux.
Got it.
Cricoid pressure,
will you, please?
Marty, your daddy didn't
mean to do this to you.
‐ Cricoid pressure?
‐ I didn't mean to do this.
Crike's 28.
Lavage is...positive!
Alright, call the OR.
Tell them we're on our way up.
‐ Doug, are you done?
‐ Almost.
Hang on, hang on.
I got it.
We have to take
your son upstairs
to do an exploratory
laparotomy.
‐ What's wrong with him?
‐ Well..
We have to control
the internal bleeding.
Oh, my God.
I gonna need you
to sign a release form.
Okay, fine. Just‐just don't,
just don't let him die.
We do this every day.
He has a good chance.
Hold that elevator!
‐ Connie.
‐ Hang on..
You're gotta cover my
patient in trauma one.
You're leaving
in the middle of your shift?
Everything is on the chart.
‐ Where you going?
‐ I'll be back in an hour okay.
‐ Can you do it for me?
‐ Sure.
‐ Pulse is 80.
‐ Second unit's in!
Second unit's in!
Don't let him die! Please!
I need you
to sign here again, sir.
Fine, just‐just
don't let him die.
‐ I understand
‐ Please?
‐ I understand..
‐ Please don't let him die.
Turkey burger, please.
No onions.
What kind of, uh, salad
dressings do you have?
Caesar, ranch, Italian,
lo‐cal Italian
bleu cheese,
honey mustard, catalina
oil and vinegar
and poppy seed vinaigrette.
I'll have the soup.
‐ So.
Enjoying your year?
It's been educational.
Mm, I bet.
Thoughts of staying
come fall?
I've entertained the idea.
Good.
Is that what you wanted
to talk about?
No. No, not exactly.
Must I guess?
Well, there's no way to say this
but flat out, so here goes.
'Lizzie,
our relationship has not'
'moved in a direction
I would have liked.'
Now, partly that's because
I have trouble communicating
these types of feelings
but the fact is..
I find you...very attractive.
‐ Dr. Romano.
‐ No, no. Let me finish.
Now, I don't know what your
long‐term plans are and uh..
I'm not foolish
enough to think
that colleagues can have
a romantic involvement
without,
uh...entanglements but..
'...we obviously have a lot
of common interests'
'and we share the same
insane schedule'
and uh, it makes sense so..
I would really like you
to consider, uh, a date.
'Going out with me on a date.'
What do you say?
I'm flattered,
uh, and shocked.
Really? I would have thought
you could see right through me.
No. No, not at all.
Uh, however, um..
...seeing as I‐I do
work for you..
...I don't think it would
be such a good idea.
Oh.
Uh, not that under
other circumstances..
Oh, oh. Oh, I see.
‐ You‐you have a policy.
‐ Yeah, yes.
No fraternization, uh,
with people at work.
Oh, well, okay,
I respect that.
Uh...just pretend
I never said anything.
I'm sorry.
No. Hey! Huh, I, uh..
Had to give it a shot.
You know what's funny?
For a while there, uh..
I really thought I was competing
with Peter Benton.
Huh.
'Can you open your fist?'
How about your fingers?
Just...do that?
How about now?
Just your fingers.
What are you doing?
Weaver said to examine him
like he's any other patient.
By pinning his arm down?
I'm trying to isolate
finger motion.
You're not afraid
of hurting him?
Actually, yes.
He's been trying
to tell me something.
'Oh, head CT is normal.'
No subdural bleeds.
No sign of brain abnormalities.
Hey, he opened his hand.
How about that?
‐ Oh, he's got a bad lac.
‐ Yup.
'He might have cut a tendon.'
They didn't teach this stuff
in med school, did they?
Oh, I guess we can call
a hand surgeon down here.
'Yeah.'
‐ What did you do?
‐ Nothing.
Is he having
a seizure or something?
I‐I, I don't I don't know.
The X ray indicates you have
what we call atypical pneumonia.
‐ What does that mean?
‐ Well, there's several kinds.
You don't by chance have any
birds in the house, do you?
How did you know?
Psittacosis pneumonia..
...is carried by small birds.
What? Is it a parakeet
or a dove?
‐ A falcon.
Only thing Daniel
loves more than me.
That's not true.
Oh, I wanted to go
to Italy for our honeymoon.
He didn't want to leave
Sinbad that long.
Who was going to feed him?
What does he eat?
Uh, p‐partridges.
‐ It's not pretty.
‐ He doesn't eat them alive.
We kill
and clean them first.
That's where I come in.
Well, that's probably how
you contracted the pneumonia.
I'll get a blood test
to see what type..
...but we can treat it
with antibiotics.
Funny.
I thought I was
covering the ER.
I was there, so, I took it.
What happened
to your post‐op notes?
You know, I thought we
were past these games.
‐ Excuse me?
‐ The adolescent competition.
He was in bad shape. Come on
Elizabeth. Give it a rest, huh?
Peter, I was simply
commenting on how strange‐‐
You don't simply do
anything, Elizabeth.
Is something the matter?
‐ The boy could bleed out.
‐ I mean with you.
Has something happened
since this morning?
No. I'm fine.
Dr. Benton. I didn't know
you were working today.
‐ Yeah, I am now.
‐ Hmm.
Glad to hear I'm not
the only surgeon without a life.
Six‐year‐old male sustained
a splenic fracture..
‐ Bus tour?
‐ Thank you.
‐ Sandy Mader?
‐ Yeah.
Hi. I'm Carol Hathaway.
We spoke on the phone
about your ex‐husband.
Look, I'm sorry.
I can't help you.
Just go right on.
I'm working, okay?
Yeah, look, I‐I don't pretend
to know the history here.
That's right.
I just...your ex‐husband
isn't going to make it
through the night.
Paul walked out on us, okay?
Here you go. Bus tour.
He just left.
He couldn't hold a job.
He couldn't handle it,
so, he just left.
Now, I feel bad
for him, I do.
But he's not part of our lives
anymore. Bus tour.
All he wants to do
is see Molli.
He was never there for her
but now he wants her
to hold his hand
and watch him die?
You really want him
to die alone?
Who are you? This is none
of your business.
I'm not putting my daughter
through that, alright?
I understand how you feel..
...and you don't know me..
...but trust me
you're making a mistake here.
I was a little girl
when my father
was dying in the hospital..
...and I couldn't see him.
I wasn't given a chance
to say good‐bye.
I know, you think
you're protecting Molli
but she's gonna have to live
with this the rest of her life.
Did you know him, your father
before he died?
‐ Did you know him?
‐ I remember him.
Molli won't remember Paul.
She has absolutely
no recollection of him, okay?
Now, I'm sorry,
but he chose this for himself.
Has anyone seen Carol?
Uh, she had some
administrative stuff upstairs.
‐ On Sunday?
‐ Something about payroll.
Yeah, well, Mr. Canterna
is asking for her.
He needs 40 lasix IV.
I'll get it.
Kerry, your labs came back.
Mrs. Weinbach tested
positive for HIV.
No, Mrs. Weinbach
is the older lady with the bird.
Yeah, I made them redo it.
I‐I asked
for cold agglutinate
and antibodies, not HIV.
Are you sure?
It was marked on the form.
Oh, my God.
It makes total sense.
I don't know why
I didn't think of it.
You want to do another one?
No, I can't do an HIV test
without consent.
So, now what?
He's been on methadone
since birth?
Yeah.
No interruptions?
You haven't stopped and started?
Uh‐uh. No.
Seven months is a long time
to be on methadone.
It's pretty tough
on neurological development.
Yeah, well, they tell me
to start giving
him less, but it doesn't work.
You still using?
What does that
have to do with it?
‐ If you breastfeed.
‐ I don't.
Your baby has...a high fever.
He's sweating.
His pupils are dilated.
He has abnormally
high heart rate.
These are all signs
of withdrawal.
Now, why would that be?
I don't know.
You're the doctor.
When was his last dose?
Yesterday. I ran out.
My clinic is closed
on Sunday, so, I came here.
‐ You want methadone?
‐ It's what he needs, right?
‐ You don't need it?
‐ What are you talking about?
I think you're using your baby
to get methadone.
You're crazy.
I can get that for free.
Yeah, if you're clean, you can.
I think, otherwise you come here
when you can't score.
Forget it.
I don't need this.
But baby needs to be admitted.
No way. You'll call the cops.
You come in here
with this story
because no place else
is gonna give you the stuff.
Now, if you leave here
that baby is not
'gonna get
the treatment he needs.'
Then give me some
and let me go.
Until next time?
Vicky...you addicted your son.
You strung him out.
Don't you think it's time
to do something right?
We should wait for his family.
Someone's gonna start
looking for him soon.
What if he's homeless?
He couldn't survive
out on the street alone.
The cops are, uh, checking
the neighborhood now.
He can't live
that far away.
‐ Hey.
‐ Hey, take it easy.
Take it easy. It's okay.
Why does he keep banging
like that?
Maybe he is trying
to tell us something.
I'm sorry.
I don't understand.
‐ What is that? Ring?
‐ Wait.
‐ Ring what?
‐ A‐a phone?
You want us to call somebody?
Uh, lie still if that's
what you want us to do.
If you want us to..
Yes.
‐ Four?
‐ Four, four, four what?
You giving us
your telephone number?
Yeah, yeah.
Four is the first number
of your telephone?
Yes, yes.
Here. Thanks.
Then what?
Four, then what?
‐ Then two.
‐ Two?
Yeah.
I'll tell the father..
...and I'll, uh,
I'll meet you in recovery.
‐ Hi.
‐ Yeah.
Your son sustained
irreparable damage
to the blood vessels
supplying his spleen.
Okay.
We had no choice but
to perform a splenectomy.
But...he's alive?
Yeah, yeah, of course.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Thank God.
Look, in time, h‐he'll
make a full recovery.
Now , listen to me.
He's going to be prone
to certain infections.
So, he's going to need to
be vaccinated against‐‐
Just...thank you.
Thank you so much.
Yeah.
I made a mistake
about the birds.
You may have what's called
pneumocystis pneumonia.
Is that worse?
Well, we need to get a sample
from your bronchial tube
to confirm it's PCP.
But since it's the defining
illness of AIDS
we should do an HIV test.
‐ Aids?
‐ That's a good one.
We need to be sure.
You don't know Loretta.
Can I speak with her alone?
‐ Why?
‐ No, i‐it's alright.
Uh, Daniel's practically
my husband.
To tell the truth...
we made a mistake.
We need written consent
from our patients
to test for HIV.
However...
we tested you by accident
and it was positive.
I don't understand.
No, it's a mistake,
uh, a mix‐up.
Perhaps another test
would remove any doubt.
I'll take care of this.
Doctor.
Just give her something
for the pneumonia and we'll go.
‐ I can't do that.
‐ Don't make me report you.
‐ Excuse me?
‐ You tested her illegally.
Yes, but it would be unethical
to let her leave untreated.
I don't want to burden
her with this.
Have you been tested?
We're not talking
about me, alright?
There are drug programs
that would drastically
enhance both your lives.
Can't you say they're, uh..
...for something else?
I think you should find a way
to explain it to her
or I'll have to.
You disappeared on me.
I needed
to check on something.
Molli's still not coming?
I'm afraid not.
It's okay. It's better this way.
She shouldn't see.
Do you want to write her a note?
I could take something down.
Yeah.
No, it's too late.
It wouldn't be fair.
I think she'd really
like to hear
something from you,
I really do.
I was going to make it up
to her, I swear.
I called her
a couple of times last fall.
You can guess
how that went over.
You know..
...I figured
it just needed time.
I'm so glad you called me. I was
about going out of my mind.
I can't believe he was able
to give us your phone number.
Mr. Lorenzo, I am so sorry.
I lost all track of time.
I got..
stuck with the rejects.
Uh, I'm sorry.
John Carter.
‐ You understand him?
‐ Katherine Dunlap.
'I'm Mr. Lorenzo's
personal assistant.'
It takes a while
to get the accent.
Accent?
Slow, but I'll forgive them.
He says you're a little slow
but he'll forgive you.
Thanks.
Uh, c‐can you tell him
that they need
to operate on his hand?
You just did.
He understands English.
'It's one
of his many languages.'
'He's one of the worlds leading
experts in hieroglyphics.'
That's fascinating.
Liar.
I understood that.
Would you excuse me
for a second?
Thank you.
You're welcome,
Mr. Lorenzo.
Gamma.
Oh, John.
I'm sorry to bother you
at work.
What's wrong?
Uh, I'm not happy the way
we left things earlier.
Do you have a moment?
Uh...yeah, sure.
‐ Want to sit down?
‐ No, thank you.
John, I respect your opinion.
If you think we should
keep Chase at the institute
I'll support that.
I can't guarantee you
that it's going to make any
difference but I'm not
ready to give up on him.
I never intend to.
Neither do I.
Well, I'm glad we've got
that straightened out.
Me, too.
John..
...I understand
the freedom that comes
with financial independence..
but money or not
we're still your family.
I know.
You were always
your grandfather's first choice.
He's much too proud
to come to you now
but he'd really like
you to come to him.
What are you asking me?
Finish your residency
if you must.
You can always
practice medicine part‐time.
But your family
needs you, John.
We need you to
run the business.
I don't know.
'Please.'
Think about it.
No. No. I don't need
to think about it.
Gamma, I can't.
I'm a doctor.
It's all that
I've ever wanted to be since..
‐ Since your brother died.
‐ Since I was a kid.
And there's
nothing else for me.
You really love it that much?
Yeah.
Yeah, I do.
Forgive me for asking.
I...I had to try.
I'll expect to see you at your
grandfather's birthday dinner.
You will.
I always wondered what you'd
be like when you grew up.
Hey, uh, Connie,
whose patient is this?
I think it's Doug's.
‐ Where's the mother?
‐ I don't know.
Yeah, it's Doug's.
Get him, will you?
Hi, sweetheart.
It's okay.
‐ What happened?
‐ Uh, I just found him alone.
Unbelievable.
Yeah, well,
this baby has a fever.
He's in heroin withdrawal.
The mother's been stealing his
methadone between fixes.
So, she split?
I told her
to do the right thing.
Maybe she did.
Unbelievable.
It's okay, buddy.
No. Please,
leave it open.
Okay.
How much longer?
It's hard to tell.
Please.
Not long.
I'm scared.
I won't leave you.
Do you have things
you wish you did different?
Doesn't everybody?
You should fix it if you can.
Maybe.
Do you want me
to read you back the letter?
Yeah.
Okay.
"Dear Molli.
"You don't know me.
"I'm your father.
"I suppose I shouldn't
even call myself that.
"You're the best thing
I ever did with my life.
"Leaving you was the worst.
"God knows I haven't done much
for you while I was alive
"But if there's
a place called heaven
"And they let me in
"I promise to always
look over you.
"Please forgive me. I'm sorry
I never got to know you."
Me, too.
I'm going to start
to worry about you.
First, you work
on a holiday.
Now, I find you alone
standing out here
in the dark.
What are you
doing out here?
Looking for you.
Well, you found me.
I have to admit
that brooding veneer
is part of your appeal
but I thought
I'd broken
through most of it.
I'm supposed to be
at Carla's Restaurant
celebrating
my son's baptism.
I see.
And you're here because?
Ah..
I don't want to feel
like an intruder, you know?
Like I have to share my son
with Carla's boyfriend.
Do you?
I mean, he gets to spend
all the time with him.
You know, how do I
compete with that?
You're his father, Peter.
You don't have to compete.
Then I thought
I'd come and see you
but, you know, you had
that lunch thing, so..
Are you jealous?
Well, you know, your
instincts were right.
Romano propositioned me.
Are you serious?
What'd you say?
I lied.
Said I don't date colleagues.
It's cowardly of me, I know.
Oh, that's okay.
I lied today, too.
‐ What, about me?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
So much for a relationship
without complications.
You know what?
Screw it.
‐ Come on. Let's go.
‐ Where?
To the party.
There's still time.
Peter, you don't have
to prove anything to me.
Elizabeth, I know that.
Look, I just want to go, okay.
Well, then you should go.
You should go alone
for your son.
This is his day.
Ah, yeah, you're right.
Hey, thanks.
Listen, um, if
it's not too late..
Hey, listen, I'll be up.
‐ Are you kidding?
‐ Oh.
Hey! Anna!
Hi, Carter.
‐ Want some cookie?
‐ Yeah.
‐ You off?
‐ Yep. You?
‐ Another six hours.
‐ Bummer.
Did you discharge
Mr. Lorenzo?
Yes. He even gave me his web
site address.
‐ Thank you very much
‐ Why?
So you could
feel like an idiot?
Max!
Hold on.
'Oh, sorry.'
That's okay.
‐ What time is it?
‐ Uh, 10:00 to 2:00.
‐ You on call?
‐ Um, I'm waiting for Carol.
She should be ready. T‐they
called it about a half hour ago.
Thanks.
‐ Hey.
'I'll just be another minute.'
'That's alright.
Take your time.'
Tough one, huh?
‐ You okay?
‐ Yeah.
You sure?
Kept asking
for his daughter.
Never thought of it
like that, you know?
Maybe he was asking for me.
Maybe he wanted to see me
and I never came.
Your dad was probably
in a coma, Carol.
I don't know.
I've been living
my mother's version of it
for so long, I don't know...
what memories of him are mine.
‐ What's her version?
‐ Everything was alright.
That it was an accident.
He was depressed, Doug.
Well, maybe it's time
you talked to your mom about it.
After he was gone,
my mom used to go on and on
about how you can
never depend on men.
Now she's head over heels and..
...I'm the one holding back.
How messed up is that?
Keeps me on my toes.
I say I want time,
but the truth is..
...I'm scared to death
of losing you.
Oh, don't be.
I'm so sorry, Doug.
Don't be.
I love you.
I love you, too.