Previously, on
"The Resident"...
Look at this one-handed tie.
It's sloppy at best,
criminal at worst.
I'm mortal.
You will witness mistakes.
I came back to apologize.
Sammie will require ongoing care
with constant follow-ups.
I don't know if we're
the best people for her.
We'll have to relinquish her.
500 million genetically-modified
cells ready to change your life
by making healthy
red blood cells in your body.
I believe in you, Rose.
You're the strongest,
bravest person I know.
I'm pregnant.
Oh, my God, you are gonna
be the best mother ever.
♪ Tastes like strawberries
on a summer evenin'... ♪
What time is this big shindig?
Like, 5:00, right?
Yes, but no rush.
Apparently, husbands are not
required at baby showers.
Are you kidding me?
Wouldn't miss this for the world.
I've always wondered what women
talk about at these things.
No, you definitely have not.
Okay, true.
Hey, right on time.
Come on in.
- Need help?
- Nope.
The booze is heavy,
but the cake is light.
Say hi to the folks
at Chastain for me.
Will do.
You take care of Nic for me.
Dude, in a few hours
you'll have a house full
of doctors and nurses.
Nic hiccups wrong,
and the party will come
to a grinding halt.
That's a good point.
Bye, my love!
Bye.
Hello, radiant queen.
How are you feeling today?
Radiant.
Been trying to sleep, but I just
can't get comfortable.
Well, how about you stay
off your feet and let me
- handle all the preparations?
- No, let me help.
Nic, please.
I carved out the day
to prep your shower.
Allow me this.
It'll keep me focused. Okay?
Okay. Have at it.
Double espresso, almond milk.
Thank you. Tomorrow's on me.
And Friday will be back to me.
I'm really liking
our prework coffees.
Same here. I really am...
What is it?
Let's go.
That's your sickle cell
clinical trial patient, right?
Yeah. Rose Williams.
I haven't seen her in weeks.
I guess that means
the gene therapy is working.
And now she's with Dr. Cain?
Looks that way.
Although it's none
of my business.
Wait, were you and Rose...?
No. No, not at all.
Well, you can still get
too emotionally involved
if you're not careful.
It's not like that.
I cared about Rose as a patient.
And I know Cain,
and I know what he's like.
I just... I don't want her
to make a bad decision.
Hey. We're doctors at Chastain.
How can we help?
A lot of smoke inhalation injury
and not enough medics.
Here, take a couple tanks
for those who need it.
Next ambulance
is ten minutes out.
Hey.
Look at me. Slow breaths.
Get this over your nose.
Hold it on.
Get down. Slow breaths,
slow breaths.
My-my son.
He's still inside!
Ty!
Thank God
we made it.
Ty!
There's your mom.
Mom!
Mom. Mom.
Oh, baby.
- What's your name?
- Doug Johnson.
- Is Ty gonna be all right?
- The boy's gonna be okay.
- Let's take care of you, all right? Oxygen.
- Okay.
Take a deep breath. Deep breath.
Doug. Doug.
Doug, can you hear me?!
Hey! Doug.
Pulse is thready but it's there.
Probably smoke inhalation
and whatever he fell through
- in there.
- Doug. Come on.
Hey! We need that ambulance.
Our guy here can't wait
for the next one.
Come on, Doug. Hang on.
*THE RESIDENT*
Season 04  Episode 13
Episode Title: "Finding Family"
Aired on: May 11, 2021
Your mother's pulmonary function
tests are much improved.
This is promising news,
considering the initial size
of the lung tumors.
And her labs?
All normal.
Carol, how are you feeling?
Uh...
better.
My cough is gone.
I've been eating organic
and no processed sugars.
And slow yoga has been a
wonderful way to start each day.
She wanted to do something
other than... swallow pills.
Well, I'm sure everything
you've been doing helped.
But we won't know
if your cancer's responding
to the targeted therapy
until we get your PET scan.
- Mm.
- You won't have long to wait.
- We'll try to schedule it for later today.
- Mom,
I feel really strongly
about this.
I think the targeted therapy's
working.
We should have a spot open
by this afternoon.
Why don't you two go home
and we'll text you
when we have a time.
Hey, they need me in the ER.
Go. Go. We'll be fine.
All right. Well, don't stress,
Mom, all right?
- Okay.
- It's gonna be all right.
It's gonna be all good.
What have we got?
Sheila in 3C... she has asthma.
And Ira in 5C...
He's allergic to penicillin.
And Rick in the basement,
he just worries a lot.
Mr. Johnson is
the building's superintendent.
So he pretty much knows
everything about everyone.
62-year-old male
with no known medical history
involved in a fire.
Syncopal episode on-site.
On my count. One, two, three.
- - He get anything en route?
- Liter of normal saline.
Okay, we got
three smoke inhalation patients.
One with second-degree burns
and one with a broken arm.
So far,
seems like we dodged a bullet.
Did anybody check
on Mrs. Hammer?
She's a fragile flower.
I'll go see.
Guys, I'm gonna take
the broken arm in Six.
No breath sounds on the left.
Fluid in the chest,
BP's dropping.
Distended neck veins.
Tension hemothorax.
What's the course of action,
Devi?
Chest tube kit. Stat.
All right, you guys got this.
I'll go deal with the
smoke inhalation on Bay Four.
Mr. Johnson.
You're gonna be just fine.
You good?
Mr. Johnson, we need to put
a tube in your chest.
- Uh-huh.
- This may hurt a bit.
Well done.
I'm gonna go check on the burns.
Now let's finish the surveys
and take him to CT.
Thank you.
♪ With a quack-quack here ♪
♪ And a quack-quack there ♪
♪ Here a quack, there a quack ♪
♪ Everywhere a quack-quack ♪
♪ Old MacDonald had a farm ♪
♪ E-I-E-I... ♪
♪ Yo. ♪
Yo.
Is anybody hungry?
Oh.
Dr. Bell.
Yeah, Dr. Bell
comes bearing gifts.
Direct from the very best
Chinese restaurant in Atlanta.
Oh.
But, shh,
some of the other patients
might get jealous.
Oh,
Dr. Austin's parents' place?
Yeah, Yee Fan made
his very special congee.
It's perfect
for tender stomachs.
No, please.
I want to sleep now.
You stay with me?
Yeah, of course we're staying.
Remember?
We're adopting you, sweetie.
You're gonna become our child,
and we'll be your dads.
I have a serious thing
for hummus.
You know, I could eat
a pint of it in ten minutes.
And then eat another.
And what's going on
at Chastain anyway?
I feel so detached.
You'll be back soon enough.
And, weirdly,
it keeps running without you.
But just barely.
No one knows what to do.
They're all like,
"Where's Nic? Ask Nic."
Hmm.
Oh, no, dad brigade.
- They're early.
- Stay put.
I'll handle it.
Guys, the party's at 5:00.
You're hours early.
- No, I just need to tell Nic one thing.
- We wanted to lend a hand.
- I-I wanted to...
- Gentlemen,
you want to help?
Here's a list of stuff
you can grab.
Uh, balloons, streamers,
cake plates.
Where do we get these?
Uh, party store.
8th and Piedmont. We're on it.
Thank you!
Go with God.
But take your time.
Wow.
I mean, can you just run
everything in my life
from now on?
I think that's everyone
from the apartment fire.
Well handled.
Dr. Pravesh.
Rose.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
- My legs hurt and my chest, too.
- Okay.
When did this start?
Uh, about an hour ago,
maybe more.
We were taking a walk
in the park.
- Got it.
- All right,
let's get you in an ER bay.
Nurse Hundley,
can you prep Bay Seven?
Prepped and ready.
You are the best.
Come with me, Rose.
Take it slow.
Hey, Conrad.
Can I talk to you for a sec?
I need you to cover her for me.
She's your patient.
I know. I...
I just need to take a minute.
Okay. You want to talk about it?
Not yet.
Okay. Do what you got to do.
Dr. Pravesh and I
saw him carry this kid
from the burning building.
He saved a life
at great risk to his own.
How many truly selfless people
do you even meet these days?
Not too many.
I'm just saying, fingers crossed
his injuries aren't too serious
and we can fix him.
Dr. Devi, surgery 101:
Never let patients get
into your heart.
Don't worry about me.
I'm all about self-control.
That's good to know.
What have we here?
This man is either the luckiest
or unluckiest patient
I've ever seen.
Broken rib lodged in the aorta?
That's
a one-in-a-million injury.
- Exactly.
- Most patients with aortic trauma
never even make it
to the hospital,
but you see right there?
His broken rib
is actually preventing him
from bleeding out.
We heard the staircase
collapse beneath him.
He got knocked around
really bad.
Okay. So, tell me,
how would you fix him?
Approach
with a lateral thoracotomy,
clamp it, remove the piece
of the rib, sew up the hole.
Well, sounds like somebody
just gained admission to my OR.
I won't let you down,
Dr. Austin.
Good.
Now go prep Mr. Johnson
and do not leave his side.
If he even sneezes wrong,
that rib could dislodge
and he could bleed out.
You're getting
a lot of text messages.
Is there some secret boyfriend
you're not telling me about?
Yeah, no. I've got
enough on my hands at work.
It's probably
just the siren call
of the online shoe stores
I've been consorting with.
Oh, my feet
are already a size bigger.
Could be an emergency at work.
Nope. Not on call.
How are you doing?
I just want to hide.
I mean, I love
that everyone cares so much.
I just...
could use some peace and quiet.
Okay, well, it's too late
to cancel the shower.
I mean, Kyle would be heartbroken.
He's been in on the planning
from the word go.
No, I don't want to cancel.
I'm just venting.
It's very sweet.
And you're right,
he is... dead set
on being the best grandpa.
Mmm. Oh, that's good.
Her incisions
are healing nicely.
That's not where the pain
is coming from.
She keeps dozing off.
Shouldn't she wake up
when you're examining her?
Well, maybe.
Her abdomen is soft.
The loss of appetite
is concerning,
but until she eats,
we won't know
how her digestive system
is responding.
I could get some Jell-O
from the cafeteria.
It's worth a try.
Hey, guys. Just a word.
What's going on?
We just got
Sammie's latest labs.
She's showing signs
of kidney and liver failure?
And her lactate is climbing.
What does that mean?
That the-the post-op infection
is taking a toll on her body,
and...
and if it continues
to get worse, then...
Her long-term prospects
are not good.
- Hey.
- Dr. Hawkins.
What's the word? Am I having
a sickle cell crisis?
Your chest X-ray looked good.
You're not having
a heart attack.
And your CT angioscan was clean,
too, so it's not a blood clot.
But you can't rule out that I'm
not having a sickle cell crisis?
That's good news, Rose.
- Take it.
- We won't
know for certain
about your sickle cell status
until the blood smear
comes back.
Every day since I finished
the gene therapy
had been feeling better
than my last.
I was walking without pain
and then jogging.
Last week
I even taught at the studio.
Now this.
I'm scared.
What if the gene therapy failed?
Look...
You did the right thing
coming in,
but there is no reason to go
to the worst-case scenario yet.
Where's Dr. Pravesh?
The ER is slammed.
There was a fire.
- He asked me to step in.
- Oh.
I hope everyone's okay.
Thank you, Conrad.
Sure.
Soon as I know more,
I'll come right back.
I've signed my life over,
Dr. Devi.
But I know I'm in good hands.
Actually, Dr. Austin
is your primary surgeon.
You're in the best hands.
I'm gonna insert
an arterial line.
You'll feel a pinch
when I insert it.
Yeah, I'm guessing
I can survive a pinch
since I've got a rib
jammed in my heart.
Y-You're gonna be
in the operating room,
though, aren't you?
I'll be assisting Dr. Austin.
Good.
Y-You're my lucky charm, huh?
If you hadn't helped
at the fire,
I might not have made it
this far.
Excellent.
That was close to painless.
And you are so young
to be this talented.
I bet your parents
are really proud of you.
That's half true.
Oh, which one's hard on you?
Mom?
- Dad?
- What we are doing today,
Mr. Johnson, is about you,
not about me.
I get it. I'm nosy.
You can tell me
all about it after.
If there is an after, that is.
Because there's a chance
I'm not gonna make it
off the table, right?
All surgery has risks.
This one, more than most.
I'll go over them again
with you.
No, thank you.
It's not like
I'm gonna change my mind.
Besides, you and Dr. Austin
will get me through this.
So far,
Rose's labs and scans look good.
So it's not
a sickle cell crisis.
We're waiting for her blood
smear to come back to be sure.
- I told her to stay put for a bit.
- Okay.
Thanks. Fingers crossed.
You ready to tell me
what's going on?
Why you turfed her to me?
Come here.
I'm not sure myself, honestly.
Look, I care about Rose.
And I'm open about that.
I've been her doctor
from the moment that she
stepped foot into Chastain.
I found her that clinical trial.
I've held her hand
through the worst of it.
I agree.
You've been exemplary.
Top-notch physician.
But this morning I saw her
in a coffee shop with Cain.
They were holding hands.
It's obvious they're together.
And I'm feeling...
I don't know.
Jealous.
But to be clear,
I don't want an intimate
relationship with Rose.
She's my patient,
and that is a line
that I'm never gonna cross.
But why is Cain, who we know
is a problematic human being
at best,
taking a victory lap
with my patient?
I want her healed, okay?
I really do.
But all of a sudden,
you know, I'm feeling...
I'm feeling protective of her,
- which is...
- Yeah, not your job.
Our patients,
when they leave the hospital,
they're gonna do
whatever the hell they want.
And who knows?
Cain's been through a lot.
She's been through a lot.
Maybe they'll be good
for each other.
You never know.
Yeah.
- Mm-hmm. You never know.
- I mean,
who would've thought
you and Dr. Devi
would be so perfect
for each other?
- Oh, get out of here.
- What?
I'm just happy
for you guys, man.
That's never gonna happen.
You are so cute.
Oh, my God.
Oh. Don't move.
Sorry that took so long.
We had a, uh, kerfuffle
over the color of the streamers.
Welcome back, guys.
Let's put everything
on the dining room table
and see what we got.
Uh, Nic, I learned today
that your father
has strong feelings
about the color orange.
Oh, yeah. That's a thing.
Glad you guys worked it out.
I thought we
agreed to not do this.
I don't
like orange. It scares me.
I wasn't making fun of you.
Can you just...?
Is that my phone?
What are you doing?
I heard it buzzing. It must have
fallen out of your pocket.
- You were reading my texts.
- No.
I... Well, I mean, yeah,
they-they popped up.
What... What is going on?
I mean, you've been powering
through the house all day
like if you stopped
for one second,
your head's gonna explode.
And, I mean, who is this person?
Who's texting you those things?
I will tell you, okay?
But not now.
Not in front of the dad brigade.
Coming through, child. But, hey,
maybe black is the new orange.
The meds should help get blood
to her organs now.
And...
now we're just standing here?
No, now we are being here.
Sometimes that's
what parents are for.
Parents.
I didn't even touch her.
No, it-it's okay.
Her belly's rock-hard.
- What does that mean?
- It means
she needs an abdominal
CT scan right now.
I'm paging Dr. Bell.
Here comes the doctor.
How's everybody else
from the fire?
I'm not allowed
to give out patient information.
- HIPAA rules.
- Oh, what about Rita's dog, Chompsky?
He's a great pup, that one.
Don't tell me HIPAA covers dogs.
Ah, look
at that. I made you smile.
All your neighbors are asking
about you as well.
You have a lot of fans.
When you wake up,
you should tell me
the secret of your popularity.
I'm the new kid around here.
I could use some tips.
Deal.
Has the, uh, patient
been completely prepped?
He has.
Informed of the risks and
has consented to the surgery?
Uh, Dr. Devi here
has laid it all out for me.
We've covered all the risks,
haven't we?
Excellent.
Well, let's scrub in
and get started.
When we see you next,
you'll be all fixed up.
Acute mesenteric ischemia.
Yeah. Her hypercoagulable state
must have led to a clot
that compromised blood supply
to her bowels.
This could be fatal.
Well, if I perform
an embolectomy quickly
before her gut dies off,
we can give her a chance.
No, no, I don't think her body
can handle another big surgery.
It's our only option...
if we're gonna have any chance
of saving her.
So, what did you get
for the baby?
A vacation home
in Aspen and an SUV.
Relax. I got her a basket
of ETFs and a trading account.
Almost as useful for a newborn
as an Aspen retreat.
You?
I got her a car seat
for that SUV.
Billie, what's going on?
Talk to me.
Okay. Okay,
so I told you, right?
When I was 13,
you know,
after we lost touch...
that I was raped.
Of course.
Well, I got pregnant.
Oh, my God. Billie.
I...
I didn't know.
This was your day, Nic.
I didn't want to make it
about me.
God, don't even think
about that, please.
I... Honestly,
I want to talk about this.
I was so young.
By the time I realized
I was pregnant,
I had no options.
I went to live with my aunt
until the birth,
and...
then I gave the baby up
for adoption.
That must've been so scary.
It was.
They took him away
right after he was born.
I barely saw him.
A boy.
Yeah.
He's 18 now and wants to meet.
He won't take no for an answer.
You know, the records are
supposed to be closed,
but nothing stays
hidden anymore.
So those text messages...
It's him.
Wow.
Do you want to see him?
I mean, are you curious?
Yeah. Of course.
I wonder what he looks like.
You know,
what kind of person he is,
what he's doing with his life,
and...
But he's the product
of something awful.
Something I have worked
very hard to put behind me.
It's not his fault,
but it's the truth.
I mean,
what if I look at his face
and all I see is
the man who raped me?
And what if he asks about his father?
Would I tell him?
Would that be fair to him?
How does that help him in his life?
God, I don't know the answer
to that question.
Hey, Nic! People are here!
Sorry.
Okay, now you know my secret,
one I haven't told anyone.
And I'm gonna ask you
to keep it.
Of course.
Can we please just drop this
for tonight?
Let's go out there
and celebrate your shower, okay?
I mean, we can talk more,
but not now.
Whatever you say, but I want
to help you with this, okay?
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
Hi, Sammie.
You ready?
Yes.
Okay.
Is there anything you want
to say before we go?
See you on the other side.
Yeah.
We will see you
on the other side, kid.
Okay.
Congratulations.
You just completed your first
posterolateral thoracotomy.
- You keep this up, and next time I will let you...
- Dissect the aorta?
...choose the music.
Walk before you can run,
Dr. Devi.
Does this aorta look normal
to you?
No.
Below the level
of the rib injury,
I'd say that segment
isn't viable.
Well, he has a building full
of best friends who need him,
so let's get to work.
Yes, let's.
All right, this aorta
is starting to dissect
at the point of injury.
So sewing up
the puncture site alone
is no longer an option.
This has just gotten
way more complicated.
- Do we need to go on pump?
- No, we can't wait any longer.
We'll do it the old-fashioned
way with cut-and-sew technique.
Tell me, how confident are you
in your vessel suturing skills,
Doctor?
Confident.
Good, because once we clamp...
We'll have only minutes
to remove the damaged portion
and sew in a replacement graft,
or Doug's lower body organs
will die of ischemia.
Clamp.
Let's go.
Excellent work in there,
Dr. Devi.
When Mr. Johnson wakes up,
I'd like for you to do
his post-op exam.
Thank you, Dr. Austin.
I'll be the first face he sees.
Hey, Mom.
Listen, I just got a text
from imaging.
Can you come in
in about 20 minutes
to take a look at the scans?
Right.
Great. All right, see you then.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to eavesdrop.
I hope your mother's okay.
Rose's blood smear results.
Oh, my God.
No sign of sickle cell.
That's incredible.
You should be the one
to give her the news, not me.
You're the one who got her here.
I will. Thanks.
You're sure there's no mistake?
I'm sure.
On the right are your red
blood cells from the day we met.
Over half are sickle-shaped.
On the left are your cells
today.
Round and smooth.
I'm gonna say perfect.
But if there are
no sickle cells,
then why was I in so much pain?
Joint and muscle pain are
totally normal
when you start hitting the gym
and dancing and doing everything
you're doing now.
- What about my chest pain?
- That's costochondritis.
It's pain in the muscle
and cartilage between your ribs.
It's harmless.
It'll go away with time.
Your body just isn't used to
doing anything normal yet.
You were just so excited
to exercise,
so I think you just
pushed yourself too hard.
I'm gonna need you to say it.
Okay.
Rose, your gene therapy worked.
And you're cured.
I don't even know
where to begin.
Thank you.
From the bottom of my heart.
You've changed my life.
I should be thanking you.
You trusted me.
And because you did,
a lot of people suffering
from sickle cell
are gonna get the chance
to be cured.
You get the results?
She did.
You tell him.
- I'm cured.
- You're cured.
I'm cured.
How's our local hero?
Surgery went great.
Doug's vitals are stable.
Uh, do either of you want, uh,
32 new but slightly barbecued
roommates?
I'm sure Dr. Pravesh has
a walk-in closet
he'd love to offer up.
Yeah, I'm sure they would be
more comfortable
with their friends and family.
Well, you know, I'm just sorry
we can't stay under one roof.
You know, it's a good group.
Are you uncomfortable, Doug?
Uh, yeah, I am.
But I think I'm just
shaking off the anesthesia.
- Do you have any chest pain?
- Ah, just heartburn, yeah.
I've had it before.
I just... need some...
He's in V fib.
Let's get a crash cart
in here now!
Charging to 200. Clear.
How long has it been?
27 minutes.
Stop compressions.
Leela.
Stop and check the pulse.
There's activity on the EKG.
That's pulseless
electrical activity,
with no true heart rhythm.
Despite three rounds of epi,
bicarb and calcium
and multiple shocks.
There is no return
of circulation.
Time of death: 19:14.
Are you okay?
I just need a minute.
Just a little longer, Mom.
It can get really claustrophobic
in there.
Yeah, she doesn't do well
in small spaces.
Spelunking is her idea
of a nightmare.
Okay, so, this is
your initial scan.
You see that?
Yellow spots all over the place.
- Hmm.
- There's tumors everywhere.
And this is you now.
No tumors.
- Not a one.
- Yes.
The targeted therapy worked.
It's a miracle.
That it is, Dad.
You said it was gonna be fine,
AJ, and you were right.
You knew all along, didn't you?
Sure, I knew all along.
We're not gonna let anything
happen to you, Mom.
Hey, guys.
So, uh, the operation went well.
And I restored the blood flow,
and the bowel resection
was minimal.
So Sammie should be able
to digest food normally.
- Oh, that's great, right?
- Yeah, it is,
but Sammie's
still on pressors, and...
given everything
her body's undergone...
There is a possibility that she
won't make it through the night.
So why don't you guys...
go sit with her?
I'll get cleaned up
and get us some coffees, and...
and we can sit with her
in shifts.
It's just gonna be a long night.
I can't stop thinking
we must have missed something.
I just spoke with Dr. Austin,
and he said
you did everything right.
Sometimes patients have
bad outcomes,
and it's no one's fault.
How am I supposed to do this job
when getting close
to my patients
and keeping distance from them
both feel wrong?
I ask myself that all the time.
But there is no...
right answer.
Not very helpful.
Okay.
What kind of doctor
do you want to be?
Well, since medical school,
my goal has been to just...
survive...
to minimize my liabilities,
and to not...
get kicked out of the club.
To be fair, a lot of that came
from my father.
Controlling...
what you thought needed
to be controlled.
Yeah.
But I'm learning that being
a dispassionate robot...
Isn't in my nature.
That it won't make me
a better doctor.
That's funny... that's
the same answer I came up with.
Oh, wow.
It's a traditional
cheongsam baby dress.
The color stands
for prosperity, virtue,
warmth, happiness,
sincerity and truth.
That's beautiful.
Paul, thank you. I love it.
Thank you, man.
Aw, I can't wait to see her
in this.
Okay, the next gift is
from Jessica and Irving.
Yep. So, it was too big to wrap.
I just have to say,
I want one of these for myself.
Oh!
That's perfect. Look,
put that little girl in there,
and she'll be asleep
in two minutes.
Yeah, that's after she's done
checking her stock portfolio.
Thank you, Marshall.
Not sure where
we're gonna put all this stuff.
It's so generous. Thank you.
Well, lucky for you,
there's only one gift left,
mine,
and it's small.
Oh...
Our moms.
It's beautiful.
Thank you, Billie.
Can we see?
Kyle and Marshall
got me the photos.
It's for the baby's room,
so she never forgets
her grandmothers,
who I'm sure would have loved
to see her but...
left this world too soon.
That's my mom.
That's Grace Nevin.
So pretty.
She's just about your age
in this photo.
And my mom, Giorgiana,
on the right.
♪ So much has passed... ♪
They're here with you in spirit.
- Thank you, Billie.
- Yes.
Love you, Nic.
I love you.
♪ So try
till your dying breath ♪
♪ To hold on to happiness ♪
♪ 'Cause life's just a moment ♪
- ♪ And one day it's over ♪
- What?
♪ And it's cruel
how the time can pass... ♪
That's good, right?
Yeah. It means
her infection's lessening.
It's... it's not just good,
it's great.
♪ Hold on, hold on, hold on ♪
♪ Hold on to happiness... ♪
Can I have another one?
Sure thing.
I'll go grab one.
♪ Well, I miss
talking late at night ♪
♪ Getting drunk
on cheap red wine ♪
♪ Yeah, we were so close... ♪
Well, after a day like today,
I think we need to go celebrate.
Dinner at Roy's Steak House,
on me.
Don't you know your boy by now?
No way he's gonna let you
pick up the check.
Okay, then how about Yee Fan?
Well, even if it's your
restaurant, I'm still paying.
You know how tight he is.
- Bye, you guys!
- Love you guys. - Bye!
- Mwah! - Mwah!
- Love you. Thank you, man.
Thank you, Ellen!
- All right. Drive safe.
- Bye, you guys.
♪ So try
till your dying breath ♪
♪ To hold on to happiness ♪
♪ 'Cause life's just a moment ♪
♪ And one day it's over ♪
♪ And it's cruel how
the time can pass ♪
♪ The deepest rivers
move so fast ♪
♪ And life's just a moment ♪
♪ So
know when it's golden ♪
♪ Hold on, hold on, hold on ♪
♪ Hold on to happiness ♪
♪ Hold
on, hold on, hold on ♪
♪ Hold on to happiness ♪
♪ And treasure while it lasts ♪
♪ 'Cause you never get it back ♪
♪ Never get it back ♪
♪ No, no ♪
♪ And regrets
can hurt the most ♪
♪ And when you got it ♪
♪ Don't let go ♪
♪ Just try ♪
♪ Till your dying breath ♪
♪ To hold on to happiness ♪
♪ 'Cause life's just a moment ♪
♪ And one day it's over ♪
♪ And it's cruel... ♪
Something on your mind?
I'm just a little worried
about Billie.
- Want to talk about it?
- I can't. Maybe someday.
Fair enough.
Baby showers are awesome.
Why have you
been holding out on me?
You're sweet.
You tired?
A bit. Why?
I don't think
we're gonna get much sleep.
What are you talking about?
My contractions.
They started an hour ago.
They've been fine
to manage, but...
they're getting closer together.
We're going to the hospital.
I think I'm in labor.
- Let's go.
- ♪ Hold on, hold on, hold on ♪
♪ Hold on to happiness. ♪
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org