Previously on ER:
Your mom will get
a new heart, Lucy.
I got paged for an organ transport.
Heart donor. Plane leaves in two hours.
The, uh, heart's in Seattle, so we won't
be back until the middle of the night.
- A heart retrieval for Joanie?
- Yeah, it's good news.
- Waiting on a kidney transplant?
- Yes, long story.
Anyone else you want us to call?
No.
Hey.
Let me go, you bastards.
Let me go. Let me go.
Okay, what do we got?
She's not gonna tell Banfield.
Anybody could have missed it.
You wouldn't have.
You've got it all twisted, girl.
- You should just shut up about this.
- No, you shut up.
I wasn't the one out
with that bitch all night.
I told you, it wasn't like that.
I have no idea how long I'm
gonna be stuck in this place.
You're gonna have to
reschedule my entire day.
Please? MARQUEZ: Just a sec.
I'll be with you in a second.
Please. I found a
baby. I think it's dying.
- You found it? Outside?
- In front of my apartment.
In the vestibule by the
mailboxes. Inside but still cold.
I need an infant warmer,
IV access, and a rectal temp.
Try an antecubital vein.
- CBC, chem panel.
- Add a blood culture too.
- How old, you think?
- Can't be more than a couple weeks.
- Umbilical stump is on but it's clean.
Somebody tied
it off with a string.
- Tenting. Dehydrate it.
- He. We got a boy.
How's that IV coming?
Got it.
I'm drawing the bloods.
Send the lytes critical.
- What fluids do you want?
- Six pounds.
Fifty cc saline bolus.
Temp's 35.7.
Was there a note?
Anything? Ma'am, was there...?
- Where'd she go?
- Who?
- The girl who brought him in?
- She was here a minute ago.
He's seizing.
Point-25 milligrams Ativan.
Sleep okay? K's down to 4.8.
Take a deep breath.
And another.
Good. Lungs are clearing.
- I'm actually starting to feel...
- You were lucky.
- You skip dialysis this week?
- No.
- Stay away from salt, weigh yourself?
- Yes.
If your labs come back okay,
we discharge you this afternoon.
Maggie will go over dietary restrictions.
Make sure you stick with the program.
And pay attention to your
fluid intake, all right, doctor?
That was brisk.
I really don't need to go over
the dietary restrictions again.
Nope.
Put that down.
- Who are you?
- You eat?
No. KURTAG: Liquids?
- Not since last night.
- Who paged me here?
- Me. How are his lungs?
- Drying out. I was gonna order a x-ray.
Do it now. Sats? CLAYPOOL: 92.
Coags, call the blood
bank, electrolytes.
- What's going on?
- Dr. Kurtag from the transplant team.
UNOS called. There's a chance
they may have found you a kidney.
Hi. I'm Carol
Hathaway. Who's who?
Chris Zafares,
OSHU, Portland, lungs.
John Pares, St.
Luke's Boise, liver.
Amela Ratkovich, Salt
Late City Medical, pancreas.
Neela Rasgotra, Chicago,
heart. What's the hold up?
16-year-old kid riding his bike home
from the movies, drunk driver hit him.
Grandma said yes to organ
donation and then changed her mind.
- Why? CAROL: She
squeezed his hand.
She got a spinal cord reflex.
- The kid squeezed back?
- Yeah.
- So, what now?
- Well, I've ordered a CBF study.
- Doug Ross, attending physician.
- Hi.
- How long's that gonna take?
- Hour, maybe two.
- Grandmother's got consent?
- Yeah.
No mom or dad to ask?
Dad's gone, the grandma's
trying to find the mother.
She's gonna do the right thing.
Sit tight, have
coffee, watch TV.
We'll get back to you
as soon as we can.
Still no mom?
Number the grandmother
gave is disconnected.
- Busy downstairs?
- Yeah, I gotta get back.
Grandmother's alone,
frightened. She could use support.
I asked her if I could call anyone else.
She said, "No, just find my daughter."
Let's hope we didn't bring all
these people out here for nothing.
Hmm.
Okay. Hi. I've gotta go.
Did you run the test?
We'll get the results soon.
Don't get your hopes up.
I've heard of people in
coma for a very long time...
and then they suddenly wake up.
We don't think
Billy is in a coma.
- He squeezed my hand.
- I know.
But it was probably
just a spinal-cord reflex.
The test that we ran earlier
indicates there is no brain stem activity.
He squeezed my hand.
I'll come and find you when the
new test results come in, okay?
There were five kids
riding their bikes home...
and the car only hit Billy.
- Can I get you something? Some coffee?
- No. Thank you.
- Why is he seizing?
- What do you think?
Sepsis? MORRIS: Maybe.
- Glucose, 88.
- Uh, um... Electrolytes?
Add ammonia level,
serum ketones, lactate level.
What are you thinking?
- Inborn errors of metabolism.
- Rare.
- We don't know if we don't look.
- Ativan's on board.
- We still need an etiology.
- Infection?
Is that a statement
or a question?
All right, ceftriaxone, 150 milligrams.
Set up for a cath UA and an LP.
Labs are back.
Bingo. Sodium is 115.
- Daria, why so low?
- Uh... Dehydration?
Or maybe mom was
watering down formula.
- Watering it down?
- Trying to make it stretch.
I've seen it before.
Formula's expensive.
- Hypertonic saline.
- What about the risk of myelinolysis?
He seized. We have
to correct his sodium.
Fix it too quickly, he
could sustain brain damage.
We're not gonna do it too quickly.
Ten cc bolus of 3 percent saline.
Hey.
She's hanging in there.
It's amazing, isn't it? No
heart but she's still alive.
So they told you?
That another heart
might be coming?
They're not gonna screw it up again.
And that was a one-in-a-million thing.
You know, having someone
that you really care about...
who you really
love, who's sick...
that's a lot like
running a marathon.
You just gotta take one step
at a time, one day at a time.
But if you keep running
and having faith...
that it'll happen, then one day,
eventually, you'll finish the race.
Repeat sodium is 122.
Hemogram and the rest
of the lytes are normal.
Headed in the right direction.
Keep normal saline
going at 10 cc's per hour.
- You really think it was just the fluids?
- Looks likely.
Maybe he's hungry?
No. No, no, no.
I... I try to keep the relationship
with the babies strictly professional.
- Daria?
- Hmm, me?
Oh, for God's sake.
Get Family Services down
here and call the PICU.
They're gonna have to watch him
overnight and follow his electrolytes.
- Did the girl ever show up again?
- Uh, what girl?
- The one who brought him.
- I haven't seen her.
The police are gonna wanna
talk to her. Family Services too.
- I'll look around outside.
- Okay.
- Yeah, I think he likes you.
- Oh, no, it's just the grasp reflex.
Sure it is.
Cappuccino machine's
broken, so no lattes.
No lattes in Seattle. Is
that some sort of cruel joke?
So you're almost done with
your surgical residency, huh?
- Yep.
- You gonna stay at County?
You guys are from Chicago, right? We
have one kidney heading to Tacoma...
another to Spokane,
but the guy got the flu.
UNOS kicked out a match
in Chicago, Northwestern.
Thought you wouldn't mind
hauling an extra cooler on the plane?
- The grandmother sign off?
- Not yet. CBF just came back.
We're gonna go talk to her now.
The CBF allows us to measure
the blood flow in the brain...
by injecting radioactive
isotopes into the bloodstream.
Now this is a normal brain.
That's the radioactivity.
Now this is a dead brain,
which is essentially silent.
That's your grandson's brain.
There's no blood flow.
No corneal or jaw
reflex, no gag reflex.
He failed the apnea
test and now the CBF.
Nora, Billy's gone.
She needs to see him.
- I'm sorry? She?
- His mother needs to see him.
Did you reach her? I tried
the numbers you gave me.
Maybe there's another number.
- I don't know. CAROL:
Does she live in Seattle?
I don't know what she
would want me to do.
- I could send someone out to find her.
- His mother needs to be here.
How you doing?
- Uh, hungry.
- Yeah, well, don't eat.
I'm thirsty too.
We'll get you some ice
chips to suck on. Half a cup.
- Where are we? KURTAG:
There's been a delay.
What kind? KURTAG: No idea.
Kidney's coming
from the West Coast.
There's been a delay. Soon
as your kidney's in the air...
- we'll haul you to pre-op.
- So it may not happen?
What, you were doing
something more important today?
If it takes longer, all the
better to dry your lungs.
We got two days on
a kidney once it's out.
After I see your labs, I may
wanna hold off a day anyway.
Okay.
We can't browbeat
her into donating.
She didn't give you
more info on mom?
No.
- Who's in there with her?
- Neighbor.
- You okay?
- Ha, ha, I'm just tired.
Go home. You've been on
since last night. I can finish this.
No, I'm gonna stick around.
How were the girls this morning?
Complaining.
Thursday, spelling test.
Mm, you know, I'm
a very good speller.
- Yeah.
- Heh, heh.
Grab yourself some
coffee, stay awake.
- Okay.
- I'm gonna try and intercept the neighbor.
- Find out more about the family situation.
- Okay.
- So you guys are from Chicago, huh?
- Yep.
- Where? I used to work there.
- County.
No kidding.
I did my residency there.
- Really?
- What?
- You were a surgeon?
- No, Pediatrics. Emergency pediatrics.
- Is Kerry Weaver still kicking around?
- No, she, uh, left a couple of years ago.
Mm-hm. Peter
Benton? Susan Lewis?
Was Abby Lockhart around
when you were there?
No.
- How about Greg Pratt?
- No. Hmm.
- You're in Surgery, right?
- Yeah.
- How about Anspaugh?
- Yep. He's still there.
Yeah? NEELA: Yeah.
Well, you say
hello to him for me.
Tell him Doug Ross said hi.
- Sure.
- I didn't even hear the murmur.
- They can be transient, tough to pick up.
An IV drug user with a fever? I
should have been thinking endocarditis.
- We've all missed one of those.
- That's what Laverne said.
Laverne is a wise woman.
You should listen to her.
Look, don't say anything
to Banfield, okay?
I already questioned her clinical judgment
once today. Evaluations are this week.
Eighty-four-year-old woman
with multiple sclerosis.
Fever and vomiting for two
days. BP, 102/64, heart rate's 120.
I tried to get a line
in but I couldn't.
Uh, she really can't hold her
head up very much anymore.
Okay.
- Hey, Frank, what do you got open?
- Curtain 2.
Okay. Can she hear
me? Understand me?
Oh, yeah, she understands,
but she doesn't speak very much.
But, uh, she's
sharp as a tack, doc.
Okay. I'm Dr. Gates.
You've been vomiting?
Her name's Marjorie.
Okay, ready? On three,
guys. One, two, three.
So, Marjorie, you've been
vomiting for a few days?
Uh-huh.
- What medication is she taking?
- Oh, I got a list here. Uh... Oh, here.
Baclofen for muscle spasms,
Clonazepam for tremors...
Ditropan for bladder,
and Zoloft for depression.
- Okay.
- Move your head, sweetheart.
Can you open your
mouth? Good, all right.
Now take a deep
breath will you, please?
Good, Marjorie. Yeah, very good.
Okay, let's do 10 of IV
Reglan, gram of rectal Tylenol...
CBC, chem panel, UA, and
what am I leaving out, Daria?
- Oh, um... A chest x-ray.
- Portable chest, right.
Yeah.
We form a circle and we draw.
And that will take
us to about 5:00.
I thought you were NPO?
- What the hell are you doing?
- Ha, ha, I'm working.
- What are you doing?
- I'm waiting.
- Nice socks.
- My feet got cold.
You look ridiculous, Carter.
I didn't know you
were on staff here.
Yeah.
- Renal failure?
- It's a long story.
- Are you on my transplant team?
- No, I'm General Surgery.
I saw J. Carter on the board...
- figured I'd check it out.
- Uh-huh.
- Kurtag?
- Yeah. Yeah, I just met him today.
- Is he any good?
- Oh, he's terrific.
He trained with Tullius at the
Brigham. Uh, a bit of a prick though.
Yeah, I kind of picked
up on that already.
So I... I thought you
were still in Africa?
I thought you were still in private
practice out in suburbia-ville.
Yeah, well, Reece is 13 now.
He's 13? Oh, my God.
How does that happen?
- What about you, you got kids?
- No.
- You can get married though, right?
- In theory.
- Sorry.
- Don't be. It's just another long story.
- I, uh... I guess I should get back.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- It's really good to see you.
- Yeah.
Did they tell you what
time you're going up?
No. We're in a bit of a holding
pattern, waiting for the kidney to arrive.
I got a hernia. I'll check
back in on you, though.
That would be great.
Hmm.
- What's up?
- Transpo team from Salt Lake...
is losing their patient. I
spoke to the neighbor.
Billy's mom split six,
seven years ago. Meth.
Neighbor does not think
grandma's seen her since.
- Talk to Nora about it?
- No, she wants to talk to you.
Okay.
- Hi, I'm Doug Ross.
- Suzy Nepsee.
I'm gonna go find a cup of
coffee. You want anything? Okay.
- Nice to meet you.
- It was nice to meet you.
Uh, your daughter, what's
her name, Billy's mother?
Melissa.
Do you have other children?
When was the last
time you saw her?
What was Billy like?
He's wonderful.
Smart, funny, handsome.
He loves music, especially
the kind that I can't stand...
and he plays it really loud.
Yeah.
Uh.
Lots of friends.
There's always kids coming
in and out of the house.
Big heart.
He really cares about people.
Even the little kids. I mean,
that's really unusual, you know?
- Sounds like a great kid.
- Yeah.
Generous?
Yeah.
Yes.
What parts do they use?
Well, uh, Carol, you...?
Pancreas, kidneys, liver, lungs.
Corneas to help
the blind see again.
Bones, tendons, cartilage,
ligaments, to help people walk.
He can change
lives for the better.
Five lives, maybe
10, maybe dozens.
Billy's heart could possibly save
someone else's life before dark.
It's not gonna make
up for what you lost...
but it is something.
You guys wanna hold
up here just for a second?
Can I...? ROSS: Yes.
Mr. Manning?
- Oh, call me Paul, please.
- Paul, the results are back.
Your wife has a urinary tract
infection that's spread to her kidneys.
We need to admit her to
the hospital for IV antibiotics.
- Oh, well, can't it be done at home?
- Home treatment is not as effective...
- as in-hospital.
- She'd prefer it at home.
A kidney infection can
be life-threatening...
in a woman your wife's age.
Um, I think she's trying
to get our attention.
- Oh, uh, she's thirsty.
- Daria, can you get some water, please?
No, no, no. No water.
Water will choke her.
I got something here
that I know will work better.
A little peach juice.
Here, we're gonna have
some peach juice, darling.
Here we go. Here we go, darling.
There you go. Easy, easy, easy.
She just doesn't wanna
be in another hospital.
Okay, we'll see what
we can do. We'll be back.
Easy, girl. Easy.
- You're gonna let him take her?
- It's what she wants.
- She has a treatable infection.
- She's 84, she's frail, she's disabled.
You're gonna send her
home to die from an infection.
500 Levaquin for Mrs.
Manning in Curtain 2.
They know what they're asking.
If she wants to die at home,
who are we to say she shouldn't?
Hey, hold the elevator, please?
- How's the child?
- Stabilized.
But we're gonna have to keep him a
couple of days, make sure he's okay.
Woman who dropped him
off give you an address?
No. Mm-mm.
She told a desk clerk she
was late for work and then left.
We'll begin a search
for the parents or family.
I contacted the police. They don't
have any reports of missing babies.
If no one shows up before,
uh, we discharge him...
then I'll take him to the ERC
and get foster proceedings started.
- He's a cutie.
- Oh, yeah.
I'm gonna appoint
someone from the staff...
to be his protective
custodian while he's in here.
You up for it?
- Sure.
- Good. I'll get the paperwork.
Oh. Excuse me.
Where's our plane?
What happened to our plane?
The plane that came from Chicago?
The G5? They had to leave.
- They what?
How much time do we have?
Eight hours until this heart
needs to be in a chest...
or we might as well chop it
up and use it in shepherd's pie.
- Hi, uh, we need a plane.
- Excuse me?
- I... I need a plane now to Chicago.
- Do you have an aircraft reserved?
No, our plane left
and we need another.
Something about service hours?
I don't have anything available
now. I can make a few calls...
- see if I can get a flight crew in.
- How long?
I can get a crew in
three hours, maybe four.
No, no, no. We don't have
four hours. You see this?
There's a heart in
here. A human heart.
In there? NEELA: Yeah.
There's a woman in
Chicago who needs this heart.
I don't know if they'll do it.
They're supposed to
be going to Cleveland.
You like reggae music? - What?
Carter?
- Hey.
- You okay?
Yeah. Well, they
gave me Kayexalate...
- to lower my potassium.
- Hmm.
- Oh, that is just cruel.
- What?
I'm dying of thirst.
I'm starving too.
What else you got? A burger
hidden in your scrubs there?
- No, just an energy bar.
- Mm.
- That's just wrong.
- Mm, peanut butter.
- Ha-ha-ha, oh, God.
Mm-mm-mm.
- So where is everybody?
- Who?
Your people. Your family.
My folks are in the
Bahamas for winter.
They know what's going on?
They couldn't make it,
even if they wanted to.
Come on. Fire up the jet, they
could be back before leave post-op.
- No more jet.
- Really?
It's a recession man.
Haven't you heard?
Heh. Tell me about it.
My mortgage just reset.
So, uh, how long
were you in Africa?
- Four years.
- Yeah?
- Is that where you met your ex?
- Kem.
She's not my ex yet.
Would you like to
see a picture of her?
Sure.
You married a sister?
She's half Congolese.
She was raised in France.
Wow.
And she's gorgeous, man.
You gonna let this get away?
Not my choice really.
Does she know what's going on?
That you're here waiting for a transplant?
She's in Paris. Ahem.
Her mom's sick. It's a whole...
Dr. Carter? Excuse me.
- Everything okay?
- We are moving you.
Where's Kurtag?
Could you grab that bag?
Heads up. Let's go.
Wish me luck, huh? - Yeah.
Mom?
They found a heart?
You should call her.
- Who?
- Your wife.
She'd wanna know, maybe come.
Ahem, yeah, well, I don't know.
Being on your deathbed and all,
she could swoop in, be by your side.
- Very romantic.
- Deathbed.
I know your surgeon.
You know what? Reece is going to
a Bulls game with a friend's family.
I'll stick around for a little bit, make
sure Kurtag gets all the sponges out.
You don't have to do that.
I'll be at home on the sofa,
watching SportsCenter anyway.
- They take her in already?
- Yeah.
You mind if I stick around?
That would be nice.
Was that it?
Mm-hm.
- Somebody order a kidney?
- Hey, we'd just about given up on you.
You get lost?
Stopped, got my nails done in
Boise. Figured, what's the hurry?
Flight was good?
- You like reggae?
- What?
Take care, huh?
Does anybody know
when he's coming?
How about a rough estimate?
More than a minute, less
than a hockey season?
More than an hour but
less than the lifespan...
- of a giant redwood tree?
- Carter.
I'm so hungry,
thirsty. I'm tired.
- I'm cold. My arm just fell asleep.
- Stop being a baby.
I feel like I'm hanging out of this
thing. Can someone cover up my crotch?
He's here.
We have a visitor.
I don't remember being asked
if Dr. Benton could scrub in.
I'm a friend of the patient.
- He asked if I would observe.
- Uh-huh.
- Put him under, let's do this.
- Whoa, whoa, what about the checklist?
- Excuse me?
- Safe Surgery Checklist.
I've had 10 cases today, doctor.
All the more reason to take
the necessary precautions.
- It'll only take a minute.
- One minute.
John Carter here for a right
cadaveric renal allograft?
Correct.
Does the patient
have a known allergy?
- No.
- Does Anesthesia anticipate...
- a difficult airway?
- No.
The risk of bleeding
greater than 500 cc's?
I sure as hell hope not.
Let's go, put him under.
Whoa, whoa. Everybody slow down.
Now let's just take our
time and introduce the room.
What's next? We all hold
hands and sing "Kumbaya"?
- Sheila Lane, scrub nurse.
- Paula Cheney, circulating nurse.
Kay Schumaker, anesthesiologist.
Randall Okerman,
chief surgical resident.
Ethan Dean, surgical intern.
Peter Benton, observing
general surgeon.
- Concerns from the surgical team?
- That you're wasting my time.
- Nursing concerns?
- Don't have reperfusion solution.
- We won't need it.
- I'll have some sent up.
Were antibiotics given
the last 60 minutes?
- Just starting them now.
- Ten blade.
Hold it, hold it, hold on.
If you run antibiotics prior to incision,
you cut the risk of infection by half.
Dr. Benton, you're a guest
here and I don't like guests.
As a friend of the patient,
you're welcome to sit, observe...
and shut up.
Ten blade.
That sucks. - What?
There's not much atrial cuff.
Pulmonary artery's a little short as well.
We can still use it?
It's been seven and a half
hours. We're at the limits of time.
Fixing this is only
gonna prolong the delay.
- We don't have a choice.
- Sure, we do. Wait for another heart.
What about the
pericardium as the buttress?
- Use it to graft to the native atrium.
- We're really on the edge.
Even with ischemia, she's got a
better chance of surviving with this heart.
If we leave her on the
ECMO, she's gonna die.
Four-0 Prolene on an SH needle.
Dr. Rasgotra, take us through the steps.
Donor left atrium to
the native arterial cuff.
Arterial and venous
anastomoses are complete.
Releasing the clamps.
Suture lines look
good. No leaks.
Five-O for the ureter.
Shouldn't it be
pinking up by now?
What happened to
sitting quietly, Dr. Benton?
No, seriously, shouldn't it be?
Sometimes it takes a minute.
I don't have a
parenchymal pulse.
Crap. We've got an
arterial thrombosis.
Re-clamp, take down the sutures.
- Satinsky?
- Where's the clot?
Renal artery. It's
obstructing the blood flow.
You're gonna have to take
it out and start all over again.
Problem solved.
Flush with heparin, saline
and reperfusion solution.
Reperfusion solution?
We've got it. We're all set.
Good thing we had
some laying around.
How long to get the reperfusion
up from the pharmacy?
Fifteen minutes.
What happens if
you don't have it?
You made your point.
- I disagree, doctor.
I think that this is an
excellent teaching opportunity.
Fifteen minutes of warm ischemia.
Organ would have taken a major blow.
A chance we would have ended
with a non-functioning kidney.
Wouldn't you agree, doctor?
If we're all done teaching here,
perhaps you would assist me...
in getting this kidney back
into the patient's body?
Where do you get that checklist?
Now, people.
How long? NEELA: Nine
hours and 14 minutes.
I've got the airway.
Get the transesophageal
echo ready.
Cut. NEELA:
Anastamoses are irrigated.
Temp's up to 34.
Okay, moment of truth.
Remove the cross clamp.
No oozing at the graft sites.
We've got fibrillation, people.
Paddles to Dr. Rasgotra. Go.
Charged to 10. NEELA: Clear.
- Still fib.
- Going again. Clear.
Fib. - Go again.
Come on Joanie,
sweetheart, you can do it.
Clear.
Hey.
Where'd you go this morning?
We were looking all over for you.
Is he okay?
Yeah. We're gonna keep him
in the hospital for a few days...
but, uh, he's fine.
Um, what's your name?
- What?
- Your name?
Family Services needs to
get a report to the police.
They need to get the
address where you found him.
See if we can find somebody
who knows anything about him.
I tried, you know, to take
care of him. I tried really hard.
You did a good job.
Bringing him here was
the right thing to do.
I thought I was gonna
be able to handle it.
But after he was born,
it was just so hard...
and I couldn't deal with it.
You're the mother?
Derrick said he was gonna
stay with me and take care of us...
but he split a few months ago.
My parents don't want
me around. They hate me.
I just thought that if I...
- So he's really okay?
- Yeah.
Look, do you wanna hold him?
No.
I wanted to make sure
he's gonna be all right.
No, please, stay.
Look, you don't have to
decide anything right now.
The weeks after childbirth
are stressful, traumatic.
You may be experiencing
postpartum depression.
We can help you with that.
There are support groups.
Look, you're just
overwhelmed, but that'll pass.
You just have to give it time.
Please, wait.
He'll have a good home, okay?
Make sure he has a good home.
It's been too long, hasn't it?
These things take time.
Would you like to see her?
Here, here. Press for fentanyl.
You're still here?
I don't wanna miss all the fun.
- What about Reece?
- He's at home with Cleo.
Hmm.
- You and Cleo are still...?
- Yep.
So how did it go?
Well...
Oh.
That is a beautiful sight.
800 cc's of liquid gold.
Hey, um, is my personal-belonging
bag around here someplace?
- Yeah, it's right here.
- There's a cell phone in there.
- Would you dial a number for me?
- Sure.
Here.
There's a speed-dial
toggle to the left there.
- John, I know how to use a cell phone.
- Okay, it's under K.
Kem.
Hey.
Did I wake you?
I have some really good news.
She's just there.
Oh, go on. It's okay.
Okay.
Hi, Mom.
Carol Hathaway.
Really? Oh, that's fantastic.
No, no, I appreciate it.
Yeah, I'll see you in
the morning. Thanks.
- Hey.
- Mm.
- Mm-hm.
That was Cindy.
Chicago called them.
The heart worked.
Went to a 36-year-old
woman with a daughter.
And the kidney too.
Went to some doctor.
- Not bad for a day's work, huh?
- Not bad.
- I love you.