Over the past 20 years,
one of the most valuable tools
a doctor has is the algorithm.
Your patient's main
complaint goes into a box...
Cristina was
supposed to fly out with
us this morning,
and she didn't show.
And then the formula helps
you decide what to do next.
Her phone's still off.
No, uh, Derek, all she said
was, "That's how it goes."
Last night after the ceremony.
And then that
smug idiot's speech
was a 20-minute ode to himself.
Ma'am, we're shutting the doors.
She'll just be one second.
His research wasn't
even research.
I read his paper on lymph
nodes. It sounded plagiarized.
I'm very sorry, but you'll
need to put your phone away.
I heard you.
Uh, I'll call you when we land.
But what happens when
the problem
doesn't fit into a box?
All right, Mama hung up on us.
Zola, time to put on
your shoes, sweetie.
Well...
You're suddenly on
your own, unexpectedly,
with about a thousand
paths to choose from.
I should have
called. I know. Uh...
But if I called,
you'd have said no.
And then I wouldn't get to
see how grown up you are.
Zola! Wow!
Look at you! What
are you, 16 now?
And I wanted to
meet my nephew. Oh.
Um... Hello to you, too.
I haven't talked to
you in two months.
Amy, what are you doing here?
A thing happened.
James proposed.
Ah! Congratulations.
And I freaked. I'm sure you did.
Just sort of freaked. Not
flee-the-country freaked.
Just suddenly...
There's the possibility
that I may be
facing a different kind of life.
The kind that you
and Meredith have.
So I thought I would come visit
and see what it's like
and get unfreaked.
Hopefully.
You're mad.
No. I'm happy to show you.
Hey, Zola, Auntie Amy is gonna
play with you and Bailey today
while I go to work. Oh. Oh.
Wow. Really not
mad. No, I'm excited.
Yeah. So, Bailey
gets bottle in an hour.
His schedule's
on the refrigerator.
Zola likes to stick
stuff up her nose,
so keep an eye on her. Oh.
Okay.
I'll see you later.
Okay, so, we
turkey-baste me in May.
And then the baby's
born in February?
Yep.
Sorry. Just, uh, need to
borrow some toothpaste.
As you were.
Okay, so, I take off the
spring, recover, nurse,
and then you take
off the summer.
Mmm-hmm. And then I
put Karev in charge of peds.
I think that that works.
Are you sure about that?
'Cause if you're
gone in the summer,
you're gone when
the new interns start.
You really want Karev in
charge of all the new kids?
Maybe push off the
insemination to July?
Kepner. Kepner.
Get out of my vagina.
Yes. Right.
Oh, wow.
It's really only
been two nights?
'Cause it feels like 10.
No. I'm not gonna
have time to pre-round.
Screw pre-rounds.
Your peds fellow
needs a consult.
No! No, no, no. Wait,
wait. You have to work, too.
You're avoiding something.
Less talk, more stuff.
No, Alex. I'm serious.
What's going on?
I got an offer from Lebackes
to work at his practice.
It's a good offer.
A really good offer.
Oh! That's great!
Why don't you
look like it's great?
I'm supposed to give them an
answer by the end of the day.
Oh.
Robbins is gonna be so
pissed. What am I gonna tell her?
Just be pleasant and
confident and firm,
smile when you talk,
and just tell her
how excited you are
about this great
new opportunity.
If she starts making
her scary, angry face,
distract her with a compliment.
That works? The
compliments thing? Mmm-hmm.
God, you're sexy.
Doesn't work on me.
Frankie McNeil, post-op,
day two after LVAD implantation.
Currently listed status
1A for transplant.
Despite the LVAD,
we haven't been able to
reverse her end-organ damage.
The good news is a heart
became available this morning.
We're just waiting for confirmation
from the hospital in Oakland.
I'm sorry, but who
are you again?
Oh, I'm sorry,
um, Dr. Russell is
our head of
cardiothoracic surgery.
Since Dr. Yang's not back,
he'll be performing
Frankie's transplant today.
But Dr. Yang's our surgeon.
No offense, but how do
we know you're as good?
I'm an attending.
She's a fellow.
Trust me, I'm as good.
Dr. Robbins and I will be
in the OR the entire time.
Frankie's in good hands.
And Link?
Breath sounds are strong, and
this morning's echo was all clear,
and his heart pump is
doing everything it should.
Link, buddy, that's great.
You're getting better.
When can Ivy come back in here?
Um...
Well, she's still sick,
so she needs to stay
in there a little bit longer.
Unfortunately,
Ivy's still in rejection.
UNOS has her
listed as status 1B,
and we're monitoring
her very closely.
Page when we know
the heart's a go...
Here you go, Doctor.
So, Dr. Yang won't
be back today?
Well, I haven't
heard from her, and
I can't exactly
postpone the surgery.
Has anyone heard from her?
Just make sure that
Frankie's ready and prepped.
Why are you hovering?
Thank you. What's
wrong with your face?
I like your hair.
Oh, what did you do?
Radiology's backed up.
Can you get me in line
for the next available MRI?
Sure.
Hey, Shepherd,
you're back to more
of a regular surgical
schedule, right?
Yes. Why?
The foundation asked
me to report on the status
of our surgeon-run
research projects.
Want to see which ones
are actually getting results.
So, what, they can start
shutting other ones down?
Neurological research
takes a really long time.
I'm looking at all the
projects, Derek, not just yours.
We can start making
these decisions ourselves
or wait for the
foundation to do it for us.
Remember, Dr. Torres and I
have a presidential seal of approval.
You're back!
You're gonna want to
stay away from me today.
Where's Cristina? She
must be devastated.
If I were her, I'd be face-first
in a pile of chocolate
chip cookies.
Stop it!
Cristina Yang
doesn't need your pity!
She was robbed!
And you robbed her!
Oh, I did?
Yes! You! You're an
Avery by association!
That pack of fools can't tell
their asses from their elbows,
never mind an
award-winning surgeon
versus some halfwit
who tinkers with science
kits in his mother's basement!
I told you to stay away
from me today, didn't I?
Mmm-hmm.
When did all this happen?
About a month ago.
Lebackes approached me.
I've been doing work
with him on my off time.
He thinks I could
make a really good fit.
So you've already
decided? You're leaving?
No. I don't know.
I mean, my fellowship
is almost over, so...
Well, when do they
need to know by?
Tonight.
What, you're not gonna
yell at me or something?
Frankie's heart is on its way.
See, we just don't understand.
Two days ago, he was fine,
and now he's struggling
to even breathe.
You gave him chemo last night.
Is that what's making
him so much sicker?
I mean, I know it has something
to do with the gene therapy.
Well, the chemo
obliterated the bone marrow,
which contained the
enzyme-deficient cells.
Such a mild dose
wouldn't make him sick.
We believe he picked
up a viral infection.
How? He's in isolation!
He has no contact with anyone.
How is that possible?
Your son has no immune system.
We've taken every
precaution, but this is a hospital.
Look at him! He's barely alive!
Maybe we should
just stop everything
and let him get
better, just let him rest.
Remember, we went through this.
He could get sicker
before he got better.
We're still on track
for this afternoon.
When you inject an HIV virus
into our very sick little boy.
Inject a deactivated HIV...
Okay, look, look,
we just need to hang
on a little while longer.
We're almost there.
Braden.
Let's give this kid a
new heart, shall we?
10 blade.
I've got it, Dr. Russell.
Yang!
This is a surprise.
When'd you get back?
Thank you for covering,
Russell, but I've got it from here.
I'm already scrubbed
and ready to go.
Why don't you take a
load off? You must be tired.
I've followed Frankie McNeil
since day one. Thank you.
Tough loss last night, Yang.
Must have stung.
Better luck next time.
It was an honor
just to be nominated.
10 blade.
What on earth are
you doing here?
Oh!
I like to keep you guessing.
Ooh. You better get in here
before I do something
that will embarrass Henry.
Oh, wow!
Ooh! Mmm.
Mmm. I should
surprise you more often.
Well, I'm not that surprised.
How come?
I thought you might
show up and poke around,
trying to figure out why
Dr. Yang didn't get her award.
Oh, please. I planned
this trip a long time ago.
I figured you'd be
exhausted from the ceremony
and need a little getaway.
You didn't plan it as a victory
lap to celebrate Yang's big win?
Mmm... That would
have been a nice feature.
Yeah.
But I think the weekend
will have other nice features.
Oh. Really?
So, why don't you
finish what you're doing?
Mmm-hmm. I'll sit here
and watch the magic,
and then I'll take
you to dinner.
Mmm.
Yes, Dr. Webber.
Hey. Hi. How are you?
Good.
How'd you sleep?
Fine, thanks.
Have you talked to
Cristina? Is she okay?
I really thought that she had...
Yeah, I know. I
was shocked, too.
Um, so, I need to
come home tonight.
You want to talk? I...
I need my iPod.
I went running
today, and I wished...
Sure. Sure.
Are you okay?
You look...
Stressed. I'm a little stressed.
I got to compile a
report for the foundation
on the value of people's
research projects,
'cause we're not gonna be able
to keep all of them, I don't think.
Wow.
What?
You guys deny her the
award and not 24 hours later,
you're talking about
shutting down her research?
You know that that was
her life's dream, right?
That's not what we're doing.
They're looking for ways to...
Classy move, Avery family.
Way to make it all
about the medicine.
Okay. What do we got?
Sam Roane, 23.
Been walking cross-country
for the past three months,
stopping only for sleep
and the pickup
that took him out.
Hypotensive with
multiple blunt trauma
and deformity to the
right lower extremity.
Paramedics splinted
him in the field.
So, three months? That
means you started walking from...
Wilmington. CALLIE: Wow.
Were you, uh,
walking for charity?
No. I mean, I fell in with a few
cancer groups along the way,
you know, for the snacks,
but it was more about really
committing to something
and following it
through to the end.
And then I got hit by a truck.
Okay, the femur fracture must
have transected the femoral artery.
That's why he's so hypotensive.
He is losing all his blood
volume into his thigh. Mmm-hmm.
Foot is pulseless and cold.
We need to do an angio
in the OR. Let's move now.
I mean, they screwed her!
And I was ready to make a scene,
but she just sat
there in her seat.
She clapped for him.
She applauded him, Derek!
No, go ahead. Get it out.
And now I can't
even get a hold of her.
I mean, she could
still be in Boston.
She could be in Mexico.
I have no idea where...
She's in OR 1. Thank God!
Is that a spinal schwannoma?
It is.
Extended into the
retropleural space?
Mmm-hmm.
Is that for me?
We're overdue for a date.
OR 3, you in fresh scrubs,
me in a ferryboat scrub cap.
You in?
Well, this could take
hours. What about the kids?
Amy's with them. We have
a babysitter named Amy?
Amy my sister. The junkie?
She's a recovering
addict, and she loves kids.
I've only been gone a day.
The tumor involves
the great vessels.
I know what you're
doing. Mmm-hmm.
And it's working. Mmm-hmm.
Yeah, his femur's toast.
He'll need an ex fix.
SFA's transected.
Okay. We got to relieve
the pressure on this leg.
I just heard from Grey,
Cristina's in OR 1
doing a heart transplant.
Karev and Robbins are with her.
Hey, Wilson, did
you happen to put on
boot covers before
you came in here?
Why would I...
Okay. I get it.
It's in my socks.
Oh! That never gets old.
I just feel like it's one thing
after another, after another.
I don't know how you
do it with three sick kids.
I'm barely keeping it
together with just one.
Teresa? Hmm?
Uh, do you have those
consent forms for this afternoon?
Oh. Yeah, I forgot. Hang on.
Yeah. Take your time.
I mean, you're their parent.
You're who they trust.
But you can't
actually help them.
That's the doctor's job.
Then weeks go
by, and all this stuff
that's supposed to
be making them better
keeps not working.
And I just, I start to wonder,
"Do these doctors really
know what's best for my kids?
"Am I just kidding myself?
"Will we ever go home?"
Sorry, Doctor. No offense.
Nope. None taken.
Uh, Teresa, I'm sorry.
You just have a
couple more to sign.
Removing cross clamp
to re-establish blood flow.
I don't see one tear, one
leak. You did it perfectly.
I mean, I've really never seen
such an efficient anastomosis.
Look, Karev. Awesome job, Yang.
Inspiring. Flawless.
Charge it to 20.
Should be pumping
any minute now.
How long does it take?
Usually, it's pretty much
right after restoring blood flow,
so eyes on the field.
This is not something
you want to miss
on your first transplant.
So...
Shouldn't it be
contracting by now?
Dr. Yang?
Starting cardiac massage.
Pacing wires now.
Get me intracardiac epi.
Come on, come on, come on. Beat.
What's UNOS saying?
We're waiting on a call back.
I don't understand.
How does that happen?
They sent us a
freaking lemon heart.
They must have injured it when
they were moving it from the donor.
It's UNOS. They've located
another heart that's a match.
It's in Portland.
How often does that happen?
Karev and I will go get it. We
can't risk another screw-up.
Well, both of us don't
need to... Now. Let's go.
Cristina, you okay? Yeah.
Dr. Yang, Frankie's already
been on bypass for hours.
And she's gonna stay
on it. Keep monitoring her.
Page me if anything changes.
All right.
That's it.
Shall we?
You really thought
I would come here
and question why Yang
didn't get a Harper Avery?
Well, you're a proud papa.
She's your prize student.
I know it's important to you.
It's important to
the whole hospital.
And you're an
investor in that hospital,
so I think it'd be
important to you, too.
It is.
That's why it's good that
there is an impartial committee.
Well...
"Well" what?
It's not that impartial.
Look, it makes no
sense that she lost.
See, I read her paper, I read
every other nominated paper.
There's no comparison...
Unless there was some
statistical calculation she blew,
some gross error buried
way down in the data.
You know as well as I do
none of them even holds a
candle to what Yang's been doing.
Number one, I'm
glad you're alive.
Number two, who do
you want me to go after?
Because I'm in your corner. Mer.
But I can't be in your corner
if you disappear on me.
Mer, not now.
Dr. Yang, they're asking
for you in the CCU.
Ivy McNeil's sats
dropped below 70.
Dr. Yang, you're
back. Thank God.
Ivy's heart is failing.
She has a lot of
fluid in her lungs.
I need to intubate right away.
Prepare for RSI with 15
of etomidate and 10 of vec.
Link. Link, don't look, buddy.
I'm here, honey.
Push etomidate.
I barely got two
words out of her.
She's obviously not okay, right?
You said she got pulled
into an emergency.
I'm sure she's fine.
You know, this is the most
time we've spent together,
just the two of us, in weeks.
It's really nice.
We have to do it more often.
Grey?
Should have left
a tie on the door.
About your portal
vein project...
Do you really need lab
staff five days a week?
Yes. Say yes. Yes. Why?
The foundation is
trimming research. What?
No, no, no. They're just
looking... The hell they are.
The Harper Avery Foundation
doesn't make any
decisions about this hospital.
If there's one thing
the Harper Avery
Foundation can't do well,
it's decide who
should get something.
Okay, I am just...
Tell them that if they cut
my funding, I cut their tires.
Cristina Yang
deserved that award,
not Dr. Nobody
Sucksalot from Hopkins.
And tell them in short
sentences with little, tiny words,
because they are boneheads!
And we were having so much fun.
Jackson and I aren't
having just a fight.
This is important.
It's not something
that can be just glossed
over, ignored, or fixed.
I can't pretend like
nothing's wrong.
Yeah, I know. I know.
You said all that last night,
then again this
morning over breakfast.
And now. You're
saying it all again now.
Hey. Wow. Look at that.
His ex fix really
looks ready to go.
Sadly, I think our
work is done here.
Wha... You're leaving?
You're not leaving.
Don't we need to review the
measurements with imaging?
No, we do. We
do. Uh, it's just...
We should really stay out
of Kepner and Hunt's way,
so we're gonna
do it in radiology,
where there are bigger screens
and better lighting. Sound good?
Well, we're almost
done here, so...
Take your time.
Let's go, Wilson.
We should take him
home! Let him get better!
Let this treatment
get more established!
We don't have to
be the guinea pig!
But the treatment can
bring us our son back.
He can live a normal life.
Or it could kill him!
They say it won't,
but this therapy
is made with HIV.
That doesn't freak you out?
It's deactivated!
Do you even know
what that means?
Do you know what that means?
Excuse me. I need to do
one final blood test on Braden.
No! No more blood
draws! No more injections!
Nothing else! We're done!
This treatment is too
much! It's killing him!
Okay, Teresa, look, I
know that you're scared.
Teresa...
No, tell Dr. Bailey we
have changed our minds.
You're not injecting Braden
with anything today. You got it?
The last time that
we were on a plane...
Can we not talk about the
last time you were on a plane?
No.
Alex, the last time that we
were on a plane together.
The first time we met. Look...
I know you brought
me on this plane
to talk me out
of taking this job.
We'll be in Portland soon.
Just get it over with and
say what you're gonna say.
It's not like I can go anywhere.
We were on our
way to pick up a liver
and a small bowel
for a 10-year-old...
And now you
think I'm selling out,
that I'm choosing
money over substance,
and that it's a waste of
my talent or whatever...
That there's more to life
than nice schedules
and a big, fat paycheck.
Well, I've thought
about it hard.
You've been awesome, but I've
already stayed here once for you.
I have to start thinking about
myself, about what I want.
I've worked hard,
and I deserve this.
I deserve to think about
myself for once, okay?
Yang is a robot.
If I just lost the Harper
Avery, I'd be AWOL,
in my bed with a
bottle of Scotch.
Although, she did just throw
pickups across a crowded OR.
Yang's a surgeon.
She cares more about her
patients than stupid awards.
What's the latest ABG?
Uh, pH is 7.15,
pCO2 is 52.
Crap. She's acidotic.
Push bicarb and
increase her sweep.
Okay. SHANE: Okay, good. Good.
Shane, she's bleeding.
It's coming from one
of the suture lines.
Page Dr. Yang now!
Ivy's lungs are doing
better after the intubation,
but I need to
place a special line
to get a more accurate
measurement of her heart.
You may want to leave
during this procedure.
No. I'm staying. I want to stay.
You ran in here after
Frankie's surgery. Is she...
There was a complication
with Frankie's donor heart,
but a second one
has been located,
and it's on its way.
I just wanted to keep Frankie
in the OR until it arrives.
What? Is that safe?
Is she gonna be okay?
She's being closely monitored.
Dr. Yang, Dr. Ross and Dr. Murphy
are on the phone from OR 1.
Put them on speaker.
Ross, update me. I'm
here with Frankie's dad.
Frankie's bleeding from
one of her suture lines.
And she's really acidotic.
Jon, you should
step out. I'm staying.
Ross, did you push
bicarb? We did.
How are her coags?
Stable, but this bleed
isn't slowing down.
Okay, well, you need
to stop that bleeding.
If she continues to bleed...
The triad of death. We know.
I'm so sorry, sir.
Okay, throw a
horizontal mattress stitch,
but careful with her tissues.
They're extremely
friable, so soft hands.
You're on the right
side of the table.
You have one chance, or else
you could rip through the aorta,
which is essential to connecting
the new heart when it arrives.
Nope.
Just take a breath,
just throw the stitch.
You can do this.
I've never put a
horizontal mattress
in an aorta before.
Only in a bowel.
From this side, I'll just tear
through her native aorta.
Well, what if I tear through it?
You won't!
You can do this.
Ross! Murphy!
We got it. We stopped the bleed.
She's fine.
They're both fine.
She gets results.
She always has, and
this is no exception.
Make me understand,
because my read is that
Yang should have clearly won.
I mean, what am I missing?
From where I'm standing,
she had it by a mile.
Richard, honestly, tell
me you're not this naive.
Well, what is that
supposed to mean?
The Harper Avery Foundation
co-owns the hospital
Cristina Yang works for.
She could never win that award.
I don't know how long
this stitch is gonna hold.
PH and bicarb?
7.0 and 14.
Dr. Yang, now she's
oozing from the IVC.
I see it, Shane. Aren't
we gonna put in a suture?
If we just keep
throwing in stitches,
she'll dissect all
over the place.
We have to get
Frankie off this table.
How? She's getting a transplant.
In this state, she'll
never survive it.
First, she gets a lemon heart,
and now we don't know if
the new one's gonna make it?
Wait. Is that Robbins?
How we doing?
The heart is out, and
we're on the move.
Want to let the
coordinator know?
Oh. Phone the pilot. Let
him know we're on our way.
So, this is how
it's gonna be now?
Radio silence till the
end of my fellowship?
That's how you're
gonna leave things?
Alex, I brought you here today
because I trusted your skills
to properly procure this heart.
And then we got on that
plane, and I started feeling sad
because you're leaving
soon and I will miss you.
I didn't bring you
today to scold you.
I'm proud of you
and I'm happy for you,
and all I wanted was to share
a freaking memory, okay?
I was being sentimental!
Oh.
You know, if I take the job,
I'm still gonna have
hospital privileges.
You'll see me around.
Shut up, Karev. Moment's ruined.
Just a few more sutures.
You know where he
was when he got hit?
He was crossing Highway 519.
He could see the water.
All he wanted to do was
walk from ocean to ocean.
He was just so freaking close.
Okay, let's check the pulse.
It's not fair, you know?
You make a commitment, it's
supposed to mean something,
and then a pickup
truck just takes you out.
Hey, you okay?
Sorry.
I just feel like
this fight with Jackson
is, like, the fight,
and I...
I don't know how
we recover from it.
Listen.
Some fights, you
just can't get past.
You know?
Like me and Cristina, it
was... It was about kids.
You and Avery?
This is your first fight.
You will get past this,
and then something
else will come along,
and you'll fight
about that, too.
And you guys will
recover every time.
This is not your pickup truck.
Now that it's thawed,
and I've added the
virus to the culture,
I just have to wash them
down and give him the injection
within the next
four to six hours,
and then, theoretically,
that's when the
magic will happen.
See, that's the
problem, though, Bailey.
So far, all of
this is theoretical,
and the foundation
needs actual results.
I need you to help me out, okay?
Give me something,
anything concrete,
that shows that your
project is producing results.
No. It will be.
Once I give this
targeted gene therapy
to my bubble
boy, I know it will.
I can feel it.
Okay, I can't exactly pitch
that we need to keep your lab
because you have
a feeling, can I?
You said you're
doing this today?
Yes, I am.
And it's going to work.
Dr. Bailey, do you
have a minute?
You pursued her.
You encouraged her.
You all but told her
she was a front runner,
when you knew she was
nothing but window dressing.
She was not window dressing!
She was nominated
for a prestigious award
that brought publicity
to her and the hospital.
You used her!
She was never gonna win
that damn thing for a second.
Nobody from Grey Sloan Memorial
will ever win a Harper
Avery, will they... Ever?
Do you want me to remind you
why there is a Grey
Sloan Memorial Hospital?
Or should I just take my
$24 million and go home?
What draws me to you,
Richard, is your idealism.
I find it extremely attractive.
But this is business.
And I do not appreciate
your coming all the
way across the country
to harangue me about the fact
that your prize pony
didn't get a ribbon!
And if it makes you feel better,
she had the votes.
Are you that naive?
Catherine, do you really think
that's why I came
all this way...
why I planned an entire weekend
with the things that you love?
Richard... I made
reservations at Cipriani's
because I know
you love it there.
And I was going to wait
until just before dessert,
and the waiter was gonna
bring you a glass of champagne.
And I was going to tell
you how much I love you
and how right for
one another we are.
How you make me
feel excited to be alive,
how you give me a reason
to get up each morning
and say a thankful
prayer every night.
I was gonna ask
you to be by my side
for the rest of our lives.
That's why I'm here.
That's why I came.
And now I'm leaving.
I'm sorry. What?
You're gonna have to say...
You're gonna have
to say it all again.
Dr. Robbins is on her way
with a new heart for Frankie,
but Ivy's deterioration
has caused her
to shoot up to the top
of the transplant list, too.
Ivy is also a perfect match
for the donor heart en route.
But that's Frankie's heart.
Officially, yes,
but under the circumstances,
the heart could be redirected.
To Ivy?
You want to give
Frankie's heart to Ivy?
No, I don't want...
Medically speaking,
Frankie's condition
is declining rapidly.
Technically, Ivy is more stable,
which would give the heart
a better chance of survival.
Wait. Just...
But if Frankie's worse,
don't you have to give the
heart to the one that's the worst?
Unless she thinks it's a waste.
You think the heart will
be wasted on Frankie?
I just want to explain
all your options.
Our options? This
is our decision?
Wait. You're asking
us to choose?
You want us to try to pick
which of our
children gets a heart
and which one doesn't?
Frankie can be fitted with a
total artificial heart for now.
We can't choose.
You have to do it.
We have three
children, Dr. Yang...
Three amazing,
beautiful, kind children.
And we can't...
We can't try and pick
between two of them.
We won't.
You have to make this decision.
Please.
There you are.
Frankie's heart is
as stiff as a rock,
and Ivy's got global
systolic dysfunction.
It's absolutely impossible.
Why didn't you call me?
Mer already yelled
at me about this.
I'm sorry, okay? I just...
I wanted to be alone, so I left.
I'm not talking about...
I just heard about the McNeils.
You should have called me
to help you make this decision.
No surgeon should
have to make a decision
like this on their own.
That's why I'm here.
That's why you have
a chief of surgery.
They're my patients.
I know their status.
I can decide this.
But you don't have to.
Yes, I do.
Prepare to start
sectioning off the vessels.
Is that a Gustafson
artificial heart?
We're getting Frankie
off this table immediately.
And the heart that's on its way?
We're reallocating that
heart. It's going to Ivy.
Russell's prepping her now.
Okay, let's move.
You guys gonna
be home for dinner?
Yeah. Sure. Sounds good.
Okay, awesome! Can't wait!
Yeah, neither can we.
Does that mean
what I think it means?
That there's gonna
be dinner waiting for us
on our dining room
table when we get home?
Have we ever even used
our dining room table?
Just remind me
to thank my sister
for letting me actually spend
an entire day with my wife.
Well, she's not a
permanent solution.
Ah, not yet, but we
have a spare bedroom.
We could give her
surgical privileges.
That would give her
less time for childcare.
I know it's not permanent,
but we spent an entire day
without dropping any balls.
You know, maybe she'll
even put the kids to bed.
Maybe we could have some wine.
You know, Amy is
making dinner for the kids.
Maybe we have time
for a little... Mmm-hmm.
It would be a shame
to end such a great day
with no dessert.
Why aren't you trying
to talk me into staying?
Oh, God. Are we still on this?
Can't we just focus on transplanting
the heart we just retrieved?
Yeah. Never mind. I'll shut up.
Of course I want you to stay.
But this sounds like an
incredible job opportunity,
and you're right. You
did stay here for me once,
and I don't want to
stand in your way again.
So if you want to
leave, you should leave.
But not because of
something that I do or don't say.
You should leave because
this is the next best thing for you,
and because you're
excited about this job
and you're ready to
go do great things.
And collect a big, fat paycheck.
Really big.
I guess you have
a decision to make.
Don't screw this one up.
Okay, let's transport her.
BP's stable. I'm gonna see
how Russell's doing with Ivy.
Bring in the bed.
What happened?
Ventricular
pressure's up to 200.
She's dissecting.
Now she's plummeted
to 15. What the hell?
Damn it. It ruptured.
Okay, we're gonna
have to reopen her.
Staple remover!
I mean, the thing I
don't understand is,
won't Braden die if he
doesn't get this treatment?
It's possible. So...
Does this happen often
with experimental treatments?
That the parents
or the guardians
just withdraw their consent?
Please stop talking.
And then what do I do
with these consent
forms she just signed?
I mean, do I shred
them? Do I toss them?
I told you. Stop talking!
Uh, I'll take care of those.
Just get one damn
suture to hold.
How's her ventricular pressure?
Zero. OWEN: Pupils?
Fixed and nonreactive.
Cristina. What?
Cristina, we've been at
this for almost an hour.
Ivy's transplant went perfectly.
Her post-op echo
is completely normal.
She should be awake soon.
And Frankie?
No.
No!
It can't be.
You...
Well, how the hell did this...
We trusted you!
What the hell did
you do to our child?
We are so sorry for your loss.
Oh, God!
We need to be with our kids.
Your stitch held. So?
I've never seen
vessels that friable,
and I've been around
a lot of diseased hearts.
You did an amazing thing.
Shane, the kid died.
It wasn't anything you did.
They want us to be
the center of innovation,
but they don't
want to pay for it.
They love it when we innovate.
They nominated Yang for an award.
She was robbed.
They're boneheads.
We can't give with one
hand and take with the other.
We have to stop this.
There's no stopping this.
Guys, they own the place.
We are just their
managing board.
This conversation is
our relationship now.
Best we can do is try to guide
them to make the right decision.
That's by making our own
decision, as tough as that might be.
Look, this is my
report, all right?
All the projects are here.
Operating budgets
versus progress to date.
Best to worst.
Take a look, but the
decision is pretty clear to me.
Uh, you got a second?
Never mind. I'll come back.
No, no, Alex, come in.
You okay?
Uh, yeah. Yeah.
I just wanted to let you know
that my fellowship
is almost done and...
Uh, well, I got an offer
from Lebackes
pediatric surgery clinic,
Oliver Lebackes' practice,
and, uh...
Well, I gave it some
serious consideration,
and I've decided to take it.
So, I guess this is my notice.
Cristina, please don't
disappear on me again.
Where are you?
Please, just call me.
Hunt. We need to talk.
If it can wait, I
really... No, it can't.
Well?
I almost didn't
go through with it.
But then I did.
And I think it's
gonna be good, right?
Are you kidding? It's
gonna be awesome!
Baby!
Oh. Compartment syndrome?
Yes. Blood went everywhere.
Mmm. Torres loves that trick.
You should just toss those.
I know. You're right.
Why am I scrubbing
those nasty things
when now you can afford
to buy me new ones?
What happened?
Wait. Where are the kids?
They're asleep. Totally fine.
What's wrong?
I can't do this.
The children broke
your sister. Hmm.
No, it's not them.
I didn't come here to see
how your perfect life worked.
I came to see if I could do it.
The whole freaking thing,
the kids and marriage
and the full-time careers.
Because I want that, with James.
And I am wrecked after one day.
It goes on the list of things
that I suck at because...
I can't.
Well, I knew that was
too good to be true.
Why don't you
go fix your sister?
I'll order takeout.
Hey. Hey.
So, you are...
Right.
Uh, I'll see you tomorrow.
April.
I said a lot of things the
other night that I regret.
And I'm sorry that
I hurt your feelings.
I'm sorry, too.
Good. So come home. Stay.
This is a conversation we're
always gonna have to have.
It's a part of who we are.
It's gonna take some talking.
But we got married.
We love each other.
We made vows to push
through this sort of thing.
I know.
I love you, too, and
we made a commitment.
And if you believe in God,
then you believe he made me.
Your husband.
Who shares your
values, which I do.
I believe we
shouldn't kill or steal.
I believe that you
should be truthful.
should treat others
the way you want to be treated.
I agree.
So, then, we can push
through this problem.
At our core, we
believe the same things.
Until I think about
telling our children
how unbelievably loved they are
by the Creator of the
universe, who also made them,
and I can just see
you standing there,
judging and dismissive,
and I just can't get past it.
Can we please just take a break
from our hypothetical
children for...
No, we can't, because they're
not hypothetical anymore.
Jackson, I'm pregnant.
So, what do you do?
How do you decide?
When you're left in the dark?
How do you make sure
you're not making the worst
mistake of someone's life?
So, now what?
We just cross our fingers
and hope he gets better?
Guess so.
Good night, Edwards.
You close your eyes.
You block out everyone
and everything around you.
Cristina?
Are you okay?
Cristina, they
were very sick kids.
Every one of them
would have been looking at
a death sentence without you.
The fact that any
of them survived...
I know this, Owen.
Frankie was on borrowed time
from the moment she got here.
You made the right decision.
You made the right call.
I know I made the right
call. You don't have to tell me.
It was an impossible
decision, and I stand by it.
I did everything
exactly as I was supposed to.
I did it perfectly.
So what is wrong?
What's the point, Owen?
What's the point of anything?
You won.
The Harper Avery.
You got the most votes.
Richard just told me.
The politics screwed you.
The foundation's
relationship with us.
They used you.
You never stood a chance.
And pray that the
voice inside you
is right.
Because once you've decided,
you can't ever go back.