So is he standing
on the frozen lake
or will he be sitting in
one of those little huts?
It beats me.
What kind of fish do they catch?
Beats me. MALUCCI: Yo!
Morning.
I can't believe he rides
that thing in the winter.
Damn. Malucci.
What? Case
conference with Romano.
Malucci admitted a patient and
I left my notes in my apartment.
Ah, that'll teach you,
sleeping at my place.
Yeah. I'll see you later.
Oh.
You should get a U-lock.
A pair of bolt cutters and
somebody's gonna leave you
with a broken chain and no ride.
Thanks, Mom.
Tired of scolding me
for not wearing a helmet?
Dr. Dave, I'd never
want to get between you
and your personal
path to brain death.
Abdominal pain,
possible ischemic bowel,
just went to CT and
needs a surgical consult.
Got those x-rays
back from Mr. Wyatt.
Oh, good. Hey, Mark, could
you finish up with Luka, please?
Sure. What's left?
Exam 2: Mr. Kechevsky,
rule out MI.
And if somebody could call
me with the enzyme results,
I would like the follow-up.
Abby, can you
handle that? Of course.
Okay. So that's it? Yep.
All right.
ER. Yeah. Yeah,
hang on a second.
Abby, it's for you.
It's my job to
answer the phones.
Just trying to help.
And I appreciate it.
Abby Lockhart.
Yes, I did call. Three days ago.
Look, whatever. I just...
I need to talk to you
about the late payments. I...
What?
Well, you'll just have
to sell 'em. I don't...
Look, I really don't
care how you do it,
just make the payments. I...
Just make the payments.
Bye.
That was my
soon-to-be ex-husband.
Sounds bad.
Yeah, he's taken a flyer on some
tech stocks with my loan money.
Ow. Well, maybe they'll go up.
Yeah, I'll never see the cash.
Okay, I'm leaving
before I fall over.
Till next time, ladies.
Bye.
Men.
Elizabeth.
Morning. I forgot some
notes for a meeting.
You look tired. Were you
watching Charlie Rose again?
Not exactly.
Uh, morning, Elizabeth.
David came over for breakfast.
In boxers and slippers?
My slippers.
Uh, hope you don't mind.
I thought you were ice fishing.
Well...
I didn't make it.
Can see that.
Goodbye, Elizabeth.
See you.
Can I freshen your cup?
Good Lord, Mother, I
practically drank the whole pot
while the two of you
were saying goodbye.
So are you amused?
Bemused?
Irritated? Shocked?
Chagrined...?
That's a start.
I suppose you think at
my age I shouldn't be...
Mother. Mother, please.
Do you really think what
the two of you are doing
is a good idea?
I'm a little older,
but I'm not dead.
His wife is. Recently.
Then bloody well good
for him for getting on with...
Mother!
Is it so difficult to imagine
that two people could
be attracted to each other
and actually act on it?
Were you using,
you know, protection?
There are diseases.
You think he's diseased?
That's not the point.
And you really
want to discuss this?
No! No!
No.
He's my boyfriend's father. Oh!
You always cared too much
about what other people think.
Even as a little girl.
I did not! Yes, you did.
Well, how would you
know? Did the nanny tell you?
Yes, Elizabeth. You
were so neglected.
Don't pretend to know
me when you don't.
I know you a lot
better than you think.
I'm just trying to say, this
could get very complicated.
Why are you always so afraid
relationships will go wrong?
Well, perhaps because
ours hasn't exactly gone right.
I have to get to work.
Hey, no fair doing paperwork
when there are patients to see.
I'm not even on yet, Dave.
Oh, I get it. Just making
the rest of us look bad?
I'm doing chart reviews for
Carter and Lucy's patients.
S-sorry. Need my help?
I've got it.
Hey, Abby, I got a
couple of cases for you.
Foreign body up the
nose and hemorrhoids.
Be right there.
Um, and the CPK was normal.
Good. Good. Discharge
him, Abby. Yeah.
Yeah, he should follow
up with Cardiology.
No, I have the
night shift all week.
Yeah, I'll see you tomorrow.
Okay. Bye-bye. Bye.
Laura!
Stop! Stop!
It hurts. I know it hurts.
I know it hurts. I'm a doctor.
I'm gonna help you, all right?
Okay, look at me.
Look at me, please.
Try to breathe slow
and easy, okay?
Now, tell me your name
and where it hurts, huh?
Laura. My leg.
Okay, try to keep
your head still.
I didn't think that you
remove nose piercings.
Uh, I got a new stud. I
thought I'd put it in the old hole.
Okay, just inject 2
cc's of air into the Foley
and pull it back gently.
Bless you.
Hey, thanks. You're welcome.
Can I go now?
I-in a minute. Um,
hemorrhoids next?
Do the initial workup,
then find me or Mark.
Okay.
Hi.
You're not planning to use
that thing on me, are you?
We'll see.
I'm Abby.
Ron Perth.
Listen, I feel kind
of stupid coming in.
I mean, I didn't
expect to feel great,
but I'm concerned.
I'm still bleeding from the...
You know, hemorrhoids.
Uh, what, they were
banded just last week?
Yeah.
You look kind of pale.
How much bleeding?
Oh, it's not that much. Uh...
Listen, I... I'm supposed
to fly back to Denver at 5.
It's my girlfriend's birthday.
And, uh, I was kind of hoping
that you could give me a cream
or something, you
know, to shrink it down?
Sorry.
I was planning to
take her dancing.
You might want to make
it just a candlelit dinner.
Need a hand? Uh, yeah.
Could you order a
CBC, Chem-7 and coags,
and prep for anoscopy.
Mm-hm.
Is that what I think it is?
I'll be gentle.
Oh, man.
Where's my mom?
Somebody get my mom!
She'll be here, Laura.
Your sister went to get her.
Laura, I need to cut
open your pants now
so I can look at your leg, okay?
Oh, my God! Is
she gonna be okay?
It's okay. It's okay.
I'm Dr. Kovac.
I already called 911.
Laura... Hey, be careful.
Her left leg is broken
and maybe a rib too.
Mom, it hurts! Oh, I
know, baby. It's okay.
Can't you do something?
Okay, can you go and tell
that lady we need her broom?
I'll get it. What are you doing?
I'm going to splint her leg.
- Why?
- I need to check
to see if there is any
damage to the artery.
We...
We heard you can't tell
anybody anything we say to you.
Well, that depends
on what you tell me.
It's...
It's about...
Sex?
Well, uh, if there's
no abuse involved
and the guys are under 18,
then everything you tell me
has to remain confidential.
So you couldn't
tell our parents?
No, I couldn't. You promise?
Go ahead. What is it?
Look, I can't help you if
you don't tell me what it is.
Um, we're afraid we might
have caught something.
Well, what do you think
you might have caught?
We heard some syphilis
was going around school.
I see.
Why don't you girls
come with me, okay?
Okay. Okay.
My chest hurts! What is it?
I'm worried she's
bleeding internally.
Oh, no. Well,
then, do something!
I mean, where's the
ambulance? It'll be here.
No, let's just...
Let's drive her.
It's okay, baby.
It's gonna be okay.
Sir!
You, the plumber. Yeah.
I'm Dr. Kovac. I need your help.
Can you make room for this girl?
You want to put her in the van?
Yeah. She needs to get
to the hospital right now.
It's urgent.
Okay, let's... Let's
go. Okay, thanks.
In his underwear? My father?
I couldn't believe it either.
What did you say?
What could I say?
I tried to talk to her
about it after he left,
but it just turned
into an arguement.
I didn't find it that amusing.
Well, it beats ice fishing.
Well, don't you
find it a little bizarre?
Well, they're adults. You
know, it's not such a bad thing.
So what? Are they
gonna keep on doing it?
Where? Your place or mine?
He's coming in to see the
pulmonologist this afternoon.
I'll talk to him.
Yeah, thanks.
- I can't breathe.
- Okay, hang on.
Her broken rib could've
punctured the lung.
Look to the right, Laura.
Now to the left.
Laura? Laura?
Oh, my God!
No breath sounds.
What's happening?
She has a tension pneumothorax.
An air leak has
collapsed her lung,
and compression is keeping
her heart from beating.
We have to put this
needle in her chest
to relieve the pressure.
Oh.
Oh, my God! Okay...
Wait, why is she bleeding?
I might have nicked an
artery when we hit that bump.
An artery?
Here, keep pressure where
the blood's coming out.
Oh, God.
Something wrong back there?
These pads are soaked.
Just keep pressing
them, okay? Okay.
Come on, damn it.
Yeah, this is Kovac. Yeah, I'm
coming in with a major trauma.
Clear a room and
get four units of O-neg.
Yeah.
Go faster. We need
to be there now!
Auto versus 10-year-old girl.
Blunt trauma to right lower
chest and fractured left femur.
Hang on, honey!
We need to set up for
a chest tube right away.
Pulse is thready.
You need any more help?
No. Got it. Thank you.
She was stable, but
then I lost her pulse
with decreased breath
sounds on the right.
Some improvement
with needle thoracostomy,
but I may have
nicked her intercostal.
What happened?
The van hit a bump
when the needle was inside her.
Why didn't you wait
for the paramedics?
I waited seven minutes.
I thought I might lose her if
I didn't get here right away.
Paramedics arrived two
minutes after you left the scene.
I'm sorry. You'll
have to wait outside.
Get a trauma panel,
UA, type and cross for 4.
Two large-bore IVs. Uh,
squeeze in a saline, prep the chest.
BP's 80 palp, pulse, 110.
I want my mom. Where's my mom?
She's just outside.
How are you doing?
Mom!
Give her something for the pain.
- Lidocaine.
- 10 blade.
- I need ultrasound.
- 28 French.
Luka, you've been
off for an hour.
We got it from here.
I'll stay.
Get X-ray up here.
Pulse ox, 92 on 10 liters.
We need to intubate.
6-and-a-half ET tube.
I'm in, hook me up.
Whoa! Uh-oh.
Chest full of blood.
Pressure's down to 70.
FINCH: You did hit the artery.
Lydia, call the O.R.,
have them hold a room.
Looks like it was
more than a nick.
Got more than a liter out.
Pressure's down to 50.
Laura.
- She's unresponsive.
- All right, let's prep
for a right-sided thoracotomy.
Not much longer now, Andrea.
Is Terri okay?
She's fine. She's
sitting over in Chairs.
There's cervical bleeding.
And thick and white
dysplasia with papules.
Is that syphilis? Dysplasia?
There's no sign of syphilis.
But we have to wait for
the blood test to be sure.
You can go ahead
and get dressed.
So I can go?
No. Your HIV test
won't take long.
I'd like you to wait.
Well, am I all right?
Let's wait and see
what the test says.
The other girl looks okay,
but get Pathology to do a
stat Pap-smear on this one.
Okay.
All right. Let's
get you dressed.
Well, Mr. Perth... Ron, please.
Ron.
Uh, your blood count's normal.
That's good, right?
Right, uh, although
sometimes it takes a while
for a crit to show a blood loss.
Yeah, but I... I feel okay.
Yeah, but I'd hate to
have you on that plane
and start to bleed
out at 35,000 feet.
You want to do another test.
Yeah.
I'm going to draw some blood,
which is then tagged
with a radionucleotide,
which I then reinject by IV.
And then a scan lets
me trace for bleeding.
Yeah, okay. As long as
I won't glow in the dark.
Nah, quick and
painless, I promise.
So honestly, is it really
the thought that counts?
Uh, about what?
Oh, uh, for my
girlfriend's birthday.
I was thinking of jewelry.
But if I go there, I've
got to go big, right?
I don't know.
The best present my
husband ever gave me
was a surprise picnic
that he packed himself.
Ah, romantic.
Cheap.
Hello. Hi.
Oh, Dr. Weaver, Mr. Perth.
How's he doing?
Rule out GI bleed.
I'm drawing some blood
for a nuclear medicine scan.
Oh, we don't do those
very often down here.
CBC and lytes come back?
Yeah, they're normal.
Abby, can I talk to
you for a minute?
Sure.
Hold that.
Okay, the belly's benign,
there's no evidence of a bleed.
So... So why order
such an expensive test?
He just doesn't look well to me.
His... His skin is pale,
his eyes are dull...
Yeah, that's hardly
diagnostic of a bleed.
I... I really don't think
the scan is necessary.
You should discharge him.
Is there a problem?
No.
I just have to
get this to the lab.
More suction. Got it.
Are you gonna
stick tie the bleeder?
No. Too close to the bone.
All right, let me get 0
silk on a Keith needle.
What are you doing?
Kennedy maneuver.
Transmural hemostatic suture.
Second unit's in. Hang another.
And autotransfuse
from the cell saver.
Take the superior
and the inferior,
and tie them tight
on the outside.
Dry as a bone. Nice.
New seizure in 2.
I should get this.
You okay, Peter? Mm-hm.
Check the BP.
How about another crit?
Yeah, fine.
Luka, let's go
talk to the mother.
All right.
Pressure's crashing.
The chest is dry.
Ultrasound. Check
the belly again.
She dropped her pressure.
She must still be bleeding.
You're right.
Belly's full of blood.
It's the liver.
She blew the capsule.
We should have
checked the belly.
Hang two units, get
her up to the O.R.!
Let's move now!
What is it?
We're taking her to surgery.
This is her mother.
Come with us. Come on.
Dr. Kovac, you've done enough.
Why don't you let
us take it from here?
I want to stay with
her. She's my patient.
No, no. Not anymore.
Why don't you go
home, get some sleep?
You think I'm going to sleep?
Luka.
That's hilarious. Oh, my God!
I can't believe
it. That's great.
Oh, wait, we gotta go. Bye.
Sorry, we were just
talking to some friends.
Terri, I need to talk
to Andrea privately.
Is she all right?
Uh, could you just go
wait in Chairs, please?
Hey, it's okay.
Thanks.
Andrea, we got
your test results.
They found some abnormal
cells in your Pap smear.
You might have cervical cancer.
We need to do a
biopsy just to make sure.
Cancer?
Was it caused by having sex?
Well, you get it from
an infected partner.
It's called HPV.
Human Papilloma Virus.
But not everybody
with HPV has cancer...
No, you can't tell my parents.
Andrea, if you have this,
you need to be
admitted to the hospital.
Anyway, they're in Europe.
And you said everything I
told you was confidential.
If you're not treated,
you could get very sick.
We also have to
inform your partner.
Andrea...
I don't know who it is.
I mean, which one.
Well, how many have you had?
Not sure.
We, um... We have these parties.
Peter, I want to scrub in.
No.
Why not? You're not a surgeon.
I'm not asking to
operate. Let it go.
I'll call you as soon as
I'm finished. Let's go.
She'll be all right.
Coming back down to the ER?
In a minute.
Come with me. I'll show
you where you can wait.
And then there was Mrs.
Saltzman in for shoulder pain
and you sent her out for an MRI.
And you were right.
C5-6 herniated disc.
And, uh, Mr. Blandeleau,
chest pain.
Ruled in for an MI,
had angioplasty.
And, uh, he's doing okay.
That's it.
Thanks.
No problem.
Are you doing Lucy's cases too?
Told Weaver I didn't mind.
How was the memorial service?
Okay. It was nice.
A little weird.
How's everything
else downstairs?
Ah, same old thing.
How are you doing?
I'm doing fine.
I know everybody who works
here. People drop by all day.
I bet.
Even my grandmother came by.
I thought you didn't
talk to her anymore.
Well, there's nothing like
a near-fatal stab wound
to put a different
spin on things.
Hey, I'm gonna be back
to work in a couple weeks.
Get rid of this bag.
Maybe take up skydiving.
Hm, you do that.
All right. Get out of
here. I need my rest.
All right. Um...
You need help back on the bed?
No. I'm good. Okay.
Well, catch you tomorrow.
Yep.
Oh, uh, John,
uh... Are you okay?
Yeah, fine.
Listen, take it easy, okay?
Yeah. Thanks, Deb.
Dad.
You're late.
Three minutes.
Appointment was 11:45.
I didn't know how long it would
take to drive back from the lake
and I was worried you might
have fallen through the ice.
Yeah. Very funny, Mark.
Like you don't know.
Just having a little fun.
Which is apparently
what you were doing.
I don't think Elizabeth
was too amused.
I'd say that's pretty accurate.
Yeah, I suppose it's wrong,
being in her place and all.
Oh, don't worry about it.
We'll go to a hotel tonight.
What?
It'll be easier for everyone.
So it's kind of
an ongoing thing?
What do you think?
This is a one-night stand?
I don't know. I...
What floor is this
pulmonologist on?
Fifth floor.
I like her, Mark. She
makes me happy.
Now, I'm sorry if that
makes you unhappy.
I didn't say that, Dad.
But she'll be back in
London in a couple of weeks
and I'll be back
on your sofa bed.
Then we can both be unhappy.
How many has she slept with?
I don't know.
Both girls have been
going to these sex parties
at schoolfriends' houses.
Oh, my God. At their age?
I promised her I
wouldn't tell her folks,
and legally I can't.
W-wait. She... She's a
minor and she needs surgery.
Well, maybe I can talk her
into letting me tell her parents.
Carol, I understand you don't
want to break confidentiality,
but this is a public
health issue now.
At least one of those
boys is spreading HPV.
And the girls at those parties
all need to have pelvic
exams and Pap smears.
So whatever she says, you
also need to call the school.
Hey, Malik, have you seen
a girl in a school uniform?
I saw two of 'em.
They went out that door.
Oh, damn it!
Excuse me?
Uh... yeah?
My name is Barbara Knight.
I'm looking for Dr. Greene.
Uh, he was here
just a minute ago.
Or maybe Dr. Weaver?
And she was here
just a minute ago too.
It looks like right
now, I'm all you got.
Actually, I just need to
find your lounge area.
Can I help you? We
don't usually let people
wait in the lounge area.
No. No, I just need to
check my daughter's locker.
Um, uh, sorry. Your name?
Barbara Knight.
I'm Lucy's mother.
I don't have the combination.
Oh, it... It's okay.
The med school gave it to me.
All right. Good.
Uh-oh. Oh, it's just...
Thank you.
I've checked into
the Ritz-Carlton.
So I won't be needing that.
Mother, this is
completely unnecessary.
They have a lovely
view of the lake.
If you'll excuse me,
I have a meeting.
Oh, stop it.
Just being practical, dear.
At our ages, there's no reason
for mothers and daughters
to be living together.
You say that as if we
ever really lived together.
I love you, Elizabeth,
but I swear, at times
you can be insufferable.
Me? I can be insufferable?
What exactly do
you blame me for?
I don't blame you for anything.
Then stop acting as if you do.
So I wasn't the
conventional mother.
How much time did
your father offer you?
This isn't about Dad.
No. It's about what
I couldn't provide.
Fathers are rarely blamed
for working too much
whereas mothers are blamed
if they choose to work at all.
Should you get married
sometime and have a child,
will you give up your work?
I don't know. I don't know
if that's gonna happen.
Then I'm sorry I set you
such a terrible example.
Technetium?
Yeah.
Didn't show any signs
of bleeding, did it?
No. And why did you order a scan
that I said was unnecessary?
It's just a feeling that I
have. I don't know what it is.
Maybe it's a nursing
instinct or something.
But the guy does not look well.
Yeah, it's the middle of
winter. Nobody looks well.
And medical students
don't order tests
when they're told not to.
It's a waste of your time
and his money. Cut him loose.
Abby, if Benton calls
down can you get me?
I'm going across the street to
grab something to eat, okay?
I thought you weren't on.
No... I-I'm not.
Have you called the police?
What?
Hey, hold on, man.
I'm not done yet.
Call them now!
Get out of my way!
You're not leaving!
Leave me alone!
Wait, now. Hold up, man.
What the hell is wrong with you?
Get off of me! You
just left her there!
I don't know anything.
You hit her and then
left. Malik, call Security.
I don't know what
you're talking about!
Yes, you know. I saw
you, and I can identify you!
It was an accident. Yeah?
And you just drove
off? Hit-and-run?
I was scared, okay?
I wa... I was scared...
So was that little girl!
I-I panicked, all right. I...
I had a couple of DUIs. But...
But I wasn't
drinking today, okay?
I just... It all
happened so fast.
I-I didn't know what to do.
Yeah, but you knew
enough to run away, huh?
D-did you bring her here?
Is she all right?
You don't have the right to ask.
All right, maybe I was
just being a hypochondriac,
thinking something was wrong.
No, you were right to come in.
And... And you'd be
right to come back.
Well, thanks. I'll,
uh, keep an eye on it.
I mean, say, for example,
in 15 or 20 minutes,
if you're feeling feverish
or sick to your stomach,
you might want to
get that checked out.
Yeah, but you just saw me.
Um, well, it might not
be me who sees you,
but somebody
would have to see you
and I'm sure they'd want
to examine you thoroughly.
Are you saying I'm not okay?
I'm just saying that it's been
an awfully bad flu season.
You wanna take a break?
No, I'm okay.
That's enough for today.
Well, that's...
Hang on a second.
You did great.
I'll get the chair...
I said I can do it!
I just wanna get
back to my room.
Dr. Carter?
What are you doing here?
Andrea, I need to talk to
you. You narked us out!
Get away! You
promised, you bitch!
Look, you need to come back in.
You said there were
rules you couldn't break.
I know what I said, but I can't.
You lied to me.
To both of us.
Look, it is a lot more
complicated than that.
Your health is in danger.
Other girls could get infected too.
Now everyone's
gonna know everything.
Andrea? Andrea!
So, uh, we'll have to reschedule
the bowel resection for 4:30.
Yup.
Hello. Sorry. I didn't
mean to surprise you.
Certainly not twice in one day.
You're here for
your appointment?
I think it's on the fifth floor.
I've already been.
Got poked and prodded
and x-rayed out the wazoo.
Damn doctors. No offense.
None taken.
And I'm sorry if my presence
offended you this morning.
Oh, I was just, uh... Well,
you said it. Surprised.
Well, I didn't mean
to make trouble
between you and your mother.
Oh, no. None that
wasn't there already.
Excuse me. And why is that?
I mean, why is there trouble?
Mothers and
daughters, I suppose.
Oh, well, you... You don't get to
own the whole ranch on that one.
Let's save a little corner
for fathers and sons.
Although I will admit mothers
and daughters are worse.
Ha. But that's just
a woman thing.
You know, the only
problem with children
is they grow up to be adults.
Yes, we do eventually
have opinions of our own.
I know. But do you
have to express them?
It's a learned response.
I'll give you that.
I suggest that the four
of us go out tonight.
You know, sort of,
bury the hatchet.
Mark thinks it's a great idea.
He doesn't.
He will.
Abby didn't discharge him?
He bounced back with
fever and abdominal pain.
BP's fallen 80/60.
Hang a unit on
the rapid infuser.
What happened?
GI bleed. I began a
rectal. He started gushing.
Probably a bleeding tic.
Type and cross four
units and call the O.R.
Yup, I already did. I'm in.
Okay, hook him up.
Thank God he came back in.
Chicago wasn't
even her first choice.
She was hoping for
something in San Francisco.
I took her when she was about 8.
One ride on a cable
car and it was her city.
Uh, although she
grew to love this one.
You don't need to hear all this.
No, it's fine.
I really just wanted to
stop by and thank you.
Lucy always talked
about you when she called.
About how she was first assigned
to you and... And everything.
She had a lot of
respect for you.
And I know that you
must have taught her a lot.
Well, she worked with all
the residents. Not just me.
I know.
But you're the one
she used to mention.
But she... She loved her work.
She was better than I
ever gave her credit for.
Um, can I ask you something?
Yes.
When you were...
Well, when that man stabbed you,
what did you think?
No... I mean,
what did it feel like?
Well, um...
It happened really fast,
and I didn't really know
what was going on.
But I didn't feel a thing.
No pain?
Mm-mm.
No pain.
Hey, Steve, did you
get that venogram?
I ordered it two hours ago.
I had a CT-guided biopsy.
You gonna be able to get it?
After my embolization.
So does that mean
sometime tomorrow afternoon?
With that attitude.
Hey, did you read a chest
CT on a David Greene today?
Who?
My father. He
came in for a scan.
I don't know. Check the pile.
That's a big stack.
Well, while you're at it,
maybe you can help me
out and read a few plain films.
Oh, yeah, or maybe you could
just work a few more hours.
Don't start.
ER guys come in
and want wet reads yesterday.
Here we go.
ICU orders portables
for every damn
feeding-tube placement.
You guys think you have
high volume in the ER?
I get high volume
from the hospital.
Hey, Mark? You okay?
That's your dad?
Yeah.
Wow. Uh, I'm sorry.
So he didn't tell you
where we're going?
Just an address.
It's the "wear jeans"
part that's scaring me.
Not to mention I don't think
my mother owns a pair of jeans.
And I don't know
if I want to see her.
Right.
I wish you were off so we
could face them together.
Yeah.
Are you all right, Mark?
What?
You've limited yourself
to one-word responses.
Uh, you know,
I'm sorry. I just...
I gotta finish some cases.
I'm gonna have
to meet you there.
All right.
I'll see you.
What did the school say?
Oh, they said
they'd follow through,
but the girls saw me there.
I suppose they didn't
listen to you this time.
No, they ran away.
Carol, you did the right thing.
I'm still gonna
call Andrea later.
Abby.
Your, uh, hemorrhoid
patient, Mr. Perth, is in the O.R.
They're doing a laparotomy.
Yeah, I heard he went
up. Is he gonna be okay?
Yeah, he should. He... He's
got a bleeding diverticulum.
You know, it's pretty lucky
that he checked himself back in.
Yeah.
I'm gonna go check on him later.
Good.
You were right. There was
something else wrong with him.
Just a gut feeling.
Hmm. I mean, he
could have bled to death
if he hadn't come back.
Well, it's a good
thing that he felt fluish.
That's exactly what
he said: "fluish."
Mrs. Williams,
Laura came out of
surgery very well.
The nurse will take you
now to see her, if you'd like.
Yes.
Thank you.
Both of you.
I was, uh, out of
line before. I'm sorry.
Ah, come on. I understand.
Did you repair her hepatic vein?
Atrial-caval shunt.
It'll be a long recovery,
but she should be fine.
You saved her life.
Yeah, I'm not so sure.
You had to open her chest
in the ER to fix my mistake.
Yeah, but we would have
had to do that anyway.
The liver laceration was
a life-threatening injury.
Look, if you waited
for the ambulance,
she might not have made it.
It's impossible to know.
Listen to me.
You made a call.
It took a lot of guts.
What do we got?
Andrea Parks. Found
down on bathroom floor.
Presumed overdose.
No suicide note,
but a lot of bottles
in the cabinet.
Any narcotics?
No. She's lethargic,
but arousable.
Andrea.
When did she take the pills?
An hour or two ago.
Her friend found her.
Well, where is she? On the way.
What drugs did you
take? Leave me alone!
Polydrug ingestion.
What'd you take?
Shut up! MALUCCI: You know her?
She came in this
morning. Cervical cancer.
CBC, chem panel, blood
and urine tox screen.
On my count. One, two, three.
We're gonna have to pump
her stomach. I'll get an Ewald.
She may not need
lavage. Pill bottles?
Yeah, I had 'em
in a bag. They fell...
Well, go and find 'em.
We're gonna need them.
Maybe you should step out.
Did you send an aspirin level?
You running this?
Pulse ox is 96 on 2 liters.
I'll run an EKG. It
could be tricyclics.
So tonight's the jazz club.
Yeah, it's a pretty good spot.
A good group is
playing. Cleo knows it too.
Uh-huh. Heh.
What's that supposed to mean?
Nothing.
You're right on schedule.
All right, Carter.
Give it to me.
Well, first, there was
probably coffee in the cafeteria.
And then dinner in a
nice but well-lit restaurant.
Nothing too obvious.
Then, maybe a sporting event.
And tonight's the jazz club.
We all know what
happens after the jazz club.
When did you lose the filter
between your brain and mouth?
I think you might have taken
it out in the O.R. last week.
Yeah. Ah-ha.
Here. Let me help
you. I got it! I got it!
Damn it!
Carter. Carter. Carter.
It's all right. It's all right.
You okay?
I lied to Lucy's mother today.
I told her that
it wasn't painful
to have an 8-inch knife
shoved into your gut.
Andrea! Andrea!
She's tachy at 120.
Terri, hold on. Do you
know what she took?
No, she was just
lying on the floor.
Was it something from
your medicine cabinet?
It was my parents' bathroom.
Do you know what was there?
I don't know. Uh, lots of
stuff. Uh, Tylenol, aspirin...
Any prescription medications?
My dad sometimes
takes pills for his back.
Do you know what they're called?
Diaz... Diaz... Diazepam?
Yeah. Sats down to 81.
She's barely responsive.
Okay, lost her gag reflex.
Let's intubate. Not yet.
I can bag her, okay?
She could vomit and aspirate.
Were there any
antidepressants? No.
Are you sure? Yeah.
Okay, any history
of seizures? No.
Push flumazenil, 0.2 milligrams.
She's hypoxic.
Intubate. Slow down.
Give the flumazenil a chance.
We have to protect her airway.
All right, good. It worked.
What...? What...?
What am I doing here?
Terri found you.
Do you remember
taking the pills?
What?
You're gonna be okay, Andrea.
Oh, God, Andrea.
What did you do?
Let's give her charcoal now.
Oh.
Well... It's an
interesting game.
Don't worry, you'll get it.
A martini would help.
Do they have those here?
Well, that should do the
trick. Loosen you up a bit.
Do you want anything?
No, thanks.
What's keeping Mark, anyway?
He'll be here. I hope.
Do you know how to keep score?
Not a clue.
But you're learning
these American games?
One by one. At least I'm trying.
I think that's rather
adventurous of you.
That meeting I was
running off to earlier...
I missed it.
Must be the first
time that's happened.
Yes, I think it was.
I was appalled at myself.
Just couldn't be bothered to go.
Went and sat by
the lake instead.
I bet that was freezing.
The only thing colder
than sitting by that lake
was the conversation
we had this afternoon.
Elizabeth, I know I'm not the
mother you wish you'd had.
That's not exactly true.
And I keep hoping that
somehow you'll forgive me for that.
The problem is you
never wanted forgiveness.
There's the rub. Heh.
Mark's father thinks children
shouldn't express
their opinions.
Yes?
Well, he's absolutely right.
I'll take over, Conni.
Sure, thanks.
How are you doing?
Okay.
Andrea, I had to tell the school
so the other students
could get tested.
But I haven't told
your parents. Or Terri's.
You haven't?
I was hoping you would.
If something happened
to one of them,
wouldn't you want to know?
Ow! Oh, God.
Now, that was ugly. Do
I get penalized for that?
Oh, there's just
a little dent there.
- What do you mean?
- We can switch lanes.
There's no dent. I'm
kidding. Hey, hey, Mark.
Hey. Hey, what kept you?
Ah, nothing. It was
just... Hi, Isabelle.
Sit down. Have a drink.
I think my ball's stuck.
That's 'cause you broke it.
Oh, stop it!
Press the button.
We'll work you in on
the next one, Mark.
No problem. But
there's not gonna be
the boys against the
girls. It wouldn't be fair.
Neither one of 'em
is any good at all.
And by the way, I'll
be back on the sofa.
Isabelle's going back
to Elizabeth's tonight.
It's sort of a
mother-daughter fest.
Sure. Grab a ball.
All right.
Oh, no, no. Eliz... Elizabeth,
you're too far to the right.
Yeah, but last
time it fell to the left.
You see those marks
on the floor out there?
The arrows? Yeah.
Aim to the one just
on the right of center.
And pull your... Pull the
ball all the way back. And...
And don't drop it. I mean,
just let it roll on the floor.
And keep your wrists straight.
That's an awful lot to remember.
Here, let me... Let me show you.
I never knew he
was a surgical intern.
Yeah. Well, no, he was
good. He was smart, you know?
He wasn't really cut out for it.
Used to spend all of his
time talking to the patients.
It used to drive me crazy.
Morgenstern...
You don't know him,
but, uh, one time he made Carter
hold a retractor for four hours.
Carter never broke a
sweat, never dropped it.
He's gonna be all right, Peter.
Yeah, I know.
Tickets.
You sure you wanna go in there?
Oh, yeah.
We're not gonna be able to talk.
Let's go get some
coffee. Come on.
You're gonna disappoint Carter.
What?
Nothing.
What? Nothing.
That was fun tonight.
Uh, yeah, it was.
Dad, I need to talk to
you about something.
Sure.
I saw your scan today,
and you have lung cancer
which has spread to your liver.
Yeah.
That's what the doctors
in San Diego said too.
How long have you known?
For a while.
Why didn't you tell me?
You remember old
Rear Admiral Norris?
Yeah, how could I...?
How could I forget him?
He was missing a thumb.
He used to scared
me to death as a kid.
He had cancer.
Every time I laid eyes on
him, all I could think was:
"Poor old bastard,
he's got cancer."
Hell, he lived another 12 years.
But still, every
time I saw him...
I didn't want it to
define me, Mark.
I didn't wanna see
it in people's eyes.
I didn't want to see it at all.
And...
I'm scared.