You asleep?
Cleo?
Mm.
You asleep? Mm-hm.
It's snowing outside.
What time is it?
Almost 6.
You know, I was thinking, um...
I have to be in at 7.
The alarm's going
off in 10 minutes.
I'll be quick.
Mm. The hell you will.
You feel it?
No.
There. Oh, wow.
It's really moving.
How long has she
been going on like this?
On and off all night.
Shh.
Go back to sleep.
I keep thinking
about that movie.
Alien. You know?
It's moving around
under his skin,
and then, all of a sudden,
it breaks its way
through with its teeth.
Amanda, stop it.
You're scaring your mother.
Amanda.
So the baby's a girl today.
Or Matthew, after
my grandfather.
Can't decide.
Last day?
Last day.
What?
It's okay.
Hi.
Did I wake you?
Uh-uh.
I was trying to let you sleep.
I should probably
get home anyway.
You should bring
a few things over.
I could clear out some
closet space for you.
Are you sure you can spare it?
I can find a couple of inches.
Somewhere, maybe.
I need to dry my hair.
Mm-hm.
Are you gonna watch me again?
You're okay?
Mm-hm.
And you?
Penny for your thoughts.
Pardon?
It means...
It means, "What are
you thinking about?"
Nothing, really.
I was thinking about the bishop.
Making love with me makes you
think of a priest with lupus?
Hm.
You watch me when we make love.
You're beautiful.
What was her name?
Who?
Your wife.
Daniella.
Did you love her very much?
Yeah.
I'm glad.
Carter. Four-year-old boy's
coming in from preschool.
Fever, trouble breathing.
Sixty-two's pulling in.
Okey-dokey.
Hey, Frank. Is
Dr. Greene here yet?
No. Said he was
coming in a little late.
Weaver's upstairs at some
big administrative powwow.
Probably suggesting
the installation
of pay toilets in the
employee bathrooms.
Is Kovac here?
He's got a dead shovel in 3.
They're trying to bring back.
I guess it's just you and
me then, with this 4-year-old.
Hey, I can take it.
Welcome back. Ha. Thanks.
How are you feeling?
Oh, pretty good.
Want me to tag along with you?
No. I've got it.
Eight weeks. Could
be some cobwebs.
Thanks, anyway.
Call me if she gets
into any trouble.
Okay.
You look great.
Oh. I still have a
few pounds to drop.
Can't tell. Oh, I should
have gotten a coat.
Go in and grab
one. No, I'm all right.
Zack Woodman, 4 years old.
Post grand mal
seizure at his preschool.
We were finishing
arts and crafts,
and he started shaking
and wet his pants.
You his mother? No,
his preschool teacher.
Feels like he's burning
up. BP's 100/60. Pulse, 120.
Does he have a
history of epilepsy?
No. Not that I know of.
Zack, open your eyes. Zack...
Excuse me. Can somebody help me?
Oh. Are you hurt, sir? No,
it's not me. He's in the car.
He's very weak. I don't
think he can walk on his own.
Abby?
What's wrong with him?
He's having trouble breathing.
Has he been ill? Yes.
When did this start?
I don't know. A couple
hours ago, I guess.
Hi.
Hello.
Can you walk?
I don't think so.
I need a septic workup, CBC,
blood and urine
cultures, chest x-ray.
Temp's 105.
Sorry. The bishop's back.
I need a weight.
Blue zone, 20 kilos.
360 milligrams
of rectal Tylenol.
Pulse ox, 82.
Put him on a mask, 10 liters.
Do you want to do a spinal tap?
He could have meningitis.
Well... Or a febrile seizure,
and he's going to wake up.
Why don't I get an LP tray?
I wanna wait a few minutes.
Give 900 of cefotaxime
after the cultures.
Well, I love what you've
done with the place, Peter.
Very Teutonic.
None of the trappings
of success to interfere
with your, um, performing
your new duties.
Well, I requisitioned
some furniture,
but I hear the form is still
on your desk waiting
for your signature.
Well, you should see my in-box.
Must be 18 inches deep.
Are those admissions folders?
Yeah. I thought I would
familiarize myself with them
before I met with candidates.
Don't bother. Kids come in,
and toss out a
bunch of tired clichés
about wanting to help people.
You could ask their favorite
color, or if they like cheese.
Doesn't matter.
Step outside a
minute, would you?
He, uh, showed up at my office
whining about not
getting an interview.
So I thought you
should shake his hand,
since this sort of falls
under your purview,
before you have the,
uh, Security toss him out.
Hey.
That's your man.
Dean Benton?
Dr. Benton.
William White.
Thanks for finding
the time to see me.
Yeah. Well... what
can I do for you?
I, uh... Uh, I got this letter.
I applied to the medical school,
but I didn't get an interview.
Teacher doesn't have a
signed emergency consent form.
He's still not waking
up. How long's it been?
Forty minutes.
Zack? Zack, can you hear me?
He needs an LP.
We don't have parental consent.
Get another doc to sign
off the chart with you.
Okay. Get the tray set up.
Frank... where's Carter?
In 4. Granny took a fall.
Dr. Carter, can I see
you for a moment?
Sure.
I've got that 4-year-old
with febrile seizure. Mm-hm.
He's still altered. I
wanna do a spinal tap,
but the preschool doesn't
have an emergency consent.
And we haven't been
able to contact a parent yet.
Any other signs?
Well, x-ray looks
like viral pneumonia.
I can't assess for a stiff
neck, but there is photophobia.
Well, where do you
want me to sign?
Oxygen saturation's only 78.
What should it be?
Hundred.
Seventy-eight sounds
like a passing grade.
Barely.
Put him up to four liters.
CBC, blood cultures, ABG,
sed rate and a portable chest.
And hang a gram of cefotaxime
in case it's pneumonia.
Pneumonia? I don't even
feel like I have a fever.
The steroids prevent
you from having fevers.
And push 125 of Solu-Medrol.
You're giving me more steroids?
You could have
a flare of the lupus
with inflammation in the lung.
There's also a chance that
you are throwing blood clots.
Oh.
Lupus makes your blood
coagulate more easily.
Have you called your own doctor?
No.
I'll call him. No.
Why? Because you... You
think I'm easier to manipulate?
I'm not nearly as Machiavellian
as you imagine me to be.
I came here because
I prefer your care.
How's it going?
Easy tap when
they're unconscious.
Looks pretty clear.
Cute kid. What's his name? Zack.
Cell count, glucose, protein,
Gram's stain and culture.
He's got those shoes
that light up when you walk.
How do you think they do that?
Want to roll him back over?
What is that?
What?
That.
You didn't tell me he
had a macular rash.
Wasn't there half an hour ago.
Must be a viral exanthem.
Could be measles.
Measles?
Yeah.
Fever, altered mental
status, pneumonia.
Or more likely he has
a virus with pneumonia,
and had a febrile seizure
from the high temperature.
That is a classic measles rash.
Abby, can you hand
me a tongue depressor?
Have you ever seen
measles? No. Have you?
Of course not.
Nobody's seen measles.
Can you, uh...?
He's got Koplik spots
on the buccal mucosa.
What?
Or he bit the inside of his
mouth when he was seizing.
Malik, There's a
Nelson's in the lounge.
Can you grab it, please?
Now.
Is Zack all right?
Uh, this is Mrs.
Woodman. I was in court.
I have to turn off my cell when
we're in session. oh, my God.
I'm Dr. Chen. Your
son had a seizure
and a high temperature.
We've done a spinal
tap to rule out meningitis.
Mrs. Woodman, are Zack's
immunizations up-to-date?
No. CARTER: Has he had the MMR?
He hasn't had any immunizations.
None of our children have.
I got it, Dr. Carter.
Abby, put a mask on Zack.
MRS. WOODMAN What's the matter?
What the hell is happening?
Get him into the
Laminar Flow Room.
Call the school. Don't
let anybody leave.
What's the matter with my son?
Your son has measles.
That's not too bad, right?
One in 500 kids
die from measles.
Frank, I'm taking
the Luiz kid up now.
Please send along the films when
you find them again, will you?
Yes, ma'am.
Hi.
Hey.
So how'd it go? Fine.
Fine? That's it?
I laid down, they shot a couple
billion more rads into my skull,
and then I left.
And that's it.
Hopefully, my irradiated
head won't screw up
any navigational equipment
on our next flight.
All right, all right.
I have to go.
Uh, lunch?
Uh, if I can. Come find me.
Okay. All right.
So did I hear
right? You're done?
Radiation treatment.
Just two more weeks
of immune therapy.
Uh, Dr. Greene? Yeah?
That's great. Hey, did they
give you the tumor back?
What? When they took it out,
did they give it back to
you? Because my uncle Al,
he's got his on
a mantle in a jar.
Guy over there
wants to talk to you.
You know, Dave, I
don't really want a...
tumor on my mantle.
Hi. Dr. Greene.
Can I help you?
Robert Wilson. Uh, is there
someplace we could talk?
Actually, I'm on duty.
It'd be better if we
had some privacy.
I'm sorry, Mr.,
um... Dr. Wilson.
Dr. Wilson. What is it?
I work for the
Illinois Department
of Professional Regulation.
We've been asked to
evaluate your competency
to continue practicing medicine.
Where in the hell
did he catch measles?
Europe, I think.
Mom was in Paris on
business two weeks ago.
Took the whole family.
She some fringe lunatic
thinks immunizations
are a conspiracy
between doctors
and drug companies?
Oh, I don't think so.
Talk to the mom. Find out if
there are other kids at home,
where the child's been,
anyone he's had contact with
over the last week.
How is he? They
won't let me back there.
We had to move him to a room
with a special
ventilation system
so that he doesn't
contaminate the rest of the ER.
Is he awake? Still unconscious.
He has pneumonia.
And, in all likelihood,
encephalitis.
What's that? Inflammation
around the brain.
Were you able to get in
touch with the preschool?
Yes. All the children are there.
Make sure they've
all been immunized.
Their parents, their siblings,
anyone that they've
been in contact with.
There's a phone at the desk.
Tell Frank that Dr. Carter
said you could use it.
Okay. Okay. Please.
You have other children?
Yes, a daughter. I
called my husband.
He's coming with her.
And she hasn't been
immunized either?
No. Is Zack gonna be okay?
Well, he's in grave condition
with a highly
contagious disease.
I'm not an irresponsible parent.
I read all the literature
on the Internet,
the parenting magazines.
I discussed it with
my pediatrician.
And he didn't recommend
the MMR? I breast-fed.
Zack's immune system could have
been weakened from vaccinations.
The immune system is
strengthened by vaccines.
Kids are exposed to
foreign antigens every day.
Vaccines aren't completely safe.
I'm sorry... They
aren't, and you know it.
The connection between
vaccinations and autism...
There is no connection.
Dr. Carter...
Zack dropped his sats.
He's at 75 at 100 percent.
He's getting cyanotic. I've
already started the atropine.
Etomidate and sux. I
need a 5-0 uncuffed ET
and a number 2 curved blade.
Please. What's going on?
There's so much lung
damage that no oxygen
can get into his bloodstream.
What are you doing to him?
We'll put a tube in his throat
to get him more oxygen. He
needs a machine to breathe?
If we don't intubate
him, he's gonna die.
I'll do it. CHEN:
No, I've got it.
Not on your first day
back. Step out, doctor.
What? Step out, doctor.
Give me some suction.
He's throwing PVCs. Oh, my God.
Come on.
Okay. I got it.
Good breath sounds, bilateral.
- Pulse ox up to 88.
- Tidal volume of 150,
AC of 14. Let's keep him on
100 percent with three of PEEP.
He's okay now?
Yeah, sure. He's great.
Is that the bishop's?
He says he's feeling better.
So he'll be able to perform
the ordination this afternoon?
What?
That's where we were headed
when he became ill in the car.
One of the kids that he
baptized at his first parish
is being ordained
as a priest today.
Where do you think you're going?
I feel much better.
Your ABG shows
an oxygen level of 58.
And your sed rate is 84.
Eighty-four. Is that good?
No, it's not good!
It's an indication
of active lupus.
Stop buttoning the damn shirt.
Is Joe still outside?
I think I'm gonna need some help
getting into these pants.
You need to be admitted
to the ICU for IV Cytoxan.
It'll only take me
a couple of hours.
If the inflammation in
your lungs continues,
you won't get enough
oxygen to stay alive.
If I skip the reception, I
can be back in here by 6.
You'll be dead by 6!
It's in God's hands.
God could give a damn.
Is there something
I should sign...
so I can go?
You're kidding! Stephanie?
Yep, she just up
and moved to Seattle.
I thought she was
living with Deborah.
No, she met a stewardess
on Alaska Airlines
Another stewardess!
Hey. We were
just looking for you.
This is Christy. Christy, Kerry.
Hi.
Hello.
Christy and I
were having coffee.
And I insisted that she
bring me down here.
I'm sorry, but a bunch of us
were beginning to
question your existence.
We were all thinking
about getting dinner tonight.
You game?
I don't think I can get off in
time. But thank you for asking.
I checked your
schedule. You get off at 6.
Don't worry. Nobody bites.
Uh, chief, can I get you
to sign off on this LOL?
Head CT's clear.
Seven-thirty?
Okay.
Oh, great. We'll see you then.
Bye.
That, uh, Legaspi's girlfriend?
Heard she's gay.
I don't know.
Hm. What I wouldn't
pay to drop in
on that little party, huh?
You turned me in?
A guy from the medical board
questioning my competency.
Don't walk away. I'm not.
I don't wanna have this
conversation in the lobby.
He wants to see
my medical records.
He's planning on
interviewing the staff
to see if I'm still fit
to practice medicine.
He can pull my license. Look,
I've been concerned about
the changes in your personality
since the surgery.
I tried to talk to you about it,
but you've chosen to ignore me.
So you call in the licensing...?
Keep your voice down.
They cut a tumor
out of my head, Kerry.
I'm sorry if I seem a
little different to you.
I wouldn't come back to
work if I couldn't do the job.
What about the
aphasia? It's getting better.
And if you're in an
emergency situation
and couldn't think of the
name of the drug you wanted,
the nurses ask 20 questions
while the patient dies?
Nobody's dying!
You've been insensitive
and argumentative.
I have not been!
You have been
shooting from the hip,
and I'm not the only one
who's expressed concern.
For the safety of the patients,
I felt I had to call the board
for an objective assessment.
I-I-I want you to pass,
so that we can all
get back to work
confident in your abilities.
Okay?
Rich people think if all the
poor kids are immunized,
then they don't have to be.
Thought it stopped snowing.
If everybody stops
getting vaccines,
then smallpox will be
back, polio, measles. Hey.
Then they'll be lined
up around the block
begging us to stick a needle
into precious
little Annie's arm.
Fifty-year-old male with
non-Hodgkin's lymphoma.
Persistent nausea and
vomiting despite Compazine.
BP's 88/58. Pulse, 130.
Mucous membranes very dry.
Gave a liter of saline en route.
He only finished the
chemotherapy last week.
Is the cancer back?
No. He's probably just
having a reaction to the chemo.
How's the little boy? Which one?
The kid with the
febrile seizure.
You brought him in?
Yeah, couple hours ago.
They didn't call
you? About what?
He has measles. You drove
an immunosuppressed patient
in the same rig?
What does that mean?
Damn it. Nobody told us.
I'll need a CBC and a Chem-20.
Watch your step.
Excuse me.
I need to review a
file of an applicant
who wasn't given an interview.
And you are?
Peter Benton. I'm the
new director of diversity.
Lucky you. This year?
Yeah.
It would be in the reject
pile. What's the name?
White. William White.
We had over 3000
applications for 150 spots.
Big pile.
Director of diversity, huh?
That position's a little quixotic
around here these days.
My David wouldn't be
working for Morgan Stanley
without affirmative action.
William Jackson White.
Thank you.
Excuse me. Do you keep files
of past candidates
that were accepted?
I need to compare them.
Compared to last
year's acceptances.
They're over there
by graduating year.
2004 is on the right.
Student Affairs.
Fax it over.
I'll be looking for it.
Student Affairs.
Yeah.
What are you doing out here?
Just getting some air.
What's the matter?
How's your bishop?
He just left.
That's good, right?
He's having an
acute lupus flare.
He left AMA.
So go get him.
Take some oxygen,
make sure he's okay.
He... He knew what he was doing.
I'm not his keeper.
So this is you, huh?
Yep.
Could use a little something.
What is that back there?
My room with a view.
Cafeteria kitchen.
Vending machine only
had turkey and egg salad.
No veggie. All right.
Thank you.
Hear about our
measles kid downstairs?
Four years old,
parents didn't vaccinate.
What's all this?
Med school applications.
Thinking about starting over?
Is this your file?
Uh, this black kid applied
and didn't get an interview.
I went to Records to find
out why and found that.
Oh, yeah? Anything interesting?
Yeah. My file
wasn't with the rest.
It was in the back with
three others filed under AA.
Affirmative Action.
That surprise you?
Hell, yeah.
Look, my grades were good, my
MCAT scores were competitive.
Yeah, but...
when I compared it
to the other applicants
that were accepted that year,
I shouldn't have even gotten in.
You're an excellent
physician, Peter.
They were right to let you in.
Oh, yeah?
This is the file of the kid
that didn't even get
an interview this year.
William White.
His grades, his MCAT scores,
they're better than mine were.
Bishop Stewart?
Mm.
Damn it.
I'm okay.
How long have you been
having trouble breathing?
I'm just...
gathering my strength.
You have to go to the hospital.
It's pretty... isn't it?
The snow.
So much beauty.
Where's the phone? I
need to call an ambulance.
No. Please. I only
need a minute.
You're dying.
Evidently.
As I was sitting here,
I was reminded of the night
I chose to become a priest.
I'd been struggling
with it for...
a long time.
Several years.
Anyway, that night,
I couldn't sleep.
So I... I got up
and... went out for a walk...
in the woods behind
my father's house.
It was snowing. Like it is now.
I don't have any idea
how long I walked.
But at a certain point...
I suddenly realized I
didn't know which way to go.
I'd gotten lost.
I was frightened.
As I looked up into
that dark night...
he came to me.
I saw all those
millions of snowflakes
drifting down toward me.
So still.
So peaceful.
Perfect.
And I was filled with the
love of our Lord, Jesus Christ.
Like pouring wine...
into an empty glass.
I'm afraid...
I may have wasted my life.
For some reason,
I never accomplished
the things I should have.
What God wanted of me.
And now I'm frightened.
I'm afraid of dying.
There. I said it.
I am...
afraid to die.
You have to go to the hospital.
The Lord is my
shepherd, I shall not want.
He maketh me to lie
down in green pastures.
He leadeth me
beside the still waters.
Is he all right?
No... Yes.
The procession is forming.
What should I tell them?
Tell them...
I think I have to
skip the processional.
When did you lose your faith?
I've found with most
people, it comes and goes.
Like...
intimacy in a relationship.
Sometimes...
it's so strong.
A passion, rapture.
And then at other
times it's impossible,
distant...
lost.
But that's not God.
That's us.
We put up our own barriers...
with our egos...
and our pain.
He's always there.
No matter what.
Bach.
I love Bach.
Well...
that's my cue.
So, Kevin...
why do you want to be a doctor?
I've given that question
a great deal of thought.
And I think it all boils
down to one thing:
I really want to help people.
My dad died of lung cancer
and I was 12.
And I vowed I would
work for a cure.
My research in molecular
biology has been very rewarding.
I expect we'll see gene
therapy in our lifetime.
I'm a people person.
The bottom line is,
I want to help people.
I volunteered for
the Pediatrics ward.
When I saw my kitty
suffering like that,
I... knew that I had a calling.
To help people in
their time of need.
You have to combine
humanistic skills...
With a passion for
making a difference.
And I really just
wanna help people.
I just wanna help people.
I wanna help people.
Help people.
How dare you?! Damn it, Kerry.
They sawed off half his skull.
Then they inserted high-dosage
chemotherapy wafers... Hello.
Into the empty cavity.
It caused temporary
swelling right next to Broca's.
Of course he had
a little aphasia.
But that was six weeks ago.
The swelling's gone down,
and he's back to normal.
If anything, I find his
honesty rather refreshing.
We could all do with a
little more candor here.
Candidly speaking then,
are you sure that you can
be objective about this?
Of course I'm not objective!
Look, I've been with
him every moment,
and I can tell you he's
making remarkable progress
and is no danger to anyone.
Except perhaps easily
threatened, minor demigods.
He may be endangering patients.
I'm not unsympathetic
to his circumstances,
but I have larger
responsibilities.
It's despicable.
And you should be
ashamed of yourself.
I hope that you end up with
a possibly fatal
illness one day,
so that I can do absolutely
nothing to help you.
What was that about?
Uh. Some days I
really hate this job.
Well, you, me and
everyone else around here.
Are you ready?
Dinner? Right.
Yes. I just have
to, uh, drop this off.
Carter, you still got that
leg lac waiting in Sutures.
I'm on it. WEAVER:
Get there by Easter,
would you, please?! Yeah, yeah.
Hey, Malik? Yeah?
Is this the measles kid's
post-intubation film? Yeah.
How come it didn't go
up to the PICU with him?
I'll take it up.
No, that's all right.
I'll do it. I want to
check on him anyway.
Phi Beta Kappa, Yale.
GPA's 3.95.
MCATs in the 97th percentile.
Yeah, sure.
Peter?
All right.
And... Carpenter.
University of Georgia.
Wait, was this the, uh...?
The geek in the Smashing
Pumpkins, uh, T-shirt,
with the... With the lisp?
Sarah. Redhead, glasses.
Oh, yeah. Right, right.
GPA, 3.79. Ninety-fourth
percentile on the MCATs.
Finalist for the
Falsberg Science Award.
Whatever the hell that
is. We've got better.
Peter?
No. Okay.
Okay, that's it for today.
We are recommending two
to the full committee,
and rejecting 14.
Great. I still might make
it home for SportsCenter.
Uh, there is another
candidate I'd like to discuss.
William White.
Who?
His MCAT scores were
only in the 91st percentile,
but his GPA was 3.80
and he was class president.
Wait, I don't see
him on the list.
We didn't grant
him an interview.
I met with him today,
and he asked me to
reconsider his application.
Oh, no. Is this that whiner
I told you to get rid of?
Where did he go to school?
University of Illinois, Chicago.
My gardener could have
gotten a 3.8 at the U of I,
and his head was run over
by an ice cream truck as a kid.
I went to the
University of Illinois.
His MCATs are well below
our admission standards, Peter.
MCATs don't predict how
good a doctor you'll be.
Just what you do the first
two years of med school.
This kid is bright.
He's dedicated...
He's black.
Yeah, he's black.
Affirmative action's
against the law, Peter.
We didn't interview one black
or Latino candidate today.
We have a colorblind
admissions policy.
If he was good enough,
he would be here.
Minorities don't
have the same access
to academic opportunities.
You want to address that
by advancing
underqualified applicants
at the expense of our
integrity and theirs?
I want him to have an interview.
♪ Lord, have mercy ♪
♪ Christ, have mercy ♪
♪ Holy Mary, mother of God ♪
♪ Pray for us ♪
♪ Saint Michael ♪
♪ Holy angels of God ♪
Clear.
♪ Pray for us ♪
Still V-fib. What happened?
Hypoxia, bradyed down to 20,
then he arrested. Another epi.
He's on PEEP? Maxed out.
And his PO-2's only 39
on 100 percent oxygen.
Charge to 50. NURSE: Clear!
Asystole.
How long has he been
down? Forty minutes.
He's had two rounds of atropine?
Lidocaine, amiodarone
and dopamine.
You got any other ideas?
Hold compressions.
♪ St. Mary Magdalene ♪
♪ Pray for us ♪
♪ St. Stephen ♪
- ♪ - St.
- Ignatius ♪
♪ Pray for us ♪
♪ St. Lawrence ♪
Vicki is dating guys now,
and Carol is getting
married to one.
Oh.
Both of these women marched
in every gay-pride parade
for the past 15 years.
I don't get it.
I do. You get
society's blessing,
your family's... Survivor
benefits, tax breaks.
Mm.
And all you gotta do is lay
there a few times a week.
I'm sorry. We're
not usually this bad.
Oh. It's okay.
Hey.
Do you realize that everyone
at this table has
slept with Kim?
Oh, my God.
Cut it out, you guys.
I bet she brought a U-Haul
on your second date, right?
Mm. I don't understand.
It's a lesbian joke. A bad one.
D... Do you want another drink?
Actually, I gotta go.
I have a early shift tomorrow.
Kerry... It was really...
It was really nice
to meet you both.
Wait. Are you upset?
No. Well, why are
you leaving then?
I don't belong here.
I dated Christy in college.
Kate and I dated
for maybe a month...
It's not that. It's... It's...
This isn't me.
I mean, my... My experience,
the jokes, your friends.
I'm... I'm...
I care about you.
I'm... I'm not interested in...
In adopting a lifestyle.
Wow, I can't believe
you just said that.
I'll call you later.
Just drive.
Dr. Kovac.
I... I was helping him
off... Off with his dolman,
and he was very short of breath,
And he just collapsed.
Oh, God.
Bishop Stewart...
can you hear me?
Call 911. Tell them
we have a man
with impending
respiratory arrest.
Mark?
Mark, you home?!
Are you okay?
He recommended
formal competency testing.
Psychiatrists,
neuropsychologists,
MRI, personality tests.
It's gonna take five days.
I'm so sorry.
The good times just keep coming.
Luka?
What are you doing?
I... I couldn't find a forest.
What?
You brought Bishop
Stewart back in?
How's he doing?
He's dying.
He might surprise you.
We get enough miracles
around here. Why not one more?
I'm freezing.
Ready to go home? Yeah.