There's this thing I used to do
when I was a kid to my mom's VCR.
I'd take it apart
piece by piece,
then put it back together again.
I left my phone at the lab.
By the time I
figured out I left it,
I was already at the
airport coming to you.
And she picked up
your phone, why?
I don't know.
She probably thought it was
me. I called her from the airport,
and then she told
me she spoke to you.
But inevitably, there was
always a piece or two left over,
something I didn't quite
know what to do with.
Is that it? Is that
everything you have to say?
That's all there is to say.
I've told you everything,
the whole story, all of it.
But if you want, I'll
go through it all again.
And she's your
research fellow. Yes.
Just your research fellow.
So, what do you
do with that piece?
Meredith.
I wish I could believe
you. You can. I'm here.
I know how this works.
I was your resident once.
It seems like you came home
because you thought
you were in trouble.
Do you try to fit it back in?
I came home because
we're in trouble.
I came home to
work on this, on us.
I came home.
Do you try to make it work?
I have to get to the hospital.
Can't you get somebody to cover?
Or do you decide you can
live without that missing piece?
You should spend the day
with the kids. They'd love it.
They really miss you.
Who is next?
We're looking at neuropeptide
"Y" receptors in marmoset brains.
Great. That's... That's great.
Which one of you
is doing a thing
where you're
patch-clamping nerve cells?
Oh, that's me.
Which one of you is
"me"? What's your name?
Uh, Collier. Renee Collier.
Renee, how's it going?
Pretty good. How are you?
I mean with the research,
Renee. How's it going?
Oh... Uh, it's... It's
going pretty well.
A few bumps in the road,
but all things considered...
The synaptic timing discoveries
you made will help us here immensely.
I want to see what you're doing.
Oh. Sure.
I look forward to
working with you.
What do you got?
Seventeen-year-old with
history of biliary atresia.
Chronic liver rejection.
Uh... Waiting on donors,
but he keeps deteriorating.
I'm running out of ideas.
Let me take a look.
I didn't pull you out of Zola's
dance class or something, did I?
No, no. Derek's home, though.
Since when? Last night.
And this morning. And?
And what?
And do you know who
answered his phone?
His biliary outflow
is strictured.
I want to examine him myself
and get a new ultrasound.
Owen!
Uh... Chief.
Hey, Dr. Shepherd. You finished
your laminectomy in OR 2?
I did. Did you need...
Oh, I'm just trying to see if Bailey
can get in here for a bowel obstruction.
Right.
OR's all hers. Great.
I felt like last night's
business was left unfinished.
You felt that way, too?
Many agenda
items left unchecked.
Yeah, barely scratched
the surface, really.
I think we need a follow-up.
Agreed.
When we won't be interrupted.
Oh, my God.
Hey, how about... How about
tonight, if you're not on call?
I'm not.
Okay, then.
Okay.
Hey, Jo, I need your help.
No, I'm not letting you do
laundry at the house again.
Alex gets crabby when you leave
your soggy clothes in the washer.
Stop. I spent so much time with
Dr. Shepherd on that brain tumor
that I'm behind in, like,
every other specialty.
I just checked my
hours. I am so screwed.
Oh! Suddenly it's lonely
on the neuro throne.
Hey, Wilson, Edwards.
I've got a lacerated
spleen in 20 minutes,
and Hunt had a
personal matter come up.
I need someone downstairs.
Start with the
headache in bed three.
Wilson, it's yours.
What did I just say?
She said "headache." It's probably
neuro. I'm doing you a favor.
Fine. But if it's something
good, you better call me.
Fine.
I just got a page?
Oh, yeah. Now, I
don't want you to worry.
She's understandably
embarrassed,
so we went ahead and
put her in trauma one.
Richard, what are you...
Okay, now. She's
shaken up, okay?
She's got a big
bruise on her back,
and aside from a nasty head lac,
there's no evidence
of other injuries.
Shepherd's with her now.
Who are we talking about?
I thought they told you.
Mom! What happened?
For heaven's sake,
Owen, shut that curtain.
Everyone can see me.
Evelyn, try not to move, okay?
Already gave half the
neighborhood a free show
just by getting
in the ambulance.
She fell in the shower,
right through the glass door.
Did you slip? I told you, you
need a support bar in there.
Oh, those things are so ugly.
She said she got
dizzy. Dizziness, huh?
I'm not surprised with
a laceration like this.
You had quite a fall.
I think we should get a head CT.
She said she was dizzy before
the fall. All morning, actually.
Really?
We got this from here. Thank
you. You can step outside.
No, I want him to stay. John
was with me when it happened.
I know, Mom.
You've been great, thank
you. My mom's really grateful.
But he's done his
part now, Mom, so...
No, I don't mean since I fell.
He was with me when I fell.
I don't understand.
Well, I wasn't with
her in the shower.
I was... I was making us some
breakfast before I went to work.
Owen, I'm John.
As in... "John."
Yeah, I still don't understand.
Honey, John and I, we're...
I thought you told him.
Told me what?
Is somebody gonna tell
me what the hell is going on?
I think what they're
trying to say is John is...
your mother's boyfriend.
How long has this been going on?
She was dizzy when
she first got out of bed.
We thought she was
just hungry, so I...
That's not what I...
How long have you two been...
In a relationship?
Mom, please. Please
don't use that word.
Evelyn, any changes
in vision? No, dear.
We've been together
a little under a year.
A year? Dr. Webber,
what do you think?
More X-rays, maybe,
on her left wrist?
Uh... I didn't realize
she had hurt...
Just to be safe.
Sure, sure. That's a
fine idea, Shepherd.
Owen, John's very nice.
I think you two have
a lot in common.
She talks about you all
the time. She's so proud.
I'm thrilled that
we're finally meeting.
How old are you?
Don't be rude. Thirty-five.
He's young enough
to be my brother.
Does he have access to your
financial information, your pension fund?
Owen Hunt!
Okay, pupils are
equal and reactive.
This is a serious relationship.
But I'd still like to get that
head CT just to rule out a bleed.
"Serious." Sure, okay.
Seriously weird,
seriously misguided.
Not that we don't have our fun.
Hey, hey, hey, stay away
from her! You hear me?
Whoa, buddy, calm down.
I'm not your buddy, okay?
I'll be changing her passwords,
her locks, her phone number.
If you so much as attempt...
- Hunt!
Let's take a walk.
Hey, Danny. Where's your sister?
Probably trying to find more
stupid stuff to cram in this room.
Dr. Grey, meet Danny,
Grey, Sloan's
resident hockey freak.
Nice to meet you,
Danny. Do you mind if I...
Hey, did you see
the game last night?
Yeah, you owe me 10 bucks.
Sharp had five shots on goal.
Yeah, and none went in.
Dr. Karev, any news?
Well, after today's scare, we
ran another set of blood tests.
We think he's developing
another infection.
Well, can we do the catheter
procedure again and drain the infection?
Well, we can try, but...
Actually, after looking at
Danny's scans and ultrasounds,
I think we could
go in surgically.
Could re-create the biliary tree
and prevent infection
from reoccurring.
Is that an option?
It's a risky one
in Danny's state.
I'd prefer to continue
with antibiotic therapy
and just keep monitoring him.
But the surgery could help Danny
while he's waiting
for a new liver
and possibly get him out
of the hospital for a while.
Well, I'm in. Living here sucks.
Well, let's not jump
into anything yet.
Dr. Grey and I will discuss it
before we seriously consider...
Well, why don't we
run some more tests,
and we'll let you know
what we think, okay?
So, you've had this headache
for a month with no relief?
Hmm, okay.
And where is the
headache located?
All over. It moves around.
Listen, I went to
China last month.
Is this the bird flu?
Or the... The... What...
What is it, the SARS?
It's one of those. I have
a headache all the time.
I get these nosebleeds.
Nosebleeds?
Yeah, the blood
starts to come out,
and then I go at it with a
tissue, and it just goes back up.
Huh.
Is that normal?
See, you're putting on a
mask. I've got the SARS.
No, this is just protocol.
Oh, hey, I see what
you're talking about.
Oh, God.
God, what?
That's not a nosebleed.
So, Dr. Avery attached the
transplanted tissue to the arm.
And, as described
in this morning's
presentation...
the fresh blood supply has
allowed the skin to regrow
without the need
for further grafts.
Dr. Warren?
Dr. Avery will perform
a primary microvascular
arterial repair first
and then follow with
a venous anastomosis.
All right, Matt. This
all looks very good.
We're gonna see
you in the OR. What?
I swear that never gets old.
Ah, if only that were true.
Okay, guys.
Excuse me. All right.
Hey.
Edwards. You need anything?
You are pretty.
I'm sorry?
Do you need anything?
Do you want anything?
Okay, that's...
That's flattering.
But, I have a beautiful
and very strong wife.
Ew, Warren. No,
I want your case.
Oh! No, not a chance.
I will give you $50.
No, I can't do it.
Come on, I need to
log more ENT hours.
And how is that my problem?
Look at this. Danny's
in full-blown cholangitis.
What was that with Danny?
Why would you
bring up that surgery
without talking
about it with me first?
You brought me on as
a consult for my opinion.
I was giving you my opinion.
He's barely able to
keep his blood clotting.
You really think he's gonna
survive a surgery that big?
I thought that's why
you brought me on,
because you wanted
some new ideas.
Have you even done
this procedure before?
You came to me. You
brought this case to me.
For your help. So
then listen to me.
What's going on here, Mer?
Nothing's going on.
Would you rather him sit
around and wait for a liver and die
or let me try a surgery
I know I can handle?
What's the deal here?
Is this about your streak?
Are you kidding me? Then what?
What's going on here?
What's your deal today?
Nothing. No deal.
I have no deal.
What in the world led you
to develop this technique?
It was for a little
side hobby of mine.
Which is?
I want to cure autism.
That's ambitious for a fellow.
What made you
decide to tackle autism?
One in 68 kids isn't enough?
Usually it comes
down to just one.
My little sister.
Ah.
I just always wondered
what she was thinking.
I hope you find that out.
Hey, why didn't
you answer my text?
'Cause I was working.
So?
So what?
How is Meredith?
What do you know?
I know she's being an ass,
pushing a risky surgery on my patient.
She's on a streak. Go for it.
Who was the woman
on Derek's phone?
I don't know. She said nothing?
Yesterday, she couldn't
stop talking about it.
All I know is Derek
came home last night.
No.
Crap.
Crap? Why crap?
A woman answers his phone,
he immediately gets on a plane
and shows up in the
middle of the night.
He's here to apologize.
Because he has
something to apologize for.
Crap.
I don't like this.
Mrs. Hunt, I know this is hard,
but I need you to not move.
I think I might be
done. Am I done?
Not quite yet. Try
focusing on your breathing.
I'm not usually like this.
I was in the military.
I served in Vietnam.
I don't panic. I
think I'm just upset.
Well, you did have quite a fall.
Not about the fall. About Owen.
I didn't mean for him
to find out like this.
He has a right to
be a little surprised.
Shocked.
But how does he think I feel?
A guy like John chasing
after a fossil like me.
It was weeks before I even
realized he was dating me.
And then, one night
he kissed me, and...
I'm not stupid.
I know how we
must look together.
I know what people
must think of us.
"He's conning her.
She's buying him.
"It's a joke."
It's what I'd think.
But then he kissed me.
And when he kissed me
we were exactly the same age.
All those years
between us disappeared.
John always says,
"Ev, there's no difference
between us except a bunch of years.
"And, frankly, they're years
I wish I'd spent with you."
Owen's always
worried that I'm lonely.
His dad died 32 years
ago, so he worries.
But I'm not lonely.
I'm having the time of my life.
Am I done?
In order for me to
get a clean CT scan,
I need for you to be
perfectly still, which means...
No talking.
John sounds amazing.
Doesn't he?
It would be so much
easier if he were my age.
But I got to tell you, it's
so much nicer that he isn't.
Oh, God.
I know. It's a little
uncomfortable,
but we can just get a good
look at what's going on inside.
Please don't find a tumor.
No, looks good.
Your tissues look healthy.
What's going on?
Nothing!
I told you to page me if
you had something cool.
Oh, it's not. Sorry.
No, it's just a...
It's just another neurotic lady
who thought her headache
was a brain tumor.
So lots of ibuprofen
and hand-holding in here.
You should go. Find
something worth your hours.
What was that? What was that?
It's some kind of critter.
What do you mean, "critter"?
It's alive? Something's
living in my face?
It's using your sinus
cavities to move around.
Oh, my God! I don't
care! Just get it out!
Hang on, all right? Hang on.
Let me put this mask on you.
Start him on an albumin drip.
I want the surgery.
Danny, we went over this. No.
I want the surgery!
Dr. Karev is gonna drain the
fluid, and you're gonna feel better.
No! I won't!
I can't keep doing
this. I want the surgery.
It's really risky. Your
body's very weak.
You don't know
what you're saying.
Yes, I do!
I can't go out like this,
sitting in some
hospital bed, waiting,
propped up with
my special pillows,
staring at crap that
doesn't mean anything.
Some hockey puck you
got signed for me out of pity,
pictures of our dead parents
who would have known better
than to just let
me sit here and rot.
All right, hey,
Danny. It's fine.
No, it's not.
It's my life. It's my choice.
Dr. Grey, I want the
surgery, and I want it today.
Kathy, he's hurting right now,
all right? Once he feels better...
Will he feel better?
I mean, he's
right. It is his life.
He has so little control
over anything else,
but he's almost 18.
He should get a say in
what he does in his life, right?
That's what he wants.
I mean, he just wants to go to
games and hang out with girls
and junk out on popcorn
with his friends at the movies.
He's miserable and terrified.
And I don't blame him.
Just... I'll give consent.
Just do the surgery.
Absolutely.
You're still his guardian.
You don't have to do this.
Just tell me that
it's going to work.
I've spent my entire adult
life taking care of him.
Now he wants a
life, but he's my life.
I don't know what I
would do without him.
Renee? Oh...
Oh, God.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm just...
I'm sorry. I broke
a cup. I'll replace it.
I'm not worried about the cup.
I'm fine. I'm sorry.
Have a good night.
Do you want to talk about it?
I've been measuring
levels of activity
and inhibitory cells
in VPA rat brains.
For months, I've been
patching and patching,
for more than a year, actually.
I've been looking for
abnormalities, and nothing shows up.
Nothing.
I'm wasting my time.
Do you know why
you feel like that?
It's because you're close.
You're very close
to a breakthrough.
I've been there. It's tedious.
It takes patience
and concentration.
And you want it. You
want a breakthrough so bad
that you have to
break something.
I'll replace the cup. I'm...
Stop talking about the cup.
Keep going.
You're right at the line.
You're gonna cross it.
Don't stop.
You should get some sleep.
Yeah.
I'll try.
Hey, so, I spoke to Dr. Webber.
Your CT results came back.
You have a mild head contusion,
so they're gonna keep
an eye on it overnight.
I suppose you have questions.
No. Um...
I brought you some, pant...
Uh... Some ladies'
underthings and socks,
in case your, you
know... Your feet get cold.
Patients are always telling me that
their feet get cold, so I thought "socks."
I spent your whole childhood
telling you to be sure
you had clean socks
and underwear on
in case you were in an accident.
Here I am.
No socks, no underwear.
Owen, ask.
It's none of my
business. I don't need to...
We met in a writer's group.
I didn't know you wrote.
Just stories.
Little things about
my time in the service.
John liked them.
One night, we stayed late
talking about my stories,
and he shared some of his.
He did a stint in the Navy.
And after a while,
we realized we were
the only ones still around.
He asked if I wanted
to go for some coffee
and keep the conversation going.
I did.
That was six months ago.
And somehow we've never
run out of things to talk about.
So, that's it? Just
coffee and conversation?
Do you really want to hear
about your mother's sex life?
Okay. Uh...
Owen, does it matter that
he's not what you pictured?
Yes, it matters, 'cause
there's something wrong here.
He's half your age.
He's younger than I am.
Mom, I think he's using you.
For what? For sex?
Well, God bless him.
Stop it. That's
not what I meant.
For money. Your pension, maybe.
That's what these guys do.
They prey on older people...
What do you mean, "these
guys"? John's not "these guys."
There's no way a
man like that could...
Could love me?
Is that what you were gonna say?
There's no way a man
like that could love me.
Mom.
Just think about it.
For a moment, put your heart
aside and try to think about it.
You should have
told me right away.
I would never have let this
guy do this to you. It's not right.
It feels right.
I want you to go.
Mom.
I don't want to see anyone
make a fool out of you.
And I won't let
anybody hurt you.
Please.
I like your mom. She's funny and
smart. I mean, I'm not surprised.
Is there a point?
Owen, if it were my mom,
I would be thrown, too,
but from talking to her, it
seems like they're really in love.
You spent 15 minutes
listening to her,
and you have this
whole thing figured out.
I know nothing about this guy.
You don't know my mother, so
please just stay the hell out of it.
We went to this
beautiful lake...
Shh! Don't speak.
With these waterfalls.
You'll scare him away.
Everyone on my tour was jumping
off this big, high ledge into the lake.
I was so terrified to
do it, but it was like
the big, high point
of the trip for them.
I didn't want to be the
only one who didn't go.
I didn't want to miss
out on the high point.
I'm so glad I jumped.
It was exhilarating.
Amazing. It changed me forever.
Please stop talking.
Do you think that's when
I got this thing in me?
Andrea, don't move.
Come to mama.
Oh, no! Stop, stop, stop!
It's grabbing. Just a
little more. Just a little...
Stop it!
Oh, my God. I'm so sorry.
Okay.
We're gonna take a little break.
Then we'll try again.
Mmm-mmm. I'm
not doing that again.
I'm not doing it.
We'll need to be very careful
when connecting the graft
to the posterior
auricular artery.
And...
There. Scissors, please.
Uh...
Hello, Dr. Bailey.
Bribery, Edwards?
You think bribery is an
appropriate standard of practice
in this hospital,
bribing for surgeries?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You tried to bribe your way
onto that surgery down there.
Warren.
Sleeping with the enemy.
You demean yourself,
and you demean medicine.
I'm sorry.
And it doesn't matter,
anyway. It didn't work.
Fifty dollars?
Fifty dollars.
Do you know how much
a full ear replantation
would have gone for in my day?
A hundred, easy.
One-twenty, even, plus
two weeks of night call.
You add in inflation,
you should have
offered him $175, at least.
Fifty dollars.
We can't even go
to dinner for $50.
Gelfoam, please. I
need more retraction.
Any more, and we'll
need to extend the incision.
Well, then we'll
extend the incision.
I need better visualization
of the bile duct.
His hepatic veins are bleeding.
His liver's too scarred.
We need to stop, give
him extra clotting factors.
We can't stop. I told
you it was a bad idea.
His body can't take it.
He's already deteriorating.
Let's pack him and get out.
We can't close him now. He
will die. He'll be dead in a week.
How long has he been
on the transplant list?
Will he get a liver this week?
I could do a hepatico-j
to decompress the liver.
That's crazy. It'll never
work. It's a chance.
I didn't ask you for a chance.
I asked you for an opinion.
Which I gave you,
which I'm giving you now,
which you refuse to listen to.
You hijacked my
patient to perform
a procedure that could kill him.
If you don't like my surgical
plan, you are free to leave.
What the hell is wrong with you?
Damn it. He's
dropping his pressure.
I'm putting a shunt in
from the splenic to the IVC.
The anastomosis
is not gonna hold.
It's the only way. Right angle.
Hello?
What are you doing right now?
I was...
It's 1:00 a.m.
How soon can you be at the lab?
I couldn't stop thinking
about your research.
You've been thinking
about my research?
Come here. Come on.
Let me show you. Look.
Oh, my God.
Yeah, I know. I told you.
It's all about the
excitatory pathways.
Here, look.
See?
Yeah.
Your blood pressure's
dropped since the last check.
You feeling okay?
I feel like I'm being
made too much fuss over
'cause my son's the boss.
Okay, so, the cat's fed,
um, I got the recycling
down to the curb.
I brought you some
clothes and stuff.
I couldn't find your journal,
so I just picked you up a
fresh one down in the gift shop.
You didn't have to do all that.
Hey.
Hey, are you... Are you okay?
Is she okay?
I'm fine.
You're very, very sweet.
But I don't think...
We shouldn't be doing this.
Not anymore.
What?
You don't need this, John.
A frail, old woman
who falls in the shower.
Stop it. Is this... Is
this because Owen...
He's my son.
And he's been to hell and back.
And he does everything for me.
And if he feels that it isn't...
Hey, hey, Evelyn.
Do you believe that?
Oh!
We need help in here!
Okay, her abdomen's rigid.
Evelyn. RICHARD:
Step outside, all right?
Blood pressure's dropping
drastically. She's going into shock.
Page Pierce, and get
Owen Hunt. Mmm-hmm.
I'm right here.
Shunt is in.
Bleeding seems under control.
You seem surprised.
I'm glad it worked.
You've questioned
every move I've made.
You, of all people? I
need you to believe in me.
ALEX: Crap, there's...
I see it. The
anastomosis is leaking.
Come on, Danny.
What happened?
Ruptured abdominal
aortic aneurysm.
The dizziness, the
bruising on her back,
they must have been
caused by a sentinel bleed.
What the hell, Richard?
How'd you not see this?
Hey, all of her injuries
were consistent with her fall.
None of us would have
thought to look any further.
I know you're worried,
but we have her.
Hey.
I need you to tell
me why you're here.
I'm gonna go. She told me to go.
Good. Go. I will.
But not until I
know she's all right.
I know she doesn't
want me, and that's fine.
But I can't just walk away
not knowing how she is.
I can't just walk away from...
I know she doesn't
want me, but I want her.
I have to know that she's
out there in the world okay.
I can't go not knowing.
She'll never even
know I was here.
You don't have to
say anything to her.
I'll go the moment that I know.
But until then, I am
sitting here in this chair,
until I know that
Evelyn is all right.
Hey. He's okay, right? The
surgery worked? Can I see him?
Dr. Grey?
Kathy, um... I'm...
I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
No!
Tell me that's not... Yes.
The VPA cells are connecting
almost twice the
rate of normal cells.
This is amazing!
You're amazing!
I could kiss you.
I mean, I won't.
Obviously I won't. Sorry.
But all the wrong
turns and brick walls,
and finding the
answer is such a high.
It's getting late.
Um...
I should go.
Do you have to?
Meredith!
Mer, stop!
He should have
lived. He couldn't.
You saw how messed
up his liver was.
I should have saved him.
I could have saved him.
If you weren't bringing me down
with your doubting and
second-guessing and distracting me.
Mer. He should have lived.
He should have lived!
He should have lived.
What?
Stop. Get off! Stop it!
Come on. No.
I'm mad at you. No, you're not.
I am. No, you're mad at Derek.
You want to take
it out on me, go on.
You want to yell
and hit and scream
'cause things are
hard at home, okay.
You want to be a mess, be a
mess. I don't care. I can take it.
But in that OR, you are
not a mess in that OR.
You tried. We both did.
You didn't do this. You
didn't kill that kid, okay?
So keep it together.
We were able to
repair her aneurysm.
So she's gonna be
okay? Yeah, that's good.
She should recovery nicely.
That was one lucky fall.
If her aneurysm had
ruptured outside of the hospital,
she wouldn't have made it.
All right.
Thank you.
Thanks. Mmm.
Uh...
Tell your mom I said goodbye.
Oh...
I ordered this book that she's
been searching for forever.
It was out of print. I
found it. I had it shipped.
It arrived yesterday.
It's in this little
brown package
on the table near the blue sofa.
Will you make sure she gets it?
Yeah.
Thanks.
John, wait.
I told you to go.
Yeah, well, Owen suggested
that you might be full of crap.
Hmm. I asked
him to stick around.
We've been talking.
Oh, God. I wish you didn't
have to see me like this.
I look so...
You look beautiful.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Okay, just relax, Andrea.
Dr. Wilson said I could have a
look at your little buddy there?
No.
Okay, I feel for you. I do.
But you got to let
us yank him out.
Wilson! ANDREA: But it hurts.
I think he has teeth.
I know you're scared.
He is, too. He doesn't
want to come out.
He has found the
perfect, safe home.
The tissues in your sinuses
are warm and damp and cozy.
But they're also tasty,
and he's gonna get hungry,
and then he's gonna
start chomping away.
And the more he
chomps through them,
the closer he's gonna
get to your brain.
And your brain...
Oh, your brain.
That'll be like
Christmas dinner.
He's here. He's right
here. Get him out.
Okay, okay, Andrea. This
is what I want you to do.
I want you to take
a great big sniff.
What? Sniff in? No way.
He'll end up somewhere
behind my eyeball.
No, he won't. Your
sinuses will contract.
It'll help. I promise.
Ready? Sniff.
There you are,
you little bugger.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. It's so gross.
And he was in my
face. What is it?
Oh, it's a leech.
Poor little guy.
Do you want to keep him?
If you don't, I will.
What? What is that?
I pulled it out
of a lady's nose.
This little sucker had me
working on one single case all day.
All day?
All day.
So you just logged six, seven
uninterrupted hours of trauma
without even trying,
all because of a stupid leech
up someone's stupid nose?
I think I'm gonna
name him Herbie.
I'm gonna put Herbie up
your nose while you sleep.
Amelia. I am so...
Sorry?
For being such a jackass?
And for how I spoke
to you. I was out of line.
You think?
I am sorry.
Good.
Don't go. Not like this.
It just took me by surprise.
I'm not always
good with surprises.
Me either.
Maybe we should get over that.
When we go without certain
things for long enough,
it's easy to forget
just how much we need them.
We forget what we had once.
We forget what it's
like to live with a thing
not that we need,
but that we want.
The kids?
Just put them to bed.
Derek?
Wait. Just...
Derek? Just wait.
I can't do this. I'm sorry.
Tell me that this
is all in my head,
that there isn't
something between us.
I know it's there.
I love my wife.
I'm married.
I don't want anything other
than what I have with her.
I have to go.
Right now I have to go.
That's why it's so important
for us to remind ourselves,
for us to remember.
I am calling Post-it.
Zola and Bailey
and tumors on the walls
and ferry boat scrub caps.
I thought D.C. was everything.
And I was wrong.
You...
You.
You're everything.
I love you,
and I'm not gonna
stop loving you.
Meredith, I can't
live without you.
I don't want to
And I'm gonna do everything
in my power to prove it.
I can live without you.
But I don't want to.
I don't ever want to.
Just because we can
live without something,
it doesn't mean we have to.