- Previously on
"New Amsterdam"...
- Our marriage is over.
I finally know the direction
that I want to be headed in.
Will you go on a date with me?
- Why are you acting like
everything is over
and done with?
- I don't know, just 'cause
you're leaving in six days.
- ♪ Rescue me or take
me in your arms ♪
♪ Rescue me, I want
your tender charm ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm lonely
- I thought I heard a crash.
- Yeah, no, it's fine.
We were just reading up
on the, uh, compliance...
- Meeting.
- ♪ Come on, baby
♪ And rescue me
♪ Come on, baby,
and rescue me ♪
♪ 'Cause I need you
- Ah, hey.
I knew it. Casey.
- What?
- You owe me 20 bucks!
- Yeah.
- Ooh.
I gotta quit using these stairs.
- Get a room.
- ♪ Come on and rescue me
- Ooh.
This is so...
I don't know what word to use.
- Fun. I haven't had fun
in a long time.
Come here.
- ♪ Take me, baby
- ♪ Love me, baby
Oh.
Hi, there.
Doctor.
- ♪ Can't you see
that I'm lonely? ♪
Mm!
- I gotta say,
we made damn good use of
my last week in New York.
- Mm. You sure I can't
convince you to stay?
- Mm, not when
they're handing out
$20,000 bonuses like candy.
- Well, I can get you free
coffee at Pain De Vie.
Mm.
You know I got the plug.
- Ohh. Do you?
Yeah.
Oh. You might get a call today
about a gig in Tanzania.
I, uh... I listed
you as my reference.
- Hm.
Tanzania.
- I know.
You think you could
sing my praises,
convince 'em I'm a real catch?
Floyd?
- Yeah. Yeah,
yeah, no problem.
I'll tell 'em exactly
what they need to hear.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- Hi, is this, uh,
Martin McIntyre?
Am I saying that right?
- Uh, yeah, you
know who this is.
- Yeah, hi. This
is Iggy Frome.
I am your date for this evening.
- Oh, my God.
I need a night out tonight
after this morning.
Sameera and Raffi were
at each other again.
- Sameera and Raffi,
what, are those your cats?
'Cause, you know, you
definitely do not want
to be talking about your
kids on a first date.
That's a... That's
a major turnoff,
big no-no.
- Okay, okay,
so you're, uh, really
going full steam
on this fresh start thing, huh?
- I'm sorry, have we met?
I think I'd remember
meeting you.
You sound cute.
- Okay, stranger, look,
I'm late for my first session.
So can we agree upon where
we're meeting tonight?
Uh, Darnellé or that Persian
place... what do you think?
- Hmm, yeah, I don't
know those places.
Those sound like, uh,
old standbys for you,
but, uh, yeah, I'm
drawing a blank.
Iggy.
- Hey, tonight, everything
is for the first time.
Since I'm the one
who asked you out,
I'll let you off the hook.
I will pick the place,
I will send you the address,
and I will see you
there at 7:00, okay?
- Oh, okay.
- Oh, and Martin?
- Mm-hmm?
- I'm really looking
forward to meeting you.
- Okay. See you.
Ugh.
I hate clocking out when
the sun's coming up.
- Oh, come on. You love
pancakes for dinner.
- Ugh. How do you
have so much energy?
- Oh, I don't know.
Maybe because I've shed
decades of emotional
trauma... My mom, my sister.
But I am finally out
from underneath it all,
so it is time I made some
big changes in my life.
So...
- Quitting medicine?
- I sold my apartment.
- Oh.
But you're definitely
not moving in with me.
Nah.
- Relax, relax.
No, I actually found the
perfect place in Battery Park.
It ticks all my boxes.
There's actually an
open house at 9:00 a.m.,
but my realtor says they
can sneak me in early.
Wanna come, be my fresh eyes?
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Battery Park's all
the way downtown.
We're not gonna
make it before 9:00.
- How fast can you get
us to Battery Park?
- Downtown?
- In rush hour?
- Well, there's a
two bedroom, two bath
with a view of the Hudson
that's got my name on it
if I can get there
before 9:00 a.m.
- Doorman?
- Check.
- Private rooftop?
- Uh, with a pool
and a vegetable garden.
- Hop in.
We might even use the sirens.
Oh, ye
of little faith.
- Please put your
hands behind your back.
- What do you
mean, under arrest?
I peed on the street.
What's so wrong with that?
- Hi, good morning, officers.
- I had to pee.
Where I was supposed
to pee? Dogs do that.
The dogs pee on the trees.
- Hey, hi.
Good morning, officers, hi.
- Why can't I pee on a tree?
- Hey, how you
doing? Hi, Carla.
You seem upset. Are you okay?
- Yeah, will you please
tell Starsky and Hutch
to stop harassing regular people
who have done nothing wrong?
- Ma'am, public urination
is against the law.
- Ooh, "public urination."
- Ah.
- It wasn't public until
you two started looking.
You pervo.
- Hey, office... officers, hi.
I'm... I'm Dr. Frome. I
work at New Amsterdam.
Can I just take
her off your hands?
What a guy!
It's... it's like I'm,
what, an old couch
from, uh, Craigslist?
- Ri... right, yeah.
- Is she your patient?
- Um, no.
No, not exactly. Carla
is a frequent flier.
She's been through
the hospital a bunch
with these kinds of issues.
So I know her.
- Don't think your
treatment's working.
- She is an alcoholic with
serious mental illness.
Uh, she can't even
control her bladder
with what she's put
her body through.
So taking her to jail,
that's not gonna do
anybody any good, right?
Create more paperwork
for you guys, so...
- We can't just turn her loose.
- Sure.
- If you're taking
responsibility,
you'll have to admit
her to the hospital.
- Yeah, I'll do you one better.
I'll take her to court.
- Lilo.
Did we have an appointment?
- I know you're busy,
but, uh, it's about
my transplant.
Right.
Lilo, look, I haven't
heard anything from UNOS.
And I promise I'll call you
the minute a lung
becomes available.
And I know waiting
can be frustrating...
- Oh, it's not that. I... I
just need some medication.
The nurse said I had to see you
before I can get 'em refilled.
- What medications?
Azathioprine,
cyclosporine, prednisone.
Lilo, these are all
immunosuppression drugs
for someone who is
already post-transplant.
- I am post-transplant.
- What?
- I...
I got a new lung.
- How?
- I bought it.
- Yeah, great natural light.
- Yeah, nothing
says "fresh start"
like floor-to-ceiling windows.
- Is that a private elevator?
- Uh-huh.
- You really need all that?
- Yeah, of course I need it.
It's turnkey.
You've seen my place.
I'm helpless on my own.
I can just move right in
and not have to do a damn thing.
- Paramedics needed,
Midtown West.
Chainsaw attack.
Injuries on scene.
- Unit 223 responding.
Oh, great.
Now I'm gonna have
to pay all cash.
- Did they just say
"chainsaw attack"?
Speech time.
Um, thank you all for coming.
Um...
I don't know what to say.
Five years ago, I was dying.
My cancer treatment
wasn't working.
I couldn't swallow
my own saliva.
I couldn't stand
without support.
I didn't know if
I was gonna live
to see my own daughter be born.
But then this place,
New Amsterdam, saved me.
And so it is a great honor
and perhaps a fitting legacy
to announce today
that our partnership
with Ithaca Pharmaceuticals
has won the battle
against bulky
large-cell lymphoma.
And we did not just
find a treatment.
We found a cure.
- To curing cancer.
Aw, you did it, Max.
- Hey.
- The clinical trial
that you just toasted?
It's a sham, Max.
- This is it.
- Uh, bring the EPK
in case we need to tourniquet.
- On it.
- Whoa, hang on.
Chainsaw attack.
I'm going in first.
- It sounded worse on the radio.
- So dangerous.
I am sorry.
- Go get me a suture kit.
Hi.
Hi. Ooh, ow.
Uh, yeah, okay.
- One of the kids bite you?
- Shouldn't have
tried to juggle four.
- Whatever happened
to bowling pins?
- One must rise to
the increasing demands
of an ever hungry public.
- Hm. They're ten.
They'd be entertained
if you farted.
- Let's get him loaded up
and back to New Amsterdam.
- Does he really
need to go to the ED
for a simple laceration?
I mean, it's gonna take hours.
I could just stitch
him up right here.
- That must be an
amazing apartment.
- Laundry in unit.
- Um, excuse me.
Hello?
- Sorry, man.
- Oh, no, no, no.
If... if you could
patch me up right here,
that'd be outstanding.
I got a bar mitzvah on the
East Side in about an hour.
- See?
Even the juggler doesn't
want to go to the hospital.
Tell Carmona to keep
the engine running.
Thank you.
All right, let's
get you stitched up.
- You're all right.
- Ah, I... I hate these places.
Feels like I should've worn
a pantsuit or something.
- Yeah, I mean, I get
that you don't have
any positive associations
with courtrooms, believe me.
But, uh, this is a
little different.
This is CARE court.
Check it out.
Yeah.
Well, I thought that, uh,
"People's Court" was pushing it.
- All right, well, you
know, the... the basic idea
is that this is
designed to keep you out
of the criminal justice
system, not put you back in it.
So people with long-standing
compounded issues
like mental illness, addiction,
chronic homelessness,
they get the care and the
treatment that they need.
- Mm-hmm.
Hi. Good morning, guys.
Uh, this is Carla.
- Yeah, I don't... I don't know.
I don't know, Doc. You
know, maybe I'll just
be sneakier when I pee.
- Carla, hey, hey, I... I...
I know that you
hate accepting help.
I know that. I know.
And I can only imagine how
shaming and insulting it is
for an obviously
intelligent human being
to have all these
people insinuating
that you can't
manage your own life.
But what you're
doing is not working.
It's not.
I mean, don't you want a
shot at something more?
- This is Dr. Reynolds.
- Dr. Reynolds, this
is Dr. Selemani.
- Dr. Selemani, yes.
Uh, Nurse Gabrielle
Morris is on my staff.
Um, actually, can
I call you back?
This isn't a great time.
Yeah.
Yes, uh, seven hour
time difference.
I'll call you
back ASAP. Thanks.
- Here are your
labs, Dr. Reynolds.
- Thank you, Nurse Gabrielle.
- What is it?
- Lilo's new lung,
his body's rejecting it.
- I don't get it.
They said everything went great.
- Who said?
- The doctors.
- Okay, Lilo, listen to me.
I'm gonna need the
medical records
from your transplant, okay?
I'm gonna need the
donor's blood type,
HLA match, the age,
medical history.
I mean, hell, do you even
know who this person was?
- No, I have no idea.
And I don't care.
I was on your donor
list for two years.
Two years of waiting and
struggling to breathe,
two years of you telling
me to be patient.
- Well, that's how it works.
- I wasn't gonna sit
around twiddling my thumbs
until I died.
So I researched online.
I drained my 401.
I went to Honduras.
- Honduras?
- Well, don't look
at me like that.
It was a real
hospital, real doctors.
They found me a lung right away.
No waiting, just results.
So I'm sorry if I don't exactly
know where it came from.
But I was busy
trying not to die.
- Um, so your body's
rejecting that lung,
and the only way we're
gonna keep you alive
is if we take it out...
today.
- Let's go, let's go!
Come on, people.
Money never sleeps.
- You're a monster.
- Lincoln Center
to Battery Park?
If we hurry, we
can still make it.
- Lower East Side,
two car collision.
People trapped in vehicles,
possible fatalities.
All available units,
please respond.
- There are two
other rigs nearby.
If you want, we can say we're
still working things here.
- No, lights and
sirens. Let's roll!
- Unit 223 en route.
- It is right there
in the data breakdown.
- Yeah, which clearly shows
the efficacy is well above
the combined SEER
stage survival rate
for B-cell lymphoma.
- Yes, you were correct.
The success rate is 89%.
Astonishing.
- So?
- Look at the study's
participant breakdown.
- Okay.
Uh, ages 25 to 65,
89%...Caucasian.
- That is a non-diverse
participant pool.
Those numbers do not reflect
New Amsterdam's
patient population.
It definitely does not reflect
the general population.
If we do not test this
on a wider demographic,
how can we prove that it
is safe and effective?
The last thing that we want
is another tha... tha...
Sorry, sorry, what?
- Thalidomide...
- Thalidomide.
It's a drug from the
'60s that they would give
to pregnant women for nausea...
- Mm.
- And they didn't test
it on pregnant women.
So they didn't know that it
would cause birth defects.
- If we do not test
Lymphodril properly,
this miracle cure could wind
up being a death sentence
for anyone who is not white
between the ages of 35 and 65.
- How could I have missed this?
- It was a blind trial.
We all missed it.
- Yeah, but this is everything
that I've fought against.
This is Big Pharma at its worst,
and I just signed off on it.
- So what do we do?
- The only thing we can do.
We can't release this trial data
for FDA approval.
- But...
- That means...
- Yeah. We're gonna kill
the cure for cancer.
- What was he
thinking? It's insane.
- He didn't know.
- He didn't want to know.
Buying an organ is
illegal for a reason.
Now I have a patient
who's gonna suffer
lifelong consequences because
of a stupid decision he made...
Assuming he survives.
- And you can bet the donor
didn't hand over the lung
out of the goodness
of their heart.
I've worked in countries
where people are killed
for their organs.
- You wanna know the worst part?
Now I have to take a
perfectly good lung
and throw it in the incinerator
when there are people who
could benefit from it.
But because of how
it was procured,
nobody gets it.
- Unless...
- Unless what?
- What if there's a way
it doesn't go to waste?
- Good morning, Your Honor.
I first met Carla, uh,
after a nice long bender.
She suffered acute
alcohol poisoning.
She was admitted
to New Amsterdam.
She came to behavioral
health for a consult.
And I diagnosed her with
post-traumatic stress disorder,
offered her help by way
of therapy and medication.
And Carla said no.
Didn't you?
Over the next decade,
Carla and I have replayed
that first visit many,
many, many times,
always with the same
result, haven't we?
Yeah. Now, I would
try that hard for anyone.
I would.
But, uh, Carla is...
Um, she's kind
and warm and very funny.
And she's got a lot to give.
We need her to stick around
so she can keep on giving it.
I beseech the court
to enter Carla
into the full CARE program
with mental health care,
uh, rehab services, and housing,
the full meal deal.
- Thank you, Dr. Frome.
- My pleasure.
- Carla.
- Hm?
- Do you have anything to add?
- Um...
yeah, I just... One
question out of curiosity.
Who is that guy?
- Uh, I'm your
court-appointed advocate.
- Well, he's... he's advocating.
He just... he made a big
speech and everything.
So what are you advocating
for that he isn't?
- Your rights,
because if you enter
the care program,
you'll be giving all of 'em up.
Tell
me that isn't true.
- It's not as bad as it sounds.
- Is that true?
- Come on!
Help. Help!
They're still inside.
- I need a trauma bundle
and cervical collar!
You take the passenger.
- Already on it.
- Are you with me, sir?
Airbags didn't deploy.
Collar.
- My son's hurt.
Help my son.
- I'm o... I'm o...
I'm okay, Dad.
- We're gonna help everyone.
- It's a chest laceration,
possible pneumothorax.
He's lost a ton of blood.
- His pulse is weak and thready.
- He's going in
and out of shock.
Can you smell that?
- Yeah.
The engine's gonna blow.
We... we gotta move.
- Passenger's coming out.
Move, move!
You're gonna be okay.
- Ah.
- Oh, it's jammed.
The seatbelt's jammed.
- Here.
- Okay. Get the gurney.
Go, go.
What's your name, sir?
Paul. Paul.
- And what do you have
planned today, Paul?
- Soccer.
- Well, you might
be a little late,
but we're gonna get
you there, okay?
Okay. All right.
Casey, we gotta go!
Come on. You get
the shoulders.
- Okay. All right.
- Carmona, Whitaker,
you're with us, okay?
The kid's in the second bus.
- On my count.
One, two, three.
- All right.
- All right. Come on.
- You got him?
Okay.
We gotta go.
- Hey, he's not gonna make it.
You know that, right?
- Let's go!
- Max, this is Ithaca
VP, Eric Hillbach.
- Tell me what I'm
hearing isn't true.
- I wish I could, all right?
We don't like this either.
- You're actively withholding
your own trial data
for a drug that has been proven
to literally cure cancer.
- Karen...
- Don't "Karen" me.
This was a huge breakthrough
that could change the world.
And now what? You're
having second thoughts?
- Without that data, we
don't get FDA approval,
and this drug will
die on the vine.
- Yeah, and it should,
because your trial
was inequitable,
and you know it.
- Nearly all of participants
were white from the
perfect socioeconomic class
to afford this drug,
should it come to market.
- And they all had cancer.
- They did, but if this
is the only demographic
that we're testing, then
how are we gonna know
that this drug is safe and
effective for everyone?
- Dr. Goodwin,
Lymphodril targets
the specific genetic
defect in the cancer.
So trial demos don't matter.
Only people's genes matter.
- I think that what mattered
was getting fast results
and saving money.
- Right, that's why
you did a blind trial
with limited parameters
so you didn't have
to go out and do
community outreach,
and you didn't have to
earn people's trust.
- Max.
This drug is a huge deal,
and while it may not have
been tested on all of mankind,
there is irrefutable
proof that it saves lives.
- Some lives.
- If we don't bring
this drug to market now,
there are patients
who will actually die.
You want to own that?
- No, I just want to own
a trial that doesn't
say "whites only."
- This is madness.
These were your
parameters, not ours.
- Uh, what do...
What do you mean?
- The participant field,
the expedited timetable,
every parameter was set
by the New Amsterdam
oncology department.
- What are you saying,
that somebody here
made these decisions?
- From our department? Who?
- Who is it, Max?
- Helen Sharpe.
- Can't you go any faster?
- Welcome to my world.
Street's clogged.
- Yeah, well, we're bigger.
Just push the other
cars out the way!
- VFIB.
- Okay. Clear.
Shocking.
- Still no pulse.
- Going again.
Clear. Shocking.
- I got nothing.
- Damn it. Going again.
Clear. Shocking.
- Nah, still nothing.
We're gonna have to
start chest compressions.
Lauren...
- I don't have a bone saw,
cautery or retractor
or anything.
I...
Give me your knife.
- What are you doing?
- I'm figuring it out.
- What the hell are you doing?
- I'm opening this guy up.
And then what?
- Okay. Okay.
I'm gonna start his heart.
- With what?
- Hey, do me a favor.
Can you, uh, hold
this retractor?
Okay.
- Got it.
- All right, all right.
Hey, I know this rig can't fly,
but if you don't get
us to the 'Dam quick,
this guy is toast!
Carla.
- No one wants to
take away your rights.
- Yeah? Well, that's not
what my advocate
over there said.
- You want to live a
happier, less stressful life
with your PTSD and your
addictions under control.
Right?
- Yeah, yeah, sure.
- Okay, great.
Well, the CARE court
can help you achieve that goal.
All you have to do is
stick to the program,
and your rights are your own.
- Carla, if you go
into this program,
what are the chances that
you will go off your meds
or continue drinking?
- It's pretty close to
100%, if I'm under oath.
- If that happens,
the CARE court can
legally compel you
into a conservatorship.
Isn't that right, Your Honor?
- Yes, if she
becomes an impediment
to her own treatment.
- We are way,
way past that point.
- I just think it's only fair
that Carla knows exactly
what she'd be signing up for.
- Yeah, what am I
signing up for, Iggy?
- Conservatorship means that
this court would be empowered
to make every choice for you...
Who you see, where you stay,
when you take your pills.
Is that what you want?
- If you comply,
that is not going to happen.
- She just said she won't.
- I'll help you.
- Let her answer.
I will help you.
You'll have help.
You can do this.
You can do it.
- No.
- So Your Honor, it
would be a violation
of her rights to enroll
her into the CARE program
against her wishes.
- Then take away her rights.
Mandate her into
the program today,
right now.
- Wait a minute, Doc.
What are you doing?
- Your Honor,
I intervene with
people who are about
to die by their own
hand all the time.
- So now we're
equating her refusal
of help with self-harm.
- Look at her medical record.
Her liver is cirrhotic.
Her kidneys are in failure
because of drinking
she admitted she
has no control over.
What... what... What
else would you call that?
- A drinking problem.
- For people like Carla,
a drink might as well be a gun.
- I'm sorry, Your Honor.
There is zero evidence
that Carla will die
with her next drink.
- How slow a death is
slow enough for you?
One hour?
A day? A week?
This woman is killing herself
right in front of us, and
I am trying to save her.
And I'm asking
the court. I am...
I am imploring the court
to help me save her.
Mandate her into
the program today
against her will if you have to.
It is the only way
that we can save her.
- Okay, we're gonna
resect the lung.
Gentle.
Okay.
All right.
Well, I see minimal
inflammation.
Now we're gonna
perfuse the organ.
Is the box ready?
- Ready.
- All right.
Okay.
Here we go.
It's ventilating.
- Yeah.
It'll be in a
near-physiological state
in no time.
- Dr. Reynolds, why
go through all this?
We can't transplant that lung
into any of our other patients.
- That's why we're gonna
put it where it belongs...
In the original donor.
Talk to me.
- They're in a small town
just outside of San Pedro Sula.
- All right, how soon
can we get 'em here?
- We can't.
They won't travel. They
won't even talk with us.
- How could Helen do this?
I mean, she knows that
trial diversity is an issue.
Of all people, she
would've shut this down.
- Maybe under normal
circumstances, yes, yes.
But when the trial started,
things were different.
- Di... how?
Medical bias didn't
start three years ago.
- You don't see it.
- See what?
- She did it to save your life.
- No, she, uh... no.
I mean, my cancer was
totally different.
- But they both shared
similar genetic mutations.
The research was new.
It would not have been a stretch
to believe that Lymphodril
could have cured you too.
She chose the fastest
way to make that happen
because she loved you.
- Coming through,
coming through!
Watch your back!
- We're not stopping,
just passing through.
Gotta get to the OR.
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
- I thought you were
apartment hunting!
- Come on.
Come on, Paul. Come on.
Stay with me.
Don't you quit on me.
- Get cardiac bypass ready.
- Okay.
- We got it from here.
- You're a good guy, Iggy.
You, uh, care
and all that good, cozy stuff.
- Just give it a chance, Carla.
Come on, please.
- I can't take that chance.
Even I would bet against me.
If you were any
smarter, you would too.
See you around, right?
- Yeah.
- See you around.
- She's gonna die
in the streets.
- Probably.
Land of the free, Iggy.
Land of the free.
- Mr. Murillo, hi.
My name is Dr. Floyd Reynolds,
and this is Nurse
Gabrielle Morris.
Do you speak English?
Okay, um...
- Oh, no, no, no.
- Oh.
- Thank you for meeting with us.
- Is this going to
be another lecture?
Well, we
are about to submit
the, uh, data for FDA approval.
- And you're okay with that?
- Uh, no. No, actually,
neither of us are.
- That is why we are
immediately starting
an expanded trial of Lymphodril.
On whose dime?
- Well, the trial
inequities were on us,
but, uh, Lymphodril
is your drug.
They're your profits,
so it's your dime.
- This is a list of
health organizations
that serve populations
that were not
included in the original trial.
- Howard University
College of Medicine,
Great Plains Tribal
Chairmen's Health Board,
uh, Mission Health Cooperative.
- They're all
ready to run trials
on the demographics
that we missed,
Native American,
African American,
Asian, Latinx, Middle Eastern...
- Uh, this may come
as a surprise to you,
but we bring drugs to
market to make money,
not hemorrhage it.
Why would we do this?
- You have to admit, the
world is a diverse place.
If you want to be in
business in 20 years,
you have to include everyone.
- Yeah, and if you don't, we
can just walk out the door.
And then we'll bury
these trial results,
and then nobody gets this drug.
Or... we can do this right.
- Okay.
Okay.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
- Oh, Paul came through.
Don't be so thrilled.
- Of course I'm thrilled,
but I lost the stupid apartment.
- Ah.
- So much for fresh starts.
- Ah, it's a big city, LB.
Huh? You'll find
the right place.
Like here.
- Uh, excuse me.
Are... are you
showing this place?
- Yes, I am.
- Ah, never mind.
If it's a turnkey that you want,
this definitely ain't it.
Matter of fact, this is like
the opposite of a turnkey.
This is like, uh,
black hole chic,
a blank canvas
without the canvas.
Eh, you gotta pick
out every fixture,
every light bulb,
every wall socket...
Paint coloring, floor covering,
walls, ceilings.
- I love it.
I love it.
You mean your interior
designer is gonna love it.
- No. No, I... I... I'm
gonna do it all myself.
- Lauren, um, you lived in
your apartment for ten years,
and you never even
hung a poster.
- Well, I just
turned the metal trim
inside an ambulance
into a chest retractor.
I can do this.
I mean, I need to do it,
'cause that's the only
way it's ever gonna feel
like it's really mine, you know?
If... if I make every decision,
if I do the work thoughtfully,
meticulously, painstakingly.
That's the way I wanna live.
- All right. All right.
I think she's gonna take it.
You are crazy.
- Oh, my God, I love it so much.
- I didn't know
you spoke Spanish.
- Yeah. Yeah, I've
done my fair share
of traveling myself, you know?
I even spent the
first six months
of my residency in the DR.
- Mm.
Well, it was pretty sexy.
- Oh.
Well, would you like to go
to dinner with me tonight?
I can order in Spanish.
- You know, I'd love to,
but I... I need to
make it an early night.
I leave for Tanzania tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
- The recruiter,
he said that he had
never heard a recommendation
like you gave me.
He said that he had to
make up an emergency
just to get you off the phone.
Yeah, you said that you
went on and on so much,
sounded like you
were in love with me.
- I think I am.
- Hi. Martin?
Hi. How are you doing?
I'm Iggy.
- Iggs...
- Oh, wow. Nice to meet you.
I... oh God, I'm
mucking this up already.
Look at you. I
didn't think you were
gonna be this, uh, attractive.
- Thank you. Uh, are we gonna
do this all night?
- Oh, fully, yes.
We are definitely doing
this all night long.
Because, uh, I didn't
know what you were into,
I took a safe shot, and, uh...
- Roller skating.
- Yeah,
'cause who doesn't
love roller skating?
- Sure.
- Hi.
Um... uh, shoe size?
- You know my...
- What?
- It's 11. My shoe size is 11.
- 11, nice.
Uh, one 11, and I am a 12.
There you go, 11.
- Yep.
- Thank you very much.
And, uh, that is for you.
Keep the change.
Uh, so what did you say
you do again, Martin?
- Iggs, stop.
- What?
- Look, what if we try
this and it doesn't work?
I don't know if I
can handle that.
I know the kids can't handle it.
We can't keep
playing make-believe.
- Yeah, I know. Um...
I... I'm scared too.
But you know, if... If we
both want a fresh start,
like, really want a fresh start,
I don't know how else to do it.
Do you?
- So... where are you from?
- I am from Wisconsin.
Where are you from?
- I am from Massachusetts.
- You're from...
Of course you are.
- What do you mean,
of course I am?
"I'm
from Massachusetts."
- No, I... I lost
my accent years ago.
- You lost your what?
- I lost my accent.
I
don't talk like that.
- Yeah.
- ♪ We're home, we're
home, we're home ♪
♪ Oh, we've come home
♪ We've come home