The conjoined twins
Dot and Lily Cronin
spent an uneventful night
in our pediatric
intensive care unit.
They'll be evaluated
this morning,
and if they remain stable,
the surgical team,
under the supervision of
Dr. Frisch and Dr. Latham,
will attempt to separate them.
Lungs sound clear.
The latest chest X-rays
are good.
No infiltrates.
Vitals and saturation
are stable.
The girls are healthy.
In my opinion, they're
strong enough for surgery.
Dr. Rhodes?
I agree with Dr. Bekker.
Actually, Dr. Rhodes will
not be in the operating room.
Dr. Latham and I
will be performing
the cardiothoracic portion
of the separation.
What?
You've been so involved
since the beginning.
What if we spoke
to Dr. Frisch?
Believe me, Dot and Lily have
the finest surgeons
in the hospital.
We'll be back soon
to take the babies to the O.R.
Excuse me.
Connor.
Why aren't you on the team?
He pulled himself out.
Why?
Because we lost a patient?
I lost her and her baby,
because of my poor judgment.
I made the wrong call
on her treatment.
But the Cronins
are counting on you.
They're counting on the team.
She's right.
Look, I can understand if
you're having second thoughts.
Yeah.
I'm worried about my sister.
Why? She told you
she was going to Las Vegas.
Yeah, but she's not returning
my calls or texts.
She's ashamed
she stole those drugs
and lied about it.
I still think we could've
handled it better.
Handled it better?
Emily committed a crime.
She's lucky
she wasn't arrested.
As soon as she
wants something,
I'm sure you'll hear from her.
Morning.
Good morning.
What?
Dr. Halstead, incoming.
Hey, after work...
Mm-hmm?
You wanna meet me
on the balcony?
Okay.
All right.
Monique, with us. Cesar?
Bert Goodwin,
60-year-old male.
Goodwin?
Trauma One.
Neighbors found him
unconscious in the garage.
Motor running.
Intubated in the field.
Carbon monoxide poisoning.
Tachycardic at 120.
BP, 145 over 95.
EKG shows
slight ST depressions.
Sats at 92%.
Okay, on my count,
one, two, three.
Monique, 12-lead EKG.
We need
a carboxyhemoglobin level.
CBC, BMP, coags, lactate,
troponins, and a chest X-ray.
Got it.
Maggie, call the ICU.
Have them set up
a hyperbaric chamber.
Copy.
And page Ms. Goodwin.
Let her know.
Is this her husband?
Ex-husband.
How's the position
of the twins?
Good for peds surgery.
CT?
Bit of a shadow in my field.
Can we adjust the light?
Good.
Has everyone
got room to work?
No, bypass is in my way.
What if you move the machine
to the foot of the bed?
You could run the tubing
along the sides.
That way, you won't cross
with anesthesia.
Ah. Good idea.
Tell me again
why you're not in there.
So, are we good to go?
All right, it's show time.
The pressure in the chamber
unbinds carbon monoxide
from hemoglobin.
It allows oxygen to bind.
Now, we've already seen
a significant improvement.
Bert's carbon monoxide levels
are down from 55% to 15.
Now, at 10%, we can
take him out of the chamber
and lighten the sedation.
He could've pulled into
the garage and fallen asleep.
Maybe he had a mild stroke.
We'll test for that.
His girlfriend died,
Dr. Halstead.
He tried to kill himself.
Dr. Choi, that homeless girl
that you treated
a couple months ago,
she's back with her friend.
They're asking for you.
Hey, Nat...
Yeah?
You free?
Kiki, Deb,
you remember Dr. Manning.
What's going on?
Oh, she's really sick.
BP's 102 over 68.
Heart rate, 112.
Temp, 100.
My stomach hurts. Headaches.
You are running a fever,
so let's take a look
and see what's going on,
all right?
Hey, Deb, you're looking
a little under
the weather too.
I'm just tired.
Still living on the streets?
It's okay.
Not so cold.
Her liver is
slightly enlarged.
I'm gonna be sick.
Okay.
We can help you
with the nausea.
4 milligrams of Zofran.
We'll run some tests.
Let's get a CBC, BMP, LFT,
hepatitis panel.
Whoa, whoa.
Ah. Let's get Deb
into a room,
take a look at her.
Okay. Come on, I got ya.
Better run the same labs
for Deb too.
Yeah.
Mr. Goodwin,
do you remember me?
I'm Dr. Halstead.
Mr. Goodwin...
I remember.
Good.
Can you follow my finger?
Okay. How 'bout this?
Can you touch your right
forefinger to your nose?
Mr. Goodwin,
can you try to touch
your right forefinger
to your nose or...
Why didn't you just
let me die?
We're gonna get you
through this.
I'll be back
to check on you soon.
I think he'll be okay.
Damn, Bert.
How could you do this?
Can't you think of
anyone else but yourself?
Sharon, come on.
It... It's selfish
and pathetic.
Not helping right now.
Attempted suicide is an
automatic five-day psych hold.
Fine.
Sharon, do you have a minute?
The board wants
to meet with you.
What is it?
More complaining about
the money we're spending?
I have to go.
Sharon...
Look, I have a situation
to deal with.
Tell them
I'll get back to them.
This facility, Holly Oaks,
has a good
staff-to-resident ratio.
They also have a nice package
of supplemental services.
Art, music, pet therapy.
It's still a nursing home.
It's a cardiac rehab facility.
Why can't I go back
to my apartment?
No. You just got
a new heart.
You have to be monitored
very closely,
particularly for
the first three months.
I don't deserve you.
Can we just focus on
finding you a place to live?
You're about to be discharged.
But it's true, Sarah...
I don't deserve you.
Dr. Haywood, time to get you
in the cardiac chair.
Can't it wait?
No.
No, you have
to change position
to prevent pneumonia.
Find a place you like.
We have
a public health issue.
Liver panels came back.
Both Kiki and Deb
tested positive for Hep A.
Oh, no.
We need to admit them
to the PICU.
Yeah, but then what?
It'll only be
for a couple days.
Then they'll wanna go
back out on the streets,
and they'll be...
They'll be contagious.
Highly contagious.
We have to report this.
I understand they live
in some kind of encampment?
Yeah, with a bunch of
other kids in close quarters.
It's got to be cleared out.
DCFS will have to find homes
for these kids.
Meanwhile, let's get
a team over there
to see who else is infected,
and immunize everybody
who's been exposed.
Natalie and I should go.
We've treated them.
They know us, April too.
Okay, I'll stay and
look after Kiki and Deb.
All right.
Please, can we have
just one more minute?
Yeah. Guys, hold on.
We love you so much.
Are we doing the right thing
taking this risk?
Yes.
Look after them, Dr. Rhodes.
Don't let my babies die.
Thomas.
Hey, Dr. Choi.
You know April. Not sure
if you met Dr. Manning,
but she was here with me
a couple months ago.
Thomas, we need
to examine everybody,
but first we need to see
anyone who's not feeling well.
The most sick first.
Laura.
Laura?
Is she the one
who had the baby?
Yeah.
Where is she?
Laura?
Dr. Manning?
Have you seen my baby?
No, but I know she was
adopted by a good family.
Temp's 101.
When was the last time you
had anything to eat or drink?
Significantly jaundiced
and dehydrated.
Liver's enlarged.
We need to get her
to the hospital.
No.
Laura, you have to.
You have hepatitis.
You could die.
Call an ambulance.
Thomas, who else is sick?
Over here.
Excuse me.
Hey, I'm Dr. Choi.
Hey.
Emily...
Ethan?
Emily, what are
you doing here?
Nowhere to go.
It's all right, okay?
I messed up.
Have you been able
to eat or drink anything?
No, it makes me throw up.
Don't worry,
you're gonna be okay.
I'm gonna take care of you.
Ambulances are on their way.
Oh, my God.
Take it easy, Em, I got you.
What's up, Jay?
Gunshot victim... Just waiting
to get a statement.
What'd Natalie say?
I'll tell you tonight.
You didn't ask her yet?
You've had Mom's ring a week.
It's gotta be perfect.
Do you have any idea what
real French champagne costs?
More than you can afford.
Don't I know it.
Hello?
Yes, he's right here.
Dr. Charles, it's for you.
Dr. Charles?
Yes, this is
Mr. and Mrs. Coveny.
Uh, Detective Miller
in Madison,
he said
that you called him,
that you're interested in
the case of our daughter,
Olivia.
She disappeared ten years ago.
Mr. Coveny, um...
Why did you call?
Well, I'm a, um...
I'm a forensic psychiatrist
here in Chicago,
and I'm interested in
your daughter's case
purely in a clinical
point of view.
Come visit us.
We'll tell you about Olivia.
She was
really remarkable.
Dr. Charles,
if you find out something,
call us, please.
Uh, of course.
Let me give you my number.
Clamps are on.
A lot of bigwigs here.
Hopkins, Mayo, Duke.
Dot's inferior vena cava
is more anterior lateral
than anticipated.
We'll have to reconstruct
the atrium to get it closed.
What does that mean?
They need to continue
the surgery on bypass.
I'm afraid we're gonna have
to put the twins on bypass.
You were right.
Thanks, Kelly.
Hey, Bert.
You mind if I sit?
Just for the record, I'm not
here on official business.
I just...
Came to say hi to an old pal.
Leave me alone, Daniel.
The other day, I heard
these two residents
talking about this ten-day
master cleanse.
You ever heard of that?
Reminded me of the time
that you and I went on
that grapefruit diet.
You know, something about
the enzymes in the grape...
Please.
You're wasting your time.
Just go away.
Your fever's gone down.
Heart rate and blood pressure
have improved.
All good signs.
Uh, what about Kiki?
She's doing better too.
Maggie, if Deb and Kiki
are both stable,
we can send them up
to the PICU.
We got more coming in.
Dr. Manning?
You're going to Treatment Two.
16-year-old female,
suspect Hep A.
Febrile and hypotensive.
My stomach hurts.
We're gonna help you
with that, all right?
Emily?
Possibly Hep A also.
You're going to
Treatment Four.
Febrile and tachycardic.
Call Radiology.
We need an ultrasound of her
liver, right upper quadrant.
Got it.
Transfer her on my count.
Ready?
Yep.
One, two, three.
Let's get a CBC, BMP, LFTs,
hepatitis panel,
and a chest X-ray.
Got it.
She hates me.
She doesn't hate you.
I don't blame her.
Just get some rest.
I'm not going anywhere.
Laura is emaciated, lethargic,
and profoundly jaundiced.
Incubation time
should be similar,
but she's presenting
so much worse than the others.
I know you delivered
this girl's baby.
I'm sorry, Natalie.
Both hearts on bypass.
We're ready to go.
One more echo
to confirm positioning.
I'm seeing a pretty large
muscular ventricular
septal defect in Dot's heart.
Why didn't we see this
on previous imaging?
Doesn't matter.
We'll have to correct it
before we can proceed.
Is this a big problem?
Patching a hole of unknown
size near the heart's apex,
a difficult spot to reach,
yeah, it's a very big problem.
To get access, we need
to make a ventriculotomy.
No, in this case,
with the abnormal anatomy
of the heart, by cutting
into the ventricle,
we can disrupt the heart's
conducting system.
The heart might
never beat again.
We lose one girl,
we lose them both.
Excuse me.
I think we should patch
the hole using
the sandwich method.
Two pieces of Gore-Tex
on either side.
More incisions in
her tiny, fragile heart.
No, too risky.
Use a transcatheter
VSD closure device.
That's a cath lab procedure.
We never do it
on an open heart case.
It's the only way
to reach the VSD
and not damage Dot's heart.
No incision.
We snake the patch in
through the atrium.
Dr. Latham...
No, he's right.
It's our only option.
I will take
full responsibility
for the outcome.
Indeed, you will.
Dr. Rhodes will perform
the procedure.
Go scrub in.
Yes, sir.
Connor...
I have to do this.
You realize if those babies
don't pull through,
your career is over?
Yeah. I do.
Sharon? Can I just
talk to you
for a second?
Yeah.
So...
Bert isn't talking
to Dr. Chapman,
he isn't talking to Dr. Reese,
not even talking to me.
You two were married
for 30 years.
30 years.
Oh, I'm sorry, I'm just...
please, I'm asking you,
could you...
Could you talk to him?
Just try and open him up.
So, you think that
because of all
those good years,
I owe him something now?
I'm just saying that,
coming from you,
it might make a difference,
that's all.
Well, let me ask you
this, Daniel,
what did Bert owe me
when he walked out?
You suspected
a comorbid illness.
You were right.
Laura?
Your HIV antibody tests
came back as negative.
However, you did test positive
for both hepatitis A
and hepatitis C.
I am very sorry.
Hep A is recent,
but the Hep C, we think
you've had for a long time.
It's damaged your kidneys
and your liver.
My baby,
did I give it to her?
We don't know.
We'll have to contact
her parents
and have them bring her in,
so that we can
test her as well.
My little girl.
Now, luckily,
if she is infected,
at this early stage,
we can treat her.
When she comes,
can I see her?
We'll see if that's possible.
Have you decided
on a rehab facility?
Oh, you pick one.
I'm not gonna be
living there, you are.
Sarah, I'm sure you'll find
the best one,
or at least the lesser
of all the evils.
You know,
I suddenly love choral music.
Just like my heart donor.
It's good to see you.
The nurses aren't
very good company.
I hardly ever see them.
What do you mean? They're
supposed to be walking you.
Haven't you
been outside today?
Nope.
Nurses put me in this chair
and left me.
I imagine she's very busy.
Hey, uh,
this transplant patient's
supposed to walk
every three hours.
We are short-staffed today.
I'll get to it when I can.
Never mind, I'll do it.
Come on, Dad,
we're gonna go for a walk.
Oh, I'd like that.
So far, we have
five Hep A patients.
One adult
and four adolescents.
One of the patients
also has hepatitis C.
She gave birth to a baby
a few months back,
put her up for adoption.
The adoptive parents are here
to get the baby tested.
Please keep me informed
if those numbers change.
Oh, and another thing,
Peter Kalmick called.
They're asking
for you upstairs
in the board room.
Yeah, I know.
I... I'll get to them.
Oh, and have you been up
to see Bert?
No.
I can't see her
field of positioning
as much as I had hoped.
Can you get
the device in place?
Give me a second.
Okay.
Snaking the catheter
into position.
Pulling the first half of the
patch into the left ventricle.
But if you can't see
or feel the alignment,
you can't be sure of deploying
the second half correctly.
So we'll have to open
the heart even more
to make the repair,
which is exactly
what we're trying to avoid.
Maybe not.
Let's try
a flexible pharyngoscope.
Maybe we can see
where the patch is lying
before we deploy.
Beth?
Here.
Dr. Rhodes...
Well?
Uh...
Yeah, I see it.
All right, aligning the patch.
And deploying.
The VSD's repaired.
Now we can proceed.
I got some fluids in you.
Should be feeling better.
Heart rate and blood pressure
look good.
Em, I, uh... I...
I'm just...
I'm so sorry
for what I did.
I lied to you.
I'm so sorry.
Don't worry about that.
Hey, I'll be
right back, okay?
We can send Emily upstairs.
Good.
And when she gets well,
you should talk
to Dr. Charles.
We'll see.
He knows places, group homes
that could take her in.
So, you want me
to send her away?
She needs professional help.
Let her be
somebody else's problem?
Ethan...
That's how I've always
dealt with Emily.
I can't do that anymore.
Oh, Dr. Charles.
Hello.
Bob.
And Dr. Reese.
Sarah was taking me
for a walk.
As soon as I get him back,
I'll finish rounds.
Dr. Charles, why don't you
see me the rest of the way?
Let Sarah get back
to her real job.
Uh... Sure.
Thank you, Dr. Reese.
You know, Sarah told me
that a woman
in her support group
says her husband came away
from his heart transplant
a changed man.
Really?
Yeah, I did
a little googling.
It turns out that there's
a lot of anecdotal evidence
that transplant patients
experience profound
personality changes.
Yes, uh, "anecdotal"
being the key word there.
Oh, no, actually
there's a name for it.
It's called
cell memory phenomenon,
the theory that
memory is stored
in the neurons of
donated organs.
I mean, it would
certainly explain
why recipients develop
the tastes
and preferences and habits,
even dreams of
their heart's donors.
What are you doing, Bob?
Your antisocial
personality disorder
isn't gonna be affected
by a transplant.
The issue is your brain,
not your heart.
Glenda, could you escort
Dr. Haywood back to his room?
He has had a nice, long walk.
Sure.
Yeah.
Well, Sarah seems open
to the possibility,
or do you think she's just
another young, gullible woman,
Daniel?
Uh, yes, hi, Mr. Coveny?
It's, uh, it's Dr. Charles
from Chicago Med.
I so appreciate your
invitation to come up
and visit.
It's very helpful
for my research to get
a complete picture
of everyone involved.
Seems like the world's
forgotten about Olivia.
We're just so grateful
to talk to someone who hasn't.
Left her room
just the way it was
the day Olivia disappeared.
That was taken
the summer between
her freshman and
sophomore year in college.
She was a science major
at Madison, right?
And she minored in astronomy?
Did she get to know
any of her professors?
No, she never mentioned
any of her professors.
The police
interviewed everyone.
No one knew anything.
Olivia loved monkeys.
Where's the third one?
Oh, yeah, when we picked
her things up from the dorm,
it wasn't there, we don't know
what happened to it.
Laura?
I have some good news.
Your baby's okay.
Look.
My baby.
What's her name?
Anna.
I promise we'll take
good care of her.
This way.
Thank you.
Of course.
So, the baby tested negative.
Yeah, and Laura
got to see her.
That's great.
Yeah.
Good omen.
What?
No pulse.
I'll bag her.
Milligram of epi.
Come on.
The girl with Hep C.
Hold compression.
Another milligram of epi.
Come on.
Hold compression.
Asystole.
No.
Laura, come on.
She's gone.
Time of death, 15:25.
Have you been able
to reach her family?
Not yet.
You know, the last time
you brought Lyla here...
Just before
she passed away,
as sick as she was,
she had the presence of mind
to ask me
to look after you
when she was gone.
Sharon, I...
I'm sorry for the
pain I caused you.
You know, I don't need
or want an apology
from you, Bert,
but I'm not gonna sit here
and lie to you either.
It was hard,
the way you left me,
our life.
But what's done is done,
and I'm a big girl.
I'm working it out.
But we can be proud of this.
We have raised
three wonderful children.
Don't do this to them, Bert.
Don't you dare do
this to them.
And you let these people
help you.
I just told you.
I can't let you in
without his permission.
It's just that Dr. Haywood
is entering this rehab
facility on very short notice,
and it's just important
that I get him
a few personal items.
Uh, you know,
toothbrush, toothpaste...
Have him call me.
Liver separation is complete.
Both hearts as well.
Already off bypass.
Decannulated as well.
Pacing wires are in.
Patch is holding.
Both hearts look good.
So, what's included in your
massive transfusion protocol?
Well...
And how responsive
is the blood bank?
They'll come in with a cooler
stocked with 4 units of reds
and 2 plasma.
Well, can I see the data
and your process
improvement indicators?
Well...
Excuse me.
Can I help you?
Ms. Goodwin, this is our
new division chief of trauma,
James Lanik.
Jimmy.
New chief of trauma?
Ms. Goodwin is
our Executive Director
of Patient and
Medical Services.
Looks like you weren't
expecting me.
News to me.
I just got the memo.
Well, it's nice to meet you,
Dr. Lanik.
Hospital intrigue.
Yeah, you'll see.
Sharon, congratulations on
the twins.
Come join us for champagne.
How is it we have
a new chief of trauma
and I wasn't consulted?
I've been trying to get you
to meet with us all day.
But we should've
given you a heads-up,
and I'm sorry.
The position
needed to be filled,
and I know
Dr. Lanik personally.
He is first-rate.
Sharon, this is Gwen Garrett,
our new C.O.O.
New? We never had
an old C.O.O.
Well, it's a recently
created position.
Help run the hospital
a little more efficiently.
Efficiently or economically?
Uh, both.
Ms. Garret's done
a wonderful job
minimizing red ink at
several large pharmaceuticals.
I look forward to working
with you, Ms. Goodwin.
As do I, Ms. Garrett.
It's amazing.
Excuse me, Dr. Rhodes,
Ralph Ballard.
Have you got a minute?
I gotta run to my locker.
I'll meet you on the balcony?
Sure.
Will, care to come
celebrate with me?
Uh, no thanks.
Natalie...
It was her?
Yes, but...
Please.
Told Emily when she gets out,
she can stay with us.
Ethan, you can't trust her.
Look, you know
how hard
she's been trying,
how great she was
with patients.
Yeah, until she quit
without notice.
Look, I know she said some
awful things to you and...
No, it's not about that.
Then what is it?
You're the one who always told
me how important family is.
Yes, and I treated Emily
like family.
I stood up for her,
I told you to give her
another chance,
and how did she thank you?
Thank me?
She stole drugs.
She lied to us.
Ethan, she's damaged.
You can't fix her.
I gotta try.
She's just gonna bring
her mess into our lives.
April...
I'm sorry, but she's
coming home with us.
No, Ethan,
she's going home with you.
Natalie!
Hey...
I wanted this
to be so special.
Uh, a view of
the city, champagne.
Not like this,
not in a parking lot,
but, I'm not
gonna let you go...
Not without asking.
Will...
Just wait.
Will you marry me?
So, tell me, did you
orchestrate this whole thing?
Reluctant hero comes in
and saves the day?
You give me
too much credit.
Do I?
Your ambition
strikes me as boundless.
Wait a second,
do you really think that?
I don't know what to think.
Yes, you helped keep
those babies alive,
but I'm sure you also
secured yourself
an attending position.
Uh, God, Ava, I...
What?
You bastard.
You got an offer tonight,
didn't you?
That guy in the PICU?
Mayo Clinic.
You got an offer
at the Mayo Clinic?
I can't believe it.
And of course
you're going to take it.
Would you?
Yes. Absolutely.
Great.
Oh, Dr. Charles.
Come to say good-bye.
I did.
You all set to, uh,
head off to rehab?
Well, actually, Sarah has
asked me to live with her
while I complete my recovery.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
Sarah's taking you
home with her?
Mm-hmm.
Huh.
Well, I guess she certainly
turned out to be
the devoted daughter
you were looking for.
I'm a very lucky man.
So, guess what, I, uh...
I decided I'm gonna
head up to Madison
and give that forensic
psychiatry seminar.
Oh, you decided to do it?
Yeah.
It turns out that
they got a bit of
a dark history up there
at the university, you know,
some homegrown crime
of their own.
Oh?
Yeah, around ten years ago,
I think around the time
that you were teaching there,
the, um... The Olivia...
Coveny case?
You remember?
No, doesn't ring a bell.
Her parents are convinced
she was murdered.
Murdered?
Well, just because
a girl is missing
doesn't mean she was murdered.
Oh, uh, so you do remember?
Hm? What? Sorry?
Well, I... I didn't say
that she was missing.
Oh, well,
guess I just assumed.
Yeah, I was kinda surprised
when you said
you didn't remember,
because she was a...
She was an astronomy student,
actually, one of yours.
Ah, so, this is
where this is going,
this little dance of yours.
You're suggesting
I'm a murderer. Really?
You know what's
the most fascinating thing
about serial killers?
Even the most brilliant ones,
they all have this weakness,
where they can't seem
to resist taking
a personal item
from their victims,
you know, like, uh...
Like a trophy.
Trophy?
Yeah, in this case,
I think it's a
little stuffed monkey.
Oh, please.
Why don't you just admit
you lost?
I'm going home
with my daughter,
and you can't do
anything about it.
Give it up.
You appreciate the irony,
don't you?
That you've got
this new heart,
this new life,
and you spend
the rest of it in jail?
Bob?
Dad?