They say life doesn't
give you second chances.
But we do.
Surgeons do.
Hey. ER? Yep.
Uh, so, sorry about last night.
Don't worry about
it. You're mad.
We just... We really
lost track of time...
I'm not. It's fine.
Forget it. Oh.
You break a bone,
we put it back together.
You bleed, we make it
stop. HERMAN: Well?
You flatline, we
resuscitate you.
What did you decide?
I didn't! I was up all
night. Mmm-hmm.
Then you had ample time.
You can't drop a bomb
like "I have a brain tumor"
and expect me to decide
anything. I need to know more.
You don't need to know anything
that you don't already know.
Okay, great. Why the pills?
I'm getting a migraine.
You're not helping.
This... This is what I mean.
Is it a migraine
or is it the tumor?
What kind of tumor is
it? What does it mean?
Are you gonna get
tremors during surgery?
You're talking me through a
procedure and you slur your speech?
I need to know more!
You don't get to.
Of course I'm not gonna do
anything to endanger my patients.
I am handling my
situation responsibly,
but it is my situation, and
you are not entitled to it.
You are entitled
to my knowledge,
to my years of discoveries
and mistakes and dead ends
and blood and
sweat and innovations
that you don't have to go
through. That's the deal.
The chance to take my work
into your future.
Just you.
So could you please
make up your mind?
But as much as we give
people second chances,
surgeons don't usually get them.
Surgeries are canceled.
Round on my service.
I have an appointment.
And don't ask what it is, 'cause,
of course, I'm not gonna tell you.
Because the kind
of mistakes we make
are sometimes
impossible to recover from.
What's wrong with you?
Uh... I was up all night.
Me too.
Ah, Sofia's been acting out, asking
questions about me and Arizona,
and I don't know what to
tell her or how to tell her,
so I'm just not sleeping. I'm
miserable. Why didn't you sleep?
Oh, you don't want to know.
What's going on?
Derek and I were up
having sex all night.
Yeah, I kind of didn't
want to hear that.
Sixty-nine-year-old male, jumped
two stories from a burning building.
Shocky, BP's 95 over
60 with a rate in the 120s.
GCS 14 in the field.
Hattie...
Why am I looking at two
patients on one gurney?
She's dead. OWEN: What?
Hattie... We
couldn't find a pulse.
And we tried to pull her off,
but the husband just held on.
He was agitated. He
wouldn't let her go.
So we had to stop 'cause we
were afraid we were gonna hurt him.
What've we got? Oh, wow.
Hattie...
Witnesses said he carried
his wife out the window
and jumped to escape the fire.
We think he was
trying to break her fall.
Let's get them into trauma one.
Amy, where do you need me?
You got the head
lac in bed 3, right?
Yeah, that's nothing.
I can jump in on this.
I don't need you.
Is that good management,
you leaving your star
player on the bench?
You won't be for long.
People are always hitting
their heads on something.
His skin is mottled
and cyanotic.
We have to get her off of him.
Sir, you have to let her go. No.
We have to move her
to help you. MALE
PATIENT: No, no.
Sir, what is your name? Norris.
Is she... MEREDITH: Norris...
You don't have to worry
about that right now, sir.
No, he does, actually.
Of course he does.
Norris, what is your wife's name?
- Is she...
Harriet.
Hattie.
Norris.
Norris, it's time to let
Hattie go. She's gone.
Gone? What do you mean gone?
Norris, she died.
No. No.
She's gone. I'm
sorry. Hattie, no...
You did everything
you could. No! No...
You helped her
through the hardest part.
You held her, you protected
her, and she died in your arms.
And I'm sure she couldn't
think of a better way to go.
She's no longer in any
pain, Norris, but you are,
and she wouldn't want you to be.
You have to let her go now
so we can help you, okay?
She's mine. I can't.
Norris. Norris, I'm so sorry.
It's time.
Okay.
On three.
One, two, three.
Let's go. Come on.
I'll go pronounce. Hattie...
Hattie...
Honey... Honey...
Airway's intact, but
there's a little soot.
Hypotensive and a rigid abdomen.
Pupils are equal and
reactive bilaterally.
Right lower leg is
tense and swollen.
I'm gonna measure
compartment pressures.
Quiet. Breath sound
is decreased on the left.
Add right tib/fib
to the trauma films.
Quiet!
I got a pulse.
Barely palpable, but it's there.
Trauma two! Pierce,
Shepherd, you're with me.
She's alive?
She is.
You'll take care of her?
I will.
I'll take real good
care of her. I promise.
Where's Dr. Herman?
Did you call my mom?
You said to wait until there's
something to be worried about.
Well, now I'm worried.
Why isn't she moving?
Emily, Corey, I'm concerned
that the baby might be
bleeding into the tumor itself,
and it's causing
her to be anemic.
Oh, my God. Will
she be all right?
Where's Dr. Herman?
She had an, um, appointment
with another patient.
Well, she can do
something, right?
She said she'd do everything
to get the baby to term.
That was the whole point
of planning fetal surgery.
And that's still the point.
Dr. Herman will likely perform
an intrauterine transfusion.
I will apprise her,
and we'll come back
and talk to you about
how to move forward.
Sit tight, okay? Okay.
Where is Dr. Herman?
I have no idea, but
she better pick up,
because Emily Jensen's
baby's gonna die.
Good tube placement.
Yeah, the hemopneumothorax is
bigger. Edwards, prep for a chest tube.
Before you do that, Edwards,
can you check with CT again
and see when they can take us?
But she's bleeding
into her lung.
I know, but I felt a depressed
temporal bone fracture,
and she has spinal fluid
coming out of her ear.
I need a CT to confirm.
I'm on my way up to Radiology. Is
anyone free to update the family?
Mmm-hmm.
Sarah?
What are you doing here? Amelia.
You're a doctor?
I am, yeah.
My parents, they were in a fire.
Oh, God.
Okay. Um...
This is what we know so far.
Your father has some internal
injuries and a leg fracture.
Your mom has some bleeding
into her lung and a cranial fracture.
As her neurosurgeon, I'm gonna
need to do some surgery to...
Wait.
You want to do
surgery on my mom?
No. No. I'm sorry,
but no. No. I...
Excuse me. I need
a different doctor.
Sarah...
She cannot touch my
mother. It's not just...
I need a different
doctor right now.
Okay. Calm down. Let's just...
No! I want another doctor!
What's the problem here?
She cannot touch my
mother. She's a drug addict.
I can't have her
operate on my parents.
Hold it. Dr. Shepherd is our...
Is a junkie.
I met her in Narcotics
Anonymous. She's hooked on oxy.
She overdosed with her boyfriend and
woke up with him dead in bed with her.
I want another doctor.
Now!
Come with me. Just
come with me, please.
No! I'm... No, no!
This way, please.
You keep her away from them!
Hunt, don't worry. I've got this.
Keep her away from them!
Follow me, ma'am.
Calm down and follow me.
What was that?
You just took Amelia's surgery?
What was I supposed to do?
Take her side.
She was being attacked.
The woman had it
out for her, Meredith.
If anything goes wrong,
she'll go blaming her
because she was an addict.
You're gonna go talk to
Owen, right, and clear this up?
Yes, I will.
I paged you three times.
Yeah, keep your pants on. I'm
consulting on three babies here...
I have a mom whose fetus
is bleeding into her SCT.
She needs an
intrauterine transfusion.
It's inserting a 6-inch
needle into an umbilical vein
without rupturing membranes
or inducing bradycardia.
I've never done one,
and Herman's AWOL.
So, you deliver. You'll
take the baby out.
I'll repair the SCT myself.
Alex, the baby's 28 weeks.
The whole point in seeing Herman
was to try and get her to term.
Yeah, it'd be great if she were
here, but I know how to save this kid.
You've reached the voicemail
of Dr. Nicole Herman.
Herman, Robbins again.
The Jensen baby's anemic,
and the MCA flow is 70.
I will give you 30 minutes,
and if I don't hear from you,
I'm gonna do a C-section
and resect the SCT.
Okay. I'm gonna book an OR,
and can you be ready in
30 minutes if I need you?
Yeah.
That's good. Okay. Thank you.
She's losing it. Yes, she is.
Look, it's your first solo
surgery. It's a big deal.
If you're too nervous,
I am more than happy
to take it off your hands.
I'm not nervous.
Great. Then you'd
better not be pregnant.
Because if you let Karev
throw a baby in there,
I will never forgive you.
I'm not pregnant,
and I am not nervous.
I know how to fix a hernia.
Step one, medial dissection.
Step two, identify triangle
of doom, avoid the iliac vein.
Step three... Puke.
Bailey's gonna eat you alive.
No, she's not,
because I'm a badass.
Step three, lateral
dissection. Step four...
Identify triangle of pain.
See? Great.
I have got this procedure down,
and I am not afraid
of little bitty Dr. Bailey.
Think you could turn the
faucet on for me, Dr. Badass?
I'd do it myself,
only I'm so little bitty.
Shh. Here she comes.
That's really scary, the idea
of her operating on someone.
Did you know she was an addict?
It must be because
she's Shepherd's sister.
I need to talk to you.
She just said it in
front of everyone,
all this stuff that I said
at meetings about...
It's okay. Are you sober?
How is it okay?
Everyone is looking at me.
Are you sober?
Of course I am.
Did you disclose your
recovery when you were hired?
I didn't have to! Derek hired me.
He knew. I assumed people knew.
And you've done nothing wrong.
Okay? She did.
She violated your privacy.
And you are under no obligation
to tell anyone anything more,
unless you've done something to
compromise your ability to do your job,
and you haven't.
So you don't need to
say anything more about it.
Okay.
Those are your rights.
It's the past, and you
don't have to defend it.
I thought I got away from it.
Coming here, I thought...
I thought I had a chance to...
But you never get away from it.
No.
No, you don't.
What do I do now?
You just stay on track.
You look after
yourself, do your job.
And as soon as you can,
you need to get to a meeting.
Well?
Time's up. Let's
take the baby out.
You're making the right call.
Hey, it's Robbins, again.
So you've left me no choice, and
for all I know, you could be dead.
So I've made my
decision about you.
I am telling Chief Hunt as
soon as I get out of surgery.
Is that her? Yeah, that's her.
Dr. Shepherd. Um...
Could we go somewhere
private and talk?
I'm busy right now, actually.
This is important.
Listen.
Is there anything
you want to tell me?
To clear this up?
I don't.
I think you heard all the facts.
What I heard was a very
distraught woman shouting.
And I think there is
another side to this story.
A woman requested another doctor,
and I was removed from the case.
That is her right.
People have rights.
Listen, I am just trying
to have a conversation.
That is none of your business if
I'm doing my job. Am I doing my job?
Amelia, I am trying
to help you here.
I just...
I don't have to
discuss this with you.
And that's your answer?
That's my right.
Okay.
Let's clamp and cut.
And here she is.
I've got her.
All right, let's
exteriorize the uterus.
Starting an umbilical line.
How's she doing?
Let's pre-oxygenate
her before we intubate.
Can you handle this?
You just need to deliver the
placenta and then close the...
I've only done about
a million C-sections.
How you doing now? ALEX: Bad.
OR 7 is waiting for us.
Graham, I'm going with the baby,
so just come and find me
when you're done, all right?
All right, let's go!
We're on the move!
Damn it. This lobe is trashed.
We're gonna have
to do a lobectomy.
We really have to
take that much lung?
We'll try to save
as much as possible.
Wait. Where's the
bleed? Where's the bleed?
I can't find it.
Okay. DEREK:
Everything okay there?
All right. Here's what you do.
- Drop the suction.
- Yeah.
Now reach in there
and grab the hilum
and twist it off
like a garden hose.
Just slow the flow of
blood until I can find...
Ah! Yes. There we go.
Hattie...
That was really cool.
You may keep going,
Dr. Shepherd, but go easy.
Hattie here has a hot
date with her husband.
Okay. Gotcha.
Sinus flap coming off.
Yep, just like it's supposed to.
Good.
- Boy or a girl?
- What's that?
Your baby.
Oh, right. Yes. Um...
Actually we have
decided to be surprised.
That's a good call.
Ah, it's April's idea.
Actually, it's driving me crazy.
What would be the point
of knowing everything you
possibly could about your child
when it's so much fun to be
hopelessly unprepared, right?
Yeah, we found out
my son was a boy.
See?
Yeah, but I didn't know
he was gonna be delivered
by an intern in a
pitch-black room
in the middle of a superstorm,
but surprises happen.
That's a good story,
but I find no comfort in it.
Yeah, well, and this.
I've been on the
bench for weeks,
yet here I am, saving a woman's
life without even opening her skull.
Embrace surprises, Avery.
Lateral incision's done.
Going for medial now.
His spleen is shattered. Give
me the longest Kelly you have.
Here you go.
He was a human
trampoline for his wife.
Pretty amazing. Better
than burning to death.
I can't imagine.
I can imagine throwing
my wife out a window.
Ex-wife.
Everyone keeps saying
that things will get easier,
and I'm sure everyone can't
be wrong, but, man, I am...
I'm really ready
for the easier part.
I think Derek and I may
have hit the easier part.
Yeah. You mentioned.
I don't know. We keep
calling these time-outs,
you know? CALLIE: Mmm-hmm.
And then we're
so busy time-outing
that we forget we're even mad.
- Hmm.
I don't know. He seems
better, at home, at least.
I keep waiting for the other shoe to
drop, but maybe there is no other shoe.
There's a shoe.
You know what
your time-outs are?
Band-Aids.
They cover the mess, they
stop the bleeding for a little while,
but you're just ignoring
the damage, and then...
Good times.
Trust me. There's
gonna be another shoe.
Awfully quiet over there.
Just focused, Dr. Bailey.
Do you think you should be
updating me on your progress?
Yeah.
I, uh, just finished
the medial dissection
and identified the triangle of doom,
then lateral dissection, triangle of pain.
All that's left is the mesh.
Sounds like you have
everything under control.
Totally. Totally under control.
And you didn't
barf in your mask.
Bravo.
Okay, you have to
resect really carefully,
especially this premature.
Oh, no. There's another bleeder.
You're gonna have to
devascularize this whole thing.
Yep, yep. I got it.
This is nice. It's
like old times.
You haven't let me get
used to the new times.
Dr. Robbins, Dr. Maddox
has asked for you in OR 6.
Ugh. Graham. It's
a simple C-section.
I can take this if you got to go.
- He says it's urgent.
Put the blood
- in a rapid infuser!
- Graham?
The placenta was adhered,
and as I started to pull,
everything started bleeding!
How many units has
she gone through?
Uh, I don't know. - Graham!
Two, three! Eight.
I did what I was supposed
to! I pulled at the placenta!
Gown and glove me right
now! Damn it, Graham.
It looks like placenta percreta.
It's probably invading
deeper structures.
Can't you see that? Ugh!
Why didn't anybody stop him?
All right, listen, call Hunt or
any trauma surgeon that's on call.
- On it.
- Graham, move.
Move!
Your mother had
a spinal-fluid leak.
I was able to stop it
without opening up her skull.
She's still in surgery,
and we hope to repair the
damage to her right lung.
Your father has
some internal bleeding.
We'll know more soon.
Thank you both so much.
I didn't want to do that to her.
That other doctor.
I'm in recovery, too.
I broke an oath.
I wanted... I want to
be supportive, but...
But it's my mother.
We'll let you know when
we know more, okay?
Derek, what am
I looking at here?
What are you talking about? Amy?
What that lady said,
how much of it is true?
Is it all true? She's
a drug addict?
She killed her boyfriend?
She's my sister.
I'm asking because I need to know if
we want her out front as neuro chief.
I'm asking you if you think
she's the best person to
be heading the department.
Okay.
I get it. She's your sister.
Say no more.
Thanks.
Shh.
I'm here! Placenta percreta
invading the bowel and bladder, right?
I paged Hunt.
Where's Hunt? APRIL: He's busy.
Well, I didn't want
you to see this.
Oh, please. Where
do you need me?
Get in here and start clamping.
The ultrasound
didn't detect this?
No, even Herman didn't see it.
And pregnant women
have a higher blood volume,
distended vessels,
they bleed out faster...
Oh, can it, Graham.
Oh, no. No, no, no.
What is it?
It extended to her kidney.
And the ureter... Lap pad!
Keep that blood coming! She's
losing a liter every two minutes!
Good lord. How do any
of us even have babies?
See, that's why I
didn't want you in here.
I see no other injuries.
The bowel is intact.
I think we can close.
How much longer do you guys have?
- What's up?
I've called for an
emergency board meeting.
Is this about Amelia? - It is.
Didn't Derek talk to you?
He did.
Owen. Owen!
Callie. Other shoe.
- We got this. Go.
- Close for me.
Shh.
Did Owen talk to you?
I didn't tell him anything.
I don't have any...
Did he talk to you
about your job?
He's saying he's
gonna take my job?
You'll talk to him,
right? I did. I did already.
I think I might have
given him the idea.
Oh, no. Derek,
no. I didn't mean to.
I'm sorry. I will fix it.
He wants to give you my
job, and you're gonna let him.
No, I'm not.
You son of a bitch.
You son of a bitch!
Don't. You kept me here!
Don't. Amy, don't.
You asked me to come.
You asked me to stay,
when I was building a life...
A new life, a second
chance that I had given myself
just so that you could
feel better about leaving.
I was trying to help you, and
I was trying to help myself.
I was just try... And
you gave me this job,
and you have abused me
since the second I took it.
But that is not enough. You
need to destroy my entire...
How can you do
this to me? I will...
To me? I will fix it!
How can you do
this? I will talk to them!
I will talk to all of
them, and I will fix it.
You're my brother.
I'm looking for Derek
Shepherd. Have you seen him?
Uh, mmm-mmm.
Oh, there you are.
What is going on? What
is this meeting about?
There's not gonna be a
meeting. I'm gonna talk to Hunt.
He said he already
talked to you.
He did.
Well, did you set him
straight about Amelia?
I didn't.
What? Not right now, Mer.
I can't talk to you
about this. Not right now.
Derek, what did you say?
What did you do?
I just finished my first
solo TAPP surgery.
All right. Did you
throw up in your mask?
No. Why does everyone
keep asking me that? I nailed it.
Medial, lateral,
pain, mesh... Boom!
What about the triangle
of doom, the iliac vein?
What about it?
Well, you skipped it.
No, I didn't.
Jo, you didn't say it.
But I did it.
In there. I didn't skip
it in there. In there, I...
I did it, right?
Are you asking me?
Medium clip. - Got it.
3-0 silk. Hang another unit.
She's gone through 100
units of blood products.
Dr. Robbins, Dr. Karev
is asking to see you.
Oh, her baby.
Did he say what's wrong?
Just that he needed you.
Damn. Go.
No, I can't leave
this woman. I got her.
Make sure her baby's okay.
Oh! Sorry!
What happened?
Where's Dr. Karev?
What is it? What happened?
Oh, I finished. It went well.
You were all in a
twist about this kid,
so I thought you'd want
to update the dad with me.
Oh, God. Alex,
no, his wife is...
Is the baby okay?
Yes. Uh, the surgery went
well. Her vitals are good.
She'll likely need to stay
in the NICU for a while,
but she's looking good.
Has Emily seen her?
She's still in surgery.
Um, there were some
complications during her C-section.
Wait, she's still in surgery?
We're doing everything that
we can. I have to go back.
Everything you can?
How serious is this?
She lost a lot of blood.
Where's Dr. Herman?
Dr. Herman had a plan.
Now you've got my baby in critical
care, and my wife is bleeding to death!
I don't even know who you are.
I have to go back.
Where the hell is our doctor?
It was just a
misunderstanding with Owen.
He'll take care of
it. He said he would.
He did this, Meredith.
Why should I believe that?
Why do you believe it?
Because he's your brother.
That's why he can do it.
It's why he could steal my toys
and pull my hair and call me names.
It's because I'm family.
It's why he thinks he
can get away with this.
You don't get it.
No. I don't.
I was raised as an only child.
And I'm historically
lousy at being a sister.
You're here right now.
That's good enough.
You don't remember?
No, I... Of course I remember.
I just wanted to double-check
with you, to be safe.
My lateral dissection,
it looked good, right?
I don't think I went
anywhere near the iliac vein.
You don't think...
Wilson, either you hit the
woman's iliac vein or you didn't.
Which one is it?
I don't...
So, what do we do now?
We run a CT... No.
I run a CT. You?
You just stand here and pray
that your patient isn't
bleeding to death right now.
So Robbins is tied
up. Should we wait?
No, yeah, we should get started.
No, no, no.
Well, Derek, we just
need to figure out...
I know you're trying to
figure out what's going on.
I know you've heard
some stories about Amelia.
I let you believe something.
I let you believe that...
Shepherd, you were pretty
clear when we spoke, so...
She's in recovery.
She works really hard at it.
She's been successful
in recovery, and...
This hospital should
have protected her.
This woman should
have protected her. And...
More importantly, I
should have protected her.
I didn't.
And I didn't because
I wanted her job.
I wanted my old job back.
So now we're here.
My fault.
Derek, why did you even...
She should stay
where she is, Owen.
She can do the job.
She is doing the job.
I couldn't do it any better.
How's his baby? Is
there any change?
No. She's good. She's
stable. Let me do it.
No, I have to tell him.
How? How, Alex? How do I
tell him that his wife is dead?
Where the hell is Herman?
She should have been here.
That's not helping! I was here.
Emily was my
responsibility, and I lost her.
So let me do it.
Placenta percreta is
very difficult to diagnose,
and in cases as severe
as Emily's, it's usually
insurmountable.
If your baby had come to term,
it's likely Emily would have died.
No.
Corey, this is what
you have to understand.
If I'd done the surgery we'd
planned, it's likely that, down the line,
we would have lost
Emily and your daughter.
Dr. Robbins did everything
within her power for your wife.
But she saved your baby's life.
Your baby is alive
because of her.
I'm not sure what that was about,
but it doesn't change anything.
Okay? I can't
do it. I won't do it.
You abandoned me.
You left me no choice
but to take that baby.
You made me...
Are...
Go ahead. Finish your thing.
Well, I, um...
Oh, no, no. Go on. Get it out.
Thank you.
What?
What's happening?
Yesterday, my doctors decided
I need some aggressive
radiation therapy immediately,
so that's where I
was today. It just
hit me a little harder
than I expected.
Everything I said
to that man was true.
You saved a baby
that we would have lost.
I watched you.
I logged in to the
hospital interface.
I monitored your
progress all day.
You made the right call.
You made all the right calls.
That's not... If
you had been here,
you would've... Mmm-mmm.
No. The only thing I could've done
is perform an intrauterine transfusion,
try to keep the baby in a little
longer, get her closer to term.
And maybe we could have
detected the percreta earlier,
but it doesn't mean we could've
done anything for her that you didn't do.
I want to know how to do it,
the intrauterine transfusion.
'Cause if there's a chance
that I could've saved that mom,
then I need to know how.
For the next time.
I can show you tomorrow.
Unless you're planning to have
a conversation with Chief Hunt.
Okay.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Go home.
It's gonna be fine.
Hey, I'm gonna be
here with you, okay?
Edwards, out. Yes, ma'am.
How was the CT?
She never made it to CT.
Wait... This was
your surgery, Wilson.
I'm gonna need you
to talk to the family.
Oh, my God.
She's dead?
She's dead? Oh, my
God. I never said that.
I remember doing
everything correctly. Wilson.
I even...
She's fine!
What?
I didn't say she was dead. I
said she never made it to CT.
You're... You're
screwing with me.
I didn't take her to CT
because I saw you do
it in the OR, Dr. Badass.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God! You have a problem!
No, you do. You
second-guess yourself.
This was the first in a
career full of surgeries
you will be doing alone.
Before too long, there won't be
anyone to catch you when you fall.
Your patients need to trust
that when you take them into
surgery, you know what you're doing.
Now, how can you
expect them to do that
if you don't even
trust yourself?
You are so mean.
I am, indeed.
Tell all your
little bitty friends.
Hey.
I heard about your
patient. You okay?
There was so much
blood, Jackson.
I mean, I know we
see it all the time, but...
Yeah. I just...
I didn't think it
was gonna stop.
And I know it can be scary.
But you and our
baby are just fine.
So do not worry, okay?
I'm not worried.
Are you worried?
All the time.
How can you not be?
You know how.
Right.
It's all in God's hands.
Yeah.
God, I don't know
how you can do that,
just write off all the
unanswered questions.
We don't get to
know the answers.
That's your answer.
I don't know why that
woman had to die tonight.
She exsanguinated. That's why.
Yeah, okay. But why?
Because all of it just...
All of it just happens.
You're really comfortable
with that answer?
Hmm?
Yeah.
See, I don't know
how you do that.
Is that you?
How's Hattie?
Thoracotomy. I had to resect
her entire right lower lobe.
Or she's gonna
need rib stabilization.
Norris, too. Ex-lap,
avulsed spleen.
Torres did a fasciotomy on his right
leg. I think it's gonna be okay, though.
We'll see if her lungs
don't shut down overnight.
We gave them the
best chance we could.
Yeah. We'll see.
We'll see.
Again, about last night...
Would you let it
go? I'm not mad.
Well, you sound like
someone who's mad.
Of course I'm mad.
You invited me to dinner, and
then you didn't come to the dinner,
at your own house!
I know. I told Derek it was a bad
idea. You didn't want to talk to Richard.
I wanted to have dinner,
with people and conversation.
I don't know anyone here.
I have no friends.
I do nothing at night.
I go to the grocery store,
and I buy sad
single-serving packets of food
for sad people who eat alone.
I was really
excited for pot roast.
And people!
I changed my outfit four times.
And, no, I didn't want
to talk to Webber,
but that wasn't gonna
stop me from coming,
because I'm really sick
of talking back to my TV,
and I'm scared
I'm gonna get a cat.
And I was really excited
that someone had
invited me to dinner.
So, yeah, I'm pretty mad.
Hattie's awake.
What?
What happened?
Mom, there was a
fire in your apartment.
You've had surgery,
but you're doing well.
Your husband saved your life.
He picked you up and
jumped out a window with you.
Well, that was stupid.
Oh, Norris, you saved my life.
I nearly killed you.
But that doctor, she promised.
Where is she, that woman doctor?
Oh, Dr. Shepherd.
She promised they'd save
you, and she was right.
Are you busy tonight?
Oh, well, I was going to
catch up on some reading,
some medical journals, but...
Oh, actually, no.
No, I am, um, not busy. Why?
This was Ellis' house.
This is where you grew up.
It was nicer before
Alex trashed it.
Oh, shut up. It
smelled like books.
Well, it smelled a lot
better when I lived here.
Now it just smells like Karev.
Wait. You lived here, too?
Everybody lived here.
I practically lived here
with George, right?
George was my ex-husband.
He was in their resident class.
O'Malley.
I'm sorry. Your husband?
Yeah, she does dudes, too.
True. I did him once.
True.
She did.
I didn't do him.
I did do George, though, once.
Yeah, yeah. Oh, God.
Yeah, yeah. We're
all related through sex.
We all have sexual
relations. That is horribly weird.
Hi.
It's hard to give
second chances.
I probably should've
called first, but...
Someone told me to go home,
and I wasn't really
sure where I should go.
See? Everyone lives here.
Beer's in the fridge.
Hard stuff's on the counter.
Thank you.
It's even harder
to ask for them.
A chance to do it again,
knowing what you know now,
what you've learned,
a chance to do it
completely differently.
You okay?
I was at a meeting.
I'm moving out.
Tomorrow.
I'm sorry.
I'm just so sorry.
Don't, Derek. Don't even bother.
I didn't mean to hurt you.
I'm sure you didn't.
I'm sure you didn't
even think about me.
You saw an opening,
and you took it.
I have always wanted to
protect you ever since Dad died.
I didn't want to. I'm sure
you didn't want me to.
But I promised.
Shh.
Then you came up
here, and I realized
I didn't have to worry anymore.
You were okay. You were fine.
You were more than fine. You could
take care of yourself now,
and I didn't need to anymore.
I needed you today.
A chance to right our wrongs,
to try and correct
our mistakes...
I don't know who I am anymore.
Not anybody I ever thought
I'd be.
I try and make the right
choices for Meredith,
the kids, you.
And, um...
I'm angry all the time.
I'm miserable, and I don't
know what to do with it.
All I do is hurt people.
The last people I
want to hurt, and I just...
I just can't get control of it.
I don't know what to do anymore.
I know how you feel.
We call it rock bottom.
A chance to try and start over
from scratch.