One hundred and forty patients, 27
admissions, has to be a shift record.
I got a record. There's a guy in Exam 4
that swallowed 50 hot dogs in 19 minutes.
- Shift record, as in "shift over."
- Who has Pelar now?
- Which one's that?
- Kidney stone in 7, since this morning.
I admitted him to Urology.
- I just need a diet order.
- Two grams sodium.
Give me the beer. PABLO:
No. This is my personal property!
- Give me the beer!
- Two grams sodium in 7.
- I need help with a Foley.
- It's personal property!
What room? HALEH: Right here!
- No!
- What's the problem?
He's drunk, combative, and he
won't give up his beer! Give me...
- Is it open?
- Oh, Abby, I need help!
I need to pee!
- Sorry. I just punched out.
- That's gonna cost you.
Where's Mark? Mark
Greene, your Attending.
I think he quit.
Silvadene and dress
the second-degree areas.
Kerry, have you seen Mark?
Elizabeth, I need you
to see a post-op seroma.
Can I put my baby
down? Where's Mark?
- Try Curtain 3. TAKATA:
No urine in the last hour.
Bolus a liter of Ringer's.
Call for a renal consult.
Dr. Weaver? X-ray's behind, and
my wrist fracture wants to leave AMA.
Jing-Mei, you're Chief Resident.
Don't check with me on every patient.
You have to learn to
keep things flowing.
We don't have time for
ones we can move quickly.
Turf and admit, treat and street.
- Mark!
Bag him. Prep the
neck, 1 percent with epi.
- What do you think you're doing?
- We got jammed.
You said to meet
in the parking lot.
Drunk boating accident, busted
his face. We need to crike him.
This is exactly why we
need a weekend nanny.
- A weekday nanny's bad enough.
- It doesn't make us bad parents.
I just want to
raise our children.
Then be home when you say
you'll be home. I'm an hour late.
- Sats are down to 84.
- Introducer needle. Five more minutes.
Finish the procedure, give it to a
Resident and meet me upstairs.
You're in trouble, doc.
You're being stubborn.
- I'm not.
You have 6 weeks on your Residency.
You don't have a job elsewhere.
You know she's
looking for an Attending.
- She should ask me.
- You're being stubborn.
I don't think I'm being...
- Abby!
Hey, can you try for a line on Barney
before you go? He's back with cellulitis.
- I'm off.
- Conni said you found a vein last time.
- But I'm off.
- He's asking for you.
I'm off. I'm off. I'm
gone. I'm out of here.
- Someplace important to be?
- Home. I have to be back here at 7.
- Have a good night.
- See you tomorrow.
Hey!
Talk to Weaver.
How did it sting you in there?
- What?
- A bee flew in his Coke.
Can I ask you a question?
Airway's clear, no
wheezing. 50 of Benadryl, p.o.
Better get that new
Attending in here, huh?
Hey, Haleh, I need a visual
acuity on the foreign body in 8.
- In a minute.
- Are you actively recruiting?
Is it word of mouth?
Are you headhunting?
Running a classified
in the annals.
Unresponsive initially.
- What's the half-life of glyburide?
- Ten hours. Overdose?
- Sixty milligrams.
- Admit him.
The hypoglycemia
lasts for over a day.
- Because I was thinking about applying.
- For Attending?
- It is my next step.
- Oh, yeah. Right. Of course.
You don't sound enthusiastic.
We were hoping for someone at
least five years post-Residency.
- But, yeah, certainly apply.
- Right.
In case you can't find anybody better.
- John!
John! Can you clear
a toe lac in Curtain 2?
- I'm off.
- He's been waiting five hours.
- I can't get to it. We need the bed.
- I'm meeting my parents for dinner.
- You can dispo him in 15 minutes.
- I've done my share of dispos today.
- For me?
- Sorry. Give it to Malucci.
Malucci's not here for another hour.
Cleo is stuck with pulmonary edema.
I'm babysitting four ICU
players. We're down two nurses.
And the rack is overflowing. Please?
If you could just take one easy patient.
That's all I'm asking.
- All right. One patient.
- Thank you.
Wait. What room?
We were unloading the volcano.
I dropped the base on my foot
between the lift and the platform.
- Volcano?
- The show ends...
with this big volcano explosion
with real live lava and steam and crap.
- Not real lava.
- No, but it's real-looking lava, though.
- This is more than just a cut.
- The damn thing almost sliced my toe off.
Yeah. It was just hanging there
like a big noodle or something.
Have to do a digital block, have to wait
for X-ray, have to sew a two-layer repair.
- You signed up for it.
- This'll take more than an hour.
Hurry up. Maybe we can
catch the end of the show.
- The guys are opening for Metallica.
- Guys?
- We're roadies for Touching Wood.
- All right! What's the name of the song?
- "Rapture Bitch."
- I like that song.
It's not even their best song.
I'll numb the two nerves in
your toe, and then I'll wash it out.
Then we'll take
you for an x-ray.
- You want to wait outside?
- No, I'm cool.
That happens.
Take his set of vitals. Run in
a liter of saline if he's postural.
Carter, he's not breathing.
What?
The surgery
caused the infection?
It may have contributed, yes. But
because of his compromised state...
he wasn't able to fight off the infection
even with appropriate antibiotics.
I told him not to drink so much.
If you'd like to go in and see
him, I'll be in there in a minute.
- Jacy, Jacy, could you take her?
- Oh, of course. This way.
Sorry. He started seizing. I had to
give him Dilantin and get him to CT.
- We are not doing this anymore!
- What?
No more weekend shifts that
are even close to one another.
We got jammed. Four
hours should've been enough.
I'm not explaining to a
woman why her son died...
while my baby is
screaming in her face!
- Okay.
- I'm not!
I said, okay.
She missed her nap.
Get her home. Give her 4
more ounces and put her down.
- Is the milk defrosted?
- Yes.
But you'll have to take
another out for tonight.
Okay. I got it,
I got it, I got it.
Is that our homeless guy?
- Post-op bacteremia. He died of sepsis.
- He has a mother?
Apparently, we
all have a mother!
Yes, yes. She's a little cranky.
That's all right. You'll be all right.
- Give me some cricoid pressure.
- Sats are down to 90.
All right, I'm in. Bag
him. What did you take?
I didn't take anything.
- Him. What did he take? Drugs? Alcohol?
- I don't know.
Some beer, some pot,
some Georgia Homeboy.
- That liquid G?
- Yeah.
Call for a vent, B.A.L.
and tox screen. Cleo!
Take this guy. Respiratory
arrest from a GHB overdose.
- I can't.
- I'm off duty.
- I have the stampede.
- What stampede?
Guitar player collapsed at a rock
concert. The crowd just mobbed the stage.
- Where? MALIK:
At the United Center.
No way. Metallica or us?
- Any head injury?
- Just slumped to the floor.
- History of seizures?
- Girlfriend might know.
- Okay, ask her.
- Have an intubation from the concert?
Apneic on scene. Pupils
are equal and reactive.
Carter tubed his friend. He
thinks they mixed alcohol with GHB.
- BP's 122/78.
- Doctor, three crush injuries rolling in.
I'll be right there. Blood
gas, B.A.L. and tox screen.
And have Carter follow
their labs together.
There's a guy in a
ponytail, says he knows you.
- Take a name. Make him wait.
- BP, 100/60. Pulse, 110.
Complains of abdominal pains, no LOC.
Contusions to the trunk and extremities.
- His family coming in with him?
- No, he was by himself, but it was crazy.
Who brings a 7-year-old
to a heavy-metal concert?
One, two, three.
All right, portable C-spine, chest
and pelvis. Trauma panel, dip a urine.
What's his name? Kevin, I'm Dr. Finch.
Do you know your phone number?
- I can't breathe.
- We'll help you.
- They were pushing.
- Good breath sounds.
I know, but you're safe now.
Epigastric tenderness.
No rebound or guarding.
Sinus tach at 112.
- Is there a Dr. Benton here?
- Me.
A unit called in from St. Rafe's. An ER
doc thinks he's got your kid over there.
What?
Deaf, 3 or 4, Reece Benton
written inside his jacket.
- He okay?
- They're looking for a parent.
- Where's Carla?
- Who's Carla?
- His mother.
- I don't know.
Dispatch asked me to
see if I could find you.
Lily, get another
surgeon. Peter, go.
- What sort of look you going for here?
- Hey.
- Bought a TV?
- Yep.
Anything else?
Sony PlayStation.
I was thinking more along the lines
of furniture. You know, table, chairs...
- bed.
- I got an aquarium.
Yes, I see.
- Couldn't get a bigger one, huh?
- The next size up was pretty expensive.
- I thought we were gonna go out to eat.
- I'm still hungry. Want to play?
- I don't think so.
- We can hunt zombies together.
Couldn't we just
reason with them?
- I think I'm just gonna go home.
- No, no. Stay.
No, no. Zombies and a
pizza isn't really my thing.
You're right. Let's go.
I agreed to suture a toe
lac, now I got three patients.
Those two are the same
guy. Order the same stuff.
- Get Chen.
- She has a head trauma.
I don't care. Get her.
I'm handing this off.
He might be famous one day.
You can say you helped save his life.
We're in the Emergency
department. Ask for Dr. Finch.
It's extension 7614.
- I'm trying to be gentle.
- But it hurts.
What happened to Peter?
- Personal emergency.
This is Kevin, crushed against
the stage at a Metallica concert.
Hello, Kevin. Aren't you a
little young for Metallica?
They didn't start yet. It
was the warm-up group.
We're trying to track
down his parents.
Got the answering machine.
Any evidence of bleeding?
No. Liver and spleen are intact, but
there's moderate epigastric tenderness.
Could be an abdominal-wall injury,
small-bowel perf, a bruised pancreas.
- Want to get a CT?
- And serial exams.
We'll see if anything declares itself.
- Kevin? Oh, my God!
Kevin, I'm so sorry.
- You let go of my hand.
- I tried to hold on. I'm sorry.
- Is he okay?
- Who are you?
Marla. I'm his babysitter.
His parents let you take
him to rock concerts?
My boyfriend came over with
tickets. He was gonna be in bed by 11.
Do you have a number for them?
- Did you call it?
- I wanted to find Kevin first.
You found him.
Draw up etomidate,
sux and grab Surgery.
- That our last crush victim?
- I don't know, I just got here.
Multiple rib fractures,
needs chest tubes.
Curtain 3. Get out
of those gym clothes.
- Chief, I just got here.
- Come to work dressed properly.
Dr. Weaver?
Yosh, I need 100 of
mannitol in Exam 4 right away.
- Do you have a minute?
- No.
You're not thrilled to see
me. I screwed up last...
I'm not interested in
a private investigator.
- Frank, still waiting on that head CT.
- Just went down.
How long? FRANK: Who knows?
- Well, get Radiology on the phone.
- I found her.
There's a new database for adopted
children looking for their birth parents.
I ran a couple of old
clients through, and you hit.
I double-checked this
time. It's your mother.
Anyway, if you're
interested, it's 400 bucks.
My new cell's on there.
- Hi, doc.
- Hey, you still here?
- He never leaves.
- And you do?
Only because you
take so long to move.
You know them?
We met at lunch.
Is the smoke gonna bother you?
- No.
- Hi, Luka.
- Hey.
Delirium tremens, right? - Yeah.
Abby?
- Diet Coke and a couple menus, please.
- We stop serving at 10.
- It's, like, 10:02.
- I'm sorry.
I'm starving.
- Do you have appetizers or anything?
- He may not have thrown out the soup.
- What is it?
- Like a potato cream.
Sure. That's fine.
- All right.
- Thanks.
Anyone here you don't know?
You want me to put
him on line for a unit bed?
He'll be extubated by
the time that he gets one.
- Who is that?
- His girlfriend, I think.
I'll find out what's going on.
Yeah. Okay. Can you just tell them
that John is running a little bit late?
Be mellow. It's good.
He's all good, okay?
- Tell her he's all good.
- He's all good.
- I saw him stop breathing.
- We're helping him breathe.
- You don't just stop breathing.
- It's an overdose of alcohol and GHB.
- He'll wake up in a few hours.
- Are those blood stains?
No. Are you okay?
My asthma gets worse
when I get stressed out.
- Let's take a look at you.
- I need that back.
Take a seat right here.
I'm gonna need a good, deep
breath through your mouth.
- Those are blood stains.
- They're not.
- There's a body up there.
- Can you be quiet?
- You have a history of heart murmur?
- No. Just asthma.
- You on something?
- A little acid.
- I'm not talking to you.
- No. I don't do drugs anymore.
- Any fever? Chills?
- Is something wrong?
Hey, don't touch that.
Haleh, find her an open room. Have
somebody work her up for endocarditis.
Someone? As in you?
I'm Dr. Benton. My son is a
patient. The cops brought me here.
No. Three waiting for
Med/Surg. What's the name?
Reece Benton. He's
4 years old. He's deaf.
Right. Have a seat, please.
Okay. Yeah. I'm
holding here. Yes.
Reece. What happened?
Were you in a car?
Did you hurt your head?
- Can I help you?
- I'm his father. He lose consciousness?
- Keep that covered.
- Was he in his car seat?
- You have to talk to the doctor.
- Where's his mom?
You're busy. Tell
me where she is.
Dr. Benton? Julia Scoft.
So the police found you.
One of the nurses thought that there
was a Benton at County with a deaf son.
- What happened?
- It was a single MVA.
- Where's Carla?
- Can he understand me?
- Was Carla or Roger driving?
- Your wife swerved...
She's not my wife.
- Oh, she isn't?
- No, no. We have shared custody.
Well, does she have a
husband or a close relative?
- Why? What's her status?
- I really need to speak to a relative.
How many people died here today?
- I don't know.
- You're afraid to tell me.
- I honestly don't know.
This place is full
of dead people.
Have you had any
teeth pulled recently?
- No. Why?
- Any infections?
- My piercing's been bothering me.
- Oh, it's so dope.
Your piercing?
- Where is that?
- Show him!
No!
- Melody...
- Harmony.
I think that you might have bacteria in
your bloodstream infecting your heart.
It's important that we locate
the source so we can treat it.
Oh.
Did you do that yourself?
- No. My friend Fiona.
- How long has it been like that?
Three months. She said it would
take time for the swelling to go down.
Definitely infected, and
I'm gonna have to drain it.
No! Don't drain her! Don't
let them drain you, Harmony!
- Get her off!
- Chill out, you're peaking!
Doctor! HARMONY: Dianna!
Dianna!
- Dianna!
- Oh...
Dianna, are you okay?
Ow.
I'll make a new chart.
What made you become a nurse?
I can't remember.
Ever see anything like this?
- How long has it been like that?
- Two, three years.
- You should get that looked at.
- So look!
By a doctor. You should
ask Luka. He's good with pus.
Cigarette?
- No, thanks.
- You sure?
Yeah. I'm trying to quit.
Wanna meet for breakfast
tomorrow? We could do it early.
Hey, coz! What
about my toe? I'm first!
Next time you're
back in town, then.
I'm sorry, Dad.
I'm sorry too,
Dad. I'm so sorry.
How long do you have
to fix it before it falls off?
Dave, I need you. Suture
his toe. He's already blocked.
I can't help you. I got
a chest pain rolling up.
Where the hell is Chen?
- Somebody go get me Chen!
- Are you talking to me?
Yes, actually. Can you
find her for me, please?
- Dr. Carter, Pelar is finally going up.
- Who?
- The kidney stone, to Urology.
- Good for Urology.
Well, Abby says she gave
him gent, but it wasn't charted.
- So should I give him a dose?
- Not if she gave him one.
- Then what do I do?
- Call her.
She's not at home.
- Call her cell.
- You got her number?
You know what?
I need to yell at her anyway.
Hello?
- Having fun?
- Carter?
Are you out having a good time?
No, not exactly.
What are you doing?
I am setting a wrist
on an "LSDiva."
You're working?
Someone talked me into coming
back and begging Weaver...
and I got sucked back
in to the ER vortex.
I didn't tell you to
talk to her tonight.
- You give gent to the kidney stone in 4?
- No.
- Malik said you did.
- No. That was the gall-bladder guy.
- I thought you had an early shift.
- I do. Luka dragged me to this bar.
So much for quitting.
- Oh, hey.
- What?
- Who is that?
- It's Carter.
- Is that Luka?
- Can you hang on a second?
Things are dying down.
I'm going to Doc Magoo's.
Things aren't dying down.
I've got five patients. I'm not on.
Then sign out. Go home.
I gotta go.
- You don't need to hang up for me.
- It was about a patient.
- You ready to go?
- If you want.
- Yeah, Luka, I want.
- Fine.
What? Now you're mad?
Finish your cigarette.
I'll pay the bill.
Excuse me. I'm looking
for Carla McGrath.
Roger.
I'm sorry, man.
- Is that her?
- Yeah.
- Do I go in, or what?
- The doctor will be right back.
What's he gonna tell me?
You should just wait.
Peter, come on.
What's he gonna tell me?
She came in without a blood pressure.
They worked on her for over an hour...
but she had massive internal
bleeding, and it was too severe to repair.
Was she awake?
No. She was...
There was a faint
pulse in the field...
but she was pretty
much gone on impact.
We were supposed to go
to Wisconsin this weekend...
but I had to work last-minute.
- You sure Reece is okay?
- Yeah, yeah. He cut his head, but...
Mr. McGrath? Dr. Scoft. I
was the treating physician.
- I'm here if you have any questions.
- Can I see her?
Of course.
I'm right here if you need me.
Orderly to Central Supply.
Orderly, please report
to Central Supply.
We had to trim a little hair.
The doctor will
be with you shortly.
Mom.
Reece.
Mommy went away. She's gone.
Mommy was hurt very badly.
I can't.
She was...
She was bleeding.
The doctor...
Mommy went bye-bye.
She went to be with God.
I can't.
She's sleeping.
She's sleeping forever.
Mom.
I can't.
She won't wake up.
Sometimes people can't wake up.
Reece. Reece, Reece.
Mommy died.
Mommy's dead.
No response to Narcan.
BP's 108/76. Pulse, 110.
- Young for chest pain.
- He was complaining all day long.
- Thought it was a meatball sandwich.
- On my count. One, two, three.
Any history of early heart
disease in your family?
Our grandmother had diabetes.
CBC, chem panel, 12-lead
and a portable chest.
- What's his name?
- Paul.
- Paul, can you hear me?
- Pulse ox, 98.
Well, no evidence of
trauma. He just collapsed?
He's been pushing himself hard.
His first solo show opens Monday.
I haven't seen him
sleep the whole week.
Does your brother do drugs?
- No, I don't think so.
- Are you sure?
It's the first time I've seen
him since he moved to Chicago.
- All right. Let's get a tox screen.
- Here's your EKG.
I don't think he would.
He's an artist, but that...
ST elevations are off the
charts. He's having a major MI.
What? MALUCCI: Heart attack.
- He's 27.
- It happens with stimulants.
- Cocaine can constrict the arteries.
- Oh, God!
- 40 of tenecteplase. Gotta bust the clot.
- I need Attending to order thrombolytics.
- Let's go!
- You need to run this by Chen or Weaver.
- Get one of them!
- Shooting.
Pressure's dropping
to 70/30. Pulse is 130.
Bolus 500 of saline.
Halsted clamp.
You got bleeders popping
up like prairie dogs.
Pediatric pancreatic transection.
Splenic vessels won't separate.
How old? CORDAY: Seven.
You're not taking the spleen?
Not if I don't
have to. 4-0 Vicryl.
How much blood loss?
Over a liter.
- Dr. Corday?
- What?
Taching at 140. CORDAY:
Must've torn the splenic vein.
- Side-biting clamp.
- Dr. Corday.
- What?
- You're leaking.
Oh, damn!
- Is that breast milk?
- I should have pumped.
Is it sterile?
No, you're
contaminated. Scrub out.
- Fresh gown, fresh gloves.
- It's gonna leak again. Go pump.
Hang a unit of packed cells.
- Now!
Okay!
What the hell does the
guy want, a suite at the Ritz?
His manager freaked out
when I said we had to move him.
Excuse me. I thought this
guy wasn't even famous yet.
It's not about fame, jerk-off.
Jim, can we clear this
whole area here? Thank you.
- So, what do you want me to do?
- Find an open telemetry bed.
- You gave the last one to his friend.
- All right. Any open exam room.
- Fascist.
- Freak.
- Geek.
- Goof.
What?
Okay. Where were we?
- Does it take this long to fix a toe?
- When your buddies come in OD'd, yeah.
Hey, that's not my fault.
- Saying it's mine?
- You need more doctors or something.
Doctor, this is Vince
Newberry's mom.
- Who?
- The OD you sent to telemetry.
- You don't remember?
- I see lots of patients.
- He almost died.
- I saved him.
- Do you know my name?
- Hi, Mrs. Newberry.
- What kind of doctor are you?
- Why don't we take a step over here?
- I'm still here!
- I'm Dr. Carter. I treated your son.
- I heard he stopped breathing.
- For a moment.
We put a tube in his throat, a machine's
been breathing for him for a few hours.
- Is he in a coma?
- Not exactly. He should wake up soon.
- It's that liquid G junk, isn't it?
- Along with alcohol, yes.
I told him to stay
away from that stuff.
It can be dangerous.
- Where is he?
- Your... Your nose...
- What?
- Your nose is bleeding.
- Oh, damn! Not again.
- Take a seat right here.
Give it a good pinch.
You know, every time I get
worried, it gushes like a fountain.
Shouldn't I be there?
He's having a heart attack.
You have to give the
doctor room to work.
- Nitro's going to 10 mics.
- Titrate to a systolic of 100.
- Do you need help, Dave?
- One 27-year-old with acute MI.
I'm thinking cocaine.
We're ready to push TNK.
- Hold on. Did you get a tox screen?
- I sent one.
He's killing off myocardial
cells while we wait.
- Any recent surgery?
- No.
- Bleeding disorder?
- Clots well at blood draw sites.
- X-ray's clear.
- Dr. Chen.
- PCO2 and your subdural's up to 30.
- Oh, okay.
Increase the ACU to 16
and drop him to 80 percent.
- So, what about the cath lab?
- It takes them two hours to get in.
- Where's Weaver?
- I can't find her.
- Did you page her?
- Yeah.
You want to wait
for him to arrest?
Okay. Do it.
- How about ReoPro?
- If Cardiology takes him for stenting.
Won't need it if we lyse the thrombus.
- Doc, the tox screen.
- Cocaine, right?
- Negative for cocaine and amphetamines.
He could've just taken them.
Haven't had time to show up.
- Did you do a lipid panel?
- No, but we could add it on.
- We've got V-tach.
- Charge the paddles.
- No pulse. Starting compressions.
- Charge to 200. Push an amp of epi.
It's too early for a
reperfusion arrhythmia.
Get ready to intubate. Clear.
- Still V-tach.
- Charge to 300. Page Weaver again.
Clear!
I'm taking a cab.
- Where did you go?
- I was waiting for you outside.
I thought you were
coming back in. I...
Bye-bye.
Sorry. That guy's father got diagnosed
with prostate cancer last month.
- He was asking about treatment options.
- Go talk to him.
- He's calling tomorrow.
- I'm fine.
Luka, you forgot
your credit card.
- Thanks.
- The last two were on the house.
- Oh, no. How much?
- Our treat.
We want to make sure
you're gonna come back.
- Here. For you.
- Thank you. Good night.
- Night.
- Nice meeting you.
Yeah.
- Could you be a little bit more rude?
- Could you be more friendly?
- I'm glad one of us is.
- Go back inside. Cure cancer for the U.N.
- Where are you going?
- Taking the El.
- Still V-fib.
- 100 of lidocaine. Charge again to 360.
Good breath sounds.
- There you are.
- Clear!
- I am not staying.
I'm going to pack
this woman's nose...
and then you are gonna
take the rest of these misfits.
You're sure there
wasn't GI bleeding?
Stool was guaiac negative.
No contraindications.
- Clear!
- What happened?
- Fatal MI. Probably drug-related.
- Are you sure? He looks Marfanoid.
- What?
- Marfan syndrome.
Tall stature, pectus
excavatum, loose joints.
- You got a history.
- I did. Brother didn't say anything.
- He might not know.
- They have weak connective tissue.
- Keep going.
- He's dissecting.
- Try amiodarone. Might get a rhythm.
- We gave tenecteplase.
- What?
- He had ST elevation.
Thrombolytics to
an aortic dissection?
- We didn't know it was a dissection!
- He's bleeding into his chest.
- Thoracotomy tray.
- No! He'll bleed all over the floor.
We gotta do something.
O-neg cryo and FFP.
We can do a chest tube to confirm
the hemothorax and start a line.
Okay, let's go! Prep the chest.
I was trying to have
fun. Is that a crime?
No. Go have fun.
If I can be left waiting in the street,
I can certainly walk home by myself.
Why do you make a big
problem out of everything?
- Like you have an insect in your anus.
- Hey, it's "bug up my ass," Luka.
"Bug up my ass." If you're gonna
insult me, at least get the words right.
- How's this? Stop being such a bitch.
- Okay, fine. As soon as you grow up.
You're so mature. You don't
even know what you want.
Yes, I do. I want to go home.
You're like the schoolgirl who can
have any boy and treats them like crap.
Why don't you just call me
a whore and get it over with?
I'm tired of it. You're not that
pretty. You're not that special.
I'm pretty enough
in the dark, aren't I?
You're never happy. I don't think
you're capable of being happy.
Six months ago, you
didn't care if I was happy.
If you're not depressed,
you're just angry.
And you're married to a ghost.
- At least I treat you with respect.
- Oh, I know. You're a saint.
- Thora-Seal.
- I can't thread the guide wire.
Rotate the bevel 90 degrees.
Damn it! CHEN: No good.
- Looks like his entire blood volume.
- How much O-neg do we have?
- Third and fourth unit are up.
- Get another four! We need that FFP!
- Where is Weaver?
- We've been paging her for 15 minutes.
- Doc Magoo's.
- What?
She said something about
going to Doc Magoo's.
Right. I know. You're always
so good, and I'm so bad.
- I'm sick of being patient.
- I'm a mess, you're so understanding.
- And I'm a burden.
- Carter, your mother, your moods...
- Why don't you just break up with me?
- I think you want me to.
If I'm such a horrible person, how
could you possibly want to be with me?
I don't know how to be
with you or help you...
I don't want help.
I don't want to be pitied.
I don't want to be saved.
Okay.
- Okay. I give up.
- Okay?
What does that mean?
What does that
mean? Why don't you...
I'm done! I'm done,
okay? Carter can have you.
Okay.
Okay. The catheter is passing.
- Any pulse with compression?
- Weak one.
- Got the plasma. CHEN:
Yeah. Run it in here.
- Are we cracking him or not?
- He can't clot. He'll exsanguinate.
He already has.
- Please get Weaver, John.
- Haleh, can you page her again?
If we're gonna try
this, we gotta do it now.
I am not opening his chest without
Weaver. Could you get her? Now?
Okay. Go ahead, prep. 4-0 silk.
- We can't wait.
- Wait!
- Slow down, Doogie!
- He's got a tube in his throat!
You were gonna draw a blood gas.
- Is that his doctor?
- Yes.
We need a private room!
Dr. Weaver?
- Wait. Where are you?
- Chest-tube output is 4 liters.
Ruptured aortic dissection.
We gave 40 of tenecteplase.
Put the scalpel down.
He's had cryoprecipitate,
4 units FFP.
- He might clot.
- He'll keep lysing the thrombin.
Gotta open the
chest to fix the defect.
It's a proximal lesion.
Can't cross-clamp.
- Can we try anything else?
- Stop compressions.
You killed him.
- Almost done, okay?
- One more.
One more. Hey.
You okay, Reece? Doctor
will make it better. Right?
I know. Mom's gone.
Finished. I'll have the nurse
dress it, and then you're free to go.
All right, thanks. I can
remove the suture, right?
In seven days.
Listen, they're transferring
her to the morgue till morning.
I've gotta find a funeral home.
- You call the parents?
- Yeah, they're on their way.
- Listen, Roger, tell them that I'm...
- It's cool.
Can you take him tonight?
I'm gonna have to stay.
Yeah. I was going to anyway.
Right, right. Thanks.
Reece, you have to go with
your father tonight, okay?
But I'll see you tomorrow...
or the next day, okay?
I love you too.
You don't know what
Marfan's looks like?
He's an artist. His brother said he
was up all week. I was thinking cocaine.
Did you check the blood
pressures in both arms?
- I don't think so.
- Did you or didn't you?
No.
You didn't recognize the
widened mediastinum?
Not until after he arrested.
Apical-capping tracheal shift to
the right is classic for a dissection.
I was told that it was clear.
- I meant, no hemothorax.
- Wait a minute.
You didn't look at the x-ray before
you signed off on thrombolytics?
Jing-Mei.
Jing-Mei?
- No. I should have.
- Yeah. You should have!
Look, you didn't answer your page.
We had to make a quick decision.
That's your job! Make quick decisions
based on the information available.
You had the right information.
You didn't bother to look at it.
- You've never made a bad call?
- Not as stupid and lethal as this one.
Then show up and make it
yourself. We paged you three times!
In a perfect world,
Dr. Malucci...
I wouldn't subject any
patients to your care.
If you knew your ass from your
elbow, or even gave a damn...
- I do give a damn. I do give a damn.
- This man might still be alive!
He dissected into his coronaries. He'd
probably never survive surgery anyway.
Well, we'll never
know that, will we?
The rest of the family should be
screened. I'll talk to the brother.
Wait. Dave, I'll do it.
- No. I will.
No one talks to
anyone about this case.
Is that clear?
- Is that clear?
- Yes.
Ice that back, Carter.
- Get up and help me! Mark!
- What?
Get up and help me!
There's poop all over the
bassinet. It's running down her legs.
- You didn't tighten the bloody diaper!
- God! What time is it?
- Now!
- Okay, okay, okay.
- I heard her crying from downstairs!
- I'm sorry. I must have passed out.
- I told you to double up!
- I thought I did.
- Look at this!
- Calm down. It's not fatal.
Yeah, okay! You take
her! I'll run her bath.
Why don't you just go back to
bed, and I'll take care of her?
Don't make me the bitch just because
you can't follow simple instructions!
- I was just offering to take care of it.
- Splendid job you've done of it so far!
Fine. You take care of it.
I've got a shift in three hours.
What do you think I'll be doing in
three hours? I'm the feeding trough!
- If I could breast-feed, I would.
- Oh, great. Great! You take it!
Take it all! The sore nipples,
the rashes, the hemorrhoids...
the leaking in your trauma
gown, the public humiliation...
sleep deprivation, the incontinence,
for goodness' sake. It's all yours!
There you go.
Watch out for that
volcano next time.
Malik, can you dress that
toe and fit him for a cast shoe?
Sorry, I'm off.
Can I help you?
Did anyone turn in a pager?
No. I don't think so.
Carter, I saw your
lady with the nosebleed.
I'm scheduling her for
a septoplasty next week.
- She had a defect?
- That you could drive a truck through.
I guess 2 grams of
coke a day will do that.
- Nap note?
- I was supposed to be off last night.
You're not in Surgery.
Don't punish yourself. Go.
No. I'm on at noon. I'm
just gonna go pass out.
Bad idea. You
know what they say:
"The longer you stay,
the longer you stay."
Conni, I need you to dress
a toe for me in Curtain 2.
- After my break.
- Yeah, whenever.
Hey.
Reece, what's wrong?
Bad dreams?
You want to sleep here?
Come on.
Okay. It's okay. It's okay.