Previously, on
"The Resident"...
He is using
while he's working,
- and that's a problem.
- How much did you scam
- the taxpayers for?
- Wait, I remember: One billion dollars,
that you used to finance
your campaign for governor.
Find me every ounce of dirt
on that Dr. Bell.
I'm gonna destroy him.
Claire avoided American
health care and it killed her.
It was my fault.
I should have
seen the signs earlier.
Even if you had, it would
probably have been too late.
And maybe we could grab a drink?
That sounds like
just what I need.
You cool with them together?
Eh, she can do better.
We are here tonight
to honor someone who
has done more for Chastain
than perhaps
any other one person.
He has saved more lives
than can possibly be counted.
For someone who hates
getting dressed up,
you look...
It's not actually
the dressing up I mind,
it's all the pointless
small talk and forced smiling.
Well,
your dad seems right at home.
Like a pig in... mud.
Here to present the award
for a lifetime
of service to Dr. Bell
is yet another
powerhouse surgeon
and our own beloved CEO,
Dr. Kit Voss.
Thank you, Marshall.
I'm very happy to be here
tonight to present this award.
I think you all know that
my admiration for Randolph Bell
goes far beyond
his skill as a surgeon,
his dedication as a doctor,
and his kindness
as a human being.
It is my great honor to present
the Lifetime of Service Award
to Dr. Randolph Bell.
Dr. Randolph Bell,
you've been served.
*THE RESIDENT*
Season 06  Episode 08
Episode Title: "The Better Part of Valor"
Aired on: November 15, 2022.
Pharmacy,
dial 2219. Pharmacy, 2219.
I'm not sure coffee
at the crack of dawn
counts as a romantic date
for most people,
but it sure does hit the spot
for an ER doctor.
Want to grab dinner tonight?
We could try that new Thai
place in In man Park.
You mean like a real date?
- Mm-hmm.
- Hell yeah.
Did you find someone
to watch Gigi?
Oh, I'll get right on that.
What do we have?
13-year-old male,
Malik Sheridan,
possible overdose.
Unknown substance,
likely opioids.
Barely a pulse
when we got to him.
13? Damn it.
Narcan, four milligrams,
intranasal given.
Multiple doses epinephrine.
Heart rate's improved,
but he's remained unresponsive.
Attempted intubation
but has a difficult airway.
Hypercarbic arrest.
How long has he been out?
At least 20 minutes.
His friend called 911.
- Trauma room nine.
- What's your name?
- Tally.
- Tally, I'm Dr. Hawkins.
What did Malik take?
I don't know.
- A pill.
- What kind of pill?
Conrad,
his breathing is shallow.
Let's move him
so we can intubate.
- Good.
- On my count, one, two,
- three.
- Three.
He's gonna
arrest again if we don't
- get him breathing better.
- Let's try drive down
the CO2.
Pupils still pinpoint.
Let's give him another dose
of Narcan and start a drip.
Pushing Narcan now.
He hasn't
flinched since he got here.
- Mac 3, to me.
- On it. Hundley?
Go, got it.
Intubating now.
Good bilateral breath sounds.
Get him on the vent.
Is he gonna wake up?
We're going to do
everything we can
to make sure that happens.
Tally, where'd
the pill come from?
This much Narcan should have
pulled him out of this.
Are we missing something?
Cerebral edema?
I hope not.
Tally, what time...
Go, I got him.
Can I sit down?
He's gonna be so mad.
I shouldn't have called 911.
When his parents find out...
You probably saved his life.
Tally, the pill.
Did you see him take it?
Do you know where he got it?
Amir had it.
Malik's older brother.
He plays football,
but he hurt his back a while ago.
He got a lot of pills
from the doctor.
Careful.
I don't think this pill
is from the doctor.
We got to wash those hands.
Even a small amount on your skin
could be dangerous.
He's stable.
Percocet.
Definitely counterfeit.
Probably fentanyl.
Can you get this tested, fast?
We've got fentanyl test strips
up front.
I'll have results
in five minutes.
Full tox will
take a couple hours.
Tally, we need to call
Malik's parents right now.
Yeah, and we need to find Amir.
These pills
are really dangerous.
If your friends have more,
we got to find them.
You don't want anyone else
to get hurt, do you?
Malik's phone.
The password is 61309.
My birthday.
I'm not saying
cancel the deposition,
but maybe just postpone it
until we have more information.
I've been deposed
a thousand times.
I'm more worried about Leela.
'Cause the first time
can be a little rattling.
Leela's not the one being sued.
It's you in the line of fire.
The case isn't even close.
I've gone through all the records.
There's nothing.
Claire Williams' sepsis
was so far along
that even if the kidney stones
hadn't masked it,
we couldn't have saved her.
You know that's not
what this is really about.
I know. You think
it's about the governor
and revenge for my performance
at his little press ambush.
It's definitely the governor.
And this lawyer, Costican...
I heard he was the governor's
fraternity brother.
And a big campaign donor.
I can handle him.
He's a snake.
He wants to embarrass you.
Why else would they serve you
a subpoena on stage
in front of hundreds of people
when you're getting an award?
It's not like
you're hard to find.
You're here
at the hospital every day.
Oh, please, just postpone it.
I don't scare that easy.
How is it that a woman
who cuts people open for a living
is nervous about
talking to lawyers?
In the OR they're not
hoping I make a mistake.
Which is exactly what
these lawyers are doing.
Babe, just tell the truth.
What if somehow I end up
saying the wrong thing
and then they use it
against Bell?
It's gonna be fine.
I promise.
How can you be so sure?
Because I know what we did.
I've gone over the records,
just like you.
We checked every box
with Claire.
It was textbook.
And I know what a good doctor
you are.
You're biased.
Test came back on the pill.
It was fentanyl for sure.
- Malik's parents are on the way.
- Good.
Cops should be here soon.
You reach the brother yet?
Tried three times. No answer.
That... kid's walking around
with poison in his pocket.
If he hasn't taken it yet,
he will.
Can you track him?
People track their kids'
phones, right?
Amir is at Young man High School.
It's only two miles away.
Yeah. Go.
Take some Narcan.
Here's extra.
Help! Please!
Stand back, stand back.
Is Robert going to be okay?
Is he dead? Oh, my God.
He's gone.
I got you, bud.
You guys know Amir?
Amir Sheridan.
He's a football player.
Hey. Come here.
Come here, come here.
Keep him on his side.
Keep talking to him, okay?
Someone get a teacher out here
until the ambulances comes.
Don't volunteer anything.
Only answer the question
that's been asked, nothing more.
Yeah, I've done this
before, counselor.
Many, many times.
I've... never lost.
I've never settled.
So, I know you're just
trying to do your job.
But trust me,
this lawsuit is a nuisance.
So, what aren't you telling me?
Costican is not
your ordinary lawyer.
And this...
Is not your ordinary
malpractice suit.
What do you mean?
Most depositions
are pretty tame.
This one won't be.
Costican is a loose cannon.
He's got private detectives
out there
talking to former patients
of yours.
They're digging through
everything.
Combing through records.
Those records are private.
In theory.
But these guys are scary
and well-connected.
We have to be ready
for anything.
So, what are they looking for?
The more important question
is what are they gonna find?
We've got three more
teenage overdoses!
Pronounced one dead
at the scene,
these two were still alive
when I got there.
On it. Bay two.
Lost this kid's pulse
about 90 seconds ago.
Take him to trauma room 12.
This is Amir Sheridan,
Malik's brother.
I think he took a fall
down the bleachers.
Head laceration,
probable rib fractures.
All right, his breathing's
not so hot.
We need to intubate him.
Looks like he took
a hell of a spill.
Page Neuro. Dr. Sutton
needs to take a look at him.
I got this one.
You go get the others.
All right, thank you, man.
Come on, sweetie.
Come back to us.
Let's get ready to intubate.
Pulse-rhythm check.
No pulse.
- Pulmonary embolism?
- Resume compressions.
Let's give him another round
of epi, bicarb and calcium.
Airway definitely not secure.
Preparing to intubate.
I need an RT in here.
I thought it was an overdose.
He passed out and fell.
Head trauma.
Looks like rib fractures
on the right.
Pulse is strong,
so we got something.
Have you checked pupils yet?
Nope, it's all you.
Give me 20 of etomidate
and 150 of sux.
Uneven pupils.
That's not good.
Definite trauma to the brain.
That kid never stood a chance.
By the time Conrad got to him,
he was already gone.
These fentanyl overdoses
just keep climbing.
Crazy.
Pushing past 200 a day,
nationally.
Kids are supposed to learn
from their mistakes,
not die from them.
And this one here is gonna
need both of our expertise.
It's a damn shame.
Meet you in CT.
That's two minutes.
Pause compressions.
We got a pulse.
His brain has been
without oxygen
- for a long time.
- Yeah,
we've given him a shot.
Not time to celebrate just yet.
We'll get him to the ICU
and send him through
the scanner on the way.
Good.
I'll go check on Malik.
Hey, I heard you had a bunch
of overdosed kids in the ER.
I came down, I wanted
to see if I could help.
Uh, yeah, multiple cases
of fentanyl poisoning.
This kid had a PEA arrest
on the way in,
we got him back,
but it's not clear what's left.
So, nothing surgical?
Dr. Austin and Dr. Sutton
have a head trauma
that'll probably
end up in the OR.
Okay, right.
I-I'll check with them.
This one of
the fentanyl overdoses?
So young.
Yeah. 13.
Two of the older ones
are in real trouble.
Another one was dead
at the scene.
You find the rest of the pills?
Yep. Older brother
had them in his pocket.
13 years old, kid probably
never took anything stronger
than an aspirin before.
We should not be saying
they overdosed.
That kid was poisoned.
Dr. Devi,
at what point
was it clear to you
that Claire Williams
would need surgery?
Well, when the kidney stone
was resolved,
she developed an acute abdomen.
Culture showed florid
gram-negative bacteremia.
Her lactate was very high.
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
Have you assisted Dr. Bell
in surgery before?
Yes, many times.
And how many of those patients
have died under Dr. Bell's care?
Object to form.
I don't know
a specific number...
So, you have seen Dr. Bell kill,
or, uh, lose a patient before?
Object to form.
Mr. Costican, please.
There's no jury here.
Theatrics aren't necessary.
Do you believe the surgery
performed by Dr. Bell
was a factor in
Claire Williams' death?
I am certain she would have died
without the surgery.
She was already
in refractory shock
and she was clearly ischemic.
The surgery was the only way
to save her.
Were you aware that Dr. Bell
received financial compensation
from a medical device
company, QuoVadis,
whose products he recommended
to Chastain patients?
Objection, relevancy.
No, sir.
Dr. Bell's financial affairs
are not...
So, you were not aware
that artificial heart valves
made by this company
resulted in
patient deaths at Chastain?
Objection, relevancy.
No. I'm not a heart surgeon.
I assume you're familiar
with the symptoms of, uh,
multiple sclerosis?
Yes.
Could you describe them?
Symptoms vary widely
from patient to patient.
- And some may be asymptomatic for long periods of time...
- Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
What would be typical?
MS can cause neural disruption
between the brain
and the rest of the body.
This can cause numbness
or weakness in parts
of the body, tremors, sometimes.
Would any of those
symptoms interfere
with one's ability
to perform surgery?
Object to form.
They could.
But hundreds of thousands
of people in this country alone
are living normal lives with MS.
Plenty of surgeons with MS
who are successfully
operating today.
Thank you, Dr. "Pravish."
It's Pravesh.
Pravesh.
Thank you, Dr. Pravesh.
Dr. Pravesh,
have you ever heard
Dr. Bell referred to
by the nickname HODAD?
Excuse me?
Have you ever heard
Dr. Bell referred to
by the nickname HODAD?
It stands for
Hands of Death and Destruction.
I don't...
No one refers to Dr. Bell
that way now.
Now.
But in the past?
I don't recall.
Costican is hellbent on arguing
this in a courtroom.
Now, have you stopped
to ask yourself why?
Because I see
a big, waving red flag.
Now, you and I both know that
Randolph is a great surgeon,
but the things that could
come up in a prolonged trial...
You think he should settle?
I do.
But he did nothing wrong.
That might not matter.
This is bigger than
any one patient
or even one doctor.
It's a fragile moment
for Chastain.
If he loses this suit,
we all lose.
Sorry to bother,
uh, I'm the new scrub tech.
I just wanted to say
I look forward
to working with you in the OR.
You're up, Dr. Bell.
Just, uh, just give me
two minutes.
So, you're done already?
Yes.
How'd it go?
It was, um, it was fine.
Not great.
Have you seen Jessica?
No.
Will you talk to her for me?
I'm...
I'm gonna need her help.
What are the criteria
used to make a differential
diagnosis of sepsis?
Well, there's no specific test.
A diagnosis of sepsis requires
the presence of infection,
whether it's proven
or suspected.
Usually very low blood pressure,
rapid heart rate.
Sometimes increased
breathing rate, fever.
And all those were present
in Claire Williams
when she was first examined?
I did not perform that exam.
I'm sorry, you...
you didn't examine
your patient before surgery?
I did. You referred
to the first examination.
I didn't perform
her initial exam.
Of course I...
examined her prior to surgery.
But still, no diagnosis
of the sepsis
until Claire Williams
is already in surgery?
- Object to form.
- No.
- Sometimes surgery is exploratory...
- Is it true
that after Claire Williams
was declared dead,
you said to Dr. Devi, quote,
"It was my fault, I should have
seen the signs earlier"?
No, I don't recall that.
I apologize
for the interruption,
but Dr. Bell is needed
in emergency surgery.
Uh, we're in the middle
of a deposition.
Surely there's
another surgeon who...
Well, apparently,
I have a life to save,
so this legal colonoscopy
can wait for another day.
- Thanks.
- No problem. I hate lawyers.
Thought your brother
was a lawyer.
Exactly.
According to his CT,
there's definitely
a hemothorax on the right side.
Subdermal hematoma
and uncal herniation I'm seeing
gives us very little time.
We've got to his skull open
- if he's gonna have any chance.
- That's all you.
Brains before lungs.
I'll take care
of the chest tube in the OR.
- Oh, his heart rate's dropping.
- Ah, damn it.
We're really coming
down to the wire here.
Get him on the table
and we can scrub in.
How's the kid?
Malik?
Woke up long enough
to extubate him.
Think he's gonna be okay.
How was the deposition?
- They asked me about HODAD.
- HODAD?
- What did you say?
- Well, I...
I dodged it.
But it didn't really matter.
They clearly already knew.
Kid's awake.
Hey, buddy.
How you feeling?
- Terrible.
- I bet.
Your brother and some of
his friends took the same pills.
Your brother took
a pretty bad fall.
He's in surgery right now.
Is he gonna be okay?
I don't know yet.
One of his friends, Robert...
He didn't make it.
Tally?
She didn't take anything.
You're lucky to have her.
You almost died.
She probably saved your life.
My best friend.
- I don't know what I'd do without her.
- Yeah,
I know the feeling.
When can I see my brother?
He's still in surgery.
But I'll take you up
when he comes out.
Resecting the dura.
How do these kids overdose
at school on a Wednesday morning?
Conrad told me
he was prescribed Percocet
for the football injury.
And when it ran out...
He probably went
looking for more.
Guessing he found it online.
Most of the counterfeit pills
on the street these days are fentanyl.
It's cheaper
than dirt
and incredibly powerful,
so all the illegal labs
mix it into everything.
Poisoning your
customers can't be good for business.
Okay, dissecting down
to the intercostals.
Kelly clamp.
I need double suction.
There's blood everywhere.
Ablate one area
and another one starts bleeding.
Found it.
Cauterizing the source vessel.
Through the intercostals,
into the pleural spaces.
32 chest tube.
His cortex is very swollen.
I'm not sure
we got here in time.
You've given him the best chance
against permanent brain damage.
There's too many close calls.
This young man is definitely
dancing with death today.
You need
something, Dr. Sullivan?
Oh, hey, uh, no, I was...
I was just checking on something
I-I noticed before that was...
You know, I once caught a nurse
swiping drugs off my cart.
Poor thing
was totally strung out.
That's terrible.
- What happened?
- I had to report it.
Lost her job,
destroyed her career.
Sad, really.
She was a great nurse.
That's tough.
- That's a loss, huh?
- Well,
addiction doesn't discriminate.
Could happen to anyone.
Okay, yeah, uh...
it seems fine now.
Okay.
Thank you, Dr. Lee.
- Finished so soon.
- Yeah.
That was fast. How did it go?
We're on a break,
which I manufactured.
- That bad?
- It was brutal.
What did Marshall say?
It... it was good, routine.
He's totally behind you.
You're a terrible liar.
I'm an excellent liar.
You just know me too well.
The truth is Marshall's worried.
He thinks maybe
you should settle.
Settling would be admitting
there was a mistake.
And there wasn't one.
I trust your judgment.
- But?
- The stress is bad for you.
And don't tell me you can handle it.
This isn't about
your emotional fortitude.
It's about your MS.
Okay.
Uh...
No, you're right, I...
As usual.
Uh, yeah, all right, let's...
settle this thing.
They refused to settle?
Just like that? Just refused?
And, also...
this OR tech from the surgery,
Donald Killian.
What's he saying?
He's saying you were showing
symptoms of MS in the surgery.
What-what symptoms?!
That's...
that's ridiculous.
This guy begged
to be part of the surgery.
He's a plant.
It... it's all payback.
My MS had nothing to do
with Claire dying.
I could have been completely
cured or flat on my back,
she was gonna die from sepsis.
We need to get back.
It's gonna be okay.
Of course it is.
- Right?
- Mm-hmm.
What do we do?
- Hey, thanks for coming.
- Sure. What's up?
- You look awful.
- C-Close the door, would you?
What's going on?
I'm, um...
I'm in a bit of a jam.
Dad, you're scaring me.
Don't.
Where did you get this?
It was in the operating room.
Left over after a surgery.
I was going to use it.
- On myself.
- You what?
Let me explain, okay?
It was a mistake.
Obviously, I know that, okay?
That's why I called you.
Look, everything
under control, okay?
I... It was-it was
perfectly sound, medically.
I ca-I can
show you the protocol.
What in God's name
are you talking about?
My meds, for...
fatigue and a-anxiety...
I-I... I balance them
very carefully.
They allow me
to perform miracles in the OR.
- It's just, it got...
- This isn't Xanax,
this is Propofol.
This could kill you.
Kincaid, please!
I just, I'm...
I called you, okay?
I need your help. Okay?
So, please.
Look, originally,
they were prescribed. And then,
in the move and...
and then changing doctors,
like...
I can handle
my own medical condition.
Bell is on meds.
He-he...
he couldn't function
without them.
I-I...
It's the same for me,
except my condition
is brain-based...
- Fatigue, anxiety, depression.
- Well, if that were true,
you'd be under the care
of a medicating psychiatrist.
- Why aren't you?
- Absolutely.
You're absolutely right.
I-I should be, I just...
We're-we're a little late...
for that.
Don't you understand
what it's like...
What is required of me
every time I go in there,
being a pediatric surgeon...
What that-what that feels like?
The... Holding the precious
lives in my hands,
the-the parents begging me
to save their children.
- Hour after hour, day after day...
- Okay, you have to stop
this endless rationalizing.
You're too smart
not to see this for what it is.
- You are an addict.
- Okay.
You know the diagnostic criteria
as well as I do.
I saved Padma's twins.
On my regime.
It works.
The-the pills make it possible.
- But without...
- Oh, my God, this is crazy.
This is crazy.
You're right.
It's like I-I want
to stop, I need...
I need to stop.
And I need your help.
I know that I need help.
What are you asking me for?
Prescribe me my medication.
Just, it-it's legal.
And then, over time,
gradually titrate me off.
Monitor my progress.
We can do this.
Oh, my God.
I am not enabling this.
- You cannot ensnare me in your addiction.
- Okay, okay, just...
- How dare you?
- Okay, you're right, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
You're absolutely right.
I'm just a little desperate.
I'm grasping at straws.
I would never...
I would never
do anything to hurt you.
You know that.
- All right, I will help you.
- Thank you.
We can...
find you the right
rehab facility...
I'm not going to a rehab.
Kincaid.
We're i-we're in the middle
of, uh, uh, fund raising
for the new
pediatric surgical center.
- I... Look, things are going well.
- I-I'm not
negotiating this with you, Dad.
If you want my help, this is it.
Either you go to rehab
or I have to report you.
Well, you're not
doing that, obviously.
Come on. That...
I would be fired.
My career, everything...
It would-it would
be up in smoke.
There's another way, Kincaid.
I-I can't go to rehab.
Then I'm going to Dr. Voss.
No, please, come...
Uh, anything that you want.
But you cannot tell Voss.
And you cannot tell Conrad.
That's just...
It's just a line we can't cross.
I told you,
I am not bargaining with you.
Hawkins will go to Voss.
You know that.
And then everything
is over for me.
All right? No one's gonna
have a-a pediatric surgeon
on their staff
who has a drug problem.
All right?
Think of all that would be lost.
Years and years of training,
all the lives
that I still could save.
I can fix this.
With your help.
Just don't tell anyone.
Come on, you can
do that much for me.
If you go to rehab...
I won't tell anyone.
Not even Conrad.
I will lie for you,
one last time.
And then... I'm done.
Thanks.
Thank you.
I'll make some calls.
You okay?
Yeah.
You want to talk?
No, I'm good.
Hey, um...
can we rain check
on tonight?
My dad has a conference
in Dallas
and I said I'd drive him
to the airport.
Of course.
After this kind of day,
I just want to get home
and hold on to Gigi
till she's 18.
See you tomorrow?
Well, that was
hairier than expected.
Understatement of the year.
This young man is lucky
you were on you were
your A game today, Sutton.
Mm.
It's a pleasure riding shotgun
with you, Dr. Austin.
Placing an epidural drain.
Now, before I close the skin,
why don't you give us
a look at those pupils, Dr. Chu?
Sluggish, but equal
and reactive.
All right, well, that's hopeful.
But not definitive.
It'll be days
before we really know.
Yeah, well, he's young,
that helps.
So, whatever happens,
it's gonna be a long road.
I hate these wait-and-see cases.
Take a horrible tragedy
and amp it up with uncertainty...
Feels cruel.
All right,
let's close him up
and get him off this table.
Hear, hear.
"Breathe In Bleed Out"
by Jared Lee playing...
♪ Breathe in ♪
♪ Bleed out ♪
♪ Bleed out... ♪
Hey.
How'd it go with the lawyers?
Uh, it's-it's pretty routine.
- Uh, listen.
- What's up?
I want to ask you a favor.
All right.
Just between us, I'm just having
a little bit of a flare-up.
It's nothing serious.
- Mm-hmm.
- Just a little numbness in my hand,
a little tremor.
And I don't want to make
a big thing out of it.
It would upset Kit.
So, I was thinking just a quick
hit of prednisone...
would knock it down.
Shouldn't your neurologist
prescribe that?
Well, yeah, but she's away at
a conference this weekend, so...
I understand.
I'll give it to you, just...
you need to see your
neurologist when she gets back.
♪ Breathe in ♪
♪ Bleed out. ♪
The illustrious Dr. Voss.
Governor.
Uh, gentlemen,
will you excuse us?
The case is super solid.
Do not settle with her.
Please, Dr. Voss, sit.
Can I get you a drink?
I'm not staying.
So...
you came here
to try to beg for mercy
on behalf of your husband?
I don't beg, Governor.
But I am willing to negotiate.
So, why don't you tell me
exactly what you want
and we can try and sort this out
like adults.
Well, you know,
I don't give a rat's ass
about Chastain Hospital.
Although my polling
is awfully convincing that
the high price of health care
is a winning issue.
You know, the truth is...
your hubby picked a fight
with the wrong man.
He tried to embarrass me.
And I'm afraid that can't stand.
I got to make an example of him.
So, what I want
is for Dr. Randolph Bell
to lose his job,
possibly his medical license,
and whatever shred
of a reputation he still enjoys.
The truth is, Governor,
that you miscalculated.
Because you think
Randolph Bell is like you:
Vain, self-important,
small-minded.
Hungry for money and power.
But the thing about
men like that... men like you...
Is that more than anything,
they're afraid.
Sad, really.
But Randolph Bell is not afraid.
Because he's not
fighting for himself,
he's fighting for what's right.
You think that
by attacking his reputation
and livelihood that
it's gonna make him back down,
scare him away?
Well, it scared him enough
to send you here.
Oh, he doesn't know I'm here.
And, honestly, I only came
because I'd rather see Dr. Bell
saving lives than wasting
his time fighting with you
and your little attack dog.
I thought you came to negotiate.
Yeah, I know.
But now that we've talked,
I realize there's no point.
You've got nothing to offer.
Yeah, my lawyer tells me
we have a strong case.
You don't.
And when, eventually,
they throw out your lawsuit,
expect to see me
on the courthouse steps
with a dozen
of Atlanta's best doctors
talking to the press
about how nuisance
malpractice lawsuits
are driving up the cost
of hospital care.
I think it's a winning issue.
That was a rough one, huh?
Well, my part was a cakewalk
compared to what Billie did.
You know, there's a reason
a picture of your face
is on the side of the building.
He's stable.
We won't know what the damage is
until he wakes up.
How's the little brother?
He's gonna be okay.
Those poor parents.
You know, I don't think
I ever quite understood
what it meant
to have your children
walking around
a dangerous world.
You know, I've talked
to countless parents, but now...
...it hits different.
- Mm-hmm.
- You know?
My twins aren't even crawling
and I'm terrified
for them already.
Nothing really prepared me
for how different
being a doctor felt
after having Gigi.
Never truly realized
how fragile we are
until I held my own
flesh and blood in my arms.
Yeah.
Now, some part of my brain's
always thinking about
the different ways
Gigi might get hurt.
You know, you're not
really selling
the parenthood thing here.
It's the best thing
that ever happened to me.
But thank God
I don't have twins.
That's not helping
either, Hawkins.
Hey.
How'd the deposition go?
Pretty smooth,
though that lawyer
was a piece of work.
Yeah.
I wouldn't want to be Bell
right now, or Kit.
Like dealing with
his MS diagnosis
wasn't bad enough, and now this.
Well, I think with
the right person by your side,
you can deal with
even the worst stuff.
Well, thankfully neither of us
have to face what they do,
but if we ever do, I definitely
want you riding shotgun.
Mm. Although I'm pretty sure
you're riding shotgun.
You know
I'm a better driver than you.
In a car, maybe.
But in life? Uh...
What are you still doing here?
I thought
you'd gone home hours ago.
Just waiting for you.
There's nothing for me
at home if you're here.
You're sweet.
What's wrong?
I may have done
something stupid.
Well, I think that's unlikely.
I met with the governor.
I know.
But I really thought
we could come to
an understanding.
Get him to drop the lawsuit
or at least settle.
And that didn't happen?
I thought maybe
we were being paranoid.
But it's real and it's personal.
This guy wants to destroy you.
I may have
lost my temper, slightly.
Why are you smiling?
This is far from over.
We are in for
one hell of a fight.
No, I know.
But whatever they bring at us,
we'll face it.
Are you ready?
We're really gonna do this, huh?
I wanted to, um...
stop by my place
and-and get a few things.
- Toothbrush.
- I'll buy you a new one.
How long a drive is it?
Couple hours.
You know this place?
No, but they've got
a great reputation.
They focus on treating doctors.
There's no shortage of docs
who struggle with addiction.
I'm scared, Kincaid.
I know.
Me too.
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org