- Previously on The Resident...
- The device industry
needs people like you
to fix a broken system.
If you see something
that's not right,
you will be there to
blow the whistle and fix it.
We manufacture
everything ourselves
right here in Atlanta.
I want a top-notch attorney.
Someone who wears a
fancier suit than you do.
And I get half a million
dollars to make bail
so I can get out
of this rat hole.
It's our first year of marriage.
Come with me to San Francisco.
I can't leave.
This is crazy,
meeting here today,
the day of your wedding.
I'm not going to San
Francisco with Priya.
- Y-You're not getting married?
- I don't know what I'm doing.
All I know is she took the
job, and I'm staying here.
No. Whatever happens
between you and Priya
has nothing to do with me.
I'm not breaking up a marriage.
And if you are staying here,
that changes nothing for us,
because I-I'm leaving Atlanta.
What do you mean?
I'm quitting my job.
Why?
Let's just say the medical
world turns out to be
not what I expected.
Hold on a second.
I don't understand.
- What happened?
- I can't talk about it.
I have to meet Gordon
Page for a tour with investors.
Julian... it can't
end like this.
- Yes, it can.
- Wait, wait, don't go.
Everything's falling apart.
For me, too.
Good-bye, Devon.
Wow. You didn't
make that, did you?
If I'm going to be tortured,
I want to look damn good.
- Tortured?
- I hate weddings.
- I love them.
- They're all the same.
You know exactly what's going
to happen, and they're long.
So long.
Well, I'm sure
you will cheerfully
suffer your way through
Devon and Priya's.
We got to go. We're gonna
be late for our presentation.
- Wish us luck.
- You're gonna need it.
Bell spending money
to actually help patients,
that's not really his thing.
This is premature.
Or optimistic.
We only spend one
percent of our revenue
on community services.
That's way below the
four percent required
to maintain our
nonprofit status.
In plain English,
Chastain gets 20.6 million
every year from Uncle Sam.
And in return, we do nothing
to justify our tax break.
So you're proposing the
board fund a free clinic
for the uninsured
and establish it here,
right across the
street from our ER.
The proximity to Chastain
could be a huge advantage.
We could defer patients who
can't pay their hospital bills
to the clinic, where we
can give them better care.
How much is the
rent on this space?
The city owns the
building, and has agreed
- to let us use it for free.
- You've been busy.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Well, it's a lovely
idea, but so far,
it's all just pie in the sky.
When am I gonna see
some real numbers?
Who's gonna staff it?
Volunteers from Chastain,
medical students
and retired nurses.
Not everything's free.
We will have to hire
a top primary-care physician.
Sounds like a... a win-win.
Call 911. Let's just
get him to the ER.
Marshall, tell
me where it hurts.
♪ ♪
He's been getting steadily
weaker these past few months.
I'm old. It's normal.
65 isn't old. It's the new 40.
We know what's
wrong, but this...
this is what gave me
a tentative diagnosis.
Listen.
I still have a heartbeat.
That's reassuring.
Daddy, be serious.
You have a loud heart murmur.
An echocardiogram
confirmed that he has
severe aortic stenosis.
His aortic valve is
so tightly narrowed
that the blood has a hard
time leaving the heart,
robbing the rest of the
body of oxygen-rich blood.
Which is why I'm so darned
tired and out of breath.
I'm gonna bring in
our best surgeon,
Dr. AJ Austin,
and he's going to
explain the options
of valve-replacement surgery.
He's got a great beard, too.
Well, how long will this take?
- I got to get to Nicaragua.
- Nicaragua?
Another one of his Habitat
for Humanity projects.
I'm retired, returning to
my first love, carpentry.
Well, you can expect to stay
in the hospital for about a week.
Full recovery may take a
while, but you are young,
and you're in good health, okay?
So let's admit you,
get you fixed up.
Nicaragua's waiting.
Dr. Hawkins, can I have a word?
Of course. What's wrong?
Look, I lost my mom
when I was born.
It's always just
been the two of us.
And now my dad is
helping to raise my son,
who just adores him,
and... and, look, I get it.
All hospitals are dangerous
and surgeries have their risks...
I'll keep an eye out for him.
Thank you.
- All right.
- Yeah.
Hey.
Amazing man.
- Okay.
- So warm with his daughter.
I wish he were my father.
Well, right now your
real father needs you.
He's coming into the ER.
I want transport
to Atlanta General.
- My regular doctor is there.
- How's that gonna look?
Our chairman of the
board won't be treated
in his own hospital? Come on.
All right, BP's
105/80, pulse is 110.
Put him in bay ten.
I already have a team
of doctors working...
We need a diagnosis before
we transport you anywhere.
I know exactly what
this is. I have Crohn's.
I've had it for 20 years. I
know how to manage it.
Doesn't look that way.
Why didn't you tell me?
- Why would I bother my son?
- Uh, wild guess,
- because I'm a doctor.
- It's under control.
Every once in a
while, it flares up,
and this is one of those days.
One, two, three.
Crohn's can have
dangerous complications,
so let's get you
up to the VIP wing.
We'll get your records and
tag in your gastroenterologist.
- Excellent idea.
- Our VIP wing
is nicer and far better equipped
than Atlanta General's.
They're ganging up on me.
They're trying to
take care of you.
Feldman, keep me posted.
I'll make arrangements
to admit you.
- You didn't know?
- He doesn't tell me anything.
He's impossible.
Mm, flashing back to that
time you sprained your ankle
and wouldn't let
anyone help you.
I was nothing like that.
A father and son who
refuse to be treated.
I'd say the apple falls
directly under the tree.
Listen, Todd, you, me,
Paris, this New Year's.
It's gonna be insane.
We'll go clubbing.
We'll just have a
really good... I got to go.
Hey, uh, you had three
incoming calls, two from...
I can find it. I wrote it down.
It's somewhere right here.
God, help me.
Um, I know one was from Roberta,
uh, from that lab
place with the initials.
They all have initials.
Do you have a
learning disability?
Um, and your
lawyer, McMullins...
- McCrary.
- Mc-McCrary.
Uh, he is in your office.
- Hold my calls.
- Actually, wait, hold on.
He seems a tad sleazy to me.
Maybe you should
have my dad hook you up
with one of his lawyers.
This deposition you gave
Lane Hunter's lawyers,
you should have called me.
Dr. Hunter is charged with
the death of Lily Kendall.
How long were you
and my client lovers?
Um, I was not in love with her.
She says you slept
with her many times.
Uh, a-a-a few times.
Not many.
How many times is "many"?
What are you not telling me?
There's some kind of sex tape.
In the legal world,
there's a term for this.
It's called a disaster.
This woman is as
popular as Hitler,
and the fact that you were
with her between the sheets
is gonna make
people's skin crawl.
You'll be fired. Your
reputation will be...
Look, enough.
This is how I get out of it.
I'm all ears.
I've agreed to post her bail
and help her find a good lawyer.
- Seriously, you're just
digging a deeper hole.
- Hear me out.
She could get off.
There's a doctor in Texas
who raped his patients,
just got off with a slap
on the wrist, no jail time.
Kept his license.
They're gonna paint
her as aggressive,
not criminal.
Dr. Hunter saved
hundreds of lives.
And if she gets off,
then any lingering sense
that Chastain is to
blame goes away, too.
Everyone's exonerated.
Dr. Hunter's bail is set
at five million dollars.
Ten percent of which
they'll need in cash.
You don't get that back.
That's what the bail
bondsman charges.
Well, she'll pay me back.
- She has money
in offshore accounts.
- You believe that?
Look, it's the
least of my worries.
I'd pay half a million
dollars to make this go away.
Welcome to QuoVadis.
We are very excited
to give you the first
exclusive tour.
Now, a little housekeeping
before we proceed.
NDAs have to be signed.
We guard our trade
secrets with our lives.
I think you can trust
a four-star general.
Well, as Ronald Reagan
said, "Trust, but verify."
How's the VNS pilot
going at Chastain?
So far, so good.
We just cured
intractable seizures
in an eight-year-old boy.
It's the kind of
story we live for.
DARPA is very
interested in VNS devices
for brain stimulation and more.
Yeah, it's a great market.
I was an early investor
in two tech giants,
and even they
weren't this paranoid.
Well, trust me, our
technology is worth it.
You understand that,
for military contracts,
all products must, by law,
be made in the United States?
All QuoVadis devices are
manufactured at our facility
here in Georgia.
This is where we
design all our prototypes.
do all our testing.
From start to finish,
made in the USA.
Our engineering is unrivaled,
and our patient
outcomes show it.
But if that doesn't
convince you,
then how does a
thousand percent return
on your investment sound?
By the end of this year,
we are projecting revenues
of 50 million.
Next year, after
we go nationwide:
500 million.
In three years...
five billion.
- How's he doing?
- Better.
He's on hydromorphone for pain.
Doesn't seem so intimidating
just lying there, does he?
I can hear you.
Well, keep me updated
on his condition.
I want his ins and outs.
Complete breakdown.
Urine, stool, the works.
No secrets between a
doctor and a patient, right?
You're not actually his
doctor. Dr. Simmons is.
Dad, this is the
chief of Chastain's
gastroenterology department.
She's a leading expert
in Crohn's disease.
- Dr. Bell.
- Irena.
- Thanks for joining.
- Mr. Winthrop,
I have spoken to your
team over at Atlanta General.
They sent over all of
your records, and I think
I have a pretty
good lay of the land.
So now I just want to
run some blood work,
check for inflammatory markers.
But, once you're
stable, if you do still want
to be transferred over
to Atlanta General,
- we can arrange that.
- Thanks.
Feel like a helicopter ride?
Your insurance will pay.
I think I'm good here,
- thank you.
- We've started you
on IV fluids, and we'll
need to put an NG tube in
- to help decompress
your abdomen.
- Yeah, that should
get you feeling better
so you can get some rest.
Thank you all. I'm
sorry to be a bother.
If we're done here, I
want to talk to Conrad.
Alone.
Of course.
Thank you.
Talk to him like you
talk to all of your patients.
- How's the pain?
- Mm, better.
I've been dealing
with this for 20 years.
It started shortly
after your mom left me.
Okay, wait.
Mom didn't leave
you. You left her.
Well, that's irrelevant
at the moment, isn't it?
Yes. It is.
Go ahead. What
were you gonna say?
Look, Conrad, thank
you for your help.
Now let Dr. Simmons take over.
I came back here to
get to know my son,
fully aware of the things
that stood between us.
And I think we've
made real progress
in leaving the past behind.
So let's not endanger that.
Okay, fine.
Whatever happens,
I can't be a burden.
It's not my style.
You do not have
to take care of me.
This is what I do, Dad.
You okay?
Yeah. I'm good.
Are these meant
to be form-fitting?
- I don't want to look fat.
- You wear scrubs.
Horrible green
scrubs, like, every day.
Exactly. Hello, Mrs. Pravesh.
Hello.
You look lovely today.
Thank you. Yes, I
do look smashing.
But all eyes will be
on the happy couple.
I'm so proud of you.
I'll try to keep it that way.
What does that mean?
Nothing.
- Hmm?
- Nothing, Ma.
Go. Go, go, go. Let us
finish getting dressed, okay?
See you in a bit.
Yes. Bye-bye. See you.
He's thinking about screaming
kids, mortgage payments,
the dad bod.
It's a wedding,
not a funeral, dude.
Dad bod is inevitable.
Thank you, guys.
Yes. Yes. Excellent.
Yes, we will.
Another two commitments,
each for 25 million.
I'm happy for you, Gordon.
The lab is incredibly
impressive.
You are a great salesman.
You should celebrate.
Take the afternoon off.
I wouldn't know what
to do with myself.
Personal trainer is
waiting in the gym
for my lunchtime workout.
I'll be back in an hour.
There are great things on the
horizon, Julian, for both of us.
You picked the
perfect VNS patient.
And I will reward you.
♪ ♪
Hi.
Julian Booth, sales. Mr. Page
left his phone in the lab.
I'm just gonna go
in and get it for him.
Hey. I was just looking
for Gordon Page's phone.
Okay, no worries.
Um, if you find it,
just bring it to
the office, okay?
It's called a TAVR.
We snake a catheter
through an artery in your groin,
and we replace the
valve in your heart
without ever cutting
into your chest.
Is... is that as
simple as it sounds?
Well, I've only done a few
hundred TAVRs in my career,
and every single one of them
have gone off without a hitch.
Now, I have an opening,
and I can schedule it
this afternoon, once
your pre-op tests come in.
I could even fit in
nine holes of golf,
if I played golf, which I don't.
Wait, this-this afternoon?
That is so soon.
I mean, I have so many
questions. What are the risks?
How long will he have
to stay in the hospital?
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, slow your roll.
Every surgery has
its share of risks,
especially for an
older gentleman.
- Oh, watch yourself.
- However,
for a mature,
well-seasoned adult,
and in such good physical
condition as yourself,
the risks will be minimal.
Well, let's get this over with.
Nicaragua awaits.
Those houses won't
build themselves.
Very wise man there.
There.
Ah, it's a stricture
in the area of your
father's last anastomosis.
It's probably
been there a while.
If it gets any worse, he's
gonna be completely obstructed.
Yes, I'm gonna recommend
that we schedule surgery
sometime in the next few days.
Why so fast?
If it gets completely
obstructed,
it could compromise
blood flow to the intestine.
I would trust
Dr. Simmons and Conrad.
Once the blood
flow is compromised,
the intestine may perforate,
- and then you would be septic.
- That's life-threatening.
When would you do it?
How long is the rehab, and
what are the risks of the surgery?
Well, all surgeries have risks.
But this one we do routinely.
And I'd recommend you have
it done sooner rather than later.
Tomorrow. That would be best.
That way, we can do
some pre-op testing,
book an OR and
line up a top surgeon.
Anybody but Bell.
He'd be at the
bottom of my list.
See, isn't it great
having a doctor
in the family, Mr. Winthrop?
Looks like I'm in your hands,
- and I will do whatever you say.
- Tomorrow it is.
Okay. I'll book an OR and check
the general surgeon's schedule.
Now, there is one more
issue. I have all of my patients
fill out a health care proxy
and a medical directive.
This is not to say I expect
you will need it. I do not.
- But even I have one.
- It's standard of care, also.
If there's anything I've
learned at Chastain,
it's that there are
no guarantees.
If I'm incapacitated,
my son has my medical
power of attorney.
I trust him to make any
decisions that need to be made.
There must be someone
closer to him than me
to make those decisions.
We're making progress,
but there's a 20-year gap.
He doesn't have anyone but you.
That's kind of a testimony
to how he's lived his life.
Here he is, sick.
No one's visiting.
I don't want this
responsibility.
Rose never leaves
her father's side.
They finish each
other's sentences.
I barely know my father.
Well, maybe you should fix that.
Gordon here. What's up?
It's me, Randolph.
I have a favor to ask.
I love doing favors.
I need money. A fair amount.
Huh. Well, I could
let you in on the IPO.
Those shares will
be worth millions.
That could take six months.
You need it fast.
How about a position
on the board of directors?
It's salaried, of course.
The figure is generous.
Well, how much
are we talking about?
How much do you need?
Half a million.
Ooh, that is steep.
But easily handled. I can
advance you the cash right away,
and we'll find a
quid pro quo later.
There are so many ways
for a high-profile doctor
to help QuoVadis.
I have one job today, and that's
to get you to the
church on time.
The venue is
downstairs in the hotel.
I think we'll make it.
And you have two jobs.
Hmm? Right. The rings.
Oh, my God. Oh, where are they?
I heard a ding when
I got out of my car.
I thought I dropped a
penny in the sewer, but...
Stop it.
You.
You know, the
funny thing is that
you actually thought
that was funny.
Is losing your sense
of humor part of
the marriage vows?
Look, man, are you okay?
Because you don't seem okay.
And I'm here to talk and
listen if you want to talk.
I also have a getaway car ready.
- Hello, beta. How are you?
- Hi, Mom.
May I have a word?
I'll be by the
elevators, pacing.
Big day, huh?
- Nervous?
- A little.
Thank you.
I remember my wedding day.
You know it was an
arranged marriage, right?
And yet it worked out.
Yes, it did.
Eventually.
It was not easy.
I was trapped in the beginning.
It was not love at first sight.
And, Devon...
there was somebody
else in my life.
But I was a good girl.
I did everything my
parents told me to do.
So I broke it off
with this young man
because I knew that
they didn't approve.
Mom, if there's something
that you want to tell me,
just say it.
It has taken me a long time
to accept my fate.
I would lie awake
in bed at night
thinking about that
other young boy.
What was he doing?
Does he miss me?
I even thought of contacting
him so many times.
- You love Dad?
- Yes.
I'm happy now, Devon.
I've come to love your father.
He's a good man.
But this is
and this will always be
your decision.
I want you to marry the
woman who has your heart.
Okay? Okay.
I hope it's Priya.
But, Devon, if it's not,
don't do this for
me or for your father
or for anyone else.
We just want you to be happy.
Okay?
Mark Truscott, FDA, product
regulation, Atlanta division.
I'm a high-level
device rep for QuoVadis Labs.
I know the company.
I believe that my firm...
I know that my firm
is engaged in a
wide-ranging fraud.
Uh, do you have proof?
I can get it. I signed a
nondisclosure agreement
when I was hired,
so I would need whistleblower
status to give you my name.
- I can arrange that.
- And I want
the assurance that you'd
investigate immediately.
Lives are at stake,
and I feel sick at what
I might have been a part of.
- Are you in Atlanta right now?
- I am.
I-I need details
to arrange all this.
We close soon,
but I could meet you
outside of the office.
I live in Decatur.
Do you know Glenlake Park?
- I can find it.
- 4:30 in the north parking lot.
And from this moment on,
you must keep
everything confidential.
Don't talk to
anyone but the FDA.
- I don't plan on it.
- I'll see you shortly.
McCRARY: You realize
these QuoVadis terms put you
in a very
uncomfortable position.
I realize it gets me the
money to make Lane's bail,
which makes the
sex tape go away.
You think she'll hold up
her end of the bargain?
What choice do I have?
The cash they're giving you
to be on the board of directors
is listed as an advance
against future stock earnings.
If the QuoVadis IPO goes south
or doesn't happen at all, you're
on the hook for a lot of money.
The QuoVadis
IPO is a no-brainer.
In five years, they'll be
the biggest device company
- in the country. Next.
- This agreement gives QuoVadis
unlimited rights to your image
or likeness across all forms
of marketing, in perpetuity.
TV ads, billboards, pamphlets.
You sure you want
your name linked
with QuoVadis until
the sun burns out?
Well, forget about
the sun burning out.
My image is gonna be in
the toilet by the weekend
if we don't do something.
Look, I just want to make sure
you did your due diligence
on this Gordon Page guy.
- How can you know...
- You know who else
is serving on the board
with me? Two senators,
the governor of North Carolina,
a former Secretary of Defense,
and an astronaut.
Guy went into space.
Do any of them know
jack about medical devices?
Dr. Okafor, your opinion
on the progress of the catheter?
Slow.
You know, impatience
radiates off you
like fog off a Maine coastline.
This is a simple procedure,
and we have a wedding to catch.
Oh. Well, the rumor
is you hate weddings.
I hate being late
more than I hate weddings.
I see a definite
family resemblance.
Yes.
Bart Jr. is very close
with his grandfather.
They spend a lot of time
together while I'm at work.
Mm. Well, Bart Jr., I just
got word from the OR,
and your grandfather's
surgery is going just fine.
He should be
out in half an hour,
so you can visit him then.
Does that sound good?
Thank you. Thank
you for updating us.
Of course. I'll let you
know when he's out.
- I love these suspenders.
- Thank you.
Guiding the wire into
appropriate implanting
position at the aortic annulus.
This allows the
delivery system to align
for maximum stability.
Notice how
oh so delicately I push...
Ah.
There.
You may deploy.
Now, slowly turn the deployment
- device counter...
- Done.
I'll close while
you put on a suit.
You do own a suit, right?
Wow, you look amazing.
So do you.
He looks good. We can head out.
Hey.
We don't have to
leave right away.
Fourth quarter.
Terrible game.
How you feeling?
Better, thank you.
Look, you mentioned before...
- About your mother.
- That she left you,
and that's not
how I remember it.
Do you want the truth?
Yes.
Okay.
You remember Jack Rogers?
Uh, our next-door
neighbor, yeah.
Your mother fell
in love with him.
- I don't believe it.
- Oh, you think I'd make it up?
I loved your mother.
That was a low point for me.
Rogers was married, as well.
So she left me,
sure that they
would be together,
but in the end, he
stayed with his wife.
And that was the beginning
of a long, downward slide
for your mom.
For-for both of us.
Now, I am not blaming her,
'cause I was gone a lot,
and understandably,
she thought I didn't
appreciate her.
She was a good woman
and a great mother,
and I should have made
her my priority, and I didn't.
And you, as well.
I have to ask.
I have these nightmares.
I see her falling down
the stairs, you arguing,
and...
Did you hit her?
No. Absolutely not.
I mean, we fought
over your custody,
and it got ugly at times, but
as far as physical violence
towards your mother
or any woman... never.
Conrad, I am flawed
in many ways,
but not like that.
I would sooner die.
I'm glad you came back.
You're my father,
and I love you.
Mark Truscott? FDA?
Gordon Page
would like to see you.
♪ ♪
Mark Truscott and I
went to college together.
He's not the only
person at the FDA
who has a stake in QuoVadis.
Take out your company phone.
Unlock it.
Now set it so it
won't lock again.
I trusted you.
What about the patients
who trusted QuoVadis?
- Our devices are safe.
- No, they're not.
I saw the data you gave
Chastain on the VNS.
It wasn't even tested.
You put it in a child.
A child whose mother
lost her other son to cancer.
Your lab is a sham.
Your factory, too, is
an empty warehouse.
You import
everything from China.
Top medical device companies
all use products from China.
And label it "made in the USA"?
Others did exactly that.
This is fraud. Outright fraud.
How in God's name did you
think you'd get away with this?
I'm not getting
away with anything.
They're safe,
safe as any others.
Your heart valve killed people.
You are not a team player.
I signed a
nondisclosure agreement.
I-I can't tell anyone
what I know.
If you just let me go, I...
I'll disappear.
I gave you the
golden opportunity
to get into the
future of health care.
To make a fortune.
Do you know what I hate
the most in this world?
Betrayal.
You made it.
I wouldn't miss
it for the world.
- I'm gonna say hi to Micah.
- Mm-hmm.
Where's your date?
Oh, well, I plan on meeting
the love of my life here.
It happens at
weddings, you know?
Mm-hmm.
Wow.
This looks awesome.
I am dying for these saris.
I want all of them now.
- It's all so romantic.
- Ugh, wake me
when the ceremony is over.
I take it you're eloping.
Why get married if you
don't want kids? And I don't.
At least, not for the
foreseeable future.
Yeah, me, neither.
You don't want kids?
- Since when?
- I already have a child.
My sister, Jessie.
Hey. You're not on
call. None of us are.
Guys, let's turn off our phones.
Ooh, that's a radical move.
One of life's greatest
events. Birth, death, marriage.
And we should honor it.
Hey, guys. Any of
you seen Devon?
I need to speak to Priya.
Uh, you can't. It's bad luck.
Hey, Priya? Priya?
Devon?
What are you doing here?
Can we have a minute, please?
Mm.
You look great.
So do you.
The most beautiful I
have ever seen you.
What's this about?
We've been together
for three years.
And four months.
And I've loved
you all that time.
And, just as important,
I've respected you.
And that's why I have
to tell you the truth.
Recently, I've been
attracted to somebody else.
I didn't sleep with
her, but I did kiss her.
It's-it's over, and I'm
never gonna see her again.
I tried to put it behind me,
but I can't.
I can't marry you.
Not when I have feelings
for somebody else.
You deserve
somebody that loves you,
and only you.
It would be wrong,
for the both of us.
Your timing sucks.
I realize.
Everyone's here.
Family came from India,
from Boston, from England.
I know, but do we go
through with it because of that?
Why did you wait
until now to tell me?
Because I thought
it was nothing.
Some last-minute panic attack.
But I realize now
that I have real
feelings for this person.
I'll do whatever
you tell me to do.
I'll talk to everyone. I'll talk
to both parents. It's on me.
You've humiliated me,
and you think this little
speech gets you off the hook?
No, no, I... no, I don't. I...
I'm-I'm ashamed of
myself for hurting you.
But lying or not telling
you would be worse.
Priya.
Please, I'm...
Who are you?
Not the man I loved.
Get out. I never
want to see you again.
Get out!
Hey, I told you
it would be fine.
I'm so relieved, Dad.
We just can't do it without you.
Well, looks like you're gonna
be stuck with me for a while yet.
Hey, honey, you
want to kiss Grandpa?
We're gonna let him
rest, okay? Yeah?
Hey, amigo. Ho, ho!
It's gonna be a whole new
phase of life for you, Dad.
Thank you, darling,
for being here for me.
I feel so sorry
for all the people
who are in the
hospital all alone.
That'll never be you.
Good night.
Oh, my God. Mr. Winthrop!
He has a rigid abdomen
with tenderness,
guarding and rebound.
Stand back.
Free air. It's a
bowel perforation.
He needs emergency surgery.
Wh-Who's on call for
emergency gen surg?
Dr. Bell.
Uh, page Bell.
And find Conrad now.
♪ ♪
♪ There's no sense ♪
♪ No matter what you say ♪
♪ What sticks inside
ain't gonna fade away... ♪
- Dr. Bell.
- Marshall Winthrop,
emergency surgery, OR 2.
♪ I'm falling away ♪
♪ Too low... ♪
Call the blood bank.
Tell them to type and
cross ten units for standby.
Scalpel.
♪ Falling away ♪
Perfed above the
prior stricture line.
♪ Falling away ♪
Conrad.
♪ Falling away... ♪
He's hemorrhaging.
Sponge stick. Sponge stick.
♪ Falling away... ♪
Suction.
Suction. Suction.
♪ Falling away... ♪
He's bleeding out.
♪ I'm falling away. ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH