Previously on New Amsterdam...
Dr. Bloom. Dr. Bloom?
The last few weeks,
I've been taking a little bit
more Adderall than prescribed.
I think you may need
help. I'm just tired.
Mr. Powell could have died.
Run the cardiac
surgical department.
There is no cardiac
Then build one.
When we aim high energy
external beam radiation
at the cancer in your throat.
If you move then, you die.
I don't want everyone
to see me so weak.
The answer's yes, Max.
I'll be your deputy.
I don't even know what
some of this stuff is.
Babe, I didn't know
we had so many friends.
This is a return, right?
No way. No?
Cloth diapers are way
better for the environment.
Yeah, but disposable
diapers are way better
for sleeping in on Sunday.
Fine. "Maybe"
pile. "Maybe" pile.
It's very cute that you think
you're sleeping in on Sundays.
Yeah. Electric snot
sucker? Return.
How do you suggest we remove
snot from our baby's nasal passages?
The old-fashioned way.
You put your mouth
on that nose and you...
That's disgusting! Keeping. suck
up all this thing. No, it's fun, babe.
What about a baby...
A baby blender?
That's a maybe. I mean, we
don't have an adult blender.
All right, well, the
Swedish here says, uh...
Oh! Well, in that case,
return. Hmm. Return. Yeah.
Mmm.
Oh, babe, more nausea?
Mmm-hmm.
Hey, I thought Helen said
that you wouldn't experience
chemo nausea so soon.
Well, maybe I'm...
Maybe I'm special.
Maybe you should stay home.
Mmm-hmm. Mmm-mmm.
I'm good.
I'm already over it.
It's fine. I'm raring to go.
I'm not gonna let a little
cancer slow me down.
I'm fine.
How can I help?
Figured out why the old
Cardio Department lost its way.
Our conflict of interest policy.
What's wrong with it?
Well, we don't have one.
Big Pharma could buy me an
island, and no one would know.
Could be fun. We should
mandate total transparency.
Uh, how many other
hospitals do this?
Zero. I guess
we'll be the first.
In clinical trials, do you know
what you want in ideal candidates?
Oh, I know this
one. Sick people?
Diversity. Yeah.
Our candidates need to be as diverse
as the country we're aiming to treat.
Yeah, so what's the problem?
The country I'm trying
to treat isn't Finland.
Hmm.
I can see that.
Yeah. I'll make some calls.
More glitter, right? Okay, yes.
So, New York has seen a
spike in Polynesian refugees
because their countries are, you
know, sinking into the Pacific Ocean.
Right. Not a lot of
them speak English,
like these little cuties right
here. From Tuvalu, aren't you?
Imagine I just said, "How
can I help?" in Tuvaluan.
I wish I could, but I can't,
because nobody speaks
Tuvaluan in New York.
Literally. Like, less than 20
people. I need a translator.
Oh. Okay. So, I just
learned the word for "potty."
Oh, did you? But
I'm gonna take off.
Okay.
Oh. Oh! Gladys!
My department was just flagged by HCC
for "disproportionately providing coverage
"to patients ineligible
for Medicaid and for..."
Solved.
Thought that was gonna go in.
Still solved. Pretend it went in.
But they said they
would cap my budget...
It doesn't matter. We
treat everybody here,
and if they're not covered, if
they're covered, it doesn't matter.
The price...
We treat everyone. That's
the power of New Amsterdam.
Excuse me.
Max, are you okay? MAX: Yeah.
Oh...
Max, you want
us to wait for you?
Oh, God, what is the medical
term for "barfed my face off"?
This isn't a great time.
You don't even know
what just came out of me.
I'm not just talking
quantity, I'm talking quality.
I mean, what the heck could I have
possibly eaten that's gonna come out...
Max. What?
This is a consortium of top oncologists
being hosted by a WHO facility in Haiti.
Everyone, this is Dr. Goodwin,
our medical director.
How you doing?
Hello.
Let's pick this up
in 15, shall we?
Sorry about that. It's fine.
I'm consulting on a
very challenging case.
A digression about
the texture of your vomit
was just the mood-lightener
that we needed.
Happy to help.
And you need anti-nausea meds?
Mmm-hmm.
This is harder than I thought.
Silver lining?
When we start radiation tonight,
your throat's gonna be
too sore to eat anything.
Less nausea.
So, you'd walk by, and
you'd see all this smoke
seeping out from under the door.
But it wasn't a fire. It was the
cardiologists' smoking lounge.
In the hospital?
Yes, building C.
Third floor.
They had the fire department
called on them at
least twice a month.
I can't believe you've never
told me that one before.
It was a different time. Just a
wonder more patients didn't die.
Yeah, no kidding.
Oh! No, it's okay.
It's okay, I got it.
No, no, no, I got
it. Henry, it's cool.
Thanks. I've been
trained for such situations.
Just got to get the
big chunks, right?
Yeah. Thanks. Kick
the rest under the table.
Clumsy.
You know, my intern
days were totally tame.
I don't have any crazy stories,
you know. Oh, don't be so sure.
Those memories will come
flooding back once you're my age.
For example, I have a temporal
bone surgery scheduled tomorrow.
Now, back in the day, we
wouldn't even consider operating
until we could see discoloration
in the neck and the jawline.
Oh.
That's crazy.
Okay. Thank you so much.
Lauren. I'm late.
Lauren.
I am deeply sorry. If you
would just hear me out...
You rooted through
my bag for drugs
after I explicitly told
you that I was clean.
You just couldn't
trust me, could you?
It's not that simple,
and you know it.
I was concerned.
I overstepped. What I wanted...
We were friends.
We still are. How?
You asked for help. You
admitted you needed help.
Let me help you.
How about this?
From now on, you stay on your
side of the hospital. I'll stay on mine.
Oh, hi.
Max?
Hey, Dora told me I
could find you in here.
Yeah. Oh. Okay.
That's all right. I can wait.
Oy.
Hey. How can I...
Yeah, okay. Yeah, I got it.
So, let's say, hypothetically, I
have a friend here at the hospital.
Let's call him, uh, Dr. Dre.
And what if he kind
of, sort of, maybe,
shouldn't, probably be
performing surgeries anymore?
We're not having an
unofficial conversation
about an impaired
physician, Iggy.
We have a system.
I know.
I just don't want to ruin
anyone's career, you know?
Well, if you're concerned enough
to bring it to me here,
then it has to be official.
All right? No half
reports, no pseudonyms.
By the way, maybe
pick a better one. I know.
Just tell me what's going on so I
can investigate the doctor properly.
Come on, man.
Can't we just hypothesize
about it for a little while longer?
Iggy, your name will be
kept confidential. I swear.
It's Dr. Maravich.
What's going on?
Do you speak
English? Yes, yes, yes!
Please, you have to
help him! He needs help!
Severe dehydration.
Okay, let's get him over
to Bay 27 for a workup.
What's your name? Ivan Velez.
Ivan, how do you know him?
Uh, Miguel, we are brothers.
You must help him, please!
He feels hot. Ivan, look at me.
How long has he
been sick like this?
Uh, about a week.
He started shivering, and he
couldn't drink or eat anything.
We thought he needed
sleep, but it only got worse.
Does it hurt to swallow?
You have to help him!
I'll do everything I can.
Bloom, lymphs are swollen.
Okay, open for me?
What? What do you see?
He needs an FNA, ASAP.
Who's on call for
oncology? Dr. Sharpe.
Daddy, who's that man?
My name is Dr. Kapoor.
I'm going to help your mom.
She can't see. Her
eyes are broken.
Then I'll try to fix them.
Let's find a healthy
snack, kiddo. Yeah.
We'll be just outside.
I see from your records, Maren,
you've had a rough time. Yeah.
My organs, they shut
down during Violet's birth.
I couldn't stop bleeding. I
was in the ICU for nine months.
Ian had to make
arrangements. Just in case.
But you survived. Mmm-hmm.
Well, most of me.
So, you developed an adenoma
at the base of your brain.
It's pressing on the optic chiasm
and causing your blindness.
Yeah, and everyone
says they can't remove it
because I can't have
anesthesia 'cause of my liver.
That's right. But there
is a new treatment.
Non-surgical. I won't
even need to break the skin.
How?
It's MRI-guided
focused ultrasound.
Non-invasive, no anesthesia.
Just one catch.
Yeah. There's always a catch.
Before I can address
your brain tumor,
we need to replace
one of your heart valves
also weakened by Violet's birth.
But I'm sure my colleague, Dr. Reynolds,
can do that without anesthesia as well.
Wow.
I would love to see
my daughter's face.
her eyes. I would.
Hi. I got your page.
Yeah.
Mr. Velez?
This is Dr. Sharpe.
She's gonna biopsy
your brother's throat,
so we can figure out
what's making him so sick.
Open up for me, Mr. Velez.
Arroyo. His name
is Miguel Arroyo.
I thought you
guys were brothers.
We're like brothers. You
know, we are Boricua.
We grew up a town
apart on La Isla,
but we never knew each other
until we came to New York.
When did you move here?
Hurricane Maria took everything.
My home was washed away,
and no one was coming to help.
So I left to find work, so
I could rebuild one day.
Took any job I could get.
Construction, picking apples.
And that's where I met
Miguel, on a farm upstate.
We both lost
everything but faith.
She brought us together
to protect each other.
You see? So, we
are more than friends.
Specimen cup.
Here.
Admin sent me about a nameplate?
Oh. Yes.
Great. Thank you.
I've been calling for a month.
Just tell me what
you need, Dr. Merritt.
No, actually, I'm Dr. Reynolds.
Oh. Nameplate says "Merritt."
Right, and I want it
replaced with "Reynolds."
"Dr. Reynolds"? Correct.
Okay, gonna have to get the
Chair of Cardiothoracic Surgery
to sign off on a
request like that.
Not a problem. I'm the Chair
of Cardiothoracic Surgery.
Dr. Merritt. No, Dr. Reynolds.
Well, it says
Dr. Merritt's the Chair.
Well, he's not. I'm the Chair.
Well, then why are you
in his office? This is my...
Um...
You see how confusing this is?
Well, I have this same conversation
with every patient that comes in here,
which doesn't help them to be confident
in the doctor they chose to cut them open
because he can't even
get his name on the door.
Yeah, I'm thinking you
might need a new nameplate.
Yeah.
Henry.
Chemo stomach. It's no joke.
You're telling me.
Thanks for coming.
Sure.
You know what this
room used to be?
Hmm, I think legal had it.
Well, the fun part is
who had it before legal.
In '67, we'd call this
the "Nookie Closet."
Did you? Now it's a
stone's throw from HR,
so why don't we let that one sail
right by? Mind if we get right to it?
Not at all.
I'd like to schedule you
for a medical evaluation.
Nothing wrong with
my health, Dr. Goodwin.
Just consider it
a formality. Okay?
This hospital requires a
medical eval every two years.
I passed my last exam
less than a year ago.
With flying colors, I might add.
I don't like it any more
than you do, but it is my job.
I've been in practice
for more than 40 years.
All of them here.
I can do my
surgeries blindfolded.
I appreciate that, Henry,
I do, but I would still like to
schedule you for a routine eval.
Tomorrow.
Of course.
You got to do your job.
So you need me to
perform a valve replacement,
so that you can do an
MRI-focused ultrasound.
It shouldn't be a
problem. Keep scrolling.
Oh!
Your patient can't
withstand anesthesia.
That's right, but
if I can perform
a procedure on the
brain without anesthesia,
you can certainly do the
same thing for the heart.
Yeah, the only noninvasive surgery
is catheter aortic replacement therapy.
Yes, do that.
Which requires a C-ART device,
which New Amsterdam does not have.
So we'll get one.
Yeah, sure. "So we'll get one."
A C-ART device costs $3 million.
I made Maren Thompson a promise
that I would help her see her daughter.
I'll get you this device.
Okay, guruji, look.
I can't even get my name
on my own door, all right?
They're not gonna just
buy you a $3 million device.
We will see about that.
Uh, remember when you told me
we'll treat everyone
here no matter the price?
That's the power
of New Amsterdam.
Yes, well, we need
a C-ART device.
Okay, I'll call HCC. Done.
Do you know what
a C-ART device is?
Will it help your patient? It's
the only thing that will help.
Good enough for me. Thank you.
Yeah? Hey, hey, hey.
I thought you were gonna
handle that whole Dr. M situation.
Yeah, handled. Medical
eval scheduled for tomorrow.
Well, he moved his temporal
bone surgery up to today.
Help! Help! He needs help!
What's happening to him?
Push two milligrams of Ativan.
Biopsy results? They just
came back. It's not cancer.
Must be an infection.
Given the ulcers,
it's got to be viral.
I'll start acyclovir. I
saw polys on the biopsy.
Bacterial's much more likely.
Or the polys are due
to a secondary infection
on top of the viral infection and
irrelevant. It's my ED, my call.
And if I disagree
with your call?
Bloom, we got four more!
Similar symptoms to Mr. Arroyo!
Visible ulcers in the
back of the mouth.
Four more?
Where did they come from?
- Watch out.
We all work together.
They were all sick, too!
Mind if I scrub in?
What are you trying to prove?
Nothing. Just here to observe.
I've done this surgery
hundreds of times, Dr. Goodwin.
I don't need the
hospital's medical director
standing over my shoulder
evaluating my every incision.
Then pretend I'm not here.
You trying to throw me
off my game, is that it?
I expect all the surgeons in my
hospital to perform at their best
whether I'm here
watching or not.
Anyone's not performing
at their best, it's you.
Running a hospital
while undergoing chemo?
You have no right to judge me.
This isn't about me.
I've helped thousands
of patients at this hospital.
Thousands. My
record is sterling.
My reputation impeccable.
Henry, you're a legacy here.
Damn right I am.
But what story do you
want told in the end?
That you were a
titan in your field,
or that you were a doctor who didn't
know when to lay down the scalpel?
There'll come a day, Max,
when you won't be able to
perform as well as you once could.
Maybe sooner than you think.
Well, they all work together out at
some vineyard out in Long Island.
And they're all exhibiting
the same symptoms?
To a T.
What at a vineyard could
have made them all so sick?
Let's find out.
The owners made us sleep
in this old, rundown barn.
All crowded together, cramped.
How many of you?
Seventeen, sometimes 18.
At night, I just tried to think
of my family back home.
Yes, there were so many rats.
I've been picking since
Hurricane Georges.
Been 20 years since
I've seen Puerto Rico.
Have you harvested
at this vineyard before?
No.
And I will not go back.
I will starve first.
The owner treats us like
animals. Pays us nothing.
And everything was
damp and wet all the time.
Mold everywhere.
I'm thinking pesticides led
to an autoimmune reaction,
erythema multiforme. EM
would explain everything.
Their kidney function is fine.
The rats and the close quarters
are the perfect breeding
ground for the hantavirus.
Something's off.
We're missing something. Really?
I think Sharpe may
have nailed it. Hanta.
No, it's not hantavirus.
Okay. Because?
Because...
I have a gut feeling.
Or you're just disagreeing with
me because it's my diagnosis.
Everything okay here?
Yes. It's fine.
Okay, at the risk of
stepping into something,
I'm gonna make the call.
Treat for hantavirus.
Suction. Suction.
I dropped a bottle, Iggy.
One stupid bottle.
I was...
I was worried.
You moved the surgery up
because you knew you wouldn't pass
the medical evaluation.
I moved up my surgery
to prove the evaluation
wasn't necessary.
No, Henry, come on.
I may not be a young
man anymore, Iggy,
but I am a surgeon with
over 40 years' experience.
And that counts for something.
At least, it should
count for something.
You really buried the lede on the
whole C-ART device, didn't you?
$3 million?
To be fair, you did say,
"No matter the price."
No, you're right. I
really should have asked
more prudent follow-up questions.
Like, "Does it cost $3 million?"
To be clear, New Amsterdam
will never get a C-ART device.
See, what'd I tell you? The
system can't handle the small things.
Why in the hell should we be surprised
when it can't handle the big ones?
Didn't let me finish.
New Amsterdam will
never get a C-ART device,
so you should do the surgery
at a hospital that does have one.
What are you saying?
University has a C-ART device.
We have a patient.
Peanut butter, jelly.
So, as our sister hospital,
they'll let us do the surgery there?
Not exactly. And
definitely not for free.
But her insurance
won't cover University.
Yeah, and then I
can't do the surgery.
No, you can't,
but Dr. Merritt can.
Last I checked, he's
still credentialed at Uni.
Okay, wait, wait.
Impersonating another doctor
is grounds for malpractice.
I can lose my license.
I can go to prison.
Nobody is suggesting
impersonating anyone, all right?
You are the Chair of
Cardiothoracic Surgery
at New Amsterdam. Just say that.
This is crazy.
Even for you. Do you
want to help the patient?
This is how.
Are you really
talking about this?
Sneaking a patient across
the city into University Hospital?
If the system can't
handle the little things,
then it certainly won't
notice the big ones.
Sure.
University Hospital.
Can I help you?
Dr. Nottingham.
I'm here to observe a C-ART
procedure as part of my residency.
I called earlier. Observe who?
The Chair of Cardiothoracic Surgery at
New Amsterdam. It's nice to meet you.
Dr. Merritt?
That's what it says on my door.
Pushing the delivery
system up to the aortic valve.
You're nearly there.
How much longer?
Ah-ah-ah... Don't rush
me, and I won't rush you.
If we get caught, it's my
name on the schedule.
Well, Dr. Merritt
will cover for you.
I didn't see anything.
Thank you, Maren.
Sheath's in place.
Got it.
Inflating the balloon.
Leaflets are moving.
Maren, you'll feel
some pressure.
Nice and easy.
Almost got it.
All right, new aortic valve's
in place. Deflating the balloon.
Wonderful. Let's get her
back to our hospital now.
Dr. Reynolds. I see it.
What? A bleed at
the cath insertion site.
It's a common side effect, but
Maren's gonna have to remain flat
with a sandbag on her
hip to keep the pressure on.
For how long?
It looks like you're gonna
have to do your
procedure here as well.
But I'm not Dr. Merritt, either.
Got them all on a cocktail of antivirals,
and we're doing active fluid replacement.
Thanks.
You don't think it's hanta?
No.
What do I know?
You know, Henry was shattered,
just standing there watching
the surgery go on without him.
It's like looking at a broken
man. You did the right thing.
Did I? Yeah.
Then why do I find myself
trying to recall Judas' good traits?
Iggy, I know he's a good
friend, but so are you, okay?
You didn't betray him,
because somebody could
have gotten hurt or worse.
Well, his body is
going. His mind is not.
Very few doctors have
that kind of expertise.
I mean, if we send
him on his way,
all that knowledge, all that
expertise goes out the door with him.
We might as well be saying, "Hey,
Doc, thank you. You're ancient.
"Don't need you anymore.
Don't let the door hit you
"on the wrinkly old
ass on the way out."
Hi.
Oh.
Hello. How are you?
Hello. Goodbye, Iggy.
Huh?
Leave. Yes, I'm sorry.
Bye.
I'll be back in 10. I just
need to fire a few people.
You know you
can't fire me, right?
I was referring to Iggy.
Yeah, you can't fire him either.
Yes, I know, Max.
But it makes me look in charge,
and right now I could
use a little bit of that.
How are things
with you and Bloom?
Fine.
Um, how are you feeling?
Good, yeah.
Aside from Iggy starting
an international rumor
that we traffic in
ageism, pretty good.
Your nausea?
Chemo tried to slow this
man down, but you know what?
It failed?
No, it succeeded, big-time.
But the drugs you
gave me are helping.
Good.
Well, it sounds like you're in the
right frame of mind to start radiation.
Aren't you glad you swung by?
So glad.
Okay.
Everyone just act normal,
like you belong here.
Like we're doctors
in a hospital?
MRI lab is down this way.
How are we gonna get in?
You might have to
schedule us again.
I'm starting to miss
the real Dr. Merritt.
How are you doing,
Maren? Nervous.
I haven't let myself be
hopeful in a very, very long time.
I know this whole process
has been rather unorthodox,
but I made you a promise,
and promise I will keep.
Dr. Kapoor, what
are you doing here?
Huh.
Funny story, actually.
Dr. Carlebach was one of
my best interns back in the day.
And now he's this big-time
neurologist here in University.
Yeah, Dr. Kapoor tried to
recruit me to New Amsterdam.
I wanted to go. I
really did, Vijay,
but my med school
loans were out of control.
I had to go private.
It's nice to meet you. Likewise.
I got to admit, I still miss
my days at The Dam.
Making the most out of
nothing, thinking outside the box.
Always such an adventure.
Funny you should
say that, Dr. Carlebach.
Initiating sonication pulse.
And going again.
Mrs. Thompson, we're using
high-intensity focused ultrasound
to pinpoint the tumor
at the base of your brain.
Oh, okay.
Maren, how are you feeling?
Uh, honestly, I don't know.
I thought I was doing this so that
I could see my daughter's face,
but I don't think I am.
I think I want her to see mine.
I want her to see me seeing her
being proud and growing up
and falling down, being scared.
I want her to know,
all her life,
that she's seen.
The tumor is responding.
Hey.
Is this seat taken?
You know, we're doing
everything we can for Miguel,
and the others. Thank you.
What's that?
A santo.
After Maria, our house
was just mud and water,
and the trunk of a huge tree
where my bedroom once stood.
I went to a santero in town
and asked him to carve this
from the wood of that tree.
As a reminder? No, no.
There are many
santo on the island.
This one is Anima
Sola, the Lonely Soul.
She is in purgatory,
bound to the flames forever.
And I pray to her for
strength and patience,
and redemption.
Why redemption?
I, um...
I liked to drink. Too much.
And I could not stop.
And I would be
dead if not for her.
She helps me to say no.
She reminds me to
always think of tomorrow.
She keeps me alive.
And yet you work on a vineyard,
surrounded by
temptation every day.
Miguel helps me with that.
Never lets the others tempt
me with the angel's share.
"Angel's share"?
In the barrels, the top
layer of wine, it evaporates.
They call that
the angel's share.
I like that.
So do all my
friends. Believe me.
And all the other workers.
At the end of a shift, they
would dip into the crush and drink.
After the way they treated us,
they felt like they
deserved a little taste.
Well, I'm sure the
angels would agree.
Blood pressure 60 over palp.
Then he's fading
fast. Add dobutamine.
Ten micrograms per minute.
It's odd that his
heart rate is 78.
It should be 178. The
antivirals aren't working.
Mariana! Mariana, hang
a bag of streptomycin!
Wait, no, no, no! Don't. The
hantavirus is affecting his heart!
He needs a pacing wire.
He needs streptomycin, okay?
I don't have time to explain.
Do you trust me or not?
I am setting up a pacing wire.
Lauren, you open this door!
Lauren! What are you
doing? Don't do this!
Call Dr. Goodwin.
Ready?
Come here.
Here we go.
Mommy, will you
be able to see me?
- Well, I hope so, honey.
- Almost there.
What do you see, Mrs. Thompson?
Mommy?
It's okay, baby.
Because in my head
and my heart, I see you
so clearly, okay?
I see you perfectly.
I don't understand.
I thought you said
it was gonna work.
The tumors were destroyed.
Surgery should have worked.
There must be
something we missed.
Miguel Arroyo is stable.
Let's treat the others for
oropharyngeal tularemia.
They got it from drinking
partially fermented wine
right out of the barrels.
That's why Ivan never
showed signs of illness.
He's sober.
You know, you and I
working together like this...
It's not gonna work.
You're right.
Hey, how was your
radiation treatment?
Mmm, like a relaxing
vacation at Chernobyl.
Right.
Henry, hi.
Um, if this is about the exit
paperwork, I was about to get to it.
Yeah, good. Great, okay.
Don't get to it.
Excuse me?
Because you're not exiting.
Can I tell him because
of your whole throat thing?
Could I stop you
if I wanted to? No.
Okay, I am
very happy to tell you that
we, here at New Amsterdam,
would officially
like to offer you
the brand-new position
of Chair of Telemedicine.
"Telemedicine"? MAX:
Video conferencing.
We can reach our sister hospitals
in Latin America, disaster sites,
war zones, all around the world.
Yeah, all in need of
experienced doctors like you
to help guide and consult them
through complicated surgeries.
Surgeries that you've
done hundreds of times.
Thank you.
It's your experience that's
irreplaceable, not your hands.
I just don't see anything.
May I touch your face to
perform an examination?
Yeah, that's fine.
Please close your eyes. Mmm.
I would like to try latanoprost.
That's...
What's wrong?
Your eyes are harder
than they should be.
This indicates glaucoma
might have developed.
But there is no way you
would have ever known about it.
There's always a catch, right?
Please lean your
head back for me.
Yeah.
Blink.
Oh, that's a beautiful
drawing, baby.
Yeah.
Oh!
Can you see us? Yes,
my love, I can see you.
Can you see me? I can see you.
You can?
I can see.
It turns out being Dr. Merritt
does have its advantages.
Come here. Ohh!
I see you.
Retractor.
Hey.
Oh. Looks like
someone's feeling better.
No, don't thank me.
Thank your brother
and his santo.
She told me the answer.
El Anima Sola? Yes.
You two are really
lucky to have each other.
I don't really get along
with my real sister.
But what you two have,
you're gonna rebuild.
I know it.
Here. Please, for you.
No, I can't... Yes,
yes, yes. I insist.
My brother, he will take care of me,
and Anima Sola, she will take care of you.
Thank you.
Max?
What's wrong?
I've...
I've been round and
round in my head,
but I can't see that
there's any other way.
Helen?
This is harder than I thought.
I think that I need to report
an impaired physician.
No, we already
took care of it. Max...
I'm talking about Bloom.
Babe, is that you? Yeah.
Hey. Hi.
How is the guy who's not about
to let cancer slow him down?
Profoundly humbled.
I made dinner.
Steak, baked
potato and broccoli.
Wow.
Chemo?
Radiation.
My throat, it's already... Babe.
Helen said that I wouldn't
even feel it for four to five days.
Well, you really are special.
So special.
It smells...
It smells amazing.
Sorry. Hey.
You've got nothing
to be sorry about.
Maybe you should put
me in the return pile.
Nope.
You are a keeper.
Stay there.