Previously on ER:
Alex, what happened?
No, you can't break and
steal things. You know that.
Are you sending me to live
with Grandma and Grandpa?
It's not who I am anymore.
No, it's okay. It's no big deal.
I won't be a part of this.
Have Crenshaw get me a
surgeon who wants to operate.
Leaving so soon?
Did your drunk ass hit that kid?
Look, you talk about raising
K.J. to be honest, right?
My dad's going away, isn't he?
A secret engagement
would be fun.
When was the last time
you actually went to Mass?
Look, that doesn't
matter. It's a tradition.
- Not mine.
- Well, churches are beautiful.
And a little bit creepy.
I don't hear you
making any suggestions.
Well, the only thing
I know for sure...
is that I don't want it...
to even remotely
resemble my first wedding.
Okay. Where was
your first wedding?
In his parents' backyard. You?
A church.
Uh, did you wear
tulle or taffeta?
What do you know about tulle or
taffeta? Are you going soft on me?
I read about them
online. Look, wait.
Tell you what, why don't
you plan the wedding...
and I'll plan the really important
stuff, like the honeymoon?
- Okay.
- Okay?
She needs débridement
and IV antibiotics.
Admit to Surgery.
We'll do it in the O.R.
Ma'am, we're going to admit you
so we can fix these bedsores, okay?
May I present the esteemed
Dr. Neela Rasgotra?
Say hi to Mae Lee Park. She's
our new surgical med student.
- Nice to meet you.
- Heard a lot about you.
- Great. All good, I hope.
- More or less.
We left out the part about you
being our unwanted ER stepchild.
- I'm Ray Barnett.
- Pleasure.
Mae Lee published a paper
with Dr. Zimmer up at UCSF.
I jumped at the
opportunity to snap her up.
Anyhow, that pretty much
concludes our official tour.
I so appreciate
your taking the time.
Oh, it's my pleasure.
We should probably
get out of here.
I need to sign off
on my obstructed CF.
I've never seen a
transduodenal choledochostomy.
Yeah, me neither. Sounds cool.
I didn't know we were
getting a new sub-I.
Really? I'm shocked
you weren't notified.
Bring that up at your next plebe
rally. Add it to your list of demands.
- Where do you work?
- Connie's Cakes.
Place is like Temptation Island.
Cakes as far as the eye can see.
- My hips could not cope with that.
- You're telling me, sister.
What's the deal with wedding
cakes? They're so expensive.
I saw one that cost $2000.
Can you put a price on the
most special day of your life?
Well, what if it sucks?
That's what the tasting's for.
Okay. Hope, what's your plan?
Observe for a couple hours.
If no rebound, Benadryl
and a course of pred.
Great. Let's write a scrip for a
couple of extra EpiPens just in case.
Twenty-three, we'll be ready.
- Did you sign off on my food allergy?
- Yup.
I need one on my bumsicle.
We got choppers coming
in. Two minutes out.
Family crashed in the blizzard. They
were trapped in their car for two days.
Devin Paxon, 40, hip fixed
in flexion, probably dislocated.
Pulse, 86. BP,
90/60. Sats, good.
EKG, x-rays of pelvis, right
hip, femur, C-spine and chest.
Charlotte, baby? We're okay.
You just be brave.
Come on, talk to me, baby.
Charlotte, 10. Scalp lac,
dehydrated and hypothermic, but alert.
BP, 85 systolic.
Charlotte, we're gonna get you
warmed up and feeling better, okay?
Bair Hugger, heated saline
and warm, humidified O2.
Hey, Dad's definitely
more critical.
Julius Paxon, 45.
Hypothermic. Bradycardic,
in the 40s. BP, in the 70s.
No sign of major trauma.
All right. EKG, monitor, chem panel,
CK, CBC, Foley and a portable chest.
How you doing,
Lockhart? You miss me?
No. Can't say that I did.
I marked your initials on
the back of all the tags.
I can keep track
of my own clothes.
Not you. I don't
know those other kids.
This is really gonna suck.
If you keep
saying that, it will.
Come on. They got a good
soccer team, indoor pool. Huh?
Hey.
It's only a couple hours away.
I'm gonna visit every weekend.
Yeah, like that should help.
- Got more saline.
- Good. He's lost his shivering response.
Pupils are sluggish but reactive.
They were out there for two days?
Trapped in the car after they veered
off the road, skidded into a ditch.
The road, it's supposed to be closed
for the winter. Shawnee National Forest.
Shawnee? That's far.
- You were the closest open to trauma.
- How we doing?
I was driving when
the blizzard hit.
We were lost. I couldn't see.
Hip looks dislocated. Other than
that, cold and a few abrasions.
Pulse, 90. BP, 95/60. DEVIN:
Please, you have to find Spencer.
- Sats are good.
- Okay, four more of morphine.
Hope, talk to me.
She's just a little dehydrated,
BP holding at 85 systolic.
It doesn't look too bad.
How do we proceed?
CBC, C-spine, chest
x-ray and a rectal temp.
Good. Make that happen.
Hey, your name
is Charlotte, right?
I know it seems scary,
but we're gonna fix you up.
Your mom and your dad too.
What about Spencer?
- Who's Spencer?
- Her 14-year-old brother.
- He's still out there.
- What, is he on another chopper?
No. He went to look
for help last night.
That's how we found them.
Kid set fires close to the location.
We followed the smoke to
the family. No sign of the boy.
Please, you have to
go and get Spencer.
Sats are dropping, only 83.
Okay, please tell Mr. Morales...
that there are things that he can
buy that won't get, uh, stuck up there.
You know, with a wide
base or a string attached.
My Spanish definitely
ain't that good.
No. Okay, just get
me a translator, please.
Hey, Morris. Do you
still use that travel agent?
Angie? Yeah, she's the best.
You gonna go somewhere?
- Need to get away from the cold.
- I'll get you her number.
Sam, my ankle guy is
waiting for his posterior splint.
Do I look like a magician?
When it's done, you'll
be the first to know.
Tread lightly, my friend. She's
been barking since she got here.
I can hear you, Frank.
What, do you want some too?
Sam. Hey, hey.
- Everything okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
I am gonna send Alex away
to a school for at-risk teens.
You know, emotional
problems and stuff.
It might be good.
He's dealt with a lot.
Yeah.
Hey.
I just can't help but feel
like I'm giving up on him.
We both know that's not true.
- Yeah. ZADRO:
A little help here.
Mario Dunston, 42, single
GSW to the left chest.
How are you doing, sir?
It hurts really bad
when I breathe.
Pulse ox, 92 on 5 liters.
Tachy at 120, BP at
100 palp, had four of MS.
- How's the other dude?
- Got another guy.
Call X-ray for a portable and
set me up for a chest tube.
Morris, Trauma 2. Hey, Dawn.
Donnie Moore, 17, GSW, entrance
through the right temple, no exit.
Tubed him for agonal resps.
Donnie? Donnie?
Purposeful hand movement.
Okay, hold CT and an O.R.
This guy may have a chance.
- Thanks for lending us your truck, Tony.
- Yup.
- We'll see you later tonight. Bye.
- I shouldn't be too late.
What are you doing? Let
your grandmother sit in front.
It's fine. Makes me feel
like I'm being chauffeured.
Be good. Don't
steal any paintings.
Don't kill any patients.
I'm allowed one a day.
One.
Okay, curved Kelly.
HemoCue is 14.2.
Need to ask you a
few questions, Mario.
I'm a little preoccupied, man.
What beef you got with
your Two-Niner buddy?
What you sweating me for?
I didn't do nothing
but get shot.
Y'all get out there
and arrest somebody.
You got anybody in mind?
How should I
know? Y'all the cops.
All right, guys, come on. Let us
work. He's not going anywhere.
Thanks.
That was for me, not you.
Thirty-two French
on a vascular clamp.
- How many times you been shot?
- This makes eight.
0 silk on a driver.
- Only 200 cc's out.
- Okay.
Looks like you didn't bag a
main vein. You're one lucky guy.
Yeah, I'm what
they call black Irish.
He's having ectopy.
Yeah, QRS is wide.
What's his temp?
Down to 84.
What's happening?
He's vasodilating...
which means the colder blood from
his extremities is lowering his core temp.
Charlotte, honey?
I'm okay, Mom.
That's my good girl.
Don't worry, they're
gonna find your brother.
We're all gonna be okay.
I can't get this hip back in place.
- Let me try.
Wait, hold on. Hold on, hold on.
- Ah, I got it.
- He's at V-fib.
- All right, start CPR.
- Charge to 200.
Okay. Charging.
Clear.
- No change.
- What are they doing?
Your mom's asleep
so they could fix her hip.
And they're trying to
help your dad's heart.
Clear.
Still V-fib. Charge to 300.
Dad.
All right, let's move
her out into the hallway.
Come on. We gotta let them work.
No, I wanna stay. Dad!
Clear.
No change. One milligram of epi.
He can't stay in
V-fib for much longer.
Clear.
Mario Dunston.
Street name is Monster.
Got out of Stateville
a few weeks ago.
He's a real O.G., huh?
Did 20 years.
Gang-related shooting.
He left a kid paralyzed.
Hell, if he remains stable,
you guys can talk to him soon.
- How is he doing?
- Still 250 cc's out.
You collapsed a lung, minor bleeding.
Should take about three days to heal.
The cops need to ask
you some questions.
What for? I ain't
got any answers.
You just did 20 years. You
cooperate, maybe they'll be lenient.
Lenient?
What they need to be
lenient for? I didn't do nothing.
Well, then tell them who did it.
I didn't see who did it.
Oh, you were just an
innocent bystander?
Yeah, okay,
Monster. Suit yourself.
Name is Mario. Or Mr. Dunston.
Whichever you prefer.
Morris.
What's up?
You need anything?
No, I'm straight.
Is he gonna be all right?
I don't know.
Sam, could you give us
a hand in here, please?
Junior?
Junior! Junior.
Hey!
- Junior, you all right, man?
- You're gonna pull your chest tube out.
Sam, call Security. What
the hell are you doing, man?
Come on. Get Security now!
Let me go. That's my son!
Junior! Junior!
That's my son. Junior!
Is he all right?
They found him unconscious
at the bottom of some stairs.
Not far from where
they found you.
Is he all right?
We won't know for
sure until he's had a CT.
He took a pretty
hard blow to the head.
You still have absolutely
no idea what happened?
- Damn it.
- V-fib again.
Anything I can do?
- Charge to 360.
- Come on, Donnie.
Charged.
- Blew a pupil.
- Clear.
Okay, another amp of epi.
Why is this patient
in brain-stem failure?
Multiple hematomas pushed the uncus
across the free edge of the tentorium...
compressing the brain stem,
knocking out his vegetative functions.
Charged.
- This guy's a goner.
- Clear.
Okay, another
round. Charge to 360.
Clear.
Okay, that's it.
Clear the room and have Social
Work try to contact the family.
Gates, call it.
Time of death, 11:12 a.m.
- How does it feel?
- Throbby.
That will go away.
Can I get you anything?
Hot chocolate or some Jell-O?
Is my dad gonna die?
You know, there's some great
doctors working very hard right now...
to make sure that
doesn't happen.
You just need to try and
think positive thoughts.
You are a tough
little girl. I can tell.
Films look good, Mrs. Paxon.
Your hip is back in place.
Thanks. It feels much better.
Hi, baby. Are you okay?
She's good.
We're gonna need your consent
for a procedure on your husband.
- What procedure?
- There's a problem with his heart.
Oh, my God.
Charlie, baby, Mommy
will be right back.
Your husband's heart has
stopped from being too cold.
We need to perform
a thoracotomy.
What is that?
It's a procedure where
we cut open his chest...
and pour warm water
directly onto his heart.
That sounds dangerous.
Is there another way?
It's not standard, but it's the
fastest way to get his temperature up.
That's why we need your consent.
I don't know. I...
Maybe we could wait until
he wakes up and then...
The risk of dying from hypothermia
could probably be greater.
Well, I can't do this.
Mrs. Paxon. We cannot do
this without your permission.
What would your husband
want? Is he a fighter?
Yes. Yes, he is.
Then sign the consent.
- Hey.
- Hey there. Haven't seen you.
Yeah, I've been buried.
Yeah, me too, I'm
knackered. Lunch later?
Kovac has me on scut patrol
and this board looks chock-full.
- Maybe after your shift?
- Yeah, I'll drive you home.
Hey, Neela. They
need you in Trauma 1.
I'm on my way.
I'll see you later?
Hey. Angie's number. I gave her the
heads-up, she's expecting your call.
- Thanks, Archie.
- Said she had family-resort hookups.
Fun for the gremlin, swimming
with dolphins, water slides.
We might not be
bringing gremlin.
Oh, a little kick-start for
the old postpartum love life.
I feel you, big guy. All right.
Hey, Frank, I'm gonna be getting
my caffeine on if anybody's looking.
Hey. Is Dr. Kovac
going on vacation?
Yeah. A little romantic
getaway, I guess.
They're getting
married. I just know it.
Abby was asking a patient
about wedding cakes.
That getaway
smacks of honeymoon.
Have you met Abby Lockhart?
Not exactly the marrying kind.
We're female. We're
all the marrying kind.
I can smell a wedding
a mile away, Archie.
It's like a sixth sense.
- Still in V-fib, no pulse.
- Rib spreader.
All right. Hold
ventilation for a minute.
Okay. Now, as the lung
deflates, try to feel for the heart.
Okay, I feel it. No effusion.
Oh, good. Now you can
start internal compressions.
Got the first 10 liters.
Hey, Pratt.
- Hey, Charlotte, how did you get in here?
- The door.
We ready for the saline?
Yeah, go ahead. Pour in the
first liter and get suction ready.
Come on, hey, turn around.
You shouldn't see this.
Okay, the first
liter's going in.
What are they doing to my dad?
Pouring warm water in his heart.
It can help him fight off the cold.
This is all my mom's fault.
You were in an accident.
It's nobody's fault.
She was driving and
they were fighting.
Families fight, it
doesn't mean that she...
It's because she cheated.
That's why they're
getting a divorce.
Oh, thank goodness. Sorry. I
came back out and she was gone.
Come on, sweetie. Your
mom's asking for you.
I wanna stay with my dad.
All right, tell her
mom she'll be fine.
- It's okay.
- Where do you need me?
Internal compressions.
Sterile sixes to Neela.
What, are you expecting a call?
Spencer.
I keep texting him, but
he hasn't written back yet.
Charged.
Ladies and gentlemen, we
have a rhythm and a pulse.
Is this the father of the family?
- Yeah.
Trapped for 48
hours after an MVA.
Hypothermic to 84 degrees.
V-fib arrest,
refractory to shock.
Why is his chest open?
Bypass wasn't available, we did
a thoracotomy for rapid rewarming.
- Was that really necessary?
- We got a rhythm.
Okay, we'll close him up.
Suction fluids from the chest.
Cover the incision.
Take him to the O.R.
- Do you want me to scrub in?
- No.
This is a good teaching case for Mae
Lee. Stay down and finish your consults.
What's going on?
He wanted to talk to his son. I
was giving them a few minutes.
The police wanna know
if they can talk to the boy.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, that's fine.
Hey, we ain't finished yet.
- Police need to talk to your son.
- What for?
They found him at the
scene. He might be involved.
Don't say nothing, Junior.
Everything's gonna be all right.
Damn, man, stop
calling me that, man.
We still gotta
wait for the CT...
but so far looks like
just a mild concussion.
My guess is he's fine.
So did he tell you
what happened today?
Fell down some stairs.
He fell? That's it?
That's it.
You're only making
it harder on yourself.
Give it up, Junior. Come on.
I told you, I don't
know nothing.
88th Street Bishop on Two-Niner turf.
What were you doing over there, man?
We know you had
beef with Donnie.
Where they taking him?
Up for that CT I told you about.
So?
Heard you guys got
pretty hot. Got into it.
- Why don't they just leave him alone?
- Hey, lay down, okay?
You don't wanna pull
that chest tube out.
Hey, yo, cop! Hey!
I'm in here.
What do you want?
Y'all want a statement?
Oh, now you're ready to talk.
Yeah.
I shot that punk. Nine milli.
Would've capped
his ass again too...
but he got me before I could.
You shot him?
Yeah, that's right.
What, I stutter?
So why don't
y'all go on ahead...
and ask me your little
questions for your little report?
What you wanna know?
We're treating the Paxon family.
Have Search and Rescue contact
us at County if there's information.
Dr. Lockhart. L-O-C-K-H-A-R-T.
Didn't find Spencer yet, huh?
Hey, guys. I made a latte run.
I remembered how much
you like extra cinnamon, Abby.
- I'm gonna put them in the break room.
- Pratt, you got a minute?
Yeah, come on. Walk with me.
I gotta sign out. I have
a family emergency.
- What?
- It's really important.
I'll be back in the morning.
It's always something
with that guy.
So check this out. I got
this O.G. with a GSW.
Just confessed to shooting
some kid from a rival gang.
But it doesn't add up.
I don't think he did it.
First he says he had nothing
to do with it. Then he confesses.
I mean, if he did it,
why would he confess?
If he didn't do it, why
would he confess?
How would I know?
Did you ask him?
- I thought maybe you could talk to him.
- Did you ask Kovac?
- Why would I do that?
- Let me think.
Chief of the ER, great with
people, years of experience.
Yeah, but you know, this is
kind of more in your wheelhouse.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. And
exactly what wheelhouse is that?
You want me to talk to
this dude because I'm black.
Well, yeah. I mean,
you are black, aren't you?
That's wrong, Morris.
What? We do this all the time.
If I had a pregnant
girl, I might get Abby.
Big Croatian, Kovac.
I didn't come to you
with my autistic Irish kid.
You could've. You should've.
Hey, what is the big deal? You
know that I love the black man.
You don't wanna
get into this with me.
Look, I got a black
guy from the inner city...
confessing to a crime I
don't think he committed.
You were a black
guy from the inner city.
I thought you could
relate on a level that I can't.
You think that just because we
both grew up black and poor...
we somehow magically relate.
Well, there's nothing
magical about it.
Black isn't just one thing.
We don't all share some sort
of collective consciousness.
I know you may think we
all look alike, but we're not.
- Thanks for making a coffee run.
- Yeah, no problem. There's sugar too.
Aargh. Where is my
darn stethoscope?
It's the third one I've lost.
- I knew it!
- What?
- You're getting married.
- Am not.
- Why are you looking at wedding mags?
- They're, uh, there.
Why were you asking
wedding-cake questions earlier?
I was... I was curious.
Okay, fine. Look me in the eye
and tell me you're not getting married.
- No.
- Why not?
Because that's stupid. I...
- I am not getting married.
- You looked away.
I knew it, I knew it! Oh, God, ah,
this one would look so pretty on you.
Luka asked if we
could keep this quiet...
It's in your eyes, you have the
glow. I can't wait for the glow.
- I can't wait to try on wedding dresses...
- Hope!
If you tell
anyone, I'll kill you.
Do you hear me?
Kill you, as in dead.
Got it?
What's up, bro?
Mr. Dunston, I'm Dr. Pratt.
- I'll go get his next dose of Ancef.
- All right.
Looks like your bleeding
has slowed down.
Your lung should heal in a
few days with the chest tube.
Yeah, that's what the
other dude told me.
Y'all changing shifts?
No. No, not exactly.
Just thought maybe you'd
wanna talk to somebody.
What, you like a shrink?
No. I'm not a shrink.
For some reason, Dr. Morris thinks you
didn't commit the crime you confessed to.
Oh.
So this is like a black thing.
Hey, excuse me, nurse.
I'm sorry, you might
wanna step out.
We about to have a black-man
talk. Ain't that right, doc?
I'm trying to help you.
Hey, go on ahead, break it down.
Why don't you tell me what
kind of help you think I need, doc?
You know what? Forget it.
That's right. We ain't
got nothing to talk about.
- You don't know me, fool.
- No, I don't know you.
I know I work on a parade of
dudes just like you every day.
Where you from, Dr. Pratt?
You one of them
North Shore brothers?
No. I'm from right here.
55th and Michigan.
So you think because you
got your little doctor degree...
you got out the ghetto,
you can judge me?
Nobody's judging you.
Mistakes you made are all yours.
That's right. And 20
years I spent paying.
I did my time, brother.
Strip searches,
nasty-ass food...
piss, take a dump
when they tell you.
It's like you didn't even exist.
Everything.
Your family, your friends,
your whole life just disappears.
And you still didn't
learn a damn thing.
Hey, man, look here, I learned.
- Yeah, but you're still banging, right?
- I didn't say that.
But yeah.
Yeah, I used to bang back in the
day. Boy, you couldn't tell me nothing.
Then my son came.
I gave all that up, man.
Years ago.
Now I just get through the days.
I try and raise my boy right.
Make up for lost time, you know?
Then how come your boy is
concussed, the other kid is dead...
and you're sitting here
with a bullet in your chest?
Mario? Hey, Mario.
Hey.
When was his last morphine?
Four mgs about an hour ago.
We've got muffled heart sounds.
Pressure's down, 80/60.
Give me the SonoSite. Is there
more blood in the Thora-Seal?
No, not a drop.
All right, squeeze
in a liter of saline.
Mario? Mario!
- Keith.
- Hey, Tone, how you been?
I'm all right. Where is he?
I wouldn't have called
you unless it was bad.
Started up with one of my
customers. Almost got himself killed.
How much does he owe?
Tony, your pop, he's
on a bender, you know.
Most of the time, it's
just the weekends...
I got it. Thanks.
Mike.
What the hell are
you doing here?
Shouldn't you be off playing
doctor with somebody's wife?
That's enough. Let's go.
Get your hands off me.
Enough. You're done. Let's go.
Little Tony.
Come on.
Can't drain with a catheter.
We'll never get it all out.
Is this the tamponade?
He's a candidate for a
subxiphoid pericardial window.
She's right. Prep from
nipples to umbilicus.
- Pressure's only 80 after two units.
- He needs to be decompressed now.
Masks and sterile gloves
for me and Mae Lee.
Thirty cc's of 1 percent lido.
You ever seen a
subxiphoid pericardiostomy?
I've read about them.
- Dr. Dubenko...
- It's a little crowded in here.
Tell the Paxon family Dad's
chest closure went really well.
They can see him in
Recovery. Two of Versed.
Take the edge off.
What are y'all doing to me?
We need to drain blood caught
in the sac around your heart...
keeping it from beating.
CT on the Dunston boy was
clear. No fractures, no bleeding.
- Okay.
- Is that Junior?
Yeah, he's gonna be fine.
Hey.
Can you take a look
at him, make sure?
Versed's going in.
Yeah. Morris.
Hey, man, when y'all
gonna let me out of here?
Oh, my bad. You
got someplace to be?
Don't worry where I gotta be.
Do your chart and
let me up out of here.
What, you got a job to go to?
You going to school or something?
Look, you got a
mild concussion...
so you're getting
out of here today.
It's too bad I can't say the
same thing about your pops.
Man, he ain't my pops.
Only time I ever seen that
fool was on visiting day.
Yeah, well, looks like you're
gonna be visiting him again.
What, you didn't know?
He's going back in for
shooting that Two-Niner.
Hey, Dawn, what was his
name again? Like, Donnie, right?
Mm-hm. Donnie Moore.
Let me tell you
something, Junior.
Your pops, he ain't no joke.
He told five-0 everything.
Man, he must really
want all the credit for this.
Come on, man, you
don't have to front for me.
I mean, tell the truth.
It's gotta be kind of cool, right, to
have a pops with that kind of rep?
I mean, look at him. The man's been
shot eight times and he's still here.
Yeah. That's one bad
dude right there, Junior.
Look, man, don't
call me that, man.
Look, he didn't even do nothing.
I shot that fool.
- Yeah, right.
- It was me.
Yeah, okay.
All right. Look, yo, five-0.
Yo, get your ass in here, man.
Look, he ain't do nothing. He
ain't got nothing to do with this.
I shot that fool and this mother... He
tried to stop me, so I shot his ass too.
I threw my nine down the
garbage chute. Y'all go look, find it.
Look, man, you ain't my
father, man. Stay out of my life.
You ain't my father.
You a bitch, man.
- Man, you a bitch, man.
- Come on, come on.
- Let's go.
- No, get off me.
- Put your hands behind your back.
- Get off me.
Get off me, cop!
We're gonna grab you a hot chocolate
and then go up and see your dad.
- You sure you don't want anything?
- No, thanks, I'm fine.
Why is she so sleepy?
Oh, no, it's just the
medicine. She's okay.
Pulse, 48. BP, 75 systolic.
- Spencer!
- He's unresponsive.
How did you find him?
- Damnedest thing.
They triangulated his cell phone from
text messages someone was sending.
- Spencer, it's gonna be okay.
- I'll go get Dr. Kovac.
CBC, chem panel, EKG, CK, warm
saline, a Bair Hugger and a portable chest.
Honey, stay out there
while we work, okay?
Hi. CHARLOTTE: Hi.
- I gotta go wake up the mom.
- Dr. Pratt gave her 5 of Versed.
- You might wanna try flumazenil.
- You got it.
Are they gonna cut open
Spencer like they did my dad?
No, only if they have to.
I hope they don't have to.
Only 400 cc's of
mediastinal output.
BP is 124/82. Everything
is back to normal.
How about his crit?
Holding steady at 40.
This guy's as tough as nails.
Hey, about earlier...
Oh, no, no, no, don't sweat it.
I just want you to know you
can come to me for help anytime.
- Likewise.
- All right.
Oh.
All right. Hmm.
Hey.
- Hey, um.
- You got it.
You're not supposed
to hang on that long.
Okay, yeah.
- Or that tight.
- Oh, yeah, sorry.
- Peace out, man.
- All right.
So looks like you're good.
No more bleeding in your
chest, nothing around your heart.
Those tubes, they
stay in a few days.
Could I get something to drink?
Uh, yeah. Water okay?
I just wanted to apologize about
how things went down today.
Don't even trip. I
should be thanking you.
Saved my life, man.
I meant your son.
Man, you bust your ass trying
to protect the ones you love.
- Try to keep them from making mistakes...
- Yeah, they make them anyway.
I kept telling him to forget it.
He shot that Donnie kid over nothing,
because he looked at him the wrong way.
Kids, man.
You try to hold on to
them as long as you can.
Then one day, gotta let go.
Then maybe someday
they'll come back.
Yeah, maybe.
Hey, good luck to you, man.
Thanks, doc.
Hopefully, I never
see your ass again.
Hey. They found Spencer Paxon.
Get out of here. How is he?
- Not great.
- Well, do they need some help in there?
Uh, Kovac and Abby are in
there. You have a good night.
All right.
Asshole slumlord.
You got one week, Mike, one.
Should've been paying
me to live in that dump.
Then you're on your own.
You can stay in my room.
Listen, I want you to
know, I really appreciate it.
I really do.
And you won't
even know I'm there.
Hello.
You're home early.
Yeah.
Everyone, this is
Mike. Mike, everyone.
It's a pleasure.
These are the Rileys.
Meg's parents.
Oh.
I'm sorry about your girl.
It's a damn shame.
Where's the head?
Over there.
Who was that guy?
That was, uh, my father.
He wasn't feeling so well,
so I thought I'd help him out.
- Is he okay? GATES:
Yeah, he's fine.
So how many
paintings did you steal?
Just one. A lovely Degas.
It's a poster we're gonna
get framed for my bedroom.
That sounds terrific.
Tony, a minute?
Sure.
Everything okay? Did
she behave herself?
Yeah, you bet. Had a great day.
She seems to be
handling it well.
She has her good
days and bad days.
She's a fighter like Meg.
We don't wanna disrupt her
school year. She's been through a lot.
But we should start working
out the details for the move.
And she'll adjust
quickly. She's young.
Yeah. Well, family's best.
Oh, yeah. We have
six acres, the horses.
- Eh?
- And the good schools.
And we'll want you to visit.
You know, birthdays,
Thanksgiving.
You're always welcome.
Oh, thank you.
Wisconsin is a great place.
It is.
- Hey, Grandpa.
- Yeah.
What's up with that
secret ingredient?
It's secret. Now
remember, don't look.
- You guys seen Tony?
- He left early.
Gates leave me a message, Frank?
Let me check. No.
I'm out of here. You leaving?
Yeah.
Hey. I have info
about Abby and Luka.
Excuse us, nosy nellie.
Can you keep a secret?
It's confirmed.
The wedding is on.
No way. Wow.
I guess this means
I owe you dinner.
Have you ever known
Abby to be violent?
Your rescued kid is crashing.
Kovac wants you back in Trauma.
- Can I go in there?
- No, it's not a good idea.
Wait with your mom.
She'll be waking up.
- I won't freak out, I promise.
- Okay, fine.
Just wait right there.
What happened?
Runs of V-tach. We
need you for CPR.
Temp is 86.
Bypass should be
available by now.
Let's get the perfusionist
down here now.
I'm not cracking his chest.
Excuse me. Hi.
I'm Samantha Taggart.
This is my son, Alex.
We've been expecting you.
Nice to meet you,
Alex. I'm Mrs. Dawson.
I need you to fill
this paperwork out.
Okay.
Yo, Greg, what's up, man?
How you been?
I'm good. I'm doing good.
How about you?
How you think?
Yeah. Stupid-ass question.
Good to see you, dog.
Been a long time.
Yeah. Too long.
But seriously, I mean,
how you holding up?
It's hard, man.
Waiting on trial
over a year now.
Food sucks.
Mostly just miss K.J., you know?
Miss seeing him growing up.
Worry about him
all the time, man.
Then I think about the
kid I hit when I was drunk.
His folks, what I
made them go through.
I don't want this for K.J.
I don't want him
to end up like me.
And ain't nothing I
could do about it in here.
Hey, D, um...
Man, I'm sorry I never
wrote you back, man.
So you got my letters.
Yeah, I got them.
I should've visited.
On the real, man, I
didn't know what to say.
I just know I hate
seeing you in here.
And believe me, I tried to do everything
I could to keep you out of here, but...
Yo, yo, Greg, hey, don't
even worry about that, man.
All that's on me.
If it hadn't been for you, I'd
probably still be out there drinking.
It's all good,
baby. We straight.
I'll always be your friend, man.
Thanks for coming, for real.
Okay, Spencer, can
you squeeze my hand?
Come on, Spencer,
try to squeeze my hand.
There you go. Good job.
Core temp is 94.
Nice work. ICU ready for him?
Yup.
- Is he gonna lose the frostbitten toes?
- Three of them don't look salvageable.
- Small price to pay.
- I'm gonna call Pratt.
He worked on the family.
I'll tell him the kid's okay.
- Do you wanna say hi?
- Can he hear me?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Spence, it's me, Charlie.
You saved us.
You saved us all.
- Okay, let's go.
- Move back, sweetie.
Hello?
Oh, hey, Abby.
Really?
Wow, that's great.
No. No.
No, I appreciate the
call. Thanks for calling.
No. No, no, no, I'm fine.
Really, that's really
good news. I'm just tired.
Yeah, it's been a long day.
All right, then.
All right. Good night.
Bust them in a stereo Cause
I got to keep on walking
On the road to Zion, man
We got to keeps it
burning On the road to Zion
- You remember that?
- How could I forget?
Okay, yeah. That
was a fun night.
That was a fun night.
Oh, God, it seems
like a million years ago.
Well, we could do
that again sometime.
Minus the whiskey. I can't
bounce back like I used to.
Ooh, yeah, tell me about it.
Well, thanks for the ride.
I'll see you tomorrow.
I'm off.
Okay. Then I'll see
you when I see you.
Neela.
We'll just show you
to the room, then.
Okay, buddy.
Behave yourself, okay?
I'll see you in a couple weeks.
Mom, I don't wanna stay here.
Come on. It's gonna be okay.
Mom, please.
I'll be better, I promise,
okay? I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Hey.
You gotta be brave, okay, baby?
I love you.
Mom, I'm sorry, okay?
Mom, please.
Mom, I'll be better, okay?
Mom, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Please.