Biology determines
much of the way we live.
From the moment we're born,
we know how to breathe and eat.
As we grow older,
new instincts kick in.
Oh.
- We become territorial.
- Towel?
Oh.
Ow!
- Oh! Sorry! Sorry.
- Jeez.
Yeah.
You know this isn't normal?
We learn to compete.
- Let's go, Torres!
- Oh, shoot.
- I told him we'd
work out this morning.
- This is like working out,
- it's just more fun.
- - Come on, no pain, no gain!
- Go away, Mark!
- What?
Be nice. He's lonely.
- Did you just say my...?
- Oh!
Right. Nice.
- You finish. I'll wait.
- Uh...
- We seek shelter.
-  - Take a look at some of the fine details up here.
It was built around
the turn of the century.
- These are the original doors?
- You bet.
Wait till you see the upstairs.
Antique hardware on those
windows. That's a cool fireplace.
You know, it's
really a lot of space.
If we knock through this wall,
we'd get all that light to flood through.
You like the fireman's pole?
Hm...
OK, um, this could be our
house. I kinda need you to care.
We'll think about it.
Most important of all?
We reproduce.
I drank a lot of
tequila in college.
- After.
- It's been a while
since I've done OB rotations,
but I don't recall tequila
getting in the way of conception.
- It's the opposite, actually.
- I could have,
uh, endometriosis
- or adhesions or...
- She's gonna come in here
and she's gonna
say everything's fine.
Sometimes biology
can turn on us, though.
So, we have a few
things to discuss here.
Yeah, biology sucks sometimes.
Hostile? Did she really
call my uterus hostile?
Are you forgetting
what she said after that?
What? About my hostile uterus
causing me to miscarry the first time?
Or the likelihood
that it'll happen again?
- That there is a treatment,
she said.
- Hostile.
- You're just getting
stuck on a word.
- How would you feel
if she called your
penis angry or snide?
That's a good point. But the
important thing is that you're healthy.
Just think of all the fun
we're gonna have trying now.
I'm late for rounds.
- You paged?
- Did you know that bariatric centers
are some of the leading money-makers
in hospitals right now, Dr. Bailey?
- I have rounds...
- That's interesting,
considering
that Seattle Grace doesn't have one.
Do you know why we don't have one?
Space, Dr. Bailey. We
don't have enough space.
Oh. Chief, OK, if
you go anywhere near
my Denny Duquette Memorial Clinic,
you'll come to work tomorrow and find me
and every nurse who loves
me chained to its doors.
We need money, Bailey. Ever since
the shooting, we've been in survival mode
when we need to be in fight mode.
Ground-breaking surgery mode.
Back to number one ranking mode.
It's my turn to have
Cristina Yang on my service.
That's all the fight
I have in me today.
- Hostile uterus.
- House hunting with my husband.
At least it's not cancer.
At least you're calling
him your husband.
Oh. Baby steps. Whatev.
Hey. Do you know how long April and
Jackson are planning to stay in the house?
- As long as they like. Why?
- April's taken
over Izzie's room.
Which was fine when it was
temporary, but I live in the attic.
And I sleep next to
Christmas ornaments.
April's best friend just died.
She's all alone.
I'm not evil, it's just...
She's annoying, OK?
I find her annoying.
Really? I find you
much more annoying.
A car ran into a
Laundromat! Multiple traumas!
- I'm not wrong.
- Hm...
Pretty annoying.
You coming?
Baby steps don't include
multiple traumas. You go kill it.
Ooh! Hi. You need to start
sleeping with Mark again.
- I do?
- Yeah. For my sake. You do.
He won't leave us alone, at the
apartment, at work, in our bedroom.
It's like I'm dating Mark against my
will. Come on. Twice a week. That's all.
I am not baby-sitting Mark for
you. Besides, I'm too tired for sex
with anyone right now. I was up
all night dictating charts. Again.
There's a thing called a
resident that can do that for you.
Yeah, and my resident is Avery.
Still knocking over
trays in the OR?
Yes, and scribbling patient
orders in his third-grade scrawl,
and paging me in the middle of the night
for patients who are nowhere near dying.
- At least he's nice to look at.
- True.
Thank you.
You just got called
a dumb blonde.
Can you find out about my
husband? His name's Larry.
- He was in the car with you?
- No, he was in the Laundromat.
I hit him! I don't remember anything. I
was in the car outside the Laundromat.
The next thing I know, the
car's inside the Laundromat
- and there's screaming
and...
- OK.
Do you want to order
her labs or take her scans?
You can take her.
Take it all. Taker.
- What?
- Lost vitals
in the ambulance bay.
Get me epi and charge
the defibrillator now!
That's him! That's my husband!
It's... Is he gonna be OK?
I cannot go out this way.
I can't die in a freak
Laundromat accident. Ow!
- Sorry.
- You cannot
find anything wrong.
I'm supposed to go
to Brazil next week.
Rio. I just perfected my accent.
I'm fine. How are you?
Nope. I just asked you
if you had a condom.
'Cause that's the one sentence I
learn before traveling someplace new.
Yeah. Now, you
totally think I'm a slut.
No, I don't. Um... Take
a breath for me, please.
It totally makes
you think I'm a slut.
Until I tell you I have
Huntington's Disease.
Yeah, you're not gonna
find it on the chart.
The paramedic was so cute,
so I just didn't mention anything,
because the whole
fatal genetic condition,
- it just doesn't scream sexy.
- Have you started
showing symptoms?
No. My, um... my mother died.
So I got tested for the gene. She
was 45, so I have about ten years left.
Five, if you count the
ones I can actually enjoy.
Well, the accident shouldn't
affect your Huntington's.
I know that. I'm just telling you so
that you get that you have to work
really hard to fix me. Because I can
live with the fact that I'm gonna die.
But to die doing laundry? No.
I wanna accidentally fall off the
Eiffel Tower because the three men
and the multiple
orgasms were too much.
You should've
seen it, Dr. Robbins.
His "pottaballet" kicked
the other kids' asses.
- It's pas de bourrée, Dad.
- Isn't that what I said?
You said it in American, Fred.
It's French. Right, sweetie?
Yes. And it's not something
that you really kick ass at.
Can we talk about the cancer
now? Anything to make them stop?
Yeah. Um, Dr. Karev?
Jake Fisher, 15,
osteosarcoma of the right tibia.
Today he'll be getting
a minor bone dissection.
How long after the surgery
before I can dance again?
He's anxious 'cause his ballet
company's doing Swan Lake this spring.
It's like his Super Bowl.
Jake, your recovery will
depend on today's scans.
They'll tell us how much
the chemo shrunk the tumor.
But trust me, we
will have you back
on your feet as
soon as possible.
Can you tell me when
the pain started, Mr. Fink?
A few days ago. I'm a biologist.
I'm in the middle of an experiment...
Pan!
Oh! Stop!
Don't take that anywhere!
That could be research lost.
Sir, you're very sick. You need to
put aside your work for the moment.
It's not just work.
It's a cure for asthma.
- What?
- Dr. Bailey?
Just get rid of the vomit, Yang.
I don't think you
want me to do that.
There's my cure.
Isn't he beautiful?
Research has found worms produce
an enzyme that cut down on allergies.
- I'm applying
the theory to asthma.
- You eat worms?
Yang. How long do
these experiments last?
Mm... Standard is a month or two, then
I take the anti-parasitic to pass them.
But I can extract more
enzyme the longer I grow them.
A year's pushing it, apparently.
You've had these
worms inside you
- for a year?
- 343 days, to be exact.
I haven't had an asthma
attack in six months.
Dr. Bailey?
My, they've grown.
You have a nasty bowel
obstruction, Mr. Fink.
- You need surgery.
- Oh, no, that won't do.
Surgery will throw off
the entire experiment.
- I'd like another option.
- Sir, OK, I'm sorry, but...
It's three years'
research, Dr. Bailey.
Research you'd be contaminating
the minute you cut me open.
OK. Dr. Yang's gonna give you fluid
and put an NG tube down your nose
to open the obstruction.
It will be painful.
And if you don't improve in a few
hours, you're getting the surgery.
Option two it is then.
- You know he's crazy, right?
- Crazy's relative, Yang.
In fact, some people might say
that missing rounds this morning
when I'm in charge
is crazy behavior, too.
But here I am, trusting you
to take care of my patient.
Maybe I'm the crazy
one. What do you think?
Am I crazy to trust you
to take care of my patient?
No. But I haven't been
swallowing worms.
His pain's not too bad. That means
his tumor probably shrunk, right?
- If the chemo did its job.
- Guess who just scored a table
at that new sushi place
that's impossible to get into?
- No way.
- 8:30, table for three.
- You know, I don't eat sushi.
- Yeah, you do.
Yeah. I did, but then I got sick
after I ate one of those pre-packaged
rolls at the cafeteria. Bad memory.
- You two go.
- I'll change the
reservation to two.
- What?
- Torres, you should see this.
God, I hate this job sometimes.
Lila, your CT shows that you
have a ruptured diaphragm.
So you're gonna need surgery.
How will we proceed, Dr. Avery?
Part of your stomach's
gone into your chest,
so we'll place your stomach back
and repair the diaphragm with mesh.
Dr. Grey, do you agree?
I would do a direct repair
with suture instead of mesh
- because the defect
is so small.
- That's right.
Dr. Grey, draw pre-op
labs. You're scrubbing in.
- Lila, do you need us to call anyone?
- No, it's just me.
But I would really like it if
he would wait by my bedside.
Yeah, you and every
other woman in this hospital.
- All right, I'll see you in the OR.
- - Thank you.
Oh, please tell me you've
gotten to make out with that.
No. Married. So no.
That's a bummer.
- Any babies?
- Uh, no.
But thinking about it.
Um, did you need
me to scrub in, too?
The question should be, "May
I scrub in?" Like you want to.
Right. It's... May I?
No, I think I've got
all the hands I need.
Dr. Altman.
I know, I've been
off my game lately,
and you've suffered
because of it.
But right now I need you
to give me another chance.
OK, please?
I... I want to scrub in. OK?
OK. Yeah. I just, um...
OK. OK.
- Mrs. Davis's scans are clean?
- So is her ultrasound.
- I think we should do an EEG.
- Really? Do you
think that's...?
She lost control of her parked
car, has no memory of how.
So I think that's necessary.
But you outrank me, so whatever.
Well, sure, fine, let's do it.
Um... Hey, how would you feel if I
started a chore wheel at the house?
The boys are so messy and I did
one with Reed at our old apartment.
And you'd be surprised
how well it works.
Are you moving in?
Like, permanently?
Um... Why? Do you think that's not
OK? Should I talk to Meredith about that?
That's up to you. But I wouldn't
bring up the chore wheel.
Meredith would hate that.
- Hey. How's our
reckless driver?
- Uh, she's not reckless.
She may have had
syncope or a seizure.
Hey, Mer, Lexie and I were just
talking about the housing situation...
- If this is
about Izzie's room...
- No.
It's not about Izzie's room.
It's about a chore wheel.
April would like to start one.
- That's a great idea.
- What?
Great. I'll set it up tonight. Hey,
um, how'd it go this morning?
- Eh!
- - What happened this morning?
- But you're OK, right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- Why wouldn't you be fine?
- Nothing. I have to go.
- What was this morning?
- You should talk to Meredith.
What are they saying? Are they
saying the chemo didn't work?
We should wait for your parents.
Oh, my God.
You want to cut off my leg.
Look there's a
sprinter with prosthetics
that runs faster than
guys with real legs.
There's got to be another
way. More chemo...
- Prosthetics today,
it's amazing...
- You don't get it!
I need my leg!
- I get it.
- No, you don't.
It's...
I can't explain it.
I...
Just... I'll show you.
Let me show you.
If he gets injured,
this is on you, Karev.
You see that? That's my boy.
It's that... right there.
Build me a leg
that'll let me do that.
And she called it
hostile? That's...
Well, at least it's nothing too serious.
I'll do research on treatment options.
- Her uterus is friendly.
- It's sunshiny.
- Untouched by the
scourge of man.
- Peppy ovaries, too.
Hey. The vending
machine's working again.
- What?
- Nothing.
Is this the same nothing that has to
do with where you were this morning?
I was at the dentist this
morning. I have bad teeth.
Oh, OK. So teeth
are code for what?
I went to the OB today. I have massive
baby-squishing fibroids in my uterus.
- Oh, that's terrible!
- Eh, get over it.
- You knew?
- Knew what?
- Nothing.
- The vending machine's working again.
- My patient eats worms.
- Dude, Altman fire you yet?
- She's not gonna fire me.
- What'd you do?
She thinks he's a hot
piece of brainless ass.
Oh, you're totally
gonna be fired.
Situation is under
control, thank you.
You got a line on any weird
bone cancer treatments,
so I don't have to cut
off my ballerina kid's leg?
Right, cause my
memory's all I'm good for.
There was a story in the news
recently where they used a cadaver bone
- to replace a cancerous one.
- You get my fries.
- You paged?
- Dr. Knox's sister
just put her house
on the market. They just redid
it, it's close to Meredith's house
and it has never been
a fire station. Right?
- You paged me
to talk real estate?
- That,
and I thought you
might want to observe.
Guy got caught between a
car and a washing machine.
You don't see that kind of crush
injury every day. No pressure.
Thank you. But I
have to monitor worms.
- A rotationplasty?
- I don't know.
It's not possible with
this part of the leg.
- Fibular grafting?
- Oh. No. The cancer's
seeded his fibula.
What?
You don't like Mark, admit it.
- I like Mark.
- Liar.
I like him. I do. We're
just... You know.
- We're different.
- Oh, my God. How are you different?
Tell me. Because I don't
think you actually are.
- What?
- Should I leave?
Shut it, Karev. I'm waiting.
Look, it's not that I don't like
Mark. It's just that he's... Mark.
You know? What you
see is what you get.
Besides, you like him. What do I care
if his abs are where his soul should be?
- Oh, my God.
- Found it!
I found it right here!
We don't have
to cut off his leg.
- Page Dr. Bailey
and book an OR.
- Surgery?
No, please, can't we
wait just a little longer?
Your bowel could perforate and
fill your abdomen with fecal matter.
- So no, we cannot wait.
- Can you at least
salvage the worms
- during the surgery?
- Your life is at risk
because of a hypothesis
you can't support.
Otherwise, you'd have the backing
of an actual, accredited institute.
So let the worms go.
I worked in those
institutes my whole life.
I sat in labs, ran other
people's experiments.
I was dead inside. And
now, for the first time,
I know what I'm meant to do
with my life. Everything else,
all my quirks, my fears, the
fact that people find me strange,
none of it matters,
because I know who I am.
Please.
Save the worms.
Let's get him prepped.
"Stroke, infection, heart attack,
severe bleeding, loss of life."
Oh, what the hell.
- When did the chorea start?
- Chorea?
I call that my
spastic hand trick.
- A few months ago, I guess.
- You told your doctors? They know?
- Lila.
- No guilt trip, please.
I was just starting to like you.
But you need to tell your
doctors because they can help.
I watched my mother go through
this, Dr. Grey. I know how this goes.
After the spastic hand
comes the slurred speech.
And then the trouble walking
and the difficulty eating,
and the seizures
and the memory loss.
And then the dementia sets
in so badly that you don't know
if you're in the supermarket
or the bathroom.
So screw going to
the freaking doctor.
I am going to Brazil.
Ah, Dr. Grey. I
can use your input.
Do you think Derek would consider
putting his face on a billboard?
- That's a lot of Derek.
- Pretty good picture, right?
Mm-hm.
- What do you need?
- When my mother was still here,
before she retired, do
you think that she ever
tried to tell you about
the Alzheimer's?
No. She kept it a
secret, for years.
No, I know that. But when
do you think it started?
Do you think she was trying to
tell you and you didn't really realize
that's what she was
trying to do, was tell you?
It's possible, I guess.
I don't remember...
Is everything OK, Meredith?
Yeah, it's fine. Just...
I would never go to a hospital
that put its doctors on billboards.
For what it's worth.
His BP's dropped to 90 over 60,
and he's showing signs of peritonitis.
Good work, Yang. You're
free to scrub in if you like.
Uh, even just to observe. No one's
gonna make you do anything you don't want.
I'm not ready.
Thank you, though, for asking.
OK, so we'll take
out the bone and then
treat it with high doses of
radiation to kill the cancer.
Thirty minutes later, we reinsert
the bone back into Jake's leg.
Usually, the procedure's
done using a cadaver bone,
so there's no risk of putting
cancer back in the body.
But we couldn't find a match
for Jake on such short notice.
So there's a chance the
cancer can come back?
That's why
amputation is less risky.
But if we do this, if you agree,
we will monitor Jake closely,
scans every few months.
And if the cancer returns,
we'll do the amputation.
But this is done a lot?
Uh, it's only been done
a few times in the world.
So if we do this and if we say yes,
there's a chance he'd keep his leg.
- Forever.
- We hope.
It's a big risk, buddy. God knows
I love to watch you dance, but...
What would you do?
- Oh, that's between
you and your folks.
- No. I want to know.
What would you do?
If it was my arm, and I
couldn't operate anymore,
I'd do everything
that I could to keep it.
We've run an EKG, CT
and done blood work.
Fortunately, they've
all come back normal.
You mean unfortunately.
They're waiting to
take my statement.
It was just an accident, Mrs. Davis. You
probably just pressed the wrong pedal.
Tell that to them.
They throw people in
jail all the time for this.
- There's another
test we can run.
- What?
It's called a Tilt test. It can tell us
if you fainted before the accident.
We'll schedule it right away.
- Did you get approval for a Tilt test?
- No.
OK, well, I hate to pull rank here,
but I am a year ahead of you...
We're at work, April,
there's no chore wheel.
If I want to run a Tilt test,
I'm gonna run a Tilt test.
I'd throw a party.
Fly everyone to an amazing
beach, all expenses paid.
I'd have to max out my credit
cards to pay for it, but what do I care?
I wouldn't be
around to pay it off.
- Suction.
- I'd do what Lila did. I'd quit,
sell the house and
bum around the globe.
How would Derek feel about that?
Ah, he could come
along if he wanted.
There's something sad about
that, though. Wandering around,
living in hotels,
that's not a life.
This, though...
Even if I was gonna die
tomorrow, I'd still want to do it.
Can I try the diaphragm repair?
- What?
- The repair. Can I...
Can I try it?
Uh... No, no, you can't.
I'm good though. Thank you.
Oh, he's hypertensive.
Get his pressure back up!
Get some saline in
here, quick. Clamp.
- I need more irrigation in here now!
- - Right away.
- Dr. Bailey, what's wrong?
- He's perforated.
I have to evacuate
this abscess. Suction.
- Can't you just
use antibiotics?
- If I want to risk losing him.
He needs his worms
back for his research.
- The suction will destroy them.
- - I'm concerned about his life now,
Dr. Yang, not his
research. Suction.
You did really good with this
kid today, Karev. Impressive.
Which is funny 'cause I wouldn't
think that you'd be good in Peds
just by looking at you.
OK, fine. I don't
like Mark. At all.
- There, I said it.
- 'Cause you never even tried.
- Oh...
- Take Jake here.
You think his dad was happy
when Jake wanted ballet shoes
for Christmas and not cleats?
No, this guy wanted a kid he could
throw a ball with, you know he did.
But his son loved to dance.
So he signed him up for lessons,
went to recitals and learned
what there was to love about ballet.
He tried. Because
he loved his kid.
Mark stares at my
boobs when we talk.
He starts at my face, but somewhere
along the way he gets distracted
and ends up on my boobs.
And I love guys. I love them.
But I have tried my whole life
to avoid the boob-staring guy.
Biology even helped
me by making me gay.
But now my girlfriend's
best friend is that guy,
and I don't think I need to apologize
for the fact that the only person I want
- staring at my boobs is you.
- Boobs? Really?
- You're making
this about boobs?
- He stares at them!
- 'Cause they're good boobs!
- Can I leave now?
Yes. Go. Hurry.
So we had to remove his spleen and
a kidney, but I expect a full recovery.
- And the girl that was inside?
- She's out of surgery now.
- She's doing great.
- Oh, thank God.
As for your tests, you're in
tip-top shape, Mrs. Davis.
I'll talk to the police, tell
them to come back tomorrow,
so you can have some
time alone with your husband.
- He's not my husband anymore.
- What?
Larry left me three months ago.
He said he needed
time to himself, to think.
A week later, I find out he's
living with someone else.
Her name's Kimmy.
She sings in the
choir at our church.
Kimmy.
It's a ridiculous name, right?
This morning, I'm on
my way to the post office
when I see his car
outside the Laundromat.
Thirty-eight years of marriage, and not
once did he pick up a bottle of detergent.
So I pulled over.
He was inside,
folding a pair of
hot pink panties.
Doing her laundry!
She wasn't even there!
Next thing I know, my
car's inside the Laundromat.
I feel badly... for that...
poor, innocent girl I
hit. I'm glad she's OK.
But... I know now
why they call it the
green-eyed monster.
- Mrs. Davis, I think that...
- It's awful to unload on you.
I know, I know. But I
figured you're used to it.
People must tell you
their secrets all the time
because of the doctor-patient
confidentiality law. Right?
That only applies to medicine.
No, no. You are required
to keep my secrets.
No, ma'am, that's lawyers.
Dr. Avery, I need you to...
Oh. I'm sorry, I'll come back.
No, no. Please. It's, uh...
It's cool. What do you need?
Right.
I wasn't sure if I was making
up stuff in my head, but...
now I know.
I'm doing a CABG.
How do I start?
- Wait, what?
- I'm doing a CABG tomorrow.
You want to scrub in,
so tell me how I start. Go.
Um, divide the sternum, open
the thymus, incise the pericardium.
Then take down the
mammary artery with cautery...
- Bypass has started. Now what?
- Cross-clamp the aorta,
instill antegrade cardioplegia
followed by retrograde...
Now, I want to
take him off bypass.
Re-warm. Check
the flow of grafts.
- Vent the root...
- That's enough.
Good. I'm relieved.
You're actually more than the pretty
face you make yourself out to be.
You knocked over a tray in my OR.
You get the answer wrong sometimes.
Your penmanship needs work.
None of these are fireable offenses.
But flirting, flirting into my
surgery? Batting your eyes
while I'm inside a chest cavity? I should go
to the chief and have you fired right now.
I'm not gonna
do that, this time.
Now, put your shirt on and
take care of these post-ops.
There you are. I've
been paging you.
Oh, my patient needs his
worms. I'm trying to save them. Ew!
A head.
- What's going on?
- Oh, I, uh,
need you to take my blood.
- For what?
- So I can get tested
for the Alzheimer's gene.
It's time I know, one
way or the other, right?
I have a hostile uterus,
what's a little Alzheimer's, too?
OK.
This is a lot bigger
than a baby step.
Just do it before I
change my mind.
OK.
You're still here?
I had to drop these
off before I left.
It's medication for your hand.
But you will have to see your doctor
and get it refilled when
you get back from your trip.
- They can help you, Lila.
- I'll go. Promise.
Oh, come on. I said I'll
go. No guilt trip, please.
Biology says that we
are who we are from birth.
That our DNA is set in
stone. Unchangeable.
There was a complication,
but we were able to take care of
it in surgery. You're gonna be fine.
- As long as you quit the worms.
- I understand.
The surgery destroyed
them all. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Well, every experiment
has its ups and downs.
How much time would you think
before my bowel is completely healed?
No. If you do this again, you
could die. Do you understand that?
Only if I make the
same mistakes. I won't.
Decrease the quantity,
shorten the time frame...
You know, wait, wait. Wait.
Why would you want to put
yourself through this again?
Because I love what I do.
More than anything.
You don't find something
you love that much and let it go.
You hold on to it.
Throw yourself in deeper.
Our DNA doesn't account
for all of us, though.
We're human.
Life changes us.
Post-ops are stable and
I've ordered morning labs.
Hm. Thanks.
Sloan risked his life to save mine.
Even when I was sleeping with his girl.
That's not a guy without a soul.
Maybe he's an ass who
stares at boobs, but whatever.
And your boobs?
You have nice boobs.
Maybe they're lesbian boobs and
you don't like men staring at them,
but men don't discriminate
when it comes to jugs.
You have hot boobs.
And I stare at 'em, too.
We develop new traits.
I was... I was trying
to stop the car...
Become less territorial.
Hey, so reckless driver
turned out to be a psycho killer?
Failed psycho killer. Thank God.
She was heartbroken. Her husband
left her for a younger version of herself.
- She just...
- Lexie.
You know what?
I've been a total bitch to April all
day because of you, you know that?
- What?
- I'm gonna go...
April, just stay.
You worry about April, you
let her have Izzie's room,
you talk to her about
your doctors' appointments.
And I went crazy, Alex
ditched me in a psych ward,
Mark slept with Derek's sister.
And now I find myself relating
to the crazy jealous lady
who drives into Laundromats.
April, you should go.
Lexie, I had a
miscarriage that day.
April was there.
That's why she knows about
my doctor's appointment.
And I did know that
Mark slept with Amy.
But I didn't think you cared. I can
never tell what the hell's going on
with you two. And as far
as the psych ward goes,
you were not alone. I sat by your
bedside for 36 hours while you slept.
You're not crazy,
Lexie. You're a Grey.
We stop competing.
Change of plans. Mark, you're
taking me to dinner tonight.
- What?
- We're going on a date,
you and I.
- Alone.
- Is this to make up
for the fact
- that you don't like me?
- You told him?
- No, I...
- She didn't need to.
Fine, let's go. But
you are buying.
- Thank you.
- You, uh, still want Italian?
- Eyes on my face, Mark.
- Ah.
We learn from our mistakes.
Just... Boys out! Go. Just...
Take the towel and go.
Seriously, if you
want the room...
I admitted I wanted to
drive my car over you,
so taking the room would
just make me feel worse.
But if you put up a freaking
chore wheel, I'll kill you.
We face our greatest fears.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Hi.
- Hi. Mm!
What?
Um... I'm getting tested
for the Alzheimer's gene.
- Oh... No.
- I should know.
- We should know.
- No.
My uterus is hostile. We
probably can't even have a baby.
And even if we could, my brain
is probably full of Alzheimer's,
so I wouldn't even
remember the baby's name.
Or, even worse, I'll pass the
Alzheimer's on to the baby.
Then you'd have an
80-year-old, drooling wife
and a 50-year-old, drooling kid.
- I don't care.
- Derek.
I love you. And you love me.
And whatever
happens, I don't care.
I don't wanna know. I
mean it. I don't wanna know.
The lab already
has my blood. So...
Here's what we're gonna do.
No more doctors, no more labs.
And you and I, we
have a lot of sex.
Maybe we make a baby, maybe not.
Maybe you get
Alzheimer's, maybe not.
Just... Screw the
odds, screw the science.
Let's just live.
Whatever happens,
happens.
Be me and you.
OK?
OK.
For better or worse,
we find ways to become
more than our biology.
The risk, of course...
Cristina?
Is that we can change too much.
Welcome home!
To the point we don't
recognize ourselves.
It's ours. We bought it.
Well, I bought it, but
it's for the both of us.
Finding our way
back can be difficult.
There's no compass. No map.
- I don't know what to say.
- Our house has
a fire pole in it.
- What else is there to say?
- You said this morning...
I don't care where we live.
I really don't. But you do.
You love this place.
And I love you.
We just have to close our eyes,
take a step...
and hope to God we'll get there.