- I gotta go.
- No, no. He'll be here.
I'm sure he's just
running a little late.
He's canceled two
exams. He's not gonna...
He's scared of you. Sure.
The ex-boy toy. Yeah,
that makes sense.
- He wasn't scared before.
- Right.
You think being afraid of me is
a symptom of a serious ailment?
Sudden mood swings, infantile
regression, abdominal pain.
He's passed out twice. Yeah, I
think it might be a medical problem.
- He's 20 minutes late. I'm out of here.
- Please.
He'll be here. Why?
Because he loves you and
does everything he's told?
Because I didn't tell
him you'd be here.
- He likes to see.
- Yes, he does.
Stace?
- What's going on?
- Hey.
Hi. I'm Greg House.
You must be Matt.
- Mark.
- Mark Warner. Don't get up.
Sorry. Parent
conferences. Hi. It's okay.
- Wow. Greg House.
- Yeah. Wow.
No, I haven't been avoiding you. I
just didn't want to waste your time.
The other doctors checked me
out. They said it was just stress.
College season. Kids,
parents—They're all over me.
Makes sense to me.
- Greg.
- What do you want me to do?
- You said you'd check him out.
He says he's healthy.
What's to check out?
Sorry for the mix-up, but I'm glad
you two got a chance to catch up.
- Looks like you're having fun.
- Oh, he's good.
If you can fake sincerity, you
can fake pretty much anything.
I can't tell you how
much I like your fella.
Yeah, me too.
You know, I thought
you'd be all sarcastic.
Bitter, you know,
because Stacy married me.
We should do things together. Maybe throw
a ball around or something. Guy stuff.
- We could go for a run together.
- Ah! It's Oscar Wilde.
Wow. This pissing contest
is really turning me on.
He needs to go to the
hospital. Here's to women.
Can't live with 'em,
you can't kill 'em and tell
the neighbors they're
stripping in Atlantic City.
Damn straight.
- I'm definitely taller.
- I have more hair.
And I think that—Whoa.
Mark?
- Someone call 911 for a wagon
to Princeton Plainsboro?
- Garçon!
What happened?
It's okay, ladies and gentlemen.
Nothing to worry about.
- Unless you had the veal.
- You dosed him.
I told you I'd check him
out. I was a little worried
they were gonna get
here before he passed out.
Would have been
tougher to get him to drink.
I'll give you a
ride. We can talk.
A tummy ache, cranky—
No apparent source.
Any thoughts?
Foreman, you're gonna contribute,
or are you too tired from stealing cars?
I'm being House. It's funny.
I know. You made milk
come out of my nose.
Morning. You guys got
the file. What's wrong?
Previous tests revealed nothing that would
cause abdominal pain or the mood swings.
Then we're done. What do
you think? Ball game? Zoo?
I don't care. I just want
to hang with you guys.
What about drugs?
His tox screen on admission showed
a massive amount of chloral hydrate.
Yeah. Sorry. That was me.
I had to dope him
up to get him in here.
Guy doesn't think
he's sick. Who does?
His wife. The woman
you used to live with.
That's her Indian name. On
her driver's license it's Stacy.
I assume you have a point.
You believe her over the patient
himself. That's why we're taking this case.
The truth? I hear voices all
the time telling me to do stuff.
- It's crazy, huh?
- What happened to "everybody lies"?
I was lying.
Do the things—the blah, blah, blah,
blah. All that stuff the other docs did.
If that's negative,
ultrasound his belly.
If that's negative, C.T. his abdomen
and pelvis with and without contrast.
- Did I miss anything?
- Kitchen sink.
Well, we could certainly
give that— Oh, you minx!
What you're thinking is, you're going
to save him, be a hero and win her back.
It's always impressive, that
level of twisted narcissism.
She's married. Big
clue I lost the game.
You can't be within 50
feet of Stacy Warner.
Thought she wanted
me to treat him.
Treat the husband,
stay away from the wife.
But what if they get close to
each other? What do I do then?
Hey. You have to treat
this like a regular case.
Be yourself— Cold,
uncaring, distant.
Please, don't put
me on a pedestal.
We C.T.'d your abdomen. Nothing
that would explain the stomach pain.
- What's the next move?
- Leaving.
How many more tests do I need?
How many more doctors need to clear
me before we can get back to our life?
- Just one.
- House.
It must be awkward being treated by a
man who used to be involved with your wife.
It's awkward being in a hospital
when there's nothing wrong with me.
M.R.A.'s were clean, which
means he's probably fine.
He doesn't seem paranoid.
He shows no signs of...
No. It means we have no
idea what's wrong with him.
Ben Goldstein says his schedule's
locked. He can't do it before tomorrow.
No. Today. Call him,
tell him I'll make it work.
You're cutting him open?
Oh, hold it. There's no
need for exploratory surgery.
Dr. Cameron has a diagnosis.
No, I just think it's premature
and maybe irresponsible...
to do exploratory surgery
before we know he's actually sick.
No, it's "premature" to put
him on a list for hospice care.
And it's "maybe irresponsible" to imply
my actions are not rationally supported.
All we have is his wife—
Who says his stomach hurts.
Works for me. The patient doesn't even
think he's sick. Why would he consent to...
His wife's a lawyer.
She's very convincing.
Call Goldstein. Surgery is on.
Retract.
Insert.
Leslie versus Leslie
seems to be right on point,
but I'm sure they're going
to try to distinguish it by...
Sorry. They'll try to distinguish
it relying on the minority opinion.
Double milk, no sugar.
I like sugar now.
Some people would
be annoyed by that.
You know why people sit in waiting
rooms? This is gonna be good.
People think the closer they're sitting to
the operating room, the more they care.
That's why I'm here. I'm not
moving until everybody sees me.
Are you doing
anybody besides Mark?
It's a medical question. Because
if I am, his paranoia isn't paranoia.
It's a justified response and
therefore not a legitimate symptom.
Knew you'd understand.
On the other hand, if it
was really just a medical
question, you would have
sent one of your people.
Why just push my buttons
when you can push theirs too?
Hey, Dr. Mandingo, go ask the
wife if she's been messin' around.
But you're asking
because if I am... unfaithful,
I might sleep with you.
The answer's no. I don't sleep around.
Make sure you note that in his file.
Mrs. Warner.
The surgery went well. He's in
Recovery. You can see him now.
Goldstein found nothing
but a distended bladder.
Neurogenic bladder
isn't causing the pain.
It also doesn't cause
personality changes.
On the other hand, it would completely
account for Cameron's diagnosis.
The patient's
completely healthy.
Get me the video of the surgery.
Dr. Mandingo, you're
needed at the plantation house.
Well, don't
everybody talk at once.
There's nothing there.
Stop looking at the suspiciously
empty bottle and look at the screen.
Here's why I get the big bucks.
This is nothing.
An enhanced version of nothing.
This... is the problem.
- Unbelievable.
- Tremors in the muscle fiber.
That's not peristalsis.
- That's abdominal epilepsy.
- Means there's some sort
of neurological problem.
A time bomb in his brain.
I forget. Who said
it was nothing?
I saw a very small, diffuse abnormality
in the brain waves. Probably white matter.
Means his axonal
nerves are dying.
Explains the neurogenic bladder.
Enough nerves die, he dies.
Global axonal nerve death.
Likely causes are
encephalitis or Alzheimer's.
Early onset
Alzheimer's. The worst.
He won't die right
away. He'll just want to.
I'll check the blood for
Alzheimer's protein markers.
Last I heard, Alzheimer's had a genetic
component. Did the patient have parents?
Parents died in a car
crash. No history of dementia.
Send C.S.F. for C.B.C. and viral
serologies to rule out encephalitis...
and get tau proteins to
check for Alzheimer's.
And this still
feels a little light.
I took a complete medical history. Check
out their house. Take Sparky with you.
- They live in Short Hills. Two hours away.
- You can expense the tolls.
You're not interested
in a medical history.
You're a Peeping Tom
trying to spy on your ex.
Her secret diary—
That's the main thing.
But as long as you're there, take
a peek in the medicine cabinet.
Check for toxins, heavy
metals— anything that might
explain this other than
encephalitis or Alzheimer's.
And get receipts for the tolls.
Making lunch? I
assume that's for Mark.
We know about his parents.
What about further back?
Grandparents, uncles, aunts. How
was their health? Greg hates fishing.
He's got a theory.
Most likely candidate
right now is Alzheimer's.
No. There's been no memory loss.
I mean, he forgets where he
left his keys, but who doesn't?
Any family history?
Of... whacked-outness?
His sister voted for Nader,
twice. That's about it.
You were with House
when it happened—to his leg?
Oh.
You're interested in him.
We went on one date.
It didn't go very well.
Our first date didn't
either. I was never
gonna see him again.
A week later, I moved in.
Five years. What
would you like to know?
What was he like before his leg?
Pretty much the same.
He's clear. No Alzheimer's.
Yeah, that's what I figured.
Serious mountain bike. Hasn't
been used in a while though.
He switched to yoga.
Brand-new yoga mat and tape.
Man's getting older. Or it
might indicate back pain.
Wife would have mentioned it.
Yoga's good for picking up the ladies too.
Not when you do it
in your own home.
Change could be just a
change, not a symptom.
Chase.
"Dear 'House' boys, a snack
for your highly illegal search.
Hope you like oatmeal
raisin. Love, Stacy."
Whoa. In a desk drawer, hidden
in the back under some papers.
Secret stash.
Amphetamines. Regular
use could lead to neurotoxicity.
Explains the axonal nerve
damage and the personality issues.
On the other hand,
"Prescribed to W. Brown."
Fake name. Fake prescription.
Could be, but the prescribing
doc, his name's real.
This guy's just had
his license pulled for
writing illegal prescriptions
to high school kids.
Mark's a high school
guidance counselor.
And Mr. Brown's birth date
makes him 17 years old.
Do you think maybe these were confiscated
by a high school guidance counselor?
Anything else? Um, yeah, he
switched from mountain biking to yoga.
- Could indicate— -
He's getting older.
What did the C.S.F.
say about encephalitis?
Said no. Champagne tap.
No red cells, no
white cells. Serology's
negative. Which means
we're back to Alzheimer's.
I told her he didn't have it.
The marker tests were negative.
Well, then you should have
told her that. He could still have it.
PET scan will reveal any changing
metabolic activity in the cerebral cortex.
Run him through and
check his memory.
We're going to inject a
chemical marker called F.D.D.N.P.
Then I'm gonna ask
you a series of questions.
Test my memory.
Yeah, but first we're gonna map
out some specific brain functions.
You know, check out the engine
before we take the car for a drive.
Checking up on me?
- I like all the pretty lights.
- Yeah.
Okay. Here we go.
Your full name? Mark Warner.
- Is your mother living?
- No.
Limbic system's intact.
Okay, say you find a stamped
envelope on the street. What do you do?
- Find a mailbox and mail it.
- Geez. What a guy.
His frontal lobe is working
way better than mine.
Do you remember
when you got married?
Three years ago
this July. Who is that?
What? Could be a problem
with his long-term memory.
- Big church wedding?
- Is that House?
He remembers voices. This
serves no diagnostic purpose.
I thought you skimped
on the limbic system there.
Emotional reactions. I
just want to be thorough.
Did the atheistic bride
wear a pretty white dress?
Was she thinking of you? Is that
what you medically need to know?
What jewelry did
your bride wear?
She never wears any jewelry, except
the cross her mother gave to her.
No underwear either,
at least not that day.
I remember 'cause she ripped
her pretty white dress off in the car.
That the sort of answer
you're looking for, Doctor?
I think I upset him.
You gotta stop this now.
I remember the honeymoon
was in Paris. I remember
'cause we didn't leave
the room for two weeks.
- You want the details on that?
- A little defensive.
It's not paranoia if
someone's out to get you.
Here we go.
He's sick, paranoid, and you
keep hammering him about me?
The questions were
designed to define the
operational parameters
of his limbic system.
Elevate the words all
you want. You were just
screwing with him. Low,
even by your standards.
Medical screwing.
It's what I do.
Then you run away like a 12-year-old.
Go hide on the roof like you always do.
I haven't been up
here in five years.
I don't know what's
wrong with him.
It's not Alzheimer's.
It's not encephalitis.
It's not environmental.
It's not immunological.
Every test is
negative every time.
He's perfectly healthy,
but his brain is dying.
It never occurred to me...
that you couldn't
figure out what's wrong.
I haven't given up.
So what do we do?
We wait.
For what?
Something to change.
It's one of the great tragedies
of life. Something always...
Something always changes.
Nurse?
Nurse!
What happened? What's wrong?
My toes—They were
numb, tingling, then nothing.
No pain. Nothing.
It's okay. They're going
to take care of you.
I'm scared, Stacy. Hold my hand.
What?
What's happening?
Time marches on. He's paralyzed.
His symptoms mimic a peripheral
nervous system under attack.
But he's experiencing
significant paresthesias,
and he can't move
his hands or toes.
It's peripheral.
Guillain-Barré syndrome
attacks there, not the brain.
No. No. I already did
an indirect Coombs' test.
No agglutination, no antibodies.
Initiative. Like that.
Start him on I.V. immuno...
No antibodies means he doesn't
have Guillain-Barré, period.
Period? More like dot, dot, dot.
What if he has the virus but
isn't producing those antibodies?
Come on. The chances of that— Didn't
ask about the Vegas line. I said "what if."
It would mean he's sick, and his
body's not doing anything about it.
So we either fight
it for him or it's fatal.
Fatal sounds very bad to me.
Well, without the antibodies, we can't even
test for it. Don't know if we're right.
Treatment isn't all that dangerous.
Plasmapheresis and I.V.I.G.
If it works, we're right. If he
dies... it was something else.
So the paralysis might
not be permanent.
That's our hope, but the
brain's tricky. You never know.
What was that? What?
- With the head. The look.
- He just wants to talk to me.
- Well, if it was medical,
he should be talking to me.
- I'll be just outside the door.
Leave! Go talk to him.
- You're going to leave me anyway.
- No. That's not gonna happen.
You left him, and he had a
limp. If I can't walk or hold you?
Honey, I'm not going anywhere.
I'm not going to talk to him.
- If I can't feed myself?
- Mark, what you're feeling—
It's not real. It's the virus.
- Mark? What is it?
- Mark?
His throat's closing up. He
can't breathe. Code blue! Hurry!
He's having a reaction to
the I.V.I.G. I need epi, stat.
- I can't get the scope in his throat.
- Stop that.
He's having an allergic
reaction. He's crashing.
No, he's not.
Look at his vitals.
O₂sats are within range.
I'm betting the only
abnormal sign is sweaty palms.
Push two milligrams Ativan.
No allergic reaction.
Just a panic attack.
Something obviously
freaked him out.
Can we talk now?
You couldn’t just
come into the room?
He's had five visitors drive down.
I didn't recognize any of them.
Six more have sent him
flowers, candy and a teddy bear,
which I'm sure he
finds very comforting.
But I didn't recognize any
of the names on the cards.
Shockingly, Mark has friends,
and I have some new ones.
No, it's not shocking
that you have new friends,
but it is shocking that you
apparently dumped all your old ones.
- I haven't.
- No, I didn't think so.
I just think you didn't tell any of
them that you were down here.
Now, why would that be?
What are you up to? It's
gonna take a little while.
Why would you not
tell your oldest friends...
that you were taking Mark
to Princeton Plainsboro
Teaching Hospital
to try to save his life?
I've been busy. I haven't
kept track of who knows what.
See, my old friends are telling me
to be careful. They seem to think...
He. And he sent me the bear.
Figures.
He seems to think
that I'm not over you...
and that it might be dangerous
for me to spend time with you.
I'm thinking your friends
might have similar concerns,
and so you didn't tell
them you'd be here with me.
What's your point? That
I'm still in love with you?
I should abandon my dying
husband, and we should head for Rio.
No.
Greg, I appreciate what you're doing
for us, but I think maybe Wilson's right.
Maybe you should
just stay away from me.
♪♪
What's up?
Love the bear. It's adorable.
My wife's gonna kill me. We're
having company. She cooked.
I got Mark's latest blood work.
He's not responding
to treatment.
I'm sorry.
I was happy.
He's my patient.
I'm sure he's a good guy.
He's probably a great guy.
He's apparently a much
better guy than I am.
And some part of
me wants him to die.
I'm just not sure if it's
because... I want to be with her,
or it's because I
want her to suffer.
Hey. Is it okay if I talk
to Stacy for a minute?
I'll be just outside, honey.
You two are good together.
You know nothing about Mark.
He took you to Paris.
That's good enough for me.
We never went to Paris.
Your honeymoon. It's
been your dream city.
You wanted to go since you were 16.
He actually took you. No, I had to work.
We spent the night in New York. Then
we went back to Short Hills. What is it?
When did Mark switch from
mountain biking to yoga?
About a month ago.
The same time he started
getting sick. What does that mean?
We have two more symptoms.
The patient was asked
a series of questions
to determine the
functionality of his brain.
- You grilled him about Stacy.
- Whatever.
Yeah, the point is, he told us everything
we need to know to diagnose him.
That is, if we use your fancy
PET scan as a lie detector.
See, it's a very
creative process, lying.
Now, telling the truth is a
much simpler process. See here.
Question nine. This is
where Mark gives a long,
rambling answer about
taking Stacy to Paris.
What does the PET scan say?
Minimal involvement. Just
the frontal and temporal lobes.
He said he went to Paris, and
the PET confirms it. So, what?
They didn't go.
They didn't go to Paris, and yet
Mark's brain apparently thinks...
that he really did spend 40
francs on a tour of the bastille.
So we have an intermittent syndrome
that presents with abdominal pain,
polyneuropathy, paranoia...
and delusions.
Now, here's the thing about
Acute Intermittent Porphyria.
It'll jump you in a dark alley, beat
the crap out of you, leave you bleeding.
But it wears gloves,
so no fingerprints.
Doesn't show up in blood
tests, urine tests, nothing...
unless you catch it red-handed
in the middle of an attack.
But there are other
symptoms of A.I.P.
- Such as?
- Light sensitivity.
Yeah. One of the true
tragedies of this condition...
is it makes you want to stick your
cool new mountain bike in the garage...
and take up an indoor
sport like, say, yoga.
Start the treatment.
Hematin and glucose.
If you give him Hematin now
and you’re wrong, he dies today.
There's only one way to confirm A. I.
P.— Urine sample made during the attack.
And there's no way to predict
when he'll have another attack.
Sure there is.
Acute Intermittent Porphyria
has very specific triggers.
Barbiturates, alcohol, high levels
of protein will set off an attack.
Which trigger do you think set
off Mark's? Not the faintest idea.
That's why I'm gonna give
him the combo plate. All of it.
So if he has this, and you trigger an
attack, the attack makes him worse, right?
Yeah. But then we'll know
what it is and we can treat it.
But if I don't have this thing and
you give me that shot, what happens?
No idea. If we don't
know what's messing up
your brain, we don't
know how you'll react.
Okay, I—I need a
minute with my husband.
He doesn't want the trigger.
He wants to wait, see if we can
come up with another explanation.
If it is A.I.P., how much
time does he have?
No idea. Next
attack could be fatal.
Could be six months from now.
Could be five minutes from now.
I want you to test him. Fine.
I'll send for an
H.M.B.-synthase mutation.
Genetic test. Lab will
get back to us in a month.
Give him the cocktail,
set off an attack.
No. Why not?
Because he doesn't want me to.
I'm not gonna sue you.
I'm not gonna report you.
He might. He's paralyzed.
Either you cure him, or he
won't be writing any letters.
I'm not gonna do it. Why not?
You keep asking me that
question. My answer doesn't change.
I gave him the
parameters. It's his call.
You want him to die. I
diagnosed him. I did my job.
You want somebody to
tie him down and force him
into treatment, you're
way better at that than I am.
Is that what this is? Payback
for your leg? How many
times have we been
over this? I saved your life.
Yeah, maybe. You're gonna kill
my husband to teach me a lesson?
No. He's gonna die 'cause he's
too stubborn to make the right choice.
Now we're in your territory.
I'm respecting your
husband's decision. I
don't see why you've
got a problem with that.
Because it's crap.
Because you browbeat patients,
intimidate them, lie to them.
If you think you're right, you
don't give a damn what they think.
I did what you do all the time.
The only difference is, I did it to you.
He'll never forgive you.
Yeah. He will.
Still no change. He's
not getting worse?
No. No change at all.
And that's consistent
with A. I. P., right?
Until he has another attack,
his condition's stable. Yeah.
- Mark, you've got to.
- I don't want to take that test,
not until they're sure.
- You don't know Greg.
- Not like you do.
I only met him
when he drugged me.
Boy, are my ears burning.
- What's that?
- Cocktail hour.
Just 'cause you can't hoist a few
doesn't mean you should be left out.
- Get away from me.
- Mark, if this is what he thinks
is wrong with you...
You trust his judgment more
than mine? His medical judgment.
And you'd bet my
life on that? I would.
I don't.
Smart.
It's too bad you're paralyzed.
Bing! Paging Dr. Foreman.
Leave the room. It's not your
problem. You need the consent from him.
But, Doc, he ain't right in the
head. Then you need a court order.
Okay. Then get one. We'll
wait here. I won't do nothin'.
Oh! Love the Musketeer thing.
- I got goose bumps.
- Give me the syringe.
Please. If you’re right,
this may be his only shot.
So what's your plan? You take
the big dark one, I've got the little girl,
and the Aussie will run like a
scared wombat if things turn rough.
I can't do it.
You son of a bitch!
See what I did there?
- When does it happen?
- If he had A.I.P.,
should've already happened.
- Everyone's different.
- This is not good.
He could have an
embolism, tachycardia, stroke.
What's happening?
Two milligrams of Ativan.
Is that an attack?
- Here.
- No. You'll pollute the sample.
- Chase, get urine from the catheter.
- It's not an attack! He's stroking.
He needs Ativan!
This is not a stroke. The
delta-wave burst is just a vasospasm.
Catheter's out. There's no
way to collect the sample.
Heart rate's in the
40s. Bradycardia.
- We're losing him.
- Hold him down.
- Give him something!
No painkillers. You were wrong.
Straight from the bladder.
That's as fresh as it gets.
Would you give him
the Ativan already?
He doesn't need
to be awake for this.
It's still yellow.
Move.
- What?
- You think another light's
gonna make the difference?
Organic chem— More
light, more oxidation.
Does that ring any bells?
Start the patient on 150 milligrams
glucose, 75 milligrams Hematin.
Hey. Hey.
You wanna thumb wrestle?
Come on. Oh!
He's still a maniac. I know.
Dr. House?
How's he doing?
Never better.
I thought...
you were too screwed
up to love anyone.
I was wrong.
You just couldn't love me.
That's good.
I'm happy for you.
♪♪
You fixed him.
De nada.
Thank you.
You were right.
He's gonna be fine.
No. About me.
I'm not over you.
You were—You were the one.
You always will be.
But I can't be with you.
So I'm the guy,
but you want the other guy,
who, by definition,
can never be the guy.
What's so great about you is
you always think you're right.
And what's so frustrating about you
is you are right so much of the time.
You are brilliant,
funny, surprising, sexy.
But with you, I was lonely. And
with Mark, there's room for me.
Okay.
I want to run something by you.
I will not have sex
with you! Not again.
It was miserable
that first time.
All that desperate
administrative need.
Stacy's husband is going to need
close monitoring at the hospital,
and since we can
definitely use her back here,
I've offered her a
job— General counsel.
Did she say yes?
She said only if it
was okay with you.
Yes or no?
Fine. Good.
That's some bad hat, Harry.