Previously on "The
Good Doctor"...
You put me here, and I'm
really angry about that.
I am sitting in this chair
because of that surgery.
I enjoyed our field trip.
I had a good time, too.
I'm sorry. I just...
I can't.
I know how to fix everything.
There's a surgery that
will cure Lim's paralysis.
It's not the cord.
It's a deformity of
the spinal column.
Even if there's kyphosis,
that doesn't mean...
She used to have
a 10-degree curve.
Now it's 15.
So, what do you propose?
We go through the abdomen
and chest, fix the deformity,
and stabilize the column
with cage, plate, and screws.
With the tension in the cord
relaxed, her body can heal.
It will fix the paralysis.
That might work.
Might. Might work.
Might doesn't cut it,
especially with the amount
of instrumentation
around the spinal cord.
You could poke a hole in
the gut or in the lung.
Sepsis is a very
real possibility.
I won't poke a hole in anything.
Do I need to remind
you how confident
you were the last time?
I'm sorry, but the odds aren't
good enough, not for me.
Then better the odds.
You two see if you can find a
surgery in our comfort zone.
Any objections?
No.
Then I need to get started.
I will be very busy this week.
And you never
fainted before today?
No, never.
Actually, I guess I
fainted last week.
I was at recess.
I just sort of woke
up on the ground.
I thought you wouldn't let
me do the Halloween pageant.
I'm sorry.
It's okay. We just
want you to get better.
So, you're Cinderella.
I have the main solo. I'm
singing "No One Is Alone."
Sondheim. I love it.
What's your favorite?
Why is there singing?
And why are you... green?
It's Halloween.
Heart rate's still 38 BPM.
Hopefully, we can get you
back in time for your solo.
We can't.
The electrical system in
your heart is malfunctioning
and you risk cardiac arrest.
We can easily implant
a pacemaker today
to keep it functioning normally.
Once it's in, a
pacemaker is very safe.
W-Why is this happening to her?
We will do blood work and
electrophysiologic studies
to find out.
Plus, genetic workups
on all three of you.
If it's inherited, you
might be at risk, too.
Happy Halloween.
Captions by VITAC...
I get dizzy a lot
'cause I banged my
head when I was a kid.
They know, buddy.
Oh, yeah.
Sometimes I forget stuff, too.
Chris is always
looking out for me.
He picks me up from
day care every day.
He cooks me dinner, and he
lets me play video games.
Sounds like a good brother.
Tell them what we
say to each other.
I say, "I got your
back, little bro."
And then I go, "I got
your back, big bro."
Nice approximation
of the wound edges.
You're good to go, Ollie.
Back's been bugging
me. Joys of aging.
Your pants are pretty loose.
Lost a little weight recently.
When did you see a doctor last?
I don't know.
Between Ollie and
looking for work...
Mind lifting up your shirt?
We're gonna order lab tests and
a C. T. for you, just to be safe.
That potential assistant I
liked, with the septum ring?
Mm-hmm.
Well, I watched her TikTok,
and now I'm looking
for another one.
You reading your tablet?
Yes, but I'm also
listening to you.
With the Dr. Lim surgery,
I have to do two jobs.
Well, how about you
start after our lunch?
This is a growth opportunity.
As a boss, you need to delegate.
You think I write every
line of code myself?
I am a surgeon. I
cannot delegate surgery.
So, figure out the
elements of your job
that only you can do
and delegate the rest.
That is a good idea.
The Force is with me.
Nice. Love it.
Ooh. Gorgeous.
So, the navy blue dress
or the black skirt?
They're all great. Your
date's gonna be blown away.
Not necessarily my date.
My neighbors aren't taking
me to romantic restaurants.
Your neighbors are
a 90-year-old couple
and that hermit who likes
to talk to his geodes.
It's a date, right?
This is my floor.
Wise answer, matey.
Date.
Date. Definitely a date.
Which is a problem 'cause
those outfits suck.
What else you got?
Trashy... frumpy... slutty...
not slutty enough.
God, no. Anything else?
In my closet.
We'll meet there. 8:00 p. m.
Try to
hold still, Chris.
This will just
take a few minutes.
Okay.
I would have thought that you
had more Halloween spirit.
Oh, I have a lot.
But as a professional woman,
I express it after work.
Interesting. Mm-hmm.
What are you up to?
There's a big pub crawl
around San Pedro Square.
A bunch of us are going.
That sounds fun.
Want to join?
I think I'll skip. But thanks.
No problem.
I think I made things weird
between us last night.
It's fine.
A three-centimeter mass
partially compressing
the bile duct.
Pancreatic cancer.
Hey.
You wearing that in the O. R.?
I got the genetic testing back.
Skyler has hemochromatosis.
Explains the heart problems.
Yes, but look at her
parents' results.
Mom carries the recessive gene.
But not her dad.
Which means he's not her dad.
And given how he let us test
him, he doesn't know it.
What are we gonna
tell her parents?
The genetic testing results.
Placing the generator in
the infraclavicular pocket.
Any thoughts on how?
Without destroying
their marriage, I mean?
I will delegate that
task to you two.
It will be a growth opportunity.
You also need to inform
Skyler's biological father
that he's the carrier.
Well, we don't know who he is.
Then it will be an even
bigger growth opportunity.
Adsons and 3-0 vicryl.
You have stage three
pancreatic cancer.
That means it hasn't
metastasized yet,
but it's spread to
your lymph nodes.
So, I'll... I'll do chemo?
Chemo, radiation,
molecular therapy
would give you
about eight months.
There is a very
extensive surgery
called the Whipple procedure.
It involves removing
your gallbladder
as well as parts of your bile
duct, pancreas, and intestines.
Okay. When can we do it?
It only has a small
chance of success,
and if it fails, you'll have
less time and more pain.
When Ollie was a kid, my
mom worked from home a lot.
She always had me looking
after him, which I hated.
One day, I was reading comics...
and he fell down the stairs.
You were just a kid yourself.
Ollie's injury isn't your fault.
I will do anything
to be there for him.
We'll order the pre-op testing
for the Whipple procedure.
I'm busy.
No, you are waiting on
your patient's
ear wax to soften.
We can use a thoracoscopic
and laparoscopic approach
with endoscopic decompression.
I want to present
it to Dr. Lim.
No.
This approach has been
used for tumor surgery.
Did you say "surgery"?
We're not talking about you!
It's less invasive
than my initial idea,
with a lower risk
of vascular injury.
I said no, Shaun.
This is wild.
It's like Rice Krispies
popping in my ear.
I did what Dr. Andrews said.
I lowered the risk of injury.
You didn't do what
Dr. Andrews said.
You didn't raise the
chance that we're gonna fix
her paralysis. Paralysis?
I am not talking about you. We're not
talking about you! Tilt your head.
Not good enough.
Jacob will be back soon.
Let's start with us.
The pacemaker is working great.
Thank God.
But she has a genetic disease
called hemochromatosis.
Um, excess iron is
building up in her body.
That's why she was
having heart issues?
Yeah.
And there's a small amount
of damage to her liver,
but it looks like we
caught that in time.
Iron is carried in
red blood cells,
so the main treatment is
just regular blood draws.
That's it?
Great.
Because of the forms you signed,
we're supposed to tell you
and your husband
these results together
and explain that hemochromatosis
is a recessive genetic disorder,
which means that for Skyler
to have the condition,
the gene needs to be
carried by both parents.
And then we'd explain
that you carry it,
but... your husband doesn't.
But that doesn't...
Oh, God.
Jacob's old college roommate.
We were really close
with him and his wife.
Jacob suspected,
but I denied it.
He was just so amazing,
and I was in a rut.
Jacob and I are good now.
Skyler is his daughter. I
don't want that to change.
We can't avoid your husband
finding out his test results.
Can you give us the
biological dad's info?
He needs to know he's a carrier.
I don't want him involved.
We can't tell him anything
about you or Skyler.
Privacy laws.
But if he has other children,
they could be in danger.
Mick Kang.
I better
go talk to my husband now.
Are you trying to look
like a stalk of celery?
Oh.
Ohh!
My go-to in the before times.
Pair it with...
The Louis Vuitton blouse?
Mm-hmm. Yes.
And... these.
Hot, classic.
Well done.
Only issue... They could
be hard to get off.
A feature or a bug, depending.
Let's take a break.
What's going on?
I'm a different person
now, with a different body.
That he apparently
finds attractive.
You'll figure it out.
It's not only sex.
I worry I'm just racing
to start my life again.
How much do I even like him?
Is he a nice guy?
Definitely. Cute?
Pretty cute.
Having just lost a nice
and pretty cute guy,
it goes a long way.
This'll work.
Doesn't look like we can
preserve the pylorus.
We can reassess
early in the surgery.
I was an idiot the other night.
When I almost kissed you.
Obviously, I like you.
But it's a line I can't cross.
If this is because
we work together...
It's not.
I can't date anyone right now.
But I really hope we
can keep being friends.
Okay.
If we don't do a distal, we
run the risk of... Hold up.
We clearly both like each other,
but nothing can happen for
some reason you won't share.
But you still want to hang out?
Yeah.
Let's look at the
common hepatic artery.
Our other growth opportunity's
waiting in the cafeteria.
You think I carry
a gene for this...
Hemochromatosis.
So, if you have kids...
Yeah, two boys.
6-year-old twins.
The warning signs
would be bronzed skin,
liver problems, lack
of energy, joint pain.
No.
As far as I know,
they're totally healthy.
How did you find
out I'm a carrier?
I've never even been
to this hospital.
I'm sorry. We're
limited by privacy laws.
But as long as you and your kids
get checked out, you'll be fine.
Privacy laws? Who...
Whose privacy?
I'm sorry. We can't
say anything more.
Jacob?
Daisy had a kid?
Hey, look, man, um, they
just... They called me in here.
I didn't...  No!
No, no, no, no, no. Don't!
Ah!
Ow.
Okay, residents, that
did not work at all.
You chose a very bad
place to meet Mick,
and then Mick got
his nose broken,
and then Mick complained
that you got his nose broken,
and then Dr. Andrews
berated me
for not being a good attending
when all I did was
delegate to the two of you.
She suggested meeting
him in the cafeteria.
And you didn't object. As a
feminist, it's not my place to...
You both did terrible jobs.
I have to work on
Dr. Lim's surgery.
Go check on Skyler's pacemaker.
I can see the
common hepatic artery.
Resecting the large lymph
node anterior to it.
Dr. Park, the abdominal wall.
That's not local spread.
Metastasis. We can't finish.
We have to close him
up, reverse what we can.
We will go in
posteriorly at T9-L1.
With no anterior
instrumentation,
she'll be at a lower risk of
postsurgical complications,
and her prognosis
will be improved
by completing
posterior osteotomies
to release tension on the cord.
Still too risky.
Have you even
apologized to Lim yet?
I have nothing to apologize for.
Oh, my God. Shaun.
Oh, you are still mad at me
for not following orders.
That's why you keep
shooting down my ideas.
You didn't listen to
me, and you're refusing
to accept responsibility,
so yeah, I'm a little mad,
but I'm shooting down your
ideas because they're too risky.
I don't believe that.
Okay, fine, don't
believe it, then.
I want you to stop
being mad at me
so you will like my ideas again.
Doesn't work that way.
Then how does it work?
How long are you
going to be mad at me?
I don't know.
I'm gonna go finish
my clinic hours.
Is there something wrong
with her pacemaker?
Her heart is fine.
She has jaundice.
Her liver is failing.
Hypotension from the heart block
caused unexpected shock liver.
She has been listed for
a transplant on UNOS.
I've asked for an
exception to speed it up,
but at this rate she will die
before a donor liver
becomes available.
We tested her mom.
She's not a good match,
and her dad isn't either,
since he's not her dad.
What about her
biological father?
The mom's been calling him,
but apparently he blocked her.
We could try.
You got him punched in the face.
I will talk with him instead.
No. Y-You said before that
I might have eight months.
We didn't know it
had metastasized.
I always said I
wouldn't do this to him.
You're not doing anything
to him. You're sick.
He's gonna wind up
in a group home.
There are good ones.
Patient Services can advise you.
Should we get your brother
so you two can talk?
Yeah.
Got a minute?
Not really.
Patient of mine...
he's devoted his life to
taking care of his brother,
who's got a traumatic
brain injury,
but he's dying of pancreatic
cancer and he's terrified.
The Whipple procedure
is the only...
This isn't a surgical question.
I was hoping you'd talk to them.
About your experiences with
Steve, and after he died.
Why?
It would be great for them to
see how well you've turned out.
I don't know his brother
will turn out well.
I have ASD, but he
has a brain injury.
I know, but... I lived in a bus.
I don't know where they live,
but it is almost
certainly not a bus
or you would have
already mentioned it.
I still think it could help.
It's much more likely I can help
with fixing Dr. Lim's paralysis.
Your patient is dying anyway.
Why are you in this office?
I have a meeting.
You're making this
worse with Shaun.
You do realize that, don't you?
You're making him more upset.
He's got to take
responsibility for what he did.
He's trying.
And you staying pissed at him
isn't going to
help that process.
Which is exactly why
I'm gonna stay away.
Well, you can't
avoid him forever.
Yes, I can. Stop it!
You're mad at him. He's
not going to apologize.
Someone's got to
make the first move.
And that has got to be me?
Yeah, of course it does.
He's a grown man, and
he's your husband.
He has ASD, and he's your son.
Your daughter is
in liver failure.
None of her relatives
are suitable donors,
but you might be.
You want me to give my liver?
Just one lobe. The full
liver would kill you.
I've never met her.
I mean, I...
I only heard about
her a couple days ago.
Okay, you're... You're
biologically linked.
That gives you responsibility.
I have two little
boys who need me,
a wife I'm already in
couples therapy with.
I feel sorry for this girl.
I really do.
But I cannot destroy
my family for her.
My brother's going to be
okay. We're going on a trip.
Ollie, how about
Nurse Hawks here
takes you to the cafeteria
to get some ice cream, hmm?
Sundae?
Go for it.
I found a website for
a clinic in Mexico
that offers a cure
for pancreatic cancer.
Immunotherapy, stem
cells, supplements.
I know these clinics.
They're scams preying
on desperate people.
What do I have to lose?
Your money, for one thing.
Your brother will need
it after you're gone.
If he loses me...
he'll never make it.
He will.
You don't understand.
Growing up, um, my
family was really close.
We worked the farm together.
My brother...
My brother was my best friend.
One day, the tractor rolled,
and my brother herniated
a disk getting it back up.
Doctor gave him Oxy,
and 18 months later
he moved on to heroin.
Counselors, they, um...
They told me, my mom, my dad
to cut him off,
that he needed to
hit rock bottom.
So we did.
And he did.
For a while there, it
felt like he was gone.
My brother tells me now
that our family's love,
everything my
parents taught him,
that's what got him through.
We saved him, even
when we weren't there.
Last month, he actually, um...
He marked five years sober.
Ollie can handle this.
Tell him the truth.
Don't argue with
me. - I'm not!
Stop acting like a brat.
Let's go now.
That was school.
You hit Susan Dawkins again?
She was being mean to
me, like she always is.
Well, we talked
about this, Maddie.
All you got to do
is... Is stay away.
Why do I have to
change what I do
when she's the one who's mean?
Because hitting people
isn't acceptable, Maddie.
Sometimes in life,
people are gonna be mean.
You always make
everything my fault.
No, I don't. You're
supposed to be on my side.
I'm trying to be on your side,
but you make it
damn near impossible
because you never listen to me!
You don't listen. You
just boss me around.
Oh, my God. Okay.
You know what?
Just go to your room. No.
What did you say to
me? Go to your room.
I hate you.
I said go to your room!
Hepatic encephalopathy.
Without a new liver,
she'll be dead by tomorrow.
Did you get the
exception from UNOS?
No.
Then it's over.
It's not.
Her biological father
could still be a match.
First, you two failed with
Mick, then I failed with Mick.
We need to figure it
out together this time.
Ollie...
we're not gonna go to Mexico.
Are you better?
No.
Are you dying?
Yeah.
But we are gonna spend
every minute together.
And I'm gonna find you
a great group home.
And I know that's hard.
Ollie, I am so sorry.
Rajan's in a group home.
Rajan. From my day group.
He says he's got his own bedroom
and the people are nice.
He's okay.
I got your back, big bro.
I got your back, little bro.
Can I come in?
I am mad at you.
And for good reason.
But no matter how mad I get,
I never stop loving you.
I didn't tell that
to Maddie enough.
I don't know what you want
me to take away from that.
That I love you.
I do too.
And that I had good reasons...
Non-emotional reasons...
For shooting down
your earlier ideas.
But I think there
might be something
to that endoscopic plan, maybe.
Do you have any of
her C. T. scans?
I have many of them.
Well, let's start with one.
Thanks for coming out, guys.
That was beautiful.
Thanks.
I'm Lea.
Mick. First time at the show?
Yeah. Yeah.
Uh, can I... Can I
show you something?
Sure.
Wow. She's... incredible.
Your daughter?
N-No.
Yours.
We'll go in posteriorly
with minimally invasive
percutaneous screws
and do a complete
vertebral column resection
at the maximally
kyphosed segments,
then reconstruct the vertebral
bodies with an expandable cage.
You're building a whole
new spinal column.
It's the safest way to remove
the tension in your cord
and let your body do its work.
You came around?
I wouldn't say I
came around exactly,
but I don't think
it's crazy to say yes.
At this point,
it's not a medical question.
It's an emotional one.
You got to ask yourself, how bad
do you want out of that chair?
I'll think on it.
You look...
I'm gonna use a highly
precise term here...
snazzy.
Well, I spent hours applying
very expensive snazz.
You look great, too.
Thanks.
Reservation for
two under Joseph.
One moment.
Is this the only entrance
into the dining room?
It's an old building.
I'm so sorry.
A couple of waiters are
coming down right now.
They'll carry you and
the chair upstairs.
It's no problem.
Um...
You know, I have always loved
this little courtyard
area out here.
Could you possibly bring down
one of those corner tables
and a couple of chairs?
Uh, just one, actually.
I come equipped.
I'll make it happen.
Thank you.
"A New Hope" is, of
course, a perfect movie.
Correct.
But, talking about
the recent ones,
ah, there's one that, for
me, really stands out.
"Rogue One."
Yes! Oh!
Oh, that ending!
Genuinely a stunner.
Oh, not just for the franchise,
but for any Hollywood
blockbuster.
So, what are we watching?
I'm sorry.
I didn't think that, uh...
Should I go?
Yeah.
I'm guessing it wasn't a date?
If it would help, I
could tell you about
what I thought was a
romantic trip to Acapulco
right after my accident.
It wouldn't.
It never even occurred to him
that I would think
it was a date.
Don't do the surgery.
Whatever Dr. Murphy
is proposing
I'm sure sounds
pretty good right now.
Do you even know
what he's proposing?
This is about you wanting your
old life back at any cost.
I've been where you are.
The first year
after I lost my leg,
I would have risked
anything to get it back.
But I like my life now.
I like who I am now.
Give yourself time.
Skyler? Can you hear us?
Mommy?
Oh, careful. You've
got a lot of stitches.
What happened?
You got really sick, but
these doctors fixed you up.
This man gave you
part of his liver.
He saved your life.
Who are you?
I'm Mick.
See you on Monday.
Five years sober, huh?
Do you even have a brother?
I do. But, um, he's
not the addict.
And... your addiction...
Is that the reason
why you and I can't...
Yeah.
About six months
ago, I had a setback.
Bought some heroin.
Flushed it before I
took it, but still.
My first priority is making
it to midnight without using.
My second is becoming a surgeon.
And I don't know
how to add a third
without risking the others.
Thank you for trusting me.
I really hope we can be friends.
Yeah.
We're friends.
I have reserved an O. R. for
tomorrow afternoon in case...
I've decided
against the surgery.
Thank you for your work.
Why?
She doesn't owe us an
explanation, Shaun.
Yes, she does.
I revised my plan,
like you told me.
Shaun.
I can look for less
invasive methods.
Shaun, stop.
I-It's not fair. Shaun, stop.
Dr. Lim, if your concern is
recovery time... You know what?
You don't have to stay for this.
I can show... Stop!
It's not fair.
Tell me the reasons why
you think it's not fair,
and I'll try to explain it.
I'm sorry.
I heard Lim said
no to the surgery.
You did the right thing trying.
It accomplished nothing.
When I went back to Hershey
to help my family's company,
I thought it would
fix the business,
fix things with my brother,
fix things with my parents.
Failed on all three.
But I'm glad I did it.
That makes no sense.
I'd rather do my best and fail
than always regret not trying.
When people are in
pain, try to help them.
Even if you think it
won't change anything?
That only makes it braver.
Thanks for coming.
I am Dr. Shaun Murphy.
Dr. Park wants me to talk
to you about my life.
I don't know if I can help.
But I am going to try.
Okay...