I think
you killed my father.
Give me an hour to get
to O'Hare. You'll never
see me again.
No.
We could've been so happy.
No! No, no, no,
no, no, no, no.
I need help in here!
I'm leaving Med. I...
I'm never gonna be able to
get past what happened here.
I need a fresh start.
I heard Dr. Manning
was in an accident?
Dr. Marcel.
Who are you?
I'm her fiancé.
I'm so sorry, Natalie.
What are you doing here?
I don't want you coming
around here again.
We're getting married.
What?
I don't remember you
asking me to marry you.
You will.
They found a mass.
Metastatic adenocarcinoma.
I don't want anyone to know.
I don't wanna be
the sick person.
God, when is it
gonna stop?
Hey, um, I'm sorry.
I think it's empty.
Oh. Hold on, I need
to get you unhooked.
I just don't wanna
be late for work.
Work? You just got
a bag of chemo.
You need to go home
and get some rest.
Uh-uh. It's my friend's first
day back after an injury.
And besides I have
an ED to run.
At Med?
Yeah.
They have a huge
infusion center.
You don't have to come
all the way over here.
I like to keep things
separate. And besides,
I love what you're
doing with the donuts.
Careful if you're driving.
Roads are a mess.
Yeah, thanks!
The third year
of med school will not only be
the most difficult
of your lives,
but also the most important.
Anyone know how many patients
come through our ED
in a single year?
105,000. It's 18,000 acute,
and 4,600 active traumas.
That's right.
You thinking about
going into ED med?
Is there anything else?
Anyway, for each of you,
the ED will be
both a challenge
and an opportunity
to sharpen your skills.
He loves giving this
lecture, doesn't he?
He's the only one
who volunteers.
Every single year.
Oh, I'm sorry. I thought
I had a patient.
Hmm?
Are you okay?
Yeah, just got shanghaied
onto the day shift.
Late nights, a little
pick-me-up.
Crockett Marcel,
fourth year, surgery.
Oh.
Noah Sexton.
Nice to meet you,
Noah Sexton. You mind?
Sure.
Teamwork.
So, future ED doctor,
I presume?
No. I mean, yes. But...
Well, my real plan
is to open some Urgent Cares
after residency
and try to build a brand.
Maybe take it public.
Sounds ambitious.
Then again...
I don't even know how
you folks manage to start
so soon after last call.
Hmm. Well,
see you around.
Oh-ho-ho!
First day of school.
Dang, how long we
been doing this for?
Long enough, you should know
to get a better umbrella.
Are you aware that in some
cultures, a downpour
is considered
very good luck?
Really?
Yeah.
Which cultures?
I don't know.
Dry places? Yemen?
Oh!
Relax.
The power must've gone out.
The back-up generator's
kicking in.
I better go
talk engineering.
I'll see you later.
See ya.
We must not be moving
patients fast enough if they
had time to deliver these.
Nice.
Actually,
they're for Natalie.
They're from Phillip.
It's her first day
back and all.
Oh.
Well, I'm sure
they'll look great
on her kitchen table.
Yeah.
Usually, we would...
Dr. Choi!
An ambulance skidded out
a couple blocks away.
They need help.
I'm on it.
Me too.
You in?
Yeah.
Hey, Capp!
Anybody hurt?
Driver here is okay.
That the ambo?
Patient's stable, older guy
with chest pain.
But the paramedic got it bad.
He still in there?
We're getting him out now.
Help!
Hang on!
Please!
All right.
Nice and easy.
Is anyone injured?
Ready? One, two, three.
Got him.
Darren?
Darren, what happened?
I smashed my hip.
One to ten, how's the pain?
Oh, man, it's a ten.
He's tachycardic
and his pulse is thready.
You think it's broken?
God!
We gotta go.
Let's go, let's go!
Hang in there, Darren.
We're getting you to Med.
Darren. Darren?
What's happening?
He's bleeding out
into his pelvis.
We gotta go! Easy, easy.
This is Mister Lentz.
Mr. Lentz. What's going on?
Pain in my chest.
It's all right. We got you.
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go.
Come on. Come on,
come on, come on.
Yeah.
Let's go!
Baghdad.
Pressure in two units O
positive, get a pelvic binder,
then activate the MTP.
Tachycardic and hypotensive.
Steve, what's your plan?
Bind his pelvis,
we need X-rays
and CT to confirm,
then interventional radiology
to embolize the bleeders.
Good. Let's transfer
on my count.
Everybody ready?
Yeah.
One, two, three.
Trauma labs, ABG,
chest and pelvic X-ray.
Pelvic binder.
Blood's on the way.
Okay, let's get ready to roll.
Yeah.
Roll.
Tell me as soon as you get
the scans. I'll let IR know
we're coming up.
Okay.
Back.
Okay, he's good. Bolus a liter
of saline. I think we're gonna
be in good shape.
Hold on. Let me get you guys
some dry scrubs.
No, no, no. I'm fine.
Oh, look who decided
to show up!
Hey!
Must be good to be back.
Much better than
sitting around at home.
I bet.
How's Phillip?
Phillip's great.
He's been really
helping out with Owen,
giving me time
to heal and rest.
But?
But what?
Nat...
Well, Dr. Abrams said that
I would have memory loss.
And that the loss might
include some feelings.
I don't know, I guess I'm just
excited for them to come back.
Yeah.
Anyway, how are you?
How was your vacation?
Oh, it was just fine.
You know, just a little
me time to recharge.
Natalie!
Yeah.
It's good to see you well.
Thanks, Jim.
Four weeks, though
seems a little soon
to come back from
a traumatic brain injury.
Well, Dr. Abrams
did clear me.
Well, Sam likes to get
patients off his service.
Let's do a half-shift today.
H and P's only.
Probably best
just to ease back in.
No, I don't think
that's necessary.
Doesn't look too bad,
70% stenosis
in two vessels.
He's stable from the nitro,
so I think we can
treat conservatively.
Spoken like a true
future urgent care mogul.
See? I listen.
Mr. Lentz, no injuries
from the ambo crash, I hear.
Gone over your CAT. I'd like
to schedule you for coronary
artery bypass surgery.
Preferably today.
But Dr. Marcel,
the medicine worked.
I... I feel fine.
I understand.
But you did suffer
a heart attack this morning.
I'd like to prevent you
from having another.
There must be other ways.
We could talk about other
medical options. Or possibly
revisit a stent down the road.
None of which, in my opinion,
will solve the problem.
Now, I know this is not
what you were expecting...
Dr. Marcel...
But I do ask you
that you trust me
when I say that
you might be one cheeseburger
away from a far worse event
than the one you experienced
this morning.
You really think so?
Yes, I do.
Well, if...
If you say so.
Okay.
Good. I'll talk
to Dr. Latham,
Chief of CT Surgery,
and I'll get back to you
with those details.
Dr. Sexton?
Yeah, you kinda gave him
a hard sell on a surgery.
We should really give him
all his options.
Hold on.
70% stenosis on a cath
means a 95% blockage
in three dimensions.
Coupled with a decreased LVF,
I'd say his only other option
right now is dying.
Why don't you
come up and observe?
Might be illuminating.
Yeah, Dr. Latham?
Hi, Lacey, I'm Dr. Halstead,
this is student Dr. Curry.
Hi.
I hear you had a seizure
at school today?
Yeah. In the
middle of calculus.
Has that ever
happened before?
No.
Any idea what caused it?
Maybe the giant
gas leak in our school.
We've been smelling
it for weeks.
And no one's fixed it?
No. And I've
been getting dizzy,
and nauseous, and now
I can't stop doing this.
And the soccer state
finals are tomorrow.
Yeah. Is she gonna be okay?
The arm motions,
when did those start?
Today. After the seizure.
Hmm. Okay.
Have either of you
had any symptoms?
Nothing.
Do you have any history
of head injuries or trauma?
No. It's a gas leak.
Can't you just test the air,
or my blood, or something?
That's exactly what
we're gonna do.
Let me run some tests
and talk to your school
while Miss Curry does
a quick neuro exam.
I need to get better.
Understood.
We're gonna take
good care of you.
Hey, we didn't have
a nurse in there.
Can you get someone to
drop a CVC, CMP, and
start on IV influence.
I got it.
Hey.
Welcome back.
Thanks.
You go away for a few weeks,
and everything's different.
Connor's left. And Ava?
Oh, my God...
Yeah. That was
a horrible shock.
Ugh.
You look good.
I mean, you know,
you healed up well.
Yeah.
And the concussion?
Yeah, I'm taking it slowly.
You sure?
Glad to have you back.
Hey. Hey, Will?
Yeah?
I'm sorry
you had to find out
the way you did.
About me and Phillip
getting engaged.
But I guess that's what
I was coming to your car
to tell you.
Right.
I mean, I don't remember
a lot from that day, but...
It makes sense.
I got a kid with
a gunshot wound.
T1. Dr. Lanik.
Taylor Holmes, 16, shot once
through the right forearm
and into the flank.
BP 130 over 60.
Heart rate 95.
They shot me.
Somebody shot me.
All right.
Let's move him.
One, two, three.
So what happened out there?
I don't know.
I was just waiting for
the bus. Am I in trouble?
There's no law
against getting shot.
Active bleeding
from his flank.
Let's get some
four-by-four dressings.
It's okay. I got this.
Does it hurt
anywhere else?
Uh-uh.
Can somebody call my mom?
Don't worry. We will.
Okay. Got the brachial.
Hemostat times two.
I'll apply pressure.
Get me some suction.
We're fine. Doris?
Hemostat.
See? Easy-peasy.
Your artery's clamped,
but your flank wound
is still bleeding.
So we gotta get you
up to surgery.
I need an operation?
Yes, you do.
It'll fix you up.
Dr. Manning will take you
right up in a minute.
You want me to
transfer him? Wait...
And write the note. Thanks.
All right, let's move.
I'll take it from here.
Hey, where you going?
Lanik's having me do transpo.
Are you serious?
Anything to keep me
from practicing medicine.
Huh. Well, welcome back,
Dr. Manning.
Thanks.
Any word on
when Dr. Latham's
coming back in?
He's still stuck in OR 12.
Can I get
some suction, please?
All right, then.
Let's suture.
My first day,
I'm taking this woman's
history out in the chairs,
when I feel this
warm liquid
all over my leg.
And I'm like,
did she just pee on me?
But I keep going,
until she says,
when are you gonna ask
about my baby?
And I realize that
her water just broke.
But before
I can say anything,
she passes out cold,
because now she's in
a total eclamptic crisis.
What... What happened?
Whoa.
Everybody, freeze.
Power must've gone out.
Those are the
emergency lights.
But the backup generator
should kick in any second.
Where are we at?
I got nothing.
Suction's out.
Bypass is on battery,
not sure how long we got.
Okay. I'm sure
somebody's working on this.
Be ready to
hand-crank the bypass.
You're keeping him under.
Can somebody get us
some lights?
We're stopped.
How come we're stopped?
I don't know.
Hello?
Is anyone out there?
Hello!
The whole hospital is gone.
Lights, computers,
imaging, Pyxis.
What happened to
the backup generator?
Totally flooded.
It's gonna take a few
hours to get back on.
All right.
Automatic locks'll be shut,
elevators jammed.
We'll do a sweep
to see if we can
find anyone in trouble.
Thank you.
Mags, where are we going?
All bets are off.
Take the Hybrid OR.
Here. You take this one.
Okay,
let's get ready to transfer.
Everybody ready?
Yeah.
One, two, three.
Mo, change to a pressure bag
and then send for
four more units.
You think he's
still losing blood?
Gonna find out now. You ever
checked abdominal pressure
with a Foley?
I've read about it.
It's old school.
Just put a catheter
on the bag,
then add a transducer
with a three-way tap.
Okay.
Dr. Choi,
April, they need you in three.
Okay. Hook it up
to the A-line transducer,
then watch the waveform.
If it gets above 30,
come and get me.
Okay.
Let me help you with that.
April.
I think they need all the help
they can get out here.
Steve, you good?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm good.
Now, see the water's coming
in here from the edge.
So, the backup generator is
located below a storm drain.
Are you serious?
Don't ask me.
Don't ask you?
Look, you've gotta get
this thing up and running.
Get as many men as you need.
Yeah, it's still gonna
take all day.
Northern Illinois Power
will get a spare
out to us before then.
Oh, this is ridiculous.
What is their ETA?
Two hours?
We'll have to send our
critical care patients out.
We can't.
Lakeshore Memorial's
already on bypass,
East Mercy's taking
all the overflow.
So we have to keep
a thousand sick
and dying patients alive
with no lights,
no medicine, no nothing?
Well, we'll do
the best we can.
And, Maggie, pace yourself.
Today's gonna be a marathon.
Stop cardioplegia, and
prepare to come off bypass.
Okay, removing cross clamp.
He's not getting enough flow
to his left anterior wall.
Can you up his output?
Not enough to matter.
Then we have to
continue surgery.
We can't arrest him again.
He'll never come
off the bypass.
Fine. Then we'll
do it off-pump.
But you can't sew a vessel
into a beating heart.
That's almost impossible,
even with electricity.
Graft is down.
We don't have a choice.
But, a bad anastomosis
and he'll clot off.
It'll kill him.
Well then, we'll just
have to do a good one.
Speaking of which,
do me a favor and scrub in.
I could use
the extra hands.
Man, I know it's hot in here,
but I'm kinda freezing.
Here.
Hey,
anybody down there?
Yes! Hello! I've got
a patient in here!
Here. Hang on.
Someone's coming, okay?
Natalie, what do we got?
He's losing blood.
We need to get him to surgery.
All right. Sit him up,
I'll get a sked down
to bring him out.
That...
That doesn't feel so good...
What's wrong?
He can't maintain
pressure sitting up.
Can he stay up long enough
to pull him out?
Taylor? Taylor. No.
It's not gonna happen.
Get me four units
of uncrossmatched blood.
I need to
stabilize him before I...
Hey, you okay?
Yeah, Matt, I'm fine.
What... What happened?
You blacked out for a minute.
But we're gonna get you
some blood, okay?
All right. I'm gonna get that
blood to you as soon as I can.
Thank you.
Just hang in there, okay?
Why is this happening?
Finally, a doctor.
Have you figured out
what's going on?
No. The lab went down before
they could run Lacey's blood.
What kind of
a hospital is this?
Mom...
I apologize for the
circumstances. We're
trying to remedy it.
So, what do we do next?
Unfortunately,
we can't do much.
I've called Neurology,
but it is gonna
be a long wait.
But it's just a gas leak.
Please. Just give me some
medicine or something.
Treatment for inhalation
is supportive.
The symptoms,
they have to
wear off over time.
She doesn't have time.
She needs to get
to soccer practice.
Yeah. The finals
are tomorrow.
Yeah, I gotta be honest,
given what I'm seeing,
I'm not optimistic
about you playing
in that game.
What?
You can't do that!
It's the state finals!
Dr. Halstead,
I have to play.
Everyone's counting on me,
and I have been
working so hard.
I can't let them
down now. I can't.
You need to
figure this out.
I hear ya.
And we are doing our best.
Just try to take it easy,
relax, and let us
take care of you.
I'm gonna find out what's
going on with the power,
and hopefully we'll have
some answers soon.
We're low on fluids.
Only if they need them.
Mags? Any word
on the new genny?
Still uptown.
Not even on the truck yet.
Be nice to get
the air back up, huh?
Yeah. I'm frying
like an egg.
Dr. Choi! It's Darren.
The waveform broke 30.
Airway pressure's too high.
Get me a scalpel.
And what's this for?
Abdominal compartment
syndrome.
Wait you think
that's all blood in there?
Pelvic hematoma
must've ruptured.
The pressure's so high,
he's not getting any blood
back to his heart.
But if we can't get him
upstairs to the OR how are
we gonna take care of him?
Oh, my God.
All right.
Let's bag him.
Hey. Hey, Steve.
Look at me.
Two more minutes, he would've
died. You saved his life.
Okay.
Come on.
Let's pack him up and build
a bag for those intestines.
Okay. Okay.
All right, thanks.
Will.
Yeah.
Your patient,
with the tics...
Yeah.
What are you thinking?
Good question. The fire
department just told me
the school is clean. So...
That rules out gas leak.
She seems pretty anxious.
You mind if I pop in
and say hi?
Yeah, sure.
I don't know if we're
gonna get any real answers
till Neuro gets here. But...
Dr. Halstead!
She's seizing.
It's okay, it's okay.
Two milligrams of Ativan IM.
You got it.
Stand aside.
Okay, okay, okay.
So, you weren't experiencing
any symptoms at all?
No warning?
It just came up
out of nowhere?
Yeah.
Huh.
Calculus, wow. I'm very
impressed that you can
concentrate on that right now.
AP test is in a week.
I don't have a choice.
I'm sure that we can arrange
for a medical extension,
under the circumstances.
People with medical extensions
don't get into Princeton.
I gotta...
I think I'm gonna puke.
Okay. Wait a second,
let me get you something.
Here you go.
Yeah. Okay. Okay.
You're fine.
I'll check back.
Yeah. There you go.
I'll be right back, okay?
I mean, we don't have
a choice, we need to
put them in isolation.
Yeah. But you don't know
what it is. Could be
environmental, or drugs...
Her symptoms came on
awfully quickly,
didn't they?
As of right now,
infection's top of the list.
All right then.
Start the isolation protocol.
Okay.
Maggie, I want you to put
another nurse on this case.
Sharon, everyone's
got too much
on their plate. I'm fine.
You had a lumpectomy for
breast cancer two weeks ago,
and now you're on chemo.
You're immunocompromised,
and we don't know
what these girls have.
I'm going to be careful.
Don't worry.
Pressure's tanking again.
Release the heart.
All right. We need an
intra-aortic balloon pump.
It's the only way
to hold his pressure
while we sew on the graft.
But we can't
X-ray to see if it's
in the right place...
So I'm gonna need you
to put your hand in there
to let me know when I'm in.
Don't be afraid to squeeze.
You feel it?
Nah... I don't know.
I think so.
Yeah? Okay. Turn on the pump.
Heart rate's down
to 63... 54...
It went up too far.
How high is it?
I don't know.
45.
We're cutting off blood to his
brain. I need to know.
Yeah, five centimeters.
Okay.
Stop the pump.
Okay. Turn on the pump.
Marty?
Rate and pressure are good.
Oh.
Is he gonna be okay?
Did he have a stroke?
We'll find out
when he wakes up.
Okay. Needle driver
back to me.
No, then you go back
and you look harder, Roger.
Sorry.
Hey, where's your stash?
My snacks?
Yeah.
Are you feeling okay?
Yeah. It's for that
med student, Steve.
He hasn't stopped for a minute
all day. I'm just a little
worried about him.
Here.
Thanks.
How's he doing?
I'm trying to warm
the blood up for him,
but his temp's down to 96,
and if he gets any more
hypothermic it's just gonna
make him bleed even more.
So I, you know,
I've really...
Well, he's stable
right now.
So why don't you take
a quick break, okay?
Aw, thanks.
Mmm-hmm.
I'm fine.
Just life in the ED, right?
Dr. Choi told you
his first-day pregnant
lady story, didn't he?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's not
always like that.
He doesn't tell stories
about all the earaches
and runny noses.
April, they need you
back in three.
Okay. But first,
get something in you.
No time. Vents are starting
to fail, and we're
running out of hands.
Where do you need me?
Eat, change your scrubs.
Then I'll find where
you can help out.
April...
Fine. But you're
going to three.
This is the third one.
We need to evacuate the ED.
Patient care is already
stretched to the limit.
We don't have the manpower.
I know what I'm asking for.
But are we willing to risk
a massive outbreak?
I mean, this could be
a superbug,
bacterial meningitis...
Yeah, but then again,
these young women are under
a phenomenal amount of stress,
aren't they?
Stress?
We're not
talking headaches
and fatigue here.
These girls are
having seizures...
Elsa?
Dr. Halstead?
Oh, no.
Come on, come on.
What happened?
It's okay. I'm fine. I'm fine.
No, you are burning up.
Miss Goodwin,
we need to evacuate.
Okay. Do it.
Wait. Wait.
Thirty minutes.
I need 30 minutes,
and all three of them
in one room.
I'm sorry.
Are you crazy?
Look. If it's an infection,
they've already all got it.
Thirty minutes.
Thirty minutes,
Daniel. No more.
Come on, Maggie.
You good?
Yeah.
Let's go.
Dr. Manning,
I'm really scared.
Did he get the blood?
No.
He said there's
nothing left.
Whole hospital's out.
Taylor.
His sats are dropping.
I need to intubate now.
Here you go.
You want me to do it?
No, I got it.
Okay.
Oh! Come on, Taylor. Come on.
Come on.
Damn it.
Let me do it.
No. He's just
irritated and swollen.
Natalie.
All right. Make sure
you can see the chords,
okay?
I got it.
Go nice and slow.
Don't force it.
Yeah.
There. I'm in.
His sats are coming up.
Tell me what else you need?
Get Dr. Lanik.
Hi, I'm Dr. Charles.
What's going on?
Did you get our
test results back?
Not yet.
You know what's
happening to us?
I think I do.
And this medicine should
address your symptoms.
Is it another antibiotic?
Well actually, it's not.
But Dr. Halstead
said this was an infection.
And it must be affecting
our nervous systems.
And that very well could be.
Listen, this might make
you a little groggy.
Even relax you a little.
I don't care,
as long as it works.
Finally, a generator.
We just need to fuel her up.
You got your connections
pre-installed or do we need to
lay down cable from here?
No, we're all set.
Come on. Let's go.
Let's go.
Hey. How long till
the power's back?
Five, ten minutes at most.
April?
It's Darren.
His pressure and sats
are tanking.
He's gonna code.
We need an ER REBOA.
Inflating a balloon
above the pelvis to stop
the bleeding till we
get the power back.
But he won't make it
all the way back to IR.
No. We're gonna do it here.
Call trauma. If we can
stop the bleed, they need
to ligate his iliacs stat.
You don't think this is
gonna work, do you?
V Fib. Grab the paddles.
No. No, you.
Charge to 200.
You're charged. Do it.
Do it!
Okay, clear.
Did you find Dr. Lanik?
He's stuck in the ED.
Well, we're running
out of time.
I think he's gonna arrest.
What do we do?
Get me a thoracotomy tray.
We need to divert
whatever blood he has left
to his heart and his brain.
How do we do that?
We're gonna clamp his aorta.
You're gonna open
his chest? Here?
Yep.
And what if
we can't find it?
I don't know. I've never
done it before.
Pressure's dropping.
I'm working on it...
Okay. Let's open him up.
Easy.
Clip's off.
Left anterior wall
still isn't moving.
There it goes.
Yes, sir!
Sorry.
Well, look at that.
Can you feel it?
No. Not yet.
Wait. I almost got it.
Still in V Fib.
Do it.
Okay, clear.
Clear.
Sinus rhythm.
Get me a chest X-ray.
Everybody clear.
He's still bleeding?
Where's the balloon?
There. Right above
the diaphragm.
Vitals are holding.
Bleeding's stopped. He's good.
Phew.
I got it.
Wow.
Let's go, let's go!
Doris, get those vents up
and running. Dr. Lanik,
triage surgical patients
and get them up to the OR.
Angel, you're with me.
Everybody, let's move.
Get me the charge
nurse in the ICU.
Dr. Choi, Trauma's here.
Hey.
We did it.
Heard you did the
sloppiest thoracotomy
Trauma's ever seen.
Nice job today.
Thanks.
Doesn't mean I'm not still
keeping an eye on you.
Everything came
back normal
on all three girls.
All right,
this makes no sense.
It's been 30 minutes.
Why aren't we evacuating?
I have no idea.
They stopped twitching.
What did you do?
Um... Tic Tacs.
You gave them a placebo?
Orange ones have been
my go-to of late.
I mean, don't get me wrong,
they're gonna need
some therapy, figure out
that the weight of the world
isn't on their shoulders.
Maybe a little family work.
What do you mean?
You ever heard of
mass psychogenic illness?
Yeah, like mass
hysteria, right?
Very easy to misdiagnose.
I mean, in Salem,
they called it witchcraft.
So... The seizures and the
tremors, you're telling me
really were from...
Stress and anxiety manifested
as physical symptoms.
Spread through social groups
by unconscious imitation.
Happens a lot more
than you'd think.
Remarkable how far
our brains will go
to avoid dealing
with emotions
we don't wanna confront.
Hey, either way, Dr. Halstead,
you did the right thing today.
Wait. How... How's Maggie?
She says she's fine. Thinks it
must have just been the heat.
Good. All right.
Let's get her
out of isolation.
Okay.
Natalie?
Yeah.
That night, it didn't feel
like you were coming to
tell me you were engaged.
What?
In my car. I think
you were coming to
tell me something else.
I'm sorry, Will, I'm just...
I've had a really long day.
Cool. Of course. I'm sorry.
Goodnight.
Wait.
I just have to ask.
Do you love him?
Phillip. Are you sure?
Am I sure that I love him?
Just tell me.
Do you?
You know what?
My relationship with Phillip
is the only thing in my life
that's working right now.
Hey, guys. Hey, you!
Dr. Marcel.
Yeah.
I am really sorry
about screwing up the pump.
I could've killed him.
Are you kidding?
We were doing surgery
on a beating heart
with no electricity.
As far as I can tell,
you got a great set of hands.
I'm sure they'll come of use
in your urgent cares.
The right specialty,
a surgeon can still make
good money, right?
Yeah. Ortho, CT, Neuro...
And with the right team...
Oof!
Hey, good day today.
I'll see you tomorrow.
No, I'm not coming back.
What do you mean?
I love medicine.
But what we did today,
I can't do that every day
for the rest of my life.
Hey, come on.
It was a crazy day...
I know, I just...
I just can't.
Was I too hard on him?
No, not too hard on him.
Just focused on getting our
patients what they needed.
So I missed seeing
what he needed.
Babe, you are
such a good doctor.
Sometimes we get so caught up
taking care of everyone else,
we forget to take care
of each other.
No.
You don't.
You don't forget.
You're always so mindful
of everyone. So...
Aware, so caring.
I know we said someday, but...
You'd make the best mom ever.
I love you.