Previously on "ER.."
Carter!
I think I
dislocated my shoulder.
How do you think you
can improve our department?
Well, right away,
you could benefit
from an eight‐bed
observation unit.
If she's half
as impressive in the room
she just might
be our next chief.
Dr. Corday,
you gave him 50%.
My God, you're right!
I've given him a lethal dose!
‐ He's bradying down, hurry!
‐ Number 8 ET tube!
The cochlear implant
is nothing short of a miracle.
You bring in your‐your son
and we'll see if
he's a candidate.
Hey, Elizabeth,
don't feel the need
to solicit medical advice
on my behalf, alright?
I've worked with
Kotlowitz before.
That's the only
reason I brought it up.
If you'd rather I hadn't.
Yeah, I'd rather you hadn't.
♪ 100 bottles
of beer on the wall ♪
♪ 100 bottles of beer ♪
♪ Take one down
and pass it around ♪
♪ 100 bottles
of beer on the wall ♪
I've never heard
one go on this long.
Seems like forever.
He can't even count.
Never drops to 99, 98
just back to 100.
So you don't mind that
he's loud and smells bad
just that he can't
sing the song right.
♪ 100 bottles of beer ♪
♪ Take one down.. ♪
‐ Sorry. It's catchy.
‐ Who's on?
General Lee, but she's in
a meeting with Anspaugh.
Ooh, I hope you're not calling
her that to her face.
Our new chief
of emergency services?
Would I do
something like that?
Need to pop this guy some Ativan
and put him out of our misery.
Yes, I believe there's someone
asleep in the on‐call room.
Wake him up!
I can't leave the desk.
Then find somebody
who can wake him up.
We got work to do.
♪ 100 bottles
of beer on the wall ♪
Mark? Time to get up.
I'll be right there.
Mark, let's go. It's 7 o'clock.
I'm up. I'm up.
Hey, Mark, I don't want to have
to throw cold water on you.
Oh, Doug, is that you?
Oh!
♪ 100 bottles
of beer on the wall ♪
♪ 100 bottles.. ♪
99, you idiot.
Two migs of Ativan
and this guy's out
colder than the top of K2.
Sorry we had to wake you.
Oh, I'm not, ten more
minutes and my shift is over.
I would've slept
right through getting off duty.
Sweet dreams, bottle man.
♪ 100 bottles
of beer on the wall ♪
Hey. You about ready?
‐ Yeah, I'm about deaf.
‐ Wasn't really necessary, Doug.
Well, I know, but I do
it to Carol every morning.
There's fresh
coffee on the stove
toast on the counter.
Thanks for letting
me stay an extra night.
Well, we're gonna
miss you eventually.
Who would have
thought that asbestos
would take so long to get
out of an apartment building?
Probably the asbestos guys
but who's counting?
Uh, listen, it's just gonna be,
uh, you know, a few days
uh, early next week
something like that.
‐ Do we have any half and half?
‐ Yeah, top shelf to the left.
‐ 'Hmm.'
‐ What?
He didn't mention anything
about his date last night.
Well, Doug, that's because
it's none of our business.
You're not gonna ask?
No, and neither
are you, right?
Hey, no.
Right?
♪ 100 bottles
of beer on the wall ♪
♪ 100 bottles of.. ♪
This boy's a real annoyance.
He's a menace.
He's a machine.
And with four
more migs of Ativan
he is officially Chicago
in January. I'm outta here.
If you need anything
more, call somebody else.
Call someone else.
'Carter? I'm not your mother.'
'Now, for the last time,
get up.'
Why does she have to do that?
You set the alarm, didn't you?
Roxanne?
'Carter!'
Uh, yeah, I'm up.
Thank you.
Date? It wasn't a date.
‐ What are you talking about?
‐ You went out with her, right?
‐ We had dinner.
‐ Well..
She started two days ago.
I was just,
you know, being nice.
Mm‐hmm, this was
like a mercy date?
Of course not.
It was like
an introduction, that's all.
Orientation.
‐ Exactly. Thank you, Carol.
‐ Date.
You know it's just that we
didn't go to bed together.
I know, I know,
but I was up late
helping Kerry
with her portfolio.
‐ I'm sorry.
‐ Hey, ow!
I just would prefer if
you would wake me up.
You really want to get
up early to check the Nikkei?
Sorry. My battery's dead.
‐ No, I'm sorry.
‐ My car is dead.
We could just
hoof it to the El.
‐ Roxanne?
‐ Yeah.
What would you
think of decreasing
my position in small
caps by seven percent
and putting it into value?
Great, but I still
think you need to
pull back your
international equities.
I‐I don't want
emerging markets.
No, no, no, but I think
you want some in bonds
and some in
an absolute return fund
with a low correlation
to the equity market.
'I got a call.'
You need some help?
No bother.
False alarm.
We fixed him up.
Jerry helped too.
Oh, Jerry, the desk clerk.
I think I'm slowly
getting everyone's name down.
It's great how the nurses here
solve problems on their own.
We do try.
Now, how are you getting along?
Feeling settled in?
Yes, thanks. Everyone's
been really helpful.
Oh, by the way,
good job on that drunk.
♪ 100 bottles of beer ♪
♪ Take one down
and pass it around ♪
Mark? Kerry?
Do you have a minute?
‐ Uh, sure.
‐ Of course.
Feels like
snow today, doesn't it?
Maybe.
Mark, thanks again
for dinner last night.
You're welcome.
Just filling her in.
Yeah, lay of the land
kinda thing.
‐ John, do you have a minute?
‐ Sure.
Don Anspaugh mentioned
it's the 100th anniversary
of the hospital this week.
Yeah, there's
some kind of big gala
dinner Saturday night, right?
Yes, and a little publicity
for a Mrs. Ruth Johnson
born in this hospital
100 years ago today.
Wow! What does that
have to do with the ER?
Absolutely nothing
except that
Mrs. Johnson and her family
are upstairs right now.
Some mix‐up on the time.
And the Trib's photographer
can't get here
till this afternoon.
Dr. Anspaugh would like
a suitable tour guide
to keep them busy.
They should call
Willard Scott.
I suggested you.
‐ What?
‐ Yep. You're the guy.
Friendly, you're knowledgeable,
you know your way around.
Oh, I have an excellent
med student Ms. Lucy Knight‐‐
Yes, but she's working
with Dr. Ross today.
No, I can't think
of a better choice.
I think my colleagues
here would agree.
Dr. Greene,
they need you in radiology.
I'll be right there.
You could use
a light day, Carter.
Yeah, you're not quite up to
speed yet with
your shoulder yet, right?
Guess I'll just
finish this paperwork.
Thanks. I appreciate it.
She's got a big wind‐up
then she just nails it
right over the plate.
I can deal with that.
Jimmy's got
an earache and Erlene's
got this funny‐looking
sore right here
in the middle of her lip.
Okay, we'll check 'em
out, Mrs. La Bahtray.
Lucy, why don't you
start with Jimmy?
Hey, Doug? We've got an
eight‐year‐old coming in.
Auto versus bicycle.
Okay, I'm with you. Lucy,
you got this under control?
‐ Yeah, no problem.
‐ Alright.
Get away from me.
I don't like that.
‐ Oh, Jimmy, you stop that now.
‐ Oh, sweetie..
I'm not gonna
hurt you, okay?
I don't want
her doing that.
Do you want me to hold him down?
That's what I usually do.
Oh, no, it's okay, a nurse
will come in anytime.
Get off me, ma!
Okay, we're ready for you.
Ma! Get off me!
Wilson Geary, eight‐years‐old.
Crossing Morrison on his bike.
Hit by a car.
He was chasing us.
I didn't see the car.
It's okay, Wilson,
we're gonna take care of you.
'Everything's
gonna be just fine.'
Good vitals, no LOC,
complains of belly pain
lot's of road rash, possible
fracture on the left hand.
Alright, let's get that buckle?
On my count.
One, two, three.
I didn't see
what happened to Andy.
I just tried to get away.
He keeps talking about some guy
chasing him and his friend.
BP 120/72, pulse 94.
Okay, Wilson, we're gonna take
some scissors
and cut your clothes
so we can see
where you're hurt, alright?
Okay.
Cops are looking for some
other kid, taking a report
from the driver,
and they'll be in after that.
'Alright, thank you, Doris.'
Wilson, you remember
what happened?
I was riding across the park.
I got into the street,
and there was a car.
I know I must look both ways
but I was trying to get away.
‐ Get away from who?
‐ This man.
He was chasing me and Andy.
Good breath sounds.
Trachea midline.
‐ Pulse ox is 98.
‐ Tell me if it hurts here.
‐ No.
‐ Okay, how about here?
‐ Yes. That hurts a lot.
‐ 'Okay.'
'Alright, right upper quadrant
tenderness with guarding.'
'Let's get an abdominal
CT with contrast.'
'Hemoglobin is 13.8.'
‐ Ouch!
‐ I'm sorry.
Was I tugging too hard?
'Doug, got another
kid coming in.'
Eight‐year‐old, GSW.
To the abdomen.
What did she say? Is that Andy?
Hang on a minute, buddy,
why don't you just hold still?
'Let's worry about
you first, okay?'
'Don't move your head.'
You just hang in there.
‐ You're doing great.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Hey.
Hi.
Uh, pre‐op labs are
back on the gallbladder.
'Lap choly's scheduled
for this afternoon.'
We're still waiting on
the films for the ischemic bowel
and the aortobifemoral bypass
went south with pneumonia
ten days post‐op.
Yeah, I know.
I spoke to the family.
What's this?
You're prepping for your M&M?
Yeah, patient's heart rate,
blood pressure, pulse ox
time of magnesium injection
central line placed,
pacemaker captured.
After witnessing your M&M
on Dr. Swanson last year
I thought it best
to be well‐prepared.
Yeah, well, I don't think
it's gonna go like that.
‐ Neither do I, but..
‐ You know‐‐
Dr. Benton. Dr. Kotlowitz
was looking for you.
The Shimaharas are here.
Oh, damn.
Okay, um, I'll be
right there, Shirley.
Kotlowitz is putting a cochlear
implant into a three‐year‐old.
I got to go and observe.
I've never seen one.
Yeah, well, neither have I.
Listen, if you need somebody
to bounce that
stuff off of, I..
Oh, Peter, Peter, go.
I'm busy, and you've
got work to do as well.
I'll be there, Elizabeth.
I know you will.
Thanks.
'One, two, three.'
'Single gunshot
wound to the abdomen.'
'Found him
pulseless and apneic.'
Asystole on the monitor.
Two rounds of epi
and atropine given.
A liter of saline in.
What's the down time?
About 30 minutes.
I told the cops
to wait outside.
Thoracotomy tray.
O‐neg on the rapid infuser.
I'll do a cut down.
Last epi?
Five minutes ago.
Go with high dose
three milligrams.
'Do you need anything else?'
‐ No, we got it.
‐ Come on.
Hey, Pam,
did you get a name?
'Unconscious from the get‐go.'
Okay, thanks.
Excuse me, excuse me, nurse.
Is that the kid hit by
the car, Wilson Geary?
I need to talk to him.
Ah, we're still
working on him. What happened?
I don't know, responded
to the vehicular accident.
The kid on the bike
was pretty shaken.
Paramedics no sooner
got him in the rig
then we found
the other one in the park.
Did you get a name?
Yeah. We got this.
We contacted his parents.
And what about
Wilson's family?
Working on it.
‐ Thanks.
‐ Sure.
‐ Andy. Andy!
‐ Buddy.
Hey, listen, you gotta look
at me right now, okay?
We gotta fix you up first.
‐ Alright?
‐ Okay.
‐ Doing a thoracotomy.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
‐ Asystole?
‐ 30 minutes.
‐ You got this?
‐ Yep.
Alright, Wilson, I'll be back
in a little bit, alright?
‐ Okay.
What are they doing?
They're trying to help him.
Are they cutting his clothes off
and stuff like you did to me?
Yeah, that's right.
You ready to go for a ride?
'We're going to
roll you down the hall'
'and take
a picture of your belly.'
‐ Okay.
‐ 'Okay.'
Dr. Anspaugh's not here.
Shirley, that's a lie 'cause
I just checked his schedule.
‐ He doesn't wanna see you.
‐ I just need a minute.
‐ In the middle of a Whipple?
‐ I just wanna talk to him.
Have you lost your mind?
‐ Carter, be a good soldier.
‐ Two seconds, Shirley.
They're thataway.
Hi. I'm looking
for Ruth Johnson?
Oh, uh, say,
a‐are you the doc?
I've got a mole right
here back of my neck‐‐
‐ Edgar, stop your mole talk!
‐ Oh..
I'm Ruth Johnson.
Gilda here had
to use the bathroom
and you know how
the young ones
like someone
to take 'em.
Nana, please.
Hi. I'm Gilda Bernucci.
Married an Italian.
I guess we all
know what that means.
Are you the ambassador?
I guess so.
As you see,
I don't need that thing
but, uh, it seems
to make everyone else happy.
Oh. Feels good anyway.
Are you in?
Yeah! Just a minute.
Okay, then,
let's take a tour.
Hey, Jerry,
can you page Dr. Ross
when the films get
back on Wilson Geary?
‐ You got it.
‐ Thanks.
‐ Can I talk to somebody?
‐ Excuse me again.
Gunshot kid, Andy Stiles,
his parents are here.
Okay. I'm gonna go
get Dr. Weaver.
Yeah, actually, it's
his mom and her boyfriend.
Parents are divorced.
Well, what about
Wilson's family?
In Dallas on a business trip.
I'm trying to track 'em down.
He was staying
at Andy's house.
‐ Alright.
‐ Thanks for your help.
Sure.
Hey, Kerry?
Andy's mother
is waiting in chairs.
Okay. I'll go talk
to her in a minute.
Malik? She might
want to come back.
I'll clean him up.
How's the other boy doing?
I don't know.
He's just back from CT.
Has anyone talked to him yet?
The family's out of town.
Well, if Doug's
busy, let me know.
Alright. Thanks.
Hey, Wilson.
How you doing?
Okay.
Hey, Andy can have
that bed there.
Uh‐huh.
How did you like the CT?
It was no big deal.
I have a little extra time
I thought maybe
you and I could talk.
Okay.
Don't ask.
I won't, but it's
the highlight of my day.
Perhaps I should wait
for another elevator.
Good idea.
'Lizzie.'
I'm glad to see you're in
such good spirits on this
your day of reckoning.
Oh, I'm sure it'll be fine.
Well, you've got me
on your side.
I didn't think it
was a matter of sides
simply the examination
of the event.
That's just
the attitude to go in with.
Well, in case, uh,
we don't see each other
again before
the conference, uh..
Well..
Best of luck.
'Fracture of
the fourth mid phalanx.'
I'll put a finger
splint on it.
Any word from the parents?
They're on their
way from Dallas.
I just don't know when.
Hmm. Broken finger
and some road rash.
All things considered,
the kid's lucky.
Not really.
'That's pretty funny, isn't it?'
Kind of amazing really.
'Hi, I'm Carol Hathaway.'
Detective Wilson,
Chicago PD.
Young Wilson here and I
were just laughing about how
we both have the same name.
Oh, that doesn't
happen often.
It's not the same
it's my first name.
Right. Look, I need to ask
you a few questions, Wilson.
She doesn't
have to leave, does she?
Nope. I'm gonna
stay right here.
I'd like you to tell me about
what happened in the park.
'Someone hurt your friend
Andy, right?'
She said Andy was dead.
Yeah, Wilson, he is dead.
And you saw the man
who was chasing him?
Chasing you?
Can you tell me if he was..
...White, or Black,
Latino, or maybe Asian?
‐ 'Do you know what those mean?'
‐ Yeah.
So which one was he?
Wilson, did you know this man?
'Do you recognize him, maybe
seen him in the park before?'
The police just want to find
the man who did this, okay?
So anything
you tell them can help.
I don't know.
Well, was he a tall guy
or a short guy?
‐ Kinda tall, maybe.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Did he come up on
you all of a sudden
or maybe you
noticed him earlier?
He just came up
all of a sudden.
When are my mom
and dad getting here?
'You said they were coming.'
They are, they're on
their way, okay?
'They're gonna get here
as soon as they can.'
You haven't gotten off
the surgical floor yet?
We're back on
the surgical floor.
It's their favorite.
They'd like to
observe an operation
if that's at all possible
something in
the open‐heart variety.
Oh, settle down, now,
Carter, this won't kill you.
Is, uh.. She, you know, uh..
Pretty well out of it?
No, not at all.
She just has a tendency
to doze off unannounced.
Right. Well, carry on.
I'm awake.
Just playing possum.
I'm sick of meeting people.
Can we get outta here?
I don't know
where we'd all fit.
Oh, not them, us.
Once the implant's in place
we'll repair the pericardium.
We'll suture the flap and after
Patrick's hair grows back
you'll never even know
we were in there.
Except he'll
be able to hear.
Yeah, what we'll do is, activate
the device in a few months.
So, uh, if you'll
excuse me a minute.
Uh, he seems excellent.
Oh, yeah, yeah, he's terrific.
He's very aggressive.
Aggressive?
Well, I mean, um..
...as in accomplished.
So, um I guess
you guys, you tried
every other option
for Patrick, huh?
Uh, we've done
the hearing aids
uh, intensive oral training,
speech training
looked into special teachers,
special schools.
We know this isn't a cure.
No, no. But.. Man..
He'll be able to
hear a range of sounds.
Mister and Missus Shimahara?
Hi. Here you go.
We're gonna take him
down to pre‐op in a bit
but I thought in the meantime..
‐ Thank you.
‐ Alright. I'll see you.
There's my boy.
Hey, Patrick. Hey, big guy!
Is this okay?
You're not too cold?
Not too cold.
This is a bit
better view, I think.
At my age, anything
vertical will do just fine.
So how does it feel
to have 100 birthdays?
Downright appalling.
I'm so old,
I can practically remember
when this river
ran the other direction.
That's right.
That's right, they changed it.
My husband Everett
used to love this river.
Staring down at it
from 20 stories high.
He worked in one of
these buildings here?
Built 'em.
Construction spree
after the first war.
Even worked on the
Chicago Board of Trade Building.
We did real well.
Sent every child to college
whether they wanted
to go or not.
Well, they must
have appreciated it.
They seem pretty devoted.
Family should be.
Some are more than others.
My mom and dad, they, uh..
...they tend to
travel quite a bit.
Oh, don't tell me your sad tale.
I hear enough of
that at Happy Valley.
'"My kids hate me.
I hate my kids."'
"My son never visits me."
‐ On and on.
‐ I know.
'Given that you never
know what you're gonna get'
Everett and I were darn lucky
in what we begot.
Well, I suppose
we should be heading back.
They're all
terrified I'm gonna die
before they get
this picture taken.
Okay.
‐ Doug?
‐ Hmm.
Andy Stile's mom
and her boyfriend‐‐
Hey, are you the ones
who helped Wilson?
Yeah.
I'm Judy Stiles, Andy's mother.
Mm‐hmm.
This is Carl Dayton.
We're very sorry.
We didn't think it
would take this long
to make all
the arrangements.
We want to see Wilson.
He could probably
use a familiar face.
I think he might
be sleeping right now.
I just want to
see how he's doing.
We wanna talk to him.
Well, he hasn't
said very much.
'The police were here earlier.'
What'd he tell 'em?
He said he couldn't
remember anything.
Please..
...he was the last
person to see my son.
Alright.
‐ Okay, well for a few minutes.
‐ Alright.
Hey, Wilson.
Wilson, some people who
know you wanna see you.
What?
Hi, Wilson.
How you doing?
I don't know.
I don't remember
what happened.
I know. Th‐that's okay, sweetie.
‐ You boys skip school again?
‐ Carl..
'If they didn't get
into so much trouble..'
Now, how many times
did I have to warn..
You'll never have
to do it again!
Sorry.
We shouldn't have skipped.
I'm really sorry.
‐ I think we need to go.
‐ Alright.
Your mom and‐and your dad
are gonna be here real soon.
I know you're gonna
be just fine.
Hey, it's okay, Wilson.
It's okay.
Shh.
You know how patients
always postpone
right before the holidays.
There's nothing like
that prospect of surgery
to make fruitcakes
seem like a good idea, huh?
Yeah, right.
So I can fit in
Reese next Tuesday.
Well, aren't you
concerned about his age?
He doesn't fit
the FDA Requirements.
No it's been
lowered to 18 months.
Yeah, but I mean his residual
hearing is still high.
Well he's right on the bubble
but we can push that.
We can.. Lo‐look,
he‐here's the thing.
'We know it's not gonna improve,
so the sooner he can orient'
himself to a hearing world
the better, right, huh?
Oh, yeah. Yeah, right.
So, uh, let‐let's put..
...Reese Benton on my schedule,
uh, for a cochlear implant
next Tuesday a. m.
Good.
Good, good. How we doing?
Ah, Peter,
you know Alex Babcock?
‐ Yeah, anesthesiologist.
‐ 'Good to see you.'
'How'd we do?'
Kid sailed through pre‐op.
Fentanyl Oralet,
a little versed
paralyzed
and intubated in a snap.
'And ho‐how'd the parents do?'
'They could have used a couple'
'of lollipops themselves.'
'Okay, Peter,
so I'm going to implant'
'the electrode directly out
of the linea temporalis'
and then, I'm gonna put
the microphone holder
right behind the ear.
I'm gonna inject Lidocaine
and I'm going to make
a flap two centimeters
from where I
insert the device.
And I'm gonna cut through
the muscle and the pericranium
so the flap will
come right off the skull.
Alex, you going back
to Aspen for Christmas?
No. Too many snowboarders.
Felt like I was part
of an obstacle course.
Peter, can you see alright?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I don't want you
to miss anything here.
Here we go.
Hey, what are you
doing out of bed?
Looking for the bathroom.
Oh, I'll take you to it.
No, I found it.
Alright, then
I'll take you to your bed.
You're looking better.
Are you feeling better?
Wilson?
What is it,
is something wrong?
I should have
told the policeman.
They're gonna keep
asking me, aren't they?
Well, they wanna find out
who did this.
If you remembered
anything
I can go and get
the detective.
No.
Wilson, when you came in here
you said there
was a man chasing you.
He was White.
He seemed tall, but I got
on my bike right away.
Did you know this man?
Had you seen him before?
We'd seen him there earlier
and we'd seen him
before in the park
when we'd gone there to play.
Uh‐huh, and if you
saw this man again
would you recognize him?
I don't know. Maybe.
Do I have to talk
to the policeman again?
When are my mom and dad coming?
Don't worry, they'll be here.
'Hey, Carol.'
Cops had to leave.
They'll be back in a little bit.
They wanted you to know they've
got your bike at the station.
Oh, thanks, Jeanie.
'You sure it's this room?'
No, but I was
in here earlier.
Anyway, I was saying,
it's a randomized
double‐blind
multi‐center study
funded by one of those
hoo‐ha biotech companies.
And the drug is for the
treatment of fracture pain?
Mm‐hmm. Comparing it against
acetaminophen with codeine.
Hopefully, it will
come up more effective
with fewer side effects.
A colleague of mine is
coordinating it from Atlanta.
So you want me to conduct
a study at County General.
Well, I know Kerry's
doing the sternal saw study.
I thought you might
wanna oversee this one..
...if you're game.
I'm game. Why not?
'Hey, doc, need some help?'
Hey, I was just helping Dr. Lee.
We're trying to find
her earring.
You know, that's okay.
I'm gonna check the desk.
Thanks, Mark.
Isn't that
a nurse's job?
They were busy
replenishing albuterol
and mixing ipratropium.
I was trying to help
in an emergent situation.
Who actually injected
the magnesium?
I did.
Did you verify the dosage
with nursing staff?
No.
When did you
realize your mistake?
The patient went into
respiratory arrest at 1534
14 minutes into
the magnesium injection.
Continue, Dr. Corday.
Endotracheal
intubation was performed.
Heart rate dropped to 30.
The patient received
IV calcium and atropine.
A transvenous pacing wire was
placed, captured at 1556 hrs.
Who was your
supervising resident?
‐ Dr. Benton.
‐ Who left you unsupervised.
Within minutes,
she had the patient intubated
and on a transvenous pacemaker.
Because of her quick response
the patient recovered fully
with no cardiac, respiratory,
or neurological sequelae.
I think it's important that we
look at the outcome here.
Thank you, Dr. Benton,
but I'm not looking to you
for defense of my actions.
In fact, I feel that M&M has
become a forum
to place blame,
cover up mistakes
or be grateful
that there's not a lawsuit.
I would argue that actually
we should embrace our mistakes
and learn from them
to improve the system.
I believe I made this mistake
not because I was
untrained or incompetent
but because I was exhausted,
having been up for 36 hours.
If we really want
to‐to cut down on our errors
why don't we, for example,
allow on‐call house officers
to leave by 12:00 noon
on the post‐call day?
Why don't we establish
a night float system?
Air traffic controllers
work with aeroplanes
four to six hours a day.
no more than two
hours without a break.
Now, why?
Because human life is at stake.
Yet we allow surgical interns
to work 36 hours
without sleep.
Why?
'Because we've
all had to do it?'
'Because the surgeons
before us have had to do it?'
'Well, old school tradition
may be wonderfully nostalgic'
but it is clearly not in the
best interest of our patients.
Now, if you disagree with me
why don't you ask
yourself next time you fly.
Do you really want
that man in the control room
to be on his 36th hour?
She's full of piss
and vinegar, isn't she?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
‐ For an old lady.
Because she's an old lady.
Alright, everybody
look at the camera lens.
If you're looking
at the camera lens
you're in the picture.
Okay, and smile.
'Okay, I just need, uh'
'Mrs. Johnson's children
inside, okay?'
'For a quick picture.'
She's done it again.
Mrs. Johnson?
Mrs. Johnson,
you playing possum again?
Come on, Ruth.
Time to wake up now.
Ruth?
Mrs. Johnson?
Oh, God. Kate, go get
a gurney and a crash cart now.
I‐I don't want to bother you
but the boys' clothes
are all mixed up.
Andy's.. His boots are missing.
And‐and I've got
Wilson's sneakers.
Oh, I am so sorry.
If you'll just have a seat, I'm
gonna go check for you, okay?
Connie, have you seen
Wilson's belongings bag?
Maybe check under
the trauma gurney.
Hey, Connie, I need
to talk to Wilson.
Could you give us a minute?
‐ Sure.
‐ Thanks.
Wilson, wake up.
Hey, Wilson.
‐ Are my parents here?
‐ Nope, not yet.
But I got to thinking and, uh..
...Andy was probably
your best friend, right?
Sometimes.
Whenever your parents would
go out of town on business
you'd stay over there?
It's closer to school.
We could ride our bikes.
So you probably..
...shared each other's toys?
Maybe even coats..
...gloves, boots?
Andy would never
let me wear his boots.
‐ Kind of too small, anyway.
‐ Oh.
Remember when you were
trying to take them off?
Right.
So if he never
let you wear his boots
then how come
you were wearing them
when the paramedics
brought you in here?
'Cause we had a bet and I won.
A bet?
To see who
could ride faster
from his house
to the park, and I won.
And whoever won
got to wear the boots, right?
Yeah, but he
wouldn't give them to me.
I rode faster
and he knew it.
He wasn't being fair.
Are these yours or Andy's?
Neither.
They're my dad's.
Wilson, did you
put these into a gun?
No. Those are extras.
I already
had some in the gun.
And when Andy
didn't give you the boots..
...you pointed the gun at him?
And you shot him?
Not to hurt him or anything.
Just to scare him.
We had a bet and I won,
it was fair and square.
You do know,
that you hurt him now, right?
Look, all I meant
was to get the boots.
You can't go back
on a bet, that's not right.
Andy knows that.
What did you do
with the gun, Wilson?
I dropped it down a drainpipe
when I got on my bike.
See, the thing is,
none of this would have happened
if that car hadn't hit me.
You'll let me know
when my parents get here, right?
Yeah, Wilson, I'll let you know.
Oh, Nurse Hathaway?
Can you please not tell
my dad I threw his gun away.
He'll get really mad.
So you're actually telling me
that he could go home today.
Yeah, we don't have
prisons for eight‐year‐olds.
I'm not talking
prison, I'm talking
juvenile hall, detention center.
Not for kids under ten.
Can an eight‐year‐old
even understand his rights?
Or the consequences
of his actions?
Well, of course he can.
He shot Andy so he could
get the boots, right?
He wanted to scare the boy.
His intent might have been
just that, not to kill.
But he did kill him!
I mean doesn't that
count for something?
Yeah, but what?
Murder two, manslaughter?
The kid is eight years old.
Isn't it up to
the state attorney?
Yes, but he's
got to be assessed
he has to have
a psych evaluation.
And social services
has to determine
whether he can differentiate
between right and wrong.
Of course he can.
Why would he make up a story
about the man chasing them?
Does he have any awareness
of what he's done?
Has he shown any remorse?
Yeah, he's sorry
he tossed the gun.
Afraid his father's
gonna get mad at him.
Does that count as remorse?
You are telling me the police,
the courts, psych
social services, nobody knows
what to do with Wilson Geary?
Pretty much.
What a mess.
Anything else
you want me to do?
Not right now.
I'll put her things in here.
Thanks, Chuny.
I'll go talk to the family.
Apparently, she was
sucking on a hard candy
and it lodged in her windpipe.
We were able to extract it
and her BP is now 128/90.
Heart rate's 70.
Vital signs all appear normal.
‐ You mean she's not dead?
‐ No, no. She's not dead.
She's asleep,
but definitely not dead.
Can we see her?
Like I said,
she's asleep, so..
Dr. Lee?
I'm really sorry.
We looked everywhere and we
couldn't find your earring.
Oh. Well, thank you
anyway for looking.
Did you lose an earring?
Yes. Not expensive or anything.
‐ Sentimental value.
‐ Oh?
‐ Yes, I was engaged once.
‐ Hmm.
To a really lovely
man, and he was killed
in a freak horseback
riding accident.
Actually, we were on a bridge,
and the horse spooked and..
‐ Oh.
‐ Anyway, he gave them to me.
I'm so sorry.
It was a long time ago.
Yeah. David Kotlowitz, please.
Peter Benton.
Hey, David. Hey.
Uh, listen, I, um..
I wanted to postpone
Reese's operation.
Well, I mean, you know, he's
barely within the age range
and he's got a fair
amount of residual hearing
and the technology's
changing all the time.
I just, you know..
No, yeah. I‐I just saw him.
He's.. He's doing fine.
Mm‐hmm.
Yeah, well, uh, you, too.
Have a great holiday, alright?
My parents called on
the way from the airport.
My dad has a phone in his car.
You're mad at me about
something, aren't you?
No.
When my mom gets
mad she just stands
at the kitchen
sink and does dishes
and she doesn't say anything.
I'm not mad, Wilson.
I'm sad about
what happened to Andy.
I mean it's so cool if he was
in one of these other beds.
Do you know what
it means to be sad?
Wilson, do you
know what it means
to have done something wrong?
Carol, his parents are here.
Thanks, Connie.
What, you waiting on a bus?
I wish I was on
a bus going anywhere.
Oh. How'd it go
with Anspaugh?
Ah, well,
no crime, no punishment.
Seems what I did
wasn't terribly wrong
therefore no need
to penalize me
to examine a system
that has served so many
so well for so long.
Yeah, they seemed
pretty shocked
that you actually suggested it.
As were you.
Yeah, well, it wouldn't
have been my choice.
Well, you and I never make
the same choices, do we?
No.
Well, Peter, we could now.
Come on, Peter.
This should be over.
I mean some would
argue that it already is.
We haven't been alone
together for weeks.
I need to focus
on my son right now.
Look we could both draw up
a list of reasons why
but why don't we just put it
down to faulty construction?
A casual relationship has to
grow into something or it dies.
Well, it's not like I
haven't wanted to see it grow.
It's just that I..
...I don't have it
to give right now. I..
Yeah.
I understand that.
Which is why I think
maybe, um..
...we'll be better
off as friends.
‐ I'll see you around, okay?
‐ Okay.
Now, you probably
didn't know it
but we've been
off work for 20 minutes.
Get something to eat?
Maybe Rosebud
or Morton's, Johnny D's?
Home, bathtub, bed.
That's my girl.
I met them today, you know.
Seemed like
perfectly normal people.
Father's a sales rep,
office supplies.
Mother went to
Dallas with him
'cause she wanted to
visit her favorite aunt.
Wilson's parents?
Thought they'd
have to be monsters
to raise a kid who could
do something like that.
Well, that would explain
everything, wouldn't it?
Parents beat the kid,
or they yell at him
or starve him so he ends up
killing his best friend.
Then why did he do it?
Stuff happens.
An eight‐year‐old shoots
another eight‐year‐old
and you say stuff happens?
You got a better answer?
No. No, I don't.
I don't know.
Maybe his genes
are screwy or..
...his parents seem nice, but
they ignore him. I don't know.
Maybe he plays
too many video games
like every kid in America.
It's..
Doesn't it bother you
that there isn't any reason?
No, it bothers me
that you cared about him
and you believed in him,
and now you feel betrayed.
I don't feel betrayed.
I feel...scared.
I mean, if you don't
know what causes it
how do you keep
it from happening?
Are we any different
from that couple?
They didn't see it coming.
Would we see it coming?
Yeah, you bring a child
into this world
and you think that
they're helpless
but actually,
I think it's us.
I think we're the ones
that are helpless.
We probably are but..
And that's why you
love them as much as you can
and you teach
them as best you can
and then you
wish them good luck.
What do you say?
Home, bath, bed?
Hmm?
‐ Yeah.
I mean you know
if you don't have any plans
if you're not busy.
Having a drink sounds great.
Can we also eat something?
‐ Dinner, absolutely.
‐ Okay.
I have a meeting
with Anspaugh
for about 20
then I'll be right back.
‐ Sounds great.
‐ Buddy, we're going home.
What's your story?
Ah, catching up on paperwork.
Well, curfew's at 11:00.
Ha, ha, ha.
Very funny.
ER.
How about this snow?
Yeah, it's pretty great, huh?
‐ Have a good shift.
‐ 'Always.'
Whoa, you got to help me.
My wife's having a baby!
What?
Huh?
Hang on, hang on.
We're not due
for two more weeks.
Somebody lied.
Oh, God, Louis,
help me. Help me!
We're gonna help you.
‐ Okay, get Mark and a gurney.
‐ Yeah.
‐ Do something, please.
‐ Ma'am, ma'am, I'm a doctor.
Alright, alright, I got it.
Bring her up.
Good. You know how to breathe.
‐ This is our fourth.
‐ Then I guess it's coming.
‐ When did it start snowing?
‐ Crowning.
We're not due
for two more weeks.
‐ It must be all the excitement.
‐ What's your name?
I'm Louis, Louis Bernucci.
This is my wife Gilda.
Hi, Gilda, nice to meet you.
You ready to push?
On the next one,
I want you to push, okay?
Ready, and one, two, three.
Push!
God!
If it's a girl,
I wanna name it after nana.
Ruth?
Ruth Johnson.
Ruth Johnson Bernucci.
'What do you think?'
Oh, it sounds good to me.
‐ 'Yeah?'
‐ 'Yeah.'
Yeah? Okay, Gilda, I like that.
Hang in there.
You're doing great.
Good. This one, push.
This is it.
Push! Push, push, push.
God!
Okay, the head's clear.
Shoulders.
There we go.
A beautiful baby girl.
Okay, good,
let's wrap her.
Get the suction.
Okay.
Okay, there's your mama.
There's your mom.
There's your mama.
Okay, clamp.
Excellent.
Okay. Okay, alright, mom.
We're just gonna
take her over here.
'Just a minute.'
'Coming right back to mom.'
Oh!
'Good job.'
Shh, shh, shh.
Hello.
'You are so beautiful.'
‐ Good luck, Ruth Johnson.
‐ Hmm.