Good news.
I have a VIP who needs a multiple
ligament reconstruction on his elbow.
And I've got room for
a couple of residents
to assist me and Dr. Melendez.
Awesome.
I've never assisted
on one of those before.
Dr. Andrews knows that.
That's why he's acting
like it's Christmas morning.
I'm guessing you've never
operated on a pro athlete either.
Um, last time I checked,
a couple means two,
and there's three of us.
More good news.
Whoever isn't with us
will be assisting Dr. Coyle
on a double-leg fasciotomy.
Feeling lucky?
Murphy.
"VIP elbow." Sweet.
"Fasciotomy."
Ooh.
Bobby Ato? Don't think I've
heard of him. He's a pro athlete?
He's a pro. I don't know
if I'd call him an athlete.
E-sports.
Video games?
He's one of the
best in the world.
Last year, he won enough
prize money to buy his mom
a beach house in Monterey.
He paid cash.
Is he considered a
very important person
because he's an athlete, or
because he has a lot of money?
Both.
Hmm.
I have to go.
Morning. Shaun.
This is Melissa Bourne,
the therapist that
we talked about.
That you agreed to meet with.
Right, Shaun?
Hi, Shaun. It's
nice to meet you.
Hi.
Dr. Glassman thought it'd
be a good idea for us to meet
before our first in-home session.
Just to make sure you're comfortable.
I am not comfortable.
Shaun, it's gonna be fine.
You two are going
to like each other.
Dr. Bourne has a PhD
in cognitive psychology.
She can really help you, but
you have to give her a chance.
Okay?
Okay. Okay.
I'm proud of you, Shaun.
I'm already proud of you.
Notice the separation
at zero degrees?
It's indicative of complete
tears of the LCL and the UCL.
A perfect candidate for surgery.
How's your mom?
Still beating cancer?
Oh. She's good, bro.
She said she gets checked
out at the beach all the time
ever since you did her
breast reconstruction.
So, thanks, I guess?
We're gonna take good care
of you. See you in the OR.
Thank you.
Which part of the UCL is the
principal secondary restraint
to excessive valgus movement?
- Anterior.
- Everything okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
Squeeze my hands.
There is a paradoxical loss
of grip strength on the left.
There are many possible
explanations for that, one of which is...
One of which is... He has
ligament tear is in his left arm.
The anesthesiologist will be up in
a few to get you ready for surgery.
Dope. Thank you.
Uh, Dr. Murphy?
- What's wrong with you?
- Nothing.
I have a condition called...
You're autistic, yeah,
yeah, yeah. I get it.
But what is wrong with you, bro?
You gotta be legit smart
to land a gig as a surgeon,
and he just shut
you down like a noob.
I'll bring the idea
up again. I do that.
They don't respect you.
They should listen
to you the first time.
I can't control what they do.
Of course you can. That's what
playing the game is all about.
It's about controlling your opponent.
You gotta find the right strategy.
It is not a game.
Everything's a game,
man. Everything's a game.
Just sometimes the stakes are
higher, and this time, it's my arm.
So, I'm guessing you
drew the short straw?
I beg your pardon?
Well, you're here, and your
co-residents are on the VIP case.
I'm awesome, and I'd still rather
be with Melendez and Andrews.
- No, it's fine...
- Relax, it's cool.
Tell me about our patient.
Thirty-four-year-old
female, software engineer,
entrepreneur, presenting
with compartment syndrome
caused by extreme
overexertion in a spin class.
The condition has caused
the muscles in her legs to...
- Okay, great.
- I wasn't finished.
Finished enough to show
me you're smart and thorough.
You know the treatment plan?
- We need to make incisions on...
- Good.
You take lead.
We need to make a number of long
incisions down both sides of each leg
to relieve the tension and
return healthy circulation.
It's important we act quickly. If we
don't get the swelling under control,
the damage could be irreparable.
What does that mean?
I could lose my legs?
From working out too
hard in a spin class?
No, don't worry. Your
sister's gonna be just fine.
Look, I am very confident
we caught this in time.
If you could lean forward,
I just need to check your
kidneys haven't been affected.
Let me know if you
have any tenderness.
Extracting the palmaris now.
Dr. Andrews, I read your
op-ed in Gen Surge News.
Brilliant piece.
I never realized the
lack of continuity of care
was such a severe problem.
Dr. Melendez,
you have very beautiful hair.
Thank you.
Given the patient's
grip weakness,
we could do a
nerve conduction test
to rule out any
concurrent nerve damage.
No.
Okay, that looks like
a good stopping point.
Dr. Kalu, step in.
- Something wrong?
- No. It looks good.
I just want to give
Dr. Kalu an opportunity
to show us what he can do.
As long as that's okay with you.
Sure.
Thank you, Dr. Andrews.
All right, looking good.
Let's move to the lateral side.
So, what are we
doing tonight, ladies?
How about we go to Viva's?
Sounds good.
Bovie.
You're awfully quiet
over there, Dr. Browne.
I'm just focused.
I know you're used to
operating with Melendez,
but we have fun here.
I feel like when it's less tense,
people make fewer mistakes.
Okay.
You wanna take the other leg?
Really?
Yeah, best way to
learn is by doing it, right?
Definitely.
So, go for it.
Well, it's another warm day
In the city of cold hearts
They all just play the
part of who they are
And I'm here on my own
I'd rather be alone
Than try to be
someone that I'm not
And you seem like someone
who could appreciate the fact
That I'm no ordinary man
Shaun. Good morning.
Good morning, Dr. Glassman.
How'd it go with Melissa?
She was very helpful.
You're wearing the same
clothes as yesterday, Shaun.
After you.
Apparently, we
are at an impasse.
I feel strongly that Melissa
can be very helpful to you,
you feel so strongly
that she can't
that you're willing to sacrifice a
good night's sleep and hygiene.
Shaun, you smell.
I will shower in
the doctors' lounge.
Well, great. That
solves one problem.
You stayed here all night
just to avoid a confrontation?
Just say no, Shaun.
You know? Just say no.
No.
Great. That's just great.
I don't have to see Melissa?
No, you don't have
to see Melissa.
You're a grown man, you
can make your own decisions.
I just happen to feel that she
could be of great help to you.
Tell you what, you
see Melissa three times,
and I will buy you the surround-sound
system you want for your television.
Are you bribing me?
I suppose I am.
If you don't like
her, she'll leave.
And I promise I will never
say another word about it.
That's a pretty good deal.
Okay.
I will meet with her tonight.
That's good, Shaun.
Saline? I've never seen
it done quite like that.
Yeah, I had a
professor from Portugal.
Apparently, that's how
they do it over there.
It's supposed to
lessen the pain.
Well, the good news is
your tissue's nice and pink,
which means it's healthy.
Unfortunately, the swelling's
not coming down like we'd hoped.
Does this mean you're
going to have to amputate?
No, no. Sometimes it just
takes time. We'll take care of you.
Very nice work, Dr. Browne.
Hey. Can you do me a
solid and trade patients?
No. Not a chance.
Andrews let me take lead.
Coyle let me take lead, too.
So, what is the problem?
He's a little too friendly.
He patted my
back in a weird way.
I don't know, it
was... It was awkward.
I'm sure he's just trying
to establish a rapport.
Maybe. I don't...
Shaun? Switch?
No. I like Bobby.
He has very good advice.
So, who did what?
Well, I did most of the
surgery, along with Dr. Andrews,
and Dr. Kalu aided in replacing
one of your torn ligaments.
You should be back in competition
shape in a few weeks' time.
Word! What about
you? What'd you do?
I helped to clean
the grafted tendons.
Huh...
That's it?
Yes.
Come on, you
didn't get up in there?
Your muscle weakness, along
with the high body temperature,
could be an early indicator
of multiple sclerosis.
We should order an MRI.
No, we have talked
about this countless times.
Yes. We should order an MRI.
We are not ordering an MRI.
You don't respect me.
Not right now, I don't.
Dr. Andrews, Dr. Melendez.
Given the fact we're
dealing with a pro athlete,
even the slightest hiccup
could be problematic.
I think Bobby would be impressed
by our being extra attentive.
Kalu is right. He is a pro
athlete in his prime earning years.
We should make sure
we leave him 100%.
Do the MRI.
Nice score. You got
'em to listen, do the MRI.
No. Jared did.
How'd he get there
when you couldn't?
He asked nicely.
Okay. You asked nicely.
Yes. Yes, I did.
You gotta be fierce if
you want the glory, bro.
No. I do not want the glory, bro.
I just want to be a good surgeon.
Everyone wants glory. It's
how you get what you want.
And everybody's got wants.
I want a surround-sound
speaker system.
To get it, I have
to see a therapist.
I don't wanna have
Okay, yeah, that's... That's
how I got my first PS2.
Yeah, my parents bribed me to
go to therapy after they split up.
What was therapy like?
Pretty basic, bro.
She'd tell me what to do,
how to deal with my parents.
Was it helpful?
I don't know. I never did
anything she told me to do.
Is that an option?
Doing whatever the hell you
feel like doing is always an option.
Just a gentle reminder. Dinner
with my dad tonight at 8:00.
It is on my calendar.
So was the Gypsy Kings
concert, and I seem to remember...
Fair enough.
How was the VIP case?
Shaun seems off about something.
Did you talk to him?
Yes, because talking to
Shaun solves problems.
- And Andrews is...
- Is a pain in your ass.
No. He's actually too friendly.
Jared kisses his ass
and suddenly he's cutting.
Well, ass-kissing is a
useful skill for a surgeon.
That's a very beautiful blouse.
Do I still have to go to dinner?
Yes. It'll be nice. We'll have some
nice wine, and my dad will pay.
- He'll push us to set a wedding date.
- April 25th.
Did you book something?
No. But my dad doesn't
need to know that.
What do you got?
Looks like the surgically
repaired elbow is fine.
As I suspected.
But Murphy noticed
something in periphery,
a little higher up,
just above the bicep.
It was my idea.
Yes, I just said that.
So, we took an image from
higher up and noticed this.
It's encasing the entirety
of his brachial plexus.
This thing is massive.
Biopsy indicated it's
definitely a schwannoma.
And it's definitely malignant.
It's in a tricky spot, but you
might be able to remove it,
follow it up with a combo of
radiotherapy and
chemo to finish it up.
What? What's the problem?
Robert Ato. Bobby Ato?
Pro-gamer Bobby Ato?
You a fan?
I met him three years ago,
oncology consult for SF Muni.
He had cancer three years ago?
Why the hell wouldn't you tell us
that you had already had cancer?
It was in my lower
leg three years ago.
How's that gonna change
how you fix my elbow?
It would have a huge
effect on how I viewed
the symptoms that
Dr. Murphy noticed.
You didn't listen to Dr. Murphy
because you don't respect him.
'Cause Dr. Murphy is different.
I respect him. He has good
ideas and he has bad ideas.
Turns out this was a good
one. That you shot down.
Why did you hide the truth?
A previous cancer
diagnosis isn't shameful.
After the first diagnosis,
all I was thinking was,
"Will it come back?
How bad will it be?"
I was distracted,
man. I couldn't focus,
and I hit a slump and...
You were worried that cancer
was messing with your gaming?
Yeah, man! It cost
me a championship.
I decided to block it out, along
with all the thoughts of negativity
and physical weakness, and like
that, I became the best in the world.
We need to do a full body scan
to make sure the cancer
has not already metastasized.
What he said.
What I said.
This looks great.
The swelling is starting to reduce.
We can start tightening the sutures.
Finally, some good news.
You look like you're doing
better, too, now your boss is gone.
Dr. Coyle? He's fine.
You don't have to toe
the party line with me.
Trust me, I get it.
I almost rode myself
to death in a spin class
because I overheard a
couple of investors say that they
liked the concept just fine,
but that my cankles
were too distracting.
What? Your idea is brilliant.
And you're beautiful.
Screw those jackasses.
Grace, you don't get
it. You've got the face,
the perfect, little
hip-to-waist ratio.
And most VC firms are
run by a bunch of bros,
so there is an inverse relationship
between the size of my ass
and how much money I can raise.
Then you should
do something else
where you don't
have to deal with bros.
Like what, become a nun?
- Sorry.
- You agree with her?
She nearly worked
herself to death
trying to please some
pigs with money?
She shouldn't have to.
Great. Let me know
when you find utopia.
But until then,
I love what I do,
so I gotta play the game,
'cause if I call them out,
I just get labeled a
bitch, or even worse.
Your heart rate's going up.
Hazel?
Hazel? She's barely
moving any air.
Hazel, can you hear me?
Code blue! I need
to intubate her.
Give me a laryngoscope
and an ET tube.
Code blue, 4 North, Room 407.
Let's get her on 100% oxygen.
Talk to me.
Her lungs. I think it's
a reperfusion injury.
Ugh. There's no room in here.
A Mallampati three, maybe four.
- You should take over.
- You're doing fine.
Here, use the bougie.
- You feel the epiglottis?
- I think so.
Okay, go a bit further,
you should feel it stop.
If it keeps going,
you're in the esophagus.
It's stopped. Got it. ET tube?
It's gonna be okay.
Strong work, Doctor.
Best in the world or
not, this guy's insane.
Hiding from a diagnosis?
It doesn't work. It'll find you.
Bobby wanted to be
the best. He is the best.
I don't think he was
trying to be the best,
I think he was just scared.
What's that? Next
to the brain stem?
Oh. Another schwannoma.
So much for the power
of positive thinking.
He's a strange
kid. He had cancer.
Stopped going to follow-ups
because he started losing.
What's so strange? Sounds
like a classic case of denial.
I was thinking we could try
something new. Maybe gamma knife?
I don't think so. Wrong
type of tumor for that.
What if I told you
every few months that
you had a real possibility
you were gonna die?
I'd be scared. And I'd listen.
Maybe you would,
maybe you wouldn't.
Personally, I think he's right.
Shut down those voices of doom,
spend your days living instead of dying.
But he may also be crazy.
Short of making him a vegetable,
I don't know if there's
anything we can do.
Is... Is Shaun okay?
Is his work okay?
- Yeah. I just, um...
- Then he's fine.
Damn. Horse walks into
a bar. Bartender says...
We found another mass.
That's not how it goes, but
cool. Let's knock it out, too.
The mass is located
on your brain stem.
Which controls your
autonomic nervous system,
your heart, respiration.
Its positioning
makes it inoperable.
I had a good run.
Wish it was longer,
but I'm gonna go out on top.
If you went out today, could
you say the same thing?
She's lucky you were there.
Me? You're the
one who saved her.
With your help. A lot
of it. So, thank you.
Hey, look, you wanna...
You wanna get a drink?
Maybe take the edge off?
No. But thank you, though.
Are you sure? I
promise you'll have fun.
Like, I give great massages.
And I'll make a killer
omelette in the morning.
That's really
inappropriate. I said no.
I'm sorry... Where's
this coming from?
You were... You were
clearly giving me signals.
No, the only signal
I gave you was that
I wasn't interested
in the slightest.
Okay, see, I
just... I heard about
you and Kalu banging
in the call room, so I...
This conversation is
over. You're an ass.
I'm pretty easygoing, but you're
approaching insubordination.
You're gonna report me?
I'm not gonna report anybody.
But maybe next
time, try not to have
such a stick up your ass
about being asked out.
Oh, come on. I always thought
Bunny was the cutest nickname.
Of course you did, but you
could have stopped calling me that
when I was 12, or... Or 20.
Rough day?
Yeah. Yeah, it was something.
Well, this should make
you a little happier.
I have decided to take
care of your entire wedding.
We don't need it.
- You're welcome.
- We're not 21.
We're more than capable of
paying for our own wedding.
We make good money.
But you won't once you
start having kids, Bunny.
What are you doing in here?
I'm hiding from my therapist.
I am not going to get a
surround-sound speaker system,
but I am doing whatever
the hell I feel like doing.
Mmm-hmm. Can you
hand me that mop?
Okay.
Are you satisfied with what
you've done with your life?
Would you be happy
if you died tomorrow?
Uh... Satisfied? Happy?
I mean, I clean up a building.
But I... I married
the love of my life.
We raised three beautiful kids.
One of them had some troubles,
but she's doing great now.
And the other two are
doing all right for themselves.
And I was good to people.
At least, I think I was.
That's a very good answer.
I've got pictures of the
girls if you wanna see 'em?
No.
So, why do I need to quit
my job to have a family?
Agreed. She can be a great
lawyer and a great mom.
Yes, she can, but why?
Why waste your time working?
You should be enjoying life like me.
There's plenty
in the family trust.
Dad, my work is important.
I'm helping people.
Bunny, you're pushing papers.
How is that really
helping anyone?
I mean, maybe I'm
old-fashioned, but I don't get it.
I thought you were
smarter than that.
You'd prefer her to be a lazy
parasite living off a trust fund,
as opposed to actually
contributing to society?
Parasite?
My father made a lot of money.
I'm not gonna
apologize for that.
He made sure his children
and his grandchildren
could enjoy their lives.
I'm not hurting anyone.
In fact, I go out of my
way to help people.
So, I'm sorry if that
doesn't qualify me
as a worthwhile
person in your book.
I'll get the check
on my way out.
Dad, you don't have to...
What am I doing wrong, Shaun?
I don't know.
I've tried
encouraging, I've
tried being supportive.
I've tried bribing you...
I don't need a therapist. No.
Look around you, will you?
You're sleeping... What is this?
A broom closet?
Look at the sacrifices you're
willing to make just to avoid...
We're going to
pick this up later.
You have to file a
complaint with HR.
I do that and I get
labeled hostile and difficult.
Neither of which work with
my complexion or gender.
All the more reason
to take a stand.
Claire, this situation is
exactly what HR is for.
I didn't say it was easy.
Yeah, you did.
Look, it's scary and it takes
courage, but it's the right thing to do.
It's a pointless thing to do.
- They'll listen to you.
- They will shift the blame onto me.
- Like you did.
- Whoa. What? How did I...
I came to you. You
accused me of exaggerating
- to get back onto the case.
- No, no, no.
It's not what I
meant. I had no idea...
I said he was too friendly.
You said he was trying
to establish a rapport.
I'm sleeping with you, Jared,
and you thought I was overreacting.
How do you think three
strangers will see things?
Claire, I am sorry.
I am so sorry.
Don't worry about it.
It's just the way it is.
I've got a patient to round on.
Dr. Melendez and I had a talk,
and we believe we
can excise the tumor
if you're willing to
make a sacrifice.
Sacrifice?
- That sounds better than death.
- My thinking as well.
We believe we can
remove the mass,
but we'll also have to take a
piece out of your brain stem,
a chunk of the red nucleus
which helps control
the left side of your body.
You'll be paralyzed
on that side.
It could also result in
difficulty eating and swallowing.
Speech difficulties.
Let's do it.
Good for you. Here.
Hold on, hold on.
Bobby, this is
very risky surgery.
You could die on the table,
and even if all goes well,
you will be severely disabled.
Yeah, I... I was
listening, and I'm in.
Guys, hey, I get it.
If I'm dead, I'm... I'm dead.
But if not, PT, re-learning
stuff, whatever...
It's not gonna stop me
from competing. Not ever.
Bobby, your career is over.
We need you to understand that.
Yeah?
Once a gamer,
always a gamer, huh?
You got my respect.
What the hell is your problem?
If you ever threaten Claire,
take a disrespectful tone,
or so much as look at
her cross-eyed again,
I'm gonna do a hell of a lot more
than put you up against a wall.
We clear?
Your lungs are
looking a lot better.
Overall, you're in
pretty good shape.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
All part of the service.
And good for you.
I wasn't sleeping.
I heard the way you
handled that other doctor.
You heard that? All of it?
I wish I'd done that.
You were brave.
No. No.
If I was brave...
Rick Allen.
Who?
The one-armed drummer for
Def Leppard. Come on, man.
And there is the tumor capsule.
Richie Parker. Anyone?
Isn't he a NASCAR guy?
An engineer, right?
Born without arms.
And Nurse Ocampo
gets the door prize.
And now we will take just a
little piece of our friend here.
- A nice sample to test.
- Thank you, Doctor.
And now the rest.
He may not be able
to tie his own shoes,
but I wouldn't bet against
him ever competing again.
Aut libertatem aut
mortem mihi da.
Shaun, do you know
what that means?
No. It's not relevant
to this surgery.
Oh, it's relevant. Look it up.
No, it's not.
Heart rate and ETCO2 are rising.
Slight change in
body temperature.
His heart rate's 108.
Check tube placement
and suction him.
If he takes a turn, we
might have to abort.
I don't think so. I'm too
far in. Keep him stable.
He's tachy. Heart
rate's climbing.
115, 117, 120 and rising.
He is going into V-tach.
Robert Ato's dying.
I'm gonna pull out
of the pons slowly.
No, hold on. You pull out
now, you might damage
the cerebellar peduncle.
If I don't get out now, I'll
kill him if he starts seizing.
Something's not
right. Tachycardia?
Bradycardia would
make more sense.
- Ideas?
- Anyone?
Tell me what you see.
Got tachycardia, rising
body temperature, again,
muscle rigidity, CO2 is rising.
Muscle rigidity? Which side?
It's all over.
Then it's not the brain stem.
We'd only have muscle
rigidity on one side.
Think. Tachycardia,
rising temp, CO2.
CO2. It's the anesthesia.
Malignant hypothermia.
Get the MH cart.
140 Dantrolene, stat.
Kalu, Murphy, get as many
cooling blankets as you can.
We need to get this
temperature down. Now.
- Coming up.
- Now.
Hyperventilate with 100% O2,
10 liters per minute,
flush out the old anesthetic,
lower the ETCO2.
I want vecuronium on deck. We
gotta keep him under. Let's move.
And we're on.
- Uh, temp's not coming down.
- Wait.
CO2 is coming down.
Heart rate is coming down,
too. Temperature is 101.
Okay. Nice work, everyone.
Thank you very much.
Terry Fox.
Or my personal
favorite, Jim Abbott.
Come in.
Hi. I need to talk to
you about Dr. Coyle.
Dr. Browne.
I wanted to talk to you
about the same thing.
Please.
Surgery was a success.
And the outcome might
be better than expected.
There will still be significant
neurological dysfunction
on your left side, but not
as much as we'd anticipated.
Sick!
Thank you.
You did good, my friend.
You have to be patient.
Nah.
Is patience a bad thing?
Acceptance is a bad thing.
When I was a kid, I
wasn't good at jack.
But I never quit.
Found my thing.
Don't ever let anyone tell you
what you can and can't
do.
I'm sorry for last night.
It was a rough day, I was
tired. Probably had a few, too.
Your relationship with your
father is your business...
Neil, you don't have to.
I'll call your dad and...
I don't wanna have kids.
Shaun, I'm gonna drive you home.
You're gonna see Melissa. If
you don't like her, she'll leave.
But there's no
more running away.
Why do you think I'm doing this?
Because you are stubborn.
Okay. Yeah, okay,
sure, I'm stubborn,
but I'm doing
this for you, okay?
So that you can have a better life,
so that you can have a happier life.
What if it doesn't
make me happy?
What if it doesn't make me happy?
What if it only makes you happy?
You think... You think I'm
doing this to make me happy?
I'm not happy, Shaun. I'm
not close to being happy,
and you know what?
I am done explaining,
I am done bribing, and I
am done talking. Now let's go.
- No, let's go.
- No! No.
No, I want to make
my own decisions.
Shaun, can you keep
your voice down, please?
You cannot keep
ordering me around, okay?
You're not my father!
I know that, Shaun.
I don't understand why this
is so upsetting, I don't get it.
Don't let anyone, anyone ever
tell you what you can and can't do.
Okay, don't let anyone ever
tell you what you can or can't do.
I have to make my own decisions
and I want to make my own decisions!
- Hey, just calm... Shaun...
- I don't want help!
What were you thinking?
I do not need you
to fight my battles,
and I certainly
never asked you to.
And if you really respected me,
you would not treat me like some
damsel who needed protection, okay?
You would treat
me with the respect
that you would
automatically give to a man.
You'd treat me like a person
capable of handling her own life!
I don't know, maybe, maybe
it's too much to ask of you.
Apparently Andrews
agrees with you.
I've just been fired for physically
assaulting an employee.
Shaun? Shaun!
Where would he go? Is there
a place he likes to hang out?
A place where he
feels comfortable?
No. I don't know.
He's not at the hospital.
And there used to be
a picture here of Shaun
and his brother Steve.
Well, what do you
think that means?
It means he's not coming back.