Okay.
Max, snow day! Yeah.
Heck yeah, snow day. Uh-huh.
I mean, technically
it's snow evening,
but that kinda lacks
poetry, don't you think?
Sure. There's nothing quite like
the sheer magic of
the words, "snow day."
Say it with me. Yeah.
Yeah, maybe later,
cause right now I gotta get
this hospital ready
for the worst storm
that we've seen in I don't
know how many years.
Seventy-two years.
Yeah, it's a long time.
But, you know, we had
comparable snowfalls
back in 2010 and 2016,
but this one's gonna be a lot
more like the great blizzard of 1947.
Why do you know all this?
Well, you know, I have a
passion for weather. Yeah.
Check this out. Look. I put
an anemometer on the roof
seven years ago and it
remains the best decision
I ever made in my life. Look.
I mean, look at the
fluctuations in the storm.
We can track it by its
geolocation, you know?
Oh, gosh, she is
all over the place.
Yeah, well, that explains
why half the hospitals in
this city have shut down.
Can y'all take those,
go to oncology.
On it. Thank you.
Private hospitals are wimps.
Public hospitals don't get snow days.
Laura, can we turn the heat
up two degrees? Two degrees.
Thank you. I stocked up
on food, meds, supplies.
I discharged every
patient I safely could,
and I pared down
to a skeleton crew.
Well, what about you?
You going home to Georgia?
I convinced her to go
to her parents' house,
where she'll be enduring a much
more judgmental type of storm.
Oh, right, I got ya. Yeah.
Looks like you got this amigo.
Oh, you know what,
this isn't so bad.
Ah, this is nothing.
The great white-out of 1888,
they had to shut down Maine.
Literally closed it
like it was a Denny's.
Safety first.
Well, 400 people
still died that day.
But we will be fine.
Move it!
Snow day, Dora!
Snow day!
No, I hear you. - Look it!
Look, I've got this
cool weather app.
Lauren, a patient
overdosed in her room.
Dr. Thomas got caught
in the storm. What?
Is she breathing or responsive?
Respiratory rate's low,
but she's oxygenating okay.
BP? 90/60, heart rate's 92.
Okay, well, if she's oxygenating
okay, then she'll be fine until morning.
Can't you help her?
You're a doctor.
I'm here because I'm not
allowed to be a doctor, remember?
She is better off
waiting for Dr. Thomas.
One perfect Manhattan with a
twist or one Paloma with Mezcal?
Both.
How about one at a time?
Snow's not going anywhere.
No. MAX: I didn't
even ask anything yet.
But I know what
you were gonna ask.
No, that's impossible.
Go on, then. Ask.
I need you to come
in. No, see, I knew. No.
But it wasn't
actually a question.
This blizzard is gonna be bad
and I need my deputy
medical director here.
But she only just left.
And she's about to get legless.
Legless?
Hammered. Sloshed. Sozzled.
Great, so then I
caught you just in time.
I hate you.
What?
Hello?
Sharpe?
Max?
How did you know?
I could tell. You
have to go back in?
Unfortunately. I am his deputy.
Turn in your badge, Deputy,
and be an outlaw with me.
But he is my boss.
Mmm-hmm. And your friend.
Isn't it hard for him to
see you as his doctor?
You play so many other roles.
Max is very respectful of my
role as his doctor, thank you.
I apologize.
I would never question your
effectiveness as a doctor.
I just wondered if the...
The thing you guys
have made it difficult.
Excuse me, Max and
I don't have a thing.
The vibe?
What are you talking
about? There is no vibe.
Then how did I know it
was him on the phone?
Maybe you're psychic.
Just use my phone
to call the kids.
Why do you need yours?
You know that they won't pick
up now and then when you leave,
I won't have a phone
in case they call back.
I will leave mine with you.
What if they wanna talk to you?
Chrissy, our Airbnb
is five full blocks away,
I am exhausted.
And it's snowing cats,
dogs, and reindeer out there.
It's good you got in from
Vermont when you did.
See?
No, sorry, I meant,
because we need to start
Chrissy on an immune
checkpoint inhibitor tonight.
It will make her glioblastoma
respond better to her clinical trial.
That sounds like something I
should probably tell the kids.
Tell them.
You sound exactly
like me and my wife.
Always arguing
about silly things.
I'm going back to our Airbnb,
so I can get a few hours sleep.
I will bring you your
phone in the morning.
Shouldn't having cancer mean
that I get to win every argument?
Hey, there's my deputy.
Wait, where's your hat?
Oh, I forgot it
because, you know,
I was forced out of the
warmth quite suddenly.
Yeah, but not wearing a hat
in this weather is a little insane.
Yeah, I'm your doctor, Max.
Not the other way around.
Hey, are you okay?
Um...
I'm fine, I just...
I just had to walk four
blocks in a blizzard because
my cab couldn't get
past this big accident
that's happened up
the street... Where?
35th and 1st, but
there's no casualties,
just people thought
they could drive in this.
Wait, what is it?
That's right in
front of Station 27.
I was just coming to find you.
When's the last time you
got an ambulance in here?
Forty-seven minutes ago.
This is Max Goodwin
at New Amsterdam.
I need to talk to EMS
Division Chief Molinari.
I'm on.
What's going on out there?
There's a huge pileup on 35th.
Snowplows can't get through
to Murray Hill or Kips Bay.
Are calls coming in?
Many, but without snowplows,
our vehicles can't get to them.
Chief, send me a log of
all your incoming calls,
and keep them coming. Copy that.
If people can't
get to this hospital,
then we need to bring
this hospital to them.
I know being stuck at the
hospital during a blizzard sucks,
but do you know what's worse?
Needing 911 in a blizzard and
being told that no one is coming.
So I have here a list of 911 calls
within a half-mile of New Amsterdam.
Ambulances can't get
to them, but we can.
And, yes, conditions are bad
out there, but we have got parkas,
and we have got emergency
packs, and we have got chutzpah.
Everybody is gonna
pair up for safety
and we're gonna give you a
GPS Locator, so we can track you
from right here in the hospital.
And to be clear,
nobody has to go.
But we're their only shot, so...
Any volunteers?
Sweet. I've missed
field medicine.
I'll go with you.
Casey and Flores, yes.
You guys have a doorman who's
arm was sliced by a snow blower.
1891 East 23rd street.
Nottingham, Moreland, you've
got a college kid who OD'd.
32nd and 1st.
Let's make sure
we have naloxone.
Great, Levy Park we have
a man who has fallen down,
can't move, may be unconscious.
On it. Thank you.
I'll go with you.
And calls keep pouring
in so just find your patient,
treat them, and get back
here so we can send you
right back out to
treat the next person.
And, guys, let's
be careful out there.
Always wanted to say that.
- Hi, everybody.
- I'm here.
Okay, hey, raise your hand if
you find the storm scary right now.
Big kids, I know it's
not cool to be scared,
but I bet the younger kids
will feel a lot better knowing
they're not the only ones
who are spooked right now.
So, hands up. I got mine up.
I'm scared.
But guess what, guys.
I have good news.
We got games. We
got games galore.
We got hot cocoa
and we got Gladys.
How bad could it be if
we got Gladys, right?
Everyone, follow me. Come on.
I'm gonna take you
into the fun room.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And even though
it's scary out there...
Avi, that's not helpful.
No, actually, it is
kind of helpful, Avi.
Thank you. Because
that freaked me out.
Right? My heart
jumped out of my chest.
But now that I
know it was just Avi,
I don't have to be
scared anymore. Right?
Because the more
you understand things,
the less scary they are.
Which brings me to
the star of this evening,
the world's most comprehensive
and cool weather app.
Look at this thing.
We're gonna learn all about the
storm through the majesty of satellite.
Oh... Skimbleshanks.
My anemometer
is not transmitting.
Okay. Uh...
Okay. Listen, Gladys,
why don't you go in there,
break out le cocoa.
Everybody, make me a mug, okay?
Extra marshmallows for me
and I will be right back, I promise.
I'll be right back.
Candelario, what you got?
EMS just got a call.
A man on East 21st Street heard
a crash in the adjacent apartment.
Older woman lives there alone.
He's been knocking,
but no answer.
No, no, I'll go. No,
I think I should go.
No, stay here, track
everyone in the field,
and manage them
when they get back.
Okay.
Whoa!
Hang on, I thought that
you were staying here.
Older woman,
unresponsive, needs a doctor.
Max, as your doctor, I cannot
let you traipse through a storm.
Then come with me.
Everyone needs a
partner, be my partner.
What?
You have a compromised
immune system and you shouldn't...
I'm not abandoning her.
Mrs. Calloway
suffered a massive MI.
She's in cardiogenic shock.
I will page Dr. Reynolds.
There's nothing you can do.
I'd be surprised if
she lasts the night.
I'm very sorry.
Please tell me you're kidding.
My patient is dying, her husband
needs to know what's happening.
But can't you call him?
His phone is here, and he's
not answering her phone.
Okay, but it's - 10 outside,
plus with the wind chill,
Vijay, you're not young.
I don't want Chrissy and
Connor's last few words
to be about some silly
argument about a cell phone.
Okay, wait, here. Take this.
So I can keep track of you.
Mrs. Gallagher?
There she is.
I can't feel a pulse. I got you.
Starting compressions.
Clear.
I don't feel a pulse.
Going again. Clear.
I got a pulse. She's back.
Have you seen our guy?
I can barely see you.
What's that?
Oh, God. That's him!
Sir, can you hear me?
Equal round, reactive to light.
His heart rate's around 30. Cold
weather really slowed him down.
I can't move. It's okay.
You fell and hit your head.
- What's your name?
- Hugh Torone.
I'm Dr. Reynolds,
this is Dr. Jessup.
We're from New Amsterdam.
We're here to help you.
Go help my husband.
Your husband?
I was running home from the
pharmacy when I slipped and fell.
His glucose was
monitoring 475 when I left.
Mr. Torone, where do you live?
Just a few blocks from here
on 29th, 464. Apartment 1043.
Okay, and the prescription?
It's in my left pocket.
Got it.
Run!
29th, 464. Apartment 1043.
Okay. Don't worry,
I got you, all right?
You're gonna be all right.
Jessup!
You really shouldn't
have come all this way.
Unfortunately, Marlene, no ambulances
can get through the snow right now.
Please, don't waste
your time with me.
Her blood pressure is dropping.
We're gonna need Levophed.
That's back at
the hospital. Yeah.
I'll go.
No, I will. No, I got it.
I'll be really fast.
You're not supposed to be fast,
you're supposed to be taking it slowly!
I came to keep an eye
on you, but it doesn't matter
because the only doctor
you ever listen to is yourself.
I am going to the hospital, you
are staying here, end of story.
Excuse me, please.
Ugh!
Okay.
She's very good
at what she does.
She's... Dr. Sharpe
will be right back.
Thank you, but it
really doesn't matter.
You're gonna be fine.
No, I won't. I'm a clairvoyant.
I've seen the future.
Today's the day
I'm going to die.
Whoa!
Oh!
All right, come
on. I can do this.
Wisconsin Strong. Let's
go, Iggy. There you go.
Oh, God! Jesus!
Oh, God, no!
Hey! Hello?
Heart rate's down to 48
and weak. I can barely feel it.
She stopped
breathing on her own.
O-2 sat down to 89%.
Grab the Ambu bag.
O-2 sats still in the 80s.
I'm gonna tilt her head
back to get a better seal.
She's going to aspirate.
Move.
Turn her on her side.
Keep working the bag.
One, two, three.
Okay.
Just give it a minute.
Get a message to Dr. Thomas.
She's gonna need to bring charcoal.
Got it. Thank you, Lauren.
Mr. Torone,
you need to stay
absolutely still.
Can't you just
pull me off of it?
No, not without risking
injury to other organs.
I gotta find a way to
get you to the hospital
without removing
you from the spike.
How do you know
it didn't hit my heart?
Because we wouldn't be having
this conversation, Mr. Torone.
Feels like you're about to become
an important person in my life.
Just call me Hugh.
All right, Hugh.
Right now I'm just trying to
figure out exactly how
this spike is penetrating you.
Well, it definitely doesn't
feel like missionary.
Oh, God. Apologies.
Eric says I should
know people a little better
before I make
those kinds of jokes.
Lift up a little.
Oh, God. Thank you.
I'm not cold.
You're not?
Hey.
You were asleep. You feel okay?
Oh.
I thought maybe I was dead.
No, Marlene. You are
not gonna die today.
Not on my watch.
Let's sit you up.
What do you know?
You're a doctor, you
believe in science.
Facts. The known.
Well, yeah. Me and
most other people.
I believe in the hidden.
I believe there's
a deeper spiritual reality that
extends beyond pure reason.
And while that's fascinating,
it doesn't have to kill you.
Why don't we ask the cards?
Split the deck.
And show me the top
card of the bottom half.
Uh...
Yeah, okay. Okay.
Ask the cards.
Here we go, split these.
What do you... What do you see?
King of swords. Mmm.
Reversed.
A very powerful card.
But one to be wary of.
Hmm. You help people,
sometimes at a detriment to yourself.
Yes, because I'm a doctor.
I see a woman.
But there have been
some bumps recently.
Okay. It's true, but
that's every marriage.
You try to meet her needs,
but sometimes
it's just not enough.
You're going to lose her.
Yeah, okay.
Why don't you try to
get some rest, Marlene.
Look,
my wife and I have been
through a lot this year,
but we are good now,
so I'm not gonna lose her.
I'm not talking about your wife.
You and your wife are fine.
There's someone else.
Someone you care for, deeply.
And you are going to lose her.
Hang in there, Hugh.
How you holding up?
You know, stabbed.
Ah! Found it!
There's a screw
attached to the spike.
If I could just loosen
it, I could remove you
and the spike together.
Oh, like a couple.
Sorry. Even with painkillers
you're gonna feel some stuff.
Stop!
Nope.
No, no. I'm sorry.
Keep going, keep going.
Why don't you
tell me about Eric?
What's he like?
We've been
married for six years.
Together since 1987.
Eric is smart and funny.
Oh, yeah?
So loving.
He's also the world's
best procrastinator.
He promised he would
refill his insulin two days ago.
I should have
just done it for him.
Yeah, look where
that literally landed me.
Yeah, my mom
forgets to do things.
Simple things, you know?
Like I told her, before the storm
hit, to go to my sister's and she forgot.
But she's old, you
know. It's not her fault.
I still get mad at her.
I don't even know why.
Maybe you're scared
that she's starting to decline.
I don't know, I never really
talked to anyone about it.
No!
Damn thing broke.
You have to leave
me now, don't you?
No.
You're coming with me.
I thought that wasn't an option.
Well, now it's our only option.
If you pull me off, won't I die?
If we stay here,
you definitely will.
Hey!
Hello! Hello!
I fully recognize that
I'm probably yelling
at nobody right now,
but if you can hear
me, I'm up on the roof
and I would rather
not die of exposure.
Thank you!
Whoa! Hey, hey.
Don't let that door shut.
Don't let the door shut!
Damn it.
Avi?
Avi!
Hey, Avi!
Okay, Marlene, this should
be making you feel better.
It doesn't,
but that's because
I'm gonna be dead.
Marlene, what did
we say about that?
Hey, can I...
Can I talk to you
for a second? Sure.
Look, I know that
we can't leave her,
but Candelario really
needs us back at the hospital.
Hang on.
I know that I haven't
always been...
You've been so...
You've always...
Never mind. I forgot.
Yeah, it's fine.
Don't worry about it.
Yeah, no, sorry.
I forgot. It's just,
chemo brain strikes
again, so, yeah.
I know that we need to
get back to the hospital,
but we really need
to monitor Marlene.
Mmm. Um...
Yeah. Telemetry.
We could get the equipment
from New Amsterdam
and monitor her from here.
Telemetry. Helen,
you are the best.
I think that's kinda what
I was trying to tell you.
Um...
Marlene, Dr. Sharpe
has saved the day.
We are going to monitor you
remotely from New Amsterdam.
I will be right
back. No, no, no.
No, you look wiped
out from your last trip.
You stay, I'm gonna get
the equipment this time,
but I am gonna go slow,
and I will take care of myself.
Because I love my doctor.
Have the two of you been
working together for a long time?
No. Why?
I just sense a very strong vibe.
Okay.
Honey, I'm sorry,
but it's never gonna work
out between you and Max.
I don't need it to work
out between me and Max.
Max is married, I
have a boyfriend.
And most importantly,
I am his doctor.
How you doing, Avi?
I don't want to talk about it.
Storms, man.
It's just pressure
and precipitation,
but, man, they make
us feel stuff, don't they?
Riddled with the
feels right now.
What about you?
How's the storm make you feel?
I don't know.
Yeah, you do.
Why'd you kick
that door earlier?
Let's start there.
I was just being stupid.
No, no, no. I mean, it
wasn't nice, but stupid?
Nah, I don't think so.
In fact, I think it may have
gotten you exactly what
you needed, am I right?
Come on, level with me.
What were you thinking
when you kicked the door?
That no one cared
that I was there, okay?
That's a tough way
to feel, no doubt.
So what were you thinking?
Why'd you come up here?
What was this all about?
Everyone was just playing games
and watching movies, you know?
And I was...
I just left the classroom to
see if anyone would notice
and be, like, you
know, "Where is Avi?"
But, you know, no one did.
So I just kept going
and waiting for someone
to freakin' notice
that I wasn't there.
No one did and when I
got all the way out the door,
that's when I started thinking,
would anyone notice if I was...
There are people that wouldn't
just notice if you were gone, Avi.
There are people that
would be heartbroken.
You're talking to
one of them right now.
We are not alone.
Avi.
Even when it feels that
way the most, I promise you,
we are not alone.
I'm really cold.
I know. I know
you are. I'm cold.
Here, here, here.
Okay?
Loaded you up with morphine.
The hospital's about
six blocks away.
Here's what we're gonna do.
We gonna go on three. All right?
Okay, all right.
Wait, wait a minute.
If I don't make it, you
tell Eric it isn't his fault.
I would have ventured out
into a million storms for him.
Okay?
All right. You stay with me.
Just look at me, okay?
Uh-huh. All right, I got you.
All right, here we go.
One.
Two.
Three.
Okay.
Marlene, we're going to
be monitoring you remotely,
so if anything happens, we'll
be able to get to you quickly.
Yeah. And as soon as the roads are clear,
we're gonna send an ambulance for you.
Marlene?
Marlene, are you feeling okay?
I'm fine.
See? What did we tell you?
But I really thought I
was going to die today.
Well, we're very
sorry to disappoint you.
It's okay, but I should
probably tell you both.
Since I was wrong about dying,
maybe I was wrong
about my other predictions.
I guess time will tell.
The roads will be clear soon.
Get me a gurney!
We've got a bleeder.
Let's go!
Get me to the OR!
Dr. Frome!
Gladys! Hi!
Oh, God!
I assumed you were
doing something important,
then of course I realized you just
had to fix your ridiculous gizmo.
Thank you.
Let's get you boys some cocoa.
Think I might need something
a little stronger than that.
Oh, boy.
Just be with her.
Tell her what she means to you.
Chrissy...
I'm here.
I'm here, sweetie.
Chrissy, my love.
My love.
I'm here.
Lauren?
Did you take any?
No, but I really,
really wanted to.
I'm never gonna
be a doctor again.
I can counsel people.
I can support them,
but the one thing that
I can't do for anyone
is make them want to get better.
And the only way you get better
is if you really, truly want it.
I know you want it.
I do.
I really do.
Oh, man.
Sorry, I can't.
You were right.
I am tired.
Okay. It's okay.
That's why I'm here.
Maybe...
Maybe I should listen
to you more often.
Okay, just lean on me.
Come on.
Vijay, my friend.
Hey.
Heard about what
you did. That was...
They were fighting.
It made me think of the
night my wife passed.
She had made
bhindi sabzi for dinner.
We were about to watch
her favorite soap opera.
Instead, we fought because
Rohan had not come back
home and she was worried.
I told her not to be
because Rohan was
a lost cause.
We both went to bed angry.
And then she didn't wake up.
All these years, I thought that
I was hurting because I
didn't get to tell her I'm...
I'm sorry.
But now I know it's because
I didn't get to tell her that
I loved her smile.
Her mischief.
Her heart.
Let's get you upstairs
so you can lie down.
Yeah.
Right over here.
Right here's fine.
Max?
Are you feeling okay?
Yeah, I'm just...
Just tired.
Yeah.
Well, it's almost midnight.
The witching hour.
Do you believe
in all that stuff?
I don't know.
Do you?
I don't know, either.
Max?
We need to talk,
about us.
Okay.
This thing between us...
Get this jacket off me.