Incoming, car versus motorcycle.
Car jumped the rails,
hit the cyclist head on.
37 year-old male,
unconscious and unresponsive
with an idioventricular
rhythm. Obvious head trauma,
brain matter evident on
the scene, 15 minutes out.
You heard 'em. Somebody
page Shepherd. Let's move!
- Got it.
- We're on trauma rotation.
So it's our job to
take point and assess
each medical
emergency as it comes in.
- Let's get X-ray in here!
- - Retractor.
- Talk to me, Grey.
- Peripheral IV's blown,
- pressure's plummeting.
- - Running a code can be chaotic.
Sometimes the best thing you can
do is know when to get out of the way.
- Someone page
Dr. Shepherd!
- V-tach!
- No pulse. Push one of epi.
- Starting compressions!
- Give me those paddles!
- Are wide open.
I was paged down to assess
the patient's head trauma.
When they stabilize him,
I'll go in, I'll do my stuff.
- Let's see what we have.
- Got a rhythm.
That's it. He's
basically brain dead.
Um, excuse me one second.
We're still gonna have
to cross match him.
- Yeah, of course.
- Hey.
Hey, look at this.
Blood type's a match,
skin's a match. Age,
size, gender, all matching.
- We got our guy.
- We got our guy?
We got our guy.
You picked a good
night to start filming.
- Yeah.
- This is gonna be fun.
We just got a call from
Dr. Sloan. He said to hurry over,
- so we got out of bed and came in.
- - Right in.
I was in such a hurry, I forgot my
shoes. Look, I still got my slippers on.
Ha! We've been waiting
for this for so long.
Today's the day. Today
is my transplant day.
- Yay, Transplant Day!
- I'm gonna get me some arms.
Seattle Grace
Mercy West Hospital.
Home to some of the finest, most
influential doctors in the country.
Several months ago, a
gunman roamed these halls,
leaving 11 people dead
and even more injured.
Today, we visit the survivors,
their patients, their triumphs
and their disappointments. This is
Seattle Medical: Road to Recovery.
Things have changed
since the shooting, sure.
For one thing, over the last
month, we have installed a number
of new, uh, security measures.
We're trying to make
it safer for the hospital,
the doctors and the patients.
- Come on!
- So, what...
We go through this every
morning. It's me. I swear.
I just... I have a different hair
color, that's all. It's... Chief!
Chief, would you please... Would
you come tell them that I'm me? Please?
Um...
- Excuse me. What's going on?
- I just... Every day.
Uh, we are fourth-year
surgical residents.
And, uh, we're
friends. Good friends.
It's pretty impossible to work this
closely and not become good friends.
Can we call Respiratory
to get a vent down here?
He's tachycardic
and hypotensive.
Decreased breath sounds on
the left. Let's get a chest tube.
- His blood pressure's dropping.
- Let's make sure...
Sure, going through something
like that, it's brought us closer.
Not that we
weren't close before.
I mean, ask anyone. We're close.
Dr. Yang and my wife
sometimes have sleepovers.
In my bed, with me in it.
So, yeah. Yes. It's
brought us closer for sure.
- He needs a thoracotomy.
- Right, right.
- Yes, please.
- I'll work the OR.
Where's that ABG?
Sterile drape.
- Here. Take over
compressions. Great.
- I'll get it.
It's, uh, 7am. I've
been here two hours.
My interns, they
got here before that.
They check on the patients and report
to me before I check on the patients,
report to my attending.
Lily! I told you already.
Turn it down or put in the headphones.
The rest of us don't have Bieber fever.
Whatever that is.
How have I changed
since the shooting?
Um...
I don't know.
Oh, I got this.
Today, I'm going back to Seattle
Grace for my colostomy reversal.
Oh. Babe, did we remember
my robe and my fuzzy socks?
Yes and yes. If by
"we," you mean me.
Because you forgot.
I was supposed to get
this surgery months ago but,
well, the shooting
happened instead.
- You have the parking ticket?
- Yeah, in my pocket.
I haven't been back to
the hospital since that day.
I don't know how it
will feel to be back.
That's right, it's
Portman. P-O-R-T-M-A-N.
And can you tell me where
I can get this validated?
- I'll take care of it.
- Thanks.
Hey, Dr. B.
Oh!
Yeah, I don't generally make
it a habit to hug my patients.
Yeah, well, when you get
paged 911, you don't walk.
You never walk.
OK, talk.
OK.
God, I can't get past the
obstruction. Damn it. How long?
- Five minutes.
- Damn it!
Yes. Yes, do it now.
No, no, no. Lily, Lily, I
know, I know this is scary.
You stopped breathing. And
so we had to take you to the OR
and put a tube in your neck
to help get you air. No, no.
You can't talk, OK? But we called
your mom at work, and she's on her way.
Lily was admitted with
respiratory distress last night.
She has a growth
on her windpipe.
It's benign, except for
there's nothing benign
about something that's
blocking your airway.
She's had surgeries
to remove it in the past,
but it's aggressive.
It keeps recurring,
and, obviously,
it's gotten worse.
- Much worse.
- - This is the nurse's button.
If you need anything, you
push it. I mean, push it a lot.
Don't worry about being annoying.
Push it till they come in here.
It's OK. It's all right. Here.
Not too loud, OK?
It happens more than you'd think,
having to do a procedure on a kid
with no parents around. Some of
these kids are in here for weeks.
Their parents usually can't
take off that much work.
But, I mean, we try to help out.
We have these beds, we call them
parent cots, for the parents to sleep in.
But a lot of these kids
spend a lot of time alone.
Just works out that way.
Doesn't mean they're bad parents,
they're just busy parents.
I found out last
night that he...
had been in an accident.
Just before the phone rang,
I had this sinking feeling.
Motorcycles.
Donor cycles. Isn't
that what they call them?
They called me in here because
even though Sam is a donor,
they need special consent
for something like this.
I know Sam would want to donate
whatever he could so, of course, yes.
They can... They
can take his arms.
Absolutely. I have
no problem with that.
Although... it's hard.
The thought of somebody
else... holding his hand.
See that? That
could be a problem.
What if we try a bypass instead?
Derek and I? We go way back.
We grew up together, we
went to med school together.
He's... he's kinda
like my better half.
Not the better-looking
half, mind you.
So when I heard he got shot...
Every day we give
bad news to patients.
We tell them their
loved ones are hurt,
or dying, or dead.
And for the first time in my life,
I understood what that feels like.
Feels like...
No, no. You're thinking
like a nerve guy.
- I am a nerve guy.
- It goes blood supply,
then nerves.
Actually, it's tendons, then
blood supply, then nerves.
Um, hello? What about the bones?
That's certainly something
to take into consideration...
Um, we estimate the surgery will
take anywhere from 15 to 20 hours.
We'll have two ORs going at once.
There'll be five teams of surgeons.
One team for each arm, and then a
fifth just to harvest veins from the leg.
You know there's only been one
successful bilateral arm transplant
- in the country. In the world.
- In the world.
I wouldn't go so far as
calling us medical titans, but...
- We are.
- - Not the first time I've been called a titan.
Uh, right now I am prepping
the donor body to extract
antibodies from his blood.
This is all in
preparation for later,
when we'll remove, uh,
bone marrow from the donor.
And then we'll infuse the marrow
into Zack to reduce the chances
of his body rejecting
the arms, which is huge.
More than huge.
I mean, I'm no
medical Titan, but...
still, it's pretty damn cool.
Uh, yeah, Zack lost his arms four
years ago. It was an accident at work.
He is... uh, he was a logger.
So it could have gone
either way. I mean,
this thing could have come
between us, or it could have
brought us closer together. And
for us, I think it's brought us closer.
Literally. I have to
wipe his... for him.
OK, really?
That's what you want to talk
about in front of everyone right now?
- I do.
- I'm sorry.
I'd cover my face, but
I don't have any hands.
- You been good since I last saw you?
- - Busy.
Bill and I left town
right after the shooting,
and pretty much
never looked back.
So far, we've been to Paris,
Morocco, Alaska, a
cruise through the Baltic.
- What?
- Blew through our savings, but,
- hey, life is short, right?
- Sure is.
Is there anything I'm looking
forward to once my surgery is done?
Babies.
Lots and lots of babies.
Deep breath. Another.
Enter security access code.
- You're sure?
- I'm sure. I'm sure. I'm sure.
- I'm sure.
- Enter security...
There are some kinks with
the new security system.
But there are always kinks
when something... new.
But we're working them out.
We got this, um, new
state-of-the-art like, lockdown system...
To isolate different areas of the
hospital in case of an emergency.
'Cause, um, supposedly,
the last emergency, there were
some people wandering around.
Even with the kinks, I think
people feel safer, which is important.
Uh, sorry to interrupt,
chief. I just... I got your page,
- but, hey, I can come back.
- Oh, nonsense.
Congratulations. I just heard the
big news, and I am so proud of you.
- Ah...
- Uh, our very
own Dr. Robbins here
has been awarded the
prestigious Carter Madison Grant.
Yeah, I haven't told
that many people yet.
A Carter Madison Grant? Nobody
wins those. I mean, nobody normal.
Just those brainy scientist types
who are from Germany and Sweden.
- Oh, my God! You won! Are you kidding?
- Nope. She is not kidding.
- Come here!
- Oh, thank you.
No, I didn't apply for the
grant because of the shooting.
There are major gaps in the care
of children in developing countries.
Global health initiatives
exist for things like malaria,
uh, infectious diseases, immunizations,
but not for pediatric surgery.
With this grant, I could
start to change that.
Well, I applied for this
thing two years ago.
I was a completely
different person.
I was new here,
um, a surgical fellow,
single.
But now I have people
here, important people.
Which complicates things.
But this is bigger than me. This
is the opportunity of a lifetime.
So, yeah.
Of course I'm
accepting the grant.
That just means
I'm moving to Africa.
Coming up on Seattle Medical.
How long has he been coding?
Dr. Torres? Have you seen this?
Oh, no! Oh, no, no, no!
Something like this
could ruin everything.
I mean, not just anyone is a
good arm donation candidate.
Not every candidate
wants donated arms.
Most amputee patients opt
to continue using prosthetics.
Think about it.
We're attaching two cadaver
arms to another living person's body.
That's the kind of thing that could
really mess with someone's head.
Not to mention the rehabilitation
time. Recovery from something like this?
- It takes years.
- The screening process
is extensive.
We have to ensure that the recipient
is stable, mentally and physically,
determined,
patient... very patient.
And that's all before you
can begin looking for an arm.
In this case, we've been looking for
arms for Zachary for over two years.
It's been a long time coming.
- Um, Dr. Torres?
- Hm?
Uh, you've probably seen
this, but have you seen this?
Oh, my God, no.
Oh, no, no, no, no. OK,
um, page Sloan. Right now.
A tattoo?
It's just so unfair that something
like this could ruin everything.
Hi. Is it true?
You guys are scrubbing in
on the double arm transplant?
- What's wrong with you?
- Nothing.
What's wrong with you?
Oh, no, yeah, it's a very
real concern, actually.
The patient could
easily reject the arms,
not just physically, but emotionally.
The first ever hand transplant recipient
ultimately asked to
have the hand removed.
He said he couldn't connect
to it, that it felt like dead weight
sewn onto his body. That the
hand wasn't, and never would be, his.
Imagine looking at a tattoo of
your donor's wife's name every day
to remind you that
these aren't your arms.
You're making me nervous. What's
wrong? Is there a problem with the arms?
Oh, God. There's a
problem with the arms.
Well... maybe.
Um...
There's a tattoo
on one of the arms,
of the name Nicole.
- I love the name Nicole.
- Me, too. I love it.
- Couldn't love it more.
- I say we rename
our dog Nicole.
I'm gonna name myself
Nicole. Change my name.
If it means I can still get those
arms, Nicole is my new favorite name.
Yeah, I was not expecting that.
He got that tattoo exactly
one year after we met.
He took me to the tattoo shop and
told me he was gonna get this tattoo
to show me just how much he loved
me, which is when I'm pretty sure
I called him an idiot,
or something worse.
You don't declare your love
for someone by getting a tattoo.
You do normal things, like plan a
nice date, or write a poem or, hell,
drop down on one
knee and propose.
You don't brand yourself
with another person's name.
Which is when Sam said, "OK."
And he got down on one knee,
pulled out a ring and proposed.
On the spot.
After that, every time, even if we
were fighting or I was mad at him
'cause he forgot to take
the garbage cans out or...
I'd catch a glimpse of that
tattoo and I'd remember:
This guy loves me.
Even if the garbage is gonna
smell up the yard for a week.
He loves me.
Loved me.
I don't even like kids.
Come on.
Pediatric surgery has
nothing to do with liking kids.
All right, Lily. I need you to stay
still, OK, or you'll mess up the test.
I'm gonna be right over there in
that booth. And that's how it goes.
Lily, you can't have
this in the machine, OK?
I'm sorry.
Hey, look, guys, why don't you
back off for a little while, OK?
Hey, it's gonna be OK.
You go into Peds
because it's elite,
hardcore, the best of the best.
Did you know that there are only
38 pediatric surgery fellowship spots
in the country? The country.
I mean, uh, to compare,
cardiothoracic has 120.
Pediatric surgery is
the elite of the elite.
So yeah, I'd consider specializing
in pediatric surgery. For sure.
But not because of the kids.
Definitely not because of the kids.
- Airway is clear.
- - The truth is that it's actually
a good thing that the shooting
happened here instead of somewhere else,
because we are better
equipped to handle trauma.
We see trauma
every day. It's our job.
- We got a stab wound there.
- Yeah, I got it.
- My monitor.
- Oh, wow.
- Uh, he needs surgery.
- OK. Let's pack it,
- stabilize him
and get him upstairs.
- Right. Um...
There's another incoming
trauma on his way in.
So I'm just gonna stay
down here and handle that.
Yeah, I mean, trauma
is a part of our job.
So improvising and thinking on our
feet, that's what we're trained to do.
No, it's not strange
Dr. Yang isn't coming with me.
I was available,
so I'll take this guy.
She'll take the next one.
It's first come, first serve.
Everyone wants
to get in that OR.
We're surgeons. We
live to cut. It's who we are.
It's not too late, you know.
We could move up our next trip.
Skip outta here and then
just catch a plane tonight.
You've been fine this long without the
surgery, you'll be fine a little longer.
Colostomy reversal
is a very basic surgery.
On a typical day, I might
do two or three in a row.
Uh, this was the surgery I was supposed
to perform on Mary that day, the day...
That, um...
Anyway... Um,
medically speaking,
she was getting a little stoma prolapse
and some electrolyte imbalances,
so it's good that we're
doing the surgery now.
It's good to get it over with.
So we just got Lily's labs back,
and I'm taking them to Dr. Robbins.
They don't, uh...
- At least you could be happy.
- Well, I thought we were happy!
Uh, should I come back?
No, whatever.
We're done, anyway.
Uh, you have Lily's results?
Well, it's her decision, obviously.
It's an incredible opportunity.
I mean, you don't just, uh, turn
down a Carter Madison Grant.
Nobody turns down a Carter
Madison Grant. I... I know that.
I understand that, I do.
I mean, if the situation
were reversed...
Actually, no. You know what? No.
If the situation were reversed,
I would turn the thing down.
I wouldn't even consider moving
to another continent right now.
But I'm not her.
So, uh, like I said, it's
an incredible opportunity.
Hope you've got
that bone saw ready,
'cause I am really in the
mood to cut off some arms.
Unfortunately, because
of her prior surgeries,
Lily has fistulas that make removing
her tumor that much more difficult.
The tumor is now so large
that it's impinging on her airway
and esophagus. Removing
the tumor would mean removing
Lily's entire trachea, which means
Lily wouldn't be able to breathe.
- At all.
- - The other thing that's changed for me
most since the
shooting is that now
I feel like there's always
something that we can do.
'Cause I should've died.
I was shot point-blank.
So, uh, there's always
something that we can do.
So you're saying
that if you operate,
it's a death sentence.
And if you don't operate,
So, in a few minutes, we'll be
ready to completely detach the arms
- from the donor.
- Why use zigzag incisions?
- To get
maximum exposure.
- Good. See what I'm doing here?
I'm tagging each
vessel, artery and vein
so we know exactly how to
hook them up to the recipient.
It's kind of like the
back of your TV.
You need to know which
connection goes where
or you wind up with
sound and no picture,
or picture and no sound.
The minute we remove the arms
from the donor, the tissue starts to die.
So we have to
work fast, really fast.
We have a very limited window
to complete this part of the surgery.
OK.
OK, let's get started.
You don't understand. I was
sent to get coffee for Dr. Sloan
because he needs
his caffeine. Right now.
To get through the most amazing surgery
that is happening right now in OR 2.
So I'm pretty sure it's not OK to be
late for the making of medical history,
so you need to let me through,
OK, to get to that surgery,
to get Dr. Sloan his caffeine, to
witness medical history being made.
- I... My ID is valid,
I promise!
- Let me take a look.
She swiped it a couple of
times and it didn't go through.
Go!
- Enter security
access code.
- Hey! Hey!
It's yours now.
Nurse! Come here!
Call maintenance!
Dr. Avery, Dr. Avery,
your patient!
Enter security access code.
- Enter security access code.
- Dr. Avery,
hold on! Dr. Avery!
Enter security...
So we're about nine hours in.
Dr. Torres has finished attaching
the donor arm bones to the recipient
with titanium plates and screws,
and now they are beginning
to attach the tendons.
I'm on it.
Look that that!
Where have you been?
How's getting shot changed me?
Um, I don't think I love my
job any more or any less.
Um, I don't think, um...
I'm a better doctor, or worse.
Uh, if anything, it's
made me grateful...
to be here. So, yeah,
getting shot has changed me
in the sense that I feel lucky.
We've reconnected
the arteries and veins.
But we need to check the
circulation before we continue.
What we're gonna do now is release
the tourniquets, one arm at a time,
and then look to see if
the blood flows into vessels.
- OK. Moment of truth.
- Releasing
the tourniquet.
- Arm's pinking up!
- Good.
The commute's tough.
We've been coming here
since Lily's tumor got
diagnosed three years ago.
It's just the two of
us, just Lily and I.
We live over three hours away,
so it makes it difficult for me
to come more than twice
a week and weekends.
I hate leaving
her for that long,
but I just want
what's best for her.
I want her to live.
Dr. Robbins came to me and she said
there might be something they could do
for Lily after all,
something experimental.
Um, that's why you come to
a place like this, you know?
Because even if it is a
commute, three hours on the road,
it's nothing if it'll
save Lily's life.
We've completed a stent to
temporarily help Lily breathe,
and now we're gonna
remove part of her twelfth rib.
See? It's just one more example
of how our doctors here rise.
First, a Carter
Madison Grant winner,
and now, cutting-edge
regenerative medicine.
Well, there's no artificial replacement
for a trachea. We know that.
Then I remembered a
study and I thought, "Well,
what if it isn't artificial?"
We're gonna use some of Lily's own
cells to manufacture her a new trachea.
Grow it in the lab. Remove the damaged
organ, replace it with a newer model.
Outstanding. Absolutely
outstanding, Dr. Robbins.
Let me in there.
Move. Avery, Avery!
Avery, look I was waiting in
radiation. How's the patient?
Damn it! How long
has he been coding?
Avery, you're
gonna break his ribs.
OK, OK.
OK. OK.
The new security system?
Yeah, I'm not a fan.
Compressions only last for so long.
So you call whoever you need to call,
you override whatever
you need to override,
- and you open the...
- door
before I report you for the
wrongful death of a patient!
Avery. Avery, it's OK.
Just hang in there, OK?
Avery...
You can stop now.
Someone else can take over.
Avery, look at me. Look
at me. You can stop now.
Avery, Avery. It's OK, it's OK.
It's been, uh... hard
since the shooting.
I, uh... I lost some
friends that day.
You learn to think
about things differently.
Like, um, buttoning a
button. You can't do that,
you know, even with the hooks,
so... you know, I just buy Zack t-shirts
and hoodies.
He can usually get those on by
himself, by using his hooks and his feet.
I help him bathe in the morning,
and brush his teeth and shave.
It took me a long time
to get the hang of that.
But it's all in the
wrist, I've learned.
And it's late.
I thought I would
have an update by now.
So, what's the big deal?
You'll visit her, she'll visit you.
- It's just a plane ride.
- Um, can we not talk
about this right now?
- Arm's getting cyanotic.
- - The vessel attachments are all good.
- Picture. We got picture and no sound.
- Excuse me?
Move over. Just move over.
Any update?
- What? Just tell me.
- Um...
There was a possible
complication with one of the arms.
Complication?
There's a clot and they're
trying to restore blood flow, but...
He could lose it, couldn't he?
One arm is better
than none, right?
- Do you need help?
- - I could retract that for you.
- You want me to patch that?
- Gimme a second.
- Are you sure
you don't want me...
- Give me a second!
I know what I'm doing. I just
need a second. Everybody shut up.
OK. All right. There.
Picture and sound.
I think.
- That's good. Nicely done.
- Perfect.
Basically, we break the
cartilage down to a cellular level
and turn it into
a protein liquid.
We build a scaffolding
to hold the liquid.
And we cook it in an
incubator to let it grow.
This is the incubator. We're
gonna grow the trachea in here first.
Then, once it's big enough, we're
gonna insert it into Lily's abdomen
till it gets stronger. It'll
be there a few months.
Then we'll take that new
trachea and replace her old one.
Some might say that a
shooting would set people back,
then you look at
residents like Dr. Karev,
and attendings like Dr. Robbins,
and you see their innovative thinking,
their resilience. You see them
becoming reinvested in medicine.
It's inspiring, isn't it?
I've mobilized the two
intestinal segments,
and I've stapled, and...
that's it. Textbook.
In and out in an hour.
Time to close.
It went well. Mary's being
wheeled into recovery right now.
- So it's over?
- It's over.
Oh, God.
- Oh, thank you.
- Oh!
Thank you.
Oh!
This is one surgery I am
happy to have finished.
Tonight?
I may very well
take the night off.
Go out. Maybe have
a drink. Who knows?
Oh! Gentlemen and lady,
we gave a man arms today.
- All right.
- I think of it more as I gave
a man arms today, the
rest of you just helped.
Another round for
everybody but my friend here.
That's a nice shirt, by the
way. Where'd you get that?
- The special Titan store?
- You saw the way she saved
that arm today? You wanna
hear something funny?
She hooked up my TV, I'm still
only getting sound out of one speaker.
So I'll have to irrigate the
trachea with this protein mixture
a few times a day every
day for the next few weeks.
Which means I'll pretty
much be living in this hospital
to make sure it gets done right.
That's my priority, is to
make sure this trachea grows.
And it's my focus.
I'll basically be eating, breathing and
sleeping trachea for the next month.
Do people treat me differently
now, after the shooting?
Uh, well... Um, I mean, yeah.
You're here filming me, so...
I mean, people like to say what
I did was heroic, but it wasn't.
It was just a thing I had to do. I
think people like to have a hero.
And it makes them feel better,
to think that there in the
middle of all that horror,
that there's someone special
working medical miracles.
But... I...
I mean, I don't have
super surgical powers.
I mean, I'm... I did what...
Cristina is a hero.
Especially to me.
The truth is, is most surgeons
could not have done
what she did that day.
- If you had seen...
- Stop it.
- Stop. Please, just can you...
Can you just stop this?
Can we cut?
Just doing a
little construction.
Things are always
evolving around here.
For the better.
Always for the better.
Whoa! Hey!
- How'd you let that happen?
- I don't know.
- You get it cleaned up.
- You guys all right?
Hey, let me give you a hand.
Yeah, he already has some feeling
at the tops of his new arms. Look.
Ow! Watch this.
Not bad, huh?
Look, right there.
You can barely even see a scar
where they put the tube in last month.
And now I'm back today to get
my new trachea sewn into my belly.
Dr. Karev calls me
the human incubator.
He's been sending me photos
from the lab of my new trachea.
See? Look at that right there.
It's really grown.
See, right there...
I always figured I'd
grow up to be a rock star,
but I might consider
being a doctor now, too.
I mean, Dr. Karev
is pretty cool.
Check it out.
Home-grown trachea.
Whatever you do, just don't screw
around and mess up my trachea, OK?
I mean it. I know you think
you're a rock star, but no mosh pits
or crowd surfing. I mean,
Lilith Fair is OK, but...
No drinking or drugs or
smoking or driving drunk
or giving your number
out to guys you don't know.
Um...
You get that I'm nine?
Well, I really can't believe it.
The big move to Africa is
really just around the corner.
Yes, I would say things
are better between us now.
And yes, we worked it out, even
with Arizona moving to Africa.
The fix was, uh, pretty simple,
actually. I'm going with her.
Got you some new flowers. Um...
Yellow ones today, um,
don't ask me what kind.
I have no idea.
They're, uh...
they're pretty, though.
Just like you.
It's rare, but sometimes patients
do not wake up from surgery.
With every surgery,
there is a risk.
In this case, the
post operative CT
showed no sign of
stroke, no acute bleed.
We've run PET scans, MRIs,
tried fluids, pressors.
Basically, that's what I have to
go and talk to Bill about today.
Mary has been in a
coma since her surgery.
There's no sign
of brain activity,
and now she's septic.
Her organs are failing.
Best-case scenario...
um, she'd regain some function
and wakes up with extreme
deficits, mentally and physically.
But the chance of her
waking up at this point...
It's hard. To imagine someone
surviving a crazy gunman,
and then not to survive
such a simple surgery.
I have to go and
tell Bill that it's time.
He has a decision to make.
Hi.
We went through the scariest thing a
person can go through, and we survived.
So now, every
day is just a gift.
And we're all just blessed.
Blessed to be here,
blessed to be doing
what we do best,
which is saving lives.
Every day.
One life at a time.
We're healed,
so we can continue
healing others.
Is there any one thing you'll
take away from all of this?
Being a hero has its price.