- Thank you.
- Stop trying to calm me down.
You're not good at it.
- I'm just saying,
there's no reason to be nervous.
- Joey, it's Match Day.
They're gonna hand me
a piece of paper
Telling you I am going to do my residency
I understand but
- It's literally the
turning point in my life,
both the world's assessment
of my past
and a map of my future.
It's my whole life.
- That's an awfully
dramatic way to put it.
- That's because you're
not good at calming me down.
- Pathology at Chicago Med
is your top choice.
Everyone here thinks
very highly of you.
You're at the top of your class.
Plus you are
extremely attractive.
- Joey.
- Reese.
It's going to be pathology.
You'll be down
in the basement with me.
- I'm still not calm.
- Well, I-I really don't
mean to nag,
but I think it's important.
- I understand.
- I know it's what Jeffrey
would have wanted.
- I'll think about it, okay?
Bye, sweetie.
I'll see you later.
All right.
Hey.
How are you doing?
- Fine.
- Really?
- Jennifer Baker.
The drug trial I got her on,
I found out they're
giving her a placebo.
- Oh, Will, I'm sorry.
- They're treating her cancer
with sugar water.
- Well, my mother-in-law
is driving me crazy.
- Cloth diapers again?
- No.
She wants me to
get Owen christened.
- So?
She's Catholic.
It's what we do.
So was Jeff.
- Lapsed Catholic.
And he hated parochial school.
Always told me horror stories
about all the nuns.
- Eh, we all tell those stories.
Doesn't mean a thing.
Hey, take it from
a formal altar boy.
Baptism's a piece of cake.
A lot easier than a briss.
- But I'm not religious.
Wouldn't it be hypocritical?
- Eh, think of it like
a vaccination.
Do it and get it over with.
Hey, this is my world.
I'll make a few calls,
hook you up.
We'll do this together.
Incoming.
- Lisa Patrick, early 30's.
Penetrating head wound
from falling ice
off the Citadel Center.
Tubed in the field.
BP's 90 over 50, GCS 3.
That's her husband.
- Dr. Rhodes,
you're going to Baghdad.
- We were just
walking down the street.
It fell out of nowhere.
- Tell radiology
we're sending them a head CT.
- Got it.
- Set her up on tele
and get a pulse ox.
Easy.
- Set on my count.
One, two, three.
- Oh, God, is she gonna be okay?
Maggie...
- Sir, I'm gonna need you
to step to the side.
They're gonna do
everything they can.
- Gonna need an O2 sat.
- She's completely unresponsive.
- Pupils are fixed and dilated.
- Her head is crushed.
- The ice is penetrating
through the side
and the back of her skull.
- Yeah, looks like the ice
clipped the carotid.
She'll start to pump.
Two minutes tops,
and then she'll bleed out.
- All right, we got to clamp off
the carotid now.
- Well, without a scan, we don't
know what we're dealing with.
- Agreed,
but we don't have time.
- No, you're right.
Let's do it.
- All right,
chest and plastics tray.
We're gonna explore the neck to
get control of the artery.
- All right, I'll get suction.
- She's bleeding faster.
- All right, turn her.
But gently.
If that ice moves,
she's gonna gush like a hose.
Knife.
- Here, doctor.
- Okay, here we go.
- There's too much blood.
I can't see the carotid.
- Not in a good way.
Bleeding's picking up.
- There it is.
Damn it, I missed.
- Ice is melting.
- Suction can't keep up
with the bleeding.
- All right, gauze.
- 4 by 4.
- Wait, wait, wait, look.
- Yup, there.
Clamp.
- Clamp.
- All right.
Pull with the Richardson.
I need a little more exposure.
- Uh-huh.
- One more.
And there.
- Got it.
Bleeding's stopped.
- Let's cover it up
and get her up to CT now.
Nice work.
- Crushed skull.
Too much damage.
- She's never gonna wake up.
- Page from Dr. Choi.
- He's in Trauma 1.
- I want it off.
- That guy's crazy.
- I want it off!
Please take it off.
- Tell ortho hand
we're coming up.
Get a CBC, ABG, chem panel
and type and cross him for four.
- Got it.
- This is Mr. Tacker.
- He was in a hardware store.
Grabbed a hatchet,
tried to hack his arm off.
- It's not me!
- Medics gave him
a milligram of Versed
and four morphine in the ambo.
- Mr. Tacker,
I'm Dr. Charles.
What's going on?
- Can you cut it off?
- I'm not a surgeon, but I'd
like to try and help you.
- How bad's the injury?
- Cut through the radial artery,
but I think we can save the arm.
- No, no, no, no,
please don't...
- Mr. Tacker, I promise you
we'll talk about this later,
but right now,
our concern is your safety,
so we got to get you
up to surgery.
- No, no!
Cut it off!
- We'll talk later.
- I want it off!
- Any idea what that's about?
- Hmm.
I definitely want
to do a drug screen,
but I think we might be
dealing with something else.
- Crazy.
Poor guy.
- Mr. Patrick,
I'm Dr. Halstead.
I just saw your wife's scans.
I'm afraid I have bad news.
The damage is catastrophic.
- "Catastrophic"?
- Her heart is beating,
but the ventilator
is the only thing
keeping her alive.
I'm sorry, but her brain
is injured beyond repair.
Lisa is never going to wake up.
I'm very sorry.
- No...
No.
- Mr. Patrick,
you take as long as you need.
Before we take your wife
off the ventilator,
someone will be in to talk to
you about organ donation.
Again, I'm so sorry.
Agnes, let's call Gift of Hope.
But we'll give him some time
to process this, okay?
- Uh-huh.
- Thank you.
- Dr. Halstead.
About organ donation?
- You don't have to
think about that right now.
- No.
We've been trying to have a baby
for months now.
I read where you could
still use someone's eggs
when they're like this.
To make a baby.
- I believe so, yes.
- That's what I want to do.
I want a baby.
Our baby.
Roge... Roger, I'm tired of
waiting on these bedpans.
This is not something
people can do without.
Or you're gonna be up here
mopping the floor.
- Hey, Maggie.
- Uh-huh?
- You know anything
about the Maldives?
- The what?
- Chain of islands near India.
Bert is retiring at
the end of the school year,
so now he's on this, uh,
this big travel kick.
- Ah.
A week at the beach
sounds pretty good to me.
- No, no, he's talking months.
Wants to experience
it like a local.
- And he thinks you're
just gonna let him
take off like that?
- He wants me
to retire with him.
- What?
- Ms. Goodwin?
- Yes.
- We lost a patient
this morning, Lisa Patrick.
Her husband wants to
harvest her eggs.
Do we have a protocol for that?
Ms. Patrick will have to be
on life support for two weeks
for hormone stimulation therapy,
followed by
the retrieval itself.
It's an expensive
and complicated procedure.
- Well, he seems
pretty committed.
He says his wife
really wanted to have a child.
- Well, I imagine she meant
she wanted a child
she could mother and raise.
This is a little different.
- A lot different.
- I'll call gynecology
and get the process started.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
- I didn't know what else to do.
My ex-wife's in China.
I, uh, couldn't
get a hold of her,
so I brought him here.
- Hi, I'm Dr. Manning.
Mr. Jenkins?
- Yes.
- And you must be Eric.
I heard you swallowed
some magnets.
- From a game I got on my desk.
Like these.
- Sorry, I thought it was candy.
- I took my eyes off him for
two seconds to get a juice box.
Kid's got quicker moves than me.
- Mr. Jenkins used to
play for the Bears.
- Oh, yeah, I think I remember.
My husband was
a big football fan.
So how many magnets
did Eric swallow?
- Two, maybe three.
It's probably nothing, right?
When I was a kid,
I swallowed a quarter.
Went right through me.
- Have you had a tummy ache?
Has he thrown anything up?
How long ago
did he swallow them?
- Couple hours.
It's not serious, is it?
- Well, before I say that,
I'd like to take some pictures
of Eric's belly,
just to make sure
that everything's
moving through okay.
Is that all right with you,
if I take some pictures
of your tummy?
- Daddy?
- It's gonna be okay, son.
Don't worry.
- I want to go home.
- Do what you need to.
- Hey, hey, Eric.
Do you like to play with
building blocks?
Because I happen to have
the biggest block collection
in this whole hospital.
Yeah?
Okay.
Stay right here.
I think I have so many blocks,
I'm gonna need
a truck to bring them in.
- Really?
- Uh-huh.
- I'll check back in
in a little bit.
- Full abdominal series?
- You got it.
- Nurse? Nurse?
Hey, nurse!
- Are you talking to me?
- Hello?
Been here for two hours with
snot pouring out my nose.
- I'm sorry, but we need to see
patients in order of urgency.
- And I'm dying of
a sinus infection.
Maybe if you got off that iPad
and did a little work,
- Maybe you just need to
wait your turn.
And I'm not a nurse.
- Handled like
a true pathologist.
- I know, I'm sorry.
- My Match Day, I threw up
six times and passed out,
so I'd say you're doing fine.
- You did not throw up
and pass out.
- Wanted to, though.
- Was emergency medicine
your first choice?
- My only choice.
All I ever wanted to do.
- Even though it comes with
a lifetime supply of
angry snot guys?
- Has its downsides.
Then again, how many
jobs are there
where you literally
get to save lives?
I'm sure you'll find pathology
just as rewarding.
- You are?
- No.
I don't get it at all.
- It's still there.
- Yeah.
I guess they were
able to save it.
- Oh, God.
- I'm sorry, it's, uh...
It's important to us
that you don't hurt yourself.
Mr. Tacker...
I'm a psychiatrist
and I'd very much
like to help you.
But I need to understand why
you tried to...
To sever your arm.
- I told you.
It's not mine.
It's not part of me.
- How long have you
felt this way?
- Since I was a little boy.
Four or five.
I'd look at it
and it just felt strange.
Like it belonged
to somebody else.
It's like walking around
with something dead on me.
- Sounds terrible.
- I talked to a doctor
a couple months ago,
asked him if he could remove it.
He threw me out of his office.
Told me I was crazy.
But I'm not crazy.
I've been on the Internet.
There are others like me.
I've tried to cope.
I just can't stand it anymore.
- Mr. Tacker.
If it's any comfort, I'm gonna
do everything I can to help you.
- So I got ahold
of Father Brady.
He's a sweet old guy.
Of course, he asked me
when was the last time
I went to confession.
Anyway, he's pretty booked up,
but he says if we commit today,
he can baptize Owen next Sunday.
- That soon?
- Yeah.
- Dr. Halstead?
I need to see you.
- Let me just
think about it, okay?
- I just examined your patient
for the egg harvest protocol,
and I can't in good conscience
go forward with it.
- This woman didn't want to
have children.
- Why would you say that?
- She was using birth control.
Look.
- An IUD.
- Mm-hmm.
- It's not true.
- I can show you the ultrasound.
The IUD is definitely there.
- Maybe it's something else?
A growth?
- Mr. Patrick,
your wife was on birth control.
- But it doesn't make sense.
We were trying to
start a family.
- I can understand how hard
this must be for you.
- No!
We were tracking her cycles,
using ovulation kits.
We had names picked out.
- I know how much
you wanted a child.
I'm sorry things
didn't work out.
And I'm sorry you can't ask her.
- Excuse me, sir.
- Oh.
- I'm sorry.
- Oh, man...
I'm so sorry.
- Oh, please, this is
the least disgusting thing
I've cleaned up all day.
I, uh, wanted to thank you for
the way you calmed Eric down.
Since his mom and I split,
he really doesn't
get that sort of thing much.
- Well, it was my pleasure.
- He's falling for you.
- No, he isn't.
- I've seen that look
a million times.
His angel of mercy.
- Dr. Charles.
What's the word
on Mr. Tacker?
- No physical issues that would
make him want to self-amputate.
His labs are clean;
he's not on drugs.
- Psychotic.
- He is, in fact,
entirely rational.
- I think he might be suffering
from a very rare condition,
something I never
dealt with before.
B.I.I.D.
Body Integrity
Identity Disorder.
Bear with me now.
These people believe
that one of their limbs,
a part of their body,
is not their own.
His sense of self
does not extend
to the fingers of his left arm.
It stops at the elbow.
Sorry.
- I mean, who are any of us
to say where we end, right?
Or begin?
I mean, physicists will tell you
there's no physical self at all.
Right?
Just waves of energy.
A mystic will say that
we're all one big soup.
- I'm not a physicist
or a mystic.
I'm a doc who's spent his career
treating wounded soldiers
who begged me,
"Save my leg, save my arm."
You don't think you should
commit this guy?
- At this point,
my only option is to put him
on a 72-hour
suicide hold.
And then I got to
let him go home.
- And then what?
He'll try it again?
- Unless I can find a way
to treat him.
- Will.
- Hey.
What'd you decide?
Should I call Father Brady?
- No, it's, uh,
it's something else.
Jennifer Baker.
I heard from a trial nurse.
- What?
- She's going downhill.
Fast.
I'm sorry.
- I know it was coming.
But still...
If I'd just left her alone,
she would've been
spared all of this.
- Dr. Manning.
The little boy, Eric Jenkins,
his x-rays are up.
Better take a look.
- Page Dr. Rhodes, please.
- Will do.
- I'll talk to you later.
- And arms up.
- So they ever
give you guys breaks?
- Only as often
as the state requires.
- Maybe after Eric
gets the all-clear,
we could go out
for coffee sometime?
I'll try not to spill it on you.
That's really sweet,
but we're discouraged
from going out with our patients
or their families.
- I won't tell if you won't.
- Um...
Oh, gosh, I'm sorry, Eric.
I... there is this thing
called transference.
Um, people develop feelings
for their caregivers.
It's not real.
- Hi, Mr. Jenkins,
I'm Dr. Rhodes.
Dr. Manning's
asked me to consult.
- Would you mind
stepping out for a minute?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
- Eric, can you show me
what you just made?
What is that?
- These are Eric's x-rays,
and these two dots
are the magnets.
They're attracted to
one another,
and if they meet,
they could pin separate parts
of his digestive tract together
and erode through
the thin intestinal walls.
- Which could cause
systemic infection,
obstruction, bleeding.
And any of those things
could be life-threatening.
- All right, so... okay, so, um,
so what should we do?
- In my opinion, we should
remove them surgically.
- But isn't surgery
kind of risky, too?
- Uh, yes, there is the
possibility of adhesions,
motility issues.
- What does that mean?
- His digestive tract
wouldn't work as well.
- The argument for surgery
outweighs the possible risks.
Every minute that we wait
increases the chance
of a bad outcome.
- I still can't
reach my ex-wife.
- Why don't you think about it?
I'll monitor Eric closely,
we'll get another set of x-rays,
and then we'll check back
in a little bit, okay?
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- Natalie.
The kid needs surgery.
- Surgery could leave him with
a lifetime of complications.
It's not an easy
decision to make,
and that dad has to
make it all on his own.
You have no idea
how difficult that is.
- Mr. Wirtz?
Mr. Wirtz!
His pressure
just shot up over 190.
- He's not breathing
and his pupils are blown.
Call neurosurgery.
I need to intubate.
- He just got a head CT.
Look.
That's a Mount Fuji sign.
Air building up in his skull,
which means this is not mucous
coming out of his nose.
It's cerebrospinal fluid
from his brain.
He must've fallen
a few days ago.
This isn't a sinus infection.
This is an anterior
skull fracture.
And if we don't release
the pressure immediately,
he's gonna die.
I'm in.
Maggie, get the drill.
- Got you.
- Code blue team to the ED.
- Dr. Choi, I need you
to drill a burr hole.
- Can't.
Gunshot just came in.
- But this man's got about...
- You've seen it done.
Do it.
- Who's gonna do this?
- I am.
- But you're a med student.
Somebody has to.
Here.
We're both gonna
catch hell for this.
- Yeah.
- Are you sure you're
in the right spot?
- Three centimeters
from the midline.
Should be right above
the pocket of air.
- "Should be"?
- I'm through.
- BP back down 130 over 74.
- Damn, Reese, you did it.
- Uh-huh.
See what's taking neuro
so long to get down here.
- Got you.
- So I'm thinking our best
approach would be
a course of both medication...
A serotonin reuptake inhibitor...
And psychotherapy.
- It's not gonna work.
- How do you know
until we've tried?
- You see that guy out there?
They gave him something
called a nerve block.
- It's a regional anesthetic
injected near a nerve
to block a specific site.
- Maybe that could work for me?
You know, so I wouldn't
be so aware of the arm.
- Well, it wouldn't be
a permanent fix.
- I would do anything to make
this feeling go away,
even for a minute.
- Right.
I understand, I understand.
- And I would try the meds
and the psychotherapy
along with it.
- I would need your assurance
that you'd both
stick with your therapy
and that you wouldn't
harm yourself.
- I promise.
- Look, why don't I consult
an anesthesiologist
and, um...
And we'll go from there.
- Dr. Charles?
Do you think someone could get
me out of these restraints?
- All in due time.
For now, frankly, I'm just, uh...
I'm really encouraged
that we've come up with a plan.
- Ms. Patrick's still hooked up
to the ventilator.
Her husband agree
to organ donation?
- Not yet.
- He said anything?
- Just sits there.
- Hey, Father.
No, no, she hasn't decided yet.
As soon as she does,
I'll... I'll call you, okay?
All right, thanks.
Helping Natalie
with the baptism.
- Uh-huh.
She wants you to do that?
- Course.
Why wouldn't she?
What?
- You want my opinion?
- Sounds like I'm
going to get it.
- You need to give
that woman some space.
- Did you drill the burr hole
in the patient's head?
- I did.
- Ms. Reese,
you're not a doctor.
You're a student granted access
to this hospital,
strictly for learning purposes,
which means you are not licensed
to perform an invasive procedure
on a patient
without direct supervision
by an actual physician.
It is, in fact, illegal.
- I understand.
- I gave the order.
- Excuse me?
- I was confident she was
capable of this procedure.
- I'd warn you to be
very careful what you say.
- I've had extensive
clinical experience
with student doctor Reese.
I have full faith
in her abilities.
If you disagree with
this patient's treatment,
your disagreement is with me.
Don't either of you ever
put me in this position again.
- You did not have to do that.
- It's the truth, Reese.
And you're family.
We rise or fall together.
- Some help here!
I need some help!
- Daddy, Daddy!
- He threw up blood.
- Call the OR.
We're taking him up now.
- Okay.
- It's like you said, right?
The bleeding.
We should have operated.
- Wait here.
We'll keep you updated.
- It's my fault.
This is...
This is my fault.
- Looking for magnets in the
intestine is a little bit like
looking for a piece of gum
in a garden hose.
- How's the bowel look?
- Obstructed,
but no gross ischemia.
Looks like we got here in time.
One's in the stomach,
the other small intestine.
Let's get him out of here
while the bowel
still has some life in it.
Damn.
- What is it?
- The magnets must have
eroded through an artery.
- I need an extra
set of hands now.
- I haven't done that
since medical school.
Call a surgical resident.
- There's no time.
Get in here.
Here.
Hold this back.
There.
Right there.
- I'm getting a ton of blood
from the NG tube.
I got to give him a unit.
- He's a kid.
Not yet.
- I keep slipping.
- Can you get it?
- No, I lost it.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Hold still.
There.
Pinch down.
Right there.
- Got it.
- Good.
Clamps.
- Clamp.
- I don't see the vessel.
- It's buried in the fat,
but you've got it.
Trust me.
All right.
Now let go.
- BP's stable.
- Good.
Let's tie these off,
close up the holes,
and get him on his way.
Thank you,
Dr. Manning.
- Eric did fine.
He's gonna be okay.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
- Dr. Rhodes will come soon
and talk to you.
- Can I see my son?
- Yes.
In a little while.
Eric will be in the hospital
for four to five days,
maybe a week.
So I guess I'll be seeing you.
- Yeah.
- Got to get back to work.
- Sure.
- He's a young kid;
he's healthy.
He will heal fast.
Now be honest,
you kind of liked using
the giant intestine stapler.
I kind of liked using
Everybody does.
Hey, I'm sorry for earlier.
When I snapped at you.
- It's okay.
- I just...
I felt for that dad.
Single parent, having to make
that decision by himself.
- I imagine it can't be easy.
- I have a decision
of my own to make.
Nothing so momentous,
but I'm having a tough time.
My mother-in-law is insisting
I get Owen baptized.
- Oh, family drama.
Now you're in my wheelhouse.
- Yeah.
Family and religion.
- You know, religion was
actually the one topic
we managed to avoid.
Dad never saw the upside to it.
- You're lucky.
- I don't know.
I always kind of envied
the kids who went to church.
You know, they were
a part of something.
It's like they had
their own tribe.
- Mr. Tacker.
I see you've had
your nerve block.
Should be starting
to feel it by now.
- I feel so much better.
How long will it last?
- Oh, several hours.
But we could always
re-administer
for longer periods.
I wanted to use the nerve block
in conjunction with
another approach
that I've been looking into.
It's called
"pretend therapy."
- The idea is that you function
as if the limb weren't there.
See what it's like
to go through life without it.
It's cognitive work.
- Sorry, I'm so tired.
- You know what?
The anesthesiologist
administered a mild sedative
before giving you the block.
Why don't I check back
with you in a bit,
and we'll get started?
- Could you pull my covers up?
I'm just a little cold.
Dr. Charles.
Thank you.
For everything.
- Come on.
We're a team.
- Hope you're not
planning on jumping.
- No.
Everything is mixed up.
I saved a life.
And that was good, really good.
And then I got in trouble,
and that was bad.
And then Dr. Choi
stuck up for me.
Called me family.
- That sounds good, too.
- It was.
- So...
why are you out here?
'Cause it's Match Day,
and everything's mixed up!
- It'll all be clear very soon.
- Yeah.
- Mrs. Baker is too sick
to continue the trial.
- She's going home.
She's finally getting her wish.
- Yes.
- Dr. Halstead.
Dr. Halstead.
Guy in three
dislocated his shoulder.
Go.
Pop it back in.
- Okay.
- Blood pressure spiked.
- Mr. Tacker?
- I'm sorry!
- He slipped his restraint!
- He made a tourniquet
out of tubing.
Half milligram dilaudid.
- Yes, Dr. Charles.
- No, no, no, don't touch it!
The arm's dead.
You dump potassium
into the bloodstream,
he'd go into
cardiovascular collapse.
We have to amputate his arm.
Let's go!
- I'm sorry.
I had to!
- Yes!
Yes!
- Here you go.
- Mayo, baby!
Yes!
- Reese, Sarah.
- I haven't got room for them!
Yes, this is
your problem, Roger.
Get them out of here!
- This is a lot of bedpans.
Are we expecting
a listeria outbreak?
- Some idiot in supply
added a zero to my order.
So instead of four dozen...
- You got 40 dozen?
- Uh-huh.
- See?
You can't retire.
How could you give all this up?
- Yeah, how could I?
It's so much better
than the Maldives.
- Well?
You got it!
Chicago Med, pathology.
This calls for celebration.
- Yeah.
- I'll get my coat,
and um, check Groupon,
and see where I can get a deal.
Congratulations.
- Reese.
You get your match?
- Uh-huh.
Pathology.
- Congrats!
That's what you wanted, right?
- Yeah.
Yeah, um, but this was starting
to feel sort of like home.
- Yeah.
We'll miss you.
- He played us.
- You mean me.
Look, nobody likes
getting snookered.
But that's not
what's bothering me.
It's why I fell for it.
- He's a good liar.
- Not really.
I didn't see the depth
of his desperation.
You know, didn't want to.
So I just pulled out
my standard playbook...
Meds, psychotherapy.
- What else could you have done?
- I could have gone up to ortho.
Looked for somebody
to take his arm off.
- Dr. Charles, we can't
intentionally maim a patient.
- Of course not.
All I'm saying...
in cases like this,
are the decisions we're making
really in the patient's best
interest, or are they in ours?
To make us feel better?
'Cause like it or not,
that's a happy ending.
- Mr. Patrick...
- You didn't know her.
I knew her.
- Come in.
- You paged?
- Uh, yes.
Mr. Patrick wants to
go forward
with the egg harvesting
protocol.
- I don't understand.
- Despite the IUD, he says
his wife would want this.
Hospital council says
we have no choice.
We have to restart Ms. Patrick
on the protocol.
- It's not right.
Loud and clear.
- Yes.
I agree.
- So why won't he listen?
- Well, Dr. Halstead,
sometimes we want to believe
something so badly,
we ignore the reality
in front of us.
You're familiar with that,
aren't you?
- Yeah.
- Hey.
- So...
I-I appreciate all the
trouble you've gone to.
The church, the priest.
Just not like that.
- Like that?
- I want Owen to be
a part of a community.
I just want it to be one
that I'm a part of.
So I'm gonna do it my own way.
I know Helen's gonna be upset,
but I hope you won't be.
- No.
Natalie...
it's your life.
And I want whatever's
best for you.
I need to move on.
So, as Father Brady would say,
"Go in peace."
- Can you just watch her
for a minute?
Thank you.
Thank you for
not giving up on Jen.
- We're here today to celebrate
the newest member
And as we do at weddings
and funerals,
to offer our love and support.
It is the people in our lives
who bring us joy.
They are the color of our lives.
The beauty and the grace.
I can see by
this gathering today,
you will not walk
through life alone.
And so, little man,
I wish you Godspeed.
In front of all these
gathered on your behalf,
I baptize you,
Owen Jeffrey Manning.
- I thought he was gonna hit me.
But he thanked me.
- Must've been a relief.
- Jay, she was on a placebo.
They never knew.
It was all for nothing.
- No, you cared.
I think, if we care, then...
whatever happens,
it's for something.
We might not see the effect,
but...
It goes out there
and it circulates around.
It makes us all better,
you know?
- My brother,
cop and philosopher.
- You've got to think
big picture.