So you want me to
explain how you just lost?
Or do you want to stare at the
board your full three minutes,
cling to hope?
Come on. It's
called speed chess.
Hey, hey, hey, goodbye
Good game.
I said good game.
Hey! Hey!
Wait! Stop it! Listen...
Back away. Back away.
Call 911. Get an ambulance!
Tell them to send two!
My head's going to explode!
Your head still hurt?
You a moron?
Nate!
I'm clutching my head in
pain and he asks if it hurts?
What are you, some
kind of med student?
You look like you still
have theme birthday parties.
Sorry.
Any problems concentrating
in school lately?
What, besides the dreams of running my
tongue along my French teacher's breasts?
No, I'm doing quite great.
The rage and pain could
be caused by a parasite.
Does he eat a lot of sushi? No.
He was a vegetarian
until just a few months ago.
Any changes in behavior
since the new diet?
No.
He's been this way since
he became a teenager.
It doesn't matter how much I yell
or punish, he's still gonna say what...
Yeah. Let's all shed a tear
for poor little Nate's mother.
Any more stupid questions? Nate!
I hate this kid.
I like this kid.
You haven't met him.
I know you hate him. What
more do I need to know?
Kid's not a cliché. Anybody
can get into a fight after losing.
It takes real creativity to
beat up someone you just beat.
The pain's not
limited to his head.
The rest of his bumps and
bruises are accounted for
by the 17 fights he's
been in this semester.
Concussion?
MRI was clean, no
frontal lobe tumor,
and the tox screen showed no
trace of coke or amphetamines.
Nate went medieval
on the other kid.
Could be... Hold on.
I'm having a moment.
This could be Foreman's last time
mistakenly suggesting adrenal gland tumor.
Which could create excess adrenaline,
causes the head pain and rage.
But not the
personality disorder.
There is no
He's a teenager.
Being a teenager excuses
the odd inappropriate comment.
This kid say
anything appropriate?
He's having cluster headaches.
Probably been having them for
years. Question is, what's causing them?
If it were just a cluster headache,
he'd have swelling around the eyes.
ER gave him
ibuprofen for the pain.
Useless for this pain, but it
could've knocked down the swelling.
Best bet is a vascular problem.
Normal treatment for cluster headaches
is steroids, which the ER also gave him.
He's still in pain,
which means...
Normal treatment is
called "normal treatment"
because sometimes you
have to use abnormal treatment.
Start him on blood thinners,
and give his noggin
transcranial magnetic stimulation.
And don't you dare
touch that acerbic wit.
Fifty bucks to whichever of
you steps up and treats this brat.
Not the kid's fault. He's sick.
Fine. You do it.
No way. He's your brat.
I'll do it. But I've got a
job interview after work.
Anything comes up
later, you guys handle it.
Need a peer recommendation?
Thanks.
Cameron should suffice.
This isn't going to turn me into
some, like, drooling vegetable
who wets his pants, is it?
It's safe.
The magnetic pulses activate nerve cells,
which will hopefully squelch the head pain.
Is there anything you can
do about the other pain?
From the fights?
Yeah, I mean, my face,
my shoulder, my stomach.
I mean, I can barely
bend my fingers.
You're already on pain
meds. Nothing more I can do.
Sure you can, man.
Tell your homies to
quit stomping on me.
I'll get the word out
that you're a great guy.
So do people watch
what they say around you?
Because I'm black?
No, because you're gay.
Cluster headaches
can persist for years,
cause irritability or even
hostility towards others.
You mean the illness is
affecting his personality?
If these treatments
work, it could...
Change him? Yeah.
Oh, thank God!
You must think I'm awful.
Here my son's lying
in a hospital bed...
I'm pretty sure I get it.
I thought I was a bad mother.
And I hated myself
because I hated him.
What do you got for
me this fine morning?
Blood thinners and TMS had no
effect. It's not cluster headaches.
You accusing the
symptoms of lying?
Could be hemochromatosis.
Wouldn't account for
the personality disorder.
What about hypothyroidism?
He's not getting aggressive and lethargic.
He's getting aggressive and aggressiver.
What about ruptured
dermoid cyst?
Sorry. I just got dizzy there.
I was expecting to turn right.
It's Foreman's turn
to be shot down.
The thing that Cameron said.
Way to think outside the box.
But no fat in the ventricles.
It's cluster headaches.
Normal treatment didn't work.
Abnormal treatment didn't work.
Good point, Foreman.
But treatments don't always
work. Symptoms never lie.
The only approved treatment left
for cluster headaches is brain surgery,
and that's not even a guarantee.
Back off, Foreman!
If the approved treatment doesn't work,
we go with an unapproved treatment.
Hey!
Something on your mind?
Because you totally can't tell.
I had a job interview lined up
at New York Mercy yesterday.
Hospital for Manhattan's glitterati. Big
coup. Your homies would be kvelling.
Didn't happen, because
apparently I called to cancel.
I don't remember
making that call.
You think I have a
neurological issue? Yes.
Why are you jerking me around?
It wasn't me.
Yeah.
It was one of the other petty,
socially repressed asses I work for.
Maybe it was Ashton Kutcher.
If you want me to stay,
tell me you want me to stay.
Would it matter?
No, but it'd be the
adult way to handle it.
If the adult way doesn't
work, why bother with it?
I've been totally professional!
Gave two weeks' notice,
continued to work cases,
scheduled my interviews
on my own time.
You have no right to
screw with my future.
You're gonna be all whiny during
the differential diagnoses, aren't you?
It wasn't me.
I only sabotage people
I consider worth it.
You are one evil, cunning woman.
It's a massive turn-on.
You girls can gossip later.
What are you talking about?
You called New York Mercy to
have Foreman's job interview killed.
When I said, "You
girls can gossip later,"
I was throwing you
out, but in a polite way.
Well, I take it you're off
your anti-depressants.
You're deflecting. Only
I'm allowed to do that.
Does Foreman
actually think I did that?
No. Just me.
But I know something
he doesn't: I didn't do it.
Why would I do it?
Do you want him to leave? No.
Are you planning
on doing something?
I'm waiting for board approval.
But if he takes the job,
there's nothing to be done.
You had to stop him.
It wasn't me.
What are you doing?
Looking for a tell. Rapid
eye blink, twitch of the lips.
Send in Nurse Unger when
you pass her on your way out.
Oh, almost forgot.
I need to give a 16-year-old
magic mushrooms
to treat a cluster headache.
Is that cool?
Yeah, no problem.
I was being sarcastic.
It wouldn't look that way
in the court transcript.
Mushrooms have psilocybins
that work on cluster headaches.
It's either that or cutting into his
brain and going on a fishing expedition.
I assume you've considered he
could have a psychogenic experience,
possibly suffer a fit
of severe paranoia.
Well, I have now.
Yeah, it's definitely better that
the Dean of Medicine prescribes it
instead of an unhinged doctor
with a history of drug use.
Takes the stink off if the patient decides
to put on a cape and fly off the roof.
Low dose. No more than 10
milligrams, tightly controlled setting.
And make sure the
mother signs off on it.
Party on, Garth.
And don't stand in
Foreman's way. It's just wrong.
New research shows that a chemical
component in the mushrooms can...
Yeah, lots of technical medical
stuff. So when do I get them?
I went to college. I
know about mushrooms.
Friend of a friend
shot himself in the foot.
They're not giving
me a gun, Enid!
Sign the consent form.
We'll be monitoring him,
but cardiac arrest is possible.
Big "E,"
small "N"...
And if the mushrooms don't work?
The next step would be
a type of brain surgery.
Oh, God.
Pain's getting worse!
Need shrooms now!
Oh, yeah.
Nate, how's the pain?
Hey, hey! It's Skippy,
the bush kangaroo!
Your head, Nate. We need
to know how the pain is.
What I got here
is the opposite of pain.
That means you're suffering from cluster
headaches, which means hopefully...
Man, you're hot.
She's making me horny.
Deal with it.
Hey, hey, hey, you can't get me
stoned, then not close the deal.
Shut up. Take it easy.
You'll regret saying no!
Check it out.
Oh, for God's sake.
Hold it.
What are you doing?
He has undersized testes.
His other secondary sexual
characteristics are normal.
If you want to curry favor with me,
avoid discussions of other men's testicles.
Thanks.
Focus on phrases like,
"You were right about
the cluster headaches."
You're wrong about
what caused them.
Vascular problem in a major
artery wouldn't cause hypogonadism.
Okay, what causes rage, headaches,
personality disorder and hypogonadism?
Where's Foreman?
He's mad at me.
Why? No reason.
Yeah. That makes sense.
The male genitals are controlled by
the hypothalamus and pituitary gland.
We're not talking about
Foreman anymore.
Kid's being pummeled at school.
A couple blows to the head
can cause hypothalamic lesions.
We ever going to talk about what
happens when Foreman's gone?
If this were an employee-owned
airline in Scandinavia, yes.
It's not lesions. His temperature
would be all over the map.
Symptoms don't lie.
He's gone in less than a week,
and you haven't even read a résumé.
Doesn't even need to.
The two of us can handle it.
Craniopharyngioma
fits the symptoms.
Biopsy the brat's pituitary.
And let the record show I was
right about the cluster headaches.
Forget it!
It's a straightforward
procedure.
We thread an endoscopic
tube up through the nostril...
And cut something out
of my brain? No way.
If it's a tumor,
it could kill you.
Just give me more
shrooms, okay? I'll be fine.
You only need my consent, right?
Yeah, but it'll be
a lot easier if...
Do whatever you have to do.
You don't touch me, all right?
You can touch me, just not my brain.
Nate, you got to do this.
I can't take it anymore...
My God, Mom! Save me the
melodramatic hand-wringing, okay?
Loosen up! Get yourself coited.
I'm going to give
him a sedative.
You're decent-looking,
Dr. Skippy.
Why don't you
take her for a ride?
Nate?
Are you in pain?
His heart rate's normal.
Respiration's even.
What's happening?
What's the matter with him?
He's jaundiced. His
liver's shutting down.
We've started him on
sodium polystyrene sulfonate.
His liver's operating
at about 20%
and deteriorating fast.
Which means he'll be dead long
before Foreman turns in his parking pass.
So what causes personality
disorder, head pain, blah, blah, blah,
and liver failure?
Liver failure can cause
hypogonadism, head pain.
Altered mental status leads to
the personality disorder and rage.
All we need to do is figure
out what caused the liver failure.
Yes. Also, we need to figure
out how symptoms yesterday
can be caused by
liver failure today.
If his liver's failing now,
it wasn't great yesterday.
If it wasn't operating at
capacity, it could have caused...
Don't sneak up on
a person like that!
I'm listening.
Well, listening doesn't help me.
Okay. Let's go with the liver
and a time-machine theory.
Foreman, what
causes liver problems?
Wilson's Disease.
No. Ceruloplasmin is normal.
No enlargement and no
palpable mass, so no cancer.
Could be a narrowing of the bile
ducts. Primary Sclerosing Cholangitis.
Most liver damage begins with
what we put in our bodies. Foreman?
Angry teen... Alcohol.
No. Blood tests were negative.
No signs of drug use or acetaminophen
poisoning in his tox screen.
Maybe the water
was contaminated.
His mother would also be sick.
Cuddy?
Sounded like someone would back.
Go.
We'll try and muddle through
without your blank stare to guide us.
So if it's not the bad things he's
putting in, what about the good things?
He was raised a vegetarian.
"Was raised."
Means he's all grown up, or
he's not a vegetarian anymore.
He started eating red
meat a few months ago.
Unless he's been
buying cuts of mad cow,
his body would have no
problem metabolizing it.
What if he had an
OTC deficiency?
Body can't metabolize
nitrogen, damages the liver.
Run a hamburger test.
It's exactly what
it sounds like.
Stuff him full of meat, wait
for his ammonia levels to spike.
I'll double your salary.
Chase and Cameron would
mutiny if they found out.
Chase and Cameron wouldn't be
heading up their own diagnostic group.
You'd work in parallel with
House. It'll be your practice.
Separate staff, separate
cases, complete autonomy.
I've only been doing
this for three years.
Three years under House.
No better training.
And when that case comes
along that I can't figure out,
you know who I'd have to go to.
Or you can just let that patient
die. That's completely up to you.
No.
Why?
He's evil.
He didn't sabotage
your interview.
How do you know?
Because I did.
I didn't!
You believed me. Means
you're not sure House did it.
Well, somebody did it.
Somebody here did it.
I can't work here.
This isn't a medical procedure.
This is just about Doogie
making me eat garbage.
We need to see how your
liver processes the proteins.
Then get me a steak.
Some roast beef.
What if I brought him
something from home?
It has to be prepared here so we know
there's no chemicals or preservatives
that could affect
the test results.
I'm not eating anything prepared
by five-dollar-an-hour immigrant
hospital cooks in hairnets.
Shut up!
Either you start eating or I'm
going to strap you to this bed
and shove these down
your throat one by one.
Got it?
Can't get mad at me!
I'm sick!
Supposed to feel bad for me.
Nurse, full set of
body restraints.
Yes, Doctor.
Trust me. It'll be a lot less
messy if you do it yourself.
You killed Foreman's
job interview.
Why would I... Somebody did.
Wasn't me, and it wasn't House,
which means it has to be somebody
who thought he was protecting House,
which means it has to be
somebody who actually likes House,
which means it's either you
or the weird night janitor who
wears his pants backwards.
I want Foreman to leave.
House has to realize he needs
someone who stands up to him.
Cameron's in love with him, Chase
is afraid of him and I enable him.
House needs
limits. I give him...
You authorize magic mushrooms.
House is a six-year-old who
thinks he's better off without parents.
A few tummy aches after
dinners of ice cream and ketchup
might do him some good.
You're lying.
An enabler doesn't conspire
against. An enabler enables.
What? You're paranoid.
You made that call.
And because of that call,
you basically guaranteed
Foreman's out of here.
I thought it'd be fun to
work on my boat with him.
And you went shirtless,
because skin cancer looks cool.
Well, I realize I got burnt.
I'm not too worried about that.
It's these white
marks. You know.
Lie down.
I mean, that boat has all sorts of lead
paint, and there's chemicals everywhere.
When Daddy works on his boat,
does he have a cooler with lots
of brown bottles with long necks?
And does Daddy like to lie down on
his boat and go nap-nap in the sun?
Oh! What the hell?
I will give you this for
the $1.41 in your pocket.
Wait. How could you know...
A psychic once told
me that I'm psychic.
Hey! One of these
quarters is Canadian.
Give me back my syringe.
Hamburger stress test showed
no change in his ammonia levels.
Liver's properly converting
the ammonia into urea.
He doesn't have OTC deficiency.
Welcome back.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have been
taking my problems out on the patient.
Or on me.
Apology accepted.
Starve him.
And what are we looking for?
Diabetic steatosis
would screw up his liver.
Starve him overnight and
see if his blood sugar pops.
We mess with his blood sugar,
we could set off another rage.
Not a problem. You can take him.
I want something to eat!
Honey, please don't.
What happened?
I was just trying to get a urine
sample and he went crazy.
I need to eat! You're not
sticking anything else in me!
It's just a few more hours.
You're going to hurt yourself.
I'm going to hurt you!
As soon as we get a urine
sample, we can leave you alone.
You want your sample?
Here's your damn sample!
Nate, don't!
Oh, my God!
Nate, you need to get
back into bed. Right now.
Chem panel and
urinalysis confirms
the bloody urine was
caused by kidney failure.
He's on dialysis. He's going
to need it for the rest of his life.
Which is shortening as we speak.
We are looking at
a Chinese menu.
We've got symptoms
from too many columns.
They are going to overcharge us.
Multiple organ failure could
mean primary HIV infection.
That'd mean someone
agreed to sleep with him.
Plus, his serology is negative.
His uric acid's
slightly elevated.
Ten percent of males in
this country have elevated...
So we're only going to pay
attention to abnormal abnormalities?
We've been stuffing him with
meat and his kidneys are shot.
Of course his
uric acid level's...
Could be hepatic
fibrosis, or McAb.
Brat's got a genetic disorder.
Get the sequencing primers.
See if it's one of the
ones we can treat.
I can draw some blood,
but then I got to run.
Job interview?
You going to stop me if it is?
You do the nurse stuff.
They'll do the doctor stuff.
Is this a blood test for
our marriage license?
Planning on kidnapping me
to Massachusetts? Can't...
What did you give him?
Are you treating
him for something?
A sedative.
Did he need a sedative? I did.
Just shutting him up so I can
draw some of his blood in peace.
You walked in with that. You
didn't even give him a chance.
People are what they are.
He's sick.
The rudeness isn't his fault.
If he had tuberculosis, it
wouldn't be his fault either.
But I still wouldn't
let him cough on me.
Hi. Hey.
Where are you going?
The lab. We're testing our
patient's blood for a hereditary...
Cuddy thinks I sabotaged
Foreman's interview.
She's going to fire me.
I don't believe it.
She said it was
unprofessional and...
No, I mean, I literally
don't believe it.
Cuddy wouldn't fire you
for something like that.
Which means either she lied
to you or you're lying to me.
You so would have fallen
for that three years ago.
You were looking for a reaction.
You were looking for me to
feel bad for you, save your skin.
But how am I going to save you?
Unless you think I'm
the one who really did it.
Cuddy's logic was,
Foreman's valuable to
House, I care about House,
ergo, I would do
anything to save him.
And your logic was, I care about
House as much as you do, ergo...
It wasn't me.
I don't care about House.
I don't believe you.
No one does.
House is nothing more than my boss.
Foreman's nothing more than a colleague.
You're lying.
Everyone does.
But it wasn't me.
No markers for hepatic fibrosis.
And nothing for McAb.
Foreman's interview in
New York got screwed up.
I heard.
Foreman thought it was House.
House thought it was Cuddy.
Cuddy thought it was Wilson.
Wilson thought it was me.
And you think it was me?
God... You think I
sabotaged Foreman?
I don't even want him here.
I know.
Then why would I do...
I think you sabotaged Foreman
just to sabotage Foreman.
So everyone's a suspect because
everyone wants to help House,
except for me, I'm a suspect
because I'm a petty, vindictive jerk?
You actually think I would
do something like that?
It was someone.
It wasn't me.
Negative for Von Gierke disease.
And it's Tuesday.
I know.
I like you.
See you next Tuesday.
Found something.
He's got a partial HPRT
enzyme deficiency.
Means he could have
Kelley-Seegmiller Syndrome.
But it's a partial deficiency, so
it may not be Kelley-Seegmiller.
Yes, those are the
two options. It is,
or it isn't.
Kelley-Seegmiller explains
the aggressive personality.
If he had Kelley-Seegmiller,
he wouldn't just be aggressive.
He'd be self-mutilating. Chewing
his lips, banging his head.
Lovely disease.
Degenerative, fatal, incurable.
I wonder if that's why
Cameron's on the "not" side?
That and the fact that
symptoms don't lie.
Kelley-Seegmiller carriers
self-mutilate when they're stressed.
He's in ICU with a failing
liver and no kidneys.
Yeah, his life is sweet.
His vegetarian diet could have
limited the purines in his system,
slowing the disease's progress.
So let's speed it up.
Why?
So you two kids
will stop fighting.
Also, I don't feel like
waiting for respiratory failure.
Chase, find some way for the
mother to get lost for a while.
I'm going to stress this
kid till he bites off a finger.
You move me to geriatrics?
Who are you?
Dr. McCaney.
The man who's going to kick
your ass all over this chess board.
Well, I'm too weak to...
To bite yourself. Yeah.
You need some liquid energy.
Now if you consent, I'm gonna
give you this shot of adrenaline.
I don't want to play.
Aside from being
indicative of pituitary issues
and certain kinds of genetic
disorders, small testicles also indicate
that you're a big chicken.
Please don't make
me do the sound effect.
You're not going to
goad me into playing.
Didn't think I'd have to.
Thought you'd just jump at the
chance of humiliating someone.
Age before cripple. I'm white.
It is on.
Bird's Opening. Passive
approach. Sign of a coward.
Sicilian Defense.
Sign of an idiot.
Arrogance has to be earned.
Tell me what you've
done to earn yours.
I can walk.
I don't bleed out of my penis.
Check.
You know, it's a real thin
line between tortured genius
and awkward kid who can't
get girls because he's creepy.
Why are you doing this?
To stress you out.
Check.
Yeah, but why?
Well, I'd tell you,
but I figure it's more
stressful if you don't know why.
Yeah, well, I'm not
feeling too stressed.
You know that no
one likes you, right?
Yeah. Well, anybody like you?
You're dying.
Check.
Your move.
Care to lay down your king?
You can't win.
You can pin my queen.
My knight to E7.
Your king to H8.
Sacrifice rook takes pawn.
Bishop blocks.
Queen to H5.
Checkmate.
Save what's left
of your dignity.
Lay down your king.
Crap.
He's having a seizure.
Four milligrams I.V. lorazepam.
Right away.
I hate this kid.
I like this kid.
Did you get the job?
They're going to let me know.
Kelley-Seegmiller
didn't cause this seizure.
So we've got one more
symptom, one less diagnosis.
I assume they're going
to call for references.
Did you give them my name?
No.
Amyloidosis can cause seizures,
and the protein buildup
could cause organ failure.
Wouldn't alter his personality.
Whose name did you give?
My last boss.
Ouch.
That can't look good.
I hate this kid.
What if we're not dealing
with one condition?
What if it's
multiple conditions?
It's got to be one.
It's always one.
But nothing explains this
constellation of symptoms.
We've got to be
missing something.
Maybe the kid lied about some
medication. Maybe he's hiding something...
Why would he be
hiding something?
Well, I don't know,
because he's evil?
What if he is?
What if the symptoms lied?
There.
Now all we're looking at is a
simple evil jerk with amyloidosis.
You're not being objective.
Amyloidosis was your idea.
You were right. It
doesn't fit the symptoms.
Yeah, it does. Look.
You crossed it off because
you want to hate the kid,
and you can't hate
him if he's a victim...
You want him to be a victim because
you want to believe that people are good.
And if they're not, it's got
to be a chemical problem.
Except they're
not, and it's not.
Flush him with
immunosuppressants.
Get a biopsy to confirm,
and find him a marrow donor.
What'll happen to him?
Substances called
amyloid proteins
build up in the body's
organs, shutting them down.
It's a fairly rare disease,
and I'm afraid it can be fatal.
So, do you operate or
something to take them out?
He needs a bone
marrow transplant.
Dr. Cameron is
searching the donor bank.
We should test you as well.
When you first told
me he was sick, I was
happy.
Relieved.
Now...
Nate, I'm going to take a small
piece of nerve from your ankle.
Let me know if
you feel any pain.
I'm burning up.
Why can't you just knock
me out like you did last time?
Wish I could.
But your body has to be clear so
it's ready for a marrow transplant.
Hey, Dr. X.
I know you've busted
ass trying to save me.
It's all right.
I wasn't going to thank you.
I was going to tell you
you really suck at this.
We're doing our best.
That's sort of my point.
Your best really sucks.
Nerve biopsy was clean.
No evidence of amyloidosis.
It was your idea. Don't
give up on it so fast.
He's running a fever.
If it's two conditions, one of
them's got to be an infection.
We should start him on antibiotics,
see what clears up, what doesn't.
Is he having trouble breathing?
Yeah, he has mucus in
his chest from an infection.
Could also be from
an amyloid buildup.
Keep him on immunosuppressants
and biopsy somewhere else.
His sinuses.
Look, you got two choices:
engage me in a futile
argument then do what I asked,
or just do what I asked.
You're not ready.
There was a third choice.
"Don't do what I asked."
You could have defied me,
stuck the kid on antibiotics,
but you didn't.
Because you still trust my
judgment more than your own.
You sabotaged Foreman's
job interview, didn't you?
Foreman's already
been over this.
It wasn't me.
Everybody's chasing
ghosts over this,
which means either nobody did it
or somebody wants
everybody chasing ghosts.
Now, who does that sound like?
And why would I do that?
Because as long as Foreman
thought you were guilty,
he was going to be
useless around here.
You know, sometimes
I forget why I hired you.
You cost him a good
opportunity and gained nothing.
I cost him a crappy opportunity.
New York Mercy is where you go to
treat boils and cysts and build a 401-K.
If you want him
to stay, tell him.
I don't, and
there'd be no point.
You do.
And the point would be to
make him feel like he's wanted.
He doesn't need that.
All right, then, it'd make him
feel like maybe you weren't evil.
He needs that.
Talk to Foreman.
We dumped one symptom,
but forgot to add one.
Revenge time, Nate.
Are you... Yes, I am.
Black or white?
Just limp away.
He doesn't want to
play. Leave him alone.
Pick one, or this comes out.
And for all you know,
this is really important.
Stop it!
That hurts, right?
Which is odd, because
I'm really enjoying this.
You hold the pieces that way
because you can't bend your thumb,
because your bones
have formed abnormally,
thanks to all the crap that's been
pushing its way in between them.
Actually, this stuff
isn't important at all.
Your doctors said he
needs immunosuppressants.
They're idiots. It's
not amyloidosis.
It's iron.
He's got hemochromatosis.
The body absorbs iron from food
but can't process it, can't get rid of it.
Idle iron is the
devil's playground.
Builds up in the organs and
joints, whacking them in the process.
Causes all the symptoms.
Including something
that wasn't a symptom.
Those body aches? They
were not from the fighting.
His personality issues?
Sorry.
The iron's innocent
on that count.
Your kid's a jerk.
Yeah, it's probably your fault.
Although, if you'd stayed off
the meat like your mom said,
you'd have half as much
iron and be twice less
almost dead.
Oh, nurse!
This patient is bleeding,
for some reason.
Is he going to be okay?
He'll need dialysis,
gonna have to get his blood drained
every few months for the rest of his life.
My condolences.
It's going to be a
long and annoying life.
And I wouldn't have
taken your bishop.
I'd have moved my queen
to D6, defusing the threat,
then rook to E8,
attacking the king's pawn.
I'd have lost the exchange
but won the game.
I know.
I was bluffing.
And that's why
you lost.
Jerk.
You just here to watch or
you got something to say?
Still running the new
biopsy for amyloidosis?
Yeah. Still nothing.
Run the test again.
Recheck your results.
Looks like you're
in for an all-nighter.