Previously on The Good Doctor:
You don't want
me to do anything.
I spend every minute
of every day with you!
Since you feel that our time
together is something to be endured,
I decided to make
that easier for you.
Your daughter's beautiful,
needs you to get better
so you can hold her.
I read about the chill study.
She's a good candidate, I'll
take full responsibility for her.
Tell him he's going to be fine.
I can't. The majority
of COVID patients
who go on a ventilator
never come off.
Put on a mask. Now. It's
COVID. We've both been exposed.
- My mother had a necklace...
- Let me see if I can find it.
Things will be okay.
Good morning.
Morning, Shaun.
I wish you were here.
Me too.
Morning, Dalisay. Woke
up with a temp of 104.
I need heated, humidified
oxygen in a high-flow cannula.
Mom, slow down, just
let her examine you.
What? So she can find out
exactly what I just told her?
Reznick! You're back.
Got sick, got better,
got tested twice.
Always the overachiever.
Dr. Reznick, her pulse ox is 90.
We need to admit you.
Is my mom going to be okay?
Don't worry, I'm gonna be fine.
Just please water my tomato
plants, give Darcy a big hug,
and tell her Nana
loves her so much
and can't wait to play
with her again real soon.
Okay, Mom.
Nice hesitation. Why not just
suggest he get my house appraised?
Sorry, it took a
while to find it.
Thank you.
Being able to hold this and
keep it with me, it's a connection.
Like she's still here with me.
It's stuff, Claire. It's
meaningless now.
Each one of these
tells an interrupted story.
A voicemail that'll
never be heard,
a shopping list for a home-cooked
meal that'll never be made.
Beautiful. Cook
spaghetti carbonara
for a dead guy's family
and the grief is gone.
Are you here to mock
me or to help me?
Why are you here?
"Donald Sulkin."
We're reducing the pressure
of air going into his lungs
and watching his oxygen level.
So far, so good. O2 is steady.
Okay.
Yes. But his end-tidal
CO2 is falling.
What does that mean?
It's not as bad as his O2
falling, but still not good.
Turn the pressure
support back up.
End-tidal CO2 is very low,
- not improving.
- What's going on?
I think he has a blood clot in his
lung interfering with his gas exchange.
Give him a bolus of heparin,
start him on a drip, let's
get him to the cath lab. Go.
What's going on?
Where are you taking him?
Dr. Andrews? Dr. Murphy? Martin!
This is isotonic
saline, saltwater.
It's four degrees Celsius.
I'll run this into your bloodstream
until your body temperature drops
to 34 degrees Celsius.
The paralytic I gave you
will stop you from shivering
while the cold slows your heart,
your brain, all metabolic functions.
All of the energy saved there
will go towards healing your lungs.
Your baby's waiting for you.
Pete, follow him.
Pete. Follow him,
he's got the ax.
I was getting shot at.
Well, stay low, reload,
and head for the temple.
Stop messing around.
AG24, what's up
with you? You okay?
Yeah, yeah, I'm hunting for
the legendary Tusk of Ganesh
at 3 in the morning because
everything is just super.
I can't go out, I can't
sleep, I can't go to work.
Welcome to COVID,
everything sucks.
Great, good... good pep talk.
You all sleeping
in an empty bed?
- Yeah.
It's like I killed a
puppy or something.
Hey, Pete... Pete, heads up!
The fortress is the
perfect place for an am...
Okay, Pete's dead.
- You should apologize.
- Just play the game.
Not saying you have to mean it,
just saying you should apologize.
Well, that's great.
Be a hypocrite.
You married?
I'm 15.
Oh, well, thank you
for a lifetime of wisdom.
My girlfriend was pissed at me
for something I didn't even do,
but I said sorry, and
now we're back together.
Maybe I'm a hypocrite, but at
least I'm a hypocrite with a girlfriend.
Up and at them. We gotta
be downtown by noon.
Ha. Oh, yeah, we're late for the
protest. Gotta get this state opened up.
Pulse ox is 82.
Everything else looks okay.
Sure, other than my steadily
declining oxygen levels,
I am the picture of health.
- Let's start making signs.
- Hmm.
I'm thinking...
"Don't tread on
my right to kill you."
Hmm. How about, "Give
me liberty and give me death."
I need to go.
Nothing. We haven't had a patient
named Sulkin in over ten years.
Being dead doesn't change because
your loved one gets a memento back.
And fixating on dead
people? It's not a life.
How can anyone not be
answering their phone right now
if they're not an
essential worker?
What non-essential worker
are you trying to reach?
Lea.
Well, people don't go out anymore,
but they do still go to the bathroom.
This is the second time in an
hour she hasn't picked up, Claire.
We keep learning more
things about this disease.
It's...
I don't know. It's not right.
We love you, Grandma.
Mom, I'm so sorry. I love you.
And I want you to
know that we'll be okay.
We love you.
He's gone.
She's gone.
They're gone.
It's not always fun.
Whatever you're
talking about, no, it isn't.
- But what are you talking about?
- Do you love Mia?
Of course I do.
What do you love about her?
I love that she loves our son,
I love how she talks to him,
how she knows what he's thinking,
knows what he needs...
I thought so.
You thought what?
You love Kellan.
Hello. Are you okay?
I'm sorry I didn't pick
up when you called.
- I didn't want to upset you.
- It didn't work.
I had a sore throat, so I got
tested for COVID, and I'm negative.
COVID tests have a high
percentage of false negatives.
I feel fine now.
That doesn't mean
you don't have COVID.
I need to go to work.
How are you adjusting
to your new specialty?
It's great. Love
being an internist.
Well, I'm convinced.
Dealing with conscious
people isn't really your thing.
I'm fine.
You're rude, abrasive,
and now you gotta hold
people's hands and be nice.
It's a huge adjustment and I find
it completely draining. You happy?
There's a lot of different
approaches to nice.
Otherwise, I wouldn't have
lasted 40 years as a nurse.
You'll find your own.
Or maybe you won't.
Overall, everything
is looking up.
Fewer patients coming in.
When they do, we're
getting better at...
Hey, buddy. I'm sorry I
keep missing your calls.
I've got this patient, yeah, the
mom of the baby I told you about.
I basically put her into
suspended animation,
but it doesn't
seem to be helping.
When are you coming to Phoenix?
I still don't know.
You're going to make my
graduation party, though, right?
I don't think so.
This patient needs...
You? No one else
can take care of her?
I kind of went out
on a limb on this one.
Well, if you made a
commitment, then...
Your husband has
blood in his N.G. tube.
He's developed heparin-induced
thrombocytopenia. We
need to stop the heparin.
Doesn't that put him
at risk for another clot?
Yes, if he's not on the
heparin, he could have a stroke,
and if he's on it, he could
have a fatal internal bleed.
And he still has an infection,
so we can't stop the antibiotics
or he'll get sepsis and die.
All you do is tell me new ways
that my husband might die.
Every time I talk to
you, there's another way.
I mean, do you even
know what you're doing?
What is the point of
you? You're useless!
We understand your frustration.
COVID targets so many organs...
- Technically, it's your fault.
- Shaun.
Martin never left the apartment,
but he still caught COVID,
you must have exposed
him to it. On the other hand,
- we are doing all that we can to...
- That's enough. That's enough.
We're all going through crap,
but that woman's
husband may be dying.
She's allowed to
lash out. You aren't.
Hey.
I'm sorry.
Why?
What?
What are you sorry about?
Everything.
The fight, and you
sleeping in the other room,
and you ignoring me.
So you're sorry because
of the way I've been acting?
I'm apologizing.
I don't think you are.
I don't get it. You won.
I don't know what you want.
We can't have a
difference of opinion?
No. Not when we disagree
on whether you've
been mean to me or not.
You've been mean to me!
Three tours, helicopter pilot.
He's got a medal on that one.
Hey, look at this.
Same guy again.
Funny, almost as if they were
in the same unit or something.
Greg Lavin.
Died here. COVID, one month ago.
Hello, Enid Lavin?
Hi, this is Dr. Claire Browne
from San Jose St. Bonaventure.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
I just wanted you to know
that we have found
something of your father's.
A memento of his
service. Dog tags.
No, no, not his, a man by
the name of Donald Sulkin.
Donald Sulkin?
Thank you.
That's odd.
Yeah.
How does your father carry
someone else's dog tags for 50 years
and you have never
even heard of them?
How are you feeling?
My son plans to move to Montana.
Take my granddaughter
1000 miles away.
The schools are
better, the air is cleaner.
So the upside of all this is, I
don't have to move to Montana.
Is that why you
haven't okayed us
putting you on a
ventilator if you need one?
I know what
ventilators do to people.
Do you remember Dr. Pitcairn?
Pitstain?
Exactly.
Remember when I
was a first-year resident?
One of two women,
only woman of color.
I'd been warned
he'd make my life hell.
And sure enough, second week,
Pitstain starts tearing into me
about the spacing of my
sutures being inconsistent,
and I'm about to fall
apart in front of everybody,
but then you stepped in.
Brought up some charting error
he made. A tiny blip of a mistake.
He never capitalized "stat."
The whole point
is for it to stand out.
You put him back on his
heels in front of everybody.
You gave me time.
To regain my composure.
He never got to see me cry.
Please, if it comes to it,
give me a little time again.
To help you.
No, no, no.
I don't know what
to do. I love Lea,
- and I wanted her to love...
- Okay. Okay, I'll be right down.
Okay?
I don't know what to do.
I love Lea and I wanted
her to love me back,
and now she does,
but we can't be together.
How can loving someone who
loves you back make things worse?
Well, that's a... That's
a good question.
Let's start with what's
making things worse.
I think...
I think I may be... cranky.
I've never been cranky before.
I don't like it. I
think I miss Lea.
I think I'm worried
that she has COVID.
So you're going crazy
because you can't see someone?
What am I supposed to do?
Should I not talk to Lea
until the pandemic is over?
Well, that's an option.
Is that what you want?
No. No, I don't
want that at all.
But I don't want to
feel like this, either.
I want this to be over.
Well, we all want it
to be over, Shaun.
I mean, we're sick of ourselves,
we're sick of each other,
or we're pining for
someone we can't be with.
We're confused,
we're uncomfortable.
On top of everything else,
we're scared that the world
will never be the same again.
And I don't know, Shaun.
I don't have a map
for this kind of thing.
The best I can say is...
be kind.
Be kind to yourself, be kind...
to everyone.
Because what else is there?
♪ Every now and then
I get a little bit lonely ♪
♪ And you're never
coming 'round ♪
♪ Turn around ♪
♪ Every now and
then I get a little... ♪
Oh. Hi.
Well, this is a nice song.
♪ Every now and then I get... ♪
I hate this song.
Good. I was being kind.
Martin hates it too.
It was the first
conversation we had,
talking about how
weird this song is.
Who is Bright Eyes, and why is it
so important that they turn around?
♪ Every now and
then I fall apart... ♪
Now it just reminds me of him.
♪ And I need you now tonight ♪
♪ And I need you
more than ever... ♪
You're probably right.
That he got COVID from me.
It's hard.
To think of someone you love
when you can't be with them.
♪ Your love is like a shadow
On me all of the time... ♪
He seems to have a posterior
tibial artery thrombosis.
What? That sounds bad.
It is. It's a blockage
in the artery,
causing ischemia to his lower
extremity tissues due to lack of...
I want to be kind to
you. I want to explain,
but it's a very long explanation
and I don't have time for you
- to get mad and upset...
- Just go help my husband.
Okay.
Your numbers are falling.
I know.
You need a ventilator.
There's a pocket in
my purse. Reach into it.
Game Seven, 2003, American
League Championship.
Grady let Pedro go
one inning too long.
The Sox handed the
series to the damn Yankees.
My son and I cried
in each other's arms.
I've kept them
with me ever since.
It's like Jimmy's
always with me.
You're not alone.
You're stuck with all of us.
Can you take your
earbuds out, please?
I don't think that I've
done anything wrong.
But I may be wrong about
that. I suspect that I am.
I haven't been
thinking straight lately.
What with everything
going on at the hospital.
People are dying and I'm here.
And that makes me feel weak.
And then I feel scared,
and that makes me feel...
even more weak.
And then I feel relieved
and safe that I'm here.
And that makes me
feel like a coward.
Thank you.
Thank you?
I just needed an honest moment.
Something...
to let me know that
you actually need me.
And...
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry too.
Hi, buddy.
Hey, Dad.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have gotten angry
about you not coming to Phoenix.
It wasn't fair.
Thank you.
Did your mother
put you up to this?
She was right.
I don't even really care
about the party that much.
Then what was the issue?
We don't have
to talk about that.
I want to know
what's bothering you.
I know your job is important.
But sometimes,
I just want to know you care about
me more than you care about the job.
When your mom got pregnant...
I was so nervous.
Suddenly, everything was real.
Suddenly, I had a commitment.
And I wasn't sure I was ready.
And then you were born.
And in that moment,
I mean that moment,
everything changed.
I was instantly head
over heels in love with you.
You were my best friend.
And I held you,
and the words just came out,
I said, "Hi, buddy."
I'd never called anyone
buddy before in my life.
But you were my buddy.
I may make mistakes,
over and over again,
but don't ever think...
you're not the most
important thing in my life.
So, basically, you're saying your
love for me is like chemical, right?
Yeah.
Thank you for your call. Your
husband is still unconscious. Bye.
Whoa, whoa, how is
he? How was the surgery?
Dr. Andrews will explain, but
I'd rather not say anything more.
The last two times I gave you
bad news, you yelled at me.
Bad news? What is the bad news?
Oh.
Okay.
We amputated
Martin's foot and ankle.
We are now trying to
reintroduce anticoagulation
so he won't have more clots.
But he will be at risk
for more bleeding.
Thank you.
Mm.
Are you sure you understand?
He's still on a ventilator
and he lost a foot.
You were very upset yesterday.
Yesterday, I thought
he was dying...
but today he's alive.
So thank you.
You're welcome.
Can I hang up now?
Yes. Yes, thank...
I figured you're bored
of just hearing my voice,
so I brought a mutual friend.
The risks are minimal, and
whatever time you have...
some of it should
be with your family.
Yes, I'm trying to track
down a Donald Sulkin.
No. No one here by that name.
Okay, sorry to bother you.
Your plan is to call every
D. Sulkin in North America,
all to return a set of dog tags?
You've reached
Diana Sulkin. Please...
Ugh.
You want a happy
ending for this guy.
Because you and
I didn't have one.
Because we'll never know
how our story could have ended.
Hello?
Is Donald Sulkin there?
This doesn't change anything.
This can't change anything.
You're wrong. It changes things.
It makes me feel...
something besides sad.
And I need that. I
need to not feel sad.
Because everything sucks.
Everything hurts like hell.
People are sick with
COVID, with cancer, with grief,
and we can't help them.
People are dying and
we can't help them.
And what is worse,
you're not there.
It has to hurt.
A lot. For a while.
When your mom died,
you did everything you could
to not feel anything. At all.
But this time, you're facing it.
You're grieving.
You're healing.
It's time.
No. Not today.
Today.
We love you, Mom.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Mom...
I love you.
Goodbye.
♪ When the day that
lies ahead of me ♪
♪ Seems impossible to face ♪
♪ And when someone
else Instead of me ♪
♪ Always seems
to know the way... ♪
She's been waiting
patiently to learn her name.
Aria.
I'm going to call her Aria.
♪ Just one look at you ♪
♪ And I know it's gonna be ♪
♪ A lovely day ♪
♪ Lovely day, lovely day ♪
♪ Lovely day, lovely
day, lovely day ♪
- ♪ A lovely day ♪
- ♪ Lovely day, lovely day ♪
♪ Lovely day, lovely day ♪
♪ Lovely day, lovely day... ♪
Honey!
♪ A lovely day ♪
You know, my mom
used to talk about you.
A lot.
She told me what you
did in the earthquake.
The price you paid.
She said you can rest
easy if you've got that...
tough Reznick in your corner.
I'm thinking she didn't exactly
phrase it that way, did she?
No. She didn't.
Donald Sulkin?
How can I help you?
I'm Dr. Claire Browne.
Greg Lavin died at
my hospital last month.
Greg.
He had this with
him when he passed.
I gave these to Greg
at the end of the war.
We were...
friends.
Thank you.
That was beautiful.
That room is filled with
stories that were cut short.
Like ours.
But you, you have an
amazing story ahead.
I can't wait to see it.
You can come home?
I can come home. But...
But?
Do you love me?
Of course I love you.
What do you love about me?
I love that you love our son.
I love watching you two talk.
I love the way Kellan
lights up when he's with you.
I love you too.
For all the same reasons.
We both want to be there
for Kellan. And we are.
But...
you and I don't need
to be together to do that.
Are you okay if...?
Maybe it's time we
stopped coming here.
You ready to move on?
No.
But he'll still be with us,
right? Wherever we are.
He changed me.
And that's not gonna go away.
I have everything I need to
stay overnight, including this.
Negative for COVID.
I know negative tests are unreliable,
but it's my third in three days.