Previously on The Resident...
Does she know
you're in love with her?
I am her teacher, her
mentor. To be anything else
would cross a line
that I would never cross.
Nic, I know we have
new boundaries,
but I am here for you.
My kidneys will
never work again.
You have to stay on dialysis.
There's got to
be another option.
Sorry. Nothing I can do
until the donor calls back
- to schedule his follow-up.
- Kyle's a match?
It's not that you can't
give Jessie your kidney.
It's that you won't. Get out.
I've got a way to help Jessie.
How far are you willing to
go to save your sister's life?
♪ Oh, Huncho did this? ♪
♪ DJ Durel! ♪
- ♪ Steppin' up ♪
- ♪ Up ♪
- ♪ Always take the risk,
living life ♪
- ♪ Up, up, life ♪
- ♪ Go hard and don't quit ♪
- ♪ Go hard ♪
♪ Drip, splash like
the ice on the wrist ♪
♪ Brr, brr, brr, brr ♪
♪ That's a call I can't miss ♪
- ♪ Brr, hello ♪
- ♪ Set my goals like a go,
hit the switch ♪
- ♪ Go, go ♪
- ♪ Work, work, work,
check it off the checklist ♪
- ♪ Work, work, work ♪
- ♪ In a position to win ♪
- ♪ Win ♪
- ♪ In a position to go ♪
- ♪ Uh ♪
- ♪ In a position to win ♪
- ♪ In a position to go ♪
- ♪ Uh, uh, uh... ♪
Doc Bell, I'm two shots away
from jumping on my new
Gulfstream to Sin City,
so say what you came to say.
- Your father was a great man.
- The best!
His generous donations
over the past 20 years
have been vital to
Chastain's financial health.
- I would love...
- And you think
you can party your ass
- into a big fat check again?
- Diego, I'm-I'm just here
to build a relationship with you
the same way I
did with your dad.
He left you his
fortune after he passed
because he believed
you would do great things.
- What, five million?
- Eight million.
Doctor, eight million
sound fair to you?
Eight million
saves a lot of lives.
You never respected me
when my dad was alive.
I was invisible to you.
So what, now you
want some of my gold?
Let's see if the
doctor can dance.
Oh, oh!
Come on. Come on.
"Three marriages
"and the only seed of mine
that can find its way to an egg
is that jackass.
What are the odds?"
Your father's words, not mine.
In hospice, the last thing he
said to me was, "Randolph,
"children are a
poor man's riches.
My son is a rich
man's biggest failure."
Enjoy Vegas, kid.
Hope you have better
luck than your father did.
- ♪ In a position to win ♪
- ♪ Win ♪
- ♪ In a position to go ♪
- ♪ Go ♪
- ♪ In a position to win ♪
- ♪ Win... ♪
That was awesome!
Screw that kid!
So who's the next
richie on our list, huh?
Diego was the list.
Is this dartboard
smaller than usual?
Maybe you're
just larger than life
so everything else
seems really tiny.
Are you trying to seduce me?
- Is it working?
- It is.
- Oh.
- Mm.
♪ Show me, show me,
show me how you do that... ♪
66% of relationships fizzle.
45% of marriages implode.
- Hmm.
- Hmm. Why does anyone bother?
People love to spoon,
and this requires a partner.
High price for a cuddle.
Another round?
I'd love to, but I got to roll.
I'm headed to Osteria Frankie
to meet a woman whose
brilliance almost matches mine.
Mm. May your egos have
a wonderful time spooning.
I'm telling you!
True story. The guy had a
machete gash in his neck
and wouldn't let
anyone touch him.
That's insane.
So... so, what'd they do?
Told him what you tell every
patient who refuses stitches.
Suture self.
Yes, I'm kind
of on fire tonight.
Uh, you want another drink?
- Uh, sloe gin fizz, no ice.
- Oh.
♪ Spinning on
that dizzy edge... ♪
Another beer?
Sure.
♪ Dreamed of all
the different ways... ♪
- Song?
- Sure.
Anything but the '80s.
What do you got
against the '80s, man?
What do you like about the '80s?
Uh, it's a Nic thing, which
used to make it my thing.
I heard she was
gonna swing by tonight.
Do you have any
idea where she is?
Nope.
♪ You lost and lonely ♪
♪ You just like heaven. ♪
Alec, what are we doing here?
I told you, a transplant expert.
Right. But it's midnight.
You meet him when you can.
- Dr. Shaw.
- Mr. Festervan,
thank you so much for coming.
- This is the friend
I told you about.
- Nic.
Hello. I'm so sorry your
sister's in kidney failure.
But I think
- I may be able to help you.
- Well,
we haven't been able to get
her on Chastain's transplant list.
What hospital do you work with?
I don't work with any hospital.
O-Okay, w-what's going on here?
You haven't told her?
I'm an organ broker.
I'm here to sell you a kidney.
♪ ♪
An organ broker? What
the hell were you thinking?
- I want you to know
all your options.
- That is not an option.
Desperate people
are exploited enough
without us hocking their organs
- for cash. I mean, come on.
- Wait a minute.
Wait a minute. It doesn't
have to be like that.
What you are
suggesting is a crime.
That doesn't mean it's wrong.
There are countries
where this is legal.
And if done the
right way, it can help
both the donor and
the recipient survive.
We both know Jessie
needs this kidney.
Don't tell me what
my sister needs.
I trust Elliot.
You should, too.
You've done this before.
Yes, I have.
- Wow.
- Nic, thousands of people
die each year
waiting for a kidney.
I just don't want your
sister to be one of them.
I'm not buying a kidney.
Good.
Because you just burned
the bridge to the one person
in Atlanta who could
get one for Jessie.
How you doing?
I'm acing dialysis.
Even made some
friends. And one enemy.
Oh.
I won't ask.
I want to show you something.
My 60-day sobriety chip.
I just got it today.
My sponsor dropped it off.
You're crushing it.
I couldn't have done
any of this without you.
Your light got me
through this darkness, Nic.
In four months, you'll
be eligible for a kidney.
When I get a kidney...
Maybe you'll finally
stop falling asleep
during our movie nights.
Deal.
So proud of you.
Me too.
Excuse me! Excuse me. Excuse me.
How'd the board take the
news about our money sitch?
Stop talking.
You didn't tell them.
Ah, I get it now.
Thanks for keeping
me in the loop.
The loop?
You want to be in the loop?
Chastain has received
over $95 million
in donations per year
over the last decade.
In the last eight
months, that's down 40%.
Yikes. Why is that?
Lane Hunter plus
QuoVadis equals disaster.
And where are we with the
new wealth-screening software?
Locked and loaded,
Chief. Already identifying
rich patients at Chastain
who could be potential donors.
Check it out. Spit out
three names this morning.
Oh, Grayson, one
of these patients died,
and the others are not...
they're not rich enough.
These are minnows.
We need a whale.
Hello?
Mina...
you will never
guess what landed.
Dextrocardia
with situs inversus.
This man's heart is literally
on the right side of his chest,
which, obviously,
is not the right side.
Okafor, are you there?
I think so.
Well, day off be damned.
Get your butt in here
and scrub in for this CABG.
We may never see
another one like it.
This was my fault.
Are you okay?
I swerved too late.
Left or right, couldn't decide.
My bad.
Oh, God.
Think you might be
bleeding internally.
- I'm what?
- Who?
I have no idea.
I'm sending you my location.
Get an ambulance, now.
- What do we got?
- 34-year-old male
with crush injuries, deep
leg laceration, BP 85/60,
- heart rate 130.
- Okay. Trauma bay nine.
I need the ultrasound.
Is this the end?
It is likely not the end.
One, two, three.
Sh-Should I call my mom?
Is it the right time or too
soon? I don't want her to worry,
- but I think she
deserves to know. Okay,
- diffuse abdominal tenderness.
- Decreased breath sounds
on his left side.
Maybe one of you
should call. Is-is that uh,
better or worse,
hearing from a doctor?
- Uh, better or worse? Okay.
Taylor, you need to calm down.
Looking for internal injuries.
- Whose suit is that? I
was playing a night round.
- Yeah.
- I should've stuck to the day.
It's just a bad call by me.
It's just, I was so
busy, that I... you know,
and I-I can't think.
I'm so sorry, I-I didn't
mean to... I hit you, I...
How do you even play at night?
Oh, glow-in-the-dark balls.
- It's pretty awesome. Yeah.
- Oh, cool.
Why were you there?
His intestines are in his chest.
Diaphragm rupture.
I'll prep the OR.
You're bleeding. You could
have a significant head injury.
I need to check you out.
What on earth
happened last night?
I don't remember.
Okay, here we go.
Follow my finger.
Nice.
All right, clench
your jaw and hold still.
Puff out your cheeks.
Cranial nerves intact.
I'm gonna take a look
at that head wound.
Okay. What's the last
thing you remember?
Drinking with the Raptor.
I ordered another
round of drinks,
and he had to go leave
to be with his brilliant
one-night stand.
Ah, so you drank that
last round by yourself?
No. Someone else joined me.
I just... don't remember who.
Maybe the guy
from the golf course?
- Definitely not him.
- So, we have heavy drinking
with a mystery person
and a late-night
stroll on a golf course.
None of that sounds like you.
I don't lose control.
I have never behaved this way.
Well, while you figure out
why you went off the rails,
I will figure out why
you have mild amnesia.
I need to rule out a bleed.
I got to keep you
for observation.
And that means no
reading, no watching
and no thinking.
Are you putting
me on brain rest?
Yes.
He knows of which he speaks.
I don't say this often, but
do what Pravesh tells you.
Okay, there is no
way I am sitting here
while you go operate on
a man who has his heart
on the wrong side of his chest.
I'm fine, and I'm scrubbing in.
You cuff her to
the bed if need be.
You approach this
bed with restraints...
I will end you.
Just relax.
Hold still.
Are you ready for your
smile to match mine?
Wealth screening software
flagged a bona fide Moby-Dick.
Born in Boise.
Paralegal. Rents a
place in Grant Park.
Sagittarius.
Are you pitching me a
whale or your replacement?
I'm pitching you
someone who won big.
- Won what big?
- The lottery, baby.
His name's Taylor Emeye.
Dr. Nolan.
Just... hang on one second.
Mr. Emeye, I'm
Dr. Randolph Bell,
Chief of Surgery and CEO
here at Chastain Park Memorial.
Hi, Dr. Bell. Is-is
something wrong?
No, no, not at all. I just
wanted to let you know
that I will be scrubbing in with
one of our very top surgeons
on your operation today,
and you'll be recovering
in our VIP wing.
Would you prefer a suite
that favors sunrise or sunset?
Sunrise or sunset?
Sunrise or sunset, sunrise
or sunset, sunrise or sunset,
sunrise or sunset, sunrise or...
You don't have to decide now.
Okay? W-We will see you after.
Okay.
Dr. Bell.
For you to advertise me
as one of the elite
surgeons at this hospital is...
No, I wasn't talking about you.
You got something on your mind?
As a locum tenens,
these eyes have seen a lot
of CEOs of a lot of hospitals
do a lot of things in the
name of financial solvency.
This going somewhere?
Well, let's start
with staff cuts.
You fired Jana Cervantes...
My favorite scrub nurse...
And replaced her with a
less-expensive imposter.
Said nurse is in the room.
And she shouldn't be.
Exactly my point.
But the bright red
flag on the field is:
why am I in here with you
when we both know Nolan
could easily handle
this cut and run?
Now, I smell wealth screenings.
And if you would
stoop to software
to spy on your patients,
then I have to ask:
how much is your
boy Taylor worth,
and how deep of a
hole is Chastain in?
- Barking in the dark.
- Well, I know what I see.
- Well, let me educate you.
- And what I see is confusing.
Is it me, or does your golden
goose have abnormal lungs?
Brain rest not going well?
How could someone not think?
Even thinking about not
thinking constitutes as thinking.
Hear there was an incident
with a hospital gown.
God. Itchy, tortuous fabric
that will never touch this skin.
Brought you these.
You are a godsend.
Wait, did you see this?
No. What is it?
A dry cleaning tag.
I think you're
wearing Bell's suit.
God. I should have put
on the hospital gown.
Okay, so you end
up in Bell's suit
at the end of a wild night.
Clearly, you have some
things to get off your chest.
No, you're wrong. I'm fine.
The dialysis center's paging
me. Something's wrong.
Go. If you need anything,
I'm here for you, too.
Thanks.
What the hell?
What's going on?
I feel like I'm drowning.
Why are you doing
an echocardiogram?
She got a unit of blood
- with dialysis.
- That shouldn't be enough
to tip her
- into pulmonary edema.
- It shouldn't be,
but I'm afraid she has, uh,
a reduced ejection fraction.
Okay, you're freaking me
out with all the medical speak.
Can you just... can
you explain it in English?
Your heart isn't
pumping strongly enough,
so your lungs filled with fluid.
That's what's making
it hard to breathe.
Why isn't my heart working?
I'm sorry, Jessie, but
you're in heart failure.
First kidney failure.
Now heart failure.
- What's happening?
- We don't know yet.
But Dr. Williams will do a
full workup. keep us updated,
and I promise I will translate
everything into English for you.
It's too much, Nic.
We're gonna figure
things out, okay?
Just try to stay calm.
My sister needs
a kidney transplant
as soon as possible.
We're looking for a match,
but even if we find one,
Jessie's not eligible unless
she's on the recipient list.
If I recall, she isn't listed
because she's an opioid addict.
Was. Was.
She has been two
months clean and sober.
Six months of sobriety's
the hard and fast rule.
Right, that is
Chastain's policy,
but other hospitals
have different criteria.
You could decrease the
amount of time required.
- I...
- Or just... make an exception. Dr. Bell,
- please.
- If I make an exception
for Jessie,
I'd have to make an
exception for others.
It's a slippery slope.
We both know that
addiction is a disease.
She shouldn't be
punished for that.
Well, it isn't a punishment.
Chastain has a
responsibility to honor
the donors' sacrifice by
ensuring that each organ
has the greatest
chance for success.
You remember the drug
trial that you approved?
That you approved, for money?
That's what caused
Jessie's kidney failure.
She trusted Chastain.
And now she will die
if we don't help her.
Please.
I-I wish I could.
Dr. Bell and I were able
to repair your diaphragm
without incident.
But during the procedure,
we noticed your lungs have
- an irregular appearance.
- Irregular?
- What's wrong with me?
- It's most likely
you have an infection.
But there's a possibility
that you may have
an inflammatory process,
which would then need to be
treated aggressively.
Have you had a cough
or shortness of breath?
Yeah.
Okay, well, have a choice.
We can give you
antibiotics and...
if it's an infection,
it should get better.
Or we can perform a bronchoscopy
to get a definitive diagnosis,
so that we can treat you
more specifically sooner.
Which, in this case, would
be my recommendation.
A bronchoscopy.
- That-that sounds serious.
- It's a minor procedure
where we reach deep
into your lungs and take
- a little piece of tissue.
- Before committing,
I need statistics
on most common complications.
Uh, uh, am I put
under or sedated?
You'll be under
conscious sedation,
which means you'll be awake,
but you won't feel anything.
We take a thin tube, we
pass it through your nostrils
or your mouth,
down to your lungs.
Pros and cons on nasal
versus oral would go a long way
in helping me decide. Could I
have a day to think about this?
No, no. This is serious, dawg.
We need to treat
this, like, yesterday.
A hasty decision is
a careless decision.
I wish we had more time,
but that would
be putting your life
at great risk, and I am
not willing to do that.
I don't think you
want that, either.
Yeah, I-I'm just not comfortable
making this call
right now. I'm not.
- I can't...
- And you don't have to.
We will start you
on the antibiotics,
and then graduate
you to the bronchoscopy
just... if necessary.
Sound good?
Grayson wasn't at his
desk, so I let myself in.
I see that.
How was your night?
What do you care?
First time at The Depot?
The... what?
You're a member at the, uh,
Crystal Springs Golf Club.
Spit it out, Mina.
Tell me where
you were last night.
Well, not that it's
any of your business,
I had a date. Did
not go as planned,
I went home early.
So where the hell were you?
We're done here.
- You're on brain rest.
- Don't make us call your mother.
- Too soon.
- Fair enough.
We're worried about you.
Mina...
don't run off again.
We're not playing.
Irving.
I want to see Taylor. Now.
No.
I'm not playing.
Hey.
Well, your oxygen levels
and BP have improved.
And it looks like...
they got off two
liters with dialysis,
so, all good signs.
Good signs I'm
not dying right now.
Look, one day at a time.
But how many-how
many days do I have left?
I mean, come on. We both
know I'm running out of time.
If a kidney walked
in the door right now
it wouldn't matter, 'cause
I'm not on the list, okay?
So just stop pretending like
everything's gonna work out.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I know you're doing
everything you can for me.
I'm just scared.
I'm scared, too.
I just keep thinking that
Mom would be so
disappointed in me.
Jessie, no.
No, Mom would
be so proud of you.
For what?
For not giving up.
And I'm not giving up either.
Okay?
Okay.
Hey. Right this way.
It took some convincing
to get him to see us
again, so if you're not
- absolutely sure about this...
- I am.
Um, either of you want a coffee?
Uh, no. Thank you.
I didn't expect
to see you again.
I hope it wasn't the price
that gave you cold feet,
because that's the same.
$100,000.
- Ten percent down.
- I have it,
and, I, uh, I want
to move forward,
but... there's a problem.
My sister isn't on the
transplant list at Chastain.
- So unless...
- Doctors can be bought.
Just like kidneys.
I have arrangements
out of state.
So just be ready to travel.
Okay.
What's next?
Hmm.
My chaperone is getting anxious.
I am sorry I can't be more help.
No, it's all right. I
didn't expect you to.
- I'm just glad
you're doing better.
- Thanks.
Hey, um...
maybe we were out
there for the same reasons.
Figure stuff out, the things
that scare us the most.
Which is?
Well, for me, it's-it's what
to do with my lotto winnings.
Every dollar is another
decision to make,
and, uh, the money
is just such a...
an opportunity,
and I'm just terrified
that I'll do the wrong thing.
And why would you think that?
Well, because ever
since I was a kid,
I've been making the wrong call.
Prime example: when I
was nine, my folks split.
Dad was moving
to Dallas, and they...
made me pick who to live with.
They made you choose?
Yep.
And I picked Mom.
- Hmm.
- And my dad...
never forgave me.
Well, I'm pretty sure
that wasn't your fault.
That doesn't change my fear
of making a bad choice.
Especially one that
could change my life.
Hey, you're a doctor.
That means you
have to make all kinds
of life and death decisions.
What-wha... How-how?
How do you do it?
You're asking the wrong person.
A few weeks ago,
a wonderful man who
loved me proposed.
I took so long to decide
that he changed his mind.
Oh, so we're-we're
similar in that way.
No.
In every other
instance in my life,
the correct choice was obvious.
But in this instance...
I weighed my options
until it was too late.
So...
So I guess that
guy from last night
must have been a
rebound, then, huh?
What guy?
The guy-the guy,
from the country club.
The, um... I saw you two
inside when I was heading out
- to the course.
- What's his name?
I don't know. I'm-I'm, uh,
pretty sure his dad, like,
owned the club, though.
On behalf of my
people, would you please
put the yarmulke down?
We paged Grayson 20 minutes ago.
- I'll find him myself. Mm-mmm, mm-mmm.
- Uh-uh.
♪ Let me go on ♪
♪ Like a blister in the sun... ♪
What? Only a Green
Day fan after hours?
- Dude, no. Not Green Day.
- Regardless,
last night it was performed
by another American treasure.
Guess we left
- the party too early.
- Yeah, and you left
before I could get Bell
his suit back. I mean,
luckily, he hasn't asked
for his dry cleaning,
or else ya boy would be screwed.
Okay, why was I
wearing Bell's suit?
Wait, do you... You
don't remember?
Oh, man. Best night ever.
Karaoke duets,
taking shots off of random
strangers' midsections.
And the pièce de résistance?
Crashing Daniel
Leebshitz's bar mitzvah.
I mean, you were
underdressed, so I let you borrow
one of the boss man's
suits to gain entry.
Wait, wait, wait.
I have pictures.
That is Daniel and
squad, us included.
Oh, yeah.
- Oy vey.
- Oh, yeah. It was lit.
Yeah.
Wait, no, no, no, no.
Those are memories.
Grayson and Mina. First
Grayna adventure ever.
Last adventure ever.
Clearly, I came to my senses
and fled to the golf course
for some peace and quiet.
Well, not before
pouring your heart about
how much you love
surgery and dinosaurs.
Dinosaurs?
- That's crazy.
- Unexpected.
Yeah. Specifically,
velociraptors.
Raptors.
- You must've heard wrong.
- Uh, no.
I had a video on there before
you deleted it, but whatever.
Haters gonna hate.
Um, no. That's not
what that means.
Raptors...
Mm-mmm. Nope.
I got your page.
Everything okay?
Uh, yeah. There's just one
question I need help with.
What do I put for "Are
there any limitations
on the information
that can be released?"
These are to release
your medical records, Jess.
- You going somewhere?
- Nic didn't tell you?
She thinks I get
on the transplant list
someplace else, so...
Even if you're approved
and listed as a recipient
at another hospital,
the wait for the kidney
still takes years, no
matter where you are.
You'll be on the list here in a
few months. Why not stay here?
I... Hey, I just do what
the big sis tells me.
Nic seems really sure I
can get a kidney now, so...
that's good, right?
Right.
Well, maybe I'll swing by
later to talk to her about it.
Another '80s movie night?
Yeah, if she doesn't
bail like she did last night.
Why'd she bail last night?
She rushed off to the
clinic for some emergency.
Hey, there.
Hey.
You want to watch the sunset?
It's really nice.
Oh, I'd love to, but,
uh, unfortunately,
- I've come to say goodbye.
- Well, where are you going?
Well, the truth is that um...
Chastain's board is gathering
as we speak, and, uh,
I don't think I'm gonna
be around much longer.
- What? Why... why not?
- Because at the end of the day,
a hospital is a business.
And if a CEO can't find
a way to pay the bills,
then the board will
find one who can,
whether it impacts
patient care or not.
I am just so sorry
to hear that, Dr. Bell.
You've been so good to me.
Oh, thank you, Taylor.
I appreciate that.
'Cause I was
always a doctor first.
Never practiced
anywhere but Chastain.
I never-I never wanted to.
When you're a-a charity
that relies on donations,
and the...
and the donors aren't
feeling generous,
there's not much you
can do but face the music.
Dr. Bell, I want to help.
What do you mean?
I think I can.
What's going on?
His SATs dropped into the 70s.
- I was just here. He was fine.
- It's not an infection.
There's no fever, his white
blood cell count's normal,
yet he's worsening
at an alarming rate.
We should've done
the bronchoscopy.
You're damn right
we should have.
Where are we?
Pulmonary alveolar proteinosis.
Explains his
difficulty breathing.
Nothing a little
lung lavage can't fix.
Mm. All right, here we go.
Ready for some fun?
Gentle. Gentle. Don't hurt him.
Don't worry, I'll make sure
your golden goose lives
to lay another egg.
Ha, ha!
Hey. Have you seen Nic?
Is she in with a patient?
No. She's not here.
Is everything okay?
Eh, it's...
Suddenly, Nic's very confident
Jessie is gonna
find a kidney soon.
Transferring her
to another hospital.
I just... I don't know where
the kidney's coming from.
Well, your guess is as good
as mine. They must've found
a Good Samaritan donor
you don't know about.
Yeah. Nic was here last
night. Do you know why?
Sounds like you got some
trust issues to work out.
Yeah. Well, she would
do anything for her sister.
Whatever's going on,
I'm sure she's being smart
and protecting herself.
Yeah, I don't
know, man, I just...
can only think of one way
Nic could get a kidney
for Jessie right now,
and it's illegal.
And I don't think she would've
thought of it on her own.
Nic has a mind that's
very much her own.
And I'd say if she's found
a way to help her
sister, that's a good thing.
You think you're helping Nic,
but you're not.
Have you given any
thought to what happens
if this goes wrong?
She could end up in jail.
Got to close up.
You know, if she wanted
you involved, she would've
- come to you. She didn't.
- No.
You went to her,
you put this in motion,
and now you're hanging back
while she closes
the deal all alone.
All the risk is with
her. W-What... you get
- some sort of finder's fee?
- This is a joke, right?
Oh, come on.
Where is the organ broker?
This is none of your business.
- None of my business?
- Yeah.
I know you're
trying to help Nic.
But this line that she's
about to cross will destroy her.
Do you want that
on your conscience?
I just want to talk to her.
Nic?
- Conrad, what...
- Don't do this.
You didn't like jail when you
were there for a few nights,
do you really want
to go back for years?
That's not gonna happen.
You don't know that.
They'll take away
your license for life.
You'll never be a
nurse practitioner again.
I'm not a match, Conrad.
Kyle's avoiding my phone calls.
What do you want me to do?
- We'll find another way.
- How? Tell me how.
We treat her underlying
heart condition.
Now that heart
failure's involved,
you know she's
not gonna make it.
Are you telling me to give up?
No, I'm not telling
you to give up.
What I'm saying is what
you're thinking of doing is awful.
How many times have I watched
you cross a line for a patient?
A stranger to you?
This is my sister.
Be honest.
If it were me
and I needed a kidney...
It was the only option...
What'd you do?
Anything.
Hey, this is Kyle.
You know what to do.
Kyle, it's me again.
I still haven't heard
back from you. Listen,
Jessie is running out of time
and I'm about to
do something that...
Just please...
call me back
before it's too late.
♪ ♪
♪ Sometimes you don't... ♪
Should we be doing this here?
They know me here. Relax.
10,000. Good.
Down payment out of the way.
Now we talk details.
I want to meet the donor
before we move forward with this.
You already have.
Paige has been counting
tips here since high school.
The, um, the transplant staff...
They're trained to identify
if a donated organ was bought.
I shall coach donor
and recipient with a story
to explain how they
know each other.
Grade school
friends who lost touch
and reconnected on social media.
And Paige saw one of
Jessie's posts about her health
and wanted to help.
And they shouldn't
practice too much.
Can't sound rehearsed.
A... Uh, is she
prepared for this?
Don't worry about that.
She's made a choice.
Just as you have now.
♪ Aw, she cleaned me out ♪
♪ And did it on the sly. ♪
Just... just one thing left.
Yeah, the check.
The check.
Just got to sign it.
Oh... you know what?
I think this pen is out of ink.
Oh, man.
This feels so good.
Honestly, I think-I think
this is the easiest decision
- I've ever made, I mean...
- Hmm.
Maybe I'm, um,
turning over a new leaf.
You know? Oh.
Thank you.
Really.
The... Um... this, uh...
That's just the
first installment.
-Oh, yeah, right, of
course. I mean, -Yeah.
Who keeps $36 million
in a checking account?
- No, I'd be happy
to arrange a wire transfer.
- Yeah.
No, I don't have $36 million.
I mean, when the-when
you win the lottery,
they give you a choice: you
can either take the lump sum
or you can get weekly payments.
Which actually ends up
being way more in the end.
So, only idiots
choose the lump sum.
- That was an easy one.
- Uh, yeah. Smart.
I think so.
Dr. Bell, you can count on me
for 13 grand a week
for the next 30 years.
Yo, how is she?
She is in the room.
So do not speak of
her as though she is not.
Good news.
Your observation period is over.
And as your concussion
officer, I officially release you.
- Okay, I'm getting out of here.
- Or you can come watch
the bypass on this
inverses patient.
That surgery was this morning.
I had it rescheduled.
The patient needed stabilization
and I didn't want
you to miss it.
OR in ten.
Your reign of terror is over.
- You know I hate it
when you smile.
- I can't help it.
Because I finally figured out
something you're not good at.
Impossible.
Matters of the heart, Mina.
You might be a
genius at medicine,
but when it comes to love...
A proposal and now these
unexpected Raptor feelings...
Is too much.
So you purged
and you let it out...
and you did the right thing.
He's my mentor.
Nothing more.
Some lines can't be crossed.
Sometimes a velociraptor...
is just a velociraptor.
Look, I already told
Nurse Nevin I can't
- bend the rules for her sister.
- We both know
you're willing to bend the
rules when it benefits you.
How could it
possibly benefit me?
I offer you something
bigger in return.
Hey.
They'll put Jessie
on the transplant list.
What?
Now she can have
the surgery at Chastain.
All we need is a kidney.
How?
Doesn't matter how.
And we will do
everything to make sure
the transplant goes well as
soon as the donor gets here.
There is no donor.
What?
The 30-year-old woman who
was willing to
sell her kidney...
She was only gonna make
ten percent of the money.
Elliot takes advantage
of these people.
It's disgusting.
Even if...
this transplant goes
well, Jessie will always
be an addict in recovery.
I need to be better for her,
someone that she can look up to.
If I'd gone through with this...
Nic, you made
the right decision.
I hope so.
But I am not giving
up on a kidney.
There has got to be another way.
We will find one.
I know we will.
You weren't gonna say goodbye?
Just gonna pack
up and leave, huh?
Look, Nic...
I don't regret
anything I've done.
Not in the past and certainly
not in the last couple days.
I am who I am, and
that's not gonna change.
I know.
And I know you're
always gonna love him.
Thank you for everything.
Alec, honestly.
See you, Nic.
- Good luck.
- Mm-hmm.
Thanks.
Hey, Nic.
You know you never
needed me here, right?
The clinic...
It's yours.
As it should be.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH