Pressure. I need pressure.
Give me sutures...
We need an Epi.
Alert trauma.
Let the record show
that we are officially
convening a disciplinary hearing
regarding the events on February
3rd, 2012, in patient room 209.
Dr. House, this recording will
be transcribed and published
along with all supporting
documentation and rulings.
Do you have any questions
before we get started?
Yeah.
Who the hell are you?
I'm Walter Cofield. Chief of
Neurology, Mercy Hospital.
I'll be deciding
your fate today.
Cofield.
You were the Residency Director at
Hopkins before you moved to Mercy.
Which means it's safe to
assume that you trained Foreman.
Which means it's also safe
to assume that he trusts you.
This hearing isn't
about me, Dr. House.
I know you'd like
to make it about me
because then it
wouldn't be about you.
It's interesting that he picked the
old mentor to judge the new one.
Interesting, but not relevant.
The facts of this case,
on the other hand...
The facts are in the file.
If you have trouble reading
my handwriting, give me a call.
I'm going back to work.
If I just consider the file,
the facts aren't in your favor.
The facts say you
should be suspended.
Which, from what I understand,
would mean a
revocation of your parole.
The patient was a 32-year-old
high school chemistry teacher.
He collapsed while out jogging.
He was paralyzed
in all four extremities
despite the fact
that the scans...
show no sign of stroke
or structural lesions.
Did you put out an APB for a car
with a man-shaped
dent in the grill?
No broken bones,
no signs of trauma.
Transverse myelitis. Boring.
No enhancement on the MRI.
I just don't know what to do.
Please, you have to
help me solve this thing.
A little poetic license.
What are you doing?
Taking my vic-amins.
Those are Vicodin?
Did you have surgery recently?
About a decade ago.
My leg is no good
at judging time.
Were you taking
Vicodin during this case?
Uh...
Yes.
And during about nine
years' previous cases.
My process is proven.
Good things usually happen.
Bad things sometimes happen.
And when bad things happen, we
should figure out what went wrong
so we can learn
from it and correct it.
So we can assign blame.
Instead of recognizing that
bad things sometimes happen.
It was nobody's fault.
And then what happened?
Those who can, do.
Those who can't, teach.
Those who can't
teach, teach gym.
And those who can't move their
arms or legs teach us to laugh at others.
House actually presented
the case in that way?
Or are you just trying
to make him look bad?
Why would I be trying
Could be your not-so-subtle way
of implying this
was House's fault.
Given what's happened,
it's understandable
that your opinion would
color your testimony.
But I just want to know
what you said, what you did
and what you were
thinking at the time.
I don't think it was his fault.
Just tell me
your initial theory.
I thought the patient
had a liver problem.
Hepatic encephalopathy
explained why he passed out,
why he couldn't move his limbs.
But that's not the
idea House went with?
He thought Taub's
idea was stupid.
And what about your idea?
He thought that was stupid, too.
No. I meant, what was it?
Oh. I thought the patient had
normal pressure hydrocephalus.
And why did House
think that was stupid?
Oh, come on.
Unless you're an idiot, you know
why I thought Park was an idiot.
The patient had low
opening pressure on his LP.
That's what I said.
No, you idiot.
The patient had low
opening pressure on his LP.
Try unsquinting your eyes
and reading the labs next time.
Are you intentionally trying
to get me to dislike you?
That wasn't me.
The chair squeaked.
You're testifying for the record
that you actually used the
phrasing, "unsquint your eyes"?
This is not the place
to exorcise your guilt,
I just want to know exactly...
I actually used the phrasing
"unsquint your eyes."
He's hypokalemic,
could indicate a problem
with his heart, which would...
EKG was normal.
But, Chase,
a doctor who
actually takes the time
to read the lab
reports, has a point.
The guy's potassium is off.
Could be thyrotoxic paralysis.
Start him on steroids,
PTU, and beta blockers.
Mmm-hmm.
And how did these orange
smudges get on the patient file?
Seriously? That's
your follow up?
I eat a lot of Cheetos, I
forget to wash my hands.
Is my snacking really
relevant to this case?
Might be, if these were
actually Cheetos stains.
What are they?
Seriously, House?
You're blaming me?
You used Adams' shampoo.
I didn't do it.
It was a harmless prank.
My team is made up
of Type A personalities.
They need somebody to break
the tension every once in a while.
So this was a team
building exercise?
Is that what he called it?
It's what he implied.
House prefers
chaos over cohesion.
He believes that disagreement
and mistrust lead to better ideas.
He's not wrong.
As opposed to being right?
So you treated with steroids.
And then what
happened? They worked.
Our patient woke up.
Bill?
Can you hear me?
Yeah.
I'm thirsty.
That's normal. You've been
in a coma for several hours.
Can you tell me your name?
Bill. Bill Koppelman.
Can you tell me
what happened to me?
We're treating you for
an overactive thyroid.
We think that's why you
passed out and couldn't move.
Can you wiggle
your fingers for me?
Is he going to be okay?
Excuse me, but only
family members are allowed.
It's okay. They're my students.
Everyone back at school
is so worried about you.
Is he sick because
of the explosion?
What explosion? What explosion?
What explosion?
A chemistry demonstration he
was doing for his class went wrong.
Then why was it not
already in the patient history?
Because the patient
was unconscious.
But I'm assuming
Dr. House spoke to the wife.
The wife didn't know
about the explosion.
And I was the one
who questioned her.
So if there was an
oversight, it was mine.
Does Dr. House not attach
importance to patient histories?
No. He thinks they're crucial.
He just doesn't think being in the
same room as the patient is crucial.
House thinks avoiding patients
allows him to stay as
objective as possible.
He's not wrong.
That sounds like a very
diplomatic way of saying he's lazy.
That's also true.
Either way, I'm covered.
If you want an
accurate patient history,
don't ever talk to the patient.
Everybody lies.
Except me.
To you.
Would never do that.
Okay. Say you're right.
If you had actually been in
the room questioning the patient,
you could read body language,
you could ask
follow up questions,
and warn him of the
cost of lying to you.
Don't forget thumbscrews.
Can you dispute the possibility
that had you visited the patient
sooner, maybe talked to the wife,
been directed to
one of the students,
that this case might have
ended very differently?
It wasn't exactly an explosion.
It was a controlled reaction
that went a little haywire.
It was, too, an explosion.
Simon Harris filmed the whole
thing on his camera phone
and posted it on YouTube.
It got, like, over
75,000 hits already.
Looks like you've
gone viral, hon.
He had a loss of consciousness,
temporary paralysis,
but when I was told that
the patient coughed up blood,
things really started
to get interesting.
Your patient was doubled over
in pain and coughing up blood.
And you found that interesting?
Why, is that bad?
It's interesting.
I do this demonstration
every year.
But I usually have a
student aide help me set it up.
Apparently this year he
added extra hydrofluoric acid,
which is why it exploded.
The student aide was just
trying to make a viral video,
not hurt anyone.
Ended up doing both.
So we figured the patient
inhaled the extra large dose
of hydrofluoric acid, and...
burned his lungs, which is
why he coughed up blood.
If only burnt lungs explained
the passing out and paralysis.
The explosion does.
Check out the video again.
He smacked his
head against the wall.
If that caused swelling
in his brainstem
that would have led to the eventual
loss of consciousness and paralysis.
So we discussed
it a little longer
and House decided
to treat with heparin.
I wouldn't mind a
couple more details.
It was aerosolized heparin.
You skipped over the actual DDX,
and now you're
averting your eyes.
I'm growing more and
more curious by the moment.
He smacked his
head against the wall.
If that caused swelling
in his brainstem
that would have led to the eventual
loss of consciousness and paralysis.
Nobody move. Ugh!
He had on a what?
Gas mask.
The stink bomb was Chase's.
He was getting revenge
for the orange hair
and rigged it in House's office.
But House found it.
Mmm-hmm.
You can leave when
I have an answer.
Might help if we
knew the question.
How do we treat chemical
burns inside the lungs?
Maybe we can use a bronchoalveolar
lavage to wash them out with water.
Sorry, my fault, I
should have clarified.
How do we treat chemical
burns inside the lungs
without killing the patient?
Silver sulfadiazine works
well on chemical burns.
Burn cream would drown
him faster than water.
Well?
Aerosolized heparin.
Me likey.
But that's only experimental,
it's never actually
been used before.
Not true.
It's been used in sheep.
Uh-huh.
The guy was going downhill fast.
We needed a treatment
that was a slope changer.
So you busted out the
sulfur dioxide stink bomb?
It was a team building exercise.
No, it was manipulation.
You were pressuring your team into
coming up with unsafe medical ideas
just to get out of that room.
You say pressure, I say inspire.
The usual, safe ideas were not going
to work. Aerosolized heparin might.
And everyone else just
went along with this?
No. I told House I
thought it was a mistake.
And those were your exact words?
I think I might
have said "insane."
You thought it was insane
and yet you let it happen.
No, I...
If you disagree with Dr. House
on patient safety, Doctor,
it is your duty to speak up.
Otherwise, you're
equally to blame.
I did speak up. I tried.
And you failed.
And that's why I
went to Dr. Foreman.
The heparin could
cause the patient
to bleed into his
lungs even faster.
It is crazy.
But House doesn't do
crazy just for crazy's sake.
If he thinks this is the only
way to help the patient...
You did not tell me you
were involved in this case
when you asked me to do this.
I wasn't.
The heparin decision didn't have
anything to do with the outcome.
If signing off on everything
House does is a pattern,
it affects the way
House behaves,
it affects the way House's team
reacts to the way House behaves.
House
is brilliant.
I give him the benefit of
the doubt most of the time,
because I've seen
what he can do.
Getting House out of prison
is the biggest decision you've
made as Dean of Medicine, right?
And if he's suspended
as a result of this hearing,
he violates his parole
and he goes back.
And that probably leaves you
as former Dean of Medicine.
I suppose so.
You didn't choose
me to oversee this
because you thought
I could be objective,
you chose me because you
thought I'd have your back.
And I'd think twice about making
a decision that would get you fired.
Eric,
I'm sorry.
But if your
get-House-out-of-jail-free
experiment blows
up in your face,
it's not my job to
get you out of it.
After you'd
administered the heparin,
I see there was a
discharge order in the chart.
Yet the patient never left.
House ordered a
therapeutic bath first,
to wash off any residual
chemicals from the blast
but we wound up
finding something.
You have a bit of a rash.
Can you raise both your arms?
We just need to
see how far it goes.
You told me I was gonna be okay.
And now there's still
something wrong with me.
It probably doesn't mean
anything, but we want to make sure.
Of course you do.
I gotta get out of here. Okay?
Just relax.
Please just let
me get out of here.
It'll just take a minute.
We need to get a
good look at the rash.
The rash? That was nothing. Just
some irritation from lying in bed all day.
The problem was
the patient's brain.
He freaked out.
I gotta get out of here.
I gotta get out of here! Easy.
"Freak out" is a little strong.
In my opinion at the time, it was
the rash that was going to kill him.
Invasive strep.
Reasonable theory,
supported by the evidence.
The evidence
pointed to psychosis.
We caused it by giving him
steroids when he first came in.
What'd you think?
I thought Park and
Adams were both right.
But that their conclusions
were both wrong.
The neuro symptoms and the rash
were both signs of
an underlying disease.
Together with the lung,
it added up to Wegener's.
How does Dr. House handle
it when three smart doctors
come up with three different,
but equally valid ideas?
I run a diagnostic trial.
Start the patient on
high dose steroids.
Multiple birds, single stone.
If Taub is right, then he
can walk out of here cured.
If Adams is right, he will
spike a fever, get hypotensive,
we can treat it and he
can walk out of here cured.
If Park is right and he goes
all Cuckoo's Nest on us,
we can cross
"brain" off the list...
diagnose him, and he
can walk out of here cured.
Are you trying to
make this easy for me?
By your own admission, if
you give the patient steroids,
two of the three outcomes
could make him worse.
What's making the patient
worse was not having a diagnosis.
This was the
fastest way to get it.
It was the perfect
diagnostic moment.
In light of what happened,
do you still think it was the
perfect diagnostic moment?
Yes.
My theory accounted for
all the medical outcomes.
It did not account for the
disobedience of my own team.
What are you doing?
I think you're right
about the strep.
Can't hurt to biopsy the
rash while we're waiting.
Thanks.
At the time, it seemed
like a good idea.
I know this is hard.
But please tell me exactly
what happened next.
Draw up a little anesthetic.
Two cc's Lidocaine.
Get away from me!
Bill, you're in a
hospital. Calm down!
Code Gray!
So your position is that your
team's disobedience caused this?
That's not what I said.
You said you didn't
anticipate their defiance.
You implied that all would
have been fine otherwise.
So who do you blame?
Dr. Adams or Dr. Chase?
Or both?
I don't blame either one.
So who do you blame, Dr. House?
Code Gray!
Get Haloperidol.
Got it.
Oh, my God, Chase!
Prep the OR! Get a
gurney. Start an IV!
Come on.
Bleeder's gotta be in here.
Got it! Which artery?
It's his heart.
Fortunately, only the knife
tip reached the cardiac muscle.
Made a laceration
in the left ventricle
about the size of the
tip of my index finger.
At that moment, he
could only stay alive
as long as my finger
plugged the hole.
Hmm.
It could've been
me on the floor.
It should have been me.
It was my theory.
I held the needle in front of the
patient that set off his paranoia.
If you're looking for
someone to blame,
blame me.
Please continue.
Getting some ectopy.
Coming through! CHI:
Good carotid pulse.
Regular? CHI: No.
Got a PVC.
Gotta move it, people.
My diagnostic test worked.
It proved that the patient had
a steroid induced psychosis.
That's what you took
away from this situation?
The brain was not a symptom
of an underlying disease.
Your colleague was stabbed.
Are you telling
me you didn't care?
How bad is it?
Bad.
Patch.
Ready.
I can't take my
finger out, he'll bleed.
I don't think he can take it.
Oxygenation's 100 percent.
He's as ready as he's gonna be.
We gotta go for it.
On my count.
One, two,
three.
Suture.
Got it.
BP is stable.
Patch is holding.
What was his heart rate?
He doesn't have
one. He's on bypass.
Not Chase, the patient.
You're DDX'ing?
Park, come with
me. Taub's got this.
My friend is here because
you didn't listen to me.
I did listen to you.
Chase didn't listen to me.
At this point, being here
makes you feel better,
you're not helping
Chase or our patient.
Fine.
So he just walked out?
There really was
nothing for him to do.
It speaks to a
certain callousness
on Dr. House's
part, don't you think?
Who cares if House was callous?
Are you going to
punish callousness?
But you agree that empathy
is a useful quality for doctors?
House is not the problem.
Your friend got stabbed.
He may die from those wounds.
If you had been in that room,
maybe that could have been you.
I wouldn't have
been in the room.
Implicitly, you just said
that Chase was at fault.
We all knew a psychotic episode
was one of the three
possible outcomes.
And Chase brought
a scalpel in there.
He endangered Dr. Adams,
he endangered himself,
and he endangered the patient.
Thank you.
Lungs, rash, and now
excessive RR variability.
Go.
It's a hospital. There are lots of
doctors that can take care of him.
And your thinking
is that only you guys
are qualified to sit in
this room, doing nothing?
If you're motivated by caring,
just bear in mind he's a
dedicated chemistry teacher
with a pretty wife and adoring
students and a baby on the way.
She's not pregnant.
Would it make a difference?
Because I could knock her up.
Autonomic dysregulation...
Shut up.
Can you guys keep it down?
You made it, bud.
You're in the PACU.
You've been in surgery. The
anesthesia's just wearing off.
Did I have an epidural?
No.
Because I can't feel my legs.
Dr. Chase?
Robert?
Yeah.
I'm Walter Cofield.
I'm a neurologist over at...
I know who you are.
Good.
You think you're up for
answering a couple of questions?
Well, it's not like I can
get up and run away.
Wasn't my best joke.
I'm smiling because
for the last 12 hours
I've been picturing
you with orange hair.
I dyed it back.
Were you angry with Dr. House?
It was a prank, it
wasn't uncommon.
So I've heard.
That doesn't mean
you couldn't get angry.
Might actually
contribute to that reaction.
Can I ask why that matters?
Are you trying to prove
that I was distracted,
that my judgment
was compromised?
Who do you think was at fault
for what happened
to you, Dr. Chase?
Again, why does it matter?
You're a smart doctor.
You know what happened
here better than anyone
and you've worked with
Dr. House longer than anyone.
And I suspect that you've spent
every minute since
this has happened
trying to answer
that very question.
I don't think it
was anyone's fault.
I was angry but I
wasn't distracted.
And I think if there's any
chance I'm gonna walk again
it's because
Dr. House is a genius.
What about warmth? Can you
feel the sheets on your skin?
I just said I don't
feel anything.
Objectivity, House.
What about posttraumatic
syringomyelia?
A syrinx formed in the
subarachnoid space,
blocking the flow of
cerebrospinal fluid.
That'd mean the
damage was permanent.
No.
Forget the nerves.
House, if it's total
paralysis he must have...
Not necessarily.
Think arteries.
Blood flow to his
spinal column is cut off.
It's a clot in the
radicular artery.
That could be fixable.
Prep a room for an embolectomy
and let's get that
thing out of there
before it does any more damage.
And if it's not a clot?
Then you can ask Foreman if
hospital insurance covers ramp-vans.
You're through the aorta.
There.
Sensory level is at L5, it
must be the descending branch.
Can I see the monitor?
Stop there. Shoot the dye.
There it is. TAUB:
Don't get too excited.
We still gotta get it out, still could
have done permanent damage.
Patient does not have
autonomic dysregulation.
There's blood in his urine
bag. Kidneys are failing.
House, not now. Gotta be now.
Foreman's transferring
our guy to Princeton General
as soon as there's
a bed available.
Says the doctors here can no
longer be objective since the stabbing.
In the middle of a procedure
that could basically save your life,
House is actually trying
to drag people away?
How do you work
with a guy like that?
He wasn't trying to
pull anybody away.
Everyone had already
refused to work on that case.
He knew the answer.
He wanted to check on me.
But he needed an excuse.
Otherwise he could
be accused of caring.
So your testimony is that
Dr. House's complete
lack of concern
is evidence of his deep concern?
Did you just do that?
What?
Wiggle your toes.
Do you feel that?
Congratulations.
It was the clot.
Short occlusion
time of the artery,
when the swelling goes down,
you should gain back at
least some of the function.
One more thing. Sorry.
You knew that your patient
was at risk for a psychotic break
when you brought a
scalpel within his reach.
Why did you ignore that risk?
I thought I was
right about the rash.
I would do it again.
I thought so.
That's it? "I thought so"?
What the hell does that mean?
You brazenly defied your boss.
Now that happened
either because Dr. House
has established that
that's okay in his world.
Or his prank war distracted you.
Or House makes medicine a game
and you just wanted to beat him.
Whatever the reason,
it boils down to the fact that
you may never walk again
because House created an
atmosphere that promotes recklessness.
This will be our last
round of questions.
I've spoken with Dr. Chase.
You know he regained movement?
No.
Are you really this indifferent
to the fact that
Dr. Chase is hurt?
Are we going off the record
because this is irrelevant
or are you going to hit me?
Why don't you go tell
the guy you're sorry...
I didn't do anything wrong.
It's not an admission of guilt.
He's your friend
and he's not well.
He's a co-worker.
Co-worker whom you've known
for almost 10 years who nearly died.
And who's still scared
he may not walk.
Are you going to have
me fired for bad manners?
I'm just trying to
understand you.
Why a man in your
position, with your abilities,
is incapable of shaking the
impulse to act like an ass.
Could we go back on the
record and get this over with?
Put the Vicodin away, Dr. House.
My leg hurts.
Is that supposed to be funny?
Two explosions.
We're not done here.
Hey! Hold on!
Close it up.
Take him out of there.
Dr. Foreman said you'd try this.
Said to tell you he's
no longer your patient.
Hey!
Wait.
I have to get to my
car. I want to be...
Your husband has a
tumor in his lymph nodes.
You've been wrong every time.
Not this time.
The explosion in the classroom
caused the cancer
cells to break open.
It's called tumor
lysis syndrome.
His body was flooded with an excess
of phosphates, potassium, acids,
all kinds of cancerous junk.
That explains the paralysis, the
bleeding, the heart and kidney issues.
Everything.
What about the psychotic break?
Turns out we caused that.
This is treatable. Okay?
You have to tell the new doctors
he needs total body radiation
and plasmapheresis.
Move your cane, please.
Where's Cofield?
He said you walked out.
I'm walking back.
I'm not done testifying.
Apparently you were. Said
he'd have his decision tomorrow.
This case is a fiasco.
I didn't sleep last night.
Dr. House is
obviously brilliant.
Well, I think we've
heard enough.
But Dr. House is also a fiasco.
If I were to exonerate him,
condone his completely reckless,
immature, almost misanthropic behavior,
I would essentially
be sending a message
to all the other
doctors in this hospital
that it's okay to
act that way, and...
Sorry.
We're in the middle of something.
- I know.
I came to speak with Dr. House,
and when they told
me he was in here
I thought I should
say something.
I mean,
he wasn't the nicest
doctor I've ever met.
Well, I think we've
heard enough.
But he was right.
They found the tumor.
They are removing it, and
they are starting plasmapheresis.
They expect a full recovery.
He saved my husband's life.
Well, I guess that's it.
Thanks again.
As I was saying,
Dr. House's process is
dangerous and inappropriate.
But he is effective.
I've decided that I would be
doing this hospital a disservice
if I did anything to
change that process.
Congratulations, Dr. House.
This unfortunate stabbing
incident is officially nobody's fault.
Coward.
Excuse me?
You've got like 20
pages of notes there.
You were expecting to bore
us for at least half an hour.
You've got my
parole form in here.
You were going to
send me back to prison.
House, stop.
Good things usually happen,
bad things sometimes happen.
The fact that that
would-be widow
came in just in time to sob
all over your soft, mushy heart,
and the fact that her
husband is going to live,
does not change whether
or not I did the right thing.
How'd you get the firing
wire into the Vicodin bottle
without me noticing?
Why'd I even have to?
What was the point
of the orange hair?
Your hair smelled like Adams'.
Since there's no way you're
doing her without me knowing,
it means you were
just doing her shampoo.
Which means you were out
late drinking with some new girl
or because there is no new girl.
You were trying to make up
time by showering at the hospital,
but you were too lazy to
buy your own shampoo.
So I found a way to let
you know to not be late.
You couldn't just ask
me to stop being late?
What fun would that be?
None of this is fun, House.
They decided that
your being stabbed
was nobody's fault.
They're wrong.
I'm sorry.
Anything else?
I'm kind of busy.
No. That was it.
I've got it.