[ ? The Brand New Heavies :
How We Do This]
- Morning, neighbor.
- Hey.
You look fancy.
I have to be on live TV this morning.
I thought maybe you were dressed
for something later. A special event.
I've never been on live TV.
It's more of a get-together
than an event.
I had a dream.
I was on camera and I was talking
and all of my teeth fell out.
OK, why has nobody, including you,
responded to my invitation tonight ?
I've invited everyone from work
to my home over a week ago. A week.
Addison, I live three feet away
from your new home.
If you have a party, I'll be there
even if I don't want to be.
- What a delightful acceptance.
- I have to be on live TV.
You want me to come with you ?
Moral support ?
Yes. Yes.
Well, all you have to do is invite me.
- I would like you to come.
- And I RSVP yes.
Like any decent person would.
Hey ! Hands out of the mouth.
Now, you've been sick a lot
this year, right ?
Now my exam didn't
turn up anything, medically.
Now what else has changed this year ?
Job, home ?
- I'm going bald.
- [Audience laughs]
OK. See, now this is what
I'm talking about in my book.
The whole mindlbody connection.
Now your body is trying to talk to you.
Trying to get you to pay attention
with what's going on up here.
Now hair loss or no, it's the head
that's messing with the machine.
You think the ladies are lining up
to choose me over some guy with hair ?
Louis, my man. Look at my head.
Bald is beautiful. Bald is sexy.
- Virile men are bald.
- [Applause]
The Arm & Hammer guy is bald.
Louis, you're a bald man.
- Come on. Say it.
- I'm a bald man.
- You are a strong, proud bald man.
- I'm a strong, proud bald m...
- You are a strong, proud bald man !
- I am a strong, proud bald...
One more time with fervor.
You are a strong, proud...
I am a strong, proud bald man !
Yes ! That's what I'm talking about !
Bald is beautiful.
- How was the TV thing ?
- [Grunts]
- He was very inspiring.
- I'm a fraud.
You were inspiring. Listening to
the patient, the mindlbody connection...
You inspired me, OK ? Yeah.
Wasn't he inspiring on TV ?
The Arm & Hammer guy's
not bald by the way.
- He is too. He's bald.
- Arm & Hammer guy definitely not bald.
- Yeah.
- [Addison] Everybody ?
Mr. Clean's bald.
Hey, guys, I'm just trying
to get a head count for tonight.
- What's tonight ?
- My party.
- Is anybody coming ?
- Oops.
- I forgot.
- Yeah.
- I made plans to...
- I'm there. I RSVP'd.
Hey. I'm sorry I'm late.
The Arm & Hammer guy's not bald.
I know. He's just an arm.
And a hammer.
OK. Today's cases ?
- What's this ?
- Naomi's wall of miracles.
This one here is my favorite, Jamie.
The mother had hardly any eggs left.
You know, borderline FSH.
She had given up.
But Naomi did her thing and pow.
I mean, she made every baby up there.
I mean, she helped.
Those are her miracles.
Miracles.
Wow. It's a beaut.
My first husband thought
engagement rings were too extravagant.
So this is my one and only.
And this is him. This is my Stan.
You should get back out there, Pete.
Find yourself a Stan.
I'm out there.
I'm not talking about the girls
you date. I'm talking about love.
I'm talking about marriage.
Soul mates. Like us.
- You worry too much, Sylvie.
- Stan's been falling asleep.
- Falling asleep ?
- Tell the doctor, Stan.
Sometimes I just go to sleep.
[Sylvie] When I'm talking to him.
In the middle of the day.
First time I thought he was dead.
I always wake up in a couple of seconds.
It's no big deal.
But Sylvie has to go and drag me
to see the whacko doctor.
Stan ! He's a little more traditional
than I am, but he'll warm to you.
Before you fall asleep
do you have dizziness or palpitations ?
- This is a waste of time.
- No. When he wakes up, he's good.
It's almost like it never happened.
You think...
There he goes.
- Come on.
- [Both] Aah...
No signs of infection.
- You got a little swelling.
- What does that mean ?
Combined with the lack of energy
and appetite, it could be mononucleosis.
Wait. The kissing disease ?
- Have you been kissing someone ?
- Gross. No.
OK, there are plenty of other ways
to contract mono.
I'll have to take some blood
to find out.
- But I can still skateboard, right ?
- No.
Not until you're better.
Until then, you get plenty of sleep.
And no making out.
Like anybody would
want to kiss me anyway.
I don't have a lot of domain
around here.
- I'm stepping on your domain.
- Little bit. Can I help ?
I need me. The me file.
I... I would be one of Naomi's patients.
Oh, OK. Yeah.
Is everything OK ?
- Lady problems ?
- Just give me the file.
Because I might be able to help.
I'm, like, the hub,
in the Oceanside wheel.
The file, Dell.
OK.
Are you going to this Addison thing ?
- I'll go if you go ?
- You know what ?
There comes a point
when you're done with new people.
- Do I really need a new friend ?
- Not with me around.
I'm a lot of friend.
I'm two double patties of friend.
- That's what I'm saying.
What ? What are we hiding from ?
- It's Cami.
- Cami ?
- The woman Allan dumped you for, Cami ?
- He didn't dump me.
He just married her
right after he left me.
What the hell is she doing with Naomi ?
Cami Davis is a patient here ?
- You should ask Naomi.
- What is Cami Davis here for ?
- Fine. I will.
OK, freak show ?
Oh, my God. I'm pathetic.
I need to let this go.
- I'm gonna let this go.
- [Both inhale and exhale deeply]
- Who cares why Cami is here ?
- Yeah.
[Mouthing]
- Hey.
- You find what you were looking for ?
Kind of.
Did I mention I'm a total whiz
at the female anatomy ?
I'm acing my midwifery classes.
- I got it all up here.
- Yeah, yeah. Keep it up there.
Vulva !
Labium majus !
If that's flirting, you need new skills.
Could you run these labs for me ?
[Elevator dings]
Dr. Bennett. Dr. Sam Bennett ?
- I'm Dr. Bennett. Whoa ! OK.
- Let's get you to a chair.
- Right over here.
- [Addison] Easy.
Have a seat. Nice and slow.
There we... Whoa.
Did you just walk
right out of the hospital ?
- We had to get out of there.
- We ? You and ?
Me and my baby.
They were trying to kill us.
I saw you on TV.
Those things you said,
about listening to the patient,
was that just TV crap ?
No, I meant it.
Except for the Arm & Hammer part.
So you said
the hospital is trying to kill you ?
Everything they do just makes me sicker.
- How far along are you ?
- Five months.
I know I look thin,
but I'm eating, I am.
I've always had stomach stuff,
this pain.
But nobody can figure out what's wrong.
I'm doing what you said, listening
to my body, but nobody believes me.
Why don't you give me
your name and your hospital ?
- I'll talk to your doctor.
- I can't.
I can't give you that.
You scratched your name
off your hospital bracelet ?
She won't give us
any of her information.
- She's afraid we'll send her back.
- You're damn right.
- I'll get Dell to call the hospitals.
- She came here because of Sam.
She was inspired by Dr. Sam.
Well, then she's going to want
to go back because Dr. Sam is an idiot.
I'd like to run some tests.
OK, fine. But just until we figure out
where she belongs.
- You had to go on TV.
- Thank you, Sam.
- Does she seem a little...
- Did you RSVP to her thing ?
- Oh...
- Yeah.
Damn floor got off balance.
Were you dizzy
right before it happened ?
Maybe a little.
What's happening to him ?
Is he gonna have to go to the hospital ?
Stan, I'd like to run some basic tests.
We'll get an EKG, an MRI.
Let's see if we find anything.
You fix Stan. Hear me ?
Like I said, he's my one and only.
Hey. I got a 70-year-old male
presenting with syncope.
These what you'd run ?
OK. He's hypertensive, diabetic.
Could be a TIA or an occult arrhythmia.
I hope not.
- OK. Thanks.
- Yeah.
You should RSVP for Addison's thing.
She's starting to get squirrelly.
Yeah, I'm not sure.
- She's getting to you.
- She is not.
I'm not going there.
She's definitely getting to you !
So, he doesn't have mono ?
- Test came back negative.
- Oh, thank God. I'm going to call Dad.
You don't seem happy. You were hoping
for a contagious disease ?
I knew I didn't have it.
I know what's wrong with me.
- What's that ?
- I'm in love.
Is that awful ?
That's great, right ?
Not when the person you're in love with
doesn't like you back.
- Who is she ?
- Someone at the skate park.
- Does she know you like her ?
- No.
If I tell, it'll change everything.
[ ? Thief : Sunchild]
I don't know, man.
Don't you gotta go for it ?
Ask her to do something
or hang out or...
I thought about it,
but I don't want to mess everything up.
I'm not saying it's going to be easy.
I mean, I know. I've...
- I got to...
- What ?
This girl I like,
I've been trying to get up the nerve
to say something for a long time.
I mean a long time.
- For real ?
- Yeah.
I'll tell you what, a pact.
I'll do it if you do it.
Let's spill our guts, see what happens.
- Pact.
- Boom.
- Violet ?
- Why is Cami Davis here ?
- Why was she seeing you ?
- Violet.
I know. But why was she here ?
- Do you really want to know ?
- OK, don't tell me.
I will tell you
if you really want to know.
No. No matter what I say.
No matter what I do.
Don't tell me.
Because it's not smart.
And it's unhealthy
and I should mind my own business.
- Swear you won't tell me.
- I swear.
OK.
Are you OK ?
What if Stan doesn't
really want to marry me ?
- Why would you think that ?
- Hear me out.
These "attacks,"
what if they're caused by stress
about getting hitched to me for life ?
Sylvie, there are a lot
of possible reasons.
They started right after he proposed.
Hey. I just checked on our Jane Doe.
Why are you checking on my patient ?
- This is not midwiff school.
- She's having contractions.
[Groaning] Is the baby OK ?
The medication I'm giving you
will stop the contractions.
Just focus on your breathing.
OK. Breathing.
Here we go.
The fetal weight is low for five months.
But...
...the heartbeat is present and strong.
- For now.
- Nobody thought I could get pregnant.
Not my doctors, my boyfriend.
My body's been messed up my whole life.
This baby ? It's a miracle.
Total cliché, right ?
No. No, I get it.
I'll do whatever you say.
I can't lose my baby.
- I hear you have something of ours.
- [Naomi] She came here on her own.
We called every hospital in the city
to find out where she came from.
- You know our Jane Doe ?
- Rebecca Hobart.
I'm going to arrange transportation
back to Saint Ambrose.
Rebecca wants to stay here.
We are keeping her.
Is that so ? I think your guest
left out more than her name.
- What do you mean ?
- Rebecca Hobart's a 51 l50.
- She's on involuntary hold ?
- That's right.
The patient you are aiding and abetting ?
She's straight out of the psych ward.
She doesn't seem crazy to me.
She's very convincing.
- Like all good Münchausen patients.
- Wait. Münchausen ?
She's making herself sick
for the attention ?
In and out of psych wards
since she was 18.
Joint pain, stomach problems,
all kinds of vague symptoms,
but her tests don't back her up.
- But she wants to be treated here.
- Her mother is her medical guardian.
Under state law, if her mother wants her
back at the hospital, Rebecca goes back.
Agreed. She goes.
She's having contractions.
You want to move her now,
make her lose the baby ? Be my guest.
Why would you light a fire
under Charlotte King's ass for a 51 l50 ?
- I ought to 51 l50 your skinny...
- Rebecca is not...
Have you talked to her ? I believe her.
Münchausen. These people are
exceptional, spectacular liars.
- Take it down a notch.
- People get angry. It's normal.
- Sam is trying to help.
- Sam doesn't like conflict.
Whoa, ladies. Off topic.
I think Violet should do
a psych eval on Rebecca.
- The woman has a long history...
- Sam, do you agree with me ?
Your next patient is in room two.
- Bless you, Dell.
- Addison. Addison.
Why are you fighting so hard
for this woman ?
Since when do you give up on people ?
- I'm just trying to look out for you.
- Well, don't.
Hey, Addison. I'm coming. OK ?
Don't tell me this is because
I forgot to RSVP to your party.
Can I ask Violet
to do the psych eval or not ?
Fine.
I don't need a shrink. This is why
I didn't tell you about the psych ward.
I need you to be off your feet.
Your contractions just eased up.
If no one can figure out what's wrong
with me, they'll keep saying I'm crazy.
They'll take my baby away.
We'll do everything we can
to keep that from happening.
But we need you to help us.
Now come on.
Sit down.
Talk.
My first marriage was lonely.
You know.
I can't get stuck in another marriage
with a man who doesn't love me.
You really believe
Stan doesn't love you ?
Well, I'm not... I don't know.
He could just be using me for the sex,
I suppose.
The sex ?
We have damn good sex.
Sylvie, your first marriage...
It has nothing to do with Stan.
You know you can't let the past
hang over you like that.
Neither can you, kid.
You're not as screwed up as I am.
- You deserve better.
- But be honest, Pete.
The timing of these spells and
the proposal, pretty damning, isn't it ?
OK. I know I seem like this guy
that dates women from the Internet...
OK, I am this guy who dates women from
the Internet but that's only because...
No, scrap that. No good. OK...
You're beautiful
and you're funny and...
You're annoying, but in a way that's
endearing when it's not driving me crazy
and the point is...
The point is, I love you.
I'm in love with you
and... I have been forever.
I love you.
Were you just saying
"I love you" to your genitals ?
No.
[Door closing]
Hey.
There's... I want to talk to you.
Tell you something that I... uh...
What are you doing ?
- That's Cami's urine sample.
- You're spying on Cami's pee ?
No.
This Cami thing is eating at me. Right ?
It's really all I can think about.
So, if I were a patient,
what would I tell myself ?
That talking to yourself like
you're two people is a sign of insanity.
I would tell my patient that they need
to figure out a way to move on.
To get some information
so that they can move on.
And that relates
to Cami's bodily fluids how ?
What if Cami's pregnant ?
I mean, if I know that Cami is pregnant,
that would be a big step
in really solidifying
that it's over between me and Allan.
Do not steal that urine.
- Right. OK.
- Yeah.
All right. What did you
want to talk to me about ?
It would be better later.
No, no, no. Just tell me now. I need
to focus on something other than Cami.
It's just...
You know, I made this pact,
and there are some feelings that...
Violet !
Step away from the pee-pee.
Right, right. Right.
I am removing myself from the situation.
That went perfectly.
[Violet] Rebecca doesn't totally fit
the Münchausen profile.
Do you think
I'm personalizing this case ?
Like maybe I need to believe
in the happy miracle baby ?
Well, instinct's a bitch.
You only know if you can trust it
after the fact.
OK, look. You and I don't
know each other that well.
We're not friends.
But you could share.
I guess.
No. No, no, no. I don't want to...
Yes. Yes. Let's... share.
Yeah ?
God. It's just...
I have fertility issues.
And Naomi... I don't know.
And I'm all cranky about it
and I have a right to be. A right.
I'm right... and all.
I know. You know ?
The sharing, it's...
It's not so good.
No.
Hey, I don't even want kids.
But the idea
of my ex's new wife having one ?
- It's making me nuts.
- It's better to know. Get through it.
Naomi won't tell me anything.
Let me tell you something about Naomi.
Don't let her tell you
what you can and cannot know.
In fact, go look at the file yourself.
Yeah.
I mean, you just wait
until Dell is away from his domain...
...and then you go for it.
You go get your answers.
You're a little bit of a crazy,
you know that ?
- Yeah.
- I like you.
Michael, what happened ?
- Why'd you tell me to do that ?
- Do what ?
I knew I shouldn't have said anything.
Michael, who did this to you ?
- Brian.
- OK, who's Brian ?
He's the one I asked out.
The one I love.
Can you imagine being ten
and already knowing who you are ?
Some kids know. They just know.
This poor guy came out, got his heart
broken and his ass kicked in one day.
I got to do something.
You should do what you're doing.
You got to listen.
Stay on top of the situation.
Kids like Michael are at high risk
for self-destructive behavior.
That's usually when they're teenagers.
You think he might hurt himself now ?
It happens.
OK. OK.
I'll talk to his parents. Thanks.
Hello, closure.
I'm having them run an echo
to check for heart abnormalities
and tests to rule out artery
obstructions and seizure activities.
All these tests. You're not
doing this just for me, are you ?
I know I'm pushing for an answer, but...
As much as I adore you,
I wouldn't do that.
I'm doing it for Stan,
the guy that called me a whacko.
Pete.
Sylvie, this is Addison. She's our gyn.
- You're new.
- How do you do ?
Pete, if you get a moment later,
I could use you for a consult
on my patient's nutritional status.
At which time I'd like
an RSVP to my party.
OK.
Or you could RSVP now.
- I'll wait.
- Or I could uninvite you.
You like that one.
Don't do that. Don't mother me.
She reminds me a little of your Anna.
My wife was nothing like Addison.
Well, there are similarities,
but Addison is... tougher.
Addison doesn't need...
she doesn't need.
Which makes her seem perfect for you.
Can we focus on Stan ?
This is Cami Davis' file.
Just... I got to know. Tell me.
- I told you I wouldn't.
- But now I'm telling you to tell me.
No. I swore I wouldn't.
Well, just give me the file and then
you won't have to tell me anything.
Don't make me hurt you.
You're freaking out a little.
I am freaking out a little.
Michael's missing ?
We got home and he went to lie down.
But when I checked on him, he was gone.
I thought maybe he went to go settle
the score with those kids who hit him.
I've left him a dozen messages.
I texted him.
He usually calls right back.
Do we call the police ?
No. Let me check the school again first.
Maybe I just missed him.
- I'll check the skate park.
- Are you sure ?
- You've got patients.
- Let's... Let's just find Michael.
Come here ! I felt the baby moving.
You have to feel this.
This is Mrs. Hobart, Rebecca's mother.
The ambulance is waiting downstairs.
Get her out of here.
- Mrs. Hobart, she's had a rough day.
- You have no idea.
- You want to hear how Rebecca operates ?
- Shut up, Mom !
- Let's just take this slow.
- She starves.
Or she eats God knows what to get sick.
She dupes a hospital into believing her
till they figure out what's going on.
- Get her out of here !
- That's enough.
- OK, remember our breathing ?
- [Inhaling and exhaling slowly]
Good. Good.
What ? What is it ?
These labs show
you haven't eaten in days.
She lied.
- She has been making herself sick.
- What a shock.
No, no, I did eat !
I'll make sure
her contractions are gone.
Then she's yours.
I thought you believed me.
I did.
Oh, God.
OK. I have Stan's labs.
MRI looks good. Blood levels, good.
- All the tests check out OK.
- Thank God.
Right ?
Sylvie. You don't know... We don't know
that this has anything to do with you.
Then find me another answer.
So much for being inspired, huh ?
Oh, crap. Addison. Wait.
Wait up !
Uh... We need a little bit more time
with your daughter.
- Sam.
- Dr. Bennett, this is...
You've been through hell. And maybe
your daughter is a master manipulator.
But she risked a lot to come here
because she thought we were different.
And better.
And I believe we are.
We can figure out
what's wrong with your daughter.
- We need a little more time.
- You think...
- Sam, please don't indulge this.
- [Sam] We want to help your daughter.
That's all we ask.
OK. One hour.
You get one more hour.
Brian ?
Do you know where Michael is ?
Hey, hey, hey. Whoa.
Where's Michael ?
- He's a freak.
- He's your friend.
No, he's not ! I thought he was
until he said that stuff.
- You hit him 'cause he said something ?
- He asked me on a date !
And I bet he wishes he didn't,
but he did.
So, he's going
to have to live with that. Can you ?
He can't just go around
saying stuff like that. Not here.
- Michael's missing. I need to find him.
- He's what ?
- Do you know where he could be ?
- No.
Hey, Brian ! Come on.
There's a parking lot where we hang at.
There's a cool ramp that we skate on.
Maybe he'd go there.
I didn't mean to hit him so hard.
- Tell him I'm sorry, OK ?
- Thanks.
Sam, I appreciate
what you're trying to do,
but what can we possibly find
in an hour ?
Why did you make promises
you know we can't keep ?
Because maybe we can. OK ?
Is there anything else we need to cover
before we can get our heads in the game ?
I have a need.
I need to know why Cami is here.
- You made me promise not to tell you...
- Spill.
It's a bladder infection.
From having too much sex.
Cami and Allan
have been having a lot of sex.
Good. It's not cancer.
I was just afraid it might be cancer.
Well, it isn't.
Good. Done.
Now... Rebecca.
Michael.
I was gonna run away.
But I don't have any money.
Besides, running away is lame.
- So then I thought I'd just jump.
- Michael.
Then jumping's even lamer
than running away.
I talked to Brian.
He feels pretty bad.
Yeah, well, he doesn't love me back.
No.
Look, some kids are cool with it.
Yeah, but I don't want
to hang out with them.
I want to hang out with Brian.
I wish I was somebody else.
What are you talking about ?
I wish I was you.
- You're old.
- Yeah. I am old.
I am elderly. But you're young.
You will have a lot of chances
to fall in love again
with someone who's really into you,
big time.
And me being so old and all, right ?
I'm done.
This one, this girl, this love ?
That's probably it for me.
And I didn't have the guts
to tell her how I felt.
I looked at her, I just... I couldn't.
You told Brian.
And you're a lot braver than I am.
Damn.
You little punk.
I don't want to go home yet.
We can hang out for a while.
Then we need to tell your folks
you're OK.
I don't know. I don't...
Nothing's jumping out at me.
You're the one who believed. Why ?
Because I thought
she was telling the truth.
Ignore the files.
Ignore all preconceptions
and let's look at the facts
as if everything Rebecca has told us
is the truth.
Which would mean
that the hospital missed something.
Then she's saddled
with a psych diagnosis.
The doctors would assume
that her worsening symptoms
are just signs of destructive behavior.
That could indicate a worsening
of her real condition.
So, what's the missing illness
that started it all ?
One that makes her feel
stomach spasms and pain after she eats.
Associated with occasional
joint pains and fevers.
And comes and goes in cycles.
Did they ever get a GI camera study ?
- I didn't see it in her records.
- [Violet] How'd that help ?
The camera could get to places
in Rebecca's body
that previous work-ups couldn't
have seen. It's a new procedure.
If she had an occult form
of an autoimmune disease...
Affecting deep sections
of the intestines...
- It would flare-up in times of stress.
- She wouldn't absorb nutrients.
Explains why she says she eats,
but labs say she's not.
So they could've missed it.
- They definitely could've missed it.
- All right.
I was playing tug of war
with the wheelchair.
- Charlotte is stronger than she looks.
- They took her ?
- Rebecca's gone ?
- She's gone.
Do you know what this girl's mother will
say if she finds out I ran another test ?
What will she say if the test could save
Rebecca's life ? Hers and the baby's.
Y'all really want me to get fired,
don't you ?
If you need a win
to get the hospital off your back,
- take full credit for the fix.
- I don't care about the credit.
OK, I do care about the credit.
But I care about helping this girl more.
We'll set up for the camera study.
All right.
Something Sylvie said has me wondering.
I spoke to you in confidence.
I might know what's wrong with Stan.
- You do ?
- You two have been having a lot of sex ?
- A gentleman doesn't discuss...
- Yes.
Different positions ?
I'm not going to stand here and
get the third degree from this pervert.
Mostly one position.
Because of his sciatica, I'm on top.
- Hmm... Show me.
- Oh, for the love of... What ?
Sylvie !
He holds me here.
Supporting me on account of my hip.
OK. Good.
This is where I draw the line. I...
Stan, you OK ?
Does that happen
every time you press there ?
All that repetitive motion formed
a trigger point in the muscle,
causing a painless migraine.
You move the wrong way, you pass out.
Painless migraine ?
You get the neurological signs,
but never the headache.
And that's all it was ?
My intensive muscle therapy
should do it.
And we can treat that sciatica, so that
you can try some new sexual positions.
- He loves me.
- I told you.
Thank you, Pete.
You don't know how much this means.
Or, yes you do.
Now it's your turn.
Why are you here ? In my practice ?
Throwing your too-much-sex-itis
in my face ?
You know about that ?
There are a million other doctors
you could've gone to.
Why did you come to the place
where I work ? Just to mess with me ?
I just needed to pick up the results
of my labs.
That still doesn't answer the question !
Why here ?
He talks about you.
I mean, all of you.
How good you are.
I wanted the best.
You're here to scope me out.
I shouldn't have come, I'm sorry.
Cami.
You don't need to worry.
You're like two years old.
You're pretty,
you're the Barbie Dreamhouse.
I am not your competition. Trust me.
I wouldn't be so sure.
We've got the results.
- And ?
- You have Crohn's disease.
You were eating
and it was making you sick.
So you believe me ?
- I believe you.
- You believe me.
You believe me.
The chances of your baby being healthy
are very good.
I'm sorry.
[Both crying]
[Naomi] Hey. Hey.
- How did it go ? How's Rebecca ?
- Dr. Sam hasn't lost his touch.
You ? I'm the one...
Fine. Dr. Sam is a god. Today.
- Do you want some wine ?
- You guys are hanging out here ?
Yeah, we have red and I can get
some white from the fridge.
You know, no. Wait. No.
I got food.
I bought a barbecue grill.
I dragged bags of ice across the beach !
And I invited all of you people and none
of you even bothered to RSVP
because your lives
are so busy and great,
and yet here you sit drinking wine
in the lobby like animals.
- We're coming.
- [Pete] Yeah.
We were waiting for you guys
to get back from the hospital.
Oh...
I... Well then...
[ ? The Thrills :
There's Joy to be Found]
There's no way she's right.
He is not thinking about me.
Of course he's thinking about you,
are you an idiot ?
- You don't have to be mean about it.
- Well, you're hard to forget.
Cooper.
What, I'm just saying, you are very
loud, you have a lot of curly hair...
Boys.
OK. You have been pissed off
at me all day.
I was wrong about Rebecca. I'm sorry.
Why'd you tell me that there was no hope
for me to ever have a baby ?
- Because...
- I have two eggs left. Two.
I looked at my chart. Why didn't you
tell me that my FSH was borderline ?
It means there's still a chance.
Didn't want you hanging on to something
that'll probably never happen.
You need to stop protecting me.
You don't get to decide
what I hang on to.
What, and Sam with his mindlbody thing ?
He inspired you to look again,
to ask for more ?
That's his thing now.
Yeah.
It made me feel like... there's hope.
That I'm not alone.
You think you're alone ?
Look around.
Hey. What you all talking about ?
Oh, a strong, proud bald man.
- It really is just an arm and a hammer.
- Let it go, Sam.
Please. Please.