Clear!
Charging. Clear!
Okay, I'm calling it.
Time of death, 8:32.
Hello, Diana. Shall we?
LV tear's within a zone
of fresh tissue necrosis,
implicating recent myocardial
infarction as the instigating event.
Unfortunately, the medical
records show that Dr. Penza
never suspected heart disease,
instead, giving steroids for an
erroneous diagnosis of asthma,
thereby causing the fatal tear.
I suggest these findings
warrant further investigation
into Dr. Penza's standard
of care for this patient,
making this my third such recommendation
regarding Dr. Penza this year.
Concluding autopsy with
examination of the brain.
Dr. Treiber?
I'm cold.
Yes, it's mine.
And, yes, I know
that I can't drive stick.
And, no, I don't care that I
parked in a handicap spot.
"Staring death in the face has
changed my life." What a cliché.
The cliché is to lead
a more meaningful life.
I've taken a holy vow to
lead a less meaningful one.
I've spent my
life caring, giving,
and searching for the profound.
Now it's time for selfishness,
indifference, and embracing the shallow.
Your scan's in three days.
Tell me this isn't
just you killing time
until you find out if your
cancer's gonna kill it for you?
I just paid $75,000 for a
ridiculously impractical car,
the depth of shallowness.
And tomorrow, I'm driving it to
Cleveland to meet my boyhood crush.
The years have not been
kind to David Cassidy.
Julie Christie, Doctor Zhivago,
Shampoo. I was precocious.
She's opening some kind of
charity animal clinic, or something.
I'm neglecting my patients
to fulfill a silly fantasy.
Textbook selfishness
and indifference.
Or you've made
sure that your patients
are well covered,
the car is a rental,
and while waiting to get Julie
Christie's autograph, you'll adopt a puppy.
I don't even care whether
you believe me or not.
Indifference.
He tried to cut
open his own skull.
Head CT and tox
screen were clean.
Interesting.
Cotard delusion. Also known
as Walking Corpse Syndrome.
A disconnect in the amygdala
convinces you that
you're secretly dead.
Case solved, rendering it...
What's the past
tense of "interesting"?
No prior history
of mental illness,
and before you say it was caused by
antivirals, I've already ruled that out.
Plus Cotard's doesn't explain
the paresthesia in his hand.
Also, Treiber won't let
any other doctor near him.
He trusts your work.
Treiber's the patient?
What's the future
tense of "interesting"?
How's Wilson doing? Wilson's
scan is at the end of the week.
If his kickass chemo
shrunk the tumor
to an operable size, he'll live.
If it didn't, he'll die.
That must be very hard. Is
there anything we can do?
Other than the prayer
circle, what is there?
Patient's AST is high.
Psychosis could be
brought on by liver failure.
Maybe Hep C?
Bilirubin and serum
protein levels were normal.
It doesn't explain the tingly
hand or why Chase hates him.
I don't hate him, he hates me.
He hates all doctors.
And it's mutual.
He only hates the
ones that screw up.
And you.
And they only hate Treiber
because he finds their mistakes.
Mistakes are a wee bit
easier to find on a dead patient.
A distinction he fails
to recognize. He's a rat.
Who makes the
hospital a safer place
by keeping doctors
accountable and focused.
What if he got something
from a cadaver?
He handles a lot of them.
You suggesting we DDx them all?
No, just his last one.
She had bad knees.
If she used dimethyl
sulfoxide for joint pain,
current from the defibrillator could've
converted it to dimethyl sulfate.
When Treiber cut into her,
her blood released toxic fumes.
Everyone in the
basement would be sick.
Well, gas would've
dissipated quickly.
His lungs are fine.
Blood clots make more sense.
One in his hand
explains the paresthesia,
one in his carotid explains
the psychotic episode.
You two look for toxic exposure.
Adams, you can
help Chase ultrasound
his evil nemesis for evil clots.
I know House doesn't
like seeing his patients,
but doesn't a fellow
doctor rate an exception?
Psychosis appears
to be intermittent.
Just snapped out of
it long enough to ask
if House actually
ordered this test.
Don't worry, we're simply
carrying out his direct orders.
Right, I forgot. That's
what you were hired to do.
Which is fine. His
diagnostic error metric is .17,
compared to the
hospital average of .32.
You actually think you can
quantify the value of every doctor?
Someone should.
And since I'm the only
one who sees everything...
Right. You were hired to diagnose
people after they're already dead.
No sign of stenosis or clots.
Every doctor, every diagnosis,
every treatment, every result.
It's pretty impressive.
It's pretty Orwellian.
All written in his secret code.
He has to keep it confidential.
Just like the
Wannsee Conference?
The Big Brother metaphor
wasn't pointed enough for you?
You had to throw in Hitler?
A couple years ago, he
noticed a link in child deaths,
and it's completely changed
hospital policies on...
I get it, Treiber is nerd king.
The more people we kill,
the more lives he saves.
Test is negative for dimethyl
sulfate. Her blood is not toxic.
Then we should look for toxic
exposures from something else.
You really think the hospital is
idiotic enough to issue toxic supplies?
Have you seen his tools?
Treiber doesn't always
use "hospital issue".
Then he's the idiot?
No, but I don't want to explain
that assumption to House.
Found something.
Thought we'd
make it a road trip.
'80s music, junk food, beer.
I have a dental appointment.
That I'm going to make now.
Ah... I'll let you drive.
Not worth listening
to you whine about
your feelings and
fears for three days.
It's not gonna happen.
I've taken a vow.
People don't change.
You're a person.
Ergo, pass.
Yes, that's why I brought
this. 20ccs of propofol.
You can accompany me willingly,
or I will, when you least expect it,
inject the contents of this
vial into your bloodstream.
The fall might result in a
concussion, or fractures,
or you might get lucky,
and simply wake up somewhere
near Allentown with a nasty headache.
The choice is yours, and
in case you've forgotten,
I am indifferent.
We leave tomorrow
morning at 8:00 a.m.
No clots.
No gas.
But we found enough of this
to reanimate the entire morgue.
He's jacked on caffeine.
Stimulant psychosis.
How many times do I
have to solve this case?
So all we have to do is hydrate
and observe him for 24 hours?
Why don't you tell him it was your
idea? He might warm up to you.
If you get an ear in the
mail, it's probably mine.
My Abdomen! It's my abdomen!
It's just the effects of
withdrawal. The pain is normal.
No. No, this isn't right.
Abdominal pain and
distension means
we were wrong about
stimulant psychosis.
They could be
coexistent problems.
He might just
have an obstruction.
You know what House
says about coincidences.
I didn't feel any masses when I
examined him, and no bowel sounds.
Where's House?
He hasn't come in yet.
And neither has Wilson. I've
already tried him three times.
Here we go again.
Diabetes could cause nerve
damage in his hand and gut, and...
Except his glucose
levels are normal
and he probably would've
mentioned he was a diabetic.
What about ulcerative colitis?
Earlier attacks
caused thrombosis...
We already looked for clots,
and there was no
blood in his stool.
Try him again.
And Wilson's.
Wherever they are, they
don't want to be disturbed.
If we take 78,
we can do the Sweet Treats
& Salty Eats Snack Food Trail.
My trip, my itinerary.
We have to cover 300 miles today
to be there with plenty of time
to catch Julie by 4:00 tomorrow.
And that thing I said about
letting you drive? I lied.
What?
I'm impressed.
Not by that, but by your real
effort to maintain the façade.
It's been almost an hour and there's
been no mention of the elephant in the car.
Well, I declined
the elephant option.
Uh-huh.
In three days, you're gonna
find out if you live or die.
You don't want to talk about it?
No, but obviously you do.
So we're gonna talk about
it, but because I want to?
I am neither talking about it
nor talking about
not talking about it.
You are hard-wired
to talk about it.
It's how you cope,
it's who you are.
Yeah, well, from now
on, I am not me. I'm...
I'm Kyle Calloway.
I thought your porn
name was Rusty Packard.
Kyle is roguish, carefree, and
shares no qualities with James Wilson.
Can Kyle drive stick?
Treiber won't let us do
anything without House.
House just took
himself off the case.
You said no bowel sounds
when you examined him.
No, like "diminished",
or "none at all"? None.
You think it's an
intussusception?
If it is, it could mean
cancer's behind everything.
Let's get a plain
film of his abdomen.
Treiber will refuse
any procedure
that wasn't ordered by House.
Only if he knows it wasn't.
You want to lie to a guy whose
favorite pastime is getting doctors fired?
We're adults with
advanced medical training,
not children left
alone with scissors.
It's one X-ray.
If we had a phone, we could've
found somewhere a little less charming.
If we had a phone,
you'd be making calls,
downloading porn and
playing Angry Birds.
This trip is about me,
and I like this place.
It's not about you not
wanting me to have a phone.
You're weak.
You knew that you'd backslide
and spend your time
talking to teary ex-wives,
and your parents.
Trying to make them feel
better about you being sick.
Bacon burger with fries
looks awful. I'll have that.
I'll have The Big One.
You sure? It's $79.
Unless I finish it in an
hour, in which case, it's free.
It's an 80 ounce steak.
I'm hungry.
And an iced tea, please.
Big One's up!
This place doesn't
take credit cards.
My meal is going to be free,
and I'm going to be
inducted into the Wall of Pain.
Hello, Kyle.
No! Belly film was normal.
No sign of an intussusception
or any other obstruction.
House says it's there?
Sometimes House is wrong.
Run my bowel.
That's serious surgery. General
anesthesia, long recovery...
We can do a contrast
enema if you need more proof.
I have drawers filled with
people who had clean scans.
I know how easy it
is to miss something
unless you use your
own hands and eyes.
Run my bowel. We'll let
House know how you feel.
How I feel is twisted
in white, hot agony.
His orders were to look
for an intussusception.
Until you actually do that,
I refuse any other tests.
Fine.
No, not fine!
We need to talk... And I
want you to do the surgery.
Statistically, you're the
best surgeon in the hospital.
Kyle! Kyle!
Come on, you got this!
You got this! Come on!
Twenty five seconds.
You got this!
Come on! Home stretch,
Kyle! Home stretch!
Fifteen seconds!
Kyle! Kyle! Kyle! Kyle!
No, don't chew! Just swallow!
Just keep the meat down.
- Six...
five, four... ALL: Five, four...
For the love of God,
swallow! three, two, one!
Time!
Yes! Yes!
Yes! Oh, you
magnificent bastard.
Smile!
It still counts, though, right?
No hard feelings, right?
You'll find out
when you wake up.
If you really think
I'm a good doctor,
why do you treat
me like an idiot?
It's not because
you lack talent.
It's because you've wasted it.
Did you know I applied to be a fellow
with House the same year as you?
No.
I quit my other program,
relocated, broke
up with my girlfriend.
Then your father made a call
and, suddenly, you had the spot.
That was almost 10 years ago.
Do you know what I could've done
after even three
years with House?
Gone to the CDC, WHO,
started a diagnostics
department some place
they'd never even
heard of such a thing.
You've been given everything.
Looks, talent, my future.
Nine years later,
look what you've done with it.
Ugh!
Must be nice to be puking
for the old-fashioned reasons.
I'm glad I did it.
You see those people
out there cheering for me?
I was a hero.
For one fleeting moment,
for an incredibly stupid reason,
for a bunch of morons
I'll never see again.
God, it felt good.
And now if you'll excuse me,
I think I've made
room for dessert.
How long do you think
you'll work for House?
As long as he lets me.
When House was in prison, you
worked at Mercy, in plastics, right?
Know what I did? Surfed.
For nine months. Yes.
And if I didn't have two
daughters and alimony,
I might have done the same.
A fellowship's supposed to
train you to stand on your own.
Foreman's dean of the hospital,
Cameron's head of
emergency medicine in Chicago.
And Kutner and Amber are dead,
and Thirteen's having sweet
Sapphic sex on some island.
Look at this, in
his small intestine.
Is it an intussusception?
No.
Guess Treiber was right.
He hasn't checked his voicemail.
Or his email.
It's been almost 24 hours, shouldn't
we call Foreman, or the police?
I think this makes
him a fugitive.
We don't have to tell anyone.
Treiber's symptoms
started in his frontal lobe
and moved through
his nervous system.
Hands, bowels, muscles.
Intermittent porphyria.
He's in the middle of an attack.
The longer we wait to treat with
haemin, the more damage it causes.
The longer we wait to tell him
House isn't running the case,
the more damage
that causes. It's fraud.
It's only an issue
if we're wrong.
It's more than one X-ray,
more than exploratory
surgery even.
This is a drug that will
damage him if you're wrong.
Same principle.
I want a threesome.
Shouldn't we try
a twosome first?
Two women. Oh.
I know they're
probably overrated,
and I'll probably be
gravely disappointed,
but I want one anyway.
No, you don't.
Well, Kyle wants one.
Kyle's only one day old. He
doesn't know what he wants.
I don't want to think
about consequences.
I don't want to think about...
I don't want to think about
anything, I just wanna do.
Okay. I need you to do
exactly what I tell you.
Yeah, yeah.
Porphyria?
I know the anesthesia
makes it hard to focus,
but we need to start
you on haemin right away.
House believes very
strongly this is the right call.
Okay.
This thing is peeling.
Well, that is the
cost of cowardice.
Should've gone
for the real thing.
I feel like I'm cheating.
"A", it is only cheating
if you don't have cancer,
and "B", it's Wednesday
afternoon. Pickings are slim.
And more importantly, sober.
The cancer cut is the surest
way to the pity-pooty party.
One down, one to go.
What? Wait, wait, what?
She said yes? To a threesome?
She's empathetic.
She's a hooker.
Gave me a cancer rate.
No, I have never
paid for sex in my life.
You still haven't.
It's my treat.
It's either that or you find
two very open-minded women
to fall in love with
you in the next hour.
Bartender seems nice.
She seems female.
Want something to eat?
My friend is dying of cancer.
God, you poor thing.
It took my mother two years ago.
But you can't give up hope.
He's pretty much resigned.
Just wants to go out with a bang.
And another pun, what
time do you get off?
Pleural effusions.
It's not porphyria.
We're gonna need
to put in a chest tube.
I want Dr. House.
We'll tell him exactly...
I wanna talk to him!
I want House! Where is House?
Where is he? Where's House?
We don't know.
You didn't have
to sleep out here.
Four's a crowd.
Apparently they
left a long time ago.
So, how was it? Was the
amateur as good as the pro?
It was confusing,
perfunctory, and a bit sad.
Never mind.
And exactly what I needed.
Thank you.
You feel like buying
me breakfast?
One of them stole my wallet.
You're lucky he's
not pressing charges.
Porphyria was a legitimate call.
Until the pleural effusions.
We've done everything House
would have if he'd been here.
You lied to a patient.
Treiber's condition
is declining rapidly.
He's agreed to let
me take over the case.
Dr. Chase will have no
further contact with the patient.
Fine. I didn't say
you were off the case!
Sit down.
I ordered a cardiac MRI,
enlargement of the left ventricle
suggests an infiltrative disease.
It's sarcoidosis.
We could start him
on corticosteroids
and do a cardiac
biopsy to confirm.
I disagree.
I was wrong about the porphyria,
but I wasn't wrong
about the nervous system.
It's a prion disease.
That's why his symptoms
have progressed so rapidly.
It's possible he was
exposed and didn't know it.
Brains are often stored and not
tested until weeks after autopsy.
Treiber's too good to not
take the right precautions.
Maybe the problem is
he thinks the same thing.
His job's built on the premise
that doctors make mistakes.
That includes him.
We should do a brain
biopsy. In his condition?
Then we biopsy the
brains in the morgue.
Find the one that exposed him.
It's a needle in a haystack.
There's four of us.
Come on, we can
at least start him
on amphotericin
to halt the progress
while you do your heart biopsy.
No, we can't. Amphotericin plus
the contrast dye for the biopsy
would overwhelm his kidneys.
We have to choose one or the other.
Biopsy his heart.
Wallets go in the
minibar freezer.
If there's no minibar, the toilet
tank. I've got exactly $20 left.
I'm sorry, I wasn't familiar
with hooker protocol.
We could use your credit cards.
No, we won't. I'm
still on probation.
Leaving the state without
permission will really P.O. my P.O.
Doesn't matter.
We can't even afford
gas to get home.
And we're three
hours behind schedule.
We have enough
gas to get to Julie.
I don't care about
anything else.
What this time?
Just wondering how
long this can last.
You're still hoping that I'm
gonna wake up and admit
that Kyle Calloway is
just some lame excuse
to have some naughty
thrills, aren't you?
I'm actually hoping you won't.
I like Kyle.
Oh, come on!
Whoo!
Whoa! Whoa!
House!
You okay?
My leg still hurts.
Come on!
We got 20 bucks to go 11 miles.
Why aren't you
answering your pages?
I'm busy.
The biopsy showed
fibrosis in his cardiac muscle.
So it's not a prion disease.
It means Foreman was wrong, too.
He wants everyone to
meet in his office to DDx.
So he can tell us
all it's an infection?
Interesting, or maybe you should
consider not being such a baby.
My first instinct was an
exposure from a corpse.
Treiber spends
all his time here.
If it's not toxic
gas, or prions,
then it has to be something
else. He's not perfect.
Are you trying to cure
him or discredit him?
Treiber can only see me as
"Not House", Foreman, too.
And they're not wrong.
So you're not coming upstairs?
No. And when this
case is over, I'm quitting.
He's not quitting.
He already called
other hospitals.
Treiber did get under his skin.
He'll get over it.
Fibrosis has to be a
response to an infection.
Chase said you'd say that.
We'll test the biopsy
samples for viruses,
and start him on anti-virals.
You're not even
going to talk to Chase?
He didn't leave after he
got stabbed in the heart.
I think we're okay.
Either you're right, and
your friend is just really upset,
or you're wrong, and he's
come at this calmly and rationally,
and you're about to lose a
good doctor. Either way...
This is Oubliette, Ohio.
Buses don't run here after 1968.
Ina said there's a
bus every 15 minutes.
Ina is living in
Alzheimersville.
Been here at least half an hour.
Where are you going, Ina?
Naples, Florida.
Ben and I have a beautiful
three-bedroom condo, all on the one floor.
You're waiting for
a bus to Naples?
Comes every 15 minutes. Ben'll
be wondering where his dinner is.
Cab.
Whoa! Cab!
20 bucks, 11 miles. Come on!
Come on, let's go.
Julie is gonna be at the clinic
for another 45 minutes,
we can make this!
She thinks she's in Florida.
Okay. Bring her with.
I'm waiting for the bus.
Bus isn't coming, Ina.
But this cab is going to Naples.
Ben'll be getting
awfully hungry. House.
We'll tell the cabbie
to call the cops.
They'll come pick her
up. Take care of her.
Then I'll stay with
her until they do.
Goodbye, Kyle.
Bus comes every 15 minutes.
Oh, shut up.
Find anything?
Not yet.
Running tests for MRSA.
You've got everybody
worried about you quitting.
You here as my
boss or my friend?
If I was here as your boss,
you'd be suspended by now.
I've learnt a lot here.
Enough to run my own team.
It's time I moved on.
Unfortunately, that's how I felt
last year, and the year before that.
Maybe there's a
reason you haven't left.
You need structure and support.
Somebody else calling the shots.
You didn't come down
here as my boss or my friend.
You came down as House.
You're trying to insult me
into making a decision?
We've both seen it work.
Either you rise to the
challenge and quit,
or you stay
as a team member.
Dr. Treiber! Dr. Treiber!
He stopped responding when
I was changing his IV bag.
Peter, open your eyes.
Coma.
Treiber's comatose.
All brains on deck.
Where should we start?
We think you might be right.
I'm not.
You couldn't have
gone through all of these.
Don't have to.
Treiber's reports are thorough to
a fault, his methods are fastidious.
The answer isn't down here.
Treiber didn't miss
anything, we did.
So what? Psychosis,
abdominal pain,
pleural effusions,
enlarged heart, coma.
Autoimmune, maybe
Goodpasture's. Kidneys are fine.
Vasculitis? No fever.
Lymphoma? Would've
seen it on the heart biopsy.
Soap. It's the soap.
I blew it.
Oh, God, here it comes.
As always. All I wanted
was some meaningless fun,
and I couldn't even
last three days.
Sound asleep! I'm sleep talking.
I had the chance to
fulfill a lifelong dream.
I swear I will jump out of this
moving bus if you don't shut up.
But instead, I sat with a sad,
old woman for an hour and a half
who forgot I existed three
seconds after she left.
And the stupidest thing?
I never even had a
crush on Julie Christie.
In 12th grade, I was madly
in love with Melanie Robbins
who happened to look exactly
like Julie Christie in Doctor Zhivago.
And she really liked me.
We played spades every lunch
period in Mr. Charlton's classroom.
But, of course, there
was this other guy.
A great guy, very popular.
He had a car, he had
a band, a moustache...
Kyle Calloway.
I assumed that...
I hoped that we would go
to the senior prom together.
But she asked me for a favor.
She asked if I minded if she went
with him. She asked me if I minded.
And I said I didn't.
And that was it.
And I just did it again.
I let it go, like I
let everything go.
And here I am,
sitting on this bus,
with tickets I bought
with my watch,
heading back home,
so a CT scan can decide my fate.
I don't want to go back, House.
I just...
I just want to keep being Kyle.
Kyle would've ditched that sad,
old woman from the bus stop.
He probably would've
ditched me, too.
I can live without Kyle.
Sno Ball?
Guess this isn't heaven.
We found out who screwed up.
You.
It was your industrial
strength antibacterial soap.
The additional triclosan
does two things well.
Kills MRSA, and makes
your thyroid look stupid.
It thinks the triclosan is a real
hormone and closes up shop.
Excessive use over time,
combined with excessive use of this,
led to hyperthyroidism,
which went undiagnosed
until it presented with psychosis.
When the ER put
you on sedatives,
it kicked you into
myxedema crisis.
Don't know that I ever
would have thought of that.
House taught us
to look for irony.
Hey.
This wasn't House.
My locker key.
I'll give you your own team.
Thanks.
But it's time to step
out of the shadow.
It's about time.
Any news?
Not yet.
You come here so I
can talk you out of it?
I came to say thank you.
It's been fun.
"Fun"?
Sounded pithier than, "We've
shared a variety of situations".
Let me know about Wilson.
Why did you let him go?
Legal loophole, 13th amendment.
Abraham Lincoln may
have looked great in that hat,
but his labor policies...
House?