Previously, on Grey's Anatomy...
The person that beat up
DeLuca is someone I thought
you left behind years
ago. You're a good doctor!
You're exactly what we
need right now in the clinic.
- The Denny Duquette Clinic?
- Unless you want me to fire you.
I took a pregnancy
test last night.
And, as I sat there
waiting for the result,
I just watched him get
more and more excited.
And when that
stick was negative...
Owen's heart broke.
And... I was so relieved.
Now look me in the eye and
tell me that he won't hate me.
Have you met the new
resident? She is great.
- This is...
- Murphy!
Dr. Robbins.
- You guys know each other?
- Um...
Yes.
Why would a Leah Murphy fail
here, only to thrive somewhere else?
There is a fundamental flaw in
how we are teaching our residents.
And we have got to fix this.
- You and me.
- And Dr. Webber.
The residency program is
your husband's department.
I know it is.
"If it ain't broke,
don't fix it."
- She's coming today?
- Mm-hmm. She is.
The saying's as true
of the human body
as it is of a washing
machine or a blender.
What did you tell the staff?
I sent them an
e-mail, let them know
that she'll be at the
hospital for a couple of days.
That she would be
here to observe. Assess.
At this point, that's all
she'd be doing anyway.
Good. Smart. No need to give
anyone a scare. Not until we know more.
A good surgeon knows that
if you go screwing around
with something that
doesn't need screwing...
This is the right call?
This is the right call.
You're the one who is
liable to end up screwed.
I'm saying you wouldn't be
late if we didn't stop for gas.
We wouldn't have had to stop
if you ever put gas in the car.
The light wasn't
even blinking yet.
When the light is blinking,
it's already too late.
Who stops for gas
before the light blinks?
And I'm late.
- Have a good day.
- Yeah.
I know. I have to
talk to him, and I will.
But I haven't yet, so you don't
have to look at me like that.
I was just looking at my phone.
- Everything's fine with me
and Owen.
- Oh, yeah, it sounds great.
It's absolutely fine.
We're gonna be married for a
long time, so the baby conversation
can sit on the back
burner for a while,
and it'll be fine
because it... It's fine.
You just said, "It's
fine," a lot of times.
Hey. Did you guys
see this e-mail?
What e-mail?
"An education
consultant is making a visit
"to observe and
assess our program"?
Who is Dr. Eliza Minnick?
Wouldn't know. I
didn't get the e-mail.
Education consultant,
double board-certified,
sports medicine specialist.
Published 52 papers in the
Journal of Surgical Education. 52?
This is because of me, isn't it?
They're gonna overhaul the
program because I beat up DeLuca.
Everything isn't about you.
That doesn't even make sense.
A teacher beat up a student.
Oh.
That makes sense.
The e-mail makes it sound like she's just
gonna wander around and wander away.
Well, yeah, Bailey's
not gonna BCC
a mass-firing announcement
to the entire staff. People panic.
- Why would you say that?
- You serious?
Minnick's kind of a legend.
I know a guy at Foster who
dated a girl at Innsmouth
when she was doing their
program's makeover. Heads rolled.
Warren, you seriously
know nothing about this?
Mm. I've told you, Miranda
and I keep it real separated.
I don't want to hear that.
Your marriage can be adorable
on a different day, okay?
You need to get answers.
This is probably happening
'cause of you, anyway.
What's that supposed to mean?
You really think a
resident does a C-section
in the middle of the hallway
and everyone forgets about it?
Dr. Webber.
Dr. Webber, is this because of
me? Because of my trouble last year?
Look, it's none of
my business, but...
I just hate to think that people
might get fired because of me.
Warren, no one's getting fired,
I don't know where you got
that, but don't worry, okay?
- This is not about you.
- Good, 'cause I just...
Well, the aortic stenosis
doesn't look too severe.
- A valvuloplasty might...
- Did you get anything
out of you mom?
I got called a "Nosey Rosie"
and then she changed the subject.
Oh, did you see Minnick's
TED Med talk, though?
- I think she's fascinating.
- We'll see how fascinating
she is
when she starts
handing out pink slips.
I'm safe, because there's only a
handful of people in this country
who can do what I do,
unlike cardio surgeons.
Well, you know what they
say. "Last one in, first one out."
Well, that's not how
it happened on D-Day.
Ain't nobody safe
on the battlefield.
That's not ominous at all.
I just don't know why you
wouldn't discuss it with me.
I'm sorry. Look, she had
an opening in her schedule,
and I jumped at it. It
happened very fast.
Yeah, too fast to tell
the Residency Director.
You got these people worried.
I don't know what to tell them
because you didn't
keep me in the loop.
Oh, no one should worry.
Dr. Minnick is here to...
look around,
observe. That's... all.
Just to see if there's
anything we could do better.
All right.
When she arrives, I probably
should be the first to meet her.
She and I could chat,
I can show her around,
- introduce her to people.
- That's gonna be a problem.
She's already here.
Well, if she is in there
with my residents,
I'm not missing any more
of this meeting than I have to.
- You will be missing all of it!
- Look, Bailey...
No, she asked to speak
to the residents alone.
Whatever she needs, she
gets. You will leave them be.
Please.
So... I work with
attending surgeons.
I train attendings to train
you, and the best way
I know how to do that is to
hear from you about them.
I would love to get just a
clearer picture of the hours.
The instructors. Who
you love, who you hate.
I want to hear it.
- Shoot.
- Sorry, but you're here
for two days.
- We have to work with them.
- I get that. You have to ask
if that's the best path to
take to get to what you want,
which, I assume, is to
be able to stand in an OR
and confidently, seamlessly
perform a flawless solo surgery
not tomorrow, not next
year, not two years from now,
but today, right now,
without hesitation,
because that's what I'm
offering. A chance to do that.
And don't worry.
This room is a vault.
Nothing leaves these walls.
Look at them all lined up for
her, like little ducks quacking.
Yeah, you ever see
that movie The Birds?
Is that Minnick? What
are they telling her?
I don't know, but
she's taking notes.
April, you're on Tinder?
- What? No. No, I'm not.
- Yes, you are!
That's the Tinder bing.
The "I've got a match" bing.
I love that bing.
- Really?
- Yes, okay?
It was, an impulse decision,
and now it keeps making noise.
I would kill to know what
they're talking about in there.
Well, I think they're
talking about us.
- Why?
- 'Cause they're looking at us.
Scatter!
Well, Doc, how soon can
Enid be back on the lanes?
She's missed league
night three weeks running.
We're in a bowling league,
some of us ladies from the home.
- The Gutter Girlz... with a "Z."
- I see.
And regionals are next month,
and we've just got to
get her back in the lineup
if we're gonna take
down those Ball Bellz.
Dr. DeLuca, glad
you could join us.
- Meeting run long?
- Yeah. Sorry.
Well, Enid, it looks
like your gallbladder
is definitely inflamed. I'd
opt for surgery if I were you.
- Surgery? Really?
- Well, it's pretty non-invasive.
We'll have you back in your
bowling shoes in a couple weeks.
- If you think that's right.
- Are you kidding? That's perfect.
Well, those Ball Bell hags
won't know what hit them.
Given your age, Enid, though, we'd
need to do a cardiac assessment,
and after that,
you'll be ready to roll.
You know best, Doc.
- So, how was your meeting?
- Yeah, just, uh, interesting.
Okay. Interesting...?
Kind of...
confidential, I guess.
Yes, of course, but I've been
known to keep a secret or two.
Well...
Nobody would know it
came from you, is my point.
- Get outta here.
- Thank you, sir.
Hold still, Mr. Lawson.
That's great.
There's free fluid in Morison's
pouch and around the spleen.
I told him not to
try to do it himself.
You want to install insulation,
you pay someone who is
professionally not a moron.
Those guys are a racket.
- Owen, I need to get in here.
- Well, I'm in here right now.
And why do we need
insulation in the first place?
It saves 30 cents on the dollar.
He complained of severe
back pain, Dr. Hunt.
I need spine films now.
Now we're in the ER. Factor that
into your figures, Uncle Scrooge.
Spine films won't help if I
miss a liver lac, Dr. Shepherd.
Emmett, any idea
how far you fell?
You mean when he
crashed through the ceiling
or when he rolled down
the stairs afterwards?
Don't you dare hire
someone to fix that ceiling.
- I'll do it.
- You? Emmett, you are broken.
Yeah, he very well might be.
Mrs. Lawson, maybe
you should wait outside.
- Right this way.
- You brought this on yourself.
Endocutter.
- Hi.
- Hey, Dr. Grey.
Dr. Bailey said I could
observe some surgeries today.
My surgery? You won't
even know I'm here.
Okay, Warren, I'm
gonna use the stay suture
to approximate the two
ends of the small bowel
and then insert the
Endo GIA and fire it.
Hmm.
"Hmm"? Do you
have a better idea?
I just wonder if Dr. Warren
could do the anastomosis.
I assume you've used
the GIA before, Dr. Warren.
Many times.
Never on a portion of the bowel
this close to the cecal valve,
- which is why you'll
watch me do it. Ah.
See one, do one, teach
one. The old standard.
Oh, It's still pretty current.
Seventy-two hour shifts were
pretty current, too, until they weren't.
But the mandatory
80-hour work week
has ultimately saved
more lives than it's harmed.
- Wouldn't you say, Dr. Grey?
- Sure.
Most people
resisted it, too, at first.
I know it sounds crazy,
letting the resident dive in,
but wouldn't you rather
know that your surgical assist
can actually assist?
If a patient goes south, who's
more likely to save them?
A resident with less
hands-on experience, or more?
Closing the enterotomies.
Ligaclip, please.
Or you could hand the
instrument to Dr. Warren.
Give him a shot. Ever
used it before, Warren?
Next time you decide to
send a watchdog into my OR
with opinions about
how I do my surgeries,
- do me a favor. Don't.
- I beg your pardon?
Minnick barged into my
bowel resection, uninvited,
then she wouldn't stop talking.
Listen, Bailey brought
her in, I'm trying to talk...
- You got to get her out of here.
- Okay, my understanding?
She's not gonna
be here that long.
I don't really care.
You are the director of
the residency program,
so direct her. To the door.
- Okay, why are we in the clinic?
- The hospital has eyes.
Whatever it is,
just make it quick.
No residents this morning
screwed up my schedule.
Look, I found this.
It's Minnick's notebook.
It's not so much her notebook
as it is a notebook that
she wrote in and left behind.
- Stealer.
- You can't be in here.
I get in trouble
when you're in here.
- Shut the door.
- No, get out!
- All right, no problem.
- No. Just hold on. Look. It's a list.
The attendings' names,
ranked. The residents sold us out.
What? Where am I on it?
I don't know, but I'm
at the bottom of the list.
I have never been at the
bottom of any teacher's list.
- I am a top-of-the-list person.
- Turns out, so am I. Look at that.
- I'm not even on there.
- So what? Neither am I.
Well, of course you're not.
Because you're not...
You work in the clinic
now, and you're not...
- Nope. No more. Get out.
- Maggie, you paged?
Yeah, Minnick ranked
the attendings in order.
- There's a list.
- Guess where I am.
That's it? I have a patient
with a possible spinal fracture.
You paged me
"911" to look at a list?
At least you're on it.
Who the heck is Emilio Shepherd?
- Hey, Edwards, do you do Tinder?
- I have.
-Do you know how
to turn the sound off?
- You got a lot of matches.
- I know.
Hey, when you swipe them
away, they don't see that, right?
It's not like they get the
message, "No. Rejected."
They get the message
'cause they get no message.
- And you are silent.
- Thank you.
Except this guy
wants to go for a drink.
God. What do I say?
If it were me, I'd
say yes. He's cute.
- Hey.
- Whoa! Hello.
- What's up?
- Hi.
There's early impingement
of the spinal cord, Owen.
- I need to do a spinal fusion.
- You see this?
There is air under the diaphragm.
I need to take him for an ex-lap.
Why? He's
hemodynamically stable.
Because I stabilized him, and I
need to make sure he stays that way.
- Is that Dr. Shepherd?
- Yeah, that's her.
- He needs
his fracture stabilized.
- Oh, that's why I'm here.
Hey, guys. Eliza
Minnick, from the e-mail.
I was actually hoping to
observe that spinal fusion.
Tough luck, it's
gonna be an ex-lap.
- You don't have
to be rude.
- I'm not being rude!
I just want to make sure
that my patient stays alive.
You made it worse. I didn't
think it could get worse.
- I'll come back.
- Mm-hmm.
The ex-lap is not
the priority. It is.
We'll slowly increase the speed
and see how your heart does, okay?
How long do I do this?
Just a few minutes. Make
sure you hold on to the rail.
Lulu, you don't
have to do this at all!
You think I'm gonna let her get
in 10,000 steps today before me?
- Not a chance.
- It's just like at the mall.
You can't stop for a pretzel
till we hit all our steps.
But it's a little less fun
without the promise of a pretzel.
What do you mean, she's made a
list? She's only been here half a minute.
Riggs is ranked higher
than I am, and I'm his boss.
You need to get
that out of your head.
She hasn't even met you.
Where you might fall on
some crackpot's nonsense list
doesn't matter one iota.
Was I on that list?
Hey, Enid, are you okay?
Honey, you don't look right.
I don't know.
- Dr. Webber?
- Enid?
Enid, honey, you okay?
Murphy, gurney,
crash cart right now.
- Oxygen!
- All right, Enid, we've got you.
Hey, you ready
to get out of here?
I'm actually gonna stay here
tonight. He has a spinal surgery.
In the morning.
Yeah, I need to make
sure he doesn't develop
progressive neuro deficits
in the middle of the night
since you had to
do your surgery first.
Oh. So it's my fault.
Well, I'm saying if I had gone
first, I would be going home.
Yes, there'd be nothing left
to do because he'd be dead.
- Unlikely.
- Amelia, Edwards can keep
an eye on him.
If something happens, he would
be paralyzed before I got here.
All right, then.
Have a good night.
Enid, you're stable right now.
We've got you on a nitro drip,
beta-blockers, anticoagulants.
Yeah, we're concerned you
might've had a small heart attack.
Oh...
- What... What do we do, now?
- Well, you have a couple
of options.
We can put you on a
regimen of medication,
or we can operate. An
angiography with possible stenting.
The benefit of that being that
you'd be back on your feet sooner...
Oh, if that's in time for
regionals, well, that sounds great.
But her age being what it is,
- surgery comes with more risks.
- Her age?
But her age shouldn't factor
into it. She's a plow horse.
She's the Gutter
Girlz' secret weapon.
No, I'm not!
The team's average has
gone up since I've been out.
Paula told me.
You're better off without me.
Stop it right now.
I won't hear it.
Choose surgery. We
need you, you hear me?
Oh...
Okay.
- Yes.
- Oh, attagirl.
Dr. Webber, will you
excuse me for one moment?
Dr. Minnick.
Hi. I just wanted to say hi and
welcome. I'm Maggie Pierce.
- Oh. You're Maggie Pierce.
- I am. That is me. I am... me.
Now I can finally put
a face with the name.
Maggie Pierce,
prodigy cardio chief.
Please. Prodigy? It's...
It's not all that great.
Oh, I know.
- Hmm?
- It's great if I'm your
patient 'cause I'm asleep
and you don't
have to talk to me,
but if I'm your student,
God help me, right?
- Right.
- It was nice to meet you.
- Everyone's complaining
about her.
- Who? I want names.
Everyone. And I
don't blame them.
Look, Minnick is doing
more than observing.
She was interfering
with our surgeons.
Their process,
their techniques...
Okay, first off,
they're my surgeons.
Okay, very well. Then I
will deal with Minnick myself.
I will let her know her role is
observing and nothing more.
No, you will not.
- And why not?
- Because that's not the deal.
Look, I gave
Dr. Minnick permission
to interact with the
staff how she sees fit.
She needs to know how
open we are to new ideas
before she can make
her own decision.
Decision?
- Are you giving her my job?
- No... No. Of course not.
I want her to work with you.
Why? Is there something
wrong with this program?
I...
just think...
What... What the
hell is it, Bailey?
Because it looks like
you're trying to hire someone
to dismantle a system
that I spent years...
That we spent
years trying to build.
And for the life of me,
I can't understand why.
Because medicine is
changing constantly.
You're the person
who taught me that.
And we... Everyone
here needs to be able
to change along with
it or get left behind.
It's my decision to
make. I am the chief.
I know.
It's a job I fought very
hard for you to get.
I just want to know
what it means.
Am I a bad teacher? Am
I the only bad teacher?
Am I gonna get fired?
- Why don't you ask her?
- If I do that,
then she'll know I'm
an accessory to theft.
It's kind of nice, not being
the only criminal for once.
Maybe I'm the only good
teacher. Maybe they're all fired.
- She made a mistake. That's all.
- You don't know that.
I do, because the only person
who should've been
left off that list is me.
Look, my trial starts in a couple
weeks, and I don't even exist.
- I'm not even here anymore.
- Alex, I didn't...
Look, if she left you off, it
was a mistake. That's all.
Look, I got to lock up.
Okay. She's down.
There's breast milk in the fridge,
but I'll be home in a couple hours.
So, you're going
on... a date, like a...
Like a date, date.
Yeah. Date-date.
Huh.
"Huh"? What's "huh"?
Is it so hard to believe that a
handsome, accomplished man
would find me date-worthy?
No, it's not. I'm
super date-worthy.
Where'd you meet
this guy? At work, or...
We met on Tinder.
- You're on Tinder?
- So what? So are you.
That's... Not... Not...
Not lately, I'm not...
- How did you know that?
- Because you
came up on mine once.
- Really?
- Well, why wouldn't you?
I mean, we're...
You're really close by.
- Yeah.
- I swiped left, so...
No. Yeah. No, no, I
would... I would, too.
Yeah, thank you.
I got to go.
In the OR, I got to do so
much more of the surgery,
but man, was she rubbing
Grey the wrong way!
And, uh...
Seems like the attendings
don't really like her,
but the residents...
Aren't you gonna do the thing?
You know, the thing where
you try to get me to tell you more
about what the
residents are thinking,
and then I can say that maybe I
shouldn't, 'cause you're the chief,
and then you can say,
"But you're my husband."
and I can say, "I know, baby,
"but I'm gonna have to
invoke Church and State."
You okay?
I don't know.
What do you need?
Tell me I'm doing
the right thing.
You're doing the right thing.
- Morning.
- Can you pour me one of those?
I just spent the last hour
getting trailed by Dr. Minnick.
She is... opinionated.
How'd it go last night? You
seemed to come home a little early.
Everything go all right?
You kidding? It was great. It
was, like, just so fun. So fun.
I mean, he's actually...
Yeah, he's pretty amazing.
- Amazing?
- Mm-hmm.
How so?
Like, so amazing
that we're gonna...
We're actually gonna
go out again tonight.
- That's how "so amazing" it was.
- That's great. That's great.
- This coffee is, like...
- Is it amazing?
Yeah.
I don't know what
you're so upset about.
Laying the patient on his belly?
He's open with only a
negative pressure dressing
holding in his edematous bowl.
It can't take that kind of pressure.
Hi. Thanks for letting me watch.
- I told you, I have a solution.
- I'd love to hear it.
- This is still happening?
- Oh, yes.
An anterior approach would
save him from a second one.
You know I can't chance having
the hardware contaminated.
You want to fill his
spinal cord with crap?
- I'm gonna find another surgery.
- Take me with you.
We figured out how to
assemble an OR table,
leaving a hole in the middle.
We're using a binder
to support his belly
so that we don't place pressure
on the abdominal incision.
- That's...
- Crazy! He'll eviscerate.
No, he won't, not
with the binder...
His guts could still end
up on the floor, Amelia.
They won't. Edwards will check
the dressing every five minutes,
if he starts to eviscerate, she
will hold pressure until we're done.
- She'll go under the table?
- Yes.
And check that
the guts are still in?
- Yes.
- That's...
- Genius.
- Yeah, that... That'll work.
- Can I add one little wrinkle?
Dr. Edwards has the potential
to learn from this procedure,
which I bet you've seen a
few times, right, Dr. Hunt?
Yeah.
Then why are you assisting, and
why is she the one on the floor?
Now, that's genius.
Murphy, you came here
to learn from me, right?
That's what you said?
Yes, absolutely.
How's it going?
Don't be shy. I wouldn't
ask if I didn't want to know.
If there's anything I can do to
help, I'd really love to hear it.
- Really?
- Yes, please.
You're a great surgeon.
A really great surgeon.
But... sometimes I have a
hard time keeping up with you.
You're so fast. I mean, fast.
And I'm good. I worked
really hard to get good,
But I'm studying so
hard to keep up with you.
Then sometimes I think I know what you're
talking about, but then... my brain is melting.
Dr. Murphy, I think I'm
gonna need you to go.
I'm... I'm so sorry. I thought
that you wanted me to...
I need you to go book an OR.
This is way worse than we thought.
Look. Right there. The left main
coronary artery is almost occluded.
- She needs a coronary bypass?
- That's right. Go. Now. Hurry.
Dr. Murphy? Where's the fire?
Oh, Dr. Webber.
Glad you're here.
What is this? What
are you doing here?
This is a teaching opportunity.
An emergent CABG has
just fallen into our laps,
Dr. Pierce has
agreed to let me use it
to demonstrate my teaching method
for anyone who wants to observe.
- No. Absolutely not. I am
interested to see how it works.
This is a high-risk procedure.
Enid's age makes
her a high-risk patient.
We're not gonna turn her
surgery into a skills lab.
Come on, now. This
is a teaching hospital.
Every surgery is a skills lab.
Well, I'm gonna talk
to Bailey about this.
Yes, good, you
should talk to the chief.
- Oh, believe me, I will.
- She already approved it.
She thinks it's happening, and so
do all those people in the gallery.
Now, this patient's emergent.
We shouldn't waste any more time.
I'm going to retract the
nerve roots now, Penfield,
carefully, to avoid
nerve damage.
Remember, the most important
thing is to take your time.
Dr. Hunt, everything
okay down there?
- Yep. No leaks.
- Great.
Actually, Dr. Hunt,
if you could...
move your foot.
Thank you.
Dr. Pierce, why don't you
trade places with Dr. Murphy?
Because Dr. Pierce is standing
where the lead surgeon needs to stand.
Traditionally, yes, we're
trying something different, right?
When this method is working,
the resident and the attending
function as one surgeon.
The resident's the hands,
the attending's the brain.
You follow?
Let's give it a try. Murphy?
Murphy's taking the
lead. Look at that.
I date men, but I might seriously
ask Dr. Minnick to marry me.
- Dr. Karev?
- You supposed to be up here?
- You gonna narc on me?
- I'm thinking about it.
Think of it this way.
In a couple weeks,
you might never
have to see me again.
This might be the closest
I get to an OR again.
Well, fine, if you're gonna
be all pathetic about it.
If you feel like you can continue...
Dr. Pierce, you talk her through.
Go ahead and
place the stabilizer.
And if you get stuck,
you... You stop.
- Ask for help.
- You stop.
And then ask for help.
Don't get me wrong. I love
see one, do one, teach one.
It's how I learned.
It's how we all learned.
So, why put it out to pasture?
We're putting it on
steroids. With this technique,
the resident gets to see one,
do one, teach one all in the
same surgery, every surgery.
Seriously, marriage!
Expect a save-the-date.
Okay, yes. Got it.
- Hey.
Um...
So, I was thinking that maybe we
don't need to discuss the dating thing.
We could just kind of keep
that to ourselves, you know?
You have a problem
with me going out?
No. No, no, no. It's not that.
You should do what you
want. I want you to be happy.
This is not a
"you" thing. It's me.
This whole thing
is all pretty...
- Very weird.
- Right? God, it's so weird.
You said...
Last night was not
amazing. It was awful.
I sat down for all
of five minutes,
and when he got up
to get drinks at the bar,
I faked a page.
- You faked a page?
- Yeah.
I told him there was an
MVC, and I'm pretty sure
at that exact moment, someone
crashed their car, 'cause I lied.
- That's not how it works.
- And then I ran like the wind.
I don't know how people
do this. I've never done this.
I've never, like, sat
across from someone
and said, "Hi. This
is me. Who are you?"
I had, like, friends that
turned into boyfriends.
I met Matthew at work.
Then you.
Here we are.
How do you do this?
Well, you're kind of doing it.
I mean, you dip your toe.
You start by dipping
your toe into the water,
and then, eventually,
you learn to swim.
Well, that's easy
for you to say.
You probably dipped
your toe all over town.
Look, you faked a page out there.
Okay? You got good instincts, kid.
It'll be a while before
he's up and about,
- but Emmett's gonna be fine.
- Oh, wow.
Thank you. Do you mind...
Is it possible for me
to stay here tonight?
- Oh, I don't know...
- Please.
Last night...
Would you believe we have been married
for 20 years and never spent a night apart?
I mean, you spend that
much time with someone,
it gets so they drive you crazy.
But last night,
he wasn't there...
and I couldn't sleep.
There's an Emmett-shaped
hole in our house.
Literally, there's a hole in the
ceiling where he fell through.
Big moron.
Don't squeeze the
heart too much, Murphy.
- Got it.
- Okay.
- There. Way to go, Murphy.
You just placed a
heart-stabilization device
- all on your own.
- Now let me...
Don't touch. Just
use your words.
- Use my words?
- Mm-hmm. Explain it to her.
Incision. Shunt. Anastomosis.
That is not what I'm asking.
Break it down. Go step by
step. You're trying to skip ahead.
Dr. Pierce thinks ahead.
Her mind is fast.
Faster than anyone's.
So she shouldn't be asked
to dumb things down, okay?
Murphy, can you
do the next step?
I can try, but if Dr. Pierce is
more comfortable stepping in...
I guarantee you she is,
but you will be more
comfortable after you do it.
Okay. Now that we've
stabilized the heart,
we will administer esmolol to
slow the heart rate for better control.
Right, now go ahead and
incise the diseased artery.
I don't... I don't
want to do this.
I don't... I don't feel ready to
do this. Will you? Is that all right?
It's more than all
right, Murphy. Exactly.
No shame. When you've
reached the limit, you tag out.
And when she does, you'll be able
to see exactly how much she knows
and how much
she has left to learn.
All right. First, I'm going
to measure the shunt.
Okay.
Let me back up.
First, I will incise
the target artery,
and then I will
insert the shunt.
And after that, then I'll
prep for anastomosis.
Dr. Webber, will you check
the internal mammary for flow?
- Already started.
- I noticed. Maybe Dr. DeLuca...
- No.
- I'm sorry?
This artery that will allow
this woman to survive.
I'm not putting it in the
hands of a first-year intern
who hasn't taken out a tonsil.
DeLuca, you've anastomosed
a vessel before, right?
Yes, ma'am. I've assisted
on a femoral-artery repair.
That is not the
same thing. Not at all.
So, right there, I'm assuming
you know what that is.
Uh... Yes, it's... It's the IMA.
Exactly. See how it
branches off to the right?
Hey, just because he knows...
You hit a branch of
the mammary! Ah, hell!
DeLuca, move and
start some suction.
DeLuca, you are right there.
- I can't see anything.
- I got it. Got it.
I did it. It's done.
I had a clip for
Dr. Webber. I just... fixed it.
Right?
You're upset, clearly.
Oh, is it clear? Good.
I was afraid you might not catch
my drift, because you're insane.
Have you never
accidentally nicked a vessel?
Of course I have. You
did this on purpose.
You were about to
clip the artery anyway.
I want you out of this hospital.
When I was two,
my dad was looking through the
phone book for swimming lessons.
My mom said, "Here's one",
and tossed me in the pool.
- Did I drown?
- That's your innovation?
Throw a bloody patient at a
novice to see what happens?
They did that 100 years
ago. On the battlefield!
Dr. Webber, there were four
surgeons around that table
we knew could've
stopped her bleeding.
And when DeLuca made that save,
we learned there were actually five.
If he were allowed to perform in
every surgery like he did today,
he would learn more and faster
with less pressure and less risk.
The patient was never in danger
because we were standing right there.
You know I'm right.
Cardiac enzymes are trending
down. She's gonna be okay.
That was humiliating.
It was inexcusable. And
she's not gonna do it again.
I'm sorry you had
to go through that.
She's right. I'm
not a great teacher.
- Oh, come on.
- No, the thing is I am a genius.
As a student, I learned
better and faster than anyone.
I was a rock star. But as
a teacher... Minnick's right.
I'm not that great.
Her system works.
She's right.
She's an ass, but she's right.
Dr. Webber? She's
gonna be okay, right?
Yes, ma'am.
I think you'll have your secret
weapon locked and loaded
before the regionals.
Dr. Webber, do you think I
would push her to get surgery
for some silly tournament?
She's tried to drop out
of the team six times,
and that team is the only thing
that keeps the lot of
us from sitting around,
watching TV in the common room,
and moldering away like all
the other old, wet sponges.
She needs to stay in
the game. We all do.
Sometimes we just...
need a little push.
Owen, wait up.
I thought I might
ask for a ride home.
Yeah. Yeah, I can manage that.
Thank you for earlier.
Edwards really did get a lot
from watching that spinal fusion.
Well, I'm glad to hear it.
You're not still mad about
having to sit on the floor.
Amelia, I have operated in sinkholes.
I don't mind sitting on the floor.
Can we just let it go? It's not
important enough to argue about.
- I have let it go.
- No, you haven't.
You don't... All
day, it's been...
Can we just set a reset
button and move forward?
I am moving forward.
By myself, apparently,
because you can't be
bothered to sleep at home.
- I've had patients.
- Every night
for the past two weeks?
- You didn't have to stay here.
- Yes, I did.
- Because of me? Come on.
- I don't wanna do this.
- Did I tell you not
to come home?
- I cannot keep doing this.
- Doing what?
- I don't
wanna have a baby!
Hey. You lost?
I forgot. Chief Bailey's
office... fourth floor?
- Yeah, right off the catwalk.
- Great. Thanks.
Um... You made a mistake.
- I'm sorry?
- I am great,
and your little list, or
whatever the hell that is,
should have my name on it
'cause I raise great
surgeons, and I will raise more.
Fetal surgery is... a
very exclusive practice,
and there are hardly any of
us. I am like a rare, exotic bird,
and if you stop me from teaching,
I may be the last of my kind.
What list?
From the room. The
residents. You left it there.
I was just trying to
learn everyone's name.
- Writing it down
helps me remember.
- Oh, great.
So, you don't... need
to remember my name?
Arizona Robbins? That
name attached to that face?
No, that's not one you forget.
Night.
- You're interested
in the game, now?
- I'm interested in these nachos.
- Watch it.
- Oh.
Oh, shoot.
I forgot.
The guy I blew off last night?
I made a rain check for
tonight and I forgot to cancel.
Mm. Is this the dude?
Let's get a look here. That's
an odd choice for a photo.
He looks respectable. You
should go. Go dip your toe.
I want to dip my
toe in those nachos.
No, no, no. Gross. Go.
Give the guy more than five
minutes. Have a drink. Have a laugh.
If it gets weird,
then just text me.
We'll get you out of
there in two minutes.
- Do it.
- Okay. Fine.
No, I don't... I just...
I look like I'm just...
You look terrific.
Would you just go?
- Dip it. Get to dipping.
- Fine. Okay, geez.
- Hey. It's late.
- Can I stay here tonight?
Yeah. What's wrong?
I don't want to talk about it.
I just need a place to crash.
Nope. She can't stay here.
- You can't stay here.
- Alex.
- Mer just said...
- I don't care what Mer said.
You can't crash here. Go home.
- It was my room
before it was yours.
- Go home and fix your crap.
- I can't.
- You're freaking out,
because you got some
sword hanging over your head?
Me, too, and I can't do a
damn thing about it except wait.
You can fix your stupid sword.
Go home and get the
freaking execution over with.
I did. I told him.
The sword fell.
Take my room.
- She talks to me now.
- Mmm.
Thank you.
Everyone's talking about
what you did in that OR.
I have a tendency to shake things
up. And if I come here, I certainly will.
Will you? Come here?
I still have a few
other offers to field,
but... I'm definitely
interested.
That's great to hear.
You should know,
they'll hate you. The staff?
It happens everywhere I go.
Everyone hates the agent of change.
I'm used to it, I'm good at it,
but you should be prepared that
they'll hate you, too, for bringing me on.
Also, if I take the
job, I work alone.
I like Dr. Webber,
respect the hell out of him,
but if I come on, I
don't share authority.
I am the authority.
- Oh, I'm sorry. I can come back.
- Oh, no need. We are all set, here.
It's been a pleasure.
- She makes me feel old.
- She is a puppy.
Yeah, you know, when I was chief, I
was the one pushing through things,
selling the board on robotic
surgery and bringing in new ideas.
I mean, that's all you're trying to
do, is to bring in something new
and trying to bring me along
with it, whether I like it or not.
I was resistant. I'm sorry.
Oh, you don't have to...
No, we all have to be
pushed, and she pushes me.
It's hard to admit
when we're wrong,
that even though everything
looks fine, there is a problem.
You know, I'll be happy to work with
her. I think we'll make a good team.
Something is broken,
and you have to see where
it's going and set about fixing it...
So, is she gonna stick around?
She's thinking about it.
Well, let's keep
our fingers crossed.
Or it's all gonna come apart.