I mean, Hannah's kind
and super cute.
She's a catch, no question.
But you're still in recovery.
But Sean,
he's a donor match
for you, Dean.
We can get you in
for surgery next month.
Did you talk
to Sean today?
He's not answering his phone.
Didn't show up for work.
Try not
to think the worst.
2.0 put Med
on the map.
To show just how much
I believe in this OR suite,
I'm gonna put
my life in its hands.
2.0 hitting the stock exchange
benefits Dayton Corporation,
not Chicago Med.
The large lesion
that Crockett attempted
to ablate?
It's not on
Richard's CT.
2.0 created the lesion
on its own?
Crockett wasn't responsible
for Richard Evans' death.
2.0 was.
Hey.
I don't have long.
Got a meeting with Goodwin
and legal. What's up?
If it's about
Richard Evans' death,
cancel that meeting.
What?
You were not
responsible.
Aw, come on, Will.
You saw
the surgical record.
I got too close
to the hepatic vein.
I caused the clot.
Because you were trying
to ablate a large lesion.
Yeah, so?
It's still my fault.
No, because actually
that lesion wasn't there.
What do you mean?
It didn't exist.
Yes, it did.
It was clearly evident
in the intraoperative CT.
Right. 2.0's CT
during surgery,
but take a look
at the pre-op CT.
They're not there.
I don't understand.
How could what 2.0
showed be so different?
2.0 made it up.
During surgery,
you asked 2.0
for navigational guidance.
It didn't have the data
to give you that guidance,
so it created a lesion
that did not exist.
Why would it do that?
Unfortunately, in a way,
we've taught 2.0
to please us.
What it did was a misguided
attempt to help you.
We're actually seeing this
across various AI chat bots.
But in 2.0's case,
it's not as harmless
as giving you
the wrong
driving directions.
It can kill someone.
It did.
And until
we can figure out how
to install guardrails,
we've got to shut it down.
So, Jack launched
his IPO.
Yeah, it's a big day
for him.
And us.
Ah, I don't know
that Jack's corporate
business impacts us.
Why don't you go over
and say hello?
I got my phone
to keep me company.
Ah, I think
she looks busy.
You two having problems?
Kind of had a row
last night.
You know? I asked her
to move in with me.
Oh.
Uh, and it was a mistake,
I take it?
I guess it was.
I mean...
I don't know.
Maybe it was the timing.
Right?
Look, she just lost
her life savings
and her apartment.
That's another conversation.
But she's broke,
doesn't have a place
to live.
Oh?
Yeah.
Said I was treating her
like a charity case.
Yikes.
What?
Yeah, and why didn't I ask her
to move in before?
That's a tough one,
Daniel.
I mean, I can get how
she'd feel that way.
She seems like a pretty
independent woman.
I don't know.
Why didn't I
ask her before?
I don't know.
Is Sean here?
Yeah.
What happened?
He's okay, Dean.
He fell off the wagon,
passed out.
A friend brought him in,
said it was alcohol
and benzos.
We're running
a tox screen
just to make sure
there's nothing else.
How's he being treated?
Heavy fluids and dextrose,
a dose of flumazenil.
He's awake right now.
Hello, son.
I'm so sorry.
No, it's all right.
It's all right.
I let you down.
No.
It's gonna be okay.
We'll get past this.
Just rest.
Dr. Johnson,
I'm Dr. Halstead.
What've you got?
Husband and wife.
Fred and Janice Anderson.
Early 50s, MVC.
Car went off the road
into a tree.
Fred was trapped for several
minutes inside the vehicle
while it was on fire.
He was extricated
and intubated
due to stridor
and respiratory distress
from smoke inhalation.
Carboxyhemoglobin tested
in the helo was 55.
Janice was able
to self-extricate,
complained of chest pain.
Gave her 50 of fentanyl
en route, satting at 95,
GCS 15.
Let's go.
Airway's intact.
Bilateral breath sounds.
Heart rate 122.
BP 130/86.
Same as en route.
All right.
No outward signs
of blunt force trauma.
X-ray?
Chest first, Mike.
Clear.
That looks okay.
Okay, now pelvis.
Clear.
That looks good too.
All right.
All right, Nancy,
call over to CT.
Let them know
we're sending him
for a pan scan.
Got it.
Loren.
Maggie.
You're running
an air ambulance now?
Yeah, I got
my accreditation.
Guess we're seeing
more of you.
Vitals are good.
Satting at 95
on two liters
of oxygen.
C-spine?
Clinically clear.
She has a couple broken ribs,
minor pulmonary contusion.
Nothing serious.
Okay. Thanks, Kai.
Yeah.
Ms. Anderson,
are you still
feeling pain?
It's not that.
Can you tell me
what happened
with the accident?
Janice?
My husband...
Fred is stable.
What is it?
He tried to kill us.
He tried to kill us!
Hey, Jack.
Hey, Crockett.
I was just headed up
to pre-op,
see if I could find
a flattering gown.
Fat chance, huh?
Yeah, well, listen.
We can't do your
hernia repair in 2.0.
Sure we can.
That's the whole point.
No. We discovered
there's a serious problem
with the system.
Come on, Crockett.
You're not still
beating yourself up over
Richard Evans, are you?
I told you,
the entire surgery
was a Hail Mary.
He was terminal
to begin with.
Jack, the AI
gives bad advice.
Hell, it makes stuff up.
We got to shut it down.
Look, every surgeon
makes mistakes,
all right?
Even the best.
Don't blame the scalpel.
2.0 sent me after a lesion
that wasn't there.
It produced images
of a tumor
that did not exist.
The platform is defective.
You understand?
Let me show you
the pre-op scans
next to 2.0's.
No, no need.
I trust you.
Right, well, let me
figure out what to do
about this.
Thank you for bringing it
to my attention.
Yeah.
Yeah, of course.
What's up?
Husband and wife, possible
murder-suicide attempt.
At least that's what
the wife says.
I have to tell you,
I don't believe it.
This is Dr. Johnson.
He runs the medevac service
that flew the couple in.
Yeah, I've known them
for years.
The Andersons
are a devoted couple.
Fred could never
do anything like that.
Yeah. Fred's intubated
and currently in
the CT scanner.
Can I talk to her?
Yeah.
Mrs. Anderson,
how are you doing?
I'm Dr. Charles.
Psychiatry?
Can you, to the best
of your ability,
try and, you know,
just tell me what
happened today?
I was driving and
Fred suddenly grabbed
the wheel and turned us
off the road.
Oh, man.
That must have been...
That must
have been terrifying.
Yes.
I screamed at him
just to let go,
and he wouldn't. He...
Before I could brake,
we hit the tree.
Had you been quarreling
or anything?
No!
It's just completely
out of the blue.
Okay.
We've always had
a very happy marriage...
I thought.
So nothing out of the ordinary
recently relationship wise?
I don't know.
Fred has seemed
a little different lately.
Different how?
A little off.
Out of sorts, you know?
Really down.
I always ask him
if anything's wrong.
He always says he's fine.
I just don't understand.
I mean, to do something
like this, it's...
Look, I completely understand
how upsetting this must be,
but I promise you,
we're gonna get some clarity.
All right?
In the meantime,
can you try and get
some rest for me?
All right?
And I'll check back
with you in a bit.
Thank you.
Okay.
Hey, Dean.
Sean's tox screen
came back.
Hi.
You okay?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Just a headache.
So what about Sean?
Well, good news.
There were no other drugs
in his system.
Cold comfort.
All right. Thanks.
Never should've...
Never should've let him
give me his kidney anyway.
Why?
You think somehow
all this was your fault?
He was already fragile.
I just added another
level of stress.
From my experience, it's...
It's very hard to say
what factors lead to
anybody relapsing.
Well, I'm gonna remove
one of those factors
and tell him
that I don't want
his kidney.
No, Dean.
That's the last thing
that you should do.
Sean already feels terrible.
That'll make him feel worse.
It could send him
into a spiral.
Hannah, we both know
there's a problem with him
donating now anyway.
Yes, but we don't need
to tell Sean that yet.
Okay? Don't take this
away from him.
Dr. Archer,
Maggie wants you
in treatment six.
All right.
Sarah, sweetie?
This is Dr. Archer.
What's going on, Sarah?
Hurts, pretty bad.
Yeah? Abdomen?
For how long?
Couple of days.
It's getting worse.
Okay.
Vitals are normal,
and there's no fever.
Okay. Milligram for
hydromorphone for the pain,
and we're gonna
do an ultrasound.
Will that be okay?
Okay.
All right. Okay.
Can I take these
from you?
Yes. Yes.
Peanuts?
For the squirrels.
Okay.
Okay. It's gonna feel
a little cold.
All right?
I'm not seeing anything
out of the ordinary.
Have you been having
any other symptoms?
Well, I've been...
Constipated.
And that isn't usually
an issue?
Uh-uh.
Okay.
Gonna need to do a CT
of your belly.
It's kind of an X-ray
to help us
find out what's
going on, okay?
The techs will be in
to bring you up to radiology.
Thank you. Thank you both.
Fred's awake and extubated.
You can talk to him now.
Mr. Anderson,
how are you doing?
I'm Dr. Charles.
Loren, is Janice
all right?
Look, she's injured,
Fred, but not seriously.
Oh, thank God.
Can you remember
what happened
this morning?
What did Janice tell you?
That I grabbed the wheel?
Yeah, and, you know,
drove the car off the road.
I can't explain
what happened.
I wasn't in control.
How do you mean?
It wasn't me.
So... Somebody else
was in the car?
No.
I'm sorry. I'm just
not quite following.
It was this hand.
It grabbed the wheel.
I couldn't stop it.
It wouldn't let go.
"It wasn't me, it was
my hand." I gotta try
that one some time.
What do you
make of it?
I'm not quite sure yet.
I guess
we report it to CPD.
No, it's not
a CPD matter,
and deputies
from Grundy County
where the accident occurred
are investigating.
Okay.
Well, what do you want me
to do with this guy?
You want me to see
if psych unit has a bed?
Let's just hold off
on that for a second.
I'd really like to take a look
at these CAT scans.
Will you give me a shout
when they're up?
All right.
You're still booked
for surgery in 2.0.
Let's pick this up later.
Come on, Jack.
After what I told you?
Look, Crockett,
I appreciate the concern,
but there's no risk here.
You've done the procedure
a million times.
The platform
is defective, Jack.
Come on. Just cancel
the surgery or move it
to a regular OR.
I invited people
to observe 2.0 in action.
These are investors.
These are friends.
I'd look ridiculous,
and forget the IPO.
Jack, you can't promote
a platform that doesn't work.
It's actually dangerous.
Put off the IPO.
I'm not gonna start sowing
doubt into the reliability
of the system.
You can never
recover from that.
Okay, if you don't, I'm sorry,
but I won't do your surgery.
You can't be serious.
Oh, I am.
You know, I could easily
find another ten surgeons
to take your place,
who'd be happy
to take your place.
With or without you,
this surgery
is moving forward.
That's up to you.
Crockett.
Crockett, come on!
You're the face of 2.0.
You have been
from the get-go.
I want you to perform
the surgery.
And look, because it's you,
I will make this promise.
Once the IPO is launched,
I will sideline the platform
until every last bug
is worked out.
Now, how does
that sound? Huh?
Come on, man.
I'm your patient.
That's gotta mean
something to you.
He won't budge.
He's gonna move forward
with the surgery
with or without me.
Then we've gotta go public
with the scans.
Come on, Will.
Forget the legal nightmare.
It won't work.
How can we prove
the veracity
of the scans?
2.0 can make them up.
So can we.
He'll likely accuse me
of trying to cover up
my mistakes.
He's right. Even if
we went down that road
and didn't get hauled
in front of a medical board,
it could take years.
It certainly wouldn't stop
today's surgery.
So? What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna do
the hernia repair.
Why?
If 2.0 does deliver
incorrect scans
or recommendations,
I can't have some novice there
who's gonna get thrown.
I have to protect Jack.
Crockett, listen to me.
Jack promised after the IPO
he'd sideline 2.0 and fix it.
Okay?
And you believe him?
Well, I don't see
as I have a choice.
Hey. Sarah's CT scan
came back.
It's a bowel obstruction
from a sigmoid volvulus.
Her intestine
is twisted on itself.
So let the OR know
we're coming up.
No, we can't have
surgery here.
She has terrible insurance.
Registration just called
and said that Med is not
even in her network.
They won't approve
an operation.
So, obviously, she can't
afford to be out of pocket
for the surgery.
So I just need to transfer her
to a hospital in her network.
That's all.
Yeah.
Hey, Dean.
I'm discharging Sean.
Thanks.
All right.
Sign right here.
Hey.
How you feeling? Huh?
Well, other than
screwing up?
But I am feeling good
about one thing.
I got a message
from Dr. Cameron.
Turns out I'm a match
to donate.
Pretty great, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Look, um,
I know it's no excuse,
but I know why
I fell off the wagon,
and I promise
it won't happen again.
Um...
You guys don't have to hide
your relationship anymore.
I'm okay with it.
Uh...
What?
I don't understand.
I'm gonna be honest.
I have feelings for you.
So when I saw you
and Dad together,
I guess it hit me
pretty hard...
No, hold on. I'm sorry.
What do you mean you
saw us together?
In the doctors' lounge.
Well...
I don't know what
you think you saw.
Whatever it was,
you misinterpreted it.
Dr. Asher and I
are just good friends.
Really?
Absolutely.
I mean, this?
No way.
I mean, no way.
Yeah, yeah...
That...
Yeah, okay.
He's got the idea.
Okay.
Sean, I...
I mean, I'm...
I'm touched
by your feelings
for me.
Wow.
I feel pretty stupid.
But, um, like I said,
I'm over it.
I'm just glad
that I'm a match.
Yeah, well,
we're not there yet.
So, you know,
why don't you
just head upstairs,
hang out and grab a bite,
and I'll give you a lift
at the end of my shift?
All right?
Yeah.
All right.
Come in.
Ms. Goodwin,
you have to stop
Jack Dayton's surgery.
That's Dr. Marcel's case.
Why is it your concern?
2.0 is responsible
for the death of my
patient, Richard Evans.
What? How?
Its AI produced
a phantom lesion
that led Crockett to make
a fatal surgical error.
That thing killed
my patient.
That's a very serious
charge, Dr. Halstead.
Does Dayton know this?
Yes, but he's insisting on
going ahead with the surgery
to promote the platform
for his IPO.
And where's
Dr. Marcel in this?
He's stuck.
He won't abandon his patient,
especially because the AI
is unreliable.
Ms. Goodwin,
you are the only person
who can do something.
If Dayton were risking
his life, I could get a court
order to stop it.
But no judge is going to rule
an elective hernia repair
a life-threatening
procedure.
So there's gotta be
another way.
Dr. Halstead,
Chicago Med is now
a for-profit private hospital.
Jack Dayton
basically owns it.
So if he wants a surgery,
I no longer have
the authority to stop it.
I can't stand what
this place has become.
Dr. Charles, there's a couple
deputies here investigating
the accident.
They wanna question
Fred and Janice.
Okay. Well,
take a look at this.
His head CT
came back.
Right here.
Calcification.
Atrophy in
the frontal lobe.
Looks like it happened
a while ago.
Yeah.
I would tell our visitors
to hold off for a bit.
Highly unlikely a crime
was committed here.
So you, Mr. Anderson,
have had a stroke.
A stroke?
A small one,
some time ago.
See right here?
Frontal lobe?
A stroke?
You recall recently
having any headaches,
dizziness, weakness
on one side of the body
or the other?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Bad headaches,
right before Easter.
Huh.
You know, that would
time out just about right.
How about since then?
I feel weak at times.
I forget things.
I thought that
was just age, maybe.
I've got a hunch
that you have
a very rare neurological
condition called,
believe it or not,
alien hand syndrome.
Can absolutely be
brought on by a stroke
disrupting blood flow
to the primary motor cortex
and causing
involuntary grasping,
difficulty releasing objects.
That's why I grabbed
the steering wheel.
Yeah.
I couldn't let go.
Exactly.
Oh, my God.
I know it's a lot to take in,
but, look, there are
treatment options.
There are.
We'll need a neurologist
to confirm, of course,
but the first thing
that I'd like to do is I'd
like to bring your wife
into the conversation.
Would that be all right?
Yeah, please.
Thank you so much.
Okay. I'm about to start
Mr. Dayton's hernia repair.
A hernia is a hole
in the abdominal wall.
For you all to get
a little bit more
about the procedure,
2.0 shows
the patient's anatomy
in three dimensions.
Loading.
First I will open
the skin.
Then I will dissect
the tissues
to define the borders
of the hernia.
Once I have this completed,
then I'll close it primarily
or use a piece of mesh
to bridge the gap.
So how about let's say
we do the real thing?
Dr. Song?
You're good to go.
Great.
Okay. 2.0, what is
the optimal location
to make the incision?
One centimeter cranial
and one centimeter
caudal to the umbilicus.
Okay, very good.
Thank you, Carmela.
Making the incision.
I'm so,
so sorry, Fred.
Oh, God.
Are you kidding me?
I don't blame you
at all, sweetie.
What can we do for him?
Well, there's no cure,
per se,
but the condition
is treatable.
There are
several modalities,
visual spatial coaching,
cognitive behavioral therapy.
Um, there are medications.
Oh.
I'm sorry. I have to
make a call.
Woah, Janice, let me
get somebody to...
I'm all right. Really.
I won't be long.
Oh, my God.
It's true. I knew it.
Knew what?
She's having an affair.
Having an affair?
You saw how
she left the room
to take a phone call.
I mean,
it's not the first time.
She's been
so secretive,
so distant.
Doesn't necessarily mean
she's having an affair.
Dr. Charles,
what if when
I grabbed the wheel
it was some kind
of a subconscious thing?
Like, you know,
maybe deep down I wanted...
I can assure you, Fred,
that your condition
is entirely neurological.
Okay?
No psychological element.
Nothing subconscious
about it.
End of story.
Okay.
We're still waiting
on the ambulance
to transfer you.
I just put another call in.
Thank you.
Is the pain
getting worse?
Yes. Terrible.
Why don't you lie
on your back and let me
check your stomach?
Okay.
Okay. Ready?
Okay. Okay.
You're not going anywhere.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
Dr. Archer?
Yeah?
Sarah Malone,
she's febrile,
she's vomiting,
and her BP's soft.
Most likely fully torsed.
She needs an operation
now before her intestine
becomes necrotic.
By the time the ambulance
gets here and she's
transferred, admitted...
She could die.
Not gonna wait.
All right. We'll have
the operation here.
Okay. But what about
her insurance?
She could be in debt
for the rest of her life.
Unless we do the surgery
off the books.
Of course, that means
Jack Dayton's for-profit
hospital won't be reimbursed.
Can't say I have
a problem with that.
Okay, but how? How?
We can't take her
to the main OR.
I'll just do it
in her treatment room.
That's all. Okay?
Now you use your renowned
powers of persuasion.
Get me an anesthesiologist.
Okay?
Thank you, Dr. Archer.
Just the anesthesiologist.
Come on.
Okay.
I'm now freeing up the bowel
from the hernia sac.
Warning.
There has been
a full thickness
small bowel enterotomy.
2.0, I have not
injured the intestine.
Please reevaluate.
Protect the field
from gross contamination.
Assess damage and decide
between primary repair
versus resection.
No, that image
is not correct.
2.0, I repeat,
I have not cut
into the intestine.
The bowel is intact.
If you do not address
perforation,
there is a 100% chance
patient will become septic.
Okay, everyone.
There is no perforation
of the bowel.
No complications
of any kind.
2.0 is either off-target
or its sensors
are malfunctioning.
Dr. Song, would you
please show the gallery
direct view of the field?
Coming up.
Okay.
As you all can see,
there is no perforation
of the bowel whatsoever.
Repair bowel
perforation immediately.
Dr. Marcel, should I
shut it down?
Yes.
Chance of mortality, 90%.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I can assure you all,
Mr. Dayton is not at risk.
This is a procedure
I've performed
hundreds of times.
I can easily proceed
without 2.0.
Continuing to reduce
the hernia.
Great, there you are.
What's up?
Uh...
I wondered if you'd come
spot me in a surgery.
Laparotomy.
Spot you?
Yeah.
I'm feeling
a little wobbly.
I'm an OB, remember?
Don't you want
a surgical resident?
No. See, the circumstances
are unusual.
If admin were to find out
about this, we'd probably
get fired.
Ooh.
What an incentive.
I take it that
this is important.
It would save
the patient's life.
Kinda why
we're here, right?
It's definitely
sigmoid volvulus.
Alpha retractor.
All right.
Help me untwist
the sigmoid.
There we go.
Got it?
Yeah.
That looks viable.
Yeah, but the sigmoid
is really floppy.
Yeah, it just needs
to be resected, and...
And re-anastomosed.
Uh...
Dr. Archer?
Yeah.
No, I just... For a second,
let me sit down, will you?
Uh...
Okay.
Thanks. Hannah, you good
to take over?
Absolutely.
All right.
Marty, how's the patient?
She was bone dry,
but after two liters
of Ringer's
and one of albumin,
she's making
adequate urine.
Okay, great.
Let's get this
sigmoid resected.
Janice.
Dr. Charles.
I'm sorry that I ran out
like that.
Is everything okay?
Actually, I just spoke
to my doctor,
and I got some
very good news.
Oh, that's who
texted you?
Yes.
I had a biopsy
a couple of weeks ago,
and I just found out
that it's negative.
Congratulations.
That's very good news.
Does your husband
know about this?
No. I never told him.
Like I said, Fred seemed
to be struggling
with something.
I guess it was the stroke,
but I didn't know it.
And... Anyway, I didn't want
to add to his problems.
I didn't want him
to worry.
If I may, I think it might
be a good time to fill him in.
I just... I think
there could be a...
A pretty serious
misunderstanding
brewing here.
Oh?
Yeah.
And, you know,
maybe the sooner,
the better.
Okay.
Hey, Sarah.
Uh, you know
where you are?
Hospital.
Okay. Can you press
against my hand?
Mmm.
Okay, great.
And again.
Good.
Sarah.
You're gonna be
just fine.
Mmm. Thank you.
You are welcome.
I thought
you'd be dropping by.
2.0 is not
ready to be put
on the market.
Not without verification
of its data set.
Right now we don't know
the data sources.
It could be biased
or false.
And not only that.
In the wrong hands,
the data could
be manipulated.
As you and your
friend demonstrated.
Friend? No.
It was just me.
Just you?
Yes.
I couldn't risk
2.0 killing anyone else.
I appreciate your passion,
Dr. Halstead,
but I don't believe
for a minute
you have the technical
wherewithal to pull that off.
I suspect Dr. Song
had a hand in it.
My letter of resignation.
If Dayton comes looking
for a culprit, you have one.
So your plan
is to take the blame?
Let's just say
I hope it ends
the matter.
You realize I have
no choice but to accept
your resignation?
And I hope you also realize
that I don't want to.
It's not gonna be easy
for you out there,
Dr. Halstead.
I can't give you
a reference,
and Jack Dayton
has been known
to be vindictive.
Where I grew up,
everyone I knew
was vindictive.
Will Halstead...
What are we gonna do
without you?
You have been
a constant source
of irritation
and a constant source
of inspiration.
Your leaving
will be a great
loss to us.
A great loss to me.
You had no right.
I'm just as much
to blame as you are.
No, I put you up to it.
I'm the one
who hacked
the system!
At my insistence.
Will!
Grace, you're
a brilliant doctor.
If you destroy your career,
I'd never forgive myself.
It's over.
It's done. Let it go.
He resigned?
I know.
Over 2.0?
The malfunction?
Talk to him.
Are you kidding me,
Halstead?
Why didn't you
read me in?
I didn't see
a reason to.
What?
To protect me?
Or did you think
I wouldn't go along?
Does it matter?
Yes, it matters.
And for the record,
I wouldn't have.
Damn it, man.
I disagree with Jack
and his IPO,
but I never would have
gone this route.
Come on.
You said it yourself.
2.0 wasn't ready.
It needed to be sidelined.
Sidelined, yes.
Blown up, no.
Whatever its faults,
2.0 has been an incredibly
valuable tool,
and now no one's ever
gonna wanna use it.
Crockett,
it was the only way.
It had to be done,
and you know it.
You're still here.
So is 2.0.
Fix it.
I guess they both made
some pretty wild assumptions
about each other.
Yeah. Even after
so many years together.
You know, it seems
like they both feared
there wasn't enough love
there to fully trust.
Amazing, right?
Human beings' capacity
to doubt each other,
doubt ourselves.
Yeah.
Hey.
I was glad to hear
your surgery went well.
That's debatable.
I'm alive,
which I'm grateful for.
Well, from what
I understand,
your recovery time
should be minimal.
Yeah.
Only one hitch, though.
2.0?
IPO is dead.
Yeah.
Some of your doctors
were against putting
this platform on the market.
They'll be happy now.
It's an amazing
innovation, Jack.
It just needs more time
and development.
Right, and who exactly
is gonna fund that?
What do you mean?
I'm ruined, Sharon.
I put all my eggs
in that basket.
I leveraged everything.
I'm sorry
to hear that, Jack.
Yeah, well, listen,
it's not the first
fortune I lost,
so I'll survive.
Not sure
about all of you.
I don't understand.
I have no other recourse
but to sell the hospital.
What are you doing?
I am... I'm writing
a letter to...
To you.
Can I read it?
Sure.
"Dear Liliana."
That's all I got so far.
Daniel, the problem
isn't just about me
moving in with you.
People are always
noticing our differences.
You are the big
important doctor.
I'm just the janitor.
Lili, I gotta be
honest with you.
You sound an awful lot
like your brother.
Didn't we already
handle this stuff?
You don't feel
sorry for me?
You don't think
that I'm a charity case?
I can't feel
a little bit sorry
for you?
You lost
your frickin' house.
But a charity case?
Are you kidding me?
I look at you
and I see this strong,
independent woman.
You know, if anything,
I spend, you know,
a fair amount of time
thinking that I might not
be worthy of you.
What do you mean?
Look, just because
I have a fancy title,
it doesn't mean
I don't wake up
with the same
doubts and insecurities
as everybody else.
I mean, you wanna
know why
I didn't ask you
to move in
with me earlier?
I was terrified
you'd say no.
Look.
You
are the best thing
that's happened to me
in a long, long time,
and I probably
could have told you
that earlier too.
So let me just be
crystal clear
about something.
Okay?
I am in love
with you, Liliana.
There you have it.
Then I owe you
an apology, Daniel.
I misunderstood.
It's very hard for me
to feel dependent
on someone,
even if I love
that person.
Hey! Happy couple.
How nice.
Let's go. I parked the car
in the loading zone.
Hey. Has Dr. Cameron
come in?
Yeah.
Antibiotics?
You're septic?
Let me see.
Let me guess.
Bacterial peritonitis
from your dialysis catheter.
Right. Right.
Did you hear
about Will?
I did, but we're still
talking about you, Dean.
This is your third infection.
Enough DIY.
You need to be on hemodialysis
in a proper clinical setting.
Three times a week
for four hours?
Yes.
No, not for me.
Thank you. No way.
Dad.
Sean, hey.
What's going on?
What's the matter?
It's just a little infection.
Your father needs
to switch to
a different type
of dialysis.
Hannah, come on.
Whoa, wait, wait, wait.
Why do that?
I'm here. I'm ready.
Let's do the transplant.
What?
They won't let you.
Why? I'm a match.
There's a rule.
You need to be at least
six-months sober
in order to donate.
What have I done?
No, no, no.
It's not a big deal.
I'll just go on hemodialysis,
like Hannah says.
Dad.
Sean, come on.
Please. It's just six months.
Don't worry about it.
Will?
No.
You can't go.
I have to, Maggie.
I have to.
I'm sorry
I have to say goodbye.
This is not easy.
You've been my family
for so many years.
I'll never forget you.
You will always
be a part of me,
and I'll always be grateful
for the time we had together.
I know we all want to wish
Dr. Halstead the very best.
Thank you.
Will!
Hey, buddy.
Man, look how big
you got.
Mom, he's here!
Hey.
Is that all
you brought?
I didn't know how long
you'd want me to stay.
I'm never gonna let you go.