Dying isn't easy.
The body was
designed to stay alive.
Thick skulls...
strong hearts...
keen senses.
Morning.
When the body starts to fail...
medicine takes over.
Morning. Kim, Sean.
How're you feeling?
Ready. Today's the day.
How are you doing?
OK.
Surgeons are
arrogant enough to think
there's no one we can't save.
- You need a consult?
- Kim Allan.
She has stage-four
large cell lung cancer.
I removed a second mass from
her right lung about two months ago,
but tests show the
cancer had spread
to her lymph nodes
and to her liver.
She was readmitted last
week with pulmonary edema.
I drained as much
fluid as I could,
but she's having a
tough time breathing.
That's too bad. You
gonna have to intubate her?
- She doesn't want that.
- You have to treat her
palliatively.
I don't see what else
we can do for her.
- She wants us to help her die.
- Like I said,
dying isn't easy.
Since the state requires
two physicians' signatures,
I've asked Dr. Hunt
to look over your chart.
OK.
Her prognosis says that she
has less than six months to live.
I have informed her of
her treatment options.
She has met with a
psychologist who has determined
that she is mentally fit.
And this can serve as
her second oral request.
OK.
You have to say it.
Washington State says
I have to hear you ask two
times at least 15 days apart.
It's so weird.
It's like I'm applying to die.
If you're having
second thoughts...
You saw how bad
it got last night.
It's just gonna get worse.
I would like to end my life
through
physician-assisted suicide.
Excuse me, um...
I'm just gonna go see what's up.
Dr. Altman?
How long does it take?
To die?
Once I take the barbiturates.
Can we not talk about
this? It's just, um...
We're not there yet.
We are there, Sean.
We are.
Kim, to answer your question...
about 45 minutes.
It takes about
45 minutes to die.
Three dates. No
sex. Just talking.
Do you have any idea
how much you can learn
about someone if
you remain upright?
I bet you didn't know Teddy
hates the word "moist."
Hates it. Would really
prefer people say "damp."
You hear me? I'm growing again.
- I'm, like, grown.
- - She's making cartilage from scratch.
She's preoccupied
these days. It's super hot.
- I'm gonna be late.
- Bye.
She doesn't want kids.
Arizona doesn't want kids. In
her womb, in her house. Ever.
- She told me.
- What did you say?
Nothing. We're doing so
great. I don't want to ruin it
by being the crazy desperate
girl with the aching womb.
Better than being the
crazy childless woman
who sits at the playground
watching the children play.
They have laws
for people like that.
You gotta tell her.
So in the third quarter
of the collection,
rate of Medicaid was
what percent again?
Hey. Would you
excuse me one second?
OK. You have 30 seconds.
OK. So this woman comes
into the ER with abdominal pain.
She's had it on and
off for about six months,
and a lot of doctors have told
her it's either an ulcer or gastritis.
Get to the point.
You have 15 seconds.
So it occurs to me that the
nausea is probably caused
- by a positional shift...
- CSF. Brain tumor. Got it.
Not just any brain tumor. She's
got this huge, beautiful ependymoma.
- So Shadow Shepherd...
- Dr. Nelson.
OK, Shadow Shepherd is going
to do intraventricular resection
and let me assist.
And I may even get
to debulk the tumor.
That's it?
OK, sorry for the interruption.
So where were we?
Percentage third quarter Medicaid.
What was the rate of return?
- How close?
- Two minutes.
- It's Nicole, right?
- Three guys waiting
on an ambulance?
- Must be Nicole
behind the wheel.
- Have you seen her ass?
Man, I'd love to hit that.
- Morning, chief.
- Sorry about that, chief.
It's quite all right.
And I am not the chief.
- Hey, Nicole!
- Hey.
Nick Kelsey, 32, injured
skiing off a helicopter.
- Vital signs are stable.
- Wasn't the helicopter
that did it.
- It was the avalanche.
- Idiotic either way.
He's got two idiot friends coming in
behind him but he's got the worst of it.
Open fracture to the left
tibia and left hip fracture.
What are you looking at, chachi?
What happened? We were
in the middle of a consult.
You're her doctor. You
shouldn't push her to do that.
I offered her options. I
told her about hospice.
She doesn't want to die a slow
death hooked up to machines
or be so heavily sedated
she might as well be dead.
And I have to say, I don't
blame her. This is an act of mercy.
Act of mercy? You're killing
her. Just so you're clear,
by writing that prescription,
you're killing that woman.
All right, then.
I'll find someone else.
Watch it, watch it! Heads up!
You need to work on your
passing game, Hunt, you ball hog.
You need to work on your game!
- On your four!
- No!
- Not a chance, major!
- Get it!
- Watch out, watch out,
watch out!
- I got him! I got him!
Break it up, break it
up, break it up, you two.
- We're only down by three.
- Yeah, because you suck!
Don't be insubordinate.
Sir, you suck, sir.
- I mean, Dan, you play
like my grandma.
- Whatever.
Get your battle rattle.
Time to go to work.
Owen, come on!
I need to reduce this ankle
dislocation. Give him ten of morphine.
We need to treat his frostbite.
You like the tips of your fingers?
- Yes, please.
- You jumped out of
a helicopter on skis?
Yeah. You can't get powder
like that anywhere else.
I'm seeing fluid
around your kidney.
We're gonna need to
do a CT of your abdomen.
Do what you gotta do. Me and
the guys are running with the bulls
in Pamplona next year.
Gotta be up on my feet.
Hey, Phil, tell those doctors
they need to fix you up
so you can run with
the bulls next year!
- You're an active guy.
- Once a year, anyhow.
Better than nothing. Once
a year, we live like men.
- You almost died like men.
- On my count.
One, two, three!
Big-ass car bomb
waxed half their unit.
They tried to evac, but it
turned into an insurgent fire-fight.
GSW to the abdomen. Let's
stabilize him till we get him to an OR.
Get me some wet bandages
and an occlusive dressing.
All out of those.
OK, uh... some
wet towels and, uh...
That. We'll close him with this.
Gekko, give me that
roll of two-inch tape.
I need a laryngoscope and
E-T tube. I need to intubate!
- Finish this!
- I'm on it!
- Pupils fixed and dilated.
- He's way past go.
- Who's next?
- Over here, sir!
Colonel Mooney, sir, sandstorm's
coming. Command's ordered us to move.
- You're kidding me. When?
- Now, sir.
All right. People,
secure your patients.
I almost have my guy stabilized.
You'll ride with him
on the medevac.
Take my amputation
and the head trauma too.
Hunt, we'll take your GSW
in the APC. Let's move!
- Want me to go?
- No, I'm fine.
- You hate helicopters.
- I know.
I'm fine. I'll see
you back there.
- See you back there.
- Yep.
Shall we scan him first?
See what kind of
damage we're dealing with
in case we need an OR. He's
got some abdominal bruising.
Yeah. Yeah, OK. You take this.
Uh, get him up to CT.
How come you didn't
get hurt in the avalanche?
I never got off the
helicopter. I was about to jump
when the avalanche started.
You missed it, Tommy.
Friggin' awesome!
Yeah, Tommy, friggin' awesome!
Yeah, Tommy, friggin' awesome.
Dr. Altman said you requested
to lower your pain meds?
They make me fuzzy.
I don't want to be fuzzy today.
Did she tell you?
That you're going home? Yeah.
- I changed my mind.
- What?
No, no, not about...
I just... I want to do it here.
In the hospital.
I don't want Sean to have to
deal with my body afterwards.
Don't worry about that stuff.
We can make this
place like home.
You know? Get rid
of all these machines
and get some of our stuff,
my quilt, some pictures.
Some wine.
- Can we have wine?
- I don't see why not.
If you need wine, maybe
you don't really want...
I don't need wine. I want wine.
But I think you're
gonna need it.
You seem scared.
Are you... scared?
Stop worrying about me.
All these things are happening,
and I'm making
all these choices,
and I have no idea
how you're feeling.
- I'm not feeling anything.
- Sean!
I'm talking about
where I'm gonna die.
You have to be
feeling something!
I'll go home and get the stuff.
Sean...
Red or white?
Red.
In a wine glass,
not a plastic cup.
OK.
It never changes.
You have the same fights. I
mean, even when you're dying,
you have the same fights.
You want to know
how they're feeling,
and they don't want to tell you.
- Sorry.
- Don't be.
I think they don't know.
When you ask them
how they're feeling,
and they don't want to tell you,
and you think
they're being difficult?
I think they really don't know.
OK, relax. Deep
breaths. Deep breaths.
Good.
Where do you stand on
physician-assisted suicide?
I'm not opposed to it.
As long as we're talking
about controversial stuff,
let's get something straight:
Arena Football is not real football.
Mark. Mark, wait.
This is not me getting
to know you. This is...
I have a patient who's terminal.
She wants to die, and she
wants my help. And I want yours.
See that? The tumor's
pressing down on the floor
of the fourth ventricle,
which is causing the nausea.
So you debulk the tumor, and
then you move on to the stalk?
No. You debulk the tumor.
Dr. Shepherd has requested these
scans. His schedule has freed up.
He's decided to do
the resection himself.
Oh, no! That's
my... I am debulking.
- It's my tumor.
- It's Dr. Shepherd's tumor now.
- Dr. Hunt, can I help you?
- No. No, I got it.
Oscar-four-kilo,
this is echo-five-golf.
- Anything, sergeant?
- No, sir. I think
it's the storm.
Well, they know we're
coming, right? All right.
- Where are we going?
- Green Zone, baby.
They'll stabilize you.
Then you are going to
a hospital in Germany,
and then you're
gonna go home. OK?
- Teddy get there yet?
- No word.
Don't worry, I'm sure
your girl's just fine.
Stop it. I'm serious.
We're friends.
Keep telling yourself that.
Hunt! You all right, Hunt?!
- I'm OK! You OK?
- Yeah.
We must've hit an IED.
- How're the patients?
- I don't know.
I gotta find 'em all.
Everyone's gone. We lost Gekko.
Dan? Dan!
Owen?
- Owen.
- What?
You paged.
When you did Kim Allan's
evaluation, did you scope her?
- What? Wait, is that her chart?
- Dr. Altman's patient,
who, according to this, you ordered
pulmonary function tests one week ago.
I'd like to know if, during that
evaluation, you did a bronchoscopy.
- Is there a problem?
- Answer the question!
- Why are you interrogating me?
- PFTs can give you
false positives,
and a patient may kill
herself due to incorrect data.
It's routine, so
we probably did.
Probably is good enough for you?
Probably is good
enough for Dr. Altman?
What is going on? Are...?
Owen.
- Did you call Lani?
- Um, you should call your wife.
She'll freak. Tommy,
call her when I go in.
Downplay it. It's a broken leg.
A little frostbite
on your fingers,
but nothing terrible.
You're about to...
scream really loud.
That was worse than when I
broke my ankle on Kilimanjaro.
- You climbed Kilimanjaro?
- Couple years ago.
I made it to the summit, while
these guys got altitude sickness
- half a mile from the top.
- You guys
are hard-core.
We gotta be. I sell insurance.
Phil and Tommy are accountants.
These trips are all we got
to keep our blood moving.
Show them the picture of you on
top of Kili with the rubber chicken.
That doesn't look like
you on a mountain.
Oh, sorry. That's my
daughter, Hannah.
Ladybug for Halloween.
You telling me you
don't want one of those?
You stole my surgery,
right out from under me.
It wasn't your surgery.
It was Nelson's surgery.
It's beyond Nelson's skill level.
Right? That's what you said.
My diagnosis, my tumor, my
debulking. Can I scrub in at least?
You're on Nelson's service.
If I switch you, it's
gonna look like favoritism.
- Dr. Nelson's been
given an aneurysm.
- You stop talking!
- Calm down, people are staring.
- You stole my surgery.
He stole my surgery!
- Everything OK?
- Yeah. It's fine.
Everything's, uh... fine.
Have you had lunch yet
today? I'm headed down.
I can't eat in the
cafeteria anymore.
Vultures won't leave me alone.
- Vultures?
- People need things from me.
Seems like everybody has a
pressing problem that can't wait.
- Shepherd, you have a minute?
- See?
My lunch is making me sad,
and I haven't started eating it yet.
- Say something.
- Shut up.
I was gonna go for lasagna. I don't
know why I didn't pull the trigger.
- Say it.
- Shut up!
- Say what?
- Nothing!
Hello?
OK, then.
You don't say it, you're
gonna regret it for a long, long...
- Enough!
- OK. What is it with you two?
- What is your problem?!
- Teddy...
You go to Shepherd behind my back
about a patient you don't even know.
You have no idea what
she's been dealing with,
the kind of pain that she's in,
pain that's only gonna be worse
after I ram a tube down her throat
because you're
having some problem
with her exercising
her legal right to die.
So I want to know what
the hell is your problem?
You missed it. Altman tore
Hunt a new one in the cafeteria.
The whole hospital's
talking about it.
Not to me.
I walk in a room, and all the
conversation grinds to a halt.
Come on. You don't talk
locker-room talk in front of the coach.
I'm not a coach
anymore, I'm a player.
I take a shower
like everybody else.
Richard. You're a little
bit like everybody else,
but mostly, you're
still the coach.
It's a sign of respect.
You'd be wrong to
take it any other way.
You know the drill. We've
put you in a twilight state.
Next, we're gonna spray
lidocaine in the back of your throat
- and pass the scope...
- I don't get it.
She had this test last week. Is
there a chance the results are wrong?
- It's very unlikely.
- But it's possible?
You wouldn't put her through
this again for no reason.
You must think there's a
chance the tests were wrong.
There are questions being raised
that have nothing to do with...
By who? Raised by who?
- Sean...
- Just talk to me!
'Cause I'm standing here
thinking my wife's gonna die today,
and if that's not gonna happen,
if there's a chance that
she might get better...
Your wife isn't
gonna get better.
This test is unnecessary, and
the hospital is covering its ass.
- Thank you.
- No problem.
Julie, can you find out if
Dr. Bailey's on her way?
OK, doctor.
If I wasn't happily married,
I'd hit her.
I'd hit her hard.
Sir, I think what you
wanted to say was "hit that."
I don't think you
wanted to say that at all.
I hear Shepherd
took your surgery.
- How'd you hear that?
- Apparently,
you yell really loud.
Well, I have to hold a
retractor for Shadow Shepherd
while Derek debulks my
tumor. So yes, I yell very loud.
Yeah, well, the key
is to think of yourself
- as one of the Whos
down in Whoville.
- What?
You know, when the Grinch
came down and stole their presents,
they didn't let that
ruin Christmas for them.
Instead, they came out
on Christmas morning,
and they sang.
You're gonna go into that
surgery and you're gonna sing.
Sing, Cindy Lou. Sing.
Your scalp lac is small
enough that shooting in lidocaine
would be more painful than
throwing in a couple staples.
- Is this gonna hurt
like my fingers?
- Not too much.
Sorry. Sorry!
OK, that's it. Got it.
The hand was swelling so much,
it would have
popped the finger off.
What?
You still trying
to save the arm.
You gotta tourniquet it.
- If I do, you'll lose it.
- It's not about the arm.
If I can tie off that
brachial artery...
Owen! It's not about the arm.
You're right. I
know. You're right.
Dan, listen to me.
The back of this truck, it is
trashed. Most of the supplies,
all of the morphine. There's
no morphine, no lidocaine.
You bring whiskey?
OK, we got it. We
got it. We got it.
No... I don't think we do.
Dr. Hunt?
Kim Allan's bronchoscopy confirmed
that nothing more can be done.
Sloan signed off. He did
his due diligence, but it's over.
You're not gonna kill him.
I won't let you kill him.
- You're not gonna kill him.
- Dr. Hunt!
The patient in
question is a woman,
and no one is
trying to kill her.
She's choosing to die.
You should go home.
- I have a surgery.
- You're done for the day.
Go home.
OK. OK.
Can you... can you hold this?
- Can you put pressure there?
- I don't...
OK, I'm gonna have to move you.
I can't. I can't. I'm too tired.
No, no, no! Dan,
wake up! Wake up!
I have to.
It's gonna hurt like hell,
but I have to find something
to pack this wound
till someone comes.
Someone's coming?
OK, here we go.
Here we go.
Please, please! Please! Please!
Sorry. I'm sorry.
There we go. There we go.
Hypothermia.
That's the last one.
Stop that.
Someone is coming.
Help is coming.
You've been
saying that for hours.
I'm coagulopathic.
I'm probably acidotic.
I'm in the triad of death.
No one is coming.
- If I could just move you.
- I need you.
I need you to say
a Hail Mary with me.
Dan.
- I don't know it.
- That's OK.
It's OK. Just say it with me.
- Hail Mary...
- full of grace.
- Full of grace.
- The Lord is with Thee.
Blessed art thou among women...
blessed is the fruit
of thy womb, Jesus.
Blessed is the fruit
- Holy Mary, Mother of God.
- Pray for us sinners...
now and the hour of our death.
Now and the hour of our death.
- Amen.
Make sure Lisa gets
my ring. All right?
Don't give up, Dan.
Don't use it to propose
to Altman or something.
But you should
propose to Altman.
You know, you two... You should.
- You should.
- Shut up. I'm engaged to Beth.
And you, you're gonna
give that ring to Lisa.
OK?
- Come on. Come on.
- No.
- Move your hand.
- That's an order, soldier.
- No, sir.
They're working
on Nick's kidney.
I was able to
stabilize his legs,
but it's gonna be a
long recovery process.
You may need to let his wife know
it's a little bit more than a broken leg.
Yeah. I told my wife,
and she's calling Lani.
My wife can handle her better.
So you summited Kili,
you run with the bulls,
but you're scared
of your friend's wife?
I was scared on Kili.
- I hated every minute of it.
- So why do it?
Nick and Phil.
They're my boys. And
they love adventure.
Me? I got a kid.
And bad knees.
But I can't ruin it. We're
a team, you know?
- So you just suck it up?
- Close my eyes
and hope I don't die.
I can't actually
give you the drugs,
but you can have this prescription
filled in the hospital pharmacy.
Again, I want to emphasize
there are other options.
We can make you comfortable.
- I just have one question.
- Owen, no.
What if they find a cure? I
know that it's a long shot,
but isn't saving your life
worth gambling on a long shot?
- Dr. Hunt, I will
call security if...
- Let her answer.
I'd like to hear the answer.
Maybe...
you have to be
dying to understand,
but there's this
thing that happens...
where death stops being scary.
What starts being scary is hope.
'Cause it's not true.
Even if they found a
cure for cancer tomorrow...
it's too late for me.
And hanging onto hope, it
may make you feel better...
but it just makes me feel alone.
I don't want to die alone.
OK?
I am not afraid of this.
Why are you?
Why are you so
afraid to let me die?
Dr. Hunt?
The pharmacy wouldn't
take my insurance card.
There was some problem,
so I had to go to
a cash machine.
And I'm running around
trying to get enough cash
to buy the pills that
are gonna kill my wife.
Anyway...
here they are.
There'll be a moment...
when she dies, her
face will relax, and...
all that pain that she
was in will be gone.
And you will feel relief.
Relief for her, relief for you.
You will know with
absolute certainty
that you did the right thing.
Just for a moment.
You gotta let me go, Owen.
OK? You gotta let me
go, please. This hurts.
It hurts.
It's OK. It's OK.
It's OK. Look at me.
OK. You gotta do it.
You gotta do it. I
can't make you do it.
OK. Please, it hurts.
It hurts. It hurts, it's OK.
It's OK. It's OK.
OK. You gotta do it.
You have to hold
on to that moment,
because all the rest of it
is just your own garbage.
You'll be in physical
therapy for six months,
but, with luck, you'll be
ready for your trip next year.
- Pamplona, baby!
- Pamplona!
Pamplona!
Oh, come on.
He hates this stuff.
The adrenaline, the adventure.
He does this just for you guys
because you guys
love it, and he loves you.
And... that's my
rant for the day.
I'm sorry. I like to see people
keep their legs. Ignore me.
I'm starting my own business.
Keeps my blood pumping.
I'm with Tommy.
Sorry, Nick.
I can't believe you guys.
I almost died jumping out
of a helicopter when I wanted
to go wine-tasting in Napa.
Napa!
Place looks different.
Something's different.
- Something I can help you with?
- You were jealous of her today.
- I'm sorry?
- Meredith.
That's why you
stole her surgery.
You miss the pace of back-to-back
surgeries, the adrenaline.
Yeah, I do.
Schedule yourself
one surgery a day.
In the morning, early, an
hour before anyone else.
So at the very least,
you start your day good,
you start your day cutting.
You don't have to
sign all the paperwork.
Patricia is an excellent forger.
If you eat alone in the
cafeteria, you are a sitting duck.
You need to eat
with someone else.
That way, people are more
likely to leave you alone.
You can eat with me.
Thank you.
Living is better than dying.
Until it's not.
I'm scared.
Come here.
But even if letting a person
die is the right thing to do...
it's not what
surgeons are built for.
We are arrogant and competitive.
I'm sorry.
I know you're mad at me.
I'm not mad.
- I'm in Whoville.
- Whoville?
Whoville.
We don't like to lose.
Um...
This is really
hard for me to say
'cause I really care
about you and...
Oh, my God, you're
breaking up with me.
Mark? Is it Mark? Are you
sleeping with Mark again?
Are you one of those fake lesbians
having a vacation in lesbian land?
No. Stop.
God, it's not bad.
This thing I have
to tell you isn't bad.
Um... I just...
I want to have a baby.
At some point in my life.
That's all.
I really... I have
to have a baby.
And death feels like a loss...
even when we know it's not.
We know it's time.
- We know it's right.
- Hey, there.
- Hey.
- Come in.
I helped my patient die today.
You wanna talk about it?
No.
We know we did
everything we could.
It's OK. You gotta do it.
You gotta do it. I
can't make you do it.
You gotta do it.
OK.
What are you...?
I couldn't sleep.
Are you OK?
But it's hard to
shake the feeling
that you could have done more.
Yeah. I'm fine. Go back to bed.
Owen...
- What are you thinking?
- Nothing.
Nothing.
Go back to bed.