♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
Addison?
Sweetheart, open the door.
No, I'm fine. Thanks.
Open the door
so we can talk.
Oh.
Talking.
Talking is so overrated.
No, it's okay. I'm fine.
Thanks. Go away.
We can, uh, you know,
talk later.
Addison, I don't--i don't want
you to feel embarrassed.
No, it's okay.
Clearly, I had it coming.
I did the same thing to Sam
when he proposed to me,
so karmically, you know,
I mean, Karma...
Is so awesome.
I-I didn't say no.
You didn't say anything,
which is... fine.
It's fine. It's fine.
Because now i'm...
Locked in the bathroom
like a crazy person,
which I'm sure makes me
so attractive to you.
You want me so badly right now,
I'm betting.
I love you.
I love you--the brilliant,
the stunning, the bitchy,
the crazy in the morning,
in the afternoon, 3:00 P.M.--
okay, just stop.
Don't say anymore.
All right? 'Cause you say
these nice things,
and it just makes me
more in love with you
and that just makes me
want to marry you more,
which isn't helping,
because I just proposed to you,
and you didn't say yes.
Or no. I-I didn't say no.
Baby, just open the door,
please.
I am in this. All right?
No questions,
no reservations.
Do you not want
to get married?
It's not that.
It's just--
it's a big step.
The biggest step. And I...
I want us to be ready.
So that's a no?
It's not a no.
It's just a...
Not right now.
You're gonna lock yourself
in the bathroom again.
Okay, well, I'm gonna be
right outside here,
on the other side of the door.
Right here. I'm not--
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm gonna be right here.
So what's new?
That was pretty big,
don't you think?
I don't want to talk about it.
Not with you.
I don't think that's true.
I mean, you're here,
in our spot.
You know if you come,
I'll show up.
Don't give me the look.
I'm only here
because you want me to be here.
It's been a while
since we caught up.
I've been busy.
I know.
It's good.
You're happy.
I want you to be happy.
I want you
to forget about me.
That's never gonna happen.
So here is the thing--
I didn't say no.
I'm still thinking about it.
What did I say?
To never mention it again.
Addison--
never mention it again.
Please, sweetie.
Everything's normal.
It never happened.
Okay. So what's the thing?
Oh, Mildred,
the social worker.
I told her about
our status change.
What?
The move, that you moved in.
So she needs to meet with you
before the hearing,
because until Henry is
officially mine,
you know, by law, I have
to update her every time--
a new guy moves in?
Of course I will meet
with Mildred.
Yeah?
You're okay with that?
Hey. I love Henry.
I love you. I'm okay.
Are we okay?
Absolutely. You love Henry.
You love me.
I love you.
We're good.
Have either of you
been sleeping?
Not me.
Not since Sarah went missing.
But Dana...
The pills help, I think.
Dana?
Yeah.
They do.
They help me.
And when I sleep,
Sarah's there, smiling.
Sometimes
I can even hear her.
Well, it's been about
six weeks,
and I wonder if...
Perhaps we should consider
weaning you off the pills.
I don't think
that's a good idea.
I'm worried that she's becoming
too dependent on them.
So what?
What's wrong with that?
This medication
can be addictive.
It's not meant
for long-term use,
and I think it's having
a-a numbing effect on Dana.
That's the point.
You want her to feel this?
She can't feel this,
because I'm feeling this,
and I gotta tell you,
that if one of us didn't need
to be conscious,
if one of us didn't need
to talk to the cops
or make a public plea,
if we could both be numb--
I would be taking anything
to not feel this.
You can't take away her pills.
Ron--
no. No. No.
She falls asleep,
and for a couple of hours,
it's okay.
But then she wakes up,
and...
This nightmare that we're living
is back.
She starts to scream
because we don't know
where our baby is.
I cry.
When I wake up, it hits me
again, and I cry.
He holds me.
He's been good to me.
He's there.
So you're leaning
on each other.
In the face of this tragedy,
your reconciliation, it...
It's a positive.
I can't believe it.
You're sure?
I'm sure.
Well, maybe fifth time's
the charm.
Oh, it's early yet,
but I'm confident.
Just remember to take it easy
and stay calm.
That's--that's so important.
And you call me
if you're worried about
anything, all right?
Oh, I can't wait
to call Danny.
He's at a conference
in Hong Kong,
but he's gonna be
so thrilled.
Thank you, Dr. Reilly.
Sure.
Uh, Megan, you remember
Dr. Montgomery.
Of course.
Um, your boyfriend's
a genius.
Mm.
I'm pregnant again.
Congratulations.
Thanks again, Dr. Reilly.
Sure.
Now listen,
I-I did tell Megan
that it might be time
to consider other options.
Ahem.
I did, but she begged me
to try at least one more time,
so...
Addison.
Mm?
I did not say anything.
We agreed to disagree.
Your patient...
Your practice,
your prerogative.
Ah.
Dr. Shepherd.
Dr. Peterson.
So glad you could join me.
Oh. That's yours?
I forgot my orange soda.
You can only get it in
the vending machine up on four.
Busy day?
About normal.
Me? I had 12 patients--
all emergent,
all within a half-hour.
It was crazy.
Reminded me of when I used to
wait tables back in the day.
Mm.
This is nice.
What is?
You and I
having lunch together.
Not together.
You are eating lunch.
I'm eating lunch. We happen to
be doing that at the same table,
so, you know, not a date.
Of course it's not a date.
If it were,
you'd be enjoying yourself.
We'd be having
a picnic on the beach--
I don't like sand in my food.
Which is why the mountains
are ideal.
We could have dinner
in front of the fireplace
at some historic lodge--
air is too thin
in the mountains.
Hard to breathe.
Doesn't sound like much fun.
Not compared to
the happiest place on earth.
How about Disneyland?
How about we eat
at the same table,
not together, in silence?
Um, you should know--
dude, silence.
Right. Don't call me "dude."
And there's ketchup
on your face.
What, tomorrow? I thought
it would take Mildred
at least a week
to set the appointment up.
It's fine.
I know what to say.
So what are you gonna say
when she asks you
about you and Henry?
I'll explain that I only
give him glass and knives
to play with when I leave him
alone for hours on end.
Jake.
Stop worrying.
Isn't that Angela?
Hi!
Hey, honey. Wow.
What a nice surprise.
Yeah. Addison, hi.
Hi.
Now wait a second.
Shouldn't you, uh,
shouldn't you be studying?
Dean's list every semester.
Are you seeing, um...
Yes. My boyfriend wanted
to see it, so...
Oh, Ethan's here?
No. I moved on.
What'd he do?
It's less of what did
and more of what he was--
a total jerk, you know,
stupid frat boy.
I'm way too good for that.
Yeah, you are.
Hey. Baby.
Hey.
Hi. I'm--I'm Addison.
Addison, yes.
I'm Eli Wilson.
Yeah. This is Jake.
How you doing?
Dr. Jake Reilly,
Angela's father.
Of course. Angela's told me
so much about you.
I'm in awe of m.D.S.
I'm a doctor, but I'm a phd.
It's not the same.
No.
So you teach?
Human sexuality.
That's where we met,
in class.
Human sexuality class?
I see.
Hey, Eli.
The movie's about to start.
Uh, it was great to meet you,
and, uh, you are even
more beautiful than ange said.
Oh.
See you later.
Wow.
Not a word.
Not a single word.
I mean, what the hell is
she thinking?
That he's handsome,
sophisticated, a doctor.
He's not a doctor.
He's a teacher.
I was a teacher.
You know what I mean.
She's a grown woman.
No. No, she's not.
She's a little girl clunking
around in her daddy's shoes,
pretending to go off to work.
You need to let her
make her own mistakes,
take her own path.
I'm worried about her.
This is...
This is bad.
Well, it could be worse.
How?
She could be a drug addict,
like her mom.
He's 50?
Seriously?
I could date him,
except he's a little old
for me.
It's a disaster
in the making.
You don't know that.
I mean, if Angela was 40,
and the guy was near 70--
we'd think maybe she was
after his money.
It's a phase.
It's never gonna work.
Well, of course
it's never gonna work.
How can you be
in a meaningful relationship
with someone who's more
than twice your age?
Except that the maturity is part
of what attracts her to him.
Well, she should date
a grad student then.
Jake must be
blowing a gasket.
Why is he blowing a gasket?
And more importantly,
why are we whispering?
Jake's daughter is dating
a man way too old for her.
Oh.
You do know
that Jake isn't here, right?
Sam, Angela's 20.
She's a woman.
- 20's not a woman.
- Maya's 19, and she's a mother.
Giving birth
does not imply maturity.
Fathering a child
certainly doesn't.
Oh, you can't generalize.
You know, 70 degrees in may
doesn't seem quite as warm
as 70 in December.
See, I like what you did there
with the may and December.
I'm saying that every 20
is different,
and your transition from boy
to man, form girl to woman,
depends on
individual circumstance
and life experience.
He's her professor.
Oh.
Well, then forget it.
There's definitely a...
Questionable power dynamic
there.
Mm. Sometimes the student has
the power.
Mm.
Did you sleep
with a professor?
Not so much a as...
Three.
Three? When did you study?
Oh.
Was one of them a woman?
Look, I was fairly troubled
in college.
It was a dark time for me.
So exploring
my sexual boundaries
was a way of taking back
my sexuality.
And one of them was a woman?
Look, no parent
wants to think
of one of their contemporaries
as helping their child explore
sexual boundaries.
There's something wrong
with this professor guy.
He needs to find a playmate
his own age.
Yeah, well, Angela seems
pretty taken with him,
and Jake's gonna
have lunch with her today
and--and talk about it.
He--he thinks it'll be okay.
Yeah, he's dreaming.
Mm-hmm.
I understand
you have a child?
I do. Angela.
Her mother passed away
quite a while ago.
Angela's in college,
and we're very close.
We, uh, we talk all the time,
you know, about--
about everything.
I'm sure
you think so.
Excuse me?
I have five children.
They share the trivial stuff
just to throw you off the scent
of the really bad stuff.
Yeah, well,
I-I gather as much,
but even with all the hell
they put you through,
uh, you know, I adore kids.
I love Henry as though
he were my own,
and, you know, I do have
experience in this, uh,
I mean, even though ange
hasn't lived with me
for quite some time,
parenthood is a lot like, uh,
riding a bike, right?
No. When you make a mistake
riding a bike,
you fall,
you break your own neck.
When parenting a child, failure
can be harder to notice
and impossible to fix.
Okay. But the odds are better
for Henry
because he has Addison and me
sharing the responsibilities.
And you both work.
Right. Um, but one of us is
always there for Henry.
I mean,
he's never left alone.
There's a home inspection
component to this.
I'd like to come by
in a day or two.
Please have the child present.
Absolutely.
What, uh,
what is that?
I need to send your fingerprints
electronically
to the department of justice.
Part of the background check.
Place your finger
on the scanner.
Please try not to move.
Dr. Reilly,
is there a problem?
No.
No, of course not.
Hey. How'd it go?
Mildred's a little scary.
Well, I told you
what she was like.
Yeah, I wish
you would've told me
about the, uh,
fingerprinting, too.
Oh, I thought I did.
Why? You got a record
that I should know about?
Jake.
It's gonna sound
a lot worse than it is.
Okay. Start talking right now,
'cause I'm freaking out.
It was a long time ago.
Lily's--
Lily started using again,
and her dirtbag dealer
came over to the house,
our house, so I went outside
to tell him to go away.
He refused, and things got
a little out of hand,
so there was a fight.
I was protecting
my--my wife and child.
Okay. So you hit him.
That doesn't sound so bad.
Well, that wouldn't be so bad,
but I beat the crap out of him,
the cops came,
and I was arrested.
Did you go to jail?
Just for a night.
But I got out on bail.
I was sentenced to probation,
did some community service.
The thing is,
when you're arrested,
they take your prints
and they stay in the system,
so if Mildred
runs my prints...
Henry's my son.
This adoption is
everything to me.
Addison, this dealer
was an animal
with a rap sheet longer than
"war and peace."
Okay? The judge--
he understood my side.
So if Mildred reads my file,
she's gonna understand, too.
It's gonna be okay.
I promise.
So...
How's school?
That's not
what you wanna ask.
I was easing into it.
Don't.
All right, look, I'm sure Eli is
a very nice man.
Actually, you know what?
I'm not sure.
I think this is
a very bad idea.
I don't need your permission.
You used to trust me.
I believe I've earned the right,
as your father, who loves you,
to at least state my opinion.
It would be different
if he weren't your professor.
For one semester.
Then he won't be
my professor anymore.
But we both know
that's not what this is about.
You don't like
how old he is.
No, I don't. He's my age.
Someday I'll be your age.
And then,
if you still want to,
you can date him
in the nursing home.
So if he was ten years younger
than you, that would be okay?
I mean, what's the cutoff?
39? 28?
Listen, sweetheart, you're--
you're on--
you're on different planes.
All right? He's got 30 years
more experience.
You're into your what,
second real relationship? Hmm?
He'll hurt you.
Ethan hurt me.
He was my age.
What looks right on paper
isn't always right.
You married a drug
addict and you were happy.
I'm trying to protect you.
I don't need protection.
I'm an adult.
Not if you have to say it.
I love you, dad,
but I also love Eli.
So don't make me choose, because
you're not gonna like my choice.
You think that social worker
will find out?
I don't know.
I thought you were
gonna kill that guy.
I would've done anything
to protect you and ange.
I still would,
if it matters.
It does matter.
You need to suck it up.
Don't--don't tell me
to ease up on Eli.
I'm telling you to be there for
our daughter because I can't.
So hey, whatever that means.
Lily--
no. No.
You push too hard the other way,
she will marry him.
You know that, right?
Dr. Shepherd, we have to stop
meeting like this.
Don't get too excited,
Dr. Peterson.
I'm just signing off
on a consult.
Do you think
you could call me James
and I could call you Amelia?
Nope.
Okay, well, that'll make
my next question tougher.
You know, Billy's
on north canyon?
I'm there every Friday night.
Really, really good fries.
Anyway, you should come.
How many times are you
gonna ask me out on a date?
I wasn't. I was just saying,
I eat dinner there,
and you could
eat dinner there,
and if we happen to be
doing that
at the same table,
so be it.
And we don't have to talk
at all.
Think about it.
You know,
really, really good fries
are hard to come by.
Mm.
No more mentions of Sarah.
It's been a while. She went
missing from the E.R.,
what...
Six weeks ago.
And three days.
I hope
that she's still alive.
They found Elizabeth smart
after nine months.
Well,
that's the exception.
The odds of finding
a missing child
drop exponentially
after the first couple of days.
Her parents--i don't--
I don't know how you live
through something like that.
I guess at some point,
you gotta move on, right?
And when exactly is that,
would you say?
I'm asking. Seriously,
weeks? Months?
When is it okay
to move on with your life?
Never.
It's not that simple.
Letting go takes time.
You're plagued with memories
and betrayal
and guilt.
You know,
after Angela's mother died,
I think it took me a year
to smile again.
As for letting go, I think
that just depends on the person.
Yeah. In this situation,
there's no body,
and therefore no closure.
Exactly.
It's all speculation.
So if Sarah's alive
and comes back after Ron
and Dana have given up,
they'll never forgive
themselves.
But if she's dead,
and they don't move on,
they could spend decades
just waiting.
I... I don't know
how to counsel them.
So lunch didn't go so great.
Well, what did you think,
once you told her
that you didn't approve,
that Angela would just end it?
She likes him.
Apparently, she loves him.
I mean, what the hell does
she see in the guy anyway?
I'm not sure I can answer that
without getting in trouble.
All right, I'm sure the guy
has his positive attributes,
and if he weren't the lech
after my daughter,
I might even see them.
This--this can't go on.
Well, it can
if they want it to.
I mean, honey, there's really
nothing that you can do.
I can call the university
and have him fired.
Well, that will all but ensure
that she marries the guy.
Look, Angela's a smart girl.
She's gonna figure it out.
But I tell you what, she's gonna
get there a lot faster
if the two of you make peace.
What? No.
Yes. You need to suck it up
and invite them over
for dinner.
Oh, no.
Megan's in the E.R.
I'm so happy you're here.
I started cramping and I kept
trying to stay calm
and tell myself all the stuff
you always say,
but it wasn't working.
Something is definitely wrong.
No, Megan, you know that
mild cramping is normal
after fertility treatments.
I know. But this--
your beta h.C.G. Is fine.
Your os is closed.
There's no bleeding.
There's no discharge.
It's too early to see anything
on the ultrasound,
but your--
your tests were normal.
You're scared.
That--that's all.
Oh.
Oh, god.
Uh, I'm that person.
I'm the crazy patient
who freaks out every 15 minutes
and pulls you away
from your life.
I'm so sorry.
Come on now.
No need to apologize.
No, I do. I'm so embarrassed.
Oh.
I'm not this fragile person.
Really, I'm not.
It's just--
Danny's away, and this is
our fifth time trying.
And no matter
how hard I try to relax,
I'm just... waiting.
For what?
To lose the pregnancy.
Last time I made it 12 weeks,
which was a big improvement
over four,
but nine months--
that's an eternity.
And after so many...
Failures...
I just feel like
the odds are against me.
No, Megan, we--we talked
about this. Right?
With every roll of the dice,
your chances of this one
sticking actually improve.
Really?
Yes.
You have to be patient
and have a little faith.
And not be hysterical.
That would help, too.
Okay. Now there's
no medical reason
why I shouldn't
discharge you.
I-I'm not ready to--
I-I just feel better
here in the hospital.
Is that crazy?
No. The hospital's
a safe place to be.
Would you mind--i mean, I know
you're busy and everything,
but could you stay just--
just for a little while?
Just until I'm sure
that everything's okay?
Hey, babe.
Hey.
I'm sorry I'm late.
You were late two hours ago,
but you're in time
for leftovers.
I was at the hospital
with Megan.
What, did she miscarry again?
No. Nothing's wrong
with her medically.
She was scared, though,
thought she was losing her baby,
so I stayed with her.
You were paged
over six hours ago.
Yeah, well, fear
isn't like pain, honey.
You can't just medicate someone
and leave in five minutes.
Well, yeah, you also can't
sign up for nine months of this.
That's what I do,
especially in Megan's case,
with her husband gone
as much as he is.
She needs the extra support.
I think that the level
of doctoring that Megan needs
is bordering
on unreasonable.
That's not fair.
She's making up excuses
to see you.
She thought
something was wrong.
Well, something's
definitely wrong.
Part of it's in her head
and part of it's on you.
What the hell does that mean?
Okay, you seriously cannot see
how you are complicit in this?
You are so kind and so available
that you make it easy
for patients
to take advantage of you.
Look, if I can't be there
for my patients,
if I can't give them
all that I got,
then I might as well
give up medicine.
Okay, but you cannot be there
for all of them all the time.
You've got to set boundaries
because they won't.
Stop. Stop trying to tell me
how to practice medicine,
how to run my life,
because I was doing just fine
before you came along.
But I am here now,
and the choices that you make--
they affect our life.
I mean, how is it
that you can commit
to these women you barely know
and you can't commit to me?
I'm a fertility specialist.
The women that come to me--
when they get pregnant,
it's my job to see them
through the nine months,
and I won't stop doing that,
no matter how jealous
or insecure or crazy you get.
W--
this is not about me.
Really?
Because everything else is.
Nice job pissing off
the entire world.
No, just the women.
Really? You gonna grab Eli
and take him
to a cigar bar then?
Look, I got it from ange,
I got it from Addison.
I don't need it from you.
Well, Addison's right.
Balance, boundaries--
those things matter.
You always gave too much
at the office.
Look, you cannot blame
the drugs on me.
I know.
Okay, 'cause I was there
all the time,
until I couldn't watch you
destroy yourself anymore.
I know.
But what I'm saying is,
you don't have to avoid
going home anymore.
There's no more drugs
in your life,
no more terror,
no more me.
It's just the woman
who loves you, her kid,
and our kid.
There's nothing in your way
except you.
You look like crap.
Thanks.
I just meant--
no, I feel like crap,
so it's fitting.
You know, one of the many things
that I've learned this past year
is to be a very good listener.
I appreciate it,
but the elevator ride is
way too short
for what I've got going on.
Jake.
Dr. Shepherd.
See you.
You know, one of the many things
I've learned over the past year
since I joined the practice
is that apparently,
everyone else's business
is mine,
so I'm just gonna say it--
James is a good guy.
Okay.
Amelia, my daughter is dating
her college professor,
and while I wish
she wasn't dating at all,
if she has to be, then, well,
I think someone like James is
a pretty good catch.
Well, why don't
you date him then?
I'm spoken for.
I don't think of him
like that.
Yes, you do.
It's pretty obvious.
It's just--everything's good
now, you know, and I don't--
you did all that work,
you've come so far,
don't...
Don't walk away
from an opportunity.
You deserve to be happy.
Be happy, Amelia.
This was a brilliant idea.
I'm so glad
I listened to you.
Angela's your daughter
and is the most important thing
in the world.
You and I can resume fighting
after dinner,
but in the meantime,
let's just make the best of it.
Shall we?
Thanks again for having us over.
Yes, thank you.
No, we're just happy
that you could make it on
such short notice, right, honey?
Yes, very happy.
Um, so, Eli,
Angela tells me that you're
a big basketball fan, huh?
And so is Jake.
Oh, is that right?
Well, we should catch
a Lakers game sometime.
I think they have a real shot
at winning it all this year.
You know,
I like Oklahoma city.
They're young, fresh,
no baggage.
Hmm. But the, uh, Lakers have
the veterans and the experience.
That's important
for a balanced team.
Balance is overrated.
I think the rookies
are doing fine on their own.
Dad.
You know, excuse me.
No. Uh...
Let them go.
Look, uh,
I know what
you're thinking.
Oh,
I doubt that very much.
Angela's very special to me.
Sure.
Lovely young woman
who adores you,
who thinks every word out of
your mouth is witty and clever
because she probably
doesn't know
you've been using
those same, old tired lines
on women your age for decades.
Yeah, that's gotta be nice.
I wasn't looking
for an ego boost.
Then what are
you looking for?
Because there is definitely
something wrong here.
When you finished your phd,
she was in diapers.
Look, I understand
your reservations.
She's your daughter.
You're protecting her.
But I'm not a bad guy.
Okay, I was married
to a woman my age for 20 years.
It didn't work out.
So now you've decided to use
the female student population
as your own
personal dating pool?
I have never
dated a student before.
But... Angela is...
Kind and bright
and beautiful
and curious--
I know her attributes.
I raised her.
I love her.
Yeah, well, that's too bad.
'Cause this is over.
I won't stop
seeing your daughter.
I'm not asking.
I'm telling you.
This needs to end.
Or what?
You don't want to find out.
What? I didn't lose my temper.
Semantics. That was
a very thinly veiled threat.
Oh, I meant it.
I know.
Pretty sure he does, too.
Would you want me to give ange
away at their wedding?
Well, I think there's another
wedding to consider before hers.
I told you, I don't want
to discuss that with you.
Look, babe, I...
I get it.
It's hard to let go.
It's still easier than
the alternative.
Which is?
Hanging on to something that's
no longer yours to hang on to.
I didn't know what to do.
She won't...
She won't move.
Dana?
Hey.
Dr. Turner.
What are you doing here?
Ron was worried about you.
She's still here...
In this room.
And I need that.
Her raspberry shampoo...
I can still smell it
on the pillowcase.
And the sand in her shoes
from the last trip
we took to the beach.
I want my baby back.
Where is Sarah?
I wish I could tell you
that Sarah was alive and okay
and coming home tomorrow,
but I don't know that.
Nobody does.
And I'm not sure if you will
ever be able to get closure.
♪♪♪
But you two are still here,
so you need to live.
We can't move on.
I'm--I'm not saying move on.
I'm saying
don't stand still.
Sarah is...
Is our whole life.
We can't just give up on her.
You're not giving up.
You will never give up.
You will never stop waiting
for Sarah to return.
And if she does come back,
then you'll be here,
together,
a stronger family unit
to welcome her
back to the family
that she loves.
What if she doesn't?
♪ like lions ♪
You hope.
♪ Long enough ♪
You hold on tight
to each other.
♪ We're scions ♪
And maybe at some point
this will hurt just
a little bit less.
♪♪♪
♪ Hold on tight ♪
♪ wait till the stars ignite ♪
Mm.
This is Dr. Reilly.
Megan? What's--what's wrong?
Megan?
I'm in here.
Okay, Megan,
talk to me.
What hurts?
I started cramping
really badly.
I can't sit up.
My head is throbbing.
All right, well,
those sound like symptoms
from the progesterone shot
I gave you yesterday.
No.
It's happening again.
I'm losing the baby.
Well, you're not running
a fever.
Have you been spotting at all?
I don't think so.
All right, well, do me a favor.
I want you to take
a couple of deep breaths.
Mm, that's not gonna help.
Please, for me.
Mm. It's not working.
Megan, please.
Keep breathing.
Just slowly. Ready?
I'm starting
to feel better.
Megan, you...
You can't keep doing this.
It's not good for you
or the baby.
What if this is like the others?
What if I can't carry to term?
You have to stop thinking
that way, okay?
I need you to stay focused
on how strong you are
and how your baby is feeding off
of that strength.
Megan, you're a fighter,
and I will be by your side
the entire way, all right?
♪ Long enough ♪
♪ nothing's adding up ♪
All right.
♪ We're scions ♪
♪ oh ♪
Whoa. Wait. What...
What--what are you doing?
I'm thanking you.
No, I'm your doctor.
You're so much more
than that.
You relax me,
you hold my hand,
you--you rub my belly
when the cramping gets bad,
you're here for me
in the middle of the night.
I tailor my approach to each
patient on a need-by-need basis.
You wanted a baby, and I wanted
to help you achieve that goal.
That--that's it.
That's not true.
We have a special connection.
I know you feel it, too.
I...
Megan, I'm sorry if you--
if you misunderstood.
♪♪♪
I-I know I didn't have
an appointment,
but I just wanted
to clear the air.
It's good you came in,
actually.
What's this?
A list of doctors.
I don't understand.
I think it's best that
you choose someone else
to, uh, see you
through your pregnancy.
But...
You said you'd be by my side.
That was before I realized
that my level of care
was being misinterpreted.
You let me know who you choose,
and I'll send over the file.
Now I have a...
I have another appointment.
Megan. How are you feeling?
Your boyfriend made
a pass at me last night.
That is not true.
I don't know how many other
patients he's done this to,
but I bet I'm not the first.
Megan!
He kissed me.
Megan, don't do this.
Where's your husband?
Is he out of town
on business again?
Is he ever here?
You don't know
anything about me.
Does he even want a baby?
Stop it. Stop--
I'm sorry. I am so sorry
that things have not
turned out the way
that you planned,
but that does not give you
the right
to blame the one man
who has tried to help you.
You do not get to lie about him,
not ever.
Come on in. It's open.
Okay, that's Mildred.
I want you to do a guy a solid
and you be
on your best behavior, okay?
What is wrong with you?
Ange, this--
look, this is not
a great time. All right?
I don't care.
You are my only family,
the man I looked up
to my whole life,
and now you're just being--
your father.
All right,
I'm being your father.
I love you, but I don't
like Eli, not for you.
Tell me Eli misunderstood.
Tell me you didn't say
those things to my boyfriend.
Look, it's my job
to keep you safe.
By threatening his life?
Is this a bad time?
I am so sorry. I-I'll do
anything to make it right.
I-I'll call Mildred.
Please, just...
Say something.
It's going to be fine.
I know you're mad,
and you should be,
and you were right about Megan,
about Angela,
about everything.
I'm sorry, truly.
I fully accept
all of your apologies,
but I truly believe that
everything is going to be fine,
because Henry is my son,
and you are the love of my life,
and we're supposed to be
a family,
and Mildred will see that.
I know she will. I just...
I just know it.
You didn't come this morning,
to the bluffs.
You can't just show up here.
I came to say good-bye.
You don't need me anymore.
No.
Don't go.
She loves you.
She trusts you.
She's committed to you.
And you feel the same.
♪ ...out into the world ♪
I'm sorry.
♪ Closing time ♪
Don't be.
Our vows...
They were
till death do us part.
It's time.
♪ Closing time ♪
And it doesn't matter
that you didn't ask her.
♪ So finish your whiskey... ♪
I know you.
Old-school,
gentleman,
and the kind of guy
that thinks the man should ask
the woman to get married.
♪ Can't stay here ♪
Babe...
♪ I know who I... ♪
You gotta bend a little.
♪ Want to take me home ♪
♪ I know who I want
to take me home ♪
♪ I know who I want to take
me home ♪
♪ take me home ♪
♪ closing time ♪
♪ time for you to go out ♪
♪ to the places you will... ♪
I prefer steak fries,
but I guess these'll do.
♪ Closing time ♪
♪ this room won't be open... ♪
Just be careful
with the ketchup.
Mm.
♪ ...or your sisters come ♪
♪ so gather up your jackets ♪
Honey?
Sorry I'm late.
I just got hung up
at the hospital,
and I just w--
♪ closing time ♪
♪ every new beginning ♪
♪ comes from
some other beginning's end ♪
♪ I know who I want
to take me home ♪
♪ I know
who I want to take me home ♪
♪ I know who I want... ♪
Um...
Hi.
I always imagined
I'd be the one to ask.
There'd be flowers and candles,
I'd be wearing a suit,
and it would be
somewhere fantastic.
But this place--
this place is fantastic.
It's ours--
you, me, and Henry.
So...
If you still want to spend
the rest of your life with me,
then...
Ask me again.
Are you sure?
♪ I know who I want
to take me home ♪
I love you,
and you're the last man
I ever want to say that to.
Let's get married.
♪ ...who I want
to take me home ♪
♪ take me home ♪
♪ I know who I want
to take me home ♪
♪ I know who I want... ♪
Let's get married.
♪ To take me home ♪
♪ I know who
I want to take me home ♪
♪ take me home ♪