You know that story, where a
child gets trapped under a car...
and their parent finds
the superhuman strength
to lift the car and
save the child's life?
I always wondered
if that was real.
Are you sure you don't
want me to go with you?
- I could go with you.
- No, I'm fine. I just need a second.
I could go with you. I have the
day off. And you need people.
It's good to show them
that you have people.
You don't want to look like some
lone-wolf assailant with no friends.
All they're doing is
setting a trial date.
It'll take, like, ten minutes.
The security line will take longer.
- Stop fussing!
- Okay, fine!
If you're sure, fine. Good luck.
If someone I cared about,
was hurt or trapped...
would my instincts kick in?
Would I know what to do?
- You want to sit a minute?
- No, I'm fine. I got to go. Bye.
Okay. Well, call me or text me.
And try to come
home early, okay?
Would I lift the car?
Jump in front of the bullet?
Would I be able to beat
somebody senseless?
I like to think I would.
Alex?
- Maybe we sit a minute.
- Okay.
We have time.
I guess this line could
go slower. Except no.
There's no such thing as moving
slower than not moving at all.
So never mind. I take it back.
Yeah, I thought half an
hour early would be enough.
9/11, man. Everybody's
a suspect now.
Look at that lady. Does
she look dangerous to you?
Not really.
Maybe that guy if you
took his coffee away.
I look more dangerous than that
guy and I'm just here for traffic court.
Contesting a ticket.
I totally didn't stop
at the stop sign,
but I'm banking on
the cop not showing up.
They almost never show.
I do not have the money to
throw away on this right now.
Just got knocked up.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
What are you in for?
Just setting a trial date today.
Trial date? Are you dangerous?
How far along?
Early still. Sixteen weeks.
That redness on your
hand, you had it long?
Like a week or so.
Any unusual symptoms?
Leg swelling, abdominal pain?
Okay, you definitely
seem a little weird now.
Sorry. It's a habit. I'm
a doctor at Grey Sloan.
You should get
that rash checked.
No. I got to stick
to the budget now.
I got enough doctor's
visits coming up.
I do not need to add more.
You can afford to see me. I
work at the free clinic there.
Damn it! I'm late.
Get that rash
checked! Think about it!
Yeah.
That's me, the
girl with the rash.
Thanks.
They're setting the trial
date right now, as we speak.
I'm still waiting to hear.
Date? Wow. Makes
it all feel so real.
Yeah, and I know it's good news.
It means the end's
near, but things finally
just started feeling
more normal again here.
Yeah, brings it
all right back up.
You still talk to
Karev at all, or...
We don't talk. We barely
even see each other.
It's a little like he and I
never even existed so...
Yeah.
Gotta go. I'm on Bailey's service.
Tell me if you talk to your lawyer.
All right.
Robbins, have you
met the new resident?
She is great! No, amazing! She's
better than some of my attendings.
Woah! Hold on a second.
I didn't know we
got a new resident.
Yeah, Webber just hired
her. She's... Hold on.
Dr. Robbins, this is...
Murphy!
Dr. Robbins. Hi.
You guys know each other?
- Umm.
- Yes.
Leah... Dr. Murphy used to...
- I used to work here.
- Yes.
I have patients.
You realize your shenanigans
this morning made me late.
Well, you own the hospital.
You can be as late as you want to.
And you can't tell me my
"shenanigans" weren't worth it.
I don't like being late.
- Big surgery?
- Meeting with Bailey.
- Really? What about?
- Well...
You hired Leah Murphy back?
Why? Why? Why?
Why would you do that?
With Blake gone, it
seemed like perfect timing.
I thought you fired her because
she wasn't cut out to be a surgeon.
Yeah, why would
you bring her back?
She did the work
to prove me wrong,
and Foster's Residency
Director said she excelled there,
and I think she deserved
a second chance.
Don't you believe
in second chances?
No!
I mean!
Hey. I'm just
headed up to surgery.
Just wanted to say good morning.
You were gone when I got up.
I get early surgery.
Listen, you... You want
to talk later, maybe?
- I mean, we didn't last night.
- Nope!
Amelia...
people don't always get pregnant
their first try, and I just
don't want you to feel...
Are you kidding? I'm fine!
- You're fine?
- Yeah, I'm good.
I'm great, even. Yeah, for sure.
That's good. That's
good that you're so good.
Incoming! Any second. MVC.
Kid with possible head trauma,
dad with multiple abdominal issues.
- We could use neuro.
- Right behind you.
Robbie Reeves, 12, MVC.
Restrained passenger. Vitals stable.
No LOC on the scene.
Small scalp laceration.
- It was like a roller coaster!
- All right. Robbie,
I'm Dr. Shepherd.
Where's my dad? I got to ask
him how fast we were going.
It looks like he's
pulling in behind you.
- Your head's hurting?
- Barely. Can I ask him?
In a minute. I'm gonna
check you out first.
Bob Reeves, forties, the driver.
Some abdominal bruising, tenuous BP.
Large wounds on the left leg.
Robbie? Where's my son?
Somebody tell me
if my son is here.
Sir, he's here. They just
took him inside, okay?
Okay. Okay. Good. Thank you.
You got some nasty bruising.
You got pretty banged
up out there, Mr. Reeves.
You should see my car.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
All right. Contact
dermatitis, bed four.
Hey, look who showed up.
Well, I can't be
the pregnant lady
who ignores unsolicited
medical advice.
- That lady's a jerk.
- Let's see this rash.
That's all it was,
right? Medical advice?
Because, if you got me worried
just to get a date or get in
some pregnant lady's pants,
- that would make you the jerk.
- Just doing my job... promise.
How long have your
hands been itching?
Uh, like a week, maybe more.
Not that I'm not available.
I am, or, I could be.
A baby belly doesn't
exactly equal baby daddy.
There is a baby daddy.
He's not attached,
I mean, not to me.
- You don't have to explain.
- I kind of do.
Hospitals give me the
creeps, so talking helps.
Okay, so there's a baby daddy.
Jeremy, my best friend,
since we were kids.
We made one of those pacts,
you know, if we both wound up
single at 40, we'd make a baby.
I thought it would be
needles and test tubes,
- turns out that's really pricy.
- Yeah, it's up there. Look this way.
Look the other way.
All right, good.
So, one night, there was
a lot of tequila, and boom!
I got this little parasite
that sucks all my energy.
Silver lining, though...
I've been losing weight.
I always thought that
would go the other way.
You're losing weight. How much?
I don't know,
enough to drop a size.
What? What's that look?
Just want to run some tests. Can
you hang out here for a while today?
You've got me worried again.
Is there something wrong?
Should I call the baby daddy?
Well, if you're stuck here, a
little company couldn't hurt.
You've made no
move to fire Karev.
There's no replacement
surgeon. What is the plan?
Karev's been removed from
surgical service, pending his trial.
I don't understand why
he's still working here at all.
If a doctor on our staff has been
charged with a felony assault,
he should not be a
doctor on our staff.
Well, he's innocent until proven
guilty. We have a justice system.
I don't wanna throw away
a good surgeon's career,
- because of one mistake.
- I know. That's your tendency.
That's my tenden...
What's my tendency?
Leniency. You have a
tendency towards leniency.
Are you joking?
You know what my
nickname used to be?
- They called me the Na...
- Benjamin Warren.
Dr. Bailey, I believe in you.
I think you have an
extraordinary future ahead of you.
And I wouldn't dream
of coming in here
and telling you
how to do your job.
But if you don't take some
steps to replace Dr. Karev...
I will.
- You paged?
- Yeah, come take a look.
All right, assist the head lac.
Sir, I'm gonna need to take
a look at your wound, okay?
Okay, that's really deep. We're
gonna need to get this debrided
and covered with a local
muscle flap, right away.
Looks like he took a beating.
Car hit the median. They're
lucky everyone survived.
My kid was in the car with me.
This guy was all over the road.
- There's blood in his abdomen.
- Better book the CT.
Three lanes he whipped
across to cut me off.
I mean, what the
hell? Who does that?
Oh, God. Robbie.
What's happening with
my son? Is he okay?
We passed a bunch of cars, and
we kept going faster and faster!
Follow my finger with your eyes.
- Ow.
- That is quite a cut
you've got there, Robbie.
- Does it hurt?
- I can take it.
Is my dad okay? 'Cause I
should probably check on him.
Right.
I mean, he's my dad.
- You okay, Robbie?
- I'm fine, Dad.
- Thanks for waiting.
- It's fine.
Jackson can cool his heels
for a few more minutes upstairs.
I'm not hurt. I'm
really okay, Dad.
Mom's on her way, buddy, okay?
Listen to the doctors until she
gets here. You hear me? Behave.
I always behave, not
like that jerk that cut us off.
I bet next time he'll think
twice. I bet we did teach him...
All right, all right. Buddy...
All right, dad.
I paged Bailey over an hour ago.
How long does it take to
walk over to the damn clinic?
- What are you doing?
- I'm sorry. I'm nervous.
I am, too, but
boundaries, remember?
I can't hold your hand?
I've held your boobs.
Can we please not talk about
how the sausage is made?
Can we not call
our baby a sausage?
Sorry, guys, just
another minute.
And, by the way,
you said it was lovely.
It was, in its own way.
I also said let's never
speak of it again, remember?
So, what was all that about?
Is there something
we need to know?
Yes, but I need a surgeon
to officially assess you,
and I can't seem to get one.
So, if you guys could just hang
tight, I'll be right back, okay?
Hey. My bladder rupture
repair... done and done.
And I'm about to scrub
in on a nasty volvulus.
- What do you got?
- A kid in a car accident.
He's lucky, though. I'm
not seeing much of anything,
just a small congenital
AVM, nothing to do there.
If he's clear in a few
hours, I'll send him home.
Hey, you got a minute to talk?
Owen, there's
nothing to talk about.
But you love to talk, and
you're not talking about this at all.
Hear my words and just
take them at face value.
And I know, I
wouldn't mind talking.
I am fine. It's just...
Why the rush, you know?
What?
Well, I mean, we were barely
engaged, and now we're barely married,
and we're already
trying for kids?
Why all the pressure?
Let's just be us for a minute.
You know, enjoy us
and feel what it's like
to be two people in a
marriage, newlyweds,
before we add to it, right?
Is um...
If that's what you want.
Great.
- She gave you an ultimatum?
- Mm-hmm.
And she called
me lenient. Lenient!
You were lenient.
- I was not! I was not lenient.
- Yes, you were.
You were a lenient
and kind and wise chief,
- who ruled with fairness.
- Yes, I was fair. I was fair-minded.
Lenient makes me sound weak.
- I know.
- And I believe
in second chances.
Look at Leah Murphy. She
persevered, and she improved.
She asked to come back.
I feel that kind of
fortitude is to be rewarded.
And more so, I
believe it will reward us.
That's how I feel about Karev.
And I'm right.
- Right?
- You have to decide that.
I mean, that's why they call
them the tough calls, Bailey.
"That's why they call
them the tough calls"?
That's all you got? I
just called you wise.
Heads up.
Look, the clinic
is a joke, I know.
And nobody wants
to go over there.
But it's not a joke
when a pregnant lady
has to wait over an hour
for someone to come over
and confirm that she has cancer.
I've paged you multiple times!
I'm the Chief of Surgery. Why
aren't you paging a resident?
I want you! The surgeon
with the most expertise
to give this patient
the best chance!
Look, you stuck me over
there. It's your freaking clinic.
At least have the decency to
answer your own damn pages.
Not today, Karev. You do
not want to push me today.
Meet you there in five.
You were saying about
not wanting to fire him?
- Hey.
- Hi.
I'm on Dr. Bailey's
service, so...
Right.
- I'm Dr. Bailey.
- Hi. Jeremy.
Wow. This is a lot
of fuss for just a rash.
Okay. So hit me.
The symptoms that
Dr. Karev noticed...
your weight loss, the
itching on your hands,
when we see those symptoms
together, it's a red flag.
So, we took a look at your MRI and
detected a mass on your pancreas.
Oh, God. Is it... cancer?
- It's... too soon
to know for sure.
- But it could be?
We'll need to do a biopsy to
confirm, and we can go from there.
And you figured all this out
just by looking at my hands.
I was hoping I
was wrong. Still am.
You and me both.
All right, let's get
some irrigation in here.
I don't get road rage.
Do you get road rage?
I don't chase people
down. I'm not crazy.
Yeah, but other people.
- Other people are crazy.
- Yeah.
Well, actually sometimes,
April, you get a little crazy.
What? Warren, bovie this.
Well, somebody cuts you
off in traffic, you unleash
a stream of obscenities that'll
tear the paint off the walls.
Kepner? Really?
Well, it's just a release.
They can't hear me.
Yeah, they just think
you're on the phone. Yeah.
Oh, God. You don't do that
with Harriet in the car, do you?
- No, never. I would never.
- Oh, and you can't honk.
That just makes
crazy people crazier.
No, no honking, not ever.
When I flip someone
off, I always do it
below the dash, where
they can't see it, you know?
Or maybe you don't do anything.
- Solid advice.
- Absolutely. Clamp.
You're not even chewing.
I'm hungry, no time.
Waiting on biopsy results.
Did Pierce tell you about
her new favorite resident?
I can't operate, I don't care.
I mean, technically,
it's an old resident.
Leah Murphy.
- She's back?
- I love her.
Really great suture
techniques, steady hands.
- How are you?
- Great! Married.
Newlywed of two
months, going strong.
Super strong.
Can Webber really rehire
her? I mean, I am on the board.
What is the problem?
We needed a new resident,
and she's a good one.
- Robbins slept with her.
- So did Alex!
If you go there, be
careful. She gets attached.
Excuse me.
- Have you seen her yet?
- No.
I mean, do you think it's
weird she hasn't called us
to let us know
she's coming back?
- Who's back?
- Leah Murphy.
She was in our intern class,
then she left in the
second year of the program.
- Not by choice.
- What happened?
She didn't fight hard
enough to get in the OR,
- or study or prepare.
- Yes, she did.
She drilled through a patient's
leg all the way down to the table.
Yikes.
- That was an accident!
- Did I also mention she almost
brought the hospital down
with harassment lawsuits
and complaints
against attendings
because she was
sleeping with attendings?
Well, in fairness, I
slept with an attending.
Attendings.
Both Robbins and Karev.
- Robbins and Karev?
- Don't remind me.
Not that I care, but still,
just don't remind me.
It screwed with her head,
so Webber asked her to leave.
Just goes to show...
don't crap where you eat.
Hey, guys! Someone sitting here?
Hi! No! Sit. We
were just talking...
Talking about me?
Figures.
Umm.
Anyway, uh, welcome back.
- Damn it.
- Advanced pancreatic cancer.
I say we start with
neoadjuvant chemoradiation.
Hope it'll shrink the
tumor, then we can resect it.
- Follow up with more chemo.
- But she's pregnant.
How can the fetus
survive that kind of chemo?
- It can't.
- We'll have to recommend
termination.
If we can schedule
it for this afternoon,
we could start the first cycle
of chemo as early as tomorrow.
This isn't some accidental pregnancy.
There has to be some other option.
This is the best option.
You don't know that.
You don't know her.
I know what I'm looking
at on these scans.
Then look harder. I
mean, there has to be...
Okay, you marched
across the street.
You yelled at me to come
and assess your patient.
Me. Nobody else would do.
And now I'm here. I am assessing.
I can't help if you
don't like what you hear.
I convinced her to
come to our clinic.
I told her we could help her.
It's pancreatic cancer.
- There's only so much
help we can give.
- You're not even trying!
Okay, you are on
thin ice, Karev. Thin!
This is not the time to get...
I am the surgeon. I know
my recommendation.
We're done here.
Robbie, I have some good
news. Your dad's out of surgery.
So, as soon as your mom gets
here, she can bring you to see him.
My mom will be
pretty happy about that.
Yeah, I bet she will.
She's probably pretty scared.
I bet she is.
Robbie...
if you are scared, it's okay.
I mean, it's all
right to be scared.
It's all right to say
you are, talk about it.
He got so mad.
- Yeah. It's okay.
- And we went so fast.
I thought we were
gonna go off the road.
I thought we'd die.
I just want my mom.
She's coming. She's on her way.
And you're safe now, okay?
Okay? Robbie?
- I just want...
- What's that?
- Hurts...
- Robbie? Do you know
where you are?
Can you squeeze my hands?
Okay, I'm right here with
you, and I'm gonna help you.
- This is Robbie's...
- Warren, get in here!
- Robbie?
- We need some help here!
- Get her out of here.
- What's happening?
We need you to step back.
Okay, somebody call upstairs.
Bump whoever's in CT out.
We're coming up there now.
Let's go.
What's wrong with him?
They said he was fine.
And he was, but I
really have to go now.
His CT was fine. No
contusion, no fracture.
He has an incidental
AVM in the left temporal.
It must have ruptured.
If his AVM ruptured,
that's bad, right?
- Really bad.
- I want an OR on standby.
Make that happen right now.
- Robbie's in surgery?
- Yeah, he had a brain bleed.
They took him up as
soon as they detected it.
Today was supposed
to be a good one.
Robbie said he wanted me to
take him to buy a comic book.
Yeah, that kind of thing
doesn't happen much anymore.
He's 12 now.
And everything I do pretty
much embarrasses him.
But today, when that guy
cut me off, I was so pissed.
I mean, he could have killed
us. I just... I took off after him,
and then we hit a slick
spot and we lost control.
We hit the wall.
He's with Dr. Shepherd
now. And she's excellent.
Hey, sweetie. How's Robbie?
There's no news.
He's still in surgery.
Bob, what happened?
I don't understand.
I'll check back in a few.
This guy cut me off,
and I just got so mad.
I'm sorry, but it sounds like...
you want me to
terminate my pregnancy.
Oh, man.
We need to begin treatments
as soon as possible.
And the baby
couldn't survive them.
So, the baby's healthy.
The thing that's wrong
here is me, right?
Well, how much time do I
get? If I do what you're asking
and I get all the treatments,
how much time will I have?
Less than a year.
Then what is the point?
Why can't we just wait
until the baby's born,
and then you can nuke my
body full of chemo all you want?
You're not listening.
She's not listening.
They're saying...
that without the treatments,
the cancer will kill you
before the baby's even born.
In a month, two months,
you'll both be dead.
I went to court... to
fight a traffic ticket
so I could save 360 dollars, so we
could buy an organic crib mattress.
This is how my day
started. And now I'm...
All day long, I have been
thinking that there is...
there's a reason
that I was in that line.
There's a reason that I met you.
And I don't believe in
God or fate or anything.
- She doesn't at all.
- But this is it?
I met you so you can tell
me that our baby has to die...
and then go crawl off
somewhere and die myself.
These are my options?
Just death?
And more death?
- What about a Whipple?
- A Whipple?
A what?
The baby wouldn't survive
being under that long.
Then we do it open.
Cut the time in half.
We forgo the first round of
chemo and do this surgery instead.
Remove the cancer from your
pancreas without harming the baby,
then close you up.
And that will save them...
that will save them both?
No, but it could keep
you alive long enough
to deliver a healthy baby.
It'll buy you both some time.
Dr. Karev.
What the hell? You are not
some hotshot surgeon right now.
You are a doctor in the clinic.
You cannot go around
suggesting outrageous procedures.
I was giving my
patient her options.
The patient you only have
because I gave you the chance
in the clinic in
the first place!
I'm sorry!
But I wasn't wrong. I didn't
promise the impossible.
Yeah, I overstepped,
and I'm overstepping again
and pissing you
off, and I don't care.
Go on, get mad at me, but
don't take it out on the patient.
Just give her a freaking chance.
When I tell you to know your
place, know your damn place.
- Push 25 of Mannitol.
- This happened so quickly.
Spontaneous hemorrhage,
but we are gonna get him back.
We have to get him back.
V-fib. Charge paddles to 120.
Clear.
Asystole.
Push another 25 of
Mannitol. Check his pupils.
Fixed and dilated.
Let me see that.
No, no. No, no!
No!
He's gone. You did
everything you could.
Seem to have poor back-bleeding
from the inferior mesenteric.
Murphy, what do
you do about that?
Create a circular button around
the artery's origin, harvest it,
- and then re-implant
it in the graft. How?
Use a partially occluding
clamp on the graft to make a cuff
incision and over-sew the
inferior mesenteric artery
- with running 4-0 Prolene.
- And then what?
After the completion
of anastomosis,
we check the Doppler signals
on the sigmoid mesentery.
Exactly.
You've double-checked
every suture I've made,
and you're pimping me
with complicated questions.
- They told you my story.
- What? No.
- What story? Is there a story?
- Who cares?
What they didn't tell you, what
they couldn't have told you...
is that when I left here,
things really sucked.
Then I got into the
program at Foster,
and I worked harder
than I've ever worked,
and I became the best. And
then, Dr. Pierce... you happened.
I'm sorry?
During a cardio
rotation, I found the article
you wrote about awake
VATS, and I was riveted.
So I researched other
things you had written,
and... it became very clear to
me that I'm not just a surgeon.
I'm a cardiothoracic surgeon,
and I had to find you...
and learn from you.
I found out that
you'd been hired here,
and I thought, "Well, crap."
And then I realized, "Well, crap,
I have to figure out a way
to get back here somehow."
And now, I'm in an OR
with the Maggie Pierce.
- Sorry, Dr. Riggs, no offense.
- No, none taken. I get it.
I just hope that
whatever you heard...
I can't control that.
You know, when I first got here,
I was so miserable, I tried
to quit after two weeks.
People hated me so much,
I got punched in the face.
- Had exactly one friend.
- Kepner. She likes everybody.
Um, should we wait
for Jeremy to get back?
No, his stomach goes
bonkers when he's stressed out,
so he might be a while.
I wanted to talk to you
about scheduling the D&E.
Dr. Karev said there was a surgery.
Why aren't we doing that surgery?
Because it's very risky
to you, to the baby.
I already have
an expiration date.
Aren't we past a little
worried about some risks?
If we did this,
if we could remove the tumor
and keep your pregnancy intact,
by the time you deliver,
the cancer will have still
grown, unchecked for six months.
It'd be too far along
by then for us to treat it.
I mean, you would literally
be sacrificing your
own life for your child's.
I can see it, you know?
See what?
Jeremy pushing
our kid in the swing,
touching his toes
when they're in the sky.
And the baby
thinks it's so funny.
I can see them
growing older together...
getting to the good stuff.
Jeremy showing him
Star Wars for the first time.
Episode IV, 'cause you
can't start anywhere else.
High school, college...
his first apartment.
Jeremy's there, and
he's the best dad.
I picture that, and all
this crap is for something.
A happy ending.
I die, but there's
something good, still.
There's something good to see.
I picture it your way...
and everything goes black.
There's nothing.
Only death.
If this is the only chance
that my baby has to survive...
I am not looking
for a guarantee.
I'm looking for a chance.
Where'd you take Veronica?
She's in pre-op.
I was explaining to Jeremy
what to expect after her Whipple.
Thank you, Dr. Bailey,
for everything.
Have you seen a... hoodie?
Veronica's hoodie.
It's black, had a hood.
I was looking for it and
Dr. Bailey came up and...
- You sure she left it here?
- No, I'm not.
I'm not sure because I
wasn't paying any attention.
So, who knows? Who the
hell even knows where it is?
I can't... I can't do
this. I can't raise a kid.
Not by myself, not without her.
This was a good idea because we
had it, because we were gonna do it.
She's the one that thinks of
things, who keeps track of things.
I'm in charge of fun ideas. She's
in charge of, like, common sense
and where the
freaking hoodie is!
The next hoodie I lose,
my kid might be wearing it.
What if my kid is
wearing the hoodie?
I've worked with a
lot of parents, a lot.
- There's only one trick.
- What's the trick?
Show up. That's it.
Be there. Be around.
It's what you're doing for
your kid and his mom now,
and you're already good
at it. Give yourself a break.
She's my best friend.
She's always been there.
Always.
You ready, Veronica?
Is Dr. Karev gonna
be in the surgery, too?
Uh, he's needed in the clinic.
Then will you tell him
"thank you" for me?
The accident caused damage
to a weak spot in his brain.
We tried to repair it, but...
Robbie went into
cardiac arrest on the table.
No.
- I'm so sorry.
- We did everything we could.
Mrs. Reeves.
Laura.
If there's anything
that we can do...
I wish it was you.
It should've been you.
It should have been you!
Should've been you!
Mrs. Reeves.
Mrs. Reeves, come
with me, please.
You want to talk about it?
I'm just waiting to
hear how surgery goes,
so I got some time to kill.
Or not. I'm cool either way.
Or maybe just sit.
Sometimes sitting helps.
I'll just go.
I had a baby.
A baby boy.
- I had a son.
- Had?
When I was living in L.A., um...
He was born with
anencephaly but...
without a brain.
So, he lived for...
43 minutes...
And I held him.
I got to hold him.
And then it was time.
And he was...
He donated all of his organs.
And then I let him go.
And it almost killed me.
I didn't know.
No, you wouldn't, um...
I never told my family.
Not... Derek, not Meredith.
No one.
I haven't told Owen all of it.
And I don't think I can.
He wants a family so bad.
How do I tell him that...
- He won't look at me
the same way.
- Are you kidding?
He's gonna hate me.
I don't think so. It's Hunt.
Uh...
I took a pregnancy
test last night. I, um...
And I thought I might...
And, as I sat there
waiting for the result,
I just watched him get
more and more excited.
He wanted it so badly.
And the longer I sat
there, the more I felt like...
I was dying.
I couldn't breathe,
I couldn't move.
And when that
stick was negative,
Owen's heart broke.
And...
I was so relieved.
I could breathe again.
See.
Now look me in the eye and
tell me that he won't hate me.
Thank you.
Hey! I'm sorry. I'm sorry,
if I was weird earlier.
I was just...
I didn't know you were coming
back, so I was a little thrown.
Yeah. Yeah. I've
been thrown all day.
Yeah. But it is good to see you.
I saw that you went
into fetal medicine.
- That's very impressive!
- Yeah. Thank you.
I'm gonna get these
labs to Dr. Riggs.
- I will see you around.
- Bye.
You okay?
I can't stop thinking about it.
I watched Robbie stand
there and talk to his dad.
I mean, he was
fine. Then he wasn't.
Hi, baby.
- Just...
- April, it's secure, I'm sure.
I know, I know.
- I just wanted to double-check.
- Yeah.
One second.
Yep. Looks okay.
Dr. Lair, 4612. Dr. Lair, 4612.
DeLuca!
Hey, did you hear from
your lawyer about a trial date?
Yeah, it's coming
up soon. Goodnight.
Wait. Wait. What's up?
- Nothing.
- Try again. What's up?
We shouldn't talk
about the case anymore.
Wait. What?
I know you're talking
with Karev. I saw you.
And after all
that stuff you said
about how you guys
never talk anymore?
We were working
on a case in the clinic.
I didn't exactly have a choice.
What? You think I'm some
sort of double agent, and I'm...
No. No, I don't think...
You just... You
pick the bad guy.
Jo, the guy who hurts
you or hurts other people,
and... you deserve better.
Maybe you can't
see that, but I do.
When I see you
with him, I just...
Whatever, I... I got to go.
Hey, I'm about to head
out. You gonna be long?
I thought maybe, I'd throw
something on the grill, and...
No, I have a cervical spine
dislocation that just came up.
I will be a while.
Well, you know, I'm
not hungry. I can wait.
You shouldn't.
I'll be pretty late, so
don't wait up, okay?
Um, I'm sorry...
They were supposed
to tell you not to wait.
- I had a Whipple.
- I know. I waited anyway.
We need to talk.
You're right. We do.
Because, I'm not
firing Alex Karev.
You think this is lenient.
You think this is about
my personal feelings.
You're right.
You don't train a surgeon without
becoming personally involved.
At least, I hope not!
Now, I've made mistakes,
and those who trained me
afforded me the
opportunity to grow,
and I'm damn sure
continuing that tradition
with a surgeon as good as Karev!
So, Alex Karev stays
right where he is.
When someone you
love is in physical danger...
finding the strength you
need to save them is easy.
That's fine.
I'm sorry?
It's fine. Karev can
stay where he is.
We have a much bigger
problem than Karev.
After this morning, I started
looking into Alex's record,
and Ben Warren's,
and this Leah Murphy,
and all these people
who got second chances.
April Kepner, Meredith Grey.
And I wondered, why
did they need chances?
Why did they screw
up in the first place?
I'm sorry. I don't
see what you're...
We used to be the leading education
program on the whole West Coast.
So why would a Leah Murphy, fail
here only to thrive... somewhere else?
It's how we're teaching.
There is a fundamental flaw in
how we are teaching our residents.
And we have got to fix this.
- You and me.
- And Dr. Webber.
The Residency Program is
your husband's department.
I know. I know it is.
But sometimes, the
threat isn't physical.
Sometimes, it goes deeper.
In which case, no
instincts can save you.
No superhuman strength.
No adrenaline rush.
You didn't call, you didn't text, you
definitely didn't come home early.
I had to check on a patient.
- How did that go?
- Fine. She's still gonna die, though.
- How did court go?
- Fine. Not a big deal.
You can't power your way
out from under the crashing car.
I want waffle Sundays.
Am I supposed to
know what that means?
Well, every Sunday...
I want to do waffles,
like a family, all of us...
you, me, the kids, Pierce,
everybody, all together.
- Okay.
- I want to do that
as long as we can...
before, you know, I go away.
It's important to me.
- Okay.
- And Amelia. She should come, too.
You need to be nicer to
her. You need your sisters.
I'm not gonna always be
around. You're gonna need them.
All you can do is sit...
She talks so much.
So let her. Okay?
- Okay?
- Okay.
And wait...
Do I have to help
make the waffles?
That's my thing.
Stay out of the kitchen.
And wish things were different.