Whoo!
Still raining, I see.
It's Bangladesh
out there, Jerry.
Hi.
Hey. How are you?
Go for a swim?
Yeah... something like that.
You're in early.
I couldn't sleep.
The couple next
door at the motel
were working on
some kind of record.
Motel?
Yeah. I haven't had
time to find a place.
I heard the West Side's
nice, not too pricey.
Internship still
at poverty wage?
27 grand.
Yeah, but see, second year,
it jumps all the
way to 30 grand.
Uh-uh... 28.
Carol grew up on the West Side.
Talk to her.
She'll tell you where to look.
Thanks.
Okay.
Dr. Benton? Dr. Benton?
Oh.
What time is it?
It's 5:00.
How long since you've been home?
Has, uh, Tabash been down yet?
He rounds at 7:00.
Why don't you go home
and take a shower?
I have to scrub
in in 30 minutes.
Do me a favor... if
there are any changes,
page me, okay?
Hey.
What are you doing?
Watching you sleep.
For how long?
I don't know.
It's raining.
You're beautiful.
Good morning, Doctor.
Early bird catches
the worm, huh?
I was actually waiting
for Mrs. Ginsburg.
I was hoping to catch a couple
of minutes with you today.
Well, Marla doesn't
get in until 7:00.
What's on your mind, Doctor?
Uh, now?
I was sort of hoping for an
appointment this afternoon.
Well, there's no
time like the present.
Uh... you know, I'd
prefer to come back later,
if that's okay with you.
Are you intentionally trying
to irritate me, Dr. Carter?
No, sir.
Then speak up.
Um...
I've been contemplating
leaving the surgical program.
I've been considering
it for quite some time,
and I feel that, um...
I've made an error
in selecting surgery
as my specialty.
Uh... f-for the-the most part,
the training has been excellent,
but I just feel that, um...
ultimately, uh... I
don't belong in surgery.
And... and I would suspect
that you would agree with me.
I certainly do not!
You don't?
You entered into
a contract, Doctor...
A contract with
this institution.
We agreed to give you
the finest surgical training
available in the nation
in exchange for six
years of your best effort.
I understand that.
I understand that,
but I just think...
I do not give a
damn what you think!
This is not summer camp.
You cannot just
run home to Mommy.
You're going to suck
it up and stick to it.
That's what men do.
But I...
Are we communicating here?
Yeah.
Good! And if I ever hear
this kind of crap coming
out of your mouth again,
the only kind of medicine
you'll be practicing
is picking out a cough
suppressant for yourself
down at the Jewel!
Hey, Dr. Greene,
Dr. Weaver's looking for you.
Dr. Greene, you okay?
Yeah, yeah.
I'm fine, Jerry. Thanks.
Well, West Town's great.
You know, a lot of
it's been bought up...
Lawyers, investment bankers.
You can still find a nice place.
How much do you want to spend?
Uh... $600 tops.
Wow.
Have you ever thought
of finding a roommate?
You'd get a lot more space.
I'm looking forward
to living by myself.
Four years of undergrad,
four of med school,
three years of pedes...
Shared a bathroom
the entire time.
I grew up with two
sisters, one sink.
It was a nightmare.
Seven brothers.
Seven?
Yeah.
Where are you in the lineup?
Oldest. I wrap a mean diaper.
You?
Youngest.
Wow, eight kids.
Was your dad
independently wealthy?
Mailman.
So, uh, Mrs. Martinez...
Chuck has some
pain in his right hip?
Yes. He's been home
from school all week.
He's just getting over a cold.
Okay, Chuckie boy,
let's take a look at this, okay?
You like sports?
Yeah?
You, uh, slide into home
trying to beat the
throw from center field?
No.
His temp's 99.8.
Ow!
Did you fall off your
skateboard or your bike...
Anything that might
have hurt your hip?
I don't have a
skateboard anymore.
He wouldn't wear his
elbow and wrist pads,
so I took it away.
Uh-oh. Your mom's
right about that.
Licorice? Mom?
Yeah.
Has he had any kind
of penetrating wound or injury?
No.
Been in the woods camping?
Nature hikes at
school... anything?
No.
Um... CBC with a diff.
Chem seven, sed rate,
ultrasound, blood cultures,
and let's get an arthrocentesis.
I'm going to have
to call down Ortho.
Okay.
I don't think it's
any big deal, Chuck,
but we just got to make sure.
Hey, Dr. Greene.
I talked to Dr. Weaver
a couple of days ago.
Did she tell you about it?
Talked to her about what?
I'm hoping to leave
my surgical residency.
You're what?
I'd like to be considered
for a spot in
emergency medicine.
What did Anspaugh say?
He was less than enthusiastic.
Mark, Doyle has a
chest pain in curtain two.
You've already missed
this year's match.
I was hoping for a spot
outside the match
and that you'd put in
a good word for
me with Anspaugh.
Was Dr. Weaver
supportive? Mm-hmm.
You know, Weaver has
a better relationship
with Anspaugh than I do.
She could probably be
more persuasive.
Mark?
Okay. Thanks.
Tell me how it goes.
Sure.
Retract the liver inferiorly
and rotate it medially.
Peter, the coronary ligament.
Right.
Immobilize the right lobe,
exposing the vena cava.
You all right?
The vascular clamp.
Yeah.
Yours?
Shirley, can you
check that pager
over there on the table, please?
I'll suture, you retract.
6237.
Problem, Peter?
Uh... uh, Dr. Hicks,
uh... look, I'm sorry,
but I've got to go.
What?
I'm sorry.
Shirley...
Call Dr. Pittard to assist.
I think he's in Recovery.
39-year-old male
working out at the gym
when he experienced
the onset of chest pain.
Mr. Munder has a family
history of coronary disease.
My dad died at 36.
Vitals are normal.
BP's 100/50, pulse is 48.
Pulse ox 99.
So, you were at the
gym, Mr. Munder?
Yeah, weight circuit.
I was on the bench
press when it started.
What happened when you stopped?
It went away.
Do you smoke?
Hell, no.
His BP and pulse are low.
Yeah, but he's an athlete.
Oh, God, am I
having a heart attack?
It's probably just muscle
strain, Mr. Munder,
but with your family history,
we're not going
to take any risks.
Dr. Doyle?
Hep lock, CBC,
chem seven, cardiac enzymes,
portable chest and an EKG.
Don't forget the
low-tech approach:
Give him an aspirin.
Your husband looks a
little thin, Mrs. Curwane.
Has he been eating?
Whatever he
wants, I give to him.
Abdomen's distended.
See if there's a surgeon around.
No guarding or rebound.
No palpable organomegaly.
I can't find a vein.
Is your husband
on any medications?
Uh, yeah. Here.
CBC, lytes, LFTs, amylase...
and an abdominal series.
Tenormin, hydrochlorothiazide,
Altace, thorazine...
Burt... Burt, honey...
you be strong now.
You be strong...
Mommy's here...
Mommy's here.
Hey, Carol, somebody
may call you.
I put you down as a
character reference.
You're kidding, right?
No, it's this...
Big Brother thing.
The thing with the kids?
One kid.
You don't see enough here?
You know, a couple
of hours a week...
Good for you, Doug.
Eh, well.
Hey, what are you doing tonight?
You want to get
some oyster shooters
at Shaw's Crab House?
Sorry, I have a date.
Oh, yeah?
Who's the lucky guy?
Toby Minz up in Hem-Onc.
Yeah, Toby. Good.
He's a great guy.
A little lacking in
the hair department.
Except for his arms.
You ever seen his arms?
Carol, Ortho called.
They're going to
be at least an hour
before they can do
the arthrocentesis.
Thanks.
Arthrocentesis?
Oh, eight-year-old
kid with hip pain.
Del Amico is worried that
it might be septic arthritis.
That's an awful lot of tests
for a kid just getting over
an upper respiratory infection.
I think she was just
being overly cautious.
I tell you what, you know what?
Hold everything except
for the CBC and diff
and I'll check him out.
Okay.
All right.
Toby Minz?
Hey.
You get any sleep last night?
Mmm. On and off.
He's off the oscillating vent.
Mm-hmm.
The nitric oxide works.
We were able to move
him onto the respirator.
And?
The ultrasound
showed no hemorrhage
or dilatation of ventricles,
and the CT revealed no evidence
of periventricular leukomalacia.
What's he saying?
The structures of
the brain are okay.
Thank God.
So, most likely
there'll be no
developmental problems
or disabilities, right?
Well, there can be problems
associated with anoxia...
What's anoxia?
Your baby was deprived
of oxygen in the womb,
so there's always
the possibility
that there could
be brain damage.
Oh...
Will he be able to
play with other kids
and learn to read?
If you're asking me will
he be a doctor or a lawyer,
I can't say.
Chances are, your
baby will be fine,
but a certain percentage do
have neurodevelopmental problems
and/or learning disabilities.
What... percentage?
Infants delivered at 32
weeks with no complications
have a better-than-98%
chance of being normal.
Well...
what about the ones
born with complications?
Your child... had
several serious
complications at birth,
and no one can give you
an accurate percentage.
It's not an exact science.
Babies are resilient.
We'll just have to wait and see.
You're buying a gun?
Yeah, I think I'll feel safer.
What are you getting?
Sig Sauer nine-millimeter.
The guy at the pawnshop's
trying to sell me a Colt .45.
Lot of weapon for a beginner.
Stick to the Sig.
I'm going to check
on our chest pain.
Hey, how's the hand?
It itches like hell.
Thought you weren't
going to let anybody sign it.
Rachel's Brownie troop.
Hey, Dr. Greene, a detective
from Chicago PD called.
He said he's going
to come by later
with some pictures
for you to look at.
Thought the circus was over.
Maybe they caught somebody.
Hey, how's Rachel doing?
Jennifer's back, so
Rachel's with her.
Listen, uh, Doug, could
you write me a script
for some Percodan?
Your ribs still sore?
Yeah, the pain's
keeping me up at night.
When are you seeing
that hand guy again?
Monday.
I could write you
for five or six to
tide you over...
Mark, we need you over here.
I could use a few
more than that.
ST elevation in
two, three and AVF.
Malik, 1/150 nitro sublingually.
What's happening?
Is he having a heart attack?
It really hurts!
How's his BP?
BP's 125/80.
All right, five migs of morphine
I.V. push every 15.
Start a nitroglycerin drip.
O2 to 15.
Is he having a heart attack?!
Mrs. Munder...
I'm afraid so.
Oh, God! I knew it.
Heart rate's down to 45.
Looks like a block.
Second-degree Mobitz type two.
Atropine, .5 migs.
Please don't let me die!
I'm hearing rales.
Lasix, 40 milligrams I.V. push.
He's going into failure.
Let's set up for a
transcutaneous pacemaker.
What's up?
92-year-old man,
history of vomiting
and dehydration.
He's agitated,
abdomen's distended,
no bowel sounds.
Could be a small
bowel obstruction.
Meds?
Hydrochlorothiazide,
thorazine, Altace and Tenormin.
Kerry...
Bedsores.
Sacral area, too.
He's coming in from
a nursing home?
No, his wife's been
taking care of him at home.
Not very well.
Abdominal series back yet?
Should be any minute.
Dr. Weaver, can I talk
to you for a minute?
Uh, sure.
I, uh... I talked to
Dr. Anspaugh this morning.
Is he going to let you out?
I think a few words from you
would be helpful.
You're still interested in
pursuing emergency medicine?
Mm-hmm, yeah, I asked
Dr. Greene about it.
He seemed supportive, but...
with the match over,
he thought it might be
difficult to find a spot.
Kerry, I've got an LOL in
six, weak and dizzy all over.
I'll be right there.
Dr. Greene's probably
right about finding a slot.
We only have so much
salary budgeted for next year.
I'm sure it's already
been committed.
That's okay. You
don't have to pay me.
You... you don't need a salary?
No. No, I'm fine.
So you'll put in a good word
with Dr. Anspaugh for me?
Sure.
Thanks.
Hey, did the kid with
the hip get moved?
I don't know.
Check the desk.
Carol, do you know
where Chuck Martinez
and his mom got moved to?
Doug Ross released him.
He didn't talk to
you about it first?
Uh, no.
Do you have any
idea where he is?
I think he's in the lounge.
I tell the guy, "You've got
to put your head down,"
so he looks me in the eye
and he pukes everywhere.
Pukes on the floor...
He was my patient.
You had no right to release him
without consulting me first.
What are we talking about here?
Chuck Martinez, my
eight-year-old with the sore hip.
You ordered
$4,000 worth of tests
for a child with
toxic synovitis...
He was my patient.
I sent him home with two Advils.
You are working
under my supervision.
How do you know it
wasn't septic arthritis?
Because I looked at the CBC, I
looked at the diff; it was synovitis.
What if it's early-stage?
Dr. Del Amico, you want
to put an eight-year-old boy
through a painful
orthopedic procedure
on the remote possibility
that he's suffering
from a rare diagnosis
that your tests
do not even indicate.
You know what?
If you want to gamble
with your patients' lives,
that's fine, but
don't do it with mine.
He's in complete heart block.
Eighty-eight. Pulse ox?
Is he dying?
He's dying, isn't he?
We need you to stand
over here, Mrs. Munder.
It's not capturing.
Connie, get the
transvenous pacemaker
and the portable
fluoroscope down here now.
E. Ray, what's open?
Trauma one.
All right, let's go.
You want me to call Cardiology?
Tell them we can't wait.
If they want the
procedure, they'd better run.
Abdominal series
doesn't show obstruction.
So it's not surgical.
Uh-uh.
Probably an ileus.
Crit's 51.
Potassium's 2.1.
Okay, let's get some
potassium going.
Put 40 milli-equivalents
in a liter of saline,
run it over two hours.
What about the bedsores,
malnutrition, dehydration?
Yeah. Does she have
any help at home?
No.
She doesn't even
look strong enough
to take care of herself.
Mrs. Curwane...
I don't think your husband's
going to require surgery.
Oh.
He has an ileus...
A section of his intestinal
tract is paralyzed,
and that's making him sick.
Paralyzed?
It could have been caused
by one of his medications.
So...
we're going to work on that.
Does your husband
get enough to eat?
I-I cook for him every day.
All his favorites.
We're sure that you
do, but does he eat it?
He's fine.
We're just getting
older, that's all.
We're also concerned
that he might not be
getting enough exercise.
Does he have a
walker so he can get out
of bed and move around a little?
He's been sick.
When he's feeling better,
he's out in the
yard all day long
with his roses
and his vegetables.
We had the most lovely beets
and beans last season.
Just lovely.
Mrs. Curwane...
I think...
maybe it's time to consider
placing your husband
in a nursing home
or a rehabilitation facility.
I take good care of him.
You've done a wonderful job,
but now he needs
more than you can give.
We've lived in our
house for 48 years.
Burt loves that house.
You just fix him up...
and I'll take him home.
That's where he belongs.
Found her in Grant Park
face down in the mud
in the pouring rain.
14, maybe 15.
BP's 90/50, pulse
56, temp's 101,
skin clammy,
cool, slightly dusky.
We got two I.V.s
going... Glucose 120.
She's had two of Narcan.
Vomited all over
herself. Track marks.
Any ID?
No way was I sticking my hands
into this kid's pockets.
Jerry, what do we got open?
They're just clearing
somebody out of trauma two.
Lot of kids squatting over
there by the baseball fields.
Carol, better take a look.
Oh, damn it! Lily, get Dr. Ross.
Tell him to come to trauma
two as soon as he can.
I can handle an OD.
We're coming through!
Get out of the way!
O2, ten liters by mask,
and two more
milligrams Narcan I.V.
Prep for gastric lavage.
I've run hundreds
of adolescent ODs.
I don't need Ross down
here holding my hand.
I didn't call him
down here to baby-sit.
She's a patient of his.
Her name is Charlie.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
We picked up a
guy over at Mercy.
He mugged a doctor
in the parking lot,
knocked him around.
We thought it might be your guy.
I don't remember much.
Just look them over
and tell us what you can.
He was black, then?
Just tell us if you recognize
any of these men.
Take your time.
I don't know...
Uh...
I think maybe this guy.
I've seen him before.
He could have been
a patient or something.
Okay, Doc, thanks for your help.
Is that the right guy?
You know, I remember the pants.
I saw the pants.
They were dark blue,
and the shoes were black.
Yeah, we got that in the report.
You know, that might
be... might be the right guy.
I just... I didn't see much.
It happened so fast.
Is there, uh...
a pop machine around
here somewhere?
Yeah. That's across
the hall by the chairs.
Thanks.
You want anything, Ford?
No, thanks. I'm okay.
You know, this guy... he
knocked you around pretty good.
I can give you a
couple of names...
Some victim's groups,
people that handle
this sort of thing.
I'm fine, thanks.
Sure.
Son of a bitch!
Aw, damn it.
Paramedics found her
face down in the mud, OD'd.
She's got track marks,
skin pops, cellulitis.
We're lavaging her.
CBC, chem 20, tox screen?
And a blood alcohol.
Foley's in.
Get the antibiotics going.
Be my guest.
All right, Ancef, one gram,
gentamicin, 50 milligrams I.V.
How old?
Fourteen.
Going on 40.
I'll call her mother.
A miracle, huh?
Have you held him yet?
Uh...
no.
He's small, but strong.
You name him?
You know, actually, we
haven't even had time
to talk about it.
I think we both thought
it would be bad luck.
I think it's safe now.
I've got to get back.
You coming?
In a bit, in a bit.
Okay.
Someone going to get the phone?
I got it last time.
You did not.
Did, too.
You never answer the phone.
I always answer.
ER.
Carter, it's Gerontology.
How's it coming
with Mr. Curwane?
I got somebody from
Social Work coming down
and somebody from
PT and Nutrition.
This is Dr. Carter.
Yeah, I'm still holding.
I hate talking with caseworkers.
So, Mark busted a
chair in the lounge?
Yeah... smashed the coffeepot,
bunch of mugs...
It was a real mess.
Where is he?
Said he had to run an errand.
Hey, I need to talk to you.
Anybody want to
help me out over here?
What's up, sport?
Yeah, I'm looking for somebody.
The ambulance brought
her in from Grant Park.
Does she have a name?
Yeah... Charlie.
I don't know her last name.
Who are you?
A friend... a close friend.
A close friend and you
don't know her last name?
I'm not that kind of friend.
So, look, you going
to tell me where she is?
No, her mom's coming.
You can ask her.
Oh, her mom.
She ain't coming.
She's in jail... possession.
Well, then Charlie goes to DCFS.
Yeah, fine. Whatever.
Look, just tell her Tommy
stopped by, will you?
I'll be on the
corner after 10:00.
I'll make sure she gets
the message.
Doug, Charlie's coming around.
Oh, uh, okay, Jerry, I'm
on the line with DCFS.
Will you page me in trauma two
if they ever pick up?
Jeanie?
Gerontology's all backed up.
I'm going to go up there
and see if I can grab somebody.
Dr. Weaver?
You should've warned
me about Dr. Anspaugh.
What happened?
He wouldn't even discuss it.
I'm sorry... I thought
maybe you could turn him around.
Personally, I would love
to have you in
emergency medicine,
but whatever your difficulties
with Dr. Anspaugh are,
you'll have to
solve them yourself.
Tox screen came back.
Uh, positive for
cocaine, benzos, opiates.
Blood alcohol's .23.
CBC shows a white count of 15.5.
Hemoglobin's 9.8, crit 28.
Elevated AST and bilirubin.
Hepatitis? Mmm.
Restraints?
I don't want her to bolt.
Would you take them
off for me, please?
Hey, she's still my patient.
I understand that, but
I need to talk to her.
She's not going to want to talk
if she's wearing restraints.
Just don't leave her in the
room alone without restraints.
Okay, you know what?
I'll do it.
Hey, you.
So, your bellybutton
ring is infected.
What did you do, do it yourself
with a rusty nail?
I don't feel so good.
Yeah, well, we
pumped your stomach.
Found more chemicals in there
than a toxic waste dump.
I was just partying
with some friends.
Mm-hmm.
So you graduated to
smack now, did you?
When can I go home?
Where's that?
With my mom.
We hear your mom's in jail.
I won't go back to foster care.
Is that where you were?
The guy was trying
to do me all the time
and his wife was a drunk.
Sounds rough.
You going to let me go?
Where?
I've got friends.
I know... friends you can
share a dime bag with,
if you want.
Who's the cheerleader?
Hmm?
That's Dr. Del Amico.
She took care of you
when you first came in.
She the one who ruined my high?
Mm-hmm.
You like her.
Okay, I'm going to get
ahold of your caseworker,
and we'll try and get you
into rehab, get you dried out.
Or you can keep
screwing up your life
and you can end up
dead in some alley.
It's going to be your choice.
I'm pretty tired.
Mm-hmm.
Jeanie.
Hey, hi!
What are you doing here?
That new job site's just
on the other side of Wells.
I thought I'd find out
what time you were going
to be home for dinner.
Jeanie, an MVA pulling up.
Guy got T-boned by a
semi on the Kennedy.
Uh, Kerry, this is
Al Boulet.
We met last year. Hi.
Here they come.
Okay, uh, I got to go.
I'll be home around 8:00.
You're not cooking, right?
I've got all sorts of surprises
lined up for you tonight.
No frozen dinners, please.
Home by 8:00, huh?
Guess we've got
some catching up to do.
When did you start smoking?
Bummed one from Doyle.
So, I hear you had
a meltdown today.
You picked a fight
with the lounge.
Yeah.
Feel better?
Not really.
Mark, I'm not going to write you
that prescription
for the Percodan.
I think you got
to get some help.
I'm fine.
Taking a chair to
the lounge isn't fine.
It's never happened
to you, Doug.
You don't know.
I'll get someone else to
write me the Percodan.
Okay... all right.
If you ever want to talk,
you know where
to find me, right?
Dr. Carter!
Dr. Anspaugh.
Dr. Weaver just
dragged me down here
for a surgical consult
on a traffic accident.
It seems you were
nowhere to be found.
I came down as
soon as I was paged.
Would you like me to take it?
No, thank you, Doctor.
I'll see you
upstairs for rounds.
Hey, Carter.
You got a bunch of
people waiting on you
in curtain three.
Said you called them
down for a consult.
Right.
Right, thank you.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
John Carter.
Carla Kramer, Social Work.
Daniel Shaw, Dietary.
Anne Ferguson, Physical Therapy.
Hello. So, you've
all had a chance
to, uh, see Mr. Curwane,
review the chart?
Why don't we take
a step outside, then?
Hey, Peter.
Move over.
How'd you find me?
It wasn't hard.
It's what you used to
do when you were little.
Whenever you'd get in trouble,
you'd go down to the church.
You knew if Daddy
found you there,
he'd figure you were
already repenting
and he wouldn't have the heart
to take the belt to you.
You're saying I was
that calculating as a kid?
Mommy thought so.
Me, I think Daddy was right.
You were harder on yourself
than any of us could
have ever been.
Carla says she hasn't seen you
since first thing this morning.
I didn't know it was
going to be this hard.
What?
The baby.
He may have brain damage,
developmental problems, autism,
mental retardation...
They can't even say.
Or he might be fine, right?
Either way, you're
going to love him
more than you can even imagine.
I can't handle it.
Sure you can.
You'll have to.
That's your son up there, Peter.
The world is hard sometimes.
It can't always go the
way you want it to go.
I miss Dad.
By the way, is there any chance
that there might be some
place that could take both of them
and let them live together?
Does she need nursing care?
She may have a little dementia.
She seems a bit out of it to me.
Dr. Carter, time for rounds.
Alden Lakeland has rooms
that will accommodate couples.
Oh, great, great!
Dr. Carter?!
Um... I'm sorry.
I have to go.
What?
Rounds... I'll be
back in an hour.
Doctor, you're the one
with the relationship
with the wife.
We're not likely to get very
far without your involvement.
This is ridiculous.
Dr. Carter!
Uh... I'm not coming.
You're what?
I have a patient who
needs my attention.
Rounds are a requisite
for this program, Doctor.
So is patient care.
You come to rounds today, or
don't ever come to rounds again.
I'll be there if and when I can!
All right, Doctor.
Anyone thinking cocktails?
I got to pick the
kids up at my sister's.
I'm in.
Me, too.
You got any money?
Better than
money, girl... Credit.
Hey, Charlie's caseworker
finally showed up.
She's waiting out in chairs.
Oh, this ought to be fun.
Whoo-ee!
Girl, you look great!
Thank you.
Hey, E. Ray, if Dr. Minz calls,
let him know I'm on my way up.
Okey-dokey.
Good night.
Uh, Dr. Ross?
Yeah?
You know Ms. Newman
from DCFS, right?
Yes, I do.
Hey, hi, how are you?
Charlie's resurfaced again, huh?
Yeah, polydrug OD...
Cocaine, meth, heroin.
She ran away from the foster
home about a month ago.
Yeah, she said that
she was molested.
Well, Charlie
says a lot of things.
Yes, she does.
Oh, damn it.
I'm out of here, E. Ray.
If anybody asks,
I left hours ago
and you haven't seen me.
Dr. Greene!
Pacer's capturing,
vitals are normal,
tapered off the dopamine.
Mr. Munder is headed upstairs
to get a permanent
pacemaker tomorrow.
Feeling better, Mr. Munder?
Much... thanks.
Great... Take care.
Doctor?
I'm sorry... I'm off duty.
If you need a physician,
I'm sure someone...
No, Doctor, I'm Judy Munder.
I just wanted
to thank you
for saving my husband's life.
Must be incredible...
Making a difference
in people's lives.
Good night, E. Ray.
Good night.
I hate this.
She's going to need
money to get high.
This is the fastest way.
That pimp guy said
he'd be on a corner?
Yeah.
He didn't say what corner,
and how do you know he's a pimp?
Dealer, whatever.
He's out here
somewhere if she is.
Pull over.
What?
Pull over... we'll ask around.
Someone's going to know
a dealer named Tommy,
hangs out with a
kid named Charlie.
What?
Someone wants to steal your car,
that alarm ain't
going to stop them.
What are we doing out here?
She reminds me of somebody.
Who's that?
Me.
So, you headed home
for a special dinner
and some surprises?
Probably just a
pot pie and a video.
Al's not much of a romantic.
So you guys are back together?
You don't approve.
I don't know.
Does it matter if I approve?
It does to me.
It would help if I understood.
I don't know if I do.
You know, it's funny, Kerry...
I'm happy.
I'm happier than I've ever been.
How can that be?
And that's because of Al?
No, it's because of me.
I'm not afraid anymore.
Of death?
Of living my life.
I see things now I
didn't see before.
I know what's important.
I know what isn't.
I've been in love with Al Boulet
since the first time I saw him.
I was 16 years old.
I know he's been
in love with me.
Jeanie...
Good night.
Hey, what's up, girl?
Can I have your name?
This party's going
to be booming.
Hey, what's up with that party?
Why don't you
want to look at him?
Hey, let's go, man.
She's cold.
Let's go, man.
Hey, hey...
Yo, wassup, man?
Yo, look who's up.
You're not sleeping.
I seen you.
Wakey, wakey.
Wake up!
He's awake now.
Yo, bro, lend me
20 bucks.
I don't have any money.
Sure you do, man.
Come on, man, we got
to get us something to eat.
Yo, man, let's go.
Shut up, ese!
I'm talking to my friend here.
Glasses man, we're hungry.
You don't want
us hungry, do you?
This is my stop.
You don't want to give me
some money, man?
Yo, we're getting off.
What?
This is our stop.
We're getting off.
Back off!
Hey, hey, hey!
Be cool, man!
Get on the train!
Yo, be cool, man!
Get back on the train!
Be cool, man!
Shut up! Shut up!
Be cool, glasses man!
Shut up!
Chill out, glasses man.
Be cool!
Chill out!
Hey!
Later.
Uh, anything?
No. You?
Yeah... that kid
with the wild hair
saw Charlie yesterday.
Said this guy Tommy's
usually around,
but she hasn't seen him tonight.
Heard he and Charlie scored
some hash and a good squat.
Anything else?
Yeah, that 15-year-old
with leather pants
said she'd do you for nothing.
Ah, that's something.
So, what now?
Come back tomorrow night.
If they got a decent squat,
they're not going
to come out again
until they need to score.
All right, well, you want
to get something to eat?
Uh... as in something to eat
or as in maybe something to
eat will lead to something else?
Something to eat.
How long ago did
you and that nurse
Carol Hathaway break up?
A long time ago.
How about this:
How about you drop
me back at my motel,
and we hit some takeout
drive-through on the way?
Sounds romantic.
Dr. Anspaugh?
I'm late for dinner, Dr. Carter.
Good night.
Please? It will
only take a minute.
This is not the
time or the place.
It's not that I dislike surgery.
It's been incredibly
challenging,
and the training
has been excellent.
You are a wonderful
surgeon and a fine teacher.
Get to the point, Doctor.
I admire surgeons and surgery,
but it's not the
type of medicine
I want to practice.
I can be a competent surgeon.
I can learn the techniques,
the mechanics...
but I'll never be
a great surgeon.
Dr. Anspaugh, I can
be a great doctor,
a doctor who spends
time with his patients,
who's there for them.
I'm good at it.
Really good.
I can make a difference
in people's lives.
Don't make me give that up.
Please don't make me waste it.
I've often wondered
over the years
if I made the right decision...
in becoming a surgeon.
But you seem
so... certain.
What are you?
Twenty-six?
Twenty-five.
What happened to your patient?
The one you missed rounds for?
Mr. Curwane.
I got him and his wife
into a nursing home... together.
It's supposed to be very nice.
I'm sure it is.
You find me in the morning.
We'll see
if we can work something out.
So, Toby doesn't
get to come inside?
Doug! God, you scared me.
I was hiding over
there under the El track.
You're lucky one of the
neighbors didn't see you.
They would've called the cops.
What are you doing here?
So, Toby doesn't
get to come inside?
It was only the third date.
Toby definitely does
not get to come inside.
What?
Sit in the rocker.
All you have to do is hold him.
Support his head.
There you go.
Now just rock.