That's my Uncle
Miles on the grill.
Uncle Miles?
Is that ginger head
with you?
Is that my
baby girl Becca?
Can you believe
how big she's gotten?
Hey, Grandma.
Hey, sweetie.
This is Will.
Hi, Will.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
Why don't you go
see your Uncle Will?
Okay.
Stay with Will.
Hi.
Okay.
Denise?
Hey, Mags.
I didn't think you
were gonna come.
Oh!
Just decided
to fly in at the last minute.
I'm glad you did.
Will Halstead, come over here
and meet my sister, Denise.
Okay, let me hand her over.
I'll take her.
Yeah, nice to meet you.
Come on, sweetie.
All right.
Hi, Denise.
So are you to blame
for the big mouth
on this one?
Please, Maggie's been sassy
ever since she could talk.
It's not my fault.
I was born that way.
So, what should we do?
I'm off on Monday
and the weather's
supposed to be great.
I'm actually flying back
to Dallas in a few hours.
I got to be back
at the makeup
counter tomorrow.
Let's make
the most of it then.
Okay.
Come on. Let's go say
hi to everybody.
Hey.
Morning, Ms. Goodwin.
Good morning.
What brings you
in on a Saturday?
I could ask you
the same thing.
I'm filling in as
trauma attending.
We haven't had
an elective heart surgery
in a week.
Yes, I know we've
had some cancellations
since Dr. Downey died,
but we can't expect
to rebuild a destination
program overnight.
We've got a great team.
Word will spread.
Connor! Incoming.
With you.
Patient name, Glenn Simon,
57-year-old male.
GCS 15, vitals stable.
Got knocked off his horse
at the polo ground.
Gross deformity
to the right femur.
All right,
let's go to T Three.
Mr. Simon, can you
tell us what happened?
My buddy Harvey is a cheater.
That's what happened.
Tried to pull
a 90-degree ride-off.
Knocked me clear off my pony.
All right, let's get
X-ray and call Ortho.
Got it.
All right, let's move him
on my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
Mr. Simon, any pain?
Not there.
Okay.
Looks like
you found it.
Yep.
Let's get him off the board.
All right,
on my count.
One, two, three.
Gently. There we go.
Get an IV started.
Hang a bolus of saline.
And 5 milligrams of
morphine for the pain.
We're gonna get you
fixed up, Mr. Simon.
I never like to admit
that my wife was right,
but I'd be in a lot less pain
if I stuck to golf...
Like she asked me to...
Mr. Simon?
Mr. Simon,
can you hear me?
He's stroking.
All right,
give 20 milligrams
of labetalol.
Let's get him
to CT and echo now.
Maybe I'll come
and visit in Dallas.
I can use some
primping.
You know, I actually
might be out of town
a bit over
the next two months.
But after that, yeah.
Bye.
So, uh, how long has she
been living in Dallas?
I don't know.
She moved maybe nine,
ten years ago.
Let me guess.
Because of a guy?
Something like that.
Denise!
Is she all right?
Whoa, easy, Denise.
Denise?
It's okay.
I'm right here.
Are you okay?
I can't see.
Okay, okay,
okay, okay.
Okay, breathe. Breathe.
I can't see.
Breathe.
You should've seen it.
Yeah, pretty good.
What's gotten into you?
What? Nothing.
Okay,
something's different.
You look happy.
I'm just glad to
have a weekend shift.
Looking forward
to a quiet day.
Hey, Nat.
Will has the day off.
Thought Jeff could follow you.
Sure. Okay.
All attending to...
What do we got?
Mid-20s male.
Found him down by
the train station.
GCS 14. Fever's 103.
BP's 160 over 90.
Heart rate 110.
Sir, can you tell
us what happened?
I don't think
you'll get very far.
He doesn't speak
a word of English.
No ID.
This is everything
we found on him.
It's a foreign currency.
Let me see that.
Yeah, it's Thai.
If he just arrived
to the US,
he could have brought
whatever this is with him.
Let's track down
a translator online.
Right. Let's get him
to T Two.
Okay.
Mr. Simon, we're taking you
up to the surgical ICU.
You understand?
Glenn, honey. I'm here.
Glenn? Glenn.
Mrs. Simon?
Why isn't my husband
saying anything?
Mrs. Simon, I'm Dr. Rhodes.
I'm taking care
of your husband.
Why don't we find
somewhere where
we can talk?
So your husband has what is
called a bifurcated vena cava.
It allowed the emboli
from his leg fracture
to bypass his lungs
and go straight
into his brain.
With your consent,
I would like to operate.
I'd like to get
a second opinion.
Glenn has a partner
who's on the board
at the Mayo Clinic,
and I'm sure he could refer us
to a cardiologist there.
I understand. As long
as he has the fracture,
he's at risk of
having another stroke.
And we can't fix his
leg until I fix his heart.
Waiting could put him
in even greater danger.
Fool still thinks
he's 25 years old.
I came here to give him
a piece of my mind,
and now this.
Mrs. Simon,
we have a great
team here at Gaffney.
I believe when your husband
comes out of surgery,
he's gonna be good
and ready to receive
a piece of your mind.
Okay.
Will... Uh, Dr. Halstead
gave her a dose
of IV steroids.
Now her vision is
starting to return.
Any idea what may
have caused this?
Not yet.
Can we get
you anything?
No, you both got
enough on your plate.
And I'm fine. Really.
Denise, I would really
encourage you to stay.
I really... I'm okay.
Where are you going?
If I leave now,
I can still catch my flight.
But a second ago,
you couldn't see your hand
in front of your face.
Yeah, and now I can.
Thanks for the great care.
Don't be stubborn, Denise.
You know I've
always had migraines.
This is just
another passing episode.
A transient blindness
can actually be caused
by a number of things.
We should run some more tests.
Exactly.
What happens
the next time that you have
one of your passing episodes
and you're driving
on the expressway?
Fine. Fine.
Can we make this quick?
This is what I get
for trying to take on
a 12-pound pot roast.
Good news is it's just
a second-degree burn.
Might blister and swell a bit,
but you'll live to
cook another day.
BP's 160 over 90.
Let's page OB,
have them take a look.
You're, uh,
seven months along?
Yeah. Why?
Honey, are you okay?
Oh, everything's okay.
Your wife's blood pressure
is slightly elevated.
I'd like to get some labs
and an ultrasound
just as a precaution.
Is that necessary?
I've been seeing
my doula regularly,
and she says
everything's good.
I'm right on track
for a home birth.
I know
you must think we're some
granola-fed hipsters,
but that's not it.
My sister miscarried
after an amnio,
and I promised myself
I would do everything
as natural as possible.
And that includes
protecting my baby
from the harmful sound waves.
I understand
completely.
But in some cases,
high blood pressure
can affect fetal growth.
I just want to rule out
any possible complications.
Well, I guess it's good
to be on the safe side.
Right, honey?
The patient's
not speaking Thai.
If I had to guess
based on his inflection,
it's an Indonesian dialect.
If you want, I'll contact
the network administrator,
see who they have in Jakarta.
Please. Thank you.
Thank you.
Okay.
So, Mr. Clarke. Fever,
chills, vomit, diarrhea.
Chikungunya,
Dengue, Yellow fever?
Maybe, that or one
of 100 other diseases.
Welcome to the future.
Migration, climate change,
the whole world
is on our doorstep.
So what do you
do when you have
an infectious disease
of an unknown origin?
I'd start with CBC,
CMP, blood, sputum,
urine cultures...
Uh, rapid mono and strep.
Good.
You start the H&P,
and I'll put in the order
and hang some
IV Metronidazole.
Will do.
Actually, totally my fault.
Overdid it on the PT.
Had to do that last leg lift,
and this is my reward.
Am I boring you, Doctor?
Oh, no, sorry.
I stayed up all night
attacking the library,
got all the way to Bowlby.
Mmm-hmm.
Bowlby? Great stuff.
Made Charles Darwin
the fascination
of an entire
generation of shrinks.
Bowlby said that Darwin
had a panic disorder.
Oh, yes, ma'am.
Charlie had a dark side.
Wait till you get
to Barloon and Noyes.
Dr. Charles, Dr. Reese,
thanks for coming down.
What's up, Ethan?
What do you got?
Amanda Kendrick-Dobbs.
Seven months pregnant,
gravid belly,
history of fetal movement
and Braxton Hicks
contractions,
all signs of
a normal pregnancy.
So what's the issue?
There's no baby.
Dr. Rhodes?
I'm Leah Bardovi.
I'm starting my surgical
residency here.
Welcome to Chicago Med.
So, clinically speaking,
the patient will be dead?
Just long enough for me to do
the repair on his aorta.
And then we will warm him up
and restart the heart.
Hmm.
Did a lot of these
under Dr. Downey?
A few.
You know, he's the
reason I applied here.
When I got my match,
I told my dad
that I'm going to be training
under the greatest surgeon
in the world.
And now,
I'm just honored
to be learning
from his protégé.
Cooling jackets prepped?
Standing by.
Then let's
do this. Scalpel.
Appreciate the visit,
but we just want to make sure
the baby's okay.
Why are you here again?
Oh, we try and look in
on all our expectant mothers
as part of a routine
wellness assessment.
It was actually Dr. Reese
who flagged your
high blood pressure.
Yeah, have you been
under any stress lately?
Maybe something at work?
Oh, I'm not working.
I haven't been since
we moved here last year.
Yeah, when my firm
transferred me from Denver,
we thought it'd be a good time
for Amanda to stay at home,
focus on the baby.
Where did you say
Dr. Choi was, again?
We're pretty sure
he's just waiting
for the rest of
your blood work.
We will go check in
with him right now.
Thanks both for your time.
Okay. Great.
Good luck to you.
Thank you.
Notice how she didn't ask
about any test results
or anything?
Oh.
Yeah.
That's 'cause on some level,
she knows the truth.
So what are we looking at?
I don't know, Reese.
What are we looking at?
Uh, well,
no grandiose delusions
or other signs of underlying
psychiatric illness,
so I think we can
rule out psychosis.
Mmm-hmm.
Then how is this
even possible?
Well, in a lot of cases,
the anxiety produces
a hormonal reaction.
Causes all of the physical
signs of pregnancy
without a growing fetus.
We need to figure out
why having a baby's
so important to her.
Or more specifically,
why being pregnant
is so important to her.
Right.
So, what do we do now?
I see no value
in withholding this
from them any longer.
So, what do you say, Doctor?
Do you want me
to break the news?
No,
don't worry, Grandma.
No, I'll let you know
as soon as
the tests come back.
Me, too. Bye.
Hey.
Hi.
How's your sister?
Stubborn as ever.
I am here for you
if you need anything. Okay?
Thank you.
Yeah.
Dr. Manning.
Hey, Mags.
Uh, the translator
in Jakarta struck out.
Apparently,
there are over 700
languages in Indonesia.
What about his fever?
He's up to 104.
Let's get him into
a negative pressure room.
Hang some IV Tylenol,
and let's see if
there's any way
we could put
a rush on those labs.
Okay.
What was that?
What was what?
You, Jeff, the body language,
the touching on the shoulder.
Something is definitely up.
Hmm...
You mean I'm right?
Do you think it's weird?
What, you hooking up
with your late husband's
best friend?
Not hooking up.
Whatever you
want to call it.
You're asking me
if it's weird.
Yeah.
A little.
Don't stress out about it.
I learned a long time ago
that you have to do
what makes you happy,
even if some people
think it's strange.
Dr. Manning.
Okay.
What's happening?
He's in bronchospasm.
Let's bag him and
get some racemic epi
and 125 milligrams
of Solu-Medrol IV.
Sats are still dropping.
I need a better airway.
Let's tube him.
Twenty of Etomidate,
100 of Sux.
You're gonna intubate?
Mmm-hmm.
Here you go.
He won't be able to speak
to a translator if we do that.
We don't have to
worry about a translator
if he stops breathing.
Dr. Manning.
I'm in.
Start a neb treatment.
I got it.
Sats are coming up.
There's got to be someone
somewhere in this city
who can communicate
with this guy.
All right, I'm on it.
Placement's good.
Sorry, if it felt like
I second-guessed you there.
Let's get him moved, okay?
Yes, Doctor.
Call upstairs.
All right,
go on bypass.
Cool to 20,
but do not crash cool.
Find me when he gets
to 32 degrees,
and we'll arrest the heart.
Yes, Dr. Rhodes.
So far, so good.
He's taken well
to the anesthetic.
We should be able to start
the repair in an hour or so.
Thank you, Dr. Rhodes.
Mrs. Simon
was just telling me
how impressed she was
with your confidence.
Could you excuse us, please?
I need a quick word
with Dr. Rhodes here.
Where's Dr. Latham?
I was just about to page him.
You signed up for
a high-risk surgery
without consulting
an attending?
All I did was open
him up and cannulate.
It is the Sabbath.
I didn't want to bother
Dr. Latham until I had to.
Glenn Simon is a man
with lots of connections.
You were worried before
about the state
of the department.
You'll have even
more to worry about
if you don't pull this off.
Page Dr. Latham now.
These machines
are the worst.
You obviously
haven't seen the ones
down in pathology.
Just, I'd kill for
a bag of Vitner's.
Mmm, don't overthink it.
Go for the next best thing.
Hey, Will, you got
a second for a curbside?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Rapid strep
and mono were negative,
LP normal.
I'm afraid it's
something exotic,
but we won't have
the cultures back
for another couple of days.
And now with
the bronchospasm...
Yeah, it could be
almost anything.
Exactly.
And I gotta confess,
I am at a complete loss.
Well, whenever I find
myself in the weeds,
I go back to something
one of my clinical
attendings used to say.
"The answer is
always in the history."
That's your pearl of wisdom?
We can't get a history.
We're lost in a maze.
Then retrace
your steps.
Every decision you made,
each path you took
or didn't take.
Examine it all.
Sorry, Nat.
Will, what do the presence
of retinal
autoantibodies indicate?
What?
This mean what
I think it means?
Right?
I have cancer?
Possibly.
"Possibly"?
We don't know for sure.
There's a chance
that your loss of vision
was caused by your body
fighting some kind of tumor.
Is there any history of
cancer in your family?
I don't know.
Uncle Paul.
He's fighting
bladder cancer right now.
Really?
Any other medical history
I should know?
Any injuries
or any illnesses
or surgeries?
No.
Denise?
I'm gonna send you
over for a CT scan.
In the meantime,
let's take a quick look.
Enter.
If you require lights,
you'll have to
turn them on yourself.
Sabbath rules.
Dr. Latham, I understand
I should have consulted you
before recommending surgery,
but I'd developed
a rapport with Mrs. Simon,
and I thought since
you observe the Sabbath...
A man's life
always takes precedence.
So, you plan on
opening up the heart,
tying off
the bifurcated branch,
and closing everything
back up in 30 minutes?
Mmm-hmm.
Any longer and there
could be significant
cognitive deficits.
I understand.
If you don't
over-sew the connection,
he could develop
a deadly pseudoaneurysm.
That might take
an even experienced
surgeon an hour.
Pardon me, Dr. Rhodes.
The patient's temp
is down to 32 degrees.
Thank you, Leah.
You realize that by waiting
as long as you did to call me,
you've given us
no other surgical option.
I thought this
was our best course.
Thirty minutes.
I can make it in time.
I've done surgeries equally
as challenging before.
While assisting
Dr. Downey.
Yes.
In the cockpit,
a co-pilot's seat
is right next
to the captain's,
but the view out of the window
is surprisingly different.
Our bodies
are complicated.
Sometimes, um,
signals get crossed,
and our brains say one thing
and our bodies
hear something else.
I don't understand.
Is there something
wrong with the baby?
Yes. Well...
Not exactly. Um...
It's complicated.
What exactly are you saying?
Um...
Is there someone here
who can actually explain to us
what's going on, please?
If you give
Dr. Reese a minute,
I think you'll find
that she has
an excellent grasp of...
So, go ahead.
Explain, Dr. Reese.
I am sorry,
but there is no baby.
We lost the baby?
No. You never had one.
You don't know what
you're talking about.
No, see, the evidence
is actually right here. Um...
You have a condition
called pseudocyesis.
Uh, you may have
heard it referred to as
a hysterical pregnancy.
Are you saying
my wife is crazy?
No, she's not.
She's not saying that at all.
She's saying that sometimes
the mind has the ability
to play tricks on the body.
I... I can feel my baby.
I don't care what
this ultrasound shows. It...
Your machine must be broken.
I can assure you it's not.
Your blood test confirms it.
Well,
then your lab's broken, too,
'cause I'm pregnant. I am!
Honey.
Okay, okay.
No! No.
Hey, back off.
No! No!
Honey, honey.
Honey...
Get away from her!
Get me out of here!
We need
some help in here!
Let me go!
No!
It's okay.
Dr. Charles, I'm sorry.
Hey, hey, hey!
Where are we?
Body temperature's
at 20 degrees Celsius.
Flow down.
Clamp.
Clamp is on.
Give cardioplegia.
Plegia's on.
Heart's arrested.
Start the clock.
Stage is yours,
Dr. Rhodes.
Metz and Debakey.
Here, Doctor.
Okay.
Upper abdomen looks clear.
Wait a minute.
What's this?
I think this thing
is acting up again.
Maggie, do me a favor
and reboot it.
I had it serviced last week.
It should be fine.
Yeah, but right here.
It's my prostate gland.
I'm a transgender woman.
My doctor recommended
not removing the prostate,
'cause the surgery
would be too complicated.
Well,
it's definitely enlarged.
Before I send you
over to the scan,
I'm gonna need to
order another panel.
Maggie, run down
to phlebotomy,
have them draw up a CMP
and check her PSA levels.
Tina can do that for you.
I'm a civilian today.
But you have much
more sway with the lab.
I'll be right back, okay?
If you want me out of
the room, just say so.
Well, excuse me.
Why didn't you tell me
your sister used to be a man?
It's not my place.
It's up to the patient.
Then you should've
gotten her to tell me.
This is crucial
medical history.
How long ago
did she transition?
About nine years ago.
Was it hard for you?
Harder for her.
If it were my family,
she would have been disowned.
Well, it's taken time.
We had a lot to learn.
Mr. Dobbs, please calm down.
We just want to help you.
You've done enough.
The second she wakes up,
we're out of here.
I think that'd be a mistake,
but I'm not gonna
stand in your way.
We're done.
So?
He's sending her home
as soon as
the sedative wears off.
We're gonna let them leave?
Yep.
We can't put her
on a psych hold?
Doesn't meet the criteria.
I mean, is she
a danger to herself
or others?
Is she unable
to take care of
her basic needs?
I've been
doing some reading.
There was this one case
where they put
a woman under anesthesia
and her belly deflated
and she thought
she had a miscarriage.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
So...
Are... Are you actually
suggesting that we do that?
I'll go get her
discharge started.
So, we're giving up?
When's the last time
you had some sleep?
Are you sending me home?
No.
I just think it
might be a good idea
to get some rest.
You know?
You've been up all night.
Come back tomorrow,
start fresh.
Yeah, you're, uh...
You're right.
I, uh, should
get out of here.
Do you know how many cases
we're looking at yet?
Natalie.
One second.
Okay.
Yes, I will test him right now
and send over the results
as soon as we get them.
Thank you.
Who was that?
The health department.
Looks like our John Doe
might have the measles.
Measles? But he doesn't have
any Koplik spots.
Doesn't always
present that way.
Well, then how
did you figure...
Ah!
It's a belt buckle.
Flip it over.
"I Survived The Stampede"?
It's a roller coaster.
That amusement park
down in Champaign,
they just confirmed that
they had an outbreak
of the measles.
Five cases, kids who
were never vaccinated.
This whole time
we were assuming
that he brought
this exotic disease
into the country with him.
And now,
it actually looks like
he caught it here.
The labs will confirm it.
What?
I've known you
all these years,
and I never realized
how genius you are.
I'm serious.
How did you even think
to look at the belt buckle?
When you're in the weeds,
always go back to the history.
No, wait! Wait for me!
Perfect.
My husband just went
to go get the car, so...
I'm really sorry.
I wish I had done
a better job
explaining things.
Explain what?
That I'm hysterical?
That I'm not
carrying a baby?
I'm sure my boss
is regretting ever
offering me this position,
and I really wanted to be
good at it,
and now, well, again, I'm...
I'm really sorry.
You're lucky.
What? I'm lucky?
You care about what you do.
You know what I did
before I moved here?
I was a skier,
an extreme skier.
Wow.
Sounds like quite
an adrenaline rush.
Yeah.
But it was more than that.
It wasn't just
something that I did.
But it was who you were.
Yeah.
What you said about my baby,
is it true?
Yeah.
Maggie?
What happened?
Uh, she wouldn't let
me examine her.
She's leaving.
What?
Did you know it was offensive
to use the word "transgender"
as a noun?
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
Okay.
Yeah.
What happened?
Exactly what I
should have expected
from a dude from Canaryville.
Oh, come on, Denise,
he's a little awkward
and all,
but he's good people.
And a great doctor.
You know what?
I'll have my prostate checked
when I get back.
No! You're not leaving.
Not without
a definitive diagnosis.
You need to have all this
checked out annually, Denise.
You want to know why
I don't come back that much?
I don't always need everybody
judging my choices, okay?
Please, the family?
They embrace you.
I'm not talking
about the family.
I'm talking about you.
The second I see you
at the family reunion,
you're...
You're throwing shade about
how you were born this way.
I was mocking myself.
Just admit it.
You hate what
I've done to myself.
I miss my brother.
Is that such a bad thing?
Well, he's gone, damn it!
Not to me!
Not totally!
Look,
I'm sorry that I hurt you,
but I'm not gonna lose you.
So, if I have to
drag you kicking
and screaming
into that CT scanner,
that's what I'm gonna do.
I'm scared.
We'll get through this.
Time?
Six minutes.
Precisely.
Six minutes, 11 seconds.
You still
have another layer to go.
Damn it.
More suction.
You have
a clear line to the vessel.
Suction is not your problem.
You're not gonna make it.
I have plenty of time.
Not at
the pace you're going.
You've done 57% of the work
in 81% of your allotted time.
You are not
gonna get there.
Your nonstop
number crunching
isn't helping.
Thirty minutes.
That's what we agreed.
That's what you promised.
I'm taking over.
Step aside, Dr. Rhodes.
I can do this.
Step aside!
Dr. Downey may have been quick
to put his faith in you,
but my faith
takes longer to earn.
I've spent nearly
my entire life feeling
at war with my gender.
It figures the one piece
I didn't get rid of
is what's gonna kill me.
Biopsy came back.
Pretty much
what we suspected.
You have prostate cancer.
With treatment,
I am hopeful
it can be cured.
But, uh, you'll need
to see a urologist
as soon as you get home.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
There is a second option.
You could stay in Chicago,
and let us take care of you.
I'd like that.
Okay.
Hey, you tracked
down a translator?
No.
That's his cousin, Farah.
Turns out his
name is Pitopang.
He speaks Mamuju.
Came here
from West Sulawesi
a month ago
to work in his
uncle's restaurant.
Always wanted to
ride a roller coaster.
Wow. Thanks, April.
Okay.
Hi, I'm Dr. Manning.
Your cousin has the measles,
but he should
make a full recovery.
My cousin said thank you,
and he thinks you two
make a great couple.
Mmm.
And yes, ladies,
he is fluent in Spanish.
You think he
hired a publicist?
Doesn't need to.
He's a Rhodes.
Plus he looks like that.
Hey. There's our rising star.
Yes.
What are you talking about?
"40 Rising Stars Under 40."
Yeah, you're number 11.
Hey, don't feel bad.
There's always next year.
Or maybe the cover of People.
I swear I knew
nothing about this.
If you say so.
By the way,
how'd the surgery go?
Uh, yeah, it was good.
Thought you were going home.
Uh, I was just going
back over Darwin.
According to Hayman,
Darwin's issues
might have been
entirely physiological.
Perhaps some kind of
mitochondrial disorder.
Huh.
Mmm-hmm.
You don't say.
Yeah, I... I ran into
Amanda on my way out,
and I found out
that she used to be
an extreme skier.
Really?
Uh, I don't know,
maybe being pregnant
was her way of replacing
what she had left behind.
Nature abhors a vacuum,
I guess.
Speaking of which, um...
You mind?
Ms. Goodwin?
Dr. Rhodes.
I don't know if
you've seen this,
but there's a new issue out.
Yeah. Uh...
I had no idea that
I was gonna be
a part of this article.
No one called or contacted me,
and if they had,
I never would have...
I approved it.
You did?
It's good publicity.
Yes, but did you
actually read this?
I mean,
"Dashing young surgeon
"is poised to lead
Chicago Med
into the future."
No, I have
no problem with that.
Ms. Goodwin,
look, the surgery today,
Dr. Latham was right.
I wasn't gonna make it.
I thought I was
more ready than I am.
So, if you're looking
to promote the department,
you should look to him.
I mean,
he is a great surgeon.
Latham is a great surgeon,
but they wanted
someone under 40.
Stay humble, Dr. Rhodes.
Your time will come.
Huh?
What do you think?
Too big?
No, you'll grow into it.
You are now an honorary member
of the Lockwood tribe.
Thank you.
I will wear it with pride.
Who are you looking at?
No one.
Ah!
That cute pathologist,
Dr. Shore.
Nina.
Nina?
Mmm.
Ah.
Well, don't feel like
you've to stay here
and entertain me.
I've seen enough
of you for one day.
Okay.
How do I look?
Mmm.
You know,
when I think about Malcolm,
it's times like these
that I miss the most.
Malcolm?
Mmm.
Go on.
Hey.
You ever figure out
what you wanted?
Yeah. Yeah,
I think I did.
At Johns Hopkins,
they have a Shabbat elevator.
It stops on every floor.
No need to press a button.
What can you do?
Down?
Good Shabbos, Dr. Latham.
Shabbat shalom,
Dr. Rhodes.