It's just a migraine.
Honey, until we're
completely sure...
Is the pain a tight
band or pulsating?
Good question.
Pulsating, light bothers me,
nausea. I get these all the time.
You said you can feel a...
What did you call it? A...
An aura. I know, but...
Exactly how often do
you get these symptoms?
I just ask, since your boyfriend
doesn't seem to recognize them.
Zane and I have only known
each other for eight days.
It moved fast.
Ellie. Did you feel
your foot twitch?
No.
Positive Babinsky.
What does that mean?
It's not a migraine.
Oh, that.
I was performing due
diligence on my new roommate,
who might be a violent maniac,
and look what I found in his closet.
It's cute.
You moved in with two suitcases.
You only have four pairs of underwear.
How the hell did a
parrot make the cut?
I'm a Parrothead. A
Jimmy Buffett enthusiast.
The "Margaritaville" guy?
Well, he has other, far better songs,
but yes, the "Margaritaville" guy.
It brings me luck.
Scary to think what your
life would be like without it.
Can I have it back?
It's fun getting to know you better.
Worth every damn bit of sacrifice.
Ooh!
I was demonstrating a torch
lift this morning and, bang.
"Ballet master."
You're a dancer?
God, no, I'm like the CEO.
At my age, I'd be the
Betty White of the troupe.
Is she a dancer?
I don't know much about culture.
I assume I just sprained
something, right?
Uh, we will need neuro
and abdominal exams,
X-rays for fractures,
CBC for infection,
cultures to rule out
a spinal abscess...
You're... new, aren't you?
It's my second week here.
It's actually only my
first day seeing patients.
Am I your first?
Yes. Sorry. But yes.
Well, that's impressive.
Whoever is supervising
you must really trust you.
I'm not sure that's true.
They won't let me
join their stupid gym
because I had
high blood pressure.
How am I supposed to
lower it if I can't work out?
Two hundred over
105. That is quite high.
I just told you it was high.
Are you a smoker?
Yeah. Pack or two a
day. More if I feel crappy.
And...
do you have diabetes?
You reading those
questions out of a book?
- Yes.
- Have you ever done this before?
- I told you. You have to trust them.
- I don't.
Then act like you do.
Go away.
Nothing more romantic than spending
one of your first dates in an E.R.
Well, stressful experiences
release oxytocin,
same hormone that
creates emotional bonds.
This might actually
cement their relationship.
Next to the hippocampus.
Is that a tooth?
Dermoid cyst. Cool.
She's having a seizure.
Secure her airway, push
two milligrams Ativan.
- Thank you for trusting us enough...
- Please report.
Uh, 58-year-old male
dancer with back pain.
I ruled out red flags like
osteomyelitis and kidney infection.
But I did find evidence of a
mild L2 compression fracture
with moderate wedging and evidence
of impingement on the neural canal...
You want to start beta blockers?
Me? Yeah. I think my patient's
a stroke risk. BP's 200 over 105.
It was the same
at her gym earlier?
Can you raise your arms?
Okay. Now, try to
squeeze my hands?
I did all these tests with her.
You're gonna give me
stuff to lower blood pressure.
That would kill you. Now
push against my hands.
If she's in danger
of having a stroke...
She's not. She's
already having one.
Smoking on estrogen
put her at high risk,
loss of circadian blood
pressure variation confirms it.
Stick out your tongue.
We gotta get a CTA...
No. We're treating with IV tPA.
Don't we need
to locate the clot?
We just did. Right deviation means
a right vertebral artery occlusion.
You can close your mouth now.
Her seizure and coma were
caused by a dermoid cyst.
It's a pocket of tissue with
bits of teeth, hair, and fat.
She likely got it
before she was born.
What can you do?
The less invasive option is to put
in a drain to release some pressure,
treat with anti-seizure
meds and steroids,
then basically watch to see
if the swelling goes down.
And the more invasive?
Surgical removal.
But the cyst is deep inside and
wrapped around major arteries.
So it is more likely
to fix the problem,
but it carries risk of
stroke or paralysis.
We need a decision quickly.
Ellie's sister is
on the paperwork,
but we haven't been
able to reach her.
Do you know where the
parents live, or any other siblings?
He might still be on a
business trip, but, uh...
you can try her husband.
If we can't reduce the swelling, she
will have permanent brain damage.
Is that him?
Brendan.
We need you to make a decision.
Yeah, yeah. I'm not sure
that I'm the right one to...
I mean, right now...
I hate her.
You don't. You're
angry. You're hurt.
Because you love her.
Fifty-eight-year-old male
dancer with back pain.
Moderate vertebral wedging and
impingement on the neural canal.
Yes. I think an L2
compression fracture.
Prescribe anti-inflammatories,
a brace, and PT.
Then discharge him.
Do you want to
re-check anything?
No.
Remember to floss your
brain after every meal, people.
Aspirating.
Do you think we
should be doing this?
I know we have to legally, but
maybe her husband isn't the one
who knows her best,
knows what she wants.
Better than the guy who met
her last weekend. Arachnoid knife.
Well, that guy,
she's in love with him.
- Apparently.
- Maybe she loves them both.
Aren't you a romantic.
Watch for perforators.
I've been polyamorous for years.
Well, when I was monogamous,
I was jealous, possessive,
egotistical.
Our patient wasn't
honest, that's not cool,
but other than that...
Good margins all around.
Let's dry up the field
and close her up.
I never would've guessed
I was your first patient.
Felt more like the fourth.
By the way, did I
detect an accent?
No.
I mean, I had one, but I
worked really hard to lose it.
No one ever notices it anymore.
Eastern Europe?
Brooklyn.
Williamsburg. I grew up
Hasidic, speaking Yiddish.
I left it a long time ago.
You left the religion?
The religion, the
culture, my family.
It must not have been
easy, growing up that way,
knowing you were a doctor.
- Excuse me?
- My generation, you could get bashed.
You could get thrown in jail.
We had to learn codes,
how to read each other.
You should thank
your lucky stars
you get to live your
life the way you want it.
I don't know what
you went through.
Please don't pretend to
know what I went through.
- Sir?
- My gut.
Code blue!
The surgery seemed successful,
but we need to monitor for
seizures over the next 24 hours.
Is this high enough?
Little to the left. No,
to the right. Yeah.
You never said
anything was wrong.
Can we have the
room for a moment?
I'm sorry, but we
really need to check...
You're worried about talking in
front of them? Embarrassing me?
I didn't think
anything was wrong.
When I met Zane, it...
made me realize
something was missing.
Or at least, I think
that's what I'm feeling.
- You mind tilting your chin up?
- Sorry.
Why couldn't you
just talk to me?
Or... Or leave me?
I don't know.
Were you happy?
With him?
I guess I should go.
Brendan?
Who are these people?
- Ellie, do you know where you are?
- Wait, why am I in the hospital?
Suprarenal aortic aneurysm.
It ruptured as he
was being discharged.
- Clamping aorta now.
- How much blood is he down?
We suctioned out two liters and
gave six units on the rapid infuser.
The aneurysm caused his
back pain. Dr. Wolke missed it.
I did an abdominal exam.
Aneurysms are
very hard to catch.
Experienced doctors miss
them all the time. Pott's scissors.
The aneurysm is 6.5 centimeters.
Dr. Wolke should have felt it.
It felt like normal
musculature. I'm so sorry.
We'll never know what you felt.
There's no way to know if you,
or any doctor, for that matter,
would have detected this.
I would have.
He asked me if I
wanted to double-check.
If I had, I would have caught
the aneurysm before the rupture...
Stop it.
He made a mistake.
He might have. But you did too.
No. You told me to back off.
I didn't tell you to
abdicate responsibility.
When a first-year asks if you
want to re-check their work,
your answer should
always be yes.
The fact they're
asking is a warning sign.
I didn't know that.
It's called retrograde
memory loss.
Luckily, it seems to have been
temporary. She's lucid again.
We're running an MRI and
lab tests to see what caused it.
Thank you for telling
me. I know I'm just the...
You care.
Maybe things with Ellie and I
weren't always perfect, but...
It was exciting.
When I was with her...
I'd never felt that way before.
I took care of her when
she was sick, I never strayed.
And it wasn't about the
things we did, it was about...
being with her.
She stuck by me
when I needed her.
Last year, I was... I was
drinking way too much.
It's hard to imagine
being without her.
I just can't imagine
She's stable. Q-hour neuro exams
and monitor for signs of elevated ICP.
I believe you're
getting a call, Dr. Park.
You're a Parrothead.
Wear it proud.
Can we just agree
to have some limits?
Maybe not everything
I own is fair game.
Mm, no.
Perfect.
Trust me. It'll be worth
every damn bit of sacrifice.
I've said that twice now.
You've said a lot of things
twice. You have limited creativity.
It wasn't creative at all.
It's from Jimmy Buffett's
"Cheeseburger in Paradise,"
one of his "Big Eight,"
so big even I know it.
You, sir, are no Parrothead.
Mia does woodwork
as a side hustle.
She made it for me on
our first trip to Hawaii.
Lovely. Wait, no, that's
not right. "Pathetic"?
And do you toss away all
mementos of past friends and jobs?
If a job cheated on me,
I might want to move on.
When's the last time
you dated someone?
When's the last time you
acted like a human being?
So years?
Yeah, I definitely
found the right word.
See you at home.
You can't sleep?
You want some warm milk?
My mother has like
18 prescriptions for this,
some of them are
actual prescriptions.
I can sleep, but need to figure
out how to supervise better.
How many of these are
you planning to read tonight?
Just the relevant
sections of each.
Tech bros are always watching
TED Talks on leadership.
That could be quicker
than those books.
How about tomorrow
we have a date night?
Why would we need a date night
if we're in a relationship
and living together?
Because it'll be fun.
I'll schedule date
night for tomorrow.
Great. Think of
something for us to do.
There is one thing that
helps most people sleep
that my mother did
not tell me about...
What makes a great manager?
Some say it's all
about planning.
Others, charismatic leadership.
A third group...
Your temporary memory
loss was caused by some fat
that leaked from your cyst.
We can remove
it via a craniotomy,
but there is a real risk
of more memory loss.
Maybe permanently.
What will I lose?
The time prior to the surgery.
Days, weeks, possibly months.
But if we don't operate soon, the
risk of brain damage only grows.
I can't do it.
I don't even know
what I want right now,
but I do know that I don't want
the decision about my marriage
forced on me by an operation.
Please. Find another answer.
You are not very good at your jobs
and I'm not very good at teaching you.
So we are going to focus
on one step at a time.
You will master
each skill separately.
I've made a list of 400 skills.
I didn't have time to
finish it last night because...
Dr. Wolke, you will be
focusing on physical exams,
you'll find a list of the
seven post-op tests
to be conducted on Carl.
Dr. Jackson, you'll
find relevant seminars
on conquering nerves
in the workplace.
What are good
activities for a date?
What does she like?
Cars, coding,
Zelda: Breath of the
Wild, Sauvignon Blanc,
Skittles, RuPaul's
Drag Race, camping...
I had a very romantic
time camping in Big Sur.
This is for tonight.
I haven't gone on many dates.
But everyone loves movies.
Healing nicely. No
redness or swelling.
I'm going to palpate
around it now.
Look, I need to apologize.
For bringing up your
personal life the other day.
No. You have nothing
to apologize to me for.
So what's next on your list?
Checking for signs of
infection inside your abdomen.
Open your eyes wider.
You have signs of jaundice.
I think your liver is failing.
The liver is being damaged
by a new aneurysm.
How? A genetic
predisposition or...
More likely when
we fixed the first one,
we increased the
pressure upstream.
Can we stent the celiac?
Anatomy's too tricky.
Aortic to celiac bypass?
We'd just risk a new
aneurysm forming upstream.
Maybe, but it solves
the problem in front of us.
He'll die without
an intervention.
He'll probably die either way.
Let's all take the time to
research alternate solutions.
If we can't come up with
something better in 24 hours,
we proceed with the bypass.
She's saying no for
emotional reasons.
So the answer isn't medical.
It's emotional.
We think Zane
should talk to Ellie...
No. I don't want him
anywhere near her.
To convince her to
do the craniotomy.
From you, it's
self-serving. From Zane...
Wait. If she doesn't want it...
You said you can't
imagine life without her.
If you meant that, you'd risk
anything to keep her alive.
Including her memories of you.
Well done, Shaunie.
I really needed this.
The system update
yesterday went bananas.
I've been flooded
with complaints.
Total nightmare.
How's work? Did the videos help?
Yes.
Tell me more.
One of my patients developed
a secondary aneurysm.
Now, I need to find a
surgical fix by tomorrow.
Otherwise, he will probably
die. I brought Skittles.
Shouldn't you be
at the hospital?
Yes. After you go to bed, I
plan to go back and do research.
Shaunie, go to the hospital.
No. We made this schedule.
Someone else needs you.
More than I need you.
It's a hospital. It's
filled with sick people.
But tomorrow, will
someone need you
to come up with a
way to save their life?
Maybe.
Probably not tomorrow.
Okay.
I am canceling date night.
- That's rude.
- Oh, well.
Then...
I should...
go to the hospital.
Mm-hm.
They're prepping
Ellie for surgery.
Any last-minute questions?
What should I do?
Forgive her.
Under the right circumstances,
every human will stray.
We're not hardwired
for monogamy.
I'm guessing you're not married.
I'm not saying that
it's wrong to feel angry.
She wasn't honest with you.
But the alternative to forgiving
her is losing someone that you love.
Then what?
If she comes back to me
just because she forgets him...
my marriage wouldn't be honest.
I have an idea.
We could remove more proximal
aorta and extend the graft.
And rebuild the
celiac trunk with what?
Dacron?
Branches are too complex.
This Lancet article
on polymer materials...
doesn't work, but...
thin-film nitinol?
Did we break him?
We have the material.
It's his veins.
- Hey.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Did we reestablish
personal boundaries?
This morning's presentation
is on... who's not moving on?
Exhibit A.
Canoodling on a very
romantic hillside with...
With my gay best
friend. Can you leave?
Exhibit B.
A XXL Rob Gronkowski jersey.
Just the latest fashion style, from
a woman who hates the Patriots
or an ex-boyfriend's...
Not an ex. I hooked up with
Gronk. Seemed worth preserving.
Rob? Or one of his brothers?
Props, I guess.
Exhibit infinitum.
Two ticket stubs to
Quantum of Solace.
Now, you once called
Daniel Craig "James Blond."
And yet, 11 years later,
these were in your drawer,
on top of an instruction
manual for a 2019 cellphone.
Which means you dug
them out within the last year.
Why? I can only assume
you are currently once again
hooking up with
the James Blond fan.
- How could you possibly deduce...
- I also read your e-mails.
You've been sleeping with an ex
without asking for any commitment.
It's just sex. It's not
keeping me from anything.
What's more likely to prevent
someone from moving on?
A parrot in a drawer
or an ex in your bed?
I'm at least getting something
hot from the situation.
You're just
wallowing in failure.
So if your bag's empty, I'm naked
and have to go to the bathroom.
It's called a
Y-shaped vein graft.
Your aorta is damaged
from the aneurysm
right where it branches off.
We're going to find a vein in
your leg that's similar in size,
cut it out, and use it to
replace the damaged artery.
How bad is it?
This is an excellent solution.
If it works.
What are the actual
chances that it doesn't?
That I'm going to die?
I don't want to give a number.
I mean, I can't.
I literally can't.
There are too many factors.
I can call in Dr. Murphy...
I don't need to hear
numbers. How bad is this?
Bad.
Thank you.
Whatever happens, you're
gonna be an incredible doctor.
And I am honored to
have been your first patient.
I screwed up.
That first exam.
I felt something.
I should have known
it was an aneurysm.
We could have saved
you before it got bad.
Why?
You were my first patient.
I need you to do
something for me.
I need you to pray.
You must know a
prayer for the sick.
I'm not a believer anymore.
Neither am I. But...
Ellie, do you know these men?
Of course. Brendan.
And...
And are you a
friend of Brendan's?
Something like that.
A lot has happened
in the last week.
So before you went under,
the doctors made a video.
It's sort of a message from
your old self to your new one.
Um...
I just want you to
know... that I love you.
Tell me about the day you met.
I was in the middle of
an art exhibit in SoMa
and I noticed this
guy and he was...
looking at all the
same paintings
I had been looking at and, um...
Need another six-O loaded
backhand for the arterial stump.
Graft is secure.
Take off the Satinsky clamp.
Good perfusion
to his lower body.
Heart rate's spiking.
There's no ST elevations.
BP's tanking. Did he
thrombose the graft?
Distal anastomosis is pulsatile.
But there is blood pooling
in the left lower quadrant.
The right, too.
He's bleeding
everywhere but the graft.
- It's DIC.
- Send a stat ROTEM and coag profile.
Start compressions, give
epinephrine and get the defib.
- Set it to 120.
- One-twenty. Clear.
Compressions.
No response.
Go to monophasic at 360.
Clear.
Why aren't you shocking again?
He's in asystole.
Dr. Lim?
Dr. Wolke.
He's dead.
Time of death: 7:23 p.m.
Take as much time as you need.
I was in love with him.
All those moments I had, him...
Meeting at the gallery, the conversations.
I don't remember any of them.
But they were real.
And they brought up feelings...
ones I don't remember
having for a really long time.
But all they made me
think of was you, Brendan.
Hearing how I met Zane just
reminded me how you and I met.
Chelsey's party and you showed
up in that ugly bomber jacket.
And Zane taking me to the hospital
reminded me how you nursed me
for months when I
broke my femur in Aspen.
And the whole time...
I just couldn't stop thinking about
how much I must have hurt you.
And I don't...
I don't I know if
you can forgive me...
but I love you.
And I... I want to come home.
Well, you're wrong.
That bomber jacket
was really cool.
He died.
I tried stepping back.
I tried brainstorming.
And he died.
I don't know what people
are thinking or feeling.
I can't communicate what I need.
And more patients will die.
You don't think your ASD had
anything to do with your patient's death,
do you? Because it didn't.
It did.
Asher wasn't sure about
his abdominal exam.
I should have known that.
Shaun, you're going to do... most
things better than anyone else.
And there are...
days when you're gonna
fail like everyone else.
Today might be
one of those days.
So...
what do you do then?
You go home, you be
with the people you love.
You take comfort in that.
And then you wake up
tomorrow and start all over again.
You can go home.
I just...
don't want to be
alone right now.
I opened a Bumble account today.
I swiped right
three times today.
Gronk's jersey didn't
have a tag in the back.
It's symbolic.
You have any idea how much
the real one'll be worth one day?
Fair enough.
♪ Wastin' away again
in Margaritaville ♪
♪ Searchin' for my
lost shaker of salt ♪
♪ Some people claim that there's
A woman to blame but I know ♪
♪ It's my own damn fault ♪
I'm glad you're here with me.
So am I.