Given goodish behavior
and eight of 12
months’ time served,
we have the discretion to
grant parole Friday the 10th,
five days from now.
Are you sorry
about what you did?
Yes.
Yes?
That's the correct
answer, isn't it?
Are you trying to annoy us?
No. I'm just trying to give you the
answers you need to cover your asses,
fill out your forms
and let me out of here.
We need you to show us remorse.
Is that how our system works?
Release the best actors?
I shudder to think what
that world would be like.
You drove your car into
your ex-girlfriend's house
and then fled the
country for three months.
I knew that her daughter was
at grandma's, like every Friday.
And I saw everyone else
move into the living room...
They could have moved back.
Which I would have noticed since
I was driving right towards them.
Shut up.
We got an order to
reduce overcrowding.
But let me be clear.
You mouth off to one guard,
we catch you with a single
cafeteria tray in your cell,
you break any rules I
don't even remember,
you can park your ass
here for four more months.
So forget being sorry. Can you
stay out of trouble for five days?
Yes.
Gather up for meds.
Asofa.
Yeah.
Why you keep helping him out?
Yeah. Why would
I wanna make sure
that my homicidal cell mate is
taking the right anti-psychotics?
House.
Mendelson.
He's on 80 milligrams
of propranolol, this is 40.
You're right. Sorry.
No worries. I like
my nurses naughty.
You know, I'm starting
to think, Mendelson,
you just really like
the taste of my spit.
Hey, House, check
out our new brand.
You've really got a thing
for swastikas, Mendelson.
Like an ironic thing?
It's a German name.
So is House, and I'm Jewish.
Nah. I'm a black, gay gypsy.
Knight to king's bishop three.
Queen to king's bishop seven.
Hey. You're House, right?
I got these weird pains in
my elbows and in my knees.
You know what's weirder is
how the clinic is a large room,
and you somehow
confused me with it.
Well, to be fair, I am large.
Hi, Rollo.
I realize this is probably
a rhetorical question.
Why are you stealing my stuff?
Hey, House. I heard
you're on short time.
You won't need this.
You heard about my parole.
But not about my violent reactions
when people steal my tuna.
Put it back. Nuh-uh.
Really?
You're stepping to a guy who
outweighs you by 50 pounds
and who is carrying a cane
which, while prison-approved,
will still cause some issues
if inserted into your colon.
Yeah, like you
losing your parole.
And you ain't gonna
rat me out neither,
'cause you don't wanna get a snitch
jacket and wind up shanked in the showers.
So you're just gonna
let me walk out of here.
You wanna get
back at these guys,
get out alive on Friday.
Okay? Now, go to work, House.
And that was
checkmate, right? Yep.
I heard you're on
that short time, House.
If you like tuna,
you're a little late.
I want your stereo
and your headphones.
It can wait till you
finish your work.
Drop it off in my cell.
99.9. I'm gonna start
him on ceftriaxone.
Good catch. I might
have missed that.
It's not gonorrhea.
I didn't say it was.
Not out loud. You're just figuring a
joint pain plus fever plus a low lifestyle
equals a ceftriaxone
prescription.
So you saying I got the clap?
I've only been in here one
week, my girlfriend's clean.
I ain't got a
girlfriend in here.
How do you know
about ceftriaxone?
House used to be a doctor.
Not going back.
And that look of shock
is elitist and offensive.
Doctors can be
degenerates. This is America.
There's subtle eyebrow loss.
It's lupus.
Well, there's no discoid
or malar rash on his face.
Which would be dispositive
if he was just a giant head.
He's got a point, but
I'll let you make the call.
No, there's no reason
to search for a bodily rash
since lupus doesn't
usually present that way.
"Usually"?
Well, I guess that's good
enough for prison work.
You don't write people up
for mouthing off, do you?
Not usually.
You don't want to
mess with Stomper.
He didn't get that name because
he's a fan of Santa's reindeer.
You think one of Santa's
reindeer was called Stomper?
You're missing my point.
I'm not gonna listen to a guy
who can't name the reindeer.
You saw what happened
in the yard with Diaz.
He barely said a couple of
words and set the boy off.
Oh, no.
I know that look.
Hey, Stomper. Where's my stereo?
I brought it to your
cell. It ain't there.
I was just getting to that part.
Rollo followed
me in and took it.
No way Rollo diss
me like that. Way.
I don't want to start any
rumors, but... But what?
He was all, "I can
take Stomper,"
and I was all, "How come?"
And he was all, ""Cause of how
Diaz kicked his ass last month."
In fact, he actually called
you "Stompee," with an "E."
I think his gist was...
You took my stereo?
Get out of my house,
Stomper, I ain't got no stereo.
What's this, then?
What? I didn't put that there!
You gonna lie to my face,
you lying son of a bitch!
What? I didn't do anything!
Next time I will
take your stereo!
That's enough!
Ow!
That was stupid.
Is that like a
synonym for "clever"?
Time they get out of solitary,
I'll be teaching physics
at the University of Fiji.
You have four days left.
How many more tricks do you got?
Don't.
Another pet?
This is gonna end badly. Again.
Remember, we talked about this?
Or at least I talked and
you stared at me eerily?
I think it was eerily. Eerily
felt like the best-case scenario.
Hey.
Take off your shirt
so I can find the rash.
Now you wanna help me?
'Cause that doctor
didn't believe you?
Well, if you could think of a better way
to prove that she's an idiot, I'm all ears.
Now, let's get this over with.
Yeah.
That's Nicole.
She lives at her mom's now,
on account that she lost her job.
Her mom hates me,
so she can't visit, she
ain't accepting my calls.
That's what happens
when you date a 12-year-old.
You don't believe me?
Belief implies a level of giving a
crap that I'm never gonna achieve.
Pull down your pants.
Hey.
It's not that I was trying to
prove you're an idiot or anything,
but lupus boy and I were
at the beach this morning,
and I noticed a
rash on his left thigh.
I checked you out.
You were a pretty big deal.
What went wrong?
Something very
obvious and very boring.
Drug related?
Forging prescriptions?
You're good.
Just like lupus boy will be,
when you start him on prednisone.
Name should have been a
giveaway. I'll send him up.
Why are you so sure I'm
gonna do what you say?
Because you're a smart, old
money trust-fund girl who took this job
because your liberal ideology
makes you want to make a difference,
but you're already getting
bored, and this is interesting.
Why would you say any of that?
Your shoes.
A different, expensive pair
every day, but never leather.
Which means you're
both rich and liberal.
Antique locket that's unpolished
gold, not some hipster thing.
It's a family heirloom,
which means old money.
Osler scarf, only on Fridays,
which means you did
your residency at Hopkins.
Which means you're smarter than
our interactions would so far indicate.
And your eyes.
The only time you haven't looked bored
in the three months since you've been here
is when we've been
discussing this diagnosis.
So, yeah, you'll
treat him for lupus.
House.
He wants you.
Parole?
You didn't tell me.
I didn't want a big
emotional scene.
You know what the rules are.
On short time, tax goes up.
How many do you want?
All of them.
Come on, Mendelson. I
should be on six a day.
I get four and I give you two.
Fine.
I'll get one in my
cell after lights out,
plus Wednesday, Thursday,
Friday. That's 11 in all.
I count 20.
You knew on Monday, you
get out Friday. Five days.
Should have told me earlier.
They give out four a day, max.
You'll figure something out.
You're a creative guy.
What if I just go into
protective custody
and spend the next
three days in the hole?
You could PC up.
But then you'll get out.
And unlike you, I got
friends on the outside.
Porter.
Doc. What you need?
I'm running a special on
grilled cheese this week.
I got some new girly mags, too.
I was thinking of
something more Vicodinny.
At least 16, and I need
them Friday at noon.
Man, that's pricey,
but it can be done.
How about you have one
of your peeps on the outside
send $200 to my
boy up in Trenton?
I am peepless.
This is just you
haggling, right? No.
You ever seen me chatting
on the phone? Taking visitors?
All right. I'm gonna
have to clean you out.
I'm gonna need to see some tuna, I'm
gonna need to see some stamps, stereo...
Just give them to me
as soon as you can.
What happened?
I was trying to use
the phone, I just...
I just got jostled
a little, that's all.
Who hit you?
No. I just... I just
bumped into the wall.
It's not lupus.
Is that good?
Does it feel good?
Sick.
No, I'm just going
through a bit of withdrawal.
I'm trying to survive on one
a day for the next few days.
No.
Fix him.
It's not lupus.
He broke his arm.
Or it is lupus, and
he was in a fight.
He was in a jostle.
Because if he admits he was in
a fight, then he goes to the hole.
That's why he'd lie to the guards.
He's got no reason to lie to me.
Oh.
See? There are those eyes again.
How about a viral
syndrome or MRSA?
No, wouldn't chew
up the bone that fast.
But reaction to meds could.
May I? May you what?
Make me lose my job by
showing you a patient file?
But why don't you
assume no recent meds?
How long can I assume
that he's been smoking,
based on his yellow fingers?
You're thinking lung
cancer, metastatic.
I'll x-ray him on Friday.
We share a traveling x-ray
machine with two other clinics.
I'm out of here on
Friday. He's not.
Well, but if he throws
a clot and strokes out,
you can use the x-ray
to do the autopsy.
Start him on blood thinners.
Very interesting practice
you must have run.
No need for tests,
no need for proof?
Where are you going?
To the proof store.
You were right about Nicole.
About me not
caring? I thought so.
It wasn't her mom. It's her.
She doesn't want to talk to me.
Please. I'm trying to listen to
your lungs, not your self-pity.
Cancer can wait.
Hey, you heading out
to the yard? Mmm-hmm.
Mind trying to
find me a cricket?
The old swap trick.
You don't think that'll piss
off your cellie even more
when he figures
it's a different bug?
I'll dress them the
same, like in Vertigo.
I'll try. But they spray so much
pesticides, I'm surprised we're alive.
Good point.
Hey.
How's it coming?
It ain't.
Confederates be giving
themselves spanking new tats.
They putting a claim
on all my Vicodin.
Now I love you
and all, my brother,
but not as much as I love my gang
of crazy, roided out Nazi bitches.
Now try an inch to the left.
Hear the difference? Yeah.
It's called an
acoustical shadow.
Means he's got a tumor.
How did you find that
without a stethoscope?
I didn't even know
you could do this.
Start the blood thinners.
So I for sure got lung cancer?
No. Yeah.
All you've proven is there's
an anomaly in his chest.
Which means your initial
diagnosis could still be right?
Which, apparently,
really bugs you.
I could do a clotting test.
That's a good idea.
We're just gonna cut your earlobe
a bit and check back in two minutes.
If there's a little blood
bubbling up, that's normal.
But if it's completely clotted,
it may indicate cancer.
Okay? Ready?
Are you really leaving medicine?
What are you gonna do?
You know, for someone who
asks as many favors as you do,
you sure don't make
any effort to win me over.
Before I went to med school, I
thought about getting a PhD in physics.
You ever heard of dark matter?
The way galaxies rotate,
the motion of the universe,
it means there's six times
more stuff than we can detect.
It's been theorized, but no
one's ever proved it exists.
So you'd want to research it?
Why? It's the greatest
mystery there is.
Theory of everything.
And completely
divorced from humanity.
Me and humanity, we
got together too young.
You have a gift.
There is something in this
world you are undeniably great at.
You can read people.
You understand them.
You gotta go back to medicine.
Well, if that gift is related
to what brought me here,
you'll understand why I'd
wanna check the returns policy.
Hey! Is this supposed to happen?
Cool.
Jiminy didn't chirp
much last night.
If it's a disease,
he's six inches under.
But this could also
be pesticide poisoning,
which bicarbonate of
soda has been used to treat.
See? Just so much, and no more.
Mmm.
This is where you say thank you.
Or I say thank you
for not killing me.
Thank you.
Hey.
The x-ray didn't show any tumors.
The acoustical shadow was just a lipoma.
I'm thinking... You all right?
I'm fine.
Ibuprofen?
It's not gonna help.
You can look at the
patient file if you want.
You trust me?
Any reason I shouldn't?
You're really not good at reading
people, are you? Or buildings.
People are complicated.
And people change.
Not that much to the first
and not at all to the second.
But if it'll get me the file...
If we add clotting disorder to the
symptoms, it's gotta be a toxin...
This guy's the only
one with symptoms.
It's either gotta be his
cell or his workstation.
The laundry. So maybe
a solvent or detergent?
Can you get me an
escort to gather samples?
Dr. Adams.
Why does this man have a file?
You need to get cotton swabs.
Not now. I got something to do.
You're a prisoner on tier time.
By definition, you
have nothing to do.
I'm gonna call her family,
her friends, her work.
I'm gonna get
through eventually.
You're moving slower,
you're getting weaker.
This thing is attacking your
bones, your joints, your blood.
Look, my girl's more important.
She's not your girl, you idiot!
She was the girlfriend
of a loser drug dealer.
You think she's got the self-control
to wait around for three years?
You think she should?
There's a reason we're locked
away from nice, normal people.
Your life outside is over.
Your friends, your girl,
everyone you worked with,
they've moved on.
Get out of my house.
Get out!
Where's Sykes? Off
at his other clinics.
Great. I'm gonna
go to the laundry.
Give me some swabs... No.
What? He yelled at you
for letting me see the file.
You'll get over it. Few
years of therapy maybe...
Why did you lie to me
about what you were in for?
Okay, so I drove a car into a
wall instead of stealing some pills.
You obviously don't care what
I did, you care that I lied to you.
You feel jilted. I feel stupid.
It doesn't even make sense.
Why are you doing time?
You didn't have any priors.
You didn't hurt anyone.
I had a bad lawyer.
I'm sorry.
We can't talk about
this case anymore.
We hear you're gonna need an
incentive to get all my pills by tomorrow.
I can't get all 20,
but once I get out...
Give us a minute.
Why do you think
I'm on buspirone?
The stress.
I get the runs almost every day.
Any sign of weakness,
20 guys would line up
to stick a sharpened-up
toothbrush in my eye.
So as much as my better nature,
really, wants to give you a pass,
it just wouldn't be
good for my health.
See you tomorrow.
I need your help.
You got any matches?
No. That's serious contraband.
What are you planning to do?
How about a stick of gum?
Sure.
I'm gonna need that, too.
Why?
Why do I need the pen
that you always carry
around and never write with?
This is plan B.
What happened to your cheek?
What is it?
A fire?
House, we gotta evacuate
this area. Come on.
Hey, House.
You were saying something
about how I should, like, swab or...
You're confusing me
with the clinic again.
What, you're abandoning me?
As soon as you leave, I am.
Why? What changed?
I'm just done. No you,
medicine, fixing people. Done.
Now, get out. No.
Your lips are swelling.
Open your mouth.
Did you just eat something?
Meatloaf, potatoes, coffee...
You allergic to anything?
Guard!
You're going into
anaphylactic shock.
Guard!
Damn it.
I gotta make a hole,
so you can breathe.
House, get away from him!
He's having an allergic
reaction. He can't breathe.
Lie on the ground with your
hands behind your head.
Alvarez, look at what I'm
doing. It's a tracheotomy.
Come on, man. You
know I'm a doctor.
What's wrong with him?
I have no idea.
Saving us both from
contraband charges.
It's been great knowing you.
I need to be taken
into protective custody.
Wow, that was great.
I think I really
dodged a bullet there.
You don't need PC?
Nothing personal.
We'll reschedule.
Rain check, I promise.
It wasn't the food.
It was the heat.
It's mastocytosis.
Could be set off by hot liquids,
like the coffee he just drank.
Masto's usually a
skin disease. "Usually"?
It can hit any organ.
Joint pain, osteopenia and
anaphylaxis, eyebrow loss.
It fits.
It's a possibility. I'll run
some blood tests. Thank you.
No. No! It's almost impossible
to confirm masto with blood work.
Just give him five aspirin.
If he has masto,
he'll go into anaphylactic shock
and won't be able to breathe again.
You do understand the
meaning of the word "confirm".
I'll do it.
I almost died in that cell.
House, you're in here
because you think you can do
whatever you want, whenever you want.
You can't. And neither can I.
The ACLU would have my job,
my license, maybe even my house
if I do an unauthorized,
experimental...
But if it is masto... It's not.
Well, what do you have to
lose by giving him the aspirin?
I'm not taking the risk.
It's his risk to take.
If he has another attack and
there isn't a doctor in the next cell,
he could die.
For one second, will you stop
covering your ass and do the test?
I think House is right.
No.
You're a moron and a
coward. I'll do it myself.
Guard.
You're done here,
just like every other place
you've ever set foot in your life.
If I ever see you in here again,
I will write you up and
they will revoke your parole.
Dr. House.
Did you get all the
Vicodin you needed?
I'm not an idiot.
That fire, that
bruise on your face.
I talk to prisoners, I know about exit
taxes. You're clearly getting squeezed.
I need 20.
And let me back in the
clinic when Sykes is gone.
I'll take care of Nick. You
can't if you're not willing.
Just take care of yourself.
Well done.
I knew if you'd learned
nothing else in here,
you'd learned the smart
thing is to fall in line.
You're absolutely right.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
I need back-up here.
Hey! Hey! Son of a bitch!
You gotta get past me
before solitary, you hear me?
Come on. Come on!
Thanks for getting
me to the clinic.
Take him out.
I got only two years
left in my stretch.
Take him out.
C.O.! Need a little help here!
I need back-up! I need back-up!
Without back-up there will be a fight here.
Alvarez!
Sullivan, back off!
Mendelson, you'll
be held responsible!
Hey, I'm just playing solitaire.
Hands behind your head.
On the ground!
You are so lucky.
We got a guy in an ambulance
heading to Princeton General.
Another dozen getting
ear gas hosed off them.
Hey, sit down!
Back off!
Sit down!
Where's the aspirin?
Oh, God. Did you get
beaten up on purpose?
House. What are you doing?
Hey!
House, open up.
This is a direct order.
Yeah, it's always
a direct order.
Eight months, and I haven't
heard an indirect order in here.
Dr. Adams!
They're gonna
revoke your parole.
They're gonna charge you with extra crimes.
You'll be here six more months, minimum.
Sorry, distracted.
You were saying?
I checked your file. You
didn't have a bad lawyer,
you had no lawyer.
You took the first deal they offered you
because you wanted to punish yourself.
You think getting beaten up,
you think saving this one
guy will wipe your slate clean?
No.
Then why are you doing
this? Because I have a gift.
Once you drink this, you should
get an attack almost immediately.
That is, if I am right.
You just bought yourself
months in solitary.
Was it really worth it? If
I'm wrong, no, it wasn't.
No! No! No! Get
the cup! Get the cup!
Drink it! Drink it!
No! Grab the cup!
Hands behind your back.
What were you
thinking? I don't know. I...
I was... I was scared.
No!
You're fired.
You're beyond fired.
You're completely un-hirable
anywhere. Do you understand that?
Yes. Now shut up and
let's see if he has an attack.
Come on. Just
a little more time.
Get him out of here.