Mm.
The clothes a surgeon wears
help to present an image.
The lab coats and
badges and scrubs...
All work together to indicate
a person of authority...
Someone you can trust.
When the clothes come
off, that's a different story.
We're sensitive,
vulnerable...
Human...
And just as prone to
questionable judgment
as anybody else.
Yes.
His hemoglobin is what?
Okay, so just, just do an MRI.
And a hemoccult, and I'll be right in.
My idiot intern thinks she found
a rare retroperitoneal tumor.
So now I have to go in
and tell her that she's wrong.
Well, I'm sure she'll still
be wrong in 20 minutes.
I can take care of
Zola this morning.
I don't have to
lecture until 10:00.
Still not sure it justifies
the size of my paycheck.
You're a great teacher.
I should know. I was
hot for teacher in my day.
Oh, really? MEREDITH: Mmm-hmm.
Mmm.
So what is on the
ol' agenda today?
Ah! Just catching
up on, Thomas' plan
for tomorrow's open PDA
ligation and left main bypass.
I've never seen one before.
Yeah, that's because nobody's
done it that way since 1993.
How long do you
suppose that's gonna take?
Seventeen hours give or take.
That's perfect.
What does that mean?
Nothing.
I have 20 minutes.
Want to go again?
I guess so.
That was the last time.
We can't do this anymore.
No, no, we won't, because
this is the last time, ever.
Okay.
I'm gonna get some
coffee. I'm gonna go pray.
Cool.
Ah, morning, Hunt.
It's beautiful out there.
Webber, what's with the tie?
Oh, just thought I'd
up my game a bit today.
Yeah. Where's yours?
Oh! I had kind of a rough night.
Oh! Oh!
Got a spare. Oh, thanks.
Don't mention it. Yeah.
Good morning, Bailey.
What's with the tie?
It felt like a tie kind of day.
Oh, well, does it also feel like
a small bowel
obstruction kind of day?
I'd be happy to
have you scrub in.
Not this afternoon. I'm busy.
Oh, I'm sorry.
You have an appointment
with your haberdasher?
Now what is so wrong with a man
taking a little pride
in his appearance?
Hello, handsome.
Catherine, there you are.
Yes, here I am.
Mmm. Nice tie.
Yeah, whatever's
wrong, that'll fix it.
Barnett decided everyone
should create new passwords.
You do it in the settings menu.
But I can't access the settings
menu without a new password.
So you're trying to break in?
Hey, probably gonna need to
go back in and do a redo ORIF
on Brody Wright's
humerus fracture, okay?
When the hell is
Robbins coming back?
Uh... Wait, did you see
her? Did she see you?
Robbins is here?
Oh, damn it.
What? Uh... Um, she's...
She's being fitted for
her first prosthetic today,
which I wasn't
supposed to tell you,
because the only way I was able
to get her to agree
to come in at all
was to promise that no
one knows she's here.
Which makes two promises I've
broken, if you count the time I said,
"I promise you won't lose your
leg," which she certainly does.
I didn't see her.
Good. Don't.
Tell her I hope it goes well.
No, I can't,
because then she'd
know I told you she's here.
Yeah, right.
Do you need me
to write this down?
Hey, Dr. Robbins.
Good morning. David
Moore. I'm your prosthetist.
Um, you know, we're gonna
be working together for a while.
You can call me David.
Can I call you Arizona?
What's a while?
Well, till one of us dies
or your leg grows back.
Yeah, that joke's always a risk.
Which one of these is mine?
Uh, none of those, actually.
Today we're just gonna get
you started on a post-op socket,
and that'll give us a good idea
of what's most
comfortable moving forward.
May I?
Mm.
Oh! Excellent.
You see how there's
no scar tissue?
That means it's healing well.
Oh, great.
Yeah, it is.
All right. Let's get to work?
Just stop having sex with him.
I am trying to fit
in. I live here now.
I have to just, you know, adapt.
So I'm making friends.
But you don't even like him.
Who says I have to like
him? He's my sex friend.
Eww!
Well, what about the
ancient guy? What about him?
You want me to be sex
friends with the ancient guy?
No. I want you to be regular
friends with the ancient guy
and stop having sex
friends in general.
I am regular friends
with the ancient guy.
He, frankly, is my bestie.
He's my you here in Minnesota.
Well, how does the
ancient Minnesota me
feel about you being
sex friends with Parker?
You know, it's no big
deal. Parker is fine.
A little reptilian, a
little chatty, but fine.
This is a cry for help.
It's a cry for an orgasm.
And how's that working out?
Meh!
Dr. Grey, the radiologist report
does indicate a
retrocrural mass,
which means I could
be right, right? Or not?
Holy crap. What?
I gotta go.
Holy crap.
Is it a big surprise?
It's very big.
Will I need to use two hands?
Two hands won't be enough.
Ooh!
Dr. Webber, does
this bed go down at all?
Bryan, this is the urologist
that I was talking to you about.
This is Dr. Catherine Avery.
Before you say anything, no, these
aren't basketballs in my pockets,
and, yes, I am very
happy to see you.
Surprise.
I don't understand why
you've let it get this bad
before seeking treatment.
He's using it as
an excuse to avoid
our 10-year high school reunion.
Paula, I am not. He is.
It wasn't this bad before.
I mean, I've seen other doctors
who prescribed pills that
never seemed to work.
Then a few months
ago, everything
sort of just blew up.
He wouldn't even have
come if I hadn't dragged him.
I would have. When?
After the reunion.
Bryan, there's no need to fear.
By the time we get
finished with you,
you'll be hitting that reunion
with 98% less scrotum.
Dr. Thomas, the
PDA was one thing,
but now with the blockage,
does that mean two surgeries?
No, it means two procedures,
both of which I propose to
perform during one surgery.
We'll fix your PDA from
the side, then flip you over
and then open up your
blocked arteries from the front.
Flip me, spin me...
Whatever you want.
If it means not feeling like
I'm trapped in the body
of an 80 year old anymore,
I'm in. THOMAS:
Janet, believe me.
I know exactly how you feel.
Because he's old.
He's very, very old.
Don't mistake Dr. Yang's
disrespect for a sense of humor.
She hasn't got one.
No, no, no. I respect you.
You're a historical landmark.
Case in point.
Like the Grand
Canyon. Keep it up.
Only older.
All right. Enough.
Just a smidge. Oh, my God.
A smidge older than that.
I work out all the time.
I read Men's Health.
And I don't eat
anything I actually want.
And you're telling
me I'm gonna die?
This tumor is difficult to
resect. It's not impossible.
Rob, you're in
private security, right?
Yeah, I'm a bodyguard.
All right. Well, that's my
job, too. I have your back.
Yeah, you know what?
This tumor is
just a little punk.
Can I have some tissue, please?
Any questions?
When you performed
that transcranial resection
of clival chordoma in 2003,
did you realize you'd
become a major influence
on surgeons around the world?
Any questions
about central lines?
Okay, look, I get that you
went over this in med school,
but as interns,
you're gonna be asked
to insert central
lines every day.
Do it incorrectly, and
the patient could die.
I could be watching
a whipple right now.
I heard that Dr. Webber has a
patient with scrotal lymphedema.
- Scrotal lymphedema?
- Ladies.
Dr. Shepherd. I have a
question about central lines.
Great. Go ahead.
In learning to insert
your first central line,
did you develop any of
the skills that contributed
to your influential clival
chordoma resection in 2003?
Dr. Yang, can I see you
for a second, please?
You know, I'll be right back.
Is this gonna take long?
Just a quick question.
Did you even try to suggest
a less invasive approach?
Uh, yeah. Of course I
did. A hybrid surgery.
Only one incision,
done in half the time.
When? When did you suggest it?
I don't know. Yesterday.
What did he say?
He said, "Are we a hospital
or a pizza delivery service?"
He asked if we needed it
done in 30 minutes or less.
He is so stubborn.
Yeah. But he's not wrong.
I mean, his way minimizes
the risk of recurrent shunt.
I mean, it's old school, but
I never would've thought...
Got it. Sounds great.
Okay. So I can go back?
Yeah, go, go. Enjoy
it while you can.
What does that mean?
Will I be off probation soon?
Just go.
Most men would just
bring a girl flowers.
You know, this is a very
dangerous game we're playing.
I've done my best to
keep Jackson in the dark
about the further adventures
of Catherine and Richard.
Which is why I made sure to
grab Dr. Quaid for the skin flap.
There's no reason Jackson
needs to be in that OR.
Maybe that's a mistake.
I come into town
to work on a case
that has a large
plastics component
and don't bring him in?
You saying it seems suspicious?
Maybe. Oh, maybe not.
It's just like high school.
I know. Isn't it fun?
Ooh, when you said you
were busy, you weren't kidding.
Dr. Bailey, how
nice to see you. Hi.
What happened to your
small bowel obstruction?
Cleared up.
Hey, you wouldn't
need an extra set
of hands on those
puppies, would you?
Uh, well, actually, I was hoping
that April Kepner
could come aboard.
Kepner?
Yeah, I'm, you know, I'm
taking her under my wing.
She's fragile. You understand.
That is a giant scrotum.
I do not understand.
I'm sorry, Bailey.
Next time.
Hey. You're the prosthetist?
Yeah. I've always thought that'd
make a good title for a movie.
Hey, David Moore.
Alex Karev, peds.
Uh, if you're looking for
Dr. Robbins, she's over in the clinic.
We're about to do a plaster
cast of her residual limb.
But you've got a few minutes.
Oh, no, that's cool.
I was just hoping that you
could tell me how she's doing.
Any scar tissue or contractures?
No. So far, so good.
All right.
How soon before she's
back up on her feet?
That's a little harder to say.
I should have a better
idea after tomorrow, though.
Tell her you stopped by?
No, no, don't, because I didn't.
All right. Keep trying, folks.
Nobody gets it the first time.
Or the 40th time, apparently.
I just can't seem
to locate the vein.
Okay, give it to me.
I...
Um...
Close your eyes.
Visualize the anatomy.
Subclavian vein is
what you're looking for.
Okay, walk it up the clavicle.
Okay. Watch on the
angle. Not too deep.
I see it.
Mmm. Watch your angle.
Boom. That's arterial blood.
He's gonna bleed to death.
So not boom?
No. Not boom.
You've gotta work around the
azygos and the hemiazygos veins.
There's fatty tissue, lymph
nodes, lymphatic tissue
and the sympathetic chains,
not to mention the fact
that the tumor has lifted
up the inferior vena cava
and is adherent to the aorta.
This is a mess.
I know.
So how do we get the entire mass
without having to
resect the aorta?
I have no idea.
Yeah, I'm happy to
take this off your hands.
I called you for an opinion,
not to steal my surgery.
No first-year attending
in her right mind
is gonna want to take
on something like this.
I mean, not when
full responsibility
for every decision
made in the OR
falls on her shoulders...
Mine.
Don't come crying to me when a
man's bleeding out on your table
just 'cause you think you bad.
Oh, she's bad.
Yeah, we'll see.
I still don't understand
what it is I'm looking at.
Those are testicles, Dr. Kepner.
Don't worry, sweetheart.
They're not supposed
to look like that.
I know what testicles are...
Jackson didn't mention
that you were coming.
He didn't know.
He made it very
clear, he would like me
to stay out of his
personal business,
so I am doing my best.
Well, I think that's great.
I've made no such
promises to you.
You need to start prepping
for next year's boards.
There's a fellow in our
gynecology department
that's an excellent
tutor. And he's cute.
That's not really even...
I said it before, and
I will say it again.
You're just too uptight, baby.
You need to get L-A-I-D.
Dr. Avery.
Look at me.
I am having the best
sex I have had in years.
Mm-hmm.
And it's just opened
me up like a flower,
blossoming towards the sun.
Mm.
That's a powerful image.
I bet that fellow knows
his way around a woman.
Oh, relax. I'm kidding.
See that? That's what I mean.
Uptight.
But I will give you his
number, just in case.
Hey, Dr. Webber.
Dr. Webber.
Um, yes, sir.
Why is my name on
tomorrow's OR schedule
for a scrotal lymphedema
surgery with you?
Got the wrong Avery. I'm doing
the surgery with your mother.
My mother's here
performing a surgery with you?
But we were hoping that you'd
be available to do a skin flap.
Actually, she sent me
to find you for a consult.
O... Okay, sure.
Yeah, I'll just be
a minute. Great.
Just a few more minutes, okay?
It's fine.
Oh! Uh...
Sorry. I thought you'd be ready.
That's because you didn't
check your voice mail.
You just looked
to see who called.
If you had checked
your freakin' voice mail,
then you would know that I
was still gonna be here a while,
because you would've
gotten the freakin' message!
I'll come back.
You know, my brother, he
never checks his voice mail either.
It's maddening.
Derek must be so proud.
You'll be, like, Mr. and
Mrs. Impossible Tumor.
But that's the problem.
I mean, he's not
Mr. Impossible Tumor anymore.
And I don't want
to rub his nose in it.
He's trying to be so
cheery about teaching.
Aw. That's so sad.
It's not sad. It's
just an adjustment.
Can you imagine never
doing surgery again?
I can. I do. I mean, he
didn't see this coming.
So I just try to
enjoy it while I can.
Oh, my God. He
doesn't see it coming.
Oh, my God. Thanks,
Mer. I gotta go.
Okay.
Oh! I hate teaching.
You love teaching.
I just never realized
how much I rely on
just having them be able
to watch me do the thing.
Well, I used to love it
when you stood behind me
and whispered
instructions in my ear.
Well, I can't do
that with all the kids.
How are you? How are you?
Yes, I know.
So I'm guessing your
intern didn't like finding out
she was wrong about the tumor.
No, she didn't like it at all.
This is the last time.
The last time was the last time.
Yeah, but this is
the last last time.
I have to be in the OR all
day tomorrow with your mom.
You're in that surgery, too?
What do you mean "too"?
Wait. You're gonna be there?
Yeah. No, no, no.
We cannot both be in that OR.
She's gonna figure it out.
She is obsessed
with my sex life.
She's having amazing
sex, so I have to, too.
Ga... Wh...
Sorry. Sorry. You
don't want to hear that.
Webber's still banging my mom.
That's who she called
the best sex of her life?
Ohh.
And we're done here.
White wine. MAN: What kind?
The big kind?
Torres, it's late.
Yeah.
Well, you know how they say
one of the biggest things
couples fight about is money?
Turns out money fights ain't got
nothing on an amputation fight.
I can imagine.
Yeah, but I can't
get mad or yell,
because then I'm the woman
yelling at her one-legged wife.
So I've been
sleeping at Mark's, but
I don't think I can take another
night in my dead best friend's bed.
It just reminds
me that he's gone,
and I end up having
the worst dreams.
It's getting so bad, I even
considered asking Shepherd
if I could crash in his
trailer in the woods.
Mm. That's pretty bad.
Yep.
Sorry. That was a lot.
Oh, I asked.
I'm not sure you did.
It's fine.
Honestly...
I haven't been
sleeping too well, either.
Want another?
Uh, yeah.
Yeah? Yeah.
He'll have another.
Not to add insult to injury, but
that's the worst tie I've ever seen.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, coming.
Well, hey there.
Uh...
I didn't know we... We're not.
What's your deal
with Dr. Thomas?
You came here to talk
about Craig Thomas?
Well, color me disappointed.
You said, "Enjoy him while
you can." What does that mean?
Come on in.
It's cold.
Are you firing him?
We can't fire him.
We can
force him to retire, though.
Listen, telling you this
breaks a whole bushel
of board regulations.
Tell me one mistake he's made.
He hasn't. Not yet.
But when he does,
his age will make it an instant
malpractice suit
that we will lose.
He's years behind the
medical education curve.
You said it yourself.
He refused to try a
minimally invasive technique.
Why,
because he's stubborn
or because he doesn't know how?
That's why you've had
me working with him.
Well, yeah, you represent
everything that is new
and smart and
advanced in our field.
You're his opposite.
And when the time
comes to make a case,
it won't hurt to have
you help us do it.
You should've told me.
Ethically, no.
Ethically, yes.
You should have.
Honestly, I never would've
thought you'd have a problem with it.
I can't see anything.
You described them as,
"So big, a sheet
couldn't cover them."
I may have exaggerated.
Okay, ladies, this
isn't a sideshow.
Gentlemen, step right up.
That's it?
Okay. That's not okay.
Oh, great. Karev's here.
Here to make us all
laugh with funny jokes
about my hands on a man's parts.
This isn't funny. That poor guy.
I know.
Can you imagine
becoming so swollen
that a surgeon
needs to use a scalpel
to dig out all
that excess tissue
until the testicles and
cords hit the open air?
I mean, who even knows what
happened to his penis in all that mess?
That's not okay.
Nice.
Your mother won't stop
asking me why I look so tired.
Why do you look so tired?
They look so cute
together. Shut up.
Think they look
tired? Go to hell.
The hybrid surgery
was a good pitch.
Yes, it was.
So why aren't we doing it?
Because we have a
surgical plan. Hmm.
Do you have a problem, Dr. Yang?
Nope. But I think you do.
I think you reject my pitches
because they scare you.
I thought you were
learning something from me.
I have.
I have learned that mortality
is breathing down your neck,
and you are running from the
future like a scared old chicken.
I won't change my
plan just because...
Won't or can't?
I'm perfectly capable of
threading a catheter, Dr. Yang.
Prove it. Prove me wrong.
Take a deep
breath for me, Bryan.
Good. And let it out.
Um, what about my recovery time?
I mean, is there any chance I
won't be able to walk for a while?
God, Bryan. Stop
hiding from Amy Miller.
I'm not. She probably
won't even be at the reunion.
She will. Sheryl
Thompson told me so.
Also said she's single.
You're not that skinny kid
from rocketry club anymore.
You're smart. You're funny.
You're good enough for Amy.
Actually, you're
too good for Amy.
You would be the
perfect guy, except...
Except I've got giant balls?
No!
Except that you don't.
It's a good trade, Grey.
My two leisurely
abdominal surgeries
for just one retrocrural tumor.
This is getting a little sad.
No, I'll tell you what's sad.
Meredith Grey flaming out
'cause she doesn't know a
good bargain when she sees one.
Stop, Mr. Mays.
Mr. Mays!
Mr. Mays, stop!
Should've made the trade.
Dr. Bailey. Hey, I might
be interested in a trade.
He's right over there.
I mean, do I call for backup?
Do I get a net or what?
Forget it.
I would operate out here,
but I don't think it's
particularly sterile.
You lied to me. I didn't.
That intern was in the hallway
bragging to all her little friends
about my once-in-a-career tumor.
She said you didn't even know
where you were gonna start.
With a tumor like
this, no surgeon would
until you're open
and on the table
and I can get a
look at the thing.
Yeah, well, that's terrifying.
I know. That's
why I didn't tell you.
You're an emotional guy.
Not usually.
I mean, at work, I'm in
dangerous situations all the time.
But then, you know,
it's all about the client.
So I'm not allowed to freak out.
But right now, I'm freaking out.
Okay. Well, today you're
allowed, because I won't.
That intern's got a big mouth.
Yeah. Tell me about it.
Dr. Torres.
Um, did you hear anything
about Robbins' fitting?
I mean, Moore said...
You spoke to Moore?
I told you not to do
that. If she'd seen you...
Look, I'm the one
who cut off her leg.
If she has a problem
adjusting to the prosthetic
or if it turns out she's
gotta have more surgery...
I mean, what if I screwed it up?
She even blames me
for being on the plane.
She doesn't blame you, Karev.
She doesn't even
know you made the cut.
I made the call, okay? I
was supposed to protect her.
I'm the bad doctor, the bad
person. Your name never comes up.
Now if this doesn't feel right,
I can adjust it or we
can try a whole new cast.
It's fine.
Don't rush this.
If it's not right, you're the
one that suffers, not me.
Okay, let's get
you up on your feet.
No, that's fine.
I don't need to...
I need to see you
take a few steps.
Let's see how it feels when you
put some weight on it, all right?
No. Hey, let go!
Arizona, you can't
do this on your own.
You need help.
If we do this right and we... And
we get you on a prosthetic that fits,
you'll need less, but
you are not there yet.
And, you know, you're very lucky
to have people in
your corner that care.
You should let them help.
You're like a gift from God.
I was talking about
me. I barely know you.
I'm here because this is my job.
I have plenty of other things
I could be doing right now.
Yeah? Well, why
don't you go do them?
You know, I think I will.
Okay, folks. Let's get started.
Dr. Shepherd?
Yeah.
We were wondering
if, instead of a lecture,
we might be able to watch
Dr. Grey remove that rare tumor.
Dr. Grey is not
removing a rare tumor.
Yeah, she is. No, she's not.
But she and Dr. Brooks
are in OR one right now.
What did you say to him?
Who?
Thomas.
Because, you know, legally,
I could get in a lot of trouble
for telling you about the...
I didn't say anything.
It was his idea.
Really?
He just suddenly
changes his mind
and goes with an approach
he rejected two days ago?
I know. I was surprised, too.
I was, like, "Whoa!
What a surprise."
Okay.
No, actually, maybe
we lucked out.
I've never seen him
use one of those.
I wouldn't even allow it if I
didn't know you'd be in there
to take over when he craps out.
When he does, it might
just be all the board needs
to proceed with his dismissal.
Dr. Yang.
Suction.
I'm sorry. You're
just such a badass.
And I shouldn't
have been bragging,
but I liked feeling
like one, too.
If I was a real
badass, I would've just
kept my mouth shut,
been stoic, silent.
Yeah. Why don't you try that?
More suction, please. Mm.
Hey.
I can't get good visualization.
That's a big tumor.
Yeah, it is.
She didn't even
tell me about it.
I found out through
one of my interns. Huh!
My wife is bubble wrapping me.
Shepherd, you have a reputation
for needing to be
bubble wrapped.
Excuse me?
You fight for your patients
against the worst possible odds,
but when things get messy
personally, you're gone...
Off to the woods to
drink and grow a beard.
And with everything
that's happened
and this lawsuit
keeping it all alive,
maybe she just
worried that the
slightest little thing
is gonna make you
run off to that trailer
and leave her alone
in the house you gave her,
not sleeping at night because
whichever room she lays down in,
she just can't get away from
the fact that you're just not there.
Sounds like you had that
all teed up and ready to go.
Yeah. Yeah,
well, a version of it.
It's meant for somebody
else, you know,
but, it kind of works here, too.
You don't think
she's coming back.
No. No, I don't.
Here it is.
Where do we start?
We need to identify the
testicles and the cords.
Don't want to damage them.
Yes, ma'am. I'll
keep my eyes peeled.
I'm having the best time.
Forceps.
What's with the face?
I'm not making a face.
I've spent a few thousand hours
looking at you with a mask on.
I know when you're
making a face.
Bailey, I'm not making a face.
Just so you know, I did
not bully April Kepner
into giving up this surgery.
She approached me.
So... Nuts to her.
Get it? Nuts to her?
Oh, come on. You get it.
I'm a urologist, Dr. Bailey.
Of course I get it.
Hey, I spend most
of my day in a bowel.
Doesn't mean I
don't laugh at a fart.
Oh! Tough room.
Oh, hey, Avery, knock, knock.
I think I just located
the left testicle.
Yes, you have.
I will continue to excise
the surrounding tissue.
If someone can just
get a hand underneath...
- Yeah.
- Oh, sorry.
No, no, no. Please.
Go ahead. No, I insist.
For Pete's sake. It's
just a little testicle.
Somebody get up in there.
Of all the organs in the body,
of course it had to be this one.
Damn.
Damn it.
You know, I'm pretty sure
no one's ever closed a PDA
by swearing at the catheter.
I don't need any
tips, thank you.
I've used a guide wire before.
Really? Was that before
or after you learned to use
sheep's blood to lift a witch's curse?
Would you be quiet?
Damn.
Just relax.
Ahh.
I can't pass the wire.
You better take over.
Here.
Your right wrist.
What about it?
Just turn it in, like this.
I don't have time for
this. Just try it. Try it.
All right. All right. All right.
Oh! That's all, huh?
That's pretty neat.
If you'd like, I can advance
the balloon for you...
Back off, sister.
Eyes on your own work.
Oh!
Ohh!
You okay?
What are you doing here?
I was looking for Moore.
Wow!
It looks great.
Incision's healed
well. No edema.
You haven't completely destroyed
my department, have you?
Me?
I'm the one thing that's
kept that place together.
This guy Barnett's a
one-man wrecking crew.
We need you back.
I'm trying.
You know, Callie's trying, too.
Hey.
Boy, that went like
gangbusters in there.
It did, huh?
You could look a
little less disappointed.
The guy's a historical treasure.
That's funny. No, it's not.
You're right.
But on the bright side,
you're out of surgery
sooner than expected.
What do you say to a little...
I'm meeting a friend for drinks.
Nice.
That's nice. You're
making friends.
Good night. Well...
It's a little loose.
And it... And it
pinches right here.
And it hurts a little there.
Okay.
Well, let me see what
we can do about that.
Dr. Shepherd. I was visualizing
the anatomy all wrong.
But if I just do it the
way you told me...
Excellent work.
Keep going.
It's not so hopeless after all.
Hey, you got a second?
Yeah.
Good news, Bryan.
The procedure went as planned.
Amy Miller's got a
lot to look forward to.
You know, it's
really not about Amy.
But Paula and I have
been friends for so long,
I've never really
known how to say it.
Son, it's none of my business,
but I don't think you oughta
be ashamed of your feelings.
Seems to me we just
surgically removed
the only thing you had
to be embarrassed about.
Hey.
There's a whole lot less
of you under that blanket.
Would you mind?
No, not at all.
Hi.
Think we'll get
invited to the wedding?
Hey.
I need a moment to talk
to Dr. Webber, man to man.
Oh, no. No, you don't.
Mom!
It's all right.
Well, all right, then.
All right, here's the deal.
I understand
how two people can
be drawn together
even though they know
it's incredibly wrong
and it's something that
shouldn't have happened.
Sex is a powerful force.
All right, look...
You hurt my mom, and I hurt you.
I wouldn't hurt your mom.
I like her.
And I don't like
that you like her.
Well, man to man,
you're just gonna
have to deal with it.
You don't want a piece of this.
Not today.
I'm watching you.
I hope you like the view.
I know what you're thinking.
I'm married.
I haven't forgotten that.
Actually, I was thinking
that all of that over there
took some pretty big balls.
How was your day?
Fine.
How about the tumor? Hmm?
I was in the gallery.
That was no big deal.
I'm not gonna grow
a beard and run off
and live in the woods anymore.
If you have a good day,
I want to hear about it.
It was amazing, actually.
I didn't know where
the hell to start.
I stood there staring
at the thing forever.
I knew that supraceliac aorta
was gonna be a bitch to get around.
And I couldn't risk
clamping without
killing off the gut
and the kidneys.
And then finally,
it just came to me.
Mattox Maneuver.
That's a trauma move.
Right, and it exposed the
other side of the kidney,
and wham... I had
perfect visualization.
What is that for?
Contact high. I might
not come down for hours.
Okay, Sofia's
down for the night.
And I'll be at Mark's
if you need anything.
American Bake Off
is on in a few minutes.
It might be hard for
a surgeon to admit...
But there's no shame
in simply being human.
It can be a relief
to stop hiding...
To accept who you really are
and let the world
see you that way, too.
Mom.
You okay? I'm fine.
Are you sure? Yeah.
Want to have sex?
Yeah.
A little self-awareness
never hurt anybody.
I know they're
trying to push me out.
Got this watch at a
surprise retirement party
four years ago.
I mean, it's a piece of junk,
but I wear it just
to screw with them.
They are so polite.
They don't dare say
anything directly, you know?
Yeah.
It's been a while
since I've had anyone
who cared enough
to give me grief.
Mm.
I'll have another tequila,
and something that
contains actual alcohol
for my friend
here. No, it's late.
It's, like, 10:15. Have a drink.
Okay. Yeah.
I'll have...
An old fashioned.
What?
Really? An old... You know what?
I'll have two. Two. Make
it two old fashioneds.
There you go.
Old fashioned.
Because when you
know who you are...
It's easier to know
what you're about...
And ultimately...
What you really need.