Hey.
Drawer's empty.
You didn't have to do that.
Oh, I didn't.
Uh. Most of these drawers have
been empty since I moved in.
How's that?
Subtle.
Your place is so...
spare.
I just thought...
What?
It was intentional.
It's not.
*NEW AMSTERDAM (2018)*
Season 03  Episode 09
Episode Title: "Disconnected"
Aired on: April 27, 2021
♪ She rocks
through the treetop ♪
♪ All the day long
♪ Singin' and a-boppin',
and a-singin' her song ♪
♪ All the little birds
in the jaybird tree ♪
♪ Love to hear Luna go
tweet, tweet, tweet ♪
Max?
Hey, Gwen.
Could you sing faster?
We're late
for our pre-nap walk.
Yeah, sure.
Oh, speaking of sleep,
I'm gonna be done
by 7:00 tonight,
so I will have time to read
and put Luna to bed.
- Right.
- No, no. I'm serious.
Gwen, on the dot.
Kids need routine, Max.
- That's all.
- Yeah.
Which is what
I'm trying to do.
Well, I...
I know you're trying.
We all know you're trying.
If there's something
you want to say, Gwen...
See you at 7:00, Max.
I will see you at 7:00.
Oh, morning.
Your school called.
Again.
You skipped calculus this time.
That's 'cause I already took
calculus when I was in Iran.
School saw my records.
Why must I repeat?
It's the way it is, Mina.
Like my world history class'
take
on American hegemony?
This isn't a joke.
Under my roof, under my care,
which means
school, college, job.
Don't I get a vote?
If this were
a true democracy, then yes.
But since you've learned
the truth, no.
What's the first move?
My old job,
it's waiting for me.
Do they know
the reason you left?
Yes, I told them
everything.
Plus, I'm tight
with the foreman.
And, like, we're supposed
to trust you?
It's handled, okay?
Careful.
You sound triggered.
That happens out in
the streets, you are done-zo.
Give me the three names
on your phone list. Go.
- You got a place to live?
- Covered.
Covered ain't an answer,
primo.
- He ain't ready.
- I got seven people
on my phone list,
not just three.
All know my story.
I found a studio apartment.
It's under the A train,
which is perfect
because you literally
have to be crazy
to want live under the A train.
And if I lose my job,
my pad, or my temper,
I got backups.
- Yeah.
- I got a cousin.
She's got a
brownstone.
There's a bed in there
for me.
She's vaccinated,
in the program, and...
Okay, great, you got a plan.
Good.
What's your purpose?
Since the world doesn't care
about your plan,
what makes you think
you're ready?
I know the source
of my trauma.
My role in it.
The pain, which I've learned
to forgive myself for.
The healing, which I'm
an active participant in.
And I know the debt I owe
to those who've loved me,
starting with love
for self.
Oh, my God.
Chance Becker, everybody.
Ready for reentry.
Look at this guy.
Help!
Help! Help!
- What happened?
- Drive-by.
My daughter got shot.
Pulse is weak and thready.
Get her to Trauma One!
Start two large bore IVs,
normal saline wide open.
Please, save her!
We're gonna do
the best we can.
Send crit, coags,
type and cross.
She's in hypovolemic shock.
About to hang a bag of O neg.
Probably a pumper in her chest.
Another shooting,
another child.
Where's the bleeder?
- Come on.
- Dr. Bloom.
Cardiac arrest just rolled in.
- You got this?
- Go.
V-fib arrest on transport.
Shocked three times
with no response.
Okay, push high dose epi.
Clear.
She's back.
Let's take her to Bay 30.
Headed to the OR.
- Who do we have here?
- Corona test negative.
Robin Perez, 61.
Blurred vision, dizziness,
and low blood pressure.
Now, why does that
sound familiar?
Same symptoms
as the two sisters
we just moved to Bay 23 and 24.
And the guy over in 26.
Dolores?
- What you doing here?
- I don't even know.
I got dizzy,
and then I was gone.
- Aw.
- Hey, ladies.
It's Bruce.
- From 425?
- Oh.
Is Miss Vera with you?
Miss Vera?
No.
Did you see Mr. Olenchalk
from the fifth floor?
Oh, I am right here.
What the heck is going on?
Wait, so you all
know each other?
We live in the same building.
It happened so fast,
I... I couldn't really see.
I mean, it was such a blur,
but maybe Black or Latino?
I don't know.
His hoodie was hiding his face.
Oh, my God! Allison!
- Ma'am, ma'am!
- Mommy's here.
I need you to keep your
mask on until you're tested.
Look, we're going to the OR.
The bullet's lodged
near her spine.
We're gonna do everything
we can.
We'll keep you posted.
This is what happens
when you defund the police.
We've got more fake
coronavirus cures out there.
- How do you know?
- Because a patient suffering
from acute cardiotoxic
poisoning had this on her.
Rona-Vaxx?
Nice name.
"All natural, organic.
"Made from the petals and stems
of the cascabela thevetia
flower."
Yellow oleander.
A plant that's toxic to, you know,
all living vertebrates.
I guess "Drink this,
and you die"
doesn't really fit
on the poster.
First, it was the
essential silver toothpaste,
then the aromatherapy oils
that actually cause
lung inflammation.
And who can forget that surge
of patients brought in
to my ED after drinking bleach?
Actual bleach.
Now this.
Yeah, another case
of disinformation.
If only it were one case.
They targeted
a low-income building
in East Harlem
with these flyers.
Hundreds of residents.
They're getting worse.
How many more didn't come in?
How many more
might be poisoned?
Okay, team, two goals.
We're gonna go door-to-door.
Any resident
who has ingested Rona-Vaxx,
we immediately escort them
to an ambulance.
If somebody has bought
and not yet ingested it,
the Department of Health
will meet them to exchange it
with a debit card on the spot.
Clear?
Great, let's roll.
Second floor, third floor.
Go.
- "Let's roll"?
- I don't know.
I was trying to fire people up.
No good?
Hi there, ma'am.
Do you live here?
What's it to you?
Oh, I just have a question
for you.
Did you buy any of this?
Sure did.
Man was wearing scrubs
like you.
Said he was a doctor.
Well, he wasn't.
- Oh, and I guess you are?
- Yeah, yeah.
I even brought my ambulance
to prove it.
You didn't ingest this,
though, did you?
Oh, no.
My son Nathan,
he lives in Buffalo.
He researched Rona-Vaxx
on the Internet
because we don't have it here,
and he said it was shady.
Well, I wish everyone
in your building had a Nathan.
As the current head
of the search committee
to find a new
chair of neurology,
it is incumbent upon me
to inform you that...
- You picked someone?
- Uh, no.
No, um, but that's only
because I haven't...
actually met with anyone yet.
- What?
- I know. I know.
I tried. I did.
I just... you know what it is?
I'm too close to it.
I...
I got emotional today
looking at résumés
that are still inside
of the envelopes.
That actually happened,
so I am appointing you
the interim head
of the search committee.
Ta-da!
But I'm already
the interim chair of neurology.
Exactly, that's how I know
you can handle it, so...
- Dr. Frome.
- Yeah?
I know it's hard,
but there's no doubt in my mind
that you're the person
who should be making
this incredibly
important decision
to replace Dr. Kapoor.
Mm-hmm, and the decision
I'm making
is that you should make it,
okay?
Uh, Dr. Frome?
Chance. Hi.
- Are you okay? What's going on?
- I... I hate to, uh...
Well, you know that old job I
talked about in group earlier?
- I do, yeah.
- Did that not work out?
No, they're actually
closing down.
I see.
That's... that's a bummer.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
- Yeah.
But thanks to our class,
I got resourceful.
I already found a new gig.
I just need
a character reference,
so would you mind?
Would I mind?
Here, give me that thing.
I truly appreciate it,
Dr. Frome.
Can I use your back?
Can I not be in charge
of the search committee?
- Here we go.
- Handled.
And, Chance, congratulations.
I'm proud of you.
Where's the...
Where's the new gig?
- Oh, you didn't see?
- No.
It's here.
At New Amsterdam.
First paycheck, lunch is on me.
Doesn't the American
Psychiatric Association
frown on being friends
with patients?
Mm-hmm, actively,
but we're not friends, so...
Does he know that?
Yeah.
And, girl,
when they played them slow jams
at the skating rink,
here comes Thom,
holding his hand out
like Billy Dee Williams.
"You want my arm to fall off?"
I couldn't help it.
So when I saw his face pop up
on our school reunion page,
I couldn't help myself neither.
Miss Juanita just had
to reach out.
Had to.
I hadn't seen his face since
he joined the army
right after high school.
Well, her father
had something to do with that.
I told you,
we ain't going there.
But it's like
we just picked up
where we left off.
So what's next
for you two lovebirds?
Gonna make up for lost time.
Hit Route 66.
The Gateway Arch,
the Meramec Caverns,
Petrified Forest.
He's been promising me
that trip since we been kids.
I'm gonna fulfill it too.
Thomas,
uh, the bruising on your arm
and underneath
on your side here.
I know.
We've just been busy
catching up and whatnot.
I'd like to run some tests.
Tests for what,
Dr. Sharpe?
She thinks
my cancer is back.
- Lap pad.
- TS kit on the tray.
Okay, that should do it
for the bleeder.
But if she has any hopes
of walking again,
we'll have
to take the bullet out.
Nurse, can you call
Dr. Salaita?
Will do.
Do you want
to update her family?
Yeah, but before I do,
will you take a look at this?
- Powder burns?
- Yeah.
And you see
that stippling there?
Seems inconsistent
for a drive-by.
This was close range.
I'm gonna call Social Services.
I can't believe I gotta go
to the hospital for this.
You all got the vaccine.
The rest of us
just do what we can.
We're gonna take good care
of you.
I promise.
Whole building's
accounted for.
We're taking 16 back with us,
and housing bought back
46 unused treatments.
Of snake oil.
It's like we're living
in the Wild West.
Well, these families
might as well be.
This building's located in
the middle of a Wi-Fi desert.
If you can't access
the Internet,
you can't debunk the snake oil.
And this is just
gonna keep happening.
Fake news, fake cures,
unless...
Unless we do something
about it.
Something like what?
We're gonna get
free broadband access
for every household
in New York City.
I mean, I've heard
of 4G and 5G but never no G.
Not in New York.
That's crazy!
And imagine what it's like
for people in rural areas
without broadband.
I mean, no wonder the virus hit
the way that it did.
Yeah.
What you got in the bag there?
- Oh, this?
- This is, uh...
this is my secret weapon
to fight injustice.
Oh, whoa.
And a secret it shall remain,
I guess.
Order up, Dr. Frome!
- Chance.
- Yeah.
It's one filthy chai,
just the way you like it.
- Five pumps, coconut milk.
- No, no.
I didn't... I didn't order this.
It's all good.
I got you.
Hey, next in line, please.
Your résumé and references
are...
impeccable.
I never thought
we'd find someone
to replace Dr. Kapoor, but I...
Thank you, Dr. Kao.
I've devoted my entire life
to the nervous system.
I see.
You were head of neurology
at Holy Cross in Houston
for 12 years.
Can I ask what brought you
to New York?
Simply put, regular
psychosocial stimulation
is good for your brain.
I believe it's essential.
I so agree!
Our senses deliver information
that's key to survival.
Exactly.
So how would you describe
your leadership style?
- I lead by example.
- Uh-huh.
Management should share
the same sacrifices
as their team does.
And I give each weekday
its own funky theme.
I'm sorry.
How do you mean?
Like Moon Tower Mondays,
basically '70s garb.
Tahiti Tuesdays.
Waikiki Wednesdays have
to be reconceived because
employees start recycling
their Tuesday outfits.
You want to guess Thursday?
No. I'm good.
How are you feeling, Sydney?
Tired.
So ridonkulous the Rona-Vaxx
made me this sick.
Actually, it's not,
because Rona-Vaxx is not
a real treatment for COVID.
Well, I'm just lucky
that my silver pills
didn't kick my butt like this.
You're taking silver pills
as well?
Yeah, only 'cause my dude
with the hydroxychloroquine
bailed upstate.
Hydroxychloroquine.
So you're taking all three of
these things at the same time?
And obvs it's working 'cause
I'm, like, COVID-free, right?
Okay.
Evan Nashton,
board member extraordinaire.
- You here for the big meeting?
- Oh, God.
- Not the suit.
- What? This old thing?
You only wear a suit when
you're trying to shake us down.
Shakedown?
Evan, I'm offended.
I mean, can't
the medical director
of New York's
largest public hospital
just have a friendly chat
with the CFO
of New York's
largest telecom company?
Just two old buddies gabbing,
huh?
Save it.
You have some idea.
I'm sure it's inspiring
and financially ruinous.
Do you know how many
households in New York City
- don't have broadband?
- 500,000.
- 5... oh.
- That's exactly right.
Now, wouldn't it be cool if you
hooked them up?
- "Hooked them up"?
- Yeah.
Free Internet for everybody.
Take the thing that
my company sells for money...
- Give it away for free.
- Right.
You know, when people
can't afford
their power bill,
Con Ed doesn't show up
with a new AC.
Broadband is the same,
a utility to be paid for.
Right, and if broadband
is a utility,
then it's like power
or clean water.
And shouldn't everyone
have access to that?
Think about it.
Telemedicine.
Prescription refills.
Our patients will be healthier!
Look, I applaud
your idealism...
No, no, I applaud yours,
like when you donated
free Internet
to impoverished areas
in sub-Saharan Africa.
You helped people in a desert
5,500 miles away.
Now, surely, Evan,
I think you can do
a little something
for the broadband desert
right here
in your own backyard.
I'll give you ten apartments.
17 housing projects.
One building, and you
don't speak to me for a year.
Done.
It's always a pleasure
to casually bump into you,
Evan.
Thomas, three years ago,
your leukemia was in remission.
But now your cancer
has mutated
into a new, aggressive form
that won't respond
to any of our treatments.
And...
if we tried another protocol?
I'm afraid there aren't any.
How much time does he have?
I may be able to get him
a couple of extra months.
Good ones.
You'll need to come
to the hospital every few days
for blood transfusions
to stave off...
I can start all that
when we get back from our trip.
No, no.
Thomas, in order to get
those extra couple of months,
we need to start
the transfusions immediately.
That means staying here
in New York.
No Route 66.
Well, if I only have
a little time left,
then each day
is going to count.
We're taking this trip.
Without the transfusions,
your pain will be excruciating.
You'll begin vomiting blood
as your body breaks down
on itself.
That will occur
within a matter of days,
which means you will bleed out
in some motel
in the middle of nowhere.
Is that how you want
your love story to end?
Social Services?
The wound was close range,
all right?
It wasn't a drive-by.
And I have an obligation...
We only had that gun a month,
okay?
Allison must have found it
when she...
It wasn't my husband's fault.
Then why make up some story?
Just tell me how she is.
She's stable.
But in order
to take the bullet out,
she's gonna need
a riskier procedure
and it's gonna take
some more time.
It was the demonstrations.
Black Lives Matter.
The protestors.
We were scared.
You saw the news.
They were smashing windows,
burning property,
beating people up.
We just wanted
to protect ourselves.
But apparently,
not all lives matter.
It's your daughter.
Um, excuse me, everybody?
Can I get everybody's...
Can I... can I get... can I, um...
Hey!
Listen up!
Wow, loud.
Thank you.
So I have some news.
You are all here
because you were sold a lie.
A fake cure.
Disinformation
that you couldn't debunk
because you didn't have access
to the correct information.
Until today.
Hold on to your nasal cannulas.
Everybody is getting
free broadband access.
- Really?
- What is that?
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
How the hell
you pull that off?
- Don't say the suit.
- Can't deny the suit.
Is this a "fell off the back
of the truck" situation?
No, totally legit.
Where do we pick up
our computers?
Uh, well, I didn't get
any computers.
That's a'ight.
Tablets are way cooler anyway.
Yeah.
Yeah, they are.
But I didn't get
any of those either.
You think everybody's
got smartphones?
Uh, I guess...
So basically, he got us gas
but no stove.
- Oh, that makes sense.
- This guy.
I understand it now.
What did you get us?
What do I do with that?
I ain't got no phone.
Alexis Luther,
my favorite board member.
- No.
- No?
I didn't even say hi yet.
I'm familiar with the suit,
Max.
And I'm impervious
to whatever you think
its powers of persuasion are.
No, no, I'm just here
to tell you
that you are no longer
on the board
of America's
greatest public hospital.
- What?
- Sorry. Sorry.
To be clear,
you're still on the board,
but we are no longer
America's greatest hospital.
See, you remember
when you gave us
those computers and laptops
from your company?
You said they were
state-of-the-art,
but my doctors are telling me
they're pieces of junk, okay?
But they don't use
the word "junk."
That's impossible.
Just ten months ago,
it was top-of-the-line tech.
Right, but in an IT eval
with two dozen other hospitals,
we came in dead last.
Isn't that right, Dr. Frome?
Our computers are outdated,
right?
Oh, gosh, I mean,
you know, maybe
a little tricky at first,
but now they're awesome...
Now they're struggling.
I mean, you were just telling
me about that graphics issue.
Um, I don't really
use graphics for much, so...
No, no, you don't, 'cause
they're pretty much unusable.
Oh, I see.
- Dr. Frome, you're very polite.
- Thank you.
We can't let courtesy
impede this hospital's
public standing.
100% agree.
Totally.
Yep. What he said.
How many new units
are we talking?
Ooh, I don't know.
Maybe three, four...
Thousand.
- Yeah.
- 3,000 or 4,000.
400 is the best I can do.
Sold.
I... thank you.
Thank you, Alexis.
That's very generous.
Always nice
to casually bump into you.
Yes, very good to see you.
Why would you do that to me?
That was terrifying.
- My computers are fine.
- I know. I know.
But the board would never agree
to donate new computers
to a random building full
of low-income residents, so...
But if we got 400 new ones,
we would have
400 perfectly good used ones
that suddenly need a new home.
I was right there with you.
I got it.
Why are you dressed
like James Bond?
I'd tell you, but then I'd...
have to kill you.
Please have a seat.
May I have a Perrier?
Oh, we don't
actually have that.
Ah.
Dr. Kao running late?
Oh, my God.
I'm Dr. Kao.
Sorry, it's a short last name
that tends to get lost
in introductions.
You're
Dr. Agnes Kao?
I am.
You're 12.
I wish.
Well, not 12, but...
I'm older than I look.
You're interviewing me
for the position
of chair of neurology?
I'm trying to.
I don't hear any questions.
Sydney, can you hear me?
I'm barely getting a pulse.
- Heart rate's 20 and dropping.
- Damn it.
One milligram of atropine.
IV push.
Heart rate's 45 and climbing.
What... what's happening?
You're okay, Sydney.
You're okay.
Knew I should have never came
to the hospital
in the first place.
I'm only getting sicker.
Okay, try to relax.
Take deep breaths for me.
I'm just saying.
I never needed that machine
before today.
Okay.
Dialysis cleared the Rona-Vaxx
poison out of her blood,
but her EKG is still showing
low voltage and pseudo-infarct.
That doesn't make much sense.
Unless she was born
with cardiac amyloidosis.
- An autoimmune disorder?
- Well, think about it.
It'll cause heart palpitations,
fatigue, shortness of breath.
Making her think
she had COVID.
While masking
her real issues.
Page cardio, stat.
Now what?
Heart rate's skyrocketing.
BP plummeting.
- Bleeder?
- No.
Surgical fields are clean.
- Septic?
- No fever. No white count.
- Med reaction?
- No rash.
There.
Left ventricular thrombus.
That is a massive clot
in her heart.
Yeah, that explains why
her blood pressure's so low.
If we don't do something,
she's not gonna make it.
Clamp.
Scalpel.
Chance, hi.
What...
- Oh, hey.
- What are you doing?
It's day-old muffins, and...
Yeah. No, no.
That's...
- They're not that stale.
- No, Chance.
This is, um...
Uh, I need you to hear me,
okay?
I need you to really hear me.
Um, our relationship is very,
very important to me,
which means that it needs
to be protected.
That's why we have
structured sessions, right?
We arrange a time and a place
to meet,
we meet up, we share.
It's great, but it's safe.
And it's protected.
But in order for our
relationship to be effective,
we can't... we can't have
this kind of casual contact.
Do you understand?
That means no muffins,
no free chais,
no popping in to say hello.
I'm just talking about
boundaries here, Chance.
I... yeah.
Okay.
Well, it's just,
you're the closest thing
to family I have.
But I'm not your family.
I am your therapist.
That's it.
You know, which...
You know, that's...
I have the same relationship
with all my patients.
The same rules apply, you know?
I feel bad that
I wasn't more clear.
- I think it's my fault.
- No. No, I get it.
Thanks, Dr. Frome.
Now,
I like to pride myself
on listening to my patients,
so...
This is your Route 66 road map.
These red dots here, these are
your stops along the way.
Now, here, when you get to your
beloved Meramec Caverns,
you'll call Dr. Dutton
in Branson.
He'll have a bag of platelets
waiting for you.
Oh, my God.
And then...
in Albuquerque,
next to the Petrified Forest,
is Dr. Cho,
who will take care of you.
And then it's on
to the Grand Canyon,
where you'll stop at Flagstaff
and meet Dr. Perlin.
So each red dot has
a transfusion center?
Think of them more as,
um, pit stops along the way.
But it is absolutely crucial
that you stick to this route.
Okay?
I won't mess this up.
I should warn you both
that this may not be easy.
Thom will face some significant
challenges along the way.
There will be days
that he'll feel sick.
Days he'll feel exhausted.
Call me any time
you want to check in.
You sure you want to do this?
Take it.
Unless you want my arm
to fall off.
- Thanks again, Dr. Goodwin.
- Oh, of course.
Now you're COVID-free,
and you're vaccinated.
And this laptop
is gonna be a lifesaver.
Yeah, literally.
And now you can
look up real remedies
for whatever ails you.
I don't even need
to bother Nathan.
I already found something
for my knee problem.
- Good.
- Clay enemas.
Wait, what?
Well, it sounded better
than powdered ants, see?
No, no.
Don't click on that.
That's a pop-up.
You don't want...
See how well it knows me?
Vera, it doesn't know you.
It's tracking you.
- Oh, is that bad?
- Yes, that's bad!
You don't know where
this information comes from.
This could be just as bad
as Rona-Vaxx.
But it's on the computer
you gave us.
I know, but, Vera,
you can't believe
everything that you read
on the Internet.
Oh, so instead
of one lying ad in the lobby,
now I have a whole lying
machine in my apartment?
How is that progress?
Hey, I got the message.
Is Chance okay?
Security found him
in the stairwell.
- We're checking for burning.
- For burning?
- Why? What happened?
- They said he drank cleaning fluid.
You're here
for the department interview?
Yes.
Is there a problem?
But I'm sorry.
You're Dr. Lució?
Dr. Romy Lució?
That's right. Yes.
I studied your neuroanatomy
book in med school.
How often is there a fresh take
on epithalamic structure?
In fairness, not often.
And you're here?
You're really here
for the chair position?
Would you like
to start the interview?
Why?
That's often how it works.
You won the ANA Award
in neuroscience
and the Wolfe Neuropathy
Research Prize
in the same year.
Your book gave me purpose.
It changed my life.
I'm hiring you...
Right now.
Hmm, can you do that?
They said this was
my decision to make.
Practically forced me
to make it, so you know what?
I will.
Dr. Lució,
come meet
your new department.
Oh, okay.
Look who's awake.
I heard about your big save
on my ticker.
Cray, right?
No.
Not cray, actually.
Not remotely cray.
This is an underlying condition
that you have had for years,
and we would have known
about it a lot sooner
if you'd come in
for a routine checkup.
Eh, you live and learn.
- Can I go now?
- No!
Listen to me.
This isn't over, okay?
You're gonna need follow-up
and actual medication.
And you have got to stay away
from those crappy fake cures.
Crappy?
You only figured out what was
wrong with me because of them.
Technically yes, but that's...
So the way that I see it is,
they actually helped.
Oh, boy.
Soma Kulkarni, my all-time
favorite board member?
Skip it.
Hard no.
I heard what you did
to the others.
That's fair, but listen.
I have been doing this
whole thing backwards, okay?
I've been running around
trying to get everybody
broadband access without
considering, access to what.
Listen, I'm not asking
for much, really.
I just need a portal.
A portal to information
that people can trust.
That's all I need.
Having access to broadband,
to information, is a right,
but what I finally realized is
that it's the quality
of information
that affects
our quality of life,
so let's create a safe space
outside the walls
of this hospital.
The New Amsterdam
Tele-Health Network.
Let's call it N.A.T.H.A.N.
A place where
our patients can go
anytime,
day or night,
for care,
for connection...
And community.
Okay. All right.
All right.
Shh, guys.
Shh. Shh. Shh.
A fully integrated system
with the information
people need
to make the right
health-care decisions.
Just like walking through
the doors of New Amsterdam,
and all from the comfort
of your home.
Done.
I'll even design it myself.
Yes!
Thank you.
Um, I have to go.
It's story time,
and my daughter's a stickler,
but thank you.
Max?
Next time, stick to the scrubs.
This is just... wrong.
Yeah.
Oh, thank you! Thank you.
That's... what
a wonderful introduction.
Thank you so much.
Dr. Vijay Kapoor,
chair of this department
for 35 long years,
and in that tenure,
he used his...
unique perspective
and his old-fashioned ideas
to run this department
straight into the ground
while tarnishing
the very tenets of neurology.
What he did was a disgrace.
It was an embarrassment.
But as your new chair,
I vow to rectify
his inept failures.
And I will redress
his egregious oversights.
And I will restore dignity
to this department
by throwing away
every last thing
that Dr. Kapoor
has ever touched.
Think we could have
a minute?
Thank you.
I failed you.
Chance, even the fact that you
were concerned with failing me
is, um...
It's just proof
that I failed you.
And I did. I failed.
Um...
So I am, uh...
I'm transferring you
to another therapist
at another hospital.
Wait, what?
- No.
- Yeah.
No! You can't!
I'm sorry.
Oh, please.
I'm... I'm sorry
that I couldn't give you
what you needed.
Dr. Frome, you can't do this!
You can't!
Dr. Frome!
No!
Hemiplegic?
Instead of paraplegic,
Allison's paralysis
is hemispheric.
In her case,
the right side of her body.
Could it be temporary?
Months, years.
It all depends on how long
it takes her to heal.
Either way, it won't be easy.
Oh, my baby.
I think they'd like
to speak with you.
Wait, what? Why?
Mr. Mulvane,
you panic-bought a firearm
and left it loaded and unlocked
in the proximity
of your daughter.
And when she got hurt,
you tried to cover it up
by filing a false police report
based on race,
a felony in New York.
- Wait, I...
- No, I'm not done.
Because then
y'all had the audacity
to claim that all lives matter
while the police
were combing the streets
profiling Black
and brown faces,
faces like mine,
which apparently
don't matter enough to you.
And here's what I don't get.
What I will never get is if
it's intentional on your part
or you're simply conditioned,
because you definitely
aren't the first
to falsely accuse a brother.
And I doubt you'll be the last.
This is the part
where you thank me
for saving
your daughter's life.
We... we're not racists.
♪ Is it that time
where I put my hand ♪
♪ Where the drink is
in my blue denim jeans ♪
♪ If only you knew
what I mean ♪
Hi.
You look comfortable.
How was school?
I don't know.
I dropped out.
I took my GED.
Like you said,
school, college, job.
I said tons of things
that you haven't done.
Why start today?
You can stop pretending
to be my parent.
I am not your mum,
nor will I ever pretend to be.
However, I am in charge
for making the best decisions
for you...
You mean the best decisions
for you!
The decisions that make
your life easier.
Really? Do you think any of
this is making my life easier?
Isn't that why I'm here?
Because you feel guilty
for ignoring your brother
for all those years?
How can you even say that
to me?
Oh, so I'm just here out
of the kindness of your heart?
You're here because
you're my family!
That you ignored
for your whole life!
You don't know what
you're talking about!
I know what family is,
and what you're doing
isn't even close.
It was your grandfather,
my father,
who just left his wife
and child back in London.
Me! I was the one
who was abandoned first!
I was the one
who was ignored first!
Ta-da!
Shh!
You'll wake Luna.
What?
Gwen, it's not even 7:00 yet.
I'm early.
Yeah, sorry, Max.
We had a big day.
Poor thing was so tired.
But couldn't you have
kept her up just a few minutes?
I mean, I was... I really wanted
to read to her.
I needed...
Of course you did.
But keeping a tired child up
solely for your benefit
would not have been very fair
to her, now, would it?
I do appreciate you
being punctual, though.
In fact, I just might be able
to make my 7:30 train tonight.
Good night, Max.
What the...
It looked smaller
in the picture.
I can take it back.
No, it's...
it's fine.
It's just very, very big.
Is it real?
Very much so.
Why?
It's just, uh,
I'm not really good with
living things.
I disagree.
Sync corrections by srjanapala