♪♪
I'm going to tell you a secret.
Doctors are not Gods.
♪ Magic in my fingertips,
candy-colored skies ♪
♪ Everybody's watching,
they got stars in their eyes ♪
We like you to think
we have all the answers.
♪ Hey, mama, hey, mama ♪
♪ Click, clack, get up and go ♪
You have to trust us enough to let us
cut open your flesh and
poke around at your insides.
So it's helpful if you think
we have it all together.
♪♪
♪ Hey, mama, hey, mama ♪
It's helpful if you don't know
that, just like you,
we're anxious, we're insecure,
we're angry.
♪ Here I go, feeling right
from head to toe ♪
♪ Hey, mama, hey, mama,
hey, mama, hey, mama ♪
You have to let us
come at you with a scalpel.
♪ I got moves that'll blow your mind ♪
♪ Spin it 'round just one more time ♪
So it's helpful if you don't know
that, just like you, we're wrecks.
♪ Hey, hello, turn it up and let it go ♪
♪♪
- Dr. Shepherd.
- Shh.
It's been a week.
Shouldn't you tell someone?
Your family? A friend?
I don't need your advice
or your concern.
What I need is for you
to follow HIPAA
and keep your mouth shut...
and my latest labs and a triple latte.
♪ Hey, mama ♪
♪ Oh, my, my, here I go ♪
♪ Feeling right from head to toe ♪
Do you know how many
people live in this house?
A lot. That's how many.
And you and I are the only ones
who do our part.
We're the good ones, right?
Ohh.
What is all this stuff?!
You're gonna have to talk to Alex.
♪ Ain't nothing gonna
stop me now, stop me now ♪
Gotta go. Gotta go.
♪ Ain't nothing gonna
stop me now, whoa-oh-oh ♪
You're perfect.
And Alex is wrong.
And Mommy needs a minute!
♪ Ain't nothing gonna stop me now ♪
♪ Whoa-oh-oh-oh ♪
She's still grumpy, huh?
Ow! Watch it, Avery!
Pain is a great sign.
Your nerves are regenerating
and forming connections
to the graft.
I don't see any sign of
rejection from your biopsy.
I mean, you are recovering
much faster than we'd hoped.
So I can get out of here soon.
We need to e-mail my C.O.
about transport.
Okay, slow down. We need
to check for infection
and do physical therapy.
Uh, he will be in the lobby
in 15 minutes.
I told you my grandfather
does not like crowds.
And I told you to be there anyway.
Hey, mister.
Guess who's coming home soon.
Mmm.
So, you ready?
Everything needs to be perfect.
Absolutely pristine, functional.
No room for error. Perfect.
Harper Avery hasn't
stepped foot in this hospital
since I became chief,
and I need to show the man
that we are a competent,
autonomous, well-oiled machine
with no glitches and
no need for supervision.
Labor pains, all right?
Those happen
even in well-oiled hospitals!
You are a rock star, Miranda Bailey.
Now go kick some Harper Avery ass!
- Hey! Don't be late!
- On our way.
- Okay.
- Meredith?
Avery mentioned that you did
a biopsy on Megan yesterday.
- Is it all okay?
- I can't discuss a patient.
I suggest you speak to the family.
Right.
Hey, I'll round on Dr. Carr for
you while you're at the thing.
- Thanks.
- You want to talk about that?
Nope.
Walter Carr is your patient?
Okay. Brody, it's all you. Excuse me.
Walter Carr. 64.
Presented with shortness of breath,
leg swelling, and sinus tachycardia.
CT scan showed a 24-inch blood clot
extending from his
right iliac vein to his heart.
Okay. Did she just say 24?
I sit a lot.
I'm a psychiatrist. I work upstairs.
Oh! I knew I'd seen you around.
He works up...
We tried to treat the clot with TPA,
but due to its size,
Dr. Pierce has planned
an open thromboembolectomy
for this afternoon. So, risks?
Showering of the emboli to the lungs!
- Right-sided heart failure!
- MI, stroke, death!
- Uplifting.
- Sorry.
Okay, Brody, why don't you
place an arterial line?
Dr. Carr, try to get some rest.
- Yeah.
- All right.
Hey, there.
It's nice to see you, Meredith.
Now you'the one who needs
the tape and glue guy, huh?
♪♪
I'm just... I'm saying that
the skill level is curative.
It's a curative level of sex.
It erases pain and fixes things.
Like Eliza... erased
on a cellular level.
J-Just... She's gone!
Last night, Carina
had me up against the...
You're late for the thing.
This is not
every department head!
I said every department head.
Pierce, where's Shepherd?
I haven't seen her all morning.
- And Grey?!
- You don't want her mood here.
- Sorry I'm late.
- Oh, wait, wait.
Thanks.
$15.8 million in repairs?
Insurance covered most of that.
"Most" is not all.
Look, we took
the opportunity of the fire
to address some design elements
that needed updating.
- Design elements?
- Yes.
Hello, Dr. Avery.
I am Chief Miranda...
Bingy. I remember you.
What is this... window dressing?
Don't you people have jobs to do?
♪♪
He doesn't like crowds.
Nope.
CT, MRI, biopsy results
all confirm it is a
benign Grade I Meningioma.
- I have it up on the board.
- Ah, slow down. Who's he?
- My resident.
- Mmm.
Andrew DeLuca.
DeLuca, this is Tom Koracick,
head of neuro at Hopkins.
Oh, he's heard of me.
See Shepherd's hands, DeLuca?
- Mm-hmm.
- All me.
I should charge every time
she uses them.
He's the most arrogant teacher
I ever had.
I didn't want to call him
for this, but...
Say it. You have to say it.
Out loud.
You're the best.
Damn straight. Oh! I like this.
Never should've called you.
Uh, I need an MR angio
to check the venousoutflow
and the tumor vasculature.
I got one two days ago.
And I need to know
what it looks like today.
Yeah, I have a consult
in a half an hour.
You've got a grapefruit-sized
tumor on your frontal lobe.
Your Chief of Surgery doesn't want
you anywhere near a consult.
You... Oh. You haven't told her.
Tom, I removed
an inoperable osteoblastoma
from a kid's jaw a week ago.
I'm fine. I just... I need
you to just follow my plan.
I'm not gonna follow your plan
because the part of your brain
that makes plans is compromised.
Your plans, your judgment,
your decision-making,
your impulse control... it's all tumor.
You understand?
You are not a sound mind now,
and you haven't been for years.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 14 Episode 03
Title: " Go Big or Go Home"
Um, why don't we all sit down?
Grown-ups only, Jackie. Take a walk.
Actually, I hold the
majority vote on the board,
so I'll be staying
to hear your concerns.
And it's "Jackson" or "Dr. Avery."
What is this... backtalk?
It hasn't been "backtalk"
since I was 18.
There's coffee and pastries.
Chief, could I have a minute?
Oh, uh, now isn't a good time.
I understand, but it's urgent.
Then please speak with Dr. Webber,
and he'll fill me in.
Dr. Avery, I'll be more than happy
to walk you through every
decision you're questioning.
I hope you cleared your day.
So, how was the birthday party?
Oh, well, there were 23 very
loud superheroes in my house,
but justice was served,
and fun was had by all.
It sounds like things
are going pretty well.
Yes, they are.
Except I cannot shake this mood.
Mood?
Hi, Dr. Carr.
I need to draw a blood gas
and do an EKG.
- I'll do it, Brody.
- Dr. Riggs instructed me to.
I said I'll do it.
♪♪
That's the mood.
Does Owen know?
What about Meredith and Maggie?
No. And I don't want them to know.
How long has this thing been growing?
I'd say close to 10 years.
He can remove the entire tumor.
I can help cover her service,
but she doesn't go near patients
until she's tumor-free and I clear her.
That's the only way I stay.
Richard, he can't just decide...
Frankly, the entire neuro community
wondered what kind of a surgeon
tackled the tumor in Nicole
Herman's brain, and now we know.
Who's Nicole Herman?
Nicole Herman was a fetal
surgeon who was diagnosed
with an inoperable astrocytoma,
and I saved her life.
Yes, we all read the case report,
but you also permanently blinded her.
- That was unavoidable!
- We don't know that now, do we?
- Honey, it'll all be over soon.
- Do not talk to me!
Okay, Marnie, you are only
4 centimeters dilated.
What? My water broke hours ago.
I know, but your cervix
is being stubborn.
I'll be back, okay?
Warren. Good.
I did an ablation on
Marnie's baby at 18 weeks.
To be safe, I want to be
there when she's born,
but the labor's protracted.
Will you monitor her closely
and keep me posted?
Uh, did we happen to skip the epidural?
She had one during her last delivery,
but her BP dropped so low
that she almost arrested,
so that's... that's not an option.
- And Pitocin?
- She's severely allergic.
So...
- So... this is your day.
- Yeah.
Let me know when she's 8 centimeters.
Fantastic.
♪ Swimming through our minds ♪
♪ Where the birds all sing ♪
♪ Uh-huh, yeah, yeah ♪
You paged me?
Peds trauma?
Yep. Incoming.
Mm.
♪ Where do you go? Where do you go? ♪
♪ We can do anything ♪
I missed you last night.
I needed clean clothes.
♪ We can do anything ♪
♪ Anything we want,
whatever you want to ♪
♪ I want you ♪
What do we got?!
Pete Hover. 16.
Status... post blunt trauma
to the abdomen and left leg
from hot-air balloon landing
gone wrong.
He also has some flash burns
to the upper extremities.
Does anyone have my phone?!
I need to text Jamie.
I need to know if she saw my Ho-Co-Pro.
- Your what?
- My homecoming proposal!
I was trying to ask Jamie Hall
to the homecoming dance.
- Oh, like a promposal.
- Yes!
I passed out before
she could give me an answer.
- Ow! Ah!
- What is this?
The hydrogen cannisters tipped
and melted the cape onto the tux
- and the tux onto his skin.
- Wha... A cape?
I didn't wear a cape with my tux
to the Ho-Co-Pro!
T-That's just the stupid balloon.
Let's get him inside now.
So, I try to check up on her,
and she bites my head off.
I tell her about Teddy,
and she's completely unfazed,
but she still wears her wedding ring.
I mean, I don't know what
the hell she wants me to do.
You know, live miserably alone
and still keep her shoes in the closet?
Sorry. Did you... need this card?
I haven't farted naturally
in six months
because of a bag attached to
my side.
And I have a stranger's abs
sewn onto me.
I'm separated from my child
by 10 time zones.
And I just sent the man
that I'm in love with
back to the woman he fell in love
with while I was supposedly dead.
Oh, but let's keep discussing
your tragic life.
Gin.
I need to get out of this room.
What is going on?
Um, I-I wanted to talk about
how things ended between us.
Huh?!
You know, you and I.
Uh, why?
Well, I-I-I've been
thinking a lot about us,
and, you know,
things ended so poorly.
I-I wanted to try to...
ameliorate the situation
and shepherd in a new era.
I thought we were fine now.
I mean, d-define "fine."
Are we... Are we friends?
Are we colleagues?
Do we tell each other things?
- Important things?
- I mean...
I'm fine now, but I wasn't.
You dropped me like I was
severely burning your hand,
and then
never said a word about it.
It was kind of humiliating.
Right. Yeah.
I-I shouldn't have...
I shouldn't have done that.
And you told Richard Webber,
my biological father...
what I'm like in bed.
He knows what sex sounds
I make now because of you.
I'll never live that down.
W-Well, to be fair, I-I didn't know...
You know,
you did owe me an apology.
Thank you for manning up.
I'm good now. We're good.
O-kay.
And when we first out Megan
was alive, I was gracious.
I was supportive.
I mean, I was... wonderful.
I put him in the car to go see her,
and when we found out that she
needed surgery, I was there.
I was more than there.
And his thanks was to put you
in the middle of a triangle?
Yes! Except there's no triangle.
I was very clear.
I told Megan that.
But Megan turned down the proposal
because she felt that...
Because she was confused.
I don't do love triangles.
I was raised in one.
I fell in love with my husband in one.
I am done with triangles.
All I did was take your advice
to embrace not being alone.
So the triangle's my fault?
Yes. Except there is no triangle.
Is Nathan in love with you?
Dr. Carr.
We wanted to discuss
your procedure.
Dr. Grey, are you consulting, as well?
- No, she's not.
- She can stay.
We're old friends,
and, uh, she can hear whatever
it is you need to tell me.
Okay.
Well, instead of opening up your chest,
we want to use something
called the Angio-Vac.
It's essentially a vacuum that
we attach to your blood vessels
so it sucks the clot out
rather than cutting.
- I've never heard of that.
- It is on the newer side,
but it would greatly reduce
your risk of complications,
which are potentially severe
with a clot of this size.
So, if you want to think it over,
talk to your family.
No need.
One son hates me. I hate the other one.
And my wife's been dead for 10 years.
I have trouble letting go of stuff.
- She's still seeing patients.
- Consults only.
She... tried to schedule
a surgery a couple days ago,
but I told her
I'd report her to the chief.
You should've reported her to
the chief regardless, DeLuca.
I understand it's complicated,
but the patients' safety
always comes first.
I-I don't know how you all
didn't catch this.
There had to be signs.
Was she erratic?
Impulsive? Obsessive?
Can you guys hear me in there?!
Just waiting on the contrast.
DeLuca, I need you
to go to medical records
and pull charts on Nicole Herman,
uh, uh, Katie Bryce, Kyle Diaz...
You're not working right now.
Robbie Reeves, Elsie Clatch,
Veronica Kay.
I need, uh... I need my notes.
I need the operative report,
imaging studies, everything.
DeLuca?
Wh-What?
DeLuca is my whipping boy now,
not yours.
Contrast is in, and
we need you to stop moving.
Got it?
Never should've called him.
Ow!
Do you have to do that?
I know. I'm sorry, Pete.
But the burns just
seem to be superficial.
No. I want to return the tux.
It was a rental, so now I'll owe $300.
I spent everything I had
on this Ho-Co-Pro.
I still don't know
what that is, but I hate it.
It's an elaborately staged plan
to invite someone to a dance,
usually accompanied by a fun pun.
"Jamie, you make me feel
sky-high. Go to Ho-Co with me."
See? Pun.
Pete?
Jamie! D-Did you see my sign?!
I-I asked Coach Greer to give it
to you when he was dialing 911.
She's the one. She was
in the middle of track practice
when I was landing.
Oh, Pete,
I think we found your sign.
- Do you think you can straighten it out?
- Ohh.
Is he gonna be okay?
- He crashed in a hot-air balloon, so...
- Jamie,
um, we'll update you
as soon as we can.
Can you...
♪♪
What am I looking at?
Uh... years ago...
I also had a brain tumor.
Derek removed it.
But I had some bad days.
What I'm saying is,
I've been where you are.
I know how frightening this is.
This is you?
Optic nerve looks pristine.
Clean margins, no shift.
You were lucky.
N-No, those are my pre-op scans.
Okay, you see the tumor r-right there?
That? That's not artifact?
No, it's a tumor!
I was dizzy for weeks.
I almost went blind!
That's a tumor.
What's this...
some kind of competition?
I could've removed this tumor
before breakfast with my eyes closed.
Oh, now you're just being unkind.
Koracick would let me remove this tumor
while he removed mine.
I have patients.
Did they even have
microscopes strong enough
to see this tumor back then?
So, I looked up this Angio-Vac,
and it's a veno-bypass cannula.
It wasn't designed for a 24-inch clot.
Okay, did you happen to see
that I was one of the authors
on those papers?
Did you happen to see that
one of your patients died?
Uh, yeah. It was completely
unrelated.
- The only...
- Okay! Mer,
I asked Riggs for his help.
Walter's age and blood pressure
would make an open surgery
too dangerous.
Now, Riggs has experience
with this technique,
and if it works, Walter will be
out of here within a week.
And why... Who is this guy
to you anyway?
None of your business.
Ohh. Oh, he's your shrink.
♪♪
My feelings toward Riggs...
way past anger.
It's more like rage,
bordering on physical violence.
Good. Right.
Now the only question is why.
And you're still wearing
your wedding ring.
I spend weeks in your office
taking your advice.
You're a bigger mess than I am.
We teach best what
we most need to learn.
And people pay you for that?
Heh. Trust me.
You're not gonna do any better.
Us messes have all the answers.
What drew you to Nathan?
What drew you to ignore symptoms
of a two-foot blood clot?
Sorry. Mood.
Meredith, the best way
out of this mood...
The best way out is through.
I know.
And this surgery could kill me.
So let's stop dancing around.
Why don't you sit back down?
And let's talk.
Is this really what you
want to do right now?
If you could have a scalpel in your hand
at the end of your life,
would you want to?
stop loss insurance.
Oh, Lord. I can read. I see it.
- How long have they been in there?
- Too long.
I wish I could help, but it seems
whenever I try and help today,
people are dismissive and rude
and just downright mean.
Buongiorno.
- Hi! Hi.
- Mwah! Mwah!
You want to come to lunch with us?
- Marnie is still at 4 centimeters.
- I...
We've tried laps, squats,
bouncing on the birthing ball.
- H-Her cervix won't budge.
- Give her oxytocin.
We can't. She's allergic
to Pitocin and Syntocinon.
- All forms of it.
- No, no, no, no.
Not synthetic oxytocin.
I'm saying natural oxytocin.
No one is allergic to that.
Great! How do I do that?
I assume that she's referring
to... nipple stimulation.
Uh, it can increase the body's
natural levels of oxytocin.
Nope! I'm not doing that.
You wouldn't be the one doing it.
Can we please go to lunch?
I'm not talking about,
uh, upstairs stimulation.
I mean... downstairs stimulation.
With climax, of course.
- Of course.
I-I beg your pardon?
T-The patient's water is already
is broken, so I don't think that
anything should be, you know,
going... going up there.
Uh, okay, nothing needs
to go "up there."
There is a perfect
little bundle of nerves
on the outside, Doctor.
- Y-Yes. I'm... I'm aware.
- Uh-huh.
- But, um... I...
- We're just... We're gonna...
Yeah, we're gonna figure
something else out.
- Thank you.
- Warren.
How long has this mother been laboring?
- Uh, 20?
- I'd say almost, uh, 20 hours.
And she still has 6 centimeters to go?
That's hours and hours
of more unnecessary pain
and risk of complications
when the body has a built-in mechanism
to speed this process along.
It's no mistake that God put
the G-spot in the birth canal.
That's the first time I've
ever heard those three things
in the same sentence.
I'm only saying what gets the
baby in also gets the baby out.
It's... It's just not how I do things.
Warren, let's go.
Well, she thought
differently last night.
What about this
abdominal-wall transplant?
It cost hundreds of thousands,
and the patient is still
in the hospital!
Megan Hunt is in the military...
You think the Army is going to pay
for something that experimental?
I don't think someone
should have to apologize
for saving an American hero.
Jackie, keep quiet.
The foundation put me on the board.
Your mother put you on this board.
Which means I have a say,
and Dr. Bailey, from
everything that I have...
Enough! I'm already holding
enough hands in this room.
Now, we'll talk tonight at
dinner with the wife and child.
Choose some place nice.
I told you I'm divorced.
Right. Your father's son.
Yep.
Why did you have to do that?
Oh, for heaven's sake.
He's a grown man!
And a very fine man!
If you'd let him get a word in.
- You wouldn't know the...
- It's business, Catherine!
It's not personal!
That's the problem
when women are in charge.
It's always personal.
Look what it's made you two
do to this place.
"Meet me in the on call room"?
My wife might get the wrong I...
All these people, I...
They came to me for help,
and I messed up their lives.
I either killed them or I broke them.
A-And these...
these are just Seattle!
I still have to contact L.A.
a-and get the files that...
Um, before you do that,
um, how about I take a look?
Um...
♪♪
It's time that we thought
about C-section.
Absolutely not.
I know, but if it develops
into a serious infection,
then you're putting
the baby in distress,
and then both of you will be at risk.
And if I die, my new baby
and my 2-year-old
lose their mother,
which would put us all at risk.
I know that you had a difficult
delivery last time. I do. But...
She almost died!
From the medications.
So we'll skip the epidural,
and we'll go straight
to general anesthesia.
Isn't that even worse?
There's got to be
something else we can try.
Anything.
Please!
♪♪
Belly looks good.
I'm pulling the scope.
You know, people
shouldn't ask big questions
unless they already know the answer.
I asked Emily Jamison
the day before prom.
She said yes, we walked there,
and I got to third base.
Kepner probably had the perfect dress
and... gave the dude a flower
to pin on his jacket.
Ooh!
I bet his name was John.
- Or Mason. Something clean.
- Then, afterwards...
We had... milkshakes at Jimmy's,
and it was awesome.
The entire night was awesome,
and I want that for Pete and
Jamie because they are 16.
Let them
have their teenage ideals
'cause soon they'll grow up and realize
that, you know, no matter
how many vows you make,
you still wind up in
a new apartment, all alone,
without your kid half the time.
The flower's called a boutonniere.
And his name was Joseph.
♪♪
♪ Mom and Dad told me ♪
♪ When you were on your way ♪
I've checked your mortality rates
since you arrived at Grey-Sloan.
It's a 0.9%.
Derek's was 1.3%.
Yours is better than his,
and he didn't have a brain tumor.
♪ I didn't know a best friend's
what I'd get ♪
All I see here is successes
a-and surgical firsts.
You didn't hurt these people, Amelia.
♪♪
But you are hurting
the people that love you.
If you don't let them
help you through this,
you'll hurt them a lot worse.
♪ You can follow my footprints
♪ But you don't have to fill my shoes ♪
You could've had anyone!
Why Riggs?
♪ It's just a path for you to follow ♪
He pursued me.
And you resisted.
I did.
♪ You can take the road less traveled ♪
And then I gave in.
Why?
He got me.
He knew what it was like
to lose the one you love most
in the world,
and he didn't imagine
for a minute
that he could ever replace
Derek.
I'm so impressed
with how far you've come
in talking about your feelings.
Well, you taught me well.
Well, then, I'm
so impressed with myself.
You know, both you and Riggs
share the same pain,
but there's a big difference
between presumed dead and dead-dead.
You think I'm jealous.
I'm not. I'm angry.
I'm angry because I made
myself very clear to Megan,
and then he went in there
and made me look like a liar.
But... That's fair enough,
but that's not really
what you were angry about.
- It's not?
- No... Ah! Ah!
Dr. Carr?
Bolus him with amiodarone,
start a drip,
and page Maggie Pierce right away.
- Okay.
- Ohh!
Shouldn't we take a break?
No need.
I've come to a decision.
Were we waiting for one?
This place is clearly not
worth the financial drain,
and I don't want the foundation
or the family name anywhere near it.
I'm pulling the funding. Done.
W...
If the foundation pulls out,
we'll fold. Immediately.
- Not my problem.
- You are not wrong...
- we have spent a lot of money.
- Millions.
Yes, we've spent millions
in order to make more,
but there was smoke damage
and water damage,
and we could've just repaired it,
but instead we improved it
because we hadn't had
a design update in many years.
And if we want to attract
and retain elective surgery clientele,
which is this hospital's
primary source of income,
we needed one!
And, sir, a resident set a fire...
because she was trying to save
a child from being kidnapped.
And that same resident's bravery
has been all over the news.
So I suggest to you
that to pull our funding now
would prompt a public outcry
and bring about a PR nightmare
for your foundation!
Fine. The hospital can keep its funding.
But you're fired.
Catherine, can you
take Bingy somewhere else
to have her feelings?
I need the room to make some calls.
He must have showered
small emboli to his lungs.
If Mer hadn't been with
him when the clot broke,
he'd be dead by now.
I didn't even know
she was in therapy. Did you?
TEE looks good.
Not that we talked about that stuff.
Now we don't talk at all.
She doesn't talk to me
unless it's to yell at me.
I thought you were getting
back together with Megan.
Not exactly.
And you're not with Meredith, either.
No. She couldn't want less
to do with me.
I'm not really sure
why I'm even still here.
Increase the suction.
He should be with Grey because I don't
keep people from the people they love.
I was kept from the people
I loved for 10 years. It sucked.
Okay. Slow down. I don't want
you to tear your sutures.
No, you don't want me to get stronger
and get out of here.
- Megan, come on.
- Just because you are
in an unhappy marriage
doesn't mean that everyone else
has to be unhappy with you.
Wait.
That's not what I'm doing!
You went to go break up
with your wife,
she was extra mean to you,
and so you stayed with her.
- It's more complicated than that.
- Except that it's not.
Okay, all right.
You're right. Right.
Okay, my marriage sucks,
don't know what to do about it.
But just because you're right
doesn't make me wrong.
Please slow down.
Owen, I need to be with Farouk.
Your wound will open,
you'll get an infection,
and Farouk will lose
his mom completely
instead of just missing her
for a little while.
I'm right, too. Okay?
We're both right.
So, he'll be on crutches
or maybe a wheelchair,
but Pete should probably still
be able to go to the dance.
Oh.
Oh?
Well, I didn't want to have to
say no to his Ho-Co-Pro.
You were going to say no?
I might've said yes.
But then he crashed
his hot-air balloon
in front of the whole school,
and it made me
weirdly popular.
17 seniors have already friended me.
I may have a chance of going
to Ho-Co with Rick Hannan now.
Jamie, that boy worked two jobs
to rent a hot-air balloon
and an ugly tux, for you.
Life is too short and too hard
to care more about
your social-media status
than the person who did that for you!
I... I was proposed to with a flash mob.
A guy paid dancers to put on
a whole show for me.
Do you know how rare that is?
Guys like that do not
come along all that often,
so when they do,
you say yes!
You got a flash-mob proposal?
That's so sweet. Did you marry him?
That's... That's not the...
That's not the p... the point...
The... The point is,
you go to the dance
with the guy who crashed
the hot-air balloon for you,
not... Rick Hannan.
So...
You decided to use my technique?
No. No. No. No, no.
My patient and her husband just
wanted a little alone time.
- So he's using his technique?
- No!
No!
Maybe. I don't know.
You know what? It doesn't matter.
Because... Because it's
not gonna end up working,
and they're just gonna end up
getting a C-section anyways.
I don't understand
why Americans are so prude.
When you add pleasure to pain,
pain can become pleasurable.
In the bedroom...
some people even ask for pain.
A hair tug...
a well-timed bite on the neck...
- Dr. Robbins!
- Yeah? Mm-hmm?
Uh, I-I think she's crowning.
Oh, okay. Great!
Sorry. I was in surgery.
What's wrong? Who died?
These are mine.
A patient of yours?
No, um... this is my brain.
I have a tumor in it.
A benign meningioma.
I'm sorry. What?
Maggie, I have a 10-centimeter
tumor in my left frontal lobe,
and I'm having it surgically removed.
Maggie, don't cry.
My mother died. I am allowed to cry.
I cry all the time.
It's not malignant!
It's... We can fix it!
It... Come on. It's kind of hilarious.
I'm a brain surgeon,
and I got a brain tumor.
All these MRis and an angio...
How long have you known about this?
A little over a week.
Amelia.
Owen and Meredith don't know, either.
I'm gonna need your help telling Owen.
And, um, you are gonna
have to tell Meredith
because I can't do it.
She's been telling me
I'm crazy for years,
and, um...
this kind of makes me...
kind of makes her right.
And I hate that. I...
I think more than anything,
I-I hate that.
♪♪
You e-mailed me at 4:00 a.m.
in the morning
raving about Megan Hunt's
abdominal-wall transplant.
You used the word
"groundbreaking" 35 times.
Never once did you mention
that it was pro bono!
I am in the middle of a conversation
with the Army to get that money back!
Well, maybe they can help pay for how you
redecorated the whole damn hospital!
- You said the walls look lovely!
- Miranda!
I have worked with Harper for decades.
Now, you need to take a long walk,
and let me go back in there...
And say nothing on my behalf
like you just did?
I will fix this.
I will stand up for you!
But you embarrassed that old white man.
Now, you need to let me go back in there
and fix it my way in my own time.
- Respectfully, I can't do that.
- Miranda.
- Mm!
Always have to wake his snoring
ass up in the board meetings.
Harper.
Harper, wake up, honey.
Ohh!
Harper? Oh, my God.
- What? What?
- Oh, my God!
We need a crash cart and a gurney, stat!
And hurry! 'Cause this man is dead!
- Oh! Oh!
- Ooh! Ooh!
Well, do we know what happened?
It looked like a stroke
or maybe a cardiac arrest.
It looked like we killed the man.
We? You know,
I don't even work here anymore.
- What's that mean?
- He fired me.
Well, he can't do that.
Well, he did.
Well, he can't do that anymore.
Harper Avery was not only a
permanent fixture in medicine.
He was my grandfather.
I take special comfort
in knowing that he died.
D-doing... Doing what he loved.
Mom?
"Unbelievable"...
was the word he used.
Harper spoke about how he was
astonished by our work here.
Which is really
a testament to your work,
the incredible job that you're
doing under the superb...
superb guidance of Chief Bailey here.
Hey.
Oh!
Yeah.
Hey!
Ahh. Yeah. You're still here.
Yeah, I thought it might be nice
if someone were here
when you woke up.
Oh.
You just want to hear what I was
gonna say before I croaked.
I think I've
already figured it out.
That's what all the messes do, right?
Oh, I have something for you.
Here. I just...
They took it off for surgery.
Huh?
Mm.
♪♪
What's with the bag?
I've got plenty of
personal days saved up,
so I thought I'd take some time,
see what's next.
No.
Okay, you don't get
a vote on this, okay?
We're not friends.
You've made that clear.
Because I'm angry!
Because you got a gift
that I'll never get.
And you're wasting it.
You are throwing it away.
We had the same dream.
And when you didn't fight for her,
you're betraying that,
and you're betraying me.
I'm not betraying you!
She doesn't want to be with me
'cause she thinks I'm in love
with you, and I am!
Okay? Or I was, and I'm...
I'm not gonna look at her and lie!
God, you can be infuriating sometimes!
Nathan, life is complicated,
and Megan gets that.
You don't have to lie.
You have to fight.
Show her that you love her!
Remind her of why
she fell in love with you.
Make her see that she is
your first and only choice.
Please don't blow this.
♪♪
He fired me.
No, he didn't.
The words from the man's
mouth were, "You're fired."
Well, doesn't count if the person
died right after saying them.
Oh!
Everything hurts.
Pain is radiating from all sides.
I learned a little something
about natural pain relief today.
You did?
Uh-huh.
♪♪
Ohh!
What the hell is that?
It's my Ho-Co-Pro.
Are you asking me to a dance?
No, I'm... I'm asking you
to come back home.
♪♪ Francesca Blanchard's "Free" plays...
♪♪
♪ Find me a place ♪
♪ On the West Coast ♪
♪♪
♪ Where everything ♪
♪ Is yellow ♪
♪♪
♪ I'm so tired of feeling the blue ♪
Pete?
You up for a visitor?
Yeah?
♪ I'm so tired of feeling the blue ♪
♪♪
So, how do we do it?
How do we save lives when
ours may be falling apart?
♪ In the ocean ♪
♪♪
♪ Where time and space...
Well, for one thing,
we never perform surgery
without an assist.
Hey. You paged me?
- I did.
- You paged me.
We haven't spoken in weeks.
- Owen.
- I know.
But I need to talk to you now.
Oh, oh, so,
all I've wanted to was talk,
and every time I come looking for you,
you're holed up in this room,
staring at people's tumors.
I've needed you, and all
you've done is blow me off,
and honestly, I'm at the point
where I don't care...
♪ You seem so free ♪
Why's your name on those scans?
♪♪
♪ You seem so free ♪
We look at the case.
How's he doing?
Back in sinus rhythm. Sats are good.
♪ You seem so free ♪
Do you have a minute?
Yeah.
♪♪
We gather the team...
And accept we don't
have to go it alone.
♪♪