How you doing, Nurse Hathaway?
If I were driving,
we would have been there
by now, Paramedic Shepherd.
You got to love these
late summer runs.
Especially up to Humboldt Park.
You ever been to
California and Division?
Yeah, that little outdoor cafe?
Cappuccinos every morning.
Yeah, well, slip that
vest on before you order.
We always promise
these rides'll be exciting.
We might have to wait
on those cappuccinos.
Yeah, right.
Excuse me. Excuse me, pardon me.
Are you taking the call?
We got this one.
Just relax, right. We're here.
He's cyanotic. Oh,
man, looks like he's lost
about four liters.
Doesn't look good.
Uh, multiple gunshot wounds,
chest, abdomen.
He's lost a lot of blood.
Hey, Raul!
Yeah?
We've got Payaso over here.
He's not breathing, no pulse.
We're in full arrest.
How about you?
I've got brains all
over the asphalt, bro.
Well, then come over
here. We need you.
You can help me tube him.
You got it.
Here, you check his rhythm.
Come on!
Where's the
ambu-bag? Behind you.
7.5?
Come on!
A little cricoid pressure.
Got it!
You bag him.
I'm going to try and stick him.
Come on, dammit!
I think we're fine.
His name's Payaso?
It's a nickname.
It means "the little clown."
Worked on him, what,
about three times before?
Dumb-ass little kid.
You're really pissing
me off, Payasito!
Crackhead at 14.
We need a line.
I can't get a vein
anywhere here.
Pedro!
Hey, excuse me,
can we get a little crowd
control here, please!
Move, everybody! Move back!
Move back!
Esta bien, senora.
Esta bien, por favor.
Come in here.
Coming through!
One, two, three.
Give them room, give
them room. Back it up.
Six GBH.
Move it back!
Please, everybody, back up!
Back, back, back!
I need you all to
move back, please!
Back up! Out of the
way! Out of the way!
What's our M.A.R.?
Give him another amp
of epi in two minutes.
Got it.
Welcome to hell.
Lydia, you seen Carter?
Not lately.
Hey, Kerry.
Hey, Peter. These your sprouts?
One ER rotation together
and that's what you
remember about me?
They're dead. I need the space.
So, uh, how's it going?
Uh, my first day here, and
I've only upset Doug Ross.
That's not too bad, huh?
You must be losing your touch.
Good to see you again, Kerry.
Thanks, Peter.
No can do.
That's not the kind of attitude
that we encourage
around here, Bob.
No can do, Dr. Ross.
You love saying that,
don't you? No can do...
Anybody seen Carter?
Anybody seen the chocolate donut
that Bob refuses to bring me
from the cafeteria?
He's in Exam 4.
Dr. Weaver said no
more food errands.
Inappropriate use of personnel.
You just love
Dr. Weaver, don't you?
It appeals to that whole
Germanic thing in you.
I am Polish.
Screaming twins, Curtain 2.
All right.
Morning, Susan.
Uh-huh. What have you got?
Fourteen-year-old,
multiple gunshot wounds.
Asystole, 2 amps epi,
2 mgs atropine in the field.
How long's he been down?
Thirty-five minutes.
Looking for miracles?
Two liters of normal
saline already in.
On my count.
One, two, three.
Slumming with the paramedics?
Yeah, recertifying for my MICN,
so pretty much.
Come on, Payaso,
you've survived
worse than this before.
He's in fib. Let's shock
him. Two hundred.
Four units O-neg.
Crash 5. Got the loop.
Clear?
Clear.
Three hundred. Clear? Clear.
360?
Yup. Clear.
No breath sounds
on the left side.
Hemothorax. Chest tube tray?
Got your O-neg.
Another amp of epi?
Yeah, let's high-dose him,
five milligrams.
Scalpel.
Bag.
Tube.
Oh, man, the
blood's pouring out.
Shh, he's still asleep.
God, we had such
a night last night.
You wouldn't believe it.
Triple MVA... Car
versus horse trailer
in the middle of Chicago.
What a mess.
I had such a blast,
but we didn't get
to bed till 5:00,
and now, I am late for rounds.
So if you are still here
when he wakes up,
will you tell him I said thanks?
Thanks.
Carter...
Carter!
There's already 1500
CCs in the Pleurovac.
Thoracotomy tray?
Let's do it.
Time down?
Uh... Forty-four minutes.
Aw, jeez, there's
a bucket's worth.
Haleh, get some lap pads.
Somebody get a light in here.
Double MVA at the back
door. What have you got?
Multiple gunshot
wounds to the chest,
full arrest...
Susan?
High dose epi, atropine,
4 units O-neg.
He's exsanguinated
into the left chest.
Your pals are
pulling up to the curb
You might give them a hand.
I work here. Nurse Manager.
Kerry Weaver. Chief Resident.
How long has he been in arrest?
Forty-five minutes.
Too late for miracles. Let's
call it. We need the room.
It's my case, Kerry.
We got a 7-year-old kid
and his mom coming in
who we can save.
We've got a
14-year-old on the table...
Who we can't.
Call it.
What was that time?
Forty-five down.
Susan.
All right. I'm calling
it. Time of death, 7:19.
Someone call Housekeeping.
Poor tidal volume. No response.
Another gurney please!
Tube him and use number six.
Mannitol? 30 grams.
We need x-ray in here!
Welcome to hell.
Absolutely nothing
happened, I can assure you.
You know, she must
have made the other bed
because that's where
she was sleeping,
because, you know,
we didn't do anything.
Carter, do I look
like your father?
No. Actually, not at all.
I don't care what you did
or didn't do,
except for oversleep,
which you did,
and despite your extended nap,
I'm going to assume
that you're fully prepared
for this morning's surgery.
Absolutely.
Good, because I'm
going to work your ass off.
Good. Great, because
we're doing the, uh...
Thoracic outlet syndrome.
Right.
Carol!
You scared me.
I know. I do that
to a lot of people.
Sorry...
and I'm sorry I didn't
realize who you were earlier.
Oh, that's all right.
You, uh, enjoying
paramedic ride-along?
Yeah, it's kind of fun
being out for a change.
Good, you know,
I've been
reorganizing a little bit.
Can I run some things by you?
Okay.
The doctors really need
to write down their orders
when they give them.
No more of this
three-hours-later crap
and blaming the
nurses if it's not done.
That'd be great.
And I think that
residents are capable
of cleaning up after procedure,
don't you?
Are you going to tell them that?
Sure, why not?
And they're going to stop
peeking through the charts
picking the most
interesting cases.
I mean, you don't get a
choice. Why should they, right?
It's gonna be a bumpy ride.
Already is.
So, thoracic outlet syndrome.
I really haven't had
a chance to, um...
It's the lung, right?
Don't get me started
on the Brigham.
What?
They bring me in
to set up their
emergency medicine
training program.
They keep me on
the line for six months.
Damn thing never
got out of committee.
Bunch of mud-phuds.
Mud-phuds?
MD/Ph.D..
Bench scientists doing research.
Running gels, chopping up DNA.
Northern blots,
Western blots, Southern blots.
Blots?
Don't get me wrong.
They're good people.
They're smart people,
but they couldn't
diagnose a cold
if it stood up and
sneezed on them.
So you must be pretty
glad to be back, then.
You bet you!
Give me a good sick body,
needs a little slicing,
and I'm a happy man.
Go find Benton, will you?
I believe we're ready.
Maybe it's just too
complicated for tonight.
No, no, no, no. I
want to see you.
I just, um...
I promised Jackie I would...
Uh, Dr. Benton,
I think that all he really needs
is some active
resistance therapy
for that left leg.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
That's good. I, uh...
I, uh, I promised Jackie
that I'd pick up Steven
after football practice.
Walt's down with the flu.
My class is over at 7.
I can make it by 7:30.
How about 8?
Al's off at 10.
Tsk...
Oh, man.
Yes, you're my yummy yummy.
Hey, Bob! You seen big Susie?
At the desk.
You look very sharp.
Thank you.
Did you hear that, bumpkin?
She says I look sharp.
Hi, Susie!
Chloe, what are you doing here?
Oh, I'm running so late.
Will you take the baby
to daycare, please?
We're learning Windows.
I cannot miss
class this morning.
It's very complicated.
How are things at Midwest Biz?
You know the academy?
Yeah, night school,
two years ago.
If you need any help,
I'm actually pretty good
at all that computer stuff.
Oh, thanks, Jerry.
She should have
been here an hour ago.
I know, but don't
I look sharp, huh?
Yeah, you do.
Hello.
Okay. Thank you, Susie.
Okay, so you're going to
pick her up after work, okay,
because I got that job fair.
That's tonight?
I put it on our weekly schedule.
Yeah. That's right,
that's right. I forgot.
Okay. Bye, Susie.
Bye, sweetie!
You need any help?
No.
Shh...
Excuse me.
Oh, yeah. Sorry about that.
Okay, yeah. Shh...
So just hold up his arm.
He's a pretty big guy.
Oh, yeah. 380, easy.
Big arm.
You know, you'd think we'd have
some kind of
pulley thing for this.
Watch the pleura.
Don't want to puncture it.
We do.
We do?
Hold it up higher, Carter.
Keep the neurovascular
bundle out of the way.
Uh, let's Bovie
this little fella, please.
So the, uh, pulley
thing, it's not working?
Periosteal elevator.
What did he do?
Overslept.
Well, this will
teach him a lesson.
Yeah, well, that's
what we're here for.
To teach him, right, Carter?
Don't...
move that arm.
Just out of curiosity,
how long is this surgery?
I need the rib cutter.
And, uh, Bovie, please.
So Rachel had her pancakes,
then threw up at 6:30.
Jen had a breakfast meeting.
I missed the first train out.
While I'm waiting for two hours
at the station,
I start talking to this guy
named Gozukizil.
So he's heard I'm a doc, right?
Next thing you know,
he's pulling down his pants.
He wants to show me
some mole on his butt.
I don't think I'm cut out
for this commuting thing.
Yeah, Mark, that's
really interesting
but it's just been
a lousy morning.
I've got a crying
baby in my arms...
Here's the diaper bag...
So maybe we can talk
when I get back from day care.
Sure.
Oh, I see
Kerry Weaver made it in.
Have you had a
chance to meet her yet?
Oh, yeah.
She's in, all right,
and I've definitely met her.
Good.
Great call on the new
chief resident, Mark.
Really special.
Hi, Al. It's me.
Hi.
Uh, listen, I'm sorry, honey.
I hate to do this again,
but they changed the
study group schedule.
Yeah, for tonight.
I know, but what can I do?
Well, how about a late dinner?
No, I probably won't
get out till midnight.
No, no problem.
It was running
fine this morning.
Started right up.
Yeah, I'll be careful.
Okay, thanks...
and, Al, I'm sorry.
Okay.
I'll see you tonight.
Okay, bye.
Sticky bag lady for you.
Maple syrup would be my guess.
Yeah, it was a real mystery.
She fell
while trying out
her new rollerblades
down on Michigan Avenue.
Want to take her, Susan?
Gee, I really would,
but I've already taken
the next patient in line.
Rhinorrhea with otitis,
Exam 5.
Okay.
Conni, let's get a room.
Oh, man, I hate the sticky ones.
Oh, you got another one?
Yeah. Hitchhiker.
Flagged us down on the way in.
She asked for you personally.
Loretta, right? Mm-hmm.
Same room?
Sure. Why not?
Looks like she's doing
the old PID Shuffle.
Pelvic inflammatory disease.
Occupational hazard.
I just bring them in.
I don't need to
know what they have.
Five hundred
milligrams tetracycline
and a dose of mebendazole
for the baby with the pinworm.
There you go.
Now, I've written them all down.
Are you happy?
And those will be
generic, Dr. Ross?
Yes, Haleh, those
would be generic.
Mrs. Beals, I'm Dr. Ross.
This is Haleh Adams,
and you must be Byron.
Yeah. He burned himself.
I'll say.
Let's take a look.
Yeah, boy.
It looks kind of...
kind of cool and
gory-looking, though, huh?
You feel that?
Yeah? So you say this
happened while you were at work?
The manager called me.
He had the cops and
the fire department there.
They were all yelling
So I grabbed Byron here
and I brought him here.
The manager?
Yeah, we live in a motel.
The Harbor View.
Although there's no harbor,
and there's no view.
Byron set the room on fire.
I guess we probably
don't live there anymore.
What is the
differential diagnosis
for pelvic pain?
Ectopic pregnancy?
Appendicitis?
And...
Stress in the workplace.
What else?
Mittelschmerz, PID,
endometriosis,
ruptured ovarian cyst,
to name a few more.
My money's on PID.
You had it before?
Yeast infection,
urinary tract infection...
Not much I haven't had.
Tests?
CBC, lytes, pregnancy,
cultures for GC and chlamydia.
Barinski?
Pelvic ultrasound?
Not quite yet,
but let's assume for the moment
that it is PID.
How do you want to treat her?
Ceftriaxone
and Zithromax.
She is way ahead of you here.
Joanie, how is she?
Oh, Susan, thanks for
coming up so quickly.
What's wrong, little one?
Are you okay?
She's burning up.
I think it's just
a slight fever,
actually, but you
know the rules,
no fevers, no infections.
Yeah, yeah. Thank
you for calling me down.
I want to get her
checked out right away.
I'm sure it's nothing
serious, Susan.
Did you call Chloe?
No, this is one
of her class days.
You're the contact.
Oh. Right.
I figured you might want
to take her downstairs first.
Yes, yes. Thank you.
I don't know who's
in worse shape,
mom or the kid.
Let's worry about the kid first.
Get a hold of Jack Chandler,
child psychiatry.
I don't know if he's on
today, but track him down.
He owes me a favor. Okay?
Okay.
Thank you, Haleh.
Doug, Doug, I need
you for little Susie.
Fever retrieval from day care.
Maybe she should
go straight to Pedes.
Let me just take a look here.
What's the story
with this little one?
She's burning up.
Well, not really.
I'll check her out.
Might be roseola.
She looks
like she might
be getting a rash.
I don't actually see that.
Maybe she's bacteremic.
Is there anything going around?
Always, always.
Big Susie, why don't
you go on your break
and let your
friendly pediatrician
take a look?
Okay? Yeah, okay.
Come here.
Thanks. Bye.
Dr. Lewis?
Dr. Weaver asked if you could
take the bounce-back back pain
in Exam 6.
Ah, bounce-back back pain.
Right, sure, and Bob,
could you do me a favor
and call my sister for me?
Chloe Lewis.
Midwest Business Academy.
The number's on a card
in my wallet in my bag
in a drawer in a
desk in the lounge.
Tell her Susie's sick
and she needs to
come pick her up.
Bag, drawer, desk, lounge.
Thank you.
Got it.
So what do you want to do?
How about some Jim
Beam and call it a day?
Well, we should get a CBC
and a Chem-7.
Lytes?
Lytes are in the Chem-7,
but before we order any tests,
why don't we
observe the patient?
What's wrong with him?
Okay, does the fact
that he's bright yellow
suggest anything?
He's jaundiced.
Probable alcoholic,
uh, hepatitis.
I'd start him on a banana bag
and check his LFTs.
Carter, take this whiny guy.
Frequent flyer
complaining of stomach pain.
Exam 4.
Betadine, Kerlix,
adult no-necks.
God, I love County.
These private hospitals
get all bent out of shape
if you try to steal
their supplies.
Stealing supplies?
We were just saying
how it's not really considered
theft here at County.
I know. I was joking.
There's
a Mrs. Rodriguez here.
You brought in her
son this morning,
a 14-year-old.
Anyway, someone
said you knew the family.
I think it's probably best
if they hear it from
someone they know.
Sorry.
I don't know the family.
I've never seen them before.
This is...
this is not what I do.
Why don't we put
this stuff down?
What was his name again?
Uh, Payaso.
No, that's a nickname.
It's, uh...
It's Carlos, I think.
Mrs. Rodriguez,
I'm Carol Hathaway.
I'm a nurse here
at the hospital.
Senora, no hablo ingles.
Go ahead.
Your son Carlos
was brought in this morning.
He had multiple gunshot wounds
to his chest.
We tried to save him
for 45 minutes.
We used all our capabilities,
but his heart
stopped, and he died.
I'm very sorry.
His name is Rawlings.
He's 51 years old.
Acute onset of right groin pain
last evening,
accompanied by
nausea and vomiting
times three.
No bowel movement
in the last 24 hours
and notes a previously
reducible mass
that suddenly became
tender and non-reducible
after sneezing several days ago.
He's currently on no medications
and has no allergies.
Upon physical exam,
a small, tender,
non-reducible mass
was appreciated in
the right groin area,
consistent with a
strangulated hernia.
All right, don't
just stand there.
Let's get him up to the
O.R. Let's move. Come on.
IV and foley are in.
CBC and lytes are back.
O.R.'s been notified.
Carter, you ordered all that?
Yeah. Good pickup.
Thanks. I was examining...
All right, let's
just get him up.
Come on, move. Clear! Clear!
I think you're the only resident
whose handwriting
the nurses can read...
Well, that's something.
So let them read it.
Break down the meds
when you're ordering them, okay?
I don't want a screw-up
because some nurse
forgot the heparin.
Actually, the nurses here
are pretty good, Kerry.
The nurses here are
downright great, Susan.
I think they deserve
that from the rest of us.
Oh, good, Doug. How is she?
She's fine except
for the noise factor
and a slight cold.
She'll be fine in a day or so.
Thanks, Doug.
Oh, it's okay. It's okay.
You just have a little cold
is all.
That's all. That's all.
It's okay. Dr. Lewis.
Yes?
It's okay.
Your sister isn't there.
Did they say where she went?
No, they said she
hasn't been there
in three weeks.
What do they
call it, "drop off"?
Dropped out?
Yes.
You're kidding, Bob, right?
Shh.
Why don't you give me a hand?
Susan?
Susan,
Bob tells me you've
been sitting here
for 20 minutes. Shh.
Are you in some
kind of a fugue state?
Shh.
We've got a trauma coming in.
A bank robber.
Some little old lady
mowed him down
while he was fleeing the scene.
Hit him with her car.
It's all very exciting.
Malik will watch the baby.
I slid the peanut under
the spermatic cord.
What's a peanut?
Huh? Oh, I'm sorry.
I keep forgetting
that you haven't
done surgery yet.
It's a small clamp with
some gauze on the end of it.
I'm sorry.
Are you sure you
don't mind this?
I mean, I could
probably practice
on some patient.
No, no. You, uh...
You're actually
pretty good at it.
Yeah, but I missed one
earlier this morning and...
Oh, in that case,
I think the veins
are a little over there.
Yeah.
It's a pretty complicated
surgery, actually.
I was really surprised
that Dr. Benton let me
Bovie those bleeders.
You're kidding.
Mm-mm.
I didn't think med students
got to Bovie anything.
It's very rare.
Did you do it in that
surgery this morning?
The thoracic outlet
syndrome? No.
That's pretty much
standard stuff.
They didn't really need
me too much on that.
Hey. That looks pretty good.
Maybe I could draw
some blood later.
Sure.
Carter.
BP's 100/50,
pulse, 120.
Blunt trauma to the
abdomen, both legs and head.
Car threw him around 15 feet,
knocked him right
out of his sneakers.
Cops kept questioning him
as if he wasn't gorked
out or something.
They were following
us all the way in.
On my count...
One, two, three. Now, please.
Love your work.
Always.
Let's go. Hurry up, Connie.
Oh, we have a child bank robber.
Get a CBC
type and cross-match,
6 units, Chem-7.
Get a Foley in.
We need some x-rays.
Cross-table C-spine.
Chest, pelvis,
and both lower extremities.
Connie, could you please call
for the portable, now?
Connie, get some O-neg down here
while you're at it.
How you doing, Susan?
Really well. Thank you, Mark.
Has your day gotten better?
Good bilateral breath sounds.
Actually, no.
Seems to be a little
tension in the workplace.
Holy moly. Check this out.
Whoo-wee. Lottery time.
You think anyone will notice?
I know I won't.
He needs a peritoneal lavage.
Can we get that prepped?
And where the hell's the Foley?
All right, let's get
that lavage going.
Hey, you boys,
want one of these?
What?
It's kind of a
policy thing with us.
Wet-Naps are for wimps.
Oh, yeah?
Well, it might help clean off
some of that primordial ooze.
What?
Hey.
Why's 23 here?
Maybe there are
multiple victims.
Hey, Larkey,
the boys at dispatch
screw up again?
Nah.
We were out cruising
for snow cones
heard the call.
Is this the seizure?
Heat prostration. Fell down.
Started mumbling in Lithuanian,
which our junior
ticket taker there
diagnosed as a seizure.
Okay.
Well, it looks like you have
everything under control here.
Your rig's a little
sloppy, though.
Hey, some of us
are trying to work here.
Yeah. Hey, Larkey.
So, where are those snow cones?
You did excellent
work today, Carter.
Oh.
A lot of students freeze up
on their first Bovie,
but you were calm, steady.
Morgenstern was impressed.
Really?
So was I.
Vaguely.
Choledocholithotomy,
first thing in the morning.
And then I can scrub in?
7 a.m.
Dr. Benton, about the
IV thing that happened...
Carter, just don't oversleep.
Right.
I'd always heard
banks put dye in
with stolen money.
Well, I guess it's better
than being puked on
but, uh, harder
to get out, I hear.
Yeah.
I don't suppose
we get to keep the money.
God knows, County
could use it, huh?
No, I don't suppose.
I understand your
niece has a cold.
Mm.
Well, fluids
and fever-control measures.
Yeah, Malik's looking
after her in Room 5.
I saw her.
She is quite adorable.
Thank you.
Susan...
You got a little spot
right there, under your chin.
Can I come in?
What is this, Grand Central?
Are you all right?
It's just dye, Mark.
That's not what I meant.
It hasn't been a
very good day, okay?
I know you're
worried about the baby
but it's just a cold.
Rachel used to get them
all the time.
She still gets
them all the time.
I know you're the expert, Mark,
but you don't need to tell
me that children get colds.
Doug Ross has told me that,
Kerry Weaver's told me that.
Believe me, I get it.
I didn't know that you and
Kerry were close enough yet
to be, uh...
talking about little Susie.
She told me about calling
that code this morning.
Mark, she is irritating as hell,
and you know it.
Well, I'll admit that
she has a style...
Problem? Challenge.
You would think on her first
day she'd at least try and be nice.
Maybe she thinks
that way about you.
Sorry.
You think you're going to
be able to handle this okay?
Do I have a choice?
Take a look.
No, thank you.
It's great.
It's high,
which means it's scary.
Compared to what
you do for a living?
I'm very careful down there.
I'm being careful.
Man, and I'm a wimp
for using a Wet-Nap?
That's different.
Oh, it's a policy kind of thing?
Yeah.
It's, like...
whoever's driving the car
gets to pick the music,
except for country,
which is unacceptable,
and whoever drives gets to pick
where we stop for lunch.
They decide who
stays in the ambo
and who goes up
on the Ferris wheel.
Raul never gets
to drive, does he?
No.
So, if you're so
afraid of heights
what are we, um...
what are we doing up here?
I figured we should
have a little quality time.
So, this is a
sacrifice on your part?
Yes, you could say that.
Not to mention the
sacrifice Raul's making
in staying on the ground.
Who?
Okay, one more time.
Excuse me. Dr. Ross?
Uh... Mrs. Beals.
Could you excuse
me just for a second?
It's not really Mrs.,
but that's okay.
Look, I really need
to make the afternoon shift
or I'm going to lose my job.
Byron will be okay
with you, right?
You can't leave yet.
I have to, or they'll fire me.
I'm just going to have
to take Byron with me.
Byron has to still see
the child psychiatrist.
He's in there with him now.
Dr. Ross, please.
I really need this gig.
Okay. All right.
We'll, uh...
we'll watch out for Byron.
You get back as soon as you can.
Okay. Thanks.
Oh, thank you, Haleh.
When did you reach
Jack Chandler?
I haven't.
Where's my mom?
She'll be back.
Probably gym class, right?
I don't even go to school.
I don't have to anymore.
Where's my mom?
Uh, Dr. Meyers, can I see you
down the hall just for a second?
Yeah, sure.
Byron, we'll be right back,
okay, buddy?
So, this kid is a real mess.
Who the hell are you and
what are you doing in there?
Psych resident.
I'm trying to help
this 9-year-old.
Yeah, well, this just
isn't the kind of case
you can just poach out of the ER
Hey, I was called
down here, okay?
By who? By whom.
By Dr. Weaver, chief
resident. Code red!
Somebody call the
damn fire department!
Just rip it out! Rip it out!
Open the door!
I got it.
Byron!
Where's the kid?
What kid?
Call security, will you?
Byron!
Hey.
Hey, are you okay?
Come here. Let me see.
It's okay.
Everything's
going to be all right.
Where's my mom?
You kind of had me scared there
for a minute.
Where's my mom?
We'll get you your mom.
It's okay.
Where's my mom?
It's all right.
This thing break
down on you again?
You should have called me.
I would have come out here
and helped you. Al...
you know Peter
Benton, don't you?
Remember, I did
some physical therapy
for his mother last year?
My husband, Al.
Yeah. You came by
the house once, right?
Yeah, yeah, right, right.
Surgeon, right?
Uh, resident.
Well, yeah.
You know, surgical resident.
You know anything
about distributors?
Peter's brother-in-law
is a mechanic.
His mother talked
about her family...
a lot, all the time.
Sounds like my mom, doesn't it?
Listen, uh...
is there anybody
you want me to call?
No, no. I think we got it.
Why don't you give it a try?
Yeah, okay.
There you go. We got it.
I got to get us some
new wheels, man.
This thing's shot.
Hey, it's good to see you again.
Yeah. Take care.
Mrs. Beals, please...
I told you, there is no "Mrs."
Cindy, okay?
Please don't leave yet.
Byron's a very sick little boy.
He needs psychiatric help.
He could have burned himself up
in there.
Look, I'll take him to work.
He likes that.
He'll be okay there.
Listen. Okay.
Taking him to work
is not going to solve
any of his problems.
Well, neither are you.
Look, I really
appreciate your help
and I'll do all
the follow-up stuff
for his hand,
but I've got a cousin
who's going to put us up
and she's waiting out in the car
and she's got a
bunch of kids home,
so we really do have to go.
Someone going to
answer the phone?
Hey, Bob. What's going on?
What's happened to you?
What do you mean?
Oh, we were goofing
around on that last run.
You know, sticking our
heads out the window and stuff,
the way dogs like to do it.
It's a good look, Carol.
Hey, Bob, have you
seen Dr. Weaver?
Suture Room.
That bounce-back
migraine's here again.
Not now, Jerry.
Only trying to get you
out in time for your train.
Curtain 2.
Thank you.
We tend to run out
of Vicryl before nylon
and the lidocaine with the epis
always low, and the 25-gauge...
Kerry, excuse me, but
would this be a good time?
Thank you, Dr. Carter.
I appreciate your staying late.
Sure.
Who the hell gave you the right
to call in a psych resident
on one of my patients?
The nine-year-old pyromaniac?
Seemed appropriate.
We were waiting
for Jack Chandler,
who, as I think you know,
specializes in children.
Chandler's not on call today.
He was giving me
a curbside consult.
You're not even
on the curb, Doug...
He was going to stop by.
Kerry, he owes me a favor.
You're asking
an extremely
distraught 9-year-old
and his extremely
distraught mother
to hang around, delay treatment,
so you can have some
buddy come by and chat?
So instead you send in
some prepubescent resident
who upsets the kid so much
he sets the curtains on fire.
He set the curtains on fire
because you left him alone.
If Chandler comes
in on a curbside,
he's not going to write
anything in the chart,
he's not going to be
responsible For any follow-up.
Where does that leave the kid?
And where's that kid left now?
His mother took him out of here
AMA.
And whose fault is that?
The psych resident
was not managing his case, Doug.
You were.
I'm out of here.
Doug...
I said that I'm off.
Doug, come on.
Wait a minute, okay?
Did I miss something here today?
Let's just say
that the last train to Milwaukee
is in 48 minutes,
and I plan to be on it.
So now's not a
good time to tell you
you've got a blunt
trauma to the chest
pulling up to the back door?
See you tomorrow.
Dr. Harrison to ICU.
You okay?
I'm afraid to move.
Every time I do,
she starts to cry.
It's an amazing sound, really.
Tell me about it.
I got two of them at home
and a new one on the way.
Congratulations.
I didn't even know.
No one does.
I guess I just announced it,
but when you got to move them,
you got to move them.
Take your chances.
Oh, Conni, I'm sorry
about my attitude today
In that trauma.
You were pretty
pissy, all right,
but it was worth it
just to see you take
that green splash.
Here. You want
to try a hand-off?
Yeah.
Oh.
There she goes.
Shooting.
We need a 12-lead EKG.
Let this be a lesson
to you, Daniel.
Never try to catch
a running back
with your chest.
I can't breathe too well here.
Well, take it easy.
You're gonna be okay.
It's just a bruise, right?
He's hyperventilating.
Yeah, you would be
too if you took a helmet
to your solar plexus.
Get a pulse ox.
BP's falling, 70/40.
Pulse ox is 92.
Great. Put him on a mask.
Six liters.
Is something wrong?
Yeah, Daniel, you
should've tackled lower.
Blood gas is back.
PO-2, 65.
PCO-2, 28,
pH, 7.48.
Okay, he's hyperventilating
but his PO-2's way too low.
Shortness of breath.
Acute hypoxia
in an otherwise
healthy 15-year-old.
JVD, muffled heart sounds,
crashing BP...
Pericardial tamponade?
Blunt trauma?
It happens.
What's a pericarpal tempernard?
Is that something bad?
I can't breathe too well.
I can't breathe. Twelve-lead?
No time.
Pericardiocentesis tray.
It's a bizarre thing, Daniel,
which makes you
a very bizarre guy,
but we like that around here.
There's bleeding
in the sack around your
heart, so it's not beating right.
We're going to numb the area
and then we're going
to insert a needle
and drain the blood.
You're going to stick
a needle in my heart?
Don't worry, Dan.
I've done it a thousand times.
John, why don't you
move in for a better look?
Sure.
I'm using a subxiphoid approach.
Forty-five degree angle.
We're aiming
at the left shoulder,
drawing back as you
advance the needle.
Cool.
See, Dan, there's nothing to it.
BP's coming up. 100/60.
Mark, didn't you say something
about catching a train?
Oh, no.
Oh, oh...
God, please... um,
thanks. Good night.
Night.
When were you going to tell me?
I tried, Susie.
I really did.
Hey, I got another job
for a couple of days.
Waitressing.
Made 110 bucks.
School was too hard.
They had all these
different programs.
You had to move
this file into this file.
It just...
it made me feel so stupid.
All the other
girls in the class,
they already knew how to type
and how to write
business letters.
I always thought
a letter was, like,
a letter, you know?
They had all the right clothes.
I didn't have any of that stuff,
except for what I
borrow from you,
and even then,
it doesn't look right on me.
I really wanted this.
For Susie.
And to show you
that I could do it.
I didn't tell you
because
I knew that I would
disappoint you.
And because I
thought that just maybe
this time I wasn't
going to screw up,
but...
What happened to
the waitressing job?
Good night, Chloe.
Hold on!
Hey, wait!
Damn!
Enjoying the view?
I'm glad you came by.
I wasn't sure you would.
I wasn't sure you'd want me to.
No, no, no. I'm glad.
I, uh...
Look, you know, Jeanie, I, uh...
I thought I could
do this but, um...
We can't. I know.
We've talked
about all this before.
It's just...
it's hard.
Yeah, well, so is this.
You got to tell him.