Whatever this is,
I don't want it to end.
Sorry. I didn't know.
Natalie, this is Claire,
my ex-wife.
How long before
Auggie gets a liver?
He's low on the list.
You're pregnant.
How could this happen?
You cannot tell my parents.
Dr. Sexton!
What were you thinking?
He had the right to die
on his own terms.
He could lose his residency.
Noah should've thought about
that before he acted.
You're fired
for negligence.
May I have a coffee
to go, please?
Of course.
Double coming up.
I'm embracing
my Italian heritage.
Oh, right.
Look at him.
Still can't believe
he fired Noah.
You don't know
the whole story.
Hey. What are you doing?
Did you even
make it home last night?
I'm sorry, what?
Kinda busy.
You're your own
worst enemy, Ethan.
Morning.
Listen, um,
about last night,
I shouldn't have shown up
unannounced like that.
It's fine.
And I completely understand
if you and your ex are...
No. It's nothing like that.
'Cause there's a lot
of history there, so...
Natalie, my ex and I are not
getting back together again,
if that's what you mean.
She just dropped
something off.
Oh, I just thought maybe...
Dr. Manning, Dr. Marcel,
got an incoming trauma.
Ambo just unloaded.
Okay.
Got it. Baghdad.
What've we got?
Cindy Morales, 32.
Contractor.
She fell off the scaffolding
at a construction site.
Landed on rebar.
It didn't go
all the way through.
We stabilized it at the scene.
Patient's mildly tachy,
but BP is stable.
Okay. Hey, Cindy?
Stay nice and calm
for me, okay?
All right.
Here we go, guys.
Nice and gentle, now.
One, two, three.
Cindy, I'm Dr. Manning.
This is Dr. Marcel.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
Can you tell me
what happened?
Got dizzy. Fell.
"A" and "B" intact.
Do you remember
when you got dizzy?
Today. That's what I get
for skipping breakfast.
BP 118/74. Heart rate 120.
Okay.
Sorry. Call for blood,
type and cross
for six and six.
We're gonna give you
something for the pain.
A hundred of fentanyl.
All right, let's get
her up to CT.
I want to see what
we're dealing with before
we take her into surgery.
Don't worry, Cindy,
we're gonna take
good care of you, okay?
WOMAN OVER PHONE:
I'm sorry
to bother you with this,
but I couldn't get ahold
of Anna's mother.
No. I am... I'm actually
really glad you called.
She's always been pretty much
of a straight-A student.
I guess just this
online learning,
it's just been a challenge.
It's hard
to get students to focus,
especially, when they miss
several Zoom classes.
She's not going to class?
She hasn't been handing in
all her assignments, either.
Really?
You know what? I had no idea.
Um, she does her homework
over at a friend's house.
She's part of, like,
a study pod.
Uh, she's there right now,
or at least I hope she is.
You may wanna start
checking her work.
You know what, it sounds
like I'm gonna have to.
Look, this has been
a difficult year for everyone.
I just thought I should
bring it to your attention.
Yeah, and you know what?
I appreciate it.
I will, uh, definitely talk
to her after school.
And thank you again
for the call.
You're welcome.
Hey. Could I get
a quick word?
Um, sure.
Those just, uh... They fell
out of Anna's coat pocket.
Dan, I am so sorry
you had to find out this way.
HIPAA, I get, okay?
But couldn't you have
found a way just to give me
a little heads up?
I tried to get Anna
to talk to you.
I feel like an idiot.
I'd no idea she was
even sexually active.
Like, not a clue.
Look, all that
I can tell you is that
she's scared and confused.
Shoot.
I'm sorry. I gotta run.
Um, are you okay?
Yeah, yeah.
Okay.
Over 200 people
from the American
Hospital Association
have RSVP'd
for your presentation.
A lotta little Zoom boxes.
Okay. What's the breakdown?
Mainly physicians?
Yes, but also pharmacists,
some hospital administrators.
Glad I included
the slide on cost savings.
If this goes well today,
hospitals all over the country
will want to join this trial.
That will increase
our visibility
to get this drug to market
that much faster.
Sabeena, this presentation
is gonna go great. Promise.
Hey, Will.
East Mercy is jammed.
They're diverting patients
to us. I'm gonna need you.
Sure, but at 3:00, you know
I got my presentation.
Oh, sorry, you're gonna
have to push that.
Ethan, come on,
you cleared this yesterday.
I know, but I just
can't spare you.
Don't worry. I'm doing it.
Hey.
April, with me, please.
Lucky you.
Stop.
Mr. and Mrs. Bowman,
I'm Dr. Choi,
this is Nurse Sexton.
Hi.
I understand you passed out
this morning.
Carol overreacted.
I'm fine.
Didn't need
to call a damn ambulance.
How long was your
husband unconscious?
I don't know.
Um, maybe a minute?
He's never passed out before.
I got worried,
and so I called 911.
Any chest pain,
shortness of breath?
There's nothing wrong
with my heart.
It's my head.
It's killing me.
Did he hit it
when he passed out?
No.
BP 147/90.
It's slightly elevated.
He's been in pain
for almost a year.
A year?
Oh, here we go.
I thought it was
my teeth, okay?
And I went to the dentist.
Had a root canal,
got a tooth pulled.
Nothing helped.
Just kept getting worse.
Did you see a doctor about it?
Of course I did.
Okay. Can you
follow my finger?
Our family doctor thought
that it might be migraines.
Another doctor thought
that it could be anxiety.
Stupid quack. No!
Mmm. Mmm-mmm.
I understand you're
in pain, but I do need
to finish my exam.
No, no. No,
it hurts too much.
Okay.
Uh, let's get a 12-lead
EKG, CBC, BMP,
cardiac labs, and a head CT.
Waste of time and money.
Mr. Bowman,
you lost consciousness.
That's concerning.
It could indicate an issue
with your heart,
or blood flow to the brain.
In order for us to help you,
we have to run these tests.
Eric, please.
We have health insurance.
We're already here.
All right. I'll check back
in a bit.
Thank you.
Yeah.
I saw a hamburger.
He was really mean.
That's no good.
We'll have to have
a talk with him.
Are you a police officer?
No, buddy, I'm a doctor.
Hmm.
He's jaundiced
and has ascites.
Is that causing his confusion?
No. That's from a buildup
of ammonia in his blood.
It's affecting his brain.
I'm gonna start him
on lactulose,
which will help bring down
the ammonia levels,
but the problem is,
everything I'm seeing
points to end-stage
liver failure.
He needs a transplant
as soon as possible.
Thank you, Dr. Ziesler.
I should stay. I can get
a sub to cover my classes.
Mmm-mmm. It's okay.
I'm taking
the day off from work.
I'll be with him.
Are you sure?
Mmm-hmm.
I'll keep you posted.
Okay.
Yeah.
Hey, Ben.
Hi, Sharon.
Hey.
Hey. How's Auggie?
Not any better,
and we don't have
a donor yet.
I'm sorry, Maggie.
Weren't you looking
at Heredity & Me to see
if he had any relatives?
Yeah, but it didn't
go anywhere.
I even asked
the ED staff to get typed.
I'll get the word out
to all departments.
Hopefully, we'll find a match.
That'd be great.
Okay.
Anna!
What are you doing here?
Just, I need to talk
to you about something.
Can it wait?
I really need to talk
to you now. Could you
get in the car, please?
What?
I, um...
I found these
in the front hall.
Does she know?
Sweetie, what is going on?
You're 15 years old.
I had sex one time! Okay?
And we tried to be careful.
I'm gonna ask you a question,
and I want you
to answer me honestly.
Did somebody pressure you
into having sex?
No. Nobody pressured me
into doing anything.
It was Ryan, my boyfriend.
Your boyfriend?
I thought that Mom
didn't want you to date.
No. She doesn't.
She doesn't let me
do anything!
Honey, she's just
trying to protect you.
Does she know?
God, no. And please
don't tell her.
Honey, I'm not gonna
tell her, you are.
I guess I just wish
you could've felt like
you could come and talk
to us about this.
I was gonna tell you...
before your lawyer walked in.
Oh, God.
This thing with your mom,
it's just complicated.
Yeah. Yeah. No, I get it.
You guys are so busy fighting,
you totally forgot I existed.
Sweetie? Honey?
That is not true. Anna?
Going to Treatment Four.
22-year-old female.
Jumped out
of a moving vehicle.
Positive LOC, GCS 11.
Good breath
sounds bilaterally.
BP 90/60.
Oh, my God.
You know her?
That's Kelly Bissett.
The kidnap victim?
Yeah. Mrs. Bissett, hi.
I'm April Sexton.
Do you remember me?
I helped treat your daughter
a few weeks ago.
Of course, I remember.
Can you tell us what happened?
I don't know. I was driving,
she just opened the car door
and jumped.
On my count.
One, two, three!
Lot of road rash.
Let's go.
How fast were you driving?
Um, maybe 30? I don't know.
Hi, Kelly, my name
is Dr. Halstead.
Can you hear me?
Do you know where you are?
GCS 12. Slightly better
than in the field, but she's
protecting her airway.
I need a CBC, CMP,
coags, tox screen.
I also want an ECG and
let's get her to CT, stat.
On it.
Let's go.
Is she going to be okay?
She's breathing on her own,
and her heart is strong.
That's a good thing.
We'll know more
when we get her scans back.
Mrs. Bissett,
I have to ask you,
when Kelly jumped
out of the car,
do you think she was
trying to kill herself?
I don't know.
I really don't know.
Okay.
Give me some suction here
where the rebar is.
Pressure's starting to drop.
Okay. Keep giving her
blood and plasma.
Rebar goes right through
the hilum of the spleen.
Got to get it out before
I get control of the vessels
and remove the spleen.
It's gonna bleed
like hell. Okay?
Laps and curved six
ready to go?
Ready.
All right. Here we go.
Okay.
Laps!
How's her pressure, Marty?
Ninety over sixty-six.
Okay, keep giving her product.
Hey. How's she doing?
Spleen's coming out now.
All right.
Damn.
What is it?
Tumor the size
of a golf ball.
On the back wall
of the stomach.
It didn't show on the CT.
Too much scatter
from the rebar to see it.
Can you resect it?
Not without
the patient's consent.
I'm gonna send
a sample to pathology.
Miss Bissett?
Dr. Charles.
I just heard about Kelly.
Mmm.
Um, Dr. Halstead
told me that
she broke her pelvis,
and has a concussion.
I'm so sorry.
Yes. They took her
for more tests.
So, I understand that she
jumped out of your car.
Do you have any idea why?
Were you having
an argument?
Taking her some place
she didn't want to go?
No, just the opposite.
We were going to Navy Pier.
Oh.
I used to take her there
all the time
when she was little.
Oh.
She loved it.
So did my youngest.
Oh, boy. That Ferris wheel
was her favorite.
What was Kelly's?
Yeah, I don't remember.
She liked it all.
I thought she'd be so happy.
I just don't understand
what happened.
Any incidents or issues
before today that are
standing out for you?
Not really.
Hmm.
Just... I never know
what she's thinking.
Look, she's been gone
for over 12 years,
during which, she went
from being a little girl
to an adult.
There's bound to be
a period of transition,
and you just gotta
try and be patient.
She's my daughter.
Yeah.
But to tell you the truth,
it's like we're strangers.
You have news?
One of the donors
you had typed
is a match to Auggie.
That's wonderful.
Yes, but unfortunately,
there's a problem.
The donor has amyloidosis.
So?
Maggie...
I know it causes protein
to build up in the organs,
but that might not
happen for years.
But it will
happen eventually,
and when it does,
it will be life-threatening.
Yeah, but who knows
what treatments
they might have by then.
Sharon,
Auggie needs this liver.
I understand.
I'll tell you what,
if Dr. Ziesler confirms
that it's an emergency,
I can allow
the transplant to proceed.
She will.
We got your test results back.
Your labs and CT
came back normal.
I told you so. You know what,
you never should've
brought me here.
Oh, Mr. Bowman,
I did hear a slight murmur
when I was listening to
your heart earlier,
and I'd like to do
an echocardiogram.
No. No. No more tests.
Can you get this off me,
and where are my clothes?
Actually, Mr. Bowman,
an echo is a non-invasive...
You know what? I've had
that murmur since I was a kid.
There is nothing wrong
with my heart.
Then an echo will prove that.
Every time you people poke me
or jab me with a needle,
you make this pain
in my head worse.
Why don't you fix that?
We will.
But you came in today
because you
lost consciousness.
A potentially
life-threatening issue.
So, please, let us find out
what caused it.
Fine, but you are just
like every other crap doctor
that I have been to.
Eric, please.
You know what? Shut up!
I am sick and tired
of you treating me this way,
talking to me
like I'm a child.
I am trying to...
Shut your mouth!
I'm not done talking!
I'm sorry, Mr. Bowman,
could you please not...
You can just stay out of it.
Let's all calm down.
I can't be around you
when you're like this.
Then go! Get out! I don't
want you here, anyway!
I don't want to be here.
Hey, Cindy.
It's Dr. Marcel
and Dr. Manning.
How are you feeling?
Tired.
Yeah, I'm sure.
That's understandable.
So, I want you to know
that the surgery to remove
the rebar went well.
Now, unfortunately,
there was significant damage
to the spleen,
so, ultimately,
we had to take it out.
But during the surgery,
we discovered a large mass
in your stomach.
A tumor.
And I'm afraid to say,
it is malignant.
I knew it.
You did?
I've been
having pain for a while.
Just like my mom.
She died from stomach cancer
five years ago.
I'm so sorry to hear that.
Look, I left
your abdomen open,
so, with your consent,
I could take you to the OR,
and we can remove
that cancer right now.
No.
It's best to remove
the tumor before it has
a chance to spread.
I won't do the surgery.
Just please, close me back up.
Okay, then, we can have
an oncologist come by,
and discuss further
treatment options.
I can't do that. I won't.
May I ask why?
For years, I watched my mom
go through painful surgeries.
Chemo made her so sick,
she couldn't get out of bed.
All those
horrible treatments,
and she died, anyway.
Cindy, you have to understand,
cancer treatments
have come a long way.
Cindy, without treatment,
the cancer will continue
to grow.
If you choose to do nothing,
this cancer will kill you.
Then, at least,
I'll die on my own terms.
I hate the thought of
standing by and doing nothing.
Yeah.
This rate, she'll most likely
be dead in six months.
You know,
she's effectively
killing herself.
Can we argue she's suicidal?
Seems like a long shot.
Don't close her up yet.
Let me talk to Ms. Goodwin.
I've actually been thinking
about you quite a lot
the last few weeks,
just wondering what's it been
like for you, being home?
How has it been going?
Okay.
Yeah?
I mean, getting your
freedom back,
being able to come and go,
make your own decisions,
it's gonna take a little
getting used to, right?
I guess.
Yeah.
And how about you and
your mom? How's things
going between the two of you?
She told me that
she was taking you
to Navy Pier,
like she used to
when you were a little kid.
Gosh, my kids, they just
used to love going there.
Especially my youngest.
That Ferris wheel?
Did you ever go on it?
I don't know.
I can't remember.
No? I'm just curious, Kelly,
what do you remember
from that time?
None of those things.
None of what things?
That my mom keeps
talking about
that we used to do.
Baking cinnamon rolls
every Saturday morning,
reading Harry Potter
books together...
Well, I can't imagine
how upsetting that must be.
But try and understand
that your captor,
he did everything he could
to wipe out your identity.
And he had years to do it.
But I think that with time,
and with a little help,
and a lot of patience,
that those memories
are gonna start coming back.
I really do.
I don't know. I just...
I can't remember any of it.
We're ready to take
Auggie to surgery.
Hold on
just a second.
Madeline, what's going on?
DCFS won't
allow me to approve
Auggie's transplant.
But Dr. Ziesler signed off
on it. She confirmed that
it's an emergency.
I heard there's an issue
with the transplant.
DCFS is calling it off.
The liver is compromised.
Only a family member can
consent to the transplant.
But Auggie doesn't
have any family.
I'm sorry, Maggie.
These are DCFS rules.
This is insane.
Isn't there
something else we can do?
Not at my end.
Our drug can give people
their lives back.
Based on preliminary data,
we can project an increase
of 2.7 quality-of-life years.
A tremendous improvement.
This drug
could reduce hospital stays
by as much as 22%,
resulting in
significant savings.
And our initial calculations
estimate that to be
well over a hundred
million dollars
in the first five years.
Money that could fund
transplant programs
and stem cell research
to not only advance the
treatment of heart failure,
but to one day,
eradicate it altogether.
Thank you for your time.
That was spectacular.
Very effective.
Thanks.
Look at that.
You know, you should consider
doing this as a full-time gig.
Oh, yeah. Really?
No, I'm serious.
You could have
a bright future
running clinical trials.
Uh, I don't know.
I could set up a meeting
for you with Mark Barragan,
Kender's CEO.
I'm flattered, really,
but I'm an ED doc.
You know, treating patients,
it's what I love.
Speaking of which,
I'd better get going.
It's too bad you can't stay
and wait for the rest of
the rave reviews to come in.
Oh, hearing 'em from you
is all I need.
I'll see ya.
Hey. Mr. Bowman's echo
was normal.
Yeah. There's
nothing wrong with his heart.
So, why did he pass out?
I don't know yet.
I'm trying to figure out
if it's connected
to the pain in his head.
Maybe shingles
or a nerve disorder.
A little sleep
might be a better idea.
It's Mr. Bowman.
They're coming.
What happened?
He got a horrible jolt of pain
in his jaw, and now he can't
even open his mouth.
Let me take a look.
See that, I barely
touched him.
Yeah.
All right. Mrs. Bowman,
do certain things seem
to trigger an attack?
Eating, drinking,
brushing his teeth?
All of that. I can't even turn
the fan on in our bedroom
without the breeze
hurting his face.
Okay, April, 50 of fentanyl.
I need to get you an MRI
of your head and face.
Eric, Eric,
listen to me, please.
I think I may know
what's causing this.
Something the other doctors
never considered.
Listen to him, Eric.
Eric, please.
Eric, let me help you.
Listen, listen. Please.
April, let them know
we're coming up.
Yeah.
Mrs. Bowman?
This is Dr. Abrams.
I'm amazed Dr. Choi
is actually right.
It's a classic case
of trigeminal neuralgia.
What is that?
It's a condition where
an artery is pulsating
against a nerve.
And eventually, the nerve's
insulation is worn down
to the point where every pulse
triggers the nerve to fire.
Causes excruciating pain,
as I'm sure you've witnessed.
So bad, that patients
have been known to
take their own lives.
And judging from
the scans, the extent
of the nerve damage,
I think the pain was
what caused your husband
to lose consciousness
this morning.
We've been to so many doctors.
Why didn't any of them
find this?
Incompetent, maybe?
No.
Um, it's often misdiagnosed
as a dental issue because
of the pain in the jaw.
Is there a cure?
It can be managed
with medication,
but I recommend surgery.
A microvascular decompression.
I cut a small window
in his skull
and insert a piece of Teflon
cushion between the artery
and the nerve.
That sounds dangerous.
Much less so
with me doing it.
Okay.
Maggie,
his sats are dropping.
I'll up the flow of oxygen.
Go to ten liters.
Maggie, if he doesn't
start to improve,
I'm gonna have to intubate.
Hey, little man,
can you hear me?
Mom...
Oh, no, sweetie.
It's Maggie.
No. Mom.
I'm right here.
Sharon.
Yeah?
Auggie's getting worse.
They're gonna have
to intubate him soon.
Oh, Maggie.
I'm so sorry.
I just spoke to Ben.
We've decided
to adopt Auggie.
Great!
I know.
That's wonderful news.
He already
sees us as parents.
Gastern said that
a family member could
consent to the transplant.
But you won't be
granted parental rights
overnight, Maggie.
I know.
But Auggie is running
out of time, Sharon.
If he doesn't get
the transplant today,
because of some stupid rule,
he could die.
All right,
call the transplant team,
get Auggie to the OR.
I'll sign off
on the surgery.
And what about DCFS?
Well, if they wanna
raise a stink, fine,
I'll go to the press.
Believe me, they don't
want this tried in the court
of public opinion.
Thank you!
So, I thought it might be
a good idea if the three
of us could sit together
and come
to a better understanding
of what happened this morning.
We were talking
this morning about how
you've been sharing
all these memories
with Kelly.
And she's having
a difficult time
accessing those,
and that's been painful
and confusing for her.
I'm sorry, Mom.
It's all right, honey.
I remember my room,
and I remember my bear,
but all these memories,
all these happy memories
you keep talking about
are just gone.
Right. And in
the car this morning?
What was going on?
What happened?
I couldn't take it anymore.
I wanted to get away.
Almost like the despair
that you had
at not being able
to reclaim
that part of yourself.
It just made you want to flee.
Does that sound right?
Well, you know,
Kelly's memory issues
are actually understandable,
given the ordeal that
she's been through.
But I couldn't help noticing
that you, Ms. Bissett,
you were also having
a hard time remembering
something this morning.
And that was Kelly's
favorite ride at Navy Pier,
which is a place you said
you'd been to a lot together.
Do you think
there's a chance that
you might be embellishing
these memories a bit?
Embellishing the truth?
It's my fault...
It's my fault she jumped
out of the car.
Mom, no.
We hardly went to Navy Pier.
What?
And the baking,
Harry Potter,
we got through half
of book one...
I always wanted to do
all these things with you,
there just never seemed
to be enough time.
Right.
But it was just
the two of us.
I had to work.
And then one day,
you didn't come home
from school.
And I could never
make it up to you.
Getting you back,
it's a miracle.
And I just want to be
the mother you deserve.
Hey. I spoke to Ms. Goodwin.
She nixed my idea.
Said even if we put her
on a psych hold, we couldn't
force her to have surgery.
Right. It was worth a shot.
Yeah. She's 32.
So young.
Guess you should go
close her up.
Let me talk to her
one more time.
Okay.
Alone. Please.
Are you gonna
close me up soon?
I really wanna
get out of here.
Yeah. I'm sure you had
your fill of hospitals
when your mom was sick.
I can't even stand
the smell of flowers.
People used to send them
to her hospital room.
Then to the house,
after she died.
You know,
I lost my daughter
to leukemia
about ten years ago.
Just a few months
after her first birthday.
I'm so sorry.
It must've been horrible.
She used to fall asleep
on my chest.
Greatest feeling
in the world.
Man, I remember looking down
at her little face,
imagining all the things
I was gonna do with her,
take her to see Santa,
teach her to ride a bike,
walk her down the aisle.
She was so small,
but so tough, you know?
Put up one hell of a fight.
Taught me more about
courage and resilience
than I could learn
in a lifetime.
I don't talk about this
with many people.
Why did you?
Because your life
is just as precious
as my little girl's.
And you need
to fight for it.
Fight for it.
Okay.
Hey.
Hi. She, uh,
agreed to the surgery.
That's wonderful.
Yeah. I'm gonna go
book her an OR now.
How'd you get her
to change her mind?
Made it personal.
Anna?
I got pizza, honey.
Hawaiian pizza.
Which, interestingly enough,
it turns out was invented
in Canada.
I'm bleeding.
Okay. Uh... Let's, uh,
get your coat on.
Okay.
And get you to the hospital.
So, we can figure out
what's going on.
I thought
I made myself clear.
I'm sorry, but I didn't
have a choice. And that
presentation was important.
More important than the ED?
I was only gone an hour,
and I cleared all my patients.
That's not the point, man.
Look, how am I supposed
to run this department
if I can't trust my doctors?
Look, this trial
is sanctioned
by the hospital.
If you have a problem with it,
take it up with Goodwin.
A chemical pregnancy?
It's when the fertilized egg
has chromosomal abnormalities
and doesn't fully implant
into the uterine wall.
It's like having
a really bad period.
You wouldn't have known
you were pregnant
had you not taken that test.
Anna,
you're gonna be fine.
I'll give you two
some time.
Thanks, Nat.
Of course.
You know, honey,
I've been thinking a lot
about what you said.
And you're right.
You know, Mom and I,
we've been having
a tough time, and we've been
arguing about a lot of stuff.
But one thing that
we absolutely agree on,
is how much we love you.
I'm really glad you're here.
Oh, honey.
Me, too, sweetie.
So, since I'm not
pregnant anymore,
Mom doesn't have
to know, right?
We can deal with
all that stuff later.
Mr. Bowman,
it's Dr. Choi.
We're all here.
Thirsty.
Here, would you like
an ice chip?
Hmm.
You're in recovery.
Mmm.
The operation went well.
How are you feeling?
Oh, my God.
It doesn't hurt anymore.
The pain, I don't believe it.
Oh, honey.
The pain is gone.
Oh! Really, honey?
Yeah.
Oh, Carol.
Carol. All those
horrible things I said...
They were terrible. I was...
We don't have to talk
about that right now.
No. I am so sorry.
So sorry.
It's okay. It's okay.
I'm so sorry.
Oh, sweetie, it's okay.
Mr. Bowman
got his life back
because of you.
Oh, it was
a tough diagnosis.
I got lucky.
Mmm. That wasn't luck.
You went the extra mile
for him.
He was so horrible,
another doctor
might have given up.
But you didn't.
Just trying to do my job.
Hey,
about Noah?
What you did...
I get it. It's not easy
being in charge.
I'm hungry.
Now, we know
you're feeling better.
Can I have pizza?
Mmm-mmm.
We'll start
with something lighter
and see
if you can hold it down.
Sabeena,
I've been
giving some thought
to your offer
about meeting with
your guy at Kender.
I'd like to take you up on it.
Sure.
But I thought you said
your heart belonged
to the ED?
I don't know.
I'm just trying to keep
my options open, I guess.
Brilliant.
I'll get something
on the books
as soon as possible.
Thanks.
You leaving?
Yeah.
I'll walk you to your car.
Great.
Oh, baby.
No.