Dada, hi.
Later, Daddy!
That's from last week.
One recording doesn't prove
he's a present father.
How about 100?
My client records one of these
almost every day.
I've made a supercut.
The judge will love it.
You don't want to take this
before a judge.
You're right.
They'll throw us
right out their chamber.
The standard for grandparents
to claim custody
over a willing parent
demands evidence
of deprivation, addiction,
or abuse.
He fails to meet
the standard of fitness
set by Barnett v. Jeffries.
Barnett?
Are you kidding me?
What judge will believe
that a widower doctor
who still wears
his wedding ring
and sings his daughter
to sleep every night is unfit?
He is unfit.
No.
Advise your client
that Dr. Goodwin
is showing
extraordinary compassion
by not pursuing charges for her
reckless disruption of custody.
No, those voice recordings
are beautiful,
but you only made them
because you don't see Luna
for days at a time.
Dr. Goodwin has
a very important job.
Well, you could leave it.
You could work fewer hours,
but you choose work over Luna
at every opportunity
even when it meant
sending her away for months.
You work in a hospital.
You've brought a child
into the middle of a plague
to make yourself feel
more like a father.
You were in a recovery ward
for days
because you exposed yourself
to toxic chemicals.
Did you stop to think
about Luna then?
I think about her
every moment of every day.
About protecting her,
but no one will be safe
until everyone is,
So that is a lot
of people that...
You saw a room
full of poison,
and you ran right in.
You were thinking of Luna?
You nearly orphaned her.
Her mother is dead.
Luna will never remember her,
and if you died,
all she'd have is voice memos.
The sound of some dead stranger
who loved her,
just not enough
to put her first.
Georgia died in your care
knowing she never came first.
She was our daughter.
We're not letting that happen
to our granddaughter.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe she is better off
with you.
Claud's "Jordan" plays...
♪ Spending
♪ Your time with
♪ The same friends
♪ How do I reach you, baby
♪ I've been thinking lately
♪ That you're
too good for me ♪
♪ How do I tell you,
darling ♪
♪ I've been underwater
♪ I can't breathe
What are you doing?
Oh, um, I'm...
Looking at my stuff.
Mina, I am so sorry.
I was putting
the laundry away, and...
That's fine,
but I need to work now.
College applications.
Oh.
I didn't know
that you were applying early.
I have friends at NYU.
Sarah Lawrence and...
No, no, it's fine.
Are you sure?
I'm not staying in New York,
probably not even the country.
Well, I went to Cambridge.
Maybe I can write you
a letter of...
No.
Recommendation.
Thank you.
Here.
You still have a fever, babe.
Oh.
I can't stay home
again today.
There's too many people
that need my help.
And they'll still need
your help tomorrow.
Be grateful it's just the flu.
Ah, so I'm gonna
drop the kids off at my mom's,
and then I'll
be down in my office.
You want anything?
Yeah,
a stronger immune system.
I need a full workup
in an hour.
I need your advice,
but you can't make
any of it about you.
Only you would ask
for a favor
by opening with an insult.
There's this woman
I've been spending time with,
a coworker, and it's become
a bit of a situation.
Please,
half my ED is sleeping
with at least one other person
in the building.
It's fine.
She's married.
Oh.
It's an open marriage.
Dr. Bloom?
Not now.
You come.
♪
Okay, go.
I don't know
how it got to this.
Our chemistry's insane.
Yeah?
And honestly, I just
can't stop thinking about her.
Now, I'm not down
for the polyamorous thing,
but it feels kind of weird
hanging out as friends
with this secret attraction.
Well, it's not a secret.
It's keeping something
complicated to yourself
to protect the other person.
Well, can't do that,
and I'm seeing her tonight,
so please tell me
how to end it
before I fall off this cliff
and somebody gets hurt.
Huh,
why does this sound familiar?
I knew it.
Right, right,
because it's exactly
what you did with us.
You start something
that you've already decided
doesn't have a future,
so even though it's great,
you're gonna torch it.
Well, because it's not
what I wanted.
Look, I never wavered on that...
A traditional marriage,
a Black family.
Yet you let Evie go.
Look, Floyd, I know that you
like to think of yourself
as this man who walks the path,
but you keep ending up
on the cliffs.
Incoming.
I don't know.
Maybe it's because
you really want to jump.
Five-year-old Kiri Almeida.
Status: post heart transplant.
Increasing shortness of breath.
Pulse...
She's got
a congenital heart defect.
Had four heart surgeries
and a transplant last year.
They have her file.
You can read everything.
Hey, Dr. Reynolds.
Ted, Madeline, what happened?
Kiri can't breathe.
Oh, Kir, I thought we agreed,
no more emergencies.
Let's type and cross.
Well, she's AB.
Kiri's been my patient
since she was born.
Well, could she be
rejecting the heart?
I have to do a biopsy.
But could she?
Yes.
The question is how badly.
Book an OR and page Dr. Sharpe
for a biopsy.
80-year-old man
found in St. Vartan's Park
with extremely high blood sugar
and altered
sense of consciousness.
Alert and orientated times zero.
Sir, can you hear me?
Okay, let's run a chem 7,
CBC with diff,
and let's get
a blood tox screen stat.
Got it.
And who is next?
She's had
so many risky surgeries.
Yeah,
it's all standard protocol.
I know, but for a child?
Extracting heart sample now.
Prepare to withdraw
the catheter.
Yes, Dr. Reynolds.
Heart rate holding steady
at 75 BPM.
What's the severity
of the rejection?
It's 2R? 3R?
Ox at 95.
Dopamine and vasopressin
all 4.
Zero.
Zero?
There's no evidence
that she's rejecting the heart.
Then what the hell's
causing her symptoms?
Tox screen's crazy.
Is that dioxin?
Who gets poisoned with dioxin?
Dioxin poisoning
was a favorite of the KGB.
Yeah, didn't we agree
that we'd leave
our nerd interests at home?
Oh, Cold War era spy craft
is the opposite of nerdy.
It's awesome.
And the Cold War
is also, you know, over.
Yeah, but the KGB players
didn't just disappear.
Man, everyone knows
that they're the guys
who poisoned
Viktor Yushchenko in 2004.
And now I'm worried
that you're serious.
This man is our patient,
not a Russian spy.
Sounds like Russian to me.
Reed?
Max.
Please don't tell me that
we're short on vaccines again.
I can't take that today.
No, no, we have the vaccines.
Problem is,
they've been thawing all night.
This freezer's dead.
How many are in there?
1,000.
We're gonna have to toss 'em.
Toss 1,000 vaccines?
Unless you have a Ferrari
and plan on delivering them
door-to-door.
Max!
That was a joke!
Max.
We are not tossing
1,000 vaccines.
Too many people
still need them.
We need to make it safe
for everyone.
I'm sure we'll get
some walk-ins.
Take 'em to the prison ward.
Vaccinated.
Homeless clinic
across the street.
Vaccinated.
Everyone in our system
who's wanted the shot
has gotten it.
Max, that's good news.
Uh, when do they expire?
Six hours.
Okay, now, that's good.
No, that's actually bad.
Not if we move quickly.
I will post
on the hospital's website.
You hit up social media.
If we've got six hours
to give out 1,000 shots,
then let's get
1,000 people in here now.
Thank you.
Oh.
The kids make it
to your mom's okay?
Please don't be mad.
That's the sashimi salad.
Here's your octopus roll.
Reed.
Hmm.
What is this?
Great response.
We've already administered
50 doses,
and the line's growing.
Most of these people
look like
they just stepped out
of a country club.
I literally saw a guy
checking his stock portfolio.
No, it's wrong, okay?
We need to get this vaccine
to the people
who need it the most,
the ones
who don't have access to it.
This isn't our patient base.
Our patient base
can't just leave their jobs
because they got an email.
Our patient base
probably isn't on Twitter.
I am so sorry, Reed.
Why?
Because you're gonna have to
apologize to all these people.
Why am I gonna
to have to apologize?
Because I'm taking
these vaccines.
Come on, man.
Max,
what you're doing right now
seems kind of crazy.
We need to get this vaccine
to the people
who can't come
to the hospital or won't,
to the holdouts
and to the communities
who are literally dying
at twice the rate
because they're being
vaccinated at half the pace.
But the people
who showed up...
Can be rescheduled.
If they can show up
at a moment's notice today,
they'll have no problem
showing up tomorrow.
Please don't do this.
Reed, no one is safe
until everyone is safe.
These vaccines expire
in six hours.
Four.
How are we feeling,
Mr. Osheyevsky?
Leave me alone.
Look, I have to ask.
Do you have any idea
how something as toxic
as dioxin ended up
in your bloodstream?
They want me dead.
Who wants you dead,
Mr. Osheyevsky?
Dr. Bloom?
Mr. Osheyevsky's son is here.
Okay.
I don't have a son.
Dr. Mendez to ER 1.
Okay.
Uh, have Mr. Osheyevsky's
visitor tested,
and I will meet him
in the waiting area.
Will do, Dr. Bloom.
Casey, move Mr. Osheyevsky
to the procedure room.
Close the blinds and stay
with him until further notice.
You think he's in danger?
Just as a precaution.
Sweet.
Oh, the exhibit
sounds exceptional.
It is.
I love Magritte anyway,
but the Briton stuff...
Sorry.
I'll wait in your office?
No, no, no, no, no, no,
Mina, come join us.
This is Alex Dorsett.
She's on our board
at the hospital.
Hello, Mina.
Your aunt's been telling me
all about you.
As I mentioned,
Alex is on our board,
but she also happens to be
the undergraduate dean
of Columbia University.
M... um, s...
Mina?
I told you
I wasn't staying in New York.
Yeah, it doesn't hurt
just to...
You invited me here
for lunch.
This is an ambush.
No, this is me caring about
you and wanting to help you.
I already told you
I don't want your help.
No, you told me
that you don't want me
writing you a letter.
Because letters are supposed
to come from people
who know you.
You obviously
don't know me at all.
Well, Kiri's chest X-ray
and CT scans
aren't what I hoped for.
Her lungs seem to be failing.
Why?
I don't know yet,
but we started her
on a cocktail of antibiotics
to help fight infection.
At least she's
not rejecting the heart.
That's your takeaway?
Just trying to find something
to hold on to, Ted.
Kiri.
Honey.
I'm sorry.
Oh, it's okay, baby.
Oh.
Floyd?
Excuse me.
Kiri, does this hurt?
Okay, just relax.
It's okay.
What's happening?
Her liver is failing
as well.
I went to the hospital
to see you,
but I found out you were sick,
and I got scared
because I really need
to talk to you.
You need to talk
to me about what?
This.
A restraining order's
pretty harsh, Dr. Frome.
And you're violating it
right now...
And you need to leave.
But...
but don't you want me
to get better?
Of course
I want you to get better.
But I can't help you.
And you need
to leave right now,
or I will call the police.
Sit down!
You're gonna help me.
Dr. Frome,
I need you to help me.
I'm not better.
You promised I'd get better,
but you lied.
Chance, please.
My father lied too.
He said he wouldn't hurt me,
but... he did.
And when I cried,
he called me weak
and damaged goods,
and...
no one in the house
would help me.
No one,
which is why I did what I did.
Chance,
your family died in a fire...
that you set by accident.
Guys, I'm telling you,
this vaccine
is so worth it, okay?
We don't even know
who you are.
Sorry, I told you
I'm the medical director
at New Amsterdam.
New Amsterdam?
Yeah.
You guys tried to sue me
when I was late on my bill.
No, no,
we don't do that anymore.
Tuskegee,
Henrietta Lacks, antebellum.
You've had a lifetime
to earn my trust,
and you never even tried.
Why should I trust you now?
Sickle cell anemia
screenings,
forced sterilization,
night doctors.
So you want to give me
one shot now,
another in four weeks,
and then I got to come back in
for a booster?
I got no money.
I got no house.
All I got is a history
of you killing us,
and I still got the vaccine.
Wait?
You did?
I don't trust you,
but I trust the science.
I got the shot last month.
Save your breath.
I'm already vaccinated.
Even though you sued me,
I still got the vaccine
from you.
I hear there are soldiers
refusing the shot.
I hear there's
doctors and nurses
that don't want the vaccine.
Heard that too.
If you're looking
for holdouts,
you should check
your own backyard.
Ben Osheyevsky?
Yes, hi.
Hi.
How's my father?
Can I see some ID?
Of course.
Oh, I must have left
my wallet in the car.
My wife couldn't find
a parking spot,
so I just hopped out and ran.
Is he okay?
I need to see some ID.
I need to confirm
that you're family.
Well, who else would I be?
How did you know
that your father was here?
I called every hospital
in the city.
Well, my patient is saying
that he doesn't have a son.
Well, he does.
Ben, I had to park
four blocks away,
and the meter was broken,
and then I had to get tested.
You left your wallet.
You thought his dad was a spy?
I know it sounds crazy,
but, well,
he said he didn't have a son,
and while I don't usually
suspect my patients
of espionage,
this particular drug...
How was he poisoned?
We don't know yet.
My father was a tailor
who spent 50 years
in the garment district.
We hardly ever saw him.
If he was a spy,
at least we might have had
some cool stories.
I know he's upset
because we've been
looking into homes for him,
but he's never
wandered off before.
Where is he?
Uh, just give me a second.
What?
First her lungs,
then her liver,
now her kidneys.
Yeah.
I don't want to put Kiri
through any more operations,
but that may be
our only option.
Will she at least be on
the top of the transplant list?
How many more surgeries
can she take?
What do you want to do?
Nothing?
Okay, guys, can we...
Can we go outside?
I just want to make a plan.
And I don't want her
to be in any more pain.
Our daughter
is going to die, Ted.
Guys, guys.
The only thing
that's gonna get you
through this again
is each other.
Dr. Malloy, call 247.
We're separated.
Five months now.
Ironic, isn't it?
The first minute that Kiri
doesn't have any problems,
we find out that we do.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
Dr. Reynolds,
can I have a word, please?
Please tell me
you have good news.
Our request to put Kiri
on the transplant list
has been rejected.
With multiple organ failures,
they don't see her
as a viable candidate.
How are they holding up?
They're not.
They've been
through so much together.
I mean, I really thought
nothing could break them.
They had the perfect family.
There's no such thing.
So your dad hurt you.
You said that he called you
"damaged goods"?
Chance, I can barely
get to the bathroom.
I'm not... I'm not
gonna run anywhere.
You asked me
if I want you to get better.
I do.
I really do.
Um, you need to help me.
You need to...
My whole family
knew what he was doing...
But they still let it happen.
So...
I shouldn't feel guilty
for what I did, but...
I get it.
No, no, you don't.
You can't!
I do.
How?
How can you know
what this feels like?
Because...
I killed someone too.
I fully support
the vaccine effort.
I think Operation Warp Speed
has been a tremendous success.
Thank God.
I thought you were gonna say...
Personally, I didn't get it.
No, Todd, why?
I've chosen to wait.
Till when?
Everyone you know
is dead or dying?
May I speak freely?
Of course.
Without your
liberal condescension?
Maybe.
I have
no underlying health issues.
I've been fortunate
to primarily work from home,
so I've decided to wait
till the end of the line.
But this is
the end of the line.
Millions of people have
already been safely vaccinated.
To keep waiting now
would just be insane.
It would be crazy.
It would be...
I'm sorry.
I tried.
Whatever happened
to my body, my choice?
Well,
it's not just your body.
Not getting the vaccine
could hurt someone else...
My daughter.
Fair point.
Really?
Sure, I'm pretty open-minded,
unlike some people I know.
Fair point.
Look.
All I'm saying is
that a lot of the conservatives
that I work with
still have questions.
Conservatives are here
in this hospital?
I hate to burst your bubble.
Unvaccinated?
Some.
Who?
Are you asking me
to name names?
No, uh... no, Todd.
We're never gonna have
herd immunity,
we're never gonna be safe
until everyone is vaccinated.
But I'm not part of a herd.
I'm an individual
allowed to make
individual decisions
for my own health care.
But you were also a soldier,
part of a unit.
You fought alongside
other people whose beliefs
and opinions may have
been different than yours,
but you fought as one.
That's all
I'm asking you to do.
I have 1,000 vaccines
ready to go
and only one hour
to deliver them
to I don't know who,
so I'm asking you, please,
to round up as many holdouts
as you can
and meet me
in the conference room.
I'm asking you
to fight with me...
So we can try to get back
some of what we lost.
I have been looking
all over for you.
Casey, what the hell
is going on?
What's going on
is that I was right.
Mr. Osheyevsky is a spy.
Well, was a spy.
You're serious?
And not just a regular spy.
I'm talking, like,
a KGB double agent for the CIA.
It's the best day of my life.
Could you,
uh, give us a minute?
Oh, for sure.
I'll be the lookout.
KGB, huh?
The dioxin was yours.
I would rather die
than be sent to some home
like my son wants.
I am nothing
but a burden to him.
Is it possible
that he feels that way
because he never really knew
who you were?
It was my job
to keep secrets.
I understand...
But is it still?
Dr. Reynolds?
Where are we?
She's in respiratory arrest.
O2 stats are down to 84.
I'm gonna intubate.
Prepping intubation kit now.
Oh, baby.
I don't know what's happening.
Your body's
not rejecting your heart.
No, just everything else.
Floyd.
Her blood type,
you said it was AB.
Guys, think back
to four or five weeks ago.
Did Kiri get sick or...
I don't think so.
No, she had that stomachache.
About a month ago,
but it wasn't...
Lisa, get me tacrolimus
and methotrexate.
What's happening?
Hopefully Kiri's more
extraordinary than I thought.
Okay, what do you see?
Okay, it looks
like she had E. coli,
but this complication
is so rare...
But?
We were right.
Her blood type's changed.
She's not AB anymore.
Nope.
She is type O,
same as her new heart.
Which explains why
her body's rejecting
everything but the heart,
so if I bombard her
with immunosuppressants...
Go!
Go take care of our girl.
Max?
Todd?
Come in.
Wow, everybody, come on in.
Uh, you can
get set up right here.
Thank you all for coming.
But seriously, thank you.
You're welcome.
Uh, okay, everyone just...
Let's form a line,
and we'll be with you
in one second.
Thank you so much.
Okay, we're gonna do this.
Okay, there we go.
Um, you're the man, Todd.
You'll just feel
a little pinch.
Max?
Yeah.
Don't say it.
Max, I'm sorry, but...
Max?
I'm sorry, sir.
We're too late.
I don't understand.
These vaccines have expired.
They're no good anymore.
Just now?
But a minute can't
make a difference, can it?
There are regulations.
I'm sorry, Todd.
Sorry, everyone.
We're out of time.
His name was Tobias.
Toby.
He was two years
younger than me.
He was definitely the favorite.
He was handsome,
confident, skinny.
I was...
I was me.
I could have cured cancer,
and it wouldn't have been
enough for our old man.
But Toby,
oh, Toby could do no wrong.
He was a golden boy.
So it was prom night,
um, senior year.
And Toby
was with Jenny Harmeyer,
queen of the cool kids,
and he'd rented a tux
and a limo and the whole show.
Um, I was up watching TV
when they came home late,
drunk.
They were kissing
and laughing and teasing me.
Making fun of the fat brother.
I just...
I hated the way he treated me,
especially in front
of other people,
in front of Jenny.
So that night...
I'd had enough, you know?
I called out
to our parents upstairs
to wake 'em up,
knowing that he would be busted
for drinking.
He was so pissed,
but what could he do?
He just... he snatched up
our mom's keys off the table,
and they went back out again.
Made it about two blocks
before he broadsided a truck.
No seat belts.
They both
went through the windshield.
Jenny lived, and Toby died
on the way to the hospital.
Iggy!
Oh, I'm gonna go get the kids.
You want anything?
Uh...
Yeah, some soup.
Sure, what kind?
Lentil...
from that little place I like
on 9th and 11th.
You got it.
Okay.
You could have
told him I was here.
How would that have helped?
I want to help you.
Tomorrow afternoon,
I'm gonna go
down to the courthouse,
and I'm gonna get this revoked,
but you have
to promise me one thing.
I need you to meet me
at my office tomorrow
at 3:00 p.m. sharp...
and we're gonna pick up
your treatment
exactly where we left off.
Are you gonna tell anyone
I was here?
No.
Not even Martin?
No, not even Martin.
This is between me
and you, okay?
Thank you, Dr. Frome.
Now, go before my family
gets back with my soup.
Stop right there!
Don't move!
Listen, don't move.
Iggy?
Iggy!
I got you.
You're okay.
Dada.
Dada!
Dada, hi.
Hi, Dada.
Hi.
Dada, hi.
Thought I might
find you up here.
Dada.
Dada, hi.
Dada!
Max...
do you want some advice?
I'll take it.
You fight for her, Max.
Fight for her.
It feels like
all I do is fight.
This morning,
I had 1,000 vaccines
and a line of people
ready to take 'em,
and that wasn't enough for me.
I wanted to aim higher,
do better,
so because I was stupid...
Nobody got 'em.
Because I had to fight.
That wasn't really
a punch line.
When have you ever not wanted
all of us to aim higher?
To fight?
It's all a fight.
Luna, Mina...
vaccines, this hospital...
Us.
♪ And I'll run to you
when the waters rise ♪
If you don't have
to fight for it,
it's 'cause it's not worth it.
♪ Run to you
if bombs ignite ♪
♪ I'll still call to you
♪ If I lose my sight
♪ And I'll fall for you
if you need a fight ♪
♪ Using all that we can
♪ Dominating all the land
♪ Terrified it's gonna end
Wow.
Good start.
♪ Don't know
what it's all for ♪
♪ Don't want it anymore
♪ And I'll run to you
♪ When the waters rise
Mm.
Want to take it slow?
Nah.
I want to take you
right here.
♪ If I lose my sight
But knowing
you're with another man...
♪ I'll fall for you
I don't know.
Maybe the type of relationship
I want doesn't exist anymore.
Maybe it never did.
♪ Using all that we can
And even though my body
is telling me
to just let go and jump...
♪ Dominating all the land
♪ Terrified
I can't.
♪ How do we
come back again ♪
♪ And we know
the whole while ♪
♪ All that's good
♪
♪ All our past problems
♪ Understood
You were right.
We don't know each other,
and that's on me.
I keep hammering on
at you to open up,
but that has to go both ways.
♪
♪ We would come to know
♪ Our falsehood
I don't like
talking about myself.
♪ When the waters rise
Especially about...
about painful things.
But that can
leave me quite alone.
Perhaps you're
a little like that too?
♪ And I'll fall for you
♪ If you need a fight
♪ And I'll run to you
♪ When the waters rise
That's your grandfather.
My father.
♪ If bombs ignite
And he died
when you were three.
♪ I'll still call to you
♪ If I do go blind
♪ And I'll be all for you
♪ If you lose the fight
When did you know?
Well, you hate lentil soup,
and you used the safe word
from my practice.
9th and 11th.
911, not too subtle.
How did you...
keep him calm,
from hurting you?
I told him about my brother.
What, how he died in Iraq?
I gave Chance...
everything.
I gave him every part of me.
I just wanted him
to get better,
but it was never enough.
So I made up a story.
I lied,
and it worked.
I don't know
what that says about me.
I don't know what that says
about me as a human being
or as a therapist.
I don't know.
It says you finally
put yourself first...
And that's a good thing.
♪
I'm an addict.
I mean, I'm in recovery...
but I'm always
gonna be an addict.
I know.
I, uh... I've been
with women before,
like, a few times,
never in a relationship.
I know that too.
I can't cook, like, at all.
I mean, like, I would burn
this entire place down
if I even tried.
That, I kind of guessed.
I don't want there to be
any secrets between us.
I think I know everything.
You don't.
The thing is, I wish I...
I never told you before...
I love you.
Max, what are you doing here?
I thought to call,
but then I realized
what I had to say
needed to be said in person.
Everything that you said
this morning is true.
I'm not a perfect father,
and I never will be,
but I am a good father...
Max...
And I will be better tomorrow
and the day after that,
and you know who loved
that part of me
more than anyone?
It was your daughter.
And I get the pain
of losing her.
I really do,
but she would never want Luna
to be without her dad.
If you want to go to court,
we can,
but you'll lose.
And when that happens,
I will walk
out of that courtroom,
and you will
never see Luna again.
And I don't want that...
for Luna, for you...
for Georgia...
Because she knew so clearly...
what you clearly don't.
And that is that I will never
stop fighting for my daughter.
I will fight for her
until the day I die...
And I'm here to take her home.