.
- How long have you been awake?
Ethan?
- Since 1:00.
- Well, I didn't leave
a toothbrush and eyeliner
in your medicine cabinet
so I could sleep in your bed
without you.
- I've been in therapy.
Not just Dr. Charles, but the
group he sent me to at the V.A.
Thought I'd be further along.
Thought I'd at least
be sleeping.
Beginning to think
it's a waste of time.
- Ethan, you know...
PTSD--there's no quick fix.
It's a process.
Come back to bed.
- Gotta go for a run.
- [sighs]
- This is not my first rodeo.
I-I've been through this before.
You sit there deciding who gets
to see the doctor next.
And the answer is me.
I'm next.
- Mr. Coleman, there are people
in front of you.
- My heart is beating
inside my head.
- Find a magazine
and please wait your turn.
We've been through this.
- Tell me something.
Leah, where's your heart?
In your chest, right there,
behind your bra?
- You step back now.
- Not mine.
No, mine's floated up my neck
and it's beating
inside my skull.
It's just--it's beating
inside my skull
and it's driving me crazy.
Please, man!
- Hey!
- I need to see a doctor!
- Hey, sir!
- Excuse me!
- Security!
- Sir--
April, get security.
Sir--
- I need a doctor!
[panting]
Can someone please help me?
[grunts]
- Dr. Choi!
- Whoa, whoa.
- Sir, look at me.
Wait, wait, wait.
We need to get you
back into the waiting room.
- I could have lied;
I could have said
that I had chest pains.
You would have had to see me
then, but I'm not a liar.
- Okay, okay.
Sir, why don't you
just come with me?
Come with me.
It's okay.
- Someone's gotta make it stop.
- Okay.
- It's gotta stop.
- We will get to you
as soon as we can.
- No!
[shouting]
[screaming]
Will somebody see me now?
[sobbing]
- Page Dr. Charles.
.
- I'm not crazy!
I'm not!
- Mr. Colman, I'm Dr. Choi.
We need you to stay calm.
- Didn't help--
it's--it's still pounding!
- He says his heart is pounding
inside of his head.
- Mr. Coleman,
I need to examine your ear.
- I don't care about the ear!
[screaming]
- Let's get him something
for the pain.
5 of morphine IV, please.
- Got it.
- Mr. Coleman, I'm Dr. Charles,
psychiatrist.
- Just because I'm a vet
does not mean
that I am a mental case.
- You did walk in here
and stab yourself in the head.
- Because no one--
no one would help me.
- Well, look, I-I just need
to do a little evaluation,
ask you a couple questions;
that be all right?
- I'm not crazy.
I'm not a drug addict.
- You're wearing six shirts?
- Yeah, but just
one pair of pants.
Why's that?
- Isn't it obvious?
To--to muffle the sound
of my heart.
- Does it help?
- Nothing--nothing helps!
[panting]
Please...somebody...
- Good morning.
I'm Dr. Manning.
I bet you're Bo.
- And I'm Griffin.
- Well, hello, Griffin.
Nice to meet you.
- Did you see that man?
He stuck a pencil in his ear.
- Yes, it was very bad,
wasn't it?
- Yeah.
- Sorry you had to see that.
- The boys were playing
in the driveway
waiting for the school bus.
- I see you fell off
your hoverboard.
I see a lot of hoverboarders
in here,
if that's even a word.
- Yeah, he hit
a patch of gravel.
I tried to keep it cold.
- Let me know if this hurts.
- [groaning]
- I see there's no abrasions
on the palm.
- It--it feels like
it's sleeping.
- Hmm.
You know what I think?
I think this is
a very broken wrist.
- I do too.
It made a bad noise.
- Griffin, honey, please.
- Did you hurt your hand
as well, Mrs. Taylor?
- No, no, no.
Kitchen accident.
Burnt myself.
It's fine.
- Well, I'd like to get an X-ray
of Bo's wrist.
- You know what,
I'd prefer you didn't.
I don't want to expose him
to unnecessary radiation.
- It's just a minute radiation
exposure and it is necessary.
A surgeon needs to go in there
and reposition the bones.
- But if they're already
operating,
why do you need a X-ray?
- An X-ray will tell the surgeon
exactly what needs to be done.
But I do need your permission.
- [sighs]
Okay, it's fine.
- All right, well, someone will
be in to take you up to X-ray.
Thanks.
- [groaning and stammering]
Fresh balloons every day.
- Yeah, I know.
His room is starting to look
like a party store.
- [chuckles]
I appreciate you checking in
on him the way you do.
- Oh, please.
Eric's my guy.
Tell him I'll be up
during my break.
- All right.
- Your ride's here.
- Hold that, hold it please.
Thank you.
- [laughs]
- Honey, the only thing
that's worse
than dating a patient
is dating an athlete.
- Well, his son is the patient,
and he's retired.
- Don't get me wrong.
I love athletes.
But in my experience, they're
little kids in men's bodies.
Bad long-term bets.
- Ventricular septal defect
repair.
Lots of people born
with holes in their hearts.
Procedure's a mainstay
in the CT repertoire.
Good one to get under your belt.
You mind my talking?
- No.
- Straightforward,
high success rate.
Mostly kids,
sometimes a newborn,
in which case, stay focused on
the simplicity of the procedure.
Try not to be distracted
by the fact
that an infant's heart
is smaller than a strawberry.
Can take you out of the moment.
- Right.
- So far so good.
- You punctured
the tympanic membrane
and went into the middle ear.
We can do the repair.
It's called a tympanoplasty.
- Just listen to my heart.
It's loud, right?
- Sounds normal to me.
- [scoffs]
That can't be!
- You know, Mr. Coleman,
I'm a vet too.
I know something about PTSD.
- It's not that.
I-I saw combat,
but I-I was okay.
- What happened?
- My convoy hit an IED.
I took a back full of shrapnel.
That was it.
- Mind if I take a look?
Looks like it was serious.
I'm sorry.
- I was out of the hospital
in a couple weeks.
That was three years ago.
I was doing fine.
This thing with my head
and my heart,
that started
just six months ago.
- I wish I could tell you
there's a physical reason
for the problem.
- [groaning]
- I can't see one.
- Morning.
- Hey.
- I heard Mr. Baker
dropped the lawsuit.
- Yeah.
- That must be a relief.
- Not exactly the happy ending,
but yeah.
- Reese, are you chewing gum?
- Oh, it's sugarless.
- Well, that's not the point.
It's unprofessional.
Spit it out before you go
see another patient.
- Dr. Reese.
- Not quite.
Hey, Joey.
- To congratulate you for
getting your Pathology Match.
- Oh, it's beautiful.
- Can you read it?
Bubonic plague bacillus.
- That's amazing.
- It's from the Royal London
Hospital; it's 1893.
- Wow.
- Do you like it?
- I love it.
- Joey, I am so sorry.
I have to steal her.
Dr. Halstead in 4.
- Thank you.
- Reese.
Spit out your gum.
- Any pain?
- Nope.
- Dr. Halstead?
- Mr. Kellogg,
this is Ms. Reese,
fourth year med student,
soon to be doctor.
- Congratulations.
- Grab a hammer, will you?
Mr. Kellogg is
a gymnastics teacher.
- I fell.
Honestly, I'm--
I'm not hurt actually.
It just--it happened
on school property,
so I gotta get a doctor's note.
- Pupils look good.
Ms. Reese is gonna check
your reflexes,
then we'll get you
out of here, okay?
- [exhales]
- You okay?
- Yeah, fine.
- [distorted]
You okay?
- Oh...
- Reese!
- Oh, whoa!
- So it's pretty clear what
bones in the wrist are affected.
But what I'm actually curious
about is this.
This is a previous fracture--
one that's already healed.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I don't remember seeing it
in Bo's history.
- Hey, sorry.
Got here as soon as I could.
How's Bo?
- His wrist got broken, Daddy.
- I'm afraid your son's
gonna need surgery.
- Oh, God, you hurt yourself
pretty good, huh, big guy?
- Dr. Manning was just
showing me Bo's X-ray.
Appears that he's broken his arm
before and we didn't realize it.
- Oh.
Well, that must have been
from last year
when he fell down the stairs.
He hardly complained;
we just thought it was a sprain.
Remember that?
- Mm-hmm.
- Poor Bo.
Bo's hand is cold.
- Griffin, don't touch
your brother's hand.
- Aaron--
- Sorry, I just--
I don't want him
making it worse.
- It is cold.
The capillary refill's delayed.
- Wait, what does that mean?
- He's losing circulation.
Not enough blood flow.
April, call the OR.
Tell them we're on our way up
right now.
.
- I'm so embarrassed.
- Don't be.
You fainted.
- Yeah, right on top of
that poor gymnastics teacher.
Did he say anything?
- Only that he was very
impressed with your dismount.
Reese, your EKG and BP
are normal,
so I think
what we're looking at--
- Is a vasovagal syncope, right?
- Probably.
Just gotta figure out
what the trigger is.
- Okay.
- You know, maybe blood sugar.
Let's get you some orange juice.
- Yeah.
- Thanks, Mel.
Well, I'm no Dr. Charles,
but is everything okay with you?
- Everything's great.
The--oh, the tuba player
living above me?
He finally moved out.
And of course,
I just got my Pathology match.
And, oh--
Look.
Joey gave me the bubonic plague.
- Wow.
He must really like you.
- He does.
[sighs]
And he's very excited about me
going into pathology.
We're both excited.
You know, Dr. Halstead,
I'm sure this was nothing.
- Probably.
But just to be safe,
let's order a CBC
and we'll take it from there,
all right?
- Okay.
- All right.
The patch is done.
And the heart's closed up.
- Okay, then.
Moment of truth.
Give warm blood cardioplegia
to restart the heart.
- I'll need sutures
for the chest.
- She's in third degree
complete heart block.
- I can see that, Marty.
- What do you want me to do?
- Dr. Rhodes?
- Relax. Hold on the pump.
One of the patch sutures must've
bagged the conducting system.
- Mm-hmm.
- Suture cutters.
- That one.
Here.
- Normal sinus rhythm.
- Good call.
- Because of the edema
in the boy's hand,
I'd say he broke his wrist
at least 24 hours ago,
if not longer.
Also, she said
he hit a patch of gravel.
You'd expect there
to be abrasions on his hand,
but there are none.
Combine that
with the previous fracture...
- You suspect abuse?
- I don't know.
Maybe.
- Where's the boy now?
- In surgery.
Dr. Reyes feels confident
he'll be able to save his hand.
- Thank goodness for that.
- Yeah.
- And you said there's
an older brother as well?
- Griffin.
He's ten.
- Well, if there's
a possibility of abuse,
we have to protect
those children.
- I just--I don't want
to rush to judgment.
I feel like my radar
has been off lately.
- You're referring
to the shaken baby case?
- We put that woman through
hell, and she was blameless.
- Well, before we call DCFS,
let's get a second opinion.
- I know we're supposed to keep
our emotions out of the OR
but every time we get
one of those newborns,
I'm just a wreck, even when it
turns out all right.
Amazing how
you keep your cool.
He's an ace, Dr. Downey.
- Yes, he is.
Nice work in there.
- Thank you.
- Where you going?
- I gotta get back down
to the ED.
- And miss the best part?
Telling the family
their baby's gonna be just fine.
The honor is yours,
Dr. Rhodes.
- Mr. Coleman'll be ready
to transfer in the morning.
- Good, I've got him set up
with psychiatry first thing.
Hopefully the right meds
and therapy
will help get this
under control.
- Good luck with that.
Mr. Coleman, this is Dr. Glass.
She'll be supervising your care
at the V.A.
- Oh, fantastic.
- Nice to meet you.
I heard the surgery
was a success.
- No, it wasn't.
I still hear the beating.
- Auditory hallucinations
are complicated.
- It's not an hallucination.
- Whatever it is,
we want to help figure that out.
Now Dr. Charles has contacted
a psychiatrist at the V.A.
Should follow up this afternoon.
- It's useless talking
to you people.
- Dr. Choi, would you like
to weight in?
- It's possible
Mr. Coleman is right.
I think we should get
a chest CT.
- What's the brother's name
again?
- Griffin.
Wait--wait a second.
I already challenged them
on the injury.
Now I walk in
with a psychiatrist?
So who're you gonna be?
- Still me.
Just, uh...
not advertising.
- Okay.
Hi.
- Dr. Manning, how's Bo?
- Are they still operating
on him?
- Last we heard,
he's doing very well.
You must be Griffin.
- Yes, sir.
- I'm Dr. Charles.
Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you too.
- As soon as Bo moves up
to the ICU, I'll let you know.
- When he comes home,
I'm gonna take care of him.
- Griffin.
- Ms. Taylor, Dr. Manning told
me that you burned your hand.
Would you like us to redress
that while you're here?
- No, no, no, it's--it's fine.
It's practically healed.
- [giggles]
Mommy's clumsy.
- Is there a reason you're here,
Doctor?
- Well, waiting for a child
to come out of surgery,
that's a stressful time
for--for any family,
and we like to make ourselves
available
for questions, concerns.
- I thought you just said
the surgery was going well.
- It is.
- So why would we need
to talk to anyone?
- Aaron, please.
- Look, can't you see
what this is?
This phony concern
for your hand?
- Is Daddy in trouble again,
Mommy?
- No--no, honey.
- Doctor, let's step outside.
- Can I come with you?
- You stay here, Griffin.
- I'm not stupid.
I've been waiting for this.
You think I abuse my family?
- We do have
a-a couple of questions.
- I didn't touch my boy
or my wife,
and if you think I did,
that's fine.
You call family services,
call the police,
have 'em give me
a lie detector test.
I don't care.
Now if you'll excuse me.
- What do you think?
- I don't know.
I mean, something's off, right?
- I think so.
.
- Hey, Reese.
How you feelin'?
- Fine.
- Haven't seen a swoon
like that
since I took my niece
to see Justin Bieber.
And she just...
Oh!
- I'm fine.
It was nothing.
- [chuckles]
Glad to hear it.
- Hey, is everything okay?
- Why do people keep
asking me that? Yes.
- Dr. Halstead ordered
a full panel on you.
Did something happen?
- How is that any
of your business, Joey?
I thought you were
supposed to be running the labs,
not interrogating patients.
- Sorry.
I was just concerned about you.
- It's just unprofessional,
Joey.
There is a protocol in the ED.
It's not like pathology.
- Okay.
Well, here.
Um...
Everything came back normal.
- See?
Well, don't give it me.
Give it to Dr. Halstead.
- Okay.
- Mr. Coleman, the CT scan
we took of your chest
showed a lot of scar tissue
from your shrapnel wounds.
- So?
- It's not affecting your health
or your heart functions.
But this scar tissue
has created a malformation
which acts like
an echo chamber.
It amplifies
the sound waves of your heart.
I could see it affecting a dish
of Jell-O on your tray.
- So I was right.
It is physical.
- Yes, the vibration carries up
to your inner ear.
- You really are hearing your
heart pounding in your head.
- God.
Finally.
So what are you gonna do
to make it stop?
- I'm afraid
there's nothing we can do.
- Come on,
an--an operation maybe?
- There's too much scar tissue,
and it's too close
to the heart.
An operation
just isn't feasible.
It's okay, it's okay,
it's okay, it's okay.
- You gotta do something.
This is driving me crazy.
- Listen to me.
We'll talk to Ear, Nose,
and Throat.
See if there are any options.
- Please, please, do that.
[sobbing]
Please.
[grunting]
[panting]
- I've spoken to the Department
of Child and Family Services.
They'll be here in an hour.
- Thank you.
- Dr. Rhodes,
trauma one incoming.
Talk to me.
- 18-year-old female hit
a guard rail, flipped her car.
Open left tib/fib,
BP 90/75.
- Rotate.
- Heart rate 130, GCS 10.
- All right,
she's gonna need ortho.
Call X-ray.
Alert the OR.
- Got it.
- One, two, three.
- Transfer.
It's okay, sweetie.
Let go of the purse; it's okay.
- Give her the purse.
- Let go.
- It's okay.
- You can give her
the purse, okay?
You can give her
the purse, okay.
Hey, I'm Dr. Rhodes, okay?
Maggie, see if you can
find me a name.
- Looking for it now.
Dr. Rhodes.
Skyler.
- Hey, Skyler, listen to me.
You were in a car accident,
and you broke your leg,
but we're gonna
take care of you, okay?
Hey, see if you can find
her family.
- Got you.
Sweetie, I have your purse.
- Thank you.
[crying] Thank you.
- BP's crashing.
- Pulse ox is 78.
- She's lost consciousness.
- Give me 100 of Sux,
20 of Etomidate.
- Need a hand?
- Yep, throw in a tube.
- On it.
- Tube and scope ready, Doc.
- Hang a Mag and KRider.
- Got it.
- She's bleeding from somewhere.
Get the level one transfuser,
trigger the MTP.
I need the FAST scan
and a chest X-ray.
- On it.
- Move it here.
- Blood is on its way.
- I'm in.
- All right, there's no
free fluid in her belly.
Get the X-ray in here.
- Dr. Rhodes,
take over.
- Got it.
- Increase O2 to max.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
- Get her on the board.
- Coming in.
- X-ray, clear.
- Clear!
- Her left side is whited-out,
and her mediastinum's
shifted to the right.
- Tension haemothorax.
Chest tube tray now. 36 French.
- Got it.
- Gown.
- Here you go.
Hand me the trauma shears.
- Airway clear.
- Dr. Halstead.
- Thank you.
- Get the pleur vac.
Set up for suction.
- All right.
- Coming through.
- I've got it now.
Suction's prepped.
- Stand by.
- We need more sponges.
- Yes, doctor.
- More four by fours.
- She tore something major
in there.
- Transfuser's here.
- Hook it up--start with
the blood and the plasma.
- Got it.
- Starting now.
All right, we need
some more lab sponge in here.
- We're going up to the OR now.
- Yep.
- Hi, Dr. Charles.
- Hey, Griffin.
Where're your--your parents?
- Dad went to get some pop.
Mom had to go to the bathroom.
- Oh.
What'd you find?
- Nothing.
- I thought I saw you
pick something up.
- Oh.
A button.
It's that lady's.
- Oh, the one who got hurt.
- Uh-huh.
- Yeah.
What you gonna do with it?
- Give it to the nurse,
so the lady can get it back.
I'm not in trouble, am I?
- No.
But you know what,
let's...
Let's find Mom and Dad.
It's kind of a scary place.
- I'm not scared.
- No?
- I want to be a doctor.
- Really?
Why's that?
- The knives.
- What?
- To help people.
- There you are, honey.
I told you to stay put.
.
- Rib spreader.
- Yes, Doctor.
- Dr. Rhodes.
- Blunt force trauma,
massive left-sided bleeding.
4 PRBC's and 4 plasma given.
Had a hard time
getting her under,
but there's no time left.
So here we go.
Long metz and Debakeys to me.
- I'll get the lung
out of the way.
- She's moving.
Marty?
- I've given her plenty of Roc,
but it's not circulating.
I can't relax her.
- I'm opening the pericardium.
- Damn it.
Right atrium's torn
clear off the cava.
- Give me a Satinsky.
Gotta try to clamp it.
- [gasping]
[monitor flatlining]
- She's gone.
Dr. Rhodes?
- Time of death: 14:21.
- Just spoke to my guys
at the V.A.
There's nothing they can do
for Mr. Coleman.
How 'bout you?
- Our ENTs said the same thing.
So how do we keep this guy from
shooting himself in the head?
- The thing is, his condition
has a physical cause.
It's not some complex
psychological issue.
It's a matter of Mr. Coleman
learning how to cope with it.
- That's a tall order.
- I know.
But it's a problem he can see,
you know what I mean?
In a way, isn't it easier
to deal with things you can see?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
- So, it's not the father?
- In my opinion, no.
I think the father--
very possibly both parents
are protecting Griffin.
- A sociopath, really?
He's just a little boy;
he's only ten.
- Sociopathic traits
are identifiable
in very young children,
infants even.
- Couldn't the picking up
of the button
just be a normal curiosity?
- Most children when confronted
with such a horrific event
would be repelled.
They'd be frightened, upset.
He was drawn to it.
And then to--to focus
on an object
instead of the person who had
been so terribly injured...
I think that Griffin's
a danger to that boy--
the whole family.
I mean, the burn
on the mother's arm?
What--what's that about?
- Okay, so what can we do?
- Very little.
We inform DCFS
of Dr. Charles's opinion.
If they deem Griffin a threat
to his brother and his parents,
they'll recommend removing him
from the house.
But it's only a recommendation.
They can't force the issue.
The parents have to take
that step.
- Her pericardium was
filled with blood.
She was bleeding to death
inside of her chest.
- That's why the anesthesia
wasn't working.
It wasn't circulating.
- I better go notify the family.
- I'll do that.
You should get back to the ED.
- Okay.
- Reese, you okay?
- Uh-uh.
- It happen again?
- Vertigo.
- Maybe something is going on.
We should run some more tests.
- [sighs]
No. I know what it is.
Pathology.
- What--what is--
what are we doing?
What is all this?
- There's something
we'd like to show you.
There.
We wanted you to meet
your brother-in-arms.
- Brother-in-arms?
- Yes.
Your heart.
- Do you see how hard
your heart is fighting for you?
Fighting to keep you alive.
Mr. Coleman, we can't make you
the person you were before.
And dealing with this
is going to be a long process.
But it would help if you could
begin to think about
that pounding in your head
in a different way.
- More like a reminder.
- A reassuring,
comforting sound--
that your heart
is there for you.
- [crying]
- Wow!
You don't have to do this.
- I'm happy to.
What are you gonna make me?
- A rocket ship.
- Ooh, I can't wait.
- Thanks.
- I'll see you tonight.
- Mr. and Mrs. Taylor?
I understand Bo's surgery
went well.
Have you been up to see him?
- Yes.
He was still asleep, though.
- Listen, we owe you both
something of an apology.
We were wrong
about your situation.
Could we step into
the consultation room
so that I can explain?
- What about Griffin?
- You can watch him
from in there.
- All right.
- Griffin, honey, you stay here.
We'll be right back.
- Okay.
- Mr. Taylor, I don't believe
that you are an abuser.
But I do think that you are
covering up for one.
Your son, Griffin.
- [scoffs]
That's ridiculous.
- We're concerned
for Bo's safety.
- And yours, frankly.
- We're talking
about a little boy here.
- Who has been exhibiting
some very serious
anti-social behavior.
- Look, you just met our son.
You can judge him like that?
- I would love to be wrong
about this.
And you should have Griffin
thoroughly evaluated.
But if indeed we're talking
about psychopathy here--
- Psych--
psychopathy.
- He's still young.
His brain is still developing.
There are very real things
we can do
to intervene and help him.
Behavioral therapy has shown--
- No, no, we're not listening
to any more of this.
Nedra.
- I recommend you do.
Because if you don't,
ultimately, Griffin may have to
be removed from your home.
- No.
- Let's go.
.
[electronic alarm beeping]
- [whimpering]
- Griffin!
Griffin?
- What did you do?
- Nothing!
- Blood pressure spiking.
Heart's racing.
- Get away from your brother.
- I didn't do anything!
- [sobbing]
Oh, my God, sweetie, it's okay.
Mommy's here.
Mommy's here. Mommy's here.
- Heart rate, BP's coming down.
- What's happening to Bo?
- He's terrified.
Fear response is
an involuntary reflex.
Even though
he's heavily medicated,
he's aware he's in danger.
- [sobbing]
Sweet boy.
My poor boy.
- Mrs. Taylor...
- [crying]
- Mrs. Taylor, you know
you have a problem.
Please let us help your family.
- I've been looking for you.
- Why, so you can
yell at me some more?
- No.
I wanted to say I'm sorry.
And to ask you something.
- Okay.
- First, I really do love
the plague slide.
It was very thoughtful.
- But...
- [exhales forcefully]
Will you still like me
if I don't go into pathology?
- You're not going
into pathology?
- I want to be in the ED.
I actually like
treating patients.
- Okay.
- Really?
Okay?
- Reese, you gotta
get over yourself.
- I know I do.
You're so sweet.
Thanks.
- DCFS recommended that Griffin
be separated from the family.
- Good.
- No.
The Taylors aren't
going to do it.
- What?
I don't understand.
They saw.
- "Heart will not accept
what the eye can see."
Willful blindness, right?
I'm afraid this is not
gonna end well.
- I wish we could have
done more, Dr. Manning.
- Yeah.
- Hey!
Bet it felt good
to get out of that room.
- Uh-huh.
- Is that the amazing
rocket ship you made?
- Gotta get you to bed.
- Will you come say good night?
- You know I will.
- April, I've been thinking
about what you said,
the transference stuff.
I see you're a great nurse,
but that's not why I want
to go out with you.
Okay?
- Okay.
You're wrong about him.
He's a good guy
- Let's hope.
- Good night, Christy.
- Ms. Goodwin.
- Ms. Reese?
- I was wondering, is there any
way that I can undo my match?
- Come again?
- Undo my match in pathology.
- Matches are binding.
- I understand, but I thought if
you were to say something--
- Ms. Reese,
it's a legal contract.
Good night.
- Good night.
[exhales]
- Good night, Dr. Manning.
- Good night.
Mrs. Taylor.
- Sorry.
I'm going up to see Bo.
- I heard about your decision.
- It's a phase.
He'll grow out of it.
- You have to protect Bo.
- Do you have children?
- A son.
- And...
what would you do?
Would you send him away?
- Hey.
Tough loss today.
- Yeah.
- Sorry.
- Thanks.
- Buy you a drink?
- Uh...
Yeah, sure.
- Great.
Meet you at Molly's?
- See you there.
- You got group at V.A.
tomorrow?
- Yeah.
- You gonna go?
Remember Mr. Coleman.
You, Dr. Choi, have to fight
as hard for yourself
as your heart does.
- I'll go.
- Good.
- [sobbing]
She's gone.
My baby's gone.
I want her back.
[wailing]
- [exhales shakily]
[crying]
- Okay, if you say so.
- What?
- Thank you.
- Appreciate it.
I better go.
Afraid he'll wake up
and I won't be there.
- Sure.
- God.
Sorry.
Not much of a first date.
- Mm.
It was perfect.
- Hey, two beautiful,
unescorted ladies.
You're not stepping out on Bert,
are you?
- No, he's taking
a night course.
Hindi.
Three times a week.
- Ooh, okay.
- Yeah.
- Bert's not still
on that travel kick, is he?
- More than ever.
- Huh.
- Hey, Will.
- Hey, Herrmann.
You seen Connor?
- Nah, not tonight.
Hey.