♪ I think that I like you,
ooh, ooh ♪
On average,
our hearts beat 70 times per minute.
- ♪ Like you, like you ♪
- ♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
- ♪ I think that I like you ♪
- ♪ Oooh, ooh ♪
In the same 60-second period,
we blink between
10 and 15 times,
swallow once,
and take up to 20 breaths.
Okay,
you can't fall asleep here.
The kids.
You have to go,
please.
Right.
Go, go, go.
Come on.
Okay.
Please.
I'm up.
♪ Shake that sugar,
show me what you're made of ♪
What are you
lookin' at?
♪ Make me want some more ♪
♪ Oh, mi amore ♪
♪ Dance with my flamingo ♪
- Bye.
♪ Give you all you want
and a little more ♪
Bye.
Tip-toe.
Don't forget to tip-toe.
Quiet as a mouse.
Our hearts beat...
...our lungs breathe,
our bodies keep us alive...
♪ I think that I like you ♪
...and most of us
barely notice.
♪ Ooh ♪
Oh, hey... Zola.
Uh...
♪ I think that I like you ♪
We just take it all
for granted.
Um...
♪ I think I like you a lot ♪
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 15  Episode 22
Episode Title:
"Head Over High Heels"
Sync corrections  by  srjanapala
What did she say?
Did she ask you what
you're doing here?
- No.
- What is she doing up?
I-I-I don't know.
She was thirsty, I guess.
I mean, my kids know you
as the sad guy from the couch.
An embarrassing chapter
in my life, yes.
Have I apologized for that recently?
I'd like to. - [ Chuckles ]
I mean, I had a whole plan
for telling my kids about us
with ice cream, and they could
talk about their feelings,
and now
it's just blown.
What?
Why are you smiling?
You were planning on
telling your kids about us?
Okay, okay, I'm sorry.
- Um, what can I do?
- Don't be sorry.
You can just go.
Quietly.
Bye.
Wait, wait, wait,
let me check,
make sure
the coast is clear.
Okay, coast is clear.
Okay.
Bye.
Yes, yes, yes,
Megan, I'm gonna be there.
I said I'm gonna be there,
so...
What do you mean
I might throw up?
What kind of therapy
is this?
Okay, yes.
Yes, yes, yes.
It's okay. It's okay.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
Listen, listen.
Oh!
Lis...
I'm gonna be there,
okay?
Just...
I-I'll call you later.
No. No.
I never told him
to call Ben "Dad."
T... Y-Yes, I'm aware
that you are Tuck's father.
And please do not raise
your voice at me...
Hello? Tucker?
M...
My ex-husband overheard
our son call Ben "Dad."
And now Tucker's hurt,
Tuck feels bad,
- and Ben is oblivious...
- Thanks...
And, somehow,
it's all my problem.
Are you asking my opinion
about all of this?
I would way rather give
my opinion about your life.
Hmm.
In that case,
how did you tell Tuck when
you started dating Ben?
Is this about
you and DeLuca?
Oh, I see
everything, Grey.
I am the chief.
Uh-huh.
He told you.
Who? Richard?
Well,
the man's very chatty.
So, Zola actually saw him
last night at the house
before I had a chance
to talk to her, so it was...
- She's back.
- Oh.
- What?
- Jo's back. She's here.
Oh, and here, I thought
she might be dead, or...
Don't do that.
Don't give a speech about
how you thought
she was dead
or lost a limb or left me
or whatever, all right?
She's not okay,
and I don't know why.
Just don't be Bailey
about it, please.
Dr. Karev.
Welcome back.
I'll be in the lab.
That was way worse than if
you had been Bailey about it.
- Mnh.
- Mm-hmm.
Dr. Bashine to the OR.
- Dr. Linda Bashine to the OR.
- Is it ready?
It's ready.
So, it's happening?
It's happening.
Can we tell them?
W-We can tell them, but try to
contain your wagging tail
because this could be nothing
and could do nothing.
We don't want to bait them
with false hope. It's cruel.
Right.
Just hang on.
What?
I need to wag my tail
for a second out here.
Man, I hope this is not nothing.
Me, too.
So, wait, you're saying my mom
might be able to use her arms again?
We're saying
there's a clinical trial
with stem cells being directly
injected into the cervical spine.
That's turning quadriplegics
into paraplegics.
That's...
That's what you said.
In some cases, yes.
We just need
your approval,
and then we can get started as
soon as the stem cells arrive.
Mom?
Yes.
Yes, please.
Are you nervous?
I throw up before
every job interview.
I just ace them.
So arrogant.
I love it.
But why
San Francisco?
My fellowship year
is almost up.
I have to interview at places before I...
No, I'm saying there's
a lot of
excellent jobs right here.
And I hear
the weather is worse
in San Francisco than
it is in Seattle,
and the rent
is triple.
And... hills.
You're on my vertebroplasty
today, right?
I'll see you there.
And the sports teams!
Seattle has
better sports teams!
I'm guessing.
It's a bowel obstruction.
I know the symptoms.
I have IBD.
I've had three obstructions
and three surgeries.
All right,
what are your symptoms?
Pain, bloating, cramping...
Bowel obstruction symptoms.
- Ow!
- Okay,
I'd love to take
your word for it,
- but I have to get you a...
- Get a CT. Yeah, I know.
Can you just
order it, please?
It really hurts.
Okay.
Dr. DeLuca?
Yeah?
Uh, I have a patient
who's...
- Are you a doctor?
- Uh, I am, yes,
but I'm gonna need you to
check in with her first, okay?
I-I just had a little trouble
puttin' on my shoes.
- Oh. Oh.
- Oh.
Yeah, maybe you should
help her first.
I see a small
pericardial effusion.
The shoes were new.
I went dancing.
A little underground club
I was supposedly too old for.
Had a few shots
too many.
And I took off my shoes to walk
up the stairs to my apartment,
and... that's all
I remember.
You slept like this?
Oh, crap.
Gemma?
Uh, excuse me.
You two know each other?
Um...
Through, um,
a mutual friend.
Well, Ollie isn't
around anymore,
so thank you
for your concern,
but, as you can see,
I'm... I'm all set here.
Gemma,
how did this happen?
I think you and I both know
how this happened.
Josh Sterman, 21,
has hereditary osteoporosis
that caused
a compression fracture
at T-11 to T-12,
scheduled for
a percutaneous vertebroplasty.
I'll inject cement right here
into the vertebral body
to restore
its integrity,
then you'll be
good to go.
You'll be out of here
in time for dinner.
Pop-Pop?
Dr. Bailey!
Josh, you remember
Dr. Bailey?
She's the one who takes out part
of my bowel every few years.
Uh,
recurrent diverticulitis.
Now, the last time
I saw you,
you were, what, a foot shorter
and studying for the SATs.
He aced 'em!
Aww.
And thanks to you,
I saw him graduate from
high school and get into Udub.
Next stop,
business school.
I can't finish
those applications
until my back
stops hurting.
He's getting
- a vertebroplasty today.
- Oh.
Did I say that right?
I thought we'd be seeing
Dr. Lincoln,
the fancy sports guy?
Oh, well, Dr. Kim is
Dr. Lincoln's fellow.
He's being wooed
by the top hospitals
and some
pro-sports teams.
You're lucky you've got him
while he's still here.
Thank you,
Chief Bailey.
So, I will, uh, check back
a little later.
Pressure's on, man.
Wow.
Which one
is that one?
The Arc de Triomphe.
From Paris?
The golden plate represents
the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier.
Hm.
It's cool.
Be back in a second.
Dr. Ruta,
please contact the lab.
Any word from
the rare blood organizations?
Well, I'm waiting on
that call from Amsterdam.
He's getting weaker.
I need that blood.
I've called Cristina.
I even called Marie Cerone.
Thanks.
What about Jo?
She said anything yet?
Not at all?
It's happening again.
It's not. No, they're
happy for a while...
- It's not happening.
- ...then they break...
- She's not broken.
- ...and then they leave me.
Listen to me.
You have to trust her.
She isn't Izzie.
She isn't Ava or Lexie.
She isn't your mother.
And she's not broken,
and neither are you.
She's going
through something.
And she's been through worse and
come out on the other side fine.
She's just not ready
to talk about it yet.
I've been there.
You give me space.
You give me time.
Right?
Okay.
It's not
happening again.
Wow.
That's a lot
of journals.
Oh, you got binders, too.
Great.
Yeah, this is the lab where boring
things go to get more boring.
Bailey's really
piling it on
now that she's
chief again, huh?
Yeah, didn't help that
I was out for a while.
Mm-hmm.
Okay, well, I don't want to
bother you, then.
Bother me how?
Oh, nothing.
I just thought
maybe you could help me
with my
spray-on skin research,
but you seem pretty
underwater, so...
Wait.
That sounds way better
than any of this.
Then again,
so does a root canal.
Well, that's just the winning
attitude I'm looking for.
- So, you're a licensed therapist?
- I am.
'Cause I don't believe in,
you know...
alternative...
whatever...
You know, holistic...
voodoo stuff.
No voodoo.
Got it.
Well, Megan
swears by this...
Whatever this thing is
that you're doing, so...
Neuro Emotional
Technique.
Mm.
It's a psycho-therapeutic
modality
in which I use
muscle testing
to determine
where in your body
you might be holding on to
unresolved patterns of stress,
- like trauma, physical injury...
- Hmm. Muscle testing.
Is that like when you, uh,
get weak when you're lying?
Because that... that is
a party trick, not science.
You're right.
It's not the most precise
system of diagnosis,
but, often, when your mind is
trying to hide something from you,
your body will still
throw you under the bus.
Well...
This helped Megan
with her trauma, so...
And she was held hostage
in Iraq.
For a decade.
Presumed dead.
So I figured, if it helped her,
then what the hell?
Megan is convinced
that I am incapable
of allowing joy to
exist in my life
due to some
unprocessed trauma
that your weird voodoo therapy is
supposed to help me with, so...
Do you think
she's right?
Ow!
This is worse
than it's ever been.
I-I know it's hard,
Avi,
but I'm gonna need you to hold
still for another little while.
Okay?
You're doing great.
- Hey, you paged?
- Hey.
Uh, yes, I have a 24-year-old
patient with IBD.
She presents with
severe abdominal pain.
She thinks
it's an obstruction,
but, I mean, she's in
way too much pain.
I-I think it
might be a perf.
- Ow.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- I'm... I'm waiting for
the images to come up, so...
Okay.
How was, uh,
Zola this morning?
- She freaked out?
- I...
- Traumatized?
- I mean,
I don't think so,
actually.
I think she was
kind of normal-ish.
I mean, it's hard to hear her
over my own tell-tale heart.
Right?
I mean, why...
Why do we feel so guilty?
We're not doing
anything wrong, right?
Well...
Do you even like kids?
What?
Well, we really haven't
talked about it,
and I do
have three of them.
I have 16 first cousins,
age 2 to 15.
The 14-year-old, Tony,
always calls me about girls.
He's been doing that
since he was 9.
The 5-year-old, Sonia,
she attaches herself to my leg
when she sees me,
and I basically wear her
like a leg brace.
The 2-year-old,
Nicholas,
likes to put things in my hair
and then dig them out.
Your problem's not gonna be
that I don't like kids, Mer.
Your problem's gonna be that your
kids might like me more than you.
- You think?
- Mm-hmm.
Oh.
Scans are up.
Okay, Avi,
your scans are up.
We're almost done here.
Oh, my God.
You didn't run
a pregnancy test?!
No, no, no, Qadri said she ran
standard labs and then a CT.
What... Oh, my God.
You guys,
I'm not pregnant.
I just have...
Oww!
Avi, you are pregnant,
and you are in labor,
and it looks like
you're crowning.
What?
- Let's page OB and page the chief.
- Yep.
Uh, Dr. Pierce,
can you excuse us?
I-I'd like a few minutes alone
with Gemma if there's time.
- Of course.
- No.
Gemma. No, I don't
want him in here.
Dr. Webber...
Gemma,
don't be ridiculous.
- You are not my doctor.
- No, I'm your friend.
And I owe it to Ollie
to check on you.
Ollie is dead.
I don't want you in here
preaching at me, praying at me,
- pretending you relate.
- Except I do.
No, you don't.
You got a wife.
You got kids.
I had a sponsor.
I had Ollie.
And now I got a stiletto
in my chest
and a bottle of tequila
waiting for me when I get home.
And I don't want to hear what
you got to think about any of it.
So get out of my room
before I call security.
Oh,
for God's sakes, Gemma.
Get out.
Um, you better run
a tox screen,
make sure
she's not still drunk.
You arrogant
son of a bitch!
Get out!
- Gemma, please calm down.
- Get out!
- Please... Gemma, please hold still.
- Dr, Webber, get out! Please.
- Did you page OB?
- Yeah,
it's a busy
delivery day, apparently.
Oww!
Okay, Avi,
good, push!
How do you give
a pregnant woman a CT?
Qadri ordered the CT.
'Cause I had
my period yesterday.
This makes no seeeense!
Bear down, Avi.
Good job.
Oh!
Oh, my God.
Two wombs!
- What? Ah!
- Hm.
Oh, look at this!
It's a u-uterus didelphys!
Look at this, Grey!
I'm a little busy right now,
Dr. Bailey!
What the hell
is uter... Aaah!
You have two uteri, but you're
only pregnant in one!
Oh, my Go-o-o-o-d!
- Good job, good job, Avi.
- Come on.
You're almost there.
Head down, okay?
Come on.
Okay.
Here's your baby boy.
So, did you ever follow through
with the whole...
birth-mom thing?
Have you been talking
to Alex?
Not about that, no.
- Well, you were right.
- About?
You know what?
Y-You said that you
needed me to help you
with spray-on skin,
so can we just
get to it already?
It's a process.
Right now, we're focused on
aerosolization and coverage.
I was wrong.
This is a lab
where boring things go
to get more boring.
Mm.
Injecting cement.
♪ Your grace ♪
Is that it?
Just because I made it look easy
doesn't mean it was.
Do you have them?
The... The stem cells?
Are they here?
Uh, not yet.
Now we just have to get some
blood samples from your mom
before the procedure.
I can't quite breathe.
I-I mean, I can't
get a deep breath.
And I think it's
because I'm so aware.
I'm aware of my hands.
I'm aware of my legs.
My fingers.
When I walk... every step...
I'm aware.
I'm in awe.
We're anxious
and we're depressed
and we mope and we worry
about an extra five pounds
or our...
Our stupid job.
Since the accident,
all I can think about
are my feet
and my hands
and how grateful
I am for them.
♪ Way too close
to color your comfort ♪
- ♪ All dressed up but kept undercover ♪
- And I want them for my mom.
I want her hands back.
I want them so badly,
I can't... quite breathe.
♪ All dressed up
but kept undercover ♪
All right, we need to suspend
the patient's breathing
for about two minutes
while we inject.
Lucky for everybody, I can do
a lot in, uh, two minutes.
Y...
What?
Oh.
You miss
your boyfriend.
Who?
Ortho Barbie.
Shepherd, I can't believe
you have a thing with a jock!
It's not... Shut up.
Is it weird having sex
with a cartoon character?
Does he drip ink on you
when he sweats?
Okay, I made you laugh.
Come on. Spill.
I need deets, and you,
obviously... you need advice.
Fine.
Yes, he looks
like a cartoon God,
and the sex
is athletic,
and there is eye contact,
and nobody cries after,
and he's funny and fun
and easy to hang out with,
which is just
confusing to me
because it's
so not my type.
Oh!
Okay.
He's your Altman.
Hm.
- My Altman?
- Yeah,
you know, somebody so good
and unbroken and kind
that they just seem
wrong for you,
but, really, I mean,
you...
You've never
been happier.
So, yeah,
he's your Altman.
Oh, Tom.
You poor guy.
So, you came home from Germany,
and you got back with Amelia.
But that
wasn't what you wanted.
It was.
Amelia was... perfect.
I mean, if there was...
There was no Teddy, then...
- There is a Teddy.
- No, there's not.
I mean, she and I,
we just...
we have bad timing.
But the timing was right
in Germany,
and still, you blew it up.
Accidentally.
Was it an accident?
It's the opposite of what you
went to Germany to do, Owen.
So why would you
blow it?
You're not stupid.
You don't like hurting people.
Why would you do it?
Uh, I...
I don't know.
Well, it seems like you
might be caught in a pattern.
And if we can find
the original event
that started that pattern,
we can just stop it
from replaying.
That's it.
And that's your
E.N.T. thing?
It's N.E.T., but whatever.
Are you up for that?
Does it involve electric shocks
of any kind?
I'm on my way
to a consult,
but I wanted to make sure
everything went okay.
Josh was awesome.
Access site looks great.
How do you feel?
No more stabbing knives
in my back.
I think we're better
than okay, Chief.
- Good.
- Hey,
what's the over/under
on the bathroom situation?
- Ooh, ooh.
- Do I need to continue to lie here?
- You can go.
- I'll stop by later.
All right, coming down.
- Ooh.
- Good, careful, careful.
Any tightness?
No, no, I'm good.
Ah, so,
what's your number one?
UCSF, apparently.
Well, I have a Skype interview
with them later, actually.
Blow it off, man.
Hospitals are boring.
Find yourself a hockey team,
you know?
Fights, skates to the face,
busted shoulders.
It's a real money-maker
right there.
Josh? Josh?
Josh?
- Call a code!
- Oh, my God.
- We need a gurney over here.
Josh.
- What's... What's happening?
- We need help.
Take him outside.
Get a crash cart now.
What's happening?
Oh, my God, Josh!
- Get me cardio.
- Josh!
Start bagging him
and get an ABG now!
How's she doing?
I just need to make sure
that her heart isn't affected,
and then I'll do
a pericardial window.
It's pretty simple.
You really shouldn't
be here, Richard.
The last time
I saw Gemma,
she was taking a cake
for 17 years' sobriety.
Then Ollie died,
and I stopped going to
meetings for a while,
and I guess
Gemma did, too.
But you didn't drink.
No, no.
I took a baseball bat
to a bar.
And if I didn't have a lot of
money to settle with the bar,
I would've
lost my license.
I could've
gone to prison.
I was a dry drunk,
Maggie,
and I was angry,
and it was painful,
and...
if it weren't
for Catherine, I...
Dr. Pierce, we have a 911 page
for cardio from ortho.
Altman's in surgery,
and so is Roberts.
Oh, go, go.
I can handle it.
She doesn't want you
on her case.
Look, I'll talk Qadri
through it.
- Go where you're needed, Maggie.
- Okay.
Hi, Avi.
How you feeling?
Hey.
- Look at him.
- Hello.
Look at what I made.
Yeah.
It's Tucker.
Again.
I mean, really.
There are worse things
than to have two good men
who the boy feels close to.
So you'd be cool
if Tucker got remarried
and Tuck called
his new wife "Mom"?
Now, why would you say
a vicious thing like that?
I'm just saying, I just...
Can we please talk about me?
How did you tell Tuck
that you were dating Ben?
I... You know, on some level,
Tuck already knew.
Look, all you have to do
is show up,
make it clear what's happening,
answer her questions.
All she wants to know is that
you're there for her,
and you're not going anywhere
no matter what.
Okay, so, apparently Qadri
did do a pregnancy test,
but she didn't
wait for the results
because Avi was so sure
she knew what was going on.
Okay, I'm gonna
say a thing,
if only to spare you
the humiliation
of your girlfriend
having to say it.
- Trust, but verify.
- Trust, but verify!
I heard about
this morning, too.
You're really batting
a thousand today.
Oh, it...
It was in the middle of the night!
Let's go back
to Germany,
and just...
- to when you saidthe thing to Teddy.
- Mm-hmm.
Just focus on
what you were
- feeling in that moment.
- Okay.
Just be there,
and hold your arm strong.
Okay.
And...
Okay, there it is.
- So, now, just let that go.
- Mm-hmm.
Think about something else,
anything else,
and let's check
the concept of nervousness.
Of despair.
Feeling of distrust.
Sensitivity to
someone else's distrust.
Your distrust.
Okay, so, it's yours.
That's crazy.
Do you feel
distrustful of Teddy?
No.
Can you remember
a time in your life
when you felt that way?
Uh...
You know what?
That's a broad question.
Let's just check
when it could've happened.
Conception to five.
Listen, w-why don't we just
skip to the Iraq War,
'cause if we're talking about
trauma, that's where it started.
So...
Okay.
Was it
during the Iraq War?
No, it's not
the war, then.
Five to ten?
Five?
Six?
Seven?
Eight?
Nine?
Ten?
Do you have a memory of feeling
distrustful when you were ten?
No.
I don't know.
Okay.
Do you remember feeling joy at ten?
Probably. I was ten.
Don't look too hard.
There's probably a memory
sitting right there.
Just the first thing
you think of.
I won an award.
There was
a Science Bee at school.
And, um,
lasted three days.
All grades.
I beat everyone
at the school.
How'd you feel
about that?
Great. Proud.
Best that I've ever felt.
It doesn't
sound like it.
So you told him
to go to Germany.
Because every time
I looked at him,
I could see him
thinking about her.
And he went,
and she rejected him.
He went to Germany,
declared his love,
and she declared it back.
She loves him, Tom.
She always has.
And... And now
there's a baby.
I was kind of hoping
she was
a one-night-stand-
between-friends baby.
Nope, she is definitely
a love baby.
Except for
the salty brunette
who keeps showing up
back in his bed.
Tom, I'm telling you this
as a friend...
Owen and Teddy
are inevitable.
Hey!
Stem cells are here.
OR 2 is prepped.
My man!
See you in there.
Yeah. Ah. Mm!
- Shut up.
- Shepherd.
We're about to perform
an experimental procedure
in which we might give
a paralyzed woman
the use of her arms.
"Inevitable"
doesn't scare me.
Let's go off bypass.
I-I was careful. I...
I don't know if you used
the wrong amount of pressure
or if the cement
was too liquid,
but the pulmonary artery
is destroyed.
I pieced it together, but
the graft is barely holding.
What can I do?
This is a temporary fix
at best.
We could consider
putting him
- on the transplant list.
- Transplant?
If you can think of a better way
to save your patient from dying,
I'd love to hear it.
Damn it. Schmitt, suction!
The repair
didn't hold?
There is nothing here
to hold onto.
Clamp!
Flap!
Suction!
I ran home after school.
I had this big certificate
with a seal.
You know, like, uh, foil.
I remember that.
And, uh, my mom was
waiting for me in the kitchen.
And I was about
to show her it,
and then she said,
"Owen, sit down."
So I sat down,
and... she told me
that my dad died...
that day.
So...
I'm sorry.
What about the prize?
The certificate.
What?
Oh. I-I didn't tell her
about that.
I didn't tell anybody.
I was, um,
you know...
I was ashamed
that I was so proud,
that I was so... happy
when she was so sad.
And my dad was, um...
Owen, I think you've been
reliving this moment ever since.
No, no, no.
I think you don't
trust joy.
I think you stop it before
something terrible happens,
before the bad news comes.
But it's not
coming anymore.
That moment is over.
It came,
and you're okay.
So let's
stop the replay.
How?
Okay,
I want you to...
I want you to put your hand on
your wrist like this, okay?
And then put your hand
on your forehead.
And just sit
and breathe.
Dr. Franco,
please call extension 523.
You don't quit, huh?
You bring
a "Big Book"?
You planning
to read to me
while I'm too weak
to stop you?
I just wanted
to update you.
Dr. Pierce had an emergency
with another patient.
So... she didn't
do your surgery.
I did.
Oh.
So I can sue you.
Buy me
a new pair of shoes.
You do
whatever you want to.
Although it would make you
a serious ingrate,
seeing how I saved
your damn life,
you stubborn drunk!
Ow, ow. Hurts.
Hurts when I laugh.
Well, it ought to hurt.
You punctured
your heart with a shoe.
Heh.
That's a new bottom
if I ever heard one.
I had 17 years.
I know.
I want 'em back.
The years
don't matter, Gemma.
Just today.
It's just... It's just
one day at a time.
You start your count all
over again and tell me that.
Well, not long ago,
I almost did.
I slid my chip
across a bar,
traded it
for a line of shots.
You did what?
It was a very bad day.
Tell me more.
You stubborn drunk.
Thank you
for finding this study.
Thank you for inspiring me
to find this study.
I'll thank you both
to stop
before I vomit
into an open spine.
Okay,
suspend her breathing.
Okay.
I know you love Ben
and I know you didn't mean to,
but it hurt
your father's feelings,
so you just have to
say you're sorry
and go back to
calling Ben "Ben."
Wait, hold on.
Pop-Pop.
Hey, what happened?
Something went wrong.
- They took him. Dr. Bailey,
- What? Josh should be out by...
something went
really wrong.
Okay, uh,
I'll find out, okay?
I'll be right back.
No.
How?
Massive pulmonary artery
embolism.
The bone cement...
Okay, wait, I don't want
to hear it from you.
I want to hear it
from you.
The cement leaked,
causing a blood clot.
He went
into cardiac arrest.
Dr. Pierce tried to repair
the pulmonary artery.
We tried everything
we could, and we...
You made a mistake
on a healthy
21-year-old man.
And that man is now dead.
That's what happened.
Schmitt, you close.
And you...
You are gonna stand
right next to me
and take in every moment
of that grandfather's grief.
And if you're a good surgeon,
you'll remember it.
And you'll never make
this mistake again.
Look, the way I see it is we can
keep working in awkward silence
until it's time for you to
go home, or... I vote that.
...or you can tell me what
you meant by "I was right."
'Cause I could, maybe,
help you feel,
I don't know,
one drop less crappy.
You told me
not to go looking,
and you were right.
- That's all, so...
- Jo, I told you not to go
looking
if everything was okay.
You went looking, so maybe
everything was not okay.
Maybe you needed that.
No, no. You know what?
I had everything.
I had a marriage
and a job and...
Yeah,
Alex is right here.
You got a great job
right here.
You're doing it right now.
I'm spraying water
on a paper towel,
and Alex
is anything but happy.
'Cause he's
worried about you.
He's trying to help.
Come on.
I knew it.
He sent you here.
No, he didn't.
Jo, that's not
what this is.
Then what is it?
The guy's worried,
okay?
He's...
wondering.
Why don't you just
communicate with him?
'Cause it would only hurt,
and it won't help.
You don't know that.
I had all this happy,
and I just...
tossed it aside
like it
would always exist.
I mean, we...
We see it all the time.
We diagnose patients
with terrible diseases
or we tell someone that
their husband dropped dead
of...
Of a heart attack,
and all they can say is
they were fine yesterday,
and they were.
They were fine.
I was fine.
And I took it
for granted,
and now it feels impossible
to get it back.
It was Mer.
It was Meredith that asked me
to look in on you.
She knows how our parents
can screw with our heads.
I'm here, okay?
I'm working.
You came to work
drunk, Jo.
You're still drunk.
I can smell it.
I'm thinking vodka
in the water bottle.
I'm glad you had the decency
not to see any patients today.
- That's nice.
- You don't know
- what you're talking about.
- You're in a lot of pain,
and you're trying
to numb it.
I get that, okay?
It's not gonna work.
I'm telling you.
You're gonna ruin your life.
Jo, don't leave.
Just talk to me
for a second.
I'm trying to help you.
You set foot in this hospital
drunk again,
you're not gonna be met
with compassion.
Kadiatou's "Say Something"
plays...
♪ Say something,
I'm giving up on you ♪
The surgery went well.
I see that.
Yours?
- ♪ I'll be the one ♪
- Did not.
- I'm sorry.
- ♪ If you want me to ♪
And Dr. Pierce
did everything she could,
but...
...the damage was
too extensive.
I'm...
You said we'd be lucky
to have that doctor.
You said
Josh would be in good hands.
- What happened?
- I know. I know.
Oh.
I'm so sorry.
♪ And I... ♪
My boy.
♪ ...am feeling so small ♪
♪ It was over my head ♪
♪ And I knew nothing at all ♪
Hey.
Yeah,
it's nice to meet you.
♪ Say something,
I'm giving up on you ♪
Hey.
♪ And I'm sorry that I couldn't ♪
- ♪ Get to you ♪
- Okay, now all we do is wait.
I hope we didn't
get their hopes up for nothing.
Oh. Thank you.
How do you feel about.
- ♪ I would've followed you ♪
- sushi burritos?
That sounds like
a culinary abomination,
and I need one
immediately.
Could you give me
one minute, though?
♪ I'm giving up on you ♪
Look, I know you think
you're being brave
by fighting for Teddy,
but that's not
what's happening here.
Y-Your hopes are up.
They're way up...
And hope scares you.
And that's why
you're, uh,
hiding behind a very pretty,
very decent guy
to cover the fact that you're
still hung up on Owen Hunt.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
A thing I've learned
is that life
is a series of choices.
And that sometimes,
there is an easier, softer way.
- H-He is uncomplicated, yeah.
- Mm-hmm.
And it so refreshing.
Oh. It is like diving into
a cold pool on a hot day.
Ah.
Am I hung up on Owen?
Sure.
Maybe I always will be.
But am I using Link?
No.
I'm just choosing
an easier path.
You might want
to try it.
♪ Say something,
I'm giving up on you ♪
♪ Say something ♪
Hey.
I was looking all over
for you.
Thought you might've
tried to postpone.
Can't just postpone
a job interview.
Yeah, I know.
But they could make
an exception, you know?
Because of
what happened today.
Oh, you mean 'cause I
screwed up so completely
that someone's dead?
Oh, yeah, sure, let me just
call up the hiring committee
and fill them in, Levi.
So, you think
you're in the best condition
to interview
for your dream job?
Just e-mail 'em, okay?
Then we can
get out of here.
No, you don't get it!
'Cause you let failure
hold you back your whole life.
It's basically
your entire identity.
But it's not mine.
So much of the world operates
without us
ever thinking about it.
Dr. Kim,
it's nice to see you.
Your application
is tremendously impressive.
Hey, Dr. Hogans,
thank you for making the time
to talk to me.
I've wanted to be a part of your
program since I...
...since I first, uh,
chose ortho as my specialty.
We expect it
to work out in our favor,
and, most of the time, it does.
Let's just go home,
order in.
I have to go to my place
and get some clean clothes.
I'm so tired,
I might just crash there.
Move in with me.
What?
I love you, Maggie.
I don't want
to take it for granted.
I don't want to miss it.
Yeah.
Move in with me.
We worry about the future
and think about the past.
Oh...
Okay.
Hey, come here.
Come here, come here,
come here.
Hey.
♪ Somewhere past tomorrow ♪
- ♪ Is better than it seems ♪
- Teddy. Look.
♪ Would like to ever dream ♪
- Okay.
- ♪ If you're ever broken... ♪
And we so often miss
what's right in front of us.
It's a tiny field outside Lake...
♪ Being told to show ♪
You were drinking at work?
♪ Tired... ♪
Jo, I'm done.
The field...
You hear me?
I'm done.
I need you to hear me.
I need you to talk to me.
- ♪ Know you're bound for glory ♪
- I love you, Jo. I love you, but I...
If you love me,
you will let me...
No, no, no, no, we're not
playing that game anymore.
We're not playing that "if you
love me, you'd leave me alone."
You went to Pittsburgh,
and we were good.
- Stop.
- We were good,
and then you come back,
and you won't talk to me,
and you're drinking at work.
Please.
So how about
I just go to Pittsburgh
and find out what the hell
happened to my wife?!
♪ So get up off your knees ♪
Huh?!
- ♪ Hope is still alive ♪
- We take what's good and easy
and working for granted...
♪ I know you'll find ♪
I will talk to you
when I'm ready to talk to you.
And if you ever threaten
to go to Pittsburgh again,
I will leave you.
Are we clear?
If you ever
come to work drunk again,
I'll tell Bailey.
Great.
We have a deal.
...until it's no longer good
and easy and working for us.
It's normal,
but we can do better
because there are tiny,
beautiful gifts
we're given every day.
Here we go.
So, the reason why
you saw Dr. DeLuca here
the other night
was because he and I have been
spending more time together.
Is he
your boyfriend?
He is.
What's that mean?
Well, that means
that I like him a lot.
Not more than you,
but a lot.
Are you gonna
kiss him?
Probably.
- Ew, gross!
- Oh, gross!
Is he gonna sleep on the couch again?
No, he won't be
sleeping on the couch,
but he may be coming around
a lot more, so...
But I'm not
going anywhere.
You're stuck with me.
Can he leave
his guitar at home?
And it's up to us to appreciate
them to the fullest
while we can.
Sync corrections by srjanapala