Why are you late? You're
not going to like the answer.
I already know the
answer. I missed the bus.
I don't doubt it. No
bus stops near Brad's.
You spent the night, the alarm
didn't work— or maybe it did.
I didn't sleep with him. Girl,
either there's something...
I missed the bus!
There's something either very wrong
with you or something very wrong with him.
There's nothing wrong with him.
Please tell me you know that for a fact.
Melanie, I gotta go.
You're lying, aren't you?
I wouldn't lie to you.
Good morning, guys!
Good morning, Miss Rebecca!
Everybody's in their seats? Yes.
Okay. Sydney, why don't you
tell us what you did this weekend?
She look—
Come on, Sydney.
We know you're not shy.
How come we always have to tell you what
we did, and you never tell us what you did?
Okay.
I had a really great weekend.
- But you can't tell
Miss Melanie, okay?
- What did you do?
I made a new friend.
It's so much fun to
make new friends, isn't it?
Yeah. Yeah.
Did you tell your mom and
dad about your new friend?
Absolutely.
You should never keep
anything from your parents.
And I told mine...
Wha— -
Ca— Ba...
Ha— Ba—Cra...
C—A— L...
H— E— "The!"
We know that word. "The."
Twenty-nine-year old female.
First seizure one month ago.
Lost the ability to speak.
Babbled like a baby.
Progressive deterioration
of mental status.
You see that? They all assume
I'm a patient because of this cane.
So put on a white coat like the rest of us.
I don't want them to think I'm a doctor.
You see where the administration
might have a problem with that attitude?
People don't want a sick doctor.
That's fair enough. I
don't like healthy patients.
The 29-year old female— The
one who can't talk? I like that part.
She's my cousin.
And your cousin
doesn't like the diagnosis.
I wouldn't either.
Brain tumor. She's
going to die. Boring.
No wonder you're such
a renowned diagnostician.
You don't need to actually know
anything to figure out what's wrong.
You're the oncologist. I'm just
a lowly infectious disease guy.
Yes. Just a simple
country doctor.
Brain tumors at her
age are highly unlikely.
She's 29. Whatever
she's got is highly unlikely.
The protein markers for the three most
prevalent brain cancers came up negative.
That's an H.M.O. lab.
Might as well have sent
it to a high school kid
with a chemistry set.
No family history.
I thought your
uncle died of cancer.
Other side. No environmental
factors. That you know of.
And she's not responding
to radiation treatment.
None of which is even
close to dispositive.
All it does is raise one question:
Your cousin goes to an H.M.O.?
Come on. Why leave all
the fun for the coroner?
What's the point of putting together
a team if you’re not gonna use them?
You've got three overqualified
doctors working for you, getting bored.
It's a lesion.
And the big green thing in the middle
of the bigger blue thing on a map...
is an island.
I was hoping for something
a bit more creative.
Shouldn't we be speaking to the
patient before we start diagnosing?
- Is she a doctor?
- No, but...
- Everybody lies.
- Dr. House doesn't like
dealing with patients.
Isn't treating patients
why we became doctors?
No. Treating illnesses is
why we became doctors.
Treating patients is what
makes most doctors miserable.
So you're trying to eliminate the
humanity from the practice of medicine?
If we don't talk to them, they can't
lie to us, and we can't lie to them.
Humanity's overrated.
- I don't think it's a tumor.
- First year medical school—if you hear
hoof beats, you think horses, not zebras.
Are you in first year
medical school?
No. First of all, there's
nothing on the CAT scan.
Second of all,
if this is a horse,
then her kindly family
doctor in Trenton makes the
obvious diagnosis, and it
never gets near this office.
Differential diagnosis, people.
If it's not a tumor, what are the
suspects? Why couldn't she talk?
Aneurysm, stroke or some
other ischemic syndrome.
- Get her a contrast M.R.I.
- Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease?
- Mad cow?
- Mad zebra.
Wernicke's encephalopathy.
No. Blood thiamine
level was normal.
The lab in Trenton could have
screwed up the blood tests.
I assume it's a corollary if
“people lie" that "people screw up."
Redraw the blood tests and get her
scheduled for that contrast M.R.I. ASAP.
Let's find out what kind of
zebra we're treating here.
Radiology, please call the page.
I was expecting you in
my office 20 minutes ago.
Really? Well, that's
odd because I had no
intention of being in your
office 20 minutes ago.
You think we have
nothing to talk about? No. I
just can't think of
anything I'd be interested in.
I sign your paychecks.
I have tenure.
Are you gonna grab my cane now, stop
me from leaving? That would be juvenile.
I can still fire you if you're not doing
your job. I'm here from 9:00 to 5:00.
Your billings are practically
nonexistent. Rough year.
You ignore requests for consults.
I call back. Sometimes I misdial.
You're six years behind on
your obligations to the clinic.
See? I was right. This
doesn't interest me.
Six years times three weeks—
You owe me better than four months.
It's 5:00. I'm going home.
To what?
Nice.
Look, Dr. House, the only
reason why I don't fire you...
is because your reputation is still
worth something to this hospital.
Excellent. We have a point of
agreement— You're not gonna fire me.
Your reputation won't
last if you don't do your job.
The clinic is part of your
job. I want you to do your job.
But, as the philosopher Jagger once
said, "You can't always get what you want."
You're not my doctor.
Are you Dr. House?
Thankfully, no. I'm Dr. Chase.
Dr. House is the head
of diagnostic medicine.
He's very busy, but he has
taken a keen interest in your case.
We inject
gadolinium into a vein.
It distributes itself throughout
your brain and acts as
a contrast material for the
magnetic resonance imager.
Basically, whatever's in your
head lights up like a Christmas tree.
- It might make you feel
a little light-headed.
- Dr. Cameron.
I'm sorry. I have to stop
you. There is a problem.
You pulled my authorization!
Yes. Why are you yelling?
No M.R.I.'s, no
imaging studies, no labs.
You also can't make
long distance phone calls.
- If you're going to fire me,
have the guts to face me.
- Or photocopies. You're still yelling.
I'm angry! You're
risking a patient's life.
- I assume those are two separate points.
- You showed me disrespect.
You embarrassed me. And as long
as I work here, you have no legal...
Is the yelling
designed to scare me?
Because I'm not sure what it is I'm
supposed to be scared of. More yelling?
That's not scary.
That you're going to hurt me? That's scary.
But I'm pretty sure I can outrun you.
Oh, I looked into that
philosopher you quoted—Jagger.
And you’re right, you can't
always get what you want.
But as it turns out, "If you try
sometimes, you get what you need."
So, because you want
me to treat patients,
you're not letting
me treat patients?
I need you to do your job.
Do the M.R.I. She folded.
I've got to do four
hours a week in this
clinic until I make up
the time I've missed.
2054. I'll be caught up in 2054.
You better love this
cousin a whole lot.
All right, Rebecca, I know you may
feel a little claustrophobic in there,
but we need you to remain still.
Okay, we're going to begin.
I don't feel so good.
It's all right.
Just try to relax.
Rebecca?
Get her out of there. Oh,
she probably fell asleep.
She's exhausted. She was
claustrophobic 30 seconds ago.
She's not sleeping. We
gotta get her out of there.
It'll just be another minute.
If she's having an
allergic reaction to the
gadolinium, she'll be
dead in two minutes.
Hold her neck. All right.
Oh, she's ashen.
She's not breathing. Epi.5.
Come on.
I can't ventilate.
Too much edema. Where's
the surgical airway kit?
Yep. Coming.
Good call.
We'll get that tube out
of your throat later today.
Just get some
rest for now, okay?
Told you. You
can't trust people.
She probably knew she
was allergic to gadolinium.
Figured it was an easy way to get
someone to cut a hole in her throat.
Can't get a picture. Gonna
have to get a thousand words.
You actually want me to talk
to the patient, get a history?
We need to know if there's
some genetic or environmental
cause that's triggering
an inflammatory response.
I thought everybody lied.
Truth begins in lies.
Think about it.
That doesn't mean
anything, does it?
12:52 p.m. Dr. House checks
in. Please write that down.
Do you have cable
TV here somewhere?
General Hospital
starts in eight minutes.
No TV, but we've got patients.
Can't you give out the aspirin
yourself? I'll do paperwork.
I made sure your first case was an
interesting one. Cough just won't go away?
Runny nose looks a funny color? Patient
admitted complaining of back spasms.
Oh? I think I read about
something like that in the
New England Journal of
Medicine. Patient is orange.
The color? No, the fruit.
You mean yellow. It's
jaundice. I mean orange.
Well, how orange? It's
probably— Exam room one.
Dr. Kahn, you're
needed in pediatrics.
I was playing golf and my cleats got stuck.
It hurt a little, but I kept playing.
The next morning, I
could barely stand up.
Well, you're smiling, so I take
it that means this isn't serious.
What's that? What are you doing?
Painkillers.
Oh, for you. For your leg.
No, 'cause they're yummy.
You want one? Make
your back feel better.
Unfortunately, you
have a deeper problem.
Your wife is having an affair.
- What?
- You're orange, you moron.
It's one thing for
you not to notice,
but if your wife hasn't
picked up on the fact that her
husband has changed colors,
she's just not paying attention.
By the way, do you
consume just a ridiculous
amount of carrots
and megados vitamins?
Carrots turn you yellow,
the niacin turns you
red. Find some finger
paint and do the math.
And get a good lawyer.
Deep breath.
It's cold.
He's been using his inhaler?
Not in the past few
days. He's, um, only 10.
I worry about children taking
such strong medicine so frequently.
What happened to your leg?
Your doctor probably was concerned
about the strength of the medicine too.
She probably weighed that danger
against the danger of not breathing.
Oxygen is so important during those
prepubescent years. Don't you think?
Okay, I'm gonna assume nobody
has ever told you what asthma is.
Or if they have, you had
other things on your mind.
A stimulant triggers cells
in your child's airways...
to release substances that inflame the
air passages and cause them to contract.
Mucus production increases,
the cell lining starts to shed.
But the steroids— -
the steroids stop
the inflammation.
The more often this happens...
What? The more often
this happens, what?
Forget it. If you don't trust
steroids, you shouldn't trust doctors.
My mother passed
away four years ago.
She had a heart attack, and my father
broke his back doing construction...
♪♪
It's House. It's
urgent. I'm sorry.
You couldn't have knocked?
Steroids. Give her steroids.
High doses of prednisone.
You're looking for support for a
diagnosis of cerebral vasculitis?
Inflammation of blood
vessels in the brain is
awfully rare, especially
for someone her age.
- So is a tumor. Her sed rate is elevated.
- Mildly.
That could mean
anything. Or nothing.
Yeah, I know. I have no
reason to think that it's vasculitis.
Except that it could be.
If the blood vessels are
inflamed, that's gonna look
exactly like what we saw on
the M.R.I. from Trenton County,
and the pressure is gonna
cause neurological symptoms.
- We can't diagnose that without a biopsy.
- Yes, we can.
We treat her. If she gets
better, we know we're right.
- And if we're wrong?
- Then we learn something else.
Why steroids?
Just part of your treatment.
You haven't had many visitors.
No boyfriend? Three dates.
I wouldn't have stood by
him if he were vomiting all day.
What about work? You
must have friends from work.
Pretty much everybody
I like is five years old.
The nurse said you're
stopping my radiation.
We're just trying some
alternative medication.
So where's your family from then? Steroids
aren't an alternative to radiation.
The tests weren't
really conclusive.
We're treating
you for vasculitis.
It's the inflammation of
blood vessels in the brain.
I-It's not a tumor?
I don't have a tumor?
You should have told her the
truth— It's a long shot guess.
Thank you. If House
is right, no harm.
If he's wrong, I've given a dying
woman a couple days' hope.
False hope. If there was any other type
available, I would have given her that.
Why are you
smelling Billy's pants?
I'm not. Looked like you were.
- I was smelling the floor.
- Oh.
Do you have any
pets in this class?
No. But we used to have a gerbil,
but Carly L. dropped a book on it.
Careless.
- Do you need to smell it?
- No. I'm smelling for mold.
I don't need to smell it.
You could smell our parrot.
You said you didn't have
any pets in this class.
A parrot is a bird.
Listen, Jackson's
not the father...
Parrots are the primary
source of psittacosis.
It's not the parrot.
And psittacosis can lead to nerve
problems and neurological complications.
How many kids were
in the class? Twenty.
How many are home
sick? None, but...
None. But you figured
that five-year-olds are more
serious about bird
hygiene than their teacher?
Have you been through her
home? She lives in Trenton.
I can go up to her room tomorrow
morning, ask her for the key.
Would the police call for permission before
dropping by to check out a crime scene?
It's not a crime scene.
As far as I know,
she's running a meth
lab out of her basement.
She's a kindergarten
teacher. And if I were a
kindergarten student I
would trust her implicitly.
Okay. I'll give you
a "for instance."
The lady back there...
who made your egg
salad sandwich...
Her eyes look glassy.
Did you notice that?
Now, hospital policy is
to stay home if you’re sick.
But if you're making $8.00 an hour, then
you kind of need the $8.00 an hour, right?
And the sign in the
bathroom says that
employees must wash
after using the facilities,
but I figure that somebody
who wipes snot on a sleeve
isn't hyper concerned
about sanitary conditions.
So what do you think—
Should I trust her?
I want you to check the patient's home
for contaminants, garbage, medication.
I can't just break
into someone's house.
Isn't that how you got
into the Felkers' home?
Yeah, I know.
Court records are sealed. You
were 16. It was a stupid mistake.
But your old gym teacher has a big
mouth. Should write a thank-you note.
- I should thank him?
- Well...
I needed somebody around
here with street smarts.
Okay? Who knows when they're
being conned, knows how to con.
I should sue you.
Pretty sure you can't sue
somebody for wrongful hiring.
But I'm pretty sure I can sue if you fire
me for not breaking into some lady's house.
Doing research. People
are fascinating, aren't they?
Why are you giving
Adler steroids?
Because she's my patient. That's what you
do with patients— you give them medicine.
You don't prescribe
medicine based on guesses.
At least we don't since
Tuskegee and Mengele.
You're comparing
me to a Nazi? Nice.
I'm stopping the treatment.
She's my patient.
It's my hospital.
I did not get her sick.
She is not an experiment.
I have a legitimate
theory about what's
wrong with her.
With no proof.
There's never any proof.
Five different doctors
come up with five
different diagnoses based
on the same evidence.
You don't have any evidence.
And nobody knows anything, huh? Then
how is it you always think you're right?
I don't. I just find it hard to
operate on the opposite assumption.
And why are you so
afraid of making a mistake?
Because I'm a doctor. Because
when we make mistakes, people die.
Oh, come on.
People used to have more
respect for cripples, you know.
They didn't really.
So how you feeling?
Much better, thanks.
Are you Dr. House? I
thought he was a he, but—
No.
Don't eat too much, too fast.
Thank him for me.
Right.
Should I discontinue
the treatment, boss?
You got lucky.
Cool, huh?
Okay, once again.
Good.
Am I ever gonna meet Dr. House?
Well, you might run into him
at the movies or on the bus.
Is he a good man?
He's a good doctor.
Can you be one
without the other?
Don't you have to care about
people? Caring is a good motivator.
He's found something else.
Feel this, both sides?
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Okay, squeeze.
Harder. All right.
He's your friend, huh?
Yeah.
Does he care about you?
I think so. You don't know?
As Dr. House likes to
say, "Everybody lies."
It's not what people
say. It's what they do.
Yeah. He cares about me.
I can't see.
I can't... see.
A little help in here!
Your chest will
be sore for a while.
We needed to shock you
to get your heart going.
Okay, can you arrange
these to tell a story?
She couldn't put them in order.
Could the damage have been caused
by a lack of oxygen during her seizure?
No. I gave her the same test
five minutes later. She did just fine.
The altered mental status is
intermittent, just like the verbal skills.
So what now?
Given the latest symptoms, it's clearly
growing deeper into the brain stem.
Soon, she won't be able to walk.
She'll go blind permanently, and
then the respiratory center will fail.
How long do we have?
If it's a tumor, we're talking a month
or two. If it's infectious, a few weeks.
If it's vascular, that'll probably
be fastest of all. Maybe a week.
We're gonna stop all treatment.
I still think it's a tumor. I think
we should go back to the radiation.
She didn't respond
to the radiation.
Well, maybe we didn't
see the effect until
after we started steroids.
No, it's not a tumor.
Those steroids did something.
I just don't know what.
So we're just gonna do nothing?
We're just gonna watch her die?
Yeah, we're gonna
watch her die. Specifically,
we're gonna watch
how fast she's dying.
You just told us— Each
diagnosis has its own time frame.
When we see how fast it's
killing her, we'll know what it is.
And by then, maybe there's
nothing we can do about it.
There's got to be
something we can do.
Something better
than watching her die.
Well, I got nothing.
How about you?
Bastard.
Oh, Cameron. I need you for
a couple of hours. What's up?
When you break into
someone's house, it's better
to have a white chick
with you. Adler's house?
Why don't we just ask
her for her keys? For all we
know, she'll be running a
meth lab out of her basement.
I'm tired a lot.
Any other reason why you think you
might have chronic fatigue syndrome?
It's kind of the
definition, isn't it?
definition of getting older.
I had a couple headaches
last month, a mild fever.
Sometimes I can't sleep, and
I have trouble concentrating.
Apparently not while researching
this stuff on the Internet.
I was thinking it also
might be fibromyalgia.
Excellent diagnosis.
Is there anything for that?
You know, I think
there just might be.
I need 36 Vicodin
and change for a dollar.
Exam room two.
House doesn't
believe in pretense.
Figures life's too short and too
painful. So he just says what he thinks.
Nothing interesting
in the garbage.
"I say what I think" is just another
way of saying "I'm an assho"...
Well, if you wanted to be judged
for your medical prowess only,
maybe you shouldn't have
broken into someone's home.
I was 16.
Don't know about ticks, but
her dog's definitely got fleas.
I managed to make it to
17 without a criminal record.
Yeah?
Well, you obviously didn't
grow up in my neighborhood.
That's right. You stole a loaf of bread
to feed your starving family. Right?
You always eat during break-ins?
Am I supposed to respect their food
more than I respect their DVD players?
You want some? No.
You gonna go
hungry until she dies?
No. You know what?
After centuries of slavery,
decades of civil rights marches...
and, more significantly, living like a
monk, never getting less than a 4.0 G.P.A.,
you don't think it's kind
of disgusting I get one of
the top jobs in the country
because I'm a delinquent?
We'll eat, then we'll
tear up the carpet.
You went to Hopkins, right?
Yep.
So you went to a better school than I
did. You got better grades than I did.
So how did you get the job?
You stab a guy in a bar fight?
Nothing.
It's not a tumor. She's
getting worse too fast.
- She can't stand up.
- No toxins? No medications?
Nothing that would
explain these symptoms.
Family history of
neurological problems?
Not that I could tell from
her underwear drawer.
You said "nothing that would
explain these symptoms."
What did you find that doesn't
explain these symptoms?
Dr. Wilson convinced you to treat
this patient under false pretenses.
Adler's not his cousin.
That's ridiculous. Ask her
yourself. Can we get ba...
- She's not Jewish.
- Rachel Adler's not Jewish?
I had ham at her apartment.
Dr. Foreman, a lot of
Jews have non-Jewish
relatives, and most of
us don't keep kosher.
I can see getting through
high school without
learning a thing about
Jews, but medical school?
Okay, maybe she’s Jewish, but
she's definitely not your cousin.
Really? This guy is—
You don't even know her name. You
called her Rachel. Her name is Rebecca.
Yes. Yes, her name is Rebecca.
I-I call her Rachel.
You idiot! Listen, he's...
Not you. Him.
- You said you didn't find anything.
- Everything I found was in my...
- You found ham.
- So?
Where there's ham, there's pork.
Where there's pork,
there's neurocysticercosis.
Tapeworm? You think
she's got a worm in her brain?
It fits. Could have been living there
for years. Never occurred to me that...
Millions of people eat
ham every day. It's quite
a leap to think that's
she's got a tapeworm.
Okay, Mr. Neurologist,
what happens when you
give steroids to a person
who has a tapeworm?
They— They get a little better,
and— and then they get worse.
Just like Rebecca Adler did.
In a typical case, if you
don't cook pork well enough,
you digest live tapeworm larvae.
They've got these little hooks,
they grab onto your bowel, they
live, they grow up, they reproduce.
Reproduce? There's only one
lesion, and it's nowhere near her bowel.
That's because this
is not a typical case.
Tapeworm can produce
20,000 to 30,000 eggs a day.
Guess where they go? Out.
Not all of them.
Unlike the larvae, the
egg can pass right through
the walls of the intestines
into the bloodstream.
And where does the
bloodstream go? Everywhere.
As long as it's healthy, the immune
system doesn't even know it's there.
The worm builds a wall,
uses secretions to shut down
the body's immune
response and control fluid flow.
It's really very beautiful.
As long as it's healthy.
So what do we do?
Call a vet, nurse the
little guy back to health?
It's too late for
that. It's dying.
And as it dies, this parasite loses the
ability to control the host's defenses.
The immune system wakes up, attacks
the worm, and everything starts to swell.
And that is very
bad for the brain.
It could still be a
hundred other things.
The eosinophil count was normal.
- It's only abnormal in 30% of cases.
- Proving nothing.
No, no, no, no. It— Don't you see? It
fits. It's perfect. It explains everything.
- But it proves nothing.
- I can prove it by treating it.
No, you can't.
I was just with her. She doesn't
want any more treatments.
She doesn't want any more experiments.
She wants to go home and die.
Would you excuse us, please?
I'm Dr. House.
It's good to meet you.
You're being an idiot.
You have a
tapeworm in your brain.
It's not pleasant, but if we don't do
anything, you'll be dead by the weekend.
Have you actually seen the worm?
When you're all better,
I'll show you my diplomas.
You were sure I
had vasculitis too.
Now I can't walk and
I'm wearing a diaper.
What's this treatment
gonna do for me?
I'm not talking about a
treatment. I'm talking about a cure.
But because I might be
wrong, you want to die.
What made you a cripple?
I had an infarction.
A heart attack?
It's what happens when
blood flow is obstructed.
If it's in the heart,
it's a heart attack. If
it's in the lungs, it's a
pulmonary embolism.
If it's in the brain, it's a stroke.
I had it in my thigh muscles.
Wasn't there something
they could do?
There was plenty they could do,
if they'd made the right diagnosis.
But the only symptom was pain.
Not many people get to
experience muscle death.
Did you think you were dying?
I hoped I was dying.
So you hide in your office,
refuse to see patients...
because you don't like
the way people look at you.
You feel cheated by life, so now
you're gonna get even with the world.
But you want me to fight this.
Why?
What makes you think I'm
so much better than you?
What, you're scared
you'll turn into me?
I just want to die
with a little dignity.
There's no such thing.
Our bodies break down. Sometimes when
we're 90. Sometimes before we're even born.
But it always happens, and
there's never any dignity in it.
I don't care if you can walk, see, wipe
your own ass. It's always ugly. Always.
We can live with dignity.
We can't die with it.
No treatment.
Maybe we can get a court
order, uh, override her wishes,
claim she doesn't have the
capacity to make this decision.
But she does.
But we could claim that the illness
made her mentally incompetent, right?
A pretty common result.
That didn't happen here.
He's not gonna do it. She's
not just a file to him anymore.
He respects her.
So because you respect
her, you're going to let her die?
I solved the case.
My work is done.
Patients always want proof.
We're not making cars here.
We don't give guarantees.
I think we can
prove it's a worm.
It's noninvasive. It's safe.
I'm not completely sure, but— Yeah,
yeah, yeah. What's the damn idea?
Have you ever seen a
worm under an X-ray?
A regular, old, no-contrast,
hundred-year-old-technology X-ray?
They light up like shotgun
pellets, just like on a contrast M.R.I.
Which is the same thing as a CT
scan, which we did, which proved nothing.
The worm's cyst is the same
density as the cerebrospinal fluid.
We're not gonna see
anything in her head.
But Chase is right. He's
right. We should X-ray her.
But we don't X-ray her
brain. We X-ray her leg.
Worms love thigh muscle.
If she's got one in her
head, I guarantee you
there's one in her leg.
Hold still, Rebecca.
This here...
is a worm larva.
So, if it's in my
leg, it's in my brain?
Are you looking for a guarantee?
It's there. Probably
been there six to 10 years.
- Do I have more?
- Probably.
It's good news.
- What do we do now?
- Now we get you better.
Albendazole.
- Two pills?
- Yeah. Every day,
for at least a month, with a meal.
- Two pills?
- Yeah.
Possible side effects
include abdominal
pain, nausea, headaches,
dizziness, fever...
and hair loss.
We'll probably make you keep taking the
pills even if you get every one of those.
Why did you hire me?
- Does it matter?
- Kinda hard to work for a guy
who doesn't respect you.
- Why?
- Is that rhetorical?
No. It just seems that way
'cause you can't think of an answer.
Does it make a
difference what I think?
I'm a jerk. The only thing that matters
is what you think. Can you do the job?
You hired a black guy because
he had a juvenile record. No.
It wasn't a racial thing.
I didn't see a black guy.
I just saw a doctor...
with a juvenile record.
I hired Chase 'cause his
dad made a phone call.
I hired you...
because you are
extremely pretty.
You hired me to get into my pants? I
can't believe that that would shock you.
It's also not what I said.
No, I hired you
because you look good.
It's like having a nice
piece of art in the lobby.
- I was in the top of my class.
- But not the top.
I did an internship at the Mayo Clinic.
Yeah. You were a very good applicant.
But not the best. Would
that upset you? Really?
To think that you were hired
because of some genetic gift
of beauty instead of some
genetic gift of intelligence?
I worked very hard
to get where I am.
But you didn't have to.
People choose the
paths that gain them the
greatest rewards for
the least amount of effort.
That's a law of nature, and you
defied it. That's why I hired you.
You could have married rich.
You could have been a model.
You could have just shown up and people
would have given you stuff. Lots of stuff.
But you didn't. You worked
your stunning little ass off.
Am I supposed to be flattered?
Gorgeous women do
not go to medical school...
unless they're as damaged
as they are beautiful.
Were you abused
by a family member?
- No.
- Sexually assaulted?
No!
But you are damaged, aren't you?
♪♪
I have to go.
I followed her.
- Oh.
- I couldn't stop thinking
about what that doctor said.
I told you not to listen
to him. He's an idiot.
I was orange!
- I don't want to know what you found out.
- You don't care?
I'm your doctor.
You've been good to me and good
to this hospital. Of course I care.
But I don't see how this
conversation can end well for me.
Either your wife is having an
affair, or she's not having an affair,
and you have come here because
you rightly think I should fire him.
But I can't. Even if it
costs me your money.
The son of a bitch is
the best doctor we have.
Feeling any better?
I can't complain.
As you know, the
hospital has certain rules.
And as you also know,
we tend to ignore them.
But I think this one's gonna be a
little obvious unless we get your help.
If anyone asks, you have 1
1 daughters and five sons.
Hi! Look who's here!
It's so good to see
you guys. I missed you.
Is this for me?
It's beautiful.
Oh, I love you guys.
I wanted to thank Dr. House,
but he never visited again.
He cured you.
You didn't cure him.
Okay, I want a hug and a kiss from every
single one of you! Get up here right now!
- There.
- Hold on.
She's converted.
You said she was your cousin.
Why would you lie?
It got you to take the case.
You lied to a friend to save a stranger.
You don't think that's kind of screwed up?
You've never lied to me?
I never lie.
Oh. Right.
- Why do we do this?
- Because we're doctors.
If we make mistakes, people die.
Dr. House?
You have a patient.
He says he needs a refill.
Got change for a dollar?
That's some bad hat, Harry.