- Previously on The Resident...
- Dr. Shaw says that some people
have to do this
three days a week,
- four hours a session?
- We're doing a workup
to see if your kidney
failure's reversible.
And my kidneys will get better.
Right?
No reason not to be optimistic.
It's not about being fair.
It's about being honest.
I was a project for you,
and now it's finished.
The same issues
keep coming up
over and over again.
Still a lot we
need to talk about.
Tomorrow? My place?
I'll swing by before work.
Hey.
Looks like we're
finally doing this.
Looks like it.
You first?
Oh. Okay.
Have you ever woke up
in the middle of the night
and finally realized something
you've never understood before?
Uh... I guess.
I mean, not often, but yeah.
I'm built to keep
moving forward.
If there's a
mountain, I'll climb it.
If there's a race, I'll run it.
But what I don't do is
stay in the same place.
And that's what you
think we're doing.
I think...
I think I want something
you don't want.
Movement towards our future.
I'd marry you, Nic.
But I don't ask
because you don't even
want to live together.
Why are you putting all
this pressure on me now?
Why is making more of a
commitment to me a burden?
I am here to help.
That should be a relief.
I have been taking care
of everybody around me
since I was 13 years old.
I just... I learned to
take care of myself.
You know what I think?
Holding up the world
has become your cross.
Okay. If this is gonna become
a litany of what you
think are my faults,
- I just... I can't.
- No. That's not what's going on.
I'm putting down boundaries.
Can't go forward
if we don't have
the same level of
commitment, and we don't.
You know what this feels like?
Emotional blackmail.
I don't move in with
you, so you just leave me.
Telling you what I want
is emotional blackmail?
Yeah, that's what
this feels like.
Okay, well, then we see
this completely differently.
Yeah, I think we do.
If you're not interested
in going forward,
for me, it's time to
take a step back.
- If that's what you want.
- It's not what I want.
When I go home
at night, no matter
what's going on in my
life, I want you there.
You don't feel the
same. That's the problem.
Conrad.
It's...
Come on.
At work, we go back to
what we always were: friends.
Colleagues.
Sure.
That's a given.
♪ Look at all this heartache ♪
♪ What is left? ♪
♪ Forgetting how it started ♪
♪ This is how it ends ♪
♪ Oh, no ♪
♪ I know I've done some wrong ♪
♪ I'll pay for it ♪
♪ But it's your turn to talk ♪
♪ For once I'm listening ♪
♪ Say that you don't want me ♪
♪ Say that you don't need me ♪
♪ Tell me I'm the fool ♪
♪ Tell me you've been tortured ♪
♪ Tell me you've been beaten
and what I've done to you ♪
♪ Even if it doesn't matter ♪
♪ Matter what's true ♪
♪ Tell me that I'm unknown ♪
♪ To you ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Say that you don't want me ♪
♪ Say that you don't need me ♪
♪ Tell me I'm the fool ♪
♪ Tell me that I'm unknown. ♪
Help! Help!
- Sir, you all right?
- I'm okay.
- Help!
- Help! Help! My wife! My son!
- Somebody call 911!
Help my wife, my son!
Please, my wife, my son!
- Help! Help, please!
- Okay, go to my son! Go to my son!
- He's hurt, he's hurt! Honey!
- Please help!
Danny! It's okay.
- Honey, just put
pressure, please.
- Help me!
- Please, I need
both hands, okay? Okay?
- Please help me.
- Honey, I love you. I love you. Just try to stay with me.
- Please!
- Danny, stay with us!
- I'll be right there.
- Please.
- My mom.
- Honey. Danny!
Honey, please, just...
You got to put pressure.
Keep it. Keep it.
Danny?! Danny?!
♪ ♪
Uh, Chastain Base
Station. Go ahead.
On scene with two
level-1 traumas.
MVC with significant
passenger-side intrusion.
In the process of
extricating an adult female
and teenage male
with critical injuries,
including a GSW.
Up. A level-1 trauma, incoming.
I was really hoping
nobody came in with
holes in them today.
Move to Japan. Ten
gun deaths a year.
- We get that every month.
- We're just one hospital.
- In one city.
- In one state.
It's completely senseless.
Tokyo Medical Center.
I'll put in a good word.
Hey, I'll take it, bro.
Hawkins, hang on. Two
incoming level-1 traumas.
37-year-old female. Hypotensive.
Intubated en route
for respiratory distress.
GSW to the chest.
All right, Feldman,
Okafor, with me
and the GSW in Bay Nine.
- What happened?
- I saw the shooting. I was right behind them.
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
Patient two, same accident.
14-year-old male,
extricated from the backseat,
- open femur fracture.
- Hawkins, Pravesh and Vosh
with the femur fracture in Ten.
If you were a witness, they're
gonna want to speak with you.
ABCs. Let's call them out.
I'm Dr. Pravesh. Buddy,
what's your name?
Dan... Danny.
- Airway intact.
- Bilateral breath sounds.
Danny, do you
know where you are?
The hospital. My mom!
She's in good hands.
Pulse is 130. Blood
pressure 100/60.
Let's bolus two liters IV fluids
- and send off a type and cross.
- Now his leg.
Checking the pulse.
There's no blood flow
to the distal extremity.
Fracture must be
compressing his blood supply.
We need to reduce it here
and get him into traction.
Danny, on a scale of one to ten,
can you tell me your pain level?
Zero.
In three, two, one.
It looks arterial. Tourniquet.
Get two units of
blood down here now.
The broken femur must have been
helping to tamponade the bleed.
All right, time to figure
out why Danny has no pain.
Okay. Look for other injuries.
Danny, we're gonna
turn you over now, okay?
One, two, three.
He's been shot, too.
Possible spine injury.
We need to get him to CT now.
Damn it.
Pressure's dropping fast.
The bullet punctured her heart.
- Let's redline her to the OR.
- No, she'd be dead
before we get
to the third floor.
Emergency thoracotomy,
right here, right now.
Okafor, let's get it.
Okay, give us space, people.
Cutting the pericardium,
exposing the heart.
There's the bullet hole
Put your finger on it!
Defect in the left atrium.
Pressure's holding.
Good. Let's get
her to the OR, stat.
Mina, do not move your
finger till we get upstairs.
I know that.
I'm sorry transport hasn't come.
It's been a little
crazy down here.
Let's check in on the baby.
How you feeling, Mrs. Davies?
Oh, the pain is really bad.
You know, I was
gonna go natural,
but an epidural's starting
to look really golden.
That can be arranged
when we get you upstairs.
What is it?
Baby's heart rate isn't
quite where we'd like it to be.
- Uh, what does that mean?
- It means we're
going up right now.
Get your bag.
Hundley, call Dr. Stewart.
She may need an
emergency C-section.
- Okay.
- It's all right, honey.
- Don't you worry
about this, okay?
- All right.
Everything is gonna
be fine. Don't worry.
You know, once the science
fair is over, I say we hit up
the Natural History Museum.
Oh, I'd rather
visit the aquarium.
If I lose, I don't
want to do anything
but sit in the hotel
room, eat pizza and sulk.
We can beat this traffic if
we go straight and turn later.
Being late is not an option.
Trust me, guys. I got this.
Okay.
See? Cruising now.
What is this lady doing?
If I had just stayed in traffic.
If I... if I'd just
waited for the turn.
- This isn't your fault.
- Well, whose fault is it?
Who shot us?
The cops think the shooter
was targeting someone else,
so it was just the wrong
place at the wrong time.
I feel so helpless, you know?
Look at me.
I'm-I'm sitting here,
there's barely a
scratch on me, and my...
My wife and my son
might not survive.
They are with our very best,
most experienced
surgeons right now.
I promise, we will do
everything that we can.
Let's get her on the table.
Okafor, keep your finger
on the hole in her heart.
Drape the patient.
Betadine prep.
One, two, three.
♪ ♪
Have you ever seen
a purse string suture
performed before, Okafor?
Of course. Do it fast.
I can only keep pressure
for so much longer.
It's one of medicine's
most rudimentary,
yet lifesaving procedures.
Less narration, more action.
Suction.
All right.
Now, you take a deep breath.
And hold it...
and don't you move a muscle.
Okay, three is the
magic number, Okafor.
You hear me?
One, two, three.
Bravo. Muy, muy bravo -
if I say so myself.
All right, let's check.
Is there any other
obvious damage?
No. Looks like the
bullet made a clean exit
without damaging
the other organs.
- Good.
- Yeah. That's probably
the only lucky thing to
happen to this woman today.
All right, well, you close up,
take her to CT, make sure
we didn't miss anything.
Dr. Pravesh is
going to assist me.
He asked to scrub in. We're
shorthanded today, so...
I hope that's okay
with you both.
Of course. It is a good thing
you came in when you did.
All right. Dr. Pravesh, have
you delivered a baby before?
Um, nope. This'll be my first.
Then you are in for a treat.
I've delivered thousands,
and, uh, every one
is as special as the first.
All right, seconds away.
Ah. Um...
how long have you
been in the U.S.?
My entire life. I
was born in Jersey.
Oh. Well, good for you.
We ready?
All right. Here we go.
Ten blade.
Thank you.
All right, thank you.
Just relax, honey.
You're doing great, beautiful.
Hey, give me fundal pressure.
Little more.
Head.
- Okay.
- The doctors are
doing a great job.
Just relax.
Get under here.
There we go.
Okay.
- She's okay?
- Yeah.
Congratulations. She's perfect.
Oh. Oh, sweet baby.
Aw.
Lea, honey, we got lucky.
She looks just like you.
Oh, welcome to the
world, sweet Fiona.
Yeah.
You have a minute?
Uh, yeah.
Any results from Danny's CT?
It's happening now.
How's his dad?
I mean...
second-guessing every
moment that happened before,
everything...
that he could have done
differently to avoid it.
Yeah, imagine.
Could've been me.
Nic?
What do you mean?
I was upset after this morning,
so I pulled over.
They passed in front of me...
and then it happened.
Should've been me.
Wow.
I'm so glad you're okay.
- It's awful.
- Anyway, um...
you had something to tell me?
I wish it could wait, but...
Jessie.
Her kidneys aren't
getting any better, Nic.
So...
we keep her on
dialysis for a while.
They will never recover.
She's been off dialysis for
two days. She's still anuric.
Her B.U.N. and creatinine
levels are climbing,
as well as her potassium.
Have you told her?
No. I knew you'd
want to be there.
Well, let's tell her together.
Nic told me they're
visiting from Tennessee.
They were on their way
to Danny's science fair.
I hope the scan shows
us something we can fix.
The bullet entered the
spinal canal at L2-L3.
Explains his loss of
feeling at the waist.
Now it's here, at L5-S1.
The bullet is migrating.
Could cause permanent
damage if we don't take it out.
There's a traumatic liver
laceration from the accident.
That I can fix.
Good.
The question is...
will this poor boy
ever walk again?
So...
so my kidneys will
never work again?
Are you sure?
The drug trial did
irreversible damage.
You have to stay on dialysis.
Okay.
Okay. For how long?
The rest of your life, Jess.
No. What? That's...
that's not possible.
H-How will I-how
will I ever get a job
or go back to school?
There's no way.
That's no life at all.
Come on, there's got
to be another option.
There is one.
A kidney transplant.
But for now,
you're not eligible to be
listed through Chastain.
They're not gonna put
you on the transplant list
directly from rehab.
You just have to be sober
for at least six months.
And once those six months
are up, we can start the process.
Just go, please. Just go.
Jess.
Just leave me alone, okay?
I'm so sorry.
We're gonna figure it out.
You know, in six months,
if she gets on a
transplant list...
there's still a
three-to five-year wait.
Not if I'm a match.
You'd donate a kidney?
Of course I would.
She's my sister.
Okay. Just keep in mind,
if she relapses...
the drugs could
damage her new kidney.
Well, I choose to believe
that this is a wake-up call,
and she won't
relapse ever again.
Something to keep in mind:
why are you first
in the donor line?
Sacrificed so much for Jessie.
Maybe your dad
steps up this time.
We can't even count on
Kyle for a birthday card.
A kidney transplant?
Not a chance.
Nic, I know we have
new boundaries...
but I am here for you.
Thank you.
You nervous?
I am, actually.
It's rare for me.
But one slip of the hand,
and that poor boy
will never walk again.
I like his chances
in your hands.
How many bullets have you
cut out of healthy young men?
Too many to count.
- You?
- Same.
My daughter Amelia
did a science fair.
Some silliness with
plants and chlorophyll.
Placed dead last.
I was still a proud mum.
Fond memories, because
we were lucky enough
to make it to the fair.
A bullet from a random shooting,
nothing to do with
us, out of nowhere,
didn't rip through our
bodies and send us to an OR.
They were in the wrong
place at the wrong time.
Very unlucky.
Luckily, he's with us now.
♪ ♪
Beautiful, huh?
Nothing better in the world.
Thank you, Dr. Pravesh.
For everything.
My pleasure.
Just checking in on you guys.
Hey. Dr. Stewart?
Dr. Stewart, hey.
Glad I caught you.
I was just in the Davies' room,
and I noticed some
blood in Lea's catheter.
Yeah. She just had
major abdominal surgery.
Some bleeding's normal.
Yeah, I-I get that.
But would you mind checking
on her, just to be sure?
I appreciate your
concern, Dr. Pravesh.
I have delivered
thousands of babies,
and I have seen every
postpartum problem there is.
So leave my patients to me. Hmm?
Okay, almost done.
Now for the really scary part
of the surgery. Are you ready?
As I'll ever be.
And...
and done.
Spine's all yours.
Okay.
Help me get access for
an anterior
approach to the spine.
Another first.
- It's psychosomatic.
- No way.
You're putting yourself in the
place of the patient's mother.
It's very human of you, but,
Kit, in here, you're a doctor,
and a damn good one.
So just channel your normal
bravado, pull yourself together,
and fix this kid's spine
so he can walk again.
Right. Sorry.
There you go.
She's so cute.
How long until she speaks?
Hey.
She got to learn how
to hold her head up first.
- Where's Mommy?
- Right here.
Say hi to your amazing mama.
Hey, darling.
When are you gonna
come home, Mommy?
Soon. Soon.
You go ahead and
be a good little girl
for your grandma, okay?
You okay?
Something hurt?
- Yeah, my stomach.
- Okay.
Hey, Rachel, Daddy's gonna
call you back, okay, sweetie?
- Okay.
- Love you.
Here.
Hey, hey. Whoa, whoa.
Careful.
- Let me take her.
- Okay.
- Here, I'll take her.
- You got her?
- I got her.
Okay.
What's the matter?
I don't know.
Lea, you okay?
Lea.
Liam still hasn't
opened his eyes.
- Excuse me, my wife needs...
- I think something is wrong.
I-It's very common.
Just try and relax.
- Excuse me. Can someone come, just...
- I'll be there in a minute.
Oh, alarm in 4210.
Mrs. Hobbes' IV bag
is probably empty.
Uh, Mrs. Henderson in 4233.
I'm guessing the O2 monitor
just slipped off her finger again.
Hey, my wife in 4238...
Oh, one sec. Maternity.
No, you need pediatrics
for that. I'll transfer you.
Sorry, what room?
4238. Lea Davies. Can a
doctor come check on her?
She's really weak, and
now her belly is hurting.
Well, she had the
baby a few hours ago.
It sounds about right.
No, no, no, no, no.
It's more than that.
Now, she wasn't like
this with our first child.
- Was your first a C-section?
- No, but...
It's normal. Trust me.
She just needs some sleep.
I'm telling you,
something's wrong.
Now, if you can't come,
can someone else?
Maternity. Give me five minutes.
What's the patient's last name?
Nurse Fallon to NICU.
Chastain has been incredible.
Everyone swooped
in to help our family.
Nurse Nevin was there
when the accident happened.
Glad I could help.
Your operation went perfectly.
Not a hitch in the giddyup.
Not many people survive
a bullet to the heart.
- But where's Danny?
- He just got out of surgery.
We were able to
repair his liver laceration
and remove the bullet
from his spinal cord.
His spinal cord?
Is he okay?
We'll know more tomorrow.
Dr. Pravesh, how can I help you?
Hey, just checking in on
Lea Davies in room 4238.
I just got an anxious
call from her husband.
Right, uh...
- Right. Crap.
- When was the last time
you checked on her?
I don't know. I'm sorry.
We're short-staffed.
Seems like everyone
is having their baby.
Well, it doesn't seem
that busy anymore.
Why is it so difficult to
look in on Ms. Davies?
I need to make sure
that she gets proper care.
She's getting the same
attention as everyone else.
Respectfully, it seems
to me that she is not.
- Hey.
- Thank God, Dr. Pravesh.
So glad you're here.
Lea keeps saying
her stomach hurts.
How are you
feeling, Mrs. Davies?
Her pressure's a little low,
but in the range of normal,
especially after a C-section.
We'll be right back.
That much blood in the
catheter is not normal.
Dr. Stewart, we have
Dr. Pravesh on the line.
- He says it's urgent.
- Talk fast, please.
I have a planned C-section
starting two hours late.
You recall I
mentioned seeing blood
in Lea Davies' Foley catheter.
It is worse. Significantly.
- What's her BP like?
- 92/55.
She seems altered,
barely conscious,
even when being spoken to.
She is in a lot of pain.
All right, fine.
Go ahead and send off a CMP,
- CBC and coags.
- No.
Lea needs a CT.
Nurse Fallon to NICU.
Tell me you are not that guy.
What are you implying?
That you haven't listened
to me or to her husband,
and you are not taking this
case as seriously as you should.
I treat all of my
patients the same.
I believe what I
see. And in the ER,
I have seen you do way
more based on less information
for patients that look like you.
That is an offensive...
That is a ridiculous accusation.
Fine, all right. If it'll make
you feel better, go ahead.
Get a CT. I'll check in as
soon as I get out of surgery,
if that's all right,
Dr. Pravesh.
He ordered the CT and labs.
I need you to put a rush on it.
A rush. Do you understand?
Yes.
Hey, where are Lea's CT results?
It hasn't been done
yet. I've been trying.
I swear. They keep
saying they're backed up,
and I don't have the
authority to override...
Unbelievable. Well, why
didn't you just call me?
The ER has a clear set
of protocols. Don't you?
Where's your standard of care?
Dr. Pravesh! My
wife needs help now!
So Cold. I need blankets.
- I'm so cold.
- Okay. Okay.
- Page Dr. Stewart.
- He's in a delivery.
I don't care! Get him here now!
We need Dr. Stewart in 4238.
- What's going on?!
- I'm trying to find out.
Blood pressure's 78/43.
- Get the ultrasound.
- Her labs just came back.
Hematocrit is down to 18.
She's gonna be okay, right?
- Right?
- Hang two units of blood.
Doctor, help her.
What is going on?
- Free fluid everywhere.
- She's bleeding internally.
And she's hypotensive.
We got to get
her to the OR stat.
- Don't leave me.
- I'm not. I'm not, baby.
- I'm scared.
- No.
You're gonna be okay.
Everything is gonna be okay.
All right. I'll
take it from here.
- I'm not leaving her.
- I want to be with her, too.
Hey.
- Lea. Lea!
- Don't leave, please!
I want to... I want
to be with her.
You can't this
time. I'll be there.
Through downtown Atlanta,
extending down into the
central business district.
There are isolated storms...
Ten blade.
Call Trauma!
Massive transfusion
protocol. Now.
Suction, Pravesh! We
need to find the source.
- God.
- Give me more!
Ugh. More!
She's bleeding internally.
I can't find the source.
- Step aside.
- Laps. Suction.
And get the cell saver. I
want to keep her pressures up.
A big vessel must have cut
loose to cause this much bleeding.
How long ago was the
C-section? Six hours.
What?
What the hell happened?!
Lea Davies wasn't a priority.
I found the bleeder.
Tear in her bladder.
Right angle and a stitch to me.
Ask yourself...
would this have happened
if Lea wasn't black?
Not now, Pravesh.
Then when?
This happens far too often
to women of every color.
But it's four times more likely
to happen to black women.
That's a fact.
Mr. Davies, I'm Dr. Austin.
I'm the surgeon who was
called into the operating room
to help the team
taking care of your wife.
Lea suffered internal bleeding
during the C-section.
The bleeding was catastrophic,
and her heart stopped in the OR.
I'm very sorry to tell you
that, despite our best efforts,
your wife has died.
♪ ♪
Let me see my wife.
I want to be with her.
♪ ♪
All right, I've got
to get to work,
but there is food in the fridge.
And listen, it's not
all bad news, Jessie.
I got you into the
weekday morning dialysis.
At least you'll
have weekends off.
Thanks, Nic.
Listen, we didn't talk
about this yesterday,
but I'm gonna make
sure you get a kidney
when that six months is up.
I haven't been tested yet,
but with any luck, I
can be your donor.
You'd do that for me?
What do you think?
Thank you.
I love you.
I love you, too.
♪ You may get lost... ♪
Hey, hey.
Hey, big guy.
How you doing?
How's Mom?
She's doing great.
Danny has something to show you.
Ready?
All right.
Wiggle the toe I touch.
Ah.
Excellent job, my man.
♪ Oh, oh, keep
your head, child ♪
♪ Keep your head, child ♪
♪ We will stand the rain ♪
♪ Keep your head, child,
keep your head, child ♪
♪ The sun will shine again... ♪
Now, I know, in this situation,
an apology is not enough.
But from the heart
of this hospital,
I'm here to offer one.
Your pain can't even
be imagined, and I...
I want you to know that
everyone here at Chastain is...
we're just devastated.
Your wife suffered
what we refer to as
a "never event,"
something that
should never happen.
I can't tell you
how sorry we are.
♪ You may fall down... ♪
Apologies are routine now
because they help
prevent lawsuits.
Most people who receive
them don't take legal action.
He's not gonna get away with
dodging the
consequences this time.
- Oh, I know. I'm as upset as you are.
- Not a chance.
I saw it. I lived it.
I'll never forget it.
Same day we save a mother
and son who by all rights
should not have survived, a
young healthy woman dies.
A tear in her
bladder was fixable,
and wouldn't have killed
her if she hadn't been ignored.
And you'd better
believe I'm gonna identify
whether it was a
series of system failures
that led to this catastrophe...
More than that was
involved, Dr. Bell.
I know what you're thinking.
But I've known Dr. Stewart
and Nurse Colby for years.
I've never seen either of
them treat a patient differently
because of race.
People can have
unconscious bias.
You're absolutely right.
This can't happen again.
I have some ideas
to safeguard every mother
that comes into this hospital.
I'm listening.
After yesterday's tragic event,
we are gonna create a
review board to examine
every maternal death or
near death in this hospital
over the past few years.
We're gonna pinpoint the
problems, and we're gonna
implement a new standard
of care immediately.
And these protocols will
include comprehensive checklists,
maternal crash carts,
simulated training drills.
We need communication
and teamwork
to prevent all forms of
bias, racial or otherwise.
We need to ensure that
every person is heard.
The United States is the
most dangerous country
in the developed
world to give birth in.
There's no excuse for that.
I know.
I know. I know.
♪ But they won't fall forever ♪
I know.
Look at you. Look at you.
Daddy's got it.
♪ But we will change the tide ♪
♪ I know you feel alone ♪
♪ But I'll be by your side ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Keep your head, child,
keep your head, child ♪
♪ We will stand the rain ♪
♪ Keep your head, child ♪
♪ Keep your head, child,
the sun will shine again... ♪
CHARLES S. JOHNSON
IV: Kira deserved better.
Women all over this country
deserve better.
There's no statistic
that can quantify
what it's like to tell
an 18-month-old
that his mother's
never coming home.
There's nothing that I
can do to bring Kira back.
♪ Hey, yeah... ♪
But what I can do is to fight
as hard as I possibly can
to make sure that we send
mothers home with their babies.
♪ Yeah. ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH