And you're sure he didn't
leave until after 9:00?
Absolutely. We watched the
Devils demolish the Rangers.
The game started at 7:00.
Neither of you stepped
out between periods?
Get beer, pick up a pizza?
We stayed at my place, we
were together the whole time.
And you said the Devils
won? Yeah. Four-zip.
Kovalchuk had two, Arnott
and Parise each had one,
and Marty got the shutout.
I'm sorry? Marty?
Martin Brodeur,
Devils' starting goalie
for, like, the past 20 years.
He played awesome, as usual.
Your Honor, may I submit the sports
page from the New Jersey Chronicle
on October 9th, 2011?
Objection. Relevance.
Goes to the
witness' credibility.
Go quickly.
Would you please read
the caption under the photo?
"Martin Brodeur stops
one of his 36 saves
"on the way to a
shutout victory."
That's what I just said.
That the defendant couldn't have
possibly committed the robbery
because he was with you,
watching Martin Brodeur
shut out the Rangers.
Yes.
Thank you.
Your Honor, may I submit the
Chronicle sports page from October 10th?
Your Honor... This is
what you call going quickly?
Just two more
questions. I promise.
Please read the highlighted
text at the bottom of the page.
"In Sunday's sports section,
"New Jersey Devils' goaltender,
Johan Hedberg, was..."
That's it. Keep going.
"misidentified as Martin Brodeur
"in a photo caption
and box score."
An understandable mistake
given that Martin Brodeur was
scheduled to start, but bowed out
after taking a shot to
the throat in warm-up.
Which brings me to my
most relevant question.
Did you and the defendant
spend the evening of October 8th
watching the Devils game on TV,
or did you just read about
the game in the Chronicle
while concocting
this false alibi?
Excuse me, Your
Honor, may I approach?
You sure you don't want to wait
till after he answers
your question?
No.
I'm gonna need a continuance.
Now? You're one answer away
from destroying their whole defense.
Your Honor... Oh, shut up.
You know it's true.
Let's finish this up. I can't.
Why the hell not?
Because I think I'm
having a heart attack.
Great. Call an ambulance.
Thinks he had a
heart attack, but didn't.
His EKG, cardiac enzymes
and catheterization are all normal.
Because it's an anxiety attack.
Probably because
he just turned 40
and still goes by
the name "Tommy."
It's not anxiety.
I had the ER docs
interview his wife,
she confirmed he's
been feeling fine.
Nothing out of the
ordinary at work or at home.
She probably also believes that he
thinks Salma Hayek's breasts are too big.
Which is why I had
them admit him anyway
and treat with alprazolam.
No improvements.
Because... Because
for some patients,
the diagnosis of anxiety disorder
can actually increase anxiety.
Which is also why I told him he
had a minor respiratory infection
that was easily curable
by the medication.
You lied?
I ruled out heart attack
and anxiety disorder.
Interesting.
I know.
Impressive.
What, the wiliness with which
Foreman ruled out anxiety,
or his complete wiliness-lessness
before he met me?
The fact that you managed to
smear jelly on nearly every page.
Shingles could cause chest
pain before a rash appeared.
Pain would be restricted to
one dermatome, not cross them.
Asthma induced
pneumothorax would,
and might not show up
on a posteroanterior x-ray.
No history of asthma.
They did a lateral view as well.
No sign of pneumothorax
or deep sulcus sign.
I treated an inmate once
with similar symptoms
after he tried to poison his
cellmate with chlorine gas.
He didn't realize sharing a
cell also meant sharing the air?
Chlorine gas pools
near the ground.
He thought he'd be
safe in the top bunk.
But why would anyone
try to poison our guy?
He makes a living
sending people to prison.
But he's not in prison, and
it's kind of hard to gas a guy
unless you can seal
him in a room first.
Which is why Arceus created a
universe with three states of matter,
and 300 solid and liquid poisons
that could cause his symptoms.
Arceus?
Look it up. And
alkalinize his urine.
Then search his
home, talk to his wife.
See if you can get her
to tell us what she used.
Wait, why would you
think his wife poisoned him?
Because dangerous people don't
break into your home, they live in it.
And although his kids are old
enough to want Daddy dead,
they're still too young
to do anything about it.
It must be such a pleasure
to live in your head.
You're right. The kids
might be precocious.
You handle his house.
You handle him and his wife.
They get to just hang
out and do nothing?
If you need help, you can
take whoever you want.
I'll take Taub. I'll take Taub.
Interesting.
No, it's not.
It was a 50-50 choice. I'm
totally fine with Taub or Park.
Cool. I'll take Taub.
And I'll take Park.
That was fun.
Not really.
Nice move, boss.
Lying to the patient.
I had no choice. I
knew House wouldn't
take the case unless
I ruled out anxiety.
You need a girlfriend.
To keep me from
lying to patients?
To give you the
excitement you need
so you don't go looking for it.
You're not working
for House anymore.
Which means you no longer
have him to blame if you get caught.
I'm not looking for
excitement, I'm doing my job.
Part of which is to make
sure House does his.
Girlfriend might not be so bad.
It's less dangerous than
where you're headed,
and that's from a
guy with one alimony
and two child support payments.
It's this new
curve control thing.
It automatically slows the car
when it senses I'm
taking a curve too fast.
You really think I
care about your car,
or are you just trying
to avoid talking about
why you don't like
working with me?
There's nothing to talk about.
House liked poking ant hills
with a stick when he was a kid,
and now he wants to
do the same with us.
House is an ass, but
he's an intuitive ass.
He obviously noticed something.
Yeah, the fact that
we work well together.
He thrives on conflict and is
looking for someone to torment.
Don't let it be us.
I don't see how that's possible.
Tommy's the most
popular guy in his office.
He's even had defendants thank
him after they were sentenced.
Why would they thank him?
Because he doesn't
treat them like scum.
He makes them feel like
he's helping by offering a plea,
or even just by letting them pay
their debt and clear their conscience.
And even if someone
wanted to poison him,
I don't see how
they would do it.
He never eats or drinks anything
that we haven't made at home.
Wait, you mean, literally,
like, not even a bottle of water?
No.
So, he was obviously
afraid of something.
Yeah. Rats, mice, cockroaches.
My first job out of law school
was at the Health Department.
If you'd seen some
of the kitchens
and the processing
plants I have,
you'd cook all
your own food, too.
The poison wouldn't
have to be in food.
Have you gotten any strange
letters or packages recently?
No.
It also wouldn't have
had to be at work.
We've got two young kids.
There's definitely no poisons
I could've accidentally
been exposed to at home.
What if it wasn't an accident?
How are things between
you and your wife?
Are you asking me if I think
my wife is trying to kill me?
Yes. I am.
Absolutely not.
This is coming from a man
whose eyes are wide open.
I've prosecuted hundreds
of despicable acts
by husbands, wives,
parents. I can assure you...
I love my husband.
And I would not ever,
even for a second,
consider doing
anything to hurt him.
No pesticides, fertilizers,
or fuel in the garage.
You find anything?
No. There's not even a bottle
of White-Out in this place.
Maybe we should look again.
Maybe we should leave
before the police get here.
Well, even if a neighbor saw
us break in and called 911,
unless they said we were
armed, it's low priority.
We've got another five minutes.
He's a prosecutor. Obviously
he knows a lot of cops.
His house is not
gonna be a low priority.
Good point.
Wait.
The dining room's on
the other side of that wall.
Yeah, so?
But it ends, like,
3 feet further over.
You gotta be kidding me.
A second ago, you
wanted to run like hell
and now you want to
look for secret passages?
There's a magnet
on the fridge they use
to open child proofed
cabinets. Go get it.
Hurry up.
Here.
Holy crap.
Don't tell me.
The jealous wife,
in the dining room,
with bipyridyl herbicide.
We didn't find any poisons.
You obviously found something.
Yeah. A hidden bunker with
enough guns to defend Fort Knox.
Or break into it.
Cool.
That's impossible. You must've
broken into the wrong house.
Then you have creepy neighbors
because there were photos
of you and your kids all over.
I don't understand.
How could this...
I had it put in during
the remodel last year.
But we went over
the plans together.
It's not on the plans.
I didn't want the
city to know about it.
I'm sorry.
I should've told you. I just...
I didn't want you
and the kids to worry.
About what?
Tommy, what is it? Why would
you think you needed so many guns?
You're not gonna believe this.
He's worried that
"Too big to fail"
applies to our banks
but not our government.
How'd you know?
Because it's what
every idiot with a bunker
full of assault
rifles is scared of.
Heather Sweeney?
It'll just be a couple minutes
till someone's ready to see you.
Maybe it's not
stupidity, it's a symptom.
Cocaine abuse can cause
paranoia and chest pain.
This isn't necessarily
paranoia. Societies do fall apart.
Look what happened
with London in the riots.
There's a difference
between an isolated riot
and the fall of civilization.
April Donaldson?
Sorry, misspoke.
Imagine what would happen
if there was a terrorist attack
on the food supply,
or a pandemic where we
had to ration the antibiotics.
That's ridiculous.
Ouch.
Oh, shut up. We know what you're
trying to do and it's not gonna work.
It was a little harsh.
Stop being so...
What? Paranoid?
You're gonna look pretty
foolish if that was a wrong guess.
I think you're a good
person and a fine doctor,
but it's ridiculous to
think anyone needs
an arsenal of assault weapons.
He's obviously paranoid.
What about Fahr's disease?
He's not hallucinating.
As far as we know.
We should do a mental
status examination
and get a CT of
his basal ganglia.
No, we shouldn't.
If it's not poison,
it's most likely
atrial fibrillation
brought on by
hyperthyroidism or sleep apnea.
Looks like we got ourselves
a good old fashioned cat fight.
No, we don't. We have a
reasoned disagreement.
Still, there's only
one way to settle this.
Actually, there's
two, but we don't have
enough Jell-O for the first.
Mini-mental, CT,
and get a hair sample
to check for past cocaine use.
Check his TSH levels
and get a sleep study.
Sorry, gotta
make it a fair fight,
which means
you're stuck with her.
He's not stuck with me.
And it's not a fight.
Excuse me, miss.
What is your name?
Mariel Wilkerson.
Hah.
You don't look like
a Mariel. You're up.
So what do you think? Is
the patient paranoid or am I?
I don't think stockpiling weapons
is the most reasoned response,
but given what I've seen at
Bloomingdales on Black Friday,
I wouldn't say it rises to
the level of mental illness.
And me?
Again, given what I've
seen at Bloomingdales...
Don't let House get to you.
It's all of you. I feel like
you don't respect me.
Chase certainly
didn't try to hide it.
Chase respects you.
He's just more
comfortable working with me
because he's known me longer.
And I'm not just saying
that because you own a gun.
I don't own a gun.
I've thought about
it, but I'd probably
end up shooting
someone in my own family.
Like, when my brother tosses his
toenail clippings behind the couch.
What about you?
If anarchy breaks out,
I plan to do what my ancestors
have done throughout the ages, run.
Sounds like a good plan.
You got a moment?
Stop telling the nurses
I'm looking for a girlfriend.
What makes you...
Two lunch offers
and a box of cupcakes
since this morning.
So a few people are nice to
you and your first thought is,
"Hmm. This seems strange."
I haven't even had time
to eat my own lunch,
much less run around trying
to recruit nurses for yours.
So can I get back to work?
You're lying, aren't you?
It's for his own good.
He's not paranoid,
he's just stupid.
Well, shouldn't you put
yourself in that group?
You own a gun.
Our patient doesn't own
a gun, he owns an arsenal.
And I don't own a gun.
Yes, you do. And you're a felon.
So, you'll end
up back in jail...
That is actually not one of the
many reasons that I don't own a gun.
Why would I need a gun? The
only thing I own worth protecting,
a thief would need a crane
to get out of my apartment.
You don't own anything you need.
You own things you want.
And you're definitely the
type who'd want a gun.
You like anything dangerous.
Monster trucks,
motorcycles, fireworks.
Everyone loves fireworks.
Watching them, not making them.
I'm telling the truth.
I stand corrected.
If you believe me, then
this issue will be resolved
with no further
action necessary.
Absolutely.
It's not resolved, is it?
Not even close.
It's not cocaine. Hair
samples were clean.
It's not looking good
for Fahr's either.
I'm not seeing
any calcifications.
You sure?
They can be pretty hard to
detect in people under 50.
See?
What?
We all disagree all the time.
It's not just me and Park.
Nice try, but I'm not
getting in the middle.
So why didn't you want to
go with her this morning?
She's weird.
She's not weird.
She's a good doctor.
Most good doctors are
weird. Look at House.
Am I weird?
Yeah, but you're hot, so
it's easier to put up with.
You're completely normal
and a pleasure to deal with.
You're weird.
In a good way?
Maybe we should just
concentrate on the medicine.
You own any guns?
That's not medicine.
But it's related to
medicine. Kind of.
What do you think?
Yeah. But not for protection.
Despite what the media
would have us believe,
you think we live
in a very safe world.
You just think they're fun.
How did you know?
Working in a prison, you learned
criminals rarely target
random strangers,
and you've got more money
than you know what to do with,
so anything that seems
different and fun is worth trying.
And you?
Not here in the States. Back
home, I keep a few for hunting 'roos.
You hunt kangaroos?
But they're so cute.
They're also delicious.
You're screwing with me.
Totally.
There's no calcification.
Looks like we're both wrong.
You don't need to stay.
We won't have the
results until the morning.
It's okay. I'll stay.
Go. I'm sure your mother's
ready for a break by now.
Give the kids a kiss for me.
You think it's the end of the
world, but you wanted kids.
Oh, honey, come on.
I don't think the world's
coming to an end.
Look.
You have a spare
tire in your car, right?
That's what those guns are.
I mean, I hope to God I
never have to use one.
But if we can wake up
and learn that the entire banking
system has gone bankrupt overnight,
it just seems stupid not
to have a jack in the trunk.
Just in case.
And you've always...
What's that from?
I don't know.
You don't feel that?
No.
He also spiked a fever
overnight. Could be TB.
You wanna say it? Say what?
There's no sign of atelectasis
or infiltrates on the chest x-ray.
Yeah. That's med-speak
for, "She's an idiot."
Systemic sclerosis can
cause lower extremity ulcers.
It would have to
be pretty far along.
His first symptom was
just a few days ago.
His paranoia started
at least a year ago.
If he's paranoid.
So it's either not sclerosis,
or it's extremely
aggressive sclerosis.
We should biopsy the skin
lesion and start him on enoxaparin.
Shouldn't we wait for the biopsy
results before we start treatment?
Now's your chance.
She's leading with her chin.
I agree with her.
No, you don't.
Which means you're both idiots.
Get to work.
I know you don't
think I'm an idiot.
Does it matter?
If you're just looking to amuse
yourself at my expense, then no.
But if you feel the
need to manipulate me
to make me useful, then yes.
I thought we'd gotten past that.
If we hadn't gotten past
that, you wouldn't be here.
But ability isn't always enough.
Just ask Yngwie Malmsteen.
So this is you
trying to help me?
No, this is me helping me, and
amusing myself at your expense.
Which brings us back
to, why do you care?
I deserve respect.
I'm a good doctor.
People respect you.
They just don't like you.
Where's your wife?
She just needed some time.
Not a fan of the
guns, I take it.
It's not the guns, it's...
I shouldn't have lied about it.
I'm guessing
it's a little of both.
And a little of, "Who
the hell is this guy?"
I'm not a nutcase.
I just want to do everything
I can to protect my family.
Don't worry, I'm
sure she understands.
At first I thought it
might be frostbite.
But I haven't really
been out in the cold.
And yet your first
thought was frostbite?
Yeah. I guess I was
just going by how it looks.
It looks absolutely
nothing like frostbite.
You serious?
With some difficulty.
Then what is it?
A sign that you need
to take a long vacation.
At least a month.
A vacation?
Wait, is this like a
Bucket List thing?
It's cancer?
It's silver.
I'm guessing silver nitrate
mixed with petroleum jelly
that your boss put
on the petty cash
so he'd know who to
have arrested for stealing it.
Damn.
Yeah. Damn.
It's diffused into your skin.
The only way to get rid
of it is to get new skin.
That normally happens
every 30 days, so...
I hear that La Crosse, Wisconsin
has got the world's
largest beer can.
Here's the per diem schedules.
These are supposed
to be in a computer file.
Sorry, since Claudine left, no
one's been inputting the numbers.
I miss Claudine.
She left because of you.
I thought that was Nadine.
Her, too.
Where are you going?
You still have an hour left.
Emergency page takes precedence.
Can you... I don't know
how to use the program.
Then find someone who
does. I gotta get out of here.
Got your page.
You're an ass!
Admit it.
Let me down.
After you admit it.
I'm a little tired. I
think I'm gonna go...
All right, I admit it.
Despite the fact that I
know there's a gun in here,
I'd never find it because
you are more devious...
Clever. Devious.
All right. Fine, clever.
More clever, and you'll always
be one step ahead of me.
You're either preparing
to fight Pacquiao,
or you're having one
heck of a bad day.
I'm Anita.
Eric. Nice to meet you.
And you can tell Taub
that he's gonna get the same
treatment as this heavy bag
if he doesn't cut this crap out.
Who's Taub?
You know, I'm sure
you're a nice person,
and you have no idea what
you've gotten sucked into,
but really, I'm not interested.
Okay, and I'm sure
you're a nice person,
but I just moved from Atlanta,
and this is my first
time at this gym,
so I definitely don't know
who this Taub guy is.
But I already
agree. He's a jerk.
Are you sure you
don't want to start over?
Take your time. I'll be around.
Taub, it's Foreman.
Can't talk now. Little busy.
What's going on?
Need some droperidol in here!
I gotta go.
He was hallucinating he
was being attacked by bears.
Points again to paranoia.
I agree, except for the "again."
Acute onset points to tularemia.
Or it's been chronic, which
points to GAD autoimmunity.
Explains the
neurological impairment,
as well as the
normal blood work.
Tularemia doesn't always
show up in the blood work either.
You know what else doesn't
show up in the blood work?
Nothing. This could
all be psychiatric.
An untreated schizoid disorder,
he's finally lost the
ability to suppress.
Schizophrenia doesn't
cause skin ulcers or fevers.
No, but digging
delusions out of your skin
with dirty fingernails
could cause both.
I don't think he's a psych case.
Because you're
paranoid about paranoia.
Because his symptoms point toward
an infection that's spread to his brain.
I think we should treat with
high dose broad spectrum...
Which will kill him if
it's a GAD autoimmunity.
Treat for GAD.
Corticosteroids and
IV immunoglobulin.
I'm not paranoid. And
they don't dislike me.
They don't even really know me.
Did they tell you that?
I didn't ask because you
wouldn't believe the answer.
If it makes you feel
better to think that.
You're the one
everyone dislikes.
You probably don't
even think it's GAD.
You're just agreeing with her
because you think it'll create
more conflict between us.
There's only one
way to find out.
Actually, there's two, but we're
still waiting for that Jell-O delivery.
Let me know how it goes.
Gotcha!
You poor dumb bastard.
Touché.
God, this is exactly
what I needed.
Tell me about it.
Nita? Oh, my God.
Who's that, your roommate?
No. It's just... You have to go.
Why, what's the big deal?
Please, I'm...
I'll explain later.
Just hurry up, please.
You have a boyfriend?
No, he's not my boyfriend.
He's my husband.
I'm really sorry.
Hey, I thought you weren't
getting back till tomorrow.
His fever's going
through the roof,
which means we
were wrong about GAD,
and the steroids kicked
the infection into high gear.
Or it is GAD and we
started treatment too late.
Increase the steroid dose.
We can't.
If it's an infection,
we'll kill him for sure.
With neurological symptoms progressing
this fast, he's dead either way.
If we increase the steroids,
either death comes slower,
which means we were too late
with the GAD, or death comes faster,
which means we were
too stupid with the infection.
We were already stupid with
infection, but it's not too late.
He's young and was
perfectly healthy two days ago.
He can fight this off, if
we give him a chance.
Fine, but a shotgun is not gonna
work. We need a sniper rifle.
Start running DNA
assays for sporotrichosis,
meningococcemia, and any other
Boggle-winning words you can think of.
You just said you wanted
to increase the steroids.
Now you wanna just...
I changed my mind.
But... Do what Park says.
Well, you don't have a gun.
But you do have my sunglasses,
my tennis racket, I
can't imagine why...
Had to kill a mouse.
It's really hard with those
stupid, little sunglasses.
And my money clip.
Was there any money in it?
Not anymore.
Can I go to bed now, or do
you want to do a cavity search?
Lock up on your way out.
This is ridiculous.
Every moment we waste
looking for a phantom infection
is time we could
be treating him.
For the wrong diagnosis. If it
was GAD, he'd be having seizures.
And if it was infection,
there would be some sign
of it in his blood or CNS,
which there isn't. Yet.
I'm beginning to think we
should just go with House's idea.
This was House's
idea. He said...
No, I'm talking
about the Jell-O.
At least it wouldn't be
so annoying to watch.
Taub. You got a minute?
You're an ass. You know that?
What's the problem? Some cute,
young nurse baked you cookies?
No. Some guy almost
caught me making out
with his wife in
their living room.
And how exactly
is that my fault?
If you hadn't been
screwing with me
and put the idea in my head...
So you don't date anyone
unless I put the idea in your head.
You really do need
psychiatric help.
Unlike you, I don't need drama.
I like my job and I'm
happy with my life.
You're so happy with your life
you've got nothing
better to do at midnight
than to come back
into work to yell at me?
Stay out of my business.
You're blaming the wrong guy.
Good for him.
Married one's not a
keeper, but it's a start.
You're an idiot.
He has stridor
but no obstruction.
He's anaphylaxing.
Get me a trach kit.
Scalpel.
It's not working. There's no breath
sounds. Doesn't make any sense.
His trachea's blocked
below the incision point.
We need racemic epinephrine.
We tried that already.
We're gonna try again.
It's our only choice.
We got him
breathing, but barely.
At least we know tracheal
edema isn't from anything we did.
Because we're
not doing anything.
Which is a good thing because
neither GAD nor a systemic infection
would cause anaphylaxis
or tracheal edema.
And an allergic reaction
wouldn't get worse
three days after
he was admitted.
So we got nothing.
Unless he was
still being poisoned.
By who?
His wife wasn't even
here when he hallucinated.
Good question.
Now we're the
ones being paranoid.
What about squamous
cell carcinoma?
If it's only in his epithelium,
it wouldn't show up
on his chest x-ray.
It is possible, but...
Wouldn't cause hallucinations.
It could if he also had
paraneoplastic syndrome.
Get a biopsy.
You think it's cancer?
I think you should get a biopsy.
Admit it.
Two hours ago, I
found this in your closet
in a box with your name on it.
I knew you'd move it
somewhere outside your apartment
until you were certain
I'd given up looking.
So, I had to convince you
that I'd given up looking.
It's not a gun.
Yes. It's a paperweight
with a handy storage compartment
for .45-caliber bullets.
And that's not
a bullet. Admit it.
I'm more clever and more
devious. You can even have it back.
It's not my problem if
you go back to prison.
My problem is you thinking you're
always one step ahead of me.
This proves nothing,
because it's not a gun.
It's a prop.
From Dorothy
Dietrich's magic act.
Look it up.
She's the only woman ever
to do the catch a bullet trick.
I won this off her prop
master in a poker game.
House... It's fake.
It's plugged.
Look for yourself.
Hey! Hey! Don't
point that thing at me.
It's not dangerous
because it's not a gun.
House... House, just stop it.
Fine.
What the hell are you doing?
Pull the trigger.
Don't be insane.
They're blanks.
You pull the trigger,
I drool a little fake blood,
and I spit out the bullet
that the audience thinks
I caught with my teeth.
Go ahead. Shoot me.
I'm not shooting you.
All right. I'll shoot you.
Don't! House, don't!
Even if they are
blanks, people will freak.
It's not real.
Which means you didn't
prove that I have a gun,
which means you've
proved nothing.
Admit it.
All right.
All right, what?
You win.
And it feels good.
You were wrong.
Don't feel too bad, we all were.
His trachea wasn't
swollen, it was blocked.
By a psuedomembrane
growing across it.
Means he's not paranoid, is
an idiot, and was poisoned.
What are you doing?
Give me a Machida scope.
Hold his legs, he's
not gonna like this.
Because you're not
gonna be able to breathe.
But I need to see
down your barrel.
Good news is,
the poison didn't
come from your wife.
It came from a little
bastard of a bacterium
whose crap can cause chest pain,
respiratory
distress, skin ulcers,
the growth of pseudomembrane
across the airway,
and in very rare
cases, hallucinations.
Call the CDC. Tell them we
need antitoxin as soon as possible.
Diphtheria?
We didn't guess it
because nobody gets it.
Instead of building bunkers,
you should be getting boosters.
As in the routine vaccines
against stuff that is actually scary.
Diphtheria?
House pulled it out of nowhere.
Cool.
You just getting in?
I had a meeting about a
new parking validation system.
Cool.
How are you feeling?
Not great.
But better.
The antitoxin is working. He'll
be able to go home in a few days.
That's good news.
But we've moved out.
Oh, come on, honey.
I'm sorry I lied, but...
I know. Okay...
It was for our own
good, but I don't care.
I don't want to be lied
to, and I can't live like that.
And I can't live in that home.
Oh, please, don't.
I love you.
I love you too,
which is why you're not
gonna live there either.
I don't care if we
might need them.
I just know that I can't live
my life feeling like we do.
It's not worth living in fear.
Okay. I'm sorry.
Hey.
Thanks.
You know, there's a bunch of
us going to happy hour after work.
I'm craving nachos.
You interested?
Thanks, but I got a lot of
work I need to get done.
Sure. Well, if you change
your mind, we'll be at Rudy's.
Okay.
Hey.
Hey. Hey.
Would you like to get a
drink sometime after work?
You mean all of us? Or just us?
I was thinking
just the two of us.
Did Taub put you up to this?
No.
It was just something I'd been
thinking about and I figured,
"What the heck?
Might as well ask."
Yeah, well, it's
probably not a good idea,
you know, with us
working together.
Didn't you marry someone
you used to work with?
Yeah, but...
All right, sure. When?
Tonight? Sure.
Hey, I changed my mind.
Okay.
Glad you changed your mind.
Hey.