- This guy says
we've never met before,
but there's something about him
that seemed familiar.
There.
- I remember
when this was taken.
- So you two were close?
- Your father
never wanted you to know.
We were in love.
- There's a blue Impala.
Been idling there
for, like, 15 minutes.
- You're being paranoid.
- This woman
has very strong ties
with the Serbian mob.
- We can't do this.
It's not safe.
Milena, wait.
- Vasik settled with the feds?
- Well, there's still some
state and criminal cases
going forward, but...
You've been awarded
$1.2 million.
- My offer's been accepted,
buying that building.
Oat milk, huh?
- Mm, it's supposed to be
better for the environment.
But still getting it in
a disposable cup, so...
- A bit of a wash.
- Small talking about coffee.
We've become those coworkers.
- We could always talk
about work.
Pulled a LEGO out
of a patient's nose last night.
- Oh, that's exciting stuff.
- The patient was 34 years old.
- Oh.
- Dr. Halstead.
Pleasant surprise.
The infamous Dr. Hannah Asher.
- The infamous
Dr. Matthew Cooper.
- Hi, how are you?
Um, wow.
You are looking quite well.
It must be
that new landlord glow.
Congrats, by the way.
The apartment buildings
in Canaryville, right?
- That's right.
- The old homestead.
I love that.
It's nice to see someone
came out ahead in all this.
- What are you
doing here, Matt?
- Getting the old ticker
checked,
making sure I'm in
fighting shape for the trial.
Anyway, I got to run.
I look forward to seeing you
in court.
All right, take care, man.
Bye.
- What a dick.
You didn't tell me
that you bought
an apartment building.
- Hey, Doc Scott.
- Hey.
Stefan.
You all right, man?
Something up
with your gunshot recovery?
- No, I'm cool.
You did me right.
That's why I'm here, actually.
Sung your praises to my boss.
Now he needs your help.
- Your boss?
Oh, well.
You know, I caught
your case by chance, man.
I'm a pediatrician.
- Really?
That's even better.
It's actually
my boss's daughter
who isn't feeling well.
- Okay, um, well,
tell him to bring her in.
I'll take a look.
- Sorry, Doc.
Boss doesn't work that way.
- Oh, a... a house call.
Okay.
Um, let me text my boss and
tell him I'm going to be late.
- No.
It's no problem.
You can do that from the car.
♪
- We meet again.
- Thank you.
Um, you know,
it's Crockett with an R.
- Help.
I need help.
- Hey, hey, hey.
I'm a doctor. Are you hurt?
- Not me.
My grandson Zeke.
Backseat.
- Hey, bud.
Stretcher! Hey!
I need a stretcher.
Hey, talk to me, bud.
What's going on?
- My belly hurts.
- This might hurt a little,
okay?
- He has liver disease,
autoimmune hepatitis.
This morning,
he woke up so sick.
We got here
as fast as we could.
- Okay, put your arm around me.
- Oh, God.
Please don't let it
be too late.
- Why don't you call
an ambulance?
- We were outside the city,
and they only
serve the local hospitals.
- Okay.
Get him into the ED.
I'll be right there, okay?
- We've been to all of them.
They won't help.
Just help my grandson.
You're his last hope.
♪
- Zeke Belkin,
fulminant liver failure.
Transplant status, 1A.
His time is running out,
and his grandmother, Celeste,
knows it.
She tried to donate a portion
of her liver to save him,
got turned down.
- So they're coming
to ask for a second opinion?
- Well, more like
a fifth opinion.
These are
Celeste's medical records.
Blood type and anatomy
are a match to Zeke, so...
- She's 68 years old,
overweight, type 2 diabetes,
high blood pressure.
Her labs are terrible.
- Yeah, and the kid's
only 12 years old.
- No.
No, no. This hospital too?
- I'm sorry, Ms. Belkin.
- But I've been exercising,
eating better.
I'm stronger than I was before.
I'm the only family Zeke has.
Please.
Run the donor
screening test again.
- Okay.
We will.
Just hang tight, and we'll
have a nurse come by
and get things started, okay?
- Thank you.
- I feel for them,
too, Crockett,
but what you just did
wasn't smart.
- Look, I couldn't
turn her away.
Her grandson's dying.
She's likely his only chance
to get a liver.
- I hope you haven't
overpromised,
because unless her labs
have improved,
there's nothing we can do.
♪
- I'm still struggling
to wrap my head around it.
Was my father the man I knew,
the rigid,
by-the-book sailor,
or was that all an act,
and his true self
was this secret life
with Gerald?
- The two aren't
mutually exclusive.
- Yeah, I guess that's true.
But end of the day,
it was still a lie, right?
To himself, to me,
to who knows who else?
- You check in
with your family
about this yet?
- I, uh...
I tried to... I talked
to my sister Emily about it,
but it was clear she had
no idea, so I dropped it.
My mom... I don't even know how
to approach the conversation.
What if she already knew?
That means she went along
with the lie
and kept it from me.
And if she didn't know,
then I'm just outing my father.
The whole thing is, um...
- It's a lot, right?
I just think you got to
be patient with yourself.
You know, give yourself time
to figure it all out.
- It's the ED.
Maybe work would be
a good distraction.
- Nikola Corluka.
- Mr. Corluka, I'm Dr. Scott.
- Stefan trusts you,
so I'm trusting you.
This is Eva.
She was awake all night.
Stomach pains,
nausea, vomiting...
- And fever.
I checked her temperature
again a few minutes ago: 100.2.
- My wife, Lena.
- Hey, Eva.
I'm sorry
you're not feeling so great.
I'm going to try to help.
I need to press
on your tummy,
and you let me know if it
hurts, okay?
Anything?
What about now?
- Ow, that hurts.
Don't press anymore.
- I won't. I promise.
So, Eva, what is
your favorite food?
- Ice cream.
- Mmm, delicious.
If I brought you a big bowl
right now, would you eat it?
- I don't think I could.
It hurts too much.
- I get it.
I need to talk to your parents
for a minute.
An ultrasound will confirm,
but pretty sure
it's her appendix.
It needs to come out.
- So make a list
of everything you need...
ultrasound, other supplies...
and I'll have
Stefan bring them.
- I'm not a surgeon.
And we can't do
the operation here.
Eva needs the hospital.
- I'm more comfortable at home.
- Nikola.
It's Eva.
Listen to the doctor.
- Okay, what else?
I want the best surgeon.
And you're not leaving my side.
- Oh, fudge!
- I'll take over.
Thanks.
I'm Nurse Lockwood.
This is Dr. Asher, OBGYN.
- I'm Mary, uh, Morgan.
This is my... this is
my husband, Jesse.
- Nice to meet you both.
So Morgan,
how far along are you?
- 37 weeks?
- We're supposed to have
three more, right?
- Your first baby, huh?
- It's that obvious?
- Aww.
Good vitals.
Baby heart rate's 136.
- 136?
Is that good?
- It's excellent.
- There you go.
Morgan, has
your water broke yet?
- Uh, no.
But... but Jesse's been timing
the contractions.
- How far apart are they?
- Damn. I didn't push
the timer button.
I thought that I did.
- Pushing the button.
Timer's on.
- Okay Morgan, I'm going
to check you out, okay?
- Okay.
All right, you're about
5 centimeters dilated.
- What's that mean?
- Baby's on its way.
- Okay, Morgan,
do you have a birth plan?
I think I want to do
a natural childbirth
without drugs.
This is...
- Two minutes. Two minutes.
- All right, guys,
we're going to move
up to labor and delivery.
Go from there.
- Oh, God.
We're going to be
parents today.
- Morgan, Jessie,
I'm a midwife.
Would you like me
to stay with you?
- Yes!
- Yes.
- Okay. Okay.
- Mr. Henderson, Dr. Archer.
This is Dr. Choi.
- Morning.
- Miles.
My daughter, Anya.
Apologies for the mud bath.
We were doing
an obstacle course race,
you know.
Rope climb, army crawl...
- You know,
father-daughter bonding.
- Good, clean family fun.
- Yeah, it was till I fell.
Eh, just missed a handhold
and hit the ground
kind of funny.
- Yeah?
Can you flex up and down
for me?
- Yeah, yeah.
- As far as you can.
- Did you hit your head?
Experience any dizziness,
loss of consciousness?
- No. No.
Just a bruised ego.
- Well, I'll get
an x-ray to be sure,
but I think it's just a sprain.
- Cool.
- There's another race
in a couple of weeks.
Think he'll be ready?
- Well, hell yeah,
I'll be ready.
Come on.
- A tech will be by
with that x-ray in a minute.
- All right.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
- It seems
pretty straightforward.
No surgery necessary.
So I'm going to peel off.
- Okay, Chief.
- Then my health is better?
- Yes.
Your donor screening labs,
overall,
have slightly improved.
But the numbers are still
not ideal for surgery.
- Is it a yes or a no?
- I still want
a pre-op clearance
from internal medicine
in cardiology,
but as of now, yes.
You can donate a portion
of your liver to Zeke.
- Oh, Zeke, it's
finally happening.
- Ms. Belkin?
- Yeah?
- It's important for you
to know that even though we've
approved the surgery,
the operation
hasn't gotten any simpler.
These situations
can be life-threatening.
- Understood.
But it's not my life I'm most
concerned about right now,
so whatever consent
you need, you have it.
- Okay.
Let's get you admitted.
I love you, honey.
- Love you too, Grandma.
♪
- Okay, Zeke, so this is
what's going to happen next.
- I don't think I can do this.
- Look, I know it's scary.
But Dr. Blake...
she's the absolute best.
You know, it'll
all be over soon,
and afterwards, you're going
to feel so much better.
- You don't understand.
My parents died of COVID.
And I think I gave it
to them because I wasn't
old enough to be vaccinated.
Now this operation... I could
kill my grandmother, too.
- Hey, hey, hey.
That's not going to happen.
- You don't know that.
- Hey.
- I don't want to put
my grandma in danger...
but I don't want to die.
- Hey, hey, hey.
I don't want to die.
- It's okay, Zeke.
It's all right.
- And I'm not just tired.
I'm utterly exhausted.
But it's like all the time.
I'm also sore,
stiff, the works.
- And Dorian, how long
you've been feeling that way?
- Off and on for a few months.
I finally dragged myself
out of bed
to see what was going on.
And I hate hospitals.
But I heard
Maggie Lockwood works here,
so thought I'd give Med
the benefit of the doubt.
- Okay.
So you know Maggie?
- I haven't seen her
since high school.
But, yeah.
- No kidding?
Maggie's on a case upstairs,
but I can let her know
you're here.
- No.
No, that's... that's okay.
I don't want to bother her.
- Okay, so tell me.
What was Maggie like back then?
- Just a little whirlwind.
She was popular, valedictorian.
She ran every club back then.
- Yep. Sounds like Maggie.
- You know, she and I... we did
"Seasons of Love" in choir.
She over-sang everyone until
the teacher gave her a solo.
- Yeah, that was probably
her plan all along.
- You know what?
You might be right.
- Lymph nodes feel okay.
No tenderness or swelling.
CBC, BNP, TSH, blood cultures,
and a liver panel?
- Sounds good.
We're going to try and get you
some straight answers today.
- It was nice
meeting you, Dorian.
- Thank you.
- Yes. Okay.
Uh-huh. Thank you.
Eva has just been put under.
The surgery will last
about an hour.
I'm praying for Eva,
that she'll come through this
like she did the last time.
- Last time?
- Eva had a medical scare
shortly after she was born.
Thankfully, the doctor
said it was nothing.
Still, I was so afraid.
- Sir, can I get you
or Mrs. Corluka anything?
Food, water?
- Did I ask you for anything?
- No, sir.
- Then leave me alone.
- Yes, sir.
♪
- You worked
alongside Dr. Cooper, correct?
- He'd come down
to the ED to consult...
- Don't tell her.
Tell the jury.
- Yes.
We collaborated
on several cases.
- And in those collaborations,
did Dr. Cooper mistreat
or misdiagnose a patient?
- No.
But the VasCOM
was approved for use...
- Just keep it simple.
Just yes or no,
but with confidence.
- So you would describe
Dr. Cooper as a good physician?
- No.
- You just said Dr. Cooper's
patients were well cared for.
- Yes.
I mean, he was
a good physician,
but he committed fraud.
- No.
Now you just took the bait.
Okay, now you're on record
as saying Dr. Cooper was
a diligent, caring physician.
- You're twisting my words.
- Yes.
And so will Cooper's lawyers.
- All right, I can't do this.
Look, if I say the wrong thing,
it could blow the whole case.
No. And then Cooper
gets off the hook,
and this was for nothing.
- I think that's
enough for today.
- Yeah, me too.
- I need to get
back to my patients.
- All right, Will, I know
this is frustrating, okay?
It's just... this is a big case.
So I'm sorry, but I'm
just going to keep on
being the prick lawyer.
- Wonderful.
- Hey.
Look on the bright side.
You got an apartment building
out of it.
♪
- You're quiet.
Visualizing what we need
to do, I hope?
- Yeah.
I been thinking about Zeke.
Just terrified
something's going
to happen to his grandma.
Cried on my shoulder.
Tore my heart out.
- Okay, stop, stop.
Stop talking.
Celeste's surgery is
already difficult enough.
But for you to bring
Zeke's fears
into the OR with you, that's...
that's not helpful.
Let's just concentrate
on the task at hand.
♪
- That's great.
So we're out of here?
- Your LDL cholesterol's
a little high,
but nothing to worry about.
Just maybe cut back
on the red meat.
Otherwise, yeah,
you're good to go.
- Oh, thank God.
Because I am starving
but didn't want to go till
I knew what was going on.
Dad, do you want
anything from the cafe?
Kind of already
pulled up the menu.
- Why don't you get me
my glasses?
I guess this is what
losing a step looks like.
Can't run, can't see.
Whatever.
You know,
why don't you just give me
the, um, roast beef sandwich?
- What did he just
say about red meat?
- The turkey wrap's
pretty good.
- Then just what
the doctor ordered.
Always... always
taking care of me.
- Miles, I noticed
you were having
trouble seeing the menu.
You mind if I take
a quick look at your eyes?
- Sure.
All right.
♪
- Uh...
I am seeing a bit of a swelling
in the back of your right eye.
I'd like to get an MRI.
- Really?
That doesn't sound good.
- I just want to be thorough.
- Yeah, well, I guess that's
what you want in a doctor.
So, okay.
Let's do it.
- Great. Thanks.
- Yeah.
- Small world.
I've got trail mix
in my lunch box too.
Yeah.
I eat them when I'm stressed.
And really just the chocolate.
I know fruits would be
healthier, but grapes, apples?
I'm allergic.
- Hmm.
Me too.
- So all your tests
came back normal.
I'm afraid we don't have
any answers for you.
- I should have known.
The headaches... they kicked in
about half an hour ago.
And whenever I get them,
bad news usually follows.
- You know, there
are a few more tests
that we can actually run.
- Anything.
I just want to know
what's going on
so I can start feeling better.
- Okay.
Hang tight.
- Stiffness, fatigue,
and now headache?
Could have been
infection somewhere.
- I'm thinking the same thing.
Let's get an LP and an MRI.
- I'll order them up.
♪
- Hey, Eva, feeling better?
- Can I have ice cream
with sprinkles now?
- How about we start
with a popsicle?
The operation was as
routine as they get.
Eva may feel tired or sore
for the next few days,
but this time next week,
I do expect
that she'll be back
at full strength.
- Hey, sweetie.
I'm proud of you
for being so brave.
Eva.
Eva?
- Hey.
- Eva, can you hear me?
- Stat's dropping, 70s.
- We got a pulse,
but she's not breathing.
Call a code and bag her.
- What's happening?
- Mr. Corluka,
please, step back.
- I want to know
what's going on.
- Intubation and drugs.
40 milligrams sux,
six milligrams etomidate.
- What are you doing?
- I'm helping Eva breathe.
- Pushing meds.
- Oh, my God.
- I'm in.
- You said she's doing better.
Why did she stop breathing?
- I don't know.
A possible heart dysrhythmia.
- I don't want theories.
I want answers.
- I don't have any.
I need to run tests.
- Nikola.
♪
- Do what you have to.
- CBC, CMP, blood,
gas, mag, and false.
Chest x-ray, EKG, and an echo.
- Hepatic vein is not
cooperating, is it?
- Does not want
to take the suture.
Okay, let's try this again.
The vein is so friable.
It's like tissue paper.
Don't want it to tear.
- You through the vein wall?
- Coming out the other side.
Got it.
- Nice job.
- One suture.
Long way to go.
- You're
doing great, honey.
Just keep breathing.
- You keep breathing.
Oh, I changed my mind.
I can't do this.
I want the epidural.
- I'm sorry, Morgan.
We're way far past that point.
You're too deep into labor.
- Okay, a few more
big pushes, Morgan.
- Okay.
- Oh, my God.
That's a head.
- Now breathe out
and push.
Slow and steady.
Keep on pushing.
You got this.
- Yeah, the head's out.
Head is out.
What?
Head went back in.
What happened?
- Okay, Maggie, turtle sign.
Get her in McRoberts,
apply suprapubic pressure.
- All right, Jesse.
I need you to step back.
The nurse is going
to take over for us.
- What's going on?
Is my baby okay?
- Yes, shoulders
are just stuck.
- Morgan,
on your next contraction,
I want you to push
exactly as you have been.
I'm going to push
from above
while Dr. Asher pulls
from below.
- Okay.
- Okay?
- Push.
That's it.
That's it, Morgan.
You're doing great.
Keep pushing.
- The baby's coming.
Yes!
Got him.
It's a boy.
- Oh, my God.
He's beautiful.
- He's enormous.
- So interest rates
are going up again.
You landed
your apartment building
just in time.
- I guess I got lucky.
- You still are.
Got a tenant for you.
- I'm not ready
for renters yet.
Units aren't even done.
- Think of it this way:
one less renter to find
is one less headache.
- Yeah, all right.
Send me their info.
- You already got it.
It's Dr. Asher.
- No.
Just not a good idea.
- All right.
But I'll keep looking.
We can figure out
the finder's fee later.
- Uh, no, Doris.
- Is that Miles' MRI?
- Yeah.
- Ah.
I'll back you up.
- Hey, Miles.
We got your results.
Where's Anya?
- Had to take a work call.
- Oh, we can wait for her.
- No, no, no.
It's fine.
I don't want to interrupt her.
It's a new job.
- Okay, so your MRI
revealed optical neuritis.
It's inflammation
of your eye that causes
discomfort and vision loss.
- Good news is, typically,
optical neuritis
will resolve on its own
with time.
- Good news implies there's...
there's bad news.
- The MRI also revealed
two small plaques
in your motor cortex.
Now, we'll run
some more tests to confirm,
but that finding plus neuritis,
I think it's likely
we're looking
at multiple sclerosis.
- Wow.
MS?
For real?
- I'm afraid so.
- That's muscular, right?
I'm going to lose
more than just a step.
I'm going to keep getting
weaker and weaker.
- When Anya comes back,
we can discuss
next steps to help you...
- No.
Do not tell my daughter.
- We won't.
Right, Dr. Choi?
♪
- Zeke?
- He's doing wonderfully.
- As soon as you're feeling up
to it, you can go visit him.
- He asked me
to give you a message.
You rock, Grandma.
Celeste?
- BPs dropping, 88 over 62.
- Celeste?
- Heart rate's on the rise.
134.
- Damn it.
She's bleeding.
Bolus a liter and then two
of blood, two of plasma.
Let's go.
- It's got to be
the hepatic vein.
Didn't hold the sutures.
We've got to open her back up.
- Clearly, they're not
discussing Miles' diagnosis.
- Maybe he's, you know,
still processing
or trying to find
the right words.
You know,
didn't want to scare her.
- Or he's just not
ever going to tell her.
The longer you hold on secrets,
the harder they are to admit.
My father took all
of his to the grave.
- I completely appreciate
where you're coming from.
But I mean, how he wants
to go about it...
kind of up to him, right?
- But it's a betrayal.
By keeping quiet,
he's doing to Anya
what my father did to me.
- Normal,
every single test.
- Yes.
I also did a CT head,
MRI and additional blood labs
for endocrine disorders.
And they were all normal too.
- I don't understand.
Is this good or bad?
- Right now, I don't know.
- You don't know.
You don't know.
I'm so tired of that answer.
- Dr. Scott, she's
over-breathing the vent.
RSBI is 50.
- What does that mean?
- Eva's breathing
well on her own again.
Eva, can you hear me?
Okay.
Set up the extubate.
- So she doesn't need
the machine anymore?
- No.
It doesn't appear so.
- And you don't know why
this happened either, do you?
- I don't.
I'll re-review her labs,
her history.
- That's backwards.
- Mrs. Corluka, you said
a doctor treated Eva
shortly after she was born.
But I don't see it
listed in the records.
- We didn't go to the hospital.
The doctor came to our home.
One night,
her SIDS monitor went off.
I went into her room,
picked her up,
but she was fine.
The doctor did an exam,
but found nothing.
It never happened again.
- SIDS monitor.
You know, I'd like
to run one more test:
an exome sequencing analysis.
- What is that?
- It's a genetic test
that targets proteins.
I think it might provide us
with some answers.
But it is expensive
and can sometimes cause issues
with insurance companies.
So we need to contact...
- Run the test.
- Dr. Choi.
Have a minute?
- Of course.
- I know my dad.
And whenever he's keeping
something from me, he says,
"Everything's fine."
He's saying that about his MRI.
It makes me worried
that it's not.
- I'm sorry, Anya,
but I can't disclose anything.
HIPAA rules.
- I guess I just have
to trust
that he's telling me the truth.
- Anya, you know,
with your dad's vision trouble,
he might need you
to help with the fine print.
You know what the CARES Act is?
- No.
- It requires hospitals
to give access
to patient medical records.
This is linked to their portal.
Maybe you can help your dad
put in his personal information
to access his chart.
Medications,
test results, everything.
- Oh.
Okay.
Thanks.
- Sure.
- Need more suction.
- What you expected?
Hepatic vein not able
to support the sutures?
- It's not the problem.
Ah, there we go.
Bleeding is coming from
the raw edge of the liver.
- Let it go.
I got it.
- The clip I placed came off.
- It faulty?
- No.
Doesn't seem to be.
Not sure why
it didn't hold.
- Well, it's an easy fix.
Swap it out.
Dr. Blake?
- Hemostat and clip applier.
♪
- You all right?
- My positioning's just off.
- Okay, what do you need?
- Dr. Marcel, I think
you're at a better angle
to apply the clip.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
Take over.
- Okay.
- Congenital what?
- Central hypoventilation
syndrome, CCHS,
is a non-inherited gene
mutation that affects
the autonomic nervous system.
In Eva's case, her brain forgot
to tell her body how deeply
or how often to breathe.
- Then Eva had this forever?
Why didn't we know?
- Well, she had been
getting by.
But today,
with the appendectomy,
she needed extra oxygen
to come out of anesthesia.
She couldn't do it.
- Is there a cure?
- Unfortunately, no.
But there are treatments.
Eva's case is mild.
I suspect that she'll be
most vulnerable
to breathing lapses
during sleeping.
I recommend
a ventilation machine
like a CPAP
to monitor oxygen intake.
- Stefan.
- Da, da, on it, Boss.
- Thank you, Dr. Scott.
I raised my voice earlier,
but I'm...
- I get it.
It's your daughter.
Excuse me.
♪
- Well, looks like
he told her the news.
That should make you
feel better, huh?
- Hey, Dean.
- Yeah?
- Decided I don't want
the chief position any longer.
You keep it.
- Really?
Why the change of heart?
- I guess, uh, just not
who I am any longer.
- Huh.
All right, well, you know me.
I'm not one to argue,
so, uh... Deal.
- Good.
I'll tell Ms. Goodwin,
make it official.
♪
- Hey, Morgan.
How are you doing?
- Sore, bottom and top.
He hasn't stopped feeding
since he came out.
- We think he's going
to be a sumo wrestler.
- Well, he's off
to a very good start.
His birth weight is
a new hospital delivery record.
11 pounds, 9 ounces.
- Seriously?
My last Leopold
predicted seven pounds.
That was way off.
- Yeah.
Estimating birth weight is
still an imperfect science.
- Apparently
so are due dates.
Almost three weeks
we thought we had.
We put them aside to finish
the nursery, buy clothes,
pick a name.
We thought we were so prepared.
Guess not.
- Pretty safe bet
that just when you think
that you've got
it figured it out,
this little guy is going
to throw you a curveball.
My advice is just
to roll with it.
- I have placed thousands
of clips, Crockett.
What happened today...
- It worked out,
and Celeste is fine.
- Thankfully.
But it could have just
as easily gone the other way.
I should have felt
that clip hadn't engaged.
- Look, I...
I backed you into a corner
when I agreed to new labs
for Celeste.
I threw you off your game.
- It's my OR,
my responsibility.
Not everything's
about you, Crockett.
- Dylan.
- Oh, Milena.
- Hey.
I'm sorry about today, okay?
It wasn't my idea
to drag you in.
Stefan pitched you to Nikola...
- Eva's better.
It's all that matters.
- I can't wait
for this case to be over.
- Yeah, me too.
♪
- Hey, Celeste.
Just checking in.
What's going on?
Are you in pain?
- No. No.
I'm happy.
Thank you for taking a chance
on me, for not giving up.
- You're very welcome.
I'll let you rest.
- Okay.
Oh, when you see Dr. Blake,
would you pass on my thanks
to her also?
- She hasn't been by?
- No. Not yet.
- Okay.
Yeah, I'll see
if I can track her down.
- Thank you.
- You got it.
- Hey, Miles.
Here's your discharge papers.
I asked you not to share
my diagnosis.
You said you wouldn't.
- Miles, I'm sorry,
but your daughter
knew something was going on.
- Seriously?
You're going to argue with me?
Protecting Anya is
my job, not yours.
- I understand.
You know,
Anya's new job is in Seattle.
I didn't tell her about the MS
because I knew
she'd give it up to stay here
to take care of me.
And she has.
- I didn't realize, man.
- No, you didn't.
Just go.
♪
- That looked uncomfortable.
What'd you do?
- Something maybe
I shouldn't have.
- A new you, huh?
Good call giving up
the chief position.
♪
- Hasty getaway, huh?
It's never a good sign.
- Yeah, it's been a long day.
I just want to go home.
- Pamela, what's going on?
I know I hurt you
after surgery.
Just a bit vague on how.
- It's not you, it's me.
- Oh.
Well, thank you.
That clears up everything.
Come on, Pamela, talk to me.
If I... if I've done
something, just tell me.
- I told you,
it's not you, it's me.
It's literally me.
The clip didn't hold
because I didn't engage it
tightly enough.
I couldn't engage it.
- What do you mean couldn't?
- My hand at rest.
Rock steady.
But when I pinch
my fingers together...
There's something wrong
with my hand, Crockett.
There's something really wrong.
- Hey. Hey. It's okay.
- Thank you.
Oh, hey, I was hoping
I'd catch up with you.
When you get
your schedule tomorrow,
let's find time
for another practice session.
- Okay.
- Listen, um, I realize
that I haven't fully expressed
my gratitude
for all that you've done.
You're still bearing the brunt
of the consequences,
and I'm the one
that got you into this mess.
So thank you.
- Appreciate that.
I also appreciate you
not congratulating me
on my apartment building.
- What?
- Well, that's been
the takeaway for most people.
- Huh.
Don't listen to them.
You're a good man,
Will Halstead.
You stepped up.
But then, you always do.
- Looking for an apartment?
- Yep.
A few decent ones.
We'll see.
- You know, my units
aren't totally done yet.
- Oh.
- Actually, one is livable.
Just needs a coat of paint.
But if you want it, it's yours.
- I don't know.
That's...
- What?
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I'm sure.
- Well, then okay.
Yeah.
Thank you.
- Yeah, we'll sort
the lease out tomorrow.
And I'll get you the keys then.
You should know,
I'll be across the hall.
So...
- So... neighbors?
- Neighbors.
- Thank you.
- Hey, I think you know
my patient in four.
- I do?
- You went
to high school with him.
Dorian Harwell.
- Oh, my God.
I haven't seen him in 25 years.
Is he all right?
- He had
a grade 1 glioma.
Waiting on
a neurosurgeon consult,
but his prognosis is good.
- Is he okay to see visitors?
- Uh-huh.
- Okay.
- Maggie.
- Yeah?
- Um...
Is he my father?
- Oh, sweetie, no.
- Okay.
But if he isn't, then who is?
- You've never asked me
that before.
- I know.
But just meeting Dorian,
it just made me think.
- I'm sorry, Vanessa.
But I can't tell you.
Your biological father
and I agreed
that we would never
contact you.
I broke that agreement,
but I can't make
that choice for him.
- But maybe you could
just reach out and ask him
if he'd like to meet me.
- Vanessa.
We didn't stay in touch.
I don't even know where he is.
- Okay.
♪
- But I can ask around
and try to find him.
- I... I'd love that.
Thank you, Maggie.
- Yeah.
♪
- I guess I really upended
Miles' and Anya's lives.
- Look, at least
Anya got to hear
Miles' reasons for withholding
the truth from her.
I wouldn't be at all surprised
if he actually convinced her
to take that job.
Seriously.
But look, whatever happens,
at least now,
they need to figure out
what happens next together.
And that's a good thing.
- Yeah.
Let's hope.
I never got to have
a conversation
like that with my father.
- Let's say you did.
What do you think
his reasons might have been
for withholding
his relationship with Gerald
from you?
- Maybe the same as what
Miles wanted for his daughter.
To protect me.
♪