It might sound extreme, but
I'm pretty sure I'm in love.
I thought you had three
more nannies to interview.
I do, but Joelle walked
through the door,
and Steve immediately
stopped fussing.
She held him the whole time.
- Plus, she speaks Spanish.
- Bilingual bonus.
Right? And it will be so much
easier to go back to work
if I know Steve is
happy without me.
But Shaun has reservations.
There's a whole
process involving
spreadsheets, ranked voting.
Screw that. Good nannies
are hard to find.
You gotta pounce now.
I can't just make that
decision without Shaun.
Your body is no longer
tolerating the dialysis,
and it is putting you at high
risk for stroke or cardiac damage.
We need to start you on continuous
renal replacement therapy.
"Continuous" meaning...?
Your mom has to stay here
until she receives
a kidney transplant.
I want you home, not living
in a hospital for years.
It won't be years.
CRRT is usually only
effective for about one week.
And then?
Complications will set in,
and without a
transplant, she will...
W-We're going to find a kidney.
The last two donors
weren't compatible.
Suki. Let's try
to stay positive.
How? The video I
posted last night
asking for donors only
has a few hundred views.
I don't have enough followers.
Come here, baby.
You have such a good heart.
We will place a catheter
in your right jugular vein
and start CRRT.
Looking forward to my
internal medicine rotation
with you, Dr. Reznick.
I really...
Each of the urine
samples needs a dip test.
Each of the stool samples
in the poop fridge
needs a fecal occult blood test.
Okay. I don't know how to...
Dip the pee. Dab the
poo. Send to the lab.
It's not rocket
science, MacGyver.
But first, that little blond girl,
Zelda, needs her TDAP vaccine.
And be careful. She's a biter.
- Excuse me.
- Hey.
I saw a video post
about a patient here.
Where do I go to
donate my kidney?
I was supposed to raise my
legs and slide on my butt.
Did you hear any
cracking sounds?
No. I didn't realize my leg was
hurt until we were driving home
and the adrenaline wore off.
Did that say 1.6 million views?
Turns out that when your
tech-savvy daughter helps you
with your bucket list,
you end up an influencer.
You've got a Grade 4
malignant spinal cord tumor.
How long did they give you?
About a year. 10 months ago.
Which is why I took
a break from college.
Spend as much time
with him as possible.
Make videos.
And memories.
Let's get x-rays and
a CT of the femur.
Get you back on your feet
as quick as possible.
Okay, if you'll lie down, we'll
get you down to radiology.
Jerome, do you mind just
unlocking that side?
Sorry. I need to leave.
Yes, hi. It's Aaron Glassman
checking in on those images.
Well, when...
They were supposed
to be ready today.
Fine. Can you have them call me
as soon as they come in, please?
Thank you.
Hi.
I'm Dr. Glassman.
I can just tell you
what's in there.
World-stopping headaches.
Over and over for
the past three years.
The only thing that helps is...
Oxycodone 20s.
Yeah.
And then, like a total
klutz, this morning,
I knocked my pill
bottle off the sink,
and they all fell
into the toilet.
Uh-huh.
Your prescribing
doctor is unreachable,
and it says here
you're drug-seeking.
After three years of oxy and
a revolving door of doctors,
that doesn't surprise
me. Forget it.
I'll find another doctor.
Like I said, total klutz.
Hang on, hang on.
- Sit.
- I don't have to listen to you.
I know. You don't. Please. Sit.
Follow my finger.
Look to your left.
All the way to the right.
You have a twitch in your
eye. Did you know that?
Is that a thing?
It might be a thing.
Tap your finger
and your thumb together.
There you go.
All the way to your
pinky and back.
How about a partial refill?
Tide me over? Just
until my doc gets back.
No pills, but I am
going to order you
a brain and spinal MRI.
Any family history
of kidney disease?
Not that I know
of. Mom's a saint,
and I'm adopted on
my father's side.
Under name, you
only put "Emmanuel."
Yeah, that's what
people call me.
Like Beyonce.
Hmm. Okay.
If the blood and tissue
type match with our patient,
we'll do a cross match
test and we'll see...
Yeah, we'll match.
Whenever I donate, they
tell me I have golden blood.
Rhnull?
That's the rarest
blood type on Earth.
Only 100 cases.
That makes you a
universal blood donor.
Birthplace just says Nazareth.
Is that in Pennsylvania?
No, the other one.
If the blood type tests
out, that's great news.
Almost done here.
Uh, you left occupation blank.
I'm a carpenter by trade,
but I really consider
myself a teacher.
- Dear Lord.
- Yeah, I go by many names.
Uh-huh. This man
thinks he's Jesus.
I've been sent here to help.
EGFR and uACR are normal.
Both kidneys are
fully functional.
He is an ideal donor.
Except he's obviously
crazy. He thinks he's Jesus.
Technically, we
can't prove he isn't.
I mean, the Bible says Jesus
will return to Earth someday.
There's several examples
of ordinary people
becoming holy figures
later on in life.
Muhammed didn't receive his
first revelation from God
till he was 40.
I minored in theology.
He's certainly your
patient's savior.
Without him, she's
dead in a week.
It is possible we could find
another donor, but unlikely.
But that doesn't mean we
should allow a delusional man
to make life-altering decisions.
And the surgery poses
a bigger risk for him.
We can only give him blood
from another Rhnull donor,
which is nearly
impossible to find.
Regardless, we should
reach out to his family.
Parents are dead.
His emergency contact
is his landlord.
If he wants to save someone's
life, I say we let him.
UNOS policy says organ
donation is contraindicated
if there is inability
to give informed consent
due to impaired cognitive
or intellectual capacity.
That's not our call. We
need a psych consult.
Your patient is suffering
from delusional
disorder of grandiosity.
However, he can
reliably articulate
that he understands
the procedure.
His driver's license indicates
that he has been an organ
donor for at least a decade.
That suggests this decision
is consistent with his values.
He is completely
competent to donate.
Hallelujah.
I don't know how you
live over half a century
without trying an oyster.
Well, I always wanted to.
I just... I don't know,
I chickened out because
they always look so goopy.
Well, no more fear.
Slurp away.
Mmm. Wow. Mmm.
Your femur's not fractured.
Oh. Good.
But the pain you're
feeling is called
referred neuropathic pain,
from a fracture in your spine.
It's compressing
your spinal cord.
Not good.
The tumor has infiltrated and
weakened your spinal column.
It likely fractured when you
hit the ground after skydiving.
So how do we fix it?
Open spinal stabilization
and fusion surgery.
We replace your fractured
vertebrae with a cage
and add bone grafts, screws,
and rods for support.
You should be back on your
feet in about six weeks.
That could be more than
half the time we have left.
There is another option
with simpler surgery.
No cage and no bone grafts,
much shorter recovery time,
but even a small bump
could break it again.
So I'll avoid small
bumps. Let's do it.
Dad, are you sure?
We have a mountain to climb.
We'll go get prepped.
Come on, get your
camera rolling.
I got 11 more to go.
Dad, you're so old.
Cameras don't roll anymore.
We still need to run an
MRI on the potential donor
to evaluate the
kidney's structure.
But the labs show he could
be an excellent match.
Your video worked.
Turns out you don't need
a million followers.
Just one... who
thinks he's Jesus.
Hashtag blessed.
I would like to hire
Joelle as Steve's nanny.
I worked it out.
If we cut it down to
two streaming services
and I stop buying Steve
so many cute outfits
and we don't go on
that trip this summer,
we can afford her.
- Whew. This is a very thorough spreadsheet.
- Mmm-hmm.
You clearly have strong
feelings about this.
We can hire Joelle.
- Shaun! Yeah!
- Okay.
Okay, we should call her.
Yes.
Hello?
Joelle, it's Lea and Shaun,
and we are so, so excited
because we would
love to hire you.
Oh.
- You stole my nanny?
- She wasn't your nanny.
Yet. And you knew I
wanted to hire her.
I encouraged you to
hire her on the spot.
But you hemmed you hawed
and you dilly-dallied
and you spreadsheeted,
so I took action.
And outbid me. It's so gross.
I told you that good
nannies are hard to find.
My current one is
late half the time,
and she costs more than Joelle.
I wanted to close the deal,
so I made an aggressive offer.
I feel like I don't
even know you.
I'm finished with
the perianal abscess.
Great. Dressing change
for a diabetic foot
ulcer in 5 awaits.
Nobody said wound
care was glamorous.
Joelle has experience
with special-needs kids.
And she's bilingual.
I always wanted Eden
to be bilingual, so
seriously, thanks.
You're trying to replace my
dream nanny with regifted wine?
- I'm not evil.
- Debatable.
You barely even looked at it.
Enough to see there's
no tonsillar herniation,
which is the main
criteria for Chiari.
That's why I said Chiari Zero.
That's not a real diagnosis.
It is real. It is
controversial, but it's real.
Moderate cervical syrinx,
plus occipital headaches,
plus dizziness,
plus clumsiness with
the finger tapping.
All symptoms of
Chiari malformation.
And also symptoms of withdrawal.
Not the fluid in
her spinal cord.
Too many doctors have just
fed her pain medication
or shooed her away altogether.
Because she's an addict.
And one who's around your
daughter's age when she died.
Wow. Okay.
Hannah's pain is real.
She's in actual pain.
Or she's doctor-shopping
for a sucker.
Okay. So both can be true.
She's not gonna be able
to get over her addiction
unless somebody
addresses her pain.
All right, fine.
I don't know how this
is not worthwhile.
Leave the images.
Jerome bailed less than
an hour into his shift.
I'm worried about him.
He's going through it.
I was thinking you might
go talk to him after work?
I can't right now.
Yeah, no, of course.
Anything I can do for you?
Thanks. I've got an MRI.
People are free to choose.
God is simply aware of
what those choices will be
because He lives outside
of time and space.
Isaiah 57.
Sorry to interrupt your sermon.
Lie back.
I know we just met,
but I sense a...
Like, a weight on you.
A sadness. I'm fine.
I'm guessing you were close
to the young man who died.
How do you know about him?
Dr. Allen, he's tachycardic
and his blood pressure's
elevated, 178 over 112.
Go get 20 milligrams labetalol.
People like to tell me things.
I like to listen.
So you're nosy.
Mmm. I'm friendly.
Um, his vitals are normal again.
Probably spiked due to anxiety,
maybe from the machine.
I'm not anxious. I'm
enjoying our conversation.
Oh.
Apparently, I'm the only one.
Try to keep still and no
talking during the MRI.
Hi.
Just checking in.
I was thinking I could talk
to Villanueva if you want,
about getting you
some more time off.
Thanks, but I don't
think a few more days or
weeks will make much
of a difference.
I'm not sure I can
ever come back.
I'm sorry.
Rod is placed. Lock
it in with set screws.
Thank you.
Jerome's still not back today?
No. He's not sure he
can come back at all.
Too many memories.
He's still in shock. Now
tighten the instrumentation.
At least Paul gets to know
the end is coming and prepare,
say his goodbyes.
I don't think you can
ever really be prepared.
And I wouldn't want my loved
ones to watch me suffer.
Spine is stabilized.
Continue with the
endoscopic decompression.
So you'd rather not
know it's coming?
I'll go to sleep one night,
never wake up, cut to black.
Hold up.
There's a clean margin
in the spinal column
surrounding the entire
length of the tumor.
That wasn't visible in
his previous imaging.
The impact of his
landing must have
cut off blood flow to the
tumor at its perimeter,
caused it to shrink.
I think this gives us
room to do a cordectomy.
We could remove
his entire tumor.
And take out the majority
of his thoracic
spinal cord with it.
Would paralyze him
from the T3 down,
and his cancer will
probably come back.
But it'd give him
a lot more time.
Let's close him up, see
what he wants to do.
How much of his blood
have we banked so far?
Only two units, and
if we draw more,
he'll be too anemic for surgery.
We found another in Australia,
but it wouldn't get here
until the end of the week.
We can't wait that long.
Naomi may be too unstable
to survive the transplant.
We'll have to make it work
with the patient's own blood.
We'll need to ligate every
vessel twice before cutting.
Be precise and meticulous.
I really don't want
Jesus' blood on my hands.
Luckily, we will
be double-gloved.
Give 7,000 units of Epogen
and 150 milligrams of
iron to increase RBCs.
Hi.
Are you entering
your baking era?
Nope. They're for Joelle.
But I have three reject
batches I could bring you.
- I'm good.
- Okay.
Why are you making muffins
for Park and Morgan's nanny?
Because soon she'll be ours.
I've come up with some
additional cost-saving measures
so we can pay her
a little bit more.
Mmm. There were
other candidates,
many of them very well
qualified and less expensive.
Morgan stole our son's
nanny. That cannot stand.
Out of principle.
What principle?
If we get all of the tumor,
which I think we can,
we could extend your
life by five to 10 years.
Maybe more.
But I'll be a quadriplegic.
It's likely you'll maintain
some use of your hands,
unless the edema
spreads upwards.
No, no, no, we're sticking
with our original plan.
Just get me back on
my feet again, okay?
Dad, they said years.
You'd still have all
your mental faculties.
And you'd have me to help.
Can you get me some ice
chips? My mouth is really dry.
Just think about it, please.
Eve drew this in kindergarten.
I'm the tall one. She's
the one with the hair.
She told me that her dream
was touching the sky with me.
And I promised her that
we would do that one day.
And then her mom and
me, we got a divorce,
and I lost a lot of
years with my daughter.
Well, this surgery would
give you a lot of years back.
After all these years
of being absent,
I can't ask her to spend
her 20s taking care of me.
She should finish college,
start her own life.
Hi. This is Dr. Aaron
Glassman again.
No, okay. I don't
understand the delay.
Fine. Um, can you please have
them call me back either way?
Thank you.
How you feeling?
Mm. You gave me the
good stuff, so...
Yeah, well, guess what?
After the surgery, you're not
gonna need the good stuff,
nor are you going to need
to be telling stories
about spilling
pills into toilets.
- It wasn't...
- Don't bother.
You left the emergency contact
blank on your pre-op form.
You planning to off
me on the table?
Well, I'm not planning on it.
But if something
were to go wrong,
I'm gonna need to contact
your mom or your dad.
Good luck. They kicked
me out years ago, so
if you want someone who
cares if I die, guess again.
I'm gonna take the wild
guess that they still care.
You'd be wrong.
Father, thank you for
loving us so much,
and we ask that you
heal Ruth's back pain
so she can get back to
the pickleball court.
- Amen.
The pain is gone! Thank you.
I think that's your pain
meds kicking in, Mrs. Wyatt.
Let's go.
I don't have time to be
looking all over for you.
I'm sorry. Helping people
in pain is kind of my thing.
No, it's my thing.
I'm the doctor,
and my patients don't
need your snake oil.
- I'm giving them comfort.
- You're giving them false hope.
It's okay if you're
angry. He gets that a lot.
I'm not angry. I just
need you to stay put.
I didn't mean right now.
I just feel a little...
I need help!
We cannot do the
kidney transplant
until we know why he collapsed.
He's hypertensive and
tachycardic one moment
and then stable the next.
Could be carcinoid syndrome
or renovascular hypertension.
There are no suspicious masses.
His renal arteries look normal.
His labs rule out
hyperthyroidism.
Everything about
this guy is crazy.
Crazy is not a DSM-recognized
diagnosis, but you are correct.
His underlying condition
must have psychiatric
as well as physical symptoms.
He has a pheochromocytoma.
We need to surgically remove it.
It could not be seen on the MRI,
but it has been flooding
his system with hormones.
Once the pheo's out, we may find
Jesus has left the building,
taking both kidneys with him.
If that happens, Naomi
almost certainly dies.
We could remove the pheo and
the kidney at the same time.
Given his blood type,
every surgery is dangerous
because of our limited
supply of Rhnull blood.
Ethically, there's
no debate here,
regardless of medical issues.
We remove the pheo,
then ask Jesus
if he still wants to move
forward with the donation.
Prep him for surgery.
You're trying to
steal our nanny?
Oh, Lea is trying
to steal your nanny
because Morgan stole her first.
She didn't mention that part.
Although, Joelle was not
technically our nanny yet,
but Lea is very
passionate about this,
and I'm choosing to support her.
Yeah. Me, too.
Oh, you're supporting Lea?
No. Morgan.
We need to do something
before this escalates
and we're ordered not to
talk to each other anymore.
We gotta sit down, the four
of us, and work this out.
Atrium Cafe. Tuesday, noon.
Me again.
You don't have to
keep checking in.
I, um...
I need a favor.
It's kind of a big one.
Due respect, Doctor, the
source of my divinity
isn't just a
pheo-whatever-you-call-it.
Your BP and heart
rate are stable.
Our connection to God is
not that easily severed.
I think you know that.
Why do you keep
thinking you know me?
You don't. You didn't
know my dead friend.
You don't even know who you are.
I need to place
an arterial line.
I know you're grieving.
- I don't want to talk about it.
- And you can't understand
how your friend's death
could be part of God's plan.
There is no plan.
It's a lie, and it's cruel.
And I used to believe
in it so much.
Every time I lost a
patient, I would tell myself
it's all a part of
a bigger picture.
I took comfort in believing
you were watching out for us.
Even in the midst of suffering,
you were working things
out for our good,
but it is all a lie.
My friend was murdered
defending one of your children.
You let him bleed out on
the sidewalk all alone,
and there was no one there to
tell him how much he was loved.
He knew.
I promise.
Hey. God will love you,
no matter what you say to Him
or about Him.
You just need to keep talking.
Okay, everyone, time to
vote. We need your help.
Which peak should we climb,
Mission Peak or Mount Umunhum?
Uh, Mission Peak
is an easier hike,
but Mount Umunhum has a
better view of the sunset.
I vote neither.
I hope that wasn't
a live stream.
You're the disappearing nurse.
Jerome Martel.
I'm sorry about that. I, uh...
I lost the love of my life
recently, very suddenly.
And seeing the two
of you, you know...
It must have struck a
little close to home.
I wish I had known my last
day with him was my last day.
Or my last month.
So we could have made
the most of that time.
Are you here to talk
me into the cordectomy?
Asher and I made a plan
to watch every Best
Picture winner since 1928.
We made it to The
Godfather Part II.
Asher fell asleep halfway
through, as usual.
He was snoring so loudly, I could
hardly hear what Pacino was saying,
I don't know what the right
choice is for you and your family.
But I know there is
nothing I wouldn't give
to sit by Asher's side
and listen to him snore
through The English Patient.
Dad. We could watch every one
of those 30 for 30
documentaries you like.
Even the ones about hockey.
Or we could start our own
two-person true-crime book club.
It wouldn't just be
fun and games, Eve.
You'd also be stuck.
Not stuck.
Honored.
Sure, I'd need help,
but I can't lose you after
just getting you back.
I want you to be there when
I graduate from college.
Maybe walk me down
the aisle someday.
Okay if I wheel you down?
I'd love that.
We removed the pheochromocytoma.
Do you still believe
you are Jesus?
My name is, um... Is Carl.
I remember everything, but...
I know I'm not Jesus.
Are you still willing
to move forward
with donating your kidney?
I...
I have no idea what to do.
We now only have one
remaining bag of Rhnull blood.
That makes another
surgery quite high-risk.
Donating your kidney to Naomi
would be a very
kind thing to do.
But as your surgeon, it is
not medically advisable.
I can't do it.
We've discussed and
would be willing...
Reluctantly willing.
To hire Joelle as a part-time
nanny so we can all share her.
Returning half of
what you stole?
What a cop-out.
- Told you. She's totally unreasonable.
- Excuse me?
If you want to see unreasonable,
let me hold up a mirror.
Unless you already
swiped that from my bag.
I've seen you knock-off bag.
There's nothing worth taking.
Okay. Would you be
willing to employ her
on Tuesdays and Thursdays?
And give you a 60/40 advantage?
We're the ones who found her.
We're the ones who hired her.
Youtake Tuesdays and Thursdays.
I'll throw in my wine. Deal?
No deal, but I will give
you the stack of resumes
from the people we didn't hire.
So we're supposed to just
pick through your leftovers?
You already did, except
we were still eating her.
I did not mean that
the way it sounded.
How about a 50/50 split,
alternating weeks?
I have a better idea.
You're a genius.
Savant.
So, St. Bon's is now in
the daycare business?
- You agreed.
- No, I just didn't contradict you
when you almost
immediately said yes.
I'll take more 4-0 for tackups.
You're opposed to
being family-friendly?
I just didn't realize your mini
strokes had turned you into
such a softy.
Between the daycare... and her.
What about her?
She's a patient,
who I happen to be right about.
Let's find out.
Opening the arachnoid.
Significant adhesions,
fourth ventricular veil
restricting CSF flow.
You were right. Chiari Zero.
This will only solve
one of Hannah's issues,
and arguably the easier one.
Her addiction will
still be a problem.
Doesn't have to be yours.
Watch your dissection.
I've got your discharge
papers and your ride.
My, uh, emergency
contact is my landlord.
You want me to call him?
I think my, um,
brain tricked me
into thinking I was
the most significant
person around because...
I don't really matter to anyone.
Your friend, what
kind of man was he?
Clever.
Honest.
Would make you laugh
as much as he would
call you out on your nonsense.
And really brave.
Maybe it wasn't a trick.
Maybe your brain just showed you
the type of person you could be.
Maybe you came
here for a reason.
Yeah.
I'd like to think so.
Um, I'd like to
donate my kidney.
Sectioning the artery
with a vascular stapler.
Vitals holding steady.
Kidney looks great.
Ligating the renal vein.
Removing the left kidney.
Let's get this over to Naomi.
The vein tore.
He's hemorrhaging.
Applying manual pressure.
We need suction
and Cooley clamp.
His renal vein must have
avulsed off the vena cava.
We need to get vascular control.
200 cc. That's the last
of his banked blood.
Very aware.
Please, please, do
not let this man die.
Sutures aren't holding.
Less than 100 cc
of blood left.
- Can we ligate the vena cava?
- Tissue is too friable.
That could cause
complete renal failure.
We should put in a graft.
The walls are tearing.
We need something to get
vascular control now.
A double-balloon occlusion.
We can block it from above
and below at the same time.
And we could use the existing
jugular central
line to get access.
Fluoroscopy.
I'll take the graft.
Lap sponges.
Advancing the
catheter to the SVC.
Call out when he
reaches the IVC.
A little further.
You're there.
Inflating the balloons.
BP and heart rate
are stabilizing.
Thank you.
I'm not here to ask
you to come back.
Promise.
I wrote a list.
Yeah, come in.
Anything anyone at St.
Bon's could remember Asher
ever saying he wanted to do.
Save a cat in a tree.
Learn Dothraki.
Eat pasta in Italy.
If you want, I
thought maybe we could
do some of it together.
Thanks.
But, uh
well, these weren't at
the top of Asher's list.
He was really serious about
making me get a matching tattoo.
A big spoon for me,
little spoon for him.
Tried to talk me into
it at least once a week.
I said it was too silly
for something so real.
Thanks for this.
Hey!
Dr. Reznick around?
No! And don't sneak up
on people like that.
I'm sorry.
That lady is putting
me through my paces.
I almost miss surgery.
When I lost my mom,
my whole world
stopped making sense.
I looked to religion
for answers.
I'm still searching
for what feels right,
but I do know my
mom's not just gone.
And I try to find little ways
to make her a part of my
life as much as I can.
There you are. The poop
fridge shorted out.
You've got 22 fecal
samples to relocate ASAP.
How big is your fridge at home?
Hey.
Okay.
Follow this light.
No more twitch in the eye.
Let me see your hands.
That's good, right?
Yeah, just finger tapping.
Both.
Good.
Grab my hands and make
a nice, tight grip.
Really tight, as
hard as you can. Ow!
Okay.
Next you'll be
pitching for the A's.
God, no.
Cubs or bust.
Thank you for believing me.
But, um...
I'm... I'm still a little...
Uncomfortable? That's normal,
considering the surgery
you've just been through.
Could you give me something?
Your morphine's maxed out.
But you know what I can do?
I can hang out for
a little while,
keep your mind off things.
I can get a deck of cards.
Gin Rummy or Blackjack?
I don't wanna take your money.
Ha.
We could turn on the TV.
Okay.
But I'm choosing what we watch.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Excuse me. I'll be right back.
Yes, it's Dr. Glassman.
Yeah.
And... And they're conclusive?
Okay. Um, can you do me a
favor and send them over?
I'd like to take a look.
Yeah. Um, thank you.
The gears won't turn And
the leaves won't grow
There's no place to run
And no gasoline  - Okay.
Engine won't turn and
the train won't leave
Engines won't turn And
Well, the way I feel
Is the way I write
Hey, guys, we are seconds
away from crossing off
our biggest
bucket-list item yet.
Thanks to the help of
our fantastic doctors
and a little bit of teamwork,
we have arrived at the
peak of Mount Umunhum!
Okay. Everybody ready?
Okay, three, two, one!
We're touching the sky!
The way I feel Is the
way I write  - Whoo! Whoo!
Nothing like the thoughts
Of a man who lies
There is a truth
And it's on our side
Dawn is coming
Open your eyes
Look into the sun
As the new days rise
And I will wait
For you tonight
You're here forever
And you're by my side
So, this patient I just had...
He thought he was Jesus,
real, actual Jesus.
You would have loved
it, or mocked it.
Probably both.
You know, when he said he was
a carpenter from Nazareth,
that's the thing...
Look into the sun
As the new days rise
Hi, Joelle.
- Hi!
- Oh, my gosh.
I've missed you so much!
You have done a very nice job
making this not feel
like a conference room.
Thank you.
Steve was such a
happy, easy baby.
Oh, was he really?
Oh, I'm so glad.
No, he did great.
He was the only one who
didn't even cry at drop-off.
- Really?
- Mmm-hmm.
Can't wait to see you tomorrow.
- Okay, bye.
- Bye.
Oh, you did so good, peanut.
What's wrong?
She said Steve did not react
when his parent left the room.
Which means loves it here.
Or it could be an early
indication of autism.