Previously on Grey's Anatomy...
We were in a
plane and it crashed.
We just can't let this
happen to other people's
Lexies and Marks.
The best strategy
will be to look for fault with
the people who put
you on that plane.
You're not responsible.
A bunch of people
made it possible...
And I am one of those people.
The lawyer called, and they
need us at the courthouse.
We won.
He's giving us
$15 million. Each.
So who pays? The hospital.
We don't have
that kind of reserve.
I don't sleep with my
boss. Yeah, it's messy.
I am sleeping with Stephanie.
I've never really had
a friend who was a girl
who didn't want to do it.
You really are a douche.
You're like my
brother. We hang out.
I'm pregnant.
Well, congratulations.
Congratulations.
Sorry to interrupt.
I thought you might need a
break. Maybe grab a cup of coffee?
Seattle Grace has
suffered a financial setback.
We're gonna have
to trim our budgets.
Alana Cahill. I'm a
physician advisor.
She's here to
advise and to help.
I am proposing that
we close your ER.
What?
Why don't you listen
to what she has to say?
Some of us don't have a
few million to fall back on.
You're getting us ready to sell.
I'll be making some changes.
You need to be part of
that change or get out.
I'm not big into change.
Okay, great.
Um, now let's just try a few
where you're actually smiling.
In oncology, when a normal cell
changes into
something malignant,
it's called cellular
transformation.
Look, I don't even want
to be the hospital mascot,
whatever you do...
Brand ambassador,
and you haven't
been appointed yet.
You're just a very
strong contender.
Handsome, good with kids...
Just what the buyers want.
I'm outta here.
The damn cells turn toxic
right in front of your eyes.
So as far as I'm concerned...
Look, you're going to have
some public relations reps
following you around tomorrow.
Try and be civil.
Transformation sucks.
Brand ambassador?
What does that even mean?
You get to wear a funny hat
and cut things with
oversized scissors?
All I know is, Cahill
creeps me out.
That creeps me out.
Who comes over to
somebody else's house
and starts sucking face?
You invited 'em.
What's that?
We are directly
underneath Yang's room,
and Owen's visiting.
What do you think?
Is that him or her?
Do napkins work as earplugs?
What the hell?
You're nuts.
What is that?
I don't know. A
giraffe. Dinosaur.
I'm just saying, I
don't understand
how you and Jo aren't
jumping at each other yet.
Is it a medical thing?
Need prescription
pills that are blue pills?
Is it like pent up frustration?
Is that why you're
resorting to animal noises?
We were just having
fun, like you and Avery,
only without all the groping
and bodily fluids and...
Yeah. Never mind.
Nothing like you and Avery.
For the millionth time, Jo
and I are not into each other.
Oh, please.
You and Ponytail McGee
were canines in heat last night.
Literally.
Told you they
were doing it, Avery.
Pay up.
I don't like him like that.
Guys don't just
hang out with girls.
It's not in their DNA.
That's not true.
Okay, it's true.
You two are, like,
one drink away
from crazy monkey sex.
Just stuff her turkey.
You'll feel better.
I feel fine.
Look, I'm not screwing
my ex every night,
and I'm not taking
advantage of interns
on someone else's sofa.
You're gonna pay to
have that thing disinfected.
Not taking advantage. It's
a really nice sofa, though.
Hey, Apes.
Hey, here's a question.
Um, whatever happened to
good old-fashioned romance?
No stuffing of turkeys
or disinfecting sofas,
but, you know, what
about nice normal dates
where people talk, share a
meal, get to know each other,
and then wind up together,
not because they're monkeys,
but because they have genuine
feelings in a committed way.
I mean, what is so
wrong with that, huh?
Are you gonna eat all of those?
I like this, seeing
you every morning.
It's... It's nice.
Yeah, it is. It's really nice.
I feel bad, though.
I mean, you guys
shouldn't even be here
now that the ER is closed.
Nicole's just
standing out there.
You sure you don't
want your seat back?
Aren't you cold?
My burrito will keep me warm.
You okay?
You seem a little off.
Yeah.
I worked all night.
Do you...
Do you know how boring a night
shift is with no incoming traumas?
I was praying someone's
appendix would burst
just to keep me awake.
How am I supposed to
train to be a trauma surgeon
with no ER,
no trauma?
I'm sorry. I'm tired
and I'm venting.
Dispatch to Unit 33,
we've got a 55-year-old
male with chest pain,
prior M.I., near
Pioneer Square. Over.
Unit 33 responding.
You have to go already?
I'm afraid so.
Okay.
Hey, uh...
You want to come, too?
You're with me all day?
We just want to get to
know who you are, Dr. Karev.
See you in your element.
It's important we choose just
the right ambassador for our brand.
Your brand? This
hospital isn't a luxury car.
Hold, please.
Good morning, Dr. Karev.
Pre-rounds went
well. Got your scans.
Do you want to tell me who the
creepy lady is taking our photo?
I'm Amrita.
I do public image assessment
for Pegasus Horizons.
They're buying the hospital,
and they're looking for a
face to slap on some posters.
And they chose you?
Maya Noel, 13 days old
with gastroschisis
and staged silo repair.
She was born with her
intestines outside of her body.
They've been too
swollen to fit back inside.
Is that... Am I looking
at a bag of organs?
We've been gradually compressing
the organs a little bit each day
to help them fit
back inside the body.
Imagine going two weeks without
getting to hold your own baby.
Well, good news.
Looks like we're finally
gonna be able to close her up.
Today is the day.
Oh, my God.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you! Thank you!
Hold, please.
Thanks, guys.
If I could just have
you sign this release.
Yeah.
These are real
people with sick kids.
This is not a photo op.
I was just trying... Look,
I don't care, all right?
The next kid I'm about to go
see is a very sensitive case.
All right? You don't say a word.
You do not take a photo.
You're a shadow, a
freaking shadow. Got it?
Protective of your
patients. Passionate. I like it.
Forget it. You're
waiting in the hall.
Great. Great.
Now if you could just...
Move a little
closer to her... Him.
Oh, I'm the him. She's the her.
I... No, I was born a
her, and Jess was a him.
I get it's confusing. You
mean, move to my left?
Yeah. You're kidding.
Cahill's got more of
you guys trailing me?
He's "trailing me."
It's for this brand ambassador
thing or something.
It's not a big deal.
Just... We'll be done
in a sec. Ready?
One, two and three.
How's that?
You really think it's okay
to let these people in here?
The patient's fine with it.
If he gets to
stay, I get to stay.
It's the ambassador thing.
You think this kid
makes you look good.
I always look good.
We're at UW together.
I'm a sophomore,
and Brian's a freshman.
And is that where you met?
Actually, no. Dr. Karev
introduced us.
A few years ago, I
booked an appointment
to see how old I had to be
to, you know, start the process.
He was 14.
And Dr. Karev told me about
this transgender support group.
That's where Jess and I met.
Brian walked in that first day,
and all I could think was,
"Oh, my God. He's so cute."
I thought he'd never notice me.
It's impossible
not to notice you.
I've been saving up for this
ever since that appointment.
Well, Dr. Karev, you
really changed Brian's life.
Well, you could also say
that I'm changing Brian's life,
today, in surgery,
where I'll be taking the lead.
And what is today's
surgery exactly?
A full gender reassignment?
Oh, no. Nothing
that drastic yet.
Today we're just
chopping off my boobs.
All right, enough questions.
Edwards, Wilson,
take these guys outside.
Jackson Avery as the
new face of Seattle Grace...
Now that makes sense.
Alex also makes sense.
If you want a face that's
unshaven and sweating light beer.
You've got this in the bag.
Walk with me.
Here's what I know.
They like Avery's looks
and they like his name.
Now you don't have
either of those. Gee, thanks.
But you have Africa.
Lead with Africa.
He's a scrapper and a fighter.
Now some people
find that charming,
but you're an Avery.
Use it. Own it. Impress them.
They want to be impressed.
And I saw your breakfast.
Your brain can't function
on powdered sugar.
Here.
You just carry those
around in your pocket?
Every time I touch this thing,
it deletes another patient.
It deletes a patient?
I did the exact same
thing this morning.
Here. Let me see...
Something.
Who are your stalkers?
Oh, uh, the new guys are
looking for a hospital show pony,
a face for the brochure.
Yeah, Karev's my competition.
Mmm. If you can
call it that. You can't.
Bite me, pretty boy.
And why are there no
women in the running?
Oh, there was. I
turned them down.
This face only goes
on the Nobel brochure.
And here we have
a fully centralized
electronic records system.
Everything you need to know
about any client at any time.
Smart, streamlined, efficient...
Oh, efficient.
It would be more efficient
if it didn't keep
deleting my patients.
Sing it, Grey. Don't
encourage her.
Why not? Cahill deserves it.
This morning, she gave
me this whole load of crap
about how to talk to the buyers.
Emphasize sports medicine.
Don't emphasize my research.
She doesn't want anything
to jeopardize the sale,
and neither should you.
Research is risky.
The suits don't like it.
Whereas, if you've got
the Seahawks as patients...
Ah, she doesn't
call 'em "patients."
She calls 'em
"clients," like we're,
oh, I don't know,
real estate agents.
Real estate agents look happy.
Maybe we'll be happy.
Their benefits package
says they have dental,
including orthodontics.
Now I happen to have a family
history of very straight teeth,
but Tuck may grow
up and need braces.
I don't know.
But if he does,
they have dental.
That's... I'm just
gonna focus on that.
No, no, no. We cannot settle.
We have to rise up and
we have to do something.
You've done plenty.
Maybe those of us from the plane
should keep our
heads down for a while.
Am I crazy?
I mean, am I the
only one that thinks
these wonks are
gonna destroy the place?
No.
You're not crazy at all.
I just felt like, what
kind of doctor would I be
if I didn't try to help out
all those African kids?
It takes a lot of dedication
to get a program like
that off the ground.
This is your fault.
You put these
ideas into her head.
His head.
And while I do
support the decision,
believe me, he came
to it all on his own.
She's barely out
of high school...
He. For God's sake.
She is a child! He.
She doesn't know
what she wants! He! He!
Jess, is everything okay here?
Are you the one?
What?
Are you the one
who wants to hack
my little girl into pieces?
Hey, hey, calm down.
It's gonna be okay.
Pegasus...
Racing you to a
brighter tomorrow.
Oh. I'm gonna hurl.
Click there where
it says "hospitals."
Holy crap.
They must own half the
hospitals in the country.
They're the guys who bought
out Portland Gen last year.
Right there.
Hey.
Hey, look at this.
"Hand in hand,
we'll walk together,
"partners on the road to
your brighter tomorrow."
This is who's buying us.
That's a cute logo.
Sofia would like it.
She likes horses.
It's not a horse.
It's a Pegasus.
And it wants to hold your hand.
This web site has not one
tangible piece of information
about the company
or health care.
Why doesn't this bother you?
It does, but they're buying us.
And we are all about
to gallop down the road
towards a brighter tomorrow.
So, you know, cool your heels.
Chill out. There's
nothing we can do about it.
She just told me
to cool my heels.
Have you ever known
me to cool my heels?
How do you feel
about a road trip?
I'm sorry. I lost my cool.
You think?
It's just, I learned about
this surgery last night
in an e-mail.
I mean, a stupid e-mail.
I had no idea about...
Any of this.
Guys, you can go.
We're fine here. Scram.
Mmm-hmm.
Let's go.
A surgery like this
is a big adjustment
for any parent,
let alone if you're hearing
about it for the first time.
So let's just take
a breath and...
Dad.
What are you doing here?
Hi. Hi.
My name's Calliope...
Plant...
Tain.
Plantain.
And this is...
My husband.
Um, uh...
Julio Plantain.
And he needs a doctor.
Can I see some I.D.?
He has chest pain.
Yeah.
So by the end of this seminar,
I expect all of you
to be able to perform
basic wound closures
using the interrupted
two-layer technique.
I don't like that
guy in the back.
I can feel him watching me.
No, it's just me.
I like to look at you.
Quick question, Dr. Avery.
Do you use this
technique more often
when you perform butt
lifts or breast implants?
Actually, isn't
this the technique
you used to attach the face on to
your last face transplant patient?
Well, I've never
actually done...
Sidebar. What do
you find more fulfilling,
liposuction or body sculpting?
Sidebar. Isn't it true you've
completed more successful skin grafts
than any other
doctor in this hospital?
Um...
Yeah. What are you doing?
Saving your ass. You hit
a rock and you're sinking.
Iceberg ahead, Captain.
Larry.
You know, we've got a
free station right over here
if you want to try your
hand at some actual surgery.
Please.
Excuse me one moment.
Have a seat, please.
What's up? I'm kind of in
the middle of something.
I know and I swear I wouldn't
call unless it were an emergency.
Look, I did a ride along today,
and we got this call, a kid,
about 10 years old, hit and run.
Damn it. He's still locked down.
We can't intubate. APRIL:
Can you ventilate him?
Barely. His SATs
are still in the gutter.
Okay, let's get him backboarded.
We need to load and go.
Seattle Pres is slammed, so
they're diverting us to Redmond,
but that's an hour
away, and this kid...
He doesn't have an
hour, Jackson. He doesn't.
All right. All right.
How are his vitals?
Bad. We've got no airway.
I can't crike.
He's got sub-Q emphysema.
He will die en route if we
have to go way out there.
He will die.
Are you asking what
I think you're asking?
If I am, will you do it?
And a few years ago,
we renovated the
waiting room to provide...
Chief, a moment, please.
Give me a moment.
Kepner's calling
with a hit-and-run kid.
He's in bad shape. Wait.
Kepner's in the field?
They diverted her to Redmond.
Okay? We're closer. Much closer.
So I can arrange...
Absolutely not.
We are not a trauma
center anymore.
If we take them in, and
something happens to them...
Chief, it's a kid.
Protocol dictates
the patient goes
to the nearest trauma
center, and that's not us.
I'm sorry.
You need to get
back to the seminar.
And you have to step it up.
What do you need, a
pep talk, tough love?
No amount of tough love is
gonna make up for the babies
Alex saves on a daily basis.
Can I trust you?
Why do I have to be the patient?
'Cause you look the part.
Oh, and I'm naturally vivacious.
Yeah, "manic's"
more a word for it.
I'm so sorry for the wait.
We're gonna get a doctor to
you just as soon as possible.
Well, it really wasn't a wait.
Ew. Wow. You're a
happy one, aren't you?
He's up there, too. Hmm?
Ugh.
Oh, God. It's like...
Hello, I'm Dr. Mattoo. You
can call me Kan if you'd like.
You wouldn't be here if
you weren't experiencing
some pain or discomfort.
I apologize if we
exacerbated that with a wait.
Uh, we got here, like,
half a minute ago. It's...
Okay, Mr. Plantain.
Uh, it's like the
fruit. It's Cuban.
Can you spell that for me?
Um... P-L-A-N...
T-A-I-N.
Well, Mr. Plantain,
we know you have
a lot of options for your
health care management,
and we are honored that
you've chosen us today.
It's my pleasure.
Saw your EKG. It
looks pretty good.
How are you feeling today?
Uh, well, uh, Dr. Kan,
you know, the
last 24 hours, I've...
Uh, uh, sorry. Let me
put that another way.
What brought you in today?
I'm sorry. What's wrong with
asking him how he feels?
That could take us
down the wrong road,
and because your
time is valuable to us,
we don't want to get
off on any tangents.
Well, if you ask
him how he's feeling,
maybe he'll tell
you that he's...
He's blue, 'cause...
Yeah. You know, his company
was just purchased
by a bigger company...
Yeah. That he doesn't like.
And, you know, he
can't talk to me about it
'cause I'm the
self-involved type.
You know, we just, like,
you know, shop online
and redecorate the house.
And so he's been...
He's been hanging out
at the local watering hole,
where he has been
bumming cigarettes.
And now he's experiencing
shortness of breath.
So if you ask him what
brought him in today,
he's just gonna tell you
"shortness of breath."
And then you'd miss the
whole cigarette connection.
I ask about smoking
on screen two.
Fine. Whatever.
Okay, let me get
back to screen one.
Darn it. The screen froze.
Sorry. Technical difficulties.
I'm gonna have
to exit the system
and take us back to the top.
Uh, it's okay. Take your time.
Can't really do that.
We've only got 15
minutes together today.
There we go.
Mr. Plantain,
can you spell that for me?
Wow. They really
cleared the place out.
Okay, where do we start?
You can start by
guarding the door.
Hey, no one can know about this.
No one comes in. You understand?
Mmm-hmm.
Okay.
Medusa me all you
want. You're not getting in.
I'm an attending and I'm
ordering you to let me in.
Well, you're not my
attending today, so...
Don't make me force you.
I'd like to see you try.
Hey.
Jo. It's okay.
I paged her. She's cool.
I hope you understand.
I would never ordinarily
speak to you that way,
and I look forward to working
on your service again soon.
How can I help?
You're barely 18.
You know, what if you wake up,
you realize this
was all a mistake?
This isn't a haircut or
some meaningless tattoo.
This is my life.
This is me.
All right. You feel different.
You want to belong. Okay.
I get that, but you have
your whole life ahead...
I mean, what... What's the rush?
I'm just asking for you to wait.
Brian feels like
he's dying inside.
We both do.
If you'd just listen,
Brian will tell you that
living inside of
a body like this...
I'm sorry.
Could you just give
us a moment alone?
No, I don't want her to go.
And I don't want you
mutilating yourself!
I'm not!
Brian's just trying to be...
Oh, for God's sake.
Her name is Brianna!
Dad, just get out.
Go.
Just get out!
You heard him.
I just snagged a monitor, a
ventilator and central line kits.
I have saline, infusion pumps,
a crash cart and Cristina.
I'm sorry. They overpowered me.
The fewer people who know
about this the better, guys.
I brought lackeys. What?
No, I don't need interns.
No, this room has
three internal exits.
You have a lookout on one.
Happy, Ponytail,
you man the doors.
Mousy, be the nurse.
We need gloves.
On it. Why do I
have to be the nurse?
We are gonna need lights.
No, if I turn on more overheads,
you can see it from the hallway.
We can use those.
Hello. Yep. Okay.
All right. They're
pulling up now. Let's go.
Oh, jeez.
I'm okay.
That's why we needed interns.
The door won't open?
Watch the I.V.s. Hurry.
April, what's going on?
I don't know. Jackson? Jackson!
Pull. It's starting to give.
More! More! Go sit down, Mer.
Oh, come on. Just because
my uterus is occupied...
Go sit down. I'm not kidding.
Give me your spot.
What... Don't worry.
I ditched my PR chick
before I got down here.
How did you know
that we... I paged him.
You've got an incoming kid. You're
gonna need kid-sized equipment.
I brought a peds cart
with a bunch of crap.
All right. Are we doing this?
All right, guys, on my count.
One, two, three!
Go, go, go, go.
Go. Come on, guys.
We need to do rapid
sequence intubation, stat!
We could only get a 20
and a 22-gauge in the field.
I'll start a central line.
I need some
lactated ringers. On it.
I got it. I can see the cords.
Paralytics are working.
All right, uh, I
need an ET tube.
Orange drawer. Orange drawer.
I knew that.
No chest sounds on the right.
I have to throw in a chest tube.
Uh, I think I saw
Betadine somewhere.
Wait a second. Does anybody
actually have chest tubes?
I'm trying to set
up this saline drip,
and I can't get this
thing to stop beeping.
Anyone? I can give it a shot.
All right, I'm not
finding chest tubes now,
but I got NG tubes. Did
anybody actually bring suction?
There's a portable
suction in the rig.
Okay.
I'll go get it. Thank you.
Incoming!
Lights.
All clear.
I'm in. Brooks, bag him.
So Dr. Avery is
taking a power nap.
He likes to rest up
before big surgeries.
And Dr. Karev had a
dentist appointment.
Even doctors have
to go to the doctor.
Meanwhile, have
you seen the skin lab
where Dr. Avery
grows actual skin?
Come on.
Okay, I'm back. I got it.
Help me secure this NG tube.
All right, hook it up
so we can suction.
Okay, who's got the
portable ultrasound?
We don't have one?
Happy? On it.
Wilson, get in here. We
need some more hands.
If this kid dies because
you brought Red along
on same lame idea of a date...
The ride along was a date?
I need some 4-by-4s to
control the bleeding on the scalp.
All three lines are patent.
We can start dopamine at
five mics per kilo per minute,
but we need to figure
out his I.V. drip rate.
It's different for kids,
depending on size.
Anybody have a calculator?
I always ask a nurse.
Not a real nurse.
Broselow tape
says he's 30 kilos.
Standard concentration of
dopamine is 1,600 mics per cc.
So five times 30 is 150,
times 60 minutes
in an hour is 9,000.
Divide that by 1,600.
Infusion rate is
5.625 cc's per hour.
What? I'm really good at math.
Okay, let's give him 5.6...
Except we don't have
any dopamine, guys.
We don't have access to any
non-code medications at all
unless we have a
nurse or a code...
Yes, you do.
You paged him, too?
Well, I knew we were
gonna need meds.
I have the codes. Tell
me what the patient needs.
"Don't smoke"? That
was his big advice?
Yeah, he examined me
and found nothing wrong,
which, in fact, is the case.
Oh, he was an idiot.
And now I feel like an idiot.
We're just wandering around.
We look like interlopers.
Hey, you know, let's
grab a cup of coffee.
You always look like you belong
when you're carrying a coffee.
Ah. Yeah.
No, walk with purpose.
Don't look shifty.
I don't.
Okay. Oh, look.
Okay.
Want to make sure
we're on the same page.
That makes sense.
I think one more diagnostic...
Do we have time for that?
Just one? MAN: I
think we're pretty good.
All right.
Fifteen minutes a patient?
Can a doctor learn
anything in that little time?
You get really efficient.
And patient
outcomes don't suffer?
Wow. You're that efficient?
Are you visiting a patient?
Oh, I'm Richard Webber.
This is my colleague,
Callie Torres.
Um... We're with Pegasus,
and we just wanted to
check in, get a little feedback.
See if you had any concerns.
Really?
Really.
Okay, you need propofol...
Gentamicin and...
You will be really impressed
by our next stop downstairs,
which will be the site
for our new hernia clinic.
Get down there now. Okay.
Alana. Is this the group
from Pegasus you mentioned?
Hi, I'm Dr. Shepherd.
Good to see you.
Hi, very nice to meet
you. How's the tour going?
Good? We like what
we're seeing so far.
Ah. I'm glad to hear that.
You know this is more than
just a hospital for a lot of us.
And I don't want to
sound cheesy, but it's, uh...
It's like family.
It's like home. Good.
Hey, have you ever seen
a human brain up close?
I can't say that I have.
You know what? I'm gonna
give you the unofficial tour
by way of the
third-floor coffee cart.
We'll have some coffee
first. You're gonna love it.
It's a little taste of Seattle.
I've got free fluid in
the left upper quadrant.
Crap. What time is it?
We have surgery on
Brian in 20 minutes.
Cahill will definitely
notice if we don't show.
If you guys need to go,
go. We can handle this.
Look, I'm seeing a
pneumopericardium.
Okay, we should put in
another chest tube on the left,
just to be sure. Well,
this kid needs an OR.
Guys, we've gotta move him.
We can't. Not till we have
someplace for him to go.
There's no time. Cahill's on
her way down here right now.
Okay. We're staying.
Are you hungry?
Can I buy you lunch?
Actually, we have a
very tight schedule.
We need to get down
to the hernia clinic now.
Oh, yeah.
Okay.
You know what?
Why don't I join you?
We gotta move the rig.
It's still parked outside.
It's okay. Go. JACKSON:
Move, guys, move.
Hurry!
We gotta get this thing mobile.
What happened?
He's bradying down.
We gotta keep moving.
I'm not getting a pulse!
Ross, start CPR.
Damn it. His trachea
is deviated to the left.
His SATs are dropping. I
think he has a tension pneumo.
He has bilateral chest tubes.
It must have gotten blocked.
Someone find me a 14-gauge
cannula or a 16-gauge.
Whatever you can
find, the biggest.
Got it! Guys, what about Cahill?
Oh, God. What if he dies?
What if we brought him
here and what if he dies?
Hernias are one of the most
common general surgery procedures.
And as it turns out, also
one of the most lucrative.
Why did I agree to this? JO:
Guys, we gotta keep moving.
I can't even think!
We have to move!
Cahill's coming down
right now. If we don't move...
We're moving. Yang.
Wait one second. One second.
Now keep in mind,
the site is still
under construction,
but you'll just have to
use a little imagination.
Before we go in
there, I'd like to...
Okay, right this way.
And watch your step please.
Last month, I had to do a
cardiac cath on a patient
with no signs of heart disease.
It's putting the patient
at risk for no reason.
Forget physician
advocacy. It doesn't exist.
We have no say
in anything... At all.
Yeah, and if you decide to
go crazy and think for yourself,
they know, like, instantly.
I swear the walls have ears.
Are you the reps from Pegasus?
Dr. Webber and Dr. Torres.
Hi.
Callie Torres from
Seattle Grace?
Uh...
I'm... Do I... Do I know you?
No. Kenton Giles.
I'm an ortho just like you.
Yeah, I read all about your
cartilage generation work.
It's incredible.
I didn't realize you
stopped practicing.
So you work for Pegasus now?
Yeah.
Yeah, I guess I...
Needed a... I needed
to mix it up a little, so...
She peaked, you know,
with the cartilage generation.
You know, sometimes it's best
to get out before you decline.
Yeah.
And after the anesthesia
is administered,
Brian will be ready for surgery.
And when exactly are we gonna
see Doctors Avery and Karev again?
No offense, but we're
here to trail them, not you.
Edwards, nice work. Ah.
No problem.
We're ready to scrub in.
Wilson, could you show
our friends up to the gallery?
You guys can
watch from up there.
You have a little bit of
blood on your left shoulder.
Everyone, right this way.
Here we go.
By streamlining the process,
we will significantly decrease the
hospital's hernia complication rate
and become a
destination medical center.
How many patients will this
place accommodate at a time?
Upwards of 30...
Once everything is...
Finished.
Shepherd, would
you mind taking over?
Uh, if you'll excuse me.
Right. Uh, yes.
I was gonna try a
similar research project,
but now that I'm the
face of Portland Gen,
I don't have that
kind of time. Really?
Yeah. I do a lot of press.
About orthopedic
surgery? That's great.
Well, more like, you
know, wellness, nutrition,
get eight hours
sleep, take a walk.
Sometimes I do a
photo op in the OR.
They don't want to
shoot a real person,
so they have me cutting a
chicken breast or something.
Oh.
Well, I work on the Portland
Trail Blazers, though.
Real guys, not chickens.
Yeah. Yeah, that's good.
Nothing innovative
like Dr. Torres does.
Or... Did, I guess I should say.
You know what?
I was wondering,
can this stay between us,
not get back to Pegasus?
Nothing you say to us will
ever get back to Pegasus.
Great.
Well, now that
you're not practicing...
Is there an ortho
opening at Seattle Grace?
Well, I hope you get it, the
brand ambassador thing.
I don't want to be the
face of any hospital
where I have to sneak
around and risk my job
just to do the right thing.
Screw that. I hope you get it.
All right, well, this
keyhole incision is done.
We're ready to begin closing.
Who are you
operating on, Dr. Avery?
Um...
My transgender patient, why?
What did you do?
This part of the lung is fried.
I'm gonna have
to do a resection.
The spleen is out.
Let's irrigate with
antibiotic solution.
Does somebody want to tell me
where the hell this patient came from?
Whose patient is this?
Fine. You don't have to tell us.
We can just look it up.
All I need is the
patient's name.
Wait. No.
I can do it. I'll look it up.
It's my patient. You got this?
Thank you, Dr. Grey.
Appreciate your cooperation.
Sure. No problem. I'm happy to.
Okay.
I just have to get
into the patient file.
Oh, no. What?
This keeps happening to me.
I try to go into the patient
file and I guess I deleted it.
What happened?
Cahill figured it out?
They're taking us in one at a
time to see who'll break first.
I can't lie. I'm no good at it.
They'll see right through me.
Stay strong, Dopey.
You can do it.
They started with the interns.
I'm just trying to find
out what happened.
You want to know what happened?
I'll tell you what happened.
A kid was dying,
and we kept him alive.
Dr. Karev, hello.
You mentioned the word "we."
Who else was involved?
I was. This was my call.
I took the kid in. I
decided to treat him.
We did the right thing.
We saved his life.
And that's what matters.
Not these idiotic new policies
or some stupid ad campaign.
So you can punish
us however you want.
We don't care,
because... That's enough.
Just go.
Oh, that's it? You're not
going to discipline them or...
Go.
You paged me?
No. Yes.
We have a problem.
My presence seems to
have ignited an uprising,
which makes it a little
tough for me to do my job,
especially when
you help them. What?
It was your code that accessed
the medication case on floor five.
Is that true?
That stuff you
said, Dr. Shepherd,
about how this hospital
is such a family?
Mmm-hmm. It was lovely, really.
I even think you meant it.
But it means nothing
if there is no hospital.
Do you know how much this
stunt would've cost this place
if that kid had
died on our watch?
Pegasus would've backed out.
And without them, you're done.
I am trying to help you.
But I can't do that if you are
undermining me at every turn.
If you care anything
about this hospital
or the people in it,
then it's time that
you get on board.
Otherwise the next doors
to close will be yours.
Jess, the surgery
went very well.
Brian should be
in recovery soon.
You'll be able
to visit him then.
Mr. Weston?
Is that you?
I'm sorry.
I just want to hear
how Bri... How everything went.
I sent you the
e-mail last night.
Not Brian. It was me.
He wasn't gonna tell you.
I know you guys don't talk
that much since he moved out,
but he talks about you
a lot.
He admires you.
I think he wants to
grow up and be you.
And you're his dad.
It was a major surgery. I
thought you should know.
I get why you blame me for this.
He met me
and started changing,
dressing differently
and acting differently.
But...
I'm not...
It's hard...
Being like us...
Trying to fit into this...
This mold that
doesn't fit.
He just wants you to
love him, Mr. Weston...
The way he loves you.
He didn't tell you because
he didn't want to mess that up.
You guys okay on rent?
Here.
That's all I have on me.
You don't want to be
there when he wakes up?
Change is a funny thing.
Not everyone can handle it.
Hey. So I know you keep saying
that you and Wilson aren't a thing.
'Cause we're not.
Well, maybe you should be.
She kinda kicked ass today.
Just saying.
Come on.
Come on where? Just come on.
It can sneak up on you.
It's funny how you
don't appreciate a thing
until you're about to lose it.
No.
No, don't... Don't
say that. That's...
We can still fight this.
You can fight this.
Me?
I've got an early
retirement package waiting.
Maybe I'll take it.
Good night, Torres.
Good night.
Things aren't what
they used to be.
Matthew?
Oh, hey. I was
hoping to catch you.
How's the kid?
He is doing great.
He made it through
surgery with flying colors.
Oh, that's... That's great.
That's good.
Yeah.
Uh, April, I...
Oh, man.
I had this whole thing
that I wanted to say to you,
and then you look
at me, and I just...
Okay. Pull it together.
Um...
You are the strongest, most
fearless, beautiful woman I've ever met.
You were incredible today.
You are incredible.
And...
I like you.
I really like you.
And I
just thought I should say that
so you knew, because I...
Your whole world
has transformed.
What are we doing in here?
Just wait.
I stole them from
the nurses in derm.
They won't eat 'em anyway. They're
all "no sugar" and "gluten-free."
Cheers to an incredible day.
You deserve it.
Actually, I helped,
too. So cheers to us.
Hey, powdered
sugar's your favorite.
Yeah, no. This is great. Thanks.
What?
Nothing.
You realize...
The ground beneath
you has shifted.
You guys are killing me.
It was the right thing to do.
Yeah.
You're still killing me.
Things are uncertain.
Mmm.
And there's no turning back.
She's not answering.
I really want to
wait for Cristina.
Okay, fine. Fine.
Let's wait for Cristina.
Let's just wait downstairs
where it's warm.
Yeah. No, we can't.
The walls have ears.
I'm outta here. Okay, all right.
Look, I called this meeting
because we can't just keep
our heads down and lay low.
Okay, we're the reason
the hospital's in trouble.
We have to do something.
We can't let Pegasus take over.
We have a responsibility.
Which is why I think
we should buy the
hospital ourselves.
The world around
you is different now...
Hi.
Unrecognizable...
And there's nothing
you can do about it.
You're stuck.
The future's staring
you in the face.
And you're not sure
you like what you see.
Like I said,
I'm not big into change.