Previously on "ER."
You just choose not to!
Thank you!
Next month my hair
will grow back
and you'll still be sorry.
Just for that,
I get to pick the movie.
How long's it been
since you've had something
really juicy, Peter?
From this point on,
a pediatrician
'is consulted in
all peds cases.'
Carlos must have put
Reece into day care.
HemoAid in vascular procedures.
Have you heard of it?
‐ It's the artificial blood.
‐ Felt you might like in on it.
You don't mind if I step in
and take over a little bit?
Praise Allah, no!
Six OD's, three
in respiratory arrest.
‐ What is it?
‐ It's Chase.
He has probable brain damage.
Alright. So give it up.
Where are we going?
Actually, we're right here.
‐ We are?
‐ Uh‐huh.
Rock climbing?
Are you serious?
Well, you said you
wanted to get into shape
for Yosemite
this summer, so..
This is the bomb.
Jeanie, you're the best.
This place is packed.
Listen, I wanna talk
to you about this.
‐ Doug, a couple of chairs.
‐ Okay. Alright. Okay.
Hey, what happened to Carter?
'I don't know.
I found him that way.'
Yeah, he's really
filling out, isn't he?
Yeah, seventy‐fifth percentile
for full‐term his age.
Looks like you've
really gotten a handle
on this parenting routine.
You know what? It's easy.
I just make a schedule
and stick to it.
As a matter of fact, that's our
15 minutes of quality time.
Daycare for you
and a fem‐pop for me.
Hey, hey, hey, are you okay?
Are you ready?
Oh.
And a quick pit
stop at the showers.
Yeah, right. Oh, man.
Go ahead and laugh.
Alright, come on. Come here.
You got daddy. You got me.
You got me. Alright, say bye.
I'll see you guys later.
‐ 'Bye.'
Peter Benton the father.
You gotta see it to believe it.
Alright. Now, w‐w‐what
I've been thinking about‐‐
Carter? Carter! Carter!
‐ What?
‐ Your pager.
Oh, man.
It's the ER, of course.
I knew we wouldn't get
a chance to sit down.
Well, listen, if you still
wanna talk maybe we can catch
the Bulls‐Cavalier game
tonight at McGee's.
We haven't been out on
the town together in a while.
‐ Sure. Alright. Maybe.
‐ You can check with Carol.
I don't have to
ask her permission.
Oh, man!
‐ I tried to swerve around him.
‐ Please don't let him die.
Get me 8 units of HemoAid.
‐ Hemo‐what?
‐ Blood substitute.
‐ Grab consent forms.
‐ Where the hell is everyone?
‐ I've paged them all, twice.
‐ What's the situation?
Seventeen‐year‐old complaining
of neck pain
contusions and abrasions.
‐ Get this off of me.
‐ Try taking slow breaths.
‐ Check the next one.
‐ Yeah.
‐ What do we got?
‐ 20‐year‐old passenger.
No seat belt,
complaining of neck
left shoulder, chest
and abdominal pain.
'Questionable LOC
for several seconds.'
Up and over.
Check her vitals.
See if she's hypovolemic.
Need a cross‐table C‐spine,
chest and pelvis x‐rays
CBC, and dip a urine.
Was the transportation
time under half an hour?
Must've been. Accident
happened at Jackson and Loomis.
‐ Lungs are clear.
‐ I got the HemoAid.
‐ What's her name?
‐ Ann Witchger.
Ms. Witchger, I'm conducting
a potentially lifesaving
research project here in the ER.
Tell me, do you object
to the use of blood products?
Have they been
tested on animals?
Bowel sounds present.
Yes. I believe they have.
No. No animal testing.
‐ Pulse 100. Resps 20.
‐ BP's normal.
Where the hell's all
this blood coming from?
'Cow's blood?'
We got it from
a slaughterhouse.
‐ This is all cow's blood?
‐ I told you it was a bad idea.
We were on our way to protest
the university's use of
cats in their research labs.
We thought buckets of blood
would make an impression.
Mmm, it did.
Did you hear what these
girls were transporting?
‐ We just heard.
‐ What do you got?
One squirrel, DOA.
Oh.
Reminds me of "Carrie."
The movie, not the attending.
You're funny.
Speaking of movies,
can we go to the 7 o'clock?
I don't think I'm gonna
make it to the 9:20.
I thought we were
going tomorrow night.
I thought we
said tonight. Why?
Uh, well, no,
I just told Mark
that we'd watch
the Bulls game.
Oh, well,
it's a good time
for you to tell
him your decision.
We can, we can watch
the game anytime.
You know what? I think
you should see Mark.
Hey, Doug. I just got
a call from Neal Bernstein.
He said your ER
fellowship‐renewal
papers were
due two days ago.
‐ They were.
‐ You can't just blow this off.
If you want your fellowship
to continue‐‐
Kerry, maybe I don't want
my fellowship to continue.
Got a kid in Exam 4
with a pencil up his nose.
‐ We need to discuss this.
‐ Alright. We will.
‐ Hail, comrades!
‐ David!
We weren't expecting you
back until next month.
Well, I missed you
too damn much.
Look at this place. Looks just
exactly the way I remember it.
Well, actually, we have
made a few improvements.
Yeah, I saw you eyeing those.
Help yourself, Jerry.
I made those with my
very own two hands.
‐ It is Jerry, isn't it?
‐ Yeah, yeah.
Hey, David. You've
been gone a while.
One hundred and ninety
seven days. Give me a hug.
You're looking
trim there, Mark.
Thanks, you look
pretty good yourself.
You know, it‐it sounds hackneyed
but that
myocardial infarction
was the best thing that
ever happened to me.
Well, you know, I had intended
to prepare a summary report
to bring you up to speed.
No, no, no, no, Kerry.
We'll talk shop later.
I'm here to spend some
time in the trenches.
To get back in
touch with the people
that make this place tick.
Mark, what you got?
Thirty two‐year‐old female
high fever for five days.
You know, one of
the things I learned
from my brush
with mortality
is that every
patient has a story.
Let's go learn
hers, shall we?
Clamp distally,
then check for leaks
at the proximal anastomosis.
Is that you, Peter?
Elizabeth? What
are you doing here?
I just wanted to confirm
our plans for this evening
to work on
Rocket's lit review.
Uh, seven to nine thirty,
Biomed Library.
'Yeah, yeah.
I'll meet you there.'
How about nine thirty one
we grab a bite to eat?
Look, Elizabeth, I have to,
uh, prep for an operation.
So if you don't mind,
could you, uh..
We could work at my place
and get some takeout.
Look, I know you've been
wanting to see me naked.
But this isn't
the way, okay?
Ah. Ah. Thank you.
Thank you.
So, what's your answer?
Uh, yeah, yeah.
Dinner. Fine, fine.
Um, but I've gotta
prep for a, uh..
...pancreatic pseudocyst
so I'm not gonna be able to..
‐ Please, someone help me!
‐ We need a gurney over here!
‐ What happened?
‐ My wife is pregnant.
‐ She passed out.
‐ Okay. Easy.
‐ It's okay.
‐ Come on over here.
‐ Jerry, what's open?
‐ Curtain Area 3.
‐ How far along is she?
‐ Karen's 18 weeks.
But she's been having
a really rough time.
Karen, I'm Dr. Del Amico.
We're gonna do some
tests on you, okay?
Ready? One, two, three.
Please don't‐don't hurt my baby.
We're not gonna do anything
to your baby, don't worry.
Open up.
Uh, dry skin and mucous
membranes. She's dehydrated.
'Start a line and bolus
liter of saline.'
‐ BP's 120 palp.
‐ Get a CBC, Chem‐7, and a UA.
‐ She's got no veins.
‐ I'll do an IJ line.
You're gonna be okay now.
That's alright, Karen.
Okay, now, just grab that
left handhold and you're there.
Alright.
‐ Alright!
‐ Ready to lower.
Lowering.
Okay.
Did you really
only take two lessons?
Yeah, my instructor said that
women are more natural climbers.
It's all in
the hips or something.
That's great.
I think after that climb
you deserve a pop.
What are you,
chickening out on me?
No. I'm not chickening.
I just thought you
might be thirsty.
Nice try, pal. Your turn.
Good job, Scott.
You're making it look easy.
‐ I can't.
‐ You're doing great.
Let me down.
'There's a foothold right
by your left foot there.'
Let me down. I wanna come down.
Okay. Lowering.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't
have pushed so hard.
Did you hurt yourself?
We'll just take
a break, okay?
McGee's has those devil wings.
Come on. Hog Head McDunna's
$1.99 all‐you‐can‐eat taco bar
and live music
after the game?
Jerry, can you see that
these protocol summaries
make it into everyone's box?
For you, Dr. Corday,
it would be a pleasure.
‐ 'Elizabeth?'
‐ Yeah?
I was just looking
over your study
and I noticed that I'm listed
as the only faculty advisor.
Yes. Thanks for helping me
bring HemoAid to the ER.
I assumed that
Dr. Romano was involved.
Uh, he wanted to
stay more focused
on the surgical applications
of substitute blood.
I'm surprised that he let
you go ahead on your own.
Truth is, he
doesn't know yet.
Hmm. Trying to break free?
It's more like
branching out.
Do you mind being
the only advisor?
Not at all.
As far as I'm concerned,
the study's all yours.
Good.
She lost almost
six pounds last week.
BP's 100/60.
‐ I wanna go home.
‐ Please, honey.
Let them help you.
Her OB's had her on
a saltine cracker diet.
How is anyone supposed
to survive on that?
I cannot lose this baby.
'She's already had
three miscarriages.'
‐ Karen?
‐ She's out. Trendelenburg.
‐ Oh, I'm okay. I'm okay.
‐ It's okay.
Uh, let's add multivites
and put her on a monitor.
‐ Wait. It's‐it's alright.
‐ Why is this happening?
She should be past
morning sickness.
In some women,
nausea and vomiting
persist throughout
their pregnancy.
Nine months of this?
She'll never make it.
Once her labs come back, we'll
find out what options we have.
I want you to do whatever
it takes to save her.
I understand.
Rock climbing?
Were you planning to
outshine me this summer?
‐ I paged Doug Ross.
‐ Good.
Listen, I was just about
to start a splenorenal shunt.
But, uh, I can get
somebody to cover for me.
I don't think that's necessary.
Scott just overdid it.
It's cool, dad. Jeanie
will keep me company.
Alright. But you'll page me just
as soon as Doug's looked at him?
Don't worry. I will.
I plan on kicking
some serious butt
at the Investigators' quarterly.
Dayton Memorial
can't come close
to my HemoAid
transfusion rates.
Congratulations.
I'm releasing distally.
'Looks dry.'
Hope you don't feel
slighted that I'm involving
Lizzie in the study
instead of you.
No. Of course not.
Peter, I never noticed
what a good liar you are.
What are the branches
of the popliteal?
Anterior tibial, posterior
tibial and peroneal.
You're the man!
Now comes the fun part.
Release proximally
and we'll watch the river run.
Dr. Benton, the daycare
center's on the phone.
‐ Is it urgent?
‐ 'They want you to come up.'
Okay, uh, ask them,
uh, tell them‐‐
Tell them he's on his way.
I'll finish up here.
Priorities, Peter.
Someone paged me.
Dr. Corday, Dr. Morgenstern.
Multiple GSWs to
the chest and abdomen.
Storeowner in his late 70s.
Shot with
a small‐caliber firearm.
BP, 70 palp. Pulse ox
falling, 92 on 15 liters.
His name's Won Sok Jang.
‐ 'Transport time?'
‐ 20 minutes.
Any relatives with him,
anyone to give consent?
‐ No.
‐ Ten blade.
He's a perfect candidate.
Get me four units HemoAid.
‐ He's getting cyanotic.
‐ Muffled heart sounds.
Neck vein distension.
Probable pericardial tamponade.
‐ Shall I?
‐ I've got it.
Pericardiocentesis tray.
Stick an alligator clamp
on that V‐1 lead.
BP's down to 40 palp.
Worked hard his
whole life for this.
‐ Pulse ox, 88.
‐ 'He's bradying down.'
David?
‐ Rate's 30.
‐ David?
I'm losing a pulse.
Uh, sorry. I‐I‐I've
got something in my eye.
Could you?
Got it.
Who the hell was that?
Our chief of
Emergency Medicine.
Hey, nurse, uh, I was called
down for a rule‐out appy.
‐ Dr. Carter is in Exam 3.
‐ What are you doing with those?
Taking them to Dr. Corday.
‐ Lizzie, what are you doing?
‐ Dr. Romano..
I didn't authorize the use
of HemoAid in the ER.
Uh, I've been trying to tell you
I moved ahead with an ER study.
‐ 'He's got a rhythm.'
‐ 'Faint pulse.'
And who said you could do that?
Dr. Greene signed on
as my faculty advisor.
‐ 'Dopamine, titrate‐‐'
‐ I see.
‐ I'd like to explain.
‐ Let's repeat a crit.
Well, I haven't moved my office.
I feel a lot better now.
That's because we
rehydrated you.
But with hyperemesis gravidarum,
the vomiting could continue
throughout your pregnancy
or even get worse.
I‐I can handle it.
Well, your labs
indicate that your
kidneys aren't
functioning properly.
And you have a low
potassium level
which could cause
cardiac arrhythmia.
I don't know what
Dave said to you
but I'm not giving
up this baby.
I'm not suggesting that.
But there are drugs available
which could reduce the vomiting.
But my OB said that drugs
could put my baby at risk.
There is that possibility.
But endangering your health
also puts your baby at risk.
I'm sure you'll
make a great mother.
But physically, you just
might not be able to be one
without some
medical intervention.
Would you take the drugs?
Yes, I would.
I can't.
Think about it.
If your condition worsens,
uh, your life could be at risk.
Hey, Doug, you ever been
to Hog Head McDunna's?
Great taco bar,
listen, I'm gonna have to
take a rain check on tonight.
Listen, Carol
can come along..
Hey, Dr. Ross, Anspaugh
wants you on the phone.
Oh, okay. Listen, I still
need to talk to you though.
We'll need a record of his
vitals after every bag was hung.
‐ You got it.
‐ Dr. Corday.
Uh, this is Lindsey Jang.
He is, um, your patient's son.
Uh, Mr. Jang, I'm sorry.
I wasn't aware any
relatives had arrived.
How's my father?
Well, he's being
taken to surgery.
His heart stopped, but we
were able to resuscitate him.
Did it stop because you
gave him fake blood?
No.
In fact, he
responded quite well.
One of the benefits
of HemoAid is that
it can transport oxygen to areas
where blood or saline can't‐‐
Who gave you
permission to do that?
I've got a consult.
Would you excuse me?
Good luck, Mr. Jang. Lizzie.
Mr. Jang, yes, we did use
an experimental product
on your father, but it
was intended to help him.
Here's some literature
explaining the protocol
being used.
He should've
gotten real blood.
‐ He did. If you'd just read‐‐
‐ I don't care about your study!
If he dies, I'm
holding you responsible.
‐ Hey, buddy. How you feeling?
‐ A little better.
Uh, listen, can I talk to you
outside just for a second?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Mm‐hmm. Okay.
I wanna hear.
‐ Uh..
‐ Okay.
Okay. Alright.
Uh, your labs indicate
that you're pancytopenic.
'It means you have very
low blood cell counts.'
'Well, how low?'
We're gonna tap the bone marrow
see if it's producing cells.
Also, you'll have
to get transfusions
'and we're gonna have to
put you in an isolation room.'
Okay, you know, Doug,
maybe we should talk outside.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
‐ Alright?
Yeah. We'll be back.
A bone‐marrow biopsy?
He could have the flu.
Flu wouldn't lower his
white cell count as much.
Well, his counts probably
haven't come back much
because of the chemo.
It's only been a few weeks‐‐
Jeanie, he needs the biopsy.
Well, I've seen
Scott at his worst.
You know, I'm sure
Dr. Anspaugh would agree‐‐
Dr. Anspaugh,
I already talked to.
And he said to move forward.
Okay. I'll, uh, I'll set
up Exam 4 for isolation.
‐ Alright.
‐ Okay.
Uh, about Scott's pain..
I'll take care of it.
Natalie Logan.
Off with one hat,
on with the other.
Hey, Yosh. Can you cover
me at the clinic tomorrow?
‐ Sure. Count me in.
‐ Great.
Nurse Hathaway.
‐ Hi, Natalie.
‐ Hi.
Does your dad wanna
come back for this?
‐ Oh, no, it's okay.
‐ It's not a problem.
Mark, have you seen
David Morgenstern?
No. And I'd rather not.
He just spent an hour with
my puncture wound patient
talking to her about her
collection of antique creamers.
He might have come back
to work a little early.
Oh, we need to discuss this
Doug Ross situation
at some point.
What situation?
Well, it sounds like he's not
coming back next year.
Does your father know
you're here for birth control?
Um, not exactly.
You won't tell him,
will you?
Not if you don't want me to.
How have your periods been
since your last
progesterone injection?
Light.
Any pain, leg cramps,
visual changes, weight gain?
Are you using condoms to prevent
sexually transmitted disease?
Sometimes my
boyfriend forgets.
It's your responsibility too.
‐ Yeah, I know.
‐ Alright.
Here's your
follow‐up reminder.
Have you come back
in three months.
And here are some
condoms. Use them.
I will. Thank you.
‐ Okay. Bye.
‐ 'Bye.'
John? You never returned
my call last night.
Sorry. I need to get
a new answering machine.
You also need sleep.
You look like the walking dead.
It's insomnia. I get it
every once in a while.
Yeah? Try this
for a quick fix.
‐ Doctor.
‐ Huh?
Just wanted to say
thanks for nothing.
I'm sorry, Mr. Fearn.
But your wife's not ready to‐‐
Save it for
your priest, okay?
You know what,
the minute I saw your name
I should've asked
for someone else.
‐ My name?
‐ You're Catholic, right?
What does that have
to do with anything?
Do you get extra
points for putting
a baby's life
ahead of my wife's?
‐ Is that how it works?
‐ Excuse me, uh‐‐
No, no, no. I‐I, I am Catholic.
And I'm Italian.
A‐and I'm a woman.
And I'm from South Philly.
And I'm a doctor.
And I have done
everything in my power
to help your wife
and your child.
Dave.
Listen, be patient.
Let her make her decision.
Hey, what's this I hear about
you not coming back next year?
‐ Leave it to Weaver.
‐ So it's true?
I've been trying to tell you.
I'm not renewing my fellowship.
'Cause I'm applying for
an attending position.
‐ Yeah.
‐ I can't be a fellow forever.
I don't know. You were on
your way to convincing me.
The only problem is
County General doesn't have
a Pedes ER Attending position.
Maybe it should.
A third of the cases
that come in here
one‐third of them are pediatric
but there's nobody
overseeing it.
Well, I wouldn't go that far.
So, a Pediatric Attending
would increase the care, right?
‐ So you're serious?
‐ Mm‐hmm. Yeah.
Doug, we're ready
for that biopsy.
Yeah, okay.
You back me up.
‐ Hey, Mark.
‐ Elizabeth.
I hear you got your
first HemoAid candidate.
Yeah. And lost him again.
No thanks to Dr. Romano.
‐ What'd he do?
‐ That's not important.
What can I say,
he's a jerk.
Actually, that
was perfectly put.
Don't let him get to you.
And if you need a backup,
give me a holler.
'Thanks.'
‐ Peter, what's wrong?
‐ Ah...Reece has a fever.
I've gotta get him
over to Carla's
and my damn car won't start.
Plus I've got
an ileectomy scheduled.
Well, I could take him.
My car's here.
Uh, you know, uh..
...I don't think that
would be a good idea.
‐ Come on, Reece.
‐ I'm a good driver, Peter.
Yeah, I know. I, I just
think it'd be awkward.
Well, fine. You drive and I'll
keep this little one company.
‐ Hello, sweetheart.
‐ Well, we could, uh..
Alright, we could just make it.
Uh, go get your coat.
Okay.
‐ Are you looking for a student?
‐ Uh, no. I see him. Thank you.
‐ Bull's‐eye.
‐ Kerry.
It's not wise
to sneak up on a man
when he's got
a needle in his hand.
I wanted to check on your eye.
Uh, much better, thank you.
Saline did the trick.
And after six months,
I figured it couldn't
hurt to brush up
on my anatomy.
Well, everyone can benefit
from that on occasion.
Do you ever think about
patients when you work on them?
You know, their, their
hopes, their dreams?
Honestly...no.
I never did.
But today, in that trauma
room all I could think about
was that old
grocer's life
and how he was
relying on me.
I don't know if you
heard, but...last month
I suffered a grand mal seizure
during a hazmat incident‐‐
‐ Then you know.
‐ Know what?
About perspective, about..
...looking at the big picture.
I know that
the big picture can be humbling
maybe even
destructive to one's focus
and‐and sense of confidence.
Nonsense.
Kerry Weaver,
meet John DeLeo.
Welder, father of five.
Never retired despite
crippling arthritis
outlived three of his kids,
never left Chicago.
You know all that
about this cadaver?
No. I made it up.
But if I did know, it wouldn't
make me less focused.
It would make me
a better doctor.
You're almost there.
‐ 'Crux of the climb.'
‐ 'Mm‐hmm.'
'Just a few hundred feet to go.'
Your fingers search
across the blank rock
till you find
the perfect handhold.
You feel it?
I've got it.
Okay, Scott.
'I'm gonna put the needle
in now, buddy. Okay?'
Okay.
All you gotta do is
just hold on and breathe.
You're almost there.
You're almost to the top.
Okay, I got you.
It's okay, Scott. Hang on.
Hold on. Okay.
After the E light comes on
I have almost an entire day's
worth of petrol left.
Look, I'm not gonna
risk running out of gas
in the middle of Garfield Park.
For your sake, Reece,
I hope you don't
'inherit your father's
stubbornness.'
When we get
to Carla's restaurant
I'm gonna have to
double‐park and run in.
So you don't mind
waiting out in the car, do you?
Are you still
in love with her? Carla?
What are you talking about?
It was never love.
But you're worried about
her seeing us together.
‐ I'm not worried.
‐ Is it because I'm white?
Excuse me?
Well, we spend time together,
there's a chemistry
but there's an obstacle,
is it a racial problem?
Elizabeth, I don't even know
how to respond to that. I mean..
Damn!
‐ Are you okay? Reece?
‐ Yeah, we're fine.
Damn it!
Oh, my God!
Okay, okay, okay. Here we go.
Elizabeth, call 911!
Hold on. Hold on. Here we go.
‐ What do you got?
‐ Auto versus pedestrian.
‐ BP's okay.
‐ Dr. Corday?
130/85.
Yes, we got involved, um,
in a bit of an accident.
‐ We're here, Miss Ingram.
‐ Finally.
‐ Are you okay?
‐ Yes.
Dr. Benton was
involved as well.
Involved? He ran into me.
‐ Reece was with him.
‐ I got it.
'I was on my lunch break.
I need to call my boss.'
‐ Peter, you okay?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Let me get it.
‐ No. I got it. Come on.
Pulse is 160. Resps 32.
He was crying
right after it happened.
Now he's become somnolent.
‐ What happened, Peter?
‐ I backed into a pedestrian.
Reece was in the back seat.
I think he's okay.
He was in his car seat.
‐ Alright. We'll check him out.
‐ Okay, okay, okay.
‐ Anna, can you take a look?
‐ Of course.
Hey, how's the pedestrian?
Don't worry.
She's in good hands.
‐ He feels warm.
‐ Yeah, he had a fever earlier.
‐ Hey, little fellow.
‐ No, no, no.
Let's get a CT of his head,
neck and abdomen first.
Peter, will you let me
look at that head lac?
We'll let Anna
check out Reece.
‐ No, it's okay. I'm fine.
‐ 'Peter, go with him.'
‐ 'It's okay.'
‐ It's fine.
Okay, let's get a CBC,
type and cross for four.
Let's get a chest and a pelvis.
‐ Dip a urine for blood.
‐ I have to get to work.
Someone's calling
your boss for you.
Harbilas and Kleiderman
Law Offices.
‐ Yeah. We got it.
‐ How is she?
Superficial lacs, multiple
contusions and abrasions.
Pulse ox, 99.
I checked her in the ambulance.
Her abdomen's benign.
‐ Okay. Now, does this hurt?
‐ Yes!
You were more worried
about your sick kid
than looking
where you were going.
I tried to explain
to her that you were‐‐
Peritoneal lavage tray.
I don't think
that's necessary.
Peter, Peter, you really
shouldn't be in here. Come on.
Has the trauma team
been paged?
Peter.
‐ Come on!
‐ Do it.
I should go check on Reece.
Anna's taking care
of him. Sit down.
‐ Did you lose consciousness?
‐ No. No. I was barely moving.
Well, it doesn't need sutures.
I never even saw her. She must
have been in my blind spot.
Well, don't beat yourself up.
It was an accident.
‐ Damn it! I'm missing surgery.
‐ Hey, Peter. Reece is fine.
‐ Did you get a CT?
‐ 'It's not necessary.'
Normal fundi.
He's alert and interactive.
Malik's giving him a bottle.
‐ Uh, thanks, Anna.
‐ 'Sure.'
Stay still.
‐ Damn it! Romano.
‐ 'Hold on. Hold on. Hold on.'
Stay still.
Okay.
Dr. Romano!
Peter, where the hell
have you been?
Brin's been screaming
bloody murder.
Yeah, I was in a car accident.
I hit a pedestrian.
What were you doing out on
the town when you had surgery?
Dr. Romano,
I'm afraid Peter may have
brought you down here
for nothing.
Surgical consults
for your victim?
Uh, yes.
Let's see what kind of
damage you've wrought.
Elizabeth, what did you
tell that woman about me?
We were in
the ambulance together
she wanted to know
what happened.
She works for a damn lawyer.
Dr. Benton, these two
would like to question you
about the accident.
Oh..
‐ Hi, Jeanie.
‐ Hello.
Doug told me about
Dr. Anspaugh's son.
‐ 'How's he doing?'
‐ He's holding up.
'I wanted to tell you
I opened up the clinic'
so the staff can get tested
as possible marrow donors.
Jerry's e‐mailed
the other floors
and Anna's making up flyers.
It's a nice gesture,
Carol, but‐‐
I know it's gonna be
hard to find a match
but people wanna
do something.
Well, I appreciate it.
It's just a little premature.
I mean, his biopsy results
aren't even back yet.
Let's just give the kid
a chance, you know.
The pump is computerized,
so it's gonna release
the exact amount
of pain medication
whenever you push the button.
So you're calling
the shots, alright?
Can I OD if I press
this thing too much?
It's programmed to lock out
so that won't happen.
‐ Doug.
‐ Yeah.
Alright. Be back.
I'm kind of in the middle
of something here.
Donald Anspaugh called.
He's concerned about
putting Scott on PCA.
He called you?
He wanted to know
what the ER's policy was.
I told him we didn't have one
because I was unaware
that you were
using PCA on kids.
‐ Well, I am.
‐ You should've told me.
I didn't know that I had to
ask your permission.
‐ Keep me informed.
‐ Would you have told me not to?
Doug, I'm not asking you
to answer to me.
‐ Just speak up.
‐ Okay.
This is why we need
a pedes attending.
I'll talk to Anspaugh myself,
if that's okay with you?
So, what'd Romano
say about her belly?
He agreed with Corday.
It's benign.
‐ And her labs?
‐ They're not back yet.
Carter, you gotta
stay on top of this one, okay?
Scary, isn't it?
I mean, one second,
one‐one mistake
and your whole life
just changes just like that.
Has she had
any other complaints?
Yeah, she's got a headache.
But I don't think it's anything.
Alright. Order a CT.
‐ A CT?
‐ Yeah. Just do it, okay?
'No, no.
He's been a real trouper.'
That's my good boy.
Peter, there you are.
It's just a minor accident.
Come on. Come on. He's fine.
‐ What about you?
‐ It's not as bad as it looks.
You know, I was getting gas.
And then all of a sudden‐‐
‐ Yes. Elizabeth filled me in.
‐ Just the highlights.
Well, I should really
be getting Reece home.
Thank you again
for taking care of him.
You're very welcome.
You feel better now, Reece.
Hey. Call me if he becomes
irritable or lethargic, okay?
‐ I will. I will.
‐ Alright. See you.
She takes things
in her stride.
Like what?
Peter, you've
just got to relax.
You know, if I had taken the El
or waited for that taxi
or got my damn car fixed,
none of this would've happened.
Yeah, you mean, if only I
hadn't got involved. That's it.
Elizabeth, I didn't say that.
No. You didn't have to.
Diagnosis, too many bologna
and cheese sandwiches.
And too many hours
in front of video games.
‐ Fleets enema?
‐ Yeah.
And the number of
the local cub scout pack.
Boys need activities.
Stay fit, make friends,
have fun, all at the same time.
‐ You came back.
‐ Why wouldn't I?
Dr. Weaver,
I'm losing a pulse on Plazik!
What's his history?
Presented with pyloric stenosis
secondary to
chronic ulcer disease.
Ate a big lunch,
followed by bad heartburn.
‐ He take any meds?
‐ Just bicarb. Baking soda.
‐ He's bradying down.
‐ Probably vasovagal.
Do you think the CO2
from the bicarb
is distending in his stomach?
Damn!
‐ Esophageal strictures.
‐ Here. David, let me try.
No. I can't get it either.
Get me an 18‐gauge needle.
‐ And a syringe.
‐ What are you doing?
We gotta decompress him
or he's gonna explode.
Are you sure?
Pulse is coming back.
Excellent work, doctor.
‐ Thanks for doing this, Mark.
‐ Thank you.
The bone‐marrow drive
is a great idea.
I'm glad you and Doug
are going out tonight.
He's really
looking forward to it.
What do you mean?
He canceled on me.
You're kidding. I told him
we could cancel tonight.
Excuse me.
Natalie? Is there a problem?
‐ Are you "C. Hathaway, R. N."?
‐ That's me.
I'm Natalie's mother,
Abbey Logan.
I found your
clinic follow‐up note..
...along with these.
Natalie won't talk to me.
So I thought you might.
Well, confidentiality laws
prevent me from discussing
Natalie's medical history.
'I just wanna know what's
going on with my daughter.'
I understand that.
Maybe I can answer some
questions for Natalie
in private that'll make her
more willing to discuss this.
‐ Whatever you can do.
‐ Okay. Come on.
Lizzie, Lizzie, Lizzie.
I had no idea it was
so important to you
to have your own
piece of the pie.
I didn't intend to
go behind your back.
Oh, no. Never apologize
for being ambitious.
I just wish you'd
spend your time on a study
that was more respectable.
Respectable?
Foisting substitute blood
on hapless John Does in the ER
and without their consent,
is a bit morally ambiguous
don't you think?
So you're concerned
for my soul.
Among other things,
how'd you like to become
the Chicago area coordinator
for the HemoAid OR study?
You are joking.
Drug company's
expanding the new science
and they've asked me
to oversee it.
If you join me,
you'll leap up the ladder
from worker bee to queen bee,
what do you say?
It's a generous offer.
Is it contingent on me
dropping my ER study?
I can't imagine
you'd have time for both.
Think about it.
Your parents obviously care.
Trust me.
This would seriously
flip them out.
Maybe it would reassure them
to know you're being responsible
about birth control and STDs.
Yeah, but you're not
gonna tell them, right?
I can't tell them,
and I won't.
Okay.
But sometimes it's worse
when you shut out
the people who care.
And your mother is concerned.
Your father brought you here.
That wasn't my father.
That man who you
saw me with earlier..
...he's my teacher.
Natalie, are you having
sex with your teacher?
It's not like he forces me
to or anything like that.
I mean, we really
love each other, you know?
It's just
we gotta keep it quiet.
'Because if Jim's wife
found out‐‐'
‐ He's married?
‐ Yeah.
But she's real unstable,
his wife.
'So he can't
tell her just yet.'
But when I'm 18,
Jim's gonna get a divorce.
This teacher of yours, Jim,
he's what? About 40 years old?
About that.
Natalie, what he's
doing is illegal.
No. No. I love him.
And he loves me. It's simple.
No. It's definitely not simple.
Biopsy results came in.
‐ And?
‐ Cancer's back.
How bad?
Lymphomas in the bone marrow.
That's why he was so anemic.
I told him
it was all behind him.
He made it through this before.
He can do it again.
But this means
bone‐marrow transplant.
Mm‐hmm, and more chemo, he also
gonna have to be isolated
'cause there's
a greater chance of infection.'
I did contact the National
Bone Marrow Registry.
His father or his
sister could match.
Does he know yet?
'No. I was about
to go tell him.'
'His dad's in there
with him right now.'
'I thought you'd
like to come along.'
No. I think they should
have some time alone.
You know,
I'll be by later.
Alright. Sorry.
'Well, I'm pleased
to say, Mr. Jang'
it looks like you've made it
through with flying colors.
He doesn't understand
English very well.
I just wanted to see
how he was doing.
My father wants to thank you
for helping save his life.
You're very welcome.
I told him
about your blood study
and even though I still
have reservations..
...he'd like to know
more about it.
Well, certainly.
With your help, of course.
Should you be here?
So how are you feeling?
Better. I'd like to go home now.
Well, as soon as
we're sure you're fine.
Your CT came back negative.
But these labs indicate
an elevated amylase and lipase.
‐ Dr. Benton.
‐ Oh, Carter.
You missed something
in Miss Ingram's labs.
This level indicates
a pancreatic injury.
No. You missed something.
‐ BAL?
‐ 0.16.
Did you consume
any alcoholic beverages
'during your lunch break?'
Great news. Mr. Jang's
decided to remain in my study.
That's terrific.
I guess you won't
need help from me after all.
Uh, well actually,
I will still need your support
if I'm to make
a go of this.
‐ You having second thoughts?
‐ No. No. I'm staying put.
It may not be
the smartest political move
but it feels like
the right thing to do.
Are you behind this marrow
drive? I'm very touched.
Actually, it was
Carol Hathaway's idea.
How did Scott
take the news?
That boy continues
to surprise me.
He is determined
to beat this thing.
He has a spirit
I haven't seen before.
Have you told Scott
about your own health status?
No. Of course not.
I didn't think so.
Somehow he senses something.
Respects you
as a kindred spirit.
Anyway, I know
he's eager to see you.
I wonder how many
donors actually match
for a bone‐marrow transplant?
I heard less than one percent.
I guess I won't wait
by the phone.
How's Chase?
Still pretty early.
You know Chase.
When can I visit him?
You know, Kenner's kind of
strict about visitors.
I know. Just tell him
I said hi.
You bet.
Your turn.
'You know,
she confided in me'
'cause she thought
her secret was safe.
Providing access
to birth control is one thing
sexual abuse
is something else.
Well, I just hope it doesn't
scare off the other kids
from coming in
to the clinic.
She did the right thing
by coming in here, you know?
‐ This is one unique case.
‐ Well, let's hope.
This guy's a 40‐year‐old man,
he's a teacher, he's married
and he's having sex
with a minor.
'Carol, a policewoman's
asking for you.'
Says you got
a crime to report?
Yeah. I'll be right there.
As she sobered up,
she thought twice about
getting any lawyers involved?
Her exact words were
"I wanna crawl under a rock
and pretend
like this never happened."
Yeah, well,
she's not the only one.
‐ You were lucky, hon.
‐ 'Peter!'
I thought I'd missed you.
Oh, hi.
Listen, I ran into Dr. Brin
and I convinced him
to let me assist
on a thyroidectomy
in the morning, and, uh..
...I wanna go and check
on Reece on my way home
so I think we should
cancel tonight.
Yeah, I assumed that.
I need my car keys.
Thank you, Peter.
It was a thrill
to see you in action again.
We make a good team,
you and I.
I'm sorry if I was
presumptive before.
You're a conscientious
person, Kerry.
It makes you a good doctor
and a good manager.
Well, I tried to fill the void
while you were on leave.
And surpassed me.
Probably because
of your sincere interest
in all things administrative.
I never gave a damn
about the bureaucracy before.
Didn't...interest me then.
And now?
And now...
everything interests me.
Carol, Anna, you two
have plans this evening?
No, I did, and then I didn't,
and now I don't know anymore.
I'm free. Why?
Do you fancy a girls'
night at my place?
‐ I make a mean cosmopolitan.
‐ That sounds good.
‐ Sounds great.
‐ Say 8 o'clock?
‐ Good.
‐ Okay.
I, uh, don't know
what you two are doing
but I have plans
this evening.
So have fun.
Together again.
Jeanie.
It's okay.
I've made women cry before.
How are you feelin'?
Well, this helps.
Are you sure you're not being
Mr. Tough Guy like earlier?
No. I really feel better.
Good.
My dad said that you could
come to Yosemite with us..
...if you wanted to, I mean.
Yeah, I'd like to.
Hey, the Bone Marrow Registry..
...found eight people who
preliminarily match
your marrow type.
Eight?
That's my lucky number.
We still have further matching
to do, you know? But..
Hey, it's a start. Right?
Yeah. It's a start.
Seven brothers,
seven sister‐in‐laws
twelve nieces and nephews.
‐ Number 13 on the way.
‐ Oh, my God!
You're considered
the family freak.
Oh, please, my aunt Tessa
bursts into tears
'every time she sees me.'
Well, my parents cope
by treating me..
...like a bachelor son.
Oh, come on, your families
must be very proud of you two.
Oh, sure they are.
But you, Carol, have
something that I really envy.
What?
A sex life!
Cheers to that!
I have no complaints
in that department.
Give us a little
something more than that.
Oh, please. Please.
Let's live vicariously, please.
You wanna hear
about my sex life?
‐ Yes! Yes!
‐ 'Okay.'
What do you wanna know?
Oh. Hold that thought.
Pizza's here.
‐ Let me get it.
‐ No, no. No. I've got it.
‐ Oh, Peter?
‐ Hey.
Look, I know I should've
called first, but I, uh..
‐ You were right.
‐ I was?
Yeah. I do have a problem
dating white women.
You know, actually, this
isn't really the time..
No, no, no. Listen to me.
I mean, there's a lot of stuff
you don't understand and..
Hey, Elizabeth,
do you need some more...money?
I didn't know
you had company.
‐ Hi, Peter.
‐ Bye, Peter.
It was a spur‐of‐the‐moment
sort of thing, you know.
Oh, no.
You don't need to explain.
Peter, uh, maybe we could
do it some other time
now that you know
where I live.
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, cuz.
What you watching?
CNN?
Anything going on in the world
that I should know about?
Here.
I brought you something.
It's Walker Evans.
A complete retrospective
of his work.
I think there's a photograph
in here that you'll love..
...if I can find it.
Evening, John.
Hi, Joyce.
Why, Chase, look at that book
your cousin brought you.
Wha..
'Okay, Chase.'
'Take a sip.'
Oh, no! Your book!
That's okay. Book's fine.
Book's fine.
He's been having
more trouble with that hand.
There you go.
Not a perfect match,
but it'll do.
Thanks, Joyce.
'There we go.'
You want to try it?
Okay, okay.
Hey, I'll do it. I'll do it.