On your right. On
your right. On your right.
Back, back, back, back,
back. Come on, buddy.
Yeah, Dan! Yeah!
Yea! Yea!
Back, back, back, back,
back. Watch the winger!
Yeah!
You okay?
Dan? Dan, talk to me.
Dan. Dan.
Get a doctor!
- Hey.
- Close the door.
Close the door.
Is Cuddy down the
hall counting to 50?
She knows I'm in here, in
the clinic, as she commanded.
- She just doesn't know I'm alone.
- Well, you've got a full waiting room.
How long do you think
you can ignore them?
I'm off at 4:00.
You're doing this to
avoid five minutes of work?
If I go out there, I get assigned
a kid with a runny nose.
That's 30 seconds looking at the nose,
25 minutes talking to a worried mom...
who won't leave until she's
sure it's not meningitis or a tumor.
Yes. Concerned parents
can be so annoying.
Just tell Cuddy you've
got an urgent case.
You had to leave early.
That would be lying.
And that would be wrong. But luckily
the definition of "urgent" is fungible.
Not the definition
of “case" though.
You have no cases?
You've got handpicked
doctors— specialists—
Working for you, and
they're sitting on their hands?
- Cameron's answering my mail.
- Oh, time well spent, I'm sure.
Foreman and Chase?
Research?
Nine letters. Iodine
deficiency in children.
Cretinism.
So, 4:03 p.m.,
Dr. House checks out.
Please write that down.
Dr. House. Sorry.
Done for the day.
Plenty of docs here to take care
of you. But we had an appointment.
Nice try, but this is a walk-in clinic,
which means there are no appointments.
You walk in, sign the chart,
and a doctor will see you.
Just not me. Your letter
says that we'd see you.
Not a big letter writer. Here.
When did my
signature get so girlie?
- I can explain.
- See that "G"?
See how it makes
a big loop on top?
Doesn't even look like my
handwriting. Think I have something?
What's the differential diagnosis for
writing G's like a junior high school girl?
It's impossible to
get to you through
normal channels. They
have called, e-mailed.
Perseverance does not
equal worthiness. Next time
you want to get my
attention, wear something fun.
Low-rider jeans are hot.
Sixteen-year-old male.
Sudden onset of double
vision and night terrors,
with no apparent cause.
The kid's been to two
neurologists, and he— Night terrors?
- As in big scary monsters?
- Yes.
- Where are you going?
- To see the family.
- You're going to examine a patient?
- Nine times out of 10,
there's no reason to talk to a patient.
But night terrors in a 16-year-old is a
very good reason to talk to this family.
Good work.
Margins are fine.
No lesions.
Color is good.
How long have you been
having night terrors? Three weeks.
He's afraid to go to bed. He's
exhausted, can barely function.
- What does that tell you?
- Nothing. It's just fun
watching him blink.
Name as many animals as you
can that begin with the letter "B." Go.
- Baby elephant?
- Baby elephant is actually
a good answer.
- "B" is a bear of a letter.
- What does that tell you?
Proves two things: no
neurological damage,
and your son is never
gonna be chief fry cook.
In teens, there are two
likely causes of night terrors.
- Posttraumatic stress. Any recent
shoot-outs at your high school?
- No.
- Then, Dave— - Dan.
If there's no trauma, the
other cause is... sexual abuse.
So who's molesting you? Teacher?
Extra-friendly neighbor? I'd ask if either
of you were involved, but you’d deny it.
We would never hurt Dan.
I say it here, it
comes out there.
This lack of response
is consistent with abuse.
There's no one, okay? I—I swear.
There was trauma. I got hit in
the head during a lacrosse game.
Did you know that
he got hit in the head?
- They didn't mention it. No.
- Yeah. Why bother?
No, no. We took him to
the E.R. after the game.
He was scanned. They tested
him. They said he was fine.
No concussion. It's
gotta be something else.
You hound me for my opinion,
and then you question my diagnosis.
Cool. E.R. obviously screwed
up. Kid's got a concussion.
I had double vision before I was
hit. Well, that changes everything.
You need glasses. That's
why you had double vision,
which is why you got hit,
which is why you have a
concussion, which is
why you have night terrors.
You need to see an
ophthalmologist, which I am not.
You enjoyed that. I brought
a reasonable case to your
attention, and you shoved it
in my face just to humiliate me.
You're an only child, aren't
you? Why would you say that?
Because everything is about you.
This may seem incredibly controversial,
but I think sexual abuse is bad.
I just wanted to make sure he wasn't
being diddled by Daddy—or Mommy.
Anything else is just a bonus.
I'm not an only
child. Interesting.
What? Don't move.
- Did I bore you in there?
- What? Uh, no. Not— Not really.
Are you tired?
- Sometimes.
- He never sleeps. Of course he's tired.
- Right now. At this moment. Are you tired?
- No. No.
That twitch in your
leg. Did you feel that?
- Didn't hurt.
- His leg twitched. I don't see what...
It's called a myoclonic jerk. It's very
common when you're falling asleep.
Respiration rate falls, and
the brain sometimes interprets
this as the body dying, so it
sends a pulse to wake it up.
- So?
- So, he's not asleep.
He's awake.
Admit him.
I recognize that loopy "G."
So, what does the jerk tell us?
Nothing good. The brain's
losing control of the body.
Can't order the eyes to focus, regulate
sleep patterns or control muscles.
A movement disorder or a
degenerative brain disease.
Either way, this kid's gonna be picking
up his diploma in diapers and a wheelchair.
Maybe not that bad.
Could be an infection.
You wish. No fever,
no white count.
Anyone think this
differential diagnosis might be
compromised because we don't
have an accurate family history?
- I took an accurate family history.
- You didn't even take an accurate family.
- His father's not his father.
- Why would you say that?
Thirty percent of all dads don't realize
they're raising someone else's kid.
False paternity's more like 10%. That's
what our moms would like us to believe.
Who cares? If he got it from
his parents, they'd both be dead.
- Can we get on with
the differential diagnosis?
- Fifty bucks says I'm right.
- I'll take your money.
- Hit a nerve?
- Don't worry. I'm sure the guy who
tucked you in was your daddy.
- Make it a hundred.
What about leukoencephalopathy
in a 1 6-year-old?
It doesn't necessarily
have to be that bad.
If we exclude the night terrors,
it could be something systemic.
His liver, kidneys.
Something outside the brain.
Yes.
- Feel free to exclude any symptom
if it makes your job easier.
- Night terrors were anecdotal.
- He could've had a bad dream.
- No. Parents said he was conscious during
and didn't remember anything afterwards.
- That's a night terror.
- Parents said?
That's a good point.
Before we condemn this kid, maybe we
should entertain Dr. Chase's skepticism.
I want a detailed polysomnograph. If he's
having night terrors, I want to see them.
I usually don't move
during night terrors.
I'm not restraining
you for them.
E.E.G. revealed
abnormalities in your brain...
Caused nerve
damage in your toes.
What are you doing?
- Fixing it.
- Can I talk to my parents?
Oh, they know all about this.
I'd really like to see them.
Please. I'd really
like them here.
This is gonna hurt, Dan.
Oh. Oh, God.
That's a night terror.
We did a C. T., M.R.I., C. B.
C., CHEM-7 and chest X-ray.
All the tests came back normal.
There's nothing to explain his symptoms.
Okay, but let's pretend
there's something and go
from there. Who sees
something on this M.R.I.?
No lesions in the white matter.
No structural abnormalities.
No space-occupying tumors.
He's 16, so he should
have an absolutely
pristine brain. The
smallest thing is abnormal.
Meningeal enhancement.
- My bet is viral meningitis.
- Excellent.
Do you see what he did there?
Took a small clue that
there's a neurological
problem and wasn't
afraid to run with it.
There's no evidence of
meningitis on that M.R.I.
No, there's not. He's
completely wrong.
Then what clue are
you talking about?
He knew that I saw
something on the M.R.I., so he
figured there must be
something there and took a guess.
- Clever, but also pathetic.
- So what did you find?
Take a close look at
the corpus callosum.
- Looks okay.
- Are we all looking at the same thing?
Two hundred million
interhemispheric nerve fibers.
The George Washington Bridge between
the left and right side of the brain.
It's subtle.
There's some bowing. There.
An upward arch.
Are you guessing?
Yes.
- Too bad. You're right.
- He probably just moved.
Nobody stays perfectly
still for the entire M.R.I.
Yeah. Probably got restless
and shifted one hemisphere
of his brain to a more
comfortable position.
Something is pushing on it. If
there was bowing, could be a tumor.
Do you see a tumor on this M.R.I.?
No, but I don't see any bowing either.
There's no tumor. Just a blockage
causing pressure causing symptoms.
Today, night terrors. Tomorrow,
he's bleeding out of his eyes.
Get him a radionucleotide cisternogram.
I guarantee you'll see a blockage.
Okay.
Easy.
Okay. Squeeze my hand.
All right. Squeeze hard.
All right.
Now I'm injecting a material
that's tagged with a radioisotope.
It's gonna enter your spine
and travel up to your brain.
It'll make you able to
think deep thoughts,
run a hundred miles an hour.
Easy.
Their eyes aren't the same
color, but that fleck in the eyes—
That's maybe a one-in-10
chance if they're not related?
No. House isn't gonna
pay you based on that.
Any excuse we can give the
folks to justify a D.N.A. test?
We could tell them he's
got Huntington's— whole
family should be
tested or they'll all die.
Hey.
There's a lot of blockage.
I've scheduled him for surgery.
We're gonna put a
shunt into one of the
ventricles to give the
cerebrospinal fluid an out.
No more pressure,
everything goes back to normal.
He's lucky to have
you as his doctors.
No formula. Just Mommy's
healthy, natural breast milk.
Yummy.
Her whole face just got
swollen like this overnight.
Mm-hmm.
No fever.
Glands normal. Missing
her vaccination dates.
We're not vaccinating.
Gribbet! Gribbet!
Gribbet!
Think they don't work?
I think some multinational pharmaceutical
company wants me to think they work...
Pad their bottom line. Mm-hmm.
- May I?
- Sure.
Gribbet. Gribbet.
Gribbet.
Yeah. All-natural, no
dyes is a good business.
All-natural children's toys.
Toy companies—they don't
arbitrarily mark up their frogs.
They don't lie about how much they
spend on research and development.
The worst that a toy company could be
accused of is making a really boring frog.
Gribbet, gibbet, gibbet.
You know another
really good business?
Teeny, tiny baby coffins.
You can get 'em in frog green,
fire-engine red—really.
The antibodies in yummy Mummy
only protect the kid for six months,
which is why these companies
think they can gouge you.
They think that you’ll spend whatever
they ask to keep your kid alive.
Want to change
things? Prove 'em wrong.
Few hundred parents like
you decide they'd rather let
their kid die than cough up
40 bucks for a vaccination,
believe me, prices
will drop really fast.
Gribbet, gribbet,
gribbet, gribbet, gribbet.
Gribbet.
Tell me what she has.
A cold.
There's a problem.
Complications in surgery?
Surgery went fine. He's in recovery.
But we took a vial of
C.S.F. and tested it. Really?
Turns out the bowing wasn't the
cause of his problems. It was a symptom.
Oligoclonal bands and
increased intrathecal lgG.
Which means multiple
sclerosis. And the
reason it takes three
of you to tell me this?
Because we're having a disagreement
about whether or not it is M.S.
No lesions on the M.R.I. It's early. He's
had the disease for maybe two weeks.
- McDonald criteria requires six months
to make a definitive diagnosis.
- Who cares about MacPhearson?
- I hear he tortured kittens.
- McDonald.
Oh, McDonald. Wonderful
doctor, loved kittens.
The V.E.P. indicates
slowing of the brain.
Without the lesions,
we can't be sure.
Well, if it is, it's gone from
zero to 60 in three weeks,
which would indicate
rapidly progressive M.S.
Not the fun M.S. with the balloons and
the bike rides for cripples in wheelchairs.
- We should wait until—
- Start treating him now,
maybe he can walk for another couple
of years, maybe live for another five.
Break it to the family.
I'm going home.
It'll take months for a definitive
diagnosis. What'll happen to me?
M.S. is an incredibly
variable disease.
If it is M.S., and we're not
a hundred percent sure.
What do you think
is gonna happen?
There are some medications
to manage the symptoms,
but as the disease progresses, the
problems will become more severe.
Bowel and bladder dysfunction,
loss of cognitive
function, pain—
So it's gonna hurt?
The brain's like a
big jumble of wires.
M.S. strips them of the
insulation, and the nerves die.
Brain interprets it as pain.
But by starting treatment, we're gonna
prevent that for as long as possible.
We're looking into a
couple of specialists,
and until we get you squared
away, you'll stay here, okay?
Security checked the videotapes
from all perimeter cameras.
He's still gotta be in the
hospital. Where's Chase?
Main floor. Okay. You take
the cafeteria and administration.
I'll hit the research annex
and work my way back to you.
Dan?
I'm not here. Leave a message.
Dr. Cuddy. Great outfit.
What are you doing
back here? Patient?
No. Hooker. Went to my
office instead of my home.
Dr. House.
Dan's missing. Yeah. I got
that part from the message.
You said I was needed immediately. He
shouldn't move after a lumbar puncture.
I agree. He's gonna have
a very nasty headache.
That would also be my opinion
if consulted tomorrow morning.
We wanted to keep you informed.
He heard some pretty heavy news.
This is not a toddler wandering
around a department store.
He's 16. You'll find him.
I'm going home.
So when you say, "Call me if you
need anything," you mean don't call?
No, I mean call me if
I could do something.
I'm bad at search
parties, and I'm bad at
sitting around looking
nervous, doing nothing.
What about his parents?
Should we call them?
Why? Do you think
they're hiding him?
Make sure someone
checks the roof.
Some of the orderlies keep the door
propped open so they can grab a smoke.
Dan. You okay?
There are experimental
treatments. Ongoing research.
Who knows what they'll
discover in a year or two.
This is where I
dropped the ball.
Dan, we're standing on
the roof of the hospital.
Dan.
Dan, you're not on the field.
He doesn't know
where he is. Dan.
Foreman.
Dan.
- Dan?
- Dan, no!
Dr. Foreman.
I assume you found the kid.
He almost walked
off the roof. Suicidal?
No, he thought he was
on his lacrosse field.
Look, I was gonna run
home, shower, change...
Conscious? Yeah.
How'd you talk him down?
Actually, Chase tackled him.
How come you didn't do it?
Right. Well, I am
black, but he was closer.
Come on. You
can ride up with me.
Anybody tell the family
that their boy almost
stepped off a roof?
They must be thrilled.
They're not suing, but I think
only because Chase asked...
Why does everybody always
think I'm being sarcastic?
This is great news.
He doesn't have M.S.
Parents should be
thrilled. The mom anyway.
Of course, the dad
probably doesn't know...
- Why doesn't he have M.S.?
- He was on the roof, thinking
he was on a lacrosse field.
- Conscious, and therefore not
a night terror. You want some of this?
- Yeah, sure.
He was in an acute
confusional state,
which doesn't fit with a
demyelinating disease like M.S.
Oligoclonal bands— Were real.
They just mean something other
than M.S. So, what are they telling us?
That the immune
system is working? Right.
He has an
infection in his brain.
What about sex?
Well, it might get complicated.
I mean, we work together.
I'm older, certainly,
but maybe you like that.
I meant maybe he
has neurosyphilis.
- Huh. Nice cover.
- Sorry. R.P.R. was negative.
We don't need
a definitive test to
confirm. Sure. Didn't
need one to confirm M.S.
Okay. Let's wait for
you to run titers on 1,400
viruses while this kid's
brain turns to mush.
So the fact that he doesn't have M.S.,
it's—it's really not good news after all.
Well, it is if it’s
neurosyphilis.
The likelihood of a false
negative on an R.P.R. test: 30%.
Likelihood of a 16-year-old
having sex: roughly 120%.
I'll start him on I.V. penicillin.
We're not gonna wait for that.
The most effective way to deliver the
drug is right into his brain via the spine.
We can't. In a cramped
space like the brain,
increased intracranial
pressure from a high-volume
drug like penicillin could
herniate his brain stem.
It'd kill him. No neurologist in his
right mind would recommend that.
Show of hands. Who thinks
I'm not in my right mind?
And who thinks I forget this
fairly basic neurological fact?
Who thinks there's
a third option?
- Very good. What's the third choice?
- No idea. You just asked
if I thought there was one.
The patient has a shunt in his brain.
There'll be no increased pressure.
We can put as much penicillin
into his body as we want.
Excellent. Inject him
through a lumbar puncture.
One of us is gonna do this to you
twice a day for the next two weeks.
- I'm ready. Go.
- He could get syphilis...
even if he's not
sexually active?
Well, it's—it's unusual,
but it's possible.
Okay. Relax.
It's infected, with
a really big hole,
like you stuck a nail in
it to relieve the pressure.
I wouldn't do that. Although
the wound is irregular.
It's not cylindrical. It's shaped
like a triangle. So, not a nail.
- Steak knife?
- Wife's nail file.
Nail file.
Yeah. Pain will make
you do stupid things.
- Something to take the edge off?
- Yeah.
Cheers.
So, you have family
here in Princeton?
No. Here on work?
- No. Why are you— -
Does your penis hurt?
No. What? Should it?
No. Just thought I'd toss you
a really inappropriate question.
Your lawyer's gonna love it.
Why would I want to sue
you? I want you to treat me.
- You're from Maplewood,
New Jersey, right?
- Yeah.
Now, why would
you drive 70 miles...
to get treatment for a condition
that a nine-year-old could diagnose?
It's the free-flowing
pus that's the tip-off.
I was in town. Not for
family. Not for work.
You drove 70 miles to a walk-in clinic.
You passed two hospitals on the road.
Either you've got a problem with those
hospitals, or they have a problem with you.
My guess is you've sued
half the doctors in Maplewood,
and the rest are now
refusing to help you.
It's ironic, isn't it? Sort of
like the boy who sued wolf.
You know, I bet we have
a doctor here named Wolf.
How perfect would that be?
- I'm gonna page him.
- Okay. You know what? Thank you.
I'm gonna find a doctor
to take care of this.
I didn't say I
wouldn't treat you.
- We'll drain your knee,
run some lab work. Fix you up.
- Why would you do that?
I'm a people person.
You actually treated him?
All I know is he
sued some doctors.
Who am I to assume they
didn't have it coming to them?
The cutest little tennis outfit. My God, I
thought I was gonna have a heart attack.
Oh, my. Didn't see you there. That is so
embarrassing. How's your hooker doing?
Sweet of you to
ask. Funny story.
She was gonna be
hospital administrator, but
just hated having to
screw people like that.
- Heard you found her on the roof.
- You have very acute hearing.
You notify the parents?
In due course, of course.
And is there a paternity bet
on the father of the patient?
Doesn't sound like me. Well, it does,
actually, but doesn't mean you're guilty.
You think? I saw the
parents in the lobby.
- Smart money's obviously on the father.
- My guy knows a guy who can
get you in for 50 bucks.
Fine. Tell your guy, if I win, you attend
the faculty symposium, and you wear a tie.
And if I win, no clinic
hours for a week.
My guy will call your guy.
She's very good at her job.
The treatments should
start helping soon.
Let us know if it gets easier to
focus on things, remember stuff.
Hey, Dan. Isn't Dr. Cameron's
necklace a beauty?
Something South
American, I think.
Yeah. Guatemalan.
It's a cool necklace.
- Thank you so much.
- The kid's in pain.
Don't fight it. Just
let it happen. No.
You'll be dead in
two days. No what?
I give it a day. Dan? You okay?
Dan?
- Night terrors.
- Decomposition once he's in the grave.
- Say good-bye to your mother and father.
- He's hearing voices.
You're dying.
It's all over, Dan.
You're dying. Dying. Dead!
Push two milligrams
I.V. Ativan, stat.
- It's all over.
- Come on, Dan.
Get out of my head!
Auditory hallucination shows
further brain degeneration.
Penicillin's not working. So
either it's a bad batch of penicillin,
or our diagnosis is wrong.
Square one.
Midnite. L.F.T.'s, B.U.N.
and creatinine are all normal.
- Diabetes is out, and no gap.
- There goes metabolic.
- M.R.A. rules out vasculitis.
- "I" for inflammation.
- Too young for anything
degenerative.
- "D," see ya.
"N" for neoplastic.
M.R.I. was clean.
- "I" for inflammation.
- We already did that.
Stupid to have two I's in one
mnemonic. What's the other one?
Infection.
- Oligoclonal bands still have to mean something.
- But no fevers. White count's elevated,
but within range.
We've tested for anything remotely
possible. Everything's negative.
- C.T. scan rules out subdural.
- Trauma. Later much.
You know the problem? "Midnight" is
actually spelled with a "G" and an "H."
If we could just figure out
what those letters stand for.
It's a sick brain, having fun,
torturing him, talking to him.
Scaring the hell out of him.
Get him an E.E.G., left and right
E.O.G., esophageal microphones.
If this thing wants
to talk, let's listen.
We're missing something.
This is screwed-up.
That's why you came up with
the brain talking to the virus thing?
I panicked, okay?
Sounded cool
though. They bought it.
Oh, crap.
Another reason I don't
like meeting patients. If they
don't know what you look
like, they can't yell at you.
Here we go.
How can you just sit there?
If I eat standing up, I spill.
Our son is dying, and
you could care less.
We're going through
hell. You're doing nothing?
I'm sorry. You need
to vent. I understand.
Don't be condescending.
You haven't checked
in on him once.
Blood pressure is 110 over 70.
His shunt is patent, well-placed
in the right lateral ventricle.
The E.K.G. shows a normal
Q.R.S. with deep-wave
inversions throughout both
limb and precordial leads.
L. F. T. 's are elevated, but
only twice the normal range.
Oh, yeah. And
he's hearing voices.
Go hold his hand.
Go on. I'll bus your tray.
- Got any sample bags on you?
- I don't believe you.
You're gonna run D. N.A.
tests? Their son is deathly ill.
I know. It's terrible.
But the fact is, if I
don't keep busy with
trivial things like this,
I'm afraid I might start
to cry. You're an ass.
Yeah? You want
to double the bet?
General Hospital
is on channel 6.
Dan's brain's not showing
channel 6 right now. Only mush.
No epileptiform activity.
What are you doing? Waiting
for C.B.C. and CHEM-7.
Good. Run D.N.A. on these.
What's this?
Parents' coffee cups.
I can't believe you. I've had
this conversation once already.
If you've got something else
to do, do it. Otherwise, do this.
Dr. House. Hey. Mr. Funsten.
I was wondering when you'd be
back. You got some papers for me?
You've caused me considerable
mental distress. I certainly hope so.
What? Too cheap to
get your lawyer to serve
it for you, or is it just
more fun this way?
I'm obviously prepared
to consider a settlement.
You have gonorrhea.
No, I don't. Well, maybe you're right,
but I have the lab result says you do.
Could be a false positive, and
normally I'd run a second test,
but since you're here, I'll just go with
the first. You're just trying to scare me.
It's reportable, you know. Public health
issue. I'll be sure to let my wife know.
Don't bother yourself.
The state will call for you.
If you’re clean, I'm sure
it'll all blow over. No big deal.
There's an easy way to find out.
Get one of your doctors to run a test.
Uh-uh.
These are mine now.
I'll see you in court.
West Nile negative. Not
surprising since not too
many mosquitoes passing
through Jersey in December.
No eastern equine encephalitis.
You guys aren't gonna believe this.
What's that? House is right.
The father's not the father.
Dude doubled up on me.
You're not gonna believe this.
The mother's not
the mother either.
It's not a good idea to move
your son in his condition.
- We just want a second opinion.
- We need an answer.
You idiots. You lied to me.
We didn't lie about anything.
- You, on the other hand,
accused us of molesting our son.
- Perfect.
Can we get off my
screw-ups and focus on theirs?
Theirs is bigger. You're
not Dan's parents.
We're his parents. He was
adopted. He doesn't need to know.
- I do.
- Adoption makes us just as much...
Listen. When we were taking his
medical history, were you confused?
Did you think we were looking
for a genetic clue to his condition,
or did you think we
were trying to ascertain
who loves him the most
in the whole wide world?
How did you find out about this?
- I sampled their D.N.A.
- We didn't give you any D.N.A.
Your coffee cups
from the cafeteria.
- You can't do that.
- Again, why are we getting
hung up on what I did?
- Your medical history is useless.
- No. We gave you a detailed history
of his biological mother.
Her history.
Nonsmoker, good health,
low cholesterol, no
blood pressure problems.
Dan was adopted two
weeks after he was born.
- You have his history. There's nothing
you need to know that we didn't tell you.
- Sounds reasonable.
Well, if you want to transfer
your boy, that is your choice.
I still think it's the wrong—
Was she vaccinated?
The biological mother. When she was
a baby, did she get her vaccinations?
Dan was vaccinated.
At six months.
Mm-hmm. Do you know why
kids get vaccinated at six months?
Because before that
they are protected...
by their biological
mother's immune system.
So, was she vaccinated?
An infant picks up a
regular old measles virus.
Gets a rash.
He's extremely uncomfortable,
has a wicked fever, but he lives.
Here's the kicker. Once
every million or so times,
the virus mutates.
Instead of Dan having
a fever and a rash,
the virus travels to
his brain and hides,
like a time bomb.
In this case, for 16 years.
Sub-acute sclerosing
panencephalitis.
I know. There's only been 20 cases in
the United States in the last 30 years.
I suppose you could make an
argument the kid's still in stage I.
Once S.S.P.E.
moves to stage II, it's...
Boom. Stage II
is universally fatal.
I assume it’s impossible to know
when he might move into stage II.
He's already started showing symptoms.
Could be a month. Could be tonight.
Can we treat it?
Ask the neurologist.
Intraventricular interferon.
Not gonna shove a spike
into his brain and drip
interferon without
confirming this diagnosis.
- Tap him.
- We won't get a reliable result
for measles antibodies in his C.S.F.
Not after everything
we've given him.
So the wrong treatment kills
any hope of the right diagnosis.
Why do people lie to me?
Could also kill him.
Your ball, Foreman. Tell me I
don't have to biopsy his brain.
Well, there is one other way.
You sure this isn't gonna hurt?
Yeah. It's just scary as hell.
See, we go through the pupil.
But you won't feel it.
The eye's been paralyzed.
The needle travels
to the back of the eye,
which is where we'll perform
the biopsy on your retina.
So we've confirmed that the
problem is this mutated virus.
The treatment for S.S.P.E.
is intraventricular interferon.
We implant an ommaya
reservoir under the scalp,
which is connected to
a ventricular catheter...
that delivers the antiviral
directly to the left hemisphere.
You want us to consent to this? I don't
even understand what you're talking about.
Well, the antiviral...
Look. I'm sorry.
I can explain this as best
I can, but the notion that
you're gonna fully understand
your son's treatment...
and make an informed
decision is—is kind of insane.
Here's what you need to know.
It's dangerous.
It could kill him.
You should do it.
Did you need something else?
You can't order a $3,200
D.N.A. test to win a bet.
It's not an actual cost.
I don't know if you
know this, but the
hospital actually owns
the sequencing machine.
- I'm serious.
- Tell the parents to submit
the bill to insurance.
Insurance is not
gonna pay for a bet.
Should. We don't make
that bet, the kid dies.
If not for the paternity bet, I never
would have taken their D. N.A.
Without their D. N.A., we
never would have discovered
that Dan was adopted,
which was the key to this case.
You just don't want
to pay your end.
Big mistake. My guy knows a guy.
Fine. I will let you out of
clinic duty for one week,
after you pay the
3,200 for the P.C.R. test.
Ooh.
Well, now, there's the
hundred you owe me.
Here's a hundred I
won from Cameron.
200 I took off of Foreman.
And 600...
I got from Wilson.
Very bitter.
Hey. Good morning.
Good news on your
E.E.G. Treatment is working.
And your immune
system is responding.
I know it's early, but I
just want to take a look.
All right. Let's see what
that brain of yours can do.
Name as many animals as you
can that start with the letter "O."
Ostrich.
Ox. Old elephant.
Well, that's two
better than last time.
How you doing with the
whole adoption thing?
- I knew since fifth grade.
- How's that?
Cleft chin.
I have one. My dad doesn't.
Looked it up on the Internet.
It's one of those trait things.
That's right. It's
autosomal dominant.
Since neither of your
parents have cleft chins,
it's highly unlikely
you're biologically related.
- Are you sure you're okay?
- I've got no problems
with being adopted.
I love my parents.
How's he doing?
He's doing pretty well.
He's a smart kid.
I think he's gonna be fine.
- Hey.
- Thanks.
Wheels, 18. Wheels.
That's some bad hat, Harry.