Looking great.
Mmm. Yeah, well,
the secret is, uh...
Night sweats with
aggressive vomiting.
Dose-dense
treatment's a bear, yes.
But you can't
knock these results.
Hit me, coach.
Your tumor is regressing,
your polymorphonuclear cells
are over 1,000 for
the first time in a week,
and your hemoglobin's
in the normal range.
I'd stand and cheer but, uh,
I think I'd, you
know, fall over.
Max, you should
feel good about this.
Well, yeah. No, I do, I do.
I just didn't know that feeling
this good would feel quite this bad.
Uh, Virginia?
I'm, uh, cold all
the time. Is that...
Common side effect.
Here.
And we'll hook you
up to some fluids.
This is all good news.
The chemo is working.
Hmm.
Here looks good.
Sir, do you know what
floor your room is on?
I can call someone to get help.
Oh.
Sorry, Dr. Goodwin.
I didn't recognize you.
Science is about progress.
Why are we still relying so heavily
on methods developed 60 years ago?
For the same reason we're still using
penicillin and aspirin. Because they work.
In the future, when new
techniques have taken hold,
we will look back and cringe at
the barbarism of today's approach.
And immunotherapy is
one of these new techniques.
I think it will be. But when?
Cancer patients need
effective treatments now.
How much of the cancer population
are your therapies actually helping? 1%?
More like 5%. Oh.
But some clinicians
are doing even better,
like Dr. Valentina Castro.
She even practiced
at New Amsterdam
before Dr. Sharpe doubled
down on older treatments.
Because they worked.
And forced Dr. Castro out.
Because hers didn't.
Dr. Helen...
Dr. Sharpe, please. Dr. Sharpe.
Can you tell us how you
view Dr. Panthaki's methods?
With pleasure.
I can't believe how
much I missed that.
It used to be such
a big part of my life.
It was my life.
You should come
to Brussels with me.
What, now? 'Cause I kinda thought
we were in the middle of something.
No, next week. I'm
presenting at a conference,
but you should be
up there with me.
Presenting?
Doing what we just
did in that studio.
Debating.
More like wiping
the floor with you.
Pretty sure I just
eviscerated your life's work
with my life's work.
Then I challenge
you to a rematch.
In Brussels.
Only if we get to keep
making up like this.
Luke Bauer, previously
healthy 17-year-old,
status, post fall.
Now complaining of left arm
weakness and blurred vision.
Normal and stable
heart rate and BP.
Take him to trauma one?
Tell me which came first?
The blurred vision or the fall?
Uh, I tripped
because I couldn't see.
Take him to curtains.
We're gonna take
good care of you, Luke.
All right, let's go.
Yesterday, I was
handing out flyers,
but I kept dropping 'em.
Thought maybe I was just
hungry, so I got a hot dog.
Took one bite, and
I started choking.
You know, I could
barely swallow.
After I woke up,
everything looked blurry,
and that's when
I tripped and fell.
Botulism.
Back off, dude! Sorry.
Uh, Max Goodwin. I'm
the, uh, medical director.
Just grabbing a quick
thirst-quenching beverage.
Uh, all the symptoms
that you are experiencing
are from a toxin produced
by the botulism bacteria
that is growing somewhere
inside your body, and...
Wow.
Who knew talking
could be this tiring?
That adds up.
I'll order the antitoxin.
Yeah, I'll take care of him.
Who's gonna take care of you?
You're welcome to have a look yourself,
but the concerns are pretty clear.
You're being accused of
forming a nontherapeutic alliance
with your patient, Avi Mantell.
Yeah. As deputy
medical director,
all personnel complaints
come to my desk,
so I'll be conducting
the initial review.
Okay. And after that?
Let's hope there isn't
anything after that.
Yeah, okay. I trust the process.
I, uh, pulled all the case
files and therapy notes for Avi.
Everything's there.
Great, thank you.
Yeah, you got it.
We'll talk soon.
Helen, hey, hey.
I didn't, uh, you know...
I mean, I didn't
do anything wrong,
right?
We'll talk soon.
Okay.
What's wrong with you?
Uh, throat cancer. That sucks.
Really does.
Oh.
Here we go.
Cellulitis.
This is where the botulism
bacteria is, uh, growing,
and this cut is how
it got under your skin.
How'd you get this?
Uh...
Dumpster diving, a
couple weeks back.
Let's just say my execution
wasn't a perfect ten.
I see that.
Hey, what are you doing?
I'm just outlining the infection
so that we can track
its, uh, progression,
or hopefully lack thereof.
Why didn't you come in sooner?
Don't have insurance.
That shouldn't have stopped you.
Come on, you know how it works.
You walk up to the desk,
they ask you for a card.
Without one, no one
even looks at you.
It's embarrassing.
Being invisible is almost
worse than being sick.
Did you know Luke's had
that infection for two weeks?
Not surprised.
Back then, it could have been
treated in a clinic, you know?
A few stitches,
some antibiotics.
Cheap fix. But
instead, he waited.
He ended up much
sicker and in the ED
with inefficient, complex,
and very expensive care.
All solid points
I'd love to discuss
when I'm not slammed.
All because he
didn't have insurance.
I bet half the people in this
ED don't have insurance.
Probably more than half,
but there's nothing we can do.
You know what, there is. There
is something that we can do.
We can get every hospital
administrator down here right now.
Why would I do that?
So they can enroll everyone
in a proper insurance plan.
This is what the
ACA set out to do.
To give everyone access to
health insurance they can afford.
Isn't that complicated? Yes.
Very.
But it's hurting our patients,
and it's costing us money,
and this could maybe fix both.
Health insurance is
available to these people,
and we're gonna get each
and every one of them enrolled.
This is Dr. Helen Sharpe, Deputy
Head of Medicine at New Amsterdam,
presiding over an internal
investigation into Dr. Ignatius Frome.
Also present is Ms. Tiara Dobbs.
This inquiry alleges that you, Dr. Frome,
violated hospital policy ADMN-23.
This policy addresses
nontherapeutic relationships,
including ones where members
of staff are overly invested
in a child or family's care.
I've always tried to provide
the best care possible.
Your intentions
aren't in question.
Oh. Good.
Your methods are.
Have you ever shown favoritism
towards a particular patient?
No.
You've never bought
gifts for a patient?
Um...
Birthdays, maybe. Yeah.
And... And sometimes I
might see a little something
that I know a kid would
respond to really well
or like in particular. Uh...
But I wouldn't, um...
I wouldn't call it favoritism.
So your answer is yes.
Yes.
Have you ever brought special
food into the hospital for patients?
Mmm-mmm. No.
Wait, yes.
But the patient specifically
mentioned s'mores
in session, so...
That's a yes, also. Yes.
But... We all go the
extra mile around here.
This inquiry isn't about
everyone else, Dr. Frome.
It's about you.
Have you ever initiated
uninvited physical contact?
I've never made
anyone uncomfortable,
if that's what you mean.
That isn't a no.
Dr. Frome, have you ever hugged,
kissed, or otherwise touched
a patient without invitation?
No, I have never
kissed a patient.
Have you ever hugged or
touched a patient without invitation?
Yes.
And you understand that
that is outside the bounds
of a normal
therapeutic relationship?
Yes.
I'm looking for my
consult, a seizure patient.
Feng Shen? Follow the noise.
Please, Feng is very
sick. He needs you!
Yes, yes.
I see.
Excuse me.
Hello, Feng.
I'm Dr. Kapoor.
Has Feng lost weight recently?
One at a time. WOMAN: Yes.
Feng does not want to eat.
Not at all.
Prep Feng for a lumbar
puncture right away.
You are staring awfully
hard at that screen.
Yeah, this might be an
awkward time to tell you,
but I'm in love with coronary
artery bypass surgery.
Mmm. Mmm.
What are you doing out here?
I was actually
trying to see you.
Oh, that's cool. I was
on my way to see you.
Oh, do tell.
Well, I want you to
come to Sunday dinner.
Meet my family.
Or not?
I was gonna surprise you,
but I got invited to this salon in
Harlem to see Ta-Nehisi Coates,
and you were gonna
be my plus-one.
No way. Yes!
Oh, you know that's
my boy. I know!
That's why I was so excited.
But I can meet your
family next Sunday, right?
Oh, my mom will look at me
sideways if I miss Sunday dinner,
and then my
sisters will pile on.
So you've never
missed a Sunday dinner?
College.
Oh.
Then you deserve to have Ta-Nehisi
sign your Black Panther comic.
I do, don't I?
I'm in. Yes!
Phone number? No phone.
Address?
Wherever we are right now.
Do you have a PO
box or something?
Yeah, for all my
Amazon deliveries.
Well, then, I suppose there's
no way to mail you your insurance
card. Um...
I'll be right back.
Sorry to bother
you, Dr. Goodwin.
My patient doesn't have
a social security number,
and it's required for ACA.
The family I just tried to sign
up all gave me the same name.
They're a family.
The same first name.
Okay, give me...
Give me a second.
Curious? Is this better or worse
than what you had in mind?
Luke Bauer's cellulitis has
progressed to necrotizing fasciitis.
He may have already
seeded his heart valves.
I'll page Reynolds
and book an OR.
Okay. Mmm? Dr. Goodwin.
I can't tell if my patient is a
good fit for this insurance plan,
because I can't
decipher the plan myself.
I've gotta hand it to you, Boss.
You have outdone
yourself this time.
Did I?
The entire hospital, and I
mean the entire hospital,
has been talking
about your insane plan
to sign every single patient
up for health insurance.
Seriously, what
were you thinking?
Max. Max?
Yeah, I'm right behind you.
You want me to have someone
bring you up a wheelchair?
No, no, I'm totally
good. I'm just
much slower.
You got lapped by a
92-year-old with a walker.
Ouch. But you're not wrong.
The, um, insurance thing was
flawed, but you wanna know why?
Um, it's hard to narrow down
exactly which joke to make here.
This is a public
hospital, right?
Our help is free to the
public. That's the whole thing.
People don't need
insurance to be treated here,
and most people right
now don't know that.
Then, how do you
expect to fix that problem?
Um...
Ah.
This is how we fix it.
And what exactly is included in
the New Amsterdam Family Plan?
Um, just about everything.
And how much will
people pay for it?
Kinda like nothing. Yeah?
That's what I thought.
Yeah, I'm gonna need copies.
Maybe, what do you
think, 500,000 to start?
Yeah, sure.
And then what? We hide
them in chocolate bars?
No, I was thinking we might hand them
out to every resident of New York City.
Have you and Dr. Frome ever been
alone in the same room together?
Yeah, during session.
And during session,
has Dr. Frome ever
initiated physical contact?
Why are we talking about this?
Ms. Dobbs told me that
she witnessed Dr. Frome
touch you on your
head, neck, and face.
It's okay.
Like, a hand on my
shoulder, I guess.
Or on my knee sometimes.
How did it make you feel?
This is stupid.
I'm sorry.
I am sorry, but it's important.
How did it make you feel?
I don't want to talk
about that, okay?
Does physical contact make you
feel uncomfortable sometimes?
Avi?
Have you ever been
touched inappropriately
by Dr. Frome or anyone else?
Honey.
I didn't know how to tell you.
Avi, we're gonna protect you.
Can you tell us who?
I wanna talk to Dr. Frome.
Injecting dye.
Dye filling chamber.
Right there. You see that, Max?
Small vegetation on
Luke's bicuspid valve.
Got it.
You okay up there? Mmm.
Numbers have never
been better. Huh.
That's surprising, seeing as
you've never looked worse.
No offense.
None taken.
Dr. Reynolds?
Dr. Kapoor's
requesting a consult.
Okay. I'm done here.
Oh, Max?
I took a look at Luke's calf.
The, uh, general
surgeon's on the way.
All right, tell them he's
been injecting heroin
under the skin.
He said he got it
dumpster diving.
Then he lied.
Pulmonary and
meningeal tuberculosis.
Very troubling.
Well, TB happens.
We just gotta isolate the
boy, zap him with antibiotics,
and Bob's your uncle.
Yes, if only it was just Bob.
Their entire family lives in a
multi-family home in Queens.
I've asked them
to come for testing.
All of them.
Iggy!
You need to think about this.
What's there to think about?
A patient asked to talk to me.
He's no longer your patient.
Well, those darn
doctor-patient boundaries,
famously, a weakness of mine.
There's been hearings about it
and everything. You were there.
Iggy, you are a kind man,
but if you talk to this boy,
your kindness is gonna
be used against you.
Every word you say is gonna
be placed under a microscope.
I hear you. I understand, and I
know you're trying to help me,
but if I'm not there for my patients
when they need me the most,
what am I doing here?
Why even do this job at all?
Avi has something to say to me,
I am going to listen, no
matter the consequence.
Iggy... That's it!
End of story.
Please, everyone, let's...
Let's just stay calm, okay?
TB is a very treatable disease.
But when can they come home?
TB likes to play hide-and-seek,
so the process of
eradicating the disease
from the body can be lengthy.
Ann and Feng will need
to pass three negative
sputum tests in a row.
How long will that take?
Three to nine months.
Surgery went well.
We managed to
remove all the infection.
A few weeks of pills
and you should be...
You should be fine.
Um, this is...
Well, it's just like insurance.
And you can use this
to get follow-up care.
Here at New Amsterdam. You
just walk up to any of these desks
and you flash this baby,
and they'll honor it. And
they'll treat you with respect.
And you won't get a bill.
Seriously?
Yeah.
And you can use it also at...
At one of our
rehab clinics. What...
And you should, Luke, because
what you're doing to yourself...
I knew it. Luke, I'm just...
You can just forget
your stupid card.
I'm not coming back here,
so you can talk down to me,
accuse me of things I didn't do.
You're just like everyone else.
Wait... Just back off, okay?
Hey.
I know this is weird,
but... But it, um...
This is a bad idea.
You know what?
This is unusual. I get it.
Don't even look
at them, all right?
Just hang with me.
It's just me and
you, like always.
Okay?
What's up? How you feeling?
Messed up.
Okay, that's a good start.
What's messed up?
Like,
they asked if... If
you touched me.
And you do, right?
And that's, like,
okay, because when you do,
I feel loved or whatever. Good.
But then it's like,
what do I know?
Because, you know...
Times in my past...
Before you, I, uh...
Have you ever felt differently
when someone else touched you?
Well, no.
I don't know. That's
what's so messed up.
Yeah, yeah, I get it.
It sounds confusing.
Why don't we...
Let's simplify.
Where were you,
first time this happened?
I was in Missouri.
Watching TV. FROME:
What was on TV?
A soap. A soap?
She liked them. Okay.
Tell me about her.
She'd watch me while
my mom was at work.
You know, I'd sit on her lap,
and she'd scratch my back.
Oh.
And then one day,
she asked if I...
I wanted to kiss.
You know, like
they did on the TV.
And we did.
And then she asked
me to lie on top of her.
How old were you?
Five.
That must have
been really scary.
It wasn't.
She was nice to me.
I just...
I couldn't...
Uh...
You looked forward to it.
I'm sick.
I'm disgusting.
No. No, Avi, you
are not disgusting.
The only disgusting thing here
is a woman in a
position of power
taking advantage of a kid.
Of a child.
Not you.
Why didn't you tell me?
Why didn't you tell your mom?
It's okay.
You'll feel better
if you say it.
She's my aunt.
Care to explain
this latest scheme?
Um, I wouldn't really
call it a scheme.
Nothing on that card is a lie.
We are a public
hospital and, uh,
we do treat everyone,
whether or not
they have insurance.
So you're advertising.
Yeah, exactly.
I mean, do you know... Do
you know how many people
don't even know that they
can come to us for free?
How many of these did you make?
Um...
I don't think you
want to know that.
If everyone in the city knew
that they could just walk in here
without insurance, the
whole system would crumble.
Agree to disagree. I think the
more patients that we can help
and the earlier
we can help them,
then the better
the system will be.
A public hospital only survives
because so many people
don't realize they can use it.
If everyone started coming
in here when they were sick,
this hospital would
run out of money.
Well, good thing I'm
talking to the one person
who can actually
get us more funds.
Are you trying to single-handedly
socialize medicine?
Public hospitals are
socialized medicine.
It already happened,
it's already here,
and it had nothing to do
with me.
So why don't we just call
some things like we see it, right?
The U.S. military, largest and
most funded socialist program
in the entire world.
We have public schools
and public libraries
and the police department
and the fire department,
and we can all get
behind socialism there,
but just not in our hospitals.
Is this the hill you
want to die on?
Despite all appearances, I
am not dying anytime soon.
Dr. Reynolds.
So, how are things
with you and Evie?
What?
You just went right
there, didn't you?
I'm sorry, okay?
I just don't have the headspace
for small talk anymore.
All right, well, we're
good, you know?
We're really good,
thanks to you.
You taken her home
to meet the family yet?
Not yet. Why not?
You should get on that.
You know, it's good
to have you back.
"Back." Yeah. You're
back, aren't you?
I was actually here to talk to
Max about extending my leave.
Whoa, for how long?
Like, forever.
Is there any chance I
can change your mind?
No.
Any chance, I mean, Max
can change your mind?
No, which is why I wanted
to talk to him in person.
Have you seen him?
What, it's that bad?
It's way worse.
Jeez, I thought I
was the liability.
Hey, Lauren.
You know I got you, right?
Hey, whoa, is there a problem?
Caught this guy stealing
these from the hospital.
Uh, no, he didn't steal those.
Uh, I gave them to him. It was
part of a needle exchange program.
Luke.
Well, it's, uh...
It's all out in the open now.
Hannah told us that her sister
was a victim of abuse as well.
But she never imagined her sister
would do that to someone else,
let alone a member
of her family.
I'll call Child Protective.
Great, thank you.
Will they be okay?
Yeah, I think so.
Just... It'll take a
little time, you know?
Thank you. For what?
Being you.
Yeah, I'm not sure that's
a good thing anymore.
Feng starts kindergarten
in two weeks.
- He was so excited.
- I understand,
but active TB is
highly contagious.
If you go home or
Feng goes to school,
you risk infecting a
great many people.
You can infect
your entire family.
I want NaiNai.
Will they get the best
care here at the hospital?
Yes.
Bao Bao, NaiNai is here.
And I'm not leaving.
Ann and Feng need
more than just antibiotics.
They need their family. Right.
Then their family can
come during visiting hours.
How long do you think that
80-year-old woman can sit on that stool?
Or for any one of them
can stare at their loved ones
through that glass wall?
The family will adapt. All
right? That's what I'm scared of.
They will adapt to a
life without each other.
Look, there's nothing
we can do, all right?
Ann and Feng have
to stay in isolation.
Dr. Goodwin, can I
get you a wheelchair?
Yes, thank you.
Max. Could you give me a hand?
I don't remember this
slope being so steep.
Max, you need to stop.
Why? No.
The Community Care
office needs these.
They're gonna
help pass them out.
How long has it been
since you could
swallow your own saliva?
Few days. Can you get dressed?
Shower by yourself?
Look, the chemo's working.
It's working. Stauton said
it could be as little
as three months.
"Three months"?
You won't make it three
weeks. You're wasting away.
Look, I just need to
hang on a little bit longer.
The numbers don't lie.
The cancer will be cured,
but we will run the
last course of chemo
into your dead body.
You are dying, Max.
Well, then, this may be
one of the last things I do.
Just. Max!
No, it's okay. We're
fine, thank you.
It's over, you are
done. No more chemo.
You're not my doctor. I am now.
I am your doctor, Max.
I'm taking you off the
chemo and radiation.
I'm gonna find you a different
regimen, and I'm gonna save your life.
But first thing I'm gonna
do is send you home.
It's time for you
to go home, Max.
You're going home to stay alive.
This is not the end.
Dr. Frome.
I'm sorry to have
put you through this.
Are you serious?
You put my entire medical
practice in jeopardy,
and now you're just gonna...
What? You're just
gonna let me off the hook?
I realize you were
just trying to help him.
But I didn't.
You were right about me.
Dr. Frome...
Do... Do you have any idea
how many patients
I've held in my arms?
How many kids I
bought clothes for?
Books for?
I try so hard to
make them feel safe...
Make them feel the love
that they should have
gotten somewhere else.
I can see that now.
What you did for Avi,
only you could do that for him.
That's the problem.
If you hadn't filed your report,
Avi would have gone
on to some therapist
and he would have
had a huge setback
because he couldn't speak
his truth to anybody but me.
If I'm only teaching
patients to speak to me
and not to deal with the world
after they leave my care, well...
The phrase I would use for that
is "nontherapeutic
relationship."
The rules exist for a reason,
and I broke them repeatedly.
Now the only thing for me to do
is to be a different therapist.
Different therapist
than I want to be.
Than I know how to be.
Vijay.
There's nothing more
to do for the Shens.
Ansuya and I were a
love match.
But my parents didn't approve...
So we saw them less and less.
Along the way, we made
many little decisions
that added up to
a big distance between us.
Soon
family meant only
me,
Ansuya,
and Rohan.
So you don't see them anymore?
We haven't spoken
to each other for a
long, long time.
We won't let that happen
to the Shens, will we?
No.
We won't.
Thank you.
Thank you so much. Thank you.
How long have you
been standing there?
I gotta come clean.
Okay.
Ta-Nehisi may be my boy,
but I have a whole family
who still thinks of me
as their boy.
So we won't go this Sunday.
Well, that's the thing. I'm
not saying no to this Sunday.
I'm saying no to every Sunday.
That's how important
my family is, and...
I think I was
afraid to admit that.
Why?
Well, there's a whole part of me
outside this hospital
that you don't know.
You know, like
church, my aging mom,
my sisters ganging
up on me, you know?
What if you didn't
like that part of me?
Or them?
How could I not? You
don't know my family.
Well, you're right. I don't.
So I'd better be meeting
them this Sunday.
I don't have an appointment,
but I'm hoping
you can fit me in.
Well, I will have
to check my books.
Our hotel, I can't
wait for you to see it.
It is in the center of
the historic district.
Three Michelin-starred
restaurants in walking distance.
But you won't be
joining me, will you?
I can't.
Akash, I am so sorry.
Right now, I can't imagine
sitting on a panel defending
traditional chemotherapy
when my day has been
one long crushing example
of precisely how traditional
chemotherapy can fail.
This is about Max.
Yes, it is.
Max helped me rediscover
my love of medicine
and got me back in the hospital.
And it's not just me.
You can see it on the
faces of all the doctors.
All the nurses. All the staff.
He has helped them all
so much, so profoundly.
And now
it's our turn to help him.
Say it's here Where
our pieces fall in place
Any rain softly
kisses us on the face
Any wind means we're running
We can sleep and see 'em coming
Where we drift
and call it dreaming
We can weep and call it singing
And we get a chance to say
Before we ease away
For all the love
you've left behind
You can have mine
Max.
You're not answering
your phone so...