Previously, on
"The Resident"...
We want to make you
the director of our program,
but we need to know
by next week.
- So, are you gonna take it?
- Is there anything left of us?
You're the one who made it clear
that not having kids was
a deal-breaker.
Kit Voss offered me a job.
Why would you leave
Seattle Children's?
So that I can be closer to you.
You're a good man, Dr. Austin.
I think our child should
witness that firsthand.
- Our child?
- If you're still willing.
I've gone and fallen
for someone.
You're afraid
the guy's gonna say no?
Reinforcements are here
to cheer you up.
I'm as afraid
he'll say yes as I am
- he'll say no.
- Go tell the man how you feel.
Hope I'm not too early.
Not at all. Come on in.
- Beautiful evening.
- It is.
I've been looking forward
to this for a long time.
Thank you so much
for offering to babysit.
Are you kidding?
I'm so excited.
I can't wait to meet Gigi.
Well, she's asleep now, but, um,
she'll be up
in the next couple of hours.
And if we're not back by then...
We're not gonna be back.
We're gonna live it up, Nic.
It's our first night out
since Gigi was born,
so someone has
a little separation anxiety.
You have nothing to worry about.
I took CPR training for infants,
and I have
three younger siblings.
Emergency contacts,
just in case.
There's pumped breast milk
in the fridge.
- We heat it up in the...
- The bottle warmer. I've got this.
And I will test it just
to make sure it's not too hot.
Great, and don't forget to
burp her and change her after.
Of course.
I'm more worried about Nic
than I am Gigi.
- I'm right here.
- You're gonna be fine.
Nice new jacket, Dr. Hawkins.
Ah, you like? Thanks.
Have a great time.
Just call if there's anything,
okay?
Bye.
Somebody has a little crush.
Don't be ridiculous.
"Nice new jacket, Dr. Hawkins."
Mm.
♪ Across
the railroad tracks... ♪
Daddy.
Daddy, green means go.
- ♪ I sit alone ♪
- Thanks, honey.
♪ And I think of losing you. ♪
*THE RESIDENT*
Season 05  Episode 23
Episode Title: "Neon Moon"
Aired on: May 17, 2022.
Yo, everyone.
The illustrious doctor scientist
graces us peons
with his presence
for the last time.
Oh, come on. You know,
I think I liked it better
when you just ignored me
when I showed up for my shift.
Better get into your scrubs.
You're a bit too big
for those britches.
Poor guy's gonna hate
Baltimore Hospital
for Advanced Science.
Do you know how cold
Baltimore gets in January?
And he's
a fragile flower.
Oh, you don't fool me.
I know you're all crying inside.
I'm gonna miss you, a lot.
We're well aware
what this exit is about,
and it ain't science,
or money,
because Dr. Voss would match
any offer.
Talk to Leela.
Fix this.
I wish I could.
Help! We need help
over here, please.
Can't... breathe.
All right, this way.
What's going on?
She-she was a little short of
breath last night.
We thought it was the baby
pressing on her lungs,
but she woke up like this.
How far along is she?
Five months.
Mommy, are you gonna be okay?
Of course, baby.
Hypoxemic. Elevated respiratory rate.
Rales up to the mid chest.
Sounds like pulmonary edema.
Let's get an EKG
and get her on O2.
- Mommy?
- It's okay.
Can someone... take him?
I'll call Winston
in social services.
He'll get someone
to look after him.
Come with me, sweetheart.
Fetal heart rate sounds good.
Obvious movement.
The baby looks good.
- Praise God.
- Thank you.
Let's get a stat chest X-ray.
Page Dr. Austin.
What's wrong?
What's happening?
Devon always kept the keys
in a bowl in the hallway.
Thank you so much
for reminding me.
I'm sorry.
I just really want to get going.
I can't wait for the ultrasound.
Although I already know I'm
pregnant because I can feel it.
My stomach is doing flip-flops.
And guess what,
I woke up nauseous this morning.
I told you to not have
that pizza last night.
It's not the pizza, Leela.
I feel...
- different, you know?
- Well, actually,
since I've never been pregnant,
no, I don't know.
Today's his last day, isn't it?
You guys broke up way too fast.
It's a pattern with you.
You're kind of
a relationship wrecking ball.
Oh, come on. Do you remember
when you dumped Rick Stamos
right before prom?
He was ripped
and a quarterback,
and you had a killer dress.
- I caught him making out with a cheerleader.
- Hmm.
He can't wait to go.
He's leaving Atlanta tomorrow.
He's only sticking around
for Kit and
Bell's
engagement party tonight.
I know he still loves you. Okay?
Everyone knows
he still loves you.
And sometimes
you can't always see
what's right before your eyes.
There is still time.
Dr. Sullivan,
where's your walker?
I know you're feeling better,
but you shouldn't be
on your feet alone.
I am discharging myself
from the hospital.
- You-you can't do that.
- Yes, I can.
I'm a doctor.
You can't be your own doctor.
I know my own body,
and I feel fine.
Besides, work is
the best medicine.
If you're your own doctor,
does that also make you
your own worst patient?
- Ha ha.
- You only got shot three times.
Why don't you go run a 10K
while you're at it?
You know what? You are just
the person I was looking for.
Look what you left in my room
on your last visit.
Mr. Giraffe!
He must have been scared in that
dark drawer all by himself.
No, not in the least,
he was sleeping.
He's a sleepyhead,
but he did poke his head out
- to ask for some leaves for dinner.
- Silly.
He doesn't eat leaves,
he eats chocolate ice cream.
Oh, right.
I'll drop Gigi at preschool
and meet you in your dad's room.
His lab results are in.
How are you feeling, Dad?
Fine.
No lingering symptoms?
It's been a day and a half
since my little fall.
I'm much better.
Well, it was more than
just a fall. You passed out.
Why are you getting dressed?
- I'm discharging myself.
- You...
You can't be your own doctor.
Oh, wow.
The apple fell
directly under the tree.
My father and I are both doctors
who also happen to be patients.
Other than that,
we are nothing alike.
Of course you're not.
Your labs.
You're profoundly anemic.
Your stomach pain is
getting worse, right?
Combine that
with your collapse...
Bleeding ulcer
is top of the list.
Ridiculous. No acid reflux.
No indigestion.
- Any blood in your stool?
- Okay.
Before we discuss my bowel
movements in greater detail,
can we clarify...
which of you is
my actual doctor?
You need more tests.
There may be
a simple explanation
for what's going on here,
but until we find it,
you aren't going anywhere.
Your vision is fine, Randolph.
You had an MS flare.
Okay. Well, yeah,
it was kind of rough.
They're not unexpected,
especially near the optic nerve.
With an extra pulse of steroids,
you'll be back to normal.
This should be nothing
to worry about.
See? It's great news.
You're good to go back
in the OR.
I'm clearing you for surgery.
Great.
I know that look.
Talk to me.
Every MS flare feels like
it's the beginning of the end.
The pain is excruciating,
and you're afraid
it's getting worse,
but you're catastrophizing.
- You heard the doctor.
- It is progressive.
Not necessarily.
You could go into
total remission.
I love your optimism.
I'm about to marry
Chastain's finest surgeon,
who will hold that title
for years to come.
Please,
tell me whatever is happening
isn't going to...
harm my baby.
Right now, let's focus on you,
Mom, all right?
Your echocardiogram is showing
that your heart isn't pumping
strong enough
to support you and the baby.
W-What does that mean?
It means that
your wife is in heart failure.
No, how-how can this
be happening?
Have you had
any health issues recently?
Flu... a few weeks ago.
I-It was pretty bad,
but she finally got better.
Help me!
Step aside, please.
It's okay.
Acute hypoxemic
respiratory failure.
Pulmonary edema is worsening,
which means
her heart function is, too.
Pressure's dropping.
Hanging a norepi drip.
We're having a baby girl.
We've hoped for one
since Miguel was born.
We-we cannot lose this baby.
She's decompensating fast.
We need to intubate now.
Come here.
We are trying to save
your wife's life.
Let us work so can save
both mom and baby.
Okay.
Nic.
I forgot to tell Marion
to leave the night-light on
in Gigi's room.
I left it on.
How about we put all phones away
just for the next hour?
Well, your new girlfriend
has to be able to reach me.
Oh, she's on my speed dial.
- ♪ The sun goes down ♪
- How convenient. -
♪ On my side of town... ♪
- Wow.
"Neon Moon."
Same song that was playing
right here on our first date.
You don't remember what song
was playing on our first date.
I do. It was "Neon Moon."
It's always playing on
a jukebox somewhere.
Hmm.
How about we go right to
the dancing part of the evening?
♪ I got a table for two
way in the back ♪
♪ Where I sit alone ♪
♪ And I think of losing you ♪
- ♪ I spend most every night ♪
- This is nice.
♪ Beneath the light ♪
♪ Of a neon moon. ♪
- Winston.
- Hundley?
Yes.
The mom is critical,
but the dad is calmer now.
He wants his son with him.
- Okay.
- Come on, sweetie.
Let's go see your daddy.
Winston.
Dr. Hawkins.
Yeah. Do you have a minute?
I have two minutes.
Walk with me back to my office.
What's going on?
I have a personal question
for you.
- Hope you don't mind me asking.
- No, go on.
Well, you know I lost my wife.
Yes. I'm so sorry.
Devon told me
you lost someone, too.
A partner who died suddenly.
Yeah, we were together
almost 20 years.
He had a heart attack.
Was totally unexpected.
So you know about grief.
I do. It was overwhelming.
How did you cope?
For a while, quite badly.
I almost let what I'd lost
destroy me.
But eventually I realized
I had one life to live,
and I wanted it
to mean something.
I have my daughter,
and that saved me.
But no matter what I do,
for the last four years,
I just can't let Nic go.
I keep remembering
this one specific evening.
First date after we had Gigi.
Maybe you shouldn't fight
these memories.
Maybe they're trying
to tell you something.
The past never goes away.
If you don't deny it,
you can learn from it.
Mr. Alvarez.
How's my wife?
We managed to stabilize her.
Thank God.
And thank you both.
Her heart was damaged,
likely from the flu
she had recently.
What she has is
post-viral myocarditis.
Her pregnancy makes this
even more life-threatening.
Her heart isn't strong enough
now to beat for two.
We're so sorry to say this,
but the only safe option
for Trini is to...
is to end the pregnancy.
What?
N-No.
No, that-that's impossible.
Y-You're talking about
killing the baby.
That would be murder.
We can't deliver
the baby at five months.
It's not viable.
We understand
your pain is enormous.
But we believe your wife will
not survive if we don't do this.
Mr. Alvarez,
your son will lose his mother.
Honestly, it's not a choice.
We can only save one life.
- Hers.
- No.
I-I will not accept this.
There has to be another way.
There is no safe way.
Please, there has to be!
Dr. Voss, we have a problem.
We have a patient who has to
terminate her pregnancy
to save her own life.
Her heart is failing.
- God, how awful.
- The husband is certain
there's more we can do
to save both mom and baby.
And is there?
All we can offer is
an incredible long shot,
almost certain to fail.
And what does the patient
want to do?
She can't make the decision.
She's intubated.
Her husband is
her health care proxy.
So the real question is,
do we even suggest
this alternative
that we think is
far too dangerous?
Oh, this is a tough one.
But if he won't agree
to end the pregnancy
to save her life,
you have no choice.
Just make the consequences of
your plan crystal clear
so he knows
the risks he's taking.
Dad, do not
move. You know better.
I have an itch.
We're almost done.
I don't want him to be sick,
but please tell me
he can go home.
Let's figure out
what's wrong with him first,
then plan next steps.
I'm so sorry.
He has pancreatic cancer.
I'm a doctor, a good one.
And I had no clue.
Well, that's not unexpected,
Dad.
Pancreatic cancer,
it can often be asymptomatic
until it's too late.
Okay, thank you for clarifying.
I must have skipped the part
about pancreatic cancer
at medical school.
I'm just trying to help.
Well, you can't help.
Look, I've just been handed
a death sentence.
All right, how long?
How long do I have?
Pancreatic cancer is
a terrifying diagnosis.
For most,
five-year survival rate is
less than ten percent,
but your odds are different.
Look at the scans again.
The tumor appears...
localized at the head
of the pancreas.
Yes, which means it's operable.
Now, five-year survival rate
goes up dramatically to 25%.
A cure is possible?
It is. Yes.
Cade, you hear that?
If the cancer hasn't spread.
- You need a complicated procedure.
- The Whipple.
We have a world-renowned surgeon
right here at Chastain.
He's performed the Whipple
hundreds of times.
Dr. Randolph Bell.
Still a dangerous surgery
that could have
serious complications, but...
Okay, can you please
stop measuring me for a coffin?
Let's just be positive
for one minute.
Is it too much to ask?
Dr. Hawkins just said
I can survive this.
Since it's obvious
I'm not helping,
I'm going to step out now.
You know, if anyone
can survive this, you can.
Well, that went well.
You're under
unimaginable stress.
But...
I think you need to recognize
that this is hard
for your daughter also.
Can you take the young man
out to the waiting room
for a few minutes?
- Thank you.
- It's okay.
- No problem.
- Thank you.
Mr. Alvarez, we still recommend
you end the pregnancy,
today if possible.
It is by far the best chance
for Trini.
Although there is another option
that we can try.
What is this option?
Well, we could put Trini
on a machine called an ECMO.
It would ease the stress
of her struggling heart,
and it might perhaps
buy us some time
and keep her alive
for a few more months
until she can deliver the baby
safely.
That sounds perfect.
- Do it.
- No, it is far from perfect.
You have to understand
that ECMO is very dangerous.
There can be complications
like hemorrhage, stroke,
- infection.
- Brain damage is possible.
She could wind up paralyzed.
Unable to speak. Blind.
And she could die
from any of these complications.
Then the baby would die as well.
But there's a chance
that Trini and the baby could
both be fine with this ECMO?
That is a remote possibility,
Mr. Alvarez.
So, let's be clear,
you are giving up
the absolute best chance
that we have
of saving your wife's life.
Listen.
If we end the pregnancy now,
down the road, she can safely
have another child.
My heart tells me
that you can save them both,
and I believe that
Trini would want you to try.
Please.
Why does he lash out at me?
He's scared.
Obviously, things have not
been easy between you.
But now is the time
for patience and understanding.
Of course.
I love him.
Despite the fact
that I can't remember
the last time he said
he loved me.
When I was little,
all the other kids thought
I had the coolest dad.
Charmed them all.
Bought them all ice cream.
Entertained them
at my birthday parties.
It took a while to realize
that he lives
for the reflection he sees
of himself
in other people's eyes,
and I see him too clearly.
Forgiveness and acceptance is
a beautiful thing.
I didn't even talk to my father
for years.
I realized our problems were
a two-way street.
I wasn't as blameless
as I thought.
So...
I gave him a chance,
and he was capable of
more than I ever
could've imagined.
Now we couldn't be closer.
You only get one father.
You can't change him,
and you may lose him.
Now's the time
to accept him as he is.
Thank you.
♪ Dear troubles
I long to forget ♪
♪ It seems so many of you
have collected in a day... ♪
Oh, Nic, it's not
what you think.
- What are you doing?
- Her name is Anna.
Oh, Anna. Great.
Not exactly the image I want
in my head when I'm at home
nursing our daughter
and changing her diapers.
Will you just let me explain?
Honestly, I just
want to go home.
Let's just go somewhere
and talk about it.
Once you know who she is,
you'll feel very differently.
♪ Defaulted in pain
and sorrow... ♪
Okay.
I diagnosed Anna's husband
with stage 4 lymphoma
- two months ago.
- Well, if her husband's so sick,
then why is she at a bar alone?
She isn't.
She's with her girlfriends.
It's her birthday.
And her husband's
in the hospital
after having
a bad reaction to chemo.
He's in the ICU.
Her friends decided
to get her out and away
from a situation
she couldn't control.
She'll go back in a few hours.
Sleeps in his room.
Wow.
I am so sorry.
I didn't know.
You have nothing
to be worried about.
You're the only woman I've loved
since the first moment
I saw you.
And I can't imagine
life without you.
Oh, I love you.
I'm sorry.
I'll talk to Bell
and book an OR, okay?
Just tell me.
I can't wait any longer.
Is it good news?
Look for yourselves, ladies.
Leela.
It's a miracle.
♪ Sista, sista! ♪
There's only one thing that
could make this day happier.
This pregnancy journey,
it drove you and Devon apart.
So, please,
before it's too late,
talk to him
and tell him you love him.
Hey. Came to say goodbye?
We need to talk.
That's a good idea.
Let's part as friends.
Actually, I was hoping
for something different.
I don't want you to go.
Leela, I start at Baltimore
Advanced Sciences on Monday.
I want to try again.
I'm not happy.
You're not happy.
I miss you.
And I think you miss me.
Yeah, I miss you a lot.
But nothing's changed, has it?
Actually, something has changed.
This is my patient on ECMO.
She's desatting.
I want to talk to you about
this, but I have to go, okay?
Promise me we'll talk later.
I have a big surgery,
but if you're still here...
If not, I'll see you
at the engagement party.
Her pressure spiked just
as her heart rate dropped.
Cushing's reflex.
Classic sign of stroke.
It happened faster
than we imagined.
I'm going to adjust
her arterial support
to get her blood pressure
in a tighter range.
It might be too late.
Let's get her to CT, all right?
And page Billie.
Images coming up.
Here's the problem.
Bleed, left side of the brain.
Hemorrhagic stroke?
- Mm-hmm.
- Definitely.
Damage may be extensive.
Potentially paralyzed.
I mean, she may have lost
the ability to speak forever.
And worse still, this could
just be the beginning.
I see more possible bleeds
near the dura.
I mean,
this could have been avoided.
Did you make her husband
understand
this was likely to happen?
Come on, man,
don't you think we tried?
We advised against
it in the strongest terms,
but he is her health care proxy.
And we had no idea that
she would have complications
- this fast.
- Look, all we can do now
is double down
on trying to save Trini,
no matter what condition
she's in,
and hope we can keep her
on ECMO long enough
for her heart to recover
or for the baby to mature
enough to be viable.
Can you guys give us a minute?
Look, I am perfectly aware
of the risks of this surgery,
so I know that I may not
get off that OR table.
You got the best of me.
And none of the bad.
I am so proud of you,
and I always have been.
You are the child of my heart...
...and if I haven't
said it enough,
then I need to say it now.
I love you.
All right.
Now go back to being a tough
bastard and beat this thing.
You got it.
Hi, baby.
Aw. Hi.
- Update me.
- We troubleshot everything,
but as you can see...
Her heart's giving out.
She has a few minutes left,
maybe.
Excuse me, excuse me.
What's going on?
What's happening to Trini?
Mr. Alvarez,
I am terribly sorry...
...but your wife is dying.
Just keep her
on the machine, right?
You said that it would
take over for her heart.
- Let it keep working.
- We can't.
Her heart is too badly damaged.
We tried to tell
you this was a long shot.
- It didn't work. I'm so sorry.
- No. Please.
No.
Mommy?
Do something!
Please do something!
Please.
There's nothing more we can do.
We can't bring her back.
She's gone, Matias.
No.
Don't tell me that.
And with that,
we dissect the pancreas.
Pancreas is mobilized.
Oh, wait. W...
What's the update?
Well,
looks like the tumor
has adhered to the IVC.
Which means they have
to resect it.
- If they nick the IVC...
- That's not gonna happen.
Bell's done this
thousands of times.
Dr. Devi...
- ...all yours.
- What is he doing?
He can't pass this off
to a resident.
- Leela has never done a Whipple.
- Which is why she has to learn.
Bell's there to back her up.
Satinsky clamp, 3.0 Prolene,
sponge stick and forceps.
Dr. Chu, do you have
Rh null blood up there?
- I do.
- Hang it, please.
We're in for some turbulence.
Clamp on.
Dissecting the tumor off now.
Blood pressure's in the toilet.
Going up on pressors.
Okay, Dr. Devi
has finished the dissection.
She anticipated this.
I've identified the
defect, but I'm having a hard time
getting in position for repair.
Well, remember your anatomy.
This is Cade's father,
so maybe in this case,
you should...
The Whipple is the crucible
of a surgical residency,
it's the final test.
Just get in there and ace it.
It's your OR, Dr. Devi.
- Proceed.
- Right.
Dr. Chu, reverse positioning
of the patient, please.
Okay, that's excellent.
You have a clear path
to the defect.
3.0 Prolene to you.
Closing and over sewing.
Hemodynamics settling.
That's strong work, Dr. Devi.
She rose to the occasion.
Yes, she did.
He's gonna make it out
of the OR, isn't he?
Yeah.
Now we just have to make sure
the cancer hasn't spread.
We'll know in a few hours.
♪ Should I stay
or should I go now? ♪
♪ Should I stay or should
I go now? ♪
Oh, I was so glad
you guys could make it.
- Thank you for coming.
- Thank you for including me.
- Yeah, so happy to be here.
- So, Randolph, what's your secret?
How did you land such
an incredible lady like this?
She has very low standards.
Nope. Nothing but the best
for this lady.
So, when's the wedding?
- Uh, still working on that.
- Mm...
But rest assured, it will
be intimate and fabulous.
And you're all invited.
- Hear, hear.
- Cheers.
♪ Should I stay
or should I go? ♪
"Roses Are Falling"
by Orville Peck plays...
Hey.
Hey. I got here early
so we could talk.
I heard you aced the Whipple.
That's not what I want
to talk about.
Do you still feel
the same way you did before?
I do.
I can't promise
I'll want a child in the future,
but maybe I will.
- I don't know.
- Today I watched a man
sacrifice his wife's
best chance to live
for a baby that hasn't
even been born.
He lost them both.
- That's terrible.
- Yes.
But it made me realize
something about myself.
That I'm doing the same thing,
choosing a hypothetical child
that may never exist
over the woman I love.
♪ Roses are falling... ♪
I was at fault, too.
I was impulsive and rash.
And our life together
has to be a decision
that we both make equally.
Do you want to try this again?
- Yes.
- Yeah.
♪ Roses are falling
for you, ooh... ♪
A thousand times yes.
♪ Roses from falling
for you, ooh... ♪
I have a lovely feeling
that Devon
will not be going to Baltimore.
That is a win all around.
You know I pulled Leela
into the Whipple
because she's the one
who can follow in my footsteps?
She's going into neuro
or cardio, right?
Oh, she just told me she wants
to be a general surgeon.
So I get to teach her
everything I know
and she can take my patients
when the time comes.
If the time comes.
Dr. Bell?
I just want to say thank you
for saving
my father's life today.
Well, Dr. Devi was integral.
But we got lucky and
your father got even luckier.
The pathology report came back
just before I left the hospital
and the tumor was localized.
So, there's every chance
he'll be cancer-free.
♪ And I'll do my best ♪
I am so happy for both of you.
♪ To be better than the rest ♪
Thank you.
♪ She is so ♪
♪ So sweet and tender ♪
Come here.
♪ And I'm glad ♪
♪ So glad we made it, girl ♪
♪ She's so ♪
♪ So sweet and tender ♪
♪ And I'm glad ♪
♪ So glad we're making love ♪
♪ Oh, I... ♪
I'm pregnant.
Wow. Ah.
So, I'm gonna be a father.
Yes, and I want you to know
that I'm open to you
being as involved as you'd like.
I know you're gonna be
a loving dad
and a great role model.
Just meet me halfway
and... listen?
I can do that.
But what can I do for you now?
Hmm, maybe open up
another 529 account?
For college?
Why would we need two accounts?
♪ So much more than pretty... ♪
We're having twins.
Are you serious?
Yes.
♪ So sweet and tender ♪
♪ And I'm glad ♪
♪ So glad we made it, girl ♪
♪ She is so ♪
♪ So sweet and tender ♪
♪ And I'm glad ♪
♪ So glad we're making love... ♪
- Wonder what that's all about.
Well, it's good news, obviously.
I was happy to hear
about your dad.
Rumor has it that Kit
may offer him
the peds surgery job
at Chastain.
I heard. I have
mixed feelings about that.
It would be a big adjustment.
Conrad will help you with that.
He already has.
Uh, so the two of you...
Uh, we're friends.
♪ So sweet and tender... ♪
I mean, I was under the
impression that you and he...
Are also friends.
So far.
I'll be right back, okay?
Hey.
Mm, wild guess,
you're not taking the job
at Advanced Sciences.
And I won't be sleeping
on your sofa anymore.
God, I am so done
with your furniture.
That's the best news
I've heard all day.
Why are you sitting
over here alone?
Get out there and party.
Waylon's...
This is where I met Nic.
We had our first date here.
Our first date after Gigi was born.
A lot of memories here.
Well...
maybe it's time
to make new memories.
"Neon Moon"
by Charly Reynolds plays...
♪ There's a run-down bar
'cross the railroad tracks ♪
♪ I've got a table for two,
way in the back ♪
♪ Where I sit alone ♪
♪ And I think of losing you ♪
♪ I think of two young lovers,
running wild and free ♪
♪ I close my eyes
and sometimes see ♪
♪ You in the shadows... ♪
Thank you
for a lovely night out.
Thank you for being kind
about Anna.
Her husband doesn't
have much longer.
There's something else
I wanted to tell you.
They have a child.
A little boy. He won't
even remember his father.
That's awful.
We both know what it's like
to lose a parent.
I bought
a life insurance policy.
- You did what?
- Yep.
A big one.
Well, you're not
gonna die, so...
I certainly hope not.
Mm, that wasn't a statement,
that was an order.
You know, maybe stop
riding your bike to work.
Maybe ease up on the search
and rescue missions.
No matter how careful I am,
anything could happen.
I could get hit
by a bolt of lightning.
- Stop, come on.
- We have to talk about this for a reason.
Watching Anna and her husband
in the hospital,
it just made me think,
what if that was me...
...in that hospital bed?
You know, I don't want to talk
about any of this right now.
- Just drop it.
- If something happens to me,
I want you to be secure
financially,
and I want you
to love someone again.
I mean, don't bring
a date to my funeral.
Oh, my God. Seriously?
Come on.
Unless they're nice
and Gigi likes them.
- Then that's fine, okay?
- Conrad.
After a while,
I do want you to move on.
You deserve happiness,
and Gigi deserves a father.
Just promise me,
whoever it is...
...you'll find someone
who loves you as much as I do.
Hey.
I promise.
Only if you do, too.
♪ Oh, if you lose
your one and only ♪
♪ There's always room here
for the lonely ♪
♪ To watch your broken dreams
dance ♪
♪ In and out of the beams ♪
♪ Of a neon moon ♪
♪ Oh, if you lose
your one and only ♪
♪ There's always room here
for the lonely ♪
♪ To watch your broken dreams ♪
♪ Dance in and out of the beams
of a neon moon. ♪
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Sync corrections by srjanapala