- Previously
on "New Amsterdam"...
Luna, say hi to your mom.
- Still no pulse.
- 18-gauge cardiac needle.
20cc syringe.
Now.
Told you I got you.
- You could make me
co-chair of your department,
or you can find
someone else to administer
precision target therapy...
Max's precision target therapy.
- Dr. Nottingham dropped me
from the cardiac rotation.
- Dr. Nottingham dropped you
at my suggestion.
- You made a mistake.
I'm the best intern up in here.
So good, these hands will be
coming for your job one day.
- Where--where--
where's Georgia?
- Excuse me.
Big day today.
Hey, I'm gonna need
every department
in the auditorium
around noon sharp.
- Some of us have--
what are those called, jobs?
- Yeah, but this
is all about your job.
- So this about
my thoracoabdominal repair
in OR Six?
- Touché,
but this won't take long.
I promise you.
Don't look so worried.
- Look, last time you asked me
to the auditorium,
you accused me of malpractice.
- That was a bad day.
This is a big day.
Huge difference.
Sandra Fall from billing.
- Max Goodwin from medicine.
- I see what you did there.
Big day today.
- You want every department in
the auditorium at noon sharp.
- Wow. Good news travels fast.
- That's one way
to look at it.
- I also have one teeny,
tiny favor.
How good are you
with PowerPoint?
- Don't you have
an assistant?
- Oh, Dora crossed
enemy lines into HCC.
Said she couldn't turn down
a job with, you know,
regular hours and a desk.
- Wow. Couldn't imagine.
- So about that favor.
- So, elephant in the room,
the last time Max
called everybody together,
he fired the entire
cardio department.
Who's it gonna be today?
- Now that Helen is back,
I think Max is announcing
that he's taking time off.
- Well, that's not
very exciting.
Carrot?
- No.
- Okay.
- Max hasn't taken time off
to mourn Georgia's death.
- Yeah, well,
he's compartmentalizing.
You know, one of the healthiest
ways to navigate loss
is to just
give yourself some time.
- He needs to grieve.
- Vijay, you can't
make Max grieve.
- You're not tired
of Max acting
like nothing has happened?
- Yeah, all right,
so hey, everybody,
go ahead and sit or stand
or whatever feels good.
Dr. Sharpe in the house.
Thank you for coming.
So...
We are all here
to discuss
the single most important
study of the last decade.
And I love your enthusiasm,
but pretty sure I am about
to answer your question.
With--yep--no,
with the next slide,
which would be...
uh, sorry, just--
There we go. Yes.
This study impacts housing,
education,
representation,
and especially health care.
I think you all know
what I'm talking about.
I'm talking about
the U.S. Census.
Really? Nothing?
Nothing for the Census--
- Whoo!
- One guy.
- Yeah.
- Thank you, Dr. Frome.
Appreciate it.
So how about this?
What if I told you
that your zip code
plays a factor
in how long you live?
It's crazy, right?
No? Yeah?
It's--okay--this next visual
is gonna answer your question.
Hit it.
Boom.
In Washington, D.C.,
people living
in the Barry Farms neighborhood
have a life expectancy
of 63.2 years.
But just ten miles away,
ten miles, there we go,
right there,
people living
in Friendship Heights
might live as long
as 96 years, right?
Does that--no?
Does that not blow your mind?
Just ten miles represents
a life expectancy difference
of almost 33 years.
Yeah.
- What does this have to do
with New Amsterdam?
- That's a very good question,
and I was just about
to get to that.
These zip codes are just
a shorthand for communities,
and with over 5,000 employees,
New Amsterdam
is also a community.
Yes, well done.
But here's the problem.
I don't know the first thing
about so many of you,
and I should.
I want to.
I want to know everything,
because I'm willing to bet
that if I can improve
your quality of life,
then our patients
will get better care.
Because how can you
take care of others
if you're not
taking care of yourself?
- Are we all getting raises?
- Yeah, I wish, but no.
- Are we getting
paid vacation time?
- No.
We're broke.
But I do have
a little something for you.
If you look under your seat,
you will find--
drumroll, please...
That's you, Sandra.
Yeah, do it.
You got it.
Yes, that's a drumroll.
Yes, the New Amsterdam census.
Yeah, okay.
- Whoo!
- Thank you again, Dr. Frome.
One guy.
So go ahead
and fill this form out,
and then you
can go back to work,
and I will get to work
learning more about you
because I just want to know...
How can I help?
Oh, God.
Why does this hurt so much?
- Probably because
you're doing it wrong.
You're forgetting
to extend from the knee.
- You know what?
I know a great place
I could extend my knee into.
- I'd actually
love to see that,
because at this rate,
you'll be walking
without a cane
in approximately...
200 million years.
- Dr. Ligon...
you should know
that I have always
found you to be insufferable.
- Mm.
- Christmas parties,
staff meetings,
and now I can confidently say
that same quality transfers
seamlessly to your PT sessions.
- And I've seen
80-year-old stroke victims
improve their range of motion
faster than you.
- You know what?
You try recovering
from a fractured tibia
with zero pain meds.
- Yeah,
I wish I could offer you
something besides
modern medicine,
but I'm, you know,
just a doctor.
Actually...
hold on.
- What?
- I do have one thing
that might help you take
your mind off the pain.
- Seriously?
- Huh?
Meep-meep.
But I want it back.
So don't go
getting addicted to it.
- As the new co-chair
of oncology,
I'm happy to announce
that every oncology patient
at New Amsterdam
will be eligible
for precision targeted therapy.
- If the DNA sequence
of your tumor is a match
for the available treatment.
- And all I have to do
is sign this release?
- And we'll sequence the biopsy
we already have on record.
- Which will help us determine
where the defective DNA is.
- So you're saying
my stomach cancer
may not really be
stomach cancer?
- Well, stomach cancer just
tells us where the cancer is,
not necessarily
the kind of cancer.
- Like a license plate tells
you what state you live in
but the numbers are
specific to every car.
- You lost me,
like, ten minutes ago.
Targeted therapy
is exactly like it sounds.
- It works
by targeting the cancer's
genes, proteins, and enzymes,
leaving the healthy
cells alone.
- So all the side effects
from radiation and chemo...
- Gone.
- Diminished considerably.
- So what's the downside?
- Well--
- There isn't a downside
to being tested,
and if you fall in the 5%
who qualify for treatment--
- 5%?
- But it means significantly
less chemotherapy.
Imagine coming in for two pills
instead of two hours.
- I'd miss
my Dr. Sharpe time, though.
- It also means
no more radiation.
- It means full remission.
- Well, sign me up.
- You had me at less chemo.
- See?
We make a great team.
- Manny Talis,
44-year-old school bus driver
with right-sided chest pain.
Heart rate 94.
BP 135 over 80
with resps of 14.
Normal EKG.
But when we went
to put on the EKG leads,
we found this rash.
- Ooh, okay,
get him to curtains.
Okay, Mr. Talis,
good news.
I don't think
you're having a heart attack.
I think the pain is caused
by the rash on your chest.
It's called shingles,
and it is a reactivation
of the virus
that causes chicken pox.
- Is there anything
you can do for the pain?
- Mm, ibuprofen.
- That's it?
- Oh, well,
you could try this.
Maybe you'll find it
more useful than I did.
- I'll tell you what.
I'll trade you.
One of the kids
left this on the bus.
- Ooh.
You're on.
Okay.
Well, I am gonna get
cardiology to sign off,
and if they do, then you can
recuperate at home.
- All right, thank you, Doctor.
- You're calling
the appropriate department
instead of doing it
all yourself?
Who is this Dr. Protocol,
and what have you done
to Dr. Bloom?
- Look at me evolving.
Just page Reynolds
when he's out of surgery, okay?
- All right.
- I use a clamshell incision.
This incision reveals
the pulmonary anatomy
in a spectacular fashion.
You see that?
Now, Duke, why don't you come
on over and take a better look?
Come on.
See that tissue right there?
- Mm-hmm.
- Go ahead and throw in
a couple of stitches.
Let's see what you got.
No harm in admitting
you're not ready.
- No, I'm ready.
- All right, well...
I hope you sew more confidently
than you sound.
- Dr. Reynolds.
- Duke, you got
about four seconds
till my patient goes south.
Mm.
- Lower chance of dehiscence.
- Damn, Duke.
It's like a sewing machine.
I want everyone to observe
Duke's forward sutures.
See that?
That's excellent.
- They might not get it now,
but as soon as people see
that this can improve
their quality of life
here at New Amsterdam,
then I think
they're really gonna
warm to it.
- Well, this person
just drew a hand
flipping you the bird.
- There he is.
I gotta say, boss, nice work.
A New Amsterdam census,
that is just brilliant.
- Thank you.
Finally someone who gets it.
- Except there is one community
in this hospital
that can't fill out
your census.
- Why's that?
- Well, because they're not
allowed to use pens or pencils
in an unsupervised setting.
- You mean inmates?
- Yes, exactly. Celery?
- But they're patients.
So what does that have to do
with the census?
- Well, if these patients
could fill out your census
with something
that wasn't considered
to be a weapon,
I bet they would say
they're lacking
in educational opportunities.
- Really?
Is that what they would say?
- Yes, they would,
because studies show that
education vastly
reduces recidivism
among inmate populations.
We have classrooms.
We have inmates.
Why are we not helping?
- Very good idea.
Put it together.
- Good, 'cause I already have.
- We're not done with the
preadolescent process group.
Where do I put the kids?
- You can't have kids
in here with these guys.
Are you nuts?
- Why are the kids
running late?
- Iggy, what's the plan?
- Kids, hi, kids.
Hi, guys, come on out.
Everybody
down to the end of the hall.
- I'm calling the warden.
- No, no, no need.
- Yes.
- No.
- Let's go.
- Just a stutter step, boss.
Guys, my kids,
everyone scoot down.
Nobody talk to the new adults.
Nobody look at the new adults.
Just maybe help me
beat this door down, okay?
Come here. Gladys!
- I'm here.
- Hi. Do we have
the key for this door?
- Uh, let me check.
- Your census will literally
be the death of us.
- Hello!
A little help, please.
- Do you really still
need me here for this?
- Come on.
This is exciting, right?
- I never thought I'd say this,
but please let me
go back to billing.
- All right,
just hit me with another one.
32% of employees
said they pull double shifts
more than twice a week.
- Max.
- See? We can't have that.
Let's put that
under overworked.
No, you know what?
Mismanagement.
Vijay, take a look at this.
300 employees
say that they get less than
two meals per week
with their families.
That's unacceptable.
- Max.
I think you should
talk to someone.
- That's a great idea.
Research shows that eating
family meals together,
like Luna and I
are doing right now,
can result
in lower obesity rates
and kids staying off
drugs and alcohol,
not to mention lower
instances of depression.
So you're all here because,
based on the census,
you're eating virtually
no meals with your families.
Tell me why.
Anyone?
Just shout it out.
Anybody?
- Come on, who has time to cook
after a 12-hour day?
- Long hours. Got it.
Keep them coming.
- Hey, my family lives
all the way in Albuquerque.
- Family too far.
Copy that.
- By the time I get home,
my kids have finished eating.
- Does fast food count?
- Really, Miguel?
- When you put patients first,
you put yourself second...
or third.
- So you gonna send us
home early?
- Yeah, I can't do that.
- Are you sending us
home with food?
- Currently,
I have zero budget for this.
- So what are you gonna do?
- No idea whatsoever, but--
I know. I know.
I'm working on it.
So is Luna,
so yeah.
We're gonna figure it out.
- BMI is 24.
Dead in the middle.
- All right, suction.
Clamp.
- Dr. Reynolds,
Dr. Bloom is still waiting
on that shingles eval.
Think you can handle that,
Duke?
- Yeah.
For sure.
- What are the four things
to do when diagnosing
for thoracic
varicella infection?
- One, measure the rash
and outline it with a Sharpie.
- Uh-huh.
- Two, check for
respiratory function,
making sure
the lungs are clear.
- Suture.
- Three, examine the mouth
for signs of oral lesions.
And four,
check the ear for vesicle
on the tympanic membrane.
- Well, go do it.
Clamp.
Duke.
- Hmm?
- Take off our gown.
- What happened
to your fidget spinner?
- It stopped spinning after
I threw it against a wall.
- So now you have
a rubber band?
- Every time I feel
the crushing pain in my leg,
I snap the rubber band
to refocus
on the lesser pain in my wrist.
- Is it working?
- Can't you tell
by my chipper attitude?
- I've been meaning to ask.
If you're off everything,
how are you managing your ADHD?
- There, my friend, is the
silver lining in all of this.
It turns out that pain
is a great focuser.
Now I actually
want a distraction.
- Dr. Bloom?
Dr. Reynolds sent me
to check on a shingles patient.
- Mr. Talis.
Right there.
- Thank you.
- He must really like you.
Send you down here solo.
- I can't tell if he likes me
or is punishing me.
- Yeah.
Get used to it.
- I think we got it
all surrounded.
- Yeah, looks like it.
- A few deep breaths.
- Oh, yeah.
Sounds good.
Now open wide.
Mm-hmm.
You can't keep me here!
I know my rights!
- Ma'am, ma'am, ma'am.
- I'm calling my lawyer.
- Could you at least
keep the robe on, please?
- Don't tell me what to do.
- Just come over to your bed,
and you can go ahead
and make that phone call, okay?
- Hey, Doc, we done here?
- Yeah, I think we're good.
I'll get you discharged.
- You people don't know
anything about health care.
- Heard it all before.
- Dr. Frome.
- Warden Salazar, hello. Hi.
I assure you that I purchased
all of these lawfully.
- All of these what, exactly?
- The classics.
The stuff that I'm gonna
be teaching in class today.
- I approved this experiment
but not your syllabus.
- I wasn't aware that
I had to submit a syllabus.
- "Autobiography of Malcolm X"?
- Yeah, it's a searing portrait
of race in America.
- "Catch-22"?
- Absurdist
anti-war commentary.
- "The Catcher in the Rye."
- This is censorship.
You are taking away
their rights.
- That's what happens
when you go to jail.
- Oh, okay.
Then what am I
supposed to teach?
- Teach them whatever you want.
Just don't give them any ideas.
- Sounds reasonable.
- Good luck.
Have fun.
- Hey, you paged?
- Yeah, I've got some new
budget recs for you to sign.
- Good. I've been
waiting for these,
seeing as how
you decided to split
your department
with Dr. Castro.
- She's great, isn't she?
- She is,
which still doesn't explain
why you gave her
half your department.
- Uh-oh, my chemo brain's
got me hallucinating
'cause I think I see...
- Max.
You look amazing.
- Did you get taller?
- Whoa, he totally got taller.
- I don't know about that,
but you guys look great too.
- How are you worse at lying
than you are at euchre?
- But I'm gonna look great
after I get my new
precision target treatment.
- Yes, we're all getting tested
to see if we're eligible.
- Yeah, we want the good stuff.
- I just want you
to remember the odds.
Max is one of the lucky ones.
With the treatment.
- It's good seeing you guys.
- Yeah, you too.
- Max, Max, I think what you
are doing is really admirable.
- Is there a but coming?
- No, no, no, no.
You are asking
an essential question.
How can we take care
of our patients
if we are not taking care
of ourselves?
- Yeah, exactly.
- But--
- Ah, okay,
I see what you did there.
You buried the but.
- But there is one employee
you are ignoring
who needs help even though
they are not asking for help.
- Okay, thank you.
- Who?
- You.
- Max.
- Here you go.
Latte for you
and one for you.
I'll take that.
This one goes to you.
- You're gonna pay
for this, right?
- Yes, I am.
See, the reason
that you're all here is,
on the census,
you answered that you each get
less than five hours
of sleep per night.
- We need more sleep.
Can we go back to work?
- Yeah, well, the thing is,
sleep deprivation
is no joke, okay?
It can lead
to high blood pressure,
diabetes, weight gain,
weakened immune system,
not to mention memory loss
and increased errors at work.
- So you're caffeinating us?
- Actually, stimulants
like that mochaccino
can't begin to replace what you
lose from a lack of sleep.
The mochaccinos were really
just a bribe to get you here
so I could ask you why you
aren't getting enough sleep.
So...why aren't you?
- Well, I have
to get up super early
to make it to my shift
on time.
- Yeah, I want to sleep more,
but I got real-life
responsibilities, you know?
- I always think I can nap
during my commute
but too many transfers.
- Too many transfers.
- Right.
- Mm.
- So, like, do you have
any support to fix this?
- No, no support.
Just me.
But don't worry,
because I am all over this.
And if you any additional
questions or comments,
please take them up
with Dr. Kapoor.
- Blood pressure looks good.
- Lap pad.
How'd it go?
- Rash outlined.
Lungs and oropharynx clear.
- What about
the tympanic membrane?
Eardrum.
- Yes, clear.
I think.
- You think?
- It was.
- Good.
Well, come on over.
Show us some more
of that all-star suturing.
Dr. Duke?
We're waiting.
- Okay,
so of the approved books...
For this class, I have...
I have "Aladdin."
- Whoo!
- Okay, yeah.
- Yeah, yeah, good movie.
Fun movie.
Kids' movie, really.
Um...
any dads in the house?
Where my dads at?
- Yo, what's "Aladdin"
gonna teach us about anything?
- Well, you see, I...
Aladdin didn't--he didn't
start out as a prince, right?
That's not where
it began for him,
but he did have some skills.
He was a hustler.
- Yeah.
Yes, thank you, Bijan. Yeah.
- And the book
isn't called "Aladdin."
It's "1,001 Arabian Nights."
- Yeah, no, correct again.
Thank you.
Good for you.
You're right, though.
Aladdin was a hustler
and a thief.
But he figured out
how to use those things
and turned them
into a benefit for his life.
- Aladdin goes legit.
- Yes!
Yeah, laugh it up.
He's right.
Wonderfully stated.
Yes, he goes legit.
Aladdin turns his perceived
weaknesses into an advantage.
Right?
Do you understand that?
So whatever you did,
whatever it was
to get into Rikers can be used
as a legitimate skill set
when you get out.
- My boy Luis can use
his hot-wire expertise
to help humanity.
Come on, man.
- Well, no, hang on, now.
Luis, tell me something.
Is it easy to hot-wire a car?
Like, could anybody do it?
- No, bro.
I mean,
if you're not careful,
you could shock
the hell out yourself.
But not me, though, 'cause,
you know, I got the touch.
- I bet you do.
So maybe I'm looking
at a future electrician here.
- Yo, you mean like
I'd be working for the city.
- Sure.
- Like, I could be getting paid
that union money.
- Why not?
- Yeah!
- There you go.
Why not?
Why not? Why not?
Yes, okay.
Who else?
Who else do I got?
Yeah, go.
- I got caught moving product.
- So I imagine
in your line of work,
a lot of people sell...
product, right?
So what did you do
to distinguish yourself?
- Hmm, I never came up short.
My suppliers always trusted me
with the good stuff.
- Great.
That's great.
So it sounds like
you could move
any expensive product, right?
You could be
a high-end car salesman.
- Yo, I'm done with this fool.
- Yo, yo!
- No, no, no, wait, wait!
All right, okay.
- Out, out!
Let's go!
Up! Everybody up!
Up!
Class is over!
- I don't think
that's sanitary.
- Yeah, well,
it's chew this gum
or punch someone in the face.
- Are those really
your only two options?
- Dr. Bloom.
- Reynolds give you
another assignment?
- Actually, I was here
to see Mr. Talis.
- Discharged. Why?
- Just wanted to see...
just wanted to say bye.
He's a nice man.
- Yes, he is.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
- I shouldn't have said that.
- Said what?
- That you were lucky.
After everything
that you've been through.
- Yeah, but I am lucky.
I'm in the 5%.
- That's not what I meant.
And you know that.
You can talk to me.
You've always talked to me.
- Stop.
- It's hard to know
what to say.
- I don't want you
to say anything.
It actually makes it worse
when people say something,
so just, please...
Don't.
Getting off here?
- No.
- No?
- What the hell happened?
- Started seizing
in the subway.
Finger stick glucose 120.
- Okay, get him to Trauma One
and push two milligrams Ativan.
- Got it.
- Ativan on board.
- BP 108 over 60.
- He stopped seizing.
Stabilized.
- Sat 94%.
- Airway clear.
No tongue bite.
- He has a vesicle
on his tympanic membrane.
The shingles advanced
to Ramsay Hunt syndrome.
He has a herpetic infection
throughout his whole body.
- How did we miss that?
- Get Reynolds down here now.
- So when I finished
going through the census data,
I discovered that 81 people
chose not to fill it out,
17 people defaced the census
with decidedly
colorful language,
and one person simply wrote,
"I am not your blanking
assistant."
So by using
the process of elimination,
here we are.
- So, what,
we didn't take a census
and now we're in trouble?
- No, no, nobody's in trouble.
I just want to know
why 60 questions
made y'all so angry.
- Because I have too much work
to answer 60 questions,
and I have too much work
to be here right now
explaining why
I don't have time to be here.
- Okay, makes sense.
Anybody else?
- If I don't have time
to go to my kids' PTA meetings,
I don't have time
to take an unofficial survey
so my boss can get to know me.
- That's fair.
- Yeah.
- Technically,
I don't even work for you.
I work for the city.
- You always call me
Sandra Fall from billing,
so you know what my job is,
yet you spent all day
making me do
someone else's job too.
I don't have time
for that, Max.
None of us have time.
- So it's time.
- For what?
- No, no, no, the common thread
between everyone.
All the inefficiencies
and the, you know, complaints
and the dissatisfaction,
it's all...
it's all because of time.
- So how are you
gonna fix time?
- Ramsay Hunt syndrome.
- Okay, hey, hey, hang on.
- Disseminated
herpetic infection.
It could not be clearer,
yet somehow it was missed
by your department.
- Okay, let's walk back
the accusations.
- You are lucky Mr. Talis
didn't seize while driving
a school bus full of kids.
- I gave Dr. Duke
the checklist, right?
And he said he checked it.
- Well, he couldn't have.
Otherwise,
we wouldn't be here right now.
Mr. Talis wouldn't be here.
- Duke?
- Yes, I went through
the checklist.
- Did you look in his ear?
- He said he looked.
- He has a vesicle
on his eardrum.
If he'd actually
bothered to look,
he would've seen it too.
- It must not have been there
at the time.
- There is no way
it grew in two hours.
- Okay, if Dr. Duke
said he looked,
then he looked.
- Or he's lying.
- Back off!
All right, this is my intern
you're accusing.
If there's any blame
to be dished out,
I'll do the dishing.
- Clean up your house, Floyd.
- I have the results.
- And?
- 17 of our patients qualify.
- Oh, my God.
That's amazing.
- I'll notify
the insurance companies,
some of whom probably haven't
even had a claim like this.
- Wait, there's no one
from the euchre group.
Willow Yun, Millie Tamberlay,
Mike Kiggens.
- No, none of them
were eligible.
Why are they called
the euchre group?
- They used to play...
when there were four of them.
And then Max got better,
and they...
they stopped.
- You're close to them.
Then they should hear it
from you
that they didn't qualify.
- Of course.
- I'll notify the ones who did.
See? What'd I tell you?
- That we make a great team.
Yeah.
- Now, why in the world did I
think it was called "Aladdin"?
- Nobody reads the book
if there's a movie.
- That is the sad truth,
isn't it?
Listen, I don't feel like we
had a chance to finish earlier.
- You're wasting your time.
- I don't think I am.
- Know why I'm here?
In the hospital?
- I don't.
- I swallowed a fork
for just a couple days
out of Rikers.
A fork.
'Cause recovering from surgery
is my idea of a vacation.
- Bijan, we all have
something to offer.
- Nah. That's what you say
to give yourself hope.
- Okay.
Well, then prove me wrong.
- How I'ma do that?
- When you get out, you're
gonna have an opportunity--
- You even read my file?
- When you get out--
- Yo, I'm never getting out.
I'm in for life.
Not one but two life sentences
for a crime I did commit.
Now tell me again
I have something to offer.
- I just wanted
to tell you how hard
I been practicing
my stitching.
It's gonna be
even better than before.
- Lie again,
you're gone for good.
- I forgot to check the ear.
- And you had the nerve
to lie to me about it.
- At first,
I couldn't remember,
but when I realized my mistake,
I tried to go back and fix it,
but the patient
was already gone.
- Why didn't you come to me?
- I panicked.
And then I thought
since all the other
diagnoses were negative
that the ear would be too.
- How'd that work out for you?
- I just wanted to impress you.
- Well, you didn't.
- Maybe I shouldn't
even be here.
- Hey, don't play
the sympathy card.
Because you deserve to be here.
Those skills you exhibited
in that OR are rare.
You have a gift.
But you're an intern,
and you're gonna make mistakes.
Next time, own them.
- Wait, you're not...
you're not gonna report me?
- I gave you
too much responsibility,
and you weren't ready.
That's on me.
- And Dr. Bloom?
- A mistake like this could
derail your whole career.
This stays between us.
- Thank you, Dr. Reynolds.
- ♪ Took the breath
- Max.
- ♪ From my open mouth
- Dr. Sharpe said I could
find you here
if I can't find you
anywhere else.
- ♪ In circles
somewhere else ♪
- How can I help?
- You know the one thing
on the census
that everyone has in common?
- ♪ When your love was home,
storing up ♪
- Not enough time.
- ♪ On your summer glow
♪ You went
♪ In search of someone else
- You know, when I...
when I lost my wife...
I was destroyed,
like...
parts of me shattered.
So I...I started cooking.
Her recipes.
All the meals
she ever cooked for me.
The taste
brought back memories.
- ♪ My dear
- Memories brought back...
her.
40 years of marriage,
and I'm still cooking
her meals.
You know, every culture offers
you guidance on how to grieve.
Some people build shrines.
Some tear their clothes.
Some even dance in the streets.
Everybody does something,
and...
and you have not done anything,
and I'm...
I'm worried.
- ♪ Anchor up to me, love
- You don't think
I want to grieve?
You don't think
I want to scream
every time I walk
into this hospital?
- ♪ Oh, anchor up to me
- Then I see...
Luna, and I to change
her diaper.
I have to make her bottle.
- ♪ My love
- So...
if I let myself...
grieve...
you know, truly give in,
then...
I won't ever come out.
And I'm all she has left.
- Don't overextend.
Find your balance.
- It hurts.
- Watching you push through
this difficult process is--
how else to put it--
an inspiration.
- Do you know what?
I have tried everything
to get my mind off the pain--
your stupid squishy ball,
fidget spinners,
rubber bands,
gum--and nothing works.
- Not even the gum?
Well, that's a huge
step back for medicine.
- Hey, you know what?
Instead of standing there
grinning like an idiot
and casually insulting my limp,
why don't you do something
that actually helps?
- Range of motion
is suddenly improving.
- Shut up.
- Mm.
Nurse Chatwell, pick up 1317.
Nurse Chatwell,
please pick up 1317.
- Hey, I'm sorry.
I overreacted earlier.
It's just my leg makes
my short fuse even shorter,
which is really, really short.
And I took it out
on your intern.
It won't happen again.
- Appreciate it.
You seem better.
- Yeah?
I think I found something
that helps.
- I hate disappointing you
like this.
- You said it was a long shot.
- I know.
But I gave you hope.
- Eh, negative thinkers
are always right...
or pleasantly surprised.
- I knew it wasn't gonna be me.
It was fun to imagine.
But chemo is working.
I can't complain.
- Dr. Sharpe,
I think you're the only one
that got their hopes up.
- Do you still
have a deck of cards?
- Always.
But you need four
to play euchre.
- Well, deal me in.
- Have you ever played?
- Oh, I'm kind of sharp.
- Hi, hey, excuse me.
Hi, sorry.
Can I have one minute with him?
- One minute.
- That's all I need.
Bijan, may I?
- Can't you just
leave me alone?
Incredibly
stubborn, loves teasing.
Anyway, I've been thinking
a lot about what happened,
and no matter what you did,
no matter how bad it was...
you're so smart.
- You don't know what I did.
- You are not your crime.
That doesn't make up
who you are.
You are smart.
You read
"1,001 Arabian Nights."
Those inmates in there,
they listen to you.
They respect you.
- So what?
What good is that
where I'm going?
- Well, I contacted
a program manager at Rikers,
and I gave him your name.
- Nah, I'm done
with those programs.
I don't want to take
more classes.
- No, no, no, you're not...
you're not
gonna take the classes.
You're gonna
learn to teach them.
Yeah, so many guys in there,
they don't know how to read.
They're done
with programs too.
They hate that stuff, but...
if it was coming from you...
- You want me to teach?
- Yeah.
So that your life,
what you have to offer,
which is a lot,
can reverberate well outside
the walls of any prison.
What's going on?
What are you thinking?
- No one ever told me
I was smart.
- All right, come on.
Let's go.
- Excuse me.
I'm looking for my bus driver.
- Bus driver's in 4223.
- Thanks.
- That's it.
- I did it.
I solved time.
- And how did you do that?
- With a bus.
- A bus?
- Yeah.
Well, buses, to be exact.
But for the same cost
of public transportation,
our employees
can pool their money,
charter a bus to New Amsterdam
from stations
in their own neighborhoods.
So many of our employees have
a two-hour commute each way,
and it's because
they're waiting for transfers,
dealing with delays.
Now it becomes
a one-hour commute
because it's direct.
With two extra hours
in their day,
our employees
can get more sleep,
either at home
or on a bus
that doesn't have a bunch
of stops and transfers
keeping them awake.
With two extra hours,
our employees can make it home
in time to eat dinner
with their families.
They'll have time
to go grocery shopping,
time to cook,
time to relax with the people
that they're working
so hard for.
With two extra hours,
they'll have time
for self-care,
time to exercise, read.
So when they get here,
they'll be focused, alert,
and ready to help
those who need it the most:
our patients.
- You solved time...
with a bus.
- I guess I did.
- ♪ You and me
belong together ♪
- He walks like Max.
He talks like Max.
But...
- I know.
- He isn't grieving, Vijay.
- I thought the same.
But we are wrong.
Max is grieving...
in his own way,
whether he knows it or not.
- ♪ You and me
♪ Belong together
♪ You and me
Hey.
- Hey, sweetie,
how was your day?
Hi.
Oh!