[HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING]
MEREDITH: A painful irony for doctors
is that we often have to make you sicker
in order to heal you.
Megan?
Megan.
Who... Who are you?
Sorry. [LAUGHS] I had to do it.
[BOTH LAUGH]
Will you unstrap me from this thing
so I can hug your
ridiculously pale body?
Yeah.
[BELT CLICKS]
Come here.
If a bone has healed unevenly,
we have to rebreak it.
If a scar is too thick,
we have to scrape it off
and create a new wound.
We break you down to rebuild you.
MEGAN: I was not kept in that hole.
I was tossed in the hole
when the bombing started.
They were trying to protect me.
Trauma surgeons aren't
easy to come by in Iraq.
- So all these years, you...
- I was treated really well.
They'd just, you know,
kill me if I left.
Your wife is really pretty.
I'm really happy to meet you.
Me too. [CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
Hey, stranger. [CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
[SOBBING]
[INHALES SHARPLY]
I'm so sorry.
Shh. Babe, it's okay.
It's okay. I'm okay.
I'm...
Okay, ow.
You're gonna have to... Ow.
- What hurts?
- What's wrong?
There was a bombing six months ago.
I... took some shrapnel.
There were post-op complications.
It didn't heal so well.
♪♪
Okay. Um, all right, everyone!
Listen up, please!
Uh, first, I want to thank you all
for keeping your heads
during the events of last night.
Thanks to you, there were
very minimal injuries,
and the firefighters were able
to contain the blaze quickly.
There was some damage, however,
that will need to be repaired.
Uh, the neuro ICU, the cath lab,
and pulmonary clinic...
[CLEARS THROAT]
[HUSHED VOICE] She fired Eliza.
[HUSHED VOICE] Oh, yeah. I heard.
Just give her some room.
Getting fired is humiliating.
How much room?
Like, hours or days?
...and endoscopy suites...
I've never been fired.
These stations will be off-limits
to pedestrian foot traffic.
Stephanie's gone.
She was airlifted to
a burn center in Texas.
So until further notice,
ORs 3 through 6 are nonfunctional.
Hunt, your sister's here?
Yeah, Riggs is taking her to CT.
Uh, Riggs and I, we're gonna
need to take some leave.
Understood. I'll update Bailey.
Uh, your sister will be
our first priority
- as soon as we're done here.
- Okay. Thanks.
To recap, we are to avoid
ORs 3 through 6
and the entire neuro wing,
as they are unstable.
[CLATTER]
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
And also avoid
fourth-floor nurses station
until further notice.
synced by susinz
*www.addic7ed.com*
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
Hey.
- Hey.
- You're working?
Yeah, I'm gonna work.
How's Megan?
Uh, she's alive.
And... well, not quite well,
but she's funny and sharp
and very much alive,
which is, you know, energizing.
I mean, this miracle happened,
and it makes me aware
that I have the ability
to make that miracle happen
for someone else's family, so... yeah.
I'm gonna work.
You don't think
you should be with Owen today?
You know what...
I'm super-good in a crisis,
but the crisis is over.
[CABINET DOOR CLOSES]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[WHIRRING]
And you've been here for how long?
Couple years now.
And have you met anyone...
you know, significant?
Hey.
Oh, h-hang one sec, Meg.
- Hey.
How is she doing?
Oh, she's, um, got
a frozen abdomen, but...
You know, all things considered,
she's pretty okay.
That's great.
And how are you?
Yeah, all things considered,
pretty okay.
- You?
- Same.
Hey, sorry, Meg. Where were we?
I was asking if you met anyone,
and you were buying time to come
up with an acceptable answer.
- I wasn't buying time.
- Liar.
Look. Uh...
I-I did meet someone.
And?
And... she's not you.
Smooth.
- Right?
- [BOTH LAUGH]
The southwest wing of the
second floor has been cleared,
so all of the patients
in beds 3 through 10
can be transported back upstairs, okay?
- DeLuca, what do you got?
- Beau Martinez, 14 years old.
Presents with intense jaw pain
and recurrent left-sided headaches.
Beau, can you follow my finger?
Good.
- When did the pain start?
- A few months ago.
They took these X-rays
last month. They saw nothing.
They gave him pain pills
that don't work,
and now they won't give him
any more 'cause...
They treat him like he's
a drug addict or something.
That's not my kid.
He can't even play baseball anymore.
He says it's a stabbing pain
in the jaw and mastoid area.
Thought maybe we should get
a head, cervical, maxillofacial CT.
Agreed.
Beau, I've got you.
I know this pain is real,
and I am not gonna rest
until we find out what it is
and how to fix it.
You have my word. You both do.
Okay.
- Is this Megan Hunt?
- Yeah.
Nastiest abdominal wound I've ever seen.
Massive hernia, giant fistula.
The abdominal layers have
scarred and fused to each other.
Her small bowel and colon are just...
One big blob.
And there's not enough healthy skin
to properly close the wound.
I think we just optimize her nutrition,
vac the wound, and wait.
I mean, it'll close eventually.
She wants us to reverse the colostomy.
I can't see a way to make that happen.
Well, I can.
And you taught it to me.
So, I would like to
reapproximate the abdominal wall
a little bit at a time.
Put in tissue expanders
to stretch the skin
and then pull the abdomen
back together slowly.
And then we'll go back in,
take down the fistula,
reverse the colostomy,
and I'll close with
a component separation surgery.
Which means what?
Which means
she's my new favorite person.
Who are you? I'm Meredith Grey.
Thank you for your service, Dr. Hunt.
Well, I admit I've been
out of the O.R. for a while,
but this sounds like a risky surgery.
BAILEY: It most definitely is.
And there's no guarantee
that it'll work.
Yeah, which is why Dr. Bailey and I
would recommend
a more conservative approach.
Thank you, but I just came back
from being presumed dead.
I'm not about to play it safe.
Also, it's really hard
to live with an open
abdominal wound in Iraq.
What do you mean, "in Iraq"?
[SIGHS]
Yeah, I was trying to figure out
how to tell you this.
As soon as I'm well,
I have to go back to Iraq.
My child is there.
♪♪
His name is Farouk. His parents
were Syrian insurgent fighters.
They both died in combat.
I took him in when he was 4.
He's 10 now.
I'm the only parent he has,
and he is the main reason that
I stayed sane all these years.
I'm a grandmother?
[LAUGHS]
And you couldn't bring him with you?
You're a national hero.
Tell that to the U.S. immigration laws.
If your surgery works,
I'll have a functioning bowel?
That's the plan.
Then that's what we're doing.
[WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ON P.A.]
Meredith?
I'm sorry... I would
never have asked you
to consult on Megan's case.
Oh, you didn't ask me.
Well, is you working on Megan
the best idea?
I mean, family and all,
conflict of interest.
She's not my family.
[HUSHED VOICE] Well, I get that, but...
I am the best person for this job.
Just let me help.
[WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ON P.A.]
Are you crying about the empty board?
Did you see Steph last night?
Oh. Um, yeah.
Yeah, look, we...
She was hurt, but we got to her in time.
It was kind of unbelievable.
I mean, it was, uh...
It was thrilling, actually.
You know? It was a rush.
Who am I gonna talk to now?
Who am I gonna compete against?
W-Who's gonna tell me
when I'm being ridiculous
or... or when I stink and need a shower?
Way to make Stephanie's life-changing
injuries about you.
You called it a rush!
Yeah, I guess.
Oh, and, uh, you do.
Do what?
Need a shower.
[SCOFFS]
- Hey.
- Oh. Hey.
You busy?
Uh, have you seen the board?
Come with me.
Hey, looking good, Max.
Feeling good, Dr. Alex.
- Hey, Max, this is, uh, Dr. Wilson.
- Hi.
She's gonna read me your chart, okay?
Max Spencer, 7 years old.
Has had intermittent abdominal
pain and vomiting for months.
Upper GI found evidence of malrotation
due to the presence of bands.
Needs a Ladd's procedure,
which is scheduled for...
As soon my gastric emptying
study comes back normal.
[LAUGHS] Exactly.
Wow. You're pretty smart, huh?
♪♪
Look!
Allora the Warrior Queen! Is that you?!
Max, don't blow her cover.
She's gonna be doing your surgery.
♪♪
Uh...
Are you serious?
You're gonna let me do
a Ladd's procedure? By myself?
Think you can handle it?
Handle it? I'm a frickin' warrior queen!
[CHUCKLES]
♪♪
[CELLPHONES BUZZING, CHIMING]
- You paged?
- Sub-I's.
[CLEARS THROAT] What?
As if we didn't have
enough to deal with today,
Minnick's new sub-I's are here.
- Sub-I's?
- The sub-interns.
The group of fourth-year med students
she's been courting
to be potential interns?
They're here for a six-week rotation.
She didn't talk to you about this?
Well, she may have mentioned it,
but I got pretty good at ignoring her.
[SCOFFS] Well, they're here.
And they're yours.
And they're all in the top 10%
of their programs.
So they're completely socially inept?
Probably.
[GRUMBLES]
- [KNOCK ON DOOR]
- [CELLPHONE CHIMES]
Dr. Hunt.
- Fistulagram?
- Exactly.
Are you sure you want to put
yourself through all this?
It's a tube in my belly, with some dye.
This is nothing.
- Well, I don't need to see it.
- [CHUCKLES]
I'll be back tomorrow
bright and early, sweetheart.
[DOOR CLOSES]
You don't get to see this, either.
- Yeah, I'll take your mom home.
- Okay.
[CHUCKLES]
- Goodbye, Meredith.
- Goodbye, Evelyn.
So, you and my mom
are on a first-name basis?
Well, I was in both of
Owen's weddings, so...
Both of them?
Ho-ho-ho.
This is exciting. Give me the scoop.
Which of Owen wives
did you like better, and why?
I couldn't possibly
answer that question.
Ugh. Fine.
Don't talk about Owen.
Talk about Nathan.
Who was he dating, when,
and for how long?
Okay, Megan, will you let Dr. Grey
just focus on her job, please?
- Buzzkill.
- [CHUCKLES]
Take a deep breath.
All right. Uh, here is the ER.
We are entering the ER.
As you probably know, we are
a level-one trauma center.
We are a level-one trauma center.
Dr. Webber, what is the
trauma volume for Grey Sloan?
Okay, the ER sees 120,000 cases a year.
The ER sees 120,000 cases a year.
- Of which 5,000 are...
- 5,000...
- ...related to trauma.
- ...are related to trauma.
- 22%... penetrating trauma.
Uh, your name, again? Candace Warner.
Uh, Candace, uh...
it might be a good idea
to put away the phone.
I find the voice-to-notes app
the most efficient way
to record the tour.
And I find it the most annoying
way for you to do the tour.
- [DOORS OPEN]
- BEN: Coming through!
Oh! Okay. What do you got?
Pedestrian versus SUV.
Multiple open fractures.
Arrested en route.
APRIL: Let's get set up
for an ED thoracotomy.
Mind if we observe?
Long as you stay out of my way!
Chest tray, size 6 1/2 gloves.
Ready? On my count. One, two, three.
Glove me. Betadine his chest.
Someone take over bagging.
All right.
Hey, Candace, if you were busy
dictating all of this
into your mobile device,
you'd miss all of the...
Aaaaaaahhh!
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaahhhhhhh!
- Aaaahh!
- Dr. Webber?
Okay, look, everybody out! Let's go!
Everybody out! Out, out! Everybody out!
Aaaaaah!
- Aaaaaaaaahhhh!
- Get him up.
He's 35?
Maybe now he's 38.
- And a fireman?
- Mm-hmm.
Oh, ho ho!
- Get it, Mom.
- [BOTH LAUGH]
You know, I didn't like it at first.
Yeah, I still don't like it.
But it makes her happy, so...
[LAUGHS]
I never should've stopped
looking for you.
Ohh.
Owen, look at me.
I'm okay.
There were some beatings
in the beginning
to make sure I didn't try to escape.
But after a while, I made
friends and played cards
and did surgery and raised
my kid, and I was okay.
I didn't want you to waste
your life looking for me.
I used to pray every night
that you had gone home to Mom
and married anyone but Beth.
[CHUCKLES]
I wanted you to be happy.
I still want you to be happy.
And this guilt, it's...
it's worse than useless.
And... there's something
I really need you to do.
Anything.
When I eat, it comes out through
the fistula, like, instantly.
It's disgusting.
So I'm gonna need you
to get me an ice-blended mocha
while Nathan's driving Mom home.
Are you serious?
Ice-blended mocha, stat.
Extra whipped cream.
- [KNOCK ON DOOR]
- Eliza?
Hey, come on. Come on.
I've given you all the time that I can.
Now you... you have to let me
help you lick your wounds.
Wow.
That sounded dirtier than I meant it to.
Eliza! Come on.
♪♪
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
Coffee after 5:00 p.m.? You are
never gonna sleep tonight.
Teddy?
- Hi!
- Teddy!
- What are you doing here?
- Well, Megan's home.
You didn't think I'd come
and see how you're doing?
[BOTH LAUGH]
[SHIP HORN BLOWS]
[POUNDING, DRILL WHIRRING]
[INDISTINCT TALKING]
BEN: So, what's going on here?
It's hard to say. We're still in pre-op.
Yeah, I'm pretty sure
that's the lead surgeon.
- Yeah.
- Oh, and that over there?
Yeah, I think that's
his best scrub nurse.
Huh.
- Is he hot?
- Well, he's not un-hot.
But it's only been a few dates, so...
- [LAUGHING] Ow!
- Sorry.
Just a few more of these shots
to relax the oblique muscles,
create a little more laxity.
Yeah, well, when you're done with that,
you think you can put a little
of that Botox right there?
[LAUGHTER]
That brow has not unfurrowed
since I got home.
Well, it's a brother's job to worry.
- Thank you.
- Wrong!
It is a mother's job to worry.
It is a brother's job to entertain.
Oh, so you want me to tap dance or...?
No, but if you could dig out
- the kilt and bagpipes...
- Ohh.
...that would definitely
make me feel better.
Okay, you play the bagpipes?
For one summer in the eighth grade,
and she'll never let me live it down!
Oh, my God! I want to see that so badly.
Me too. Look. Can I turn around now?
ALL: No!
Avery. You almost done here?
I-I'm doing a tumor board presentation,
and it's kind of pointless
without you there.
Amelia, this is Teddy.
She came all the way from...
From Germany, right.
Um, we spoke on the phone.
- Yeah. It's so nice to meet...
- Yes, yeah, good to meet you.
Um... I'm sorry. I'm distracted.
I have a kid
with an osteoblastoma, so...
You're presenting him. I totally get it.
JACKSON: You know what? I'm done here.
I'll just check back in on you later.
No straining those abdominal
muscles, please, okay?
Yes, sir.
[DOOR CLOSES]
What?
I've been meaning to ask.
How's married life?
[CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
How's your colostomy bag?
[LAUGHS]
Our patient is a 14-year-old
in constant and increasing pain.
DeLuca?
On MRI, he was found to have
a large osteoblastoma
involving the temporal bone,
the mandible, and the mastoid.
It encases the 7th and 8th
cranial nerves.
We managed to obtain a biopsy
through the ear,
and it is benign.
I can resect it from
a sub-occipital approach,
but I will need assistance
with a jaw reconstruction
and temporalis muscle flap.
That tumor's inoperable.
I'm not a big believer in inoperable.
God, yes. Unicorns, possibly.
Inoperable, no.
Then start hunting unicorns.
Your chances are better.
You don't hunt unicorns.
What's the matter with you?
You should treat it with radiation.
Which won't help much.
If you go in, you'll cut
- the cranial nerves.
- No, I won't.
You try to resect
along the zygomatic arch,
you could send this kid home
with no lower jaw.
What, so we just send him home to die?
No. You don't send him
home to die. You...
Send him home to
suffer in miserable pain
for the rest of his miserable life.
I was gonna say send him
to a pain clinic.
Mine is more accurate.
He's letting you do
a pediatric Ladd's procedure?
Like, the whole thing? Solo?
[INHALES SHARPLY]
Is that a bad reason to fall
back in love with someone?
[SCOFFS] Seems as good
a reason as any to me.
Mm... it's a bad idea. Like, bad bad.
Like "it ends with ruined lives
and someone going to prison" bad.
- It's...
- No.
- [CLEARS THROAT]
- "No," what?
No, I will not be your new Stephanie.
Y... She had way more patience
for all of your...
Yeah, no. No.
All right, and this is the skills lab.
Uh, Dr. Wilson, have you met
our new sub-interns?
I... didn't know that was a thing.
- [CHUCKLES]
- Hm.
This is Dr. Wilson.
She's a senior resident.
You want to show the kids
what you're working on, Wilson?
Yes. Uh, well, this is
a virtual dissection table.
- So, for this case...
- [CELLPHONES CLICKING]
...I'm going to lift the omentum
and then run the bowel
from the ligament of Treitz
to the ileocecal... valve.
[CLICKING CONTINUES]
Look up from your notes, people!
- Sir, if I may, this is why...
- No, you may not.
♪♪
♪ Can't keep my hands to myself ♪
She ghosted you.
What? What's that?
No text? No note? Just disappeared?
She ghosted you.
People do that?
Like, often enough
that it has its own term?
It's cruel and awful,
and no one should do it
to anyone ever, and...
I am so sorry.
♪ Might be over now,
but I feel it still ♪
Well, at least she was crystal-clear
about her intentions.
She didn't confuse you with
a whole Montana situation
and then just... linger.
What's a Montana situation?
Is that another term
that I've never heard of?
I feel so old.
Surprise.
[GASPS] Oh, my God!
Oh my God! You're here!
Callie left me, and she went
to New York, and she took Sofia,
and I managed to find love
again, but then she got fired,
and I've been meaning to call
you forever, and I'm so sorry.
Did I ghost you? 'Cause I'm...
I'm... I'm so sorry.
I'm a terrible friend,
and I'm so glad you're here!
[BOTH LAUGH]
♪ I been feeling it since 1966 ♪
Hey.
What? I got something on my face?
No. No, your face is perfect.
I mean...
I... have to... I have a...
What's that?
This was great, but I have, uh...
[CLEARS THROAT]
♪ Ooh-ooh, I'm a rebel
just for kicks, now ♪
♪ I been feelin' it since 1986, now ♪
♪ Might be over now,
but I feel it still ♪
Can you hear me?
Yeah.
I don't think you should be up there.
Why not?
Because what you are about to
see is decidedly unsexy.
Blood... guts.
Nah, you look good in anything.
[LAUGHING] Shut up.
- Hi.
Do you have any questions
before we get started?
- Can I see the expanders?
- Of course.
Bokhee?
Wow! That is... Wow. That's big.
We'll deflate them to put them in,
and then we will slowly
reinflate them with saline.
We're gonna need as much space
as we can get.
You know what we'd say
in the Army right now?
What?
- Say it with me, Nathan!
- Mm.
- Hooah!
Let's do this thing, Dr. Grey.
Let's do it.
Okay.
[MONITOR BEEPING]
[WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ON P.A.]
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS]
[HYPERVENTILATING]
Okay, all right.
Okay.
All right. Look. Hey.
This is a minor surgery. She'll be fine.
This stage is nothing.
[BREATHING RAPIDLY]
All right. You know what?
You... You need to put your head
between your knees.
No.
Head between your knees, Major!
Sit down.
[BREATHING RAPIDLY]
All right. That's it.
All right. Breathe.
I can't lose her again, Teddy.
I know.
I lost 10 years.
She doesn't even look
the way I remember her.
I lost her even in my memory.
And now she's back.
And I can't lose her again.
I know. It's okay.
Listen, you have a plane to catch.
I'm not going anywhere.
[BREATHING SLOWLY]
♪♪
[POUNDING, DRILLS WHIRRING]
[INDISTINCT TALKING]
Ortho docs?
BAILEY: Only louder!
[POUNDING, WHIRRING CONTINUE]
MEREDITH: Okay, you're
gonna feel a little pinch.
It shouldn't hurt that bad, okay?
That's it.
- You good?
- Mm-hmm.
Meredith, I was so sorry
to hear about Derek.
Oh. Thanks. Me too.
Who's Derek?
I-It's a long story.
[CELLPHONE CHIMES]
Oh.
This is for you.
[GASPS] It's Farouk!
Mm.
He's a selfie master.
[LAUGHTER]
That's an impressive snout.
- Yeah, excellent work.
- Where is he now?
Ah, he's with U.S. Military in Baghdad.
I haven't been able
to legally adopt him,
and he's a Syrian refugee.
It'll take years before
I can get him here, if ever.
I just want to get back to him.
Hey, Nathan, are you
planning on moving with...
Megan, uh, looks like
you could use some air.
Meredith, is it okay
if we take her outside?
Oh, my God. Outside? Yes, please.
- I got it! [LAUGHS]
- You all right?
So this is what it
feels like to be a robot.
[BOTH LAUGH]
I don't know about robot.
I'm thinking more... alien?
You think? Or, like,
strange sea creature, maybe?
[SHRIEKING]
There you go. That's it. That's it.
- [SHRIEKING CONTINUES]
- [LAUGHS]
You got a little weird when I asked
about Nathan moving with Megan.
You still upset with him?
Nathan and Meredith were a thing.
Right up until we got
the call about Megan.
And we don't want her to know.
Wait. Are you... Are you kidding?
Owen, are you kidding me?
Meredith is Megan's surgeon,
and you don't want her to know?
You ready?
Okay, you're gonna go to sleep now.
When you wake up, you're gonna be...
A warrior king!
[LAUGHS] Exactly!
Okay.
[MONITOR BEEPING]
All right. You're gonna do great, Max.
[DOOR OPENS]
RICHARD: And this is the O.R.
Dr. Karev, mind if we observe?
Um...
It's up to you. It's your case.
It's fine.
Let's scrub.
Okay, great. Let's go.
Hey. Meredith?
Meredith, you have a minute?
Hi. Yeah.
Did you read this article
that Cristina published
on ex vivo lung perfusion?
It's... It's not appropriate.
To read Cristina's article?
No, for you to operate on Megan Hunt.
Oh. She chose the surgery.
She's aware of the risks.
But she doesn't know about
your history with her fiancé.
I mean, that's a serious
conflict of interest.
You have to step away from this case.
Well, I...
You don't get to talk to her like that.
- Amelia.
- Excuse me?
- Okay, you're not Megan's doctor,
- Amelia.
So if Meredith has decided that she
is equipped to handle a surgery,
- you don't get to just show up here...
- I can fight my own battles.
...like you own the place
and talk to her like that.
I shouldn't have to.
Megan is Owen's sister,
and you're Owen's wife,
so I shouldn't have to
advocate for Megan and Owen,
who have been through hell and back...
a hell which I've personally witnessed.
I shouldn't have to show up here
and advocate for them,
because that's your job.
But you're not doing it.
I have barely seen you.
Because I have a patient.
You also have a husband.
I'm sorry. Is it 1952?
Should I put on my apron
and mix him a gin and tonic?
All right.
It's not appropriate for you
to be Megan Hunt's surgeon...
not when she doesn't have
the whole history.
Who is she?
That's... Owen's... person.
I have a patient.
Bovie.
[EXHALES SHARPLY] Wow.
That's more bands than I expected.
RICHARD: Mind if we take
a closer look, Dr. Wilson?
Be my guest.
Okay. Uh, not you, Candace.
Oh, and not you, either. Two at a time.
I want you to see what
a malrotated bowel looks like.
ALEX: Normally the Cecum
is in the right lower quadrant.
JO: But in this case,
there are abnormal fibrous bands
in the right upper quadrant,
causing compressions of the duodenum.
- [GASPS]
LEVI: Oh, my God!
- RICHARD: Oh, my God.
- JO: Oh, my God!
♪♪
ALEX: Step away from the table, Wilson.
Dr. Karev, my patient, my surgery.
Linda, sponge stick, please.
Okay.
JO: Okay, we're gonna need to change out
the contaminated instruments
for new ones.
We'll need antibiotic solution,
several liters.
And, Dr. Webber, please remove
your students from my O.R.
If you... don't mind, sir.
I-Indeed, Dr. Wilson.
Let's go. Out, out.
Let's go. Out, out, out! Out!
- How's his pressure?
- Holding steady.
Great. Irrigation, please.
You paged Avery?
Yeah. He's coming.
When?
Dr. Shepherd, have you slept?
Well, you stand in this room
staring at this tumor,
and I don't see you eat,
I don't know when you sleep.
Look, I made a promise to this kid.
And I made a promise to his father.
Also, my husband's sister
came back from the dead,
and my brother didn't.
So... sleep is not really
my thing right now.
[DOOR OPENS]
Avery. Good.
I'm thinking if we resect the tumor
and reconstruct the jaw using
a portion of the temporal bone,
we may be able to get ahead of...
This is Kathleen Sampson.
She was 17 when this picture was taken.
And this... was her tumor.
That look familiar?
I did a sub-occipital approach
and a partial tumor resection,
and then she looked... like that.
But she was still in pain.
I hadn't gotten the whole thing,
so it began to grow back.
So I had to go in after it... again.
Then again.
You know what Kathleen looks like now?
There's Kathleen.
I'm not taking that boy's jaw apart.
Please... stop summoning me.
[KEYS CLACKING]
[WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ON P.A.]
[CELLPHONE BUZZING, CHIMING]
- Dr. Webber?
- Ah. Karev.
Uh, you know, I was very impressed
with how Wilson handled...
A situation she never should've
had to handle? Yeah, so was I.
We're here to talk about
the sub-I's, Dr. Webber.
The utterly inept...
Bottom-of-the-barrel med students
you keep recklessly hauling
around the hospital.
Oh, oh.
So you two think you were
any better than them?
Karev, you scraped in
by the skin of your teeth
thanks to an essay you wrote
on testicular cancer...
that I have since found was a lie!
Kepner, you failed your boards
and got fired...
twice!
I raised you two.
I grew you into the surgeons
you are now.
So you don't get to tell me
who I will and won't teach
and how I should or shouldn't do it!
Now, I will thank you to walk away.
♪♪
Minnick's sub-I's can't be taught!
They weren't meant to be surgeons.
I'm not sure they were
meant to be doctors.
Maybe they can be
researchers in some lab,
and even that's questionable!
♪♪
Teddy, it is over
with Meredith, all right?
It was over the minute
I heard Megan was alive.
Well, then, why not tell her?
If it's so over, why are
you keeping it a secret?
OWEN: Maybe because she's been
through enough pain
for one lifetime?
Exactly! Look, there's no reason
to put her through it.
That is such B.S.
I am sorry, but I have
been there with you.
I have been the person
that found out too late
that there was a thing with Meredith,
and it just makes everything worse...
for everyone.
Okay, we were just
trying to protect you.
Well, I didn't need your protection.
I needed information.
Thank you.
I am Meredith's sister,
so if there are sides to be
taken here, I am on hers.
Just tell your fiancée
the truth, Nathan.
'Cause she doesn't want
your pity or your protection.
What she wants is your respect.
- [DOOR OPENS]
- Wait.
You had a thing
with Meredith's sister, too?
Teddy Altman thinks I'm wrong
to do Megan's surgery.
Well, since when do you care
what Teddy Altman thinks?
- [BICYCLE BELL DINGS]
- Well... I don't.
But she thinks I'm wrong,
and Amelia's on my side,
and Amelia is a little crazy.
No one asked me to do it.
I did insert myself.
Why did I do that?
Because you're trying to be
the surgeon you wish Derek had had.
[SHIP HORN BLOWS]
You need to tell Jo
that you hired someone
to find that husband of hers.
Why?
You're trying to win her back,
giving her solo surgeries, right?
Wait. You heard about that?
Everybody heard about it.
Glasses?
[BOTH LAUGH]
It was insane.
But she handled the hell out of it.
Anyway, if you want
to build a future with her,
you really should tell her the truth.
She deserves the dignity
of the whole story.
Yeah.
I really just don't know why
you didn't get your own lunch.
[WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ON P.A.]
- Hey.
I was avoiding you.
Is that what that was?
- I just figured you were a little...
- What?
Odd. Little odd sometimes. That's all.
[INHALES SHARPLY]
I hate when people don't tell me things.
So, um...
the night of the fire,
April said something to me
about me being into you
and you being into me,
and... it was weird,
and I didn't know
what to do with it, so I...
I was odd.
So... April said what?
Crazy, right?
I know.
Um... great.
Glad we're on the same page.
[CHUCKLING] Yeah.
[OWEN SIGHS]
Who's gonna do the talking?
I'll do it.
But if I don't come out
in 10 minutes, call the police.
[CHUCKLES]
Can you wait outside?
Please? We need a minute.
♪♪
Are you in love with him?
I had one great love in my life,
and he died.
♪♪
Are you a mother?
I am.
I need to get back to my son.
And I want to do everything
I can to make sure that happens.
♪♪
Nathan has excellent taste in women.
He certainly does.
♪♪
[CHUCKLES]
Ortho wrapped up yesterday.
Then vascular came in,
did some work on the walls.
This is...
The plastics posse.
Precisely.
Mm.
[SLURPING]
Stop worrying.
Dr. Grey is a bigger man
than either of you.
She'll forgive us
eventually, right? Huh.
[CHUCKLES]
AMELIA: It'll be a long surgery.
We'll have to take apart his jaw
and then take out the tumor
slowly and carefully
to avoid damaging the nerves.
And we will have to wean him off
some of his painkillers.
But you think you can do it?
You can take the tumor out?
Yes.
I think I can.
[MONITOR BEEPING]
Okay, just one more time.
We'll start by lysing the adhesions
to free up the bowel.
And then take down the EC fistula.
After which,
we'll reverse the colostomy.
Phew!
More nervous than I expected.
Well, that's not a bad thing.
Just means you care.
[WATER RUNNING]
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Hey.
Oh. Thanks.
She's gonna do great.
10 blade.
[LOWELL'S "WAR FACE" PLAYS]
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Love fades like a wave ♪
♪ Changing seasons ♪
♪ Pull up my sleeves and ♪
♪ I got my bourbon ♪
♪ I got my Jack and ♪
[ITALIAN ACCENT] You drinking alone?
I was ghosted... by my girlfriend.
Mm.
Do you know what that means... Ghosted?
Si. She disappeared.
Why am I the only person that doesn't...
W-When did this become something
that people do to other people?
I think it's because of the Internet.
We yell to our friends
and family on Facebook
in ways we would never do
across a dinner table.
We become, um, uh... rude.
Unsensitive.
- "Insensitive."
- Insensitive.
[CHUCKLING] Forget it.
I like your way better.
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ You left me bleedin' ♪
♪ Got away with treason ♪
♪ I led the battle into the trenches ♪
♪ I learned my lesson ♪
♪ I count my blessings ♪
♪ You had me howlin' ♪
♪ You had me howlin' at the moon ♪
♪ Oh, yeah, I'm howlin' ♪
♪ Oh, yeah, I'm howlin',
but not for you ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪♪
♪ I wear my war face ♪
♪ And I'm never gonna
take you back again ♪
♪ I wear my war face,
I wear my war face ♪
♪ I wear my war face ♪
Hey. Can I talk to you?
[SIGHS] Please don't.
Don't?
I'm still in love with Alex.
And I know that he hurt you,
and I know that he's... volatile,
and I know that I can't be with him,
but I can't be with you, either.
And we work together, so can we just...
Can we please just not make it awkward?
I wanted to... talk about the fact
that I'm worried about Dr. Shepherd.
But... yeah, let's not make it awkward.
♪♪
♪ Put us back together again ♪
I would like to pay for your drink.
Oh, my...
By... way of apology?
[EXHALES DEEPLY]
For your surgery the other day?
Yes! I remember.
You should probably buy contact lenses.
Already put in the order.
And for whatever it's worth,
you handled that like a boss.
My friend moved away.
And that surgery...
she would've been so impressed with me.
Mm.
[LAUGHING] And we would've
laughed really hard
- at your expense.
- [LAUGHS]
I will totally laugh with you
at my own expense.
And then she would've reminded me
of all the reasons it's a terrible idea
to do the one thing that I
really, desperately want to do.
Which is what?
♪ ...and all of my men ♪
♪ Couldn't put us back together again ♪
[EXHALES DEEPLY] What's taking so long?
Well, we knew it'd be a long wait.
MEREDITH: We go to medical
school because we want to learn
how to fix what's broken.
- Where's Amelia?
- What?
Where's your wife, Owen?
Hey, it's done. Meredith did it.
She's getting ready to close.
Ha!
[LAUGHING] Yes!
- [LAUGHS]
- Come on.
But we quickly learn
that we often have to make things worse
before we can make them better.
[SIGHS] Ohh!
[LAUGHS] Sorry.
Andrea?
Carina?
[SPEAKING ITALIAN]
[BOTH SHOUTING IN ITALIAN]
[SHOUTING CONTINUES]
♪♪
[GASPS] Oh! Sorry.
[SIGHS]
Maybe just, um, take them off?
It's risky and it's frightening
for surgeons and for patients,
but usually, it's worth it.
You get a second chance at life,
and we get to be the architects
of your second chance.
[MONITOR BEEPING]
It's win-win.
What's going on?
[BEEPING CONTINUES]
- When it works.
- Meredith!
There isn't enough tissue.
I can't close.
[BEEPING CONTINUES]
synced by susinz
*www.addic7ed.com*
Damn it!