Previously on "ER."
So, four candidates
including me.
Actually...you make it five.
This hearing aid's expensive
when I just found out
that my insurance won't cover.
I said that we share everything
and I meant everything, okay?
I practice my IVS
on a mannequin.
That's good. But know
when to ask for help.
I want you to toast the
new pedes ER attending, me.
I have heard of
foreign doctors
who were willing to
start over as interns.
If they amputate,
is it certain I'll live?
It looks like it's stopped
like two and a half blocks.
‐ Should we hoof it?
‐ I don't know.
Aren't you supposed
to be setting policy?
I'm here for
the ride‐along.
‐ I hate one‐way streets.
‐ This is nothing.
I once responded
to a cell phone call
from the middle of
a Metallica concert.
Try getting an anaphylactic
head banger past 10,000 maniacs.
Guy dropped some acid,
started him counting crows.
I have to live with
this every day.
You got any pull
with crew assignments?
Hey, hey, hey.
Hey, but if you do,
can you get us assigned
to the med team
at the Bears' game?
Look, I don't do
the scheduling, guys.
Too bad, you were almost
my new best friend.
Make way!
Hey! Paramedics
coming through!
Hey, hey! Stand back!
Stand back! Hey, hey.
Give us some room.
Looks like a single..
Whoa, whoa, jeez!
‐ It's Cujo!
‐ No, no.
He's just
protecting his owner.
‐ Okay, you open the door.
‐ Sir, can you hear me?
‐ Is he breathing?
‐ His chest is moving.
Got any ideas?
Oh, you're asking me?
Unit 57 to OCD, over.
A little puppy valium?
We need animal control
at fourth and orchid.
We've got dog barring access
to an MVA victim, over.
It'll take too long.
Look at this.
He's right.
We got to get in there.
'What do you suggest?'
‐ I got a gun in the rig.
‐ I'll keep him busy.
'You're kidding, right?'
We've got to assess him now.
'You're the boss.'
Hey, boy.
Hey, hey, hey, ready?
One...two...three! Hey!
Got a pulse.
Good breath sounds.
Get a backboard.
‐ You okay?
‐ Yeah, I just can't let go.
When was your last
tetanus shot?
‐ 1992.
‐ Haleh?
One booster coming right up.
That's okay. I'll pass.
It could be worse.
You could have rabies.
Yeah, I wouldn't
rule it out.
Think we'd notice
a difference?
So, how many
interviews today?
Two. You and one other.
Yeah, you know,
I'm still interested
but I decided not
to push so hard.
I mean, if I get it,
you know, I get it.
‐ Good idea.
‐ What do you mean?
I mean, you know,
it's just not a good idea
to get worked up
over these things.
‐ Hey, what happened to you?
‐ Ugh, long story.
‐ Rachel's sleepover?
‐ Good guess.
‐ Thanks, Kerry.
‐ What's going on here?
Graffiti guys got loose,
went crazy last night.
‐ Yeah?
‐ You're on?
No, I'm just getting set
up for tomorrow.
Color‐coordinated
charts?
Well, whoever said
Doug Ross isn't organized?
‐ I did.
‐ Take it easy.
Hey, um, Mark, don't attendings
pay for nurses night?
Yeah, now Doug
can contribute.
No, that's the ER.
I'm the pedes ER.
Yeah, well, pedes needs nurses,
right? So I'm billing.
Hey, get this.
19‐year‐old,
third pregnancy
says she doesn't know
how to use a condom.
So, did you teach her?
Oh, no, we're
way past that.
I'm talking her
into a newer plan.
Are you sure?
I'd tie her tubes
myself, if I could.
I don't know, if
the drawbridge is up
you can't storm the castle.
‐ Excuse me?
‐ Try a diaphragm. They work.
Oh, yeah, I wouldn't be too
sure. I'm three days late.
Mm‐hmm.
What? What?
These just came from upstairs.
‐ Letters of rec for chief.
‐ Thank you.
Okay, lift your sleeve.
When was the last time someone
got tetanus from a dog bite?
Don't be a baby.
‐ Nice suit, Dr. Weaver.
‐ Thank you.
I didn't know
you read "Cosmo."
‐ Excuse me?
‐ Ow!
Last month's article
on the power suit?
Oh, uh, I guess
I missed that one.
Oh, are you sure,
'cause, I mean
you nailed it down
to the accessories.
So how long
have you been on?
Oh, just now.
Yeah? Who's your resident?
Oh, well I suppose
I'll find out in a minute.
Why? Did you vie for me?
You're too much
for me to handle.
Hopefully, whoever I get
feels the same way.
No, I suspect I'll be
sidelined as a consultant
more than anything else.
Yeah.
Hey, do me a favor.
Reach in his bag
and hand me his hearing aid.
It's in the black
case, on top.
Is he having trouble
with these?
No.
So why are you
putting them on now?
I was running late.
Peter, have you
not told everyone?
Told who?
Look, Elizabeth, I don't
have time for a whole bunch
of a repetitive questions
and‐and‐and sympathy.
You sure that's it?
My son is deaf.
I know that, okay?
Okay. Okay.
Well, wish me luck.
Jeff Whitcher, 38‐year‐old
magician, inhaled flash powder.
What happened?
Trap door didn't open.
A little more
complicated than that.
Short of breath
and tachypneic.
Uh, respiratory
rate is 28.
No previous history
of respiratory illness
or inhalation of
toxic substances.
What's in flash powder?
Sorry. Trade secret.
Lycopodium wrapped
with potassium nitrate.
I looked it up
on the internet.
Pulse ox is
borderline 91.
No cyanosis.
‐ You a smoker?
‐ Occasional.
Yeah. Occupational hazard.
You can't smoke
that here.
Wasn't planning to.
What do you want to do?
Get a blood gas
and check a PO‐2.
Looks like you get
to learn a new procedure.
I just happen to have
a blood gas kit right here.
Hey, pretty good, doc.
Trade secret.
Lily, can you get
us a cup of ice?
‐ Sure.
‐ Please.
We're out of gloves.
I'll be right back.
Try your pocket.
Hey, how'd you do that?
He's got your arm.
It's not what they see..
...it's what they
think they see.
But you didn't
even move.
‐ Lucy?
‐ Yes.
A blood gas.
This one you watch,
next one you do.
Don't panic, Doug.
It's just a couple of days.
Honey, you said three days.
You said three.
Two, three, whatever.
You told me you were
regular as a Swiss watch.
Yeah, I'm regular,
not a machine.
Are you going to do
a pregnancy test, or..?
You're really
sweating this.
I may. Aren't you, a little?
I'm not pregnant.
I don't feel it.
Have you been
pregnant before?
Oh, I shouldn't
have said anything.
'What's up? What happened?'
‐ Syncope. Fourth episode.
‐ Seizure?
I don't think so.
I thought you weren't on today.
I'm not. You wanna use
the pedes room, no waiting.
‐ Okay.
‐ Here we go.
Hey, what's this?
What's this? Hey!
Could be Carter's.
They were backed up today.
Carter! Is this
your body in here?
Yeah, sorry. Transport's taking
forever. You need the room?
'Yeah, I need the room.'
Give me a hand?
I didn't even think the pedes ER
was open until tomorrow.
It's not. Just don't leave
your stiffs in here.
Lucy, take him in the morgue.
You know, we've been waiting
on a transfer
for three hours.
‐ Hey, this The Prince Albert?
‐ Who?
You know, his
ding‐dong's pierced.
He's supposed
to have a diamond.
A diamond in his penis?
Haleh said, it was tricky
getting in the Foley.
‐ Want to take a peek?
‐ That's okay. I've seen one.
‐ I bet.
‐ Hey, watch it.
I guess it's your lucky day.
It seems I'm your intern.
‐ I know. You missed rounds.
‐ Oh, it's the first day.
I wasn't exactly sure
how this was going to work.
You need to be here
at 5:00 A. M. sharp.
I hope you don't expect
any special treatment.
Look, I don't know
what you've been told
but this is more of a
formality than anything else.
Maybe for you, but you're
the only intern I have.
I need you to finish
pre‐rounding before 6:00.
I need all the vitals.
T‐max, mental status,
I's and O's.
After rounds, check the labs
and run down all X‐rays.
Go over the X‐rays yourself.
Don't trust the radiologist.
Buff the electrolytes
as needed.
You take all floor calls.
If we have clinic that day,
you do H&Ps.
And of course,
all pre‐op orders
CBC, lytes,
UA, EKG, PT.
I do know how to pre‐op
a patient, thank you.
Well, good, because
if surgery's canceled
because you miss a lab,
it's your ass.
We'll start with
Mr. Anderson.
I reduced his O‐2.
Redraw an ABG
in 30 minutes.
Monitor urine
output Q one hour.
Advance drains on beds
three and five.
One, two and six need
wet‐to‐dry dressing changes.
You're serious.
This is how it works.
As third year,
I'm busy operating.
This stuff
is not my job.
But the scut
has to be done..
...by an intern.
I have three cases today.
If you finish,
you can scrub in for one.
Oh, and this is for you.
Interns wear short coats.
'Hold the elevator!'
'Hold it!'
You alright?
‐ I said hold the elevator.
‐ Oh.
'What was he wearing?'
‐ I don't know.
‐ Where are we?
We got a multiple defensive
stab wounds
to the extremities.
One to the forearm
and one to the chest.
BP's 120/75. Pulse ox 99.
Did the guy have
friends with him?
Both lungs
are clear.
Four plus right radial
and ulnar pulses.
‐ What's your name?
‐ Bo.
Bo, we're going to take care
of you, don't worry.
Yeah, you're very lucky.
The chest wound
is superficial.
Okay, Bo, I want you
to do this with your hand.
How about a car, Bo?
Did you see a car?
Okay, now spread your fingers
and don't let me close them.
Alright, I'm tired of this game.
Just tell me who it was.
‐ Does he have to be here?
‐ Why don't you wait outside?
'He was stabbed
in broad daylight.'
You're telling me,
you didn't see anything?
You know what?
Wait outside.
Okay, let's roll him.
He's gonna go out and try
and settle this on his own.
Right now we have
to treat him.
You know what?
Forget it.
Have it your way.
'You could have pressed
that hold button.'
Damn, these
elevators are slow.
I'm going to catch
that lunch traffic.
I know it!
‐ You drive?
‐ A lot.
My son used to have
one of those.
Gave him a heart attack.
Nothing but stress.
Come on. Come on.
No, I didn't watch
the whole thing
but the part I saw
looked pretty benign.
It was my fault. Sorry.
‐ Well, you did. Thanks.
‐ Problem?
Did you know that
"Romeo and Juliet"
is rated PG‐13?
‐ I wasn't aware of it, no.
‐ Well, it is.
And I showed it
at Rachel's slumber party
and now all the mothers
are calling me.
Oh, yeah.
'Elizabeth?'
'Elizabeth!'
Can you come take a look
at a pulseless foot?
I've been waiting 40 minutes
for a surgical consult.
Normally, I would, but as of
today, I'm only an intern.
Yeah, I heard about that.
I couldn't believe it.
I don't want
to believe it myself.
I already have
five admissions.
Lab turnaround time
is pathetic.
And radiology have already
lost three of my films.
Meanwhile, Dale has me
sitting for a bleeding time
on your Ewing's
sarcoma amputation
which is a complete
waste of time.
Amputation. You're talking
about Dana Ellis?
Yes. She doesn't have
a clotting problem.
‐ Is that today?
‐ Yes.
Surgery's scheduled
for 4:00 P. M.
Five minutes.
54‐year‐old male.
Peripheral vascular disease,
cath pain at rest.
I'm thinking
arterial thrombosis.
‐ Did you get a Doppler pulse?
‐ Yeah.
Mr. Darcy, this is Dr. Corday,
our surgical resident.
Look, how long will this
keep me out of commission?
I'm supposed to choreograph
a music video next week.
Well, let me examine you first
and I'll have a clearer idea.
Are you a smoker?
Yes, but what has that
got to do with my leg?
This the vascular consult?
'Yeah. I asked
Dr. Corday to examine.'
I'll take over.
Did you get the labs on
the prefed diverticulum?
Not ready yet.
They're backed up.
Better go down there
and sit on them.
You know Romano.
Got to start on time.
Of course.
Come on.
‐ Lucy?
‐ What?
‐ Is something wrong?
‐ Nope.
Can you work up this guy
with vertigo for me?
You know how to check
for nystagmus
and cerebellar function?
Yeah? Alright.
Come find me when you're done.
We'll discuss the differential.
Got it.
What's the extension
for the morgue?
5001.
See this guy?
He's looking
for Dr. Carter.
Can I help you?
Yeah. My brother
died last night.
They gave me his valuables
but there's something missing.
I need to get a..
Well, some jewelry
off his body.
Oh, right. Right.
Oh, your brother's
down in the morgue.
‐ Last name Naughton?
‐ Yes, yes.
Definitely
down in the morgue.
Oh...can you tell me
how to get there?
Yeah. No.
Uh, they don't allow
family down there.
It's, uh..
They make you wait.
It takes forever.
It's chilly.
You know what, you know
what I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna go down there and I'm
gonna get it. Your brother.
Get your brother and bring your
brother back up here for you.
Great. That'd be great.
Thank you.
Don't mention it.
‐ Hey.
‐ What are you doing here?
Just came in to
check in on you.
How you feeling?
Well, they're
chopping my leg off.
Yeah.
Your decision?
You could
call it that.
I wouldn't have had a say
at all if it wasn't for you.
Got to go
with the odds, right?
You scared?
I thought, "Okay, I'll just
get used to it."
But..
You in pain?
‐ A little.
‐ Yeah.
Okay, I'll talk to them
and increase your dosage.
That's okay.
I sort of..
...like to feel it.
It'll be gone in a few hours.
‐ Hi, Mr. Ellis.'
‐ What's going on here?
Just came in
to check in on Dana.
She's being taken
care of, thank you.
Mm‐hm.
Listen, I wanted
to talk to you
about her
pain management.
Dana's having surgery
in a few hours.
If you don't mind,
Dr. Romano is gonna
handle everything from here.
Okay.
Excuse me. Are you
in charge of transport?
Depends who's asking.
I know this is gonna
sound really weird.
But I was just wondering if you,
by any chance, found a body.
Transport.
Yeah, what floor?
Okay.
I don't know. Half hour.
Damn!
‐ What did you want?
‐ I lost a body.
Right. Did you try
to move it yourself?
Well, yeah, you guys
were taking too long.
What was I supposed to do?
So now it's our fault.
No, it's not your fault.
‐ I just want to find the body.
‐ I'll call the morgue.
No, I already checked
the morgue, he's not there.
Yo, Gerald!
Yo, it's Tony.
You have any unclaimed
bodies down there?
Yeah, she's here now.
Hold on, I'll ask.
Would this body fit down
the incinerator chute?
The incinerator?
Yeah, that got her.
Yo, thanks, G.
Okay, I'll be right down.
You're in luck.
Someone stuffed some fat stiff
in the closet of the ICU.
Why? Why do you
have to go?
I just got to.
Well, what's the hurry?
Doctor said, it was okay.
Well, it will be okay.
He has to stitch it up first.
Besides, I like having
you around.
There's not very many
interesting people here today.
So, maybe...I'll come back.
Come on, you've got
to help me out.
You don't want to get me
in trouble, do you?
I'll write you a note.
Besides, you do not want to get
that infected, believe me.
Look, just a few minutes.
I'll get a doctor,
we'll take care of it.
‐ Alright.
‐ Good.
‐ Hey, Lynette.
‐ Yeah.
Could you get this
boy's mother for me?
Oh. He's 18.
Yeah, but he's a gangbanger,
got stabbed.
I'm afraid he's gonna bolt
to settle the score.
‐ Mark.
‐ Yeah, hold on a minute.
You admitting
that thrombosis?
He's got a high‐grade lesion
in the femoral artery.
I know. You taking him up?
Well, I need to present
him to Romano
and then we'll bring
down the whole team.
‐ When?
‐ As soon as I can.
Mark, can you
stitch up my guy?
‐ He's getting antsy.
‐ I'll be right there.
Look, Jeanie, can you
clear this neck for me?
He looks okay.
Single vehicle MVA.
‐ I ordered a trauma panel.
‐ Sure, you got it.
‐ Thank you.
‐ Sure.
How we doing in here?
Vitals are normal.
I'm fine.
Did you lose consciousness,
Mr. Lipson?
No. Listen, I told them
this really wasn't necessary.
‐ Any chest or abdominal pain?
‐ Can I go home?
No. We need to get an X‐ray
of your neck first.
Have you ever had hepatitis?
I don't think so. Why?
Your eyes
are a little yellow.
On any medication?
Prednisone, cyclosporine,
Imuran.
Those are
transplant meds.
Well, I had a new liver two
years ago.
Okay. Let's get a pro‐time LFTs
and a cyclosporine level.
Something's wrong?
Doctor, doctor,
por favor venga.
Just one minute.
You're jaundiced.
We need to do those tests now.
Okay? I'll be back.
Okay, just..
‐ 'Here you go, Jeanie.'
‐ Thanks.
‐ Um, this‐this is your card.
‐ Rosa Munoz.
Si. That's social‐social
security card.
She said her
name was Carmen.
Rosa Carmen, si.
And your name?
Luisa.
Her sister?
Um, cousins.
Okay. I understand
that you're concerned
for Angel's health,
but this would be fraud.
It doesn't matter
if he's illegal.
Oh, no, no, no.
That's her number.
‐ No, this is your card.
‐ No.
Um..
...she say that he need
a special doctor?
A cardiologist. There could be
a problem with Angel's heart.
Please take this number.
Please. Other hospital
no take him‐‐
Mrs. Munoz,
we're a county hospital.
We treat all emergencies.
‐ True?
‐ True.
Sometimes when we're
short on beds
we stick the bodies
in the storage room.
‐ Why didn't you call us?
‐ We did.
You guys, I got to get back.
Well, do you want to take
him back or should I?
He's black.
That a problem?
Dana Ellis, what about her?
Well, I'm worried
about phantom limb pain.
‐ Don't be. She's on morphine.
‐ That's not gonna do it.
I wanna put her on
a preemptive analgesia
to rewire the motor nerves.
I didn't realize
she was still your patient.
Dr. Romano, Dr. Greene
is on line three from the ER.
Waiting on a consult
on an ischemic leg.
Does he have
a pulse by Doppler?
‐ I'll check.
‐ It's a simple lumbar epidural.
It's only gonna have to put
the surgery off a few days.
Look, I hate to be
the one to tell you
but one night course does not a
pain management specialist make.
Yes, the patient
has a Doppler pulse.
‐ Dr. Greene wants an ETA.
‐ When I get there.
There's no reason
not to try it, alright?
I‐I don't know that
she's psychologically
ready for the surgery.
Three days isn't gonna make
much difference with that.
Hey, Dale, how's that
new intern working out?
She'll get the hang of it.
Why don't you give her a break?
Let her scrub in
on this prefed tic.
Hey, no, you're not. Hey!
That girl has a tumor in her
leg, cancer that could spread
very rapidly and I'm not
gonna sit idly by and watch you
experiment with some technique
you just read about last week.
‐ Dr. Romano?
‐ What!
Maybe you should talk
to Dr. Greene.
He wants something
more definitive.
If the guy's got calf pain,
tell him to do an ultrasound.
Hey, don't go anywhere.
And rule out DVT.
That'll shut him up for a while.
Leave it alone, Ross!
Hey, Carol, I have to head
upstairs to this interview.
Will you page me
the second Romano decides
to grace us
with his presence?
Hey, don't hold your breath.
Hold still.
You'll tear your stitches.
Let me out of here,
I got to go.
Why? Why? So you can take care
of the guy that did this to you?
‐ Hey, what's going on?
‐ You were right.
Bo here wants to retaliate.
You said that doctor stitched
me up and then I can go!
We just want you
to be safe, Bo.
Yeah, well,
save it, lady.
Look, ma'am, thanks
for fixing me.
‐ I'm going.
‐ Hey, wait, wait, wait!
If you want me to sign
something, I'll sign it!
Don't do that!
You'll rip your vein open.
I don't want to have you
bleeding all over the place.
You know what?
Then take it out.
Okay. You wanna leave that bad?
That's fine.
Let me get the right instrument,
I'll take it out.
You can go about
your business.
Please just wait here.
Just wait one minute.
I'll be right back.
‐ What's going on?
‐ 'We can't let him leave.'
Well, when's the
mother getting here?
Haven't reached her yet.
I'm calling down psych.
He'll be gone by then.
‐ What was that?
‐ Versed.
I'm going
to have to sedate him
till the mother
gets here.
That might be an option
if it wasn't totally unethical.
Oh, not with someone's
life at stake.
You can't restrain
someone with drugs.
He was agitated.
To finish the treatment,
we had to sedate him.
Security can keep him down here
until psych puts him on hold.
They're gonna have to prove
that the kid
is a danger to others.
He knows the system.
He'll just lie.
Well, maybe we'll find
his mother by then.
I'm gonna make sure.
Not with that.
You have a better idea?
I'll handle it.
You know what
he'll do if you don't.
I understand
your motive
and I know I asked
for your help.
Why don't you stick
with the clinic patients.
Leave the ER ones
to me, alright?
Good luck.
Look, it don't matter what I'm
gonna go do. That's my business.
Well, I don't want you ending
up here again, maybe dead.
If it goes down like that,
it goes down like that.
It wouldn't be
the first time.
You don't mean that.
Yo! What's
the rent‐a‐cop doing here?
I want you to be able
to talk to somebody.
Damn! I trusted you.
Hey, I'm just trying
to help you.
Save it, lady.
Look, I ain't talking to nobody.
Okay. We'll just wait
until your mom gets here.
My mom? What,
you called my mom?
I'll be right back.
Don't let him leave.
'Pay attention, Dale.'
Peter is one of the fastest
colon dissectors around.
Now that Lizzie's gun's
in the holster for a while.
Alright. We've got
an open abdomen, people.
Let's turn up
the heat, please.
Elizabeth, would you retract
the descending colon
while I free up
the peritoneal reflection?
My pleasure.
Uh, actually, Dale, why
don't you retract the Bovie
and give Lizzie
the sucker.
Right. Lizzie, suck out
this oozing area, would you?
If you don't mind, I've never
cared for being called Lizzie.
'Really? Dr. Romano calls
you that all the time.'
'Dale, what structure
am I dissecting?'
Uh, ilioinguinal nerve.
Oh, boy.
Elizabeth, would you
help him out, please?
Owing to the slight peristalsis,
it's obviously the left ureter.
Better get a little faster
with that suction, Lizzie.
'Okay. I've freed the sigmoid.'
Elizabeth, would you come
over here and ligate
the proximal side while I clamp
the vessels from below, please?
Certainly.
Dale, move over
and start irrigating.
'I'd prefer Dale
do any ligating.'
Just as soon as we finish
the mesenteric vessels.
Sorry to bother you, Dr. Romano,
but Dr. Greene is calling again.
Oops. Lizzie, I think you
just contaminated yourself.
‐ I did not.
‐ Better be safe, change gowns.
I didn't contaminate myself.
I saw it.
She's clean.
‐ Thank you.
‐ So don't pick on her.
Lizzie, scrub out and
go pacify Greene, would you?
‐ Hey. You're still here.
‐ Yeah.
You're certainly putting
a lot of effort
into this pedes ER,
I'll give you that.
Well, I'll take it.
‐ Hey, guys.
‐ Hey.
This is our new
pedes ER attending
and full‐time
delivery boy, Doug Ross.
What have you got for us, Doug?
You're cut off.
He's a bad tipper.
'This is Claudia Olsen.'
She's one of the candidates
for the new chief
of emergency medicine.
‐ 'Oh, a masochist, huh?'
‐ 'Yeah.'
‐ 'Good luck.'
‐ 'Thanks.'
‐ Kerry Weaver.
‐ The interim chief.
Yeah. It's nice
to meet you.
I take it you're
interviewing today as well.
How did you guess?
Well, at least
I got to go first.
It was nice
to meet you.
You, too.
'It could be hepatitis.'
But our major concern is that
you're rejecting the liver.
Well, I feel fine,
a little tired.
Do you ever forget
to take your meds?
No. I set my watch daily.
My cyclosporine level's
therapeutic, isn't it?
Mm‐hmm. I think we should
arrange for a liver biopsy.
If it's all the same to you
I would really rather
see my own doctor.
I‐I understand, but he
hasn't said anything to you
about your
abnormal LFTs?
No. I got busy,
missed a couple of check‐ups.
Well, I'm sure you know
how important follow‐ups are
after organ
transplantation.
I think part of me
always suspected
but didn't want
to know for sure.
Now I do.
You can always put yourself
on the UNOS list again.
I don't think so.
Second time around?
You qualified the first time.
You never know.
You could get lucky again.
‐ Hi.
‐ You have the Munoz kid?
I do. Yes. Excuse me
one more time. Excuse me.
Is it cardiomyopathy?
The boy's going to need
a full‐EP workup.
Did he have an ectopy?
No, and the echo ruled out
an outlet obstruction.
So the cause
of his fainting..
It's probably arrhythmia.
I'm going to try to induce it
in the cath lab
and if so,
he's going to need
an internal cardioverter
defibrillator right away.
Okay. I'm glad
we caught it.
Yeah. I'll call a cardiac
surgeon. Can you get consent?
Sure. Thank you.
Oh, don't thank me.
The kid needs it.
Yeah.
It's about time.
Where's Romano?
Just me, I'm afraid.
So, can you admit him?
Based on my other
responsibilities, I'd say no.
So you're here
to stall me?
Something like that.
That's alright.
I'll pass him through radiology.
He needs
an angiogram anyway
but tell Romano
you only bought him 20 minutes.
Yeah, just don't leave
the patient there too long.
Radiologists have a way of
snatching the procedures
for themselves if the surgeons
are slow on the uptake.
Noted. Thank you.
Uh, Jeanie?
‐ Here's the BA on your MPA.
‐ On who?
‐ Lipson, trauma two.
‐ I didn't order a BA.
I did.
It's part of the trauma panel.
Randi put it in my box.
‐ Hey..
‐ Is something wrong?
Blood alcohol's 0.04.
That's well below
the legal limit.
It still means
he's been drinking.
I finished my write‐up
on the vertigo.
I think it's just a virus
and I got you some coffee.
You don't need
to do that.
Yeah, well, I was down
in the cafeteria
looking for
something anyway.
Alright. Thanks.
Hey, I'll tell you what.
Why don't you start the IV
on the four‐year‐old
with gastroenteritis
in curtain one.
300cc bolus of saline.
But be careful.
She's dehydrated.
Could be tricky.
Right.
Hey, thanks a lot.
‐ I feel so much better.
‐ Glad to hear it.
You can call me if you'd like
some free tickets to my show.
‐ Thank you.
‐ Ooh!
Are you okay?
How'd that get there?
There you go.
I just didn't want things
disappearing on you. See you.
Hey, you haven't, by any chance,
seen a body..?
Oh, Carol, could you
help me start an IV?
She's dehydrated.
I don't want to hurt the kid.
‐ Have you tried?
‐ Not yet.
So you haven't even
started an IV Yet?
Honestly? No.
This is ridiculous, Lucy.
Everyone thinks you can.
I know. I'm gonna
talk to Dr. Carter today.
Well, if you don't, I will.
Hey! Hey!
‐ What happened?
‐ He took off.
Yeah, I can see that.
You were supposed to stop him.
There was no
talking him down.
You weren't supposed
to negotiate with him.
You were supposed to
stop him from leaving.
I can't keep him here
until you get the hold.
He didn't know that.
‐ Sorry.
‐ Oh, God.
'Hold still.
I want to secure this catheter.'
Hang on. Doing great.
How much longer?
A little bit.
Just a second here.
Okay. Now, you're going to roll
back over on your back, okay?
Nice and easy.
How long does
it take to work?
About 20 minutes
for the full effect.
You're going to start feeling
things pretty soon, though.
I'm gonna put you
on a six‐day cycle.
Three days before the surgery,
three days after, for the drip.
‐ Dr. Romano.
‐ Dr. Ross.
Hi, Dana.
I decided I wanted the epidural.
You did?
You were in surgery
so I explained the protocol.
And the parents?
They're on board.
Terrific.
You got a second?
Sure.
Alright. I'll be right back.
You did great.
Congratulations. You just
postponed the surgery.
You didn't leave me
lot of options.
Let me clear you on something.
That pedes attending thing
just barely happened.
I voted for it because
I thought, the guy's a maverick
good to shake things up
every once in a while.
But if you want to play John
Wayne, do it down in the ER
and not up here
with my patients, capiche?
This girl is in
a very vulnerable place.
‐ Three days is not a lot to‐‐
‐ You're not hearing me, Ross.
This is not about being right.
Hell, we all think
we're right.
It doesn't make
you special.
Fine.
So, did you give the
kid a cheeseburger
before or after the parents
agreed to the protocol?
I thought I might need
24 hours to talk
them into it.
Are you sure you know
what you're doing?
Hold on. Let me get
a smaller gauge.
‐ Oh, hey, you.
‐ Hi.
I have been looking
for you all over.
What happened?
You forgot about me?
Well, I, uh..
No, I didn't, I didn't
forget about you.
I have been waiting
for three hours.
Um...okay, I went
to the morgue.
Me, too. He's not
there anymore.
No, he is not there.
So where'd you put him?
Uh, I don't know how to..
'How to what?'
How to tell you how sorry
I am about your loss.
Thank you.
But where did you put him?
‐ Where did I put him?
‐ You don't remember.
Of course I remember.
Um, I couldn't find you.
I got very busy here
so I put your brother..
Where did I put him?
Radiology.
I put him in radiology
but he was kind of
in the way there, so..
...I left him...here..
...in the hall.
I'm sorry.
No problem. I can't believe
I didn't see him there. Hmm.
He's easy to miss.
‐ What's wrong?
‐ Nothing.
There aren't
any pregnancy tests.
How could we be
out of pregnancy tests?
I don't do inventory.
It wasn't
an accusation.
‐ Ooh! What is that all about?
‐ What?
The scarf.
Where'd you get it?
Got it at the gift shop.
You don't think it works?
What was wrong
with your jacket?
I wanted to try
something different.
Okay, lose the earrings.
It's throwing the whole
thing off‐balance.
Carol, Carol.
Oh, no, it's only my second
stick. I think I can get it.
I can't have students
starting IVs
on kids under ten years old.
‐ Can you do it for me?
‐ Sure.
‐ Is there a problem?
‐ 'No, it's not a problem.'
I just want experienced
staff starting IVs on kids.
This is still a teaching
hospital, isn't it?
Until they inflict
pain on children.
Lucy's great at IVs.
Show him.
This is not about Lucy.
It's a policy I'm setting.
Oh, you're
setting a policy.
Well...first time
for everything.
I'd be in a hurry
to get out of here too.
What?
We found out why
your transplanted
liver's failing,
you've been drinking.
You're not going
to believe me.
One time.
You're right.
I don't believe you.
I checked with UNOS
and you've been on the list
for another transplant
for two months.
Did you tell them?
Did I tell them what?
That you drank through
the first one that they gave you
and now you
want another one?
Come on. It wasn't like that.
It was just a day.
My son passed
his bar examination.
I knew I was rejecting,
so I figured what could it hurt?
We had champagne at brunch.
That's it. I swear.
Well, you've been lying ever
since you came in here.
Please...you
can't tell UNOS.
I really don't
have a choice.
Wait, wait, wait, please,
you're doing this to me
over one glass
of champagne?
Look, there are plenty
of people on that list
who haven't had
any champagne.
If I lose my place,
I won't last six months.
You report me..
...I'm dead.
I'm begging you.
Sorry I'm late.
There was traffic.
You take the El.
‐ Who's on?
‐ Weaver.
She's upstairs interviewing
for chief of emergency medicine.
I thought she was chief.
Where have you been?
Dr. Greene?
He's upstairs
interviewing her.
So we have no attendings.
Hey, watch it, Jerry.
Sorry, Dr. Ross.
Is he an attending?
Hey, listen, uh, normally
I wouldn't say anything
but don't you think that attire
is a little inappropriate?
It's business.
I was helping out
Dr. Weaver.
‐ Thank you.
‐ It was a great job, Kerry.
‐ We'd be lucky to have you.
‐ Thank you.
I know it was a formality,
but thanks for coming in.
Well, I appreciate
the opportunity.
Your presentation was
everything we expected.
‐ Thank you.
‐ Hey, I'll walk you down.
Went great, Kerry.
You don't think the pie
charts were too much?
‐ No, charts are good.
‐ Did anybody else use them?
You're the first.
You know, if I came
across as too eager‐‐
No, it went terrific, Kerry.
Thank you, Mark.
I never know how to
answer that question
about my
weaknesses and‐‐
Yeah, well, I could have
helped you out there.
That's a nice
leather jacket.
No, I said I wanted
to run some tests
but I can't
without Medicaid.
What's wrong?
Ah.
Didn't you know this
patient was illegal?
Yes, I did,
but it doesn't matter.
Oh, yes, it matters.
We're talking about thousands
of dollars worth of tests.
‐ The state's not gonna pay.
‐ So you won't treat him?
I'll give him
some beta blockers.
He could have
a sudden cardiac arrest.
We've been monitoring
him for three hours.
He's had no arrhythmias.
That's why we need
the EP studies.
His father and brother
have already died from this.
Did you document
an arrhythmia?
‐ No, but his mother said‐‐
‐ Alright.
Then there is nothing
else that I can do.
Dr. Kayson, this boy could
drop dead and you know it.
Well, so could
a lot of people.
He's not emergent.
I'm sorry.
You said he was stable.
‐ Single GSW to the arm.
‐ He was.
He's intubated
and hypotensive.
‐ Things change en route, okay?
‐ What's the problem?
Botched gang shooting.
They were ready for him.
Is this the guy
from this morning?
Yeah, his name's Bo.
Uh, look, we really thought
it was just his arm.
‐ He crashed in the rig.
‐ Carter, we need your help.
Come on.
Alright,
welcome back, Bo.
Okay, everybody,
on my count.
One, two, three.
Why didn't you recontact?
Things got
pretty crazy.
Alright, Carol,
put him on the monitor.
'What do we got?'
Through‐and‐through GSW,
mid‐tricep area.
‐ Where's the probe?
‐ Run it, Carter.
Decreased breath sounds
on the right.
Tracheal shift to the left.
Tension pneumo.
BP's down to 70.
‐ Pulse ox 89.
‐ Damn it!
20cc syringe.
And then I'm gonna
need a 36 French.
Alright, you want
to decompress
in the second intercostal space,
midclavicular line.
Okay, pulse is
getting stronger.
Alright, Lucy, get a blood gas.
‐ I'll do it.
‐ No, that's okay.
I showed her how to
do it this morning.
Ten blade.
'Alright, get the
pressure bag on the line.'
'Entrance wound'
'right mid‐axillary line.'
Bullet went through
the arm into the chest.
‐ Why couldn't you undress him?
‐ 'We had to scoop and run.'
'Alright, where's
that chest tube?'
I can't believe you didn't
see this chest wound.
‐ Not now, Carol.
‐ I can't get the blood gas.
Move over, I'll do it.
Alright,
chest tube is in.
That's okay, Lucy.
Those can be tough.
Come around here, help me
with the second line.
Okay, 50cc's out.
I need four by fours.
I need Elastoplast.
'Let's call x‐ray and get
a portable chest down here.'
I got the blood gas.
BP's up to 100/70.
‐ How's that second line coming?
‐ I can't.
Hey, move the drape.
You got more room.
‐ No, I can't do it.
‐ Come on, Lucy, focus.
‐ I really can't.
‐ It's just like any other IV.
I haven't started an IV,
I don't know how.
I never have.
I'm sorry.
Whoa! He's bradying down.
Chest tube is
pouring out blood! Let's go.
Get two units of O‐neg
in and call the OR.
You cost me a procedure.
Am I supposed
to ask how?
You were supposed to baby‐sit
that pulseless foot for me.
Greene let
the radiologists at him.
I didn't realize that was
part of my job description.
Hmm. Well,
you're still learning.
Mm‐hmm.
How was your first day?
As expected.
You are either a masochist
or the stubbornest woman
I've ever met.
But I have to say,
I admire your fortitude.
I couldn't handle taking orders
from a weasel like Dale.
Is that supposed
to be a compliment?
Sounded like one to me.
Oh, and you can wear
the long coat.
It looks better on you.
‐ '700cc's out the chest tube.'
‐ Take him up, Carter.
They know he needs
a thoracotomy?
Yeah. OR three.
Have the blood bank send up
four units type specific.
Yup. Hey, we were not
prepared for a major trauma.
You should have called
when he crumped.
Sorry. We were a little busy
protecting his airway.
Time out.
You guys should
have called ahead.
There was no way‐‐
Ah...you guys
should have called ahead.
And Carol, we have to be
prepared for anything.
‐ I would have been prepared‐‐
‐ Nobody's to blame, okay?
We treated the patient.
Let's move on.
You want to stick around
and review the run tape?
‐ No.
Doggy. Yeah.
You want to pet the doggy?
Mmm.
Oh, that is good.
You want him to respond
in some way, you know?
To, uh, to point or to
make some kind of sound.
Kitty says, "Meow. Meow."
Do you wanna pet the kitty?
Hmm?
Oh.
Don't like the kitty?
It's okay, man.
That's okay.
One quick hug,
then back to work.
What?
He's got to learn to focus.
Oh, come on,
give him a break.
He's only a year old.
You can't give him a break.
He's not like
other one‐year‐olds.
He needs constant
verbal stimuli.
Hey, you try.
Alright, man.
Um...here we go.
Doggy. Doggy.
Arf!
Hey, doggy. Arf.
Arf, arf, arf.
Arf, Reese. Arf.
I can't do this.
You're gonna have to learn.
Coming here twice a week
isn't gonna do it.
Listen, I might
have been able
to keep that kid here
this afternoon but
he would've gone out and done
the same thing tomorrow.
Uh, his mom's in chairs.
You want me to go talk to her?
No, no. I'll do it.
Forget a number?
Uh, no.
You still here?
Yeah, I got sidetracked.
Hey, you could use some help.
Okay, take rashes.
I was thinking
of something more permanent.
Uh, allergies?
Actually, I meant, uh,
being your full‐time PA.
Yeah. I've been
thinking about it.
I'd love to just work
with kids for a while.
I'm good at it and, somehow,
it seems more worthwhile.
Well, I don't
know about that.
At least you know,
whose side you're on.
You know, I'd...I'd love to.
I just think I've used up
all my chips with Anspaugh.
I've got some pull with him.
I think I could work it out.
‐ Great. I'd love that.
‐ Excellent.
Good.
Yeah, hi.
May I have the transplant
coordinator for UNOS, please?
Okay.
‐ I paged you twice.
‐ I don't wanna talk about it.
Well, that's too bad, 'cause I
think I deserve an explanation.
If you want me
to feel bad, I do.
I'm really
disappointed in myself.
You should be.
And that's not an explanation.
I don't know
how it started.
I..
You thought I could do it.
I wanted to impress you and it
spun out of control. I'm sorry.
Just, what did you think
you were going to accomplish?
I don't know.
I thought I could
learn on my own.
Oh, great. You can
learn on your own.
You don't need
to be here then.
You endangered patients, Lucy.
You don't need to make me
feel bad. I feel horrible.
Well, that would work
if this was about you.
But rule number one down there
is it's never about you.
You know what, go home.
'Don't come back unless
you're serious'
about learning something.
And if you ever
lie to me again
you can look
for another rotation.
♪ Oogum oogum boogum boogum ♪
♪ Boogum now baby you're castin'
your spell on me ♪
♪ I say ♪
♪ Oogum oogum boogum boogum ♪
♪ Boogum now baby you're castin'
you're spell on me.. ♪
What are you
doing back here?
I'm waiting for
the grill to heat up.
I thought this was
fend‐for‐yourself night.
Well, I'm sick of
fend‐for‐yourself.
I got us some steaks.
Steaks sound good. You got
another one of those for me?
Yup.
What's in the bag?
It's a, uh...pregnancy test.
To be sure.
No need.
I started my period.
♪ Boogum now baby you're castin'
you're spell on me.. ♪
Well, I guess
I wasted $17.50.
Well, save it
for next time.
I'm kidding.
That was a joke.
We dodged the bullet
there, didn't we?
Yup.
That's good, right?
Yeah, yeah.
Though, all day,
I kept thinking..
...wow, a kid.
You know, that would really..
...change my life.
Our life.
It would change ours.
Okay, our lives.
That would be bad, right?
You know what?
I changed my mind.
I don't want to joke about it.
Yeah.
Maybe I'm not joking.