♪ I woke up to the morning sky
first ♪
At the start of
Medical School,
you and your classmates
stand together,
wearing your lab coats
for the first time,
and you take an oath.
♪ When I get up
off this ground ♪
♪ I shake leaves back down
to the brown, brown, brown ♪
♪ Till I'm clean
No justice! No peace!
Equality right now!
- Equality right now!
- Stand up!
♪ My sisters and my brothers,
see them like no other ♪
♪ All my favorite colors
♪ It's a good day to be,
a good day for me ♪
The oath has many versions,
but each boils down to this...
The practice of medicine
should be humane and kind.
♪ My sisters and my brothers,
they see them like no other ♪
♪ All my favorite colors
It turns out there's a catch
they don't tell you about...
Medicine mimics
the world it lives in.
Hey.
Brought coffee.
You see
Richard's e-mail?
I can't look at my phone without
50 news alerts popping up.
It's like it's cursed.
He told the staff to take time
if they need it.
To rest, protest.
Worry about whether
their fiancé's gonna make it
across country
in one piece?
Anything.
He understands.
If I keep staring
at this wall,
I'm just gonna burn a hole
into it.
♪ Ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh
I should go.
And in this world,
humanity and kindness
are often in short supply.
♪ Ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh,
ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
I canceled the few elective
surgeries we had scheduled,
told the blood bank to be
on high alert,
and put five vents on standby
for incoming traumas.
- We'll have the tent outsidefor walk-ups.
- Mm-hmm.
Mnh. You think
that'll be enough for us?
I think it'll have to be.
We've just barely got
our bearings in this pandemic...
Now this.
Well, revolutions
don't schedule appointments.
Mnh!
You good?
I... I just want to be doing
something I know how to do.
Well, you've done everything
you could to prepare.
Now, look, I'll come back
if you need me.
It may take me some time
to get here, but I-I'll make it.
Wait, back...
Back from where?
I'm protesting, Bailey.
Something important
is happening out there,
and I'm
not gonna miss it...
These moments
save lives, too.
You go give 'em hell.
I'm so grateful
that you came in today.
Not that I would ask a Black man
not to march.
No, but you can text me
eight times,
asking if I'm coming in, though.
Mnh-mnh!
That was my phone
that did that.
- Oh, okay.
- It's new.
Uh-huh.
No, I almost called in a sub,
honestly,
but we're barely hanging on
with COVID,
so I figured
they'll need me.
Speaking of which,
did you read my proposal
for setting up the free
COVID testing and treatment site
for low-income patients?
I mean,
Ortiz's connections...
I think we can make
a real impact.
You know we're barely keeping
the lights on as it is, baby.
But I will revisit it
when the revenues improve.
You want us to wait
till COVID's over
before we can open
a COVID site, Mom?
Come on. Okay?
Dr. Ortiz
and I put a lot of really good
time and effort into this.
She's got great ideas.
Just let me get through
this week, okay?
- I'm late for my meeting.
- Ah.
- Love you.
- This week.
Avery.
You got a second?
Hey, everything okay?
I've been better, mate.
I don't have much time.
It's all hands on deck
here.
Probably won't even have
a chance to shower
before I see you tonight,
but I just wanted to see
your face.
Well
this is it.
My exhausted,
driving-for-three-days face.
I feel like we chose
the worst time ever
for you to make
this drive.
Nah. The sooner I'm with you,
the better.
Well, what'd you think of the
apartment listing I sent you?
I haven't even looked at it yet.
Maggie.
It's just...
I have not been able to focus
on anything besides work
and the news and you driving.
I get it, baby.
I get it.
But as far as I can tell,
Seattle real estate is the
Hunger Games with kitchens.
So, if
I want this place,
I'm gonna need to make
an offer soon.
Okay, I'll look at it.
I promise.
Alright.
Next time we talk,
it'll be in person.
Be careful. Please.
Extra careful.
Always.
I love you.
Love you.
She's still sleeping
most of the time.
She's very weak.
But stable.
Have Schmitt do her
hyperbaric treatment today.
Do we think that
Schmitt's qualified?
He'll be fine. I'll put
the fear of God in him.
That almost sounds fun.
Dr. Scott...
- Let's order an X-ray.
- Yeah.
They're in the south parking lot
right now.
Thanks a million, Irene.
I'll be back when I can.
Alright, hold still.
Hold still.
Cops did this?
Neo-Nazis did this.
"Counter-protesters,"
I think they're called.
Came at my boy
with a billy club.
I jumped in between them
just in time.
Well, he got you good.
Must've been scary.
I wanted to drop a bomb
on the whole lot of them.
If I had one,
I would have.
Oh, man, this rage
I'm feeling?
That's... That's why we need
stricter gun laws.
Alright. Well, I can get you
some Valium for the shaking.
No, I'm good.
ER's filling up. I just...
I just want to get back to work.
Am I okay, Avery?
Almost.
Next time,
make sure you guys hang
- in the back of the crowd, yeah?
- Next time?
When they're 18,
they can protest all they want.
Right now, they're going
straight home.
Jackson,
I need you out here!
Her name is Nell.
That's all I got.
She was hit with
a tear gas canister.
Shot! Not hit... shot!
At close range!
Oh, shrapnel
went everywhere.
- E-Easy.
- Oh.
- Easy.
- Keep it stable.
Trauma one's open.
Let's move.Okay.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 17  Episode 12
"Sign O' the Times"
Aired on: April 15, 2021
Uh, good circulationin
the upper extremities.
Nell, does your hand feel
numb or tingly?
Excruciating pain
isn't enough?
No acute fractures.
Canister doesn't seemtoo deeply embedded.
Someone give me
their hand.
Why?
I need to squeeze
the hell out of it.
This thing hurts.
- Two of morphine, Reuben.
- Mm-hmm.
Non-expanding hematoma,
but I cannot rule out
a neurovascular injury here.
So I think we need a CT angio
right away.
Let's prep to move.
- Okay, I'm gonnacome with you.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait!
Y-You're not taking this thing
out of me first?
We want to make sure
it didn't hit
any major blood vessels
in your neck.
Then we're gonna remove it
in the operating room.
We're gonna move as fast
as we can, alright?
- Alright.
- You ready for us to move you?
♪ Hey, hey, ho, ho
♪ Come on, girl, let's go
- ♪ Hey, hey, ho, ho ♪
- Hey, hey, ho, ho
- ♪ Come on
- ♪ Come on, girl
- That's right, let's go.
- ♪ Let's go
Okay, keep this on
for the next 12 hours,
then apply
the antibiotic ointment, okay?
Will this bandage hold?
I'm going back out.
I'll get you some extra Coban
to be safe, okay?
Hey.
Got your page.
Yeah, someone's en route
with a rubber bullet injury
to the chest.
Should be here
any minute.
Ugh, glass bricks.
- You get that, Pierce?
- Huh? Yes, yeah.
Uh, just got
a lot going on today.
Winston is driving back
as we speak.
Yeah, you two
aren't wasting any time.
- I'm happy for you.
- Thanks.
We're just trying to work out
this living situation.
Oh, you're worried?
You're wondering if he prefers
using the bathroom
with the door wide open?
Or puts ketchup
on his eggs.
Who puts ketchup on
their eggs?
Over 54% of Americans, actually.
Okay, rig's here.
Let's go.
Okay,
we have Guy Houston, 22.
Took a rubber bullet to
the chest.
Defibrillated in the field
for V-fib.
I think "died" is the word
you're looking for.
Welcome back.
Let's get you inside.
I need a chest X-ray,
cardiac enzymes,
and let's get him on
a monitor.
We're heading into
the chamber.
Breathing oxygen...
feeling light...
as if you're, uh,
floating on a cloud.
But not... not like a cloud
in heaven or anything.
Just, um, floating.
Like...
just not dead, you know?
We're healing and recovering.
What are you doing here?
Uh, post-op surgical wound
infection.
My attending ordered
hyperbaric treatment
- to enhance healing.
- Well, we're next.
And we're also VIP,
so you can go now.
Schedule's packed today,
so they're doubling up.
Crap,
is that Meredith Grey?
Maybe.
But don't talk to her.
I'm under strict orders
from the Chief
to not cause Dr. Grey
any stress.
Of course, no problem.
Just, uh,
floating like...
Are you gonna make room
or not?
Haven't even finished
this supply run...
You're already coming in
for more.
Yeah, well,
it's just one of those years.
Wait, can I fix that?
Because it looks like
you lost a bar fight.
Thank you.
Wow. Okay.
It's not like there's
a deadly virus going around...
Spread by droplets.
Oh, sorry.
It's
the bloody tear gas, I swear.
How are your sons?
They're alright.
Irene came to pick them up,
despite their complaining.
They wanted to stay out?
Yeah, they want to be
a part of the change,
not just watch it
on a screen.
But you wouldn't let them?
After this? No way.
You think that's
a mistake?
No, I, uh...
I see both sides.
You know, protesting the
policein front of the police
is scary,
and so is doing nothing.
Guess I've just buried
too much family
to see anybody else's side
but my own.
Right.
Captain
Emerson, call Radiology.
Captain Emerson, call Radiology.
Yes.
Chad Anderson, 40s,
no past medical history,
according to him.
EMTs brought him.
He evidently collapsed
while jogging.
I've given him O2,
but he's still experiencing
shortness of breath,
as well as foot irritation.
Look, I'm fine, okay?
As I was trying to
explainto your nurse here...
Dr.Tseng.
She's a second-year
surgical resident.
- Yeah, but...
- Pull your mask up.
Yeah.
Okay, look, I was just trying to
tell her that it's...
I... Sometimes, I get
shortness of breath when I run.
It's not a big deal.
I mean, you know, my...
My inhaler's expired,
so you just, you know,
you put me on
a nebulizer treatment
and you write me a new
prescription for albuterol,
and there'll be one less guy
in the room.
Mm-hmm.
Dr. Tseng, has his oxygen
saturation been above 92?
Hovering around 88.
Mr. Anderson,
is it possible
that you've been exposed to
COVID-19?
No.
Uh, it's... That's a no.
Hm. Mask up.
Hospital policy.
Move him to an isolated room
and give him a full workup...
Chest X-ray, lower extremity
duplex, and a COVID test.
Page me with the results.
Okay, hey. Doc, look,
I'll take the workup, okay,
but I don't care what
your little test says
'cause I know that
it's not real.
What's not real?
COVID.
Do I look like
a sheep, alright?
I know it's a scam.
How's she doing?
Hopefully, it's confined to
just soft tissue damage.
Well, her clavicle
felt intact.
We were marching
peacefully.
You know, she
was marching peacefully.
Can you imagine firing
poison gas at this woman?
Still marching
at her age?
What was it like
out there today?
It was beautiful.
At first.
And then it was frightening
and then messy,
but it was still beautiful.
I mean, there were
young people
handing out water
and masks.
It was...
It was organized.
There was this...
this feeling in the air.
It's...
You have to put yourself
on the line to be part of it,
but good trouble
lights you up, you know?
Yeah, sure.
Oh, scans are up.
Ah. Okay.
Oh, well, no vascular
involvement, thank God.
See?
It tore through
- the trapezius muscle.
- Yeah.
Well, let's book an OR
and extract the canister.
Yeah.
Don't see
any pericardial fluid.
That's a good thing.
Okay, so was it a...
A heart attack?
Because my dad's
had two of those.
Kind of.
It's called
commotio cordis.
Basically, the rubber bullet
must've hit you
at the exact right moment
to interrupt
your heart's normal rhythm.
The same thing happens
with a heart attack.
Yeah, you were lucky
that EMTs were nearby.
Everything was so chill,
you know?
Then there was gas and...
And screaming
and people running
in all directions.
We couldn't even tell which way
the cops wanted us to go.
But I swear,
we didn't do anything wrong.
Yeah,
I'm sure you didn't.
Your X-ray and your echo
both look good,
but I do want to admit you
for observation and bloodwork
just to make sure
your heart's okay.
I-I, uh... I s... I should
probably call my mom.
Uh, I will be right back.
Keep him on telemetry
and do cardiac enzymes
every two hours.
Hey. What happened to
not speaking
until we see each other
in person?
The landlord called,
and he said
he wants to rent to a doctor,
but he has a few offers
and he needs to
make a decision today.
Did you look
at the listing?
I did.
I'm not a fan.
It has glass bricks.
And only two windows.
And glass bricks.
Um, okay, well,
I told him
I'm gonna take it.
Maggie, you know
I need a better option
than a hotel
or a backyard tent.
It's just for now.
You know, I just want to be
in the same city.
Hey, Maggie.
And for the record, no judgment...
- Maggie...
- Do you like glass bricks?
Maggie, I can't...
I can't talk now.
- I'm being pulled...
- I'm being pulled over.
Wait, what? You're being
pulled over by the...
By the police, yes.
I got to go.
No, no, no, no.
Winston, don't hang up.
Turn on your camera
if you can,
but do not hang up
the phone.
I will stay on the line
with you.
Is she mean?
Dr. Grey?
Excuse me?
Uh, sorry.
It's just what I heard.
I also heard that
she's the best.
But she got sick before
my first day,
so I never got a chance
to see it.
I intubated a COVID patient
on the fly the other day.
Never could've done that
a couple years ago.
And my Lembert sutures,
which she taught me,
they're...
They're getting better.
Every win I've had,
any time I do something right,
I hear her voice
in my head.
She's the most influential
teacher I've ever had.
Even when she's asleep.
And, yes,
she can be toughsometimes.
There's always a reason.
I really hope I get to
operate with her one day.
Yeah, me too.
Alright.
Music off, hat off,
hands on the wheel.
License and registration,
sir.
How you doing today,
Officer?
Oh, just takin' 'er easy.
Can you tell me why
you pulled me over?
I saw...
Speed limit said it's 45...
Set the cruise to 40.
Winston, are you there?
I can't hear anything.
I'm gonna need you
to turn off your phone, sir.
Oh, it's just
my fiancée.
She's up in Seattle.
Your phone, sir.
She, uh, she worries about me
on the long drive.
Can I leave it on?
Mr. Ndugu,
are you failing to comply?
Winston.
If... If... If you're still there,
just keep me on the line.
I'm reaching for my phone.
Winston?
Oh, no, no.
Army Navy, please.
Pick-ups, Bokhee.
My mom mention getting an e-mail
from me at all?
I sense you want me to
say yes.
She probably hasn't
even opened it.
I don't know why
I haven't learned.
The only ideas that
get through to her are her own.
It's hard being
a problem-solver
when the problems
are so complex.
I could never do her job.
Yeah, well, it'd be easier if
she wouldn't ignore good advice
from people
trying to help her.
Wouldn't even bother me as much
if it was just me.
Alma Ortiz and I worked really
hard on a lot of good ideas
based on
her previous experience.
Well, listen,
give her time.
We're all feeling
next-level stress.
Something tells me that
after a week,
she'll be
a little more open.
We just pulled a hunk
of metal out of this woman,
and you're seriously
being super positive right now?
You know, you barely missed
getting hit yourself.
Yeah, it should have never
happened.
I'm just thankful that
the damage isn't worse.
What got me...
Well, you saw her.
She wasn't fazed.
She was... She was energized.
You know what I mean?
There's power in gathering
like that,
I mean, where the truth brings
so many people together.
I mean...
Well, you know.
Actually, no, I don't.
Honestly, I've never
been to a real protest.
I mean, I've protested
plenty of things...
I've boycotted businesses,
signed petitions.
Done surgeries
for free, given talks.
It seems like every time folks
took to the streets,
I always had
a reason not to.
I had to work,
I had to study.
I could always see how useful
money was to the cause,
you know,
so I guess I always felt
that writing a check was
a worthwhile substitute.
And, hell, maybe it is.
In this country, at least.
You think that's a cop-out?
I try not to judge
the way that anyone handles
the traumas that come
with living here.
And that includes you.
And your mother.
Clamp.
Hi, you've
reached Dr. Winston Ndugu.
Dr. Pierce! Just... J
ust... Come on.
Dr. Pierce!
He's in V-fib again!
Let's push a
6-milligram bolus of adenosine.
Oh, Ortiz! I need you to
keep calling this number.
It's my fiancé, Winston.
- If he picks up, you tell me.
-  He's still in V-tach.
If he doesn't,
just keep calling.
Just do not stop.
- Everything okay?
- He got pulled over.
I want the officer to know that
someone is checking in on him.
Mm.
Let's charge to 200!
Mask up, Mr. Anderson.
Mm. Sorry, I forgot.
The whole
"coro-no-virus."
Sir...
...I need you to
listen to me.
Your COVID test
came back positive.
Additionally, you have
ground glass opacities
in your lungs.
That's why
you're having trouble breathing.
And your toes aren't red
because you run without socks.
Y-You have what's being referred
to as "COVID-toe."
"COVID-toe"?
- Yes.
- Really?
That's the best you got?
COVID-toe?
Are you guys even trying?
This ultrasound of your leg
reveals a clot
that we need to treat
immediately, so...
Okay, well,
whose leg is that?
I'm sorry?
Well, see, I'm a...
I'm a runner.
We don't get blood clots.
But it's a...
That's a...
That's a nice try, though.
Mr. Anderson, please.Okay. Look.
You know what
I've figured out?
Huh?
I figured out that
this little cold
that y'all are
so terrified of...
Biggest moneymaker
since crypto-currency.
And speaking of, h-how
do you get your kickbacks?
I mean,
is it like a flat fee
from every patient
that you diagnose,
or is it like a...
A percentage deal, or...?
My m...
Um, I...
Be back in a moment.
I need to answer a page.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Take your time.
What?! What?!
Okay.
Breathe. Breathe. Breathe.
W-What?!
Stop.
Okay, let's try this.
Your blood oxygen is
dangerously low.
Your lungs
are getting worse.
And if untreated,
the clot in your leg
could travel to your lungs
and killyou.
We're seeing cases like
yoursall of the ti...
Sir, this is not
just a cold.
It's not asthma.
This won't magically
go away.
Sir, please,
let us admit you
so that we canstart you
on steroids...
...and... and put you
on blood thinners.
Look, because even if
you are a little bit wrong,
it could be fatal.
You know,
I'm still waiting on
that albuterol prescription,
Doc.
Thank you.
200 joules!
200. Stand clear.
Still V-fib.
Go again.
- Charge.
Clear.
Okay, he's back to
normal sinus rhythm.
So, what are you thinking?
I think the rubber bullet
bruised his heart.
His troponin levels
are elevated.
We gotta get him to
the CCU.
All this from
a rubber bullet?
It wasn't
a "rubber" bullet.
It's a metal bullet
encased in rubber
fired from a gun
at a human being.
They're not meant to be fired
close range or directly.
They can bejust as
dangerous. Still no answer.
- Damn it.
- V-fib again?!
He's unstable. He keeps
going in and out of sinus.
Charge.
Yep.
Clear!
He's in V-fib storm.
The myocardial contusion
is causing
a closed loop of misfiring
in his heart.
It's not gonna stop until
we get him ablated.
Push 100 mg of lido,
give him an amiodarone bolus,
and get him up to
the IR suite.
- We'll meet you up there, okay?
- Okay.
Still no answer.
Alright.
- Page Richard Webber.
- Ready? Let's move.
Tell him to meet me in
the IR suite,
and tell him it's urgent.
Ever work in a warehouse?
Not that I recall.
My patient does.
Forklift injury.
They're
surprisingly common.
It's good to know.
Hey, uh...
Uh... uh...
You might want to up
his sedation.
Sedation, right.
Uh...
Quick, before he...
- Oh! Oh!
- Crap!
That's what
I was worried about.
Okay.
Come on. C...
Maggie.
What's wrong?
Okay.
Winston is on his way
back here from Boston.
- Mm-hmm.
- He is driving, he's on the road,
and we were on the phone.
We were...
And the police
pulled him over,
and I told him to
keep me on the line.
But the police
made him hang up,
and now I can't
get a hold of him.
It's been...
It's been 20 minutes,
and I don't know
where he is.
And I have a patient who could
go into V-fib at any second,
so I have to get in there
and do an ablation.
But this is how it happens,
right? Just like this?
So, I-I-I-I need somebody
to go and find him now. Look.
Right now.
Alright, Maggie.
Alright. Okay?
What you should do now
is take care of your patient.
What if he tries to call
me and I don't pick up? - No.
- Or what if he doesn'tcall...
- Yeah.
...and the police
just take him... take him?
Look,
just give me your phone.
I'll give it
some more time.
If there's still no word,
I will get into my car,
and I will look for him
myself.
- Give me your phone.
- Okay.
Yeah?
Mm-hmm.
- Okay.
- Mm.
Oh, my God!
Oh, God, his intestines
are popping out!
Okay, okay, okay.
Let me think.
What do we do?
I don't know what to do.
Schmitt.
This isn't anyone's fault.
This isn't
anyone's fault.
The patient nearly
extubated himself
- and caused an evisceration...
- and caused an evisceration.
It is
a horrible complication...
But it can be fixed.
What is the first step?
Chee, he dehisced.
I need you to hold down
the patient
so he doesn't extubate
himself.
Paralyze him with cis
and push more Versed.
And then, I need you
to get on the intercom.
And say what?
Tell them to depressurize
the chamber
and call for an OR now.
No... No attending?
We are stuck in this chamber
until it depressurizes,
so we are on our own,
but we do not panic.
Now, we need to put him under,
so push more meds.
Now!
Okay.
There it is.
We're ready
for the needle.
He's stable.
Go. Do your call.
We'll page you
if he goes into V-fib.
- Are you sure?
- Maggie, go.
Winston?
Hey.
Oh, my God.
Are you okay?
Where are you?
I'm... I'm... I'm fine.
I... They le...
They let me go.
Why did it take them so long
to let you go?
Um, because they... they had me
get out of the car
and take my mask off.
And, uh...
And then, uh,
they had me do a DUI test.
And then, they checked
the trunk.
And then,
they checked the car.
You know, and then I had to
unpack all my stuff,
and, uh, the police dog
sniffed it over. What?
And then the dog sniffed me,
and they let me go.
So, I'm g... I'm good.
Tha... That's what took so long.
W-W-W-Why did the...
I mean, I...
Were you, like,
swerving on the road?
No, no, no.
Uh, my... my bike rack
was obscuring
my license plate, and...
And then, they saw me.
So, it just turned into
one of those things,
I guess.
They can't do that.
They...
Maggie, I'm a little bit
shaken up right now.
I don't know if I'm good to
drive yet.
I don't know if I'm...
I don't think I'm...
♪ Starting to see me
in a new light ♪
Uh, Maggie, I'm not good.
Okay.
I'm... I'm not okay yet,
you know?
Uh...
I just gotta breathe
a little bit, you know?
Okay, okay.
Okay, listen, you're okay.
You are okay, and I am here
with you as long as you need.
- Alright. Okay? - Breathe, baby.
- ♪ And I feel like ♪
- ♪ I've forgotten who I am ♪
- Breathe. You are okay.
♪ The me before you and I began ♪
♪ Starting to see me
in a new light ♪
I need saline.
His bowels
are drying out.
That's why
I asked for saline.
♪ ...behind me
till I'm out of sight
Pour it!
And what are
Dr. Grey's vitals?
What's wrong with
Dr. Grey?
Nothing, but your patient
isn't the only one in here,
and I don't want
two emergencies.
So, could you please
read her vitals?
♪ Whoa-oh
BP... 120 over 75.
- O2 sats are 95%.
- Good.
Stay that way.
I think I got it
all in.
- Don't put too much pressure.
I need to avoid
bowel ischemia
and abdominal compartment
syndrome.
♪ Starting to see me
Nice work, Schmitt.
♪ In a new light
Well,
our surgery was successful.
I was able to remove
the canister
to get your wound cleaned out
quite nicely.
No vascular damage.
We'll want to go back in
in a few days
just to get everything
nice and closed up.
Yeah, a centimeter in
the other direction
and it could have been
much worse.
Could have been better.
Could have been you.
Eventually, you're gonna, uh,
need some physical therapy
just to help get
your full range of motion back.
Sorry to interrupt.
Just wanted to check
how the toughest patient
in the hospital is doing.
Well, you found her.
Takes a gas canister
at full velocity
- and still cracking jokes in the ER.
- Mm-hmm.
Never seen the like of it.
How you feeling?
Never better.
Well, we did our best.
You might have a little bit
of scarring.
Oh, I'm not worried about
a scar.
Just go with
the rest of them.
Ferguson...
I tore my ACL
running from a tank.
Standing Rock,
well, frostbite.
And these are just
the two most recent ones.
I think I got that beat.
WTO protests, 1999.
They fired tear gas into
the crowd,
a few of us
ducked into a building,
but they pushed the door closed
before I could get inside.
I shattered my clavicle
and tore off some skin.
Hmm.
When was your first?
Oh, first march?
- Free South Africa. 1988.
- Mm.
I got started
a little late.
Yourself?
1963.
'63, as in...?
The March on Washington.
My mother took me.
I was 11.
You... Dr. King's
"I have a dream" speech?
You were there? In person?
I was.
It was August, and hot.
To be honest, I remember
Mom taking me to cool my feet
in the Reflecting Pool
more than anything.
But I do remember him
on that stage...
The sound of his voice
sweeping over us.
The power of it.
The holiness.
It felt like...
possibility.
Like, if, this can happen,
anything can happen.
Possibility like that
was rare.
And it's worth a few scars.
He thinks COVID is
a scam to trick people
into thinking
they need treatment,
and then
we make them sicker
by not treating them
for the things they dohave.
I'm sorry. I mean,
who is getting this money?
You. Me.
All of us.
And who does he think
is paying us?
The government.
Oh, and we gettin' rich.
I mean, every patient that
we admit... ka-ching.
I mean, why not money?
I mean, look at how much
coronavirus has given us...
I mean, a full-on
nervous breakdown.
A dead mother.
Constant OCD flare-ups.
Losing seven patients
in one day.
Coming home
at the end of the day
and seeing the heartbreak
on my dad's eyes.
Whoo!
Oh, no.
No.
No, no, no, no.
What on earth?!
Who discharged him?!
He signed AMA.
Said he was done
and just walked out.
He didn't get very far.
No pulse.
Hurry up with that
crash cart!
♪ Been around the world
We offered him treatment,
could have saved him.
Instead, he walked away.
♪ Is all I ever see
Most people never feel
what it's like
to be really great at something,
Altman, but we do, right?
I do. I can put
broken people together
with needles and string.
But... I can't fix this.
♪ It's getting hard
to believe ♪
I mean, how do I treat someone
who is offered help
and chooses to walk away?
I want to hope, Altman.
I want to... mnh...
Believe that, you know,
just...
Just a little longer,
and... and... and we'll be over
this brutal hill.
But...
♪ To love now, to love
now
♪ To love now
I just...
I just don't know.
♪ To love now
♪ What would it take
for us to love now? ♪
♪ All we got is each other
Hey. 30 minutes without
another episode of V-fib.
The radiofrequency ablation
worked.
♪ What would it take
for us to love now? ♪
Any more word
from Winston?
He's back on the road.
He'll be here
in an hour or two.
I'm glad to hear that.
♪ It isn't too late
♪ I know we know how
♪ What would it take for us to love now? ♪
Whoa, 17 missed calls from "Mom."
I wonder if she even knows
he's here.
Are you up for that,
or do you need me to...?
- I got it.
- Okay.
♪ To love now, to love now
Hello?
Okay, okay, okay.
Your son is okay.
This is Dr. Maggie Pierce.
I was
one of his doctors today.
Oh, hey.
Richard tells me
your new patient Nell
is quite the storyteller.
I'm thinking about going down
there to meet her
before she gets discharged.
- Why don't we have scars, Mom?
- Come again?
My whole life, whenever I see
people marching in the streets,
I hear your voice telling me
that just going to work
is heroic enough,
that we need to fix things
from the inside.
Succeed first, then give.
Like, that's what...
That's what you taught me, right?
And... And here I am.
I'm... I'm successful,
I've given,
and nothing
seems to change.
I know what it's like
to get discouraged, Jackson.
No, I don't...
I don't need a pep talk.
That's not what
this is.
I...
If our foundation is so good
at fighting the good fight,
then why isn't anything
getting better?
And don't take that
the wrong way, alright?
I'm just saying, maybe
both of us have got this wrong.
I mean, look at what
is happening
in the streets right now.
Why aren't we there?
Why the hell
don't we have scars?
Let's just drop
the "we" business
of this right now, okay?
Youmay not have scars,
Jackson,
but I have decades' worth.
And if you think nothing
has changed,
why don't
you just ask yourself
how many Webbers, Baileys,
or Pierces
you would have seen
walking through these halls
40 years ago...
20 years ago.
You have no idea the battles
that I have fought
and won for that.
And if you don't see
any scars,
it's because I'm damn good
at this job.
Of course you are.
I'm not... criticizing you.
You're incredible.
But I'm saying,
aren't you also annoyed
with all this red tape?
Having to convince
some trustees
when you have
a brilliant idea?
Like,
what about our ideas?
What about
doing something about
the Black
maternal mortality rate
instead of
talking about it?
What about building
our database
for the obvious racial bias
in medical training?
What about building our...
Our medical school
that we talked about?
So many things
we could be doing.
One battle at a time,
Jackson.
That's how
the world works.
Nah.
It shouldn't be that way...
Not anymore, alright?
I don't want to play a role
in a system that's just broken.
You sound like
your father.
Oh, that'd be the worst thing
in the world?
- Mom...
- It's been a long day.
- I didn't mean...
- ou've already said it, Jackson.
Don't try to lie
about it now.
Emawk's
"Treading Water" plays...
Nah!
- ♪ Hold on, I'll be right behind ya ♪
- Hup, hup!
Hey, Dad,
wanna get in here?
Liam keeps kicking the ball
over the fence.
Because our yard's
too small.
Come over here for a second,
boys, will ya?
♪ Closer than before,
but still not there ♪
I was wrong.
Not to try
and protect you...
I'm your Dad.
That's part of the bargain.
But I was wrong
to tell you to stay home.
This is your country,
boys,
and now is a moment.
So, you'll fight,
you'll protest if you want to,
but only during daylight
and only when I'm with you.
Sound fair?
♪ When you get to
the place you're going ♪
I heard about the one
downtown tomorrow...
If that's not
too soon.
Why would it be
too soon?
Um, your head?
Oh, yeah.
Forgot about that.
I think it's
an improvement.
Oh, do you, now?
Wha...
Hey!
♪ Let the water set me free
Oh, hey.
You need a ride home?
Um. Uh, thanks.
I'll walk.
No, let me drive you.
There's a curfew.
It's just not safe.
That's alright. I'll walk.
Jackson, you can march tomorrow.
Today's practically over.
Yeah, well, it sounds like
they're still marching somewhere.
I'll walk.
I remember that day
I first put on my white coat,
even though it was long ago.
I took the oath alongside
my classmates,
and I meant it with every cell
in my body.
I heard you eviscerated
a patient today.
What?! No!
No, I helped put the bowels
back inside.
Oh, my God, what is
Chee telling people?!
He's telling people
you were a badass
and you saved
the man's life.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't help myself.
How's Meredith?
Stable.
Her ABG
looks even better.
♪ The sound of a morning
When the wound split,
I... froze.
But then, I kept hearing
this voice inside my head
asking,
"What would Meredith Grey do?"
♪ While I'm treading water
- I know. That's stupid.
- No!
No, I've...
I've heard
- that voice before, too.
- ♪ Let the water set me free
And my advice...
- Keep listening to it.
- ♪ Let the water set me free
- ♪ As I tread this water
- Wow.
You're really going through
with OB-GYN, huh?
Mm-hmm.
I listened to the voice.
- ♪ Let the water set me free
- Hey, if you're starting
your residency all over again,
- does that mean I'm your boss now?
- No.
Well, technically,
I'll outrank you.
Okay, do you want
a ride home or not?
♪ Tell me that I haven't
reached the end ♪ -
But this world
has challenged
that oath so many times,
I barely remember
- what it said anymore.
- ♪ Tell me that I have
♪ The strength to go on ♪
♪ And any time that
I think about going back ♪
♪ Going back
♪ Let the wind and the waves
push me home ♪
I was only thinking
one thing...
"Do whatever it takes
to get back to Maggie."
"Survive and get home."
I love you so much.
So now,
- every day, I take a new oath...
- ♪ Let the water set me free
...I pledge to help build
a world worth living in.
♪ Let the water set me free
And never stop believing
that world can exist.
♪ ...set me free
- ♪ Let the water
- ♪ Let the water set me free
♪ Let the water set me
♪ Free
- ♪ Free ♪ Free,
- ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah
Calculating route.
- Estimated trip...
- ♪ Let the water set me free
11 hours.
- ♪ The water
-♪ Let the water set me free
Not today.
So far from today.
- ♪ Let the water set me free
- But someday.
Captions by VITAC...
Synchronized by srjanapala