- Previously on The Resident...
- What's the average life
expectancy of someone
- after a heart transplant? Do
you remember the Barnetts?
Two adopted kids with
medical needs, right? Yes.
And apparently, you
made quite the impression.
Absence seizures.
He's had them since infancy?
They've always been mild,
and we have them under control.
I've done some reading on
your vagus nerve stimulator.
Is it everything I hear?
It has exceeded
all our expectations.
Why would anyone sell a hip
implant that could leak poison?
This is my industry... how
do I not know this is going on?
I'm been offered a spot
on a journalism team.
It's at the San
Francisco Chronicle.
♪ ♪
PRIYA: I've been waiting
my entire career for
something like this.
Did you hear me?
I can't pass up
this opportunity.
Then take it, babe.
Will you come with
me to San Francisco?
I thought you said that you
were open to me staying here.
You said a lot of
couples are bicoastal.
It's our first year
of marriage, Devon.
We should try and be together.
I can't just... pick
up and leave.
Why not? I did that for you.
If I walk away, I'll have to
apply for a new residency.
That could take over a year.
What do I do in the meantime?
Silicon Valley is right there.
You could work on
your medical devices.
Mm, hadn't thought of that.
But you're always complaining
about the hospital...
The hours, the pay,
- the paperwork.
- Yeah. I-I complain, sure,
but that doesn't
mean I want to quit.
Priya, I...
I have worked my
whole life for this.
Promise me you'll consider it.
That's all I ask.
♪ I won't let you in, no ♪
♪ I won't let you ground me ♪
♪ Don't you ever call
me your friend, love ♪
♪ Don't you ever
call me again, love ♪
♪ No reply, no reply ♪
♪ So what you've got ♪
♪ No excuses ♪
♪ There you are ♪
♪ Same old you ♪
♪ Bet you need a favor ♪
♪ Find a girl on your radar ♪
♪ I ain't never gonna save ya ♪
- ♪ Never again ♪
- ♪ Again ♪
♪ Sail on... ♪
Are you checking my
pulse? You've been doing that
every night since I
got back into town.
And you stop breathing regularly
- throughout the night.
- Isn't that called
sleep apnea?
You didn't have it before.
I'm checking your pulse
to make sure you don't
have an arrhythmia.
Look... we are never
gonna have a normal life
if you keep overreacting
to every little thing.
I'm taking you in to
see Dr. Austin today.
♪ Funny how they
think that they know us ♪
♪ You ain't laughin',
now there is no us ♪
♪ You and I, you and I ♪
♪ Take me back around
to the place where ♪
♪ You first found me, I
won't let you in, no... ♪
Hey.
Two ships passing in the night.
Your night. My morning.
I hate when we have
opposite schedules.
I hate waking up and
not having you next to me.
If we were on the same schedule,
you could come with
me to Henry's game.
I don't know who's more
excited about it, me or him.
My money is on you.
You're getting pretty
involved with this family.
Ah, it's just one game.
♪ You and I ♪
Have a good time.
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, yeah ♪
♪ Mm, hmm. ♪
Dr. Bell, you understand
this is a deposition for the case
of The State of Georgia
v. Dr. Lane Hunter?
And may I remind
you, you're under oath.
Dr. Hunter is charged with
poisoning hundreds of patients
with unnecessary chemotherapy,
and raking in more
than $20 million
from fraudulent billings.
She's also under investigation
for the death of Lily Kendall.
So, Dr. Bell...
how long were you
and my client lovers?
♪ ♪
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Nice.
♪ ♪
Henry! Henry!
♪ Green lights ♪
♪ 90 degrees with
the top down... ♪
Here we go, here we go.
Low, drive, swing.
Excellent. Yes.
Ball!
Keep your grip snug.
Not too tight. Knuckles.
They should align.
That's it. Yes!
Nice. Okay.
Ball four.
All right, you're up.
You're up, buddy.
Good luck, good luck, good luck.
All right, here we go.
Here we go, Henry.
Good luck, buddy.
Knock the cover
off that ball, baby!
Wait for the right pitch!
Yeah!
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
Every... Everybody take a knee.
Henry?
Henry, are you okay?
♪ ♪
Hello, Randolph.
- You had me deposed.
- On the advice
of my court-appointed attorney.
Got you here, didn't it?
Now what?
You betrayed me to
save your own skin.
Look at me.
Look at me, Randolph.
I was the top oncologist
in all of Georgia.
The head of the department
at Chastain. Self-made.
Respected everywhere and rich.
I had everything,
and you did this.
- You did this to me.
- That phone call to the FBI
was one of the
most difficult things
I've ever had to do in my life.
You put me in an
impossible position.
We were an incredible team,
the two of us at
the top of our fields.
Together, we...
It was you, not me...
who ruined it.
I cared deeply about you.
And whether you
believe it or not...
I have not been able to
stop thinking about you.
Hmm.
Do you think I was born moments
before you walked in here?
I mean, please, Randolph.
The only person you have
ever cared about is you.
- Nice try, though.
- You drew me in here
with a threat.
What's your agenda?
To use your deposition
in a certain video
of the two of us at the
Four Seasons Hotel
to get out of this place.
You're bluffing.
Would you like the
Vimeo passcode?
Once the jury sees
how close we were...
I have a feeling they're
gonna believe me
when I get up on that stand.
When I tell them that
you were my confidant
from the very beginning.
That it was actually you who
told me to destroy those files.
To make sure that
nobody weaponizes
a couple of bad outcomes.
That it was you
who fueled my panic.
You misled me.
You broke my heart.
Tell me, Randy,
am I bluffing?
I want a top-notch attorney,
someone who wears a
fancier suit than you do,
and I get half a million dollars
to make bail so I can
get out of this rat hole.
Don't worry, sweetheart,
I can pay you
back when I get out.
I have a couple of
loaded offshore accounts.
I just can't access
them while I'm in prison.
What do I get in return?
I make sure to keep
you and Chastain
out of this entire case.
♪ ♪
Ah, good.
I have some very big
news to share with you.
QuoVadis is going public.
- That's terrific.
- Yes. But before the IPO,
we need a successful launch
of the vagus nerve stimulator.
The profit potential
of that device is...
enormous.
It'll be like a
pacemaker for the brain,
treating everything from
depression to epilepsy.
Damn thing even cures hiccups.
I will do whatever it takes
to make the VNS a success.
But, Gordon, can I ask you
- a few questions?
- Of course.
I just assisted on a case
with a man whose metal-on-metal
hip implant poisoned him.
It made him blind, almost deaf,
and demented.
Geez. That's horrific.
Uh, the model must
have been defective.
It was. I researched the
company that made the hip.
And they imported all
their devices from China
and pretended it
was made in the U.S.
I discovered...
you worked for that company.
If I understand what
you're saying, uh... it's true.
But I was very young.
I was barely an intern.
Look, I founded QuoVadis
to create the change
that I want to see.
That's why we manufacture
everything ourselves
right here in Atlanta.
We import nothing from
China, so that I can ensure
that we are making products
that patients can trust.
You know, this...
isn't a job to me.
This is my calling.
That's what I needed to hear.
- Thank you. I'm
calling from Chastain.
Chastain Park Memorial!
Hey, Atlanta General
ER is on diversion.
This is the start of a day
from hell. Move faster.
Look, I've already been
on hold for over an hour.
Patient records at Atlanta
General, poison control.
Yeah, patient in 8 has been
waiting an hour. Figure it out.
Irving!
Pravesh!
- What happened?
- Henry had a grand mal seizure
on the field... It's lasted
over 20 minutes now.
He has a history
of seizures, right?
Yes. Absence seizures,
but stable on medications.
He's never had a seizure
- like this before.
- On my count.
One, two, three.
Thank you.
Hey. Go.
We got this.
Let go. All right.
- Thanks for coming in.
- Well, it's rare you call
for a peds
neurologist to the ER,
so I figured it was important.
Well, he's already on
valproic acid at home.
We need to add a third
agent, phenobarbital.
Another medication?
Zoey, I know this is a lot,
but we have to be aggressive
to control these seizures.
This is Julian Booth.
Hello, I'm calling from
Medicine Tracking Dynamics.
QuoVadis pays us to
monitor prescription drugs
and alert them of
prospective patients.
There's one at
Chastain Park Memorial
that's now receiving
three anti-seizure meds:
fosphenytoin, valproic
acid and phenobarbital.
Which makes him a VNS candidate.
QuoVadis flagged this as
high priority on your account.
I don't have a patient name,
but the order came
from Chastain ER.
Hey.
You look busy.
Always.
Devon, this doesn't
have to be weird.
We are completely
capable of still being friends.
Agreed.
So, friend,
what can I do for you?
I got a call about a patient
in the ER who was just put
on several anti-seizure meds.
Henry Barnett.
Status epilepticus.
He's looking rough.
Poor kid.
His brother died
here a month ago.
I didn't know it was a child.
What's this about?
Um... nothing.
Are you telling
me he has cancer?
- No, that's not...
- Five hours in the ER
only to get in here
to have you look at
us like he's going to die.
- Ms. Waverly,
I know that you're concer...
- Are you a nurse?
What are you?
A med student? This
man is my whole life,
and you're the one
that's going to save him?
No. I want somebody
that doesn't have that look
on their face.
I'm ordering a CT...
a CT to see what is going on
so I can hopefully
rule out cancer.
See you in five hours.
It's okay, baby. Don't worry.
It's okay.
I am enjoying our stroll,
but don't you two
have other things to do?
Are you kidding? I always
have time for my favorite patient.
- We know what today is.
- And we have
no intention of letting
you face it alone, Wallace.
My wife, Anna,
would've been 36 today.
Remember her last birthday
- in ICU? We
threw quite a party.
It's hard to believe
my wife spent the last
year of her life at Chastain.
I don't think there's
a doctor or nurse
who didn't know her.
A great lady.
Think, uh, both of you...
And the whole staff...
Did all you could to save her.
Now I'm the patient.
Another year has gone by,
and now it's my turn
to spend my days here,
waiting for a new heart.
And until we find one,
you're stuck with us, Wallace.
Oh, she means
you're stuck with her.
I'm delightful.
Hey.
I heard about Henry.
How's he doing?
Finally broke his seizures.
Now he's reacting
negatively to the medications.
Well, I'm sure Dr. Eckart
has it under control.
He's Henry's doctor now.
I can't step back.
Not after everything I've
seen this family go through.
I know.
But this is why we try
to keep a safe distance
from our patients.
- I should get in there.
- Yeah.
Hey, buddy.
- You hanging in there?
- Yeah.
Is this gonna hurt?
Nah. You'll feel a little pinch.
That's just the
numbing medication.
After that all you'll feel
is a little bit of pressure.
You're really brave, baby.
Got a question for you.
Who's your favorite
baseball player?
Bryce Harper.
Washington Nationals.
That is a solid choice.
Tell Dr. Hawkins why
you like Bryce Harper.
His cleats are awesome.
Your decision's
based on footwear?
He's supercool.
Henry, you are one tough kid.
And I bet your
buddy Bryce Harper
would think you're
supercool, too.
This boy
is perfect for the VNS.
I mean, we're never gonna
get a more sympathetic patient.
Spectacular optics.
So, the VNS is approved
for use in pediatric patients?
I'm sure Gordon
has crossed his T's
and dotted the I's on this one.
Indeed, I have. We're approved.
But as a 510 device?
I know. She's worried
because with 510 FDA approval,
there's often no testing
before a device gets
implanted in patients,
which is exactly why
QuoVadis does its own research.
Now, we haven't published yet.
But everything is here,
and it's all that any doctor
could possibly ask for.
If you meet with any
resistance, just don't hesitate
to let me know. I want to make
sure we're all on the same page.
So, are you done?
Should we be concerned
about Micah's heart rate?
Your boy's gonna be fine.
We just need to adjust
his beta-blockers and
order a sleep study.
You can go ahead and button up.
Mina, can I talk to you outside
about a separate matter?
Listen, don't let your
all-consuming worry
for lover boy make
you lose your focus.
Nothing gets in
the way of my work,
and stop calling him lover boy.
It's becoming annoying.
We got a heart.
Dr. Austin, you're
on Wallace Troke's
transplant team
this week, right?
- Just say yes.
- Yes.
Isn't this the dude with
takotsubo cardiomyopathy?
- Broken heart syndrome.
- The first case I've seen
where grief literally
broke someone's heart.
His wife, Anna,
died here after a long illness.
Every day for a year he walked
three miles just to be with her
and then three miles back home.
Were there no buses running?
He liked to walk.
Said it made him
feel the importance
of his daily commitment
- to be with her.
- Oh, adorable, if nutty.
His only chance of
surviving is this transplant.
The good news is we found
an organ that's a match.
But we need you to harvest
it at Methodist Memorial.
Have you ever
assisted in the harvest
- of a heart?
- No.
Is that an invitation
- to accompany you?
- Do you need it
- embossed on stationery?
- I do not.
Then let's get
this ball rolling.
Dividing the pulmonary veins
and main P.A.
It is a perfect
organ for Wallace.
And what are we
looking for, Dr. Okafor?
Defects and
vegetations on the valves.
And an adequate
rim of atrial tissue
next to the coronary sinus.
I was getting to that.
I know.
Charge.
Clear.
Ah.
Now, back to Chastain,
where the transplant team
will put this beautiful organ
in our man Wallace.
Henry's LP ruled
out an infection,
and his MRI didn't show
anything concerning.
And that's good news.
Yes, but it still means
we don't know what's
causing his seizures.
Truth is, sometimes
we never know.
Henry's EEG still shows
runs of nonconvulsive seizures.
With their length and frequency,
if this goes on much longer,
he can sustain
permanent brain damage.
Brain damage?
What do you suggest we do now?
If the seizures continue,
we're gonna have to
put Henry into a coma
so that his brain can rest.
Are there any other options?
Actually, there is.
Julian, this is Henry's
mom, Zoey Barnett.
Julian Booth works
with a cutting-edge
new medical device
company, QuoVadis.
I am so sorry Henry's
going though this.
But we may have a solution.
We have a new VNS
device designed for cases
exactly like your son's.
VNS devices are a last resort.
And they've all had
significant side effects,
including sudden death.
This newest version is
thoroughly tested and safe.
This is for Dr. Eckart.
He is the doctor
who makes this call,
along with Henry's mom.
There are trials that show
it can be used much
earlier in epilepsy,
sometimes removing the
need of medications altogether.
If you have access
to an improved VNS
that can be used
sooner in epilepsy,
it's a game-changer.
Henry could lead a
life free of seizures.
If the alternative is
putting Henry in a coma
or keeping him on toxic
meds, isn't this worth the risk?
We don't know that yet.
This is not a decision
I would rush into.
If it were me,
I would have Dr. Eckart
go over all the data,
and then you take it from there.
- Dr. Eckart, would you mind?
- Not at all.
I'll get back to you.
Right.
They'll take you up to
pre-op and get you ready
for when your new
heart gets here.
Thank you.
You worried about the surgery?
If I die...
when I'm under...
I'm ready.
I'll get to be with Anna.
Wallace, this is a
chance at a whole new life.
I'm starting to think
that heart might be better
served in somebody else.
Not sure I want
a whole new life.
Not if it still feels
like this one.
Grief is horrible.
Breaks you into a
million pieces, I know.
But I promise you,
it will get easier.
How?
By keeping Anna's memory alive.
If you die, all that
goes with you.
Who's gonna be here to talk
about how special Anna was?
How amazing you were together?
I'll see you in recovery.
Yeah.
And... and thank you.
Thank you for coming
down to consult.
No problem.
Did you lose a little weight
since the last time I saw you?
The day hasn't
started off so great.
Hi.
Finally, a specialist.
We've been waiting two hours,
and this Indian doctor is
the only one who's seen us.
- What's the story?
- 75-year-old male
with two days abdominal
cramping and vomiting.
CT shows a partial SBO.
Mm-hmm. Okay. Can
I talk to you for a sec?
What is this?
- He has a bowel obstruction.
- Partial.
- With a soft abdomen.
- But he has significant
pain and is still vomiting.
He needs to be admitted.
To medicine.
This is not surgical.
Next time, check
with your resident
before you call for a consult.
Do not waste my time again.
Find a pair of
scrubs that fit you.
Could you imagine
loving someone so much
it could literally
break your heart?
No.
What about Micah?
Can he break your heart?
No man can break it.
What have you been through
that makes you so invincible?
It was 2014, and I was finishing
up medical school in Nigeria.
My mother is a surgeon,
working non-stop and
gone for all hours,
so it was my responsibility
to look after my sisters.
One night, after
dinner, I put them to bed
and... and decided
to take a quick nap.
A quick nap turned
into a deep sleep.
And when I woke up,
the whole house was on fire.
Immediately, I knew...
I had left the stove on.
I tried to save Kadara
and Ngozi, but...
I couldn't.
They were 12 and 11.
Wow. I'm... sorry.
I loved my sisters very much.
The grief and...
guilt consumed me.
Emotions can enrich our lives,
but they can also destroy us.
Now, I never want to
talk about it ever again.
It's been an hour. I
think it's time you called it.
Time of death, 12:03.
I'll speak to the family.
Take a break.
My husband is
still in severe pain!
Where are we at
with his treatment?
Can you just do the right
thing and come check on him?!
Hello.
Okay. Okay.
All right.
We'll up his pain meds and...
If you just, um,
give me a minute.
Excuse me?
I have a 75-year-old man
with a small bowel obstruction,
ER Bay Three. We
need to admit him.
Absolutely not. Call surgery.
I did. They won't admit.
Neither will I. I'm
not taking an SBO.
If he gets better, he goes home.
If he gets worse, they operate.
I'm not going to admit
him just to baby-sit.
We need a doctor over here!
Paramedics found
him on the freeway
with a meth pipe in hand.
Let's get him ten
of IM haloperidol
and check his blood sugar.
Eye station, now!
What happened to your break?!
- All right,
let's get him to Bay Nine.
- Okay.
Is he all right?
His seizures are
getting harder to control.
And the medications
we're giving him are starting
to affect his liver function.
So what do I do now?
I know you're scared, Zoey,
but, just-just give this
a little bit more time.
That's not an option.
Zoey needs to make her decision.
Soon.
Dr. Randolph Bell, chief
of surgery and the CEO
of Chastain has heard
about Henry's case, would like
to talk to you about
the VNS device.
As we've discussed, the VNS
is the best option
available to your son.
Well, I've looked
carefully at the data, and
- the results aren't clear.
- Doctors aren't trained
to consistently evaluate
this type of dense research.
The man can read.
And what he read said
the sample size is dismal.
But the device has
been approved, right?
It has... by the FDA.
So then why is
everyone so nervous?
- Everyone isn't.
- I am.
A high percentage of devices
are recalled after they've
been put in patients
- and have caused
permanent damage.
- That has happened
with other companies,
but not QuoVadis.
I wish there were more options
with less risk. There are not.
You've already lost a son,
and I want to do everything
possible to ensure
that doesn't happen again.
I strongly recommend you do not
go down this path with the VNS.
Ultimately, this is your call.
But I will tell you, if
this... were my child,
I would move forward
and implant the VNS.
Dr. Chao has done
several of these surgeries.
He's highly-experienced
with the VNS.
Has he implanted it in a child?
I want this to go perfectly.
I-I feel responsible.
And if the data
isn't really there...
You really think Gordon Page
would manufacture products
that aren't safe?
Hmm. Well done, Dr. Bell.
This is an historic day.
The first of many, I'm sure.
Whoa. Hold up.
The front of the
heart stopped moving.
It's acute hypokinesis
of the anterior wall.
There's a block in
the middle of the LAD.
The heart is having
a heart attack.
Yo, let's go!
Is Wallace ready for surgery?
Yes, in OR Two
- under general anesthesia.
- Good.
He'll die if we put him
back on the waiting list.
This heart may not be
perfect, but once we fix it,
it'll be his best shot. I need
to get his saphenous vein.
Should we use his LIMA?
It'll take 20 minutes
to open his chest.
You can get a
saphenous vein in five.
Time is heart.
Get me a vein retrieval kit
and start prepping
the left lower leg for
saphenous vein harvest.
Octopus clamp.
I thought you'd be quicker.
Please. That was a world record.
I've never done bypass on
a beating heart. Can I assist?
Oh, now was that
ever a question?
Hand Dr. Okafor the pickups.
Spatulate the end of
the saphenous vein,
and I will do the
arteriotomy. #11 blade to me.
7-0 Prolene.
Be careful with your bites...
Keep them evenly spaced out.
A little quicker.
I am suturing the aorta.
This is delicate work.
The heart is losing oxygen.
It could not care less.
Done.
Mm. Ah.
There's a small leak.
Mm. I see it.
Adding another stitch.
There.
You fixed it.
We fixed it.
Shall we give Wallace
the gift of a new life?
♪ Ooh... ♪
♪ No, I can't hide it ♪
♪ You're ultraviolet ♪
♪ Ooh... ♪
♪ No, I can't hide it ♪
♪ You're reading all ♪
♪ Of me, you're reading... ♪
Everything went perfectly.
How long until we
know if this works?
His seizures already stopped.
♪ Hide it ♪
Thank you.
Of course.
- ♪ You're ultraviolet ♪
- Thank you.
♪ Ah ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ You're ultraviolet... ♪
Well done, Dr. Bell.
Today was a good day,
both for Chastain and QuoVadis.
To a wonderful partnership.
♪ No, I can't hide it ♪
♪ You're ultraviolet. ♪
I hear it worked.
Nice save.
Yeah.
Great learning
opportunity for Dr. Okafor.
It's not often you
get to operate
on a heart in a box.
Hmm.
Does she know
you're in love with her?
I beg your pardon?
I'm her teacher, her mentor.
To be anything else would cross
a line that I would never cross.
That must be hard on you.
I deal.
And life is long.
Eventually, one day, I
will not be her mentor,
and she'll be my equal.
For a guy who doesn't
wear his heart on his sleeve,
that was an impressive share.
Let's just keep this between us,
all right?
♪ ♪
Hey.
You're on in 20.
Ships passing.
Henry's in recovery,
if you want to check in on him.
Thank you for the update, but...
I think it's best if I just
let his mom be with him.
Rough day?
Not really.
A touch of racism
from a paranoid wife.
Got physically attacked
by a psychotic meth head.
And what am I forgetting? Um...
Right. Priya told me we have
to move to San Francisco.
Your turn.
I have always been
sure about my field.
But now...
I wonder if I'm
making a difference
or if I'm adding
to a very big problem.
You are smart, Julian.
And passionate.
And honest.
The device industry needs people
like you to fix a broken system.
If you see something
that's not right,
you will be there to
blow the whistle and fix it.
Could the same
be said about you?
There aren't many
people like you, Devon.
Hardly any, in fact.
You were meant to be a doctor.
- Randolph Bell.
- You have a collect call
from Atlanta
Correctional Facility.
Inmate 08790, Lane Hunter.
Will you accept?
Yes.
So, have you got
an answer for me?
If it's not the one I want
to hear, that video of us
gets released tomorrow.
I've, um,
narrowed the list of
attorneys down to three.
Heavy hitters?
Yes.
- What do they say?
- That juries
trust doctors and it's
possible we will get off.
And if you do, it'll help
me undo the damage
you did to this hospital.
- Oh, so you're making this
all about Chastain, huh?
- Now, I suggest we
play on the same team from
now on, or at least pretend to.
When do I get to
breathe fresh air again?
Soon.
Very soon.
Hi, I'm one of the
sales reps for QuoVadis.
I know we don't
normally come down
to where we actually
build the devices,
but I need to
double-check on an order
for, uh, Chastain Park.
Could you help me?
I will be so quick.
I promise.
You've got five minutes.
Thank you. That's all I need.
We manufacture
everything ourselves,
right here, in Atlanta.
We import nothing from China.
This isn't a job to me.
This is my calling.
Oh, my God.
What happened to you?
The question should be
what didn't happen to me.
I have had
some pretty terrible days
as a doctor, but today
just might take the prize.
That looks really swollen.
Are you sure you're okay?
Today, I got kicked around.
Abused.
Unappreciated.
At times, I just felt
completely useless.
Then come with
me to San Francisco.
It's not easy.
If it were,
everyone would be a doctor,
because it is the
best job in the world.
Despite everything.
Because of everything.
I wouldn't trade my worst
day at Chastain for my best
making medical
devices in Silicon Valley.
I can't leave.
I'm sorry.
But, hey, hey...
this doesn't mean
that I don't want to figure
out how to make this work.
But is it really what you want?
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH