Try not to be scared
when you see him, okay?
Mom, I've seen him
sick. I'm not scared.
This time's different.
The doctors gave him an extra
course of radiation and chemo...
I know.
And you understand how
proud we are of you, right?
Gloves, mask.
Matty, you said you wanted to see
your brother before the procedure.
I know I look like an alien, but
I promise not to eat your brain.
When this is done, will you be
able to play out back with me?
I'll rip anything you
put near the strike zone.
Let your brother rest up, while
we take some of your marrow.
You don't need to be
in an isolation room,
but I pulled some strings so you
could be next door to your brother.
How many games will I miss?
Well, you only have
to be here overnight,
but you do have to
take it easy for a little bit.
I already missed two. Matty...
I know. It's okay.
It must have been a drag.
We just had to make sure you
weren't exposed to any bugs,
because your healthy bone marrow is
what's gonna cure your brother's leukemia.
Go on.
He sneezed. Maybe
it's just an allergy.
Not with an enlarged
spleen and a fever.
He's got one of 10,000
possible infections,
even if it's just the common cold, I
do the transplant, he kills his brother.
How long do we have?
Radiation obliterated
his immune system.
Even in a clean room, he's
got four, maybe five, days left.
No way we can solve this that
fast. You need to find another donor.
They're African American.
It makes it nearly
impossible to find a full match.
Tell me about it. I can't even find
the one I've got working for me.
Where is Foreman?
Nothing like a dead patient to
send you back to your choir boy roots.
Hey, you're not gonna
believe what happened.
Wilson just killed a
kid same way you did.
He's not dead.
Five days are gonna fly by. He
didn't look both ways before he nuked.
You done talking to
your imaginary friend?
Because I thought, maybe,
you could do your job and just...
Start the donor brother on
broad-spectrum antibiotics.
Great idea, if you're looking
to save exactly one kid.
Broad-spec will take at least a
week to work. We need narrow-spec.
How old is Hector?
Our patient's name is
Matty. His brother's Nick.
Hector's my dog. He's about 17?
Seventeen? That's, like, a 119 in
human years. Why is he still alive?
Five days minus 20 seconds
talking about Wilson's dog.
We need to start testing. Stool
samples for parasites, antibody tests...
Blood panel was negative
for all the usual suspects.
That's because the
infection is too small.
We start testing now, it's like
looking for a needle in a haystack.
We draw blood odds are we're
just gonna come up with hay.
We need to grow more needles.
Okay, that probably
needs further explanation.
We make the donor kid sicker.
We freeze him, we soak him,
break down his immune system.
Suddenly we're looking at some needle
that a camel can pass through the eye of.
Making him sicker risks spreading
the infection all throughout his body.
True, but who cares?
Once we know what the infection
is, we'll know exactly how to treat it.
As long as he isn't
dead yet, we're cool.
We should do what
we normally do.
Go to the kid's house, check
for sources of the infection.
Waste of time.
You think it's in the house.
I know it's in the patient.
Safer than intentionally
making the kid sicker.
Fine, go.
So exactly how sick are
you gonna make Matty?
He could get quite ill.
It certainly won't be a pleasant
experience for anyone, but it's our only...
Ever get caught in the
rain without an umbrella?
That's all we're talking
about here. Sign the form.
It's a little more complicated than
that. We'll also be doing leukopheresis.
We run Matty's blood through a machine
that filters out his white blood cells.
But without his white cells,
how could he get better in time?
We'll pump the white blood cells
back as soon as we have a diagnosis.
Then we should be able to cure the
infection in time to do the transplant.
But you can't guarantee?
We're not GM. No
recalls, no rebates.
Anymore questions while
your son's life slips away?
You really think
we should do this?
Yes.
Sorry. Your patient,
you tell them.
This is your family. It
needs to be your decision.
All you had to do
was say, "Yes, I do."
God knows it's a phrase that
you've used often enough in your life.
It was a mistake every time.
Give it a break. They said yes.
That's not enough for you. You need
them to feel good about saying yes.
I treat patients for months,
maybe years, not weeks, like you.
I'm taller.
If they don't trust
me, I can't do my job.
The only value of that trust is
that you can manipulate them.
You should write greeting cards.
Giving the parents a chance to
make a bad choice was a bad choice.
At least it would have
been their choice.
One they'd regret
at their son's funeral.
Kitchen and bathrooms were immaculate.
Whatever the kid's got, he didn't get here.
No, whatever the kid got, he didn't
get from the kitchen or the bathroom.
Nobody cleans swing sets.
Yeah, because their kid's 10
and hasn't used it since he was six.
You obviously think your time could
be better spent. Why'd you come along?
You feel bad about
what happened last week.
I'm handling it.
Think the family's gonna sue?
She only had her grandparents,
and they weren't close.
Well, that's good.
For you, I mean.
A lawsuit makes it even
harder to put behind you.
You put yours behind you?
Nope.
When I woke up this morning I...
I couldn't remember what she
was wearing when I admitted her.
Memories fade.
I killed her a week ago and I can't
remember what color top she was wearing.
I was grateful when I could
wake up not thinking about her.
I'm not like you.
Your patient died because you were
distracted over the death of your dad.
I made a calculated decision.
You acted like a human
being. I acted like House.
Could be Mucor or
Strongyloides in this dirt.
No pulmonary symptoms,
setting well, breathing easily.
Mom, I'm freezing.
How long do I have to wait?
Matty, we found an old
water pump in your backyard.
You ever drink from it?
Yeah it was gross.
We gotta test for
Mycobacteria, leptospirosis.
When did you drink the water?
Last summer?
You sure? You haven't
even taken a sip to cool off?
It was really gross.
My shoulder's bugging
me. Does that matter?
It could. Did you do
anything to hurt it?
Just threw the ball around the
other day, for a couple hours.
It's probably just a muscle
ache. Let us know if it gets worse.
So soreness and stuff,
that's not 'cause I'm sick?
Is something else bugging you?
Sort of.
He has acute scrotum. Adorable.
Please, I thought
you were dignified.
Come on, how am I not
supposed to make that joke?
Best thing about big, honking
gonads, well, one of the best things,
is that there's only a few
infections that could cause it.
Do urinalysis and cultures for E.
Coli, Klebsiella, TB, and Brucella.
Blood tests for enteroviruses
and adenoviruses.
Hopefully, the needles have grown
as fast as his sack, and we can find it.
Can Chase and
Cameron cover that?
Mind if I ask why?
I want to recheck the National
Marrow registry for an alternate donor.
In case we're wrong?
It's been known to happen.
Fine, go.
Negative for E. coli and TB. Why
is House taking it easy on Foreman?
He deserves a break.
Yeah, House is all about
giving breaks to people in need.
No on Klebsiella.
And it's Tuesday.
It's got nothing to do with
Foreman or House. It's just...
It's the day I remind you I like
you, and I want us to be together.
Thank you, I'd forgotten.
No on Brucella and
both viral antibodies.
You're really gonna
do this every Tuesday?
You take the day off, I'll
pick it up on Wednesday.
What if we're looking
for the wrong thing?
These are the only infections
that cause swollen testicles.
Why don't you just say it four times
now and leave me alone for a month?
Well, what if it's
not an infection?
His temperature's through the roof.
There's mucous pouring out of him.
I know he has an infection, but what if it
didn't directly cause the scrotum issue?
What if it just caused the thing
that caused the scrotum issue?
CK-MB is elevated.
Slightly. There's
nothing wrong with...
Indicates cardiac injury.
We stuck him in that
room, put his stupid,
little runny-nose
infection into hyperdrive.
What if it went to his heart?
Pulmonary valve looks clean.
Wait. Stop. Mitral
valve, there's a growth.
He'll need a month of
antibiotics to clear that.
His brother only
has four days to live.
The infection in Matty's mitral
valve rules him out as a donor.
This is perfect.
We drove the
infection into his heart.
Okay, perfect is too strong of
a word, but it's very, very good.
Now we know
where the infection is.
All we've got to do is remove the valve,
ID the infection, target and destroy it.
Remove the valve?
He'll be fine on antibiotics. He
doesn't need open-heart surgery.
He'll be heartbroken, on
account of his dead brother.
Either way he's got a dead brother.
The infection isn't just in the valve.
Even with targeted medication,
there's no way we can
clear his system in time.
We don't have to. We
have to clear his marrow.
After the surgery, we
harvest the marrow,
marinate it in the targeted
antibiotic, simmer and serve.
Could work. It's insane.
It is better than
a dead brother.
I'm running this by Cuddy.
Fine. Go. In fact, let's all go.
This surgery is
dangerous and life-altering,
and clearly not in the
interest of our patient.
It is, if he likes his brother.
We have a conflict of interests.
- The parents don't.
- Of course they do.
They already sacrificed Matty's
health to benefit his brother once.
They made his cold worse.
We screwed up his heart
valve by making his cold worse.
Do you have anything
to add to this debate?
Wilson's right. Foreman's wrong.
Your shirt is way too
revealing for the office.
What do you want me to do?
We should call child services and
have them appoint a guardian for Matty.
No.
Go explain the choices to the
parents, and don't let House bully them.
House.
Did he really think I was
gonna do that? I didn't.
Then, why did you let him...
I'm trying to cut
him some slack.
Nice of you.
I think he's got the yips.
Steve Blass, Scott Norwood,
David Duval all got the yips.
Great athletes, lost their confidence
and immediately started sucking.
And you're giving him
time to work through it?
Four days, and he's fired.
You don't get
better from the yips.
Open-heart surgery?
If you want both kids to
live, it's the only choice.
Due to the valve replacement.
Matty will have to be on blood
thinners to prevent potential clots.
For how long? Forever.
He couldn't participate in contact
sports, because of the risk of hemorrhage.
What about the marrow registry?
Maybe they'll find a match.
Maybe they'll ride
it here on a unicorn.
I'm afraid finding
a viable new donor
isn't something we can
realistically depend on.
Either we cripple one
son, or kill the other.
He won't be able to play baseball.
That doesn't make him a cripple.
What should we do?
You should protect your family as
a whole. You should do the surgery.
That was awesome. Shut up.
I gotta start
pretending to care.
I did exactly what
Cuddy told us not to do.
No you didn't. You did exactly
what she told me not to do.
You're completely in the clear.
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
You're actually upset. You
just said what you believed.
I also believe in patients
making their own choices.
Because it lessens your
guilt if things go wrong.
You're not protecting their choices.
You're soothing your conscience.
By that logic, a sociopath would make
the best patient advocate in the world.
Am I blushing?
You ready?
Yeah.
Thanks.
You'd do the same for me.
Don't worry. You'll be fine.
You think I'll be better in
time to pitch in the playoffs?
Maybe next season.
We should have told him.
He loves his brother, but if he
understood what we were asking of him...
He loves his brother more
than he loves baseball.
You did the right thing.
Putting any part of
this decision on him...
It's impossible for you
guys to deal with this.
How's a 10-year-old
supposed to do it?
Canula in place.
Sutures are holding.
We're all set to go.
Switch him over to bypass.
Yeah? I didn't do the surgery.
You woke me up to
tell me that you're lazy?
We biopsied a piece
before we started cutting.
I'm tired. Get to the point.
We didn't replace the valve
because the growth was
fibrous tissue. It wasn't infectious.
We've got to be wrong about...
Oh, God. What?
You know what's
wrong with Matty?
I think Hector's
committed suicide.
What are you talking about?
He took some pills.
Is he alive?
He ate half my stash.
Of course he's...
He's stoned. I'll be right in.
We cut all the way
into this kid's heart,
and all we got was this lousy,
non-infectious fibrous tissue.
How did we miss this?
Matty had a fever. He got sicker when
we suppressed his immune system.
That all points to infection.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Not
our fault. Fibrous tissue.
Something is turning his
healthy heart valve into gristle.
Fibrous tissue, enlarged spleen,
fever... Could mean autoimmune.
Autoimmune diseases aren't
passed along in bone marrow.
He can still donate. We
confirm, I do the surgery.
Lupus and Behçet's are our best
bet. Do an ANA and pathergy test.
Or it could be infection.
My memory's not
what it used to be,
but didn't we just rule
that out eight seconds ago?
Just because it's not
what screwed up his valve,
it doesn't mean it's
not in his system.
Uh-huh, and has the obvious
advantage of making us right all along.
Little disadvantage of
making big brother dead.
That's your argument?
A better outcome?
It fits.
The family has one kid with
leukemia and one with autoimmune.
I wouldn't stand next
to them in a rain storm.
That's your argument?
It sucks for them?
It fits, and we can
still help big brother.
National Marrow Registry came
up with four out of six donors.
Six out of six is two better
than four out of six, right?
I mean, I know two is so small,
but since it means that he's gonna
get Graft-Versus-Host Disease,
the marrow will attack his
body, and he'll die a painful death.
Find out what autoimmune it is.
Is this autoimmune better or
worse than the new heart valve?
It depends on which autoimmune it is.
With early detection, most are manageable.
How long will testing take?
That's the other
good thing about this.
There's literally thousands
of possible infections,
but only a handful of
autoimmune conditions.
We'll have the
answer in a few hours.
Hey, Doctor?
Is this bad?
Wanna catch a movie?
It's one in the morning.
I know a place.
Although, I wouldn't
recommend wearing those shoes.
How exactly does a dog
unscrew a bottle of pills?
Is that a riddle?
It requires an opposable thumb.
I must have left it off.
On the floor?
I think he hopped up
onto the bathroom counter.
He has arthritis.
Not me this time.
No! It's your damn dog.
He chews everything. I was
missing a file. Found paper in his stool.
An original Sun Record
78 Elvis recording, gone.
Who the hell chews
vinyl? He's vindictive.
He's had a good,
long life. It's his time.
Are you okay?
I just tripped over
Wilson's self-righteousness.
What do you got?
Matty's negative for
everything. It's not autoimmune.
So, we're back to infection.
Nick's starting to deteriorate fast.
He's got bruising all over his arms.
His capillaries
are leaking blood.
If it happens in his
brain, he's dead.
We've got to go with
the four-out-of-six donor.
Did I mention my concerns
about four being less than six?
Wilson's first wife
ignored a similar issue.
Of course, that time, it was
only fatal to their marriage.
It's either that, or we start
randomly testing Matty for infections.
I know how you hate
the word "random."
Do it alphabetically. We're
not doing that damn transplant.
Where's Foreman?
We've found a donor.
It's not an ideal match, but four
out of six still gives Nick a chance.
A partial match transplant
is extremely dangerous.
Doctor Foreman explained...
Did he also explain what sort
of pain your son will experience
if he gets
Graft-Versus-Host Disease?
Yes.
Apparently, he didn't
explain it vividly enough.
Let me give it a whack...
He also explained that if we did nothing,
Nick could start bleeding into his brain.
Matty is a perfect match. Just give
us a little more time to figure out...
How much time?
Doctor House is the
best diagnostician...
How much time?
I don't know.
And Nick can start bleeding
into his brain without any warning?
Yes, but the chances of
complications from a mismatch are...
My boys have suffered enough.
Get Matty better,
and give Nick the transplant
from the new donor.
Foreman screwed us.
No, you screwed us.
What is the point in being
able to control people
if you won't actually do it?
It's like training a dog and letting
him go on your rug, which, by the way...
Once Foreman got his mitts on
them, well, there was no way...
You don't explain chances
and probabilities, you lie to them.
You tell them Foreman's a moron,
which isn't even much of a lie right now.
You've got to talk to him.
I've got no problem
with what Foreman did.
He undercut us, and he
may have cost that kid his life.
Foreman did what he thought was
right. You, on the other hand, sucked out.
When the decision
really mattered,
you didn't have the guts
to tell them what to do.
If that kid dies, it's because
Foreman was wrong,
and because you're a coward.
Oh, goodness, I've
left my door open.
My poor dog must have run away and
been hit by a car or a truck or a train.
Or an anvil.
Thank God, you're still here.
He's still here!
Where's my stereo?
How are you feeling?
A little itchy.
It's weird, huh?
You still have no idea
what's wrong with me,
but those meds
will make me better.
We put you on a variety of medications
that will fight all kinds of infections.
Nick, you know exactly
what's wrong with him,
but maybe he's
gonna die, anyway.
Hopefully, the
new marrow will...
I can't go in there, can I?
Your infection would kill him.
So, I won't be able to be
with him when he dies?
You'll be able to be with
him when he gets better.
What's wrong?
It really itches.
Hello?
Why am I meeting you here?
You're paying for my
new cane. It was your dog.
So, that's it? You call
me a coward, life goes on?
Apparently. You showed up.
Hey.
I'm sorry.
You're pathetic. I
didn't actually mean that.
Yes, you did.
No, I didn't to infinity.
You're pathetic. Yeah?
When?
What did the labs say?
Why don't you buy your
cane at a medical supply store
like a normal cripple?
Fewer bitching choices.
Okay. What do
you got in bitching?
Right this way.
That was Cameron. The kid that
wasn't all that sick is now all that sick.
He's bleeding out of
his ears. Blood counts?
Down.
Schistocytes on the smear?
His body's not making new blood
cells. His bone marrow's crashing.
This is one of our top sellers.
It's a little too Marilyn
Manson in a retirement home.
The meds are suppressing
his bone marrow.
Or the infection's doing it.
Pretty cool.
Genuine bull penis,
stretched over a metal rod.
Penis canes are murder.
Right.
Let me see the one on the end.
You got it.
We need to stop Matty's meds.
If the marrow rebounds, it's the
meds. If it doesn't, it's an infection.
And if it's the infection?
Maybe I was wrong about
which kid's gonna die.
Bitching.
Flames?
It makes it look like I'm going
fast. Now, how's our dying kids?
Nick's developed blisters
all over his feet and legs.
He's got grade four
Graft-Versus-Host.
Increase his dosage
of methylprednisolone.
Already did. It's not working.
Feeling guilty?
I did the right thing.
Always a comfort.
Okay, what's the
other kid's status?
We're done with Nick?
God is done with Nick.
We know what he has.
We know how to treat it.
We're doing it, it's not
working. Life is for the living.
Matty's been off his meds for a few
hours, but his blood count's still tanking.
Means the meds aren't
to blame. It's the infection.
If we don't get this under control,
his blood will literally turn into water.
Cultures still aren't
growing anything.
Why not?
Because you did the right thing.
Convinced the parents to treat the kid.
All you did was yank the
weed out of the ground.
Its roots are still killing their
beautiful lawn. We just can't see it.
If we can't see it, we
don't know what it is.
If we don't know what
it is, we can't kill it.
So we got to wait for
it to grow back again.
Now, the soil is arid.
So with he and his brother
we'll be dead by the time...
What if the dandelion
was in fertile soil?
What if we take the roots from
Matty, and put them in Nick?
Turn the kid into a
petri dish, only better.
A petri dish can't
tell you when it hurts.
You want to give him
his brother's infection?
The very thing we've been trying
to avoid since the brother sneezed?
Leukemia kid's got no defenses.
Which is why he'll die.
But before he does, the
infection will spread fast.
Fast enough to tell us what it
is, in time to save his brother.
Do you see any other way?
The infection is decimating
Matty's bone marrow.
But if we give that marrow to Nick, his
symptoms could let us diagnose Matty.
But, it'll kill Nick. Yes.
You're...
You're saying we should
kill one son to save the other?
Nick is gonna die either way.
You don't know that. I mean,
he's in pain right now, but...
Nick's Graft-Versus-Host is
not responding to medication.
That can change.
Maybe he... He'll rally.
Hey, my Nick is a fighter.
Graft-Versus-Host
isn't gonna go away
because of Nick's sunny
smile and positive outlook.
Nick has survived three
reoccurrences of his leukemia.
He's being torn apart
from the inside out.
His pain's gonna get worse
and worse, until he dies.
You're just dragging it out.
You have only one
decision to make.
You can leave here
with one dead son, or two.
Tell them.
You should let us do this.
No!
We're not giving up on Nick.
Not!
The patient's parents apparently
don't want to be parents anymore.
You're a sneaky bastard. Any
ideas how we get around this?
Court order? It's hardly sneaky.
We can still save Matty.
Run more tests, find out what
infection is destroying his marrow.
Ten-thousand possible infections
at least 20 minutes per test
it'll take you
approximately eight years.
Actually, four months, assuming
the last one I test is the right one,
and, if it's the first, it will take
me approximately 20 minutes.
He's right. It's worth a shot.
He's timid. Testing blindly
is not gonna save this kid.
But standing around here will.
Wow, he sure is hurting.
The nurses say he maxed
out on his pain meds.
If I had a nickel for
every time I heard that...
Pharmacy's on the ground floor.
I'm gonna go get you some
more pain medication, okay?
Thank you.
It's not gonna help.
You're dying.
Nothing's gonna change that. These
drugs will just make you go easier.
I know.
Fourteen years on the planet,
most of them spent suffering.
Dying before you
even got to drive a car,
take off a girl's
bra, drink a beer.
Believe me, there's
plenty you haven't done.
Really good stuff.
Must make it hard
to believe in God,
or fairness, larger purpose.
But your life doesn't
have to be meaningless.
You can save your brother.
How?
Negative for CMV.
Negative for amoebas.
House called you timid.
He's called me a lot worse.
To him, there is nothing
worse. He's gonna fire you.
Even if we run 100 tests,
that only gives us a one percent
chance of saving these kids.
Better than zero. You
don't care if you get fired?
I don't know.
There's got to be a way to better our
odds from a 99-percent chance of death.
You've got to know.
It's not food-borne, because
no one else in the family is sick.
You either care about
your job, or you don't.
And Matty's the only one who drank
from that water pump in the back yard,
and we eliminated
Pseudomonas and cholera.
If you care, you fight to
keep it. If you don't, you quit.
I thought they
lived in the suburbs.
They do. Why?
And they've got a water pump?
Please, I... I want to do it.
No, Nicky, it's
not your decision.
I'm dying. There's nothing
that's gonna change that.
Hey, hey, hey. Don't say
that. Okay? You can't give up.
It's time for me to go, Dad.
You got to let me go.
No.
Please, son.
I can't... I can't... I can't!
Let me do it for Matty.
Let me do it for you guys.
So you won't be alone.
Are you sure?
No, but he is.
Get Nick back to the clean room.
The parents
agreed to infect him.
We figured out what's wrong
with Matty, histoplasmosis.
Well, what is that?
I mean, why did it...
Fungal infection. It
grows in chicken feces.
The dirt that Matty used
to build his pitcher's mound
must have sat
under a chicken coop.
Your whole neighborhood
was built on top of farmland.
We didn't test for it
earlier, because we didn't...
Can you fix him?
Full course of amphotericin
and he should be fine.
And Nick? I mean, can
you clean Matty's marrow?
Just like you were talking about doing
it, but do it fast, and get it into Nick.
I'm sorry, the reason
Matty is so sick is
because the infection
is attacking his marrow.
He doesn't have enough left to safely
take from him and give to his brother.
I'm gonna get
better now? That's it?
That's it.
And what about Nick?
Your brother was willing
to risk his life to save you.
Are you willing
to do that for him?
I can't sedate you.
You're too sick.
Please, please stop. Please.
Please. You're done, right?
Sorry, I need a lot more.
No, stop! Stop!
How much heat are you
taking from the parents?
They're calming down.
I think it has something to do with both
their kids being alive, awake, and eating.
The marrow transplant took.
Welcome back, Foreman.
You should talk to him.
Tell him how proud I am?
Hey, if you're ashamed
of him, tell him that.
Pride and shame only apply to people we
have a vested interest in, not employees.
How many hours a day do
you have to spend with someone
before they're basically family?
Good point.
But, first, I've got to tell Cameron and
Chase that they're violating God's will.
I'm just asking you to have an
adult conversation to let him know...
That he did a good
job? He knows it.
Adults don't need adult conversations,
just like I don't need this conversation.
Have you killed Hector yet?
Obviously not.
Oh. He's quiet. He's...
Is that my stethoscope?
Bad dog.
Listen...
Bonnie joined her homeowner's
association and staged a coup.
Pets are now allowed.
Oh.
If you want to keep him,
she wants a new puppy
anyway. She'll understand.
Why would I want to keep him?
You're sure?
Come on, boy.
Accidents happen.
Candy?
Good boy.
You did good.
I did what you would have.
Well, maybe I'm biased, but...
I tortured the kid.
Because you knew it was right.
You knew you were
saving his brother.
I know.
I don't like that I know.
I hate that I can listen
to a kid screaming in pain
and not even take a moment to
question whether I'm doing the right thing.
I hate that in order to
be like you, as a doctor,
I have to be like you
as a human being.
I don't want to turn into you.
You're not.
You've been like me since
you were eight-years-old.
You'll save more
people than I will.
But I'll settle
for killing less.
Consider this my
two weeks’ notice.