Oh, no. Maggie,
you are burning up.
And now you're on chemo
for breast cancer.
I'm going to be careful.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I thought I had a patient.
Crockett Marcel,
fourth year, surgery.
Welcome back.
And the concussion?
Yeah, I'm taking it slowly.
I just have to ask.
Do you love him?
My relationship with Phillip
is the only thing in my life
that's working right now.
My lymphoma is progressing
and there's nothing
more they can do.
I want to be there.
For all of it.
Egg whites...
Whoa.
What's all this?
It's a meringue.
For breakfast?
No, it's for Robin's birthday.
It's for a Baked Alaska.
The meringue goes over
the ice cream and the cake.
But Robin's birthday
isn't for a couple of
weeks though, right?
Yeah. This is a test run.
Oh.
What's the fire
extinguisher for?
I'm gonna set it on fire.
Hey, how do you keep
the ice cream from melting?
That's what
the test run's for.
Ah.
Wait a minute.
Maybe I should
play hooky today.
Stay home.
Be your official taster.
Ow!
CeCe?
Ow! Oh, my gosh.
Whoa.
Honey.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What happened?
I'm getting so clumsy, honey.
Let me look. Let me...
No, no.
Please, please. Please.
All right. Learned this one
in biophysics.
Yeah.
Stop it.
That's actually pretty cool.
It's all in the lips, ladies.
I bet.
Hey.
Looks like
we're paired
together today.
Lucky me.
Excuse me.
So, babe. That Crockett guy
is working days now?
What's the deal with him?
Not sure he's my speed.
Strikes me as someone who
doesn't take things seriously.
Yeah.
Doctor Choi.
Yeah?
Treatment Four.
Mags?
Uh-huh.
Todd Shepard? Doesn't say
what he's in here for.
Said he wanted to
discuss it with a doctor.
No, I'm in the ED now.
Treatment Room Four.
How far away are you guys?
You're positive you'll be here
within the hour?
Right. Thanks.
Sorry, I really needed
to make that call.
That's okay, Todd.
I go by Shep,
if you don't mind.
Okay, Shep. I'm Dr. Choi.
What brings you in today?
About six weeks ago,
I was diagnosed with GBM.
It's a terminal...
Terminal brain cancer.
I'm sorry, Shep.
I've got all my medical
records right here
in case you're interested.
Are you experiencing
any complications?
Not exactly.
Excuse me, one second.
The phone call I just made
was to a company called CCI.
Camden Cryonics Institute.
They're gonna preserve me
until a cure can be
found for my condition.
They're on the way here now.
To freeze you?
Um, it's called vitrification.
But, yeah.
You understand you have to be
declared dead first.
That's why I'm here.
For you to declare me dead,
so to speak.
I'm sorry, Shep, I'm confused.
The cocktail
I've been drinking
contains amitriptyline,
lorazepam and two hundred
milligrams of amphetamines.
It should put me to sleep
in a little over an hour
and arrest my heart
sufficiently for you to
declare me dead in about five.
I have a D.N.I. and D.N.R.
My lawyer assures me
it's all in order.
Doris! Come here,
we gotta pump his stomach.
Stop! I refuse treatment!
Don't listen to him, Doris.
Help! Assault!
Give me the tube.
This doctor keeps touching me,
I'll sue the whole lot of you!
Dr. Choi. Stop.
Well, here you can
see the fracture
of the distal radius.
Minimal displacement.
CeCe, are you all right?
Maggie said you took
some kind of fall...
Broke her wrist.
My arms aren't as long
as they used to be.
I've seen worse.
Four to six weeks
in a cast, you'll be fine.
What? Four to six weeks?
Well, wait a minute.
I need to be able
to use my arm.
Isn't there another
operation we can do?
Normally, yeah, we would
surgically insert a plate.
Shorten your recovery time,
but I really wouldn't
recommend that, Mrs. Charles.
Why?
You'd just open the door
to a whole host
of other complications
given your condition, babe.
It's just not worth it.
They're right, CeCe.
Let's just let ortho
put a cast on it.
It's the least worst option.
Right?
Hey, I'll go talk
to the attending.
Thank... Wait a minute.
You okay, CeCe?
She wants to make
a Baked Alaska for Robin.
It was a flambé. I was making
her a flambé for her birthday.
Okay. I'll go to the bakery.
I'll get a big old cake...
No way.
Sparklers. And we'll
do it up nice.
All right?
Daniel, I hate to
pull you away
but we've got a situation.
It's fine.
You can go. Go.
Okay?
It's fine. I'm fine.
I'll be right back.
I'm fine. I'm fine.
All right, ya all right?
He's committing suicide
right in front of us,
how's this a grey area?
Well, it's complicated,
due to his condition
and his prognosis.
Have you had a chance
to review Mr. Shepard's
medical records, Sam?
Yeah, he's terminal.
I mean, I could go in
and do a resection and
aggressively radiate but it...
It'd buy him
12 to 15 months, tops.
It's a question of "when"
and not "if" with this guy.
And Mr. Shepard has the right
to refuse treatment.
He's just a kid.
Not according to the law.
He's 18. He's talking about
freezing his brain,
for Christ's sakes.
He thinks he's living
in some kind of comic book.
Well, where are we with
cryonics, Sam?
I mean, is it possible
to freeze the brain?
Yeah, sort of,
but that's the easy part.
Hard part's
thawing it out again
and having it still work.
And that ain't even
close to happening.
Miss Goodwin, I need to lavage
this kid's stomach right now
or else the drugs'll
get into his bloodstream
and we'll be forced
to use supportive measures.
No, no. Mr. Shepard
has a D.N.I.
and a D.N.R., Dr. Choi.
So, unless the hospital
deems him incapable of
making an informed decision,
we have to honor his wishes.
All right, so let's
ascertain Mr. Shepard's
decisional capacity
and then go from there.
Uh, Daniel? Daniel?
Yeah.
Mr. Shepard?
Yes. I will talk to him.
How long before he starts
to lose consciousness?
Forty, 45 minutes.
Sharon, a word please.
Why is there someone
named Paula over there
saying that she's here
to shadow me?
Oh!
Maggie, I'm sorry.
I intended to speak with you
about that first.
For the next few weeks,
Paula is going to be
your new orientee.
Considering how much
you have on your plate.
Sharon, really, I feel great.
Don't you feel worn down
from your chemo?
No!
And you're happy with your
oncologist at East Mercy?
They're treating me fine,
Sharon.
And no one here
knows anything.
But if I've got someone
shadowing me around,
people here are
gonna start asking questions.
It's too late. Paula's yours.
But I just...
Humor me.
Hello, Keisha. Hi.
Hi.
I'm Dr. Manning.
I hear you hurt your leg?
She tripped and fell
carrying a cup of hot water
for me out of the microwave.
Spilled all over her leg.
I'm sorry to hear that.
How about I take
a look, all right?
All right, let's see.
Two to three percent
superficial partial thickness
on the left anterior thigh.
Mmm-hmm.
She has a second degree burn.
Oh, my God.
But it should be able
to heal on its own
without surgery,
but it will take a few weeks.
I'm gonna do a quick scrub
bedside just to
speed up the process.
Will you start her on an IV?
Is it gonna hurt her?
No.
I will give Keisha sedation.
She won't feel a thing.
Thank you for being
so still, Keisha.
You are a very brave girl.
All right,
I'll be back shortly.
Hey, good job.
Hey, guys.
Hi.
What are you doing here?
I thought you were
headed to the park?
Well, we were, but we were
putting some snacks together,
and we figured you might
get hungry, so, we thought
we'd stop by.
Whatcha got?
It's a cookie.
It's a cookie!
Aw!
Thank you.
I'm gonna eat it
with my lunch, okay?
Okay.
Well, why don't
we let Mommy
get back to work?
I'll see you.
Bye.
All right.
Let's head on out.
Oh, hey.
Don't work too hard.
You see this door?
We're gonna walk through
this door here...
Owen's getting so big.
Yeah.
Yeah, so, listen,
I've been doing some research
on post-traumatic injury
rehabilitation
and there's this computerized
training program funded
by the Pentagon
that's had some early success.
Now, it's not
on the market yet,
but Abrams says there's
a beta version upstairs
you can try out.
It might help you
get your memory back.
Keisha's ready
to be debrided.
Thanks. Will you hook her up
to the monitors
and prep her for five
milligrams of etomidate.
Mmm-hmm.
And I can forward you
the details on that program
if you like.
Sure.
This outfit that you've
contracted with, uh, CCI?
Uh-huh.
They're gonna store you
indefinitely with the hope
that in the future,
there'll be a cure
for the cancer
that you have?
Yeah.
Well, it sounds expensive.
I inherited some money
when Gramps died.
Enough to cover it.
Mmm-hmm. It is pretty
far-out stuff, Shep.
You discussed any of this
with your family?
I tried.
Yeah.
They don't...
They don't get it?
They don't understand?
Look.
You're here to determine
whether I'm sane enough
to make a decision like this,
aren't you?
Yeah.
Here's a hypothetical.
If the hospital across
the street could cure me,
wouldn't you feel ethically
compelled to send me there
for treatment?
I would.
Well, that's what I'm doing.
Sending myself to
a better hospital.
Only the hospital I'm going to
is in the future.
Have you really thought about
what that future looks like?
I mean, it won't be
recognizable. You won't
recognize yourself.
You're trading away,
potentially, a year
of your life.
I mean, that's something
priceless, for a huge unknown.
I mean,
you understand that, right?
Shep? Shep?
Look, if we're gonna
keep you alive,
if you're having
any second thoughts,
we need to know that now.
You know
the Apollo astronauts?
Those rockets were
just as likely to blow up
as they were to
propel them into space.
And the calculations made
to bring them home?
They were done
with pencil and paper.
Those astronauts had wives
and kids and lives to live.
You'd have had to been
crazy to climb into
one of those capsules,
don't you think?
So?
Finding somebody
doesn't have the capacity
to make an informed decision,
I mean, it's...
It's a high hurdle, Ethan.
He's committing suicide.
He's a danger to himself
by definition. Just put him
on a psych hold.
Yeah, but if you follow his
logic, he's... He's not
committing suicide.
He's, like, doing
precisely the opposite.
He's kinda remarkably
clear-headed about
the whole thing.
Then what about
the medications
he's taking for the GBM?
The steroids,
the anti-convulsives.
Those have been known to alter
someone's personality, right?
Yeah, but I mean, we...
We don't have a baseline
to compare it to.
A determination like that
at this point would
be entirely subjective.
His parents are on their way,
Dr. Charles.
Maybe they'll get here in time
to say goodbye to their son.
Hey, Dan. Hey, it's Caroline.
She's insistent
on having surgery.
I couldn't talk her out of it.
She's up in ortho.
Help!
My baby stopped breathing!
Oh...
Get help, we got a newborn!
Baghdad! Let's go!
On the move, excuse me!
Okay, step in,
close the glass.
Cyanotic and unresponsive.
Let's get her on the monitors
and start bagging.
Right away, Doctor.
Deep lac on
the left anterior chest.
Are you the mom?
Yes. Yes, I am.
What's your name?
Nicole. Is she gonna be okay?
Can you tell me
what happened, Nicole?
I was driving to pick up
some groceries, you know,
and all of a sudden,
the contractions started,
like out of nowhere.
Wait a second,
you were just in labor?
You delivered
the baby yourself?
In the back seat of my car.
That was an accident... I was
cutting the umbilical cord.
Can you get a line in?
I was supposed to do that,
wasn't I?
That's right.
Heart rate's coming back up.
Yeah, she's still
not breathing.
I need to intubate.
Somebody get me
a neonatal pack.
I can't believe you're even
standing. Come on,
let's get you looked at.
I'm not leaving him!
Nicole, it's a girl.
Come on. You've lost
a lot of blood.
No!
Let her stay, Sexton.
Tube.
I'm in. Bag and call
neonatology.
You got it.
Can someone get a chair
for Mom here?
I'm afraid, Mommy!
It's okay, baby.
The doctor said it wasn't
going to hurt.
That's right, Keisha.
Now, you may feel a little
drowsy from the medication.
It's okay to close your eyes
and go to sleep.
Monique?
She's a little hypotensive.
Is it okay to proceed?
BP?
Ninety-six over sixty.
That's not too low.
She's probably
just dehydrated.
Push the meds.
She's been complaining
about feeling lethargic
for a couple of weeks now.
Her pediatrician
couldn't find anything wrong.
I've been getting
on her lately,
for being so lazy.
What's going on?
She's seizing.
Mmm-hmm.
Push one of Ativan!
BP's crashing.
Sixty over forty.
Bolus 500 milliliters
of normal saline.
Keisha? Talk to me!
Ma'am?
I'm gonna need you
to move over here.
I need to intubate.
Draw up 50 of sux.
What's happening
with my little girl?
Your phone connects to the
CarePoint you're using, right?
Uh-huh.
I'm super-familiar with it.
FYI, got my MICN
certification last year.
So whenever you're
ready for me to do
an incoming call, I can...
You know what
would be really helpful?
You checking
all the drug expiration dates.
The drug expirations?
Yeah, there are dates stamped
on every package.
You can start with
the Pyxis over there,
and then of course,
all the crash carts.
Okey-dokey.
Yeah. Okey-dokey.
The girl's sedated on a vent?
Mmm-hmm.
Any idea what
caused her to crash?
Apparently, Keisha fell
when she burned herself.
Maybe she bumped her head
and caused an epidural bleed?
Well, walk me through
what you know.
Maybe I can help.
So, the mother said
Keisha ran a bit
of a fever last week.
But the pediatrician
couldn't find anything
out of the ordinary.
She was a little hypotensive
when I had Monique
push the ketamine,
but nothing to
precipitate this...
Ketamine? You mean
etomidate, right?
What?
You had Monique
push etomidate.
I heard you call it earlier.
Yeah. It's right here
in the chart.
That's strange. I don't...
I don't know how
I confused those two.
Whatever, it doesn't matter,
there's no real
clinical difference.
You feeling all right, Nat?
Any headaches or problems
concentrating...
I misspoke, Will.
Let's not make
a big deal out of it.
What did you put
in her side there?
Well, your daughter's got
a collapsed lung.
That tube's gonna
help her breathe.
So, how long
until I'll be able
to get her out of here?
It's gonna be a while.
It'll be okay.
Have you thought
of a name yet?
Not really.
Okay, you don't need
to do this right now,
but before you leave
you're gonna need to
fill out these forms,
for the birth certificate.
And we need to let
your OB know that
you delivered already.
If you give me a name...
No, I didn't really
have an OB.
I mean, I had one,
but they were all the way
across town near where
the baby's father lives,
and we recently split, so...
Oh, I'm sorry.
Here. I'll fill out
as much as I can.
Oh, your hand.
Melissa, may I have
some gauze, please?
You know, I can't do
any more than this without
getting you admitted.
It's okay, I'm all right.
You need to see a doctor,
if for no other reason
than to make sure you've
passed all your placenta.
Dr. Marcel? Isn't that right?
Please, don't separate me
from my baby.
She needs me with her.
Hey.
How about we just
get you registered?
That way we can get you
out of these clothes
and into something
more comfortable.
Then you can stay here
with your child.
Okay. Thank you.
April here will
scare you up some scrubs.
I'm sorry, Dr. Marcel?
Mmm-hmm.
She really needs
to be examined.
Oh, relax, Sexton.
We just saved a baby's life.
That's good news.
Look, something seems
off with Mom.
Why's she so resistant
to being seen by a doctor?
Who knows? Maybe she took
a little something-something
to get her through the birth
and now she's afraid
of having her baby taken away.
I don't know.
And neither do you.
But if she didn't just deliver
this baby, it's our
responsibility to find out.
Maybe we could figure out
a way to draw her blood,
check her HCG levels...
Oh!
You draw anyone's blood
without consent,
that's considered assault.
Now, I don't know about you,
but I like being a doctor.
And not going to jail.
If you won't help me,
I'll call DCFS in
to interview her.
Nicole's a righty,
by the way.
So?
So, if she actually
injured her hand while
cutting the umbilical cord,
wouldn't it more likely be
the free hand that got cut?
Hey.
So, what's up?
I understand you're
considering undergoing surgery
to repair your wrist.
Yes.
As your oncologist, I need to
strongly urge you against
that course of treatment.
That's exactly what he said.
Did you tell her to say that?
Absolutely not.
Your immune
system is profoundly
compromised by the chemo.
The risk of post-surgical
infection is very high.
I advise against
even minor surgery,
unless absolutely necessary.
This is absolutely necessary
because I'm making a Baked
Alaska for my daughter.
And I cannot do that
with, like, a cast on my hand.
Caroline, Robin would
happily celebrate
her birthday
with a supermarket cupcake
if she knew
what the risks were.
This isn't about
what Robin wants.
This is about what I want.
Why don't I give you two
some privacy?
What?
How about we just have
them put a temp cast
on it overnight.
And then we can
mull over the pluses
and the minuses...
Dr. Charles? Sorry to
interrupt, but you've been
requested down in the ED.
Yeah, they specifically asked
for you, Dr. Charles.
Go, Daniel. Go, please.
Heather?
Can you do me a favor
and please try and make sure
she does not get cleared
for surgery until I get back.
Daniel...
Please.
I just wanna make sure
she doesn't make
any rash decisions.
Thank you.
For the record,
CCI neither condones
nor endorses
the pre-emptive precipitation
of clinical death.
That said, we are
a service company...
Sure.
Hope the parents aren't
gonna be too much of
an impediment on this.
I don't wanna step on
anyone's toes here, but
time really is of the essence.
The second
he is declared dead,
we need to start.
Is this what you're using
to freeze him?
We don't freeze anyone.
We're gonna vitrify him.
We replace his blood
with a medical-grade
antifreeze.
As soon as his body temp hits
minus 124 degrees Celsius,
the body's liquid rises
so high in viscosity,
no molecule can budge.
Takes about three hours.
You paged me?
Yeah.
The parents wanted
to speak with you.
Mr. and Mrs. Shepard?
Please.
This is Dr. Charles.
Why is no one
stopping my boy
from doing this?
Todd just turned 18.
He can't make a decision
like this for himself.
He's bradying down.
What's that?
His heart stopped.
Well, do something!
I'm not legally authorized to.
Please!
We only have so much time
left with him!
Well, we're not ready
for him to die yet.
Have you noticed
any personality changes
in Shep since the diagnosis?
I don't know...
Has he been more impetuous,
stubborn, less willing
to listen to reason?
Yes, of course.
I'm deeming the patient
decisionally incapacitated.
As next of kin, you have
the right to make medical
decisions on his behalf.
Should we attempt
to resuscitate him?
Yes! Do it!
All right,
get me a crash cart.
Start bagging!
Quick-look paddles.
Hey, give us some room!
How long will he need
to stay on support?
Until the drugs work
through his system.
A few more hours at least.
Thank you, Doctor.
Sure.
Guess you guys
rushed here for nothing.
Well, transfer's already
paid for, so, we'll stand by,
if it's all the same,
just in case.
You can hang in that room
for the time being.
I didn't think you were
buying my personality
change argument.
Just erring on the side
of caution, you know?
Give everybody
a little more time.
You made the right call.
Thank you.
I hope so.
So, what?
You forbade me from
having the surgery? Really?
So we get married
and now I have to ask
for permission for stuff?
Is that right?
I wasn't...
Come here, come here.
I'm not forbidding
anything.
I just want to make sure
that we have enough time
to think this through.
I've thought about it.
I want the surgery.
For a Baked Alaska?
Yes.
Do you know how crazy
that sounds?
It's not about
the Baked Alaska.
It's about me showing love
to the people I care about
the way I want to.
Look, I know I'm not
the best cook in the world,
but I can figure out a whisk.
I'll help you.
No. No. No.
We'll do it together.
No!
Time is precious, Daniel, and
I don't wanna spend four weeks
not being able to use my hand.
You knew who I was when
you signed on for this.
You knew who I was.
No, this isn't what I signed
up for. You being reckless
with your health.
That wasn't the deal.
There's too much
to lose here.
I think you're being
a little selfish.
So, now I'm being selfish.
Really?
I mean,
I just found you again.
I wanna have as much time
with you as possible.
And I'm kinda hoping
you feel the same way.
I do, but you know what?
This is my choice.
Period. You hear that?
Period.
I tried to get her to let us
examine her, but she refused,
and given the circumstances
of the delivery...
No. You did the right thing
calling Child Services, April.
It's what we're here for.
Excuse me. Miss Burke?
Nicole?
Hey, Nicole,
you gotta wake up.
We need to ask you
a few questions.
She was feeling pretty
anxious about her baby,
so, I gave her Ativan.
Should wear off
in an hour or so.
Melissa, will you notify us
when she wakes up?
Of course.
Thank you.
I cannot believe
that you would
undermine me like that.
Excuse me?
You knew I was
calling DCFS in
to talk to her.
You sedated her on purpose.
Please.
You know what, you don't
wanna help? Fine. Just do me
a favor, stay out of my way.
Goodwin got you a lackey?
What'd you do
to get such special treatment?
I'm just training her, Doris.
It's not permanent.
That's not what I heard.
Huh.
Good thing I checked these.
Look how many
had almost expired.
You know, if you want, I could
rework things moving forward.
Great.
So what's next?
Actually, I'd love
a cup of coffee.
Okay, I'll run down
to the cafeteria.
I prefer Dark Matter coffee.
There's one about
twelve blocks from here.
Why don't you go get me
a red eye and get yourself
whatever you want.
Thanks. I'll be back
in a jiff.
Hey, uh, Keisha's father,
Darrell, arrived.
Had a lot of questions.
I know. I need to
go talk to them.
I'm not avoiding them. I just
don't have the answers yet.
What'd her CT show?
Came back negative. No bleed.
Bloodwork?
Glucose and sodium
are a little low,
but otherwise normal.
I'm gonna do an LP,
make sure we're not looking
at something like meningitis.
Are you sure that's necessary?
Is she spiking a fever?
Well, not today, but her mom
said she was last week,
so, I gotta check it
off my list.
Hey, you want me
to take over Keisha for you?
What? Why?
It's... Nat,
it's been a long week.
You know, and you were
out of action for a while.
I'd understand if you're
feeling a little rusty.
Maybe you should look
into that program
I mentioned earlier...
This is because I misspoke,
isn't it?
You are fixated
on me getting my memory back.
Why?
Nat, I just want you
to get better.
Nah, I don't think that's it.
I think it's about you.
You want me to remember why
I came to see you that night,
so that maybe I'll...
...tell you something
you wanna hear.
Natalie, no...
Stop it.
I am fine.
And I don't appreciate
you talking
to Dr. Abrams about
my health behind my back.
Monique. Will you prep
Keisha for an LP?
Okay.
Thanks.
Actually, Monique,
hold off on that.
I didn't want to have to
tell you this, but I'm
taking over the patient.
The parents have
lost confidence in you.
They brought their daughter in
to have a burn looked at,
and now she's in a coma.
Will, please don't do this.
I'm sorry, they want you
off the case.
Juliette!
Twenty-three-year-old female,
found down, intubated
in the field,
18 gauge in the left arm.
She's eviscerated.
Baghdad!
Bowels wrapped in
moist saline gauze.
She's gotten 500 mils
of crystalloid.
Let's go, everybody.
Let's go, let's go!
All right. On my count.
One, two, three.
Get her on the monitors.
Heart rate's 130.
BP's 72 over 44.
Trigger the MTP.
Open the hybrid room.
I got you.
Open the hybrid.
Oh, man,
her uterus is cut wide open.
Looks like she was pregnant.
Wait, what? Where's the baby?
Where's this woman's baby?
There was no baby on-site.
It had to have been Nicole.
Okay. Okay, this woman
who did this,
her name is Nicole Burke,
she is in the NICU right now
with the baby.
Come on, I'll show you.
Stop!
Let the police do their job,
Sexton! Come here
and help me retract.
You have to go up there
fast! Oh, my God.
I need some more
lab sponges.
Yes, Doctor.
So, what do you think?
Can we save the uterus?
I don't know.
It's looking
pretty ratty.
Even if we can fix it,
she'd run the risk
of it rupturing with
a future pregnancy.
I'd just do
a hysterectomy.
Well, she's only 23,
and I'm not sure
her baby's gonna survive.
I'm gonna try and save it.
I'll go scrub, but for
the record, this is against
my better judgment.
You scrubbing in or not, Mags?
I'm coming!
Oh, uh... Hey, Maggie,
are you all right?
Should I jump in? I'm...
I'm certified.
I'm fine.
Why does this
keep happening?
The drugs he took
are making his heart stop
and until they clear
his system...
Feels like only yesterday
we were waiting
to see what college
he would get into and...
Now?
We just couldn't let him
go through with
that plan of his, you know?
The...
The thought of his head just
floating in a canister
in a warehouse somewhere...
Shep told me that he tried
to talk to you two
about this, is that right?
Yeah.
I don't know
if it's any comfort,
but I was genuinely impressed
with how much thought
that he had put into this,
and how much sense
that it made to him.
Please, Dr. Charles,
tell us what we're missing.
Miss Shepard, I've been
doing this for a while.
And on a good day,
I'm just starting to think
I might be learning my way
around the human mind.
But trying to...
To fathom the thinking of
someone who's confronting
their own mortality?
Unless you're the one
who's looking down
that tunnel,
I just... I don't know
if it's possible.
I think what we need to do
is try and listen,
understand and respect
that it's their journey
to... To go on alone.
They got his heart back
in rhythm. You should
go be with him.
What we need to do?
You give us the power
to make a decision and
then judge us for making it?
Mr. Shepard, believe me,
I'm... I'm not
judging anybody.
Anyone from rheumatology
showed up yet?
No.
Lean on them, okay?
And run another set of labs.
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, hey, there. Again.
Hi, Owen.
Hi, Will.
After we got done
in the park,
we went to the movies,
and then we figured we would
come here and wait for Mommy.
Hey, Phillip...
Yeah?
Not so sure this is the best
place for kids, you know?
Some scary stuff happens here,
and maybe they can't unsee.
Oh, yeah. That's a good point.
Um...
There we go.
Now there's nothing
to unsee, right?
We told your supervisor
we didn't want you treating
our daughter anymore...
I know, I just need
to check one last thing.
Dr. Manning?
I'll have to ask you
to stay away
from this patient.
I was wrong. Okay?
Etomidate and ketamine
are not just
the same thing.
A big difference is that
etomidate unmasks adrenal
insufficiencies...
While ketamine doesn't.
Yes.
Do you see the pigment spots
on Keisha's foot?
They are a sign that
her adrenal glands are
not producing enough cortisol.
100 milligrams of
hydrocortisone.
I don't understand.
Cortisol helps the body
handle stress.
In its absence,
even the stress of
being examined by a doctor
was enough to plummet Keisha
into a coma.
BP's improving.
Her color's coming back.
She's trying to
open her eyes!
Oh, my baby girl...
She's super-cold.
I'm having trouble
keeping her pressure up.
You need to pack her up
now and get out.
Told you it wasn't worth it.
Knot and I'm done.
You're pushing it,
Dr. Marcel.
And there. Done.
Looks better than I thought.
Let's temp-close
and get her upstairs.
Open up a vac sponge.
Maggie?
I need to take a minute.
Mags.
Sexton, scrub in!
Hey.
If you need to go home early,
I'm more than willing
to cover for you.
You cover for me?
Your first day?
A little constructive
criticism, Paula,
you have an insanely
inflated sense of
your own capabilities.
"You know, I'm certified
doing this. I did
my dissertation on that."
Please!
I'm...
Get out.
I'm sorry, but I refuse
to be spoken to like that.
Is she gonna make it?
Yeah, she lost a lot of blood,
but, yeah, I'm hopeful.
Do we know any more
about what happened?
The victim's name
is Louisa Nash.
She and the assailant
were co-workers.
This morning,
Miss Burke invited Louisa over
to give her
some old baby clothes.
When her guard was down,
she chloroformed her
and forcibly removed the baby.
Who would ever do
something like that?
She lost her son
recently to leukemia.
Maybe she had some sort of
mental breakdown?
I don't know.
We were lucky and
we got an anonymous tip
about Miss Burke.
And that helped us
find Louisa in time.
Suspect's hand
needs dressing.
Is that something
you can do here?
I got it.
Take care of my baby, okay?
Tell him I'll come for him
as soon as I can.
It's getting to be
a bit of a circus.
Gwen? Gwen?
Excuse me?
Here. I'll take you
out the back way.
What's going on?
They're withdrawing support.
My wife and I decided
we're going to honor
our son's wishes.
This way, maybe, someday,
we'll get our son back.
Time of death, 19:42.
So, I'm thinking
this might have
been precipitated
by some kind
of underlying cause.
Maybe Addison's Disease?
I'm gonna have endocrinology
come down and see her.
I thought it was clear
I was gonna be the primary.
I'm sorry, but once I realized
what caused her to crash,
I had to act quickly.
I mean, Keisha
could have died.
Oh, my ride's here.
Adrenal crisis should have
been on your differential
from the start.
It was an odd presentation.
Or you just weren't
thinking straight.
I'm gonna want to oversee
all your cases moving forward,
until we know for sure
your TBI isn't adversely
affecting your patients.
Are you serious?
There's nothing wrong with me.
You don't have the authority.
I was hoping
we could do this off-book.
If not, we can formalize it
with Lanik and Goodwin.
I'm happy to talk to them.
Natalie,
it's for your own protection.
Why do I feel like
you're punishing me
for something else?
Hi, come here.
So, you ready to go?
Yeah.
Yes.
Louisa? Can you open
your eyes for me?
Hey.
You're at Gaffney Chicago
Medical Center, in the ICU.
You sustained some injuries
that required us
to perform extensive surgery,
but you are okay.
Would you like to
meet your baby girl?
Uh-huh.
Here she is.
We got lucky, the police
finding her in time.
Can I trust you
to keep a secret?
Yeah. What?
You know how that monster
was so antsy to
get out of here earlier?
Mmm-hmm.
Well, Dr. Marcel gave her
enough Ativan
to knock her out,
and while she was,
he drew some blood
and had her HCG levels checked
to see if she really
delivered that baby.
What?
You can't tell anyone, April.
Crockett could get fired.
He's such a badass.
Do you know
if he's seeing
anybody?
No, I don't.
Paula quit?
Yeah. She said,
and I quote,
"the ED wasn't a healthy
environment" for her.
You know, I had a feeling
that she couldn't cut it.
You chased her off, Maggie.
And I told you
that I don't need the help.
You're being stubborn.
I have a hospital to run.
So, if you don't want us
to treat you medically,
then you're getting help.
April?
Yeah.
Thank you for scrubbing in
for me today.
Yeah.
I'd like to start
training you to take over
the position formally.
Sure, of course.
It'll help me take some stuff
off my plate.
Does that mean
I'd be working
with Dr. Marcel?
Is that a problem?
No.
Start tomorrow?
Okay.
Thank you.
Do you really think
I'll get better care here
than at East Mercy?
Yeah.
Hey.
Why didn't you wait for me?
Because you were
still on rounds.
And Sharon offered me
a ride home.
How did your, um...
How'd your surgery go?
I didn't get it.
You didn't?
No.
They're gonna check my wrist
again in four weeks
to see if I still need a cast.
Let me get that for you.
You best not mess up
my Baked Alaska.
No, ma'am.