In 2023, a team of
scientists studying hepatitis C
made a fascinating discovery...
Complications include
blood clots, bleeding,
leaking from or blockage of
the ureter tract and...
Still studying for
the kidney transplant.
I want to be ready.
You've been studying
all night.
You're probably
over prepped.
No such thing.
Going in early again?
This doesn't have anything to do
with that mystery woman
who stayed in your bed
and followed you
around the hospital,
does it?
Nope. Just trying
to stay ahead.
Whoever's ready
can ride it with me.
I'll come.
We'll catch up.
They found that the virus
creates a "cellular mask"
to hide from our immune system
in plain sight.
When you said
you wanted to...
do something
with just the two of us...
I, um, I was expecting
something else.
Like what?
We've gone four blocks.
I know, I just -- I...
I need oxygen.
I need...
Yeah, that.
Yeah, I needed that.
Shall we keep going?
Camouflaged in molecules
already known to our bodies,
the virus copies itself
over and over.
Uh, you're not hitting
the gym this morning?
I thought I'd help you
out of the clinic
before my interview
with Heron.
Oh, I, um...
I've got some business
at the hospital this morning.
Hey, wanna meet for lunch?
It's taco day
at the cafeteria.
I don't feel like tacos.
You love tacos.
Too damn busy for tacos.
It sneaks in like a Trojan
horse past our immune system.
And by the time the body
realizes what's happened,
the infection
has already taken hold.
Why don't you just ask him?
Because
Webber doesn't want to
assist on
a kidney transplant.
He doesn't want to assist
on anything.
But you said
it'll be interesting.
For the interns.
Not for Webber.
What's this actually about?
Hmm?
I just thought
it would be nice
if the two of you
worked together.
Mer, come on. What's up?
I'm doing a liver biopsy
on Catherine today.
Her cancer may have spread.
And, uh...
he doesn't know,
does he?
I tried to
get her to tell him.
She doesn't want to.
I can't believe
you're doing this.
Breaking HIPAA?
No, making me
an accomplice.
Oh, what could go wrong?
What could go wrong?
I love you.
You know, some people
think you'll go to hell
if you swipe left
on a chaplain.
Oh, I, um...Hey.
I -- I'm sorry.
I was kidding.
I was just trying to get
to the -- the news on there,
and then my finger accidentally
opened up that app, so...
- Morning.
- Oops.
Thanks, Jacob.
Someone's a little hungry.
Oh, I like to
have extra treats
to hand out to the nurses.
That's really kind.
Yeah, well,
don't want to go to hell.
Again, kidding.
- Okay.
- ...in the morning,
so then I switched that
to Saturday at 2:00 p.m.,
and there was something else.
Oh, I, uh, I scheduled
our OB appointment
at Seattle Presbyterian.
Sure.
Why take
an elevator upstairs
when you can cross town
in traffic?
The minute people here
find out that I'm pregnant,
they'll treat me differently.
Like letting you sit down?
Giving you time to sleep?
No, like...not giving me
the good cases
or thinking I'm
not committed to the job.
It's your call...
Okay.
...but if I had a vagina, I'd
want Carina DeLuca all over it.
Came out way worse
than it sounded in my --
Yeah.
Hi. Oh. I'm sorry.
This is the best
that I could do.
But, hey, look,
you got a new microscope.
I've been using it
to look for the bright side,
but so far no luck.
Well, I have put your name
on a wait list for another lab.
I don't know what
I'll be doing there anyway.
Meredith hasn't exactly
filled me in
on the next steps
for our research.
I have an idea
to keep you busy today.
A hemangioblastoma
on the thoracic spine.
I can see that.
The patient's upstairs.
If you want her case,
it's yours.
Were you hoping
that I wouldn't notice
she's 20 weeks pregnant?
I mean, she needs to
terminate that pregnancy
before I can operate
on that tumor.
She wants to keep it,
and four other neurosurgeons
have turned her down.
Will you
just meet with her?
Uh...
Unless you're too busy?
Yeah, right.
Dr. Heron? I'm Ben Warren.
Oh, Dr. Warren --
the firefighting
anesthesiologist, yes?
I guess.
Uh, I know I'm a couple minutes
early for my interview...
Yeah, you're four hours early,
and I have two lap choles,
so I know that
your Dr. Bailey's husband,
but I -- No, I cannot shuffle
my schedule around for you.
I say no-no to nepo, right?
I --
So 1:00, coffee cart. Yeah?
Okay. See you there.
Good morning! Who is ready
to see what today holds?
That's why we're waiting here.
Oh, great! Okay.
Oh. Kwan.
I'm afraid I have
some traumatic news.
You are with Hunt
in the ER.
Get it? Trauma?
I-I'm just happy
for the work.
Oh, and, Millin, any guesses
where "I'll see you"?
Please don't.
That's right, the ICU.
Okay, okay.
Griffith,
you're with Webber,
and Adams is on Marsh's
kidney transplant.
Oh, I think I'm with Marsh.
Actually, Dr. Marsh
requested Adams.
And, Yasuda,
you're with Shepherd.
Unless you want to
keep playing telephone.
Shepherd? Got it.
Then let's get out there
and...?
Heal with love.
Yes!
You okay?
Yeah. I'm fine.
Can you pass me my tablet?
I need to watch
the weather report.
Donna Mae, you know
you can't go outside.
I know, but I just
want to see Victor Suarez.
He's so handsome,
and he's always accurate.
If he says it's gonna rain,
it rains.
I'm so sorry I'm late.
I had to stop at the peds floor
for your pudding.
You are forgiven.
Donna Mae Clarkson, 82.
Status post-CABG
two months ago. History of TIA.
Congestive heart failure
with EF of 25%.
On levophed, an insulin drip,
dialysis three
times a week, and you...
don't have
an advanced directive.
No, dear, but thank you.
If you can't make your
own medical decisions
with no advanced directive,
we'd have to assume
that if you got sicker
than you already are,
you'd want us to use all
available life-saving measures.
It could be very uncomfortable.
I understand,
but if it means staying alive,
I choose quantity over quality.
Now, pass me that tablet
and the puddings.
Here.
Meredith,
what brings you here?
A patient consultation.
Oh, well, I was hoping
you were here to see Catherine.
She hasn't been acting
like herself lately.
She won't say it, but I think
your rift is eating away at her.
I don't know what to say.
Oh, I know there are
bad feelings,
but if you could reach
out to her, I'd be grateful.
I think about it.
Nice of you to show up.
Nice of you
to tell your husband.
You know --
Uh, both of you play nice.
The only enemy in here today
is cancer.
BP is 110 over 60.
Okay.
Do you have any tingling
or numbness in your legs?
No numbness.
They just get we.
Ms. Fletcher,
this is Dr. Shepherd.
She is chief
of our neurosurgery,
and she's looked over
your scans.
Rhiannon.
This is my brother Julian
and his husband, Carl.
They...
have a vested interest.
This is their baby.
I'm their surrogate.
We have a vested interest
because you're my sister.
He's lovable,
but annoyingly smothering.
So you can just ignore him.
Please say you're here to tell
me you can do the surgery
without affecting the baby.
Rhiannon, your pregnancy
hormones have caused
the tumor
to grow more rapidly.
Removing it would
already be a challenge,
but pregnant at 20 weeks, the
risk is exponentially higher.
Access to the tumor
is limited,
and there's a higher risk
of bleeding and clots.
What about waiting a few weeks
until my OB can deliver
the baby safely?
It's possible,
but it's not guaranteed.
If you don't
remove the tumor now,
the pressure on your spinal cord
could paralyze you
or the tumor could rupture,
causing catastrophic bleeding.
Your best option
is to terminate.
No.
Rhi, we said
we could adopt.
You and I are adopted.
I want to do this.
I'll do anything.
I'll sign a waiver.
No, you won't.
End of discussion.
Three different egg donors,
six retrievals,
eight transfers
between different surrogates
and the last embryo,
the one that worked for you,
is this one.
So before immediately deciding
what my "best" option would be,
take another look.
Let's get some more scans.
No promises,
but I will take another look.
Thank you.
Alright.
Dr. Hunt.
Hmm?
I am on your service
and ready for anything.
GSWs, 20-car pileups.
Whatever you need.
Just keep me busy and elbows
deep and whatever you got.
Music to my ears.
Ronald Meinero,
this is Dr. Kwan.
Ronald broke two ribs
this morning.
Were you attacked?
Yeah, by my own ass
and gravity.
I'm recovering
from hemorrhoid surgery.
Slipped gettin'
out of the sitz bath.
Ronald needs incentive
spirometer exercises,
10 times every hour,
okay?
Watch him,
and let me know the results.
Hey, boss.
Hello, Marsh.
You're here with Meredith?
No, I'm here to do
a kidney transplant.
I thought you might
want to assist.
Well, I think I'll pass.
But maybe one of our interns
might get a kick out of it.
Well, listen,
there's actually
a groundbreaking angle
to this one.
Yeah, it's only been done
one time before in the US.
Come on. I'll walk you
through the case.
See if you
change your mind.
I'm all ears.
Let's go.
What is taking so long?
Uh, we don't exactly do a lot
of liver biopsies in the clinic.
Oh, well...thank you
for protecting my privacy.
Richard is distracted
for at least an hour.
I had Nick invite him
onto his kidney transplant.
He knows to text me
when they're done.
God...
You told Marsh?
Do you want to risk
Richard walking in here?
A lied about tacos.
I don't know what that means,
but gallbladder looks good.
No fluid around the liver.
There's a lesion here
on the periphery.
Mm-hmm.
Looks like a good target
for the biopsy.
Okay, now, Catherine,
before we drape and prep you,
you sure you don't want
to reconsider telling Richard?
I think I want to reconsider
my surgical team.
It's a biopsy, ladies.
I tell Richard when
there's something to tell.
Will y'all just get
the damn thing started?
Come on.
He requested me.
I know.
What'd you want me to do? Say,
"No, my girlfriend wants that"?
You know I stayed up half the
night studying for that surgery.
Maybe you shouldn't have.
Says the Shepherd.
What?
I need to finish up
Webber's notes.
If it were you, you would
have taken it in a heartbeat.
Griffith, change of plans.
You and I are scrubbing in on
a transplant with Dr. Marsh.
Meet me in OR 1.
Chop, chop.
Is there
another surgical option?
I don't see one.
Is that her diaphragm?
Yeah. The pregnancy shifted
her internal organs up.
Makes the tumor harder
to access.
What if you embolize
the feeders to the tumor
to stop it from growing?
It's too late.
Even though it's benign,
the tumor is big enough
to be a risk.
There's no good alternative.
Well, anyone who's gone to
four different surgeons
isn't looking for
a second opinion.
If we say no, she's just gonna
try to go to someone else.
Tom. Big day.
How are you feeling?
Mm
anxious.
I'm much happier serving
the OR table than being on it.
I'm a scrub nurse
at Hope General.
Are you not gonna intubate
him first?
No. Not today.
Uh, let me present --
Tom Costello, 33,
here for a kidney transplant
without
general anesthesia.
An awake surgery?
It was in the pre-op file.
Under "Awake Surgery."
He's been given a mild sedative
and a spinal anesthesia.
Okay, so what are the benefits
of an awake surgery?
Uh...
Forgoing
traditional anesthesia
can expedite recovery
as well as reduce
one's hospital stay,
which ultimately could
save the healthcare system
billions.
Nice, Griffith.
And I can keep an eye
on my surgical team.
Is he prepared?
Um, Dr. Adams
is -- is new to the case,
but I assure you,
he's a quick study.
Mm.
Okay. You ready?
Uh, how many Raytecs
have you opened up?
10.
Uh, go ahead.
Okay. 10-blade.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Are you sure everything
has been sterilized well enough?
We got you. You can relax.
Alright, here we go.
10-blade.
Thank you.
Still no advance directive?
Nope.
And the more I go in there,
I feel like a restaurant host
just trying to free up a table.
I don't want her thinking we're
trying to push a DNR on her.
Well, we're not.
You just need to
make sure
she clearly understands
what she's facing.
Did you explain that life-saving
measures can be invasive?
I use the word "violent."
That's an understatement.
Well, no matter
how old you are,
no one likes to think about
their own death.
So...give her a minute.
Some patients just take
a little longer
to listen to their doctors.
I wonder if she
would listen to someone else.
Knock, knock.
I don't know
why I said "knock, knock"
as opposed to
just knocking.
That's okay.
It's a great office.
Uh, it's the chapel.
Right.
It's got good light.
Windows will do that, so...
Uh, we're here, um,
about a patient.
It's an elderly woman.
She has multiple comorbidities,
and she's refusing
to sign a DNR.
Okay, she has had
multiple surgical
and medical interventions,
and another intervention would
probably do more harm than good.
So you're asking me to talk
her into signing the DNR?
I...no. No.
Absolutely not. Um...
But chest compressions
on an octogenarian
with bones like toothpicks...
it could kill her.
At the very least,
uh, her ribs would snap
and one could puncture lung,
and then we would
have to intubate her.
Yeah, really,
this is not what I do.
Um, my comfort zone is
a little more,
you know, "Am I gonna
see my dog when I die?"
I -- I think
that she's struggling
with her own mortality,
and I thought that
you might be able to help
her understand her options.
- Dr. Hunt?
- Yeah?
I just finished
another session
of spirometer exercises
with Ronald
and discharged bed 2.
Great.
If you need me anywhere else,
I can handle multiple cases.
Well, we have
a scalp lac in bed 1.
Yeah, I'll take a look.
Um...
I am interested in exploring
trauma as a specialty,
and I would love to work
on...bigger traumas.
Ah.
Kwan, traumas are traumas.
It doesn't matter
if they're caused by gunshots
or wildfires
or falls in the bathtub.
Ronald babysits
his granddaughter every Tuesday,
and he is a ping pong legend
in Washington state
and he wants to get back
to both of those things
as soon as possible.
Carla, in bed 1, she
split her head open
sliding in to home plate,
but she's excited to play in
the state semifinals next week.
They're all counting on you
to help them.
But if they're
not exciting enough for you,
then...
I'll go check on them.
I think that's a good idea.
No one can accuse you
of having a dull career.
Well, I've tried to
follow my heart.
Aww. Isn't that sweet?
You know, I'm more of
a "dance with the one
that brung ya" kind of gal.
You know,
jack of all trades is great
if you want a job
at TaskRabbit,
but -- but for a surgeon?
I think you'll find
that I'm a very good surgeon.
Oh. Okay.
"Enthusiastically
recommends...himself."
In addition to my four years
as a general surgery resident,
I was a firefighter for five and
an anesthesiologist for seven.
Mm-hmm.
When I set my mind
to something, I master it.
Right.
But what happens when the next
shiny object comes along?
I --
You gonna leave me
high and dry?
No. I wo--
Surgery, it's a calling.
It requires patience,
commitment, stick-to-itiveness.
If I may be frank, I...
I'm not sure you have
what it takes.
You want commitment?
I've carried people
down 10 flights of stairs
wearing
75 pounds of gear.
You want patience?
I convinced a hopeless teen
to step away from the ledge.
Stick-to-itiveness?
I've been happily married
for 12 years,
and I have three children that
I love more than any career.
So if you don't want to bring
me back, I'll be fine.
Thank you for your time.
You're saying
you can do it?
I'm saying I'll try.
Because I think you are someone
who doesn't like
to hear no for an answer.
And so am I.
I told you.
You wanted to give up.
I told you it was possible.
Now, I didn't say that.
I don't know if it is.
This surgery will increase
the risk to yourself.
And we don't know
that we can save the pregnancy.
If there are
any complications,
I will put
your life and health first.
I still don't feel good
about this.
I don't either.
I want to do this.
Okay. Dr. Yasuda will admit
and prep you,
and we will see you
in the OR.
Okay, Catherine, I'm going in,
so you may feel some pressure.
I'm good under pressure.
And you better be, too.
Good hemostasis.
Put a rush on that,
and, uh, be discreet.
Oh! Damn it!
She's hemorrhaging.
Okay.
She's bleeding
from her esophagus.
Let's get her on her side.
Suction!
Hold on, Catherine.
Nurse Linda,
let's hang a unit of blood.
I'm gonna get
the intubation tray.
You're gonna set up
an EGD
and let the IR suite know
we are on our way.
On it.
Alright.
We need to put in a shunt.
Okay.
This is more than a biopsy.
And what are you saying?
I'm saying that even
if we stop the bleeding,
she could go into
liver failure.
She might never wake up
from this.
Richard needs to know.
Okay.
Okay, it's in.
Adams.
Let's see what you got.
Uh, can we pause for
a needle and sponge count?
Okay, we already did one.
We'll do another one
before we're close.
Okay.
Can't be too careful.
Last month,
a patient went septic
after the surgeons left
a lap pad in her abdomen.
Okay. Bokhee,
can you count, please?
One, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight, nine --
10. We're good.
Great.
Oh, shoot.
Griffith, can you --
Check the phone
while Adams sutures? Sure.
Yeah.
It's Dr. Grey
paging Dr. Webber.
Well, she doesn't know
I got pulled into a surgery.
I'll check in with her later.
It says 911.
You should go.
No, no, no, no,
no one should leave.
Now, look,
I'm sure it can wait.
How many cc's of blood
have I lost?
Richard, you need to go.
It's your wife.
Meredith is doing
a procedure on her.
You need to go.
- Where is she?
- IR suite.
Make sure to stay upright.
Very good. Good job.
What have we got?
I'd be better at this
if I played the tuba
instead of ping pong.
Let's get him inside. Let's go.
Okay. Car flipped over
the median, GCS 7.
He was intubated in the field.
Vitals are unstable.
We might have to take
him directly up to the OR.
Kwan. Trauma one.
Okay. Keep going, Ronald.
I'll be right back.
Dr. Yasuda.
Orderlies are on their way
to bring your sister
to the OR.
Thanks, but that's
not what I...
Do you have siblings?
Yeah, I have eight.
I just have Rhi.
When Carl and I first started
looking for a surrogate,
she insisted that
no one would take better care
of the baby
than Auntie Rhi.
I said no, but after
all the failed attempts,
she offered again
and she was so determined
that I didn't fight it.
Then they found the tumor.
Am I gonna regret
not fighting it now?
I don't really know,
but, um...
Dr. Shepherd and Dr. Altman
are both excellent.
Aren't you a doctor?
You must have an opinion.
I...I wish I could tell you
it'll be fine,
but I just, I don't know.
I'm sorry.
We have 500 cc's of
blood in the NG canister.
Advancing the guidewire
I'm in
the right hepatic vein.
Aim anteriorly.
What happened?
We were doing
a liver biopsy.
She started bleeding.
So you do a TIPS procedure?
I'm about to
put in the shunt.
- Is she in liver failure?
- Not yet.
We're trying
to prevent that.
She wanted to get
the results of the biopsy
before she told you.
Take care of her.
I'll be waiting outside.
Okay, Tom,
we're almost done here.
Uh, can we do
a final count?
Yep. You got it.
Go ahead, Bokhee.
I don't hear counting.
It's 'cause
it's in our heads.
Are you sure
that the kidney is pink?
Tom, how many kidney transplants
have you done?
None! But I have seen so m--
Well, I've done more than 600,
and I've had one done myself,
so I get it's unnerving
being on the table,
but everything is under control.
Okay? We got you.
Okay.
Okay. Looks good.
What?
We're missing a Raytec.
Let's count one more time.
Okay.
Well, my faith
is based on a belief
that God doesn't
abandon me in death,
w-which I personally find
comforting.
Good for you.
O-Of course, you know,
everyone has their own
relationship with death.
It's okay and
perfectly natural to fear it.
Not me.
I'm not afraid of death
or -- or hell
or coming back as a bird.
Well, we're not encouraging you
to sign the DNR.
We just want to make sure
that you understand
what not signing it
would mean for you when --
For the last time,
I know what it means.
And I know
why I'm not signing it.
I refuse to die before
my bastard ex-husband.
I'm gonna outlive that SOB
if it's literally
the last thing I do.
Uh, it seems like
you could use some closure.
Hell, yes!
Closure on his casket
before it clicks shut
so I can dance on it.
I did not
see this coming.
Not a chance.
Things they don't teach you
in divinity school.
Well, they don't really
teach it in medical school,
either.
Oh! Victor Suarez.
Margins look good.
I've got
proximal control.
Yasuda, suction.
I've got distal control.
We've lost neuro signal
to the legs.
We need to get more
blood flow to her spinal cord.
- Bolus her with 500 cc's of LR.
- On it.
Anything?
No, and
we don't have time
to wait for it to kick in.
Start her on pressors.
Late decels. The pressors
are decreasing blood
flow to the baby.
Still no signal.
Go up on the pressors.
Give the fluids
a chance to work.
Mom's life and health first.
I know it may take
a few seconds.
Rhiannon's spinal cord
may not have a few seconds.
Doctors...
Hold off. If you don't stop,
the baby will die.
Go up on the pressors. I am
the primary surgeon on th--
Just stop!
This is a human being
on the table.
She is someone's daughter,
someone's sister.
She's counting on us
to save her
and ideally the baby,
to stop arguing
like she's some kind of
science experiment!
Just figure out what you do
and do it!
We've got blood flow
to the spinal cord.
Decels stopped.
Sinus rhythm's back to normal.
Thank God.
But, Yasuda...
Yep. I'll see myself out.
Do you see it?
No, I don't see it.
It doesn't mean
it's not still in him.
Are you whispering?
No. Sorry, Tom.
It's just a bit of a frog
in my throat.
Search
everywhere. Search the
field, search the floor.
We cannot close
until we find it.
Back table.
Sir? You okay?
I'm really not.
I am trying to trust you,
but I know the sounds
of the instruments
when they hit the tray.
I listen for them
so I can count.
Yeah.
Easy. That was a hemostat.
But the sponges --
the sponges
don't make any sounds.
You're doing great. We're
almost there. Hang in there.
That's septic patient that
I was telling you about.
Mm-hmm?
I was the one
who miscounted the lap pads.
And I am always so careful.
So if it could happen to me...
It -- It happens.
Nobody's perfect.
Deep breaths. Okay?
Why are you staring at me?
I'm not. Dr. Marsh.
What?
Find the damn thing.
Dr. Marsh. It's --
It's stuck to your shoe.
Thank you. Okay.
The, uh, the anastomosis
is complete.
We have 10 Raytecs accounted
for. We're ready to close.
Dr. Griffith, why don't you
take the lead?
Absolutely.
Are you sure you
don't want to do it yourself?
Tom.
Sorry.
Reese and I met
working in his father's
furniture store.
On slow days, we'd sit
on the showroom couches,
laughing and talking.
Oh, that sounds nice.
Oh, it was.
Then we got married,
and everything went to hell.
Our first fight was during the
wedding, and it never stopped.
The only good thing that
came out of that relationship
was my sleeper sofa.
Mrs. Clarkson,
we have some news.
We found your ex-husband.
Is he living
with that rat Sheila?
He was living at
the Oceanfront
Assisted Living Facility.
Oh.
But a couple of months ago,
he passed away.
Donna Mae,
how are you feeling?
Oh!
I know it sounds crazy,
but I'm gonna miss
that...horse's ass.
I'll sign that DNR now.
How are you holding up?
Bailey send you?
Uh, yeah.
You know,
at the fire academy,
there was a, uh,
a "burn building"
where they would simulate
structure fires.
It's, uh, it's our first time
dealing with the heat,
Smoke, the gear.
It's intense.
Pretty scary.
And it wasn't even
the real thing.
But the scariest part
wasn't the fire.
It was...It was not
being able to see my team
through the smoke and chaos,
and somehow...
...there was nothing
more terrifying than...
just that...
that feeling
of being alone.
Is there a point
to this story?
Not really.
Did the biopsy
go smoothly?
Um, if by smoothly
you mean
having to convert to an EGD
and TIPS procedure,
then, yes,
it went very smoothly.
Did you hear
from pathology yet?
Not yet.
But for now, you're alive.
And also your...husband is
outside waiting to see you.
You told him?
It...became more than
just a biopsy.
I understand.
Thank you.
I'm sorry, what?
Thank you, Dr. Bailey.
I know I've been stubborn
and very difficult, and...
But you are a big part of
what makes this hospital great,
and you -- you
should always be here.
Is that you give me my job back?
Don't make me
say it twice.
Oh!
Ohh.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, yes. Okay.
So she's gonna be okay?
She had some blood loss,
but I was able to
remove the tumor,
and she and the baby
are both okay.
Oh, my God, she was right.
She said you could do it.
And she was right.
Thank you.
I can't tell you how
much this means to all of us.
Well, we'll check on her
in the morning.
I'm sorry if I seemed
mistrustful earlier, I just...
I'm her older brother.
I've always watched out for her,
and I felt helpless.
I get it.
My brother...
...he watched out for me,
too.
Meredith, you looked me
in the eye
and you lied.
I'm sorry.
It was hard enough to get
her to agree to do the biopsy.
I'm sure you can relate.
How long have you known?
What does that have
to do with anything?
Do you know how many times
I've stood up for you?
How many times
I've defended you, Meredith?
I tried to
get her to tell you.
And you don't think I would've
been able to handle it?
I think she was scared.
That's exactly
why you should have
told me.
Shame on you.
Dictate the operative
report,and then check his
H and H before you go.
You got it.
Good work today.
So, are you still thinking
about going into trauma?
Yeah. I like
the variety of patients.
Listen, some days are
slower than others,
but most days there is
something interesting.
I don't know if I want to be
the guy waiting
around hoping for
a car wreck.
A man was in a medically
induced coma from a brain bleed.
His life will never
be the same.
His loved ones will
never be the same.
Oh, and, uh, Robertson is gonna
take over the post-op care.
But if there are signs of early
graft rejection, I want to know.
Okay.
Okay?
Excellent work today.
Thanks.
I heard you're
repeating intern year.
Yep. Yeah.
12 more months
of following orders
and barely
getting to operate.
Well, I don't -- I don't think
that's such a bad thing.
Internships should be two years,
18 months minimum.
We expect you to learn
too much, too fast.
You're gonna be more prepared.
You don't think
I'll lose ground?
If you wanna
keep leveling up,
you work with people
that make you better.
Like Griffith.
She's good. You stick
with her, you'll be fine.
Congrats on Rhiannon.
Such a victory.
Well, it's a team effort.
You took the lead.
Just say thanks.
Thanks.
So I was catching up
on some admin work,
and these are charts of
15 patients similar to Rhiannon,
and they all asked
to see you.
15 pregnant women
with spinal tumors?
Patients with seemingly
impossible cases
who have been turned down
at hospitals across the country.
People who have
only been told no.
And they wanna see me?
Well, they all
say the same thing.
They want the neurosurgeon
who is working on the cure
for Alzheimer's
to take them on.
Impossible cases.
Well, until you
get your hands on them.
So think about it.
Hi.
I was, um, completely
out of line in the OR,
but I'm glad Rhiannon
and the baby are okay,
and I'm really sorry.
Your outburst
was inappropriate,
but you weren't wrong.
Uh, Dr. Altman,
do you have a minute?
Sure.
Miranda!
Here to walk me
to the curb,
to which
I have just been kicked?
I came to say sorr--
Goodbye. Thanks.
Oh, no. I don't hold
anything against you.
No.
No, you, uh,
took care of the boss.
Can't compete
with that, right?
Plus, I take it as a sign
that I am --
I am needed elsewhere.
That's a nice way
of looking at it.
Well...
Okay.
I hired Ben Warren.
I'm s-- You what?
Well, I just --
I forgot how hard
this job is.
I never seem to be able
to do it as well as you.
The interns don't
want to listen.
Sure don't want to laugh.
Sometimes they don't
even wanna do the work.
But Ben Warren does,
and he has.
Plus, I thought that
with all your recent troubles
that you didn't need
the whispers of nepotism
following you around.
No, no, no.
Ben Warren is a keeper.
Thank you. I really...
Thank you.
Yep!
I'm sor-- No. Oh.
Oh! Oh, oop!
Beep-beep-boop.
Oh, and by the way...
I promised the interns
a retreat.
Sounds fun, yeah?
I saw the OB appointment
on our shared calendar.
Oh, yeah. Forget that.
What?
I rescheduled a knee replacement
so I could drive you.
Well, A, I can still drive,
and, B, I decided to
see someone here.
I had a patient today
who was willing
to risk her ability to walk,
maybe even risk her life,
to save her pregnancy,
so I figured that I can
sacrifice a little privacy
if it means giving
our kid the best care.
Okay.
This isn't because of
the thing I said about DeLuca?
Well...
Decaf and biscotti.
To thank you
for your help today.
You know they pay me, right?
Well...
How's Donna Mae?
Alive and kicking.
One of the orderlies,
to be exact.
I bet you don't see a lot
of patients like her, huh?
You'd be surprised.
Humanity is lovely, but, uh,
a lot of people
are nightmares.
What?
Too -- Too judgy?
No!
I like it.
Makes you feel
a little less saintly.
Mm.
I mean, you give pastries
to nurses.
The barista comps me.
We -- We hooked up
last year, so...
Kidding.
It was two years ago.
Also kidding. No.
I actually, uh...
I don't get many matches
on the apps.
Maybe it's 'cause I'm too
forthcoming about my job,
but, uh, I don't want to
spring it on people either.
Mm.
Oh, wow.
Oh!
Yeah.
That's good.
I'm -- I'm sitting right
here. You could just ask me.
Like viruses,
we also wear masks.
We disguise ourselves
to hide the parts
we don't want to be seen.
We project confidence
when we're insecure,
toughness when
we're vulnerable,
and calm when our lives
are spinning out of control.
Bringing up your family name
was out of line.
It was not your fault.
He requested you.
I could have said something...
but I didn't.
And that competition
is gonna make us better.
And we're pretty
great together, right?
Mm.
You said "girlfriend"
earlier.
I did?
Oh, yeah, I did.
Okay.
I'm cold.
The difference is
those defense mechanisms
don't always serve us.
I'm not going to ask if you're
okay because I know you're not.
Did I do something?
My sister Chloe
called this morning.
She was diagnosed
with colorectal cancer.
She's only 22.
I'm so sorry.
Altman's gonna see someone
here will take her case.
Is -- Is there
anything I can do?
Be my friend.
As great as whatever
this thing between us
was beginning to be,
I...
I don't think I can start
anything new right now.
Yeah. Of course.
Really?
Yeah.
The things we do
to protect ourselves
make it harder
to let other people get close.
As terrifying as it might be
to let your guard down,
the rewards speak
for themselves.
She looks so peaceful
when she's sleeping.
Enjoy it while it lasts.
Yeah.
How'd she take it when
she found out Richard knows?
Better than he did.
Yeah, I don't think
he's gonna speak to me
for a very long time.
I'm sorry.
Are you mad at me, too?
I mean, for letting me in
after I asked to be let in?
No, I'm not mad.
I did that, didn't I?
Yeah.
I mean, I am a little mad.
You haven't asked about
my groundbreaking
kidney transplant, though.
I'm sorry.
How was it?
It was great. It was.
I mean, it was a little
irritating, but mostly great.
I think it might be the future
of kidney transplants.
Really?
Yeah.
I want to hear all about it
on the plane.
Okay.
Let's go.
Because at the end of the day,
the only person worth being...
is yourself.