145 pounds. Johnson, Miller.
House.
I know you're not asleep.
That insight would be
a lot more impressive
if you weren't just a product
of my exhausted brain.
Aren't you curious
about why I'm here?
Curious why no French
maid's outfit, no spanky pants...
I'm a hallucination,
not a fantasy.
It's insomnia. Four nights
without REM sleep can cause...
That might explain
why you're hallucinating,
doesn't explain why you're
hallucinating Wilson's dead girlfriend.
Probably because of my secret
and very unconscious desire
to get Wilson into my bedroom.
Or maybe guilt
over Kutner's suicide
reminds you of how
guilty you felt about me.
Who cares why you're here? A
decent night's sleep and you won't be.
Guess I'll be around
a few more hours.
Need some coffee?
Addictive substances are no
substitute for nature's healing balm.
Let's make this
fast. I need to sleep.
Deaf 14-year-old started
hearing imaginary explosions.
Exploding head syndrome. Cool.
Obviously his brain knows how to hear.
Patient went deaf at age
four, complication of meningitis.
So, why no cochlear implant?
Usual suspects are insomnia,
which he doesn't have,
migraines, which he doesn't get,
and head trauma, which
didn't show up on the CT.
Damn imaginary pen.
Mom's signature's on
everything. Did Dad die?
No, I doubt it. He was a sperm donor.
Medical records couldn't be cleaner.
So, we're left with
temporal lobe seizure.
Wrong.
Someone at the wrestling meet
would have noticed a seizure.
Could have just looked
like a bad shot to the leg.
Put him in the seizure lab, see if
his head blows up all over again.
You're gonna ignore
your own subconscious?
Gonna be the limp
leading the blind.
I need a scrip
for sleeping pills.
My neighbor's dog has
been keeping me awake,
and it seems strangely
invulnerable to poison.
Why is the soon-to-be-
second-prettiest Dr. Chase here?
I'll take that as a
"Congratulations."
We're discussing a case.
Why did he close that file?
Wedding in two weeks?
I'd say you were pregnant,
but I don't think Chase's body is
mature enough to produce sperm.
It's a small ceremony, why wait?
Nighty-night.
Drugs with no lecture?
He wants you out.
Interesting case?
Possible prostate
cancer came into the ER.
Pencil cup.
No wonder his prostate is enlarged.
It's full of pool cues and cigars.
Chase's best man doesn't get
here till the day of the wedding,
so I asked Wilson to
throw his bachelor party.
No retired ministers
available to plan it?
Chase doesn't want
some big, raucous party.
So she says.
Luckily, there are people in this
world ready to stand up for what's right.
No, no, no. I
don't want you to...
Listen, of the two things I do well,
bachelor parties rank towards the top.
I get to help, right?
Starting five hertz.
House made it through
that entire differential
without mocking our patient
for not having a cochlear implant.
The patient doesn't want an implant
because he's comfortable with who he is.
It's admirable.
He's deaf, that's not an
identity, it's a disability.
It's also a culture.
The deaf have their own
schools, their own language.
Still no spiking.
Going to 20.
Anything I can simulate with a
$3 pair of ear plugs is not a culture.
No sign of seizure. Temporal
lobe activity is still clean.
Doctors. Doctors, he
can't see. One of his eyes.
"The limp leading the blind."
Is that supposed
to mean something?
I didn't think so.
So, exploding head
syndrome plus vision loss.
Subclavian steal
syndrome. Vascular defect
coupled with constant arm movement
could siphon blood flow from the brain.
We should do an
angio, check his...
Knock yourselves out.
How did I know he
was gonna go blind?
Don't get cute, Gazoo. You're in
my mind, you're obviously there.
C-reactive protein.
I noticed in his file it
was slightly elevated.
I figured the stress of the seizure lab
would drive the inflammation even higher
and lead to optic neuritis.
That's a lot clearer than
"the limp leading the blind."
It was just a glimmer. I
couldn't put it into words.
It was a long shot.
I don't even remember
the C-reactive protein level.
Obviously you do,
you just don't know it.
How high is K2?
I don't know. Me neither.
But I read a book
about it years ago.
A fierce, sexy Sherpa on
the cover, bending over to...
28,251 feet.
Cool.
An all-access pass
to my own brain.
Go play the kid some music.
Why?
Another long shot.
We're using iodine dye to track
the blood flow in your neck and arm.
House, what are you doing?
What's it look like I'm
doing? Fighting the power.
Feel that? How cool is that?
Apparently your mom doesn't
care what you're missing.
You're an ass.
He says he feels the vibrations
in his abdomen, but not his hand.
What does that mean?
It's a new symptom. Neuropathy.
Thought you were
gonna get some sleep.
The case got interesting.
It's like the zoo.
Except you can bang on the
glass as much as you want.
How'd you know
about the neuropathy?
Good question.
Enough with the riddles.
Tell me about it.
Think wrestling record.
Juggling.
No, pins, three pins.
Patient was pinned
in his last three
matches. Leading up
to that he was 15-and-0.
I figured his balance was
off from diminished sensation.
Could be increased
ICP from a brain tumor.
That we missed on the head CT?
Cutting weight for wrestling
could've led to rhabdomyolysis.
Patient went up a weight
class three months ago.
Foreman's right.
Actually, increased
ICP could make sense.
You just said...
I was processing.
It also puts a new
symptom on the table.
His deafness.
What if it was caused by NF2 cancer,
instead of his childhood meningitis?
So, meningitis
was a coincidence.
Or a by-product of the cancer
suppressing his immune system.
MRI his head.
If you're right about NF2, his
deafness may be reversible.
I'll set it up and
talk to the patient.
You two doing anything?
Do you know what a
"Broken Cowboy" is?
It was on House's
list of requirements.
I have three theories.
Why is House so into
this bachelor party?
He needs to have a reason
to be into a bachelor party?
He needs a reason
to be into anything.
Give me your wallet.
House could be trying to tempt
Chase into cheating, break them up.
You think House is into Cameron?
I think House is into
Cameron being into him.
Marrying Chase would
shatter that fantasy.
If Chase cheats, they shouldn't
be getting married in the first place.
So, you're okay with House getting Chase
smashed enough to make a stupid mistake?
Being drunk doesn't change
who you are, it just reveals it.
You think she can do
the Broken Cowboy?
God, I hope so.
NF2 is an extremely slow-growing
cancer, which makes it very treatable.
If we're right, taking
out the tumor means
there's a chance you'll
regain your hearing.
No, they said you have to.
What's wrong?
He wants you to treat the
cancer, but leave him deaf.
Sorry. It doesn't
work like that.
But why?
I don't know.
Imaging shows slightly elevated ICP,
but no masses on or around the nerves.
It's not cancer.
Slight bowing in the wall of the fourth
ventricle, could still indicate a tumor.
We brought pictures.
The fact that you sent
me on a scouting mission...
No skirts.
You're not on the guest list.
Bachelor parties are an ancient
and sacred male rite of passage.
The ventricle bowing is most likely
a pre-existing anatomical anomaly,
not the indication of a tumor.
No way to know for sure
without a brain biopsy.
If I get drunk enough, there's a chance I
might make out with one of the strippers.
Or become one.
Sold. Sold.
We can't just drill into our
patient's brain on a hunch.
God, not her. God, not her.
She's the one that got
me hooked in with Madoff.
Taub's right. It's not cancer.
Yeah, by all means,
abandon a great diagnostic
theory because it's difficult to prove.
Do a biopsy. We need to take a
better look at his fourth ventricle.
Or an older look.
The mom is never gonna let us
touch his brain without some evidence.
Patient broke his nose years
ago. Hospital could've done an MRI.
Okay.
The main reason my third wife and I
eloped was to avoid House's bachelor party.
Have you seen Caligula?
My patient's brain now versus
three years ago. See any difference?
Is he telling you
to avoid the party?
I took an oath to do no harm.
Sure, don't come,
if you want your wedding
vows to be meaningless.
This should be interesting.
You are going to commit to
that one special woman forever,
which is beautiful.
But if your commitment
the day after the wedding
is the same as your
commitment the day before,
then the wedding meant nothing.
So, and I see no logical way around
this, if you want your marriage to matter,
you have to be a wanton, trolling,
muck-covered pig the day before.
You're evil. See you.
The wall of the fourth ventricle
changed, it isn't bowed in the older scan.
Evidence of NF2, right?
You'd need to do a
brain biopsy to confirm.
I'm not going to the bachelor party.
Every time I go to one of your parties,
I end up embarrassing myself in
some new and unexpected way.
That whole thing with the
duck was hardly unexpected.
I'm not going.
Okay.
It's not okay.
Do you know who we need?
That stripper you got for
Wilson's bachelor party.
You could do body
shots right off her.
Why go back to that well? In the
nine years since Wilson's party,
a whole new generation of hot girls
have been abused by their stepfathers.
She loved cats.
Why would you remember
that a stripper loved cats?
Chase has a cat, they'll bond.
House, you entertaining
yourself up there?
Just rehearsing for the revival
of Evita. What did you find?
Biopsy shows nerve
inflammation consistent
with increased
intracranial pressure.
Something's wrong,
but it's not cancer.
He's gonna go through life deaf.
He's okay with that.
He has no idea
what he's missing.
His mom's a moron. He's gonna pay
for her stupidity for the rest of his life?
Are we okay with that?
Why are you closing? You're
supposed to put in a cochlear implant.
That wasn't in the paperwork.
Really? Well, someone must
have screwed up. I'll go track it down.
I'll wait. That's a great idea.
Let the kid spend more time under
anesthesia with his skull cracked open.
I'll wait.
I've been known to lie
to serve my own agenda.
An implant does absolutely
nothing to help me diagnose him.
Let's get an
implant tray in here.
Just try to relax.
Her son didn't want the implant.
If he still doesn't want it, after
having time to adjust, I'll take it out.
I'll blind him, too, if he wants
to experience that culture.
Remove it now.
Kid just had brain
surgery. He's not stable.
Ms. Miller, I'm not trying to
minimize Dr. House's wrongdoing,
but the best thing
for your son...
Why is she sitting?
She's not yelling, not
threatening, not pacing, just sitting.
Understand, Dr. House?
House, focus.
I need you to say you
accept the arrangement.
No problem. You're not mad.
I'm mad.
Not mad enough.
You wanted your son to hear.
You just didn't have the guts
to make him get the implant.
Once my son is stable, I
want that thing out of his head.
Why did you do this?
Because he is ignorant and
he's being raised by an idiot.
Not good enough,
you always have...
My patient is opting
into a handicap.
He's an insult to all the
other gimps out there.
Okay.
But I'm still putting Foreman
in charge of the case.
That's the arrangement?
Okay.
You're okay with
Foreman in charge?
Who you calling?
Oh, right, you don't
want to look like a lunatic.
Yeah, about that.
You think we did
the wrong thing?
I'm not sure. I'm not
even sure why we did it.
That argument you made to
Cuddy sounded pretty good.
To you, maybe.
Huh. I figured by now you'd be at the
board in your monocle and jodhpurs.
Yeah, you did something stupid.
Quick, better mock someone.
Why did you do it?
Why did I give a human
being the power of hearing?
You can ask God the same question,
he'll give you the same answer.
Patient has a fever now, too.
Probably just a post-op
complication. Arnold-Chiari?
Not without muscle weakness.
Pseudotumor Cerebri?
We checked his eyes before
the surgery. No papilledema.
Candy?
I'm pretty sure Wilson's stripper's
name was something sweet.
Maybe his fever is more
than a post-op reaction.
His girlfriend was sick a few months
ago, maybe her flu was really Epstein-Barr.
Lolly? THIRTEEN: They swap spit,
virus travels to his
brain, leads to meningitis,
leads to increased
intracranial pressure.
I agree. Taffy?
I agree.
Go ahead, start him on
ribavirin for Epstein-Barr.
Keep making decisions like that,
it really bolsters the
illusion that you're in charge.
Why aren't you in my office?
Because I know what
the word "my" means.
I did something insane, and
you're not all over me analyzing why.
It was nice.
I gave that idiot an
implant to prove to him
what an idiot he's
been. How is that nice?
You didn't do it to solve the
case, you didn't do it to save his life,
you did it to make his life
better. It was a caring act.
Which you did in a way that was
immoral and illegal, but baby steps.
Doesn't sound like us.
You can't make me
go to the bachelor party.
I know.
And you're okay with that?
What choice do I have?
Seth!
Please, God...
Seth.
Yes.
Oh!
I think he just wet the bed.
Kid's dehydrated but stable.
Thankfully the fountain of whizz
seems to have stopped for the moment.
Not before hosing
Epstein-Barr off the table.
Now, eat up.
We're gonna pick out the ice
cream flavors for the bachelor party.
Could be a systemic
autoimmune disease.
This tastes like vodka.
Well, it would be stupid if it tasted
like bourbon. That's the brown one.
It is vodka?
Flash frozen in a secret process.
Guy figured it out in his basement.
Limoncello. Genius.
Symptoms came on too hard and
too fast. Sarcoidosis is progressive.
Remember, in med school,
when Donovan gave grand rounds,
there was that guy
who was peeing liters.
Glomerulonephritis. Wrestler, steroids
could have damaged the kidneys.
The scotch is nice.
His urine would've been brown.
Donovan ruled out osmotic
diuresis, kidney disease...
Pheochromocytoma?
No hypertension, plasma
metanephrine is normal.
Devic's?
It happened at night.
That was the clue.
Night, recumbent body
position, changes in BP...
It's his heart.
Run a 12-lead EKG,
watch him for four hours.
Foreman concurs.
What the hell just happened?
Everything started to fade away.
You're getting better at focusing,
ignoring everything that doesn't matter.
Uh-oh!
He looks pissed. I
think he might hit us.
Is your eyesight
better than mine?
We need to talk about
the bachelor party.
Excellent topic choice.
I mean, surgery is so boring, and
my lying to you is just so yesterday.
It's my fault for letting you
talk me into the implant.
Cameron is not gonna
be happy about this party.
But, you, on the other hand...
Plan on spending the rest
of my life with Cameron.
So, I need to
cancel the fart band?
So, I need you to kidnap me.
Spoken like a true Aussie.
By the way, if you know where I can get
me the sheet music to Waltzing Matilda...
Hey! Want some ice cream?
We're having a sundae bar.
Sweet.
That's her name!
Sundae or Bar?
Karamel.
With a "K."
Bathroom?
Down the hall, two
doors, on your right.
Thanks.
Do I sound like her?
It takes time.
You still haven't slept?
And then I have
a clever response.
EKG, normal sinus, normal
intervals. His heart's fine.
His heart's not fine.
The heart was fine during this
test. The arrhythmia's hiding.
Or we were wrong
about the heart.
Could be the thyroid.
Hashimoto's would explain the
kid's urine and brain pressure.
Treadmill.
Or the arrhythmia is hiding.
We need to stress him.
Put the patient on a treadmill.
The patient just
had brain surgery.
A stress test could cause
a brain bleed and kill him.
I value your opinion. I
value rejecting your opinion.
You're not doing this. You
haven't been sleeping...
Cuddy doesn't actually
want you in charge.
She just wants to avoid a lawsuit
and to win an NAACP award.
And if I let you risk our patient's life
testing an organ we already tested,
we accomplish neither.
Run a thyroid panel.
How do we get him into the stress
lab without Foreman's sign off?
We could kill
Foreman. Is she new?
Focus. The lab simulates
stress. What if it's not simulated?
We could tell him his
girlfriend dumped him.
It's a tough sell since she never leaves
the room for more than five minutes.
We could kill her.
Or asthma meds. Force
the heart to beat faster.
Revealing the arrhythmia.
Nice idea.
It was yours.
I just left the room
for a few minutes.
He ripped out his implant.
So much for improving his life.
Actually, I think
we just saved it.
Look at that. Arrhythmia.
You were right about the heart.
I should have listened to you.
The correct phrasing would
be, "I should always listen to you."
He's got problems everywhere.
What goes everywhere?
Blood. Could be thrombocythemia.
Excess platelets lead to
clotting throughout the body.
Not with a normal
platelet count.
So the clotting doesn't
start in the blood,
it starts in the lungs.
Pulmonary embolism.
We should do a V/Q scan,
see if his lungs are clear.
Go.
Are you sure I did
this at Wilson's party?
Last time, you used grain
alcohol instead of the sambuca.
And it worked?
Well, it explains my lack of
eyebrows by the end of the evening.
By the power of Grayskull, I...
This is why we're rehearsing.
Ever wonder what's happening
every time our patient gets sicker?
Not right now.
First symptom, wrestling.
Then, under the lights
of the seizure lab...
Are you going somewhere
with this? Because this feels...
Just keep doing what
you're doing. It helps.
Then, under the stress of
blindness, then, post-op fever.
What do all the symptoms
have in common?
Heat.
See, if you hadn't been here, that
would've just popped into my head,
which actually would
have been way cooler.
Foreman, kid's got Uhthoff
phenomenon, which means it's MS.
Start him on
double-dose interferon.
Let's get our drink on.
Not before I've added chemical
burns to this guy's cause of death.
Patient's responding
to interferon.
Looks like I can retire
as department figurehead.
Dr. Robert Chase?
We're with the Department
of Citizenship and Immigration.
Did you recently apply
for a marriage license?
Ah... Yes.
According to our records,
your work permit has expired.
If you could come with us?
I'm his fiancée. I can
come along and clear this...
I'm sorry, ma'am. Illegals only.
I'm sure it's a mistake. I'll call you
as soon as I know what's going on.
Don't let House get
him in too much trouble.
Allow me to welcome you
to the best night of your life.
Now, a few ground rules for
the evening. Safety is job one.
We have now gone 18 days
without an injury in the workplace.
Yes, these girls are all working their
way through law school, don't test them.
House!
I knew you couldn't stay away.
This is my apartment!
You can't do this.
Clearly reality begs to differ.
Where's my furniture?
Out back somewhere.
James!
Karamel?
Hey.
How's your wife?
We got divorced.
How's your cat? Dead.
How about we go have a drink?
This way. Okay.
You're okay with this?
I paid 50 bucks for this.
You guys are great
together. Trust is everything.
I'm gonna get some
air. Keep it real.
You should be out there, enjoying
the lap dances of your labors.
I kind of like it in here.
Me, too.
To us, figuring out MS.
And the blindness and neuropathy,
and arrhythmia, and anything else we did.
What exactly did my team do?
Looked good in their lab
coats, except for Taub.
Some people just work
better alone, so to speak.
One more drink.
No. I can't. I
gotta take a break.
Meet Karamel.
Maybe one more drink.
What's that taste?
Is that strawberry?
House, you in there?
Use the other bathroom. It's
in the kitchen, looks like a sink.
Chase went into anaphylactic shock from
the stripper's body butter or something.
Is he okay?
One of the residents had
an EpiPen, so he's fine.
But we're taking him to
the hospital to be safe.
Okay.
I knew that Chase was
allergic to strawberries, didn't I?
That's why you wanted
Karamel at this party.
I suggested Karamel 'cause
she was great at Wilson's party.
I knew about her body butter, I
knew about his strawberry allergy.
I tried to kill Chase?
Why would I do that?
I don't want Cameron.
You're not a big fan of other
people's happiness either.
Hello.
You confirm? Thanks.
That kid we saved, he's dying.
It's not MS.
We were wrong.
Thank God you're
okay. What happened?
There was a girl...
Long story.
Your patient's lung failure rules
out MS. We put him on a ventilator.
Enlarged lymphs could...
Are any of you sober?
Turn around, you need
to go to the hospital.
I need to sleep.
I'm you. You can't
just shut a door.
You tried to kill Chase.
I need to push you back
down, you're dangerous.
It's the hospital.
I'm not answering.
Hello.
I'm here with your team,
trying to sober them up so they
can help treat your dying patient.
Foreman's dying patient.
What causes lung failure plus
your patient's previous symptoms?
Eosinophilic pneumonitis.
White blood cells accumulate, clog up
the lungs, lead to heart problems. It fits.
House, are you there?
It's not eosinophilic
pneumonitis.
I gotta crash.
House, don't hang
up. We need your help.
I can't.
We can solve this.
Good night.
Eosinophilic pneumonitis
could actually make sense.
No, House ruled it out because it
would affect the larynx. Patient would be
hoarse.
Which we wouldn't notice in
a deaf kid who rarely speaks.
Wait. Everyone's
getting breath mints.
We need to hear Seth speak.
That means taking out the
tube. Isn't that dangerous?
It's the safest way to
confirm what's wrong with him.
I need him to breathe
out once I pull on the tube.
Okay.
Say "ah."
I'm sorry, we were wrong.
I need to suction out your
throat before we re-intubate.
Your son smoke?
I don't think so.
Tobacco stains on his teeth.
He says he used to chew
tobacco to cut weight for wrestling.
Used to?
Chewing tobacco wouldn't
explain his symptoms.
But not chewing tobacco might.
Taub was right.
It's sarcoidosis.
The tobacco releases toxins, those
toxins suppressed his immune system.
Once he quit chewing,
the absence of those toxins kicked
a dormant condition into hyper-drive.
Is it treatable?
Usually responds to
corticosteroids and methotrexate.
I'll start the meds.
I need sleeping pills.
I was gonna hit up Wilson, but
he's not answering his phone.
He must have
left it in his pants,
which he wasn't wearing when the police
found him trying to walk home, oddly,
from his own apartment.
Pills.
Your patient is doing
fine, thanks to your team.
It wasn't eosinophilic
pneumonitis, was it?
Sarcoidosis.
Good.
House, please, talk to me.
I haven't slept through the
night since Kutner killed himself.
The wrestling
might have to wait.
I'm gonna tell your doctors
to repair your implant.
I know. And then you ripped it out rather
than live with it for a few days even.
I'm your mother.
This is my call.
I don't know if I'm making the
right one, but it's mine to make.
Sleep well?