♪ I've been havin' dreams ♪
[ Phones ringing ]
Meredith: In 1847, the
American Medical Association
published its code of ethics,
in which physicians
were encouraged to provide
free services to the poor
as part of their public duty.
[ Cellphone vibrating ]
Hey, Mer.
Karev, you're late.
It's 5:00 a. m.,
and it's not Karev anymore.
Fair enough.
What is it?
♪ How am I so deep in love? ♪
I don't know yet.
Okay, Jo.
You're late,
and it's Pro Bono Surgery Day.
I have 25 patients
to get through
and only four
general surgeons.
♪ I never feel so loved ♪
And, Jo, you need to work.
You know it,
and I know it.
So get your ass in here.
♪ I've been having dreams ♪
[ Sighs ]
♪ Splashin' in a summer stream ♪
♪ Trip and I fall in ♪
Hospitals were meant
to be centers to care
for the sick and poor.
They were meant to be places
of refuge, places to heal.
But somewhere along the way,
that changed.
♪ Crushin' weight of paradise ♪
I brought
the forms back.
♪ Solid block of gold ♪
Dr. Grey, if I may,
you were already
a legend, but this...
I mean, I don't know what
comes after "legend," but ‐‐
Helm. It's not about me.
Stop it.
Healthcare became
a commodity sold to
those who can afford it...
♪ Wait if I'm on fire ♪
♪ How am I so deep in love? ♪
[ Sighs ]
She's such a legend.
This isn't
about her, Brody.
Stop it.
Rather than a physician's
dutiful service to the public.
♪ I never feel so loved ♪
[ Whistling ]
♪♪
Hey.
Ready to see Mavis break
the record tonight?
Uh, I‐I can't go to
a basketball game tonight.
But I got
courtside seats.
Yeah, I know. I ‐‐
Uh, one of his
fellow firefighters died.
Threw a PE right as we were
about to discharge him.
Ohh.
I'm really sorry.
Yeah, of course.
Do what you need to do.
Thanks, man.
Hey.
Mwah.
Bye.
Female voice:
Surgical diagnostics complete.
This is that mobile surgery
unit we paid for, huh?
Yeah.
You, uh, come by the station,
give you a tour.
♪ Wait if I'm on fire ♪
Yeah.
[ Engine revs ]
Man: Mission response
team requested...
[ Doors close ]
♪ How am I so deep in love? ♪
That truck is dope.
It's Grey's
Pro Bono Surgery Day.
Get excited about that.
Maggie: Hey.
What are you doing
here so early?
Uh, force of habit.
And if you're trying to
talk me into
operating again, don't.
If I thought it would work,
I would, but, no,
I wanted to tell you
that I got a call
from the lawyer
yesterday.
And you were right.
Your brother settled.
So I really appreciate
you helping me through that.
And, um, I hope
that Chris finds some peace.
Well, I got a call from
a lawyer yesterday, too.
Separation papers.
Catherine's lawyer
was letting me know
how generous she is by
letting me keep my own house.
Oh, my God.
I am so sorry, Richard.
No one's sorrier
than I am.
Richard?
Meredith, no, okay?
I haven't even asked
you anything yet.
Okay, fine.
I need to put you
on the board today.
Just a few hernias,
or lap cholies.
You choose.
It ‐‐ The pro bono day
is ‐‐ is just...
Meredith, what...?
Come on.
I already lost
one friend this week.
Can't lose you, too.
Look, I'm ‐‐ I'm still
your friend.
I'm ‐‐ I'm just
not your surgeon.
Link's the father.
I know Maggie told you
that it might be Owen's,
but it's not.
[ Exhales sharply ]
Hi, Jo.
I already knew.
Link sent me a Bitmoji
last night of a baby's body
with his face on it,
which I can't unsee.
[ Chuckles ] Well, that's ‐‐
that's great news.
I'm happy for you ‐‐
both of you ‐‐
all of us, I guess,
right?
Yeah. Yep.
Yeah.
Okay. I'll see you upstairs.
Congrats.
I'm sorry you guys
got tangled up in this,
even for a moment, but now
we can just move forward.
Full steam ahead, right?
[ Chuckles nervously ]
DeLuca:
Thank you. Right here.
Has a Jared Goldstein
checked in here?
He hasn't shown up yet.
I thought he might have come
to the clinic by accident.
Doesn't sound familiar.
We're giving him
a lap cholie.
For free.
Or, uh, Bailey is.
It's, uh ‐‐
It's great, right?
Wouldn't know.
I'm stuck here.
DeLuca, are you okay?
I'm fine. Move.
Okay, Cindy Wright.
I'm Dr. DeLuca.
How can I help you?
She has a bulge
in her stomach.
And you are...?
Uh, her aunt, Opal.
Okay, Cindy, let me
take a look at you here.
Alright.
Does that hurt, Cindy?
She said that she's
a six on a ‐‐
I asked Cindy.
Hmm?
A little.
Did you do anything
strenuous lately?
Maybe you lifted
something heavy?
We moved
a refrigerator.
She helps me
clean houses.
It's kind of
a family business.
On the count of three,
I want you to hold your breath
and bear down
for me, okay?
One, two, three.
[ Whimpers ]
Whoa. Okay.
You've definitely got
a hernia in your abdomen here.
We can repair that with
a very easy surgery.
Super simple.
But, uh, is there
any other symptoms
I should know about?
It also burns
when she pees.
She's embarrassed,
but I told her
it's probably just a UTI.
Could be.
Uh, but I'll need to
do a more thorough exam.
You're welcome to wait in
the family area right over here.
Um, she has
some abandonment issues.
Her ‐‐ Her parents
left her when she was 4.
Is it okay
if I just stay?
♪♪
Sure.
Um, you know what?
Cindy, why don't you put
this gown on for me?
And I'll be right back.
♪♪
[ Sighs ]
Good morning. Welcome to
Pro Bono Surgery Day.
I appreciate you all rearranging
your schedules to be here.
I would make a speech, but we
don't really have the time
because Koracick
pulls the plug at 7:00.
So, all the beds
turn into pumpkins.
At least Cinderella
had until midnight.
[ Laughter ]
Did you have to pick today to
start telling jokes, Hunt?
You know what they call
Pro Bono Surgery Day in Ireland?
Every day.
[ Laughter ]
Great. More jokes.
Okay, Hayes,
you are on bed 8.
Hunt and Ka‐‐ Jo,
uh, you have AV fistula, bed 6.
Take Brody with you.
Wait, uh,
it's Wilson now.
Wait, I don't
like that either.
I ‐‐ Okay, for now it's ‐‐
it is ‐‐ it is Jo.
It is Dr. Jo.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ Siren wailing in distance ]
How long have you
had chest pain?
Since I enlisted.
So it's been
quite some time.
Lean back.
Could it be anxiety?
I don't know.
Are my headaches
anxiety, too?
Back pain?
Or do you think
maybe it's the IED
that knocked me on my skull and
killed a bunch of my buddies?
I was in Afghanistan.
Field surgeon.
[ Handcuffs clack ]
Are the cuffs
really necessary?
He spent a week in county
for assaulting
a store owner
with a knife
and threatening a city block
with a grenade.
And still, I can't assess
him if I can't move his arm.
[ Handcuffs click ]
Thank you.
Why'd you assault
the store owner?
'Cause he deserved it.
And the grenade?
I felt like
I deserved it.
Put your arm down.
Thanks.
Are you on any medication...
Ah.
For PTSD?
[ Groaning ] I was on
an SSRI for a while.
Helped a bit, but then
my insurance changed,
and it got
too expensive.
I don't want any benzos.
My memory's bad enough.
Kyle, if you work with me,
I promise you I'll help you.
Kyle?
Page Tom Koracick, please.
[ Clicks ]
Kyle, can you hear me?
Okay, Cindy, do you have
a history of hernias
in your family?
That might be a good one
for you to answer, Aunt Opal.
No. I don't think so.
Okay, what about,
uh, fevers, headaches,
things like that?
She's not used to
meeting cute doctors.
No. No fevers.
Okay, well, it's likely
the UTI, along with the hernia,
but I'll need a urine sample
and some other tests, okay?
How long is that
gonna take?
It's just that I have to
arrange childcare
for my other kids, so...
I'll send
a nurse right over.
Nurse Olivia, please look at me
and act completely normal.
You got that?
Okay.
Page Chief Bailey
and get a full set of labs
for the girl in bed 3.
Why? What happened?
She's reluctant to
answer my questions.
The aunt's doing
all the talking for her.
She fits
the profile, alright?
We need to keep her here
as long as possible.
Profile for what?
Human trafficking.
♪♪
Shara Freeman,
55‐year‐old female
with a history of
abdominal wall sarcoma.
Status post
multiple surgeries ‐‐
You'll forgive me
if we cut right to it.
Caitlin: I'll cut
right to it, too.
You really think
you can fix my mom?
Honey, please.
Dr. Grey is an expert
in this surgery.
She's a pioneer
in the field.
A game‐changer. And your
mom's extremely lucky ‐‐
Helm.
You're the fourth surgeon
to tell me this will be
the procedure
that makes my mom better.
How do I know
it'll be different this time,
that she won't wake up
again in agony?
You don't.
But what I do know
is where her scar tissue
starts and where it ends.
And I know exactly how
I plan to remove it.
And I also know that
she won't have
one medical bill to pay
when this is over.
So, the only way
all of that can happen is ‐‐
is if we get to it.
Okay.
Dr. Grey, uh,
O‐OR 4 is a no‐go
for at least
the next hour.
They have
the wrong instruments,
and they have to sterilize
the correct ones.
Why?
I‐I'll fix it.
Well, it's, uh,
25 surgeries in 12 hours.
There's, uh, bound to be
a hitch or two, right?
What? Uh...
Oh. Hi. Good.
I told them.
All parties involved.
It was awkward, which ‐‐
I'm not sure why.
It was all
good baby‐daddy news.
[ Sighs ] Hello?
Oh, sorry.
It's just my old job
with the Mariners.
They've been kinda
courting me,
trying to get me back
while we were going through
our whole...
Baby‐daddy drama.
You know, I'd really
love it if you didn't say
"baby daddy."
Sorry.
Dad. You're the baby dad.
Baby daddy.
Uh, uh, sorry.
[ Stammers ]
Said it again.
Anyway, um, I'm saying no,
so you don't have to worry.
I just need
like two minutes.
Do you want to say no?
Well, I mean,
it's a kick‐ass gig,
and, uh, they're
offering me basically double
what they were paying me
before, but it's ‐‐
it's a lot of travel,
a lot of late nights.
And you're giving up
this kick‐ass gig why?
[ Sighs ]
'Cause I'm about
to be a baby daddy.
Woman on P. A.:
Dr. Bormann to Pediatrics.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Okay, Cindy, do you have
any brothers or sister?
Just my cousins.
Is this gonna help you
figure out what she's got?
It's just
a little doctor trick.
You know, hospitals
can be intimidating,
so we make small talk
as a distraction.
Just helps
everybody relax.
Can I go to the bathroom?
Nurse Olivia can
take you to the bathroom
in a wheelchair.
Oh, no, I can help her.
Nurse Olivia will take her.
You can wait here.
Uh, Nurse Olivia,
would you mind helping
Cindy to the bathroom?
Thank you so much.
[ Whispering ]
Where the hell is Bailey?
She's heading
into surgery.
Well, tell her she can't.
I need her here right now.
You want me to tell
the chief of surgery
that she can't
go into s‐‐
I have a human‐trafficking
victim, Olivia.
Dr. DeLuca, I understand
that you're concerned,
but teenagers are moody.
Maybe the kid
is just ‐‐
I know what I saw, okay?
And I'm the only thing
standing between her
and freedom right now.
So just ‐‐ You know what?
Forget it.
I'll do it.
Just take her to the bathroom.
Dr. DeLuca.
Please. Please.
Please.
Nico and I are going to
this new speakeasy after work.
You enter through
a back ‐‐ old room
in the back
of this old motel.
Want to come?
Uh, watching my friend
fawn over a guy who doesn't
treat him as an equal
because the sex is good
is not my idea of fun.
Even when
there's alcohol.
Okay, it is so much more
complicated than that.
Hey, thank you so much.
Let me know when
they schedule your interview,
and I can prep you.
Dr. Lincoln, Mr. Mendoza
is on his way to the OR
for his arthroscopic
meniscectomy.
On my way.
Thanks again, man.
You deserve it.
Deserve what?
He's recommending me for his
old job with the Mariners.
Wow!
Are you ‐‐ W‐Will you ‐‐
Is it ‐‐
Uh, should we talk
this through?
I mean, uh, what kind
of job is it?
A job I take unless
I'm an idiot, which I'm not.
Helm, where am I going?
Uh, rotator cuff repair
on Mrs. Lefevre.
OR 3.
Got it.
I take it back.
You're totally equals.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Teddy, you paged?
Oh. I paged Koracick.
Do people
really prefer him?
Because that concerns me
on multiple levels.
Sorry.
Thank you for coming.
36‐year‐old male.
He's a Marine.
He has severe PTSD
and a probable TBI.
He held an entire store hostage
with a grenade
trying to
blow himself up.
And the VA's slammed,
so he's hardly had
any proper care.
Well, of course not.
And I noticed strange
involuntary movements
and intermittent
loss of awareness.
I'm thinking maybe
a complex partial seizure?
Okay. Okay, I will look for
signs of traumatic brain in‐‐
No! No! No!
Kyle, please!
Ashley, leave!
I didn't ask you guys
to call anyone!
Kyle,
it's police protocol
to notify your
emergency contacts.
I want her to go away.
I don't want her to see me
like this, please.
Hey.
No, hey, hey, no, no!
No, I ‐‐ Hey, I'm sorry.
‐He didn't mean to ‐‐
‐I'm sorry.
He can't breathe!
Let go of him!
Let go of him. He has broken
ribs and a brain injury.
[ Coughs ]
Alright.
You can give him pain meds
for the ribs,
but he's coming back
to county.
He'll go when
I say he'll go.
♪♪
Bailey. Finally.
Look, the patient won't
talk to me alone,
and her aunt ‐‐
if she's even her aunt ‐‐
won't let her
out of her sight.
She's answering all of her
questions for her.
Bailey, the girl in there,
the ‐‐ the patient, she's ‐‐
DeLuca, you assured me
that you were ready
to return to work,
and I trusted you.
Please, do not
make me reconsider.
I have serious reason
to believe that that girl ‐‐
I know you think
you know something,
but I am telling you to stop,
take a breath.
I'm telling you ‐‐
Listen to yourself.
What, is that the family
that you suspect
of human trafficking?
Bailey, trust me.
If you just go in there
and talk to her,
you'll know, okay?
Shh, shh, shh!
Stay right here.
[ Sighs ]
Hello. Hi.
I'm Dr. Miranda Bailey,
Chief of Surgery.
Chief? Oh, wow.
Uh, it's nice to meet you.
I'm Opal.
This is my niece, Cindy.
Cindy!
Now, how old are you?
It's okay.
She's the chief of surgery.
You can trust her.
16.
And you're from the area?
Not originally, but she's ‐‐
she's been here since she was 5.
Hmm.
Yeah, and you live
with your Aunt Opal?
[ Chuckles lightly ]
[ Whimpers ]
Sorry. Um, my belly
really hurts.
Well, we will make you
feel better real soon, okay?
[ Chuckles ]
Thanks.
♪♪
[ Sighs ]
And...?
That is a minor in pain
that you are keeping
from getting the care
that she needs.
Page another resident
to take care of her.
She is no longer
your patient.
Bailey, stop.
Unless you'd rather
I suspend you?
DeLuca, go home. Rest.
[ Scoffs ]
And be in my office
tomorrow, 9:00 a. m. sharp.
♪♪
Why isn't Shara
in surgery right now?
Bailey's patient got
taken to the OR,
and she got
paged away urgently.
Someone needs
to take over.
Dr. Grey!
How much longer?!
All my mom does is wait!
And she's gonna have to wait
a little while longer.
[ Sighs ]
I'm sorry.
We're doing
everything we can.
[ Monitor beeping ]
Hey, hey. Big day.
Whatcha got?
Nothing.
[ Sighs ]
Oh. Hunt.
Hey.
I have got an extra ticket
to the big game tonight.
I don't know
if you've got plans,
but this is gonna be
an amazing game, alright?
Mavis is on fire.
Hmm. Well, maybe.
Yeah. Yeah.
Uh, I mean, I kinda
would need a firm yes or no
just so I don't waste
the ticket, but ‐‐
Oh, well...
Yeah.
Then, uh, no.
[ Sighs ]
How about you?
You like hoops?
Yes! Yeah!
Mm‐hmm?
And, um, not being invited
to things
as an afterthought.
That's not ‐‐
So that's ‐‐
No.
Why don't you
just go alone?
Oh. I'm sorry.
I ‐‐ [ Chuckles ]
I forgot.
You can't do alone.
Um...
Hey.
How are you?
Good. Yeah, hi.
Yeah, I‐I can't do it.
The headaches, on a scale
of 1 to 10, how bad?
53.
Yikes.
And you said
your memory's bad?
Short‐term, yeah.
Which is why I don't
like taking meds.
I end up taking them
too many times a day
'cause I forgot
I already took them.
You know they have
little pill boxes for that.
I keep forgetting
to buy one of those.
[ Chuckles ] So, sense
of humor's still intact.
It's buried
in there somewhere.
You know what you saw earlier,
how I sort of lost it?
That's every day.
At the gas station,
over breakfast.
That's why I've been
avoiding Ashley.
She doesn't
deserve that.
Neither do you.
[ Aron Wright's "Before
the Song is Over" plays ]
♪♪
Afghanistan, and then Iraq.
[ Door closes ]
And when he came home,
it was like [sighs]
he wasn't Kyle.
♪ Let's take a step back ♪
He used to be this
hilarious, silly guy.
♪ Stop and look
at where we're at ♪
Sometimes at
the grocery store,
he would sing to whatever
oldies music they were playing.
[ Voice breaking ] He would
just dance to "Brown Eyed Girl"
in the cereal aisle.
Everybody loved it.
[ Chuckles ]
♪ For every peak,
there is a valley ♪
You know, he was someone
I wanted to be around...
for the rest of my life
because I knew I'd be laughing.
♪ So let go of all you carry ♪
♪ The gravity of such regret ♪
[ Sniffles ]
And I know he's sick,
but he's not keeping up
with his meds, and...
♪ What if the best
is yet to come? ♪
I just don't know how long
I can keep doing this.
And that's okay.
The life that you
signed up for, it's...
♪ Close your eyes
one more time ♪
It's changed.
And you're allowed
to have your feelings, and...
♪ To change your mind ♪
You're allowed
to have your doubts
and to make mistakes.
♪ It's just a dance,
you're a step behind ♪
♪ Don't leave ♪
I just feel like
if I can't make this work...
♪ Don't leave before
the song is over ♪
What was it all for?
♪ Before the song is over ♪
We're gonna do an MRI
and an EEG,
and then we will know more.
♪ Let's take a breath now ♪
Ashley, we are
going to help him.
♪ Do more than just react ♪
Thank you.
Okay.
♪ Close your eyes ♪
♪ One more time ♪
♪ Give me a chance ♪
♪ To change your mind ♪
♪ It's just a dance,
you're a step behind ♪
So, Nico said that you
used to be a team doctor?
For three years.
Here, take this grasper
and lift that out gently.
♪ Don't leave before
the song is over ♪
♪ Before the song is over ♪
A job like that ‐‐
lotta time away?
About half the year.
That's why I turned it down.
Why, is that something
you want to pursue?
No, no,
but Nico sure does.
♪ Don't you get tired
of standing? ♪
Yeah, I mean,
it's a crazy schedule,
but it doesn't have to
be a dealbreaker.
And the only reason
I turned it down
is 'cause
I'm gonna be a dad.
♪ Not every question
has an answer ♪
So, you sacrificed the job
for the person you love.
Relationships are
give‐and‐take,
but I'm not
really an expert.
What I can tell you
is not saying how I feel
has never
gotten me anything.
♪♪
Okay, exciting news,
everyone!
Have you heard of
Dr. Meredith Grey, Cindy?
Grey, as in G‐Grey‐‐
Yeah, bingo.
That's the one.
Well, she's a very lovely lady
and a dear friend of mine.
And today, she's
giving away free surgeries
to anybody who needs them.
So you two are in luck.
For free?
That's impossible.
Normally, yes, but we've got
a remarkable set of donors
here at the hospital,
and there's actually
an opening in an hour.
I can prep Cindy right now
and take her up.
That's amazing.
Honey, you hear that?
They're gonna fix you up.
Okay, let's ‐‐ let's go.
So, unfortunately,
guardians aren't
allowed past
the sterile line.
It's just hospital protocol,
right? [ Breathes sharply ]
But we can escort you
up to the surgical floor,
and we can update you
every half an hour.
Okay, well, thank you,
Dr. DeLuca.
No problem.
Alright, take her up
to the surgical floor.
Grey's operating,
alright?
What?!
Grey's schedule is packed!
I don't care. I'll do it myself
if I have to, okay?
Bring her up.
Should be a straightforward
resection.
She hasn't had
any recent flare‐ups, so...
So, get in,
get out. Easy.
[ Chuckling ] Yeah.
[ Monitor beeping ]
Hey, Jo ‐‐
No. Stop.
I can tell from the way
your voice changed
that you're about to say
that you're sorry
to hear about Alex,
and I would very much like
to not talk about that
while I'm in my happy place.
So [sighs]
thank you, but no.
Got it.
[ Chuckles lightly ]
But, you know,
if you ever need a friend...
[ Sighs ]
and Teddy is great with ‐‐
y'know ‐‐ so, if you
ever want company or ‐‐
Hunt!
Shutting up.
Hey. Um, your, uh,
surgery's in OR 4.
No, our patient's
on the table.
[ Water running ]
Oops. Uh, y‐your patient
is in OR 2 now,
as soon as Pierce
finishes her fibroelastoma.
"Oops"?
Uh, you said you wanted
to shift things around.
I never said that.
But Dr. DeLuca
said you did.
Dr. DeLuca said I did?
Well, we can't move.
Our patient's already
anesthetized.
Yeah, I know!
Can we use OR 3?
Uh, still occupied.
Ruptured pseudoaneurysm.
Tell DeLuca to stay out
of my schedule,
and also tell him
to stay off my floor.
[ Water running ]
Altman. Hey.
I didn't see you
on Grey's schedule.
Do you hate the needy?
[ Chuckles ]
I knew you were just
in this for the cash.
Y‐You're not laughing
at my very funny jokes.
Is everything okay?
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ Sighs ]
It's not Owen's baby.
[ Sighs ] Oh.
Yeah.
Tom, this doesn't change
the way I feel about you.
Hmm...
But...
[ Stammers, sighs ]
[ Cellphone vibrating ]
[ Sighs ]
My patient's
MRI results are back.
Well, don't ‐‐ don't let me,
uh, keep you.
♪♪
Hey, you know, Cindy...
is there something
bothering you?
Because I‐if there is,
if there's something wrong,
I just, uh ‐‐ I want you
to know that you can
talk to me
about it, okay?
I‐I want
to keep you safe.
There's nothing wrong.
I just ‐‐
I want this to be over with
so I can go home.
Okay. Right.
I‐I'll be right back, okay?
Hey, Helm.
No.
Walk away, DeLuca,
or I'm taking out
your appendix.
That's not a very nice
way to speak to
your chief resident.
[ Chuckling ] Please.
You are barely hanging on
to that title, and after today,
you'll be falling from it,
to your death.
Look, I may have bent
the truth slightly, alright?
No, no, no, no, no,
you lied to me,
and you got me
in trouble with Grey.
And that is worse
than lying.
That is treason.
And your patient
is not getting surgery.
So go away.
[ Sighs ]
[ Elevator bell dings ] Woman
on P. A.: Dr. Perone to 4 West.
Dr. Perone to 4 West.
Excuse me, could you tell me
where to find the...?
- Are they ready?
- Uh, yeah.
You know, we just need
to take you to
the pre‐op area
right now.
This way? Thank you.
♪♪
Hey.
Anything?
Kyle has focal areas of
gliosis on his frontal lobe.
The EEG confirms
a seizure focus.
So it's potentially
fixable.
[ Sighs ]
Kyle and Ashley
will be so relieved.
I mean, his girlfriend,
she has given up
so much for him.
Is that all love is?
Just sacrifice?
You ‐‐ You meet someone you want
to be with, you have kids,
and then, poof, goodbye,
dreams, wishes, desires?
Yes.
I gave up my apartment,
my job, my universal healthcare,
my European work visa,
and for what?
[ Chuckling ] For...
For a marriage
that might work?
Teddy,
Link's the father.
And even
if it was Owen's ‐‐
Please, stop.
Are you seriously mad at me
for a hypothetical?
Hypotheticals have
consequences, too.
We need to update Kyle.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
- I was told three hours ago!
- My mom was promised
two hours ago that
she would get a bed!
Taryn: Everyone, please
lower your voices!
We can't wait.
Things went a little
off the rails, huh?
We've been doing this all day.
It's not my fault!
I need to talk to you.
Dr. Grey, my mom hasn't
eaten in 24 hours.
Neither have I.
[ Scoffs ]
Get ‐‐ Get a handle
on your operation, Grey.
These people
are about to riot.
Please, I just need
a little more time.
I know you said you
were gonna cut it off ‐‐
Whatever. Don't care.
Just finish.
I'll pay for the OT.
Griffin Ford gave us
enough money to cover
pro bono days a couple
of times a year if we want.
I‐I was gonna put in
a chiefs' lounge
with a steam room,
you know, but, uh...
Why'd he give you
so much money?
[ Sighs ]
Anterior cerebral artery
aneurysm is what the news said.
[ Sighs ]
Wow.
I knew you were dirty.
I didn't know you
were that dirty.
You're the one who
told me to trust my gut
and try to
fix the world.
Not like that!
You want to cancel your little
charity day on principle?
Be my guest.
[ Sighs ]
I didn't think so.
[ Alarm blaring ]
Woman on P. A.:
Code violet, OR waiting room.
What is that?
What's code violet?
Meredith: It means
somebody's getting violent
with hospital staff.
Hey, hey! Stay back!
Don't you come near her!
You cannot do this!
[ Door opens ]
Hey! Stay away!
[ Alarm continues ]
Stop! Stop!
Don't move! Okay? Hey!
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Dr. DeLuca.
It's okay ‐‐ I got you.
Hey, hey! Security?
Arrest this woman
for child trafficking!
[ Laughs ]
[ Indistinct murmuring ]
No! Someone help me!
Security, you heard me!
You have to let her go!
♪♪
That is my niece!
DeLuca:
Stop! Stop! Don't move!
Security,
detain her right now!
No, no, no, no one's
gonna detain anyone.
Uh... We're all just
gonna back up.
Just stay calm, DeLuca.
Andrea, please, please, please,
stop this, please.
- This man is crazy!
- I'm not crazy!
You're hurting her!
Alright, everybody,
you know what to do.
Dangerous person
in the hospital, okay?
We need to join hands, form
a human chain around her, okay?
Let's go. Come on.
Everybody, come on.
Come on!
What are you waiting for?!
Huh? Come on! Let's do it!
[ Cindy crying ]
Mer!
Yes! Yes! Finally! Come on!
Let's go.
Get around her, guys. Okay.
What?
Don't let her ‐‐ What?
What are you doing? Huh?
What are you doing?
No, no, no, no, no, no!
What? Hey!
Bailey? Mer, come on.
[ Crying ]
- Security.
- No, no, no, no, no.
This is not okay.
Bailey: Please escort
Dr. DeLuca to my office.
Stop. What? Me?!
Wh‐‐ What, you're just gonna
let her go?
Oh, my gosh...
Okay, open your eyes,
people, okay?!
She's selling human beings!
Look at her! She's
afraid! [ Crying ]
That's not love.
That's a trauma bond, okay?
She's threatening her
or ‐‐ or her family.
I‐I know it, okay?
She's ‐‐
She's torturing her!
She's selling her!
[ Voice breaking ]
Bailey, stop this, please!
If you ever want to step foot
in my hospital again,
go with security
to my office.
[ Crying ] No.
Carina: Andrea, please.
We need to save her!
Meredith:
It's okay, Andrew.
[ Sobbing ]
It's okay.
[ Sobbing continues ]
Stop it.
[ Sniffles, sighs ]
Andrea, please,
please, please.
[ Alarm continues ]
You're all blind.
[ Sniffles ]
All of you.
♪♪
[ Sniffling ]
Don't touch me!
It's okay. It's okay.
♪♪
Woman on P. A.:
Code violet, canceled.
Hey.
Hi.
I was wondering, uh, if we
should skip the bar tonight.
Maybe go somewhere
without as many windows?
I need somewhere
with windows
because every time I try to
talk to you about something,
you distract me.
[ Chuckles ]
Great. What now?
"What now"?
That's your response
to me wanting to talk?
Well, yeah, because
it's usually something
you're pissed about.
I'm not pissed, but...
I‐If you get that job,
it's going to affect us.
I think that at least
warrants a conversation.
It hasn't
even happened yet.
A‐And what if it does?
[ Scoffs ] What? What?
So you want me to
feel bad about it?
It's my dream job, Levi.
Nico, a relationship requires
sacrifice and compromise.
And I'm the only one
who ever does either of those.
Your way always goes,
and I'm tired of telling you
that I want more.
Alright.
"Alright," what?
Alright, I...
I hope you find someone
who will give that to you.
[ Scoffs ]
♪♪
[ Water running ]
I hope
everyone's alright.
I can't imagine what else
could go wrong today.
Well, you know
the old joke.
How do you get
God to laugh?
Make a plan.
[ Chuckles ]
Your kids, uh, need
a sitter when you go out,
or are they old enough
to stay home alone?
As long as I leave enough
pizza money, they're grand.
Well, I'm asking
'cause I got amazing tickets
to the game tonight.
A friend bailed on me
last minute, so...
[ Sighs ]
American football.
Don't even
get me started.
Don't even know how
you call it a sport.
I mean, they blow
the whistle and they run for,
what, 30 seconds?
In real football ‐‐
soccer ‐‐
it's 45 minutes a half,
90 minutes end‐to‐end.
That's real athleticism,
non‐stop.
Well, my father‐in‐law
used to force me
to watch
the American football.
I just ‐‐ I couldn't
get into it, man.
Used to kind of annoy me a little bit, to
be honest. [ Trash can lid opens, closes ]
So many ads.
It's a basketball game tonight,
so, a little different.
Yeah.
Not really my thing,
either, mate.
Thanks anyway.
[ Sighs ]
DeLuca!
Hey, what
are you doing?
Looking for a new job.
I quit.
I tried.
He needs help,
but he won't listen!
Okay, Andrew,
look at me, please.
No. No.
Please.
Since day one,
all I ever wanted
was to be like you,
like all of you.
You know, just a‐accomplish
the impossible,
make a difference
I‐in people's lives.
And the more I do that,
the more you all just
judge me and call me crazy,
and I'm not!
And I'm sick of it,
and I'm done!
But you are accomplishing
the impossible,
and that's why I can't
let you quit.
I'm not your business
anymore, Meredith!
I don't work for you,
and I don't love you!
But I love you.
I love you.
You went to jail for me.
You saved me
from myself.
I cannot let you
walk away from this.
Just take some time,
take the suspension,
but come on,
this is not how this ends.
If you tell Bailey
to call
the national
trafficking hotline
and investigate
that girl...
I'll take the suspension.
Done.
♪♪
How's DeLuca?
Is everything okay?
No. How are we?
What's happening?
Uh, Mrs. Freeman
still hasn't ‐‐
Hey, Mer, this Marine Corps
vet served in two wars.
If we kick him back
to the VA,
God knows how long
it's gonna take.
Uh, y‐y‐y‐yes,
he can have a spot, yes.
Whoa, wait!
You can't just give a spot away!
We've been waiting.
My mom has been waiting!
I know how long
she has been waiting.
I have been here all day
myself. [ Indistinct shouting ]
It's not fair!
It's wrong!
You know...
Woman: Is that what's happening
now ‐‐ you're giving spots away?
I know you want to
help a lot of people,
but my mom should
be one of them.
She's in agony.
You said you'd help her.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
You should not
have to apologize
for being such
a good advocate.
I am sorry that the system
is this messed up
that you have to
fight this hard.
Your mom is going
to get her surgery.
I promise.
Your Marine is going
to get his surgery.
You're all gonna
get your surgeries.
Because we have
a very generous donor
who has graciously agreed
to extend Pro Bono Surgery Day
for as long as we need.
[ Applause ]
And I'm very happy
to announce
that we are going to start doing
Pro Bono Surgery Days
once a month here
from now on.
[ Cheers and applause ]
♪ Thought I was good,
I was good on my own ♪
♪ I was alright ♪
[ Applause ]
Legend.
[ Sighs ]
♪ Thought that I knew
everything, never wrong ♪
♪ I was alright ♪
[ Door closes ]
We have good news.
We found a seizure focus,
probably due to
your traumatic injury,
and we have a plan
to cure your seizures.
♪ Oh, I lived a whole life ♪
Will that make his other
symptoms go away?
It will definitely make him
feel more like himself.
And we can testify
in court
that this condition
caused your behavior.
♪ A love I thought I knew ♪
Thank you. So much.
[ Chuckles ]
♪ Everything before us ♪
How many years until
the VA can fit me in, though?
Amelia: They're not
doing it. I am.
I got you into
the pro bono surgeries
that are happening
as we speak.
Wait. What?
You are done
waiting, Kyle.
♪ Never understood why ♪
No.
[ Both laugh ]
♪ People always say
"Love chooses you" ♪
♪ Now I do ♪
[ Laughs ]
♪ Didn't ever think that ♪
♪ I could ever say
"I promise you" ♪
I love you.
♪ And now I do ♪
♪♪
What did you say
to that doctor?
Nothing.
Yeah, well, I'm not stupid.
I know you said something.
I didn't, I swear.
My stomach really hurts.
It was your own fault,
so stop crying.
♪♪
Hey. You feel like
Richard's doing okay?
Um, considering that
your mother's lawyers
are going after him
in the separation,
I would say he's fair.
He hasn't said a word to me
since the merger.
I guess that's why.
You know he stepped down
from surgery, right?
What? No.
Why?
Innovation.
Depression.
We've tried to talk him
out of it, but, uh,
you know how
he can stonewall.
Damn.
The last thing I wanted was
to take sides in all this.
I...
Does he know that?
I thought it was obvious.
Oh, there he is.
Richard?
You got
any plans tonight?
Did Catherine send you
to spy on me?
Why would you
say that, Richard?
Would you
put it past her?
Okay, fair enough,
but the answer's no, okay?
I just have an extra ticket
to the game tonight,
which doesn't make you
an afterthought.
Uh, I guess
technically it does.
I was going with Vic,
but that's over now, so...
Uh, I'm ‐‐ I'm sorry
to hear that.
Thanks. Anyway,
I don't know if you've
been following the season,
but Mavis ‐‐
[ Chuckling ]
Are you kidding?
Mavis has been on fire!
Did you see that
3‐pointer last week?
At the buzzer?!
Ohh! [ Laughs ]
So, that's a yes,
then, or what?
A hell‐to‐the‐yes!
Let's do it.
[ Laughs ] Okay.
[ Leon Bridges'
"Coming Home" plays ]
[ Billiard balls clacking ]
♪ Baby, baby, baby ♪
♪ I'm coming home ♪
Who'd you kill?
I think
I dumped myself.
Is that even possible?
Oh, wait.
Of course it is.
I'm me.
I left all my stuff
at Nico's place
because he convinced me
to move out of my mom's house.
And I haven't found
an apartment yet.
So I'm homeless!
Do you want to stay with me
while you look for a place?
Jo, that time in my mom's
basement was a one‐time thing.
I'm a gay man.
[ Laughs ]
That's why you're getting
the invite, dummy!
Oh.
[ Sighs ]
My place is too empty,
and I'm too sad,
and I don't want
to be chased out of the place
I bought for myself
because my husband ‐‐
because my ex‐hus‐‐ I just ‐‐
I don't want to have to go.
But it needs to change.
Like, now.
Then definitely yes.
We can be super sad
together.
[ Bottles clink ]
[ Sighs ]
♪♪
Amelia:
Let's get him up to post‐op.
[ Monitor beeping ]
[ Sighs ]
You know, I've slept with
a lot of women.
[ Sighs ]
All sizes, creeds, and colors,
and I've slept with women
whose language I speak
and whose language
I don't,
women who just left
their husbands,
even women
who just left their wives.
[ Chuckles ] You know,
I don't discriminate,
but believe it or not,
I have a code.
It's a rather,
you know, bespoke...
code, but still,
it's a...
I draw the line
at married women.
Right.
And you're about
to be one.
Y‐You have
the heirloom ring.
You have the two kids.
You might as well have a dog.
[ Chuckles ]
I may not care for
Agent Orange,
but I've been the husband whose
wife sleeps with another man,
and I‐I'll never be
that guy.
♪♪
I love you, and I want
to make this easy for you.
So go home, Teddy.
Plan your wedding.
Spend time with your fiancé.
I'll be just fine.
♪♪
Mm.
[ Breathing heavily ]
[ Chuckles ]
[ Sighs ]
You know,
we could make this work.
[ Both sigh ]
We did make it work.
No, I mean
your dream job.
You ‐‐ You said it ‐‐
it has too much travel,
but you love travel.
But now there are
new things in my life
that I love more.
[ Sighs ]
I guess.
It's just scary that
from now on,
every want and need
and desire
is gonna be put on hold
for our kid.
[ Sighs ]
Promise me we'll always
fight for our dreams.
I will always fight.
I may not win.
Maybe you should
take that job.
There are
81 away games a year.
Okay,
but the next dream.
[ Laughs ]
[ Maggie Koerner's
"If I Die" plays ]
Meredith: It's been said
that you haven't lived today
unless you have done
something for someone
who can never repay you.
♪ What would the weight
of the world say today? ♪
But that's easier
said than done.
♪ If she had a voice to give ♪
Hey, hey, what's wrong?
♪ And how much more
can we try to ignore? ♪
I, um...
[ Sniffles ]
♪ If we have a choice
in how to live ♪
♪ If I lay ♪
Owen, I...
♪ If I should die ♪
What?
I ju‐‐ I, um...
I had a really...
[sniffles]
♪ If I lay, I'll go away
to the mountain ♪
I had a really
rough patient.
♪ I'm gonna bury this hole
in our hands ♪
A vet.
War was hell ‐‐
home was hell.
He's just been through
[sniffles] so much.
♪ I swear to God I become
the biggest sin ♪
Yeah.
♪ If I die, ooh, ooh ♪
I'm sure
you helped him.
Come here.
[ Sobbing ]
♪ If I die ♪
♪ Have you ever wondered ♪
♪ What you look like inside? ♪
Because when your
life's a mess,
it's hard to be much help
to anyone else.
Hey.
I called
the trafficking hotline.
They told me not to scare
the suspect away.
But they're gone.
DeLuca.
What if he was right?
[ Sighs lightly ]
♪ And how much more
can we try to ignore? ♪
♪ If we have a choice
in how to live ♪
Tea?
Thanks.
Mm‐hmm.
♪ If I lay, if I should die ♪
Well, you did it.
♪ I'd go down in
a wall full of flames ♪
Yeah, I single‐handedly
saved American medicine.
I wish I had something more
encouraging to say.
I see it now.
The twisted‐ness.
Took you long enough.
Thanks for your help today.
And if that sounds too hard...
[ Motorcycle revving ]
♪ If I die before I live ♪
♪ I swear to God I become
the biggest sin ♪
♪ If I die, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ If I die ♪
♪♪
Well, this might
not be the life for you.
♪♪