Oh, ooh! My God, it is cold!
It must be 20 below
with the wind chill.
This is no place for a Mexican.
I thought you hated
to work night shift.
I'm filling in for Haleh.
I think we're going to see
plenty of frostbite tonight.
And bumsicles.
I hate the smell when they thaw.
Oh, place looks dead.
Well, this guy certainly is.
Randi, you know we
got a DB in the hallway?
The morgue's slow.
I put him next to the
door to keep him cool.
Ah, good thinking.
Is this board right?
Yeah. Not a single patient.
Yeah, it's too cold to be sick.
I guess I'll have some time
to work on my curriculum vitae.
What's that?
That's a fancy word for resume.
I've got tenure
review this week.
You want to join the faculty?
It'd be nice.
Dr. Greene?
Legal sent you this letter
and these charts to be signed.
They're writing me up
for not co-signing charts.
Will that hurt your
chance for tenure?
It won't help.
Competition pretty stiff?
It's about 5' 4",
red hair with a limp.
Lydia?
How'd you like to
make an easy 50 bucks?
How?
I got a grant to
study the effect
of exercise on the
circadian rhythms
of night-shift workers.
Is that why E. Ray's doing
jumping jacks in
the suture room?
Yes, but we need
one more subject.
My publishing
deadline's in two days
so I'm kind of in a bind.
Sorry. Not interested.
All right, we'll keep looking.
Wendy.
Mafkariyega keya wakt hoowa-hey?
Repeat.
Very good.
How much are a dozen bananas?
Ek darjan kele kitne ke-hey?
Repeat.
Ek darjan kel kitne ke-hey?
Very good.
Thank you.
Aren't you supposed
to be on a plane
in 12 hours, to Karachi?
I left the packing
till the last minute.
I'm going to be here all night.
Well, that presents
certain opportunities.
I have to pack.
Please.
Why don't you come back at 3:00?
I'll set my watch alarm.
Dr. Keaton?
Hey, have you seen Carter?
Someone said he came in here.
Doesn't look like it.
Oh, sorry.
Have a safe trip.
Thank you. Bye-bye.
Carol?
Mary, what's up?
Budget just came out.
We've got a crisis conference
tomorrow morning, first thing.
Crisis conference?
E.R. nursing's $94,000 over.
Well, can't we
add to the budget?
No, you're gonna have
to let two nurses go.
But, Mary, I'm
understaffed as it is.
Name me a department
that isn't, Carol.
The County's out of money.
There's just no way around it.
Now, you've got
three junior RN's.
You've got Maleek... Malik.
Malik Mcgrath, Chuny
Marquez and Connie...
Oligario.
You can keep one of them.
Well, which two get the axe?
That's your decision.
Oh, Mary, I don't know.
I've never done this before.
I have to have an answer
by the meeting tomorrow.
Are you on tonight?
Yeah.
Leave it on my e-mail.
Make sure I get it by
8:00 in the morning.
Okay, if you could choose
how to check out,
how would you do it?
That's morbid.
I guess if I could choose
how to die, I'd go by OD.
A quick stroke would be better.
If you survive, then
you're an end table.
Still no patients, Malik?
Nope, but we got
takeout... Antonio's.
We couldn't find you,
so we ordered your usual.
Oh, great. How much
do I owe you, Chuny?
Ah, put it away.
No, come on, Connie.
No, we've got you covered.
Hey. Thanks, guys.
Hey, tell me, are my hands cold?
Oh, God! Sadist!
Listen, I'm sorry about
that old surprise
Christmas morning.
Santa didn't come?
I stuck in a tag of
Christian goodwill
and I opened my door to
a homeless street urchin.
Actually, Doug,
you opened my door.
That's right. I opened her door.
She stole my
mother's silverware.
Tell Helen I'll pay for it.
She won't accept your money.
All right, but I'm not
going to offer again.
My New Year's resolution
is to resist
charitable impulses.
Mark, Risk Management called,
said we're overdue
for a safety check.
Why tell me?
You're the designated
safety officer.
They want it done
tonight. That's the checklist.
Wait, look, I've got 50
more charts to do here.
Why don't Carol and I take it.
Hey, what happened to
resisting charitable impulses?
Speaking of, anyone
want to sign up
for our night shift study?
No!
Boy, it is dead.
Finished all my charts.
It's not even 9:00 yet.
Want some action?
What do you got in mind?
Edson's sick.
If you're willing to sprint
at a moment's notice
you can take his
place on the code team.
Absolutely.
Hey, John, he boned me, man.
Benton wouldn't
let you off, huh?
Two days is all I asked for.
Son of a bitch.
You know, Dennis
if Monique is already
with this other guy
then there's probably
nothing you can do about it
even if you did fly down there.
Well, I'd sure as hell
like the chance to try.
Hey, you want to go to
that place down the street
and get some of those
home fries with gravy?
No, I wish I could. I've
got all these charts to do.
Okay. I hear you.
Look, if Benton asks,
I'll be back in an hour.
Yeah.
I thought you
finished the charts.
I have been
listening to him moan
about that girlfriend
for two weeks.
Tonight is slow enough.
So who's our first
lucky customer?
Lady with a fever.
Fell asleep at Doc Magoo's.
Waitress brought her in.
She's kind of loopy, no I.D.
Says her name's Shelly.
No needles.
I just want to sleep.
Temp's 103.
And look at this.
Photophobia.
Shelly, I'm Dr. Greene.
I need to examine you.
Leave me alone.
You have symptoms of meningitis,
which is really serious.
We need to do a spinal
tap, just to be sure.
No.
At least, let me give
you a shot of antibiotics.
No. No needles, I said.
Shelly, if you do
have meningitis
and we don't treat
you, you could die.
Die, cry, let me fry.
Do you know where you are?
In the hospital...
talking to Dr. Greene
with a head like a bean.
Do you know what day it is?
Thursday, January 16.
Bing!
Correct, Alex Trebek.
Next: "Stupid
questions" for 200.
I'm 90 percent
sure it's meningitis,
which is probably causing
her altered mental status.
She won't even
let me take blood.
She's not competent to
make her own decisions.
I need a consent override.
You've got to run it
by Risk Management.
No, I don't.
Yeah, you do. It just came down.
All consent overrides
go through legal.
Fine. Call them and tell them
that I'm doing a spinal tap
on a demented woman
without her consent.
Well, we've got
some loose tile here
and some crumbling grout.
Faulty tile and grout.
Yeah, this could be trouble
if it fell into an open wound.
Trouble, indeed.
Good catch.
Did you write down
those wobbly I.V. stands?
Roger that.
You know, you've got
a real flair for this, Carol.
Thank you.
You know...
This clock looks like it
could fall right off the wall.
You know, I don't
know how you do it.
It's well established that night
work disrupts circadian rhythms.
Yeah, I've heard that.
Our study hopes to prove
that moderate physical exertion
can switch circadian rhythms
back into phase.
When you say "moderate
physical exertion...?"
Oh, you know, just a
few minutes' exercise,
a jog around the block...
Nothing strenuous.
It's all set up in
the suture room.
I don't know if I'll be
a really good subject.
I'm not in really good shape.
You look plenty healthy to me.
Ow!
Whoa!
Oh, my God.
Kerry, are you all right?
What were you doing up there?
Safety check. You okay?
I'm bleeding.
I can stitch it up.
Yeah, I prefer Jeanie.
Okay.
And we were doing so well.
Hey, Maggie, you
got anything good?
Carol Hathaway dropped
a clock on Weaver's head.
Deliberately?
I'm foggy on the details.
Hey, kids, we got
paramedics pulling up.
Now we're talking.
Hey, nobody called
for a surgical consult.
I'm saving you the trouble
of having to page me.
Found him on the floor of
his house in acute distress.
Complains of
chest and belly pain.
Vitals normal. Wouldn't
let us start an I.V.
Does this hurt?
Ow! Looks like a
surgical abdomen.
I haven't made that assessment.
Since I'm here,
you don't have to.
Should I call for an attending?
No. No.
Up and over.
All right, let's get
an I.V. started.
I think I hear a rub.
I may have a pulsatile mass.
Give me a 12-lead
and a chest film.
Give me a cross-table abdomen.
Which one first?
Chest.
Abdomen. He could have
an aneurysm about to blow.
I don't want to
miss an acute MI.
I don't want to miss a triple-A.
If it's an MI, he
needs TPA right away.
An aneurysm needs
to go to the O.R.
Time is heart muscle.
You ever have an aneurysm
blow up in your face?
Hey, guys.
I'm feeling much better.
Sir, you need to lie down.
You need X rays.
No, I'm fine, except
for a stuffy nose.
Could I have a flu shot?
Oh, man. I remember this dude.
When he wants a
ride to the hospital
he calls 911 and plays possum.
But I'm on Social Security.
I can't afford a cab. And
it's too cold for the bus.
You came in for a flu shot?
If it wouldn't be
too much trouble.
He's all yours.
Gee, thanks.
I'm just saying,
there's no point in me
going back to general surgery.
You've learned all
there is to know?
I want to do another
pediatric rotation.
Why?
I want to be a
pediatric surgeon.
Without Dr. Keaton's
recommendation
that's not very likely.
Look, Dr. Keaton and I
had stylistic differences.
She herself said that my
technique was excellent.
Who would you work under?
Kenner.
Well, you're in luck.
He's doing a jejunal
atresia tonight. Talk to him.
If he'll take you,
you're back in Pediatric.
Okay. Would it be possible
for me to cover Pedes SICU?
That way, I can
get an opportunity
to work with Kenner.
Anything else?
No, thank you.
Chuny, you got that LP tray?
By the door.
Lydia, why don't
you give us a hand.
We may need to muscle her.
Uh, Mark...
Why won't you tell
me your address?
Excuse me. Who are you?
Dr. Greene?
Pat Guinet, Associate
Hospital Counsel.
You want to do a spinal
tap on this patient?
That's right.
She's not too keen on the idea.
Well, I've assessed her
as mentally incompetent.
We just had a fairly
coherent conversation.
Is that a medical diagnosis?
Look, Doctor, she's
clearly a borderline case.
We have been sued by
these patients in the past.
I'm trying to save her life
and you're talking
legal exposure.
Yeah. That's
what I'm paid to do.
Well, I'm paid to help
sick people get better.
Listen, I'm not going to
wrestle with you, Doctor,
but I'm writing on the
chart you're advised against
doing any procedure
on this woman
without her consent
and you and anyone
who assists you will be putting
your jobs in jeopardy.
Get a Psych consult.
If they agree she's incompetent
put her on a hold and proceed.
Until then, don't touch her.
Just one more stitch.
So, have you given
any more thought
to participating in my study?
I've got a lot of paperwork
I need to catch up on.
It won't take much time...
It's just 15 minutes
every couple of hours.
If we get busy, that
could be a problem.
It's been slow so far.
My being HIV-positive
won't skew the results?
Won't make a bit of difference.
Tonight's my last
night to collect data
and if I... ow!
My findings will be incom...
well, worthless, really
but if you're too busy
I respect your decision...
Just as I've always respected
and supported your decisions.
What would I have to do?
He scores!
Ah, we finally get
a bona fide patient?
Yeah, but we're not
allowed to touch her.
She asked for another
blanket and a snack.
Oh, so we're not a hospital...
We're a bed-and-breakfast.
Did Psych come down?
No, not yet.
Try again. I'll
be in the lounge.
You call missing persons?
Yeah, but so far,
no one's missed her.
We got a wheelchair
with no brakes
and three I.V.
stands are wobbling.
What are we supposed
to do with them all?
Hey!
Ugly...
Well, if it isn't
my favorite thief.
Hey, you got your wallet back.
What about my
mother's silverware?
I didn't take it, I swear.
Charlie, do I have
to call security
or you going to
leave by yourself?
No. Listen, man, I
need some bread.
No, I'm serious.
There's this dude
trying to pimp me,
and I don't want to...
He says I got to
pay him 100 bucks
or he's going to kill me.
Well, maybe we
should tell the cops.
No, man. I don't deal with cops.
And I don't deal with liars
who take advantage of
people who try to help them.
You're a creep, you know that?
Yep.
A creep and a pervert!
That's right!
This doctor made
me go down on him!
He gave me VD!
He got me pregnant
and now he wants me
to pay for the abortion!
Child molester!
Lovely girl.
Dr. Kenner, I'm Peter Benton.
I wanted to talk to you
about doing a pediatric
surgical rotation.
You were with Dr. Keaton.
Yeah. She's leaving...
This isn't a good time.
I'll find you later.
Okay, well, I'll be in
Pedes SICU all night.
You were looking for me?
Yeah, you're on
SICU with me tonight.
I thought Zeidenberg
was on SICU.
Order everyone's labs
and advance the
drain on bed three.
Here's one for you:
"Longing for your embrace.
"Financial Officer
seeks life of adventure
with very special lady."
Forget it.
Sounds like money, honey.
What are we gonna talk
about, Dow averages?
Keep going.
"Sensual MD, 35, 6'1."
I like tall.
"Makes up in passion
what he lacks in hair."
Not me.
I'm not so desperate
that I have to use personals.
You calling me desperate?
No, no, no. That's
not what I meant.
So where do you
find all your dates?
Actually, I haven't
had one in a while.
See?
Don't knock it
till you try it.
Dr. Greene, Psych's here
on that lady.
Who is it? McDonald?
No. It's some intern.
I didn't realize we were
coming down this hallway.
Neither did I.
Hey, which room was it, anyway?
I don't know.
Either this door or this one.
No, Doug, it's this one.
Oh, you're right.
A lot of stolen
moments in there, huh?
Yes, there were.
So should we?
What?
Open the door.
Yeah, sure. Why not?
Come on.
You got it?
Mm-hmm.
Oh. Did it always
smell like this?
I think it did.
Now, if I remember
I bet we've still
got some candles.
What?
Yep. Look at this.
Got a match?
Oh, my God.
Shelly, I'll ask you to commit
three things to memory:
A fire engine, a mobile home
and, um, a pen.
Why?
Just try to remember them.
Now, can you tell me the date?
Get away!
Temp's up to 103.5.
We're running out of time.
Shelly, the date?
I already told Dr. Green Bean.
Was she oriented to time?
More or less.
Oriented to time.
Shelly, can you spell
"world" backwards?
U-o-y-w-e-r-c-s.
Screw you...
Backwards.
Right.
Good concentration.
Now, can you remember
the things I told you earlier?
Yes.
What are they?
Fire engine, a
pen, a mobile home.
Now, leave me alone, Cornpone.
She's oriented to
person, time and place
and her mental
status exam is normal.
She's uncooperative,
she speaks in rhyme
and she's
indifferent to the fact
that she could die
without treatment.
There are specific criteria
to define incompetence.
She doesn't meet them.
We're talking about
a woman with no I.D.
found passed
out in a restaurant.
She still doesn't
meet the criteria.
Do you realize that your
decision could kill her?
You know, that kind of
hyperbole isn't very helpful.
The fact is, patients have a
right to make bad decisions.
Not when they're demented.
That's where we disagree.
Get McDonald down here.
Tell him it's life or death.
Dr. Benton? Yeah.
The Serena kid's in
second-degree heart block.
Where's his chart?
This is Kenner's patient?
Yeah, but Kenner's
back in surgery.
Where're the labs?
On the chart.
The calcium's not here.
Well, it must not
have been picked up.
Give him 30 of Lasix, I.V. push
and run a liter of saline.
We've got to diurese him.
Where the hell is Gant?
I don't know.
Damn!
Dr. Fogg at Cambridge
did a similar study with rodents
and found he could
double serum-cortisol
with five minutes
on the treadmill.
How many more minutes do I have?
Fifteen.
Dr. Weaver, I'm getting
a reading of 500 lux.
Put the goggles on her.
Goggles?
The lights in here
approximate daylight.
We want to make sure
your body thinks it's night.
Aha. What else do
I have to do, Kerry?
One more exertion test
heart and lung
readings, and that's it.
Yeah, Wendy, let's
take the RPM's up to 90.
No.
Okay.
You know, I met the
guy once, last summer.
Some type of mortgage broker.
Mm-hmm.
I just don't know when
she started seeing him.
Gant, what are you
doing down here
when there's a
kid up in the SICU
dying of hypercalcemia?
Kenner's patient.
You were supposed
to monitor his calcium.
I sent the labs in.
What good is sending the labs in
if you don't check them?
They said it was
going to take an hour.
Gant, look at this.
13.5.
The kid went into
a Brady arrhythmia.
I was about to go get them.
You know, Gant, that's the
kind of excuse that kills patients.
Now, look, if you
can't do the job,
or don't want to the job
then you don't need to be here.
You make another stupid,
lazy mistake like that
man, you won't be.
Hey. Hey, you okay?
Uh... oh, it's a code.
I'm on the code team.
Listen, we'll talk, all right?
We'll talk when I get back.
It's weird being
down here again.
Makes me realize how
unhappy I was then.
When you were with me?
Yeah. I mean, it
wasn't your fault.
I just didn't think
much of myself.
I'm sure I didn't help.
Well, a lot of
stuff didn't help.
But it's just different
now, you know?
I actually feel good.
So, what's different, besides
us not being together?
Well, you know, I used to
think I couldn't do things.
Now I'm taking a pre-med course.
Well, I trust you did
well on your midterms.
B-plus.
Clearly, you're not
trying hard enough.
Yeah.
I guess it's about feeling
in control, you know?
I guess.
And then, of course, there's
things you can't control.
Such as?
Administration's making
me fire two nurses.
Really?
Yeah, but don't tell anyone.
None of them know
and I don't know
who it's gonna be.
I'm not going to say a thing.
You know what's
really depressing?
What?
Being here right now.
It makes me realize
how much happier
I was back then.
God, you're pathetic.
Yes.
You're on the code team?
I was going to ask
you the same thing.
Well, where is A-360?
I was just going
to ask that, too.
Hey, you know where A-360 is?
Somebody's having
a heart attack.
Sorry. Have you
seen the men's room?
Got a report of a
toilet overflowing.
Nope, can't help you.
290, 310...
that's 320...
330...
It must be this way.
I'll do central
line, you intubate.
I'll do the central line.
Ever run the code before?
I've run more
codes than you have.
Well, here's the toilet.
Code team? Yeah.
You're a little late.
Oh, no.
All right, I'll take over.
I got it.
He's got a rhythm.
Yeah, I got a pulse.
Oh, thank God.
CPR course finally paid off.
Now, if I could
just find that john.
Dr. Carter will show you.
You know why I hate
going to a shrink?
Why?
Because you have to talk
about yourself all the time.
That's kind of the point, Doug.
No, it's embarrassing.
I tell her about my patients.
She lets you do that?
Sometimes.
She says I prefer
talking about them
'cause solving their problems
is easier than solving my own.
That's probably true.
Sometimes yeah, sometimes no.
You thinking about Charlie?
No. It's... I was
tough on her today.
Well, no, you gave her a chance.
Several.
There's a certain point
you just got to
say, "no, it's over."
Hmm.
Why do those words
sound familiar to me?
Hey, Mark.
Connie and I wrote
a personal ad for you.
Want to hear it?
Sure.
Okay, "Sensitive doctor,
tall, white and handsome..."
Handsome? Really?
Sure. Why not?
"Loves the Cubs
and Kawasakis..."
Wait, wait. Hold
on. I own a bike.
I don't know if I love it.
Say it anyway. Chicks
love guys with bikes.
That reminds me, I
got mine in the garage.
Your bike?
Yeah, the attendant
let me keep it here
for the winter, but I
haven't run it in awhile.
Your battery is gonna die.
I know. I've got to start it up.
Don't mention the bike thing.
I mean, I don't want to
attract motorcycle chicks.
You mean someone like me?
No, I didn't mean...
Mark, Shelly's not in her room,
and her clothes are gone too.
Check the rest rooms.
I did that already.
Randi, Randi, did you see
a female patient leave here?
Brown hair and red hat? Yeah.
Yeah, she just left.
I'll get security.
Can you grab my coat?
Yeah.
Shelly.
Shelly?
Shelly, you need
to come back inside.
I want the bus.
Shelly, listen to me.
You're very sick.
We need to treat you, okay?
Right away.
Go away.
Shelly, come on.
Hey. Hey, hey!
Put me down! Help! Help!
I want to go on the bus!
Hey!
Put me down!
Help! Help!
Help!
Why are you hurting me?
Grab her legs.
Chuny, take her shoulders.
Malik, bring her knees
up to her chest.
What are you doing?
I'm going give you a
shot to numb the skin.
No! No needles, please!
No!
I don't see a Psych hold.
Help me.
I got tired of waiting.
Help... Help...
Hold still. Help me!
I want the names
of everyone here.
Chuny Marquez.
Lydia Wright.
Malik McGrath.
No, please.
No.
I got fluid.
Nope. It's just that there I was
baring my soul in a way
I never really have before
and all of a sudden,
I hear snoring.
I'm sorry. I'm so tired.
Oh, God, and I've got 5½ hours
to make my big staff decision.
What am I gonna do?
I'm sorry. I wasn't
listening. What?
Oh, you're hilarious.
Oh, my God.
Charlie?
Connie, get a gurney!
Let's go!
What happened? Let me see.
He found me.
The pimp?
Get the gurney, Connie!
Hey.
Benton was out of line.
Was he?
Way out of line.
I felt like punching
out the bastard.
That would be unwise.
I suppose I could tell Anspaugh.
Then again, I don't know.
I think Benton's
right, you know?
Lately, I been one step behind
five minutes too late.
See you.
I thought you were
covering the E.R.
It's dead.
What I wouldn't give
for a good five-car pileup.
It's 3:00.
Time for the Charlie
Chan mystery movie.
And what's the
point of this, exactly?
We want to compare
your Cortisol levels
after indoor and
outdoor exertion.
That's it, right, Kerry?
No more sweating after this.
Get your knees up,
like a drum major.
That's it. There you go.
Go. Go. Go.
Okay, sweetheart,
now squeeze this hand.
Good. All right.
Now squeeze this hand.
Ow!
That's okay.
That's all right.
Okay, she's got a
broken right ulna.
Ears are clear.
All right. Can you
move your jaw for me?
Side to side.
It hurts.
It's okay. You're
going to be fine.
Let's get a Panorex.
I think she's got a broken jaw.
Let's get a film of the
chest, right arm, orbits.
Doug?
She has bruising
around her groin.
She may have been raped.
Okay.
All right, kiddo.
It's okay.
So you got an idea
that's gonna make
you a millionaire?
Yeah. Money in the bank.
All right. Let's hear it.
Flypaper in a can...
Say what?
It's like aerosol.
You spray it on your
car so bugs will stick to it.
Then you peel off one big sheet,
then boom, your car is clean.
You're kidding, right?
No. I'll call it "bug-off."
That's the dumbest
idea I ever heard.
Yeah. Why not just
clean it with a hose?
Okay, I got another one.
Stethoscope condoms.
I don't even want to know.
Take my advice:
Don't quit your day job.
How's it going?
Oh, Dr. Kenner.
We had a bit of a
scare with this one.
His calcium went up to 13.5,
which sent him into
second-degree heart block.
I had to diurese him
but we got him back
to a normal sinus.
Well, looks fine now.
Good work.
Thank you.
Oh, uh, Dr. Kenner...
I'd like to do another
pediatric rotation
and I'd like to do it with you.
Uh... correct me if I'm wrong.
I understood that Dr. Keaton
isn't recommending you.
Hmm. She told you that.
Well, it is a pretty small club.
We do talk occasionally.
Dr. Kenner, I learned
a lot from Dr. Keaton
but, um...
our styles were very different.
We didn't quite... mesh.
Why don't you
talk to her and, uh...
tell her your perspective
about not meshing and so on
and maybe she'll reconsider.
And if she did?
Then we could talk.
But, um...
without a recommendation,
I really can't help you.
Where am I going?
To Radiology.
We're going to take some X rays
and then we're gonna use a
machine called a CAT scan,
make sure your head's okay.
I'm scared.
It's okay.
I'll come with you.
Doug?
Hang on.
You want me to get a rape kit?
I'm gonna talk to her,
see if I can find
out what happened.
Okay.
Which bone would you choose?
I don't know, maybe a finger.
No. If I had to choose
which bone to break
I'd choose a clavicle.
Oh, that's good, no
surgical intervention.
Personally, I'd go
with a skull fracture.
Oh, you would.
Hey, Carol.
"Venture to Karachi
on the rugged
"Grand Trunk road,
which, while breathtaking
"is prone to landslides
and occasional firefights
by warring sectarian factions."
Abby, don't go.
Put the book down.
Dr. Keaton?
Did you lock the door?
I thought you did.
No, I...
Dr. Keaton, I...
Peter, could you
wait outside, please?
Anything?
Just doing the ink stain now.
I admire you, Dr. Greene.
That took guts.
Well, thank you
for your support.
And don't worry
about that lawyer
'cause I'm going to
take full responsibility.
They can't fire all of us.
Yeah.
Sorry if I offended you earlier
with that motorcycle crack.
Takes a lot to offend me.
Yeah, but seriously
I'd be lucky to find
someone like you.
Want to get the lights?
Oh, yeah.
Is it meningitis?
Cryptococcus.
You were right.
Randi, have you seen
a big, black binder?
The nursing budget?
Yeah.
Uh, it fell out of the cubby.
So, I sort of
started looking at it.
Well, where is it?
Bad news for some people, huh?
You shouldn't have
been looking at it.
I was curious.
I took an accounting course
for my fashion line, you know.
Well, that's no excuse.
It's the overtime
that's killing you.
What?
ER nurses work 12-hour shifts
and after eight hours,
they get overtime.
That's what's screwing
with your budget.
Well, I don't know
what else we can do.
Put everybody on
eight-hour shifts.
You'd save 100 grand a year.
I know how these
teacher/intern relationships
can undermine reputations...
The innuendo and rumors.
I need to know if you're
going to be discreet about this.
Dr. Keaton, I came by
to see if you would
reconsider writing me
a recommendation.
Oh.
I mean, you've always
complimented my surgical skills.
A recommendation on that basis
I could get another
pediatric rotation.
And if I don't?
What do you mean, if you don't?
Will you report my
relationship with Dr. Carter?
You think I'm threatening you?
Are you?
Dr. Keaton, if your
recommendation
isn't based on my
abilities as a doctor
I don't want it.
I can't do that, Peter.
You've got the makings
of an excellent surgeon
but not a pediatric surgeon.
Dr. Greene, another
letter from Legal.
Ah, what do you know?
I've been written up again.
Wow. Twice in one night.
They CC'd Anspaugh.
That was very thoughtful.
Jerks.
Why don't I just get
some 8 x 11 frames
and I can just put these
right up on the wall.
You should do it.
Dr. Greene, this is
George Dunleavy.
Hi. What can I do for you?
The police said that you may
have found my sister, Shelly.
She called a couple of days ago
and said she was sick.
I told her to go see a doctor.
Haven't heard from her since.
Does your sister have
any psychiatric problems?
No.
She was pretty incoherent.
Meningitis can cause
temporary dementia.
Will she be all right?
Take a day or two,
but she should be fine.
Thank you, doctor.
Sure.
Dr. Benton, I just
want to let you know
that Dr. Keaton and I
never talked about you,
never said anything about you
remotely negative ever.
Carter, it never occurred
to me that you had.
Dr. Benton, we were
just talking about you.
Dr. Gant feels
that you've treated
him inappropriately
by publicly upbraiding him.
Calling him lazy and stupid,
I understand?
No, no, no. I said what
he did was lazy and stupid.
I don't think that
was inappropriate
due to the fact that his
inattention almost killed a child.
That's not true.
You neglected your duties.
If you feel that way, then
you come speak to me...
You don't yell at me...
All right.
Settle down.
Carter...
You were there, weren't you?
Mm-hmm.
Do you feel
Dr. Benton's reaction
was inappropriate?
Well, his language was strong,
and I can certainly
understand how Dennis feels.
But given the circumstances
I'm not sure I'd
call it inappropriate.
Sounds like you
have to develop
thicker skin, Dr. Gant
and if similar issues
arise in the future
I suggest you
take them up with
Dr. Benton directly
before you come crying to me.
The hard truth is, we
don't have any more money.
Word came down that they
want me to let people go.
So who gets fired?
Nobody.
I just sent up a proposal
that will solve our
budget problems
without anyone
losing their jobs.
You're cutting back hours?
No. But instead of working
three 12-hour shifts a week
everyone will work
five eight-hour shifts.
For the same money?
A little less.
But we have to work
four hours more a week.
That sucks.
Guys, the alternative is
that two of you are history.
I don't buy that.
They got the money.
I'm not giving up my
OT, I'll tell you that.
None of us are.
We've got a contract
negotiation coming up.
If management pulls this
we walk.
That's right.
I didn't think you'd
really go to Anspaugh.
Look, I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
I didn't know what to say.
With Benton
standing right there...
John, John, it's okay.
I didn't mean to
put you on the spot.
So we're cool?
Yeah, we're cool.
I better get back to the ER.
I'll see you later.
It's like an x-ray of your head.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Will you stay with me?
I'll be in the next room.
Charlie, were you raped?
Promise you won't tell the
cops or the social worker?
I'm not going to tell anybody.
Okay.
You're going to be okay.
Here we go.
Hey, Mark!
Mark!
Hey, you forgot
your curriculum vitae.
Oh, thanks.
But after tonight, I
figure my chances
for making tenure are about nil.
But hey, I did my job
and I can do my job somewhere
tenure or no tenure.
Same here.
They're trying to
mess with our overtime.
I say screw them.
I'll go someplace else.
That's the spirit.
Well, got to go.
Hey, Chuny, you hungry? You
want to grab some breakfast with me?
Sure.
Okay, first, I got to
take the bike for a spin
around the garage just
to charge the battery.
Why don't I charge
it up with you?
Sure. Hop on.
You want me to
get inside this box?
This box is a body
plethysmograph.
It's the most accurate method
for measuring lung capacity.
And why is that important?
I need accurate specifications
on all my research subjects
or I can't correlate the data.
I'm sorry, Kerry. I
get claustrophobic.
Jeanie, look at all the
windows. You can look out.
I'm sorry, I can't.
Jeanie, if you
don't get in the box
I have to throw out the entire
study. That's two months work.
I'm not getting in the box.
You're getting paid $50.
Shut up, Wendy.
Jeanie, please.
I'm sorry. I can't.
Well, how about that?
Wendy...
What?
Get in the box.
First, we'll test
your lung volume
and then you're
getting on the bike.
But it's almost daylight.
Wear the goggles.
You won't know the difference.
How is she?
She's got a broken arm.
A lot of bruises, concussion.
She was raped.
I'll get the rape kit
and call the police.
What time does that
social worker get here?
They should be on now.
You want me to call?
No. I'll do it.
Hey, the eggs are burning.
Oh, well.
I'll just have to
make some more.
Mm.
I don't remember
calling for a surgeon.
Well, this one's surgical.
Finally got a good one.
Some guy got hit by the El.
What you got?
We got a mess. Take a look.
Yuck.
Which end is up?
Jumped or fell
in front of a train.
Open skull fracture,
multiple extremity fractures,
flailed chest.
Any signs of life?
He's got a weak pulse.
Now all he needs is a face.
BP's 60/40.
He ain't going to last.
All right, grab
hold, on my count.
One, two, three.
What is this?
Man versus moving El train.
Suicide?
One guy said he jumped,
the other guy said he tripped.
Just lost the pulse.
Put O-neg on a rapid
infuser, set up a central line.
Somebody page Gant he's
supposed to cover the ER.
I'll do it.
Carter, how are his eyes?
He's lost one.
The other one is swollen shut.
Grey matter in the hair.
Decreased breath
sounds on the right.
I'll put in a chest
tube. I'll do it.
No. I'll do it. It's a
surgical procedure.
Whose beeper?
It's coming from the patient.
Lydia, what number
did you page Gant to?
This room. 3376.
That's the number
on this pager.
Oh, my God.
What?
The patient.
It's Gant.
Dennis?
Oh, sweet Jesus!
Carter, put the tube in!
Oh, God!
Set up a thorasceal!
Flatline.
Give an amp of epi and atropine.
Hang another two
units. Let's go, Carter!
I'm trying! I'm trying!
Come on Carter! Get it in!
Come on, Gant.
Come on.