I'm proposing a mobile unit.
If the patients can't get
to us, we gotta go to them.
You have no knowledge of
the way this place operates
or the chain of command.
You're resistant to change.
It's only going to hinder
your ability moving forward.
CPD didn't find any
evidence of forced entry.
But I know how I felt.
Someone was in my house.
Wow.
What is all this?
- Good morning.
Good morning.
Have a seat.
Uh, careful now.
I might outstay my welcome.
Would that be such a bad thing?
Are you asking me to move in?
Why not?
I mean, hasn't this
been kind of fun?
Uh, what part?
Being driven from my home
by a crazed stalker or...
I know the circumstances
were not ideal,
but I love sharing
a home with you.
And I don't want that to end.
Oh, Dennis, I don't know
if I'm in the right headspace
for discussing
long-term plans right now.
I hear you. I hear you.
But you think about it.
Of course I will.
I'm hearing we're down
and OB and a charge nurse.
And good morning to you,
too, Dr. Archer.
And you approved this, did you?
Maggie and Hannah are doing
a mobile women's health clinic
on the South Side.
I sent you a memo
about it last week.
We need them on the floor.
I don't disagree,
but I was overruled.
By Goodwin?
This initiative
has her full support.
This is a one-time thing?
- For now.
- Mm-hmm.
What time are they back?
Read the memo.
Oh!
Smell that deliciousness.
Mmm. Harold's Chicken.
They're all over Chicago.
Not just any Harold's Chicken.
It's the original,
without a doubt the best.
You gotta show some respect.
Are you all doing
the well-women exams?
- Oh, we're just setting up.
- We are, yeah. Here.
Get you to take a seat
right here.
Do you need anything?
We have snacks.
We've got granola bars,
crackers, chips.
- I'm okay. Thanks.
- Okay.
Was I too thirsty?
- Kind of.
I just really need
a good turnout today.
It's the only way we convince
the board to keep funding this.
But we don't open
for another 45 minutes,
and we already have a patient.
We got this.
- Yeah.
Relax.
Okay.
Dr. Archer, take trauma 1.
- Got it, trainee.
Talk to me, Matt.
Jordan Bennett,
16-year-old male.
Fell off a reach
during a rock slide
at the South County State Park.
He's critical.
- How far did he fall?
- About 20 feet.
Massive head trauma,
arrested during transpo.
ROSC after 1 amp of epi.
Doesn't sound encouraging.
The buddy's right behind us.
Tried to rescue Jordan after
the fall, then slipped himself.
He's a real hero.
Hmm.
Let's hope for a happy ending.
Ready?
On my count. One, two, three.
- Trauma 3 is ready for you.
- Thanks, Trini.
Cody Lawson, 15-year-old
male, chest pain and bruising
from falling on the crag.
Lacerations on both arms,
a fractured left wrist,
and left knee injury.
Looks a lot better
than his friend.
Well, he rolled.
His friend fell.
- Makes a difference.
Need X-ray in here.
Get him on a vent and
place a second large-bore IV.
These boys hiking alone?
No, they were part of a group,
some kind of adventure camp.
The counselor could
tell you more.
He's coming in on the next ambo.
All right, second IV's in.
I'll check on Frost.
I know, buddy. I know.
We're getting you something
for the pain, all right?
How's he doing?
A couple of bruised ribs,
wrist, and a knee injury.
But he's gonna be okay.
Um, Dr. Frost?
Is that a rash?
It looks like insect bites.
Maybe fire ants?
Jordan was carrying this.
Wow. What's in here?
Let's look.
Ugh.
I just saw the other kid.
This was no adventure camp.
No, it looks like
they were being tortured.
ICP is in the high 30s,
and markedly reduced
brain perfusion.
Well, that's not good.
Give him one gram
per kilo of mannitol.
Is he gonna make it?
He's gonna need
a really aggressive surgery
to even have a chance.
And I'm not optimistic.
But then again,
I'm never optimistic.
- Dr. Archer?
- Hmm?
Camp counselor's here.
What the hell are you
doing to these kids?
- What do you mean?
Today was an accident.
I'm not talking
about just today.
- There was a rockslide...
- These boys... no, stop!
These boys came in.
They were malnourished.
They were freezing.
They were covered in bug bites.
It's a disciplinary camp.
Listen, man, don't talk
to me about discipline, okay?
I went through Navy boot camp.
This is abuse.
We're trying to show these kids
that their actions
have consequences.
When they act out, they get
their food privileges revoked,
or they lose their
sleeping bag for a night.
Yeah, tell me, do the parents
know anything about
what you're
subjecting them to, huh?
Do they have any idea that
you got them lugging
50-pound backpacks
filled with rocks?
Their parents signed
them up for this.
Oh.
Everything we're doing is legal.
Okay, well, I'm not gonna
take your word for it.
I'm gonna be alerting
hospital counsel.
Look, these kids
aren't star students.
Most of them are
one misstep away from juvie.
Our methods may seem extreme,
but that's because
we have a short window to pull
them back from the edge.
Mm, well, today,
two of those kids
went over the edge
on your watch,
an edge they never should have
been on in the first place.
He just opened his eyes.
- All right, thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
Hey there, buddy.
I'm Dr. Frost.
- Hey.
How you feeling?
My chest hurts.
My leg too.
Well, you bruised some ribs
and injured your knee,
so that's to be expected.
What happened?
You took a pretty bad fall.
Do you remember that?
Uh, no, not at all.
His CT scan was normal, right?
Yep, and neuro exam
was normal too.
Okay.
Do you know where you are?
Hospital.
That's right.
Can you tell me things
like your name, your age?
No, sorry.
It's okay.
Do you remember anything
about the camp?
What camp?
Thank you.
So there's dinner on the stove
when I get to the house.
Breakfast is already made
when I wake up.
He does the dishes.
Daniel, he makes up the bed
and puts a glass of water
on the nightstand.
What a prick.
No, no, no.
It's just that
I'm not used to...
Being taken care of
in a manner you most
definitely deserve.
Dr. Goodwin,
sorry to interrupt,
but we need you to come
with us to your
hospital security office.
- What's going on?
Well, I'll explain on the way,
but right now we need to
move you to a secure location.
You mean like an active threat?
No time to explain.
We gotta move.
You gonna be all right?
Uh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Dr. Charles, you know
I'll keep her safe.
Yeah, keep me updated.
Copy that.
Extensive skull fractures,
severe left-side, frontal,
and temporal contusions,
significant brain edema causing
left-to-right midline shift,
not to mention the persistently
high intracranial pressure.
I'd recommend an up-front
left-side hemicraniectomy.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
We're not sawing off
half his skull
and leaving his brain
exposed for months?
That's not how I'd put it.
Well, sort of hoping you would.
A hemicraniectomy feels
like the last resort,
not the first line of defense.
Well, we could continue
to treat conservatively
with scheduled mannitol,
ongoing paralytics
and sedation, see if we can
keep his ICPs down.
- There you go.
Let's do that. Let's do that.
Absolutely not.
I agree with
Dr. Abrams' assessment.
This is not the time for
a cautious, stepwise approach.
We're at the last resort stage.
Oh, no, no, we are not.
There was not
a major bleed in his CT.
All right, Sam, how sure
are you that a hemicraniectomy
is the right procedure here?
It's close, 51/49.
Jordan could herniate
at any moment,
and then it'll be
too late for surgery.
And when are
his parents arriving?
We haven't reached them yet.
High-risk brain surgery
on a minor without legal
guardians' consent when
there's a viable alternative,
I don't know, Sam.
Sounds kind of dicey to me.
Let's monitor
for a bit longer while we
try to reach the parents.
In the interim,
push the sodium above 145
and I'll have Gottfried in
to place an EVD.
All right.
You recognize him, right?
Oh, yes, of course,
it's Patrick Dunn.
He worked in radiology
for years.
Until you let him go
a few weeks ago.
What... you think he sent
a death threat?
Yes, ma'am, we think
it's a very high likelihood.
Look, he had
an overblown reaction,
but a lot of people did.
As long as I have worked
with Patrick Dunn,
he is always well-mannered
and completely professional.
Completely professional
with a history
of mental instability
and aggressive behavior.
He also has several guns
registered in his name.
Why would he be targeting me?
We've been monitoring
his social media accounts.
Dunn's been posting a barrage
of vitriol against Med
on social media
since you fired him.
And he posted a message
an hour ago about you.
The language is violent,
Ms. Goodwin.
Well, that... that
changes things, doesn't it?
- Hey, Mags?
- Yeah?
Can you grab some alcohol wipes?
You got it.
Hey!
Hey, what are you doing?
Stop!
Those are not yours!
Open the door.
Those medical supplies
are for people in need.
What's going on in there?
Is someone hurt?
- I'm a registered nurse.
I can help.
Please open the door.
Please.
Hey.
Where is she?
- In there.
How far along are you?
I don't know.
I think about nine months.
What's your name, sweetie?
Sylvie.
Sylvie, my name is Maggie.
I'm a nurse and midwife.
We're gonna get
through this together, okay?
So this is just
a first guess, right?
But I think that we might
be looking at some form
of dissociative amnesia.
Like you dissociate
from yourself?
Kind of, but whereas with
the sort of garden variety
"bump on the head forget stuff"
version, in this case,
your mind blocks out
personal information
and memories in order
to protect you
from a traumatic experience.
Cody seems pretty chill for a
guy who doesn't know who he is.
Weird, right?
But that lack of concern
is common
with dissociative amnesia.
Do you know, did he
experience any memory loss
before the accident?
His counselor told me no.
All right, say anything else?
He did, actually, yeah.
After Jordan
fell over the ledge,
Cody snapped,
wouldn't stop screaming,
like he was possessed
out of his body.
Keith tried to hold him back,
but Cody began scrambling down
the ridge to save Jordan
until he slipped
near the bottom himself.
That's interesting.
Cody Lawson's mother
just landed at O'Hare.
She should be here
in an hour or so.
Thank you.
Let me know when
she arrives, okay?
I'd like to be there
when she walks in the room.
- You got it.
- Thank you.
Just ride out the wave.
There you go.
Come on, cuz. You got this.
Shut up, Eli.
Okay, okay. Give me the bag.
How long ago did
your water break?
First period, around 9:00.
I found Eli,
and he walked me home.
Okay, are you the father?
No, that's my cousin.
The father doesn't know
and never will.
This is your house?
Me and my mom, yeah.
Okay, when does she get home?
Three hours or so.
Why don't we give her a call?
- No!
- No way!
Not an option.
Why not?
Aunt Donna doesn't know.
Okay, did you wear baggy
clothes to hide the pregnancy?
- My mom can't ever know.
She'd kill me.
Okay, we'll worry
about that later.
Right now, we got a baby coming,
so I'll call my friend
Dr. Asher
over at the mobile clinic.
But I forgot
my phone at the van.
I need to borrow
one of your phones.
We don't have phones.
You're teenagers
on planet Earth.
You must have phones.
Aunt Donna says
they're a distraction.
Okay, change of plan.
I need you to go to the mobile
clinic and find a Dr. Asher,
and bring her back here.
- Why can't you do it?
You're a midwife.
Sweetie, I need all
the help we can get, okay?
Okay.
Eli, go now.
Okay, all right, sweetie.
Do you mind if I
check your dilation?
Okay, I need you to
scooch to the side.
You're gonna feel some pressure.
Okay, ah, Sylvie, you are
10 centimeters dilated,
which means...
The baby's coming,
like, right now.
Yeah, I guess we're doing this.
Take Motrin for the pain,
and follow up
with an orthopedic surgeon
after the swelling goes down.
Any questions?
I'm not a monster.
Okay.
I know you and your
colleagues think that
we were abusing these kids.
I can't speak for my
colleagues, but yes, I do.
While these camps may be
legal, which blows my mind,
I think they're despicable.
So you think I'm despicable?
Connect the dots
however you will.
I've seen this method
change lives.
Changed my life.
Save your shtick.
I'm not buying
what you're selling.
Trust me.
Fine, can you at least
tell me how Jordan is doing?
Despite what you think, I really
do care about these kids.
I'm not at liberty
to discuss Jordan's
medical information with you.
Yes, you are.
I'm legally responsible
for Jordan
until his parents get here.
Do you have that in writing?
Cody, I have a visitor for you.
Cody.
Hi.
Who is this?
This is, uh, this is Shayna.
This is... this is your mom.
I'm sorry.
I don't know who this is.
Cody, you really don't know me?
Uh, no.
Oh, my God.
This is all my fault.
I should never have sent him
to that awful place.
What's wrong with her?
I just... I didn't
know what else to do.
I was gonna lose him.
Why don't you give Cody
a little rest, all right?
- I didn't have a choice.
I didn't.
- I completely understand.
- I have to go.
I'm sorry.
- Okay.
No, I can't do this.
Yes, you can.
Listen to me.
Breathe with me.
Your body knows
how to do this, okay?
You got this.
No, I can't.
My back is killing me.
Okay, okay.
Okay, let's stand up and
relieve that pressure, okay?
And then we're gonna
lay back down,
and we're gonna
deliver this baby, okay?
Okay, on three.
One, two, three.
Good job, sweetie.
Good job.
Good girl. Ready?
One, two, three.
Let's get up.
Oh!
- There you go.
Lean against the wall.
There you go, there you go.
Okay, how does your back feel?
Much better, thanks.
Good, good.
Ready to lay back down?
Yeah, sure.
There you go.
Oh, Maggie.
The baby's coming.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Let's get to the bed.
No, it's too late.
Okay, okay, hold on,
hold on, hold on, hold on.
Oh, okay, Sylvie, got the head.
Okay, I need one more push.
Okay, look at me.
You got this. Okay?
On three.
One, two, three, push, Sylvie!
Push!
Okay, I got her.
I got her.
There she is, Sylvie.
You did it, mama.
Let me clamp the umbilical cord.
There you go.
You have a healthy baby girl
with an equally healthy set
of lungs, just like her mama.
Okay, I'm gonna cut
the umbilical cord,
and then do you wanna hold her?
Just cut it, and take
her to the hospital.
I don't want her.
Sylvie, you don't have
to decide right now.
Please, just do it.
I don't want her attached to me.
Okay, sweetie, there you go.
Okay, why don't you sit down?
There you go.
Listen to me.
Everything is okay, okay?
Shayna, how are you doing?
I know that that was
a whole lot to take in,
and I just wanted
to check up on you.
Do you mind if I sit?
I was at my wit's end with Cody.
He was flunking out of school,
getting in fights.
Pretty sure
he started dealing drugs.
And whenever I'd try
and talk to him,
he would just... he would
just explode at me.
Mm, sounds like, you know,
had a whole lot of anger
that he didn't know
what to do with.
Well, he never told me why.
And then last summer,
he got a DUI.
He spent the night in jail.
I mean, my friend said
she knew about this camp.
I realize it's... it was
a horrible idea, but I ju... I...
Shayna, I get it.
You're desperate.
I just... I just wanted it
to be the wake-up call that
I really believed he needed
because I thought otherwise
he was gonna end up dead.
That's just really hard to
believe because he used to be
such a sweet and gentle kid.
Until... until when?
Until his dad died.
- And they were...
they were close?
I don't know how close they
were, but Mark was his dad.
Cody loved him.
I tried to make sure
it stayed that way.
How?
How did you make sure
it stayed that way?
Mark was a drunk.
I tried to make sure
that Cody just saw
the happy drunk,
right, the clown version,
the one that would play
video games with him all day
and wrestle, and...
when I could sense that
he was about to turn, though,
I would grab Cody and get him
out of there real fast.
And by turn, you mean?
I mean he would get violent.
I did my best to protect Cody.
I'm not sure
how successful I was.
How exactly did
your husband die?
Mark was, uh, um, fixing a...
a rain leak on our roof.
And he just loved doing
things around the house.
And he'd been drinking
all day and lost his balance.
And he... he slipped and he fell.
And Cody... Cody was there?
Cody...
- No, no, no, no.
Neither of us were.
Earlier in the day when I could
tell that Mark was turning,
I grabbed Cody, and I took him
to our neighbor Sally's house.
You know, Shayna,
there's a procedure
that I'd like to
talk to you about.
It has the potential to help us
help Cody with his memory loss.
Whoa, wait.
Hold it, hold it.
What are you doing, huh?
This patient doesn't have
an order for transfer.
We were told to take him
to OR number 5.
And who told you that?
Me.
You got consent
from his parents?
We haven't reached them yet.
Well, then this isn't happening.
Keith Bauman consented
to Jordan's surgery.
The camp counselor?
Keith has the legal authority
to make medical decisions
on Jordan's behalf.
Are you for real right now?
Very much so, Dr. Archer.
That man is the one responsible
for Jordan's injuries.
That's exactly why he signed,
to try to save Jordan's life.
Playing it safe won't do that.
All right, don't move this
patient until I get back.
Where are you going?
And?
She's absolutely perfect.
Did you check her Apgar score,
color, heart rate, reflexes,
muscle tone, and respiration?
I did.
Everything checks out.
Oh.
Where'd you learn all that?
YouTube. Yeah.
See, I learned in case I would
have to deliver the baby,
but I'm glad you did it.
Ambulance will
be here any second.
Okay, I'll go wake up Sylvie.
Okay.
What are you doing?
You shouldn't be
on your feet yet.
I've gotta get
everything cleaned up
before my mom gets home,
take it all to the laundromat.
Okay, forget about the sheets.
Drink this.
Listen, your mom's gonna
find out sooner or later.
No!
Just take her.
Make sure she's safe, that she
goes to people who love her.
Okay.
Giving up a baby
is a big decision.
It's not one that you should
be making on your own.
Now, I can talk
to your mom for you.
You don't understand.
She had me when she was 16.
She didn't get to finish
high school or go to college.
She sacrificed
her whole life for me.
And this is how I repay her?
You're afraid
of disappointing her?
Okay, uh,
she will be disappointed.
There's no way around it.
I know my mom was
when I got pregnant at 16.
You?
I was terrified to tell
my parents, especially my mom.
Pushed it off for months and...
as long as I could.
And when I finally did tell her,
she was disappointed
and furious.
But she didn't stop loving me.
She didn't stop
being there for me.
She was still my mom.
What did you do with the baby?
I gave her up.
Do you ever regret it?
Sometimes.
But you are not me.
You need to make the
right decision for you.
I just...
I don't know.
I don't know what to do.
Okay, who do you
normally talk to when you
have to make a tough decision?
- My mom.
- All right.
Well, let's call her on
the way to the hospital, okay?
Okay.
Look, it's pretty cut and dry.
I mean, Mr. Bauman has
the legal authority as granted
by Jordan's parents to make
medical decisions in the event
they're unreachable.
They still unreachable?
- Yeah.
- Yes.
Then Mr. Bauman's
consent holds.
You and Dr. Abrams can
proceed with surgery.
Sorry we wasted
your time, Peter.
Wasn't my idea.
We haven't maxed out
on conservative options.
That is your opinion.
Based on decades of experience.
Forget trying to stick it
to me for a second.
This has nothing to do with you.
I'm doing what's necessary
to save Jordan's life.
Or have you forgotten
that's our primary goal?
Cody, as I was
explaining to Shayna,
what we're about
to do is something we call
a medication-assisted interview.
Okay.
Dr. Frost is gonna give you
a sedative.
It's called lorazepam,
and it's gonna relax you.
Hopefully, maybe,
as we talk, who knows?
We might start getting
your memory back.
Are you ready?
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Pushing 1 milligram lorazepam.
All you gotta do,
pal, is just...
just relax, you know?
Just gonna have a conversation.
Okay, so I am just wondering
if at this point,
you would be able
to tell me your full name.
I know my first name is Cody,
but just because
you keep calling me that.
All right, how about if
I ask you about your dad?
Anything... anything
coming up there?
No, nothing. I'm sorry.
Hey, I don't want you
to apologize, all right?
It's not a test.
I'm just gonna keep
asking you questions.
And if something,
anything comes up, just let it.
- Okay.
- Good.
Okay, so now back to
your dad, I don't know.
Sometimes it's just,
like, little details,
you know, color of his hair,
sound of his voice,
maybe a favorite present
he gave you for the holidays.
I remember
the smell of his cologne.
Oh.
Okay, excellent.
What did it smell like?
Maybe like his shampoo he liked?
And sweat.
He would sweat
when he was working.
Right.
Wasn't he, um, working up on
the roof the day that he died?
I think he was.
Look, I know you weren't there,
but um, remember
anything about that day?
I was there.
Honey, you're confused.
He wasn't there.
You weren't...
you weren't there.
Shayna, thanks.
So what you're
saying is that you...
you were there.
I thought that your mom
took you to a neighbor's house.
Yes, she did,
but I went back home.
Okay, why?
Why'd you go back?
Because I thought my mom did.
- 'Cause you were what?
You were worried about her?
Yeah, when my dad drank,
she would
always take me somewhere else,
but she would always go back.
Oh, so you're back at the house.
Now, what would happen?
What did... what did you see?
My...
my dad was on the roof.
He was... he was so drunk
he could barely stand.
And when he saw me,
he asked me where my mom was.
And when I wouldn't tell him,
he got mad, like really mad.
And he started to
throw things at me.
And it wasn't until he threw
the hammer that...
that he lost his balance.
And he fell, and he landed
on the fence,
and the spikes went
right through him,
and there was blood everywhere.
But Dad was still alive.
He asked me to call 911.
And did you?
No, I didn't move.
- Why not?
Why didn't you call?
So she would always be safe,
so that he would
never hurt her again.
Okay, Sylvie,
so it looks like you have
a small
first-degree vaginal tear.
Am I gonna need stitches?
No, no, no.
First-degree tear heals
on its own in a few weeks.
Mom?
I'm so sorry, Mom.
All the talks we had?
I know.
I do not want this life for you.
You've sacrificed
so much for me.
I don't care about that.
I'd do it all again.
But you are meant
for better things.
I won't let this derail you.
That's... that's why
I'm not keeping it.
Wait, Mama!
Sylvie.
Give her time.
She needs to wrap
her head around this, okay?
All right, extend
the dural opening.
Got it.
What happened?
We got severe venous bleeding
from the sagittal sinus.
Skull fracture,
likely a bolster branch.
BP's dropping into the 50s.
Latest hemoglobin is only 7.1.
Lactate's been rising.
- Stay on top of it.
Push more fluids and blood.
We're already maxed
out on pressors.
He's losing it quicker
than I can replace it.
What if you drill off more skull
to get across the midline,
flap the dural on itself
to reconstruct
the sagittal sinus
and secure it down?
He could suffer a venous bleed,
or he could thrombose the
whole sinus and stroke out.
Or he could
continue bleeding out,
and we lose him
in the next two minutes.
All right. Drill?
You mind if I join you?
You're from the South Side.
I can hear it when you talk.
Probably within three blocks
of High Park Boulevard?
Two blocks.
Thought so.
You?
Kimbark Avenue.
Bet we know some
of the same people.
I guarantee we do.
Sylvie thinks I'm mad at her,
but I'm just mad at myself.
I failed her.
That's not true at all.
Then how'd this happen?
How did she make
the exact same mistake I did?
The same way you did,
the same way I did.
Life happens.
You didn't keep
your baby, did you?
No.
Know how I knew that?
You're a nurse,
and I drive a bus.
There's nothing wrong
with driving a bus.
No, but point is, mistakes
can cost you if you let them.
And I don't want
Sylvie driving any bus.
I want her to go wherever
her heart takes her.
That's my life.
That's my life's work.
She's my life.
That can't include a baby.
I get you, but this
is Sylvie's decision.
How can I leave this up
to her knowing what I know?
Because if you don't,
she'll never forgive you.
And Sylvie won't know
what to do until she...
until she holds that baby
in her arms.
She hasn't held her yet?
Well, I know why.
I told Sylvie
a million times how
I fell in love
with her the moment
I first held her in my arms.
There was no choice.
She was mine.
Sylvie knows that if
she holds that baby,
she won't be able
to let it go either.
I held my baby,
and I fell in love
with her too, instantly.
And then I said goodbye.
Sylvie will know what to do.
I gave Shayna the name
of a therapist I really trust.
And look, they got
a long road ahead of them,
but they do the work,
they got a real good shot.
- Yeah?
I mean, I certainly hope so.
Human mind never
ceases to astonish me.
I'm telling you.
I mean, Cody's gave him
a complete memory wipe
to protect him from trauma.
Yeah, I mean, I wish I could
wipe my parents
from my memory, permanently.
Not too... not too close, huh?
Haven't spoken to them in years.
Well, look,
I've been there, brother.
The thing I try
to remember when I'm...
- Uh, look, I...
- When I'm grinding on my...
I really appreciate it,
Dr. Charles,
but I got someplace
I need to be, so...
Right on. Off you go, man.
I get it.
- All right.
- All good.
- I'll see you.
Hey, it's okay.
Make sure to support her head.
She looks just
like you as a baby.
Sylvie, no matter
what you decide,
you need to hold this baby
and tell her
what's in your heart
for both of you.
Yeah.
Hey.
Mama?
Yes, baby?
I wanna keep her.
Then that's what we'll do.
But you'll have
one thing I didn't.
Me.
We'll do this together, okay?
Babies need names, Sylvie.
Her name is Sophia.
Hey, Sophia.
Hey.
Mr. and Mrs. Bennett,
I wanted
to come introduce myself.
I'm Dr. Archer.
Hi.
- How's our boy?
He's still in surgery.
I'm glad we were able
to reach you.
Yeah, we were
on my brother's farm
with terrible cell reception.
Yeah.
Dr. Lenox,
these are Jordan's parents.
Mr. And Mrs. Bennett.
During surgery, your son
suffered a massive brain bleed,
which was a complication
from the massive skull fractures
he sustained in his fall.
Unfortunately,
although we attempted
to resuscitate Jordan,
we ultimately were
unable to save him,
and Jordan died.
No, no, no.
Oh, my God, no.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
I'm gonna need you to reschedule
my morning appointment.
One second.
Come in.
I'm gonna have to
call you back, okay?
All right.
Patrick Dunn's being transported
to Med in an ambulance.
What happened?
Self-inflicted
gunshot wound to the chest.
He tried to kill himself
during a standoff with police.
He's alive, but barely.
Save it.
What?
What did you say?
Save it? Save it?
Are you kidding?
That kid never
had to have surgery,
but you pushed it, he died,
and the blame for that
falls directly onto you.
Yeah.
You think waiting
would have saved Jordan?
He was a time bomb
waiting to happen.
I gave him a chance to live.
He would still be here
if not for you.
You don't know that.
But go ahead and live
in your alternate reality
where Dean Archer
is always right,
and I will live in this one,
where sometimes
we lose patients.
You made a bad call,
and you goddamn well know it!
When your tantrum is over,
I'll be in the ED
treating patients.
You're gonna answer for this.
Subsync johnhallgeir