Crystal Fighters'
"Wild Ones" plays...
Almost all human cells
reproduce on a cycle.
♪ I thought I was a star ♪
Up to 10% of your heart
is replaced each year.
♪ From the sky I freefall ♪
Red blood cells are replaced
every four months.
Thank you.
Skin cells, every two weeks.
♪ 'Cause I thought
I was a star ♪
Uh.
♪ How long, tell me how long
can this go on? ♪
Want to get a pizza
or something?
I know a great place.
Well, it's late.
I should, uh, go to sleep.
It's only 8:30
in Seattle.
Yeah, but we're not
We're in New York,
and we are doing
a complicated surgery on
New York time in the morning.
Okay, fine.
Room service...
in bed, then sleep.
We agreed.
Just sex, no sleepovers.
But we're out of town.
- Bend the rules.
- No, it's not a rule,
so much as the basic tenet
of this relationship.
- Which is that it's not a relationship?
- Right.
No complications.
My life is already full of them.
But it's not that complicated.
W-We have adjoining rooms.
They're practically
the same.
And yet,
they are not.
But neurons,
the cells that make up
the brain and spinal cord,
don't regenerate.
I feel used!
Objectified!
Hungry!
♪ And we rage on
till we're blazing in the sun ♪
Okay.
What will it take for you
to let me go to sleep tonight,
guilt-free?
♪ La la la la la la ♪
♪ How long? ♪
Pizza for breakfast.
Deal.
♪ And we rage on ♪
♪ Till we're blazing in the sun ♪
I'm still questioning pizza
as a breakfast food,
- but this is a really excellent slice.
- Mm-hmm.
How'd you know
about this place?
Mm.
It was part of my wish.
You wished
for perfect pizza?
From a fairy godmother?
Cancer kids who are in
as bad a shape as I was
get wishes.
Osteosarcoma.
Age 10.
Full remission.
What'd you wish for?
- Baseball game at Shea Stadium.
- Yeah.
I got to meet my favorite
player, Dwight Gooden.
I remember thinking,
"I'll be back."
And the next time was with
the Mariners as the team doctor.
That is impressive.
Nothing will beat that
first time out here.
I ate here five times.
Even got a picture out front.
Oh, and there was this
great donut place
right around the corner.
Um...
Gotham Donuts!
Oh! Best glazed donut
I've ever had.
That was, uh...
Well, that was our last trip
together before the divorce.
Uh, I guess this city
reminds me of better times.
That is the exact
opposite of me.
I grew up here.
Well, not exactly here.
I was like half an hour away
in Westchester.
But my life in New York was
definitely not better times.
Wait. You're saying
we could've had donuts?!
- Admit it.
- 14 blocks was not that far.
And when you walk,
you see things
- you never would have from a cab.
- You're right.
We totally would've missed
that group of mimes
- yelling at each other.
- And the rat dragging the bagel.
That was so gross.
Amy?
Oh, my God!
- Uh...
- Amy!
Nancy!
Yeah.
Nancy Shepherd.
Oh, Amelia's sister.
You must be Owen.
Yes!
This is my husband.
Nice to meet you, Nancy.
I've heard
so much about you.
Do you work here?
I'm covering the chief of OB's
maternity leave.
Ironic, right?
How about you?
Everything okay?
Yeah.
No...
We're here for a patient.
All the way from Seattle?
Wow.
You must be very
in demand.
I guess that's why
we never hear from you.
Yep.
Been pretty busy
since I saw you last.
I operated on
Catherine Fox herself.
Might've read about it.
Also got married.
Aah.
Right. Welcome to the family.
We've got some pretty
deep-seated dysfunction,
but you've probably
figured that out by now.
Ah, what family doesn't?
Do you have sisters?
I do, so I get it.
We should catch up.
Come for dinner,
both of you.
Ah! We can't.
Taking off tonight.
She's got a big surgery
- in Seattle tomorrow.
- I do.
Oh. Well,
at least
I got to see you.
Halley's Comet comes around
more than you do.
Oh, uh...
call Mom sometime,
kiddo.
It's the kind thing
to do.
Okay.
Thanks for that.
Let's go.
I need to find a shower
so I can wash that "kiddo"
off of me before surgery.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 15  Episode 21
Episode Title: "Good Shepherd"
You got this!
- Oh, man.
- Victory Lane!
- You beat me again.
- No, man,
- you totally threw that.
- Nice race.
Okay, I'm on way too many pain
meds for you to be losing to me.
- Come on.
- Hey, Dr. Lew.
Jonah, these are your surgeons,
Doctors Shepherd and Lincoln. Hi.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- Uh, this is my brother Brady.
You know, I-I would've left him
at home, but he's my ride.
Mm.
Jonah Mays, 18.
He was diagnosed with
progressive kyphoscoliosis
at age 6.
He's had multiple
posterior spine fusions
with instrumentation
from T4 to L5
to correct the curvature.
Yeah, it's, uh, pretty much
my entire spinal cord.
I've had... 15 surgeries
in 12 years.
Some due to growth, some due to
the condition's progression.
Yeah, the metal rods bust
right through his skin.
- Can we take a look?
- Yeah.
You're in good hands,
Jonah.
I'll leave you to it.
Looks like the degree
of angulation
- has pushed the hardware off the bolts.
- Mm.
But you... you can fix
that, though, right?
Dr. Lincoln and I will
remove the rods.
We'll insert a nylon tether,
which will stabilize your spine.
It'll allow room for growth,
which means
fewer surgeries
in the future.
Good.
'Cause, uh, you know,
I've got big plans.
I'm moving to California.
I just got accepted
to UC Berkeley.
- Go, Bears!
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- One, uh... One step at a time, bro.
You're worried.
I get it.
I mean, w-who would take you
to physical therapy
and make sure that you got
to the doctor's on time?
Oh, yeah, that's right.
That's what you've always
done for me.
But I won't need it as much,
all right?
Okay.
We've got
your measurements.
We will be back to
prep you for surgery
- after we compare them to the scans.
- Okay.
Looks like we can use a vats
to anchor the bolts at T3.
Just like we planned.
Should be done by 5:00.
Ah, that gives us almost
another 24 hours
of observation before
we head back to Seattle.
That's amazing news!
I was just gonna leave you
a note,
- trying to...
- What? What?
Uh, what's amazing? What?
I just heard you say
it's at least 24 hours
till your flight leaves,
so you can come for dinner.
John and the kids are upstate
visiting his mom,
so it'll be quiet.
I'll make your favorite
chocolate cream pie.
I... I no longer eat,
um, sugar or gluten.
I'm not taking no
for an answer.
Fine, make the pie.
Good.
Text me when
you're on your way.
See ya!
Can't wait!
So...
you like pie, right?
Five minutes in
the lobby is one thing.
Dinner is a terrible idea,
and I'm not going.
You can't make me go alone...
It's like sending.
Red Riding Hood
to visit the wolf.
I'll be having pizza and donuts
in the city.
- You're more than welcome to j...
- I'm begging.
This is me begging.
Aren't I cute when I beg?
Dr. Kripen, call extension 193.
Okay, Jonah.
Pre-op time.
Are we leaving now?
Why? You winning?
Yeah. But, uh, also...
Brady went
to the cafeteria.
He said he was gonna
go get an apple,
but, uh, I guarantee you
he comes back with fries.
You know, we have this thing
about saying bye to each other
ever since our parents died
six years ago in a car accident.
And, yeah,
it was as dramatic and tragic
as your face is right now.
Oh, sorry. I...
I'm gonna give you something
to relax you,
and Dr. Lincoln is going to
mark you for surgery.
Cool. What are you
gonna study at Cal?
Uh, environmental science.
Or literature.
Or something
I haven't heard of before.
I-I'm not sure.
Renaissance man.
Nice.
Yeah, well, you know, uh,
knowing what you don't know
is the first step
to enlightenment.
You will fit right in
at Berkeley.
So, did you always know
you wanted to be a doctor?
I have four older siblings
who are all doctors.
I'm not sure it ever occurred
to me to do anything else.
Ah, told ya!
Fries.
You want one?
I'm good, thanks.
Uh, but
Jonah's good to go.
Got it, okay.
Uh, hold these for me?
Thanks, Doc.
Till next time, brother.
Mm.
Until next time.
Here.
And, uh, take that.
You need practice, 'cause
the next time I see you,
I'm-a kick your butt
for real.
Okay.
All right.
Signal looks good.
Good.
Angle looks good.
So... any food allergies?
Nancy will want to know.
Doesn't matter
because I'm not going.
Please?
The begging is cute...
Don't get me wrong.
And still, no.
You shouldn't go,
either.
Life's too short.
Life is too short
for what it will turn into
if I don't go.
One dinner with Nancy,
and I avoid months
of family gossip and drama.
They already think
I'm a train wreck.
Well, they're wrong.
Have you met me?
Amelia Shepherd.
Never told my family
I got divorced.
Ready to attach
the tether?
So they don't get you.
And what... they're mad
because you and Owen eloped?
We didn't elope.
We had a wedding.
They were invited.
They just didn't come.
Wait. None of your sisters
were there?
Or my mom.
Or brother.
- He gets a pass.
- Out of the country?
Dead. But probably judging me
from the grave.
It's complicated.
That's some serious
sibling rivalry.
Well, not every family
is Jonah and Brady.
So why go to this dinner?
I was...
flown to New York
to perform a rare
and complicated surgery.
I'm here
with my "husband,"
who is shockingly handsome
and ever so kind.
This dinner is a chance
for me to... I don't know.
Brag?
Prove them wrong?
I...
I'm not sure.
I'm just sure
that I have to go,
and that,
if you go with me,
I will make it
worth your while
in very creative ways
that you will enjoy.
Where did we meet?
At the hospital.
And how long
have we been together?
Years, but it feels like minutes
- because love is so...
- Okay,
we don't need poetry. We just
need to keep our story straight.
What color are my eyes?
You think they're gonna quiz me
on the color of your eyes?
Anything is possible.
♪ Naa naa naa naa ♪
Sometimes they look green.
Sometimes they look blue,
depending on the...
Good.
♪ Sunshine, blue sky ♪
What is Owen's favorite
pastime?
Blues guitar.
No.
No, watching World War II
movies on PBS.
But blues guitar is mine,
and Nancy's never met Owen,
so can't I just answer
as myself?
Well, I don't know your life.
I know Owen's.
You could learn it.
♪ Flying free ♪
Crap.
We don't have rings!
Half the surgeons I know
don't wear rings.
Right. Right.
Yeah.
We're surgeons.
We're smart.
No rings.
All of that
is actually true.
At least it's just Nancy.
Better her than Liz or...
God forbid... Kathleen.
Kathleen is the worst.
Kathleen's like Martha Stewart
if Martha Stewart also had
a license to diagnose you
with a personality disorder.
Nancy's bossy,
but she's also the most forgiving.
And she does make
a really nice pie.
Plus,
she is gonna love you.
And by you, I mean Owen,
who really likes to...
Watch
World War II movies.
Thank you.
You're gonna be great!
Also, you can't drink.
- Owen doesn't drink.
- He does.
I just don't want you
to screw anything up.
♪ S'My kinda happiness ♪
♪ No, I won't stop ♪
This is quite a place.
Ah, her husband's
an investment banker.
They moved here from a different
giant house in Connecticut
after he got
some big promotion.
Wait.
We never had a honeymoon...
Owen and I.
He wanted Mexico,
I wanted Paris,
so we did neither.
Instead of doing both?
Got it. Got it.
No compromises, even
on the honeymoon. Mm.
♪ No, I won't stop ♪
♪ I got my groove, oh, yeah ♪
This is a terrible idea.
Now you figure that out?
♪ With every move I make ♪
You made it.
- We did.
- Come on in.
The house is a mess.
Don't look too close.
♪ S'My kinda happiness ♪
You're right on time.
We were just about to start
on the appetizers.
- We?
- Where do you keep
your corkscrew?
We got to get it in
before she gets here.
Is that...
That sounds like...
Kathleen!
You're here!
Kathleen is my...
Other sister.
Yep.
Well, I guess
I'll put the wine away.
You wouldn't have
come if you knew. No!
Fun!
Family reunion!
Is, uh, Liz gonna pop out
of the closet next? Or Mom?
Please give me
more credit than that.
I wouldn't just
spring Mom on you.
I did call Liz,
but she was out of town.
Ah, too bad.
We could've all
compared lives
to make sure yours
are still better.
It's not like that at all.
No. This is about
Nancy's compulsive need
to fix all of us.
We are a family.
We haven't seen each other
in years.
You haven't even met Owen.
I'm sure we can all be civil
for one night.
- Kathleen.
- Owen.
You were in
the Army, right?
Uh, where
were you stationed?
Iraq. Baghdad.
My husband's traveling there.
H-He's a diplomat.
Any recommendations?
Let's move inside before
we start the interrogation.
The Abbasid Palace
is quite beautiful.
It was, uh, built
in the 12th century
overlooking
the Tigris River.
- I'll mention it.
- Mm.
H-How high does the temperature
get there in July?
It gets, uh, pretty hot.
Um, I'm sorry.
Could I use your restroom?
Of course.
Yeah, I'll show you where.
It's gonna take them
about five minutes
to figure out
I'm not Owen.
You knew about
that palace in Iraq.
Ninth grade World Civ
presentation!
That's about all
I remember.
I-I might've been able
to handle Nancy,
but that Martha Stewart one,
she's got teeth.
Okay. You're right.
We got to get out of here.
I mean, best case scenario,
the whole night's
just them reminding me that
I'm the Shepherd's black sheep.
- I see what you did there.
- That was the nickname
that they gave me
in high school.
Black Sheep.
We are not subtle people.
What are we gonna do?
We're gonna go back out there
for a few minutes.
We're gonna say
we got paged to the hospital.
Because we are not
in high school.
We are grown-ass surgeons
with medical emergencies.
- Not in high school.
- Thank you for the reminder.
I'm putting the avocados
on the side for you.
Oh, that's okay.
Uh, Owen loves them,
so I sorta got
used to them.
He's great, right?
Oh, I'm sure Kathleen's
got him cornered.
Uh, maybe I should
just go check.
Oh, can you grab that?
You are not at all
what I pictured.
Trauma surgeon.
Army.
I thought you'd be
a lot more...
Rugged?
Armed?
Uptight.
But Amelia loves to be
unpredictable,
so... maybe it makes sense.
It keeps things
interesting.
She has a history
of false starts
when it comes
to weddings.
Well, we're definitely married.
I'm saying congrats on not
being abandoned at the altar.
She would never do that.
Oh, yes, she would.
She is a Houdini-level
escape artist.
First sign
things might get hard,
and she is out the door.
I'm surprised she didn't bolt
when she saw me here.
She thinks
we gang up on her.
She provokes it, though.
Honestly,
I always thought
she was more addicted
to drama than the drugs.
But, I mean...
good thing she found someone
with Army training, right?
What's that old slogan?
"No mission
too difficult"?
Hey!
So, Jonah's scans
came back early.
- We should go.
- Ah.
We could review them
in the morning.
Um, I know you were anxious
to see them.
I think we should spend
some time with your family.
Oh, um, well, we might need to
look at his labs, though.
Oh, you know,
I just looked at them.
And we're good.
O... kay.
We'll stay.
Do you ever
run into Meredith?
I do.
I read she won
a Harper Avery.
Uh, they renamed it the
Catherine Fox Award.
But, yeah.
Uh, she's doing well.
Amelia's doing groundbreaking
research, as well.
Finding non-addictive methods
of pain management.
Well, Amelia would know
how important that is.
How about
I get that wine now?
It's fine. Really.
You should be more
concerned about
the pills
in your bathroom.
I don't want to make you
feel uncomfortable.
Too late.
Um... I should take this.
Oh, it's okay.
I'm good.
Go ahead.
Amelia said you love them.
I do!
What's happening?
Is he okay?
Hey. Did you
forget to pack Roodle?
I'm pretty sure
I put it in the bag.
What about the one
your mom got him?
Yeah, I can't find it.
That's why we have a backup.
Oh. Try giving him one of his
other stuffed animals.
I'm kind of losing it
over here.
Well, he probably shoved it
in the couch.
Okay, it's not...
It's not here.
It's not... wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait!
Here. Found it.
Here's Roodle.
There you go.
Thank you.
Can I ask you
a question?
Sure.
What's the temperature like
in Baghdad in July?
Well, once it got
to 130 degrees,
and I cooked eggplant
in the sun. Why?
Uhhhh, no reason.
Okay. Thank you. Sure.
Roodle's back.
Roodle is back!
- Oh, my God!
- No.
No way!
I don't believe you.
- Oh!
- What's, uh, going on?
Owen claims he can debone
the fish in one fell swoop.
Well, you know, I work a lot with
- bones as a, uh...
- Trauma surgeon.
I'm impressed he knows
it's called a paring knife.
I-I'm not
convinced anyone can do it.
Can and...
- did.
- Aah!
Oh, my God!
Can you do that on people?
Uh, never tried,
so I'll just say yes.
Oh! We love him.
And I love her.
Okay. There's just one thing
I don't understand.
Out of all of us, how did you
end up with the hottest husband?
Aah!
- Ooh!
- What? Ah!
Amelia was raving about
your pie on the way over.
You just
made Nancy's day.
I-I'll take
half that piece.
Oh, you can put the other one
right on my plate.
I hear my girls!
I didn't call her. I swear!
I may have accidentally
mentioned it.
This place
is so obnoxiously huge,
I can never
find my way...
There's my baby girl!
Oh!
Hi, Mom!
Oho, oh!
Let me look at you.
- Gorgeous!
- Mm!
Oh, I've always liked you with
shorter hair.
Are you going gray
under there?
Because your grandmother
was completely white
by the time she was 35.
Mom, please.
And who is this
handsome fellow?
This is my husband, Owen.
No, it's not.
Of course it is.
And he's fantastic.
You know, we were surprised,
too, but she picked a good one.
Well,
I'm sure he's great.
But when I visited Derek,
I met Owen Hunt.
And this is not him.
Okay.
I'm getting the wine.
Uh-huh.
Who is he?
Who are you?
He's my friend and colleague,
Atticus Lincoln.
You can call me Link.
What the hell
were you thinking?
She wasn't.
That's the narcissism.
Were you even married?
Yes! Yes!
Owen and I were married,
and now... we're not.
You're separated?
Divorced.
You were married
less than a year.
Actually, a little more.
But less than two.
I guess.
What... What does it matter?
Nancy and Liz owe me 50 bucks.
You bet I'd get divorced?
For what it's worth,
I thought it would last
longer than it did.
Okay,
you bet on my marriage
after you didn't come
to my wedding?
You didn't come to my wedding.
You were in jail.
She came to mine.
Uncle Ron walked in on her
screwing that usher
in the coat room.
I would've come
with proper notice,
but I'd barely heard of Owen
before the invitations arrived.
I didn't know if there
was going to be a wedding.
Okay, do you have any idea how
hurtful and insulting that...
This is why I didn't even
bother to call you
when I found out
I had a brain tumor.
This is why.
Amelia Frances Shepherd,
you have a brain tumor and you
didn't tell your mother?!
You have a brain tumor?
Are we supposed to feel better
that your fake husband
doesn't know, either?
Had.
I h... I had
a benign Grade I Meningioma
that they removed.
Completely?
'Cause this seems pretty
brain damaged.
I'd say more
like delusional.
But, you know,
par for the course.
Remember when she
bought herself that ring
and she told us all
she was engaged
to that guy
she dated in high school?
He couldn't afford to
buy the ring himself.
She got my car stuck
in the ditch,
walked home,
said somebody must've stolen it,
but left the keys inside.
That was years ago,
and I made amends!
Or when she was so drunk
at Uncle Adam's funeral
that she dropped
her end of the casket.
I wasn't drunk.
I was high.
And, yeah,
I had some bad years.
You don't have to bring up
every transgression.
Yeah,
we don't have that kind of time.
The point is all that crazy
happened before the brain tumor.
You've always been
impulsive.
You don't think
things through
or the impact they're gonna
have on other people.
You just do whatever
the hell you want.
Yeah, and then you concoct
these preposterous stories
to cover the truth that
inevitably surfaces.
Okay, girls, that's enough.
Bringing fake Owen
to dinner tonight
might just be the most demented
thing you've ever done.
And if
you're really clean now,
then we can't blame the drugs
or the tumor,
which brings us
back to personality disorder.
Okay, you don't know me.
You have not seen me
for years.
I am trapped in your minds
and on your stairs
at about 14 years old, and I am
not that person anymore.
I am sober.
I am responsible.
And I am a neurosurgeon
at the top of my field.
I save lives every day.
In fact,
I am the chief of neuro
at one of the top hospitals
in the country.
Because Derek was moving
and gave you the job.
Listen, um
I'm new to, uh, all of this.
And I haven't known Amelia
that long,
but I wanted us to stay
for dinner tonight
so you could meet the woman that
I've been getting to know,
because she is not at all
the person you are describing.
Link,
you don't have to...
She is a brilliant
surgeon,
the kind you fly across the
country when you need the best.
She just performed
a surgery
that very few human beings
on the planet can do.
She is a respected
teacher and mentor.
She cares about her patients
and her colleagues.
And she's beautiful and funny
and kind and strong.
They're sleeping together,
right?
Obviously. She's overcome
a lot of adversity.
And, sure, she feels
her feelings in a big way,
but that makes her better
than most people I know,
not worse,
because it makes her authentic.
She was an amazing mom to Betty,
and still kinda is to Leo.
I mean, even if she doesn't
have legal custody,
that baby is so lucky
to have her in his...
Wait...
Did you just say "mom"?
Did you say "baby"?
Well... crap.
You have a baby?
Baby or tumor...
Which is crazier?
Who's Betty?
I'm going with baby.
You never tell me
anything.
Come on.
Houdini.
You okay?
I said we shouldn't go.
I said we shouldn't stay!
Wow, okay.
So your sisters
are terrorists,
but now
I'm your problem?
Look, everything
was going fine
until your mom called us
on our bluff.
And I know it got
a little rough...
A little rough?
It was a lifetime
of humiliating mistakes
and dirty laundry on display.
I don't care
about your laundry.
No, I care.
You were pain management.
You were
my human blue light,
mood-enhancing
when placed over my body.
And now you know too much.
And I'm... I can't.
Son of a...
Jonah's in respiratory
distress.
We need to get to
Fox Medical Center in Manhattan,
please,
as fast as you can.
- He's bending by the minute.
- He's exaggerating.
I'm fine.
I'll... I'll be okay.
Ow! Jonah,
we took a look at your scans,
- and the tether just doesn't...
- Oh, please don't say it.
Your lungs
are compressed.
We're gonna have to replace
the rod so you can breathe.
But, uh, I-I have to...
I have plans.
W-W-What if we tighten
the tether?
That's not how it works.
I'm sorry.
The rods don't work.
Okay, I-I'll need new ones again
by the end of the year.
The tether didn't even
last for a day.
- W-What if...
- Jonah, they said
there's no other way, okay?
T-There's always
another way.
That's what you said
when Mom and Dad died.
I-I was scared because
of how many people want to adopt
somebody with my condition...
and you said that you'd
find a way, and you did.
You quit law school
so you could take care of me.
You can still have
big plans. Okay?
- Take classes here at community co...
- That's not what I want!
There has to be
something else.
A vertebral column
resection.
- What's that?
- Dr. Shepherd!
We would remove the vertebrae
causing the curvature
and replace it
with a titanium cage
that would protect
your spinal cord.
It's a very risky,
very complex surgery
with many potential
complications.
It could result
in paralysis, even death.
Mm. But if it works?
It would permanently correct
the deformity.
You can...
You can do it now?
- I don't recommend it.
- Yes.
It is risky.
But if you decide that it's
what you want, we could do it.
- I want it.
- No, no, no, no way.
Look, man.
You've... Y-You had everything.
Yale Law School,
tons of friends,
an awesome girlfriend.
Y-Y-You were even c-captain
of that weird ultimate
Frisbee team.
Hey, man, we were...
We were league champions.
You gave up everything.
Now you have h-hospital food
and waiting rooms.
I like the fries here.
You're the world's
best brother.
Okay?
Y-You're my personal hero.
But I'm 18.
I want this surgery, and I'm
gonna do it no matter what.
But I'd rather have you on...
On my side.
I can't lose you, too.
You're not gonna lose me.
This isn't the part
where I die.
This is the part where
I'm brave and it pays off.
Look at her.
Look at her eyes.
She says she can do it.
Until next time, brother.
Until next time.
He asked
about his options.
We could paralyze him.
A woman
just became quadriplegic
- on our table.
- That was out of our control.
Exactly.
There are no guarantees.
Our patient
has to come first.
I am putting him first.
This is what he wants.
This is what you want
because you've still
got something to prove.
Do I need to find someone else
to do this with me?
Because I will.
Amelia, I'm saying
it's been... a rough night.
I'm saying y-your sisters just
treated you like a teenager.
They questioned
your surgical skills.
I can't care
what they think.
You think you don't care?!
I just spent the night
pretending I was Owen!
This is not about them!
I cannot let them define me!
If I did, I would still be the
messed-up baby of the family,
the person that I revert to
when I am with them.
- And that is not who I am!
- I know that!
I'm asking
if you know that.
if you're okay.
I'm asking
if you are sure
you're not doing this surgery
to prove something
to people who clearly have
no understanding of you at all.
Jonah deserves a life
that is more than a cycle
of surgery after surgery.
It's what he wants.
And I know I can do it.
Okay.
♪ I remember the minute ♪
♪ It was like a switch
was flipped ♪
Vertebral column's out.
- Get me the titanium cage.
- ♪ I was just a kid ♪
Careful of distraction
on the cord.
♪ Who grew up strong enough
to pick this armor up ♪
♪ And suddenly, it fit ♪
♪ God, that was so long ago,
long ago, long ago ♪
We just lost the signal.
The cage spread too far.
There's too much traction
on the spinal cord.
♪ I was little, I was weak,
perfectly naive ♪
He's paralyzed.
So we revert to where we were
before we lost signal.
♪ And I grew up too quick ♪
♪ Now you won't see
all that I have to lose ♪
Dr. Shepherd...
- Shh! Please.
- ♪ And all I've lost in the fight to protect it ♪
♪ I won't let you in,
I swore never again ♪
Signal's back.
I got it.
♪ I can't afford ♪
- ♪ No, I refuse to be rejected ♪
- He is not paralyzed.
♪ I want to break these bones
till they're better ♪
♪ I want to break them right
and feel alive ♪
♪ You were wrong,
you were wrong, you were wrong ♪
♪ My healing needed
more than time ♪
♪ When I see fragile things,
helpless things, broken things ♪
♪ I see the familiar ♪
♪ I was little, I was weak,
I was perfect, too ♪
♪ Now I'm a broken mirror ♪
♪ But I can't let you see
all that I have to lose ♪
♪ All I've lost in the fight
to protect it ♪
No neurological deficits.
How do you feel?
Like I'm going to Cali.
How long should he, uh,
stay off his feet?
A day or two.
It's good for him to walk.
Ease into it, though.
Your doctors here will
oversee your follow-up,
but you know
how to reach us.
Wait. So that's it?
You guys change my whole damn
life and then you just leave?
Well, come see us.
Seattle is a short plane ride
away from Berkeley.
True.
Thank you.
Thank you guys for...
giving me a future.
You were brave.
And it paid off.
Thank you, uh, for...
Thank you.
You were brave,
and it paid off.
Do you want to go for, uh...
get something to eat?
No, um...
No, I need to walk.
I'll see you on the plane.
Brady.
You okay?
Yeah.
I just don't know
what to do.
Jonah's gonna be fine.
I know.
And I'm glad.
I just...
I don't know what I'm gonna do...
without him, you know?
Would it be weird,
you know...
W-w-would it...
Would it be weird
if I just followed him
to California
and just... I don't know...
Was... was nearby?
Was...
- I mean, he's...
- He's your brother.
I get it.
I miss my brother
every day.
But maybe try not to
follow him to college.
Yeah.
Maybe try to give him
some breathing room
to become whoever he is
outside your shadow.
And then visit.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Hey, kiddo.
Can we... go somewhere
and, uh, talk?
What... What happened
with Owen?
It just...
didn't work out.
Do you think I sabotage
relationships?
That I don't know
how to love?
Well.
That answers that.
I got you!
I remember when you were
learning to ride a bike.
Derek and your sisters
were zipping
all over the neighborhood,
and you were desperate
to join them.
And so you...
You, uh, pulled
that old purple bike
out of the shed.
You know,
the one with the...
the streamers
hanging off the handlebars.
- Mm.
- Those things were all ripped out
by the time
that bike was mine.
And you refused
to use training wheels
because you said that
was for babies.
And you wouldn't
let me help, either.
I had to... I had to spy on you
from the kitchen window.
You don't know
how hard that was.
Watching you fall
over and over again.
My other kids didn't like
to fail, but... but you...
Okay.
Yeah, Mom, I get it.
One time you took this...
This big spill,
and you... and you
ripped open your pants.
And by the time
I ran out,
you had... pulled that-
that old ratty bike up,
and... and you were
halfway down the block.
Every time you fell down,
you got up
and came back stronger.
But not that you... that you
didn't care about falling,
but... just
you weren't afraid of it.
And that's
what made you...
What makes you...
Out of all the kids...
the most
like your father.
After he died,
it was hard
to... be around any...
- anything... that reminded me of him.
- ♪ All of your days ♪
- And...
- ♪ All your days ♪
♪ Stay safe inside ♪
- ...Derek said he'd watch out for you.
- ♪ Stay safe inside ♪
And he did his best,
- but... he wasn't your mother.
- ♪ All your time ♪
- ♪ All of your time ♪
- You deserved a mother.
♪ I know you can
safely hide ♪
But h-he offered,
and I let him.
♪ When you're ♪
♪ Living undercover ♪ - And
it is my biggest regret.
It turns out that,
under
the right conditions,
neurons can recover.
I took in
a drug addict.
- ♪ Though the worst may not be over ♪
- Betty, Leo's birth mom.
♪ You can count on me ♪
- ♪ You an count on me ♪
- 15, so of course,
she already knew everything.
♪ All it could take ♪
- ♪ Is a move my way ♪
- Parenting her was...
♪ Darling, can't you see? ♪
...the hardest thing I've ever done.
♪ I will be the last to leave ♪
And I'm pretty sure she was
a tenth the trouble that I was.
♪ All it could take
is a look my way ♪
♪ Honey, can't you see? ♪
I put you through a lot.
♪ There's no more need
for hide-and-seek ♪
I know it wasn't easy.
I'm sorry I missed
your wedding.
your brain tumor.
I'm sorry things don't
go better with your sisters.
It's fine.
Not everyone's close
to their siblings.
If they can break
from normal operations
and focus on healing,
they have a chance at regrowth.
If you don't think
you're worthy of love...
♪ All of your nights,
all of your fights ♪
...if you don't think your love
is valuable, you're wrong.
♪ You're safe this time ♪
And that's on me.
♪ Though the worst
may not be over ♪
Mom,
I don't blame you for...
Oh, oh, I...
I know, hon.
♪ You can count on me, you
can count on me ♪ -
But when you most needed help
trying to...
- ♪ All it could take ♪
- ...make sense of life or...
♪ Is a move my way ♪
...loss...
♪ Darling, can't you see? ♪
...or love...
♪ I will be the last to leave ♪
...I wasn't there.
♪ Honey, can't you see? ♪
So put that on me...
♪ There's no more need ♪
...and move forward.
- What if I can't?
- ♪ There's no more need ♪
- ♪ For hide-and-seek ♪
- It's human nature to want
to fix what's broken.
Well...
then that's on you.
♪ There's no more need
for hide-and-seek ♪
- ..the bat.
- Fires.
Slaps it to right.
That one's
gonna split the gap
and head
all the way to the wall!
One run is in.
Here comes Beasley
around third,
but cut off by Montanari,
and he's, of course,
standing up...
You are kind.
And you were brave
last night, too.
With my family.
And... And in that surgery.
You didn't have to
do that with me.
Either thing.
You are...
Surprising to me.
And you deserve
a lot better
than the things
that I said to you.
You are more than
a human blue light.
Though you are very,
very good at bluelighting.
I'm sorry.
And I'd like
to make it up to you,
if you'll let me.
Lucy Spraggan's
"Stick The Kettle On" plays...
♪ I know some days are hard ♪
♪ But I know
how strong you are ♪
- Mmm.
- ♪ The front door's open if you're broken ♪
Mmm.
- ♪ Let's talk the night away ♪
- Mmm!
♪ Sometimes we get it wrong,
stick the kettle on ♪
Mm-hmm.
♪ I spend my nights alone ♪
♪ I keep these doors closed ♪
We may not be able to
replicate exactly what we lost.
- Oh, yeah.
- Yeah?
You got a little something,
too, right there.
♪ That I should just man up ♪
♪ Some days we get it wrong ♪
♪ Stick the kettle on ♪
But in its place will grow
something new.
♪ La-la-la-la, la-la-la-la ♪
Hey!
Welcome home!
- How'd it go?
- Uh, it's a long story.
- Mm?
- So come tell us.
Well, the case went fine,
but then we ran into Nancy.
- Your sister?
- Yep.
- Is she the snarky one?
- They're all the snarky one.
She invited us to dinner.
♪ Sometimes we get it wrong,
stick the kettle on ♪
- And you went?
- To her house?
And I got ambushed.
- It's a long process, but it happens...
- She was there.
Slowly, but surely...
♪ Sometimes we get it wrong ♪
...until we have what we need.
♪ Stick the kettle on ♪
Synchronized  by  srjanapala