Are you sure you
should do that here?
We're awfully close to the road.
What are you so worried about?
What we're doing is illegal!
I just don't like doing
things that are illegal.
What? So, we just
dump him on the ground?
No, you know, we scatter him.
Around the campsite.
This is our spot.
Okay, Pops. It's show time.
Everybody has something to hide.
We can't just expose all
our secrets to the world.
It's on the top
shelf in the fridge.
Hello, I'm in here.
Oh, I know. I'm sorry.
Our shower's still
busted and I got rounds.
You know what, I have
told him a thousand times,
"You put the bread on
the counter, it molds.
"You put it in the
fridge and it's fine."
I'm right, right?
Okay. Whew!
Hey, do you know
where the bread is?
You need to get
your shower fixed!
That's how we get hurt.
It's how we risk
hurting other people.
We have to decide
how much we let out
and keep the truth to ourselves.
Hey. How'd it go with the kids?
Uh, great. They're amazing. I
just dropped them off at daycare.
Thanks again for watching them.
Yeah. How about you?
How was your weekend in DC
with your husband?
It was fun.
I'm a little
exhausted, you know.
But it was the good
kind of exhausted, right?
Did you even leave the bedroom?
Was he surprised? Did he freak?
Yeah, did he freak?
Or did you just go
straight to getting
♪ frea-kay? ♪
You know, did we even push
the button, because it's just...
Oh. Mm-hmm.
Hey, look who's back.
Meredith was just about to tell
us about her weekend with Derek.
Good. Tell me now so you
don't show up in my bed tonight.
It's a good thing you didn't
walk in on this morning.
Oh.
Everyone's getting
freaky but me.
Well, actually, I was just...
Actually remembered,
I have to... Yeah.
They totally got freaky.
And I come in this morning,
and Herman's rearranged
the entire OR board
with new fetal surgeries.
I used to be so good
at one-night stands.
I missed a beat.
No, I was great at them.
And now, whenever
I'm not watching Sofia,
I just sit alone at
home in my pajamas.
I want to be out of my
pajamas and not alone.
So, go. Meet someone. It's easy.
Oh, it's easy.
Well, what do you
do? What's your line?
I don't use lines.
I'm just honest.
What do you mean "honest"?
I don't know.
They start with,
"What do you do?"
And I tell them I'm
a trauma surgeon,
and they wonder
why I chose that.
And I tell them I
served in the war,
and I fixed soldiers
on the battlefield,
and that was a
really satisfying
way to save lives.
And it still is.
Yeah, that'll do it.
Ah, you've got game, Major Hunt.
It's not a game. It's just...
What happened to the couch?
Oh.
Hey.
Sorry I'm late.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Three surgeries today, Robbins.
They're not gonna
round on themselves.
I know. I'm on it.
Yeah, Wilson just barged
in and stole my shower.
Edwards, does she
always walk around naked?
Not around the
hospital, generally.
It's like Residents Gone Wild.
Robbins, do you
live with residents?
Oh, God. Is that thing still on?
You're a grown-up. Get your
own place. I need you focused here.
Lie down, Nicole.
So, did Wilson just climb
in the shower with you?
Yeah. No. Instead of me.
Was she coming on to you?
No! Doubtful.
You know what? Can
we just... Let's drop it.
Residents Gone Wild.
Would you go? You're
making her laugh too much.
Mmm. Wow.
I thought you were
going back to the airport.
I just couldn't
get on that plane.
Thank you.
Thank you for letting
me stay the weekend,
being there for me.
It was just what I needed.
I hate the circumstances,
but I'm glad it gave us
a chance to reconnect.
I hear that Jackson and
April are coming in today.
Have you seen him?
Catherine, he asked
you to keep your distance.
And I'm honoring that request.
Look, I know how hard
that is for you, okay?
But you sent food, you call for
updates. They know you're there.
I know. I just hate it.
I'll miss you.
Well, I'll be in the OR, anyway.
I have an open colectomy today.
I could scrub in, do
your ureteral stents.
That'll give us a
little more time.
Hmm... I could make that happen.
Make it happen.
So, you and Meredith are
getting pretty tight, huh?
What do you mean?
Well, what did she say
about this weekend?
Why? Did she tell you something?
You said she told you.
Uh, no, I said she
was about to tell me.
What do you think she
was about to tell you?
What did she tell you?
Wasn't there a couch there?
Don't you want to say something?
This is the closest
thing to a funeral.
No, Dad hated funerals.
"Sprinkle me in the woods."
God, he was a pain in the ass.
Well, you can't just say that.
You know, one of
his favorite memories
was taking us out here camping.
"We eat what we catch."
"We sleep in what we can carry."
Just us men.
You okay?
Maybe we should just go.
Hey, race you to the top.
Come on. What you
got? What you got, hmm?
Oh, goodness.
It's so muggy. It's
hard to breathe.
You okay?
Hey, Curt. You should sit down.
Whoa! Curt! MIRANDA: Curt!
Curt!
Call 911!
Hey. How was your weekend?
It was nice. She got some.
She doesn't want
to talk about it.
Oh, well, I'm glad you
went. I got some, too.
Definitely don't want
to talk about that.
What do we got?
Curtis Warren, post syncope.
Thirty-one.
He's still tachycardic,
diaphoretic,
and hypotensive after fainting.
But don't just stand here,
Grey. Give me a hand.
Right over here!
Hillary List,
27-year-old female,
found unconscious at the
scene after a pretty bad tumble
down a flight of
concrete stairs in the park.
Hill, honey, I'm right here.
Oh, it's all my fault.
This was your fault?
No. No, no, no, no, no.
I didn't push her.
I proposed to her.
Okay, let's go to trauma two.
Fast scan is negative.
Because there's
nothing wrong with me.
Any changes in
your diet recently?
I told them I missed breakfast,
so I was a little
woozy in the woods.
He's still mildly
hypotensive after two liters.
I'm fine.
Ahh!
Well, there's definitely
some tenderness there.
Well, run his liver enzymes
and get a coag panel.
Let's get you into this.
You know what? I'm
gonna re-check that...
No! Look, I don't need
to put on this stupid thing.
Would you calm down?
Look, Benji, get off me!
Would you tell them to back off?
Okay, okay. Okay.
Family shouldn't
be in here anyway.
Let's step outside.
You can change, and
I will be back for you.
He's usually a sweetheart.
I'll go talk to him.
Well, Bailey, he's my
patient. I'll take it. You can go.
I took her to the park.
It was where we
had our first date,
so I thought that had
a certain symmetry.
I'll order a head CT
and an a X-ray for her
right wrist and right knee.
At the top of the stairs,
I got down on my knee
and I said,
"Hillary, when I met you,
"I felt like my life
blossomed with fullness.
"Like the sun had shone
down on me, baby."
And that's as far as I got.
I had more, but she fainted
and she fell all the way down.
I should've caught her.
Hill? Hill? Hill? Honey?
Honey. Hey, hey, hey. It's me.
Right here. Hey, I'm here.
I'm never leaving your side.
I'll never ever leave you.
I'll never...
Oh, she's out again.
Hill? Hill? Hillary?
Todd, we're gonna
admit her now. Yeah.
So, Dr. Wilson's gonna show
you where you can wait, okay?
And page neuro. I'm here.
Todd.
I'll just... I'm just gonna
be over here, baby.
Dr. Herman, you scheduled
another surgery for tomorrow?
I thought we said...
Yes, the Larsen mom. Sorry.
Is this the attendings'
lounge couch?
It was.
Dr. Herman, please stop
making me be this guy.
You can't just steal
hospital furniture.
I need this couch. This is
the best couch in the building.
It's firm, but soft.
Bouncy.
Responsive.
Would you like to try it out?
Well, um... I think that's...
I appreciate the offer, but I...
Uh, Hunt. I'm messing with you.
Larsen's gonna be a quick in and out.
- 30, OR six.
Is that fine with you?
That's fine, yeah.
And...
Was that a "no" on
trying out the couch?
Hey. So, I'm good to go?
Curt, your liver enzymes,
they're off the charts.
Any idea why that might be?
I got to reminiscing
about Dad last night.
Maybe one too
many whisky toasts.
Okay, I'm gonna get a CT.
Oh, come on.
Listen...
What are you getting at?
I ran some extra tests,
because what I was seeing
wasn't making any sense.
Your lab results for
a 30-year-old man
are not normal,
and you had the estrogen
levels of a young woman.
I just want to know what you're
dealing with so I can help you.
Hillary, the scans
show that the fall
caused an artery
under your skull to bleed.
You'll need
surgery to repair it.
And then Dr. Wilson and I will
repair the fracture in your knee.
But none of this explains
why you passed out.
Has this ever happened before?
Fainting, dizzy spells?
No, never.
Uh... Todd said that it
happened a couple of times.
You were talking on
the couch and then you...
I just nodded off.
Well, I'd like to run a complete
neuro work-up to find out...
Is that really necessary?
I know it's scary,
but multiple fainting
spells can mean
a lot of things,
heart problems...
It's not that.
I'm also concerned about
narcolepsy, cataplexy...
No, no! There's no plexies.
I didn't faint.
Not on the couch,
not on the stairs.
Okay, well, Todd said that...
I faked it.
I faked fainting
when he proposed
because I didn't
know how to say no
without breaking his
tender, little, quivering heart.
Whoa.
We should scrub in
together more often.
I could come to you on occasion.
I'm thinking he will need
a component separation.
I'll call in a plastics consult.
No, he's fine.
There's hardly any...
Page Dr. Avery, please.
Uh-huh. You got it.
If there's good news and bad
news, I want the good news first.
Okay.
The good news is, a person
can live without a spleen.
Oh.
Wow.
I'm removing yours today.
The CT showed your
spleen is remarkably swollen.
It's probably due to a
clot in the splenic vein...
Are you on drugs?
Coke or something?
Benji, come on.
'Cause I'm looking
at this organ damage
and I don't know what to think.
Do you have any idea
what it could be, Dr. Grey?
Okay. Curt.
Don't be stupid.
All right, if you're in trouble,
you can tell me, whatever it is.
You know that.
Ben. You know me.
I don't do drugs.
I never have.
Can you make that call?
He wouldn't lie to me.
Drugs are off the table.
But it's something, so try
thinking like a doctor, not his...
I am thinking like a doctor.
Maybe there's a
genetic component.
My father just died of colon
cancer. Maybe we start there.
I don't think it's his colon.
You got a better idea?
All right, then we
start running tests.
Look, I just lost
my dad, Miranda.
I'm not gonna lose
my brother, too.
Mmm-hmm. Just...
Okay, is this
what I think it is?
What do you think it is?
I'm not blind, Grey. My
husband might be, but I'm not.
Now, he has no hair
on his chest or arms.
He waxes his eyebrows.
I'd kill to have
eyebrows like that.
And then I'm looking at these
numbers and the splenic damage,
is he doing what
I think he's doing?
You have to ask Curt.
Nurses' station.
That Zola, she could
play Go Fish all night long.
You have a budding
card shark on your hands.
Yeah, well, we
eventually hide the cards.
It's the only way she'll stop.
I'll have to remember
that for next time.
Look, I just want
to say that, um...
I am not here to judge
you, but I'm a bad liar. So...
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You packed a
suitcase full of lingerie
and you went away
for the weekend.
Yeah, I...
And then Derek called me three
times asking where you were.
Meanwhile, you
texted me telling me
what a great time
you were having.
So, whatever you
were doing, whoever,
he, she, they, whatever,
it wasn't with
him, and that's all.
I want to be here for you,
but I like Derek
and I hate lying.
Grey! Pierce! Get in here!
Okay, okay. It's okay.
Call the OR. Let them
know we're coming now!
Oh, God, Curt!
Robbins. Let's go scrub.
Coming.
Listen, just talk to her,
and maybe buy her a robe.
Why would I do that?
Was this about
the naked resident?
Ooh, you and
Wilson, you're a thing.
You know what? Let's not.
And Robbins can get
handsy with the residents.
Really? I do not!
Last year, she got handsy.
HR got involved.
There are policies now.
Because of you?
Robbins, that's incredible.
It's not. Both of
you, stop, okay?
Alex, it's inappropriate.
She's a resident. I'm her
superior. I'm a girl who likes girls.
It just puts us both in a
very awkward position,
and you should respect that.
Well, I'm kind of down
for whatever happens.
I'm gonna kill you.
Hey. Hey.
You need to start putting
on pants around the house
'cause Robbins keeps
checking out your ass.
No. No. Alex, no.
You don't need to put pants
on, okay? Your ass is fine.
See? That's reportable.
No! I...
I hate you all.
I have surgery.
This is the best day.
Oh, God, I'm awful.
There is nothing
wrong with Todd.
He's nice and he's stable
and he cares for me deeply.
So deeply.
And he's clingy,
and he loves to...
I don't even know
what to call it,
but he likes to pet me.
It's really soft, and it... Ugh!
He's boring.
So, I just started
doing this thing
where I pretend to
faint so he'll stop talking.
Wow, that is...
Diabolical.
Why don't you just
tell him the truth?
Because it would kill him.
I mean, he wants to take
things to the next level,
but the more that
he feels, the less I do.
And then today, we were in the
park, and he got down on one knee
and he looked up at
me with his big wet eyes,
so I just... Faked it.
I didn't realize how
close I was to the steps.
But I had to go with
it all the way down.
You can really commit.
Yeah.
But not to Todd.
Shepherd, how's Herman?
Any changes to the tumor?
Uh, it's grown
a little inferiorly.
But it's still within the
margins I expected.
Why?
I was just checking.
Actually, um...
Her behavior is...
She's stealing furniture.
Oh.
And she was flirting with me.
Herman flirted with you?
I think so.
I... Yeah.
Did you take her up on it?
I mean, she's very attractive.
No. Yes, she is...
And tall.
I mean, she might be the
tallest person in the hospital.
You might find tall people
attractive. I don't know.
No, I don't.
Not as a rule,
but professionally,
it's not a good idea.
Is that a rule? No co-workers?
Didn't say that.
I like co-workers.
But the hospital, we
have rules that are, um...
Thank you for the update.
You wanted a consult?
Not me. CATHERINE: Me.
Mom.
I asked you to go.
I need you to take a look
at this incision, sweetheart.
She's not just trying to
check on me and April?
Don't look at me.
I got played, too.
They just took him in.
How the hell did this happen?
He was sitting up and
talking to me an hour ago.
Well, we knew about the spleen.
It made his stomach
muscles bleed,
but Pierce will clip
them and Grey...
You were right. You
were right about the drugs.
I didn't want to believe
it at first, but it's obvious.
He's using.
Okay, now, we shouldn't jump...
I'll get him in rehab.
As soon as he can
walk out of here, I'm...
Ben, wait.
What do you think
it is? Coke? Crystal?
Come on, you're usually
right about these things.
Tell me.
I think
you should talk to Curt.
Is there something
you're not telling me?
After surgery, he'll
tell you everything.
Tell me what? Miranda.
Just talk to him. He'll...
But what if I don't
get the chance to?
What if he doesn't
come out of surgery?
Oh, that's nonsense.
Now, just calm down.
Calm down?
I'm being lied to by my brother,
and now I'm being
lied to by my wife.
I'm not lying to you.
Well, no one's telling
me the damn truth!
I'll tell you!
It's only because
when he tells you,
you need to react better
than this, Ben Warren.
What is it?
Okay, Curt is...
Curt is transitioning.
He...
She is transgender.
And she identifies as female,
and she wants to
live life as a woman.
Your brother is
becoming your sister.
Oh, my God.
Oh, that son of a bitch.
He put you up to this?
Bleeding is controlled.
Clamping the hilum.
Suture ligature.
So, what did you
say when he called?
The first time, I said that
you were in the shower.
Ligating the gastric vessels.
The second time, I said
you were taking a nap.
And the third time,
I said Hunt called you in for
an emergent rectal abscess.
I hate lying.
I didn't want to spoil anything.
I need to dissect the
splenorenal ligament.
Metz.
Hey, okay.
Pierce just controlled the
gastric bleeds with clips,
and now Grey is finishing
taking out the spleen.
All right, now, he's
upset about Dad.
He's obviously having some
sort of emotional breakdown,
so we'll get him
a psych consult.
No, we won't.
Curt's crazy. This
makes no sense.
All right, the only thing that
does make sense right now
is that after the surgery,
you will talk to Curt.
Yeah. And you
will listen to Curt
tell you her good news,
and it is good news.
And you will listen, and you
will tell her that you love her
and tell her that you'll
always be here for her.
Okay, so after the fetoscope is
inserted, then I will deploy the shunt,
and you'll manipulate
the camera, right?
You're a hypocrite.
I beg your pardon?
You were so high and mighty
when I was boffing Graham.
Which one was it? Which
resident did you sully?
Oh, God. I knew
that you would...
You can't suddenly become
interesting and then clam up.
It was a year ago,
and she's gone now.
Weren't you married
last year? Yes.
No. Well, we were broken up.
I thought you just split.
This was a different...
I cheated on Callie, okay?
Oh, my God. How have
you been hiding this from me?
Hiding what?
The dirt. You're dirty.
And here I thought
you were no fun at all.
Oh, stop it. I'm...
You're a dirty, dirty girl.
You're dirty.
Minimal swelling. I like that.
Hey, can I get an ETA
on when you're closing
just so I can prep the leg?
One last vessel here.
So, she threw herself
down a flight of stairs
just to avoid telling
him yes or no?
Mm-hmm.
Have you met the boyfriend?
Wilson, go let him know that
her brain surgery
was successful.
Bring tissues.
Poor guy.
Poor guy?
I'm sewing her
brain shut right now.
Oh, Todd's the problem here?
Why? 'Cause he cares too
much? He feels too much?
He's willing to devote
himself fully to another person.
That's the problem?
If it makes the other person
want to pass out, yeah.
Well, then that's it. That's why
I can't pick people up anymore,
because I don't know
how to put them back down.
That's why I have no game.
I Used to have game.
I had such game.
Yeah?
I used to be fun and cool
and sexy and go to bars
and do this thing where
you make eye contact once
and look away.
Just reel them
in without a word.
Such game.
Hey, what was your secret?
Drugs. I was on drugs. Mmm.
So, I'm leaving out the
terrible, terrible repercussions,
but ever since I got off
the drugs, I've gotten worse.
Now I'm just all mumbling
and vomiting words
and no cool, no
sexy, no game at all.
Same here. Game over.
I want to be clear.
I am in no way
endorsing narcotics
as a dating aid.
Understood.
So, dinner's coming?
Yes, Mom.
You still haven't
told me. How's April?
Mom, she's all right.
And I'm fine. We're doing okay.
Mm-hmm.
I don't believe
that for one second.
Mom, what do you want me to say?
Mom, she's sad, obviously.
April is angry, okay?
About the baby, about God.
She just needs her space.
And I can't help her.
I just make her crazy,
which just makes
me feel useless.
She doesn't need space
so much as the
illusion of space.
You should do what I do.
Stay out of her
way, but not too far.
Find something else
to occupy your mind.
Work is good.
Yeah, be close,
but just out of sight.
And you'll be there for
her when she's ready.
Okay, I'm pretty sure what
you just described is stalking.
Your abdominal
closure should be fine.
Is that what this
weekend was for you?
Something else to
occupy your mind?
I'm not cheating on my husband.
Then where were you?
It's really not that big a deal.
Then why are you
being so weird about it?
You have to tell me something.
I have to?
I lied for you.
I'm sorry if I put
you in a position
where you felt like
you had to lie for me,
but that doesn't make
this any of your business.
Okay, maybe not. I just...
I thought we were
finally getting somewhere.
You trusted me with your kids.
I trust my babysitter
with my kids.
That doesn't mean I
owe her my life story.
Pierce, I'm sorry.
No. No, it's fine. It's fine.
That came out wrong.
You're right. Just
do me a favor.
Next time, call your babysitter.
Leave me out of it.
Oh, there she is.
Are you all right?
How is she? Is
she all well again?
She's gonna be fine. Both
surgeries went very well.
Thank you. Thank you.
Hill. I'm gonna take you home.
I'm gonna make
sure that you have
everything you need, all right?
You tell him right now.
Todd.
You have been so sweet,
and you have been so kind,
and I have been unfair to you.
No, no.
No, don't worry about me.
I love you. I'm right here.
And I'm never leaving you.
Ever.
Oh, Hillary. Hillary?
Hillary? She fainted!
Help her!
For God's sake.
She can't take
another fall like that.
Todd, what Hillary's
trying to tell you
is that she wants
to break up with you.
What? I'm so sorry.
I know that all you want is to
help her, but she doesn't want that.
She doesn't deserve it.
She's faking this right now.
What? Todd...
You deserve someone who
wants you there, you know?
Um... Someone
who needs the kind of
attention that
only you can give,
and it's not gonna be Hillary,
okay, and it shouldn't be.
And you will be
fine without her,
and it may take a while
to find the right person,
but you will find her.
You should start looking, okay?
She's right. Don't waste
another minute. Start right now.
There.
Thank you.
Just tell me, where is
this all coming from?
It's coming from
me. This is who I am.
Since when?
I mean, what, you
just suddenly decided...
Benji, I've known
since I was five.
Five?
Because, you know, I wanted to
play for the Bears when I was five,
because you don't know
crap when you're five.
I knew this.
Yeah, but why didn't I know it?
We shared a room for 18 years.
You ever have that dream
where you're pushed out on stage
and everybody knows
their lines except you?
And you're in some costume
or you're naked or whatever.
And you're just trapped
there. You can't...
That was my whole life.
Every day of my
life, pretending.
Benji, I'm tired of pretending.
I just want to be
happy with who I am.
Can you understand that?
So, now you give a
damn about what I think?
Now suddenly it matters
that I understand?
You know it does.
I'm just supposed
to be okay with this?
to accept this?
What...
Okay, I'll go talk to him.
Don't bother.
How soon do you think
I can get out of here?
I don't imagine you
need a ride to the airport.
I have a car.
What are you doing?
You scrub in with me,
you take over the OR,
so you can call your
son on a phony consult?
I needed to know
how he was doing.
I'm talking about us.
What about us, Richard?
It looks like you
got what you wanted
and you're running out the door.
You used me.
I seem to recall your saying,
"I use people all the time."
Cristina Yang, the Harper Avery.
So, why are you
so surprised now?
I was angry when
I said those things.
And I was angry
when I heard them.
I thought after the
last few days, I...
I thought we'd
moved on from that.
Richard, you were here
for me in a terrible time.
I appreciate that,
but I'm still me,
and you're not
okay with who I am.
One minute, you find a
powerful woman attractive,
the next minute,
your feelings are hurt.
You can't have it both ways.
You're gonna have to figure that
out before we move on anywhere.
I went to the airport,
I got through security,
I went up to the gate,
they called my boarding
group, and I just stood there.
I froze. I didn't
get on the plane.
I watched the plane take
off from behind the glass,
I got in my car, and I left.
Oh, Meredith.
I didn't know how to tell anyone
that I didn't get on the
plane to visit my husband.
So, I drove to one of
those hotels by the airport.
And you stayed there
by yourself all weekend?
Yeah.
You were
embarrassed, so you hid.
I kind of get that.
Well, it's... No, no, it's okay.
You don't have to
say another word.
That must've been awful.
Those cheap hotel
rooms are horrible.
You must've felt terrible
and lonely and embarrassed
and I just made it
worse by bugging you
and asking you questions
when I should've just...
I totally understand
why you didn't tell me.
If that happened to me, I
wouldn't have told anybody, either.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry, but
thank you for telling me.
Thank you for understanding.
Benjamin Warren, I'm
so disappointed in you.
She's your family.
I get it, okay?
You're so evolved, so
tolerant and quick to adjust.
And I'm just a dumb caveman.
Well, you don't have to be.
Twenty-five years, Miranda.
I counted them up today.
That's how long we
either shared a bedroom
or an apartment or a
damn tent in the woods.
It's a long time for this not
to come up, don't you think?
She wasn't ready.
If this was anyone else, there
wouldn't even be an issue,
but I told him everything.
I mean, from my first crush,
Kahlia Hogg, fourth grade,
to the night I proposed to
the gorgeous Miranda Bailey.
And everything in between.
I had to tell Curt.
First thing, always.
But now he's got the
biggest thing in his life
and he waited 25
years to tell me.
How's that supposed
to make me feel?
Well, this isn't about you, Ben.
It's her song. So, get off
the stage, let her sing it.
No, could you please
just stop with that?
I feel like it was
all a lie, you know?
Our whole life...
He lied to me.
Well, Curt needs your help now.
Yeah, well, it's
a little late to ask.
Should've asked 25 years ago.
I'm done with him.
Her.
Curt.
Um, this is Dr. Avery.
He's a plastic surgeon.
Um... You might
want to hear him out.
It's your call.
You have a name yet?
Guessing you're not
sticking with Curtis.
Rosalind.
That's a beautiful name.
So, can I call you
Rosalind then?
'Cause I don't know
what we're waiting for.
Hey, I'm Jackson.
Now, let's go over
some ground rules.
First, those off-shelf hormone
treatments you're taking,
no, those are over.
From now on, everything
that goes in your body
is approved and
regulated by this hospital.
Understood?
Absolutely.
Okay. You see a therapist?
Not for a while.
Okay. Well, it's
time to start again.
So, we'll get started
with a full medical history.
You know, I used to be fun.
I used to skate around
the halls of this hospital.
Why don't you?
Oops. My bad.
I used to go dancing.
I used to flirt and
be flirted with.
Now I live in a house
full of naked people
and all of my friends
are her friends,
and all I have is work and
I never want to go home.
Mmm. I had a busy, busy life.
I sat on all these boards,
Pacific Ballet, Seattle Opera.
Whatever was very
important to my ex.
I used to be so worried
about what he thought of me,
what my peers thought,
what everybody thought.
But now I do what I want,
when I want, and it's sweet.
I have to tell you, Robbins,
my life is so much better
now that I have nothing.
I mean, I can't
recommend a tumor,
but you should try it.
You should go home.
I am home.
Why do you think
I stole this couch?
We can't waste a minute.
I'm gonna stay here until...
Until it's over.
Whatever that means.
Then I'll stay with you tonight.
You should know
I'm not gonna have sex with you.
Shut up!
Uh, hi.
Hey. Sorry.
Do you drink wine?
Uh...
I just wanted to visit,
and people bring wine
sometimes when they're
going to visit another person.
Especially if they have...
They bring a bottle.
That's water.
So...
Because I don't drink wine.
I don't drink at
all. Not anymore.
So, I brought water, and...
I'm sorry.
I have literally no game.
I should go. It's sparkling.
Mm-hmm. Lime.
Just wanted to say hi.
Hey, do you want some water?
Not thirsty.
Okay, wait.
Amelia.
Stop walking.
I'm gonna kiss you now,
so don't say anything.
It's scary to reveal
everything about ourselves.
And now you can go home.
I'm gonna go home.
Which is that way. To my house.
Fear makes us
hold ourselves back.
Is that so wrong?
Here you go.
Okay, this is taking too long.
Dance with me.
Okay.
Maybe. Probably.
But still
it helps to be a little sneaky,
a little protective.
It's not safe to just blurt
out all of our secrets.
Never got on the plane.
I never went to DC.
Now you want to blab.
Where's Pierce?
What is she? Morning
shift? I get nights?
I went to a hotel.
What? With who? Do I know him?
No. By myself.
What, you didn't
want to see Derek?
I did. Too much.
What if I got off the plane and
he wasn't happy to see me?
What if he didn't smile?
That would be bad.
That would mean
it's done, it's over.
So, what? You
just head out alone?
I mean, why didn't
you just come back?
I was going to.
And then, I didn't.
And it was amazing.
It was just me for three days.
All by myself.
I wasn't anybody's
wife or doctor or mother.
And I kind of liked it.
If I had gone to DC,
we would've fought
or we would've
talked about fighting.
And I don't want
to talk anymore.
I don't want to fight anymore.
Alex.
I don't want to leave him.
But I definitely do not want
to be with him right now.
We can't just lay all
the truth out there,
expose ourselves to
God and everybody.
Hey, have you seen my... Oh!
Oh! A little warning when
people are over would be nice.
I told her to wear pants.
I don't have to wear pants.
It's perfectly fine if
I don't wear pants.
Doesn't make me stupid.
'Cause once the truth is out...
I'm gonna marry that girl.
We have to face it ourselves.
I don't know what's
gonna happen with us.