She loves me...
she loves me not.
I'm not a nurse in training,
I'm a nurse in decorating.
Valentine's Day.
Can I help?
Can't you just do it?
Come on.
E.R. Yeah.
Carol, can you find
Dr. Ross for Mrs. Hall?
Got to get these to
the desk. Sure. Mrs..?
Hall.
Dr. Ross. He's the pediatrician.
Yeah. What seems
to be the problem?
Tatiana, she's very sick.
Aw, you don't feel well?
She has a fever and a cough.
She just doesn't seem right.
Okay. Come right this way.
Thank you.
Mark.
It's 10:00.
So?
So, you got in at
8:00, remember?
You weren't here overnight.
I was taking a nap.
Is there anything
wrong with taking a nap?
Certainly not.
Stomach ache in two.
Bounce back migraine in one.
Can I give them an E.T.A.?
Does that tickle?
Temperature's 100.
Does this hurt?
She doesn't speak much English.
She's Russian.
I adopted her in St.
Petersburg ten days ago.
When did the fever start?
I'd waited nearly six months.
Finally, all her
paperwork was in order.
Medical certificates.
She really seemed fine.
How long has she had the fever?
Almost a week.
Let's start her on
some oral amoxicillin.
She has some upper
respiratory congestion
and an ear infection,
which is probably
what's causing the fever.
Don't worry, Mrs. Hall,
we'll take good care of her.
Thank you, Doctor.
You're welcome.
Wendy, it's nice of you to
volunteer to put those up.
I didn't volunteer.
Okay.
Happy Valentine's Day.
Oh, thanks, Lydia.
Oh, and here's another
one for your stash.
Thank you.
Uh, hello.
Whoa-hoa!
Amy, Brooke...
Hey...
Wendy, Patty...
Come on. Who are these women?
I don't even remember them.
Oh, Carter, you're so cold.
No, I mean, I don't
remember meeting them.
Please! Help! Quick!
I hit him.
He dashed off the
sidewalk chasing a ball.
I tried to swerve the car.
We've got an M.V.A.
Please!
I'll page Benton.
Okay, go in here.
All right, let's clear
a trauma room.
39-year-old male fell from
a second-story balcony.
Watch yourself, ma'am.
Hypotensive, abdomen's rigid.
Mrs. Hall.
Mrs. Hall, wait.
Jerry, will you let me know
when Mrs. Hall
comes back in again?
Sure. Thanks.
I tried to dodge him, you know.
Scalp laceration.
I can't hear a thing.
He just came out of nowhere.
He's got a fractured
left front radius.
Where do you want the I.V.?
Please help him, okay, Doc?
All right, give me the bullet.
Car versus canine. Possible...
Car versus canine?
Got a fractured
left front leg, or
maybe it's radius ulna.
Nobody's quite sure
how to take the BP. A dog.
You called me
down here for a dog.
We called the vet's office.
They're sending someone over.
So what do we do now?
I think I'll name him Bill.
What, are you crazy?
You don't like the name Bill?
Yeah, well, you can call
him whatever you want to,
but you better do it fast,
'cause little Bill here
has stopped breathing.
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.
He's one of God's
creatures, for God's sake.
I'm not a vet,
Grabarsky. You could try.
No, I'll be upstairs trying
to take a gallbladder
out of a Homo sapien.
Did I miss anything?
You were only gone ten seconds.
Poor little guy.
No collar, no tags.
He must be a lost or a stray.
I should have taken dog lab
instead of pig lab.
Digestive system,
abdomen... whoa.
Look at that spleen.
Wow!
Could we hurry this up, please?
I.V. Goes in what vein?
Uh, try the large one, and
then give him some saline.
Somebody find out
where the hell the vet is.
Okay, here it is... intubation.
It's just like with a human
being, except when you
push back the tongue,
you can see the vocal cords.
All right. Get an ambu bag.
Let's intubate.
Pneumothorax right there.
A what?
Collapsed lung. Oh, my God.
Lydia, could you get
a 20-gauge needle
on a 60cc syringe
with a three-way stopcock.
Which intercostal
does it go between?
Uh, try the eighth,
below the heart.
All right.
Hold that.
Yeah.
Easy, now.
Hold it.
Bill lives.
Oh...
Hey!
All right well, all we have
to do is sew up the lac
and get a cast on
him, and he'll be
chasing squirrels
by the afternoon.
Well, Carter, Chen, I think
you can take it from here.
Somebody call housekeeping.
Tell them to get a hose.
No problem.
That was pretty cool
the way you gave
it mouth-to-mouth.
Yeah? Thank you.
You know, they
say the dog's mouth
is the cleanest
part of its body.
What do they say about its nose?
So, she said nothing
during the exam?
Nothing. I don't get it.
She brings in the little
girl, then disappears,
she leaves a fake phone number.
Why would somebody
do that? I have no idea.
How could somebody do that?
But we don't know the whole story.
We know we can't
reach her anywhere.
You know what, I'm going to
move Tatiana out to curtain two
so she doesn't feel
so alone back here.
Then I guess I'll have to call
Children and Family Services.
Thanks, Haleh.
Sure.
Well, that wasn't
so bad, was it?
Tatiana.
Eta imya
krasivoya.
Uh... moya...
moya mama russ kaya.
My mother's Russian.
How do you say hello?
Tatiana, uh... I'm Dr. Ross.
I'm Doug. I'm... I'm Doug.
Okay.
So you do speak
a little English.
Okay.
So you don't.
You just stay right here,
and we're going
to take care of you.
Kak tebya zovut?
Oh, um...
Zovut Carol.
That was normal.
What do you mean?
It's Valentine's Day.
It's like full moons...
All the crazies come out.
Ow.
What's wrong with your neck?
I slept on the sofa last night.
Oh, sorry I asked.
Want to tell me about it?
Well, it's about five feet long.
It's got little
blue flowers on it,
and there's a spectacular stain
on the right cushion Okay! Okay!
Right where Rachel did some
projectile vomiting... Mark...
Mark. Still waiting
on that stomachache
and migraine.
I am going to go
get something to eat.
I'm loving this
semi-foul mood of yours.
Yeah. Well, imagine
if we'd lost the dog.
See you.
Bye.
Doug.
"Do not steal. Benton."
Is there anything
good to eat in there?
Think Susan really
wants this yogurt?
No.
So you and Jen
valentining tonight?
She left for Milwaukee
this morning.
You? No, no, no. Never.
I always work the night
shift on Valentine's Day
to avoid any possible
dating conflicts.
That sounds mature.
Believe me, I
learned the hard way.
Dr. Ross, an ambulance
is bringing a 17-year-old in.
Crushed legs... Some
kind of train accident.
Dr. Benton said to get you.
Thank you, Wendy.
Can you believe
I said thank you?
Thank you, Wendy,
for letting me know
I get to work on some kid
whose legs have just
been pureed... that's weird.
Ah, I thought you'd
like some company.
Sobaka! Sobaka!
Is that okay?
We had to clear the
trauma room anyway.
Thanks.
Bill?
Bill.
Carol, I could use you
in curtain area three.
You know how Mark always says
Valentine's Day is
like the full moon,
all the nut cases come out?
I never really thought about it.
Cheerleaders.
Cheerleaders?
On acid.
Sounds like, uh, Mark was right.
Okay, are you Kirk Driscoll?
Sure.
I'm Dr. Lewis. This
is Nurse Hathaway.
All three of these
girls ingested LSD?
Yeah.
Are you sure it
was straight LSD,
not mixed with anything else?
Yeah. I got them right
here if you want to check.
You laced chocolates?
Pretty stupid, huh?
Huh.
I only let them eat two each.
They could have had a
seizure, kidney damage,
gone into a coma.
We're going to have to
keep them here for a while,
make sure there's no
dangerous side effects.
You don't have to tell the
cops or anything, do you?
Yeah, we do.
Better yet, we get
to tell your parents.
Any Valentine's Day plans?
Nope.
No big date or anything?
So, what was that about?
The, uh, you know, the flowers
and the chocolates
in the fridge?
What's that all about?
Oh, that?
Yeah, that. What's that about?
I met this pediatrician...
You what?
Do what?
What?!
Hey!
Hey, Peter, what?
What do you got?
Michael Clifford, 17 years old.
He lost a dare
with a freight train.
Leg and head injuries,
hypotensive, 80/60.
Fluid resuscitated 2,000cc's
brought the pressure up to 100.
Blood loss around
three to four units.
Someone get on
the horn with O.R.
Pulse 130, pulse ox 82.
Start him on some
ancef, one gram, I.V. push.
BP's dropped. 80/40.
Where the hell's
that o negative?
It's coming.
Popliteal.
No dorsalis pedis on the left.
Let's get an angiogram.
Ow! God! He's got my hand.
He's seizing!
Help!
He's seizing.
He's grabbing!
Calm down.
Grab a bite block.
He's breaking her hand.
He's breaking her hand!
Grab a bite block.
He's crushing it!
Stretch your fingers out.
Ten migs of Valium, I.V. push.
Now! Let's move!
No! Get him off!
Bounce back migraine in Six.
I already saw him.
No. You saw the one in One.
This is the one in Six.
Don't you guys work?
Want one?
No, thanks.
Hello.
Hi. You thought I
was in a bad mood?
What?
Ah.
Oh, my God.
I got to go.
No. Don't you dare leave me.
Dr. Lewis.
Dr. Kayson.
Will you be mine?
Excuse me?
Happy Valentine's Day.
Still 100.
McGillis is here.
I'll be right back, okay?
Carol, how long is
Sparky going to be with us?
Till Grabarsky
gets off duty tonight.
One of God's creatures.
Hmm.
Hey, Deb.
Deb, you all right?
What?
I said are you okay.
Yeah, sure.
Very okay.
She left over four hours ago.
Does that constitute
abandonment?
It does in my book.
Merits an investigation.
She dumps a sick child who's six, speaks
no English, has no clue what's going on.
Carol, it's okay. Tatiana needs
to stay here at least 24 hours,
maybe longer if she
doesn't get any better.
And what happens when she does?
Assuming mom's
still out of the picture,
Children and Family Services
will find her a foster home.
There's nothing else we can do.
I have a lot of work to do.
I'm being released today.
You've made a
remarkable recovery.
I couldn't have done it
without you, Susan.
May I call you Susan?
Uh, sure.
So, you said there was something
you needed to talk to me about.
Every cardiologist ought to
go through what I went through.
Lying on that gurney, not
knowing whether you're going
to live or die, and
seeing the face
of this lovely young
resident hovering over you.
I can understand how it must
have been very scary for you.
Oh, sure, it was
terrifying at first
but then exhilarating.
And now I've got a whole
new perspective on life...
My own and my patients'.
That's terrific.
I, uh, I really should get back.
Have you thought
about cardiology, Susan?
Uh, well...
Because I think you'd
be an excellent candidate,
and I'd like to help you...
Be a... a mentor of sorts.
Thank you, Dr. Kayson, but...
No, please, call me Jack.
I'm still doing my
E.R. residency.
I think I should just
stick with that for now.
I think we should talk more
about this some other time.
Yeah, sure, that'd be fine.
Tonight, 8:00?
Dinner?
How's the pain?
I had a fifth of Demerol.
You mean 50
milligrams of Demerol?
Yeah.
I see that it's working.
Can you wiggle
these fingers for me?
I should stick with decorating.
Yeah, this guy crushed
your hand pretty good.
You've got three
metacarpal fractures,
but I think you'll survive.
I'll get somebody
to put a cast on.
How's the boy?
Boy?
The one who squeezed me,
got hit by that train.
He died...
up in O.R.
Ah, Dr. Greene
dueling meat-packers
coming in...
About five minutes away.
Carol.
What?!
Whoa.
Sorry.
Are we not loving our job today?
I am not loving the
limits of my job today,
watching that little girl sitting
out there completely abandoned.
Nothing we can do.
Maybe you need a change of pace.
How about a nice, greasy trauma?
Sunny-side up or over easy?
I think I can offer you both.
Okay, but how long
do I have to wait?
That's the beauty
of it... You don't.
Happy Valentine's Day, Doris.
Likewise, Dr. Greene.
Meet Mr. Lorenzo
Renzetti, 45, sturdy,
aluminum meat
hook firmly imbedded
in his upper left bicep.
How's that feel, Mr. Renzetti?
You can call me Lorenzo.
I don't know. It's not so bad.
Yeah, well, that's good,
'cause it sure looks bad.
Start an I.V. BP is
140/90, pulse 96, resps 16,
good distal pulses,
normal cap refill
defensive lacerations
on both arms.
Okay, Mr. Renzetti
we're going to take care of you.
People, we got to move him.
All right, on my count.
Watch your back.
Uh, on second thought
why don't you just scoot over.
Good. I got you.
You said this was a twofer.
Second guy, second unit.
I drove circles around him.
All right.
Hang some ancef,
one gram I.V. piggyback
and let's update
Lorenzo's tetanus.
I'll start a chart.
I already had that. I took my
wife to the Caribbean last year.
Oh, yeah? How was it?
It was all right.
It rained a lot.
You want a chest film?
Yep.
Call radiology
and get a portable!
Okay, Lorenzo, Lorenzo,
just stay down, okay?
Just take it easy.
I thought Paulie
would be here already.
They should have
brought him here first.
Who's Paulie? Do you feel this?
Sure. Paulie's my stupid kid.
He made a crack
about his mother.
I told him to shut up.
Okay, move your fingers.
I didn't want to fight him,
but he kept coming at me
Now your thumb. Now your wrist.
He kept jabbing me this way,
that way.
You know, you shouldn't
disrespect your mother.
Where is the son of a bitch?!
I'm sure he's on his
way, Mr. Renzetti.
Well, he better be,
'cause I'm telling you,
he's in worse shape than I am.
Okay, listen, we're
going to take you upstairs
and take this out in surgery.
There he is!
There he is! Paulie!
Hey, Paulie!
Paulie, I'm over here!
Your dad's over here!
Hey, Paulie!
Hey, Paulie, you okay?
Son?
Carol, come with me.
Paulie, you all right?
All right, CBC!
He's in V-fib!
Hold him down!
Paulie, I'm right here, son!
I'm right here.
Come on.
Damn it, is he all right?
200!
Charging!
Clear! Paulie!
Dad's over here!
You okay?
300!
Charging!
Hey, is he okay?
Clear.
He's okay, right?
Still in fib.
Damn it! 360!
And charging.
Hey, Paulie!
Calm down.
God!
Paulie!
He needs more volume.
Hang the O-neg.
Give me the tray.
Hey, hey, hey.
It's okay.
Okay. Okay.
It's going to be okay.
You'll be fine.
Exam two. Okay?
Here we go.
This way, you guys.
There you go. All right.
We'll be with you
in just a second.
Come on. You have to
admit, they're pretty cute.
They have been spray painted
which has given them hives.
Children with
hives are not cute.
So, Peter, about
the flower and candy
in the refrigerator...
Mm-hmm?
Are you going to make
me guess who they're for?
They're for my mother.
Mm-hmm.
Really.
Oh, yeah!
Oh, um, excuse me.
Where is Exam Room One?
Thanks for moving her.
Oh, sure.
She insisted on bringing Bill.
Oh.
Drivet, Tatiana.
Drivet.
Hello and good-bye...
That and about ten other words
is the extent of my Russian.
They're kind of
perfect together.
No idea where they
are or what they're doing.
Neither one of
them seem to mind.
Yeah, except the dog gets to
go home with Grabarsky tonight.
Maybe her mom will come back.
Mm, I don't think
"mom" is the right word.
Carter?
Yeah?
Dr. Ross needs you
to help with some
kids. Exam Two.
Okay. Hey, how do
you say good-bye?
Dosvedanya.
Dospen... nana, Tatiana.
Okay.
Carter, tell Dr. Ross
I need him now.
Okay.
Hey, Deb.
Are you Wendy Goldman?
Yes... Deb.
Yeah. I'm Deborah Chen.
I know that.
I had the hardest
time finding you.
Um, I'm going to
be doing your cast.
How long was he in the hot tub?
Half hour.
40 Minutes. Maybe more.
Any wine? Champagne.
How much? A little.
More than a little.
A couple of bottles.
It was Valentine's Day.
Eddie wanted something special.
He got lightheaded.
Got nauseous.
Then he threw up.
It was horrible.
Then he sank. Like a deadweight.
We went under. Both of us.
Pulled him up. Got
him on the cement.
Ran to the house...
called 911. Called 911.
You did the right thing.
Good.
We'll take it from here.
We're going to take
his temperature now.
Okay. Okay.
Rectally.
You might want to wait outside.
We'll be right back, okay?
You still think it's
upper respiratory?
Well, now that she's hydrated
I heard rales.
Could be pneumonia
or some other foreign virus
that we know nothing about.
Fever spiked up to 104.
I'm going to put a
rush on that X ray.
You give her acetaminophen?
Yeah. 15 per kilo.
God, all the times my mother
tried to teach me Russian.
All the times your mother
yelled at me in Russian.
Oh, you deserved it.
Hey.
Dr. B, Mrs. Hayden,
85, fell and cut her arm.
She's in the suture room
and she's a tad senile.
All right, give it to Carter.
He's busy taking care
of six small, red children.
All right, well,
where's the other one?
Deb Chen? Yeah, her.
Doing a cast.
All right. Have her wait.
I have to go to Radiology
Is Dr. Ross here?
Uh, what's wrong?
I'm Jake Leeds.
I need to talk to Dr. Ross.
Uh, look, he's
very busy right now.
I can find someone else...
Hey, Jake.
For you.
What's wrong?
My side and my stomach.
It really hurts.
Okay, we're going to take
him over to curtain two.
Do me a favor... call
his mom, Diane Leeds.
She's up in Risk Management.
Sure, Dr. Ross.
Carol?
Yeah.
Come on, buddy.
All right, what's wrong?
Where's it hurt?
Here we go.
It started here in my stomach,
but now it feels
like it's over here.
Mm-hmm.
All right, like this?
Yeah. There. It hurts there.
Mm-hmm. Any vomiting or nausea?
Uh-huh.
Right after gym.
Temp's normal.
Okay. Let's get
a CBC, urinalysis
and set him up
for an ultrasound.
Okay.
All right, Jake, hang tight.
We're going to
check you out, okay?
Where are we going to put him?
Admitting him.
Straight upstairs.
Haleh, could you
tell those two hookers
that their friend Ed
is doing just fine?
I think they'd rather
talk to a doctor.
Could you tell
them I'll meet them
in the waiting room?
So, what was that with Kayson?
What? Oh. Uh, you know,
he just wanted to tell me
that he was fine.
Thank me, you know?
Nice try. I saw the bouquet.
Oh, God.
Did anyone else?
It was so embarrassing.
It's all right.
He just gave you flowers.
It's not like he asked
you out or anything.
He asked you out?
Dinner, tonight.
What did you say?
I said...
Oh, uh, Mark,
chopper on the way.
Some woman choked
on her Valentine's dinner.
Okay.
I said, no, I couldn't,
that I was doing
something with you.
Oh, you dragged me into it?!
Mark, he's married.
Yeah, well, so am I.
You're looking better, Jake.
Are you feeling better?
Uh, no.
Uh-huh. Dr. Ross tells me
that you're a very
good basketball player.
Yes, I am.
I'm probably better than
he is, except he's older.
Is he divorced?
What?
My mom says divorced
people have baggage.
Oh. Well, he isn't divorced.
Then he doesn't have baggage.
Well, I wouldn't
say that, exactly.
He's faking.
How can you know that?
Because he has that
moany quality in his voice
like when he wants to stay
home from school to avoid a test.
Could be appendicitis...
Dr. Ross, he's done this before.
Faked illness?
No. Tried to set me
up with single men.
What?
He likes you. I'm his mother
and he's stuck with me.
He thinks if he can get us
to spend a little time together
then we will
naturally, you know...
Well, that's...
Obviously ridiculous.
Obviously...
And he's done this before?
Oh, yeah. I've been through
five or six departments
in this hospital alone,
not to mention hardware stores.
Jake feels that I should
either be with a doctor
or a man who knows his
way around nuts and bolts.
Mm. So how do you
suggest we handle this?
Let's cut
him open.
Mm.
The kid's faking it.
Dr. Ross, test results back
on that little Russian girl.
Okay.
Oh, man.
Her white count's at 2,000.
You mean 20,000.
No, two.
And she has pneumonia.
She's got AIDS.
Mrs. Hayden...
Mrs. Hayden?
Uh, yes?
Uh, how did you get in here?
There, uh... there is no starch.
No, no.
You know what?
We're out of starch.
But I need it for Joe's uniform.
Okay. Just sit right here.
Uh, you know what?
I'm going to have to take
a look at this arm, okay?
Uh-huh.
Now, I don't suppose
you remember
if you're allergic to
lidocaine or novocaine?
Some of the wives don't bother.
Okay. Well, we're just
going to have to jump in here.
Joe likes his uniform
and his collar crisp.
Mm-hmm.
Would... would you like
me to iron your uniform?
Yeah.
All right.
That would be great.
I just don't understand how
that woman could do that.
It doesn't matter.
It sure as hell does to Tatiana.
The situation is what it
is; we'll do what we can.
Yeah, well, it isn't much.
I mean, we give
her some antibiotics,
we bring down her
fever and we kick her out?
Children and Family
Services will find someplace
She's got AIDS,
Doug. For her to stay.
She doesn't even
speak the language.
That barely makes
her a good candidate
for being a foster child.
That's right, so what do
you suggest that we do?
Anything else.
There isn't anything else.
I know.
You know, these
patients come in here
for an hour, maybe
two, maybe a day.
We treat them as fast as we can.
We barely learn their names
and then we send them home.
Which is usually what they want.
Yeah. Well, they usually
have a home to go to.
Uh, Dr. Ross?
You still got those
chicken pox in three.
Fine, Jerry.
I'm sorry that the person
who was with you yesterday
isn't here today.
And I'm sorry that none of
us will be with you tomorrow.
And I'm glad you
can't understand
what's happening to you.
Neither can I.
Malik, move these hearts.
Let's go, let's go.
We're going to Trauma Two.
What have you got?
Anaphylaxis.
She's allergic, my wife.
You know, to shrimp and
scallops and all that stuff.
Susan, this is Mr. Goodwin.
Mr. Goodwin, this is Dr. Lewis.
We didn't know. I
mean, we didn't order it.
It must have been an appetizer.
Okay, we're going to take
care of your wife, Mr. Goodwin.
You need to wait outside.
It happened once before,
at a wedding reception
and her throat swelled
up, but nothing like this.
One, two, three.
Lydia, show Mr. Goodwin
where he can wait.
Come on, Mr. Goodwin.
Upper airway
obstruction with stridor.
She's hypotensive.
BP's 45 palp.
I'll intubate.
Haleh, get a 6.5 and
prep for a crike just in case.
Epi, one to 10,000,
2cc's I.V. push.
Oh, man, this is hopeless...
Throat's completely swollen.
Let's crike her.
Grab a trach tube.
Benadryl I.V., 50 milligrams
and Cimetidine
I.V. 300 milligrams.
Okay.
All right.
Pressure's stabilizing, 100/80.
Pulse ox 96.
Nice.
Thank you.
Start an epi drip,
one milligram in 250
at 10 mics per minute.
Keep her on antihistamines
until the swelling comes down.
Oh, God, oh, God. Mark!
What the hell happened?
Lydia, get her
husband in here, now.
Pressure's crashing.
We got to scope her.
Okay.
Did I perforate the esophagus?
No, you couldn't have.
What'd I do wrong?
Nothing.
Get a CBC,
type and cross six units.
Lytes, LFT's, amylase.
Oh, my God.
What happened?
Lydia, call for o-neg.
Mr. Goodwin, has your
wife been vomiting recently?
No.
Does she have
any history of ulcer?
No. No.
She has bleeding
varices. SB tube.
Varices? What the hell is this?
Mr. Goodwin, is your
wife an alcoholic?
Is she?!
Yes.
All right, get the
catcher's mask.
Let's roll her over.
Okay, inflate the
balloon to 200cc's.
It's in the stomach.
Okay, inflate the esophageal
balloon to 40 millimeters.
It's stopped.
Great pickup, Susan.
Okay.
Well, her fever's
back down to 100.
You're feeling
better, aren't you?
Jerry, will you keep
an eye on her for me?
Sure. Thanks.
I should have gone
into real estate.
That bad, huh?
I can't believe I got
off two hours ago.
Carol, can I borrow a pen? Yeah.
We got to do something, right?
I don't want Kayson to
think that you're a liar.
Carol, you want to come?
Oh, thanks, but I'm on tonight.
Sorry. Bye.
She's very ill.
I know.
You can't take her home tonight.
After this morning, I'm not sure
you'll ever be able
to take her home.
I don't want to.
Mrs. Hayden?
I guess you found
the starch, huh?
When I found out that
I could adopt Tatiana,
I bought a
Russian-English dictionary.
Never got much beyond
hello and good-bye.
Mrs. Hall...
Can you imagine
anything worse...
than abandoning
a child with AIDS?
No.
She was diagnosed last
Thursday at St. John's.
Look, Mrs. Hall, or
whatever your name is,
I'm not exactly sure
why you're here,
but I'm not all that interested
in listening to you
say how sorry you are.
My husband died three years ago.
It was... long and slow.
You know, I was young.
You get through, you go on.
I never really felt that
loss until last week.
I never allowed
myself to feel it
until I...
I looked at Tatiana
and I said...
"There it is."
I cannot...
I will not let myself get
that close to someone
and lose them again.
I brought her things.
I forgot how to say good-bye.
Dosvedanya.
Ma?
Ma.
Happy Valentine's Day.
This is fun?
This is fun.
It's 20 degrees out.
Okay, this is fun.
Did I tell you that Morgenstern
offered me a job as
attending next year?
What?! No, you didn't tell me.
Oh, that's right.
It was last week.
You weren't talking to me then.
So? You were talking to me.
What'd you tell him?
That I had to think about it.
Oh, please.
Well, you know, I mean,
there's Jennifer to consider,
which I didn't.
What'd she say?
What do you think she said?
That "I'm happy for you, Mark,
because I know this is
what you really want"?
The, uh, "this is what
you really want" part?
That's right.
Sounds bad.
It was.
So, what are you going to do?
I... am going to skate.
Whoa!
Help! I need a doctor!
Is there a doctor?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Wendy.
I understand that you
did it perfectly on the dog.
We'll fix it tomorrow.
I think I'm going to
stay home tomorrow.
Hang in there.
Good night, everyone.