The body has approximately
11 organ systems,
all doing different
things at the same time.
In order to keep us
functioning, or, well, alive,
they need one voice,
a leader, a master.
And in our brains, that job
belongs to the pituitary gland.
It senses the body's needs
before they even arise,
working nonstop.
The pituitary gland communicates
with all of the other glands,
telling them when to produce
the vital hormones
we need to function.
It keeps everything running
smoothly, in perfect order.
You want a muffin? No, no.
You sure? Go, go.
There's no denying it,
it has the toughest
job in the place.
Are you nervous?
You're not nervous.
Of course I'm nervous.
Been waiting for this
day my entire career,
and I promised them
candy disco rainbows.
And now I have to deliver.
Am I nervous?
You will deliver.
I just need it to be
perfect. Just today.
Oh, no, no. Go on. You
can't be late for rounds.
People will think I'm
giving you special treatment.
Go on. Okay.
No special treatment!
Okay.
I'll see you later... Chief.
Thanks.
This can't be right.
They live here?
I mean, when you said carpool,
I thought you meant just us.
Where is Alex?
Are Owen and I going out
and I didn't even realize it?
Does that happen?
Do adults even do that?
I don't know. Stop asking.
Carpooling is
supposed to save time.
This guy with the beard...
I have seen him perform
a sex act to buy drugs,
take the drugs, and fall asleep.
He's had a full day already.
And yet we're still here.
At least I think he's asleep.
Adults go home together.
They don't go out.
They don't go steady.
We're not 15.
You made out with
him on our front porch.
And I have no idea
what that means.
I thought we were
friends. What does it mean?
You sound 15.
Boo!
Alex! I've been sitting
out here 20 minutes.
Well, yell at Jo for not
changing her oil in over a decade.
Between you and this anatomy
class, my morning is shot.
I need to stop teaching
this anatomy class.
Your neighbors seem nice.
Yeah, the block's
a pit, but it's cheap.
Everybody buckled?
Webber needs one of us
to walk Bailey into her surprise
breakfast thing this morning.
No, thanks. Not I.
I hate all of you.
Chief.
Happy first day. Thank you.
I need to thank you for
giving me this class to teach.
It was very generous. I
love shaping young minds.
You're welcome.
I need to give it back.
Not possible.
Oh! I need you to
handle Miss O'Neil's
J-tube replacement this morning.
Thank you.
It's just a lot more
work than I expected,
and with three children
and my patients...
And, also, find someone to cover
the bariatric clinic
this afternoon.
And my surgeries,
which actually makes
finding time to prep
for the class impossible.
Look, I'm asking
you to do this stuff,
so do it. Anything else to say?
We're late for the
attendings' meeting.
The...
Attendings' meeting? Did
no one read my e-mail?
I think... I mean, I just...
I barely know this woman. We
had, like, two dates last week.
She asked to see
me again tonight.
It's crazy. I can't stop
thinking about her.
You know when you meet someone
and you get that flutter, that rush,
and it feels like you know
them and they know you
and you think to yourself,
"I could stare at this
person's face forever"?
Do you know what I
mean? Or maybe not.
So, I looked it up,
and Bailey's the first.
First what?
First female chief of
surgery of this hospital.
Before that, all men.
I say it's about time.
And all the department chiefs
are women. Neuro, cardio...
We got trauma. Ortho.
Let it go. AMELIA: Fetal.
Badass! Ladies.
This place is run by
ladies. It's "ladyplace."
No. It is not ladyplace.
"Ladyplace" is what my
grandma calls her vagina.
To anyone who will listen,
by the way, she is not shy.
No, we can't call
this place ladyplace.
I don't need to think of that sweet,
sweet, raunchy, old lady's vag
every time I walk
through the doors.
Me neither, but I will now.
She's coming,
she's coming! Okay?
Hurry, hurry, hurry!
Well, I'm glad to
see you're all here.
But if you had read your e-mail,
you would have known
that one of the many things
that I will be
implementing as chief
is no more weekly
attendings' meetings.
Well, actually, this is a...
See, less talking about saving
lives and more saving of the lives.
Thank you.
Okay, but... No.
Wait.
Hey, did I miss Bailey's party?
It wasn't a party.
I couldn't stop sleeping.
I think I'm fighting off a cold
or it's jet lag or just
sleeping in a bed.
Down comforter
works like morphine.
Did you talk to Jackson yet?
He slept here last night.
God, so you actually
are... What the hell is that?
What? What? What? On your back!
What's on my back? Do I
have a mole or something?
What...
What?
Arizona!
I have a rash.
It's a stupid rash.
You are completely overreacting.
I'm sorry. I work with babies.
Kepner, you've got
lesions, a cough, a fever.
You were in the Middle East.
I was traveling. I am run-down.
You can be run-down
in the bubble.
Look, we don't
know what you have.
We don't know how
contagious you are.
Hey, this is my first
day running this place.
There will be no
epidemics today.
What did infectious disease say?
Well, as of now, her
symptoms are nonspecific,
but they want to
rule out anthrax.
Any concerns about MERS?
Oh, God. You think?
I'm right here.
And you will stay right there
until your tests come back.
This stops with patient zero.
I am not patient zero.
I'm not a patient at all.
Goodbye, Kepner.
Do not cross that
line. Stay in the bubble.
I cannot...
In the bubble.
I will visit you, I promise.
May I see it, the rash?
It's nothing, right?
I'll keep my eye
out for your labs.
Okay.
But maybe we can talk if...
Look, I'm saying we
should page neuro.
Why?
Her vitals are stable,
her bloodwork's normal,
we sewed up her head
lac, she's obviously fine.
Fine, you discharge her.
Discharge who? Hi, Chief.
Her.
Uh...
"Jade Bell." Hello.
I'm Dr. Bailey.
Oh, good. More doctors.
The patient complained of
a headache and blurry vision
before she fainted
and hit her head,
so I did a complete syncope
work-up, which was negative.
So what? That led you to...
Sew up her head lac.
What is her diagnosis?
Hypoglycemia? She probably
just forgot to eat breakfast?
Wrong. You, what
did this one miss?
Beta hCG. Could you be pregnant?
Not a chance.
Look, I was in a
meeting, I felt dizzy,
and I woke up here,
but I feel fine now.
Can I go? No, you cannot.
What are you missing?
Migraine variant.
Autonomic dysfunction.
This is really, really fun, but
I have a work deadline so...
Jade, stand up for me, please.
What? Stand up, please.
We didn't miss anything.
Hi. Freak show's over. Can I go?
Whoa!
That is what you missed.
I feel naked.
That nurse Betsy...
Her name was Betsy...
She took my clothes, took them,
sealed them in plastic.
She took all of my clothes.
I have on paper panties!
You know how paper panties feel?
I imagine that
there's some chafing.
Okay.
Listen, it's a chance to relax,
so you should take a nap
and get rid of
your jet lag or read.
It's like a spa or a vacation.
I am in a bubble! I
am trapped in a bubble!
Jackson, he came in once.
He came in once,
took a look at me,
and then just walked away,
and I couldn't go
after him because
the bubble does not travel.
No, it does not.
I am alone in here.
I am trapped like a bug,
like some kind of nasty bug,
and I'm covered in disease.
You would think that he
would want to talk to me.
I am gonna die of a
mysterious disease
with a chafed,
buggy ass all alone!
Oh! Oh, my God. Don't freak out.
You've been in here
for, like, an hour.
It's not that. It's Jackson.
How can I help?
Um... Just talk.
Talk about something
else. Anything.
Okay. Um... Okay.
Oh! Here's a thing. Um...
Callie met someone.
Oh! Um...
So, are you okay
with that, or...
Yeah, super. Awesome.
Okay, that's great, then.
Yeah, I mean, I should
be happy for her, right?
And she sounds happy, you know,
happier than she's
ever been, she says.
I mean, apparently,
like, forever happy.
Do we have to talk about this?
Well, you know, she does, 'cause
she's talking to
everybody about it.
I'm surprised she fit.
20 bucks she's over 7 feet.
I mean, is it drugs
or the wrong combo
of steroids, you think?
I saw LeBron at an airport once.
She's taller than him.
Be quiet and stand outside.
Do we think it's drugs?
A growth hormone, maybe?
It's definitely not drugs.
Waiting for a
scan to confirm it.
Yeah, I'm right. You'll see.
And just 'cause you're chief
now, you're knower of all things?
Look, Jade suffers from blurry
vision, headaches, dizziness.
Abnormal growth.
Okay, put it all
together, and you get...
A pituitary tumor.
The knower of all things!
I should be chief of surgery.
Oh, wait. I already am.
You are welcome.
Where have you been?
I was downloading all
the charts you asked for,
which, respectfully,
is a lot of charts.
Are we really doing all
of these surgeries today?
Well, Bailey pushed
all her patients onto me,
so that means you, too.
Kyle Roane. Can we
push this lap chole...
No, we don't have
his liver tests back yet.
What about Dana Lee?
Hernia repair. Do we have
the urinalysis, because...
No, the labs are backed up.
I don't have time for this.
Is there anything I can do
to make your day
better, Dr. Grey?
I'm sorry. I just...
I can't say no to Bailey
because it's for the chief,
so I just need a little
break in the clouds here.
I just need a little rain.
I appreciate the apology.
Where are you going?
To make it rain.
Thanks.
Walk-ins.
Dr. Wilson. You paged?
No, I didn't.
Oh! Wow, that's weird.
Totally thought you did.
Maybe this thing is old.
Anyway, you
waiting for your labs?
Can I... Can I wait...
Oh! Thank you, yeah.
Bring me the labs
when you get them.
No, no, I meant wait with you.
Oh! Why?
I need to rush a
patient's pre-op.
I've been waiting 10 minutes.
Apparently, the system's down.
Grey tasked me with all of
these labs and these extra rounds,
and I need to prep
three patients for the OR.
So, I... This isn't
gonna work for me.
What are you...
Excuse me. - Hey!
Hi. I need the labs
for Dana Lee, stat.
- It's... It's for the chief.
- Excuse me!
Oh, no, she didn't!
We're all waiting in line here.
Thank you so much.
Oh!
Bring me those labs.
Can't wait.
How you doing?
Oh, uh... Hi, Bailey.
Or should I say "Chief"?
Yes, sir. Okay.
I just heard about the case.
A big patient for
a big first day?
Yes, sir.
And do you want anything,
a consult, anything?
Oh, no, no. I got it covered.
Thanks, though.
Prelim results says
it's definitely not
Middle East
respiratory syndrome.
So can I get out of here?
Well, they won't
clear you to leave
until they get your
Gram stain results.
Jackson.
I've been gone for three months.
Can we at least
have a conversation?
I have a consult.
I'll let you know when I get
your Gram stain results back.
Wait, wait!
Come on!
Okay. So, Jade, you
have two problems.
In addition to the
pituitary tumor there,
the fall you took caused a
fracture in one of your vertebrae,
so you will need surgery.
But more importantly, I
need to remove the tumor
as soon as possible. No, no.
No one cuts into my brain.
Look, I'm missing work.
Jade, this tumor is causing
your growth hormones
to be 16 times
higher than normal,
which means that you'll
only continue to grow.
I've been 6'6" since I
was 17. Who cares?
Actually, you're 7'2".
And a quarter, we measured.
You're growing at a rate faster
than your body can handle.
Any more force, and
your spine will collapse.
Well, how long
will surgery take?
Making a surgical plan,
the surgery and recovery,
we can get you back
to work in a week or so.
Nope. Look, I'll come back when,
you know, my
work project is over.
Sit.
Chief, I need to do a repeat
neuro check in four hours.
Four hours? No, I can't.
I know your work is important,
but this brain surgery
has to be your priority.
Really? Do you know what I do?
No.
I lead a team that's
bringing the Internet
to the parts of Africa
that don't have it.
The Internet is
man getting fire.
This is the
21st-century light bulb.
Do you know how many
lives will be changed, be saved,
how many girls will
become educated?
Do you know how
much medical knowledge,
how much information
will become available
to people who've
been kept in the dark?
This project goes live in one
week, and I need to be there.
I have to be.
Yeah, that's...
More important
than brain surgery.
Jade, I hear you.
You have the weight of
the world on your shoulders.
But believe me when I
tell you I can help you.
Okay, I'll give you the four
hours. Then I'm leaving.
Four hours?
And in that time frame, I
need a complete surgical plan
for resection of
the pituitary tumor
and repair of
the spinal fracture
that includes a recovery
time of no more than a week.
Oh! Okay, well, you know what? I
have a knee replacement right now.
I've got a VATS procedure.
Then push that and delegate
that. Now, we have to move fast.
This woman has no
interest in being treated.
You know, in fact,
she's a flight risk.
Wilson, you're in charge of
making sure she stays put. Go.
Her tumor is massive.
I mean, we need extensive scans
and time to go over an
approach for both procedures.
That takes longer
than four hours.
Well, actually, you have
three hours and 36 minutes.
Bailey, we need at least
until the end of the day, okay?
What you're asking
for is impossible.
What? It's what?
Oh! I know you
didn't say impossible.
No, nothing's impossible.
You are smart people.
You're good surgeons.
This patient has
some big things to do,
and I have every
confidence that you
will figure out how
she can do them.
Bailey. And make it possible.
It's possible, right?
Yeah, it's possible.
It's my victory as
much as it is hers.
I mean, she was my candidate.
I was pulling for her.
And so what if I wanted to pass
the torch in a celebratory fashion?
I mean, is that
so terrible? Huh?
Maybe offer a word of
support or advice here or there.
I mean, not that she asked me.
She hasn't asked
me for anything.
Well, I suppose I could
ask her if she minds if I join...
You know, I shouldn't have to
ask. She should want me there.
I should've been the
first place she stopped.
No, but she's
got it all handled.
And I worry.
It's... It's foolhardy.
You know, it's
arrogance is what it is.
And I'm gonna talk to her.
Good talk. Thanks, Kepner.
Feel better.
Can you do a
minimally invasive...
No, no, her vertebral
bodies are too large.
We'll have to use an anterior
approach through the chest.
I'll do a right thoracotomy.
I'm gonna do a
transcranial approach.
Yeah, if Bailey wants
a shorter recovery,
then an endonasal
approach will help.
Well, the tumor's too big.
The head is abnormally
big. You're gonna have space.
I'm doing a craniotomy.
I need visibility.
I'm gonna get you where you need
to be with less bleeding, all right?
Just listen for a minute.
Apparently, we
don't have a minute.
Avery, can you do a consult?
No.
It's for one of Bailey's
patients. Of course it is.
She put all her services on
hold to fix her giant problem.
She had me push
two procedures for this.
She's doing it to you guys, too.
I mean, she postponed
five of my consults
so I could handle her patients.
She didn't ask. She
just pushed them.
It's ridiculous. No offense.
- Can she do that?
- Can who do what?
Oh! Can you be chief
again? I loved you as chief.
You did stay out
of people's hair.
Very hands-off and great ties.
You know what they used
to call her, her interns?
What? The Nazi.
Bailey?
Last time she had
absolute rule over people,
and here she is again.
I love Bailey, but...
Power corrupts.
She's an iron-fisted dictator.
She's a Bond villain.
Warren. I'm so sorry.
We weren't trying
to be disrespectful.
It's all good, it's all good.
I'm just gonna go look
into some follow-up scans.
Amelia. What do you think?
What? Me?
I don't think... Don't ask me.
Uh... Dr. Grey, I've got OR 4
for the small bowel obstruction
and an angio suite
for the Swanson case.
I thought you said the
angio suite was booked.
I have my ways. Let's go.
Wait, so, they called
Bailey the Nazi?
Yeah. Yes.
What do you mean,
"Don't ask me"?
You're more pissed
off than any of us.
Have you ever had a friend
who was like a really good friend,
but you just want to make
out with 'em all the time?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I used to
do that for years.
And what happened?
Sofia.
So, um... Hey!
Question.
When you update the I and O's,
is it kind of just like
whenever you get to it or...
I like to do it hourly.
Sweet. I like that.
You like what?
Hourly. It's just...
It's like it's a good,
round time frame,
and there's one every
hour, so you don't forget to...
I don't know why I said that.
That was really weak.
Pathetic and sad.
Hey. ISAAC: Whoa!
Where you going?
I gave you four
hours. Time's up.
No, no, no. You can't leave.
You can't hold me
here. I'm not a hostage.
No, I know, but...
Bailey, may I have
a word with you?
I'm sorry. Huge deadline, sir.
Okay, where are we?
We're nowhere. Oh,
my God! Come on!
This is... The tumor has invaded
the cavernous sinus.
I'm planning an approach.
The wrong approach.
And the recovery
time that you're asking
for is completely unreasonable.
We need more time.
No, we don't have it.
Look, I have to go tell
this woman something, so...
Jade's left. She
just walked out.
You let her? I gave you one job!
Dr. Wilson was trying
to reason with her,
but she knows that we
can't legally stop her.
Or physically stop
her. Well, convince her.
Go find her and
get her back here!
Okay.
I gave them one thing!
I gave you one thing!
And I started this day thinking
we could accomplish
the impossible,
but now I'm gonna
end the day with
a woman probably
dead on the street
and a thousand African
children who can't read.
I don't know what we
were supposed to do.
More. I expected more.
So damn much more.
What do a thousand African
children have to do with this?
Jade! Please, you can't leave.
People are waiting for me.
I'll come back when I can.
No, no, no. There
may be no coming back.
Dr. Bailey was right.
Your symptoms suggest
that surgery needs
to happen now.
How many people can you
help if you're dead or blind or...
Whoa!
Don't worry. I'm gonna
get you out of there.
No, don't touch her.
Jade, don't move.
Let us through, please.
Jade, are you all right?
I caught her head.
She didn't hit her head.
Oh, my God.
I'm so stupid.
She might've aggravated
her spine fracture.
Step back. That's too
small. It won't support her.
I got it.
Jade, just try not to move.
I can't move.
I can't feel my
legs. They're numb.
Okay, on my count.
One, two, three.
Easy, easy. Watch her neck.
Good. And slide.
Dr. Wilson, are you okay?
Can I get you anything?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Good job on the door,
DeLuca. Quick thinking.
Yeah, you should
be a contractor.
You still could. You're young.
Jo, can we get an OR?
One, two, three.
Is she centered? Yeah.
Let's move.
And then today,
it's like I'm invisible.
I mean, I don't
know what it means.
Maybe the kiss meant
nothing and we're friends.
I mean, I guess
what I'm asking is,
if it were you,
if I kissed you...
Wait. No, I'm not
saying that you and I...
We're not kissing,
but if a guy kisses you
and he asks you out,
and then you refuse to look
at him for the rest of the day,
what exactly are you thinking?
I can't help you.
My marriage is collapsing,
and I can't do anything about
it because he won't talk to me.
You see? You get
it. No, I don't get it
because I'm trapped in a bubble!
You are not trapped in a bubble.
You have the freedom to roam
and talk to anyone you'd like,
so stop talking to me.
Go talk to Shepherd. Ask
her what she thinks about it.
You know what?
You're right. You're right.
If I want a reaction, I
should just force one.
I should just go right
up to her and be direct.
I'm saying stop talking to me!
Oh! I need to go.
Hang in there, Kepner.
Hey, are we ready?
Which approach
are you going to use?
Jade's fall caused
her spinal fracture
to become severely unstable,
so Pierce and I will have
to repair it at the same time.
It's not ideal, but...
We sit Jade up for a craniotomy,
it would paralyze her forever.
So we'll be doing this
surgery endonasally.
Which is the wrong approach.
We're out of options.
Warren, go scrub.
Someone needs to
sign off on the case.
All right, I will.
Do they all hate me?
I try not to listen.
So they're talking.
Did I push too hard?
Do you think I'm wrong here?
What do you think?
I think I have put us
all in a terrible position.
Yeah, well, I
think you're right.
And I'm in one, too, so
can I just work, please?
So check the urine output
and page me with any changes.
On it.
Busy day.
Has Bailey talked to
you about anything?
Talk? All she does
is talk to me or at me.
She dumped her
entire schedule on me
and expects me to
get it all done today.
Yeah, I've been hearing that.
The only reason I'm
holding up is Edwards.
I mean, she's on top of it.
I understand why Amelia requests
her. Edwards gets things done.
Bone graft is in. And...
Yeah, we're done.
Warren, ease down
on the retractor.
Got it.
Shepherd, how are we?
If I can get in
a little further,
the margins will
be close to perfect.
Hold on. Can you
advance the scope?
Damn it. MAGGIE:
What the hell happened?
We hit the carotid. I
can't see a thing. Suction.
How can we help?
We need to compress this artery.
Wilson, we need more
packing in here, now.
Set up another suction.
Blood's coming out of her mouth.
God, she's gonna bleed out.
Should've opened her skull.
I knew this would happen!
Just keep packing! Faster!
Come on! Pack! More!
BENJAMIN: Let's go.
Pressure's down to 85.
Try 5% albumin.
Call for some FFP.
Pressure's down to 75.
More suction. I still
can't see a thing.
Did we try Desmopressin?
Unit six. We're down to 75.
Oh! Hey, Bailey.
So, your adenoma
resection had a rebleed.
It's stable now.
But then Mrs. What's-her-name,
with the lap chole...
Grey, I can't right now.
Bailey, these are your patients!
Look, I'm happy
you're chief. I'm all for it.
But I am taking my day to
service your patients and mine,
and it's getting
done. I'm on it.
But if you're gonna do this to
me, if you're gonna drown me,
at least take two seconds to
listen to the update of your patients.
I deserve more
than to be dismissed.
I deserve more.
Respectfully, Chief.
- Chest tube is in.
- Guys, is there a plan here?
Because she's lost a
third of her blood volume.
I can do a muscle
patch. With a little glue,
it could form a clot, and
we can seal the vessel.
No, that's a temporary fix.
We need to open her neck and
do a primary repair of the carotid.
That's a major stroke risk.
Before she dies on
the table. Prep the neck.
Wilson, you keep suctioning.
- Who am I listening to?
- You need to listen to me!
You open her neck, she's
gonna bleed out in seconds.
You let me do this,
I can stop the bleeding and
help you remove the tumor.
Do not open her neck, please.
Move.
All right, we can use a patch
from the thoracotomy incision.
Pierce, I need a piece of
intercostal muscle right now, please.
Scalpel.
That's for you.
I wanted to give it
to you this morning,
but somebody got
herself in a big damn hurry.
It's mine.
I got it my first
day of residency.
I replaced the earbuds.
I never had anyone to
pass something along to.
But then...
I just thought that...
Sir, I don't deserve this.
Well, if you think that,
then maybe you don't...
Because I'm not the
right person for this job.
You thought I was,
I thought I was,
and I had these
great plans, but...
I mean, if this is my first day,
then I don't deserve a second.
I wanted it to go...
Perfectly.
It won't. It can't.
I mean, this job is too
much for one person.
You did it.
Because I listened to
those who came before me
and counted on those under me.
I tried to...
No, you barked like a general.
They are generals.
They know how to mobilize.
What they need is a leader.
If I did my job well, it's not
because people listened to me.
It's because they
believed in me.
Believed that I knew
them well enough
and believed in them enough
to tell them how and
when to use their brains.
I'm talking about
people like you.
That kind of belief,
you have to earn it,
and you cannot earn it in a day.
You want someone to
run a four-minute mile,
you don't chase them.
You don't give them
something to run from.
You give them
something to run to.
Avery, we need something else.
Give it a chance.
Shepherd is right.
It's not holding.
Don't move the
patch. Just give it time.
We could try embolization.
Go up through
the groin, coil it.
It'll take too long to
get a C-arm in here.
There!
Oh, my God.
It's holding. Are we okay?
I hope so.
Yeah, me, too.
Dr. Avery. It's Dr. Kepner. 911.
What's wrong? What's
happened? We need to talk.
God, April, I thought
you were dying!
I kind of am dying. I
feel like we both are.
You paged me 911
so we could do this?
Yes! Yes! Okay.
I needed to force a
reaction out of you
because I am in a glass
prison and I can't do anything.
So you're gonna stand there,
and you're not gonna walk away
and you're gonna talk to
me. You don't want to hear it.
Jackson, I... We
already talked, April.
I told you what I needed,
and you didn't hear it.
You didn't listen. You went
halfway around the damn world.
That wasn't a talk, Jackson.
That was an ultimatum,
and our marriage has never
been a marriage of ultimatums.
Oh, come on. It wasn't an
ultimatum. I gave you a choice.
No.
No, I made a choice
long before that,
long before Samuel, the
army, any of it, and so did you.
We stood up in that
weird-smelling little chapel in Tahoe,
and before God we chose to
love one another until we die.
You made that choice.
We chose to love
and honor one another.
Honor one another,
which you couldn't do.
In front of God, we promised
each other that, through...
'Cause you couldn't hear me
telling you I needed you to stay.
I needed to go!
And you went!
You did what you needed
to do. Twice, actually.
This marriage is
full of ultimatums.
They're all yours.
Look, we...
We've been through a lot.
And you've changed.
No.
I've grown.
And...
We haven't been through a lot.
Jackson, we're going
through a lot right now.
We're going through a hard part.
This is the "worse"
of "for better or worse."
This is the mud, and we just
have to pull each other through it.
We just... We have to
push, and we have to fight.
I'm not sure we are
worth fighting for.
What?
No, please don't...
Ow! God!
Okay.
So, where are we with Jade?
I got the whole tumor.
She had a bad
left carotid bleed.
I took her to angio,
put in a stent.
But she's likely
to have deficits.
Possibly a stroke, paralysis...
She's still out. some speech
and language issues...
Pressure's good, but we
won't know. vision loss.
Or she could just be in a coma.
You people are extraordinary.
I mean, I came in
here today and did
all kinds of things wrong,
but in spite of that,
you all still did amazing
and perfect work.
And you found a way to do
something that was, in fact, impossible.
So if there is a bad
outcome, it's my bad outcome.
Tomorrow...
I will be better.
Hey, Cross, let's go. You're
prepping OR. Five for Grey's lab chole.
I'm sorry. What?
Dr. Wilson has me today.
It's for the Chief.
Now, Cross. Come.
No, stay.
You've cut lines,
you've stolen nurses,
you've even rearranged
the OR board.
You are not stealing
him. He is mine. Mine.
Back off.
If the Chief needs him for
Grey, you got to let him go.
Thank you, Dr. Karev.
Cross, come.
I'll come back.
Alex, she's lying.
She's been pulling this crap
all day, saying it's "for the Chief."
She's so full of it. Stop.
Stop what? Stop whining.
Look, she worked you.
She got what she wanted
by beating the system.
It's a genius move.
If I had come up
with it, I would've.
Look, you're just
mad that you didn't.
Deal with it or come up
with something better.
What are you doing?
I checked with
Griggs. You're clear.
I mean, he was leaving, so
he asked me to let you out.
So I'm not sick.
Most likely contact dermatitis.
Told him that 12 hours ago.
Ah... And look, I'm sorry
if, you know, I hurt you.
We have to be
honest with each other.
You were just being
honest. I appreciate that.
Thank you.
I mean, you're wrong. April.
But we are something
worth fighting for,
and I want to fight.
So I'll fight for
the both of us.
I will launch a
full-scale assault.
I will ambush and slash and burn
and fight until I
am bloody for us.
I will fight to the death
because I vowed to.
And nothing that's happened
since then has changed that.
You see? This is it. You
just want what you want.
You don't care what I think.
I love you too much to let
my mistake end our marriage.
I won't break my promise
to you, so I'm gonna fight.
And I'm gonna win.
Oh! Arizona! Excuse me.
Hey.
Here. Sofia forgot this.
We're on... We
made it to page 12.
She is exhausted,
so you can probably get
away with an early bedtime.
Thanks. Mmm-hmm.
Hey, um... Big date?
Oh! You heard?
Yeah, I mean, everyone heard.
You know, you can tell me,
Callie. You can always tell me.
Yeah? Yeah.
You'd like her. She's
funny and sharp.
And we don't just find
the same things funny,
we say the same
thing at the same time.
It's really almost like... Okay.
No, yeah, you can dial
back the enthusiasm.
No, really.
It's like we share
the same brain.
I mean, read the
room. That's all.
Well, all I'm saying
is you'd like her.
Hi.
Why won't you talk to me? I...
You won't even look at
me, so help me out, okay?
I mean, are you upset,
angry, confused, or...
That one. I'm confused.
If I had to pick one.
Well, then let's talk
about it so we can...
I can't talk about it because
then we start all the kissing,
and I don't know why. I don't...
I don't know what it means.
What does it mean?
What do you think it means?
I don't know.
Well, then...
Maybe we should...
We should talk about it.
Okay.
Let's talk.
Jade.
Jade, can you hear me?
Now can I get out of here?
Yes.
Oh, you will soon enough.
Yeah.
Oh, Grey! Just the
person I needed to see.
A hot appe came in tonight.
Now, it hasn't ruptured,
but you need to...
Am I being punished
for yelling at you?
On the contrary.
It's fine. I just need to know.
Oh, you don't think you deserved
my piling my service on you.
No.
I believe you do.
What?
I'm gonna let
you in on a secret.
See, when Webber had
this job, it was easier for him.
And Hunt had it
easier than I do.
You know why? I don't.
Because they had me.
I need a me, and I believe
that you can be a me for me.
I need you to be my me.
I'd like to appoint you
chief of general surgery.
Me?
Because you deserve it.
Because you can take it.
Because I leaned on
you, and you held me up.
You are the calm in
the center of the chaos.
You have been since I met you.
And I need you.
Hmm.
You want it or not?
Yes.
Go see this appe, and
don't complain to me again.
Without a strong leader,
the whole machine's
out of whack.
Congratulations, Dr. Grey.
Now when you tell people you
need something for the Chief,
it really will be.
That's right. I know what
you've been saying today.
But it's pretty simple.
If the brain's working,
the body will listen.
Your limbs want to hold you up.
Your lungs want to breathe.
Your heart wants to beat.
But none of them are any good
without the brain.
Aren't you exhausted?
I just need to make sure
that I'm prepared for tomorrow.
The brain keeps
everything all together.
Look, you gonna
be great tomorrow.
Wait. Wait! Besides.
There are better
ways to get prepared.
Chief.
Like a boss.