Previously, on
"The Resident"...
I set up marriages
between
Indian Americans in Atlanta.
No ring,
a faint look of desperation.
You're available.
Patients need to be honest
with themselves
about their prognosis.
Based on what I saw
this morning,
you will never likely
operate again,
but you're honest
with yourself about that, right?
- Just give me another chance.
- I'm willing to watch
and see how you do,
but I see no place for you
at Chastain.
Visa expires next week.
If I go to Nigeria
on my own accord,
I could apply to return
in the future.
I'm going back to Nigeria.
I'm coming with you.
Good morning.
Hey.
Are we feeling nostalgic yet?
Nostalgia requires a yearning
for what's already passed.
I'm looking forward
to what's to come.
Well, our Nigerian adventure
begins tonight.
11:00 flight.
Mm-hmm. And 12 and a half hours
in the air.
Oh, thank God
for neck pillows.
Yeah, that would be me.
I'm your neck pillow.
Yeah.
Yes, you are.
I'll see you at Chastain.
One last shift
and our adventure awaits.
Man, AJ,
you sure got
a big collection of...
stuff.
Hey, Dad,
make sure you check in
on my vinyl collection
every once in a while.
They'll be
in the storage locker.
What do you want me to do,
talk to your records?
Make sure they're not lonely?
Hey, Ma,
you all right over there?
I'm fine.
Excuse me a moment.
You were so excited
for sleepaway camp.
It's all you talked about.
But then you-you spent
those two weeks
asking me to come back
and pick you up.
You wrote me every single day.
Yeah.
I was a mama's boy.
And I still am, you know.
I love her, Mom.
That doesn't mean
I don't love you.
You know I do.
More than anything.
But I'm going.
I really want to.
Weren't you here yesterday?
10,000 hours of practice is
a minimum for greatness.
Hmm.
I'm all in for greatness.
I'm Billie Sutton, by the way.
Fifth-year
neurosurgery resident.
I...
Let emotional irregularity
ruin your career.
I know who you are.
And you're
the legendary Barrett Cain.
You could remove a meningioma
in under ten minutes
with no complications.
Or at least you could
before the accident.
Believe it or not, I'm a fan.
Damn it.
Good morning, Dr. Cain.
How's your hand today?
Did you complete
the vessel anastomosis?
Yes. Yes, I did.
And the hand...
is...
It's perfect.
You've successfully completed
all your prerequisites.
Should I put in a request
to get you back
on the surgical schedule?
Absolutely. I'm ready.
*THE RESIDENT*
Season 04  Episode 10
Episode Title: "Into the Unknown"
Aired on: April 20, 2021
16-year-old female.
Lisa McBride.
Traumatic neck injury
following a diving accident.
GCS 15. Vitals stable.
Okay, let's get her
to Trauma Bay Nine.
Lifeguard nearly drowns.
Add that
to my emergency room bingo.
It's tradition for new employees
to jump off
the ten-meter diving board.
So you jumped?
Kind of.
I splat.
Okay, on three.
One, two, three.
I just got hired.
My boss is so mad.
I bet you she fires me.
Let's not worry about all that
until we make sure you're okay.
I just really need this job.
College applications
are expensive.
BP's dropping.
70/40.
- Spinal shock?
- Could be.
All right, bolus two liters
of normal saline.
- Get atropine on standby, please.
- What's going on?
- Am I dying?
- No.
Sometimes an injury like this
can cause problems
with your blood pressure and heart rate.
My legs and arms...
They're all tingly.
- Wiggle your toes.
- I...
Wiggle your toes.
Squeeze my fingers.
You feel that?
A little.
I don't know.
Maybe not.
What does that mean?
Let's get you to CT
and find out.
Can someone please call my mom?
Okay, have them prep an OR,
then call her parents
and tell them
that their daughter
might need surgery.
I was surprised to see your name
back on my surgical board.
Your board?
My board.
My hospital.
My rules.
Which means you don't touch
a scalpel until I've cleared you.
So then clear me.
I've done everything.
Recovery. PT.
Sim lab practice.
If you want to return to the OR,
you will do so
under my supervision.
I will be standing with you
for your first surgery back.
I don't need a babysitter.
And I don't need a neurosurgeon
with authority issues.
I look forward to operating
with you, Dr. Voss.
Going to miss you,
Dr. Austin.
You know, we never got that
drink we talked about getting.
And we never played racquetball.
Maybe I'll visit you.
We'll play a match in Lagos.
Well, you're welcome anytime,
Chu.
Right angle.
I made you a going-away present.
Kristy.
It's an OR cap.
I made it myself.
These are the colors
from the Nigerian flag.
We've had some times together,
huh?
Indeed we have.
I'm gonna miss them.
I'm gonna miss you guys, too.
Our leaping lifeguard
is headed to the OR
for spinal decompression.
Poor kid.
Has anyone seen Mina?
How's she holding up?
She may be Spock,
but I'm sure she's just
as devastated as we all are.
- Oh. Speak of the devil.
- Good.
You're all here.
I have a few borrowed items
to return.
A phone charger you forgot at my
Halloween party three years ago.
The blouse you gave me
barhopping downtown.
- Mm.
- Pre-COVID.
And your headphones. Don't
remember when I borrowed these.
You didn't borrow them.
You took them.
But it doesn't matter.
You keep 'em.
You know, I was thinking
about the time we first met.
Do you remember?
I was just finishing up
- with that...
- No, no, no, no. Don't do that.
I'm not dead.
People move away all the time.
It's not a Hallmark moment.
No need to get sentimental.
Well, at least we know
that Mina is still... Mina.
How am I gonna say goodbye
to her?
You'll find a way.
I need to see
my daughter Lisa.
Sh-She's a lifeguard.
- Mrs. McBride?
- Yes.
Was your daughter
in a diving accident?
Yes, that's her.
Is she okay?
Lisa's being prepped
for surgery.
You can see her as soon
as she gets out of the OR.
I know how hard this is.
You would do anything
for your daughter.
Anything.
But right now
you have to let the surgeons
do their work.
She's in the best of hands.
Okay.
Just remember,
you're still in a probationary period.
Follow the rules
and mind your manners.
- Consider my manners 100% minded.
- Good.
One wrong move and this poor
girl will be a quadriplegic.
Which is why I'm here...
to make sure
that doesn't happen.
Dr. Cain is the lead surgeon?
Risen from the dead,
it would appear.
Is that a problem?
I'm not sure
how fond he is of me.
But the new Billie
could learn from him,
so, no, no problem at all.
Dr. Cain,
shall we begin?
10 blade to me.
- Hey, Ma, how you feeling?
- Just a bit of a headache.
She hit the corner
of the kitchen sink.
You've been drinking
too much coffee
and not enough water.
I think she's dehydrated.
Well, that would explain
the dizziness.
We'll give you
some IV fluids.
Did you lose
consciousness?
No.
It's just...
my friend Charlene,
she got dizzy,
didn't see a doctor and...
turns out
she was having a stroke.
Now she walks with a cane.
You're not having a stroke, Mom.
Normal BP and heart rate.
EKG doesn't show anything
of concern.
Um, exam was normal.
We're running her bloodwork now
and waiting on a head CT.
S-Scuse me while I confer
with Dr. Hawkins.
Well, thanks for checking up on her.
Oh, of course.
I was in surgery
when they called.
Whatever you need, man.
I'm here.
Listen, she can be
a bit of a hypochondriac.
All right?
She came from Maui convinced
that she had dengue fever.
It was allergies.
And it's only gotten worse
ever since I told her
I was going to Nigeria.
You know?
Maybe she's just having a hard
time processing her feelings.
To be honest, we all are.
I want to keep her in the ER
for a bit,
make sure she's feeling okay.
And, selfishly,
I just like talking to her.
She has some enlightening
stories about your childhood.
Hey. You keep those
to yourself.
We'll get you on that plane
with a clear conscience.
Appreciate it.
- What's up?
- Looks like I got
my first potential date
from my Indian matchmaker.
Ooh.
Anyone interesting?
Oh, my God.
Oh, wait. Give me that.
Dr. Pravesh?
Your sickle cell patient
Rose Williams's labs came back.
Everything looks fine.
Okay. Cool.
Doctor, thank you.
Is something wrong?
Dr. Devi, have you ever used
a match...?
Mr. Benson in room 5202
needs an EKG.
Can you handle that, please?
- Sure.
- Thank you.
You are not being
helpful.
Rose.
That was a cryptic message
telling me to come in.
Is something wrong?
Good news, actually.
Your counts are excellent,
and you could never tell
that you had a devastating
sickle cell crisis last month.
Oh, that's a relief.
Honestly, I feel healthier
and happier
than I have felt
in a long time, but, um...
admitting that sends a wave
of dread over me
because I know it's temporary,
and I know
that I'll never escape that,
not for the rest of my life.
Here.
Well... what if I told you
that might not be true?
We've been through this.
Doctors always underestimate my pain,
but it is very, very real.
I know. I know.
But I've been doing
some research.
There have been some
developments in gene therapy.
Recent clinical trials
with good outcomes.
There might be a cure, Rose.
I've opened the soft tissue.
Cerebellar retractor.
Maybe less force.
You don't want
to make your closure harder.
Thank you
for the advice, Dr. Voss.
Bovie?
Elevating
the paraspinal musculature
off of the periosteal plane.
Sweeping it to the side.
And... beautiful.
Dr. Voss?
You're needed in the ER.
And you're thinking,
I can waste the rest of my day
babysitting
a perfectly capable surgeon,
or I should move on to
an operation where I'd actually
be useful.
I'm fine with either choice.
It's your hospital, your rules.
You seem to have made
a miraculous recovery, Dr. Cain.
Well done.
Dr. Sutton,
learn all you can from this man.
It's good to have you back,
Barrett.
How is your mother?
She's fine.
She's likely somatizing
her anxiety.
Conrad's doing a workup.
All of this has
to be stressful for you.
Well, for everybody.
Turns out you and I are the
Beyoncé and Jay-Z of Chastain.
I will stand for nothing less.
You know, I never realized
how us leaving would have
such an impact.
Oh, yeah, the hugging,
kissing, crying.
Oh, it's nauseating.
Do you regret this?
What?
Moving to Nigeria with me?
Listen to me.
I regret nothing.
Okay, that's my mom.
Listen, we are good.
Okay.
Anything we need
to be worried about?
Based on the test results,
everything looks
completely normal.
You see?
Everything's gonna be fine.
I am so embarrassed.
Making such a fuss
about nothing.
It's better
to be safe than sorry.
No, it's more than that.
This is supposed
to be AJ's last day.
And here I came
and made it all about me.
People often don't realize
how powerful
the mind-body connection is.
Sometimes, when your heart
breaks, your body does, too.
It's good you came in.
It's important to take care
of yourself,
even when things are hard.
Especially when things are hard.
Thank you.
Hey. Everything okay?
Labs and CT are normal.
Just to be safe,
I'm gonna set up an appointment
with her primary care physician.
She'll go
- in the next couple days.
- Yes.
So she doesn't have
to be admitted?
There is no specific
medical reason to admit her.
Please, AJ,
I want to go home.
You're sure, Mom?
I'm sure.
You have
to drill down the facet.
Her hyperflexion injury
caused the bones to shift.
We have to shave them down.
That's arterial blood.
Vertebral artery.
The bone was tamponading
the bleed.
Give me suction.
Turn it up. Now.
You'll have to remove bone to
expose and repair the artery.
I know that. Drill.
Dr. Cain?
I got it. Hold on.
Dr. Cain, I don't think you do.
Let me take over the surgery.
Give me a second.
If we wait,
you won't have to worry
about her walking again.
She'll be brain dead.
Call Dr. Voss.
Wait!
Okay, take over.
Suction here.
Hold it stable.
Drilling above and below
to expose the artery.
Two arterial ligation clamps
to me now.
Hey, can you cover
for me in the ER?
For, like, an hour.
Yeah, no problem.
Does this have anything to do
with your date with Dr. Devi?
Mina told me.
Of course she did.
No. So I have a meeting.
Remember Rose,
our sickle cell patient?
Of course. She's been
through hell and back.
Well, I think I may have found
her a clinical trial
using gene therapy.
The founder of one of these
companies running the trial...
He's an old college buddy
of mine, and he wrote this paper
about how he's revolutionizing
sickle cell treatment,
potentially curing it.
Well, we both know
he'll be incentivized
to publish
only the good outcomes
and conveniently
leave out the bad.
Like most pharma companies.
Just keep an eye on that.
Look, you know I'm not going
to get Rose involved
in anything that I don't 100%
believe in. You know that.
Of course I do. I trust you.
I just don't trust
Big Pharma.
We both love Rose.
Just...
I want this to work out for her.
Yeah. Me, too.
See you.
Would you stop following me?
I work here, too.
Yes, on another floor.
Yet every time I turn around,
there you are.
Well, maybe I want
to spend every last second
that I can with you.
Okay, if you're expecting me
to have
some emotional breakdown...
Tears, wailing, and so on...
It's not gonna happen.
How about you just admit
that you love us
and you're gonna miss us?
I do love you,
and I will miss you.
You don't look like it.
What do you mean?
This is my
"I love you" face.
You're the worst.
Okay, fine. You know what?
Go back to Nigeria.
See if I care. But I will get
the goodbye I want.
You can count on it.
Phillip, dude,
you're still driving
that nasty beater from college,
and this is what
your lab looks like?
That car treats me well, man.
We had some good times
rolling around Harvard Square
in that car.
No comment.
Look, the way I see it,
you got to put your money into
something that can do some good.
And right now that's here.
I'm proud of you, man.
I always knew you'd be
a great hematologist, but...
What? You didn't think I would
cure sickle cell anemia?
Have you?
We've completed
our gene therapy protocol
in a total of five patients.
All are currently
leading normal lives.
No more symptoms, no pain.
Did you get a chance
to look at my patient's
medical chart that I sent you?
Yes. Keep in mind it doesn't
normally happen this fast.
But we did just have
somebody drop out,
and, I mean,
Rose is a perfect candidate.
That said, I mean,
these are uncharted waters.
There is a chance... slight...
That a patient could
come out worse.
They could die.
A lot of hospitals won't risk
hosting our trials.
But you think Chastain should?
Not think. Need.
I know it's a lot to ask.
But if I can convince your CEO
to become a site in this trial,
we would be one step closer
to eradicating sickle cell
from Atlanta.
Look, I can probably get you
in the room,
but Kit Voss...
She's a different kind of CEO.
If she even suspects, Phillip,
that this is about money
or profit...
Just-just give me
a chance, okay?
I will nail it, and then
you and me, Pravesh,
we'll start changing the world.
Ah.
We've taken enough time
on your last day, AJ.
You don't have to do this.
Of course I don't have to, Ma.
I want to.
You know, today made me realize
that I've not spent enough
quality time
- with you and Dad before I left.
- Oh.
I just want to make sure you
get back, settled safely.
We won't complain
about more time now, will we?
I want to apologize
for all day, really.
Mom, you have nothing
to apologize for.
Yes, I do.
Ever since you told us
you were leaving, AJ,
all I've thought about
is myself.
About my own distress.
About how much I'll miss you.
But I should be happy for you,
about the adventures
you'll be having
with your darling Mina
at your side.
Can you forgive your mother
for her selfishness?
Of course, Ma.
You okay, babe?
Mm-mm.
Take a deep breath.
Mom, we need to get you
back to Chastain.
You can say the words out loud.
My mother has a tumor
in her lung.
AJ, I'm-I'm so sorry.
How could I have
not seen this?
When she came into the ER,
the exams and bloodwork we did
would not have caught this,
but now we know.
So we take this
one step at a time
and we focus on the
circumstances in front of us.
I'll do the surgery myself.
You know that's not possible.
It's a conflict of interest.
We do the surgery and the biopsy
at the same time.
She'll need a segmentectomy
to remove the growth fully
and maybe a lobectomy.
She needs the best hands
we got, Hawkins.
So let me do it.
Thank you.
Now I have to go tell her.
I don't understand.
A tumor in my lung?
I've never smoked.
And it could be benign,
just a harmless growth,
but we don't know.
And we can't diagnose it
from imaging alone,
so we need to do a biopsy
just to be sure.
- You gonna do it now?
- Yeah, you know, the sooner, the better.
Now, the good news is,
as far as we can tell,
we caught it early.
It looks localized.
AJ.
I need to know...
what are my chances?
Mom, biopsy first.
Mina will do it.
She is the absolute best.
So let's get our facts straight,
and then we'll talk
about possibilities.
It's going to be okay.
We are in this together.
Look, this is not
about the money.
And I know
when somebody says that,
it is always about the money.
Then what is this about,
Mr. Bondman?
You're looking at me,
and you're thinking,
"What is this white guy
from Harvard doing,
trying to cure a predominantly
African American disease?"
Well, I'll be honest with you,
it was a calculated decision.
The technology is here...
CRISPR, gene therapy.
There is a badly
underserved population.
And if Bio South can solve
this problem,
we would have the momentum
and the money to solve others.
Bio South, Phillip Bondman
would become synonymous
with curing people.
I appreciate the honesty.
But does this give Rose
a fighting chance
- at battling her disease?
- Yes, it does.
And not just Rose.
We're a public hospital now,
so we're serving
large sickle cell populations
that can really benefit
from Phillip's work here.
I want a cure, of course.
And Rose deserves nothing less.
But getting into bed
with Big Pharma...
With all due respect,
Bio South is not Big Pharma.
We couldn't be further from it.
We are small, we're scrappy...
...and we want to do good.
So, what did you say?
That I'd consider it.
In a perfect world,
there wouldn't be
a financial incentive
to make better medicine.
Yeah, but that's not
the world we live in,
so what harm is there
in giving the guy a chance?
The harm is, history is littered
with examples of
dubious advancements in science
coming at the cost
of a vulnerable population.
The Tuskegee syphilis
experiment, Henrietta Lacks...
Yeah, yeah, but in this case,
the patients have
the most to gain.
You know, a-a...
a cure for an ancient disease...
How amazing would that be?
It could also be
an opportunity to show
that this is a new Chastain.
One that will go to the ends
of the earth for its patients.
It sounds to me like
you've already made your decision.
AJ, if something happens
to me, I...
Now, don't talk like that, Ma.
This is not
our last conversation.
All right?
No one is dying here.
I know, AJ.
But I need you to hear
one thing.
Please, son,
whatever happens to me...
I want you to go with Mina.
Be happy.
Live your life.
This is important.
You deserve joy.
Thank you, Ma.
Hey, Leela?
Hey.
Yes, Dr. Pravesh?
Um...
this is gonna sound weird,
but I am working with
a matchmaker, and on her site,
you-you...
Oh, God.
You saw my photo?
Yeah.
Is that what you were looking at
with Mina earlier?
Oh, that's... that's embarrassing.
Um, I never go on that thing.
My dad wants me
to have an arranged marriage,
like my parents did,
so I just humor him,
but any time that matchmaker
offers anybody up,
I just say, "No way."
- Mm.
- I don't have time for it, and it's just... it's...
Oh, wait. Are you...
- you looking to get... married?
- No, no.
No, no.
Uh, same as you.
My mom... she just keeps pushing
and pushing, you know.
- Indian parents, right?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Okay.
Later, Dr. Pravesh.
- See you.
- Okay.
There's the mass.
Let's biopsy. Forceps.
Oh, you've come a long way since
our first operation together.
Ah, seriously, you, too?
You know, I know
I was never your mentor...
More like your tormentor...
So it's not my place
to be proud, but I am.
I'm gonna miss working with you.
Who else would have shown me
what not to do?
Let's get that to the lab.
See what we're dealing with.
Can you move your toes for me?
I can't thank you enough.
Well, you have Dr. Sutton
here to thank.
She's the one
who saved Lisa's life.
Just don't go falling off
any more diving boards.
I can't
believe I was so stupid.
Ah, don't beat yourself up. We
all do stupid stuff at your age.
But the good news is,
they removed the bone fragments
that were compressing your spine.
With some time
and aggressive therapy,
you'll be good as new.
That is wonderful news.
And your boss dropped this off.
It's the first paycheck?
First and last. Um, I got fired.
I'm sorry to hear that.
I thought I knew what this
summer was going to look like.
Make some money, get a tan,
sneak in a couple
of night swims at closing.
Probably sounds silly.
Take it from me.
Even the best laid plans
fall apart.
Things change.
You lose a job.
But the people that love you
stick by your side.
They do.
And that's a beautiful thing.
I can't even believe it.
You'll start the
trial next week. It's fast.
Most people have to wait months,
but there's an opening.
Yeah, and it's gonna be
a long, hard road, and nothing
is guaranteed, Rose.
But I have a chance?
Oh, you have more
than just a chance.
You have a damn good chance.
Barrett?
Go.
We'll be in touch.
Thank you so much.
You'll never guess
what just happened.
I've been accepted into
a gene therapy clinical trial.
That could work.
Chances are slim, but...
that could work.
This is a big deal.
Aren't you happy for me?
Yes, of course
I'm happy for you, Rose.
I'm happy for you.
Wait.
I don't know
what's going on with you,
but if there's a light
at the end of my tunnel,
there's a light at the end
of yours, too.
And what if there is no light?
What if I just have
to face the facts?
Own up to the truth
that I'm not who I once was?
You're more than just a surgeon.
Am I?
Look, I'm gonna go to Waylon's
and eat my weight
in pretzels and beer cheese.
There's a big world
outside of the OR.
If you want to see it,
that's where I'll be.
I'd like that.
Pleural studding,
too small to have been detected
on imaging.
Well, whatever it is,
it's already spread.
It's much worse than we hoped.
It's adenocarcinoma.
I'm so sorry, Mina.
Well, we can't cut
all of this out.
Um, let's close up.
No reason to put her through
the rest of this surgery.
The biopsy confirmed it.
Your mother has
stage IV lung cancer.
If she's a candidate
for target therapy,
Carol will have years.
Many years.
You and I both know
the average life expectancy...
is two years.
She's not average.
She's resilient, strong.
I know that
because she raised you.
If anyone could beat this,
it's Carol.
Your mother needs you.
In Atlanta, by her side.
You cannot come to Nigeria
with me.
I know.
I wish things
didn't have to be this way.
I wish I didn't have
to leave Chastain.
Leave you.
I will do anything
to be with you through this.
Maybe one day
I could come back.
Yeah.
Maybe.
"Are You with Me"
by Nilu playing...
♪ Wake up ♪
♪ Stay with me ♪
♪ Through the flood ♪
♪ And ♪
♪ Through the fear ♪
♪ Right now I need you here ♪
♪ I need you to stay strong ♪
♪ To remind me
where I came from ♪
♪ And where I belong ♪
♪ So wake up ♪
Hi. Can I get a taxi
to Atlanta Hartsfield?
Mm, right away.
- I'm at Chas...
- Hey, Mina. Nic's been looking for you.
I think
she wants to say goodbye.
She's upstairs in the café.
♪ I never ♪
You okay?
♪ Actually had you ♪
♪ You're not in the dark ♪
♪ Far from the light ♪
♪ And I need to know now ♪
♪ Are you... ♪
Surprise!
♪ Are you out? ♪
♪ Oh, are you in
or are you out? ♪
♪ Are you in ♪
♪ Or are you out? ♪
Mina, darling,
are you all right?
I'm-I'm fine.
♪ Are you with me? ♪
She just needs a moment.
And maybe a drink?
Yes, please.
Yeah, mm-hmm.
Here you go.
How are we ever going
to replace you?
And AJ. Where is he?
Um...
He got caught up elsewhere.
Hey, I know what
will cheer you up, presents!
I hate presents.
No, no, no, no, no.
No, no, you'll like these.
You'll like these.
They're a list of online games
you can play
with your friends.
You know, in other words, us.
But long-distance.
This way you can still join us.
And maybe
AJ will rock charades.
Thank you. Truly.
This means more to me
than you'll ever know.
Ah, there's-there's one more
from all of us.
Mina Okafor's
infamous one-star Yelp review!
"Steer clear of Dr. Okafor.
She told me my uterus sucked."
It did suck.
Ah, we love you.
We don't want you to forget us.
I will never forget you.
Speech!
Okay.
I'm not gonna stand here and...
give some speech about
how much you all mean to me
and how much I'll miss you,
because that's not who I am.
And based
on the shroud of secrecy
surrounding this party...
You all know that.
You know exactly who I am,
and yet you still care about me.
I haven't had a lot
of those sorts of folks
in my life before.
I don't always say this...
Actually, I've never said it...
But...
you're my family.
And I love you.
I always will.
♪ I can see the change ♪
♪ Come what may,
I won't regret today ♪
♪ I can see the change ♪
♪ Feel the pace of everything ♪
I need you to do me a favor.
Keep an eye on AJ for me.
He's not going with you?
His mother.
Yeah.
He has to be here for her.
Through the treatment.
It's the right thing to do.
Yeah.
I'm so sorry, Mina.
I know
how much you wanted him there.
When he's falling apart,
call me.
I'm not disappearing for good.
I want to be there for him.
We'll take care of him.
I promise.
Of everyone...
...I'll miss you the most.
Not half as much
as I'm gonna miss you.
You are my sister.
And you are mine.
♪ No, it's not for me ♪
♪ Anymore ♪
♪ No, it's not... ♪
Now, that's your "I love you" face.
♪ Anymore ♪
♪ No, it's not for me ♪
♪  Anymore ♪
♪ Anymore ♪
♪ Standing out ♪
♪ Standing
out ♪
So, it's gonna be a, uh...
long 12 hours and 27 minutes.
♪ Like a fool does ♪
No neck pillow this time.
♪ Doesn't mean I'll adjust ♪
♪ Standing out ♪
I love you, Mina Okafor.
I love you, too.
♪ Like I need you now ♪
♪ Like a fool does ♪
♪ Like a fool
does ♪
♪ Let the world adjust ♪
You know, you always said
we'd be doomed from the start.
I'm always right.
This is...
this is not over.
Not yet.
♪ I can see the change ♪
♪ Come what may,
I won't regret today ♪
♪  I am what remains ♪
♪ Standing here
in spite of everything ♪
♪ No, it's not ♪
♪ For me ♪
♪ Anymore ♪
♪ No, it's not for me ♪
♪ No, it's not ♪
♪ For me ♪
♪ Anymore ♪
♪ Anymore. ♪
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Sync corrections by srjanapala