Morning, roomie.
I'm going to the market
later. We need more apples?
No. But we need
more toilet paper.
No prob.
May I?
Angel fluff plus, two-ply,
unscented, ultra-wide, extra-soft.
Two-ply. No prob.
You have to hang the toilet paper
on the dispenser the correct way.
The paper goes over on the top,
not under hanging against the wall.
Sorry, I forgot
you like it like that.
I don't like it like that.
It's right like that.
NBD.
It's no big deal. I gotta run.
Ms. Kohli? Hi. I'm Dr. Melendez.
Sorry. I have to
practice whenever I can.
I practice whenever I can, too.
We heard you hurt your
finger. Can we take a look?
I got a crappy manicure
a couple of days ago,
and now my nail
looks disgusting.
Paronychia. It's an abscess caused
by a common bacterial infection.
We'll drain it, pack it
and send you home.
In 72 hours, the pain and
swelling will be much better,
and you'll be back to Paganini.
Apologize already.
- I did nothing wrong.
- So?
You don't wanna be iced out by
the future chief of surgery forever.
Lim could be chief, too.
Andrews hasn't decided yet.
Hey, Browne, Park, hustle in.
EMTs are less than a minute out.
Park, make sure Bay
Three is good to go.
Thirteen-year-old female,
progressively worsening epistaxis.
Bolus on the bus.
BP's 86 over 51.
It won't stop! I
can't get it to stop.
I got home, and she
was calling 9-1-1.
Not your first
nosebleed, huh, Dad?
These things usually
go away on their own,
but Riley claims it's been
like this for over an hour.
Ugh, it's not a
claim, it's a fact.
Gonna need to get her
on a monitor right away,
and apply 4%
phenylephrine solution.
Gonna need to
cauterize the bleed.
It's not my first
nosebleed, either.
I have my premiere at Davies
this weekend, hence the manicure.
Rosin, beeswax. That
stuff is tough to get off.
You play?
I know my way
around bow strings.
I dabbled in archery
when I was in high school.
- I started when I was five.
- Mmm.
I used to hum melodies
doing my homework, eating
dinner, taking out the trash.
I wanted to be
a train conductor.
There's still time.
She's numbed up,
she shouldn't have
any pain in her finger.
It's not my finger, it's
further up, by my knuckle.
No fever. Any body aches?
Uh... A little. Playing violin all day
stresses out my neck and shoulders.
It's likely tendonitis
or mild arthritic pain.
Or it might be flesh-eating bacteria,
and we may have to cut off your finger.
There's the bleeder,
at the posterior rim of
Kiesselbach's plexus.
You called 9-1-1?
She did.
- How you feeling, baby?
- Peachy.
It's a nosebleed.
I'm handling it.
She's my kid, too, Bruce.
Bet you couldn't
tell they're divorced.
Why don't I take Riley's parents
to the waiting room, so we can...
Talk about me. Adiós.
We need to know.
Shaun, what do we need
to do to know for sure?
We need to cut
deeper and get a swab.
Fingers have thousands
of nerve endings.
Clipping off even the
tiniest portion of Jas' finger
could cause permanent
damage and be career-ending.
But if it is necrotizing fasciitis
and we do nothing, she could die.
That would also end her career.
True, but the numbers,
Shaun, the data.
There's almost no
chance that it's nec fasc.
On the other hand, if we test for
it, we will definitely do damage.
Anything else?
Do you hang your toilet
paper going over or under?
Doesn't matter.
Before the nosebleeds,
it was tummy aches,
insomnia, breathing pain...
Every time we'd rush
her to the pediatrician,
but they couldn't find anything.
So, we stopped taking her.
You think she's faking it?
A therapist said it was
likely her subconscious way of
trying to get her family back together.
Divorce isn't easy for adults,
why should kids be able
to deal with it any better?
She disengaged.
Not just from us, but
her friends, school.
It's been five years.
She should have found
her new normal by now.
Looks like someone's
doing better.
Nosebleed's stopped, but Riley's
nasal membranes are pretty thin.
You should be on the
lookout for future bleeds.
Riley, have you been sniffing
or snorting any drugs lately?
What? No way. I
wouldn't do that.
There's a lot of stuff out
there that looks harmless, but...
She said no.
Does Flonase count?
I was coughing, I had a
stuffy nose, itchy throat.
I looked up my symptoms,
because what the hell
else was I supposed to do?
Vasomotor rhinitis fit.
So I went to the drugstore
and I got some Flonase.
Misuse of steroid sprays
can thin out nasal membranes,
causing terrible nosebleeds.
Quit the Flonase,
and you're good to go.
Thank you.
I need you to take her tonight.
I had to skip a pitch to an
important VC to get here.
Sorry. Didn't mean to take you
away from anything important.
You're provoking her. You
know she's an anxious kid.
I'm not anxious, I'm sick.
- Could you, for once, have my back?
- What?
This is your fault. She's
playing us against each other.
What's wrong?
My breathing, it... It hurts.
Just relax, sweetie.
Just stop, both of you.
Vasomotor rhinitis.
That is a pretty unique
diagnosis for an eighth-grader.
You'll be numb in a minute.
Seventh. And I was
wrong. Doesn't matter.
I get what you're going through.
You were smart, popular.
We don't have
anything in common.
I was never popular.
I wore hand-me-downs
from Goodwill.
I never knew my dad.
My mom was sick, I
couldn't rely on her.
- Kids that age can be total...
- Jerks.
Ass-hats. Turds.
I wouldn't send my worst
enemy back to junior high.
I got so many Ds on
my report card last year,
I got held back.
Now everyone treats
me like I'm stupid.
It's humiliating.
How'd you deal with it?
I said, "Screw it."
They already think I'm bad.
I mess around in
class, leave campus.
I do whatever the hell I want.
But you're still angry.
I didn't let my past define me,
and yours doesn't
have to define you.
Repeating a grade
doesn't make you...
What? What's wrong?
Nothing.
There doesn't seem to
be any active bleeding.
But I coughed up
blood. That was real.
It's possible it's just
post-nasal aspiration.
That the blood you coughed
up was from the initial nosebleed
and it went down your
throat into your lungs.
But my chest, it really hurts.
Hey, Shaun. What's up?
You forgot to put your coffee cup
in the dishwasher before you left.
Sorry, I was in a rush.
And remember, rinse it out
before you put it in the dishwasher.
- Noted.
- And on the top rack.
- I gotta go.
- Me, too.
Morgan doesn't want to know
what's wrong with our patient.
I find that hard to believe.
They talk about bowstrings.
I don't know anything
about bowstrings.
They should be talking
about what's wrong with her.
You can't always know, Shaun.
Sometimes tests aren't worth it.
Sometimes we don't
have the right tests.
What are you doing in here?
Lea and I disagree
about toilet paper.
And you made a good point
about finding the right test.
Thanks.
I just did a test.
On the toilet paper?
Every toilet paper roll in this restroom
has the paper hanging over, not under.
And they were installed
by professionals.
Does it matter?
"I-D-G-A..."
I think it's an acronym, or
maybe even an anagram.
I don't think Lea cares
about the toilet paper debate.
It's not a debate, I'm right.
I think you should talk
to Lea. Not text, talk.
Did you talk to Dr. Melendez
after you got in trouble with him?
- No.
- Why not?
Because I did nothing wrong.
Because you were right.
- Yeah.
- So am I.
Make sure all four tips are touching
the ground before you take a step.
Well, thank you, Iris. I never
would have figured that out.
I'm required to show you how
to use all medical equipment.
Well, I'm not gonna use it.
- You wanna know why?
- Huh.
Because I'm not gonna use it.
You remind me of
my Grandpa Eddy.
So grumpy, so adorable.
See? Look, no hands. I'm fine.
Chicken soup. Heard
it's good for the soul.
I wasn't expecting you.
Thank you. That's
very thoughtful.
I... It's... Really,
it's no big deal.
I signed up to bring
you food at the hospital,
the Meal Train that they set up.
- The Meal Train, yeah.
- Yeah.
How... How are you doing today?
Well, today is
actually looking up.
You wanna come
in, have some soup?
I have other plans.
- Oh. Yeah.
- But...
I'm actually free tomorrow.
Do you like lasagna?
I kinda love lasagna.
Great. Finally get
that second date.
- You know, you don't have to...
- No, Aaron.
I want to.
Well, then, I want to.
Okay, great. Then, um, I
will see you, then, tomorrow.
I'll see you tomorrow.
No one dabbles in archery
unless they're at summer camp.
How long did you do it?
Seven days a week
for seven years.
Why'd you stop?
It was just time...
To go to college, medical
school, be a grown-up.
It was that easy to just quit?
Archery doesn't fill
concert halls or pay the bills.
She has a slight fever.
Her rash is spreading
and she has edema.
This is definitely
not paronychia.
I know. I've moved on to MRSA.
That's possible, but
you should want proof.
If we do an open,
deep-tissue biopsy,
we will know for sure if
you have flesh-eating...
Shaun.
Part of being a good doctor
is knowing when to not
scare the crap out of a patient.
I don't think so.
This is your problem, not hers.
Your need to be
sure. Your obsession...
We need to cut off a
small piece of her finger
so we know if we
have to cut off a larger...
Shaun, you're acting like you
want to amputate her hand.
No, you're acting like you
don't want to amputate her hand.
I don't.
But that's not
medically relevant.
Her temperature is 102.
It's gone up two degrees
since we've been arguing.
Okay. We'll test her.
That tissue has begun to die.
Or it's inflammatory
infiltration.
Find anything?
We're at an impasse.
Look here, at the margin.
Subcutaneous fat
and fascial necrosis.
Shaun was right.
Let's go try to save her hand.
She is a young girl
with a lot going on.
We agree on that much.
That's why she
needs to see a shrink.
Hmm.
This... This feels different.
What, you don't believe
in emotional intelligence?
If I have to choose
between the battery of tests
we've done and your gut,
it's an easy choice.
No. You don't relate to her.
And if you don't relate to
her, you can't understand her.
You're probably right.
You think you do relate?
And do you have a kid?
My opinion about
Riley is medical.
Why haven't you told
any of us you have a kid?
That is a huge chunk of
your life you've been hiding.
I don't feel the need to share
everything about my personal life
with the people I work with.
That's your passive-aggressive
way of saying I'm an over-sharer?
Yeah.
Your opinion on
Riley is clearly skewed
because you're looking at
her through a parental lens.
I've been in her shoes, I am better
equipped to evaluate her situation.
You're the poster
child of skewed.
You're too emotionally
involved, and are overreacting
because you had a crappy
mom who didn't care about you.
And why do I know all that?
Because you're an over-sharer.
The scan's clean.
It's time to send her home.
Clamp.
Whoa. That is not good.
Muscle's weak, clamp
slid right through the fascia.
Murphy, pull the skin back.
Smells like rotten eggs.
There's only tissue damage.
If we debride her
hand carefully,
we can preserve some
mobility and dexterity.
She's gonna need close
monitoring post-op tonight.
Scissors.
We need to talk.
Can it wait? I'm late for
an all-night coding session.
You hung the toilet
paper incorrectly.
Right. Did you flip it?
Great. We're done.
You left the TV
remote on the couch.
Shaun, I am running late.
You have to put it on the
tray on the coffee table.
That is where it belongs.
If it doesn't have a set place,
then it will be in many places.
And then it will get
lost, and if I can't find it,
I can't watch the
Weather Channel...
Okay, enough about
the damn remote!
Everything in this place
has to be your way.
We have to make sure to use
two pods in the washing machine,
we have to keep the
cups to the left of the plate,
air-conditioner at exactly 74,
and we have to use one very
specific, very hard-to-find toilet paper.
And I'm trying to be accommodating,
but you are not cutting me any slack!
Oh, God. Shaun.
Shaun, I am sorry.
Are... Are you okay?
You have a ruptured Achilles.
I'm afraid your weekend
warrior days are over.
Help! Can we get some help here?
Right there.
What happened?
She couldn't sleep.
Uh... She spiked a fever.
It's only getting worse.
I can't breathe.
Okay, take a deep
breath. In, out.
104.6.
I need IV acetaminophen
and cooling blankets, ASAP.
She's tachypneic
with an O2 SAT of 87.
Is this... Is this
something new?
Or... I mean, did
she do this to herself?
She has an infection.
I think she's developed pneumonia
due to an underlying condition.
- What underlying condition?
- I have no idea.
Page Park and Lim.
No signs of PE or pneumonia.
CFTR was negative
for cystic fibrosis.
I think we may have
missed something on her CT.
There.
That slight shadow
on the bronchus.
A slow-growing carcinoid tumor could
cause chronic airway inflammation.
As the tumor grows,
the symptoms worsen,
leading to airway
obstruction and infection.
Or it's just a shadow.
A slight shadow.
It is pretty subtle.
I would like to do
exploratory VATS.
You wanna poke holes in her chest,
and go rooting around in her lungs?
Riley's body's
already compromised.
There are no obvious lesions,
and her symptoms are
more likely indicators
of a simple sinus infection.
The safer, better plan
is to treat with antibiotics.
If she has a progressing tumor,
we can't just send her
home with medication.
Pitch the surgery to
the parents, and Riley.
Okay.
Hey! Hey, hey! Don't touch
those, those are vintage.
Well, I'm just scooting
your toys over,
so it's easier to get
to your medication.
Toys. "Toys"?
Those are not toys.
That's Reggie Jackson.
Well, when that timer goes off,
Roger Johnson can
give you your medicine.
- Reggie Jackson.
- Mmm.
Hey. Guess what?
Quitting time.
Okay. Have fun. Take your pills.
Yeah.
I think I broke Shaun.
Hi.
We got into a big fight, huge,
and I was yelling, and he
just fell apart. It was awful.
I mean, he pushes and
pushes. I pushed back!
Shaun's not easy,
but you knew that.
I knew it was gonna be
hard, but living with him is a lot.
I know.
There's stuff I've never
even thought about.
And I know he has idiosyncrasies,
but there's a lot of them.
- I mean, a lot.
- I know.
- Is Shaun okay?
- Yes. No. I don't know.
He's at work.
Glassy, you know him.
Like, really know him.
How do I deal with Shaun?
Well, it's been 12 years
and I'm still learning.
He just always has to
be right. I mean, do you...
Do you know how many
calls and texts and notes
he's left me about how
I'm doing stuff wrong?
I have a pretty good idea, yeah.
Yeah, well, it's exhausting.
You know what?
We all have quirks,
we can all be a pain in
the ass from time to time.
Okay, admittedly,
Shaun a little more so.
That is not helpful.
- Sit down.
- What?
- Why?
Why? Because you're
agitated and you're annoying me,
and I can't give you
good advice in that state.
- Sit.
- Right.
Thank you.
Do you like Shaun?
- Of course.
- Why?
He's sweet, kind, honest.
Sometimes brutally honest.
There's never an
agenda with him.
He's just Shaun.
So?
So, I want him
to change a little.
You moved in
expecting him to change?
He doesn't want you
to change, I know that.
And if I made the
wrong decision?
Then you move out
and you do it right now.
It'll devastate him, but the
longer you wait, the more...
The worse it will be for him.
If Riley has a tumor,
we need to open her up to
find out what we're dealing with.
Why do you think
she has a tumor?
It's consistent
with her symptoms.
The same symptoms
she's been having for years?
Yes.
The same symptoms we've
been told are psychological?
The same symptoms
a dozen doctors have run
100 tests for and found nothing?
There is a shadow
on her CT image.
A shadow?
And it's a risky surgery?
Opening her up in a weakened
state could be dangerous.
Look, I know Riley frustrates
you, drives you crazy,
but I also know you love her.
You have a chance
to show her that.
So, you wanna do
this as a statement?
We want you to
believe in your daughter.
Because that's
what a parent does.
When she was little
and had a bad dream,
she used to come into our room
and snuggle up under your arm,
just like she's doing to me.
You would stroke her face
until she was finally at
peace and fell asleep.
She's in so much pain,
and I don't know how
to make it go away.
Riley?
Hey, um...
The doctors, they wanna see
what's going on in your lungs.
They think you
might have a tumor.
And we want them to operate.
You think I have a real tumor?
It's scary, I know,
but, yes, we do.
Her BP's dropping
out, 73 over 50.
Heart rate is spiking, 137.
Hang an IV saline bolus.
We need a 12 lead.
The necrosis has
migrated. She's septic.
There's definite
infiltration to the bone.
We're gonna have
to amputate her arm.
Polish the bone to
help stump healing.
Rasp.
Margins appear to be clean.
There's still a small chance microbes
may have spread to her organs.
If they did, then her mortality
rate just increased exponentially.
What if we put her in
hyperbaric oxygen therapy now?
Oxygen's toxic to bacteria.
There's a lot of things that
could go wrong in there.
We wouldn't be able to decompress
the chamber in time to help her.
We wouldn't have to wait to help
her if someone goes in with her.
I'll do it.
Okay. Get the chamber ready.
Lung tissue looks normal.
And there are
healthy-appearing bronchi.
Nothing yet.
Damn it! Tore a lobar artery.
BP's 81 over 49.
Oxygen sats 93, heart rate
is going up, she is tanking.
Park, I need more suction.
I can't see a thing in here.
We need to do an
open thoracotomy now.
- Browne, crack her chest.
- Ten blade and a rib-spreader.
There are only 7.18
cubic meters in there.
How does it feel?
It's fine.
I thought it might feel claustrophobic
for someone neurotypical.
It is.
Got it, but it's still bleeding.
Her stroke volume
just bottomed out.
Rapid infuse four
liters of whole blood.
Get ready to start
cardiac massage.
Wait, I think I have an
anchor in the arterial wall.
Stroke volume is rising.
BP increasing, 90 over 60.
Pulse is 90 and regular.
She's stable for now.
This was a mistake.
We need to close her
up as soon as possible.
It doesn't make any sense.
Her arterial wall
shouldn't be this fragile.
Something else has
caused it to thin out.
What else is going on in here?
Browne, I need more light.
Yeah. See that?
A localized granuloma
on the right lower lobe.
You think it's cancer?
Not sure, but
something's in there.
Park, retract the lung.
It's a LEGO.
Riley must've
inhaled it years ago.
It settled in your lung, became
encased in inflammatory tissue.
Your body's immune
response attacked it,
making you progressively
more sick over the years.
It's small, thin and
made of plastic,
there was no way of seeing
it on any of the imaging.
Ugh, this is so gross.
I'm gonna make
it into a necklace.
Good luck. Excuse me.
We're sorry that we
didn't believe in you.
We're sorry that we put
you through all of this.
We're sorry that
we got divorced.
Whoa.
You guys are way
better off apart.
We always thought you were
upset because we split up.
I was upset because
you fought all the time.
You still do.
And it freaked me out.
So, I'd hide in my princess tent,
bite my nails, gnaw on crayons,
chew on LEGOs.
We screwed up.
And we promise we can do better.
I am not saying that Ordinary
People is not a good movie.
It's a great movie.
Okay, what I'm saying
is that Raging Bull is a
superior cinematic experience.
It is raw, it's,
like, romantic...
It's romantic? It pummels
you from start to finish.
Yeah. Exactly.
Exactly. It's like adrenaline's
pulsing through your veins,
it leaves me breathless
every time I watch it.
Oh!
Do you... Do you wanna
maybe go for a walk?
It's a little cold outside.
I'm gonna kiss you.
You are? Okay.
Listen, maybe we
ought to walk upstairs?
- Okay.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- This way?
Whoa!
- Can I help?
- No, thank you.
I'll get there. I'm okay.
I'm okay, I'm okay. Ow!
Is my hand okay?
Your biopsy was positive
for necrotizing fasciitis.
We had to do multiple surgeries to
remove the infected muscle and bone.
Bone?
I'm so sorry, Jas.
We had to amputate your arm.
No.
No, my arm... My
arm still hurts, I can...
I can feel it. It's still there.
What you're experiencing
is phantom pain.
Your arm is gone.
He told you.
My arm.
My arm is gone.
It's gone...
And it's...
It's your fault.
Get out.
Get the hell out.
I can't.
Neither of us can.
- You called it.
- Hmm.
Well done.
Thanks for your help.
Finally a believer in the
power of emotional intelligence?
It did get her parents on board,
even if it's only for a little while.
They believe their kid,
and they're working on
their family relationships.
It's pretty big steps.
It was a nice moment.
But if you think
you changed them,
that they'll be different people
tomorrow than they were yesterday,
then you're kidding yourself.
Right now, my
emotional intelligence
is telling me even
you don't believe that.
Kitchen's clean,
leftovers are in the fridge.
How you doing?
Fine.
I just got a little
light-headed.
Balance isn't quite
back to normal.
Now that you're feeling a little
better, you wanna watch Raging Bull?
No.
Okay. Another time.
I can't do this.
We can take it slow.
I'm... I'm happy to just
be here with you, like this.
No, I can't... I can't
be here like this.
I... I don't want you to...
I just...
I don't want to...
I'm sorry, I just...
I need you to go.
Please.
Jas practiced violin every
day since she was five.
She put all her faith in me
to do the right thing, and...
I thought I did, I...
Shaun didn't care. He...
He didn't see her dreams,
he just saw her symptoms.
Sometimes that'll
be the wrong choice.
My second year in the
program, there was this resident.
She was kinda weird.
She wore comic-book T-shirts,
always ate the exact same lunch.
But she was smart.
She would get surgeries and
knock them out of the park,
over and over again.
I couldn't stand her.
And one day I realized, I
was competing against her,
but she wasn't
competing against me.
She spent her time observing,
asking questions, preparing
herself to be a great surgeon.
Is she?
Dr. Lim is one of the best
trauma surgeons in the country.
- Dr. Melendez.
- Dr. Browne.
Dr. Lim.
Nice save today.
I heard. Yes, good
work, Dr. Browne.
Thank you.
Good night.
You know she
showed bad judgment.
You got something
to say, just say it.
Wanna grab a beer?
Yes.
Hey.
Are you okay?
Yes.
I am so sorry for my
outburst yesterday.
I'm fine now.
I'm not, Shaun.
Coming back to California,
and starting a new job,
and moving in with you,
it's been so stressful.
Harder than I anticipated.
You're moving out?
No, I am not moving out.
We are still figuring
out each other's quirks.
Yes, you're very
difficult to live with.
I know I forget stuff, a lot.
And sometimes I snap and yell.
I promise to work on that.
And I don't need you to change,
but I do need to know that you
know you're annoying as hell.
I need to know that
you'll try to compromise.
I don't think I can use
one-ply toilet paper.
No, you were so
right about the two-ply.
Totally worth the extra $1.50.
But maybe the cups can
go to the right of the plates.
Sometimes.
Everything's unpacked.
We're officially
moved in together.
I'm gonna take these
down to the recycling.
And I know I probably didn't
put everything in the right place,
but maybe we can
rearrange it together.
I like that idea very much.