♪ Mm-mm-mm-mm, mm-mm-mm
♪ Mm-mm-mm-mm
♪ Mm-mm, mm-mm-mm-mm
In a recent experiment...
...scientists observed
that single human cells
in a Petri dish will actually
seek each other out...
♪ Walk like I talk like I run
♪ Working like a boss, we don't
need to take a freebie ♪
...and adhere to each other
to form new connections.
♪ Don't believe me,
take a peek-y, ha ♪
♪ I get what I want
what I love ♪
♪ I don't mess around
Trying to be
the first one in?
I was.
I'm always first.
When cells team up...
Big day.
...they become stronger.
They thrive and evolve
and eventually become something
bigger than their single selves
ever could have been.
Morning, Winston.
Uh, Dr. Webber.
Uh, I-I married
you and Maggie,
so, you -you can
call me Richard.
Right. Richard.
Ah.
Uh,
how's Maggie's father?
Oh, he's better.
Ah.
Yeah, yeah. I'm hoping
to go out there next week.
Ah.
How's the Webber Method
coming along?
Morning, Dr. Webber!
We were just wondering what we
should be prepared for today.
Which O.R. to be in.
And what surgeries we're doing.
Please and thank you.
I'd say the method
is going pretty well.
Let's move!
Okay.
Don't forget to breathe.
M-Mom, Mom,
stop worrying.
Dr. Hayes says Dr. Ndugu
is the best in the country.
Other people
think so, too.
I looked them up.
I'm not worried, my love.
And, also, people
don't like being told
that they were
background checked.
I'm so sorry.
It's all right.
Dr. Hayes and the Internet
are absolutely right.
I'm good.
You ready to roll?
Yeah.
All right.
Okay.
I will see you later.
Yep.
Bye-bye.
Bye.
All right.
You might want to go
and get something to eat.
Pericardiectomy
can take five, six hours.
Complex procedure.
Where you remove
the calcified pericardium
that's been constricting his
heart for God knows how long.
What kind of surgeon-slash-mom
did you think I was
if I didn't know that?
I know.
Just protocol.
You talk
to your brother yet?
Or were the curtains closed
because this is one of those
"secret" heart surgeries
that Grey-Sloan
is so well known for?
What, you have
one drink with a guy,
and you're suddenly in
the "no secrets" zone?
Don't you think
this relationship
is moving kinda fast?
I'll talk to him.
Today.
Now.
Take good care of him, or
I'll come back and kill you.
Thank you.
No, but, seriously,
I have the training.
♪♪
Unfortunately,
the VA is still stonewalling
on your coverage, but
we are making progress here.
Yeah, we now have
chest X-rays, blood samples,
and pulmonary function tests
on almost everyone.
Except Noah.
Since Colonel Davis passed,
Major Hunt --
Doctor. Dr. Hunt.
Sorry. Dr. Hunt.
Since the colonel died,
no one's heard from Noah yet.
He thinks it's my fault
that Roy died.
He's not the only one.
Uh...
You two have a sec?
Yeah, we're done here.
We'll be back
and update you later, okay?
Oh! Get down! Get down!
Get down right now!
Get away
from the windows!
Are we under attack?!
Shh. Quiet, quiet.
♪♪
What the hell
was that?
♪♪
Okay. All right.
Thank you.
Scout and Luna --I-I
just called daycare.
Everyone's fine.
Scout barely woke up.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
What was that?
I don't know.
Hope it doesn't
happen again.
Hunt wants everyone
in the ER.
Have we heard
what happened?
I'm trying to call Ben,
but he's not picking up.
We need to activate
mass casualty protocol.
We don't know
what happened yet.
It felt like a bomb.
We need to start
setting up beds
and make sure
we have enough blood.
Schmitt, grab
another resident.
Prep the trauma rooms,
cancel elective surgeries,
and tell the O.R.s
to be on standby.
Private, Corporal,
help us set up
a triage station
outside, A.S.A.P.
Yes, sir.
Owen, they're not
medical personnel.
They're patients, and
they're not in 100% health.
They're also soldiers
who have trained for
these kind of events.
In a few minutes, we're gonna
be flooded with mass trauma.
We need all the help
we can get.
There was a pipeline explosion.
He's still not answering.
It's gonna be okay.
Yeah.
So, the committee
at the FDA
said the first step
toward getting approval is,
we have to prove that the cells
can survive at every stage.
They need to make it through
the reprogramming process,
differentiation, suspension
prep, and cryopreservation
without turning into
cancerous cells.
So we've succeeded in
the cell maturation process.
I've succeeded at that.
Well, you have,
which is a milestone in itself,
but now we need to prove
that the cells can survive
once they've been injected
into the brain.
Ready here.
You're putting my precious
biopsied cells
into a fake brain.
It's a 3D-printed
hydrogel brain.
Injecting Trial 1 now.
We're using test cells,
and we dyed them blue
to visualize their behavior
once injected.
Crap.
"Crap"?
If the cells stay in a blob,
they'll die.
Very scientific.
How do we fix it?
We need to try different
injection techniques.
Okay. How many of these
gel brains do we have?
A-And how much
do they cost?
Oh, there's plenty.
And think of it
as a contribution
for, uh, you know, science.
It's a...
You made it.
Uh, bad time?
Dr. Lynne McDonald
to the nurses' station.
Dr. Hunt?
Doctor? Dr. Hunt!
Corporal Sacilotto,
what's the sit-rep
in the ambulance bay?
Still clear --
other than a few firefighters
with minor injuries, sir.
Copy that.
Stay ready.
Hey. Have you seen
your sister?
I have looked in
all the triage areas.
Her name's not on
the surgical schedule,
and she's not in radiology
and --Have you tried calling her?
Yeah, but she hasn't picked up.
I'm worried.
I mean, there was an explosion,
and she took off running.
And with her history --Teddy,
she's fine.
Are you?
I'm fine. Megan's fine.
Everybody's fine,
except for the people
who were injured
by that bomb.
O-Owen, there wasn't a bomb.
It was a --
Listen. They're gonna
need our help.
I need to do my job,
so why aren't you doing yours?
♪♪
Um, Hayes?
What is she doing here?
Is he okay? There was
an explosion. Was he awake?
He was already under
when the explosion happened.
What are you...doing?
Okay.
You can start now.
Dr. Hunt, all due respect,
I don't think
this is a good idea.
All due respect,
I don't care.
Megan, we've got this.
Great. Then start.
Look, I'm not leaving my son,
so unless you want his
already-failing heart to worsen
because his pericardium
is crushing his heart
as we speak,
I suggest you start.
Scalpel.
♪♪
How we doing?
I thought it'd be busier.
Yeah, it sounds like
most patients are either dead
or at Seattle Pres.
I'm sure Ben is --
Thanks for jumping in,
Wilson, but you can
head back up to O.B.
An exploding pipeline
isn't exactly joyful.
Bailey, I w--Got -I got it. Go.
♪♪
32-year-old
female firefighter.
Status post-electrocution --
G.C.S. 15, stable vitals.
Hughes!
Uh, Bailey. Hi.
I almost died.
Uh, let's get her inside!
Move! Move, move!
Nice robot.
I didn't approve this.
Amelia needed
a second neurosurgeon.
It would have taken us weeks
to get these gel brains
without Tom, and he's written
several papers on the use
of micro-injectors
into the brain.
And you gave me autonomy.
Don't worry.
Dave, I signed an NDA.
Well, I-I crossed my fingers,
but I signed it.
Kidding.
You like working with him?
He's brilliant.
And he saved my life.
We're ready over here.
Did you change the suspension's
cell concentration this time?
Did someone ask
for your opinion?
Uh, let me think. Yep.
Shepherd and Grey said,
"We need a second opinion
on this whole..."
Okay. Start
the injection, please.
Another blob.
Yeah, cells will remain locked
in the center,
and without access to nutrition,
their suicide gene goes off,
and they'll start
offing themselves.
The problem isn't in
the suspension or the cells.
It's in the technique.
You should look for one
with a better
surface-area-to-volume ratio.
I can't have this.
I cannot have this.
What, you cannot have
a good idea?
I know.
That's why I'm here.
Tom.
What? I --
He was not part of our deal.
Oh.
What is the story here?
Wh-It's sordid.
N-Nothing to do
with, uh, science.
Fundamentally,
he's a big baby,
but I'm willing to help
save his life, so...yeah.
Hughes, any chest pain?
Tightness?
I'm not s-I'm not sure.
I think I'm --
Still in shock.
Vic, wa-was Ben --
I'm pretty sure
he gave me morphine.
Okay. Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
What happened?
Pipeline got nicked
by a construction worker,
and the whole block went up.
Then I went up on the ladder
to put water on the building,
and a power line just went
rogue, and I got fried.
And then, when I woke up,
I was dangling from the ladder,
and Miller w-was giving me
mouth-to-mouth?
Thank God he did.
You might not be here.
Gonna have Schmitt run
a FAST exam, EKG,
cardiac enzymes, and labs
to rule out rhabdo.
Okay.
I think
he's in love with me.
Hunt?
Miller.
Bailey.
Oh.
Yeah.
There was a second blast.
Couple of rigs are
on their way here now.
Firefighters, apparently.
♪♪
Who is it?
Bailey, hold on!
Who's the patient?
Pat Aquino,
captain over at Station 23.
G.C.S. 10 T, penetrating injury
to the abdomen,
pelvis unstable.
Full thickness burns
to the face.
♪♪
Lincoln,
I'll join you in trauma two.
Okay. Let's move
carefully. On our way.
No siren. No rush.
There's a dead person
in there.
♪♪
Gibson.
Gib--
Ben.
What happened?
Who -Who's...?
Who --
It's Miller.
It's Dean Miller.
♪♪
I can't believe --
Miller.
After everything.
I know.
And Hughes?
I mean, d-does she
need surgery or...?
We're triaging her
and running tests
to rule out
cardiac injury.
It'll destroy her.
I mean, it'll destroy
all of us, but Hughes...
Oh, God.
Miller has the baby girl.
Oh, what's gonna happen
to that poor thing?
What? Ben. What?
T-There's something I need
to talk to you about.
When we were in the water
that night -M-Miller and I.
Uh, he asked me if, um...
Ben?
He asked me
if I would take Pru.
You know, if anything
ever happened to him.
Ben.
Miller. Is he...?
No.
♪♪
Oh, no.
Does Vic know?
No.
Can I see her?
I need to tell her.
Um, she's, uh --
she's getting tests,
but I don't know that we should
drop this kind of news on her.
Yeah, I'd rather
just get it over with now.
S-She really --
She hates it
when people keep stuff
from her, so...
I'll take you.
Okay.
♪♪
Um -
I-I should go get Pru
from daycare.
Do we know the plan?
I-Is she going with you two?
Um, we're still
f-figuring that out.
Hey.
Tom Koracick's
an incredible neurosurgeon.
He's a leader
in his field.
He saved
Catherine Fox's life.
Koracick slept
with my daughter.
Oh.
Was she underage?
No.
Did he abuse his power?
Was she coerced in any way
into sleeping with him?
No.
Okay, so you're willing
to slow down
a possible breakthrough
here
because your adult daughter
had consensual sex?
Have you met the guy?
I have, and I understand
he's not everyone's favorite.
I-I want him
out of my lab.
Your lab?
You put
my name on the door,
and you moved the world
to get me here.
If you don't trust me,
what's the point?
You're really gonna
let a grudge interfere
with groundbreaking
research?
This isn't personal.
When we apply
for the FDA approval,
how many people
are gonna be against us
because Tom Koracick
slept with their mothers,
their sisters,
and their daughters,
and then gloated
about it?!
And it's not the sex,
for the record.
It's the gloating!
The FDA is not going to
block a possible cure
for Parkinson's
because of Tom Koracick's
questionable choices,
and neither should you.
You don't have to be here today.
Let me handle this.
It's my lab,
my research, my money.
His name is not gonna be
anywhere near this,
and that's final.
♪♪
All right.
Let's be careful here.
We don't want to cut it.
More lap pads.
Why? Sorry.
I-I won't freak out.
I just want to know
what's going on.
We're watching
for the phrenic nerve.
The pericardium is so stuck
to the heart,
it's hard to tell what's what,
so we're moving slowly
to avoid complications.
You wanna take a break?
Go get some air?
When we were in Fallujah,
I used to tell him
about all the cartoons
he'd get to watch
once we were rescued.
I'd sing him the theme songs
to make him laugh.
After we moved to L.A.,
whenever he'd get triggered
by loud, explosive sounds,
I'd take him outside
anywhere open
and hold his hands
and hum those cartoon songs.
He never actually watched
any of them.
He was always too impatient,
but whenever he got triggered,
I'd hum the songs
and hold his hands.
It always calmed him down.
Do it.
I don't want to distract you.
And now you're worried
about distracting us?
We're fine. Do it.
♪♪
There's free fluid
in his abdomen.
He's bleeding out.
He's got an open-book
pelvic injury.
We need to take him
straight up.
Call and find out which O.R.s
are free, please!
Hunt, uh,
you want to take this?
I can stay down here
if anyone comes in,
redirect personnel.
Hunt?
Hunt!
Uh, no.
No, it's --
it's all yours.
♪♪
Get down!
Get down right now!
Dr. Hunt?
Owen, are you okay?
Are they all dead?
Who?
Okay, so, you need
to change the depth
when you're in
subcostal view.
That's it.
No crap.
You just made me forget
where I was.
It's okay
to ask for help.
I don't need help.
I know what I'm doing.
I'm not freaked out at all.
You're the intern
that brought me flowers
when my fiancé died.
Yes.
But now
I'm a senior resident
and Chief of Trauma
for the month, so...
Ooh.
Which is still
just a resident.
I'm not seeing any free fluid
or pericardial effusion.
Travis! Thank God.
These two are playing
"pin the tail on my injuries,"
and I'm on
so many pain meds
that every so often
I think I see
a little cluster of grapes
in that...
...in that corner
over there.
Vic, um --Oh, and Miller!
He sort of kind of told me
he was in love with me.
B-But not in so many words,
thank God,
'cause you know,
I didn't wa-
I don't want to break
his heart, but...
It's...
What?
What happ--
What happened?
Wait, Trav--
Is -Is Theo okay?
Travis,
what's --Theo -Theo's fine.
What's going on?
Um...
Vic, there was a second
explosion, and, um...
♪♪
I'm gonna try
and stay calm
when I ask you this
because...
what's happening in there
is already s-heavy.
Did you say yes?
Yes.
Was it just, like, a --
a "death's door" kind of thing,
or did Miller
put it on paper?
♪♪
It was the second time
he asked me.
It was a confirmation.
At any point
before you confirmed it,
did you think to confirm it
with your wife?
I didn't think
he was gonna ever...
die.
Die?
You're firefighters, Ben!
I know, I know.
I know.
But you brought home Joey
without asking me,
and that worked out
for us.
Oh, an 18-year-old
is very different
from a 2-year-old girl!
Miller was my brother, Miranda!
He was my brother!
Vic!
No, no, no, no! Vic!
Help me! I need help!
Okay.
Hand that to me.
She's in V-fib!
Page Altman!
Go, go, go, go, go.
Hughes?
Okay.
You do not do this.
Hughes?! You hear me?
Not today.
Paddles.
Charge to 150. Clear.
Come on, come on, come on.
Charge to 200. Clear.
I still got nothing.
No, Hughes.
19 can't take it.
Hughes!
Push another epi
and charge to 200.
♪♪
Come on. Let's go,
let's go, let's go!
♪ Don't you cry for me
Charge to 200. Clear.
♪ I'm not incomplete,
oh, I'm in pieces ♪
Oh. Oh, my God.
She's back.
Vic?
All right, Schmitt,
order an echo,
and then let's get
cardiac enzymes every two hours.
I want you to admit her
to the CCU
under close observation.
Hey, the electrocution
caused myocardial injury,
which is causing some
arrhythmias to your heart.
But we're gonna know more
after further testing, okay?
All right. I gotta go find Owen.
I'll be back soon.
Don't ever
do that again, okay?
Was --
Is it real?
♪ You pull me out
♪ And hold me down
♪♪
♪ You hold me down
♪ My love isn't lost
♪ Just left behind
♪♪
Not that anyone's asked,
but I'm doing great.
Splitting my time
between Boston and Baltimore.
Met a lovely
former social worker
with the world's
bluest eyes.
Shepherd, how's your
happy little family?
You're married?
No, I'm not, uh --
No.
Um, Tom, wha--
what do you think about
a motorized injector?
Or something that
releases the cells
slowly along
the cylindrical track
created by the needle, and then
we inject as we pull out?
Please. Do not make
a pulling-out joke.
Oh.
Dr. Bartley, please.
Uh, we've both grown up
since, uh, you were
a post-grad
in my research lab.
I-I took the HR seminars,
got the slaps on the wrists,
and -and learned.Doubtful.
You studied with Tom?
Briefly.
I took a postgraduate seminar
from him.
That was all I needed to realize
I had no interest
in dealing with neurosurgeons.
Well, not all neurosurgeons
are as bad as Tom.
Now, you see?
I'm already the reason
this project's gotten
as far as it has.
What do I think about
a motorized injector?
I think great minds
that were shaped by me...
think alike.
Yes?
Hello.
You have a minute?
Sure.
You look angry.
I am.
Okay.
Not at you.
Good.
I need some information.
Okay. Shoot.
David Hamilton.
I think I fell
for the charm...Mm-hmm.
...and I'm forgetting
that that charm often has
a dark side, and he's having
what amounts to a tantrum.
Yes.
I've seen them before.
Okay, so, is he
a textbook narcissist,
or do I have
some wiggle room?
I-I don't think David's
a bad guy, really.
I just -I think doctors
make the worst patients.
I didn't realize you knew.
I mean, come on.
You're on my turf here,
and Parkinson's, it's a pretty
hard disease to hide.
Look, from what I understand,
David's throwing
every penny he's got
at your project,
but he's not in it
for the greater good.
I mean, if that's what he told
you and you bought it,
then, yeah,
you fell for his charm.
I fell for the charm?
Yes, you might have.
I was thinking of him
like an investor.
A scientist with big ideas
and deep pockets.
I should have been
thinking about him
as a class A surgeon with
a neurodegenerative disease...
Mm-hmm.
...who cannot
operate anymore.
So he's not only difficult,
but he's desperate.
Y-Yeah, David's been treated
like a god around here
for a very, very long time,
and now he's becoming obsolete.
So, difficult, desperate,
and terrified.
So you can
cut him some slack,
but don't let him
walk over you.
I mean, he put you in charge
for a reason.
Gotta remember that.
Yeah.
I would be a nightmare
if I couldn't operate.
Oh, God. You would be
a pain in the ass.
So would you. Moi?
Nah.
I roll with the punches.
How much do you know
about my super-secret project?
I-I know the players,
I can guess the goal,
but what you're actually
doing -total mystery.
♪♪
Thanks for the consult.
Sure. Any time.
Miranda.
Eh -No.
Miranda, you can be mad
at me all you want, but --
I am.
But there's still
a little girl
whose father just died,
all right?
Whose mother abandoned her when
she was only a few days old.
Who needs someone.
S-Someone to love her.
She has grandparents.
Ben!
You know how badly
I've always wanted
a little girl...
to love,
to comb her hair,
to teach her how to have
a voice in this world,
but it hasn't been
in the cards for me...
for us...
and now you're telling me that
little Pru Miller needs a mom,
and all I want to do
is run to her.
So just --
But if I do
and if I fall in love with her,
which I will,
and then her grandparents come
and take her away from me,
that I cannot do.
I cannot do that.
♪♪
All right.
Good job, everybody.
Clamps off.
Okay, my sweet boy.
We're almost done.
Come on, now.
Come on.
Oh, no. No, no, no.
What?
His heart's swelling up.
Can we diurese?
No, that wouldn't work.
What? You can't close him?
Not yet, no.
Let's push epi.
♪♪
How long?
Can't tell.
Could be minutes.
Could be days.
♪♪
All right.
Come on, come on.
Oh. I've been looking
everywhere for you.
Owen?
Owen.
I'm okay.
The explosion?
The vets.
Roy, Noah,
what they've been through.
Okay.
It's okay. I'm here.
I am right here.
It's okay
to take a step back
from the veterans project
if it's too much.
It is too much.
And I'm doing it.
'Cause I've learned
how to take care of myself.
This is me...
taking care of myself.
In two minutes and two breaths,
I'm gonna go back out there,
I'm gonna be okay,
because somebody has
taught me how to manage...
...my PTSD.
Somebody taught you, too.
But nobody's
taught them, Teddy.
Nobody's helping them
with anything.
I need to help them.
Okay.
♪♪
Is he gone?
I have complete autonomy
in picking my team.
That was very specifically
a part of our deal.
You brought me in
for a reason,
so let me do the job
you brought me here to do.
Wow.
I didn't think you could
remind me any more of Ellis
than you did,
but, well, I was wrong.
If that's meant to be
an insult...
No, no, no.
No, it's not.
I'm just not my, uh -I'm not
at my best self right now.
I understand.
I don't know that you do.
I didn't understand
when I was your age.
Did you know your mother
and I worked together
on a few patients?
Just for a few months.
In 2003.
Well, that was
when she started
exhibiting
the Alzheimer's symptoms.
Yeah, it started small.
The pauses.
Casual forgetfulness.
I didn't know what it was,
but when I talked to her
about it, she bit my head off.
I was trying
to be helpful,
trying to be
understanding, but --
She was terrified.
Terror doesn't begin
to describe it.
She was losing
who she was.
I'm losing who I am.
Not -Not my memory,
but my purpose, my being.
My hands.
I see how hard it is,
and I want to help.
But I cannot help if you
continue to second-guess me.
You have to trust me to do
the job you recruited me to do.
Whatever it takes...
however long it takes...
and whomever it takes.
And who knows? Maybe
Koracick will be a bust
and you can fire him.
Wouldn't that be fun?
The epinephrine
has had some time to work.
The heart's getting better.
Let's give it some time,
see if the swelling
goes down completely
in the next half-hour.
Okay.
Uh, can someone
grab me a stool, please,
and give us a minute?
Thank you.
♪ Postman Pat,
Postman Pat ♪
♪ Postman Pat
and his black and white cat ♪
"Postman Pat"? No?
Mnh-mnh.
Massive in Ireland.
Thanks for staying.
You okay?
Yeah.
No. I don't know.
Is she --
Is she gonna be...
Her labs are consistent
with someone who's had
a heart attack,
but her echo
looks really good,
so no need for surgery.
And she's young and healthy.
She should be okay.
No, she won't.
Physically, sure.
She's so strong.
She always kicks our ass
in training.
Miller's gone.
He was...
He was like
a brother to us.
But to Vic, he was...
I mean, they were like
a different kind of close.
And I hate knowing what
she's about to go through...
because she's already
had to do it once.
I can't imagine
having to do it again.
♪♪
♪ Far from home,
far from hollow ♪
♪ Far from all that I follow
Bailey.
Um, Wilson, it's fine.
I'm -I'm sorry.
Things were tense.
They still look
a little tense.
♪♪
My husband -who I am
incredibly grateful is alive --
has signed us up to be
the guardians of a child,
a child who
lost her father today.
This little girl is so --
Lucky.
Excuse me?
It is awful that
she lost her father...
He --
...but at least she won't
grow up without a home.
She will grow up
with Baileys and Warrens,
which, to me,
is pretty much like growing up
with a Partridge Family.
I don't even know
if that reference is right
because I didn't
grow up with TV.
♪ And controlling
Oh, you haven't made
the decision yet?
Miranda.
Oh, Ben. I'm -I'm sorry.
I can't do this right now.
No, Mira-Miranda.
Andy's here.
Wha--
She's here.
I --
♪ Mm-mm-mm
♪ Mm-mm-mm-mm
Baby girl. Ohh!
Hi.
Oh. Oh. It's okay.
Oh. It's okay.
Oh,
it's gonna be okay.
♪ Mm-mm-mm
Oh.
♪ Mm-mm-mm-mm
Oh! Mm-mm.
♪♪
How does it look?
He's fine.
Swelling in his heart
has subsided to normal size.
That's great news.
Let's close him.
♪ Mm-mm-mm-mm
♪♪
Megan.
It's all right.
Farouk's all right.
Megan.
Yes. Thank you.
We'll see you tomorrow?
Okay. Thanks, guys.
Bye.
New residents?
Veterans.
They're helping me
collect data for a study.
A burn pit study.
Okay.
Everything okay?
We need to talk
about your sister.
Oh, Megan.
Owen, Teddy, I, um --
I'm -I'm sorry. I --
No. No.
You don't need to explain
or apologize, okay?
I just need to know one thing.
And I need you to really listen.
Okay.
I -we --
we are your family.
You and Farouk.
You never have to
do this alone.
Ever.
Okay?
That's really --
That's what everybody says
before they leave.
Not this time.
No one is going anywhere,
and whether you like it or not,
we are family.
Okay? Okay.
♪♪
♪ Our bones...
We are an extension
of our cells.
♪ Turn to stone
♪ And our smiles
Just like them, we are
programmed to find others...
♪ All look the same
♪ What a safe place to be
♪ Look at me...
Oh. Winston.
Doctor -Richard.
Good day, sir?
You miss her
pretty bad, huh?
Oh, my God.
It's like an ache.
Yeah, Catherine's
out of town, too.
♪ I have only...
You know,
Joe's makes a mean burger.
Are you hungry, son?
I'm starving.
...to reach out
for one another...
and find nourishment and love.
Hey.
Did your firefighter
patient make it?
Well, he's gonna need
a couple months
of physical therapy,
but, yeah.
Thank God.
What happens if I die?
What?
If I die,
what happens to Luna?
I get the penthouse,
and Luna, Scout, and I
buy an 80-inch ultra hi-def TV
with your insurance money.
Link!
I've got Luna.
That's not even a question,
okay? I've got her.
♪ With the words in my head
Thank you.
♪ It's a waste of time
All right. Let's go home.
All right.
♪ In this waiting line
♪ But I guess that's fine
Well, I've bestowed my gifts
upon you.
Now I must away before David
jumps me in the parking lot.
Night, Tom.
Like our cells,
we're not meant to be alone.
If you're trying to beat me
at chicken, you're gonna lose.
I need very little sleep
to function.
I was kinda hoping to be
the last one out.
Hamilton is not thrilled with me
for bringing Tom in,
still gotta earn points.
Well, he worships me,
so as a favor to you,
I will leave first.
♪ I got to do a little running
♪ To get back home
So you're not married,
but Koracick said
"happy little family."
I have a beautiful son.
And my son has
a beautiful dad.
And I am single.
♪ Quietly dancing around
with the words in my head ♪
You?
Married. Yeah.
To this lab.
I'm -I'm married
to this lab.
This lab is so mad
I'm leaving early.
♪♪
It's pretty, right?
Okay. It's very late now.
Please go to bed.
Okay, miss you, Mommy.
I love you, Mommy!
Hey. Sorry I'm late.
It's okay.
Yeah.
But I thought you cut back
on your hours.
I know.
If only people
would donate their organs
at more convenient times.
It would be better.
How you doing?
I'm good.
Good.
You, uh --
You work it out with Hamilton?
I did. I did.
Good.
'Cause I thought
he was gonna fire you.
That wouldn't be good.
♪♪
So, once we find each other...
...try not to let go.
♪♪