Previously on The Resident...
Dr. Benedict. My man and mentor.
You led me to believe my
arrogance killed my patient.
When, in fact, it was a
company that owns you.
Every three minutes,
the QuoVadis device
stopped Henry Barnett's heart.
I've halted the use of all
QuoVadis devices at Chastain.
QuoVadis is willing to cover
Henry's medical
bills for his whole life.
If you go public with a
grievance, this deal goes away.
QuoVadis is engaged
in wide-ranging fraud.
Our contract is
now null and void.
Dr. Benedict, please tell
us whatever you know.
I want to talk to AJ.
He deserves the truth.
What did you tell them?
I didn't tell them anything.
Gordon, do you know
how I made my fortune?
By taking over companies
on the verge of collapse.
We should talk.
Hi, this is Dr. Benedict.
I'm not in. Leave me a
message after the beep.
Abe, it's AJ.
I've been calling
you all morning, man.
I'm outside your
house right now.
I see your car in the driveway.
I'm worried about you.
Abe?
Mrs. Benedict?
It's AJ.
Anybody home?
♪ ♪
No, Abe. Abe.
Fulton County 911.
What is the address
of the emergency?
278 Barksdale Drive.
Gunshot wound. Adult
male. Thready pulse,
shallow breathing. I
need an ambulance now!
♪ ♪
Male, 65.
GSW, upper chest.
Severe respiratory distress.
Tachy to 150.
BP, 70/palp.
Okay. Two units O neg.
Activate massive
transfusion protocol.
Wait, oh, my God, is that...
Yup, Dr. Abe Benedict. I
found him like this in his home.
One, two, three, lift.
Exit wound?
- I didn't see any. Let's
get the portable X-ray.
No breath sounds on the left.
He needs a chest
tube. 32 French, to me.
Chest tube kit. And
Dr. Hawkins is paged.
Going in at the
midaxillary line.
Oh!
GSW?
Self-inflicted?
It's hard to believe,
but it looks that way.
Image is up.
Bullet is embedded
in his abdomen.
Must have
ricocheted off his ribs.
Could've hit any
number of organs.
Hundley, call CT. He
needs a scan before surgery.
I'll meet you up there.
- Dr. Austin.
- Yeah.
Listen, when you saw him,
did he say anything about
QuoVadis and Gordon Page?
No, he was unconscious
the whole time.
I am curious what
the chairman of the
board of the hospital
that just stabbed QuoVadis
in the back wants with me.
You just lost an
enormous military contract.
It's a devastating blow.
We'll recover.
Our devices are still
in many other hospitals.
The VNS implanted at Chastain
was a horrifying failure.
That's not in the public record.
- The boy's mother signed an NDA.
- That certainly helps,
for now.
One more time. Why are you here?
I'm a businessman.
The medical device industry
is an unregulated gold mine.
You can do almost anything.
I smell an opportunity.
Your company is damaged.
I can help fix that.
Oh, that's generous.
But I've already fielded
offers from three new investors.
Two, and only one
of those is viable.
But that investor
is extremely viable.
And I prefer to work
with people I can trust.
Shortsighted, if not foolish.
For all your outstanding shares.
But I need to know
where the bodies are buried.
If we're going to rise together,
I need to know everything.
No surprises.
Mm.
I think you know the way out.
Thank you.
Hello?
I tried. It didn't work.
Gordon Page saw
right through me.
He told me nothing I
didn't already know.
That is not good, Dad.
We have a situation here, too.
Abe Benedict just
came into our ER.
He tried to kill himself.
Do we know why?
No. And he may never wake up.
In which case
we'll never find out
what he knows about QuoVadis.
Well, I did find out Page has
another investor
looking to make a deal.
He gets that money,
QuoVadis will be back
in business in no time.
We need to stop that.
Do you know who the investor is?
I have a pretty good idea.
You need to meet with him
and you need to scare him off.
- I can try.
- Good.
And I'll do everything I can
to keep Abe Benedict alive.
Good luck, Conrad.
Studying for this final
is making my brain hurt.
Well, humor heals all.
What do engineers
use for birth control?
Um, their personalities.
- Pretty funny, you guys.
- Oh, Nurse Nevin,
- you're back.
- Did our test results come in?
They did. Uh, why
don't you guys follow me.
The good news is
you can both ask
for an extension
on your engineering final.
The bad news is...
you both have mono.
Mono?
Wait, how'd we both get mono?
Well, they don't call it the
kissing disease for nothing.
Oh. No, uh,
- we're just friends.
- Best friends. Together since...
Since she blocked off the
seesaw to explain the relationship
between distance and mass
to our kindergarten class.
But not together-together,
you know, it's-it's more like...
Like study buddies,
but definitely...
- Not a couple. No.
- No.
Uh, okay. Well, my mistake.
Um, but there are other
ways you can contract mono.
I mean, if you use
the same toothbrush,
- sharing food...
- We've done that a lot lately.
Cramming for finals.
All pizza, all the time.
Okay. Well, you can both
go back to your dorms.
Uh, you'll want
plenty of sleep, fluids.
Mono's not usually
a big deal, but, uh,
you'll definitely
want a ton of rest.
Thank you. That's a relief.
Um, Evan, just... humor me.
I-I want to check
something quickly.
Your finger?
Hm. O2 sat is 88%.
That's, um, significantly
lower than when you came in.
- And what does that mean?
- Uh, it means
that I actually can't
send you home just yet.
Um, Sydney, you're
welcome to go,
unless you want to stay.
I'll stick around.
Can't catch something
I already have, right?
I'll be right back.
We need to admit Evan
Weston to Chastain immediately.
You've never even
kissed a girl in your life.
OR One is prepped and ready.
I'm sorry about your friend.
Abe taught me everything I know.
When you saw him yesterday at
the conference, how did he seem?
Intoxicated.
Nervous.
He was struggling. Whatever
he knew, whatever he did,
the guilt was starting
to eat away at him.
Are you thinking this
wasn't a suicide attempt?
- Yeah.
- I think Gordon tried
to have him silenced.
You're suggesting Gordon
had Abe Benedict shot?
Well, I would believe that
over Abe putting a
bullet in his own chest.
He was a heart surgeon.
He knew where to
aim if he wanted to die.
And suicide just doesn't
fit the man I know.
Abe jogged every night on
two bad knees to keep healthy.
The man loved life.
But he also took a million
dollars from QuoVadis.
That didn't fit the
man you knew, either.
Well, doctors commit suicide.
It happens. More
than we'd like to admit.
This is too coincidental.
This, on top of what
happened to Julian,
and we still don't even
know where she is.
Looks like the bullet hit
the spleen and kidney.
It clipped his heart as well.
.22 caliber.
Sometimes a bullet has
enough power to enter the body,
but not enough to go through.
Yeah, I've seen a bullet enter
a lung and end up in a leg.
You know, if we save his
life, we can get some answers.
Let's scrub in.
Keep me updated.
His hand is moving.
Sedation is too light.
Bolus 50 of propofol
and increase the rate.
Dr. Benedict? Can you hear me?
Whoa, whoa. He's
trying to say something.
Don't let him pull out
his tube, he could arrest.
- Damn it.
- Keep the propofol at that rate.
We can't force Abe to
speak or do anything else
that would harm our patient.
Stay focused. We
need to put saving his life
above everything else.
Get him to the OR now.
The bullet hit the spleen
and the left kidney.
Actively hemorrhaging.
- There's no time for repair.
- I'll resect the spleen.
Go.
Will you look at that?
Insidious devil.
Spleen is out.
Bleeding controlled.
He's acidotic and coagulopathic.
If you cut him any more,
he's not coming off that table.
- Damage control surgery?
- Yeah.
Now, listen up. We wrap
him but we do not close.
Take him out and let him heal,
and we bring him
back when he's ready.
- You couldn't close?
- No?
The amount of surgery
he needs to fix everything
would be too much for a
body to handle in one go.
How long until
you can go back in?
It's a long range.
Could be hours, could be days.
This is not the
outcome we wanted.
Formula for stress?
Sigma equals...
applied force over...
Can't concentrate.
We don't need to do this.
Please. You need to rest.
Can't. Too hard to breathe.
If I fall asleep... I'm
afraid I won't wake up.
Sydney, Evan.
This is Dr. Hawkins.
We're gonna take
a closer look at you.
- Hello.
- Double mono patients.
Sydney is stable,
but Evan is hypoxic.
Chest X-ray was just done,
and we're waiting
on the results.
But I think we
need to up the O2.
Look, please help him.
He's getting much worse.
Yeah, we should crank up the O2.
And let's order a
breathing treatment.
I like the dedication.
Still studying when
you feel this lousy.
Finals.
Mechanical engineering.
We're gonna design
a... high-speed train
from... Atlanta to Nashville.
So he can go home
on the weekends.
That's where we're both from.
Why is Evan so much worse
when we both have mono?
The truth is it's hard
to know. Each person
reacts differently to a virus.
But he's gonna be okay, right?
Um, just one second...
His X-ray's back.
This is really bad.
All right, let's get
him to the ICU.
Okay.
Let's start him on
ceftriaxone and azithromycin.
Call respiratory. Put him on a
BiPap when we get to the unit.
And I need another full
set of labs with a blood gas.
Yes, Doctor.
ICU? That's bad, isn't it?
Well, his mono's caused
him to develop pneumonia.
- Pneumonia?
- Don't worry. Don't worry.
Listen, let's just
try to stay calm
so we can be there
for Evan. Okay?
Okay. Calm.
Not one of my best traits,
but I can do it for him.
You got this. Here,
come with me.
Dr. Friedman,
please call Recovery.
- Lactate levels?
- Coming down.
- Most recent hematocrit?
- 24% stable.
But there was a lot of trauma.
Can we take him
back to surgery now?
He needs time for his
hemodynamics to stabilize.
His IVC is leaking. We
need to repair it quickly.
- Our first pass was crude.
- We bring him back in now,
- I don't think he makes it.
- We need to decide. Soon.
I know, Mina.
How's he doing?
If we dialed back his sedatives,
do you think he'd
be able to speak?
That's inappropriate, Pravesh.
It wouldn't hurt him.
And it might even...
You are too close to this case.
And you're not?
Go back to the ER, Pravesh.
I will keep you updated.
Book an OR.
We'll give him a half hour,
we'll go back into surgery,
and we'll finish the job.
Mono patient in the ICU.
Nurse says he's spiraling down.
Evan? Evan?!
What's going on?
It's like he's
drowning. Help him!
Get him up.
He has crackles
throughout his lungs.
BiPap isn't enough.
- He needs a vent.
- Please, what does that mean?
He can't breathe on his
own anymore, so the vent
- will breathe for him.
- Evan, I'm here.
I won't leave you.
We need to intubate now.
I'm already on it. I paged RT.
You need to wait outside.
I want to stay with him.
I'll come get you
when he's settled.
Evan.
Here. Pass it over.
Exposing the heart
and the abdominal contents.
Removing the packs.
14 in total?
Proceeding to repair the IVC.
Just keep it going.
Keep it steady. Keep it.
Keep it steady.
Keep it going. Keep it.
Take a step back.
Clear your head.
I have this.
Back in the game?
Back in the game, baby.
Works every time.
You should try it.
Oh, not in this
lifetime, but thanks.
You know, it's
just now hitting me,
despite my disappointment,
how much Abe means to me.
And I am gonna give
him a shot at redemption.
Howard Loomis.
Do I know you?
Marshall Winthrop.
Oh, of course.
We met at the, uh,
Signature CEO
Conference in Boca.
Yes. And you run
CliffCrest Management,
- a hedge fund out of Miami.
- I do.
I heard whispers that you
made a special trip here
to see Gordon Page.
I'm, uh, I'm late for
another meeting.
Is there a point to this?
Just giving you fair warning.
The bad news is not
all out on this company.
A whistle-blower was
going to come forward,
a prominent
doctor on the inside.
And?
Well, this morning he showed up
in the Chastain Park ER
with a bullet in his chest.
What-what are you saying?
Just that it may or may
not have been self-inflicted.
Gordon Page is a dangerous man.
Not someone you
want to do business with.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry,
but when a man like you
tracks down a man like
me with information like this,
then I start wondering.
What my angle is.
To stop a monster from
destroying more lives.
For men like you and me,
it's usually all about money.
But with this one, it's simply
about doing what's right.
His O2 sats keep going down
even though we've
gone up on the vent.
All right, there's
something new going on.
Pull up his most recent X-rays.
God. He has new
bilateral infiltrates.
His lungs are inflamed.
It's too much trauma
from the bullet
and the surgeries.
ARDS.
What do we do now?
He's maxed out on his
vent setting. What now?
Nic, if his lungs are
failing, he won't live long.
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
He needs ECMO.
Yep.
I'm on it.
Is he dying?
The virus is making
his lungs very sick.
Even the vent isn't getting
him the oxygen that he needs.
You have to save him. Please.
We have a plan.
And I promise we're
not gonna give up.
I screwed up.
I was too afraid to tell
him how I really feel,
and now I might
not get the chance.
You're in love with him.
Last summer, I...
went to this engineering
intensive at Duke.
Thought I would set up
my future and make friends.
Then I got there,
and I... didn't.
I didn't even try.
I spent all day wishing
I could see Evan.
I quit after two weeks.
Told my family I
was just homesick.
But the truth was...
I was homesick for him.
I never told him
how I really felt
'cause I didn't want
to ruin our friendship.
And now...
it might be too late.
Come here.
We're gonna do our best.
What's happening with Abe?
Nothing good. And
his lungs are failing.
I have a patient, Evan Weston,
- who needs to go on ECMO.
- We're having the same
discussion about Abe.
Yeah, well, the hospital
has two machines.
I'll see if they're available.
Uh, ECMO? What is that?
ECMO stands for
extracorporeal
membrane oxygenation.
It's a machine that's used
when a patient's lungs
are severely
damaged and the vent
isn't providing enough
oxygen for them.
Is it dangerous?
This move is very risky.
This is a last-ditch effort.
We'll have to get
the parents' consent.
Chastain does have two
machines, but one's taken.
Has been for a week.
Great. So we have two
patients who need ECMO
if they have any chance to live.
And only one will get it.
How do we choose?
Can we transfer
one of these patients
- to a different hospital?
- They're both too sick.
- They wouldn't
survive transport.
- There must be
a spare machine
somewhere in Atlanta.
I called. All of the ones
in the city are in use.
The closest one is Louisville.
That's a day's drive away.
- Someone has to play God.
- Abe needs the machine
in the next 30 minutes.
So does Evan.
Abe Benedict is a
world-renowned surgeon.
He's got at least
20 years to live,
which means he can teach
hundreds of budding surgeons
during that time.
Saving Abe will be saving
- many lives.
- He's also a possible suicide.
Look, I'm sorry, but are
we really gonna give this
to the 60-year-old man who
might not even want to live?
Abe did not attempt suicide.
Evan Weston is
a 22-year-old kid.
- He's got his whole life...
- Look, just... look,
hang on a second.
Everybody in this room has a
personal stake in the outcome.
It's already a major conflict.
I think we should keep
emotions out of this.
- So what are you proposing?
- Statistics.
At this point in their lives,
Evan Weston has the most
years to gain. He should get
- the machine. Well, and
there's another consideration.
The patient has to survive ECMO.
Evan's young, he's far stronger.
Abe...
just had major surgery.
I am sure
that Evan is a great kid, and
no one wants to see him die.
But Abe Benedict has damning
information about QuoVadis
and Gordon Page, the man
who may have had Julian killed.
Okay, that is a speculation.
I mean, you said so yourself.
No one wants to take down
QuoVadis more than I do,
but... Mina's right.
We need to keep
emotions out of this.
Evan Weston goes on ECMO.
That's the decision.
It looks like Abe Benedict will
never regain consciousness.
Hmm. I'm sorry to hear that.
Did you speak to Gordon's
investor like I suggested?
Howard Loomis had
a crisis of conscience.
Yes, he did.
Gordon is scrambling.
But that means nothing
unless we can use his
desperation to take him down.
I'm listening.
I go back in, bluff,
make him believe
Abe Benedict told us
everything we need.
No way. You're not doing that.
I'll be wired this time.
The FBI is close.
They want him just
as bad as we do.
Son, this is the time.
If we don't seize
this opportunity,
Gordon gets away
with everything,
he rebuilds his empire.
Trust me, he'll find
the money somewhere.
Okay.
Dad.
Be careful.
This is a recording device,
and it will get every word
spoken within a 20-foot radius.
Got it.
Just stick to the script.
And remember, if
you get in trouble,
we're listening.
And we can get to you
in under five minutes.
♪ ♪
How you doing?
It just all looks so terrifying.
Is that machine really
gonna help him breathe?
His lungs will barely move,
but that's because the machine
is actually breathing for him.
Look, why don't we get you
set up in the family room?
This could take a while.
When he wakes up...
if he wakes up...
I'm gonna tell him how I feel.
I think that's a good idea.
Come on.
Things got...
complicated, lately.
Never in a million years
did I think we would
end up like this.
I'm sorry, brother.
Ready to put Evan on ECMO?
- We're all set.
- All right. Let's do it.
♪ ♪
Oxygen saturation
is up. We're at 92%.
Nic Nevin probably
just saved your life.
Live long and prosper.
We still have work to do.
I've already upped
his PEEP to 18.
No, easy on his lungs.
Push too much, they'll pop.
He's still hypoxemic.
He's showing signs of
multisystem organ failure.
How can I help?
I got nothing.
Well, what if...
Wait!
Maybe...
we just need to change his
point of view on the world.
Well, I'm open to suggestions.
Good ones, at least.
We prone him.
Turn him over, let
gravity force more oxygen
into the rest of his lungs.
He just had major
abdominal surgery.
You turn him upside
down, his incisions will tear.
His insides will spill onto
the floor... literally, Pravesh.
Let's make sure they don't.
We'll tighten his bandages.
Come on, he's in
respiratory failure.
What else do we have to lose?
I say we go with
Dr. Pravesh's plan.
Okay.
Let's call and order
the rotating bed.
Okay.
Strap him in, wrap him up.
Secured.
All right.
Turn him over, nice and slow.
Loomis has decided to
take his money elsewhere.
I do whatever it takes
to get what I want.
Hmm. I can appreciate that.
Good, because I'm still
willing to make an offer.
Same number as before.
No, that was when
you had options.
I was paying a hefty
premium then to compete.
I'm offering less now,
but still a substantial sum.
No. No. Why should I take that?
Because you don't have a choice.
Men like you and I
always have choices.
I can walk. Fold the company.
Raise capital and
reinvent myself.
Start over somewhere else.
It's my specialty.
Agreed.
But when I bury someone,
I make sure they're firmly
in the ground where nobody
can hear them scream.
You didn't do that.
Right now, Abe Benedict
is in a hospital room
at Chastain.
The air filling his lungs
is allowing his mouth to move.
He's talking.
Trust me, he's saying
things that leave you
only one choice.
I don't believe you.
You don't now.
But you soon will.
In 15 minutes, lights
will start flashing outside.
They will have a
warrant for your arrest.
Take my money and disappear.
I will run QuoVadis without you.
Go hide out on an
island somewhere
without extradition
laws to the U.S.
Live large.
That's as good as
an admission of guilt.
I don't care.
Best and final.
Call him.
Who?
Your son.
There are some details
I'd like to know from Abe,
now that he can talk.
O2 sats are no better.
It takes a few minutes
for gravity to do its job.
Yeah, well, he doesn't
have a few minutes.
- Is your dad...
- Going to QuoVadis, yes.
We're taking one last shot
at bringing down Gordon.
- Have you heard from him?
- No.
Guys. O2 sats are rising.
88.
92.
It's working.
I know. I know you're
thinking we should...
back off the sedation
to see if we can
get him to talk.
Don't you?
Abe wakes up and bucks
his vent, his O2 sats will crater.
You said so yourself:
Abe Benedict needs a
chance at redemption.
Dial back the propofol.
He's waking.
Park him at 45 degrees.
Hey, boss. Welcome back.
Can you hear me?
Now, you wanted to talk to me.
Listen, man, whatever
you know that can help us...
Please, now is the time.
He wants to write it down.
SEVER?
We got to figure
out what this means.
You did good, man.
You're gonna be okay.
This is my dad.
- Conrad.
- Dad.
- You okay?
- Gordon Page
would like to talk you.
He wants proof
that Abe Benedict is alive.
Okay. Put him on.
Dr. Hawkins.
SEVER.
You want proof, there it is.
Abe Benedict is
alive and he's talking
about you and your company.
There's nothing to talk about.
My company broke no rules.
Made devices in China,
copied faulty devices.
All the people you hurt.
I hurt no one.
Heart valves that failed.
The VNS device you put
in an eight-year-old boy
that stopped his heart
over and over again.
I built this company
from nothing.
Abe was overcome with guilt.
- Abe was a coward.
- No, he was
- a hero.
- Abe was gonna destroy
everything that
I sacrificed for.
And you tried to kill him!
I had no choice!
Dad?
Earlier today, I...
was admiring your $80,000 Rolex.
It's not often that I
change my watch
in the middle of the day.
Search him.
Who's listening to us?
The FBI.
Son of a bitch.
Bring him.
You're coming with me.
We'll leave through the garage.
FBI! Hands in the air! Freeze!
They've got a hostage!
♪ Mm... ♪
♪ When I was a child ♪
♪ I'd sit for hours ♪
♪ Staring into open flame ♪
♪ Something in it had ♪
♪ A power ♪
♪ Could barely tear ♪
♪ My eyes away ♪
♪ All you have is your fire ♪
You have to wait here.
Where's my father?
♪ Tame your demons ♪
♪ But always keep
'em on a leash ♪
♪ Mm... ♪
Conrad.
Dad.
♪ Mm... ♪
I'm okay, son.
I'm okay.
♪ My senses fooled me ♪
♪ Thought gasoline ♪
♪ Was on my clothes ♪
♪ When I was a man ♪
♪ I thought it ended ♪
♪ When I knew
love's perfect ache ♪
♪ But my peace has
always depended ♪
♪ On all the ashes in my wake ♪
♪ All you have is your fire ♪
♪ And the place
you need to reach ♪
♪ Don't you ever ♪
♪ Tame your demons ♪
♪ But always keep
'em on a leash. ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH