Previously on E.R.:
- What about in vitro?
- It's a long shot.
I'm sorry if I gave you
the wrong impression.
There's nothing
going on between us.
- We work together and that's it.
- I know, I just...
I... I thought we
could have a drink.
My real name is
Claudia. I'm a cop.
How long you planning
on being pissed at me?
- You know, I don't know.
- You wanna come home with me...
no strings attached, just
for one night, we could...
- Lucky bastards.
- Who?
You didn't hear? Five workers
at Jumbo Mart won the lottery.
Ninety million dollars.
That's 18 million apiece
before taxes, the lucky bastards.
- Heard they all quit their jobs.
- Can you blame them?
No, but there was something
about starting my shift with a coffee...
a Slim Jim and a smile
from Babu behind the register.
Frank, where's Dr. Banfield? I need
her to sign the December Q1 reports.
She and the others are at a department-
chairs meeting. She's leaving at 2.
Two? That's mid-shift.
Boss lady never leaves
early. What gives?
I'm not her social secretary.
- Minivans? Seriously?
- Mm-hm.
- If I drive it, they will come.
- Who will come?
My future wife, kids,
and our dog, Buster.
- You named the dog?
- I'm putting it out to the universe.
I always dreamed of a house in
the burbs, picket fence, big backyard.
Why tie yourself
down? You got it all.
A great job, money, not to
mention, that cool motorcycle.
No wife is gonna let you
ride that thing. Trust me.
You know what
you're having? A thrisis.
- A what?
- Midlife crisis for thirtysomethings.
Are you looking at your life,
wondering what's it all about?
- Yeah.
- Questioning your values...
and what you're doing?
- Totally.
- You gals watch too much Oprah.
- Auto versus bicycle, three minutes out.
- Okay, how do you spell "thrisis"?
Jody Nugent, 16, hit by
a car while on her bike.
- Wearing a helmet?
- Where's my stuff?
Abdominal pain, shoulder
contusion and forearm lac.
- How fast was the car going?
- My bag. Where's my bag?
- Happened on Halstead. Limit's 30.
- Like drivers obey.
- I need my bag.
- Do you know where it is?
- Must have left it on the rig.
- I need it.
- Don't worry, I'm gonna get it.
- Scanner ready, Trauma 1.
- You need me on this?
- No. We're good.
- How about me? MORRIS:
Join us when you get in.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Listen, about the other
night, I should apologize.
- For what?
- I was drinking.
- I was drunk, and if I did anything...
- Tony, we had sex.
- So I did something.
- Mm-hm. I had a good time.
From what I remember, I did too.
Oh, and then you
asked me to marry you.
I'm kidding.
- So we're cool?
- Yes, we are cool.
Because sometimes people in
this kind of situation get weird...
and things get messy,
and... You mean Sam?
- And work.
- I got it. No drama.
Good.
- I don't see any rash.
- Look at the base of the hairs.
I see these little white things.
- Something's moving.
- Moving?
He's got lice.
Uh, we could treat
with permethrin.
Not good enough. We
gotta get rid of all the nits.
- How? Pick them off?
- Gotta be shaved.
How am I supposed
to shave my own back?
- Dr. Martin will do it for you.
- I will?
Mm-hm.
Get a prep razor and a can
of... Two cans of shaving cream.
Relax, buddy. Don't
scratch so much.
- Dawn, you got this, right?
- Oh, hell no.
- Nurses'll get you back.
- I got one over here.
Hey, what you guys got?
- Barbara Feingold.
Ground-level fall, good
vitals, says wall pain on the left.
- I'm Dr. Gates. Do you have any pain?
- When I breathe.
She hit the edge
of the bathtub. Ow!
- Are you okay?
- Sprained my back trying to pick her up.
- Too much dead weight.
- Did you just call me fat?
Get a chest X-ray,
CBC and a pulse ox.
- Didn't call you fat.
- I'm still a size 8.
If you're using
the metric system.
I wanna thank
you for everything.
No need. I'm just glad
we avoided surgery.
You're not the only one.
Hey, uh, thank you for
sorting my phone out.
I told you it was easy.
Hey, no offense, but I don't wanna see
you in here again anytime soon. Okay?
Hi, Dr. Brenner. I hope
you had fun in Australia.
Thanks.
- Do I know her?
- Back from your holidays?
Yeah, three days ago. I called
you when I first got back...
and I thought we could go out,
have some dinner and catch up.
Yeah. Sorry, I was busy.
Frank, is the PNB back on
Exam 2? I mean, the BNP.
Bought you a souvenir.
It's in my locker.
You didn't have to go to
any special bother for me.
He didn't. He got something
for everybody. Watch this.
Dr. Brenner, can you help
me with a vadge bleed?
- Did you get an icon?
- Yeah.
Welcome back, Dr. Brenner.
BRENNER: Thank you.
- Uh, it's good to be here.
- Put it away, Crocodile Dundee.
Uh, Neela, have you heard
anything from Hopkins?
Uh, not yet, but thanks
for putting in the call.
Yeah, well, chief of surgery
was a med-school classmate.
I understand you're also
interviewing at, uh, Yale and Duke.
- Yeah, that's right.
- All good choices.
Frank, I will be unreachable
for the rest of the day.
- Dr. Banfield, um, is everything okay?
- Yes. Why?
- I... I don't know, I just...
- I'm fine.
Yeah. Everything's fine.
- I guess my bike skidded on some ice.
- Kind of cold to be biking anywhere.
- Still need a pulse ox.
- I'm not getting any good waves.
Ah, a finger probe is loose.
- I should get that.
- Five centimeter lac.
Distal neuro-circ intact.
- Pupils equal and reactive.
- No hemotympanum.
- Can I get that?
- What labs do you want?
Uh, trauma panel,
ETOH levels, Chem-7.
- Dr. Morris?
- What she said and a urine tox.
- Sam, I can do the foley if you want.
- She's not gonna need it.
- Is this our driver?
- She was on a bicycle.
- I don't have my license yet.
- I thought they said MVC.
- How's the belly?
- Some pressure over the liver.
I'll take the ultrasound.
The driver of the car that
hit your patient is here.
Alert, open-fibula
fracture in Curtain 2.
- How is he? Is he okay?
- He's the one that should be worried.
- Okay, whose phone is that?
- It's mine. I should answer it.
- We already called your parents.
- Why did you do that?
Archie, please.
That's my boyfriend.
That's his ring.
You can call him later. Get her
upstairs for a head and belly CT.
Sam, Curtain 2 when you're done.
- Sure.
Her ultrasound looks good.
Need help?
- Labeling the bloods?
- Yeah.
- How's anesthetist training going?
- Fine.
- It's really cool that you're doing that.
- Uh-huh.
Word is you're really
kicking ass up in the O.R.
Yeah, it's great.
It's real great.
It must be tough
juggling everything. I...
You wanna help me, Daria?
Would you see that these get to,
uh, the lab? I gotta help Dr. Morris.
- Deep breath, Mrs. Feingold.
- I can't. It hurts.
All right, titrate
four of morphine.
- This the fall?
- She slipped getting out of the tub.
I grabbed the towel
bar, but it was loose.
Someone didn't fix
it like he promised.
I told you to call the super.
That's what he gets paid for.
Blunt left chest with dyspnea.
- It was a good thing you were there.
- I wasn't exactly there.
- All right, tell me, where does it hurt?
- Here?
- Ow!
- No crepitus.
Harry lives next door, he
heard me yelling for help.
Not hard to hear. She has a
voice that cuts through steel.
You took your damn sweet time.
I thought you two were married.
- Divorced.
- Three times.
You've been married and
divorced three times to each other?
What can I tell you? I'm
a glutton for punishment.
- All right, any pain in the stomach?
- Not really.
But I do have a pain in my ass,
and he's standing two feet away.
- Hey, Chuny, you got any Ancef?
- Yeah, try the cart, first drawer.
- Hey, how's Alex?
- Good. He's getting better every day.
- That's great to know.
- Yep, it is.
HemoCue, 12.9.
Okay, call X-ray,
see if they're free.
- Any of you married?
- No.
- Never.
- Not yet.
- Someday.
- What are you, a bunch of losers?
With all due respect, you've
been divorced three times.
- It's complicated.
- Ow!
All right, Mr. Feingold,
let me check you out.
- I am fine. MARQUEZ:
X-ray's ready to take her.
She's gonna be upstairs for
a while. Now's a good time.
Stop playing the martyr.
Go with the doctor.
You see that? She
still bosses me around.
Hollis. That's her middle name.
Holler. Holler, holler, holler.
- Call me with the lactate. Thanks.
- If it isn't Chicago's latest millionaire.
- Yes, yes. Hi, Frank.
- Babu, congratulations.
I think I'm having a heart attack.
- A heart attack?
Yeah, my heart is going:
boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
Any shortness of breath,
pain radiating down your arm?
- Tightness in your chest?
- No, no, no. Nothing like that.
When did it start?
Just now when the lottery
people handed me the check.
Phew. And it was
a very big check.
Dr. Grady, Daria needs help
suturing bike girl in Trauma 1.
I'll be right there.
I think you're excited and
your adrenalin's kicked in...
making your heart beat fast.
So...
I'll be okay?
It's a big day. Enjoy it.
Thank you, Dr. Grady.
Hey. Come by later,
donuts are free all day.
I'm taking my break
now. Bab, wait up.
Okay. You've got four
healthy-looking follicles here.
Only four.
- Only takes one.
- Ah, right you are.
Okay, I don't know if, um, Cate
has explained all of this to you...
but using ultrasound guidance...
I am going to aspirate the
fluid from each of those follicles.
And then our embryologists will
isolate the eggs for fertilization.
All right, let's
get this over with.
- She's gonna be out for this, right?
- That's up to you.
- Knock me out. I wanna be totally out.
- All right.
- Do you have any other questions?
- No.
You want some Valium
so you can relax a bit?
- No.
- I do.
- We'll get started shortly.
- Okay.
Labs on your bicycle
girl. Here's a shocker.
- No drugs or alcohol in her system.
- Are her parents on the way in?
They're over in Rogers Park.
So with traffic, that'll be a while.
You don't have lice. They can't
pole-vault over from Curtain 3.
- Need some help.
- What's up?
The driver who hit
Jody, I gave him Ancef.
He's having an allergic
reaction. Diffuse urticaria.
- Trouble breathing?
- A little.
BP 85/60.
Ever been allergic
to medicine before?
I want my phone.
What the hell's going on in there?
- You have to stay still.
Okay, 0.3 epi sub-Q, 50
diphenhydramine, 125 solumedrol.
And 5 of albuterol if
his lungs don't clear.
- I got it here.
- Be right back.
- You have to stay still.
- Guys, what's going on?
- We're trying to suture the forearm lac.
- Yeah, but she will not sit still.
Get off me! You said
I could have it later!
Grady, Curtain 2, go.
Stop. We don't have
time for this nonsense.
Get off of me! Let me go!
- Daria, two of Versed, soft restraints.
- It's mine. I want it now.
- Ow! God!
- Are you okay?
- God!
- Hi. Hi.
I'm sorry. I know. I'm okay.
Ow. Aah.
I love you.
- Now, this might sting a bit.
- Aah.
Thank you, Sam.
Girl totally freaked out.
- Happens.
- Over a cell phone?
- My fault. I should learn to duck, right?
- Wouldn't hurt.
- You think this is gonna leave a mark?
- No. Not at all.
- Thanks for doing this.
- Yeah, you already said that.
Yeah, but I know how
busy you nurses are.
You know, the last thing you
need is a doctor as a patient.
- You know what, Daria?
- What?
Can I ask you something?
It's kind of awkward.
Okay.
- Are you seeing somebody?
- No.
Huh.
Wow, I could have
sworn that you were.
You have that glow.
Anyway, there's this guy
who works in the hospital...
and I think the two of
you would really hit it off.
- It's so nice of you, but...
- He's really cool.
I'm gonna give him
your number. I am.
You know, as long as
you're free and everything.
- Can I think about it?
- Sure.
Sure, but don't wait too long.
Don't wanna change your mind.
We were only trying to help you.
I got scared.
I mean, I don't like being
here, and then I saw the driver.
And I guess I just freaked out.
I'm so sorry.
We're finished here. I'll
get the sling for your arm.
- Is the driver still here?
- We're keeping an eye on him.
- Is he gonna be okay?
- Should be.
The girl's boyfriend. I
couldn't get him to wait.
Oh, it's okay, Frank.
- Hey, baby, you okay?
- Mm-hm.
I didn't know where you were.
I was so worried when you
didn't answer my calls, my texts.
Her phone was getting quite a
workout. Guess that was you.
- Yeah, hi, Tommy Cole.
- Dr. Morris.
What were you doing on a bike?
I could give you a ride
anywhere, any time.
- I didn't wanna bother you.
- Baby, you could never do that.
- Is she gonna be okay?
- Could have been worse.
I'm thirsty. Can I get
something to drink?
Is it okay if I get her a pop?
Cafeteria's on the third floor.
Okay. I'll be right back.
Did you take off your bracelet?
Um...
- No, they...
- It probably came off when she got hit.
Oh, well, I'll get
you another one.
Or maybe I should
buy a dozen, huh?
My klutzy girl.
Seems like a nice guy.
Yeah. He's the
best. I'm really lucky.
- Any pain right on the bone?
- Not so bad.
How about here on the sides?
Bingo.
Valentine's Day, 1959.
Fifty years ago next month.
Barbara and I got
married for the first time.
She was a looker. I don't
know what she saw in me.
Unusual marrying and divorcing
the same woman over and over.
And over.
Well, it takes a
lot of passion...
to keep making up and
breaking up and making up.
I bet.
So, uh, what's with you
and this pretty nurse...
you were trying
to make nice with?
Sam. Yeah. We were together,
but, uh, it's been over a while now.
Seven weeks.
You sure?
You're still counting weeks.
I spent half a century
with Harry Feingold.
What's four weeks of
rib pain compared to that?
And you kept taking him back?
The heart wants
what the heart wants.
Even though your head
screams "don't do it."
You girls must know what I mean.
- Huh. Kind of.
- Stubborn, hot-headed...
and she has this way
of pushing all my buttons.
Yeah, I know the kind.
Though I must admit, I have
made my share of mistakes.
I caught him with his secretary.
Such a cliché.
I'd stopped by
his office one day.
And the way she
handed him his coffee...
At that moment, I
knew. I just knew.
The problem is, I
can't live without her.
But the problem with that
is, I can't live with her either.
So this is it, we are done.
Sometimes it's impossible for two
people who love each other to be together.
This is it. We're done for good.
I keep trying to get it right,
but I keep screwing it up.
You want my advice to
avoid 50 years of agita?
Walk away.
CT results on Morris' bike girl.
Alex, I heard you.
Four days at Sugarbush.
I'm not sure I want you
shushing down mountains...
after all you've been through.
I'll be home later. You
can argue with me then.
Bye.
Alex wants to go snowboarding?
Sorry, hard not to overhear.
- School trip. He's not gonna go.
- I was hoping we could talk.
I can't right now.
Maybe, uh... Maybe later.
Thank you so much for that
boomerang. Alex is gonna love it.
Thought he might. Hey,
uh, how's Mr. Feingold?
Muscle strain. He's back
in 2 bickering with his ex.
That is one strange pair.
- Malik, you're my last hope.
- No way, no how.
- Last hope for what?
- To shave hairy lice guy.
- He's still here?
- Come on, Dawn. You've seen worse.
The thought of touching
him makes my skin crawl.
- Grady, shave hairy lice guy.
- Yes!
- But he's not my patient.
- He is now.
This is so unfair.
- What's his problem?
- Lice.
Oh, lovely. Is my abdominal
series back on Decker?
You realize if you were still at
Jumbo Mart, you'd be a millionaire now.
- You worked at the Jumbo Mart?
- Uh, yeah, a few years ago.
Sorting things out. Wanted to
make sure medicine was right for me.
- Thank God she came back.
- Thanks, that's sweet.
You never made the right change.
If I won the lottery, this
is the last place I'd be.
Oh, you wouldn't stay here
for the work or the people?
No, I'd be off traveling
around the world.
First up, the seven wonders of
the modern and ancient world.
And then, it's off to a secluded island
where you stay in huts over the water.
Now, there is nothing like being
lulled to sleep by the sound of the sea.
Well, personally, I think the pyramids
are overrated, and I get seasick.
Well, what would
you do if you won?
Invest in a high-yield interest-bearing
account at an FDIC-insured bank.
Wow, that's... That's really
thinking out of the box.
Don't come crying to me for a loan
when you've blown through your millions.
- Jody's CT results.
- Thanks.
- Daria. Think about what I asked you?
- Not yet.
Well, I hope you don't hate me
for this, but I gave him your number.
- You did?
- I just have a feeling about you two.
Yep. He's gonna call.
You okay?
We're friends, so I'm
just gonna ask you.
- It's about Tony.
- Oh, yeah? What about him?
I have a feeling that
he's dating someone else.
- Have you heard anything?
- Nothing.
Oh, good. Could you imagine if it
was somebody here at the hospital?
That would be too cruel. Right?
Shut up and stop
touching me, Opie.
Hello, Dr. Morris.
How you doing?
Officer Diaz, look at
you. Back in uniform.
- We caught big fish in that drug case.
- Congratulations.
So it's back on the beat until I
start the detective's academy.
Oh, great.
Maybe you can help me.
I'm taking statements in
an auto-versus-bicycle case.
Yeah, on Halstead. I treated
the driver and the girl who got hit.
I've been talking to the driver
upstairs. I'd like to see the girl...
- Jody Nugent, if I could.
- Sure, she's in Trauma 1. Come on.
You have any drugs
or alcohol involved?
No. It sounds like he
was speeding, ran a light.
I don't think so. It doesn't
look like it was his fault.
- Really?
- Do you think I'm stupid?
- I didn't say...
- I know Matt Zullo lives there.
Hey, is there a problem here?
Oh, hi. No, we were
just, you know, talking.
- And you are?
- Uh, Tommy Cole, ma'am.
My boyfriend.
Well, all your scans
and tests were good.
You can go home as
soon as your parents arrive.
- Great.
- All right.
This is Officer Diaz.
- She wants to ask you a few questions.
- I don't remember much.
- That's okay. Tell me what you do.
- Yeah, just tell them what happened.
Actually, Tommy, it would be
best if you stepped out of the room.
But he's not leaving.
Dr. Morris is Jody's doctor
and I invited him to stay.
Okay, yeah. I'll
be right outside.
Well, it's like I said.
I was riding my bike and I
must have skidded on some ice.
- Sounds scary.
- Yeah.
The driver said it seemed like
you deliberately rode into traffic.
He's wrong.
Two eyewitnesses said you rode
your bike into the street then stopped.
And there was no way for
the driver to slow down in time.
- Is that true?
- No.
Maybe you were distracted?
Something on your mind?
Having any problems
at home or school?
Everything's good.
How about with Tommy?
Jody, what really happened today?
Were you trying to hurt yourself?
Hey, so you guys done or what?
Yeah, we're done.
So you think we
could handle triplets?
- It's a non-issue.
- Twins, okay. But triplets?
Even if all four
follicles produce eggs...
the chance of three of them becoming
high-grade embryos is next to zero.
One step at a time.
We've made it this far.
Yeah, well, this is the hard
part. We have to be realistic.
Who says I'm not?
Don't be disappointed
if it doesn't work out.
Of course I'll be
disappointed, but I'll be okay.
Cate, what we have now,
especially these last few months...
I already feel
pretty damn lucky.
- Sure, you do.
- No, I'm serious. You and me.
It's enough. You
know that, right?
- You don't think it's gonna work out?
- I didn't say that.
If you didn't want me to do IVF,
you should have said way before now.
- I can't win here.
- No. No, you can't.
I'm sorry.
Baby, I'm already rearranging
furniture in my mind...
thinking about where
to put a crib. But you?
You're the most
pragmatic person I know.
The fact that we're here, in the face
of all kind of discouraging evidence...
means that deep down, you
believe we have a chance too.
I don't know what made
me think this could work.
You don't have to understand it.
Just hold on to it.
- Triplets would kill us.
- You. Not me.
- Jody's not telling the whole story.
- Probably won't with her boyfriend.
Coffee? Can't vouch for
how long it's been sitting here.
Sure.
You know, maybe I should
go back in there and try again.
Or maybe when Jody's
parents get here, she'll say...
What? Bad idea?
If there was something I didn't
want my parents to know...
You exercised your
right to remain silent.
My father says me interrogating
suspects as a detective...
will be karmic payback.
You're getting really good at that.
Much better than the other interns.
Forget it. Hairy lice guy? Very
lame trying to butter me up.
- What? I wasn't doing that.
- It was pretty obvious.
- How am I gonna get out of this?
- Oh, I don't know, be resourceful.
Joey, let me help you with that.
- This is so frustrating.
- Can't do much if she won't talk.
Maybe Psych can
get it out of her.
I'm sorry, I have to roll. If
anything changes with Jody, call me.
- Or just call me.
- I will.
Excuse me, we're here for
our daughter, Jody Nugent.
- Dr. Morris, these are Jody's parents.
- Oh, hi. I treated Jody.
How is she?
She has a separated shoulder
and a minor concussion.
You should be able to take
her if our psychiatrist clears her.
Psychiatrist?
I have some concerns
about what happened.
- What kind of concerns?
- Our daughter's not nuts.
No, I didn't say that,
but her story doesn't fit...
- Her story? Now she's a liar?
- That's not what I'm saying.
Now, look. Our daughter got hit
by a car and we wanna see her now.
Of course.
Hey.
- You wanna talk?
- Yes.
I've been thinking. I
don't wanna give up on us.
Tony...
I don't wanna be one of those
couples who never get it right...
and never work
through the tough times.
We have something
worth saving...
and I'd be an idiot if I didn't
try to convince you of that.
Did you realize that before or
after you had sex with Daria?
It was one time, Sam.
And it didn't feel right.
It just... It made
me miss you more.
- Oh, flattering, really.
- It was a mistake.
Mm-mm.
The mistake is thinking we can
put the past behind us and start fresh.
- We can.
- No, we can't.
Because you're
never gonna change.
You broke up with me. You
couldn't move out fast enough.
- Lucky for you I did.
- I told you. It didn't mean anything...
- Tony... Sorry.
- Oh, God.
Don't be. We're done.
He's all yours.
- Cefazolin's in.
- Okay, chase it with 50 of fentanyl.
I'm gonna need some
saline for the cervical wash.
- Ready?
- Ready.
Starting the propofol infusion.
How long before
we know something?
By the time she's waking up...
we'll be able to say how many
eggs we have to work with.
If it's bad news, I wanna
hear it from you, okay?
It won't be bad news.
Pressure's down to 70/30.
Barb, doll, I'm here.
- What's wrong?
- I'm not sure. Spleen looks good.
- No tension pneumo.
- What happened?
Hypotensive, we're not sure why.
- Check the belly?
- We already did. BRENNER:
No cardiac tamponade.
- Think it's an MI?
- A heart attack?
It could be. Twelve-lead EKG.
- The O-neg's here.
- Should I hang it?
Start the dopamine. She's not bleeding.
- She is.
There's an echo-free
area posterior to the spleen.
A hematoma you missed. Hang
some blood, prep for intubation.
- Surgery's here. HARRY:
She needs surgery?
Broken rib may have
ruptured her spleen.
- A central line and then the O.R.
- Push etomidate and sux.
- That's a nice catch, Tony.
- Yeah, nice.
Give her some medicine
so she'll go to sleep...
while we put in
a breathing tube.
Don't leave me, you hear?
I'm sorry for
everything. I need you.
I love you.
I know. Me too, my love.
- Betadine and steri-drapes.
- Yankauer.
- So Jody's leaving.
- What?
You cleared her medically
and Psych gave the okay.
Why didn't you find me?
Her parents were anxious.
I didn't know what to do.
How about a nice hot bath?
- We might wanna keep Jody overnight.
- You said she was okay.
I was gonna have Ortho see her,
get her plugged into physical therapy.
- Is that necessary?
- It'll be more convenient.
- We'd really like her home with us.
- I understand.
You'll have to sign
discharge papers.
I'm sorry you had to
go through this all alone.
Well, I was here.
- When aren't you around?
- Yes, thank you for coming.
- Mr. Nugent?
- Yeah?
Can I have a moment?
I'm sorry, but I can't help but
think there's something going on.
Like what? She's a good girl.
She never gives us any trouble.
Would she confide in you or
your wife if she had a problem?
Yes.
I mean, well, she used to.
Ever since she's been going with
Tommy, she doesn't talk to us much.
It's important to stay
in your daughter's life.
My wife says if I complain, it'll
just push them together even more.
Tells me that I forget how
all-consuming first love can be.
- Honey, I need you over here.
- Yeah.
Excuse me.
Hey, so how about I
bring over some DVDs?
We can just hang out, chill.
Okay, I'll tell your folks.
- You take care of yourself, Jody.
- Uh-huh.
And this is my card. My cell
number's right there on the back.
If you have any problems,
day or night, call me. All right?
I was thinking, what you said.
The traffic was
going really fast.
- I saw the red light.
- The red light?
- I wanted to...
- Not tonight, son.
- I could just follow you home.
- I said no.
- She needs to rest.
- Jody, what were you gonna say?
Never mind.
So maybe tonight's
not the best movie night.
But, um, I'll see you
tomorrow. Okay? Love you.
Okay, let's get you out of here.
- Mr. Nugent...
- We've got it from here.
- Sats down to 72.
- Elevated neck veins.
Open up a chest-tube tray.
A positive pressure can
exacerbate a pneumo.
What are you doing to her?
Broken rib may have
collapsed her lung.
- End-tidal CO2 is good.
- Two units in the central line.
- I need a...
- Thirty-two French and a vascular clamp.
- Run of V-tach. Get the crash cart.
- Wait.
- 0-silk. Thora-Seal.
- All right. Pulse ox up to the 90s.
- Strong carotid pulse.
- That's good.
- Yes, it is.
- Thank you.
Frank, you paged me?
Morris wants you to
take ankle sprain in 3.
Your buddy's waiting
for you in Curtain 1.
Really? Who?
Hello, my friend.
Babu, are you having
more heart palpitations?
Oh, no. It is my hand.
I think it's broken.
What happened?
People have been
shaking my hand all day.
- They're happy for you.
- But they squeeze so hard.
Your hand's not broken.
- It is not?
- No. And you know what I think?
I think you're nervous about
winning all that money...
and your anxiety is
presenting as physical pain.
I am overwhelmed.
My life is good.
I have the store, my
family, my book club.
Now everything has to change.
I hate change.
Take your time. You don't
have to decide anything today.
You're right. I'll sleep on it.
She denied suicidal ideation.
She's got no history of depression.
No vegetative symptoms. No
anorexia, no anhedonia, insomnia.
- The stress with her boyfriend?
- They're working it out.
She seems to have
good family support.
- I talked to her before she left.
- Did she say something?
- Not exactly.
No, well, she started
to. This is a hunch, okay?
I gave her numbers for outpatient
counseling if she needs it.
No, we have to intervene.
- Send the police to her house?
- No, but something.
- Like what?
- I don't know.
She was trying to tell me
something. Another five minutes...
Look, I know you're
frustrated. Our hands are tied.
What's the matter? Headshrinker
can't help you with your "thrisis"?
It's not that.
You know what, Frank?
I'm going out for a while.
- For how long?
- I'm not sure. Let Brenner know.
- Finally.
- Yeah, you said it.
What a gross job.
- Poor Grady.
- Better him than me.
- What about Grady?
- He's giving hairy lice guy a shave.
Well, no, he's not. I just saw
him with an ankle sprain in 3.
Then who's in there?
- Joey?
- How'd you get roped into this?
Grady gave me a hundred bucks.
Oh, man. Tsk.
Hey, sir, you'll
have to turn back.
I'm a doctor. Maybe I can help.
Please, you don't understand.
You're making a mistake. I
need to be with my daughter.
Reidy, what the hell happened?
Repetitive blunt trauma to
the head, neck and chest.
- Is he gonna make it?
- He's pulseless and apniec.
He's had one round
of epi and atropine.
Jody?
Archie, what are you doing here?
I couldn't just let it go.
I was gonna call you.
There was no time.
- Did Jody do that?
- Nope. Her father.
Tommy showed up at the
house. I guess things escalated.
The dad heard a commotion
outside and saw Tommy attack her.
It's gonna be okay.
He said he'd love me forever.
- How could he do that to me?
- I think he did it to Daria.
Ugh. I know.
- You know what? I'm being stupid.
- No, no, no. Don't say that. Come on.
I mean, hello, I broke up with him.
I don't have a right to feel like this.
- Didn't I mean anything to him?
- Of course you did.
You have every right to
feel whatever you wanna feel.
Daria? Really?
I mean, okay, she's cute and
she's smart and whatever...
but, God, really?
Say the word, me and the
nurses will take her out back...
and rough her up.
I already kind of did.
I had a guy cheat on me.
- What'd you do?
- Cried a lot, hated the other woman.
Until I realized that I should
be mad at my boyfriend, not her.
And when I really thought
about it, he did me a favor.
We weren't right for each other.
I never realized
that you were so Zen.
- They ended up getting married.
- Okay, you're not helping.
I'm sorry. Oh,
you still love him.
What are you gonna do?
I plan on being irrationally hurt
and angry for as long as I like.
Sounds good.
Can we go inside
now? I can't feel my toes.
Ow.
I think I slipped a disk.
- Babu, we talked about this.
- Ah, just kidding.
I came to tell
you I figured it out.
- You did?
- I bought a yacht.
I fly to Greece
tomorrow to pick it up.
- Are you serious?
- Yes, but don't worry.
I'm investing the rest in
a high-yield mutual fund.
And this is for you.
Wow.
Thanks.
- I'm really going to miss you.
- Likewise, my friend.
Hello?
How many?
Hey.
- Hey.
- I'm sorry.
What are you sorry about?
You were hoping there
wasn't gonna be drama.
It was bound to happen.
You wanna get a
drink and talk about it?
Or maybe we could, you
know, get some dinner at Ike's.
Thanks, it's been a long day. I'm
gonna get home. Sarah's waiting.
I can just call you later.
I don't think that
would be good.
Look, I had a great
time. It was fun.
But...?
- It's not gonna happen.
- Okay.
Maybe if it was another
time, but it's not over with Sam.
- Not for me, anyway.
- Mm.
I'd be lying if I didn't
say I was disappointed.
But I get it.
- I hope it works out.
- Yeah, thanks.
- Me too.
- Mm-hm.
Chuny, the ABG on the firefighter
in 2 came back negative...
for carbon monoxide.
- You can send him home.
- You got it. You out of here?
Oh, yes, I am. Thanks,
you two, for your help today.
Yeah, have a good one.
Night, Neela. - Neela.
Neela, hold up.
The drama never
ends around here.
Neela.
- Neela. What was that?
- What was what?
That. Back there, at the desk.
You were deliberately avoiding me.
Nonsense. I didn't even see you.
You didn't just look right at me
then take off like a bat out of hell?
Well, it's been a long
day and I'm bleary-eyed.
And by the way, Mrs. Feingold's
surgery went really well.
- That's good.
- Well, her and her ex were so grateful...
he proposed to her
again, and she said yes.
And I mean, what does a bride
wear on her fourth wedding?
- Red or black?
- I don't know. Are you okay?
Do they register gifts? I mean,
that... Yeah, that would be gauche.
Okay, okay.
Neela, you've been acting
really weird around me all day.
Have I done something wrong?
Yes.
No. You...
Which one is it?
Neela, if you're
angry with me...
You know, why do you
have to be so damn...?
What?
Charming, sexy? Good at math?
Okay, yes, I did think about you the
whole time you were away. Happy?
Yes.
But why are you so mad?
Because I like you.
I don't want to, but I do.
And I wanna be with
you. There, I said it.
- You can go ahead and gloat now.
- Gloat? Why would I gloat?
Because you predicted it. So
go ahead. I know you want to.
I'd rather do something else.