Previously on ER.
‐ Good morning.
You were involved in a very
serious automobile accident
10 days ago.
Do you understand?
And I think it would be great
if she were to marry me.
‐ Oh, God!
‐ What?
I don't have to defend
my wasted life in medicine.
‐ Do you have a son?
‐ Yeah.
When the SPG attendings start
backing you up next week
we'll make your job
a lot easier.
You are preaching
to the choir, okay?
Less work is fine with me.
If you're reinstated,
you'll let the matter drop?
Yes.
I'll be back by six.
Have you seen my gloves?
I got an idea.
Why don't we set a date?
Doug, I gotta be
at the clinic at nine.
‐ You wanna quit joking with me.
‐ I'm not joking.
I'm halfway out the door
and you wanna talk
about setting a date now?
You're right. We got all the
time in the world to do..
Oh! Oh, what are these?
What is up with you?
What is that? Doug?
See, I just wanted to get
a, get a quick size. Here.
I'll get you a rock that'll
knock your eye out.
‐ Doug, I don't need a ring.
‐ Sure you do, to make it real.
A ring doesn't make it real.
It's real because
we say it's real.
Now, what.. You do wanna
marry me, don't you?
Of course I wanna marry you.
but I've already done
the whole ring
and the setting the date,
blah‐blah‐blah‐blah‐blah..
That's not what I want.
I am so happy right now.
This is so perfect
right now.
Why can't we just
be two people
who are going
to get married?
‐ Cheap date.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
'Talk about prepared
for anything.'
I've been wanting
to use these on you.
Hey!
You haven't already?
‐ I got this, Kerry. Go inside.
‐ No. I'm fine.
Boy, I hope this isn't
an omen for the rest of my day.
Look, when Anspaugh sees
those first‐month's figures
he is going to want
to bear your children.
It's not the first‐month figures
I'm worried about.
Seriously, go inside.
It's freezing.
Synergix taking over
the ER makes good sense.
If you don't think you can
convince Don Anspaugh of that
I'm telling you I can.
Or we could just disappear,
go back to St. Barth's
let 'em all freeze to death.
Go in the car.
Think hot thoughts.
Mmm. Okay.
Yeah?
That is the filthiest thing
I have ever heard.
With the possible exception
of this..
Mmm...Kerry Weaver, you are
a bad, bad girl.
Lizzie, is this your Mustang?
Yes. I'm leasing it.
There's nothing like a good,
American‐made muscle car
is there?
If I'd known this was your car,
I'd have sniffed the tailpipe.
Excuse me?
Oh, I thought we were
talking about sex.
Uh, is Allison Beaumont
ready to go back into the OR?
You thought we were
talking about sex?
Lizzie, the Beaumont girl,
does she know
what's happening
this afternoon?
I'll get her consent
for the revision surgery.
Allison's ready
for whatever we throw at her.
Good attitude.
Yes, but she's been rather down
about her vocal cord paralysis.
Well, remind me and I'll talk
to her about collagen injection.
Actually, I've told her about
medialization therapy.
She'd like us
to explore that option.
My head‐and‐neck consult
doesn't do that procedure.
I know, but David Kotlowitz
is right across town
at Northwestern.
Insurance won't cover it.
Collagen injection is standard.
Couldn't something
be worked out?
Selastic medialization
is permanent.
Lizzie, I'll explain
it to Allison.
You stay focused on
the fibular transfer.
Damn it!
Somebody do something
about this crazy‐ass cracker!
Give us all a break,
Carlene, please.
Hey, I'm in pain,
for your information.
You know what, you need to put
a sign on this damn thing.
It just took my money.
If I give your money back will
you sit down and be quiet?
I'm thirsty.
There's a water fountain's
down the hall.
Forget it. You know, I do want
my 75 cents back, though.
Hey, I put some
money in there, too.
Nice try, Carlene.
Look, I've been sitting here
for 45 minutes!
Ain't no nurse ask me
even come over here
and ask me what's wrong!
‐ Got any more gum?
‐ Aw, nicotine gum.
You quitting smoking?
Yeah. I never
should have started.
Yeah. You shouldn't have.
Dr. Swift.
Mark Greene,
how are you doing?
You're the SPG Attending?
Yeah. I'm here
to lighten your load.
Hey, I saw you
in that documentary.
‐ Ah‐huh.
‐ You got a lot of face time.
Don't take this wrong, Mark
but you looked
a little haggard.
Are you letting this job
get to you?
'Help me!'
Help me!
‐ Oh, look at that idiot.
‐ Oh, boy.
‐ Dr. Greene, help me!
‐ We need some help in here!
I'm alright.
I'm not hurt.
‐ I'm tired of your mouth.
‐ Hey, take it easy.
Just take it easy, alright?
'So looking ahead
to your third year'
'you stand at the crossroads.'
'You have an opportunity to make
a selection in clerkships'
'that will be both challenging
and inspiring to you.'
I hope I've done justice
in presenting what I think
is rewarding
about emergency medicine.
Now, with the, uh..
...the time we have left,
anybody have any questions?
And please don't, don't
ask about the heat.
I have no idea why
this room is freezing.
Do people really
come into the ER
with foreign objects
stuck in their rectums?
I don't think that's the kind of
information people are here for.
‐ I wouldn't mind hearing.
‐ Come on.
Okay. Yeah, yeah. Sometimes.
Sometimes it happens.
What's the weirdest thing you
ever took
out of somebody's rectum?
Um..
Bowling trophy.
Now, let's, let's move on to
something more substantive.
‐ Yeah?
‐ Did you ever kill anybody?
Okay. That's substantive.
Ah! The answer is yes.
Um..
An elderly man.
I‐I‐I was a surgical intern.
And uh, while tapping
his chest I accidentally
lacerated his liver
and he died in surgery.
You left Surgery
for Emergency Medicine?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
‐ 'How come?'
Well, in the emergency
department..
...you're seeing a lot of
different people.
You're doing a lot
of different things.
You're making a difference,
you know, right on the spot.
But can you make a career
out of that?
Do you see yourself
still in ER..
...10, 15 years from now?
Fifteen years? Fifteen years.
Uh..
Yeah. Hey, sure. Why not?
Next question.
If we can have
this kind of impact
in a limited role,
I'd like to suggest
the idea of overall
contract management.
You can take off
your tap shoes, Dr. West.
From the time we met I assumed
your long‐range goal
was to take over the ER.
'I'm surprised
only by your timing.'
Can I have a moment with Kerry?
Certainly. Let me just say
that it's part of my nature
to move quickly
when something feels right.
I gotta say, Don, I've been just
blown away by these numbers.
What are they saying
about SPG in the trenches?
I haven't heard
any complaints.
Mark Greene would support
their taking over?
It would change the way
you do business down there.
We haven't discussed it.
Well, the feelings
of the rest of the staff
are something
I would need to find out
before raising it
with the board.
Yeah, I thought it was
a Ponzi scheme
when I first
heard about them.
But I've been with SPG now
a year and a half
and I'm having
the time of my life.
Twelve shifts a month,
18 days off.
‐ No kidding?
‐ Beats my schedule.
Let's see the other leg.
Yeah. Regular working hours.
And when 6 PM comes..
...and that door
hits me in the butt
I live a real life.
‐ Your knees are fine.
‐ Okay, what about my ankle?
‐ Want a portable?
‐ Yeah, call Radiology.
No. Hold on a second.
Do me a favor.
Walk for me.
Take a few steps.
SPG uses practice guidelines.
And here I've been skating by
on medical judgment.
You know how much money
is wasted on X‐rays?
Mark, If you're going
to quit smoking
you have
to detoxify your body.
Colon irrigations.
Hello, Allison.
Your laptop coming in useful?
'Looking for love
on the Internet.'
Now, there's a form of new
technology where I'm way behind.
And there are plenty of folk in
England I could be e‐mailing.
For me correspondence will
always mean..
...lovely stationery
and writing on it by hand.
'I'm a blabbermouth.
Two‐hour phone calls.'
Let me explain what we're
going to be doing to you today.
I have a consent form
for you to sign.
Yes, we're going to take you
back to the OR
to revise
your fibular transfer.
Why?
Ah‐ah. Type it out, Allison.
'Vocal‐cord surgery?'
Yes. Dr. Romano
would like to talk to you
about various options.
But right now our main concern
is with your leg.
I'll come back again
this afternoon, okay?
'I want my voice back,
Dr. Corday.'
I would have no kind of outside
life for the next six years.
Well, surgery demands
that type of commitment.
But not everybody's willing
to make that sacrifice.
‐ Got some hard thinking to do.
‐ Yeah.
You were on the PBS documentary.
Yes. I am. I was.
I'm Dr. Carter.
Laura Brown. You know, that
show's really got me thinking
about Emergency Medicine.
Yeah, you should come
to one of my sessions.
Actually, it's next on my list.
Dr. Benton, great presentation.
‐ Thanks. Take care.
‐ Thanks.
She's gonna be something.
So, we both got stuck
with it, huh?
Yeah, Romano Shanghaied me.
This thing's
a total waste of time.
You can't tell these kids what
it's gonna be like.
They won't know about it
until they're in it
And then by that time most of
them have made the wrong choice.
Yeah, I got a bunch of stiffs
in my session this morning.
All they want to know about
is if you killed anybody.
‐ What do you tell them?
‐ Just med students.
Mark, can I sound you out
about something?
Sure. We're a little
swamped down here.
‐ Can you see some patients?
‐ Absolutely.
You should know the board may
consider granting SPG
an overall
management contract.
‐ That's happening pretty fast.
‐ You think so?
Yeah, well, attending coverage
is one thing
but should we be hoppin'
into bed with them?
Well, it might
make life easier.
Shorter hours..
I want to maintain
decision‐making authority
when it comes to patient care.
No, you won't have
to give that up.
This is about Synergix taking
over administrative functions
like billing, collections‐‐
What's Anspaugh's take on it?
He's for it.
Well, it's something
to think about.
'Christmas cookies!'
Freshly baked.
Enough for everybody.
‐ Yeah? No, thanks.
‐ Homemade?
I'm not ready for the holiday
to be over.
Oh, I know what you mean,
it's the best part of winter
and now it's finished.
Not if you don't
want it to be.
Isn't he nice?
He is so nice.
These are so good!
Hello! I need
some medical attention.
Now, how long
am I supposed to wait?
I told you, Carlene,
it's a busy day.
Be patient, alright?
You don't look too busy,
Miss Chiquita Banana
over here
eating them cookies.
Listen, nobody minds
if you're in here
where it's warm, but
why can't you just be quiet!
I don't even understand
what you say.
Why don't you talk slow
and in English?
Yeah?
Can you believe me walking outta
here after that fell on me?
Look, I'm sorry
I gave you a hard time
over a lousy 75 cents.
I got over it.
My name's John.
Think I can give you
a call sometime?
I got to tell you something
up front, though
because I believe in that.
And, if it makes
a difference
then so be it.
I spent time in prison.
It's one mistake.
Had nothing to do
with violence.
But I got
a good job now
moving furniture and, um..
...I think maybe you and me
could have some fun together.
‐ Prison, huh?
‐ Yeah.
‐ I'm Randi.
‐ Randi.
Your fasting blood glucose
is 110. That's excellent.
‐ You watching your diet?
‐ And exercising, too.
I wish everybody was
that good about
controlling their diabetes,
Mr. Roussakoff.
Whoa!
Oh, that's just Mikey.
Don't be scared of him.
He likes it in there.
It's warm.
Okay. Bye‐bye,
Mr. Roussakoff.
Ma, what are you
doing here?
Doug Ross came to
see me this morning.
What?
To ask for your hand
in marriage.
What?
He said he wanted
my permission.
He was very polite.
Tell me
this is a joke.
It's not a joke, ma.
How long have you
been seeing him?
Eight months.
Oh, were you planning
on telling me?
When the time
was right.
Oh. So you intend
to marry him.
‐ At some point, yes.
‐ "At some point."
See? Even you know
this will never happen.
Look, ma, we'll talk
about this later, okay?
I got to get back
to the clinic.
I was there
to take care of you
the last time
he broke your heart.
He's not going
to break my heart.
Men like him
don't change.
Ma, what did
you say to him?
I told him nothing.
I came to see you.
You know where
Mark Greene is?
Yeah, he's right here. I've been
talking to him about SPG.
This concerns another matter.
Excuse me, Kerry.
Not a good idea to put the space
heater in the bed with you.
Dr. Greene,
may I have a moment?
Uh, yeah, sure.
Excuse me.
What's up?
Mark,
I haven't wanted it
too widely known
around the hospital
but, uh...my son Scott was
treated for B‐cell lymphoma
ten months ago.
‐ Oh, no. I'm sorry.
‐ Oh, he's fine.
The, uh...chemo
was successful.
But I just received
a phone call from his school
and apparently he's
complaining of abdominal pain
and I instructed them
to send him here by taxicab.
Yeah, it's better
to be safe.
'He didn't get along with his
previous doctor and, uh..'
I'd like you to look after his
care personally when he arrives.
'I'm sorry to hear
he's been sick.'
‐ How old is Scott?
‐ He's almost 13.
He's handled it
all quite well.
I'll stay out
of your way.
Oh, don't worry about that.
'Page me when he arrives.'
Mark.
Can you..
Was Anspaugh talking
to you about SPG?
‐ No. His son is coming in.
‐ Really?
Yeah. I knew his wife died but I
didn't know he had any kids.
Yeah, he has a daughter,
as well.
I can clear curtain three.
Do they need a trauma room?
I think he just
wants me to see him.
Right.
Of course.
‐ Let me know if I can help.
‐ Sure.
Hey, Jeanie,
can you hang with me?
Yeah. What's up?
Dr. Anspaugh's son is coming in
with abdominal pain.
I doubt Anspaugh would want me
anywhere near his son.
Listen, the boy
was treated last year
for B‐cell lymphoma so he's
probably not too happy
to come to the hospital.
Here he is.
Just another
friendly face.
Hey, Scott.
Hi. I'm Dr. Greene.
How are you feeling?
I just have
an upset stomach.
Yeah? Listen,
why don't you come in
let us check you out. This is
my friend Jeanie Boulet.
‐ Hey, Scott.
‐ There's nothing wrong with me.
Right. Well, we just want
to be absolutely sure, okay?
So, listen,
it's no big deal.
Tell my dad
it's not a big deal
'cause the whole school
was looking at me
when I got in
this damn cab.
Listen, Scott, we're freezing
our butts off out here
so, uh, why don't
you just come in
and just talk
to your dad, okay?
I can walk. I don't need
that wheelchair.
Alright.
Doug, pick up.
Doug, it's me. Hello?
Okay, listen, I don't know
where the hell you are
but when you get this
you call me right away,
alright?
You can run,
but you cannot hide.
We just go into this last room
on the left.
‐ You doing okay?
‐ I just have a stomachache.
Alright.
'Scott?'
Scott, I'm here, son.
Where's the wheelchair?
He wanted to walk,
which is fine.
Dr. Greene's one
of our best doctors.
He's going to take
good care of you.
Why can't I have
a stomachache sometimes?
You been vomiting?
Just once. Crappy seafood
restaurant
you took me to
last night, dad.
'That's why I'm sick.'
Gone to the bathroom today?
My bowel's not obstructed.
Been able to pass gas?
Yes, I said.
Alright.
Let me feel your belly.
‐ Ow.
‐ Oh, a little tender there?
Okay. Let's get a CBC
chem 20, an abdominal series.
No, damn it! No needles!
You people better not even try
to stick me with another needle.
‐ Hear me?
‐ Alright!
Alright.
No needles.
Not right now.
Excuse me. I'm trying
to locate Dr. Kotlowitz.
I'm Dr. Corday
from County General.
‐ Dr. Corday, hi.
‐ Yes.
I just wrote you a note.
I'm sorry you came all this way.
I've been called away
on a consult.
‐ David Kotlowitz, hi.
‐ Elizabeth Corday.
If I could just
have one minute
I can do quite a bit
of persuading.
I'll give you two. Why don't
you walk with me?
Oh, that's terrific.
As I said on the phone my heart
goes out to Miss Beaumont.
It was a devastating
accident.
Yes. Allison's
quite lucky to be alive
but she has
an extraordinary spirit
which is why I ask you simply
to see her, examine her..
And agree to do a medialization
thyroplasty for free.
Well, her insurance
won't cover it apparently
so, uh...yes, I suppose
that is what I'm asking.
And...why would I do that?
Believe me,
if you meet Allison
you will want to do
the procedure.
Well, I'm headed to your
part of town right now.
You know that I don't have
privileges at County General.
Yes, but any
bureaucratic matters
I'm sure that Dr. Romano
can help straighten out.
And you're speaking on
Robert Romano's behalf?
No. I'm speaking
on Allison Beaumont's behalf.
Well, it's not frostbite
but we should put it
in some warm water.
What is that?
Sounds like
a Tamagotchi.
A what?
Ah, some kid must
have dropped it.
Oh, man, a white one!
‐ I collect them.
‐ What is it?
It's like a pretend pet.
You have to
take care of it.
‐ What?
‐ It's probably hungry.
Whoever left it behind
must not care too much.
Can I have it?
No. I got to take it
to lost and found.
By the time the kid gets back,
it'll be dead.
What do you
mean, "dead"?
I'll give you 20 bucks
for it.
No! Wait, wait.
Can you tell
what's wrong with it?
No. I just saw
a report on TV. I don't know.
Thirty bucks.
Look, if someone
comes by looking
just say you
never saw it.
Forty bucks.
‐ Hey, Scott.
‐ What?
Look, I can understand
you not wanting
to be stuck anymore
but I made a bet
with your dad.
I bet him ten bucks I could
stick you with a needle
you'd never feel it.
So?
So, I'll cut you
in on the deal.
You tell me
what you want
to let me draw
some blood and you got it.
Stop talking to me
like I'm a kid.
I've had so much chemo
that my veins
have been sclerosed.
So, you just get
the hell out of here.
Hey, we got to find out
what's causing
your stomachaches.
Now, if you don't let me
draw some blood the easy way
they'll get every nurse in here
to hold you down
while you yell and scream and
they'll draw it the hard way.
Sit down,
turn your head.
I promise you
won't feel it.
How about I stick you?
The smell..
...it makes me sick.
It's in.
How'd you do that?
'Cause I'm the best.
Now you know.
‐ 'Hey, Cynthia.'
‐ Yeah.
‐ You know about these things?
‐ Oh, yeah. It's a virtual pet.
Mark got one for his daughter
for Christmas.
Wait. Someone left
it in exam one.
Did anyone call
about it or anything?
Mm‐mm.
It won't stop.
I think it pooped.
‐ What?
‐ Yeah. You see that pile there?
You're supposed to clean
it up or it'll get sick.
‐ How? How clean it up?
‐ I don't know.
Do you want me
to call Mark?
No. I can figure it out.
Wait..
You know what? I liked
the toys when we were kids.
My barbie van
was awesome.
Oh, my God, look!
It stopped.
‐ Good.
‐ He's so happy.
Yeah. Well,
if somebody calls
I'll tell him
it's in lost and found.
Actually, why don't I just take
care of it for a while?
'Anne Reilly?'
This is
Mrs. Reilly.
I'm her Meals on Wheels person
or one of them, at least.
‐ What's your name?
‐ Susan McFarlan.
Some days,
she's pretty confused
but, this mornin', she was
definitely more out of it
and she usually
has her hair combed.
Has she complained
of anything specific?
No, but I took
a peek inside.
I don't think
she's been eating.
There were plates
of food left untouched.
At least a couple
of day's worth.
Do you think she's had
a stroke or somethin'?
Well, we'll check
her out.
'Hi.'
‐ 'I'm Carol Hathaway.'
‐ Hello.
What's your name?
Anne Reilly.
You look
so pretty today.
Well, thank you.
How are you feeling
today, Mrs. Reilly?
Fine.
Do you know
what month it is?
Well, it's August.
Okay, we're gonna have
to wait a lil' while
before we can get
her into a room.
‐ Can you stick around?
‐ Sure.
Mrs. Reilly,
we're gonna talk again soon
in a few minutes, okay?
You look just the same.
Oh, just like when
you were a baby.
Okay.
Maybe ten more of those
would make a difference.
Alright, I had a hard enough
time getting the janitor
to part with this one.
I'm one of those people
that's always early.
What other presentations did
you hear besides Dr. Benton's?
None, I mean,
what, dermatology?
Can't exactly see myself
sitting in an office all day
popping pimples.
No, for me,
it's either surgery
or emergency medicine
or possibly
internal medicine
because that's where
the sickest people are
but, I doubt, it's for me.
Think you can sell me on the ER?
I don't know, I haven't
been selling too well so far.
It's never boring,
it's that I mean
there's always
something happening.
No, no,
sometimes it's slow
but, uh, you're usually
thankful for the break.
I can't wait.
Hey, Mark. Judy said she was
going to wait up in radiology
with Dr. Anspaugh's son
if that's okay.
Yeah, she should
stay with him.
‐ Did you lose something?
‐ Uh, I thought
I'd brought
an extra pack of gum.
Hmm‐hmm, you're going
through 'em pretty quickly.
I brought you an extra pack,
in here, somewhere..
...in the Bermuda Triangle.
You‐you know, it's not
like I need this stuff
you know, nicotine,
it's just, uh..
Hey, do you think Dr. Anspaugh's
son's going to be okay?
The nurses said
that he already had cancer once.
You have to worry
about recurrence.
God, I never saw him
as much as a family man.
'I mean, his wife
was only 42.'
‐ What're you doing?
‐ Uh, there's just a few.
Uh, few pills missing.
‐ I, uh...
‐ Yeah?
Well, I mean, uh, shouldn't
there be some more? It's been‐‐
Mark, my pills are in your
bathroom, in your bag.
I mean, this is an old pack.
‐ Oh, okay, okay.
‐ Wow!
‐ What are you thinking?
‐ Well, I‐I don't know.
You‐I mean, you know,
just, uh...
Mark, I don't want
to get pregnant.
No, I‐I know, you know,
we want to be careful.
‐ Yeah, oh, bingo.
‐ Hmm‐hmm.
Ah, you are great, thanks.
You're so grown‐up now.
She's tachy at 108.
BP's low, 90/70.
‐ And there's skin tenting.
‐ Tenting?
She's dehydrated, when I pinch
her skin, it stays pinched.
Yosh, let's get her
into a gown, start an IV
and send off
for a CBC, Chem 20.
‐ Want to count the urine?
‐ Yeah and get a chest film.
Mrs. Reilly, we're going to
change you into a gown, okay?
So we can do
some more tests.
Do you know if she has
any family members?
She's mentioned
a daughter
but I don't know
where she lives.
Carol, Doug Ross on two.
I'll get this.
Okay.
Doug?
Guess who stopped by?
My mom.
'Yeah.'
What are you on, drugs?
No, I just would have liked
to have told her myself.
How do you think
she's reacting?
Doug, I‐I gotta go.
I'll call you back.
Yosh, I'll take it
from here, could you, uh
escort Susan to chairs
and please find
Mark Greene for me?
Okay.
Um, if it's okay, can you
stay a little while longer?
Yeah, that's fine. I don't have
any classes today anyway.
Great.
Mrs. Reilly?
Did someone hurt you?
‐ Detective Weller.
‐ Dr. Greene.
‐ This is Carol Hathaway.
‐ Hi.
I'm still waiting
for detective Muncie
but I‐I'd like to go ahead
and talk to the victim.
‐ What's her name?
‐ Anne Reilly.
‐ Uh, let's talk in here.
‐ Her mental status is altered.
She's not responding
to questions right now.
‐ Could that be from the trauma?
‐ Conceivably.
Or she could
have Alzheimer's.
She's also dehydrated,
which could be the cause.
We need to fluid
resuscitate her first.
And also still
do a rape kit.
Were her hands bound?
Well, there is some signs
of bruising
but no signs of duct tape
like the other one.
She also had
a lower left rib fracture
and multiple contusions
one to the back
of her head.
You're assuming this
is the same rapist, right?
I don't want two of 'em
out there like this.
So, you're making
some announcements
puttin' the public
on notice?
It's a departmental
decision.
You guys gotta
stop this...person.
That's what
we intend to do.
I'll start with
the Meals on Wheels girl.
She's very, very fond
of Mrs. Reilly
so she doesn't know
about the rape yet.
Alright, thanks.
I'll show you.
Carol, um, Yosh told me
to tell you
that he moved Mrs. Reilly
into curtain three
so he could see
clinic patients.
He can't handle
them all by himself.
Oh, Dr. Ross came in.
He's helping him.
I, um, I think he thinks
you're mad at him.
Is this
the abdominal series?
This is
Scott Anspaugh.
‐ Any relation?
‐ I'm his son.
Okay, we're going to take
some pictures of your belly.
KUB or upright first?
We'll start
with the KUB.
‐ Tumor's back.
‐ What'd you say?
I don't need X‐rays
to know it's back.
Don't move.
Hey, listen, if it's bad news
you can worry about it then.
Why don't you think
about somethin' else right now?
Like what?
Rainbows and dandelions?
What's some of the stuff
you like?
‐ What's your favorite thing?
‐ John Woo movies.
Oh yeah, his Hollywood movies
or the Hong Kong stuff?
What do you know
about John Woo?
How much time do you have?
Hey, you're still around?
I sat in on
a PEDS introduction
just for the heck of it.
Peds, a very rewarding field.
Actually, I wanted to talk
to you before you left.
‐ Uh, about a favor.
‐ Sure.
Sometime, when you're on duty
could I come by
the ER and hang out?
My words weren't enough
to determine your career path?
You're good,
you're not that good.
I actually have
a shift tonight.
Oh, that would be great.
And if you'd like,
I was, uh..
I have a feeling, we could
get some dinner first.
Yeah, I'd like
but on one condition,
I buy.
The ER is your treat
dinner will be mine.
Do you like Thai food?
Yes, I do.
Hey, how'd it go
with those second‐years?
‐ Well, I didn't sugarcoat it.
‐ I didn't expect you to.
We want to weed out
the losers early.
Thanks for taking
care of it, Pete.
‐ Dr. Romano.
‐ Hmm.
It's Peter.
You called me Pete.
Well, nobody in your whole life
has ever called you Pete?
‐ No.
‐ Pete Benton.
It sounds so natural.
You've gotta be kiddin' me.
Peter, just Peter.
Huh, Wow!
Petey?
Peter.
Ah.
Hey, Kotlowitz!
Ah, Dr. Romano,
Perfect timing.
Robert Romano!
What are you doing here?
You know each other?
You've got quite
a protege here.
She's convinced me
to waive my fee and perform
a silastic medialization
on this young woman.
Well, there are still a few
matters to be ironed out.
You want to operate
on my patient?
Oh, she's ideal
for the procedure, yeah, yeah
un‐un‐unless, of course
there's a problem with that.
Great, it'll be
a chance for us
to put our heads together.
Well, I've got
to get back across town.
‐ So you'll be in touch with me.
‐ Oh, let me walk you out.
Dr. Corday, uh, if‐if
you have a moment, uh.
‐ Come stay with me, yeah.
‐ 'Alright, good to see ya.'
‐ Take care.
‐ Bye.
'Bye.'
What's the matter?
Shut the door.
Was I not clear this morning?
What did I say
about that procedure?
Well, if the doctor's fee
is the barrier, I thought‐‐
That is not the only barrier.
Kotlowitz can't operate here,
he doesn't have privileges
and we are sure as hell
not going
to move that girl
to Northwestern
for vocal cord surgery with her
leg as fragile as it is.
Dr. Anspaugh's willing to grant
him temporary privileges.
It so happens, he's a great fan
of Dr. Kotlowitz.
Oh, so, now, you are planning
my patient's
course of treatment
with the chief of staff?
We ran into him
in the hallway.
This is great news
for Allison.
Allison is my patient
I will decide
what is in her best interest.
This surgery is
in her best interest.
It is an unnecessary trip
to the OR!
No, it's not. Now, I don't know
what's going on between you
and Dr. Kotlowitz and quite
frankly, I couldn't give a...
Allison wants her voice back
and it's incumbent upon us
to find the best way
of bringing that about.
Are you questioning
my commitment
to this patient's
best interests?
‐ No.
‐ Good.
'Cause that is not something
you want to be doing.
Lizzie.
Okay, now, this time,
just make sure
that he takes
all of the antibiotics
all of the medicine
till it's gone.
Okay, all the medicine,
until it's gone.
Even if he's feeling better.
Okay, Hi,
I'm Dr. Ross.
I'm Sherry.
Alright, Sherry, now..
...I see you've been
to the clinic before.
You're still going
to the, uh, prenatal clinic?
Yes, I going
to have a baby.
Okay, what can
I do for you?
They cut my food stamps.
It was $65.
Now, it's 49.
‐ Forty nine is 16 less than 65.
‐ Mm‐hmm, yes, it is.
So, what, do I stop buying?
Well, let's, um,
milk is $1.79
eggs is $1.69,
peanut butter,
the cheapest one,
who wrote this for you?
Nurse Hathaway helped me
make my food chart.
Uh, did they say
why they cut your food stamps?
No, okay,
well, Sherry
there are a lot of agencies
that can..
...that can help you out.
I'm gonna, uh, um..
...I'm gonna get the..
...I'm gonna get some numbers,
I'll call you, okay?
I'll be right back.
Three‐centimeter laceration
to the vaginal wall
at 2 o'clock.
Oh..
Am I going
to be alright?
Yes, Mrs. Reilly.
Don't worry.
Is the baby
going to be okay?
Baby will be fine.
Contusions to the labia majora
bilaterally.
Scant purulent discharge.
Do you want cultures?
Yeah, GC and chlamydia.
'How about HIV?'
Well, we need to find out
who has legal consent.
Any word on family?
Haven't heard yet.
Oh..
I didn't have nearly
as hard a time with you.
I don't think I did.
You're doing very well,
Mrs. Reilly.
Won't be much longer.
Let's give her
a gram of ceftriaxone
to cover for STDs.
Oh, wait, wait.
I'm not going
to have a baby, am I?
No, Mrs. Reilly,
but you are in a hospital
and we're going to take
very good care of you.
Oh, I know you will, darling.
Mrs. Reilly?
Do you know
why you're here?
Do you remember anyone
coming into your apartment
in the past
few days?
People don't stop by much
anymore, do they?
Okay, Mrs. Reilly, you can
just relax now, right here.
Let's give her
another 500cc's
and let the detectives know
that she'll be
a little while longer.
She's not going
to be any help.
She doesn't
remember anything.
It's probably
a blessing.
Dr. Del Amico, a woman
just came in with her daughter
looking for her Tamagotchi,
so I told her that you found it.
Oh, okay, good, I had
to steal time away all day
to feed it
and play with it.
Hey, why does it
have wings now?
Hmm?
Oh, my God.
He's dead.
Oh, like
a little angel!
Wai‐wai‐wait,
how can he be dead?
Everytime he bleeped,
I took care of him.
I‐I guess
they just die sometimes.
But if he was sick,
why didn't he bleep?
I would have
done something.
You did
the best you could.
I'm really sorry,
but, um...
Hello, Jeanie.
Dr. Anspaugh. How are you?
I'm well.
I want to thank you
for your help today.
Well, I can imagine
what Scott's been through.
Can I ask
about the abdominal films?
There's a partial obstruction.
We've admitted him.
'Could possibly be adhesions
from the...previous surgery.'
We're gonna wait and see.
Scott's faced a lot
of adversity already in life..
...and whatever comes
he can handle it.
I like him.
Well..
...I just wanted
to say, thank you.
We can get a cab
over on Michigan.
Or we can walk off
the Mi Krob
and coconut crab curry.
Are you crazy?
It's ten degrees.
Come on, John.
It's, like, three blocks.
‐ Okay.
Look, I don't want
you to think
that I'm cursed
with indecision.
It's just, I need to be
excited about what I do.
‐ Hey, I understand.
‐ Are you like that?
Am I like that?
Ah, well, you know..
'Hey, hey, hey,
wait, wait, wait, hey!'
‐ What's goin' on over there?
‐ Oh, wait, hey!
Wait, hey, hey, hey,
wait, wait, wait!
What's going on?
I'm a doctor.
Uh‐we saw
this guy over here.
I don't know
if he's dead or what.
'I sent my buddy
to get help.'
I'm barely
getting a pulse.
His heel's frozen.
What should we do?
Go, get a cab. Hurry up,
I'll stay with him.
Come on, let's go.
‐ Taxi, taxi!
‐ Wait up!
Lizzie.
Dr. Romano.
You should go ahead and schedule
the silastic medialization.
Really?
I'll work out the details
with Anspaugh.
‐ Can I tell Allison?
‐ Yeah, sure.
I'll do it right now,
it'll lift her spirits.
I, um..
I shouldn't have let personal
feelings get in the way.
You were right, it was good
that you stayed focused
on the patient.
Thanks.
I‐I'm no good at apologizing,
so, let's let‐let that be
the last thing said
about it, alright?
And you and I.
We're alright?
Lizzie, you and I
are a match made in heaven.
Hey, Chuny, I got a homeless guy
here, with hypothermia.
Can you get me
some warming blankets?
You want heated
humidified O2?
Yeah, and can you pop
a couple of liters
into the microwave, too?
Is the ER always
this exciting?
Pretty much.
Dr. Carter.
Hey, I found this guy
unconscious over
by the medical school.
Okay, let's be very careful
on the transfer.
I don't want to give
him an arrhythmia.
One, two, three.
Good.
‐ You are?
‐ I'm Laura Brown.
Um, I'm observing
Dr. Carter.
'Second‐year
med student.'
Wants to see
what it's all about.
BP's 80‐palp,
pulse is 52.
Okay, let's get a core temp,
CBC and a 12 lead.
Alright, everybody,
let's prep for a pleural lavage.
Come on,
every second counts.
‐ Pleural lavage?
‐ Yeah.
I'm thinkin'
active core rewarming.
It's ten degrees outside.
This guy's a popsicle.
Mark, it's quittin' time.
You still on for dinner?
Oh, sure, I just want
to finish this up.
Get the next attending
on shift to cover.
Uh, uh,
I‐I'd really feel
more comfortable
by seeing this through.
Alright, I'm headin' over
to Greek Islands.
You finish in an hour,
you join me.
Got the warm saline.
Make sure it's not too hot
and then run in
another liter bolus.
Are you worried about
rewarming shock?
No, not if we provide
circulatory support
with a cardiopulmonary
bypass.
You're going to do
a bypass in the ER?
Sure, it's an excellent way
of warming the blood
or we could, uh, do dialysis.
Whoa.
I‐I just wanted to check on her.
I've got to leave.
Well, she was awake
a little while ago.
'She seemed a lot
more coherent'
which means the
fluids are working.
But she still doesn't know
why she's in the hospital.
I wanted to say
goodbye to her.
It's inconceivable
what the police were sayin'.
I don't know if..
...I don't know if I can
go back to that buildin'.
Am I a horrible person?
I truly consider
Mrs. Reilly, my friend.
I want to be a friend
to her, but..
You are a good friend.
You brought her here,
didn't you?
But I'm afraid to bring
meals to her anymore.
They're gonna catch
this man.
You just need to go home
and get some rest.
Tell her I'll...tell her
I'll call her, alright?
Sure.
Man, it's cold!
Did I miss Swift?
Uh, his shift ended
'bout 15 minutes ago.
Aw, shoot.
So, are you ready
to celebrate?
I've got reservations
at "Rosebud."
Hmm.
Or we could stay in,
that's fine.
Sounds better to me.
‐ Okay, you tired?
‐ No, uh‐uh.
Anspaugh say something
about the proposal?
His son came in today.
He's, uh, got a partial
bowel obstruction history
of B‐cell lymphoma, and..
...Anspaugh went to Mark Greene
to take care of him.
Well, he knows
how busy you are.
Maybe he's forgotten
I'm a doctor.
Sometimes, I almost forget.
That's the best reason yet
to let SPG take the load.
‐ Hmm?
‐ Yes.
What will it be,
your place or mine?
q‐ Your place has room service.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Damn it, presented like a
classic case of hypothermia.
Except for his
temperature
which was three degrees
below normal.
What's wrong with him?
Well, he's drunk.
That's it?
So, no bypass?
No, not a
total wash, though.
I can teach you how to
administer a banana bag.
We give these to everybody
who comes in drunk.
Every patient
that comes in drunk
to prevent Wernicke's
encephalopathy.
The, uh, yellow color
is a result
of putting a multi‐vitamin
in there with the IV‐IV fluid.
‐ No bananas in the..
‐ 'Dr. Benton.'
Remember me?
I'm Laura Brown.
I sat in on your
lecture today.
Uh, right.
I was observing
Dr. Carter
but this looks
a lot more interesting.
'Hmm, we're putting a
chest tube in the patient'
'before we send him
up to surgery.'
'He has a hemopneumothorax'
'which is a...bleeding
collapsed lung.'
What kind of animal
goes after the weak like that?
At least she's feelin' better.
Oh, it makes me wonder
about the whole human species.
And I'd personally volunteer
to castrate this guy.
Yosh, can you make
me a copy
of these wound care
instructions?
We're about ready
to wrap this up.
You bet.
Thanks for coming in today.
My pleasure.
It's amazing
what you've done here.
‐ Really?
‐ Yeah.
Five shifts a week,
the clinic...
It makes a difference.
I'm sorry, I yelled
at you over the phone.
I'm actually glad you spoke
to my mom, it's a relief.
I don't know
what I was waiting for.
The other shoe to drop.
Dumb, huh?
Are you off?
I've to wait
on a psyche consult.
It might take a while.
I'll wait.
Finally got an ID
on our...ice man.
Lives in a shelter
over on price street.
They're going to send
a van to pick him up.
What happened
to your student?
I thought she was going
to stick around.
She went up to go
watch Benton operate.
I think she got bored.
Well, we're not here
to entertain, Carter.
You know, she seemed
so interested.
I was supposed
to inspire those students
but I don't think
I did a very good job.
Uh‐huh, inspire 'em, how?
Through our...
our, uh, passion..
...for what we do.
‐ Passion?
‐ Yeah.
You know what I mean.
Carter, you come
here everyday.
Sometimes, you're
really cookin'
and sometimes,
you're not.
But you're here everyday,
doing your work.
One day, you'll look up
and...maybe, uh,
ten years will have passed.
It'll be the sum total..
...of what you've done
that counts
not the passion.
You want to review
some of these charts?
Yeah.
She's an awfully sweet girl,
Susan, isn't she?
She was very
worried about you.
Hmm, she reminds me
of my daughter.
I feel so silly.
Made such a nuisance
having to bring me up here
for a little bump
on the head.
Oh, ow, ow!
‐ This darn thing's caught.
‐ Let me help you.
You'll feel so useless
when you get to be my age.
I've already gotten
a bit forgetful.
The other night,
I came home
and I left my keys hangin'
in the front door.
Oh, I don't think
that has anything
to do with age, Mrs. Reilly.
'I do the same thing.'
I left my keys
in the door.
I left my keys...in the door..
'...and a man walked
into my apartment.'
Mrs. Reilly?
And he put his hand
up over my mouth...
then he made me get down,
on the gr‐ground..
Oh, God!
‐ Mrs. Reilly?
‐ Oh, my God, oh.
Shh, it's okay.
You're going to be okay, now.
I left th‐the k‐keys
in the door.
I know, I know.
It's okay.
Oh, my God!
It's okay, shh.