Incoming. Talk to me.
Female, late teens, hypothermic.
- GCS of 9.
- Trauma 2.
Can barely feel a pulse. She's really cold.
I got her.
Male, early 20s.
Fell off a plane at touchdown.
Go to Trauma 1.
Left chest is crushed. Unable to intubate.
Pale and unresponsive. Get intubation drugs.
20 of etomidate and 100 of succs.
Get a labs and a base deficit
and trigger the MTP
and start transfusing as soon
as the blood shows up.
On my count.
- Both: One, two, three.
- Transfer.
All right,
let's get that board out.
- Got it.
- Let's get a CPC and a crit.
Okay, let's roll him over.
And roll.
Hold him steady.
- Hold.
- Right here, Maggie.
Miguel. Miguel.
What's your name?
Can you tell me your name?
Miguel!
ABCs intact.
GCS 9.
All right, get warm saline bags
in her axillae, groin,
and behind her neck.
And let's cover
the top of her head
to keep whatever heat
she has in.
- On it.
- Too much blood in the airway.
Can't see a thing.
Okay.
We're gonna crich this guy.
We're gonna need
about three more.
Get a core temp.
All right, let's get the X-ray
and the FAST scan in here now.
Trach set.
Got it?
Got it.
I'll bag him.
How's she doing over here?
Heart rate's 50.
Temp is 29 Celsius.
Still responding.
Breath sounds bilaterally.
Right is really muffled.
What the hell happened?
Stowaways from Mexico.
He fell out of the plane.
She came out of the wheel well
after landing.
All right.
Let's get a look at his chest.
X-ray clear.
Hemopneumothorax.
Dr. Choi, get a chest tube
in on the right.
You got it.
Roll!
- All right. Scanner.
- Here.
Thank you.
Pressure's down.
There's blood
throughout his belly.
We need to get him up
to the OR now.
He's gonna need a lap.
On it.
Calling the OR.
Yes, 100%.
Okay. I need to set his leg.
All right, Maggie?
Yup.
Ready.
Okay.
All right.
- You wrap that up for me?
- Yep.
Whenever you're set, go.
Will do.
What's her core temp?
Still 29 Celsius.
- Got the Foley in?
- Yup.
Get 2 of Versed IV.
Get the ECD in
and set up for a DPL.
We have a very short window
to get her warm.
Versed in.
Go ahead and get me a flush.
I need heparin. Ready to travel.
All right, let's go.
Okay.
Start the infuser
and set it to warm.
Give me the big needle.
Just use the level one to warm.
Do not pressure infuse.
Got it.
ECD warming to 46 degrees.
Core temp's 35 and rising.
Heart rate's up, 60.
That should stabilize
her for now.
Good work, everyone.
Nice work.
I'm afraid she's not out
of the woods yet.
Hypothermia and hypoxia?
That's like hibernation.
It's, like, minus 60
to 70 up there.
What kind of screwed up
life did she have
that she took a risk like that?
Hey, no offense,
but not everyone's
born a Rhodes.
Thanks.
I keep forgetting that.
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -
Can you lift your arm?
I... I can't.
Can you hold it out
in front of you?
Ha! Ah!
Okay.
Does this hurt?
Ah!
He was playing in the
backyard, tripped and fell.
Dad says I'm clumsy.
You just need to watch
where you're going.
I think Parker
has fractured his left clavicle,
but we need to get an X-ray
to make sure.
The tech will be right in.
Hmm.
Why you think he gave us
all that money?
You mean he's not
honoring his late wife?
I doubt it's a coincidence
Cornelius Rhodes
gave to the hospital
where his son works.
You think?
Man who likes to be
in the center of attention.
Freaking world-class
narcissist, that guy.
Yeah, and what better way
to steal the spotlight
from his son than
by donating a million dollars?
Whatever his motives,
the money's green.
And I get a new psych ward!
Good morning.
How you feeling?
Wonderful, you know,
considering the fact
that I can't sleep longer
than 15 minutes,
and when I do actually
get comfortable,
I have to pee.
- Fun!
- Yup.
Did you try
that pillow I gave you?
Yes.
I added to the 20 other pillows
that aren't helping me sleep,
but thank you.
Oh.
Sarah's got a kid
with a fractured clav
in Treatment 1 for you.
Okay.
I'll just hit the bathroom
and then waddle my way over there.
- Talk to you later.
- See ya.
What?
How's she doing?
Still in and out
of consciousness.
Temp's back to normal.
Still waiting on her charts.
Soy El Doctor Rhodes.
ÿCómo se siente?
ÿDónde... Miguel?
Her name is Maria Gonzalez.
Miguel is her brother.
He was the one that
was brought in with her.
All right.
Maria...
your brother was
very seriously injured.
Alive?
Yes. He is.
Pero está en terapia intensiva.
Va a necesitar soporte vida.
El estaba tratando de salva.
Why was he trying to save you?
Nuestro padre...
Our father...
is narco...
Sinaloa.
Not good man.
Want to sell me.
Pero...
mi hermano,
Miguel, protect me.
He get me out.
Por favor, cuida a Miguel.
Cuida a Miguel.
We will.
Haremos todo lo Que
podamos por él.
Gracias.
Respir.
Sorry, I have to go.
Descanse.
Volveré pronto.
Respira otra vez.
On the day you were born,
the Earth turned.
The moon pulled.
The sun flared.
And then, with a push,
you slipped out
of the dark quiet,
where suddenly you could hear.
Parker's fracture is aligned,
which means
he will not need surgery.
Are you gonna put a cast on?
I want a cast!
Oh, sorry,
all you get is a sling.
Hi, I'm Dr. Manning.
Hey, well, I heard someone broke
his collarbone this morning.
Hey, buddy!
I was just telling them that
their son won't need surgery.
All right, well,
let me take a look.
Hi, Parker.
Do you mind if I check
your pulse?
Yeah?
Thank you.
All right, I'm just gonna take
a little peek in here...
see what's going on...
He's seizing!
What's happening to him?
Give me 1 milligram of Ativan.
He's having a seizure.
Does he have epilepsy?
No!
Any history of seizures?
No.
You're okay, honey!
You're okay.
Oh, my God.
What just happened?
I'm not sure,
but I don't think
it's related to his clavicle.
With your permission,
I'd like to run some tests
and see what's going on.
Of course.
Come in.
Mrs. Goodwin?
Thanks for coming,
Dr. Rhodes.
These are agents
McManus and Ramirez
from Homeland Security.
Dr. Rhodes, you have
a female patient,
a stowaway?
Yes, Maria Gonzalez.
And she was brought in
with a companion?
She was.
Miguel, her brother.
Her brother?
We understand he's
unconscious in the ICU.
Mm-hmm.
We would like
to talk to Miss Gonzalez.
Well, I'm afraid that
she's barely conscious herself.
She's in no condition
to be questioned right now.
Any idea when we'd be able
to talk to Miss Gonzalez?
It's too early to say.
This woman is a victim.
Her father is a narco.
He was planning on selling her.
Her brother was only
trying to save her.
Sounds like you had
extensive conversations
with the semi-conscious
Miss Gonzalez.
No, that's all I know.
Dr. Rhodes, you realize
we wouldn't be here
if this weren't a matter
of great concern?
Yes, and he'll let you know
as soon as you can speak to her.
Thanks.
We'll be back.
And you can count on that.
I'm trying to make this
look pretty, Cedric,
but I'm afraid you're
still gonna have a scar.
That's a good thing, Doc.
Bigger the better.
Makes my case.
What do you mean?
Well, you see, my pops doesn't
want me to have a car.
Now I can say,
"See, if I had been in my
ride instead of on my bike,
I wouldn't have this scar."
Or if you'd been
wearing your helmet.
Doc, don't confuse the issue.
What do you think?
That gonna do the trick?
Oh, yeah.
That's a Honda scar.
We aim to please.
You are good to go.
Thanks, Doc.
No problem.
She'll sign you out.
Dr. Choi to ICU.
Hold compressions.
What happened?
We lost him.
Time of death: 11:32.
Damn.
Want me to tell his sister?
No, I will.
Mis piernas!
ÿTe duele?
ÿDónde?
Mis piernas!
What's going on?
Hard as a rock.
Compartment syndrome.
She must have injured her leg
when she was unconscious
in the plane.
I don't feel a pulse.
Get me a Stryker needle.
Let's evaluate the pressure.
No, no, no, we are past that.
She needs all four compartments
released right now,
or she's gonna lose this leg.
Call the OR and tell 'em
we're on our way up now.
Fentanyl?
100 mics.
We need repeat labs stat.
CBC, lytes, and a CPK.
ORs are busy,
at least a two-hour wait.
That's too long.
We're gonna do
the fasciotomies here.
Draw up to syringes of ketamine,
70 milligrams apiece,
and get me 2 of Versed.
Whoa, wait.
You're not gonna intubate her?
Not necessary.
We can do this
with deep sedation.
The ketamine
won't give you much time.
Well, then I will be fast.
Mi hermano Miguel.
Give her the Versed,
follow it up with the ketamine.
On it.
BP's 120 over 82.
Heart rate's 110.
Sat's at 99%.
Okay.
Here we go.
I'm going for
the posterior compartment now.
Keep her still.
I'm telling you
we should be in the OR.
Just suction her out.
April, 70 more of ketamine,
and then come down here
and help hold the leg.
Got it.
Second dose is...
in.
Okay.
Almost...
Muscle looks viable,
bleeds well.
That should do it.
Wrap her up.
Send her up to the ICU.
Got it.
Let me know when she's alert.
I need to talk to her.
Her brother just died.
You listen to me.
When we are under
the gun like that,
it doesn't help to keep
questioning my decisions.
You follow my lead.
Guy's father writes a big check
and he acts like
he owns the joint.
How about you cut him
some slack today?
Look, my mother died too.
She's not getting commemorated
with a new hospital ward, okay?
I thought you said
you grew up in Chicago.
Southside.
Canaryville.
Ah.
And you mean to tell me
that you don't know
what happened
to Connor's mother?
Nope.
Well, it was 20 years ago.
You were just a kid.
Connor's mom threw herself
off the roof of their home.
Three stories.
Connor was just ten.
Are you serious?
Mm-hmm.
It was all over the news
back in the day.
And with the reception
tonight...
lot of stuff that he probably
doesn't want to
have to think about.
I got Parker's
test results back.
And?
You need to take a look.
Here.
CT negative.
We need to order...
An MRI, I know.
I already did it.
It shows excessive
demyelination.
Explains the clumsiness,
degeneration of motor skills...
And the seizure.
I don't want to jump
to conclusions,
but I'm pretty sure he has...
Krabbe Disease.
Yeah.
He's eight,
so it's late-onset.
Gives him five to seven years
before he becomes
confined to a bed
and completely vegetative.
Poor kid.
What do you want to do?
Well, I've got
to go talk to the par...
Dr. Manning?
You okay?
No.
I think my water just broke.
Oh, my God.
It did.
I guess this is happening today.
Uh, can we get
a wheelchair over here?
Look, I'm sorry, Sarah,
but you have to go
tell the parents.
What? Me?
No. I can't...
You have to.
I don't have the experience.
Go get Dr. Charles.
He will help you.
I have to go have this baby now.
Thank you.
Okay.
Breathe out.
Exhale.
Shh.
That's it.
One more time.
How much longer do
we have to do this?
- Ten more laps.
- Ugh.
Make sure everything gets
aligned correctly down there.
You know,
I am seriously regretting
making you my birthing coach.
Good.
That means I'm doing my job.
Oh, hey, handsome!
Get yourself over here.
- Sorry.
- Hi.
I had to bribe Fromson
to cover my shift.
What do you need me to do?
Okay, I need you
to walk with her for now
and be her rock.
And I will be back
as soon as I can.
Wait, you're leaving?
Got to find somebody
to cover my desk.
Yup.
We could be here
for the next 30 hours.
- 30 hours?
- No.
Not if you listen
to your birthing coach.
I'm not sure how fast
a rock is supposed to walk.
You're doing just fine.
Thank you for being here.
Natalie?
It's finally happening!
Ah!
Hi, Helen.
Hi, honey.
And you are?
Oh, this is Dr. Halstead.
Will.
I work with Natalie.
And this is Helen,
my mother-in-law.
Congratulations.
I've got this now.
Sure.
Yeah.
Hello.
Sorry I'm late.
Thanks for coming, Sharon.
A meeting without
a single doctor present?
My guess is this isn't
about a medical issue.
Peter?
Sharon, I know
you're not gonna like this...
Neither do we...
But we need to discuss
our stowaway patient.
Dr. Charles?
Dr. Manning said
you could help me.
What's up?
I have a patient,
an eight-year-old boy,
Parker Kindler, and...
uh...
You know what,
let me back up for a second.
Dr. Manning and I
were treating Parker,
and then she went
into labor, and...
Natalie's in labor?
Mm-hmm.
How's she doing?
Fine, I suppose.
Her water broke right
in front of me,
but that's not what
I came to talk to you about.
Okay.
Dr. Manning and I
just diagnosed Parker
with a terminal genetic
condition called Krabbe Disease,
and now she's in labor,
and I have to tell the parents
that their eight-year-old child
is going to die,
and that the same thing might
happen to their three-year-old.
So I guess I was just
wondering...
how do...
How do I do that?
Have a seat.
Yeah.
In my experience,
it's best to be direct
and get straight to the point.
When people get
bad news like this,
they tend to get overwhelmed.
They might ask you
to clarify things
or repeat them.
You know...
They might seem like
they have a million questions.
They might want to be left alone
to begin to process the grief.
The most important thing
is that they need to know
that somebody's there
who understands
what they're going through.
You know...
So really it's your compassion
that they need to feel.
Compassion.
Yeah.
And after you tell
the parents...
they might want you there
when they tell the child.
They might not.
That's up to them.
Wait.
Tell the child?
Oh, yeah.
The child actually
needs to know.
Okay.
Look, Sarah,
it's the hardest thing
that you'll have to do
as a doctor, right?
And it doesn't get any easier.
At least, it hasn't for me.
But we are the ones
who have been chosen to do this,
and I think that there's
a certain nobility in that.
Okay?
Good.
You want me to come along?
That would be great.
Thank you.
Given his current symptoms,
Parker has anywhere
from five to seven years
before the progressively
degenerative nature
of the disease
confines him to a bed
and eventually leaves him
in a vegetative state.
I mean, there must
be some kind of treatment.
At the moment, no.
You mean there's no cure?
There's nothing we can do?
Um...
that is correct.
Krabbe is an extremely
rare disease.
We can treat his symptoms,
but eventually Parker will need
to be ventilated
to continue living.
There is something else.
Since the disease is hereditary,
we need to determine
if Seth carries it as well.
Do you know if he's been tested?
Seth?
I don't remember.
That's okay.
I can find out.
Do I have permission
to check his natal records?
Of course.
What happens
if Seth tests positive?
Since he has not yet
presented symptoms,
the hope is we can treat him
with stem cells
and stop him from
developing the disease.
The hope?
Why don't we check
the records first
and... and go from there?
Again, I'm so sorry.
Excuse me.
Okay.
Oz, turn the room over.
Whoa.
What happened to my patient?
The Air Ambulance medics came
to take Ms. Gonzalez away.
What?
They just left.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
What are you doing
with my patient?
All right, Doc, please,
it's best you stay out of this.
No, no, no.
She is under my care.
- She... Maria!
- Dr. Rhodes, por favor!
- Are okay?
- Let's keep him back.
You get off of me.
I'm sorry, but she's
being repatriated home.
No, she is barely stable.
She can't go anywhere.
She's stable enough to travel.
She's gonna be accompanied
by a doctor and a nurse.
No, no, no.
I can't allow this.
Doctor, I'm sorry.
This is not up to you.
Mrs. Goodwin?
Yeah.
You backed me up
with Homeland Security.
Yes, I did.
Then why did you let
them deport Maria Gonzalez?
Not here, Dr. Rhodes.
Give us the room.
Hmm?
Homeland Security
did not deport your patient.
No, no, no.
I was outside.
I saw them.
It's the hospital
that's repatriating her.
The hospital?
Why... we're doing this why?
Because Maria Gonzalez
is undocumented
and without medical insurance.
We're legally bound
to treat her.
Which we have done.
She is still
in critical condition.
We contract with a private
ambulance service.
They provide medical personnel
for the patient.
That's how you justify it, then?
Look, I wish I could wave
a magic wand and fix it,
but I can't.
Maria came her for refuge.
Her brother risked everything
so that he could help her,
and he sacrificed his life.
For what?
For nothing.
Dr. Rhodes.
Damn.
There was meconium
in your water,
so we'll want to watch for fetal
aspiration during delivery.
Okay.
Oof.
Your dilation is 4 centimeters.
So... looks like
you're on your way.
Dr. Halstead,
you can come in now.
How you doing?
I'm okay.
Mm.
All right,
I got Betty to cover the desk.
I'm here for the duration.
What do you need?
- I'm really thirsty.
- Okay.
- I'll get you some ice chips.
- Oh, thank you.
All right, thank you.
Let me fluff
that pillow for you.
There you go.
Okay.
Will?
Yeah.
Natalie's husband,
my son, Jeff...
died seven months ago.
Yeah, I'm very sorry
for your loss.
Only seven months.
What are you doing?
I'm...
just trying to help.
Natalie and I are friends.
Friends?
And colleagues.
And that's it?
Of course.
I care about her.
Natalie's having a baby.
She's a widow.
She's vulnerable.
Can you just give that to her?
Tell her I'll be back later.
What do we got?
17-year-old involved
in a drive-by.
Triple zero.
Three entry wounds in the chest.
Multiple exit wounds.
He's shredded.
Intubated.
16-gauge IV in the right AC.
Downtime 12 minutes.
Get on his chest.
Open the crash cart.
Milligram of EPI.
Rapid transfusion line.
Yes, doctor.
That's asystole.
Come on.
Come on!
Dr. Choi?
He's gone.
All right. Let's call it.
18:06.
Those are my sutures.
He was here this morning.
I know him.
Cedric.
He fell off his bike.
Parker, honey,
you've been asking
why Seth had to get a test.
And why your dad and I
have seemed so sad...
Is something the matter?
Yes.
There is, and we need
to tell you about it.
Okay.
We asked
Dr. Charles to help us
in case we can't
explain it very well.
'Cause he's a doctor.
Right.
It turns out, honey, that...
You're sick.
You mean this?
No.
Something more.
You mean,
like when I get a cold?
No.
Please.
Parker...
you are sick in a different way.
So should we check
to see if I have a temperature?
Mm, we don't have to.
You don't.
Does that mean
I'm getting better?
No, buddy, it doesn't.
I'm sorry.
Unfortunately,
you have an illness
that we don't have
a cure for yet.
Is this like when Finn got sick?
Finn was my dog.
Oh, you had a dog?
Uh-huh.
He died.
Am I gonna die too?
Yeah.
You are.
But not for a long time.
A year?
Oh, longer than that.
More like five years.
That's a long time.
Yeah.
Will I get to eat ice cream?
I'm guessing...
the answer might be yes.
Push! Push, push!
Where's Will?
I don't know.
Don't worry.
Maggie and I are here with you.
Your BP is rising.
It's still okay, right?
The baby's not descending.
I'm worried that
he's occiput posterior
and stuck in the birth canal.
What does that mean?
- The baby is sunny-side up.
- Breathe.
We need to consider
a C-section.
A C-section?
Is it that serious?
Is the baby in danger?
Ma'am, I'm sorry,
but I think it would be better
if you waited outside.
No, I'm not leaving.
Helen, it's okay.
I'm fine.
I promise.
Ma'am.
- Okay, if you're sure.
- Yes.
- I got this, Helen.
- Ma'am?
I'll be right outside.
I don't want a C-section.
I don't blame you.
I think you're being
overly cautious.
That 'cause you're
treating another doctor?
I treat all my
patients the same.
We're not there yet.
Are you questioning my judgment?
I'm her midwife,
and I don't think cutting
into her is a good idea yet.
Are you going to listen
to her or your obstetrician?
Nat, I can turn the baby.
Natalie?
Nat?
Let her try.
Breathe, breathe!
Give me ultrasound.
Heart rate's decelerating.
Baby's still OP.
We should operate.
Not yet.
One more time.
Okay, Nat?
Breathe.
Breathe!
Try it now.
I think we have it.
Yes!
Okay, he's in position.
Okay?
Okay.
Give me a push.
Now!
That's it.
Push!
The baby's crowning.
We're almost there.
Okay.
I'm so tired.
Listen to me, okay?
You can do this.
Okay?
Wait a second.
Again.
Three, two, one...
push!
That's it!
That's it.
Okay, that's it.
Here he is.
We've got a tight nuchal cord.
What's happening?
Baby's not breathing.
Clip.
What's happening!
Okay, Nat.
Cut.
Tell me what's happening!
Here you go.
Someone tell
me what's happening!
Meconium in the airway.
Suctioning now.
I need you to be strong.
They're working on the baby.
Be strong.
Here.
Suction.
Keep it going.
Oh, thank God!
Hi, hi!
Here's your son.
Hi!
Hi.
Oh, yes.
And you put this lace
over this loop.
Tie them together.
And...
cut!
Hey, I have good news.
Seth tested negative
for Krabbe Disease.
He doesn't have it.
Oh, my God.
We're making a movie.
Instructional videos
for his brother.
Things that I learned
when I was little.
In case I get too sick
to teach him.
That's really nice.
Okay.
I got something to do...
- Uh-huh.
- But I'll be right back.
I know all too well
how difficult it is
for the loved ones
of those who suffer
from mental illness.
22 years ago,
my wife, Elizabeth,
lost her battle
with depression...
and killed herself,
scarring not only me,
but our two children.
Sadly, this kind of tragedy
is not unique to our family,
and therefore, I can
only hope that my donation
helps to ease the suffering,
the feeling of hopelessness,
that we and too many others
have experienced.
Thank you.
So, in memory of my late wife,
I have given $1 million
to help build
the Elizabeth Rhodes
Psychiatric Ward.
Thank you.
Thank you you all very much.
He looks just like his father.
Yeah.
He really does.
I'm gonna name him Owen.
It's Irish for "little fighter."
Given how he came
into the world.
Owen.
I like it.
It was a beautiful speech, Dad.
Why, thank you.
I had this patient today.
She came in with her brother,
and he died.
He sacrificed his life for her.
I never should have left Claire.
No.
You shouldn't have.
Hurt her deeply.
You know, I never told her
about the night that Mom died,
what really happened.
Your mother was disturbed.
She had a mental illness.
You and I both know
that that's not the reason
she killed herself.
Let me get this for you.
Hey, Dad.
I am really glad that I'm back.
All: To Owen!
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -