Surgeons can't be lazy.
The risks are too great.
That one looks
like an islet cell.
Which one?
That one. It's all puffy
and insulin producing.
It looks like a cloud.
It looks like an islet
cell or maybe a buffalo.
The second we stop
pushing ourselves,
something terrible happens,
something we never see coming.
I have no imagination, Mer.
Teddy sucked it out of me.
Let's not go there.
We're just gonna believe that
everything's gonna be okay.
We're keeping the faith.
Yeah.
She did say that she had
something great for me today.
What are you on?
Cabbage patch.
OB Still? You gotta get
out of those pink scrubs.
Why? Bailey's got me
blackballed from every surgery.
Besides, it's quiet. I get
to work on the trial stuff.
I thought Bailey told you to
stay away from the trial stuff.
I know, but I just can't help it
because I feel like
I'm this close to...
Hey! That coulda hit us.
Careful.
Nice hustle.
You know, I think this is just
more avoiding thinking about Zola.
Did you hear something?
No. We've bugged
Janet till she's sick of us,
and she doesn't
really know anything,
so we just have
to wait for the court
to give us a hearing
date, and we're just...
Keeping the faith.
Karev, throw the ball!
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Come on! Robbins,
don't be afraid of it.
Wait. It flew at my head.
Not bad. Not bad.
You like that?
I said not bad. Don't
go crazy. Uh-huh.
Sloan.
Sloan. Yo!
Focus. Hello? Okay.
Who is that?
Oh, Julia Canner or Kinney.
She's an ophthalmologist
from Seattle Pres.
Mark's been seeing her.
Every night this week.
Yay!
All right, nice throw,
Robbins. That's the way.
Webber, why don't you come down
here and show us how it's done?
Uh, let me finish the chapter. I
need my energy for the game.
In my experience, we'll need it.
Mmm-hmm.
Who's up?
Hunt. All right, come on in.
When are you gonna let me
pitch? I'm a really good pitcher.
We're fine.
Shepherd throws an
unbeatable screwball, all right?
Now, Little Grey, let's go.
Go, Lexie!
Drop the bat. Go,
go. Run to third.
Don't stop. All right. Come
on, everyone. Look alive.
Yang, Grey, you
could at least stand up.
Hi, honey.
Looking good, Chief Hunt.
Hi, Chief MacDougall.
Make it Brad.
I'm surprised to see
you out here, Hunt.
We've had this
field every morning.
Is this your first practice?
Uh, no. No, no. We've been...
I would've thought it was.
Kudos for putting a team
together at all this year,
what with all the upheaval
over at Seattle Grace.
Yeah, we've got a
lot of good players...
Webber being ousted,
all that nasty business
with the Alzheimer's
trial being shut down...
No wonder they put a
trauma guy in charge.
You must feel like
you're just scrambling
to stop the
hemorrhaging over there.
We got another
half-hour out here or so,
and then we're gonna be ready
to kick your asses tomorrow.
Oh, just a half-hour?
Is that all you need?
Hunt, I gotta go. OWEN: What?
Lexie. We got a consult. - Yeah.
Okay. No. No, wait. We're...
I gotta check on a sick
kid. Can I get a ride?
I gotta update the
boards. No, no. Listen, no...
- Is that it?
- No, we're still...
Are we done? Just... Wait!
Hustle.
Everyone. No, no.
Whoa! Looks like your
half-hour's up. Wait.
All right, guys.
Come on. Let's do it.
All right.
Got it?
I got third. I got third.
You said "great."
Is it a transplant?
Is it a heterotopic transplant?
No.
But you said "great." Is it big?
It'll probably take
you all morning.
Mr. Felker, this is Dr. Yang.
And she will be
performing your angioplasty.
Nice to meet you.
Any first year can do this.
I thought I was gonna
be working on a heart.
You're gonna be
working on preventing
Mr. Felker from
having a heart attack.
I mean, I thought I was gonna
be working on a heart in the OR.
Is someone gonna
roto-rooter my veins out?
Mmm-hmm.
So I typed it up for you.
Fielding positions, batting order...
It's all right here.
You're a good
administrative assistant.
Thank you, sir. That's
not a compliment.
I think being Chief
Resident has set you back.
I'd like to see you getting
off the sidelines more.
One, two, three.
Okay, what do we have?
Carl Shatler, sanitation
worker, mid 30's.
Fell off the back
of a garbage truck,
then hit by a car
backing out of a driveway.
Okay, vitals are stable but
he has multiple contusions,
scalp lac, and
obvious hand injuries.
Carl? Carl, I'm Dr. Hunt.
Do you know where you are?
Can you hear me? GCS 10,
and pupils are equal and reactive.
I'm gonna need the
portable x-ray and ultrasound.
Right away.
This hand's hamburger.
He's gonna lose some of this.
Oh, God. No! No!
Calm down. Kepner,
where is that ultrasound?
Give us some room here, Torres.
Okay, I just need to stabilize
the hand, and then I will...
I said, give us some room. The
hand is not the priority right now.
Fine. Page me when you need me.
Mmm-hmm.
Karev, I need you to sign these.
What is it?
A subpoena for
Zola's medical records.
They're transferring
her care to Seattle Pres.
Wait. Why? We're her doctors.
It's a conflict of
interest because
her prospective
parents work here.
That's genius. First they take
her away from Shepherd and Grey,
now they want to take
her away from her doctors?
Wait, wait, the file.
You have to sign...
Don't worry. I got this.
Let's see. The patient just
flew in from San Francisco.
She has a hypothalamic
hamartoma. What do you know?
HH Tumors are
slow-growing, noncancerous.
They sit in the hypothalamus...
Ms. Bayer, can I help you?
No, it's best if
I just hold her.
It's okay, sweetheart.
How long has she been seizing?
This is the fourth one today.
Ah.
It's getting worse, so please
tell me you can help her.
It's tricky.
Charissa's tumor is eccentric. It's
off to one side more than the other.
Protocol is a
subfrontal approach
from here, but
I'd never get it all.
The surgeon in
San Francisco said
that even if you just
got a little bit of it,
the symptoms wouldn't be as bad.
For now, until it grows back.
We'll take any relief
that we can get.
I know the risks, and
I've done my research.
And you...
You were successful on
87% of your surgeries last year.
So we want the surgery
and we want you to do it.
I'd like to try something else.
Excuse me?
I'd like to come in
from here, from above.
I think I'd have a much
better visualization
and I think I could get it all.
But none of the eight
other neurosurgeons
we talked to even
suggested that.
That's because it's
never been done before.
What are the risks?
You're passing between
two hemispheres,
so there's a
greater risk of injury,
including short-term
memory loss,
um, stroke, and even death.
No.
I can't do that.
I understand. I really do.
A subfrontal approach is
a very standard procedure.
You could probably find another
surgeon who's
qualified to do that.
Can I see the list of
who you talked to?
Uh...
Yes, but I'd rather have you.
Dr. Samuelson is fantastic.
I don't think you could
do better than him.
It was very nice
meeting you, Ms. Bayer
and I wish you the best of luck.
So why did I just
have an irate mother
claim that you refuse to save
the life of her teenage daughter?
It was a consult
for an HH Tumor.
I told her that with a
transcallosal approach,
I think I could get it all. She
didn't want to take the risk.
It's a free country.
So do it the old-fashioned way.
There are plenty of
surgeons in San Francisco
as qualified as I am to do that.
But they want you.
They got on a plane.
I won't do it. It
will grow back.
Maybe it won't.
Maybe we should just wait
and see and hope for the best.
Yes. No. I'm not
gonna do that anymore.
I had a kid in a crib in
my bedroom for a while,
and social services
took her away.
And the only thing they're
gonna say to me now
is that you gotta wait and
see and hope for the best.
It's frustrating. I get that. I
am sick of half measures.
Not in my OR.
Not today. I can't.
I think you can.
I think her best shot is in your
hands, and so does that mother.
We don't send
people home, Derek.
It's not who we are.
It's not who you are.
You're right.
Don't send her back.
So then you'll do it?
No.
I'm gonna prove to
her my way will work.
So basically what
you're saying is,
the device that you
put in him is defective.
I'm saying,
you got one of the
original devices,
and there are some
kinks to work out.
So it's a collectible.
When I die, you should
just put it on eBay.
For now, the only issue is that
you have to resume
daily testing...
Because he could become
diabetic again. Is that right?
Because the device is
basically a huge failure.
No, it's got some problems.
Which she is trying to fix.
That's why they call it a trial.
The good news is, we
figured out what was wrong.
And we're trying hard
to figure out how to fix it.
Look, I knew the risks when
they put this tiddlywink in me.
Plus, all the checkups
mean I get to see you more.
Don't worry.
You'll figure it out.
Okay, Mr. Felker. I'm going
to insert the catheter now.
I'll guide it up to the arteries
surrounding your heart.
Get ready to see a lot of
cheeseburgers and fries.
I work in fast food.
So is this all you do every day,
suck crap out of clogged veins?
Arteries. They're
called arteries.
I'm more of a
renaissance-type guy.
I'm a manager, but I have to
know how to work the fry machine,
man the grill, make shakes.
Hell, when everyone
else is busy,
I'm even the guy who
mops out the john.
Okay, we're giving you a
little more sedation now.
I guess everyone else is
busy. They gave you john duty.
Someone looks like they
got worse news than us.
I don't know about you,
but I'm cheered up already.
I may have just lost my
pitcher to a brain surgery.
But I'm telling
you, I can pitch.
Honey, you were a pro ballplayer.
Come on. Tell him. Tell him.
Tell him I can pitch.
I've never seen her pitch.
You're a pro ballplayer?
Former. I'm a pro
shipping clerk now.
Can you play tomorrow?
Doesn't he have to work here?
I will hire you now and
fire you after the game.
You are now my
administrative assistant.
Can't I be something cool,
like a vascular surgeon or...
You can be whatever you want
if you help us beat Seattle Pres.
I can help you
beat Seattle Pres.
I'm telling you, I can pitch.
Grey, I was just in
giving the Tyson family
an update on their preemie,
and the mom's
complaining of chest pains.
Already called
Altman for a consult.
Okay, great.
Did you... Have
you talked to Karev?
About?
Well, the court asked
for Zola's medical records.
Why?
It's probably nothing. I mean,
don't read anything into it.
I thought you should know.
Thanks. Mmm.
Interactive properties of islet
cells? Is that Bailey's thing?
I'm working with Bailey on this.
I thought Bailey
was pissed at you.
No. No, we're good.
Oh. Okay. Good, then.
Next in line.
I'm trying to get some information
about this adoption case.
The name is Zola...
Family services. What?
Requests for information can be
made in writing to family services.
Uh, look, I'm her doctor.
And they subpoenaed
her medical records...
I can't take your files.
Look, I'm not asking you to.
I just want to talk to
someone about this adoption.
It takes six to eight
weeks to process requests.
Never mind.
Next.
Where do I write?
What's the address?
This address.
Office of Family Court
Services, fifth floor.
Fifth floor. Thanks.
So CT's negative
for internal bleeding,
so Chief Hunt says
Mr. Shatler's all yours.
Oh, that's super.
Tell Chief Hunt I'm so grateful
he gave me the go-ahead.
Okay, was that sarcastic?
Sorry.
Uh, is there any chance you
need an assist on that hand?
I need more OR Time.
Sure. Go schedule an OR.
Oh, and wish me luck.
I'm about to tell a guy his
crappy day just got crappier.
Considering all you went
through, you were lucky, really.
That sounds like a
setup for bad news.
Uh...
Some of the bones in
your hand were pulverized.
There was extensive
nerve and tissue damage.
I'll know more once we get
in the OR and clean it up.
But there's a chance you
could lose these two fingers.
Look, I know it's a shock, but
you survived a terrible accident...
Holy crap. What are
you... What are you doing?
No, no, that's not a weapon.
That's a spitsticker.
I do woodcarving, wood prints.
I carry this stuff
with me 'cause
I have a lot of
downtime on my job.
Okay.
Um...
I'm sorry. It's
just, you kinda...
Yeah. And that scared
the hell outta me.
I was just looking for
my phone to call my wife.
Okay.
Are you gonna freak out if I
stick my hand in here again?
No.
Wow. This...
This is gorgeous.
Can I... Yeah.
Wow. Do you...
Do you sell this stuff?
No, no. Collecting garbage
pays the bills. This...
This keeps me sane.
Or it did...
Till today.
You might want
to leave the room.
She's gonna be pretty upset.
Make sure you
tell her that I'm...
I'm something of
an artist myself.
How about now? Any lights?
Yeah. Supplemental motor area.
Great. I just paralyzed
the whole left side.
So she's completely paralyzed.
We hit the right side earlier.
Mmm.
All right.
Let's try another angle.
Ding. Damn. What was that?
Fornix. Ooh!
Through to the basilar.
So she'd be a...
Mute, memory loss, brain dead.
How's it going?
I just can't find a
clean approach.
Lexie, shut down the monitor.
I guess I owe the mom a surgery.
No, no, no. No, not
yet. Not yet. Try it again.
All right, now you're
really getting on my nerves.
I'm just practicing
my coaching skills.
Seriously, Shepherd.
Pick up the damn probe.
All right. Turn it back on.
Ding.
Teddy gave me a
marathon angioplasty.
Her "great" thing
was a plumbing job.
They've subpoenaed
Zola's medical records.
That's good. It's movement.
What are you doing?
I'm gonna e-mail Janet and
see if she knows anything.
We're keeping the faith, right?
Did I mention, I can't crack
this islet cell thing either?
I've been researching responses
all day to an insulin challenge,
and just nothing.
See that? That right there?
Ooh! Yeah! That
used to be a curly fry.
And I used to be a surgeon.
Janet.
You're right. You
keep the faith.
"Dear client, I will be
out of the office all week."
I've been picturing
her making calls,
fighting the good fight
to get me my kid back,
not sitting on a
beach somewhere.
I know. Mer...
Zola's probably
forgotten us by now.
Uh...
Excuse me.
I'm trying to get some
information about an adoption case.
I'm sure you'll make
a wonderful father,
but until the judge
rules a case closed...
I'm not the dad. I'm the
doctor. The kid's sick and...
Sweetheart, I've heard
every sad story in the book.
It doesn't change the fact that
we don't release information
on pending cases.
You know, I couldn't
help but notice
the dysplastic nevus, the mole.
What?
Yeah, anyone ever
check that for you?
Yes, but...
They said it's not dangerous.
Not now anyway.
Me? I wouldn't take that chance.
Oh, dear. Oh, right.
Crappy government insurance.
That would be on the deductible.
Look, I'm a surgeon.
You give me the
stats on this kid,
I'll take care of you for free.
Yeah, she's on Judge
Brentner's docket.
Let's see if...
Wait. He's not even here
today. He's getting chemo.
So sad. Prostate.
You're a doctor. Is that
one of the bad ones?
Not necessarily.
Depends on where
he's getting it treated.
It could be postpartum
cardiomyopathy.
I'll transfer her to telemetry.
Okay.
Dr. Altman.
Why is Cristina
doing an angioplasty?
Excuse me?
I was just wondering,
and I know she was, too.
Is this all going somewhere?
I mean, I know it's none
of my business, but...
You're right.
As a first year, you do an
angio to learn a technical skill,
but an angio as a fifth year
is about learning respect...
Respect for the heart disease
that Cristina will see
for the rest of her career.
It all starts there,
in the artery.
You have to go back to the
beginning to understand the end.
Back to the beginning.
All right, so move
Avery to shortstop
and put Bailey in center field.
Bailey? Why Bailey?
Because Bailey's a leader.
She'll know who to get the ball to.
She's not your cutoff man.
Avery, he's your cutoff man.
She's tall. Where
do you have her?
Uh, left field. Can she catch?
Let's find out.
Grey, catch.
Hunt, what the hell?
Now he's your cutoff man. Yeah.
I've been looking for you. I
need my mother's journals.
Why? What's up?
I need to see her
original hypothesis.
If I'm gonna figure
out what's going on,
then I need to start
where she started.
Aha!
Aha! I knew once
you picked it up,
you couldn't put it down.
Don't gloat. Where
are they? Come on.
Nice.
The patient and her
mother are wondering
if she's having surgery today.
Should I tell them that
you are still working?
We are working. Sometimes the
body thinks better than the brain.
Grey, toss him a ball.
Hello. Yeah. Yeah.
I thought the board meeting
would be pushed to Thursday.
Your swing's too high.
Did you play ball?
Yeah. I was a pitcher. Really?
Yeah.
Right, into the parking...
Mark's in love.
With an eye doctor.
That should last 48 hours.
Yeah, I should be happy for him.
Don't worry about. Just
shake it off or shake it out
or I don't know,
shake something.
It's his new coaching persona.
Yeah, I'm still working on it.
You're still coming at it wrong.
You're approaching
the ball wrong.
I'm holding the bat wrong?
No, no, no, it's not
the bat. It's your body.
You need to adjust your head,
drop your shoulder.
I mean, you're not connecting.
The head's at the wrong angle.
I've been adjusting the probe.
You need to adjust
the angle of her head.
I went back to the lab
to test my approach.
There's a very good shot I can
access the tumor from above.
I think we can get it all.
A good shot?
This is my child.
Mmm. There are risks either way,
but this certainly
has more risks.
So she could die in surgery.
Look, thank you for
trying, Dr. Shepherd, but I...
I can't let my little
girl be your guinea pig.
Mrs. Bayer,
now in all your research,
have you ever found a story
of a kid with an HH
Tumor who ever got better?
Who ever got a job, had a life?
This is the best
shot you'll have.
Altman. Sloan, you're on first.
Bailey, you're center field.
We're doing some shuffling.
What are you doing here?
I work here.
Uh, I may not even
make the game.
I got 49 trial
patients left to call.
I gotta give them the
same bad news I gave you.
Ouch! That's rough. We
need a sub for center field.
Yeah. Shepherd, pitcher.
Shepherd's out. He told me his
brain surgery could be a marathon.
Oh! Me. Let me pitch.
Okay.
All right, Altman, pitcher. Yes.
Sloan, first.
Shepherd can be a pinch hitter.
Okay, Torres, you're on...
I need you to sign for this.
Bone plates and titanium
mesh? That's a lot of hardware.
I thought you said this guy's
hand wasn't salvageable.
Yeah, I'm gonna try and
rebuild it. It's gonna be really cool.
April, meet me in the OR.
I need a small.
They're all larges. What?
No. We can't be
out of smalls already.
I told them we needed
an assortment of sizes.
I was very clear on the phone.
Sweet.
I'll look fantastic in this.
And when you look
good, you play good.
Am I right, Avery? You know it.
What the hell was that? What?
What, are you guys
pledging Delta Chi together?
No, Sloan's pretty
cool, actually.
He's been in such
a good mood lately,
he's letting me do
half his procedures.
He let me run the
burn center last night.
Neat.
Okay.
Okay, Grey, you're...
Winning is an
attitude. We're winners.
Yeah.
Okay, so this will
hold his hand in place
so I can see the
tendon and nerve gaps...
What the Chief doesn't realize
is that a lot of the work I do
makes it possible for these
surgeries to take place.
I mean, all the staffing
and scheduling...
I mean, so okay, maybe I'm
not in the OR all the time...
April. But I...
Do you want to be an
administrative assistant?
Is that what makes
your heart sing?
No, of course not.
Then stop being a whiner.
Stop hiding behind paperwork.
If you love it, do it.
Just get in the OR.
Okay? Don't sleep, don't eat.
Just do this.
Here.
You want me to place the k-wire?
Will it make your heart sing?
Yes. Yeah, right.
Okay, placing the wire.
Okay. You're a little
too far to the left.
Okay, I got it. Sorry.
There you go. Right
there. Good. That's all right.
I didn't do anything. I
swear. Damn it. No, just stop.
What's going on? I don't
know but his pressure's tanking.
I'm hanging blood.
It looks like
electrical alternans.
He's tamponading. What
the hell? Page cardio.
These things I need
done. Is that okay?
Thank you. Thank you.
Sorry.
What is that?
Uh, my mom's journal.
No, I know what it is.
Why do you have it?
Because it's my mom's journal.
Freeze it.
Intraluminal flap and
pericardial effusion.
Damn it. He's got a
dissection. That's why he fell.
It must have started
when he was on the truck.
He probably passed out.
We need to get Altman.
Why? Do we need to go...
Yes, we need to
open him right now.
Um, April, start
the thoracotomy.
What? Me? What are you doing?
Getting gowned and
gloved. Crack his chest.
But I'm assisting.
It's all right. I got
this. Go do your thing.
But I've never done
an aortic dissection.
April, crack his chest now.
10-blade.
Here you go, Doctor. Thank you.
Okay, here's the tear.
Okay, open the
aorta longitudinally.
Now, transect proximal
to the innominate artery.
Are you sure you
don't want to do this?
You're already there.
All right. What do we have?
A thoracic aortic dissection.
Kepner excised the defect
and he's going to need a graft.
All right. Let me get
scrubbed. You'll first assist.
Torres, can you clear out?
Can you work around me?
I mean, I'll move
if I have to, but...
Torres, I'm trying to...
I know, but trust me,
I'm saving his life, too.
Can you work around me? Fine.
Yang, why didn't you
just start the graft?
I didn't need to. Kepner had it.
Okay.
I've got some
of it, but I need to
change the angle
to get the rest of it.
Okay, let's release
the Mayfield, please.
I need you to hold the probe
steady so I can adjust the angle.
You're not taking it out?
It's too risky.
If we go outside of the track,
we could hit healthy brain tissue.
Come on. Take the probe.
Hold it still. Move it even
one millimeter, it's over.
Ready? Let's give it a whirl.
Okay, good. I think...
The tumor's dropped into the
field. Let's tighten the device.
Okay. Good job.
Okay, let's start
the aspiration.
Very slowly.
Go ahead.
Heart rate's 130.
What's happening?
The tumor is pulling
on the hypothalamus.
Push 20 of labetalol, please.
Grey, hold the retractor.
Let me take this.
Heart rate's 160.
Damn it. I'm pulling
out the probe.
But you just said we're not g...
We don't have a choice.
What do we do now?
There's still tumor left.
We try again.
Why didn't you just start the
graft yourself? Why'd you wait?
Is this a trick question?
No. I'm asking.
Come on. Now I'm in
trouble for waiting for you?
You would've ripped me
a new one if I did it myself.
Two months ago, you
would've bodychecked Kepner
in order to get into
this guy's chest,
and now you let her
just do the surgery?
And you don't even like Kepner.
This is true.
Yes, I could've done it
myself, but she had it.
Exactly.
I'm done here.
Okay, then could you
girls take it outside?
Some of us have
a long way to go.
I give up. I have no idea
what you're trying to do.
I am in trouble if I cut.
I'm in trouble if I don't cut.
I'm a fifth year who
does the work of an intern.
What do you want?
I want you to make a list.
Okay, where on a blackboard?
"I will not do any surgeries
without a safety helmet."
I want you to make
a list of every surgery
that you have ever
dreamed of performing.
Mmm-hmm.
Shoot for the moon, and
I will try to get you some.
Because we're done.
You've graduated.
This is your present.
You're messing with me.
All right, you know, at
the beginning of this year,
you nearly killed
Alex Karev in that OR.
Because you just
had to get in there,
you had to be the best,
and you had to be first.
But today...
Today I saw a different surgeon,
every bit as good,
every bit as advanced,
but you were willing
to work on a team.
Today...
You put the patient
before yourself.
And that...
Is who I wanted to see. So...
You're done.
Make a list.
What...
What the hell are you
doing in here? One second.
In a second, I'm a
kick you in your sorry...
I just need to see
if the cell survived.
Yes! Yes! The cell survived.
What are you talking about?
My mom was wrong. It's oxygen.
The cells aren't
getting enough oxygen.
She extrapolated the amount
delivered based on tests with mice,
but the internal structure
of an islet cell of a mouse
is completely different
than that of a human.
Her hypothesis was wrong.
That's why the islet cells
in your device are dying.
I marked the page for you.
You mean it's
gone? You got it all?
Yes, we won't know where
we are for a couple of days...
But yeah, I did. I got it all.
Wait. So, what?
So no more seizures, and
she won't freak out anymore?
She is a teenager, so
chances are she might.
Yeah, but not
because of the tumor.
The fingers...
They're all there.
I had to build you a
new skeletal framework,
jerry-rigged some wire
through these bolts here,
but yeah, saved your hand.
Will it work?
It should.
There'll be some follow-up
surgery and physical therapy...
A lot of physical therapy,
but you should
regain full mobility.
I...
It's beautiful.
Thank you.
See? I told you
she was an artist.
Uh, Mr. Brentner?
Yes?
How am I doing?
Uh...
Someone will be in to
speak with you shortly.
Look, I'm sorry to bother you,
but I need to talk to you
about something else.
You have a kid on your
docket, Zola. She's from Africa...
I'm sorry, but I can't
discuss a case...
Look, just hear me out. I'm
Zola's doctor. She's got spina bifida.
Two doctors want to adopt
her. They're just waiting to hear.
But for weeks now, she's
been stuck in a foster home.
This is highly inappropriate.
A sick kid like that shouldn't
be with a foster family.
She needs to be in a stable home
with good parents,
these parents.
Without that, she's
only gonna get worse.
- Excuse me. Nurse? I need...
- I'll be right with you.
Don't bother. I'm leaving,
okay? I'm leaving. Just...
All I'm asking for you to do
is to take a look at this case.
That's it. Please
just take a look.
Doctor.
Attempting to influence a
judge is a federal offense.
Let's go, Shepherd!
Yeah!
Aw!
All right. All right. All right,
Karev, you're on second.
Let's get out there and
get it back. We can do it.
We are down 8-0.
We're screwed. He
should just call it now.
The new Chief's got
something to prove.
You still got your...
Yeah.
All right, come on,
Brechman! You can do it!
Come on, dude! Ring it up!
- Here we go! Here we go!
Hit it out of the park!
Hit it out of the
park! That's right!
He's got it. He's got it.
- All right.
- Yeah, you do!
Go! Yeah!
- Keep your eye on it.
- Here we go!
Get the walk!
Mmm.
Off-pump quintuple
cabbage. Do you have a pen?
What are you doing?
I'm making a list.
Teddy told me to make
a bucket list of surgeries.
I kept the faith, Mer. Who
thought that would pay off?
It's not paying off for me.
My faith is currently
out of the office.
Maybe I cured diabetes, though.
Your mom would've been proud.
No, she wouldn't.
Probably not.
Oh, God.
Here we go. WOMAN:
Show 'em your stuff.
Seriously? Really?
You want to pitch?
Whoa! Hey! What are
you doing out here?
I'm a roving
outfielder. I'm roving.
I'm roving. I'm...
Yes! Yes!
My God! It's coming here!
I got it! I got it!
Get it! Get it!
Get it! I got it!
Ball hog!
I had that. Oh, did you?
Or were you gonna let it
fall to the ground again?
What is your problem with me?
I beg your pardon?
I don't want on
your stupid trial.
I just need to get
it out of my head.
No, Mer... Are you drunk?
She is. We are.
So, what is your problem?
What is my problem?
All right, I'll tell
you my problem.
My problem is you.
Everywhere I look,
you're all in my trial,
coming in my lab,
opening my doors...
What's going on out
there? I'm not sure.
Time-out. I got this, Hunt.
Can he do that?
He seems to think he can.
Oh, this must be pretty
humiliating for you.
Yeah, you're gonna look so hot
when you get tagged out at home plate.
Oh, in your dreams.
God, get a room.
It's disgusting.
Give the guy a break.
She's on the opposing team.
So what? He seems happy.
He's happy, I'm happy.
And you and me,
we're happy, right?
Oh, what is with the friggin'
holdup? Let's play ball!
You are reckless
and irresponsible...
But it was between me and
the Chief and my husband,
so mind your own damn business!
You are not the boss of me.
Oh, thank God for that.
We're lucky to even be
able to have a trial after you...
Shut up! The both of you.
Now you, you
have a lot of nerve,
rubbing Meredith's nose in her
mistakes when you can't fix your own.
Your trial is failing.
Like it or not, you need her.
And you, even your mom, the
great Ellis Grey, made a mistake.
You fixed hers.
Now fix your own.
Get out of those
ridiculous pink scrubs
and get back to the
work you were born to do.
Now the two of you are gonna
figure out a way to work together,
but you're not gonna
do it on this field.
You'll do it Monday morning
in the lab. Is that clear?
Yes. Mmm-hmm.
Play ball!
We playing ball.
Playing ball.
That's gonna make it 12-0.
How long are we
gonna let this go on for?
She'll get there. If she can just
get a better drive off the mound...
She's terrible. Yeah, she sucks.
Oh! Want to call it, Hunt?
Team's looking a little tired.
Wouldn't want anyone
napping in the OR.
The last thing you guys
need is a malpractice suit.
All right. We're
pulling the pitcher.
Shepherd, get your glove.
No, no, not me. Lexie, get
your glove. Run out there.
Great job, hon. You
threw a really good game.
Come on. Let's go
ice your shoulder.
No. I'm just warming
up. Get outta here.
Come on. There's beer.
Now come on. No.
Let me try again.
Honey, we're
running out of time.
No, no way. We got
like five more innings.
No, I'm running out of time.
Is this really how you want to
spend our last few moments together?
Give me the ball. I can
feel my device failing.
Come on.
I hate you so much. I know.
All right, all right.
Time-out. Time-out.
- You just took a time-out.
- Another one?
Are you kidding me?
Bring it in. Huddle up.
All right.
I just want to say how
proud I am of all of you.
You are an incredible team.
Now who's drunk? Get off.
I've watched you work together,
solve problems together.
I watched you teach each
other and learn from each other.
You step up when
you need to and you...
You do more than
anyone asks you to do.
You're the finest team
I've ever been a part of.
My God. DEREK: What
are you talking about?
- That's really sad.
- Beautiful.
You don't think we actually
have a shot at winning this.
What, this? This? No,
no, no, we're screwed.
You are all horrible at
softball. But as doctors,
you're pretty great, and I am
proud just to get to lead you,
and you're all
here, so I just...
I just wanted to tell you.
But now...
Now we're going down.
So what do you say
we go down fighting?
Yes!
One, two, three.
Go, team!
Yeah! All right!
Here we go. Here we go.
All right. Come on, guys!
Let's go, Lexie!
You can do this!
Come on! Here we go!
Good game.
Spread out!
There it is.
No arm! No arm.
This is your relief pitcher?
My grandma's not busy,
she can pitch better than that.
Right in the boob. MARK: Lexie!
What? I thought she
was stealing second.
For the love of God!
She's a surgeon, Hunt.
That could've been
her hand. I'm calling it!
So, okay. So you forfeit?
No, we killed you. Game over!
You forfeit. That was a forfeit.
So we may not always be winners.
But we're not lazy.
We take chances.
We go for broke.
We swing for the fences.
And sometimes, yeah,
we strike out.
Thank you, guys, for
letting me be your ringer.
Although, I didn't
really ring much.
It was more like a thunk, but...
All right, will you
take me home?
I will take you home.
Come on. We've got
Mark as a sitter, so...
I'm taking you home.
His girlfriend's
gonna be okay, right?
Ah, it's her boob.
She's in good hands.
Are you gonna tell me
what that was about or what?
Yeah, I thought she
was stealing second.
No, you didn't.
Shh.
I think I hear my heart singing.
Can you hear that?
La, la... Are you drunk?
Yeah, I'll give you a ride home.
Be in the lab before rounds.
I will.
Good job, Chief.
You made it
through four innings.
Two more than any
team I've ever fielded.
Can I do a
heterotopic transplant?
Tonight? No.
Good call. You're a good Chief.
Come on.
Good night.
I'm good. You're fine, too.
That was a massacre.
Yeah.
I don't think we did that bad.
Oh, yeah.
Where were you yesterday?
I was doing stuff.
Why do you look so sad?
Don't be so sad. Look.
I just got a message from Janet.
I guess the judge
got in touch with her.
He's looking at Zola's files.
We're gonna get a court date.
We're getting a hearing?
We have a hearing.
We got a hearing.
We're getting a hearing.
Oh, come on.
But sometimes,
ya get a home run.