♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
Good morning, Georgia.
So it's a big day.
It's a big, big day.
Um, your sisters are coming.
So I won't be around
as much as usual
because I'm gonna be
helping your mama.
But I'm gonna make sure that
your aunts and uncles stop by
to see you.
So if you need anything,
you know, just ask, okay?
The babies are okay?
I got the nicu on standby.
Babies are fine.
Nobody needs to worry.
You know,
they're still premature.
Yeah, but multiples
usually are.
I mean, they're healthy enough
for delivery now.
They're just not in any rush,
you know?
We don't want to hurry things
along with early babies.
So how long?
Well, she's at 4 centimeters now,
and she can't push
until she's at 10,
could be in labor
for another day.
Ooh.
Oh, god help us all.
Look on the bright side.
More time to vote on names.
Would you put Zoe
on that board?
No, do not put Zoe
on the board.
Wait.
Don't cross out Hannah.
I like Hannah.
"Hannah and her sisters"?
There'd be no end
to the merciless teasing.
By whom, all the die-hard
Woody Allen fans in preschool?
Someone put Autumn
and summer up there?
Come on, guys.
We're better than this.
With names like that,
it's hard to keep
your daughter off the pole.
Hey!
The only people
who can vote on a name
are Mason
and those who provided
genetic material.
So unless
one of you looky-loos
knows a way to fast-track
this delivery,
get the hell outta here.
Thanks.
Hi.
Can you make me
some kind of basket
with all these books
and, I don't know,
some little stuffed animal
or something?
A gift basket--
can you do that?
I'm the owner.
I can do whatever.
Whose the lucky baby?
They're triplets.
My best friend. He's hav--
well, his wife
is having triplets.
♪ I lost regardless ♪
Is there a total or...
Wait.
♪ It goes for a long time ♪
♪ now how we got so wise ♪
This is you.
Yes, it is.
Will you sign it?
Sure.
♪ How do you're doing ♪
You must have
an amazing memory for faces.
No. I've, um...
Read the book five times.
It's incredible.
A real honest memoir.
It felt like poetry.
And I used to look
at your picture on the back
because, uh--
the scar, I know. Everybody
always looks at the scar.
No, it's... just that,
after all
you've been through,
there was just...
Such a light in your eyes.
You were so beautiful.
Are so beautiful.
♪ Calling you night,
stay opposing between ♪
Wow.
♪ Your fingers ♪
Well, thank you.
Charles.
Thank you, Charles.
Your total...
♪ Stay around you ♪
Can I ask you, the--the husband
that was in the book,
are you and he still--
he's--he's dead.
I'm sorry for your loss.
I'm...
I'm gonna come back and--
and, uh, pick this up later.
So if you just want
to put it into a basket,
I'll--I'll pick it up later.
♪ Fix your eyes upon ♪
♪ the writing between them ♪
Happy
formal adoption hearing day.
And, yes, I get why there's
no greeting card for that one.
Thank you.
So listen, I've got
two more patients,
and then I'm clear
for the rest of the day.
Should Henry and I come by
here and pick you up?
Well, actually, I was gonna
go home and get him ready,
but that depends on Charlotte.
Her babies are taking
their sweet time.
Okay. Well,
when we're done with court,
why don't we go
to the park?
I think swings and ice cream
is a perfect way to celebrate.
I've got a camera in the car.
The judge can take
some pictures for us.
Mm.
What's that for?
For loving Henry...
And me.
Thank you.
♪ You ♪
Good. Breathe.
Shut--
focus through it.
Oh, shut up.
Brought you
some more ice chips.
Okay,
let's take a look,
see how you're doing.
Oh, I'm a hot air balloon
about to pop.
Must be 6 centimeters by now.
5 at least.
Mm. 4 and a smidge.
80% effaced.
You sure you know
what you're doing down there?
You are doing great,
Charlotte.
Of course she is.
Ugh. Don't touch me.
What the hell
are you still doing here?
Mason has a half day
of school, remember?
You need to pick him up.
I asked Amelia
to pick him up.
Oh, I'd rather
she were here with me
and you were with Mason.
You're the one who got me
into this mess.
If Addison leaves a sharp
instrument laying around,
I just might stab you
with it.
May I go?
It's gonna be
another four hours...
At least.
Oh. All right. I'll be back.
I need some more juice.
Okay. I'll have Brenda
get you some.
Why Brenda?
I-I've been here all night. I'm
off the clock in ten minutes.
Well... I'm sure you have
a big day planned.
So go ahead. Enjoy it.
Matter of fact, why don't
you knock off early?
Just because you're the best
labor and delivery nurse
in this hospital,
and you've been with me
all through my pregnancy,
and I hired you,
there is no reason
you should be here
to help me get to the end.
Not everyone's able
to see things through.
One juice
coming right up.
Subtle.
My middle name.
Hey.
Are the babies born yet?
Not yet.
It's gonna be
a few more hours,
which is making your mama
extra cranky.
Hello.
Oh, hi.
Uh-huh.
Uh, today?
No, no, no. It's great.
Yeah. Bye.
What?
Okay. I put an offer in
on a house--
did they counter?
How do you know about
counteroffers?
Natalie's mom's
a real estate agent.
The seller doesn't want
any more money,
but another family put in
the same offer.
She wants to meet both families
and then decide.
So it's like sudden death.
Yeah, but it's gonna be
like my death,
because they want
to do it now,
but I can't do it now
because Charlotte's in labor.
But if we don't do it now,
we're not gonna have a place
for this enormous family
to live.
This is called
a lose-lose.
If I'm not there
for the birth of my babies,
Charlotte's gonna string me up
by my toes in the living room.
Our living room
isn't big enough.
Which is why
we need a house, Mason!
Dad, take a deep breath.
You're 10. How'd you get
so sensible?
Is the house near here?
It's not far.
All right. Well,
let's go win the house,
then we'll go to the hospital
and surprise mama.
Okay, if she yells at me...
I'm blaming you.
You know, you...
You are one lucky lady,
you know that?
You've got your entire life
ahead of you.
One big blank slate.
I mean,
I'm kind of envious of you.
You're brave, fearless.
I mean, you probably know what
it took me years to figure out.
You gotta live your life
to the fullest.
You can't be afraid
to make mistakes.
And I'm trying to do that now.
I...
I just hope
it's not too late.
Okay.
Good talk.
Thanks.
Hey.
Did Charlotte have
the babies?
Not even close.
She must be pissed.
You have no idea.
I've been
walking the halls with her,
trying to move
the labor along.
You're hanging out
with her?
Of course.
She's my friend.
Oh.
I just figured being around her
would be hard for you,
because of your history.
Oh.
No.
No, I'm fine.
It's--it's okay.
Good.
Mm.
I'm glad. That's good.
What?
Nothing. I was just--
I'm glad to hear
you're doing fine.
So then...
Do you ever think about--
I mean, not right now, but...
Do you want to have kids?
Dr. Peterson, you've got
a head lac in curtain two.
Be right there.
Keep me posted
about Charlotte?
Sure. Yeah.
I have never once
heard him say "quiet."
It's always "taciturn."
I caught him reading
a dictionary
in his office once.
An expansive vocabulary is
the bedrock of sagacity.
Yes, but if you actually
want people to understand you,
you might have to
dumb it down a bit.
Ooh. I like her,
Sheldon.
Where'd you two meet?
At a vending machine.
She was having trouble
with a chocolate bar,
and I assisted her.
That's true.
He was very chivalrous
with some loose change.
Thank you.
Oh, looks delicious.
Tell me
what I want to hear.
I know this has been
unpleasant for you,
but you are
in the home stretch,
and you've been...
A real trooper
these last several months.
I've been a trooper?
Honestly, no.
But I just wanted to say
something nice to you.
You're at 6 centimeters.
Ugh. I hate you.
Hey.
Shouldn't you
be getting Henry ready?
I can't leave yet.
It's today?
Henry's adoption hearing?
Well, get the hell out.
Charlotte--
don't "Charlotte" me.
First of all, Cooper's spawn
aren't actually coming out
until Henry's
college graduation--
Charlotte, you are
having your babies.
You are legally having
your own baby today, too.
So go on. Shoo.
All right, but if your labor
starts to progress
more rapidly--
I'll have Jake.
You didn't think you were
both leaving, did you?
Of course not.
I'm just gonna--
I'm gonna walk Addison out.
So no swings or ice cream
or pictures with the judge.
Well, we'll get the bailiff to
take pictures with the judge,
and there will be swings
and ice cream, just later.
Listen, you have no idea
how badly I wanted to be there,
but we can't--
we can't leave Charlotte
with some poor,
unsuspecting doctor.
She'll eat 'em alive.
I know. I just--
I don't know.
I was just really
looking forward to celebrating.
Well, listen,
you and Henry and I
have the rest of our lives
to celebrate.
Your job right now
is to go to court
and bring back our son.
Jake...
You just said "our son."
Damn right, I did.
Mm.
Go.
Okay. Okay.
Thank you. Mm.
I shouldn't be surprised
by his question.
I'm a woman.
I have the plumbing.
I love kids.
But what if my body
only makes brainless babies?
I couldn't
live through that again.
And even if I was lucky enough
to have a healthy child,
I know things now.
It doesn't matter
how fiercely you love someone.
It's not enough.
The world can be terrifying,
and bad things happen that
you're powerless to prevent.
I'm done.
I don't want to have
any more babies.
Ugh.
They are unbelievable.
Treating my uterus
like it's some kind
of airport v.I.P. Lounge.
So let's see
what's going on.
Oh, I need some
good news, Jake.
All right.
And you're at 7 centimeters.
Oh, nice.
We're getting closer.
Closer my ass.
Come on. I'm desperate.
Can't you charm 'em out
or somethin'?
They're girls.
Girls like you.
Just get down there and say
whatever it is you say to women
that gets 'em all
in a tizzy.
Your boyfriend's lurking.
Oh, go.
But be back
in 15 minutes.
Underneath
that awful exterior,
you really are just a softie,
aren't you?
Shh.
If they hear
you, they'll never mind me.
Okay.
Look... I need you
on your best behavior, okay?
Look interested,
pay attention,
and if the nice lady asks you
any questions at all, you--
no eye rolling,
grunting, or nodding.
Use my words. I got this.
Okay, I know you got it.
It's just--
I really want to win, okay?
We are gonna win.
We're so much better
than the other family.
Oh, I forgot.
What?
You need to...
Ohh, mother of god.
This is a bad one.
This is, uh, the double platinum
of contractions.
Otherwise,
I'd come help you.
I'm sorry.
I should be helping you.
I just--
I needed a place to hide.
I can't be crying
in the middle of the hospital.
Oh, it's my hospital.
You can do whatever the...
Oh! You can do whatever
you damn well please.
Oh.
It should be over
in the next millennium,
and I'll ask you
what's wrong.
Oh, don't worry about me.
I'm fine. I'm okay.
I just--i just can't...
I just can't stop crying.
Why won't it stop?
I've been asking my uterus
that same thing, sister.
Aah!
Hello there, young man.
You must be Henry.
He is, your honor.
And this is
Dr. Addison Forbes Montgomery,
the adoptive parent.
Oh, I see you work at
St. ambrose, Dr. Montgomery.
That's right.
But not so much that it would
be a problem for Henry.
I--sorry. I'm...
I'm a little nervous.
No need.
Birth mother signed away
parental rights.
Home visits completed.
What's going on?
Your honor?
Your social worker
Mildred clemons
just faxed this letter.
It seems
she has some concerns.
Wh-what concerns?
I don't understand.
I'm sorry, Dr. Montgomery.
I can't finalize
Henry's adoption today.
I'm ordering
further evaluation.
We'll set another court date,
and I'll make a ruling then.
Wh-wh-what does that mean?
What just happened?
I don't know.
Normally this hearing
is a formality.
Did something happen
with Mildred?
No, I haven't seen her
in months.
Was there anything unusual
about her last visit?
No, no. She--she just
met with...
Jake.
Okay.
I'll talk to the judge
and try and find out
exactly what's going on
and how we should proceed.
Wait, wait.
Is there a chance--
I mean, could I...
Could I lose Henry?
Try not to grow up
too fast, okay?
Because little girls
who grow up too fast
end up running off with
their college professors,
which you and I both know
is entirely inappropriate.
And we also know that
cutting off communication
with your father
because he showed
a little concern
over your emotional well-being
is, well...
Let's just say
I'll be recommending
a good private school
to your mom and dad--
one with only female teachers,
possibly a convent.
It really is
such an amazing home.
I just want whoever
lives here next
to Cherish this place
like we did,
respect its history.
Yeah.
History's
my favorite subject.
Do you know what started
world war I?
Uh...
The assassination
of archduke ferdinand.
And his wife Sophie.
Oh.
You are so darling.
Hello?
Yoo-hoo.
Hi.
Dan and Darlene meyer.
I know we're early,
but we got a call to serve food
at the mission later,
and we just didn't want
to miss this opportunity.
We love this house.
Ohh.
Well, this is Dr. Freedman
and his son Mason.
Hi. Cooper Freedman.
Hi.
Hi, Mason.
They're the other family
that's bidding on the house.
Nice to meet you...
Oh.
And your pie.
Apple pie?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, well...
It's not blueberry,
but, you know...
Um...
So you're a doctor?
Yes. Dr. Freedman.
Pediatrician.
Mm.
I just love helping children.
It's a calling, really.
Yeah, I was--i was premed.
Oh.
Yeah, but then I met Dan
when we were volunteering
at a women's shelter.
And I don't know.
Four years of medical school
and internship, residency--
it just felt like
it would take too long
to actually make a difference
in the world.
Mm.
You know?
Yeah.
Well, that is so lovely.
Walter and I like to go
to children's hospital
on the weekends
and visit with the kids.
So inspiring.
We help out
with their annual fund-raiser.
Mm-hmm.
Oh. Oh!
You are
that Dan and Darlene meyer?
That's us.
Guilty.
Oh. I have seen your names
on the program.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
You've gotta be kidding me.
Well... Who would
like a piece of pie?
- Thank you. Oh, I would.
- Yes.
You know the one good thing
about dying of cancer?
I don't have to worry
about sunscreen anymore.
Oh, hilarious. Yeah.
So lunch wasn't so bad,
right?
Violet's great.
If all your friends
are that great,
it makes me feel bad
that we're lying to them.
Well, we did meet
at a vending machine, right?
I'm not lying to Violet.
Sheldon...
I don't know how much time
I have left,
and I want to know
that you're gonna be okay
when I'm gone.
So you gotta talk
to someone.
You gotta tell them
about the cancer and about me.
I'm not ready to think about
you being gone.
♪♪♪
They're your friends.
Just... let them in.
Okay?
♪ and, oh, I've got you
in my veins ♪
♪♪♪
♪ I never knew ♪
Ohh.
Amelia, go get Jake.
You don't need Jake.
I'll decide what I need.
I'm the one having
the freakin' contraction.
Stephanie just checked you.
You're, like, 7 centimeters.
Big whoop.
You're like the uterus
that cried wolf.
Your...
Bedside manner sucks.
My bedside manner
is awesome.
You're just not having
those babies anytime soon.
♪♪♪
Come here.
Sit back.
Ooh.
My god.
How did you know?
Jake did this for me
when I was in labor.
♪♪♪
I'm sorry. I didn't...
Just lean back.
♪ And the light
spilled through ♪
♪ Comes spilling out to you ♪
Hey.
♪ Spinning out again ♪
Violet?
Oh. Oh. Oh, my gosh.
Ooh. Sorry about that.
Sorry. Are you okay?
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
You sure?
Well, I normally go
to Cooper
for these sorts of things,
but he's a little busy.
Well, I'm here.
Lay it on me.
Uh...
Well, I went to a-a bookstore
this morning
to get a present
for the cooplets,
and, um, the owner
of the bookstore
was this
very attractive man.
And, uh, he recognized me
from my book.
Okay. I wrote a book.
I don't get recognized
very much, but, uh,
it never gets old.
Right? So he recognized me,
and then he flirted with me.
Uh-oh.
And i--
I flirted--
I flirted back a little.
And then he asked me
what happened
to the guy in the book.
Pete.
And, Sam...
I forgot all about him.
For the three or four minutes
I was flirting with this guy,
I just--i forgot
Pete ever existed.
I forgot he was dead.
I-I forgot--i forgot him.
Well, that's normal.
Right?
Isn't that a normal step
in the grieving process?
Yeah. Yeah.
But it was just so...
I mean, look,
Charlotte is having
her babies today,
and I was so happy
for her.
I am. I'm so happy
for her and Cooper.
Mm-hmm.
But then I go
to this bookstore,
and I see my book about
this super awesome time
when a lady cut my baby
out of my belly.
And then I remember
Pete is dead.
And then I see you
and Stephanie,
and you guys
are so sweet together.
And then Sheldon
has found Miranda,
and she's just lovely
with him.
And then Addison and Jake,
and it--everybody's living.
And I just keep having
these waves
where I start to cry
and I can't stop.
And--and so I was
at this bookstore
with this attractive man.
And I had this moment, Sam,
where I just...
I just knew...
I'm never gonna have
another child.
My whole experience
of having a child
is Katie stealing my baby.
I'm never
gonna get married again.
My entire experience
of marriage was Pete,
and that was so... I mean,
some of it was good,
but most of it
was pretty painful.
So that entire part
of my life, it's...
It's done.
And I want to forget him.
I was angry
that I remembered him.
Because when I remember him,
it feels like I'm dying, too.
So this is it.
This is my life.
This is who I am.
This is--
this is all I get.
And I think,
you know, is it...
Is it enough?
♪♪♪
Is it anything?
Mm.
Well...
I don't know--
I don't know what to say.
I don't have
anything to say.
I mean, instead of saying,
you know, some random cliche...
♪♪♪
How about
I just give you a hug?
No, i-i, you know,
I'm just gonna cry again.
Well, then I get cried on.
Come on. Give me a hug.
♪♪♪
Oh, wait a minute.
I think I do
have something to say,
and it's not random...
Or cliched.
You--you want to hear it?
Okay.
♪♪♪
You're not done.
All right?
You're--you're unfinished.
You're a work in progress.
I mean, if I had told you
five years ago
that you were gonna have Lucas
the way that you did
or that you
were gonna marry Pete,
you would've laughed
in my face, right?
If I'd have told you
two years ago
that you'd be a widow,
you would never
have believed me.
Because you don't know
what tomorrow brings.
You know,
it could be anything.
I mean, absolutely anything.
It could be good.
It could be bad.
It, uh...
It could be this
hot bookstore owner guy
or it could just be you
and your amazing little boy.
But you don't know
because you're not done.
I mean, you won't know
the point of the book
until it's written.
The--the book
that is your life
is a work in progress.
So you, Violet Turner,
you're unfinished.
Yeah.
How was that?
That was really,
really good.
Yes.
You should write a book.
What did you do?
I am Henry's mother.
You're not the problem.
It's your fiance
that worries me.
He beat a man
nearly to death.
A drug dealer.
When you feel threatened,
you call 9-1-1.
Henry cannot live
in an environment
where violence
is an acceptable solution.
Jake was trying
to protect his family.
He's a good man. He would
never hurt anyone, Mildred.
Tell that to the man
he threatened to kill.
No, no.
You misunderstood.
Jake's daughter is dating her
much-older college professor,
and he...
He just got upset.
He was a good deal more
than upset.
If this was an issue,
why didn't you
say something sooner?
Seeing you with Henry
is what we dream about
when we place children,
so I approved the adoption.
But after meeting Dr. Reilly,
I thought I could get past
my concerns.
I have to be dispassionate
and consider
what's best for the child.
I am what's best
for Henry.
And if Henry were living
with you alone,
I wouldn't have
an objection.
Please.
I can't lose my son.
I'm sorry, Dr. Montgomery.
I've already made
my recommendation.
Now it's up to the judge.
"And the brave prince
"married the beautiful
fairy Princess,
and together, they lived
happily ever after."
I know.
I should've read the blue one
about the trains.
Fairy tales are just...
Well, they're just stupid,
you know?
And people should not
read them to their children.
It sets them up
for false expectations.
It makes them think
that happily ever after
is the end of the story.
It's not like that,
you know?
Real relationship stories...
Are messy.
Real relationship stories
sometimes have a dead prince
and a grieving Princess
who sobs in public.
And they don't end.
Sam says there's no ending,
and I choose to believe him
because a dead prince
can't be the ending.
God, you are so tiny.
I hope you never know
what I'm talking about.
I hope
you never have a dead prince.
Ah!
Oh!
If you tell me
I'm still at 7 centimeters,
I swear, I'll kill you.
Nope, you're at 10.
Page Addison, please.
You got it.
Wait.
This is it?
Yep.
If you feel like it...
Ah!
You can start to push.
Oh, I can't. I need Coop.
Amelia...
I know.
They're coming.
Oh, where the freakin' hell
is my husband?
I'll find him.
Oh.
Right from that first day,
I knew that Darlene
was the woman I wanted to
spend the rest of my life with.
Dr. Freedman,
where did you meet your wife?
Wasn't it on a web site?
No.
No, we met
at St. ambrose hospital,
where she is chief of staff.
Hmm,
that can't be easy.
There's so much bureaucracy
in the practice of medicine.
Yeah, and price gouging.
Price gouging?
Well, I'm sorry, Dr. Freedman.
Most people can't afford
any kind of medical care.
Well, I treat my patients
regardless.
But you don't practice
for free, right?
Well, I save children.
Uh, would you like
to hear about the schools
in the neighborhood?
Amelia.
Okay. We're on our way.
We gotta go.
But we're totally winning.
Sorry.
Um, look, I...
Really want to buy this house
for my wife as a surprise
because I love it,
she would love it.
And she's been through so much
and she really deserves it.
And Mason and my girls, they
could have a happy life here.
But as much as I want to live
in this amazing house,
I cannot be here right now,
um, because my wife
is in labor with triplets,
and I have to be there
with her, okay?
So I mean,
family is everything.
If we end up living
in a tent by the stream,
as long as we're together,
it's gonna be fine.
So it was nice to meet you...
But we gotta go.
Hey there. You feel like
having some babies?
No. Not without Cooper.
He's on his way.
So how'd it go?
Was it, uh,
was it amazing?
It was fine.
You don't look like
it was fine.
Well, I have two babies
to deliver,
so if you could move...
Okay.
Oh, yeah. These babies aren't
waiting for their daddy.
I need Cooper.
Well, you're gonna feel better
once you start pushing,
Charlotte.
No, I can't do it
without him.
Sorry. Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
Totally explain.
Shut the hell up
and hold my hand.
Thank god.
My hand is numb.
All righty. Here we go.
Give me a push.
Aah!
Charlotte's delivering, huh?
Finally.
She's been running Stephanie
ragged all day.
So you and Stephanie
are back on, huh?
Yeah.
Yeah. Well, good.
Good for you.
I'm seeing someone, too.
Her name is Miranda.
Oh, that's great, Sheldon.
Yeah.
All right.
I met her at radiation.
I did
eight weeks of treatment.
Now I gotta wait
another six months
before I know if it works,
but, uh...
I'm hopeful.
How you feeling?
Pretty good for a guy whose
prostate glows in the dark.
Well, I'm glad
you got treatment.
Yeah, I have a friend
who was a real pain in the ass
about it.
So anyway, uh...
Thank you.
Ohh.
Okay, Charlotte,
I need you to push.
Good.
Almost there.
Get them out!
You're so close.
Oh, don't tell me I'm close
when I still got
two babies inside me.
All right, Charlotte,
I need you to keep pushing.
Now focus.
Aah!
Good.
Ohh. Ohh.
She's crying.
She's okay?
She's perfect.
If this is, uh,
if this is too hard
for you...
No.
It's amazing.
Aah!
Ohh!
Something's not right.
Addison, talk to me.
I can't feel the head.
Is she in breech?
No, she's not upside down.
She's sideways.
Can you just do
a c-section?
It is an option,
but I still feel like
I can deliver vaginally.
There are significant risks.
The baby is transverse.
Yeah, but there's risks
with any procedure,
including c-section.
Look, Charlotte, your body's
been through enough trauma
and so have the babies.
I still think I can deliver
by doing
an internal podalic version.
What the hell is that?
She rotates the baby
until she can grab a foot,
and then she delivers her
as a breech.
Wait. Is that... I mean,
can you even do that?
Yes, Cooper. I can do it.
And is it safe?
Cooper, you know they couldn't
be in better hands.
Charlotte, it's easier
on your body than surgery
and it won't take very long,
but it's gonna hurt like hell.
Okay. Just get on with it.
Yeah? All right.
Let's get her ready.
Okay.
I'll stabilize her legs.
Okay, now you can't push
until I tell you,
but you can scream.
And you can squeeze.
All right?
So on the count of three.
Mm-hmm.
One, two, three.
Squeeze.
Oh, god!
Ohh!
Aah!
Almost there.
I can't. It's too much.
Okay, listen to me.
Listen to me.
You can do this, okay?
You can.
I just want it to be over.
It's about to be over.
You are so strong.
Our girls are gonna be
just like you.
So come on. You gotta
do this right now.
Your little girl
wants to meet you, okay?
Okay. Okay. I've got
the baby turned.
Just give me a push now.
Aah!
Good. All right. Stop.
Stop. Stop. Stop. Stop.
No more pushing.
Is that good?
She's got the body, okay?
But the head is still inside.
Just give her a minute,
okay?
Please. I'm so exhausted.
I know. I know you are,
but you're almost there.
Just a few more seconds.
Okay, now. Push.
Aah!
Okay. Okay. Good.
I got her.
Oh, god.
Hi.
Hi, baby.
Let me see you.
You want to cut
the cord, Cooper?
Yeah.
Hey, she's got your eyes.
Hi, sweetheart.
Hi. Hi.
Hi, baby girl.
Okay.
Let me take her away now.
Oh.
There we go.
She wants her mama.
You got her?
Got her.
Hey.
So what happened in court?
Mildred happened.
At the last minute,
she decided she couldn't...
She doesn't feel right
about the adoption.
What? I-I thought the hearing
was just a formality.
Not anymore.
The judge decided he wanted
to do further evaluation,
and then
he's going to decide...
Whether or not
I get to keep my son.
I-I don't understand.
Why would she...
Oh, god. No.
It's--it's me? My arrest.
And the thing with Angela.
Oh, Addison.
I'm so...
I'm so sorry. Hey.
Don't. Okay? I just--
right now, I-I can't.
I just--i know that this is--
this is not your fault.
I know that, but...
The judge could take Henry
from me, and...
I can't.
Charlotte had the babies.
That's great.
Is everybody okay?
They're amazing.
They're perfect.
Hey, hey, hey. Wh-what's--
what's going on?
Yes.
What?
The answer to your question
is yes, I want babies.
I want a lot of babies.
And I'm really scared
to want babies,
so I-I told myself
that I didn't, but I do.
Because it's a miracle.
And I really...
I really a need miracle.
So, yes, someday I want
to have babies with you.
Someday.
If we get that far.
We'll get that far.
You came back
for your basket.
I came back for my basket.
I'm glad.
Oh...
Wow.
I added some extra books--
uh, no charge--
just to fill it out
a little bit.
And then there's some books
every child should have,
so I threw those in, too.
You--you didn't have to--
it's--it's beautiful. Thanks.
I felt bad.
I made you feel sad,
and I didn't mean to.
No, no, no,
it wasn't you.
It was just...
It was me.
Okay.
You were actually
being really kind.
So would you like to get
a cup of coffee sometime
or--or a drink?
I can't go out with you.
I don't want to.
Okay.
I mean, no, it's not you.
I mean, you're lovely.
And I think if I was gonna
go out with anybody,
it would probably be you,
but--
but?
But i'm--
I'm trying to be okay
with just me right now.
And I don't wanna
mess that up
or cloud it or--
I understand.
You do?
I read your book five times.
And you're a very good writer,
so I understand perfectly.
We'll be friends.
All right.
Yeah, we'll be friends.
And thank you.
You know what?
I'm gonna write another book.
I just decided.
And you helped me decide,
so thank you.
Well, congratulations.
What are you gonna call it?
What?
The book.
What's its title?
Oh. Uh, I don't know yet.
It's, uh,
it's a work in progress.
Well, good luck.
Thank you.
Judge Harris, my name
is Dr. Jake Reilly.
I'm engaged to--
Dr. Addison Forbes Montgomery.
I know who you are.
And I know why you're here.
But I haven't made
my decision.
You can't decide what's best
for Henry without the facts.
I have them,
in a nice big red file.
That's not the whole story.
You can only get that
from me.
30 seconds.
Lily, my wife, my--
my late wife, was an addict.
She had a daughter--Angela--
who became our daughter.
Lily's dealer was
as close to the devil as...
He would kill for money.
He would--
he would kill for nothing.
And I had to protect
my family,
my... my child.
And all these years later?
I'm still protecting
my child.
When you have a kid,
it's--it's for life.
Doesn't matter
how old they are.
I was trying
to protect Angela,
and I would do the same
for Henry.
Consider yourself heard.
I'll leave her.
Addison loves that baby.
She...
She loves Henry more than
anything in the world,
and I love her
maybe even more than that,
so if you're going to
break them apart,
then I'll leave her.
I'll walk away.
But they
need to be together.
She's his mother.
♪ soul ♪
♪ the fullness in her stare ♪
♪ first of many reasons ♪
How about Caroline?
Was that on the board?
No, but... I think
that's her name.
I love it.
♪ Fills the air ♪
Hi.
Addison says Georgia
is well enough for a visit.
Hello, precious girl.
Look. It's mama.
Hi, sweet girl.
Georgia, this is Caroline.
Say hi.
Is that all right?
Come here.
Thank you, daddy.
That is--
that is perfect.
That leaves only one
unnamed king-Freedman.
What will we call
our little breech baby?
♪ For you ♪
Rachel?
Georgia,
Caroline, Rachel.
Oh, I love it.
Oh, my god!
Cooper.
Oh!
We got the house.
What?
What house?
The perfect house.
Dad wanted to surprise you,
but he didn't think
we would get it.
So we had to beat
the other couple
even though they were perfect,
and it's ours.
Oh, my god.
I bought a house.
We got a house.
I am sorry to break up
the party,
but we've gotta take the babies
back to the nursery now.
Oh, can't we have 'em
just a little longer?
Preemies need to be monitored.
And you'll see them again
first thing in the morning.
They need to sleep right now,
as do I.
We bought a house.
Well done, daddy.
Well, this has been
a good day.
Your mom and dad
officially have four kids.
I only want one.
I only want Henry.
I can't blame Mildred for
wanting what's best for Henry.
We're both
on the same side there.
But she's wrong
about Jake.
Jake is...
The best man
I've ever known.
He...
Is the man of my dreams.
Oh, yes, little one. Yeah.
♪ The fullness in her stare ♪
I'm afraid the judge
is gonna make me choose
between my love for Jake
and my love for Henry, but...
♪ We are ♪
If that happens...
There is no choice.
♪ Her color fills the air ♪
♪ it's hard to exist
when we're afar ♪
♪ she proclaims ♪
So...
When do you want
to get married?
Jake, were you not listening
to me?
We can't get married.
We can't do anything.
The judge said--
I know what the judge said.
I just came from
his chambers.
What... wait. What?
We had a little talk.
Turns out he's got
four daughters.
He told me
to give this to you.
♪♪♪
He's mine?
♪ Go ♪
♪ For you stay ♪
Henry's mine.
It's official.
So... when do you want
to get married?
Hmm?
♪ I will go ♪
♪ letting go ♪