I'm Dr. Browne, I'll be performing
your surgery today.
I'm Dr. Browne.
I'll be performing your surgery.
It's a very simple procedure.
It's a straightforward procedure.
♪ 'Cause I've never known
A love like this before ♪
It was a successful surgery.
♪ Baby, I know dreams
Tend to crumble at extremes ♪
The surgery was a success.
We expect a full recovery.
♪ We're surviving
We're still living ♪♪
I expect a full recovery.
Baby... where do you want this?
Uh, thanks, Mom. By my bag.
I'll have the lab run it.
Nausea and severe abdominal pain
after eating.
This patient could need a lap chole.
That would be an ideal first surgery.
Let's not get ahead of ourselves,
she may just need an antacid.
Hi, Michelle, I understand
your mother is on her way in.
- I'm Dr. Browne.
- I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
You need to fix my sister.
- What's your name?
- Tisha.
Hi, Tisha. Well, that is exactly
why we're here.
- To help your sister.
- Foster sister.
When did the pain start?
- About an hour ago.
- We was on the bus.
My sister rides with me every day
to school and back.
My brother and I
used to live on a bus.
Cool.
- Have you felt like this before?
- A few times.
Ow.
She has extreme
upper-right quadrant tenderness.
That's consistent with cholecystitis.
As is her fever
and elevated white count.
Your gallbladder probably needs
to be removed.
You must be excited, Claire, this is
going to be your first surgery.
Has your urine changed color?
Gotten darker?
I hear Dr. Browne might have
landed her first lap chole.
Not exactly a straightforward case.
The duct is massively dilated,
wall's inflamed,
this scarring,
it's gonna limit visibility.
The thickness of the gallbladder wall
does pose a challenge.
What do you think?
It's not her decision.
It's mine, the attending.
Doesn't mean she shouldn't offer
her opinion.
I think that, um... Dr. Melendez is right.
With the limited visibility
I shouldn't...
Only with a laparoscopic
cholecystectomy,
which I don't think we should do.
An open procedure would provide
a clear view of the gallbladder
and the surrounding anatomy
despite the inflammation.
Carly and I went on another date
last night.
Mm. What'd you do? Dinner? Movie?
We walked 12 minutes to a deli,
and had some food and talked.
- Where are we going?
- Andrews is starting an open chole.
Sounds like it's going well
with you and Carly.
Oh, yes.
She answered all of my questions.
- How many did you ask?
- Eighty-three.
Although, some had multiple parts.
"Do you want to have children?
If yes, how many and when?
Where do you plan to raise them?
In what religious tradition?"
Those are pretty intense.
They're good questions, Claire,
about important topics.
Early on, people usually stick
with lighter stuff.
Favorite movies, bands,
hometowns, small talk.
Put some laps
on the upper-right quadrant.
Here's the bovie.
Isn't the point of dating
to gather information
to determine compatibility?
- Retract the omentum.
- Sure.
Isn't that best achieved by finding out
what's important to the other person?
Hemostats.
It's a process, Shaun,
like peeling an onion.
People are more comfortable
revealing their layers gradually
as opposed to getting sliced right
down the middle.
I heard Dr. Lim selected you
for the first lead.
Guessing you drew a cholecystectomy.
Sponge on a stick.
What's your approach to dissecting,
retrograde or antegrade?
Antegrade, once I've located
the porta hepatis.
I think Carly was comfortable.
Why does it matter what kind of
questions are asked when?
- Aren't the answers what's important?
- I'm sure you're right.
- Yes.
- What is the plan for the next date?
Mm.
We didn't make another date.
Then I grasp gallbladder
fundus, and elevate it which way?
Superiorly. Is that significant?
No follow-up date?
Not necessarily. How did the
night end? Goodnight kiss?
Now I've exposed the triangle of Calot
and ligated the cystic duct and artery.
- What is the risk at this juncture?
- Lacerating the liver during dissection.
- Correct.
- We didn't kiss.
Ironically, a complication which
I've inadvertently just demonstrated.
Hold direct pressure,
I need better exposure.
I sliced instead of peeled.
You are familiar
with the Pringle procedure?
Yes, although I've never...
Clamp down the portal triad
with an atraumatic hemostat clamp.
Then use a number-two catgut suture.
Shaun? Just go to her and explain.
If what I said made
her uncomfortable,
then saying more could make her
more uncomfortable.
I sliced instead of peeled.
After Michelle's surgery,
I will go and talk to Carly.
Good.
You can talk to her soon.
OR Two had a cancellation,
your surgery is in 45 minutes.
I'm Dr. Browne, I will be
performing Michelle's surgery.
I will be removing her gallbladder,
a simple procedure.
We're gonna make sure your daughter
is well taken care of.
Ow!
- Sir, we need to decapitate it.
- No, don't. I'm begging you.
Don't. Please.
- I can't get an image.
- How did that... Is that a swordfish?
With that dorsal fin? It's a marlin.
I hooked him with a naked ballyhoo,
battled for an hour.
Suddenly, he leapt out of the water,
came right at me.
Save the story, Quint.
We need to cut the thing in half.
No, 40-plus years I've been chasing this.
You can't behead him.
We can't leave his nose in
your leg either.
His bill.
Can't you just... pull him out gently?
- I'll sign a waiver.
- The pull-out method never works.
If any of your blood vessels
are damaged, it gets messy.
Congrats,
your surgery is on the schedule.
- How's his distal pulse?
- Little thready but still there.
- We need to get him to an MRI.
- I'm not going anywhere without Franklin.
- I named him after my father.
- You and Franklin both won't fit.
How? You said he was dead.
- I didn't take a pulse.
- Get something to kill it.
- No, it's dead.
- It's moving.
Post-mortem response.
You are doctors, don't people do this?
- No!
- I'll help you review at lunch.
- Surgery's in 20 minutes.
- Good luck.
- You too.
- "I want to..."
No, no, I haven't left.
- "I want to be..."
- "Want to...
- Great."
- "...great,
- or nothing."
- "...nothing."
Got it. I'll be back as soon as I can.
Hi, you must be Michelle's mother.
I'm Dr. Browne, I'll be...
Yeah, how long will she have to stay?
Hospitals make me nervous.
- Three days to a week, depending on...
- But she's gonna miss school.
And she watches Tisha
and her brothers in the afternoon.
Your daughter has a serious infection
in her gallbladder.
She's been experiencing symptoms
on and off for a while now.
She never told me that.
Why didn't you tell me that?
- Momma...
- My point is,
she's been ill for a while,
so her recovery may take...
Mom? Please, my... my chest hurts.
- What's wrong?
- Oxygen levels are dropping, tachycardic.
I need a chest CT, stat.
You had a blood clot in the artery
that feeds your lungs,
called a pulmonary embolism.
Medicine broke it up.
- How?
- According to our scan,
it was part of a larger clot in your leg
that broke off and traveled there.
As for why the larger one formed,
when I asked you if you were taking
birth control pills, you said no.
Was that the truth?
You asked me in front of Tisha.
I'm doing it with my boyfriend,
I don't want babies,
so I'm taking birth control.
- How long have you been taking them?
- A year?
I'm prescribing condoms
for your boyfriend.
Go off the pill to prevent further clots.
Dr. Browne is gonna place
an IVC filter via your femoral vein,
in case other parts of the clot break off.
Your surgery's gonna have to wait.
What are you doing?
This is where the catheter goes in.
How did you get these scars?
I cut myself climbing a fence.
Those scars...
They're straight, in a row,
all the same length.
I don't believe you got them
from a fence.
I don't care what you believe.
Kids who cut,
most of them are really sad,
in a lot of pain,
and cutting makes them feel better.
Is that how it is with you?
I don't wanna talk about it.
Okay.
- My life sucks, okay?
- Tell me how.
Why? It won't change anything.
Talking might make you feel better.
And maybe I can help.
I live in a foster home,
but I'm not a foster kid.
I'm a whole mother,
but I've never had a baby.
My mom brought three kids in
and now it's my job
to take care of them.
Make breakfast, get the kids dressed,
take them to school,
go to school, pick them up,
dinner, homework, laundry, repeat.
I barely ever leave the house
without a kid attached to me.
Can you help me with that?
Michelle wouldn't hurt
herself on purpose.
Michelle is unhappy.
She feels pressure to look after
- her foster siblings, help out at home.
- Yeah, her home life is fine.
I'll talk to her.
It might be helpful to have her speak
with a psychiatrist.
My daughter is not crazy. We don't
do psychiatrists, you know that.
That needs to change.
- When is her surgery?
- Tomorrow.
Thank you.
I will speak to my daughter.
Don't.
It's your job
to fix her gallbladder, not her life.
It's your first surgery.
Don't get distracted.
- Have you talked to Carly?
- No.
Blood pressure is 62 over 31,
your patient is in cardiac arrest.
I know.
You're practicing
the Pringle maneuver
in the event of a liver bleed?
Yes.
- That was better.
- Thanks.
- Now you can talk to Carly.
- I need to practice.
Dr. Lim says getting away from things
every now and again,
having balance in our lives,
can be just as important
to our performance as practice.
Maybe you should get some balance
by talking to Carly, I don't know.
I'm nervous about my surgery, Shaun.
Practice will make me less nervous,
that will improve my performance.
Okay.
You should practice not causing
a liver bleed.
Planning on it.
Also, how you will recover
if you cut the portal vein,
that's potentially fatal.
Or if you perforate the small bowel,
which could cause sepsis,
leading to death.
Or cut the common bile duct
which would cause...
- Gonna talk to Carly. Right now.
- Right now?
- Aren't you still nervous?
- Nope. All better.
- What blade for the Kocher?
- What?
Incision for the chole, what blade?
Uh...
- Ten.
- Mm-hm.
No! They won't both fit in the MRI.
Fish boy doesn't buy it.
Location of the incision?
Why are you trying to help me?
Lim picked you for the first surgery.
That makes you
the front-runner for chief resident.
This is me sucking up.
I've never been big on pretense...
- Are you okay?
- What just happened?
The marlin had metal in his body.
Lures.
I think a license plate flew by me.
Franklin. Oh, no! Franklin.
Ah! It's okay. Franklin's okay.
It all came out one side.
It won't show when I mount him.
Well, thank goodness
for small miracles.
Ow!
- Got his femoral.
- Call the OR. We're coming.
Hang on, Dr. Browne.
Need to make an incision above
and below the arterial injury site.
We need to clamp
the femoral proximal to the
bleed without clipping the femoral nerve.
Got it. I feel the nerve
above my index finger.
One down.
- My hand is starting to cramp.
- Lean this way.
Rotate your wrist.
Just a little bit more.
Let's see if that holds.
Go get cleaned up.
We'll take it from here.
I wanted to check
the patient's blood work.
He's negative for HIV, hep B and C.
You don't need prophylactic meds.
I'm nervous about my surgery.
You'll be fine.
And don't ever say that again.
Why? Weren't you nervous
before your first lead?
If I was, I didn't volunteer that
to the chief of surgery, or anyone.
We're women, we're not white,
and we're surgeons.
Unicorns consider us a fabled species.
We don't get the luxury
of public insecurity.
I will aspire to repressed stoicism
in the future.
We don't need to be insecure,
because every step of the way,
we've had to be twice as good
as everybody else.
Suck it up. You got this.
Don't forget we have our session
with Dr. Donovan today.
I won't.
- Your patient?
- Mm-hm?
What are they like?
Man, woman? Young, old?
Woman.
Girl, actually.
She's tough, smart, really sad.
Her mom has her taking care
of three foster kids.
At least you were only looking after me.
- How old?
- Fourteen.
Although she acts a lot older.
She's been having sex for almost a year.
You were that age with Wayne.
- I didn't have sex with Wayne.
- What?
He was in love with you,
always sniffing around our place.
Maybe. He didn't get any.
So who? Junior prom guy, Derek?
Derek... No.
I didn't lose my virginity
until sophomore year of college.
- What were you hoping for, a proposal?
- No.
I wanted it to be special.
Ah. Good for you.
I wouldn't have held out,
but good for you.
I thought for sure you and Wayne
were doing it.
- You were okay with that?
- You were so serious.
So restrained.
We talked about birth control.
I figured, "Good for her,
she's finally relaxing, having some fun."
Well, I was so restrained and serious
because I never knew
when you were gonna fall apart.
Gotta get to work.
I'll be back before Michelle goes
into surgery.
Have you had a chance to talk to her?
About cutting?
Oh, some fool friend
of hers gave her the idea.
- She's not unhappy, it's peer pressure.
- She sounded unhappy to me.
She's upset I didn't let her hang out
with friends, typical teen drama.
She promised me she's done.
Self-harming behavior doesn't just stop.
Michelle might need...
Dr. Browne, my daughter needs to have
surgery and get out of this hospital.
You didn't tell your mom the truth
about why you cut yourself,
about how unhappy you are.
I tried. She didn't wanna hear it.
Just said that things aren't always
gonna go my way
and I need to be responsible.
Like I'm not already.
Growing up, I had to
take care of my mom.
- What was wrong?
- She's mentally ill.
Bipolar disorder,
and a drinking problem, pills.
When things were bad,
she'd forget to buy groceries,
or clean the trailer, or pick me up.
Or she'd spend all our rent
on something stupid.
Now, I thought
if I could make her life easy enough,
if I cooked and cleaned
and got good grades,
that she'd get better.
But she never did.
And for the longest time, I thought
it was my fault she was sick.
I probably still would,
if a psychiatrist hadn't
refused to believe me
when I said I was fine.
You've been to a psychiatrist?
But you're, like, a fancy surgeon.
I could have a therapist come see you
before your surgery.
Okay.
He should be getting better. It's gotta be
an infection from the marlin.
Aeromonas or
mycobacterium marinum.
- Would've responded to the antibiotics.
- Guys, I'm trying to focus.
What if he has an underlying
autoimmune disorder?
Could've been triggered by the surgery,
even the initial stabbing.
It would explain
the leg ulcerations progressing
despite good arterial flow.
We could see if he responds to steroids.
Which could kill him
if it is an infection.
We could run an ANA,
see if he's positive.
What about a parasite?
Rhinosporidium seeberi or gill worm?
Have you talked to Carly?
Sorry, I got sidetracked by a marlin.
- Come in.
- You wanted to see me?
Ms. Reynolds tells me you went
against her wishes
and had her daughter speak
with a psychiatrist.
Uh...
- Michelle asked to see a therapist.
- Only after you talked her into it.
I'm gonna report you to the
medical board. You had no right...
Dr. Browne,
were you concerned that Michelle
might be a serious danger to herself?
- Yes.
- In that case, the consult was required.
That said, Dr. Browne's failure
to inform you was inappropriate.
You're off the case.
Dr. Melendez will perform the surgery.
How are you doing?
Claire?
Today's a big day for you. First surgery?
- We don't need to talk about that.
- I think we do.
You've taken care of your mother for
a long time.
That's a pattern you both need
to break out of.
I know I haven't always been there
for you, and I just...
- I'm trying to change that.
- I know, Mom.
I'm good, everything is fine.
And your first surgery?
Is that this afternoon?
It's...
Actually, it's not. Um...
I arranged a psych consult
without the mother's permission,
so I got thrown off the case.
How could the hospital allow that?
What is wrong with them?
- After how hard you've worked...
- It's okay, Mom. They had to.
- That must be a disappointment.
- It is.
Anything else, Claire?
I'm upset, humiliated.
So, so mad at my patient's mother
for not taking care of her daughter.
And I'm... I'm relieved.
I'm so relieved
to have that weight off of me,
- and that makes me feel like a fraud.
- Don't say that.
How can I be so scared to do something
I have wanted for so long?
Because things that matter are scary.
That's how I feel about coming here,
talking about my life and our relationship.
What if I can't fix it?
What if I can't make up
for all the times I've let you down?
And then I think...
"Just be like Claire."
Because nothing stops you, ever.
You see what you want and
go after it with everything you've got.
You are an inspiration.
You're my inspiration.
Carly. Hi. Do you have a second?
OR Two is waiting to learn
the patient's mass wasn't cancerous,
so they can close.
I can come back. Mm-hm.
I'll meet you at the cafe? Okay.
Cancer. The marlin guy has cancer.
CT chest, abdomen and pelvis
showed no masses.
It's in his leg. It explains progressive
ulcerations despite arterial flow.
And why the antibiotics aren't working.
We'll send a tissue sample
from the ulcerated area.
And when I'm chief resident,
I'll remember this.
- There's a problem with Michelle.
- I'm not doing it.
- Calm down.
- Don't tell me what to do.
- I want Dr. Browne.
- Michelle? What's going on?
I want you to do my surgery.
Her, Mom, not somebody else.
Dr. Melendez is gonna do your surgery,
he is great...
He's not you. You care about me.
Everybody here
cares about you, Michelle.
Please sit,
you could rupture your gallbladder.
- I don't wanna get better.
- Don't say that.
- It's the truth!
- Michelle, you need this surgery.
That is all that matters,
not whether I do it.
I'm gonna be there, I will be watching
from the gallery the whole time.
You just... You need to sit down.
The kid okay?
I had to pull you off.
If you made the tiniest misstep,
that mom would go from threat
to lawsuit.
Is Patricia okay with me watching?
No.
You can't remove her gallbladder
from the gallery.
- What?
- You're doing Michelle's surgery.
How'd you get the mom
to change her mind?
I explained that given Dr. Browne's
commitment to her daughter,
she's the perfect choice to lead.
Especially with me over her shoulder
the whole time.
- Thank you for fighting for me.
- That's what bosses do. Let's go.
- You stood me up.
- Sorry.
What's up?
Shaun's a little worried
he may have freaked you out
with his questionnaire
the other night.
I thought it was cool.
Small talk bores the hell out of me.
Well, then, great. I'll tell him.
Shaun got worried about that all
on his own? It doesn't seem like him.
I may have mentioned
that people don't usually ask deeply
personal questions on an early date.
Claire, I like you,
but we don't really know each other.
And yet you decided how I was going
to react to Shaun's questions,
which isn't your business.
And you were wrong.
Totally, totally wrong.
Shaun and I don't need you
or anyone
to run interference
on our relationship.
Butt out.
Is everybody ready for a time-out?
Dr. Claire Browne, lead surgeon.
Dr. Neil Melendez, attending surgeon.
Dr. Shaun Murphy, assisting.
Dr. Jan Lancaster, anesthesia.
Donna Petringa, scrub nurse.
Shani Walden, circulating nurse.
Patient is Michelle Reynolds.
We'll be performing
an open cholecystectomy.
All tools I need are confirmed
to be present,
estimated blood loss, 100 cc's,
patient will go to the ICU after surgery.
Is everybody in agreement?
Dr. Murphy, have you chloroprepped
the site?
I have.
Ten blade.
Sponge.
Top layer of abdominal muscle
is exposed.
I'll need a bovie to cut through.
Nice work, Dr. Browne.
Bookwalter retractor.
I see the liver and I need to better
expose the inferior surface.
Retract the duodenum inferiorly, please.
Gallbladder exposed.
Dr. Browne?
There's more scarring
than the imaging suggested.
True.
Talk through your approach.
I grasp the gallbladder
fundus forward
and use a right-angle clamp
and suction
to develop a plane
around the gallbladder.
Kelly clamp, right-angle clamp
and suction.
That was elegant use
of the Kelly clamp.
I see the cystic duct and
behind it, the cystic artery.
I need my first assist to confirm
that I have identified the common
bile duct and it is out of the way.
- Yes, cutting the duct would be...
- Very, very bad.
Move the gallbladder,
cranially, a little bit.
Titanium clip applier.
You sure you have a clear view?
Making the cut.
She's hemorrhaging.
I can't see the source
of the bleeding.
MAP is 45 and dropping.
What do you think is happening?
Most likely, my scissors'
tip nicked the right hepatic artery.
It happens. It's happened to me.
I need to clamp the common
hepatic artery, repair the arterial wall
- with a running 6-0 Prolene sutures.
- That's what I would do.
Hey, hey, hey. Slow down, slow down.
No running. No running.
Dr. Browne, how's my daughter?
The surgery was a success
and we expect a full recovery.
I wanna see her.
Is that okay?
- Yay!
- Okay, okay.
Michelle says
she wants to be a doctor.
She would be a great one.
Uh, that therapist Michelle talked to?
Could I get her card?
- Hi, baby.
- Hey, Mom.
Three, two, one.
You were right.
He had angiosarcoma of the leg.
Had to amputate,
but the margins were clean.
- What happened to...
- Franklin!
Franklin, you amazing fish.
You saved my life!
Come on. Bring him in. Bring him in.
Oh.
Thank you, guys. Group hug.
Do you prefer to work in a team
or do you prefer to lead
or follow commands?
Team. And lead.
Hey, I'm just leaving.
Who's this?
♪ From the greatest height ♪
♪ Slow-motion life ♪
♪ You know I'd pay
To leave these tears behind ♪
♪ But it's fine ♪
♪ I know we're all the same ♪
♪ Slow-motion pain ♪
♪ Now it's all blood in the open ♪
♪ But we're not scared ♪
Message received
at 5:30 p.m. from Mom.
Hey, baby, I got your text.
See, I knew it was just
a temporary setback.
We're gonna celebrate. I made dinner.
And I'm gonna go get some dessert,
I'll see you soon.
I'm so proud of you, baby.
♪ Slow-motion life ♪
♪ Slow-motion life ♪♪