Previously on
"The Resident"...
- Who's he?
- My former stepson Jake.
No, if you cared for me,
you would've stayed in touch.
Chastain's been sold.
The plan is to turn it
into condos.
Are you on any medication
right now?
- Yes. Ativan.
- You're in withdrawal.
- No, don't call the cops!
- Hey, hey!
- What happened?
- She was stabbed.
Baby?
Looks like
your granddaughter's alive.
We need to get Nic
to a functioning hospital.
Since Randall is governor now,
is there any chance the county
would take over the hospital?
They got the governor
to agree to make Chastain
a public hospital and the staff
will return immediately.
Nic.
You're still at Chastain.
It's morning.
You're okay.
How's the baby?
Well, we heard the heartbeat,
remember?
Saw the ultrasound.
So she's safe.
No, we still haven't
ruled out any complications
that could've happened
from the attack.
You're right,
but it's been two weeks, so...
So far, so good.
Seems like our baby is strong,
like her mom.
Can't even make it through
the night without...
Nightmares.
I know.
They're getting worse.
I dread going to sleep.
We could try
some different meds.
No, I want off
the sleep meds.
Okay, I get that.
Nic, I... also think you should
see a good therapist.
Sure. Fine.
But you know there's only
one person I want to see.
You know that.
You agreed to it.
Yeah, of course.
Whatever you need.
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ My heart beats low
while the flames go higher ♪
♪ Strike the match
and then the truth... ♪
♪ I'm gonna set my soul... ♪
- Back up.
- You back up.
This is my parking spot.
I don't see a name.
There's no number.
We got here
at the same time.
You see,
it's reserved for doctors.
What are you,
a second-year resident?
Maybe third?
Internal medicine?
It's pretty obvious.
Particularly given
your bougie entitlement.
Okay, here's the deal:
If you don't back your car up,
I'm gonna call security
and they're gonna tow it.
Oh, don't you dare
key my car...
Want your special spot, Doctor?
Go park mine
somewhere else.
Oh, and leave the keys
in Nic Nevin's room.
That's where I'll be.
- Pravesh. Good morning.
- Good morning.
Yo, some demented friend
of Nic's
actually expected me
to park her car.
Word? She tip you?
You know,
valets make bank on tips.
Your first day
at the new Chastain, huh?
Yeah. I mean, it doesn't
really look any different
as a public hospital, though.
Oh, believe me, brother,
it's different.
Brace yourself
for some growing pains.
An open door means
a lot more patients
and a lot less money
to care for them.
We turn no one away,
even though our resources
are stretched thin.
Yeah, I know it all
too well.
Happened to my father.
He died alone in
a public hospital, overlooked.
If it was private,
he might have lived.
Well, we gonna fight to make
sure that doesn't happen here,
- my man.
- Yeah.
Whoa. Dr. Feldman versus
a squeaky wheel.
My money's on Feldman
all day.
Thank you.
It's not just the wheel.
We'll be lucky
if we can get it to turn on.
Red Rock sold
most of our equipment.
Our EKG machines
are now ancient and we...
Oh, my God.
- You know her?
- Unfortunately, yes.
Although she looks
a lot different
than the last time
I saw her.
Less train wreck, more...
...wow.
- Train wreck. Really?
- Mm-hmm.
Didn't think
we'd ever see you here again.
I'd ever be here again.
I'm visiting Nic.
Oh, so you're the one
who got under Devon's skin.
Here you go.
Nic is in 521.
Your car is in
the impound lot on Peachtree.
- What's her deal?
- Billie Sutton.
Most promising neurosurgery
resident at Chastain.
Or was, until she wrecked one of
Conrad's patients and got fired.
- How'd she do that?
- Hubris, basically.
It was over three years ago.
Wow, that sounds bad.
- It was messy.
- Mm.
- All right.
- See you.
Ah. I fixed it.
We keep him on fluids.
He's stable, we should be...
Oh, my God.
- Here we go.
- Easy, Conrad.
People change.
Three years is a long time.
Not long enough.
Hawkins.
Sutton.
I bet you're thrilled
to see me.
Mm, Nic wants you here,
so I want you here.
Then we won't have trouble.
Not from my end,
we won't.
Let's stick to the only thing
that matters.
How is Nic?
The attack nearly killed her
and the baby.
Physically, she's on the mend.
Mentally, each day's
a little worse.
She has PTSD,
keeps reliving what happened
and she's having
nightmares.
I sleep in her room.
She wakes up crying.
I'm so sorry it took me
this long to get here.
Where have you been?
You weren't at the wedding.
You never even called her.
- Nic was heartbroken.
- I'll explain what happened
when I see her.
You know, maybe for the moment,
we can put aside
all our triggers
and just be on the same side.
You and I will never be
on the same side.
I have worked the last
three years on my issues.
Your issues?
You wrecked
a young man's life.
It was my patient
and you cut unsupervised.
You had no right.
So we're going there. Okay.
What I did was wrong.
But I believed I was acting
in the patient's best interest.
- You got me fired.
- No, I didn't,
and you were playing God.
A fifth-year resident does not
operate unsupervised, period.
Even you.
I made a judgment call.
It was bad judgement.
I broke the rules.
I was young and stupid.
No one breaks
more rules than you.
Yeah, I break the rules
when I have to,
when there's
no other alternative,
and only to save lives.
Annabeth Higgins.
The child
your incompetence killed.
Are you done?
Because I am.
We're all human.
We all make mistakes.
I have spent
the last three years
with Partners In Health
in Syria,
pulling bullets out of babies,
doing every kind
of emergency surgery
that exists.
Penance is my middle name.
Nic is vulnerable.
She can't handle any drama.
She won't get any
from me.
Fine.
Steer clear of me,
try and give Nic what she needs
and then leave,
as soon as possible.
Hello.
Billie.
Nevin.
You look amazing. Oh.
So good to see you.
Mm.
Let's see the ring.
Oh. Look at that rock.
He did good.
Mm. We missed you
at the wedding.
Long story.
I wanted to be there.
But I'm here now.
And I'll be staying
right by your side
as long as you need me.
I don't care how long it takes.
Days or weeks.
Honey, go.
Your patients need you.
Chastain needs help
with this transition.
Yeah, go.
I've got Nic.
Trust me.
*The Resident*
Season 04  Episode 02
Episode Title: "Requiems & Revivals"
Aired on: February 16, 2021
Hey.
The board is interviewing
doctors today
for the new CEO position.
Yeah, they're talking
to everybody.
I declined.
Not everybody.
Not me.
You don't want
that thankless job, do you?
We are deep in the hole
but the situation is fixable.
I shouldn't be excluded
from providing solutions
simply because
I lack a penis.
- Wow, no women are being interviewed?
- Nope.
I wish Mina was here.
She'd have some choice words
and a few elbows to throw.
- Where is she?
- Meeting with immigration lawyers.
She has to find the best.
I can't lose her.
Neither can Chastain.
Dr. Lamas.
Where are you going?
L.A. I fly out tonight.
But you can't. We have
a bilateral hand transplant
this afternoon.
I get paid per procedure.
Can't work at a public hospital
on a fixed salary.
I'd make peanuts.
Come on, man.
It's not peanuts.
The salary is fair.
Is it north of two million?
Fine. Go.
But you have to do
Andy's surgery first.
We have donor hands
he's waited months to get.
Sorry, guys. Cedars-Sinai
is expecting me this week.
That's the fifth surgeon
we've lost.
There'll be more.
First things first.
Those donor hands will be
diverted to another child
if we don't find
a plastic surgeon
to replace Lamas
in the next few hours.
Do I look more important today?
- Should you?
- Yeah, the board needed a leader
for the ER transitional team
and you're looking at him.
Oh, good luck.
Have you seen the waiting room?
Yeah. We need to see
as many patients as we can
as fast as we can.
15 minutes each.
- What if I need longer?
- Talk faster.
- I really have missed a lot.
- Yep, we have chickens.
The things we do for love.
What about you?
What's been going on?
I mean, you look better
than ever.
No, this is just armor.
You know,
given how things ended here,
- I had to put on my best face.
- Mm-hmm.
Have you gotten any residency?
No.
I have no prospects yet.
Well, don't stop looking.
You can't waste all that talent.
Let's talk about you.
Looks like your physical
recovery is right on track.
But you're still in that bed.
Movement is medicine.
I've heard you say that
a million times.
Yeah, I just can't.
Okay, no pressure.
How long since you've left
this room?
I haven't.
Let's get you some fresh air.
- Is it time to get my new hands?
- Soon, honey.
I'm here to introduce you
to your vascular surgeon,
- Dr. Austin.
- Hey.
Is he an all-star?
I promised Andy
I'd recruit
an all-star surgical team
for his hand transplant.
Ah, well, Andy, you are in luck.
I happen to be the all-star
of all-stars.
Like Freddie Freeman?
He's a four time all-star,
you know?
And a Golden Glove
first baseman, too, you know?
Just like me one day.
Mom already bought me
a baseball mitt.
Ah, nothing like
the smell of a new glove.
And he hasn't stopped
smelling it.
Well, wait
till you can feel it, Andy.
I can't wait.
So when's my surgery?
Is there a problem?
We have a slight delay...
We lost our plastic surgeon.
But you finally
found him donor hands.
We can't lose them.
We'll find someone even better.
Uh-oh.
Is that...?
Dr. Aronson.
The new Chastain keeps
incompetent surgeons on staff?
We're shorthanded
in neurosurgery.
Top doctors don't like the fixed
salaries of public hospitals.
And so, yeah,
Dr. Aronson is filling in.
Oh, look
what the cat dragged in.
That was some
high-level restraint.
Self-help books, meditation,
a shrink, anger management,
hypnosis.
If you told me you had
a magic bean, I'd eat it.
That said, it's a journey,
and I'm nowhere near
the destination.
Billie, stop.
- Oh, God! I just felt the...
- Hey.
- Okay, talk to me.
- Oh, my God, I just had this pain.
- Where does it hurt?
- What are you doing? She's not supposed to be out of her room.
The baby. Something's wrong. I-I
just felt, I felt this pain...
Okay, okay, I'm sure
everything's fine, but let's get
that pain checked out and we'll
do another ultrasound
just to be okay.
Hang on.
- That's extra fluid.
- Yes.
See, I knew
something felt different.
The heart's beating.
The baby is alive and moving.
But there's extra fluid
around the heart.
That can have many causes.
Some of them benign.
Hey.
It's gonna be okay.
We just need
to find out what's going on.
Yeah.
I'm gonna go talk to
Nic's OB.
You up to speed?
Yes, uh, but before you go,
I have some ideas
about what's going on.
Okay.
Um, time for some boundaries.
You're not her doctor.
And you don't work here anymore.
I want to help.
Good.
Go talk to Nic.
I'll handle the medicine.
Two heads are
better than one.
I'm gonna say this once.
Don't make
the same mistake again.
Just be Nic's friend.
And try and keep your ego
out of this.
Okay?
Labs are pristine.
Vascular imaging looks good.
Our little guy is ready to go.
We just need plastics.
I've called
around to every hospital
in driving distance.
No one has the skill set
for a double hand replacement.
I mean, it's
the highest level of surgery.
I might have someone.
Dr. Jake Wong.
My former stepson.
I know Jake's in plastics,
but has he done
a bilateral transplant?
In Guatemala, four years ago.
Four years?
I'm sure best practices
has changed considerably
since then.
Well, best practices may have
to give way
to best available
on short notice.
Your last exchange with him
did not go well.
Yeah, but this,
this isn't personal... it's work.
And it's a hell
of an interesting case.
I'm just, I'm-I'm betting
that Jake won't let
his resentment of me
stand in the way.
Then go, get him to commit.
We only have a few hours
before we lose the donor hands.
Okay.
We've all
left the stove on before.
It's the second time this week.
Third, but who's counting?
I could have burned
the house down.
Age, dear.
We're all in the same boat.
No. I'm dangerous.
Has Norman been
seen here before?
No. It was a different hospital.
But the doctor said
the diagnosis was clear.
Alzheimer's.
With this disease, it's the
caregiver that has it the worst.
I'm worried about her.
Why don't you just put me
away somewhere?
Don't go through this hell.
Hell would be
living without you.
- What's this?
- A fall.
Happens a lot. Usually at night.
He gets up in the dark.
Won't stay in bed.
Prostate issues.
I have to pee all the time.
I'd like to do
a comprehensive physical exam.
Balance issues can mean
other problems.
And a lot of these conditions
mimic Alzheimer's.
All right, stay here,
you're not going anywhere.
I'll be right back, okay?
Look, I'm sorry I didn't come
to the wedding.
I missed having you there.
I knew it would be packed
with Chastain people.
Just not the best crowd for me.
And given
my history with Conrad,
the fact that he basically
can't stand me...
...I didn't want to spoil
your perfect day.
But it was harder
than you might think.
And I wanted to see you
in your dress.
Watch the first dance.
I know that this is
your worst nightmare.
You don't want
to be the patient.
You want to take care
of patients.
I mean, what kind of nurse am I
if I can't even save
my own baby, right?
What is it?
It's just I already
bought a crib.
I lose this baby, I...
...I can't help but think
that everything's
just gonna come crashing down.
No.
I'm here to catch you, Nic.
See the fluid in the abdomen
and around the heart?
Your baby has severe anemia.
How did we miss this?
We couldn't have known.
Nic's prenatal tests were
all normal.
But she must have an antibody
that's crossing the placenta
and attacking
the baby's red blood cells.
Where did it come from?
The blood transfusions.
She had so many
after the attack.
They must have triggered
the reaction.
Conrad, you know
what we have to do next.
Another transfusion.
Yes. The baby needs an
intrauterine blood transfusion.
Without it,
she won't survive.
If we do this,
there's a high chance
of miscarriage.
That can't happen.
I'm not sure
Nic could take that.
No, I'm not sure
I could take that.
This is Dr. Wong.
Hey, Jake. It's Randolph.
I need your help
as a doctor.
You want a little freshening u?
Neck lift?
Rhinoplasty?
'Cause I don't do that.
I do reconstructive,
medically necessary.
There's a boy who needs
a bilateral
hand transplant today.
And Chastain just lost our best
plastic surgeon.
He's the only one in Atlanta who's done
a hand transplant before.
Except... except for you.
Without you, the kid is gonna
lose his place in line.
And he may wait years
for another set of hands.
I'm on my way. I'll text you
when I'm out front.
Gentlemen,
Governor Randall,
sorry to interrupt
your CEO interviews, but
there's a time-sensitive issue.
We have a boy
awaiting a hand transplant
and I need emergency privileges
- for an outside surgeon.
- Surely there's someone already here...
The only doctor qualified
for this rare surgery
quit because we've gone public.
Look, Chastain can't take a risk
on an unknown surgeon
for a rare, high-risk surgery.
Well, I can promise
we will fail if we don't try.
Don't we have a mandate
to make
Chastain a hospital that
goes any distance for patients?
I will sign off
on your new surgeon.
If this goes wrong...
it's on you.
Considering where you sit,
and what you've achieved,
why are no women
being interviewed
for the CEO position?
Isn't that on you?
Hey, where are you two going?
I didn't discharge you.
Dr. Feldman did.
- He did what?
- Well, you treated the burn
and he gave us
some gauze to take home.
Your feet are dragging.
So the falls may not just
be because of balance.
Are you having trouble walking?
It's old age.
What can you do?
It's quite all right, dear.
We don't want to be a bother.
And I don't want Norman
to suffer if he doesn't have to.
Okay, the symptoms that
I'm seeing make me think this is
not Alzheimer's at all.
I'd like to do
a spinal tap.
Doc, I just want to go home now.
I'm tired.
You don't have to wait
back in line.
I'll bring the bed
to you right here.
Honey?
Give it a chance.
For me?
Good.
I'll be back.
Kit.
Jake.
Dr. Wong, thank you for coming.
Thanks for the opportunity.
You, too, 'Dolph.
'Dolph?
The patient will be prepped
and ready in a few hours.
We'll maximize time by
dissecting donor
and recipient hands
simultaneously.
Working in tandem
to limit fatigue. Smart.
- Tell me about the patient.
- Andy lost his hands
from septic shock as a toddler.
Couldn't get comfortable
with prosthetics.
Besides, he wants to
feel things again.
A pencil, his mother's hand.
Especially his new
baseball mitt.
Oh, he's a big fan
of our national pastime?
Yeah, even bigger than
you were.
Well, in that case,
I just have one question.
Where's the gift shop?
You know, a new mitt
isn't complete
without a new baseball.
Does that mean
the surgery is on?
Yes.
Dr. Wong has agreed
to be your plastic surgeon.
But are you an all-star doctor?
He is, Andy.
Do you play baseball?
I did. T-ball right through
high school.
- Position?
- Center field.
Best play?
Seventh grade.
Coach rode me all season about
getting ahead of the curveball.
Had me run laps when I didn't.
There were a lot of laps.
Lots of arguments.
Then, game one
of our World Series,
Coach puts me
in against a pitcher
who threw a curve
like Doc Gooden.
And what happened?
I thought Coach did it
to teach me a lesson.
But I got ahead of the curve
and I won us the game.
I realized
he believed in me
more than any other kid
on that team.
So, how about it, Andy...
Is my résumé good enough
to make your team?
It's a late substitution.
But you're hired.
A fetal blood transfusion?
It-It's risky,
and it's our only option.
- For the baby?
- Yeah, but we have to do it.
The alternative is we lose her.
Based on
what Gabbi's told me,
I think it's best
we put you under anesthesia.
If you're awake,
you'll see it all.
And if you flinch,
the needle could
hit the umbilical cord.
I'm a nurse,
I won't flinch.
But what if I wake up
and our baby's gone
and I wasn't there for her?
Okay.
Then stay awake.
But there's
no upside to being awake.
Not for Nic, not for the baby,
and no reason, medically,
to put her through it.
Well, there's one giant reason.
She might want to be awake.
Well, thank you
for that, Billie.
- Okay, you know what?
- I just...
I can't even hear myself think.
Please.
Nic, we will sort this out
and get back on the same page.
Don't stress.
Billie, you got a minute?
Nic was stabbed
two weeks ago, and
you think she needs to watch
a needle penetrate her womb?
- What I think is...
- You're not her doctor,
you're not her husband.
This is about you being
important and making the call,
and the call is wrong.
You haven't changed.
- But I...
- No buts.
You need to leave now.
This experiment failed.
Go. I'm not asking.
Pravesh.
What is this?
He's not taking up a bed.
I applaud the ingenuity, but
you're performing a procedure
on a discharged patient.
He might have
normal pressure hydrocephalus.
If so, this procedure
can cure him.
We can give him his life back.
But I need to complete
- this lumbar puncture.
- I get it. No stone unturned.
But you treated his burn.
Now what about
the other patients who are
in the waiting room right now?
What kind of hospital are we
if we can't spare 30 minutes
that might cure a patient
who's been misdiagnosed?
Admit him to Medicine
or have him make an appointment.
I won't ignore a patient.
That's what happened
to my father.
He looks
like Rain Man in there.
Could damage a nerve.
Put my plate sideways.
Nerve.
And extra vein.
Extra vein,
always dissect extra vein.
Oh.
He's reciting a litany
of things that could go wrong.
So that's his process.
- Interesting.
- Mm.
We have four hours
to connect these arteries
and get blood flowing
into Andy's new hands.
Any longer, and this
beautiful gift will be wasted.
Ready to tag
the median and ulnar.
Raring to go.
I like that. And you're
working at a good pace.
So are you.
Thank you for letting me
join you on the dominant hand.
The damn procurement team
did not
cut this one down
to the right length.
Good catch.
- It's too long.
- Yeah.
In my experience, even
a small length issue matters.
These hands will grow with him.
I can work fast
to line these up properly.
Do it.
We want this to be perfect.
All right. Let's cut these
mittens down to size, shall we?
Come in.
I'm here because the board
overlooked someone
who may be the best choice
for CEO.
Dr. Voss.
That's an inspired choice.
It's about time.
Better late than never.
After Kit charged into
our meeting, it became clear
we don't want
a safe choice for CEO.
We want someone bold,
trailblazing.
And Chastain needs
a new leader by end of day.
Well, this operation
is just getting started.
- They'll be here all night.
- I know.
The operation is her interview.
So I will be here watching it
all night as well.
Safe to proceed.
Visualizing the umbilical vein.
I'm going to inject the fetus
with a sedative and paralytic.
Don't be alarmed when she stops
moving around. That's the goal.
Ready to start the transfusion.
Damn it.
- What is it?
- The baby's heart's having trouble.
The blood might be too much
for the fetal circulation.
Her heart rate's gonna
bounce back. Give it a moment.
We can't give the baby
any more blood.
Baby's bradying down.
Might be a spasm of the cord.
Let's get her on her left side
to improve uterine perfusion.
On my count.
One, two, three.
Need a liter of IV fluid.
Baby's still bradying down.
There's your little warrior.
Conrad, the baby's
still paralyzed.
We hope the blood
will be enough.
But until the drugs wear off,
we won't know for sure
if she's okay
or if Nic's miscarried.
No blood.
Crystal-clear fluid.
What does that mean?
No obvious signs of infection.
This is what we call
a champagne tap.
When will we know if it worked?
Soon. We've taken out
enough spinal fluid
to see if he gets better.
Okay, Norman,
you hold still, okay?
I'm gonna pull out this needle.
Okay, dear, it's done.
Okay.
How do you feel?
Uh... I feel...
- okay.
- Yeah?
Why don't you walk for us.
Here.
Mrs. Katz, would you
like to go waltzing?
Baby steps, dear.
This is incredible.
Thank you.
So, Doc, I-I'm really
gonna be all right again?
Uh, what about my head?
All of your symptoms were caused
by an accumulation
of spinal fluid.
When I took off enough,
you got better.
Your brain's gonna fully recover
and you'll be back
to your old self soon.
And you do not have Alzheimer's.
Thank you.
My pleasure.
We'll set him up
with neurosurgery
for a permanent shunt.
You were right.
I was wrong. Sue me.
No, I was wrong, too.
I thought by working at a
public hospital that I would be
part of the problem, but what
I realize now is that I get to be
part of the solution, and
treat patients who would never
have been able
to come to Chastain.
And give the kind of care...
- that my dad deserved.
- Right.
Insurance won't
cause us problems anymore,
but you know what will?
- An overwhelmed ER.
- Yeah.
We have to figure out a system
that helps triage
less urgent cases.
That can be done.
It will be done.
But right now,
let's both go see more patients.
Good man.
I know you said go,
but I couldn't leave
until I knew
Nic was okay.
Nic's fine.
Not awake yet.
The baby?
We won't know until
the paralytic wears off.
This must be awful for you.
Look, I was insensitive.
Just not thinking about
the fact that there are
two parents involved,
and I'm an outsider.
That was wrong.
I continue to be wrong
about a lot of things,
despite my best efforts.
I'd like to revisit
what happened between us,
put it all out on the table.
I want to know you understand.
I think
I understand quite well.
Your patient had a meningioma
that had to come out.
At that point, I'd done
about a hundred of those.
Figured, "I'll pop this out,
no problem."
I'd started doing surgeries
without my attending present
because Aronson was
a lazy hack with rusty skills.
He hid behind his residents.
I didn't know that.
I cut with impunity,
I felt triumphant,
but when I tried
to wake your patient up...
Yeah, massive
left hemisphere stroke.
Because you didn't have
enough experience
to know that
the arteries you cut
weren't feeding
the patient's tumor.
They were feeding
the patient's brain.
Now that lovely man
cannot walk,
cannot talk,
will live the rest of his life
in a nursing home.
Yes, I understand
what I did,
and I will never
get over it.
You had to report me.
I've always known that,
but it was easier
to blame you than face the truth
that it was my own fault.
Mm.
Man, that was
really freaking hard.
Anyway, it looks like
you've got this,
so I'll jump.
See you in a few years.
Hey.
Say goodbye to Nic
before you leave.
She'll be hurt if you leave
without doing that.
Plates and screws are in.
Length and
angle are perfect over here.
Dr. Wong, you're up.
Microscope.
Jeweler's forceps.
Starting arterial anastomosis.
Microneedle holder
and 9.0 nylon.
Dr. Voss is running
a smooth ship.
I wouldn't expect anything less.
And the new guy?
Is that your doing?
Dr. Wong deserves
all the credit.
What you're witnessing
is God-given talent.
Both arterial
anastomoses complete.
Complete? That's all you got?
- Brother, that's beautiful.
- It's the moment of truth,
and you're bogging me down
with compliments?
Well, have it your way, Cochise.
No compliments till these
bad boys turn pink. Let's go.
All good here.
Nice.
No blood flow to the right hand.
Give me a Doppler.
It's a clot.
I'll try to milk
it out. Forceps.
The hand's too cold.
We need to help it perfuse.
All right, let's
turn this OR into a sweatbox.
- Clot's out.
- Yeah, but the artery is short.
We need to connect it.
Time is of the essence.
We can't let this hand
die on us.
We need a graft, and I dissected
extra pieces of vein.
Of course. In his premortem.
I'll take the proximal end.
- You help out on the other side.
- Yeah. Got it.
We're running out of time.
Fine work, Dr. Austin.
See there,
compliments don't bog me down.
All set.
All right, let's go.
Look at that.
A boy's dream
finally becomes reality.
I love this game.
She's not out of the woods yet.
We won't know until
the paralytic wears off,
which should be soon.
I don't feel so good.
- She's tachy to the 140s.
- She's cold and clammy.
Heart rate's in the 180s.
SVT. She needs meds
and a code cart.
- I'll get it.
- I know where it is.
I'll be back in 30 seconds.
The baby can't handle this.
I need a 10cc syringe.
Here.
Blow into this.
Hard. Try to move the plunger.
Harder.
Normal sinus rhythm.
Thank you.
There are a lot of ways
to break an arrhythmia.
My favorite doesn't involve
an ice bucket bath
that leaves the patient
wet and cold.
Okay, guys, that's great,
but can we figure out
what caused this?
Hey, Billie, let's put
our heads together,
shall we?
Yes, she went into an SVT.
Lots of things can cause that.
Anxiety, electrolytes, hormones.
Or thyroid.
But her thyroid function
was low.
It was, and we've been
giving her thyroid hormone.
And as her thyroid function
changes during pregnancy...
Now it must be too high.
I'll send off
thyroid function tests,
and we'll hold her next dose.
Sounds like a plan.
And now it's up to
our baby girl.
She's a fighter.
She'll rally.
They are beautiful, honey.
But will they work?
It'll take some time
before you feel much sensation,
but you might be able
to move a finger.
It's only a matter of time
till you're on the field
shagging flies.
Thank you.
Wasn't
exactly smooth sailing today,
but you made it happen.
With the help
of amazing surgeons.
Right, but you, Dr. Voss,
you took this on your
shoulders... at high risk...
And gave a child back his life.
I saw leadership
and calm under pressure.
Qualities we need at Chastain.
The CEO job is yours
if you want it.
You're damn right I do.
I think I felt her kick.
Conrad.
Thank you very much.
What's going on?
I think I felt her kick.
No, you do it.
She's moving.
There's less fluid.
It worked.
Thank you so much for
bringing me in on this.
You did fantastic work.
It was a highlight
watching you today, Jake.
You're an artist.
How would you like to leave
rhinoplasty behind forever?
Chastain wants you here
permanently.
So, what do you say?
I'll be looking forward
to working with you again,
Dr. Voss.
So, what does this mean
for, you know, our relationship?
That's up to you.
You take the lead.
I'll just be happy
to have the best
plastics man in Atlanta.
"Silhouette" by Active Child
playing....
♪ Sitting outside waiting
for the words to come ♪
♪ Living my life
trying to do what's right ♪
♪ In the hope of a better day ♪
♪ And all those words
you wrote me ♪
Home.
♪ Brought me to my knees... ♪
This is my home right here.
It was so good to see Billie.
Just wasn't long enough.
I'm really gonna miss her.
Actually, you're not
gonna miss her at all,
because I asked her to stay
and take care of you here
for the next few weeks.
- What? Really?
- Yeah.
Yeah. I love you.
I love you, too.
And I love you...
Tonya.
Tonya?
That's a nonstarter.
No way.
And I love you, Posie.
Posie? Not a chance.
Seriously.
Zero percent chance.
♪ You, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ To be alone. ♪
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Sync corrections by srjanapala