The human body is
full of energy.
Sprinting at full speed,
it produces enough wattage
to power anything in your house.
♪ Let me in on all the secrets
♪ That shattered you
to pieces, yeah ♪
♪ How did you survive?
♪ You came out alive
♪ So much stronger
than you know ♪
Your cells are built
to move charged ions
through the cellular membrane.
♪ You need a shoulder
♪ To lean on
♪ I'll be your bridge
over dangerous waters ♪
♪ If you need somebody
And the nervous
system is a highway
of electrical signals... You
better check your e-mail.
Zapping through your
muscles and brain.
Okay, alright, everyone,
let's try to stay inside
during lightning flurries.
I noticed a lot of
people wandering out
during the last storm.
We're here to treat
patients, not become them.
Here's one more.
Hi!
How are you this morning?
Uh, great.
I wasn't asking you.
Did you read this?
Your body runs on positive
and negative charges,
all obeying a basic
law of physics...
♪ Call on me
opposites attract.
Going for casual at the clinic?
What's the point
in even going in?
There's a massive storm on
the clinic's opening day,
I just got Meredith's
e-mail that she's leaving,
and, oh, right, none
of Luna's clothes
fit her any more.
So those are three omens,
all telling me to stay home.
Luckily, women only need
abortions in pleasant weather.
I could put up a sign...
"Come back when
the sun's out."
Okay, you eat.
I'll go find some of
Scout's clothes for Luna.
Get a plate.
What are you doing here?
I took the day off
work to help you pack.
Where are your plate protectors?
I mean, I don't know
what those things are.
But I have movers and
packers coming this weekend.
I have said this.
Yes, but will they
treat your things
with as much love and
respect as I will?
I just... Let me
do this, please.
Fine.
Hey, uh, your e-mail was
good, short and sweet.
Efficient.
It needed to be.
I don't have a whole lot
of time this morning,
so if you want to come, I
have a whipple with Nick.
How's he taking the news?
Uh, we're not talking about it.
I'm avoiding Winston so
that we don't have to talk
about his whole switching
specialties thing.
So maybe you could stay
home and we could avoid
and pack together.
That actually sounds
amazing, but no.
Bye.
It's fine.
Oh, everything's fine.
Hey, sorry I'm late. I
brought sparkling cider.
I figured this called
for a celebration.
Or not. Yeah, no,
this is serious work.
Forget the cider.
You should've brought
something stronger. Right.
Wilson, we're not opening yet.
Accreditation
hasn't come through.
Bureaucracy.
This red ribbon might
as well be red tape,
and neither one of 'em
is getting cut today.
It's a national crisis.
We scheduled patients.
I can try to take them
upstairs, pro-bono.
Bless you.
Happy opening day, everybody!
I brought some almond
croissants to celebrate.
Opening's postponed.
Uh, bureaucracy?
How do you know? It always is.
There may be a silver lining.
Bailey, I could use your help
with a sigmoid resection.
And with this storm, the
ER's gonna be packed.
Oh, shut up!
Good morning, Lucas.
I can tell from your face
that you have not
told anyone the truth.
Actually, yes, I have.
Hmm? Griffith knows.
How about Kwan
and everyone else?
I... Well, I've been busy, uh,
studying for this whipple...
so I... It's just
been this whole...
And anyway, Dr. Shepherd,
I'll, uh... I'll get right
on that thing for you.
I'll let Dr. Marsh know he
can reassign the whipple
because you have a... thing.
Stop.
This is over.
Follow me.
Now.
Geez, come on, people.
I'm not really a
to-the-minute guy,
but there is something
called on time here.
Sorry, the storm backed up
traffic from First and Columbia.
I know, I know, but everyone
else got here except for Adams.
Where's Adams?
My fault, Dr. Marsh.
I'm sure you're swamped,
but Dr. Adams has an
announcement to make.
Okay. Okay, make it fast.
Some of you have gotten
the wrong idea about me,
so I need to clear things up.
Uh, the truth is,
D-Dr. Shepherd is...
Her sister's my mom,
so she's my aunt.
I'm a Shepherd.
And yeah, that's it.
Disturbing on so many levels.
Just to be very
clear, we are not now
and have never been having
sex with each other.
Yeah, that would be really
weird if he's your nephew.
Mm-hmm.
Thank you, Dr. Adams.
Okay, so if you're related
to half the hospital,
do you know why Grey
is deserting us?
She's the reason this
program is running.
I ju... Should we be
looking for other options?
Okay, hold on, hold
on. Take a seat.
Okay. About Dr. Grey's news,
you're scared, that's
understandable.
And I want to answer every
question you might have.
But right now, there are
patients about to go into
O.R.s who are far
more concerned
with whether they're
living or dying.
They don't care about the career
moves of individual surgeons.
They don't. So today we're
gonna save lives, okay?
Griffith, Adams,
you're scrubbing in
with me and Grey on the whipple.
Yasuda, Kwan, Millin,
you're in the pit
with Altman and Schmitt.
Let's go.
Okay.
Okay, hold up, hold
up, hold up, hold up.
Take a seat, please, sit.
Surgical excellence, it
takes more than one person.
This program is more
than one person.
You are the program.
It ain't going anywhere.
Okay?
Let's go.
God help us all.
Here I am! Sorry,
weird meeting.
Apparently, even more
people in this place
are related than I thought.
Let's focus, Yasuda.
Alright, Ben Warren called ahead
and said we're gonna need a
lot of extra hands on this one.
That's cryptic. He say why?
Jonathan Bright, 42-year-old
male, local TV reporter.
Survived a crash while
reporting on the storm,
and the helicopter was
struck by lightning.
Third-degree burns, possible
spinal injury and neuro deficits.
The bottom of the seat
fractured upon impact
and impaled him through
the right thigh.
We couldn't safely
extricate him from the chair
without risking further injury.
Is my wife here?
If I'm gonna die,
I really want to see my wife.
Hi Jonathan. I'm Dr. Altman.
We are gonna work
very hard to see to it
that you don't die.
Where do you want him?
Altman? Alright, Trauma three.
Go get us some help.
Okay.
Alright, slowly,
slowly. Nice and easy.
Hey.
Wh... Uh, why
aren't you at work?
I'm not on until tonight.
I thought I'd join
you and lend a hand.
Also, I think
you're avoiding me,
so I thought I'd ruin that plan.
I'm not avoiding you. I...
Um, I-I mean... I
am a little bit.
Um, also, I want to spend
time with the children
who are moving across country.
I can leave, but I'd
rather stay and talk.
Or, you know, we
don't have to talk.
I can just, uh, help.
I brought peanuts.
Yeah, help me upstairs.
Alright. Um,
Meredith is purging,
and she is not one
for sentimentality.
Oh, hey, save what you want now
before she chucks it
all into a dumpster.
Yeah. Hey, Zola.
Uh, yeah?
Zola, we're gonna go start
upstairs in the attic.
Can you keep an eye
on those maniacs?
And, um, stay inside.
The odds of being
struck by lightning
are only 1 in 15,000.
Exactly.
Don't give it a chance.
Okay, Zola, Bailey, and Ellis.
Is that all of them?
Yes, thank you, Ms. Hobbes.
Thank you. No,
it's Tessa, please.
Wait, uh, you don't
want an inscription?
I already have some. We've
met before, actually.
My mother used to take
me to see you read
at the Seattle library.
The character of
Tessa is the reason
I wore red sneakers all
through third grade.
Oh.
Uh, Dr. Griffith, please.
Tessa Hobbes, 68,
diagnosed 12 months ago
with chronic pancreatitis.
All medical and endoscopic
attempts at treatment
have been ineffective.
Today, she will undergo
a whipple procedure
to resect the damaged
parts of the pancreas,
and I'm a huge fan, too.
Oh.
Tessa, I do feel it
necessary to reiterate,
this is a very risky surgery.
Well, I have to live through it.
I still have a story to tell.
It's tickling my fingers
and the back of my throat.
I even have a title for it...
"Tessa and the Rising Sun."
Sure you don't want to postpone
the surgery and write the book?
Oh, gosh no.
I am so sick.
I can't write.
I sleep all day.
I can barely think.
We just want to make sure
that you're prepared
for every outcome here.
Yeah, I'm prepared
for every outcome.
But my readers are not.
Every year, for over 40 years,
I've written a Tessa book.
My readers deserve
an end to her story.
You and your kids deserve
an end to her story,
so do your best to
save my life, okay?
I hate this new board.
Ah, Webber. I'm
getting rid of this.
So I hear this hospital
is in need of a new chief.
Oh, why? Have someone in mind?
Oh, yeah.
Me.
I need this.
I need to be useful again.
I was chief for five years.
I-I have the experience
and the skills,
and I will move
mountains for you.
Who could be better?
Someone who doesn't have
a suspended license.
Hunt, this program has
gone through a lot.
We're just now finding
our footing again.
I mean, promoting you...
Hey, you're a great
teacher, Hunt.
Uh, if you need something to do,
I've been asking all of the
attendings to help Schmitt.
Okay? Okay.
We need him out of this chair
in order to assess
his spine fully.
Wait, he's hypotensive. We
need to put in another line.
He may be in neurogenic shock.
Alright, collapsed
lungs on both sides.
He needs bilateral chest tubes.
Okay, it's hard to
see, but it looks like
there's a deformity
in the mid cervical
and high thoracic spine.
The impalement is near
his femoral fracture.
We're gonna need a CT.
Jonathan? Paola.
Yasuda, I need you
to put in an IO line.
On it.
I'm so sorry I went up there.
It was awful and gorgeous and...
then I just fell straight down.
Why aren't you getting him out?
We're working on it.
I'm so glad you came.
I didn't know if you'd
make it before I...
Wait! Wait, is he dying?
We need to cut him out of this
thing. Please don't let him die.
Hang on. Hang on. I need
everyone to let me ensure
he's getting oxygen
into his lungs
because without it,
he's gonna go into
respiratory arrest before
we can even turn a saw on.
I need a chest tube
tray and someone to page
Dr. Owen Hunt right now!
We are a level one trauma
center in a lightning storm.
You will see gnarly injuries.
You do not have time to gawk.
Well, we probably
won't see anyone
struck by lightning today.
Check your tablet, Kwan.
The patient intake
log disagrees.
Most people who are
struck by lightning
aren't actually hit.
They're standing next
to something that is.
Current enters wires,
pipes, the ground
until a body, and then boom.
You also don't have time
for random lightning facts.
Hey, Doctor, are you
here for us, the Smiths?
Uh, Heather, Logan, and Paige?
Yeah, my wife and kids.
Uh, they were in our backyard,
and, uh, lightning struck
the basketball hoop,
and... And they got zapped.
Did anyone lose consciousness?
No, but they were
very disoriented.
I once got a concussion
when a volleyball
hit me in the face, and
it was just like that!
I think the shock did something
to her hearing.
So now she's even more annoying.
Um, I have to, um...
Go, Dr. Schmitt.
We've got this. Excuse me.
Uh, page me if you need me.
Uh-huh.
Uh, let's get a
full set of labs...
CBC, troponins, a
comprehensive metabolic panel.
Also 12-lead EKGs to
check for arrhythmias.
Wait, wait, what?
Um, most complications happen
within an hour of injury,
but we just want to be safe.
Okay. Alright,
thank you, Doctor.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, I was gonna say all that.
Then why didn't you?
Antioxidants for the
pancreas, sugar for energy,
and it's a long surgery,
so we should eat.
Just one second.
What's that?
I made it up to organize
the whipple steps.
It's anatomical designed,
so you start clockwise
with 8:00 with the events...
SMV, Kocher, portal
dissection, bah, bah, bah.
And then counterclockwise
for anastomosis.
Oh. Tessa's like
Seattle royalty.
Man, I grew up on her stories.
I used to go to her
midnight book releases
with my dad and grandma.
Now I'm part of her story
in a tiny way, but still...
You feel better now
that the secret's out?
Uh...
different, not better.
So... Shepherd, Shep
is your nickname?
Yeah, it's my middle name.
You want us to call you that?
No. No.
You know, most people go to
work to avoid their families.
Heard.
Uh, oof, I-I-I should
check in with Marsh.
It's almost time.
Mm-hmm.
You okay?
Oh, yeah, it's just my childhood
on the operating table.
No pressure or anything.
Yeah.
Uh, I'll see you up there.
Alright. Alright.
There's a small amount of fluid
in the upper left quadrant.
The CT will give us
a better picture.
Sats back in the 90s. Alright,
let's go over the plan.
I'll hold his head to
keep the cervical spine
in a neutral position.
Link and I will hold
his legs until after the
chair's been detached
to prevent any shift in
the spinal fractures.
Yasuda, help Altman
steady the chest tubes.
Why does it sound like
you've all done this before?
We have. Yep.
I haven't.
Paola, we're gonna need
you to step outside
while we cut him out.
Wait, just one second.
I've been an ass.
I love you.
I gave up my dream for you,
and then I blamed you for it.
And if I live through this,
I will spend every day
making it up to you.
Paola, I love you.
Please forgive me.
Alright, yep.
We're good to go.
Okay. Ready? Let's do this.
Very, very slowly.
We got you.
Hey, uh, have you
seen Dr. Altman?
I'm jumping in down here.
Trauma 3, but she's not
handing out assignments.
Who is?
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
Are you here stealing supplies?
'Cause the clinic can have them.
No, I'm here to help.
No, I-I said that I
don't need supplies.
Well, you do if you're gonna
see the head lac in bed 6
and the ankle injury in 9.
Okay, uh, well, thank
you, Dr. Wilson.
I really appreciate your help.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Is that supposed to be sincere?
Yes, but for the rest of the
day, gratitude is implied.
Her pancreatitis formed a
pseudoaneurysm of the GDA.
See? Right there.
So you're gonna have
to be very careful
with the Kocher maneuver.
Right.
You okay?
Yeah.
There's nothing you
can do we can't fix.
Alright? And you
did the work, yeah?
Yeah. Yeah, so
you did the work.
You trust your instincts.
You trust your work.
Okay?
And, Adams,
you're good enough to
make your own name.
Believe me.
Uh, Marsh, can I have a word?
Yes, please, come in.
If this is about Meredith,
I've already informed
the interns that their
program is in good hands here.
No, it's not about them.
Uh, to put it directly,
should I anticipate
any goodbye e-mails from you?
Ah. No.
Uh, well
I don't know.
I mean, to be honest,
I've been so busy
with the residency
and my caseload,
I haven't had time
to think about it.
And if I had, I wouldn't
have thought for very long
because trying to
think the right way
to the right answer
with Meredith is...
She's not easy, I know,
but there's also
no one like her.
And when she leaves,
this place will feel it,
so I just need to make sure that
I'm prepared across the board.
Understood.
Okay.
Please keep me posted.
Ms. Hobbes, it's time.
Ready?
Sure am. Mm.
Are you?
We all are.
But before I take you...
Oh!
This is a real collector's item.
Meant a lot to me growing up.
My childhood was... I-I
grew up without a mom.
And this helped me to...
Helped me to see Tessa's
life wasn't perfect either.
Kids need messy stories.
That should be my epitaph.
Except you're not dying today.
I might. Let's be honest.
I don't want to, but I might.
You have another story to tell.
Dr. Griffith, don't do that.
I don't do fairy
tales, never have,
so let's not start now.
I tell children the truth
in a way that
helps them hear it.
Mm-hmm.
And I expect them
to do the same,
even when they're
no longer children.
I do have another story to tell.
I don't want to die.
I have asked my surgeons
to do their very best.
But I might not make it.
That's the truth.
So...
since this might be
my last signature,
let's make it a good one.
They're ready for you, Tessa.
Okay.
Here I come.
Hey.
Did you tell Lucas about
the pseudoaneurysm?
Mm-hmm. He's seen the scans.
I need him to appreciate
everything that could go wrong.
Why? Because he's
Derek's nephew?
Glad I could find out
when everyone else did.
He asked me to keep his
family connection private.
I respected that. Great.
And he knows about
the pseudoaneurysm.
I wasn't gonna blindside him.
I don't know what to do
either. I want to fight for us.
I want to try, but
every answer feels bad.
Yeah, because there
isn't a good one.
If I ask you to stay,
I'm being a jerk.
And if I follow you, I'm
deserting this class...
Your class.
But I haven't asked you to do
either one of those
things. Yeah, exactly.
You... You haven't asked
me to do anything. Nothing.
You don't consider
me part of your life.
Of course you're
part of my life.
You took the Boston job
without even talking...
Without even thinking
of talking to me.
And I get it. I do, I get it.
Your family needs
it, but it sucks.
It sucks, and I'm
being supportive
because there is
no other answer.
Well, maybe there
is. What do you want?
I just... I want
to do this surgery.
It's one thing we can fix.
That's all I want
from you right now.
Yeah, she has a perforated
eardrum which explains
the hearing loss.
Uh, it's common in
lightning strike victims.
It should heal on its own.
Am I okay?!
Can I keep reading?!
Will he be able to walk?
Uh, it's important he does.
This might hurt, but it helps
prevent infections, no crutches.
I just got new Jordans.
It's like the lightning
wanted my sneakers.
It wanted your sweat.
That's why you've got
burns in your armpits
and the backs of your knees,
on your elbows,
and on your feet.
It turned it to steam.
So his feet were sweating
so much his shoes exploded?
Mom! Will that happen to me?!
No, no, no, no. You have
something different!
Jonathan, you okay?
The noise... We're
almost there.
Once he's detached, we
need to use the board
to keep him flat and level.
And everyone moves at
the same time, okay?
Hold him tight, and we
move at the same time.
Remember, any movement of
his spine could paralyze him.
Let's get ready.
He's almost through.
Get in here, Julius. Let's go.
Alright, on my count...
One, two, three.
Wait, watch the lines.
Slow, slow, keep it straight.
Get this out of here.
Okay, nice work.
Let's get him up to CT.
Damn it. He's lost his airway.
Someone get me an
intubation tray right now!
Come on, Jonathan.
Alright.
Oh, wow!
I haven't seen this in years.
Remember I told you about this?
This is the Post-It note
that Meredith and Derek
wrote their vows on.
Oh, yeah.
Ugh, it's one of my
favorite stories.
Ugh. I'm going to
hold on to this.
No way I'm letting her
accidentally throw it away.
I feel weird.
It's like... I know that
I'm going to miss Meredith,
and I'll probably be diving
into a pint of Rum Raisin
very soon, but right
now, I'm just excited.
For Meredith's next
chapter and for Zola.
Yeah, well, um, as long
as we're on new chapters,
I did some research.
Turns out Grey-Sloan
has a fellowship
for vascular surgery.
And I don't want this
to turn into a fight...
Me neither. Maybe
we can revisit it
after Meredith has moved
and things calm down.
I'm filling out the application.
Nick and Teddy
gave me references,
and, actually, it
looks really promising.
Okay, sure.
For now. For now?
What is that supposed to
mean? It means, honestly,
I think you're going
to change your mind.
You've worked extremely
hard in cardio,
and I know that the last few
months have been rough...
Maggie, would you stop
for one second, please?
We just got the program
back up and running,
and it's really not an ideal
time to find a replacement.
For you. It's not an
ideal time for you.
What about me?
What about us?
Woman over P.A.: Dr. Dahanne to the
ER. Dr. Colette Dahanne to the ER.
Is he...
He's on his way to surgery.
We had to put in a breathing
tube, but he is stable.
God, that man is not capable
of letting me rest easy.
He turned down being a
war correspondent for me.
That was his dream.
He wanted to risk his life
every day in a literal war zone,
and I wanted him to not
do that because I just...
I just want to be
able to breathe.
And then he goes up
in a lightning storm.
I don't know what I'll
do if he doesn't make it.
And if he does make it, I
think I'm gonna kill him.
Paola, we are gonna
do everything we can.
And we'll keep you updated.
Okay.
Okay, I'm going to
start mobilizing
the ligament of Treitz.
I can take it. It's
okay, I got it.
I'm right here.
Adams, why don't you
mobilize it for us?
Right angle. W... Is
he ready for that?
Dissect right in
between my right angle.
Don't go deeper than
what I show you, yes.
And, Griffith, why do
we dissect the ligament?
To give better mobility
to the duodenum.
Correct. Okay.
Okay, what's next?
The Kocher maneuver. You keep
this up, you can do the chole.
Okay, well, when we get to that.
Yes. Not yet. Obviously.
Okay.
Hey. Can you see if
Mr. Vizcaino's scans are...
Are you shopping?
Yeah. Luna's
outgrown everything.
Oh, you should see
her. She is huge!
Yeah. She's gigantic.
Just like our backlog
of patients in the ER.
I just need five minutes.
Is Luna cold? No.
Is she naked? No.
Is she suffering? No.
But you know who is?
Ms. McGregor in bed four.
No. No, what?
No, you're not gonna let
the tiny bit of power
you've had for five
minutes go to your head.
You're chief resident?
Ooh, congratulations.
Guess what? You're
still a resident.
And in the world of general
surgery, I'm still an attending.
I can do surgeries
by myself. Can you?
Didn't think so.
I'm down here helping
you out of the kindness
of my warm, fuzzy little heart.
Mm. So you can say it.
Thank you.
Gratitude is implied
for the rest of the day.
Woman over P.A.: Dr. Williams to Peds
ICU. Dr. Cody Williams to Peds ICU.
Uh, I need to show you
something on a patient.
Can you take a look?
Dr. Kwan, are you
asking me for a consult?
No.
I already told him it's jewelry.
Thank you, Heather,
I know it's jewelry,
but we just need some more
details on why it's...
Well, that's bronze.
It's copper now, but
the jewelry was bronze.
Bronze is just copper
and tin together,
and tin has a lower
burning temperature.
So the tin vaporized,
and the copper
embedded itself in your skin,
so you just clean with
chlorhexidine and then debride.
Good consult.
I'll be right over there
if you get stumped again.
What did the CT find?
Unilateral facet fracture at C3
and a compression
fracture at T5.
There's also an
epidural hematoma.
I will decompress the
spinal cord and stabilize
the spine as fast as I can.
I saw extrav from the femoral
artery on the imaging.
Alright, I'll help you
with the vascular repair,
and stand by in case
there's abdominal bleeding.
Dr. Shepherd, um,
can I assist you
on the decompression and fusion?
Sure. Stand over there.
But I-I can't reach
the field from here.
I know.
Jonathan needs an
extremely delicate
and complicated procedure.
You're most useful if
you don't touch anything.
It's been a dramatic case,
Yasuda. You're doing great.
Ten blade.
Adams?
Uh, what'd I do?
Nothing. That's
just the problem.
You have to follow me.
I cannot work if I cannot
visualize the field.
Okay, on it. Don't worry about
what happened this morning.
None of that matters in here.
In here, it's perfect. Okay?
Okay.
Where are we?
Uh, 10 o'clock. Still
on the Kocher maneuver.
Kocher maneuver.
Which is what?
Mobilizing the duodenum and
pancreatic head off of the IVC.
Good.
Okay. Focus it where
I'm dissecting.
Okay. Easy with the retractor.
Okay, that's enough. Stop.
This isn't working.
Griffith, step in here. We
need a fresh set of hands.
I've got it. Yeah, you
don't have to do this.
Can you see the portal
vein, Dr. Marsh? I can.
One nick to her abdominal
aorta, and it's over.
This is not a skills
lab. He's clearly tired.
He keeps spacing out.
He's done for the day.
You're free to observe.
Griffith, step in, please.
It's okay. Where
am I, Griffith?
You've dissected to
the left lateral border
of the aorta. Good. Let's go.
You're switching specialties
to get away from me.
How could I not be worried?
How are you not worried?
Because that's not what this is!
You gotta come
see the lightning!
Oh, not now, sweetie.
We'll be right down
there, alright, buddy?
I never tried to dodge you.
You dodged me this morning.
You came here to
get away from me.
I just needed some space.
I just wanted to have some
control over something,
even if it was just
putting junk into boxes.
Maggie. Maggie. Maggie.
If we keep working together,
we're not gonna make it.
Okay? I love cardio.
But I love you more, and I'm...
I'm willing to give it up.
That is the dumbest
thing I've ever heard.
I thought you'd be flattered!
That you'd be willing to give
up your career goals for me?
Yes. No. No! No!
That is the opposite
of what I want.
of what I would do.
I would never give up cardio.
I would never, ever give
up my passion for you.
You are my passion, Maggie!
I... guess I'm not sure
that I respect that.
Maggie! Winston!
♪ Long way from the middle
Sats are dropping.
Tube is still connected.
Vent pressures are
through the roof.
There's no bleeding in the
field. What do you hear?
No breath sounds
on the right side.
There's no movement of air.
The chest tube must be blocked.
He's got a tension pneumothorax.
Scissors.
Come on, come on, come on.
♪ Oooo, oooo, oooo, oooo
Okay.
Oh, my God.
Okay. Alright,
you can continue.
Alright, good.
♪ On the other side
♪ Oooo, oooo, oooo, oooo
You read her books?
Hm, yeah.
"Tessa and the
Upside Down Garden"
was one of my favorites.
Read it in one sitting.
Then I went out and spent my
whole allowance on a cactus.
Ah. Oh, and thanks
for your help.
You know, I had
forgotten how nice it is
operating with you.
Was that a backhanded
compliment about my time off?
You're an excellent
surgeon, Bailey.
I mean, it's been a while.
I'm just stating facts.
Then I accept.
Y-You know, it's nice
to bring in new people,
and the attendings that
Meredith hired are...
Are good, but there's
really no substitute
for institutional knowledge.
Uh, the short hand. I
mean, it's efficient.
It is... No.
N-No?
No, I will not take over as
chief now that Grey is leaving.
I didn't ask you to.
But no one can run
this place like you.
J... I have a clinic to open,
and flattery will
not distract me.
Honestly, I resent it.
Bailey... No. Nope.
Ba... Ah!
You tried to butter me up
with almond croissants.
Uh.
Ben?
Everything okay?
No leaks.
Pancreatojejunostomy is patent.
Yeah, she's gonna make it.
Oh. Yes. Almost there, Tessa.
Dr. Grey, I need a moment.
Okay, well, I can't
step away right now.
I need you to take your
hands out of the field
right away, Meredith.
I got a call from Ben Warren.
There's a report of a
fire at your address.
I tried calling
Winston and Maggie,
but they didn't answer.
Station 19 is on the way.
I'll take you now. My kids?
I've told you everything I know.
Go. Go. We got it.
It's okay. Keep going.
You're in it now. Keep going.
Concentrate now. Good.
What are you doing? You
can't come through here.
Meredith! Meredith! Hey! Hey!
I live here! I-It's her
house, man, alright.
Let her through.
Alright, it's okay.
E-Everything's fine.
The kids are right here.
What happened?
Oh, my God.
- Hi.
- Mom!
What has happened?
Uh, we were upstairs,
and lightning struck the house.
We got the kids, we came down,
got outside as
quickly as we could.
I need an inch and
a half line here.
Dr. Grey, I'm... I'm so sorry.
I know this is hard,
but you got to keep
a safe distance, alright?
Okay. Okay.
We wanted to go back in and
take some boxes, but the fire.
It's okay. It's...
You're okay.
That's all I care about.
It's just stuff.
Yeah, I'm still concerned
about the JP output.
So monitor closely and
make sure to call me
and transfuse if
it dips below 7.
Of course. Okay?
Yeah.
Any news on Dr. Grey's house?
All I've heard is
the kids are okay,
and that's all that matters.
Griffith, you did great today.
It was a rough surgery
for many reasons.
You were not one
of them. Good job.
♪ Our love was born
Will he be okay?
The recovery will be long.
His injuries are
extensive and severe,
but he made it through today.
Thank you. Thank
you all so much.
You can go in and
see him if you want.
♪ To the place
where it resides ♪
Shepherd will want neuro
checks every half-hour.
And keep an eye on his oxygen.
Copy that.
♪ No matter the time
Dr. Altman...
there are nine
kids in my family.
I-I promise I have a point,
and I will talk faster.
Um, my parents
always wanted a boy,
and they kept having
kids until they got one.
And our parents always
told me and my sisters
that we could be
anything we wanted,
but it was kind of hard
to ignore the subtext,
you know... girls aren't enough.
And on almost every level,
I know that it's not true,
but they cooked it
into me pretty good.
And today you uncooked it.
Watching you work
today, you changed me.
You are a badass
boss lady surgeon,
and I want to be
you when I grow up.
Yasuda, I'm... Sorry. Is it...
Is it disrespectful to call
you a badass or a boss lady?
No. I... It's
much appreciated.
If you're gonna crack a joke
about me being more bossy
than a boss lady, I
already have it in my head.
Actually, I was gonna
say maybe you should
apply to be chief.
We kind of need the money, so...
♪ And no words to speak
♪ This isn't goodbye
♪ If you need my love
♪ Look to the sky
♪ Mm, mm
Let me show you how it's done.
Spare me.
So, are you gonna tell me
how you know so much
about lightning?
Were you struck by
lightning as a child?
Because that would
explain a lot.
Well, I'll tell you if you
tell me how you happen to know
the melting points
of precious metals.
Oh, that's easy.
My mom used to make jewelry.
And my brother and I would
sell it at the farmers' market
as a cover while my dad
sold weed under the table.
Wow. Your parents sound...
fun.
Hmm.
Honestly?
I spent most of my childhood
just wishing they
would disappear.
And did they? Nope.
They are still here.
And still high.
Okay, your turn.
Well, I spent a few
years in Saint Kitts,
where lightning
is a fact of life.
You grew up there? No.
I went there for...
I went there for medical school.
Because I didn't get into
medical school in the U.S.
But your nickname
is Blue Ribbon,
so I'm a little confused.
My nickname is just Blue
because I was a
valedictorian in high school,
all state track and field,
and a national chess champion.
But then in college,
my mother got sick,
my grades took a nosedive,
and Saint Kitts
became my only option.
And your mom, is she okay?
No.
She got really sick,
and then she died.
But on a brighter note,
we'd make a hell
of a trivia team.
Hey. Hey.
Oh, I was kind of craving
that little Italian
place on the corner.
Uh, yeah, no.
I wouldn't eat
what's in that bag.
It's not the eco-friendly
stuff that you love,
but it will get you
through the week.
What, you didn't like
Scout's Elsa shirt
cinched at the waist
with a headband?
I'm more of an Anna guy.
Thank you. I really... I really
appreciate you helping me.
Yeah, of course.
Yeah, you know, I just... I...
I knew that it was a rough day
because of the
clinic not opening.
Yeah. So, hey,
why don't we, uh,
go get takeout at
the Italian place?
There's lightning in everyone.
You get a better offer?
Opposite charges
finding each other.
They connect. They spark.
And as long as they
do, your life goes on.
Yeah, okay. Put the
scissors on the ribbon,
but do... but don't cut.
I'm... Gotta...
Does three people make
this a grand opening?
Oh, many great things
start small, Wilson.
This clinic will be one of them.
Flash or no flash?
Just take the picture, Lincoln!
Your cells keep multiplying.
Your brain keeps thinking.
Alright. Okay, I'm gonna cut.
Okay. Alright. Cut, cut, cut!
♪ When all I know is
that I'm feeling ♪
♪ Numbed out, run down, made
of stone ♪ Right! Right!
Oh, yes. We have
earned the good stuff.
Alright.
♪ There is something
telling me that ♪
Elena Bailey? Oh, my mom.
♪ All I need to do
is keep moving on ♪
She spent her life
fighting to make sure
I had every opportunity,
every freedom I deserved.
She was complicated...
Our relationship
was complicated,
but she loved me with
her entire heart.
♪ Take it one
breath at a time ♪
And that took courage.
Elena Bailey lived
with love and courage.
Now it's our turn.
Oh, it is. Yeah.
Alright, pull that
off. Oh, oh, oh.
Alright, everybody back.
Back it up. Back it up.
Back that thing
up. Back that up.
Ah.
♪ Take it one step at a time
There it is. There it is.
That's the good stuff.
There it is right
there. Ooh, look.
Your body wants to move, so
it moves, because it can.
Tessa is awake.
That was amazing!
We just assisted on
a successful whipple.
We just assisted on a successful
whipple in our first year!
Damn, there is no
job better than this.
You assisted.
I botched the portal
dissection and got benched.
I failed.
You started strong.
Plus, Grey and Marsh
were out of sync today.
I-It could have
happened to any of us.
Yeah? Would Kwan
have lost focus?
Or Millin? Hm?
Did you?
Lucas, you had a bad day.
It's not the end of the world.
Stop being nice!
Tessa could have died!
If... If Tessa had died
and your little book
was the last thing
she ever signed,
would you be in here trying
to make me feel better?
Why are you yelling at me? I
stepped in and saved your ass.
You should be thanking
me. Thank you!
Well, you're welcome!
♪ I take it one
step at a time ♪
I'm sorry. I can't.
♪ Mountain in front of me
♪ Hangs over everything
I can't.
Um... why not?
Because I can't.
Life is electricity.
Positive and negative.
Creation and destruction.
♪ Put one foot in
front of the other ♪
♪ One breath after another
It's too early to say
anything for sure,
but we're trying everything.
Thank you.
♪ Take it one step at a time
Winston found this earlier.
Uh, it fell when the
lightning hit it.
It was all I managed to take.
Destruction, sometimes
for the better,
sometimes for the worse.
♪ One foot in front
of the other ♪
♪ One breath after another
♪ I still take it
one step at a time ♪
But we're all storms inside.
♪ Take it one step at a time
Captions by VITAC...