Our drug can give people
their lives back.
Mr. Booker, we'll have
answers for you soon.
You could have
a bright future
running clinical trials.
I'm flattered, really.
Auggie is running
out of time, Sharon.
Weren't you looking to see
if he had any relatives?
Only a family member
can consent to the transplant.
We've decided
to adopt Auggie.
I'll sign off
on the surgery.
I lost my daughter
to leukemia
about ten years ago.
I don't talk about this
with many people.
Oh, baby.
No.
Dr. Virani?
I just examined
trial patient CM 42,
Alvin Booker,
and I am very encouraged.
His ejection fraction
is up, BP's stable.
EKG showed no PVC's,
normal sinus rhythm.
And he is not complaining
of any side effects.
Great.
Yeah, he's only been
in the trial a week,
and given this degree
of improvement,
I've to assume
he's getting the medication.
We'll see.
But this is all good news.
Thanks, Will.
All right.
Now, you take care, okay?
Mr. Booker,
I'll see you next week.
You bet, Doc.
Bye, Alvin.
Hey. Thanks for getting him
in the trial again.
No reason
he shouldn't have been.
I'm just glad it worked out.
Hey.
You seen Ethan?
I have a requisition
for him to sign.
He's gonna be late.
He called and said he had a
personal matter to attend to.
You're joking, right?
No. Why?
He's here 24/7. He doesn't
have a personal life.
How can he have
a personal matter?
Always a kind word.
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah.
Uh...
You remember how I told you
that, uh, my ex-wife,
she came to drop
something off?
Yeah.
It was a box of our
daughter's things, right?
Claire thought maybe
I'd find some joy
in remembering, you know?
But the thing
about it is, I...
I can't bring myself to...
I can't deal with
what's inside that box.
I don't know why.
I get it.
Yeah.
Dr. Manning?
Yeah?
Check your iPad.
Oh. Thank you.
If you're not headed up
to the OR, what do you say?
You wanna go practice
some real medicine?
You bet.
Let's do it.
Show me how it's done.
Mr. Kelton?
Hi, I'm Dr. Manning.
This is Dr. Marcel.
Hi.
I'm Tim.
My boyfriend. He brought me.
Well, that doesn't
sound fun.
You're COVID negative, though.
One thing we don't
have to worry about.
BP 101/67.
Heart rate 112.
Sats 93 on 2 liters oxygen.
Okay. Let's get a chest X-ray?
And you're having trouble
breathing.
Your temperature looks good,
but it says you're
having night sweats.
I've had bronchitis before,
wasn't this bad.
Okay. Um, sir, would you mind
standing back, please?
All right, clear.
Yeah.
Right middle lobe.
Pleural effusions.
It looks like
you have pneumonia.
Um, do you mind
if I take a listen?
Decreased breath sounds
on the right side.
God, does he need
to be admitted?
Maybe not.
I'd like to see how he
reacts to the antibiotics.
Ceftriaxone two grams IV
and one gram azithromycin.
Let's also get him
a nebulizer treatment.
That'll help
with your breathing.
And let's get him a CBC, CMP,
coags, D-dimer and an ABG.
Sounds like a lot.
It really is
the standard fare.
Okay, try not to worry.
This is manageable, okay?
We'll be back to check
on you shortly.
This real medicine,
you're pretty good at it.
Darryl, Vera.
Hey, Dr. Halstead.
What seems
to be the trouble?
She's not right.
She's not herself.
Heart rate's 85, BP's 130/70.
I noticed her ankles
are swollen and her
jugular's distended.
Hey, Vera, do you know
where you are?
White coats...
See?
Hey, increase her supplemental
O2 to six liters.
Vera, do you know who I am?
Pastor?
Honey, no,
it's Dr. Halstead,
from the trial.
Is it okay if I listen
to your chest?
Okay.
All right.
Hearing an S3 gallop
and water in the lungs.
That's why
she's short of breath.
Why's this happening to her?
Why's she like this?
I don't know.
Is it the pills
you gave her?
I don't know
what's causing it,
but I'm gonna find out.
Chest X-ray, tox screen, CBC,
BMP, BNP and troponins.
Also, ten milligrams
of IV Lasix.
Right.
I'll be back when I know more.
Okay, you just rest, Vera.
Doris.
Yeah?
Page Dr. Virani right away.
What's up?
My patient, Vera Johnson,
is in our drug trial.
She's very ill, and it's not
straight up heart failure.
Yeah.
All right, Auggie.
I'm gonna go
to work now, okay?
Okay.
I need you to
finish your eggs.
'Cause we're gonna
be taking you home
in about two weeks.
I want you to get
your strength back.
All right?
Morning.
Hey.
Hey, Dad.
"Dad"? I like the sound
of that.
You don't have to go in?
Teaching online today.
Brought us a couple of
Choose Your Own
Adventure books.
What do you like?
Prisoners of the Ant People
or The Lost Jewels of Nabooti?
Hmm.
Nabooti!
The Ant People.
Oh, okay.
All right, I'm gonna
leave you two.
Go save some lives.
I am.
Bye, sweetie. Okay.
Bye.
Dr. Choi,
the requisition?
You okay?
Yeah. Uh... Pulled a muscle
working out.
That's why I don't exercise.
It'll kill you.
She's suffering
volume overload.
Her electrolytes
are out of whack.
She's confused
and disoriented.
History of dementia?
No.
Her sodium's still low.
Hang another ten
of Lasix
and start her
on hypertonic saline.
One of your trial patients?
Yeah. First one I enrolled.
You all right?
Yeah. Um, these symptoms
are troubling.
You think it's an adverse
reaction to the medication?
Could be,
but I don't know yet.
In any case, I'll need
to inform Kender.
We may have a problem.
I'll work her up.
Let you know what I find.
Hold on. She's my patient.
She came in as
an ED patient, not a trial.
I don't see how that matters.
Dr. Halstead is familiar with
the patient. Maybe he should
be the one to work her up.
Yeah, that's fine.
Excuse me.
Thanks.
Dr. Abrams.
Good morning.
Ms. Goodwin, is it me,
or are this year's first-year
residents even less competent
than last year's?
You know,
you ask me that every year.
Doesn't mean
it isn't the case.
Hey, Crockett.
Yeah?
My patient, Ron Kelton.
Mmm-hmm.
His latest X-ray shows
the pneumonia is
starting to resolve.
Good.
No, but look at this.
Yeah. Right middle lobe
still has an infiltrate.
Yeah.
In line with community
acquired pneumonia.
His latest blood work
shows procalcitonin is normal.
His cells aren't
fighting off bacteria.
Which makes me think
that even though
the pneumonia is better...
Something else is going on.
Right.
Should scan chest
and abdomen.
That was my thought. Thanks.
All right.
Dr. Choi, Dr. Lanik.
Two peds versus auto.
You're going to Trauma Two.
Paul Beller, 35,
COVID negative, contusions
and abrasions, GCS 15.
Where's that guy?
They bringing him
here, too?
Heart rate 80, BP 128/84.
I'm okay. I didn't need
to come to the hospital.
If he's here...
We just want to
check you out.
Jim, can you take...
Don't let him near me.
Mags said
there were two.
Right behind us.
I can't go anywhere.
I can't do anything.
He's always following me.
Male,
50 years, Richard Cohen.
Dr. Richard Cohen.
COVID negative.
GCS 14. Vitals good.
Don't let Mason find me.
Don't tell anyone I'm here.
What's going on?
Other guy, Beller,
minding his business,
comes out of the post office,
suddenly, this clown
starts yelling,
chases him into the street.
Car comes around the corner,
clips them both.
Don't be fooled.
It was Mason.
That's who it was.
Thought I should
escort him in,
didn't know what he'd do next.
Thanks. We're good.
Let's transfer on my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
He had this with him.
He's gonna find me.
Always does.
Dr. Cohen,
I need to examine you.
Is that all right?
Of course. All those
know-nothings out there,
spouting their ignorance.
I listen to science.
Okay. Okay.
Can you move your head
from side to side?
Good. Up and down?
Mmm.
Good. The C-spine's cleared.
He thinks he can fool me
with these disguises.
I see right through them.
We're gonna roll you,
all right?
All right, ready? Roll.
Oh!
Back.
Tell me, Dr. Cohen,
where do you practice?
I'm not a medical doctor.
He has a Cole University ID.
I run the Neuroscience Lab.
Dr. Choi.
Dr. Cohen, what are those?
None of your business.
Put those back?
Lungs are clear.
Add a tox screen
to the standard blood work.
Also chest and pelvic X-ray.
Dr. Cohen, I don't think
you sustained
any serious injuries,
but I'm gonna have
another doctor come in
and talk to you, okay?
Long as it's not Mason.
No. His name is Dr. Charles,
and I think he can help you.
I'll check in on you later.
Stay here until
Dr. Charles comes.
There you go.
Thank you.
Made it.
Excellent.
Um, can I have a black?
Thank you, ma'am.
How's Auggie doing?
Good.
Yeah?
He's good.
And the adoption?
It's good.
All the paperwork is in, and
we had our first interview.
I think it went well.
Great, great!
Look who's here.
Hey, son.
Hey, Ma.
Maggie.
Michael.
Scrubbing in today?
Yeah.
Surgeon's implanting
one of our shunts.
Sure feels good to be back.
Good.
I gotta go, Ma.
Love you, too.
Good seeing you, Maggie.
Nice seeing you, Michael.
Thank you.
He's enthusiastic.
Yeah, this past year
was pretty tough
on him, though.
Getting furloughed
and having to move back home,
just when his life
was really moving forward.
It's been like that
for a lot of people.
I know. It's that,
of all my children,
Michael's taken
the longest to find himself.
He did not
need this pandemic.
I'll tell you, Maggie,
you never stop worrying
about them, no matter
how old they get.
Their health, their happiness.
Still, it's all worth it.
My children
are the greatest joy
in my life.
When I look at Auggie,
I know what you mean.
Hey, Jim.
The patient's injuries
are superficial,
so, I'm downgrading
and discharging him.
His name is definitely
not Mason.
It's Beller. He doesn't even
know anyone named Mason,
and he's never met
that nutjob who chased him
into the street.
By the way, Ethan,
you look like hell.
Didn't sleep well last night.
I told you being chief's
no picnic.
Yeah.
Hey.
What do you make of Dr. Cohen?
I checked him out.
His credentials
are totally legit.
He certainly knows more about
neuroscience than I ever will.
Were you able to locate
any of his family?
A daughter,
she's on her way in.
Oh, good. Far as I can tell,
he is suffering
from one of the
misidentification disorders.
There are several,
but basically, the idea is,
you look at somebody
and you genuinely believe
they are somebody else.
This Mason
he keeps referring to.
Right. A colleague, I guess,
who he thinks
is out to destroy him.
Look, he's clearly delusional.
Question is, why?
What's causing it?
It can be physical,
a tumor, brain injury,
but it can also be chemical.
We're waiting
on the tox screen.
Yeah.
We should start with that,
but be prepared
to do a full work-up.
You got it.
All right.
Are you okay, buddy?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Okay.
You can wait down here.
The CT won't be long.
He'll be back soon.
Okay.
Don't worry.
You're the strongest person
I know.
He swims 30 laps every day.
Not every day.
Let's go.
Dr. Marcel.
Yeah?
Ron is a very special person.
Before we met,
I'd kind of given up
on having a real relationship.
He's been a gift in my life.
We don't know
if anything serious
is going on.
We're just covering
all our bases.
Okay?
Okay.
Don't worry.
Her electrolytes
are slightly better,
but not much.
My lights are bright.
Honey, not "lights,"
"electrolytes."
There's been
no significant change.
Despite upping her
diuretics and the saline?
You haven't been able
to determine the cause
of her symptoms?
Still working on it.
It could be
an adverse reaction
to the medication.
We don't even know
if she's getting
the medication.
We need to unblind
her then. Find out.
That's the protocol.
Hold on.
If we unblind her,
she'll be pulled
from the trial.
She'll be taken off
the medication,
which might be helping her,
and we'll lose all her data.
Besides, we don't even know
how Kender's Safety Board
will react.
They might pause
the trial altogether.
I don't think that we have
a choice, Will.
We need to find out
if the medication
is causing this.
Sabeena, no one in the trial
has had symptoms like this.
I don't think
it's the medication.
Give me a couple
more hours to find
an alternate diagnosis.
For her sake
and for everyone else's.
Please.
I'll give you
to the end of the day.
But if her
condition worsens...
I know. Thanks.
Scan's up.
There's a mass.
And enlarged lymph nodes.
Damn it.
Second cancer in two days.
There's a chance
it could be sarcoidosis.
Cold comfort,
and highly unlikely.
No, we need an endobronchial
ultrasound biopsy to confirm.
Mason, you bastard!
You don't fool me!
I know it's you!
Careful. Hey, hey!
I know it was...
Get this guy away from me!
Dr. Charles.
I told you he'd find me!
Get back in bed.
You didn't listen! I told you!
No!
Please, Dr. Cohen,
we're trying to help you.
Don't let him near me!
Keep him away!
Keep who away?
Mason!
That's him! That's Mason!
I don't know what
he's talking about.
Liar!
I went in there
to restock the supplies.
You see? He won't
leave me alone!
Restraints, please.
Nice and easy.
When will he stop? When?
Five of Haldol, two of Ativan.
Got it.
It's horrible.
I can't go anywhere.
I can't do anything.
He follows me everywhere.
Always out there.
Remember when I said
there were several of these
misidentification disorders?
Yeah.
I think we're dealing
with Fregoli, okay?
Which was named
for a 19th century
quick change artist.
It's the delusion
that somebody
who is persecuting you
has the ability to change
their appearance.
First, he thought
that Mason was Beller.
Now, it's Doris. Whoa, Ethan!
Ethan! A little help here!
Ethan!
Dr. Choi?
Okay. Let's lay him down.
All right, Ethan?
Let's get a room.
I'm on it.
Ethan!
Ethan, can you hear me?
Ethan, what's going on?
I need a minute to rest.
Yeah, you think?
102.6. You're burning up.
Start an IV,
hang a thousand Tylenol
and fluids.
Dr. Charles.
He's had surgery.
Ethan, what procedure
did you have?
Gallbladder.
How long ago?
This morning.
This morning?
Why aren't you in recovery?
I thought I could manage.
Who's your surgeon?
Hamad. East Mercy.
He discharged you?
No, I left.
Dr. Charles, I found these
on the floor.
Cipro.
It's no big deal.
No big deal?
You know
you look septic.
Probably having bile spillage.
These aren't gonna cut it.
Give him 1,000 of Rocephin
and 500 of Flagyl.
What made you do
something so crazy?
I just wanted to
get back to work.
That's not gonna happen
any time soon, because
we're gonna admit you.
Do I understand
this correctly?
He wakes up from anesthesia,
puts his clothes on
and comes back to work?
It's just like Ethan.
Hang on. There's the mass.
Partially obstructing
his bronchiole.
It might just be
the tip of the iceberg.
Switch to 3D.
See how far
into the wall it goes.
It extends into
the parenchyma.
Not unexpected.
Capturing image.
1.2 centimeters.
Forceps coming.
Nice and easy.
Good. Open.
And close.
Thank you.
Run it to pathology.
On its way.
Hey.
You hear about Ethan?
Yeah, pretty crazy. Poor guy.
I gotta leave
for about an hour.
I need you to cover for me.
What about Mrs. Johnson?
It's for Mrs. Johnson.
I know the chemical structure
of the trial medication.
I'm taking her blood
to an outside lab,
to see if it contains
the drug's signature.
That way, we will know
if she's on it or not.
Hold on, you're unblinding her
without the company knowing?
You cannot do that.
April, I do not think
her condition is caused
by the drug.
But I need to know,
one way or not,
if she's on it.
If she's not, that'll help
narrow things down
and help me look for the real
cause of the symptoms.
But keeping the company
out of the loop,
unblinding her on the sly...
If Kender learns
about this, they will
fire you from the trial.
If Kender unblinds her,
they'll pause the trial
altogether.
Is that what this is about?
Protecting the trial?
I'm protecting our patients.
Look at Mr. Booker,
how well he's doing.
I'm not willing to risk him
losing this medication.
Are you?
Okay, then.
Hi. So, we have some news.
The mass we discovered
in the CT, we biopsied it,
it is malignant.
Cancer?
Yeah.
Squamous cell carcinoma.
Are you sure?
The good news is,
it's 1.2 centimeters,
not very big.
It's resectable, so,
we can take it out.
Mmm. The tumor predisposed
you to the pneumonia,
which is actually a blessing,
because it allowed us
to find the tumor
before it grew larger.
So, what happens now?
We take
Ron into surgery and
I remove the mass.
Hopefully, the lymph nodes
are minimally involved.
Yeah. In the meantime,
we'll loop in oncology.
After surgery, you may need
to start a course of chemo,
maybe radiation.
Hey.
Who knew pneumonia
could be a good thing?
All this really necessary?
Oh, don't you worry,
we'll have you back
on your feet in a jiffy.
Dr. C, check your iPad.
Richard Cohen's
tox screen just came in.
And his daughter's here.
Thanks, Hank.
So, as far as you know,
your dad has no history
of mental illness?
No. Never.
Right.
His tests did not indicate
a physical cause
for his mental state,
which makes it
much more likely that it
was chemically induced.
Um, which brings us to these.
Oh, no.
Yeah. Even with a tox screen,
we weren't able
to identify most of them.
And I was hoping that
you might be able to
help us out with that?
Some of them.
It's my dad's own cocktail.
Uh, Brahmi, Phenibut,
L-carnitine, Piracetam,
Ginkgo.
He's always adding more,
so, I don't know what else.
Uh-huh. So, those are
supplements that supposedly
have nootropic effect,
you know, they increase
cognitive function.
Do you think your pop
might be worried that
he's losing his faculties?
No. My father's
a brilliant man.
He got his PhD
when he was 22.
But he's always
looked to improve
his mental capacity.
He said these were safe.
Theoretically. But when
taken together with all
of his other medications,
it is possible that they could
have caused a psychotic break.
What, psychotic?
I know it's a scary word,
but it's really just another
medical term for delusion.
And I've given him something
to calm him down.
And when these leave
his system, we really
should see a change.
You know, most of his
delusions have been focused
on somebody named Mason.
Do you know who that is or why
he might be afraid of him?
There's no reason at all.
Dr. Mason was a colleague.
He was chair
of the department
before my dad.
But he had an aneurism
a year ago.
Dr. Mason is dead.
Please keep me posted
on Dr. Choi's condition,
and let me know
when they get him a room
on the medical floor.
Dr. Abrams,
I'm really sorry
if I overstepped.
Overstepped?
That's a generous
assessment.
Dr. Abrams, something wrong?
I've handled it.
Please, tell me.
He's coaching me
on a stent, which is
insulting in and of itself,
but then he has the
temerity to try to upsell me
on a new spinalscope.
He tried to upsell you
during an operation?
Look, I know he's your son,
but I can't say that I would
welcome him back to my OR.
I just got Mrs. Johnson's
blood work back.
She's on the medication.
What are you gonna do?
I have to let Virani
officially unblind her.
They'll probably
stop the trial.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
It's Mrs. Johnson.
What's wrong with her?
She's having a seizure.
Five of Ativan.
Why's this happening?
Likely from low sodium.
It causes swelling
of the brain.
Can't you do
something for her?
Believe me, we're trying.
With everything we've done,
diuretics, hypertonic saline,
her sodium shouldn't
still be this low.
Nobody else is having
symptoms like this
in the trial.
What am I missing?
There is one possibility.
With your permission,
I'd like to send your wife
for a CT scan of her head.
What about talking
to Dr. Virani?
Let's do this first.
You sure?
Yes. Mr. Johnson,
do I have your permission?
Uh...
Mr. Johnson?
If you think it'll help, yes.
Let Radiology know
we're coming up.
Well?
This is Mrs. Johnson's scan.
Okay.
And this is
a hypothalamic lesion.
A tumor?
I mean, it's small,
but it's pressing
on the pituitary.
Which explains
her low sodium.
That's what caused
her seizure.
And not
the trial medication.
If she's on it.
This is great news for us.
But what about Mrs. Johnson?
Once we correct the lesion,
pituitary function
should go back to normal.
So, we won't need
to unblind her.
No, I don't think
it's necessary.
I mean, that is such a relief.
Congratulations. This was
an incredible catch.
All right,
got the bleeding
under control.
Path says
the margins are clean
on the resected mass.
Where are we with
the level four nodes?
I'd like to wrap this up.
Hold on. I just
received something.
They're seeing cancerous,
undifferentiated cells.
Adenosquamous in appearance.
Damn it.
Have you located
the level seven nodes?
Yeah.
And?
Doesn't look great.
I'm going after them.
Get Path on standby.
Will, you know what
we did was wrong.
But we did it for
the right reasons.
It didn't affect the trial.
It all worked out.
It did all work out.
Behind Dr. Virani's back.
Are you ever gonna tell her?
No, you're right. I should.
Come in.
Hey.
Hey, Ma, what's up?
Uh, I need your
help, Michael.
Sure.
You know, it's my job
to try to make sure this
hospital is run smoothly,
which isn't always easy,
given
different people's demands
and their egos.
So, what can I do?
I need you to just be
a little more aware.
Aware?
In the OR.
Surgeons are a particular
kind of breed.
Some of them can be
easily offended.
This is about Abrams.
He was using an outmoded
piece of equipment.
I was trying to help the guy.
That's not the point.
I can't have my medical reps
upselling during a procedure.
If that's what
he told you I was doing,
I was not.
It doesn't matter.
That's how
he interpreted it.
I'm trying so hard
to get back on my feet.
Would it be too much to ask
for you to back me up
just a little?
Listen to me.
This isn't about you.
It's about
hospital protocol.
Michael?
So, your daughter
is here to see you,
but I thought it might be
a good idea if we just had
a little chat first.
I have a grant proposal
to write,
and to finish my paper
on cortical mapping.
I promise you, I won't take up
too much of your time.
And the faculty evaluation.
If I don't keep up,
you know what's gonna happen.
You know, I don't.
He's gonna get my job.
Who's gonna get the job?
Dr. Mason?
He published ten papers
a year, but three more
and I'll have 11.
Right.
So, you feel like you're in
competition with Dr. Mason?
He had my job before.
He wants it back.
Right.
You do know that
he's dead, don't you?
If I get the R01...
Wait, wait.
...that'll really show him.
Dr. Cohen, look at me.
Now, he's not as brilliant
as people say.
Dr. Mason died a year ago.
He's dead.
No, no. He's out there.
No. Dr. Mason
died a year ago,
from a brain aneurism.
He's dead.
He's dead?
I...
I have to do better.
Why?
I have to. I just have to.
Wait, is it you don't think
that you're
as good as Dr. Mason was?
That you don't
deserve his job?
That despite
all of your qualifications,
all your success,
that still, deep down,
you feel, I guess,
inadequate, professionally?
I work so hard.
I'm so tired.
I can only imagine.
You know, Dr. Cohen,
I have looked at your CV,
and from all
the evidence I see,
you are much,
much more than adequate.
And that you don't need
to compete with anybody.
Alive or dead.
Good night, Michael.
Michael?
Night, Maggie.
You know, I was so happy
when Kender placed him here,
and now, I think it might have
been better for both of us
if he'd been assigned
to another hospital.
What happened?
We argued.
I tried to talk to him
about surgical protocols.
I had to.
He took it personally.
Michael so much
wants to please me,
to make me proud.
He always has.
So. I'm the one that
could hurt him the most.
Mmm.
Hi, Ron.
I'm sorry,
we wish we had
better news.
So, analysis of the samples
we sent to pathology
show
a very aggressive cancer,
which unfortunately,
has metastasized.
We'll test the samples
to determine your best
chemo options.
But given the nature
of your cancer,
we're afraid it won't respond.
We're so sorry.
This is a...
question
I didn't think I'd be
asking this morning,
but, um...
How...
How long do I have?
Oh, God.
No.
I need to know.
How long?
We can't really know for sure.
Maybe a year.
99.4.
Temperature's down.
How are you feeling?
I'm all right.
Turnover rate
wasn't bad today.
Oh. That's a relief.
Ethan, this could've been
a lot worse for you.
Thanks for coming by.
Oh. Nurse Sexton,
guess what? It's official.
By orders of Ms. Goodwin,
Dr. Choi here
is on forced sick leave.
Good.
Gonna have to confiscate
that iPad, buddy.
Come on.
Okay, just turn it off.
So, look, you'll be
happy to hear
that Dr. Cohen
is coming out of it.
Good.
Yeah.
Buddy. What the hell?
Okay.
I realize I shouldn't
have come back so soon
after my operation.
Why do you think
you did that?
I'm the chief of the ED.
I have a greater
responsibility.
We've talked about that.
What exactly does that mean?
I have to work
harder than anyone.
Huh.
It's funny, Dr. Cohen was just
saying exactly the same thing.
In his case, it was about
proving that he was better
than his predecessor.
I'm not Dr. Cohen.
Of course you're not.
But isn't that something?
This guy,
what's really driving him,
despite all of his success,
all of his achievements,
is that he didn't feel
like he measured up.
So, you're just sharing an
observation about a patient?
Yeah.
Here's the ironic part.
It's often the people who are
the very best at what they do,
who feel the most inadequate.
Look, you have
everything you need?
The right flavored Jell-O?
I'm good.
Okay. I'll check back
on you.
Thanks, Dr. Charles.
Any time.
I'll be back
first thing tomorrow.
Okay.
Bring you breakfast?
Mmm-mmm. I'll get
something here.
Oh.
It's Goodwin. She wants
to see us in her office.
Now.
Yeah.
Come on.
Hey.
You haven't checked
Auggie's Heredity & Me
site recently, have you?
Once we got the transplant,
we didn't see the need.
Why?
It turns out, he has
a brother in California.
A brother?
His name is Keshawn.
He's four years older.
His adoptive parents
contacted the hospital and me
when you didn't respond
to their post.
Are you up to meeting them?
Ah. Maxine and Antoine Carter,
Maggie Lockwood
and Ben Campbell,
the couple
we spoke about.
They're in the process
of adopting Auggie.
We can't tell you what
this means to Keshawn.
When the boys
went into foster care,
Keshawn was five.
He remembered that he had
a little brother and he
always hoped to find him.
With your permission,
we can fly out,
so the boys can meet.
Oh. Um, of course.
Auggie'll be thrilled.
That's great. Thank you.
Thank you.
Come in.
Dr. Choi?
Dr. Virani.
I was there
when you took ill.
Uh, I'm sorry
you had to see that.
No. Please.
I just wanted to see
how you were doing.
I'm fine. Thank you.
You're one of those
never-say-die types.
I guess.
I get it.
Good night.
Sabeena.
Hi. I was just
checking in on Dr. Choi.
That's what I was
coming to do. How is he?
On the mend.
Good.
Listen, you should know...
There's a restaurant in
my neighborhood opening up
in a couple of weeks
for those
that've gotten vaccinated.
What do you say
You want to check it out?
I'd like that.
Great.
Okay. Yeah,
I'll see you tomorrow.
Hey, Crockett.
Hey.
Don't go just yet.
Um, Ron and Tim
need us to be witnesses
at their wedding.
Wedding?
Yeah. Here. Now.
I mean, do they understand
what they're in for?
Yeah, I think they do.
I mean, best as they can.
Yeah, but watching
someone you love suffer,
and you're helpless
to do anything, you know?
And after, the empty bed?
The silence and all that?
I don't know.
Yeah, I get it.
But it's worth it,
isn't it?
All right.
Come on, let's go.
Hey.
Thanks so much for coming.
We really appreciate it.
It's not the most
romantic setting,
but we didn't want
to waste a minute.
I understand.
But we decided we'd spend
whatever time I have left
together.
When you love someone,
so what
if it's only a year?
You take what you can get.
Shall we begin?
This ceremony
affirms your sacred bond
with one another.
A bond created
by loving purpose...
Happy birthday to you
She loved frosting.
I can see that.
Ooh, it looks good
on her, too.
Should have seen
what she could do
with a bowl of spaghetti.
Wow.
Oh!