Well, lunch, 1:00?
12:30.
Oh, yeah, right. Hey.
Morning.
Hey.
Morning, Dr. Halstead.
Good morning.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wait, wait, wait.
Dr. Wheeler,
you got one in Three.
Be there in a minute.
Okay. Mmm-hmm.
Morning, Jeff.
Hey, man.
This is obviously
a tremendous shock.
Dr. Wheeler was one of us.
And the burden of processing
all that has happened
will be a long
and difficult one.
So, there would be
no judgment on anyone
who would prefer
not to be here today.
At times like this,
talking about anything,
even the weather,
never hurt anyone.
So my colleague,
Dr. Richardson,
has made herself
available all day.
She'll be up in her office,
if anybody wants to stop by.
Okay?
All right, thank you.
Ms. Goodwin.
In my experience, the key
to maintaining
morale in times like this,
is to keep things
running smoothly.
Of course.
Okay if I take Dr. Reese
to fill in for the day?
Dr. Charles?
Sure.
Thank you.
Maggie, waiting room's full.
Let's keep them moving.
Trying, Dr. Choi.
What do we got?
Kid who fell in the river
about five minutes out.
Good Samaritan right behind.
Bunch of runny
noses and earaches
and abdominal pain in Six.
Dr. Manning,
you're on the kid.
Clarke and Sexton,
stand by to assist.
Reese, you're on deck.
Everyone else, take a room.
Let's go. Don't worry.
We'll get through this.
Hi, I'm Dr. Choi.
Heard you're
having some belly pain.
Yeah. It's not
a big deal.
He fell down the stairs.
Really? How'd that happen?
It was nothing.
He was carrying
a pretty heavy box of books.
We're packing up
to move next week.
And everyone thinks
reading's good for you.
Might have a broken rib.
I'd like to get some scans
and make sure
there's nothing else going on,
but it doesn't
look too serious.
I'll be back to check
on you in a little bit.
Uh... Uh...
Is there anything else?
No. It's...
It's just he's been
a little clumsy lately.
But
that's normal, right?
Tripping over his feet?
He's just
growing into his body?
It's probably nothing,
but since we got some time,
I'll run some
blood to rule out
any infections or toxicities,
just to be sure.
Thank you.
Need any help?
We got it.
Mags, put him in Baghdad?
Already on it, Dr. Choi.
Dustin Banks,
eight years old.
Fell through
the ice into the river.
Fifteen minutes
before he was pulled out.
Heart's in brady-arrest.
Core temp, 27 degrees Celsius.
Cold and dead, Sexton?
What do you think?
Uh... That he's not dead
until he's warm and dead?
You just won the first shift
of compressions.
All right. On my count.
One, two, three.
April, I need to intubate.
Fifty of sux, 10 of etomidate.
On it.
Can he hear me?
Dustin!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
The doctor will be with you
as soon as she can, okay?
Jim Kessler, 58.
Had a STEMI after
jumping in the river
to save the kid.
Aspirin and
nitro in the field.
Sinus rhythm now 120 over 80.
Mr. Kessler, I'm Dr. Reese.
Can you hear me?
Sure can.
Great.
On the count of three,
let's move him.
One, two, three.
Meds are in.
Maggie, get an ECMO unit.
Pneumonia season.
Every single
one's in use upstairs.
He's not gonna wake up
till he's 95 degrees.
What about bypass?
Both in surgery.
We can get one down here
in about 90 minutes.
Then we're going have to
keep his heart beating
until we get it.
Compressions for 90 minutes?
In five-minute shifts.
And we'll warm
him the best we can
with a left lung lavage.
Jeff, we need two 32
French chest tubes.
April, get a warmer
and all the saline
in the hospital. Let's go.
Left lung lavage?
Sure it'll work?
We're going to try.
Dr. Manning,
this is David Banks,
Dustin's father.
Is he going to be okay?
It's too soon to tell.
The benefit of hypothermia is
it preserves brain function.
But if we don't
warm him fast enough,
the cold will
eventually overwhelm his body.
So we're going to
circulate warm saline
through his chest cavity
until we can put him
on bypass, okay?
Okay, the warmer's
on its way,
but for this amount of saline,
Central Supply
needs a doctor's order.
Okay.
I promise you, we are gonna do
everything that we can.
Your EKG shows ST elevations.
Definitely a heart attack.
Ever had any
heart problems before?
Little chest pain
here and there.
My doc's got me on some pills.
Well, he should've told you
not to jump in a frozen river.
The shock is
probably what tipped you
over the edge.
Everybody's a Monday
morning quarterback.
I don't know what that means,
but I do know that
we need to assess
the extent of your
coronary artery disease,
so I want to send
you up to the cath lab.
Long as there's some
hot cocoa in it for me,
you got a deal.
All right. I'll check
back in with you soon.
Activate
the STEMI protocol.
And call Dr. Rhodes
for a consult.
You got it.
He got off lucky.
He could've gone into
cold shock,
v-fib, coagulopathy.
What a great but
crazy thing to do.
He probably didn't
even think about it.
Just saw a kid
in trouble and reacted.
Thank you.
Hey, Nat.
Hey, Jay.
It's a tough day, huh?
Yeah.
Just hang in there.
Thank you.
All right.
All Kevin's scans show
are a broken rib
and a pretty good bruise
on his kidney.
So I agree with Dr. Choi,
there's no
neurologic reason he fell.
He simply slipped.
I'd like
Nephrology to get a look
just to be safe,
but then he should
be okay to leave.
So, he'll be all right
to drive across country
next week?
Mom.
Shh.
Let the doctor talk.
Might be
a little uncomfortable,
but he'll be fine.
Thank you for all your help.
You got it.
My advice, bring some pillows.
Lead levels
and Lyme Titers?
Pretty aggressive workup
for a kid who just
slipped and fell.
Nothing wrong with
covering our bases.
Hey, Maggie?
How's the resuscitation going?
Getting 20 people from
five different departments
to work seamlessly together.
What could go wrong?
Hmm.
Well, you keep me updated.
Yeah.
Let me ask you,
did Dr. Wheeler have
any interpersonal issues
with anyone on staff?
I mean, I don't know.
I don't think so.
But he was making
some pretty big
mistakes lately.
Yeah, and it was getting worse
after the drinking incident.
Was there anything
that might have
been weighing on him?
I mean, you can tell
that he was
losing his confidence.
Hmm.
Uh...
Okay, then. I'll let
you get back to work.
All right.
I'm sorry, can I help you?
I was told
to ask for you.
Okay.
I'm Dr. Wheeler's father.
I need help!
Can somebody help me?
What happened?
I don't know.
He can't move.
Kevin, squeeze my fingers.
Just... Wait, wait.
Can you feel my hand?
All right,
let's get him to CT now.
What? What's happening?
I think your
son's having a stroke.
Oh, my God, Kevin, no.
So, the episodes
he's been having recently
could have been TIAs.
They may have been
coming for some time.
Well, it's possible,
but the CT looks negative.
It is. However,
there can be a delay
before an embolic stroke
shows up on the scan.
Exactly. Which is
why we need an MRI.
Right.
An MRI? That'll take an hour.
His stroke could be evolving
right before our eyes.
If it is a stroke.
His left side's
completely paralyzed.
What else could it be?
I don't know.
That's why I want an MRI.
Every minute
we wait to break up
the clot in his brain
increases the odds
of his paralysis
becoming permanent.
He needs tPA.
He's also got
a bruised kidney,
tPA could cause
a massive hemorrhage.
We cannot risk that
until we know for sure
what we're treating.
You've still got more
than a two-hour window
for tPA.
I can get him
in and out of the MRI
in 40 minutes.
Good. Do it.
I'm sorry about your resident.
He wasn't my resident.
Yeah. Thanks.
Yeah, it's awful.
I mean, residency,
who doesn't consider
doing it?
Still, you never think
anybody actually will.
Wait,
you thought about suicide?
Of course. Didn't you?
No.
Huh.
That's unusual.
You have moderate
three-vessel disease.
But given the fact
that you've already
had a cardiac event,
it is my recommendation
that we do a coronary
artery bypass graft.
This is pretty
major surgery, right?
It is, but you are
an excellent candidate.
So I'd like to give
your heart a day to rest,
and then we can get you
on the schedule for tomorrow.
If you say so, let's do it.
Great.
By the way,
it's a pleasure to meet you.
I hear that you
are quite the hero.
No.
Just lucky I happened
to be there.
Well, either way,
we thank you.
How did you know
he needed help?
What do you mean?
He was drowning.
No. I understand, but...
What went through your head
the moment
before you jumped in?
Was it an actual decision,
or was it more like
an instinct kicking in?
I don't know.
We should let
you get your rest.
Dr. Reese will be back
when we have a room
ready for you upstairs.
Dr. Reese?
Dr. Reese, are you okay?
What? Yeah, I'm fine.
Everything's fine.
I'm going to go
check on the room.
Where is he? My son, Dustin.
Mrs. Banks?
Hi, I'm Dr. Manning.
Your son is right here.
But let me just explain to you
what's going on first, okay?
Cheryl, I don't know
what happened.
I was right...
This is your fault.
You are a terrible father.
Mrs. Banks, please,
let me just explain to you
what's going on, okay?
Hey. How come
you're getting a snack?
It's time for lunch.
I'm sorry.
We've been slammed.
I gotta get back.
Okay. But you could've
texted and saved me
the drive across town.
I told you
I haven't had a second.
You had time to
get a snack, though.
Fine. You win.
That's a great answer.
Well, I'm sorry
my dying patient
inconvenienced you.
Come on, April.
What do you want me to say?
That's just how you
justify everything,
your work.
Now you're going to
start in on my work?
Nah. I'm going.
Rather eat by myself anyway.
You ever seen this before?
A resident
ending it like this?
Unfortunately, I have.
Yeah. Several times.
You know, about 400 doctors
take their own lives
every year, right?
Most of any profession.
I don't have a lot of
evidence to back this up,
but I got a strong hunch
it's got something to do with
taking people who have
a powerful desire to help
and throwing them
into a game
where the odds
are just stacked
against them.
I mean, this I do know,
situations like this,
it's never just one thing.
It's always a complex
set of circumstances,
and, you know,
trying to figure it out,
trying to assign blame,
it's pretty pointless.
Hey, thanks for
getting him a bed so fast.
Tough day, huh?
You and Dr. Wheeler
were friends?
No. I hardly knew him.
He came to me.
Twice.
Asking about pills,
about therapy.
That wasn't really
what he was asking for.
He was asking for help.
I don't know
why he came to me,
but he did, and now he's dead.
What kind of
terrible psychiatrist
am I gonna be?
You can't jump in
and save everyone, Reese.
It's just not possible.
It's not that I didn't
jump in to save him.
I didn't even see
that he was drowning.
Dr. Rhodes, better come here.
BP's dropping,
ST segments are elevated.
He's barely got a pulse.
He's in cardiogenic shock.
It must be another MI.
We're going to
balloon-pump him.
Bolus heparin,
start dopamine, dobutamine.
Get him on high-flow O2.
Got it.
I'll tell the cath lab
we're coming.
There's no time.
We're going to do it here.
We're...
How will we know if
we're in the right place?
If he bleeds out,
we'll know
we punctured the iliac.
If he stops breathing,
then we perforated
into the mediastinum.
But if we don't get
his blood pressure up
right now,
none of that's
gonna matter anyways.
Hang in there, Jim.
Let me know when you see it.
Almost there. Got it.
Almost there, Jim.
I got you.
All right, turn it on.
Come on,
come on, come on, come on.
Pressure's coming up,
70 over 35,
80 over 40.
Okay. Get him ready
to go upstairs.
Still no improvement.
He's always been so healthy.
What could cause
a stroke in a 15-year-old?
Not much,
and he's negative
for the usual suspects,
so if his MRI is positive,
we'll have to start looking
for less common causes.
I'm not going to have
to stay overnight, am I?
Kevin, not now.
Dr. Halstead, Dr. Choi.
Excuse us.
MRI?
Yeah.
Still no evidence
of a stroke.
This can't be right.
Well, it may not be.
It says it's a poor study
due to patient movement.
So it's inconclusive.
Tell MRI we're
sending him back up
for a repeat scan.
Are you kidding?
If this is a stroke,
we're running out of time.
Doesn't his affect
strike you as weird?
So little concern?
He's a confused teenager
who's probably also in shock.
Well, I don't like it.
It doesn't add up.
And we should figure
it out after we treat
what may soon become
permanent paralysis.
I'm not going to risk
a massive hemorrhage
and a transfusion
for no reason.
He's going back to MRI.
Hey.
I just spoke with CCU.
Mr. Kessler's pressure
still isn't coming up.
Okay. We'll give it
a few more minutes,
and if it doesn't improve,
I'll have to operate.
Okay.
Wheeler came to me,
too, Reese.
When we had that
pile-up in the blizzard
and the pregnant woman
almost bled out,
he took it hard.
I had the chance to
reassure him, but I didn't.
All right. I appreciate
that you're trying
to make me feel better,
but it doesn't.
I'm going to go check
on Mr. Kessler.
Whoa!
Noah.
Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry.
Let me help you.
Hey, I saw you and Tate
getting a little edgy.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Yeah?
Okay, good.
I just don't want
you to, you know...
What? Screw things up?
What? No, no.
I just want you to be happy
with a guy
who was an all-pro
wide receiver three times.
Three times, right?
Okay, everybody,
the bypass machine
just opened up.
We need to get
him upstairs now.
So, you'll be
able to warm him up?
Much faster, yes.
And it hasn't
been too long, right?
He might still be okay?
We won't know about
his neurological function
until he wakes up.
But this is definitely
a step in the right direction.
Thank you, Dr. Manning.
Of course.
I can't tell you how much
we both appreciate this.
He's ready to go.
Okay. Let's do it.
Hold on.
Ms. Goodwin?
They need
the bypass machine upstairs
for an emergency case.
What do you mean
an emergency?
It's for Mr. Kessler,
the man who saved your son.
They need to operate
on him immediately.
But it was promised to us!
We've been waiting for it.
Plus that man would
want Dustin to have it.
There can't be
a bigger emergency
than this.
My son is dying.
Are you just
going to stand there
and do nothing?
Mrs. Banks,
Dustin still has options,
other ways of
continuing to warm.
Mr. Kessler does not.
Without surgery, he will die.
My son is going to die.
Tell her.
Put him back on the monitors.
Wait. Wait!
Are you giving up?
No. But Ms. Goodwin is right.
We can try peritoneal lavage
to speed things up.
You are his doctor.
You're supposed to
fight for your patients!
My son is only
eight years old.
What kind of
a monster are you?
Mrs. Banks.
Mrs. Banks,
I am truly, truly sorry.
April, set up for the lavage.
Yeah. On it.
The waiting room's
backed up again, Maggie.
I'm doing my best, Dr. Choi.
We need to do better.
Too many people
losing focus today.
It's dangerous.
Is that right?
That patient in there,
Kevin, 15-year-old
with hemiparesis,
but his attending is
fixated on his mood
rather than his symptoms.
What do you mean?
He seems a little detached.
But he's just a kid
trying to play it cool.
So now we're
wasting valuable time
ordering scan after scan
when we should
be treating him.
Well, I mean, surely,
this attending gave
you his reasons, right?
He did.
But I think
the incident this morning
is clouding his judgment.
I'm not sure he
should be working today.
Really?
Dr. Charles,
we're in the business
of saving lives,
and the moment
people lose confidence
in their leader,
the fight is lost.
We've already had
one casualty today.
I won't have another.
Kevin, how are you?
I'm Dr. Charles.
Hey.
I understand you're
having a little trouble
with your left side.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
How you doing with that?
I know it can be
a little scary.
It's not that big a deal.
Excuse me, Dr. Charles,
this patient's
scheduled for an MRI.
Yes.
Okay.
Well, nice to meet you.
Yeah.
Metz and DeBakeys.
Let's get him cannulated
for bypass, and get me
a sheet of woven patch.
Woven patch?
I thought we were doing
a three-vessel CABG.
Change of plans.
This isn't an MI.
Page Dr. Reese.
Tell her I need her now.
3.0?
How's he doing?
Still only 89 degrees.
Look, I know
Dr. Wheeler had
a difficult time here.
Did he ever talk
to you about it?
No.
Was there anyone he
might have talked to?
A confidant?
Honestly, I have no idea.
Okay then.
Ms. Goodwin?
Yes?
I spent eight months
working alongside someone
who was in so much pain
that he took his own life,
and I never even noticed.
Am I a monster?
No, Dr. Manning.
No, you're not.
Excuse me,
I'm looking for my friend.
Is this
the visitors' entrance?
For the ED, yeah.
Has he been admitted yet?
I don't know.
He said he can't
move his arm or leg.
It sounds really bad.
His name wouldn't be Kevin,
by any chance, would it?
Yeah, it is.
Huh.
Tell me, is your buddy,
like, a real cool customer?
You know,
like a James Dean type?
Who's James Dean?
What I mean is,
is he the kind of guy
that doesn't really get
too worked up about stuff?
Kevin? You're kidding.
They're making him
move to California.
Of course he's worked up.
He's gotta move?
Yeah. They're just
dragging him away.
Hmm.
You're gonna
miss him, huh?
Yeah.
Sorry, tell me your name.
I'm Dr. Charles.
Emmett.
Emmett, nice to meet you.
I think that there
might be a chance
that we could
help your friend.
Could we go
see him together?
Yeah, okay.
Dr. Rhodes,
why did you bring me here?
I can't assist
on a bypass graft.
We're not doing
a bypass graft.
What? But I...
Look.
A ventricular septal defect?
Necrosis.
Lack of blood flow
from his heart attack
at the river
caused a small
patch of muscle to die.
That's impossible to find.
How did you even know
to look?
You see
this discoloration?
Uh-huh.
I missed this once.
Guy died before
we even got him off the table.
I know that you feel like
you let Wheeler down,
like you missed the signs
of him needing help.
As doctors, all we can
do is learn from that
and try not to
miss them again.
Maggie, when's Kevin Roth
getting back from MRI?
Didn't you get
Dr. Choi's message?
He took your patient
to interventional radiology.
What?
Do not administer that tPA!
Dr. Choi, now.
The hell are you doing?
His window's nearly closed.
I had no choice.
No, you don't have a choice.
I'm your attending.
And you're not willing to do
what the patient needs.
So, you're 100% sure
of the correct
clinical course?
Because to me,
this is not a clear-cut case.
Doesn't mean we can avoid
making the hard decisions.
Even if those
decisions might kill him?
Gentlemen,
if we could take a beat,
this young man might
help us shed some light
on the situation.
Hey, man.
Emmett,
what are you doing here?
I was worried.
You were worried about me?
Yeah, man.
Your text said
you couldn't move.
I didn't know if you
were dying or paralyzed.
I just came as
fast as I could.
Oh, Mr. Wheeler,
I'm sorry.
I'll give you some time.
Why did he do it?
Even if he was
having trouble, why?
I don't know.
Did you ever see
Jason do that trick
where you'd pull
a card out of the deck,
and it turns out
it's in his pocket?
Yeah. When he was a kid.
Yeah, I saw him
do it once up on
the pediatric oncology ward.
I guess he used to go up there
a couple times a week
to do magic for the kids.
And, oh, man,
did they love it.
He did this thing
where he would pull
a lemon out of his ear,
and then out of one
of the kids' ears,
and then out of another...
And they'd be
rolling on the ground.
Just 10 minutes
in their day
where they
didn't have to think
about whatever
terrible illness they had.
I didn't know
your son very well.
And I've seen
a lot of doctors
come through here.
He would've been a good one.
Thank you.
Yeah.
We had no idea.
It seems like
he's been harboring
thoughts and feelings
that he wasn't
comfortable expressing,
and his body found a way
to express them for him.
So he wasn't
actually paralyzed?
No, but he was
experiencing real symptoms.
It's why we call it
a conversion disorder.
It's the
physical manifestation
of a psychological desire.
"Desire"?
Sounds like you're saying
he wanted to be paralyzed.
I'm saying
he didn't wanna move.
And his subconscious
decided that having
a serious medical condition
might be a good way
to accomplish that.
That sounds crazy.
Crazy, no.
Complicated, sure.
But if you think
about it as a whole,
an understandable response
to what must have seemed
like an impossible situation.
I mean, having to leave
somebody that he
couldn't tell you about,
somebody for whom
he had very strong feelings.
But if he was so upset,
why didn't he seem to care
about being paralyzed?
Compartmentalization is
just part of the condition.
But trust me, your son cares.
I mean, he cares a great deal.
Just to be safe,
we'd like to observe him
in the hospital overnight.
Then probably a good idea
for the three of you
to sit down and have a talk.
They're getting
a room for him upstairs.
I'll let you know
when it's ready.
Thank you.
Damn.
The funny thing
about feelings,
you know, we think
that if we push
them down hard enough,
they'll disappear.
Never quite
works out that way.
I could've killed him.
Well, you didn't.
Cheryl?
Cheryl, I was
watching him every second,
and then Ben
called about this thing,
and I had to look
it up on my phone.
And I know you
never take your eyes
off the kids for a minute,
and I'm always working,
and you're a far
better parent than I am.
I'm sorry.
I don't know
what else to tell you.
I'm just so sorry.
Hey. I'm tagging you out.
There's a couch in
the lounge that's free.
I'll grab you in 20.
Thanks.
There's something
else I have to do.
Hey.
Listen,
I'm sorry about earlier,
going off on you like that.
Okay.
But...
But what?
I know that you blame me
for the miscarriage.
April...
No, admit it.
No matter how many
times you're told
that my working had
nothing to do with it,
you just...
You won't let it go.
But it's bigger than that.
You would've had me
quit my job a year ago,
before I was even pregnant.
You want
a different kind of woman.
I want you.
I love you.
I just imagined
a different kind of life.
I know.
I hope you find
everything you want.
You, too. You, too.
Amazing what
the mind can do, isn't it?
Keeps me employed,
that's for sure.
You know, Wheeler...
Maybe what
happened wasn't my fault,
but I didn't help.
Hey, join the club.
Look, not for nothing,
helping people is just about
the hardest job there is.
You've been doing it,
what, 25, 30...
Several years?
What... What's the secret?
I'm still looking for that,
but if I had to guess,
I'd say it had
something to do with,
you know,
just keep showing up,
keep doing your job,
put one foot
in front of the other.
'Cause when you start to get
all tangled up in here,
you know, that's when...
I mean,
it can just paralyze you.
Yeah.
Still, it's gonna be a while
before I can sleep again.
Dr. Halstead.
I think we're lucky
to have you here.
Keep up the good work.
Hey, I think he's waking up.
Dustin.
He's trying to breath.
Hang on, Dustin.
We're gonna take
this tube out, okay?
Hang in there, buddy.
We're right here, buddy, okay?
We'll take this out.
Dustin?
Can you hear us, buddy?
Hey, hey.
It's all right,
sweetheart.
Dustin.
Bilateral breath sounds
are present.
Pupils are equal
and reactive to light.
Hey, Dustin,
if you can hear me,
can you tell me who this is?
Mom?
Oh, my God.
Let's DC the lung lavage,
but keep the peritoneal going
until he's 98 degrees, okay?
Got it.
We're gonna
need to observe him
for a few days,
but this is a very good sign.
Dr. Manning?
Yes?
I'm sorry about
what I said earlier.
Thank you.
Thank you for everything
that you've done.
I'm just happy we were
able to save your boy.
How about that?
I guess every now
and then we get lucky.
Yeah.
How'd it go
with Dr. Richardson?
She stay busy?
Uh... Nobody showed.
Nobody?
Yeah, but that's...
You know, it takes time.
Trust me. People are dealing
in their own way, you know.
When I took this job, Daniel,
I wanted to
create an environment
where we would
never lose someone.
Everyone would look
out for each other.
I thought I did.
But then today, I found out
there was a very
troubled young man
in our midst,
and not a single person
knew him.
I failed.
Sharon, come on.
No, no.
You gotta wonder
about all the ones
who don't jump off the ledge,
what's going
through their heads,
how this job is
affecting them.
I worry about
these people, Daniel.
I worry about them.
I know you do. I know you do.
I wish I could protect them.
He's right here, Ethan.
I'm so sorry.
They won't need me
in the ED tomorrow,
so I'll be back
on your service.
Thank you. Thanks.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Everybody comes
to you, don't they,
with all their pain?
And you just
have to absorb it.
How are you doing today?
It was awful.
It's just awful.