You should be sitting.
Oh, that's okay. I'm fine.
Uh... Uh, excuse me.
Would you mind giving
your seat to this lady?
Didn't you hear me?
I said... I heard you!
It's okay, really. I can stand.
She's pregnant.
So that's, like, my problem?
All I'm saying is a little
common courtesy...
Sorry, Pops. I got none.
Really, it's okay.
Thank you, anyway.
You okay? Oh, yeah.
You sure? Just learning.
Just a few scrapes.
All right. You all right?
Yeah.
Ice-blended double-mocha
mocha supremo.
You're a lucky
girl, having a baby.
How far along are you?
Almost six months.
Oh, my, you're getting big!
Thanks. Twins.
My niece had twins.
What a delivery that was.
Eighteen hours on the first one.
And the second one was breech.
Excuse me, ma'am. Your order?
Oh, just regular coffee, please.
For here.
But I'm sure
yours'll go just fine.
May I?
You know, I really
rather you not.
I... Nothing personal.
It's just that when
you're pregnant...
I know. Everyone wants to
touch you without even askin'.
Although I did ask.
Regular coffee.
Thank you.
Hi, I'll have a tall
warm milk to go, please.
Nasty. SERVER 2:
Tall warm milk to go.
Excuse me?
Warm milk is nasty.
Really? And what are you having?
Double tall vanilla latte.
A latte. Didn't you know that
coffee stunts your growth?
That is so not true.
Do your parents
let you drink it?
What are you, the coffee police?
- Tall warm milk.
Thanks. You're welcome.
Double tall vanilla latte.
My balloon!
Honey, that's okay.
We've got another one. No!
I don't want blue! This
one is just as good.
No! Honey, don't make a scene.
I want yellow!
It's a perfectly
good balloon. No!
Oh, my God! Watch out!
Get out of the way! Move! Move!
Carol.
Carol, what happened? I'm fine.
Minor lacerations. Probable
shoulder dislocation.
Where's Kevin?
Is he already here?
Don't worry. I'm gonna find him.
Sure you're all right?
Oh, man, what a morning.
Lets get a trauma panel,
type and cross for four.
Set me up with a chest
tube. Peter, what do we got?
Deep lacerations to the chest.
Decreased breath
sounds on the left.
BP is 100/60. Pulse, 120.
Come on, help me, will
ya? What's your name?
Screw that! I'm hurtin' here! I
wanna speak to the manager!
You wanted the
trauma fellowship?
Yeah, well, be careful
what you wish for.
All right, 1% lidocaine.
Did you forget your trauma gown?
Tell you about it later.
Pulse ox 92 on four liters.
You on any medications?
Do you have any allergies?
No, you sons of bitches!
Just...! You just give me
something for the pain!
All right, titrate four of M.S.
Yeah, you win, bud. Morphine.
I've seen you somewhere.
The coffee shop.
Right. And before that,
the El train, remember?
You work here?
She's the manager. Oh, man!
Thora-Seal's ready.
All right, hook me
up! First crit 35.
Pressure's down
to 70. Tachy at 130.
He's bleeding out.
We've got 1000 cc's...
Blood on the rapid infuser.
Give him what he's lost,
and keep him four ahead.
All right, Dr. Corday
just took a critical,
and I've got a ton of
lacerations in chairs.
Okay, close us to trauma.
Tell the patients in chairs
we'll get to them
as soon as we can.
When's that guy
coming on? What guy?
The girl in the Rollerblades
is in a lot of pain.
Four of morphine, one
of Versed. I'll come back.
The guy, you know, the
doc who's moonlighting?
Dr. Kovac? Yeah.
I don't know. Check the
board. See when he's due.
What's this? The
driver of the truck.
Call transport. Get
him to the morgue.
Hey, you. Are you a doctor?
I got one mother of a migraine.
We'll get to you as
soon as we can, sir.
Yeah, I had some Compazine
at home, you know suppository.
Shoved it right up my ass,
but it ain't workin'. Nothin'.
Have a seat. Someone
will be with you in a minute.
They said that 20 minutes ago!
Really, they will. Uh,
Dr. Weaver? Phone.
Peter, can you
take it from here?
I'm gonna go check on Elizabeth.
Yeah, we're just
waiting on an O.R.
Carol?
Please, you have
to find my daughter.
I don't know what happened.
I don't know where she is.
What's her name?
I'll look for her.
Michelle. Michelle Kinney.
Hm, better get that checked
out. Here, I'll take a look, Carol.
It's okay, Mark. Mrs.
Kinney, we'll look for her.
But you need to tell
me where it hurts.
All over my chest.
I can't breathe.
Any pain here?
No. Not really.
Pulse ox 88 on 10 liters.
Okay, poor tidal
volume. I'll intubate.
Four of Versed, 100 of sux.
We're gonna give you
some medicine, okay?
It's gonna make you sleepy.
And when you wake up,
there's gonna be a tube
helping you to breathe.
Get X-ray down here.
And I need an ultrasound.
Dr. Corday? I'm in.
Uh, this man's here to see you.
Charles Cameron from Rush.
We were gonna have coffee.
Oh, of course. I'm sorry.
Um, I'm a bit involved here.
Mind if I hang out?
Oh, sure, sure, that'd be fine.
Dr. Cameron, Dr. Mark Greene.
Hey.
Well, um, let me
just check this page.
I'll be right back.
I've completely forgotten.
We'd set up a coffee,
you know, for an
interview at Rush.
An interview for?
Cardiothoracic.
I though you had that
sewed up with Romano.
Yeah, that's just it, the
prospect of Romano.
Seemed like a good idea
to check out
other opportunities.
You're right. Probably
is a good idea.
I'm really sorry, Mark. I
thought I mentioned it.
You don't have to tell me.
I'm looking for a little girl,
about 5, Michelle Kinney.
Not here. Got a Rollerblader.
I'm looking for him
too. Is he all right?
If the lavage is positive,
we'll take him to the O.R.
I'll tell the girlfriend.
Dr. Anspaugh,
the phone's for you.
Revisions on the Jayco report?
They call in the middle
of a trauma. My God.
The mind-numbing
day-to-day detritus of this job.
You okay finishing the DPL?
Oh, yeah.
Yes?
You gonna ask him?
Ask him what?
About the rumor he's
quittin' as chief of staff.
What?
Going back to general surgery.
I haven't heard anything.
Residents are out of the loop.
Why would he do that?
I don't know. Something about
that day-to-day
whatever of his job.
How are we doing, Carter?
All right, prep for transfer.
How tough is it to get
somethin' for the pain?
Sorry, sir, we've got a
lot critical cases right now.
And this jackhammer
in my head ain't critical?
What kind of
bush-league joint is this?!
Randi, can you kill that
guy with the migraine?
Happily.
Did a little girl come
in with this accident?
About 5? Michelle Kinney.
I didn't see her.
She might be on her way.
Just got off the MICN.
They're sending two
more criticals. Ten minutes.
W...? What do you mean?
I thought I told you
to close us to trauma.
I know but Dr. Romano
told me to keep us open.
And who asked him? I did.
It's a protocol thing.
He is acting chief.
Get back on the radio,
and tell them go to Mercy.
And, you, get
Romano on the phone.
What the hell's he thinking?
We're barely keeping our
head above water as it is.
Pressure's down to 75.
Another two units of O-neg.
No bleeding in the belly.
Chest x-ray shows diffuse
bilateral pulmonary contusions.
No signs of blood loss.
Pulse ox falling to
80 on 100% oxygen.
Let me check the heart.
Could be a tension pneumo.
Fourteen-gauge needle
on an open syringe.
Crit's 42.
There's no pericardial effusion.
No tension pneumo.
But she's got a
terrible ejection fraction.
Must be a cardiac contusion.
She's bruised the hell
out of her heart and lungs.
Another five of PEEP.
Pressure's down to 60.
Okay, mix up dopamine.
Should I book an O.R.?
Nothing to repair surgically.
Right you are, unfortunately.
What do we do?
Pressure and
ventilatory support.
That's about it.
Wait, hold on a minute.
Run up to the O.R...
Just try something.
Run up to the O.R., bring
down bypass machine.
Cart down tray now.
Prepare the groin
for bypass catheters.
Put her on bypass?
That's pretty gutsy.
It's worth a try.
Betadine and sterile drapes.
Well, well, well, this
is quite a convention.
Charlie Cameron. Still at Rush?
Rocket. Haven't seen you in...
Oh, gosh, who really cares?
So what brings
you to our fair land?
Coffee, actually. Oh.
I hear it's the best
in the city. Mm-hm.
Well, there's enough
cooks in this broth, I think.
I'll go and inspire
the rest of the troops.
O.R.'s ready.
Pulse ox 99 on 100%.
Peter, what's goin' on here?
Penetrating chest trauma.
1000 cc's out of the chest.
Taking him to the O.R.
Uh-huh, and what's his
pressure? 95 systolic, up from 70.
Whoa, whoa, keep him here. What?
Check another pressure.
He needs a thoracotomy.
A liter of initial
chest tube output
is an indication to go the O.R.
Nah, it's borderline.
How much blood?
Two units of O-neg,
1000 cc's, autotransfuse.
What's in the Thora-Seal?
Hundred cc's. Uh-huh.
And the pressure? 105/74.
Okay, so, Peter, let's review.
His pressure's in
the normal range,
and chest tube output
has slowed a trickle.
Now, as a surgeon, I
would say he's forming a clot.
As a trauma fellow,
you would disagree?
Maybe. Maybe.
If we're gonna crack
a kid's chest open,
expose him to the risks
of general anesthesia,
and put him through a
painful six-month recovery,
let's make sure "maybe"
is not a part of the equation.
Chest pain, has a history of
hypertension and diabetes...
Hi.
What's your name?
My name is Luka. It's
a funny name, isn't it?
Can you say it? Luka.
Does your arm hurt?
I'm a doctor, you know.
I want my mom.
I can help you.
So you want to come out now?
In that case, do you
mind if I come in?
Yes, of course, Lucy. I'd
be happy to mentor you.
I'm dying here! Any
of you putzes care?
I really want to focus
on emergency medicine
for my final year, and I
think it would be great
to have that one
person to go to.
I know that it will. I
had a great mentor.
What's it take, huh?
I gotta get run
over by some truck?
Yeah, I finished that DPL and
sent the head trauma to CT.
Thank you, Carter.
Have you heard rumors
about Dr. Anspaugh quitting?
No, where'd you hear that?
I heard a scarier one.
Not only is
Dr. Anspaugh quitting
Dr. Romano is the
front-runner to take his place.
Romano as chief of staff?
Carter, take this sheet.
Oh!
You okay?
Stand by with paddles.
Get ready for
chest compressions.
I'm in. Hook this up. - Mark.
Mark, when you have a
moment, I need to speak with you.
Sure.
Run of nine.
Charge to 200.
Start the bypass.
She's stabilizing.
All right.
Want to go in here?
Wean off the dopamine.
BP 120/80.
I just heard Anspaugh's
stepping down
and Romano's in
line for the chief's job.
I don't buy it. Anspaugh
would've said something us.
You're right. It's probably
just crazy rumor-mill stuff.
Yeah. I'll... I'll go upstairs
and, uh, talk to him about it.
Good idea.
Whoa, it's the fire
alarm! What the hell?
Please, tell me this is a drill!
Okay, you better prep
your patient for transfer.
I'll cover the main hall!
Where is it? I don't know.
But start moving patients
to the ambulance bay.
Are we gonna have to
move? Maybe. Be ready.
Dr. Benton, he's crashing!
Carter! Get in here now!
Paddles! Charge to 200.
Another 1500 in the Thora-Seal.
Thoracotomy tray!
Let's move! Come on!
Scalpel. Let's
squeeze in the blood.
Should I page Romano?
No time. Rib spreader.
Oh, man, there's, like,
a gallon of blood in here.
Come on, come on,
come on. More suction!
Please don't run.
Everybody move slowly and
quietly to the ambulance bay.
Three's clear. Where
the hell's the fire?
I don't know. Can you
clear exam one and two?
I got four units
of type-specific.
Hang it now.
Carter, come take over
the internal compressions.
Internal paddles are ready.
What about the fire alarm?
Let's save his life
first. Come on... I got it.
There! There, you
see? There's the bleeder.
All right, 2-0 Vicryl
and pickups. Let's move.
- You want FFP?
- Yeah. Two units
and a gram of Ancef.
Still in fib. Good femoral
pulse with compressions.
All right. Mammary
artery is ligated.
All right, paddles.
Charge to 20.
Everybody clear!
Clear.
Don't tell me you
just pulled that thing?
Maybe now I'll
get some attention.
He pulled the damn alarm!
Get back to admin. Let
people know it's a false alarm.
And you, stay down!
You move, and
I'll let her at you.
Everyone, please
listen! It's a false alarm!
You don't have to
evacuate! There is no fire!
Normal sinus.
BP's 80 systolic.
His oxygen tank is almost empty.
All right. Carter, go get
another cylinder. Let's move.
All right, everybody.
Let's get him up to the O.R.
Carter, let's move!
Go, people! Go!
Watch it!
Out of the way!
Have you ever
been to the circus?
No.
You have now.
So, all you have to do is
break off the little valve?
You can rent it and
take it to a party.
Lily, find Mr. Migraine.
Give him six mg of Imitrex.
And then call the police
and report him
for inciting a riot.
Excuse me, uh, which
room is open for Michelle?
Oh, thanks, Dr. Kovac,
but we have a pediatric
resident who can take her.
Uh, Cleo's not on yet.
She's due shortly. Why don't
you set her up in the Pedes room?
She wants to see her mother.
Yeah, that's probably
not a good idea.
The mother's been
intubated, and she's on bypass.
But we got plenty of other
patients who need suturing.
Sure. Anything is fine.
Um, I'll check the board.
Good. Kerry, I'm
gonna run upstairs
and try and find Anspaugh.
Dr. Weaver, the films are
back from the Rollerblader.
Okay.
Dr. Weaver, one last critical
coming in from that accident.
Someone they found
under the rubble.
At the back door. Okay.
Lucy, follow me on this.
Carol! Got another
lac for Dr. Kovac.
Got it.
I'll give you two or
three articles a week
and then we can go over them.
Okay, great. Good morning.
Hey, Cleo, I'm glad you're here.
I've got a Pedes case for you.
If you need help,
you can pull Carter in.
Sounds good.
Dr. Finch, do you
always jog to work?
It's only four miles.
Kind of makes you want
to dislike her, doesn't it?
This little tube right here,
that's for giving your mother
medicine to make her better.
And what's that?
That's a machine that helps
her take really deep breaths.
You know, like when you
go underwater to swim,
you take deep breaths.
I'm not allowed
to go underwater.
I have to wear wings.
Wings?
It's kind of like a life
jacket for little kids.
Oh.
They gave my mommy some
medicine to makes her sleepy.
That's right, but she's
gonna wake up soon
and be very happy to see you.
And now we're gonna
go find the doctor
who will look at your arm.
Okay.
Well, Peter, I am impressed.
We're 10 minutes in on
this teenager of yours,
and I haven't heard you so
much as whisper an "I told you so."
Okay, we're ready for
the second chest tube.
Let's make it a 36 French.
All right. Another
liter of irrigant.
By the way, you've met Charles
Cameron, haven't you? From Rush?
Uh, yeah, he has
privileges here.
Uh, cardiothoracic, I think.
Yeah, that's the, uh, same
specialty that, uh, Elizabeth...
Uh... Uh, Dr. Corday is,
uh, still interested in, isn't it?
I wouldn't know.
Oh. Hasn't mentioned much
about that, huh, lately, huh?
No, not to me. ROMANO: Oh.
Not to me either. Which is
odd, considering I sponsored her.
Why do you think that is?
I only ask you that because I
know you two have been friends.
You obviously know
her much better than I do.
Dr. Romano, do all
our conversations
have to revolve
around Elizabeth?
Well, Dr. Benton, perhaps
you and I don't need to have
any further
conversations at all.
Okay.
Some number two Dexon,
please, for the intercostals.
And, uh, I will close.
Is this the last one
from the accident?
Yup. Probably
ruptured her aorta.
Bled out in a matter of seconds.
Got a minute? Sure.
Lucy, good work.
Why don't you stay
and write the death note?
Okay. I'll get the death kit.
I talked to Anspaugh.
The rumors are true.
Both of them?
He's quitting and Romano's
gonna be chief of staff?
Donald is leaving the job,
but he's gonna stay at
County, do general surgery.
He wants to spend more
time with his daughter.
And Romano taking
over is a possibility.
We gotta do something, Mark.
I got Anspaugh to
agree to a meeting.
We can weigh in on whether
we think Romano is the right guy.
Yeah, he's not
the right one for us.
I don't get this.
You're a regular, old doctor.
Yes. But you don't work here.
No, I do work here, but
only when they need me.
I'm, uh, what they
call a "moonlighter."
Because you're
from another country?
No, because I only work
here from time to time,
when they need me.
And they needed you today
because of the truck crash.
No, uh, I'm here because
one of the regular doctors...
I thought you said you were
one of the regular doctors.
I just fill in when
someone else is absent.
Oh, I get it. You're like a sub.
A sub.
Yeah, yeah. I'm a sub. Yeah.
What kind of accent is that?
Thick.
Neighbors heard the baby
crying for a couple of days.
Finally called us in to police.
Broke the door
down. What a mess.
Any known relatives?
Neighbors didn't think so.
Mom lived alone with the boy.
They also think she has AIDS.
What about the baby? Don't know.
Need anything else?
No, we got it from here.
Tachycardia, pulse
thready, hypoxic,
or possibly fulminant
pneumocystis.
Let's get her
started on Bactrim,
three amps IV, 125
mgs of Solu-Medrol.
Make sure the O-2 is cranked
up to 10 liters. She's not moving.
You want a CBC and lytes?
Yeah. Check with the
ICU. We need to get a bed.
How's that baby?
Temp's 102.
He's dehydrated.
I started an IV.
Rales bilaterally on the bases.
I think there's a
consolidation on the right.
I need a complete blood
count and a chest film.
I'll get the portable.
Pneumonia?
It would be a pretty safe bet.
Want an HIV test?
Can't test the baby without
the mom's permission,
which is not gonna happen.
Pretty likely he's positive.
Yeah, but we either
wait for the mom
or the court to allow the test.
Now we'll start him on Cefurox.
HIV-positive, goes
ahead and has a baby.
No sign of any support.
What was she thinking?
Dr. Finch, films are back
on that little girl
with the broken arm.
Thanks, Eli.
Go ahead. I'll
fill out the labs.
Okay. Thanks.
Eli, can you get these
to the lab for me?
Oh, sure. Thanks.
Oh, wait a second, I forgot.
Add an HIV test
to, uh, this one.
Carlos Ortega? Right.
No problem.
Okay.
Am I interrupting?
No, no. Not at all.
Please, come in.
We are done here.
Hey, Vanilla Latte. I
wondered about you.
Glad to see you're doing okay.
You're the warm-milk lady.
That's right. I work here.
Yeah, but does that
mean you really work here?
Don't answer that one.
You're done. Feel okay?
Yeah. I feel fine.
On your way.
Thanks.
Oh, my God. That
boy is relentless.
I think his parents feel
quite exhausted, huh?
It seems like I
need some stitches.
I already irrigated.
I heard you were at,
uh, that coffee place
when the accident happened?
I had just left 10
seconds earlier.
I don't even want
to think about it.
Still, it seems like most
people came out of it okay.
Miraculously.
So you took that little
girl in to see her mother?
Yes.
Even though Dr. Weaver
and Dr. Greene
didn't think it was
such a good idea.
Oh, mostly they're not
sure if I'm a good doctor.
Why do you say that?
This is, like, the second or
third time you've worked here.
Yeah. Enough time for them
to stop calling me Dr. Kovac.
You know, when
people are not sure,
they tend to keep
things more formal.
I hope you will be happy
enough with your sutures
to call me Luka.
I took the girl in
because, uh, children
need to know, need to see,
even if what they
see is not good,
it's still better than being
in the dark, you know?
Having... that kind of fear.
You sound experienced
in these things.
Well, whatever experience
I have with children
didn't help me with that boy.
Carol, are you busy?
No, I just got sutured.
Their mother was
in that accident.
Massive blunt chest trauma.
They'd like to view the body.
Sure, no problem. Thank you.
Hello, I'm Carol Hathaway.
I'm very sorry for your loss.
Thank you.
Would you like
me to show you in?
Yes, please.
Did I hear Romano's
gonna be chief of staff?
You are gonna
fight this, aren't you?
Dr. Weaver and I
have an appointment
with Dr. Anspaugh,
and we're supposed to
give our honest opinions.
So you are gonna fight it. Good.
That baby boy, Carlos Ortega,
needs to get up to Pedes.
Sure. I can go with him.
We already sent
the mom to the ICU.
I'll call you. Great.
Awfully long cup of coffee.
Oh, he got paged.
Had to leave, but he came
back for a bite of lunch.
How'd it go?
Oh, who ever knows
with interviews?
I'm late for a lap choly.
I'll take that back pain in 4.
Sure. Do you need some help?
I think I'm okay,
but thanks anyway.
Mark, I don't mean to pry.
How... How are things
going with you and Elizabeth?
Okay.
You guys are still
going out, right?
Yeah, a little.
Am I gonna have to
beg for information here?
Carol, I'd hate to see you beg.
No, everything's okay,
really. You know, I ju...
Eh, I may have
backed off a little bit.
Which means she's backed off.
These things just kinda have
a life of their own, don't they?
If that's not enough,
you're gonna have to beg.
MVA, BMW vs. a Toyota.
Vital to stable,
but she's complaining
of some neck pain.
She didn't wanna come to the ER,
but she's been
very polite about it.
What's MVA? Motor
vehicle accident.
It was a little fender-bender.
I'm completely fine.
Elaine Nichols? Yes.
Ha! I'm John Carter.
Douglas' cousin.
Oh, yes, of course.
Well, seeing as we're
practically related,
could I get out of this thing?
Sure.
You just have to hold
still while I examine you.
Can't believe you're old
enough to be a doctor.
Oh, yeah.
No midline tenderness?
Turn your head to the right.
And the left.
Full range of
motion. You're clear.
Can I get up? Mm-hm.
Is that better?
Oh, I guess you are old enough.
Yes.
So no neck pain?
It's my little finger, actually.
Think I jammed it when
they stuck me on this gurney.
Let's just check them all out.
Yeah, that's the one.
Hand x-ray? I'll go order it.
Thank you, Chuny.
Yeah, we'll wanna make sure
that you don't have a fracture.
Oh. I guess I'll be
staying here for a while.
If that's all right.
So I can't really think
how long it's been.
Let's see, I...
divorced your cousin
Douglas three years ago.
Huh.
I remember your wedding.
Oh, I didn't realize
you were there.
Oh, yeah. I...
Douglas looked nervous as
hell, and you looked incredible...
ly calm.
Well, that must have been
the calm before the storm,
given the way our marriage went.
Ancient history.
But...
Divorce suits me.
Yeah. So I'm assuming
you were driving the BMW,
and not the Toyota.
What makes you think that?
X-ray confirms pneumonia.
Pneumocystis?
Looks more bacterial.
Is this the Ortega baby?
Yes. I'm Jeanie Boulet.
I brought him up from the ER.
Robert Martin, DCFS.
Any idea how long he'll be here?
Needs IV antibiotics.
At least a few days.
Well, the longer the better.
Give us time to
find a placement.
Any ideas where?
No.
The cases like this are a mess.
Mother with AIDS
on her deathbed,
probably have to go to
court to get the boy tested.
And if he's positive?
Then we need a foster family
willing to take on a
child of color with HIV.
Not exactly a dime a dozen.
Yeah.
You're late.
Dr. Benton, Chris Honegs,
Family Counseling Services.
Hey, how you doing?
Fine, thanks. But you
are a little late, so let's...
Let me get right to it.
This, as you know,
is a, uh, mediation,
in which we hope to
negotiate an agreement
regarding the
custody of your son.
Now, I am not a judge.
And this session
is confidential.
Nothing said here can be
used as evidence in court, okay?
Why can't we just go to court,
present the evidence?
Because this is
a court-ordered
mediation, Carla. Yeah.
Because you got
a restraining order
put out on me and Roger.
No, a restraining
order on you and Roger
taking my son to Germany,
where he has no chance
of developing his
language skills.
Dr. Benton.
My son is deaf.
Our son. And he knows that.
It's on the form.
And Reece would do just fine
with an American
sign-language tutor.
Okay, Ms. Simmons.
You have this tutor? I will.
And what if you don't?
Dr. Benton, please.
The purpose of this session
is to talk about
your child's needs.
He needs to be with his mother.
And he needs to
be with his father.
Yeah. So what? You gonna
bring him home from work
and put him in a bed
on the sofa in your living room?
He doesn't have his own room?
O-o-of course he does.
Since when?
We moved in with my
sister Jackie and her family.
So that, uh, you know,
Reece could have much more
of a, um, uh, complete,
you know, family unit.
As he would with us.
His black mother and
his black stepfather.
What the hell is that
supposed to mean?
What... What is that, Carla?
Because I went out
with a white woman?
I'm just saying...
You know what, I
can't... I can't do this.
Oh, yes, you can.
Court-ordered, remember?
So, what's the prognosis?
What are you doing in here?
You said to wait in
chairs, so I found one.
Ha. I didn't even
know we had a chair.
Is that me?
Yes.
Not much of a
measure of a hand, is it?
I mean, of what a hand can do.
Looks too spindly.
Well, at least
there's no fracture.
Well, that's good.
So I'm free to go?
I'll walk you out.
So do you need a ride?
I'll be taking cabs
until my car gets fixed.
I guess I was
hoping for something
a little more dramatic.
You know, a cast
or a sling, maybe.
Something to get me
out of this fundraiser
I promised I'd go to tonight.
Oh, don't tell me. That's right.
The Carter Family Foundation.
Even in divorce, Gamma
still has her claws into you?
How come I never see you
at any of these functions?
Oh, I managed to
get myself declawed.
So, what is it tonight?
Save The Lake?
No, no. It's, uh,
Children's Library?
Close. Children's Art League.
Ahhh.
Randi, can you call a
cab for Miss Nichols?
Sure.
So thank you, Dr. Carter.
You are welcome. You're welcome.
And I'll be thinking
of you. You will?
I mean, tonight, mixing it up
with the rest of the Carters.
Well, then I'll just have
to be thinking of you.
It was nice to see
you again, Elaine.
John.
Hope Anspaugh hasn't
already made up his mind.
Look, if enough of us
come down against Romano,
how Anspaugh go
ahead and appoint him?
Will there be enough?
That's the question.
You mean, if it's
just you and me?
Don't even think about that.
We all know he's eager, if
not downright breathless.
So I can find no compelling
reason not to support him.
Although, as head of
Radiology, I would like to point out
that no head of Radiology
has ever been considered
for chief of staff.
But perhaps that's a
topic for some other day.
No wonder it takes so
long to get our x-rays read.
Thank you, Steve. Carl?
Up in Psych we pretty
much run our own ship.
It was six months before I
knew Donald had taken over.
Seeing as this won't
rock my world much,
Dr. Romano's fine with me.
How about you, Jack?
Oh, God knows
I'm like you, Donald.
I've had more than
enough bureaucratic crap.
I already had one heart attack.
You find a guy willing to take
that stuff on, I say book him.
Mark.
Well, I... hate to be
the voice of dissent.
And it certainly isn't
personal, Robert,
but, uh, I feel I
should be honest.
Absolutely.
As, uh, acting chief of the
ER for the past few months,
Dr. Romano has...
Well, there hasn't been,
uh, a great deal of support.
His management
style is, I guess, abrupt.
And, uh, several members
of our, uh, staff have, uh...
Well, they've even
found it offensive.
Go on.
Well, I guess I'd have
to say that, uh, I'd worry
if Dr. Romano was to
have the responsibility
of the entire staff and faculty.
Well, thank you,
Mark, for your candor.
Kerry?
As any of us who've
been in management know,
it's never easy taking
over another department,
and I agree with Mark.
There have been a
few bumps in the road.
But I feel Dr. Romano
has succeeded
in stabilizing the situation,
and is now providing
some genuine leadership in
the Emergency Department.
So you would support
him as chief of staff?
I think it's only fair
that we give him
all the support that we can.
You hung me out to dry, Kerry.
Mark, I'm sorry.
But it was obvious Romano
was gonna get the job.
Imagine how he would
have taken it out on the ER
if we'd both gone against him.
It just seemed
politically smart.
Oh, I see. So you were
being smart while I was
sticking out my neck
being stupid and honest.
Oh, stop it.
I was only trying to
protect the department.
Well, you may believe
that, Kerry, don't ask me to.
Donald throws the dullest
meetings, doesn't he?
No wonder we all need
a little kick of java, huh?
So? What do you think?
Gave it the old
Remington heave-ho.
New look for a new job, huh?
Oh, well, back to work.
Oh, uh, actually, Kerry,
if you have a minute,
there's something I
wanna discuss with you.
Hey, did I leave my
sunglasses at your place?
Not sure. We can check later.
Right. So go on. What
else did the guy say?
Just that Carlos would
be really hard to place.
Because he's HIV-positive.
Right. And I couldn't
even tell them
that I ordered
the test illegally.
Well, you'd think
they'd wanna know,
get him the cocktail. I know.
Anyway, I realized
that I would be
the perfect foster
mom for this baby.
I certainly know
how to deal with HIV.
I think you're right.
You'd be perfect.
That's not what the
DCFS would say,
considering my HIV status.
You're healthier than
half the people in the city.
Yeah, but I'm
not married... Yet.
So there's no support
system in place for the baby
if something were
to happen to me.
Yet.
Reggie.
We can take care
of that part right now.
I've gotta get back to work.
Let's just drink our coffee.
Uh-uh. Not till you
say you'll marry me.
Reggie. You don't
think I'm serious?
I think you're crazy.
Uh-huh.
Jeanie Boulet...
..will you marry me?
Good job, Dr. Greene.
What's this all about? Your
meeting with Anspaugh.
How'd you know?
Nurses know everything.
You fought the good fight.
Thanks, Mark.
Lot of good it did us.
Mark, do you have a minute?
I was just heading out.
You know, um... I
think that we should talk.
I think we've talked
enough, Kerry.
This is about something else.
30-year-old woman,
pregnant, MVA.
T-boned with passenger
space intrusion.
No pulse. Traumatic full arrest.
Ten minutes down.
Couldn't intubate.
One, two, three.
Oh, man, she's
gotta be full-term.
Chuny, take over CPR.
I need an 8-0 tube now.
See if you can give
me some suction.
And set up a central
line. Four units O-neg.
Somebody get
another doctor in here.
Haleh, check for
fetal heart tones.
Asystole on the monitor.
Okay, cricoid pressure.
IV's blown.
I'm in. Give me an amp
of epi to put down the tube.
Blood's here. Hang
it on the rapid infuser.
She looks full term.
Fetal heart rate?
Can't find it.
What's the mother's rhythm?
Asystole. We got her intubated.
Any pulse in the field?
Paramedic said no.
Down time?
We're at 12 minutes.
The mother is dead.
Wait, why can't we try a...?
No, she's dead. We need
to get the baby out now.
All right, subclavian's
in. Go with the O-neg.
Chuny, keep up compressions.
I need retractors.
Get a baby warmer in here!
Open a cutdown tray.
No time. Give me your hands.
Hold it open like this.
All right, chest
tube, 32 French.
I'm opening the uterus.
Bandage scissors.
Bulb suction.
It's a girl.
Come here.
Shhh.
Okay, okay.
Left chest is full of
blood. Hold compressions.
Still asystole.
Okay, let's rally
here. One more try.
Give me an amp of atropine.
Repeat the epi,
and continue CPR.
Heart rate is, uh, 140.
She's pinking up.
One-minute Apgar,
eight out of 10.
She's gonna be fine.
Yeah, I think so.
Time of death, 18:48.
How's he doing?
Better. Fever's down.
He's resting comfortably.
Good. Any news on his mom?
No. I didn't realize she
has end-stage AIDS.
Yep.
Let's get him started
on the triple cocktail.
He hasn't even been tested yet.
Get him started, Kit.
Okay.
Hey, Randi, have
you seen Dr. Greene?
Uh, he left for the night.
Hey, Carter, do
you have a minute?
Yeah, sure.
Hey, so I heard it was true,
the rumor about
Romano becoming chief.
Yes, and although I haven't
made an official announcement,
he's appointed
me chief of the ER.
While they keep up
their endless search
for somebody permanent?
No. Actually, I
am the permanent.
Hey, wow!
Hey, congratulations!
Thank you, thank you.
Thank you. For letting me know.
But what I wanted
to mention to you is...
You know, I'm not
so sure it's appropriate
for you to continue to rent
my basement apartment.
What?
Well, it just feels like
whoever's down there
should be from
outside the department.
You asking me to move out?
Well, take your
time. A week or two.
Looking for something?
Oh, no, just putting
back this suture kit.
I know you don't
keep the opened ones,
but, uh, the scissors haven't
been used, the forceps.
You know, seems such a
waste to throw them away.
Are you okay?
Oh, you mean after that trauma?
Yeah. I feel pretty lucky.
Good.
You know, Luka,
whatever Greene
and Weaver think...
You're a good doctor.
Thank you.
What was it you said?
"I'll be thinking
of you tonight"?
I guess I meant it.
Ha.
So how do you like
Jeeps? It's not a BMW.
Well, it's also not a cab.
I like Jeeps.
I was thinking maybe we'd
go get a drink or something.
I don't really want a... drink.
Oh, Dr. Weaver, can
I talk to you? Yeah.
I checked on the
anaphylactic shock in four,
and her respiratory
rate and pulse are down,
so I think she'll be fine.
We're admitting the
hematuria up to Medicine,
and we're ready to discharge
the contact dermatitis.
Excellent.
And I was just wondering
if I should be doing
any extra reading
or anything tonight?
Oh. Lucy, I'm afraid
I'm not gonna be able
to continue mentoring you.
I've just been appointed
the new permanent chief
of the Emergency Department.
But that's good, isn't it?
Yes, but I'm afraid it
would seem like favoritism
if I mentored one
student over another.
You should talk to Dr. Greene.
He might have some time.
Dr. Weaver, Randi's
got a call for Dr. Greene.
Well, take a message. He's left.
I think you need
to take this one.
It's his father.
He said that, uh,
Dr. Greene's mother has died.
Hello, this is Kerry
Weaver. Can I help you?
So this what American males do
to vent their anger
and frustration?
I figured a Romano/Weaver
double homicide was overkill.
How'd you find me?
I have my sources.
I heard what you did in
the meeting with Anspaugh.
What I did was
commit career suicide.
Opened the door for
Kerry to become chief.
Speaking your mind
in front of Romano
took a lot of courage.
For what it's worth,
I'm really proud of you.
You did the right thing.
Thank you.
So, what is all this
"hitting the baseball" thing?
Doesn't look that tough.
Ha!
It doesn't, huh?
Well, you seem to be doing it.
Wanna give it a try?
Come on.
Okay.
All right. Like... Like this?
Nice! Whoa!
Is that one? Smack it.
Ooh!
Ooh. Whoops.
I'm doing okay.
You've got a good eye.
Keep your eyes on
the ball. Here it comes.
Oh!
Very good.