Previously on The Good Doctor...
- Hey! Stop!
- Danny!
Just promise me.
- What?
- No opioids.
He asked you not to do that.
He's tachycardic and
hypertensive because of the pain.
He's going into shock.
- He's not. He's praying.
- He's dying.
Forgive me.
I need to go back to
Texas with my family.
You made an error in
yesterday's craniotomy.
You closed with
only eight sutures.
The size of the
wound required ten.
We need to figure out why.
I've had a stroke.
Yes. A small one.
Dr. Glassman, please tell
us what the next step is.
Somebody please call security.
Shaun, you are out of line.
- Answer.
- It's, um...
You humiliated me in
public in my operating room
in front of my colleagues.
Do you have any idea
how much that hurt?
I don't know what to do.
You can just leave me alone.
I don't think you should resign.
Because you don't have
to do it all alone.
You're the reason I
wake up in the morning,
so whatever there
is to figure out,
all I want in the world is
for us to do it as a family.
I wanted to give you a
heads-up as a friend.
I've decided to resign.
Congratulations, Mom and Dad.
Look at what we made.
Do you think
Dr. Glassman is coming?
This is from Dr. Glassman.
How did he know his
name would be Steve?
Because he knows you.
Gloves.
Start the timer, please.
Good luck, babe. It's a doozy.
Thirty-seven seconds.
Good work.
I think that was
your fastest yet.
Second-fastest.
Fifteen minutes of independent
play is starting now.
I will log it into my app.
You sure you don't want to get in a
few extra snuggles before you leave?
Oh, I had ten minutes of
snuggles this morning.
Very nice.
I've also set up the
app on your phone.
It will alert you when it's time
for Steve's nap,
feeding, playtime...
Just in case I miss the
schedules posted on the fridge,
the bathroom, and
in our bedroom.
Yes. And I will be able to
track it while I'm at work.
Steve and I will be fine.
Just enjoy your first day back.
We can finish
reading the latest.
Journal of Trauma and
Acute Care Surgery
when I get home.
After this, Steve
should have at least
five minutes of tummy time.
Yesterday, he only
logged 12 minutes,
- which is three less than...
- I love you.
Say hi to everyone for me.
Okay. I love you, too.
I will miss you both.
I don't know why you need three
protein powders for your smoothies.
They do different things.
She's barely taken an ounce.
That's what the protein-powder
companies want you to believe.
Are you holding her right?
Yes.
She needs to be upright with
her head properly supported.
Good.
And you mixed it enough?
The same as always.
She's not interested again.
And she seems lethargic.
I'll take her to
get checked out.
Well, I'd like to come, too.
Sure. You can carry this.
Good morning. How's Perez today?
Don't know.
It's almost 8:00 a.m.
It's been "today" for
a whole eight hours.
You two haven't
texted each other yet?
We both decided we need space.
He's focused on his recovery.
I've got my life here.
I fully support that.
And your next chapter
begins tonight.
You and me. Drinks, music,
questionable decisions.
You and Jerome finally
got the surgery!
You're no longer
joined at the hip?
Jerome is obsessed
with some docuseries
about one of the many sports
that I don't care about.
Come on. It's been too long.
I've been busy.
You've been
mopey.
Fine. I agree to
drinks and music,
but I'm definitely a "maybe"
on questionable decisions.
- All right. We'll work up to it.
- Okay.
We're going out
tonight for drinks,
starting a new
chapter. That's right.
We're calling it "Bad
decisions with good friends."
We're definitely not
calling it that. Wanna join?
No, thank you.
Papa Murphy, welcome back.
Pictures of Steve.
I was just about to ask.
This way, I avoid the disruption
of pulling out my phone.
Look at that smile!
Just like his mom!
He was pooping in that one.
Here he is... about to poop.
Hmm. A theme develops.
Aw. He's got your eyes, Shaun.
I need to find Dr. Lim.
You may keep those. I
made enough for everyone.
Marcus sends
greetings from Spain.
Oh, I thought he was at a
meditation retreat in Vietnam.
He was, and now he's walking
the Camino de Santiago.
How nice for him.
I'm two surgeons down
with no one to approve
hiring a new one.
I need the board to appoint
an interim president, stat.
Just as long as
it's not O'Brien.
They wouldn't.
I heard from a staffer
who covers board meetings
that his name's
on the shortlist.
Ugh. Of the worst possible
candidates for the position.
Good morning! Pictures of Steve.
Aww.
You no longer have your cane.
Yeah. PT said I was ready.
I'm glad to have you back.
I would like to join your case.
He's adorable,
Dr. Murphy. Welcome back.
Shaun, I'm thrilled to see you,
but I'm not sure this is
the case where you want
to start as a new dad.
It is an exciting and
challenging surgery.
Thank you for coming in
on such short notice.
Hello. I am Dr. Shaun Murphy,
attending surgeon and
father of a baby boy.
He is two weeks old, and
today is my first day back,
but that will not
affect my performance
as your son's doctor.
Is it true there might
be a heart for Jack?
Yes, but the heart
isn't available yet,
and we may not
get it once it is.
We've been through this before.
Why isn't the heart
available yet?
Well, the donor family is
still saying their goodbyes
before they turn
off life support.
Jack is an excellent
match for the donor heart,
and his latest echo indicates
that his cardiomyopathy
and overall cardiac
function has worsened,
so he should be at
the top of the list.
I just want to run
some additional tests
to make sure he's
otherwise healthy.
There is a problem.
There is a small scratch,
likely from his fingernails,
which has developed
cellulitis and an abscess.
If the infection spreads
and he spikes a fever,
Jack will be ineligible
for the transplant.
We have to lance and
debride it right away.
Morning.
Hi.
This is Steve, our son,
who is now two weeks old.
Steve, this is the grumpy
man who lives down the hall
and gave you your
favorite blanket.
Shaun was very impressed
you guessed his first name.
Wanna take a stab at the middle?
Aaron.
I was lobbying pretty
hard for Bowie,
because why not name your kid
after the coolest
person who ever lived?
But Shaun insisted.
You should come over sometime.
You two both grunt a lot
and make strange faces.
I've got a lot going on, so...
We live next door. You
have nothing going on.
You're mad. And I get it.
But are you really gonna ignore
Shaun and Steve and me forever?
Is that the plan?
I'm not ignoring you.
And he's beautiful.
Congratulations.
I tried.
Any cyanosis while eating?
Maybe a hint of bluishness
on her lips last night.
I haven't noticed anything.
But given her prior surgery
and the Turner syndrome,
I thought we should...
The blood flow is reduced.
It looks like Eden's
aortic stenosis
has progressed more rapidly
than we were expecting.
Can we put her on beta blockers?
We can try, but given how
dysplastic the valve is,
I don't think it
will do much good.
You'll want to get more imaging,
but I think Eden's gonna need
another surgery very soon.
Cardiac MRI confirmed severe
narrowing of the valve,
obstruction, and left
ventricular dysfunction.
Eden needs a new aortic valve,
or her heart failure
will get worse.
Are you thinking mechanical or
cryopreserved homograft for the replacement?
Mechanical valve for a
neonate needs to be built,
and it will require
future surgeries
plus lifetime blood thinners.
Cryopreserved valves risk
degeneration down the line,
but it is a solid idea,
especially as part of
the Ross Procedure.
Possible complications?
Aortic insufficiency,
pulmonary stenosis.
We can take some time, discuss
the different options...
Do the Ross Procedure.
I'll have Asher get her prepped.
It's time to get
off the sidelines.
I'm not sure what
you're referring to.
Are you gonna throw me a ball?
You've run the hospital before.
You can handle a
few more months.
I can, but why would I want to?
- That's a no?
- Yes.
Get ready for Interim
President O'Brien.
They would never.
That's like Mao
meets Basil Fawlty.
Wow. That's two obscure
and dated references.
They're never gonna
move on O'Brien.
Well, apparently, he's
on the board's shortlist.
Throw your hat in the ring,
he won't stand a chance.
My hat's gonna stay on my
head, but I'll handle it.
Okay, Jack.
You know that little
bump behind your ear?
We have to poke it
with something sharp,
which will hurt,
but we have to do it so hopefully
you can get a new heart.
But Mr. Snugglepuff is
here to keep you company.
Asher said the taco truck
added chorizo to the menu,
and it's bus sin'.
The next late night, we
should share an order.
Not really my thing. Thanks.
The sheet papoose is secure.
Good. Dr. Kalu, cradle the baby.
Dr. Allen, sterilize
the area behind the ear.
Okay, baby, don't look.
His eyes are not yet able to focus
beyond eight to twelve inches.
The abscess is pretty deep.
It may take a while to heal.
What about a wound vac?
We don't have one small enough.
It's okay.
Maggots.
How are those better than
just using antibiotics?
Maggots work faster to
clear necrotic debris
on account of the antimicrobial
nature of their saliva
and other digestive secretions.
It's safe to put
those bugs on my baby?
Larvae.
These are medical maggots.
They've been specially
disinfected. It's completely safe.
I would use maggots on my
son, Steve, in this situation.
That is unlikely to happen,
but I hope the parallel
puts you at ease.
Go ahead.
Hmm!
You want some coffee?
Or I have a stash of
protein bars in my office.
I'm fine, thanks.
But if you want
something, go ahead.
What's your family here for?
A heart transplant,
hopefully, for our son, Jack.
How old is he?
Twelve weeks.
Oh. My daughter,
Eden, is 11 weeks.
She's having heart
surgery right now.
Y'all will be in my prayers.
Is this Jack's first surgery?
He's had other procedures,
but this would be his
first open heart surgery.
If it happens.
When it happens, I recommend
Biafine cream for post-op.
It contains a natural
compound called trolamine.
It really helped
with Eden's recovery.
How many surgeries
has your daughter had?
Uh, one. At seven weeks.
Hmm.
Eden and I are old hands.
You're two very
resilient ladies.
I'm Kate Pierce. This
is my husband, Owen.
Morgan Reznick.
Alex Park.
Would you like to...
Yeah! You can do it! Come on.
Oh! There you go!
You got it! You got it!
You got it!
Hi, Daddy. How is it
being back at work?
I just applied maggots to a baby
a few months older than Steve.
Is that Steve?
He is supposed to be asleep.
Mm. He's doing well
with tummy time.
And you mentioned
yesterday he was behind,
so I thought I'd add
a few extra minutes.
No, no.
Tummy time should not be
extended into his sleep window.
Did you not get the app alert?
You are seven minutes
into nap time.
Nope. I guess I missed it.
Delaying his nap could
make him overtired
or delay his next feeding.
The schedule is very important.
I know, Shaun, I know. It's
just a few extra minutes.
Eight minutes.
That is not a few.
It is several.
Uh, I should go put Steve down.
- Bye-bye.
- Okay.
Oh.
We had to abort the procedure.
Eden has a bicuspid
pulmonary valve.
There wasn't enough tissue
to attach it to the aorta.
And we observed
leaking at the valve.
Her heart is failing even
faster than we thought.
I'm so sorry.
What's our next move?
Oh. The maggots worked!
Baby Jack's infection
has cleared,
and the heart is
on its way here.
Eden has two bad valves
and rapidly progressing
heart failure.
We have one donor heart
and two babies who need it.
It's up to us to decide
which baby gets this heart.
Jack has been waiting
for three months.
A transplant is his only option.
He could go on a VAD until
another heart is available.
That could take months. And a VAD isn't
a good option for Jack because of the...
Morgan. Morgan.
You can't be here.
Neither of you.
I can't be anywhere else,
so either someone
should sedate me or...
Well, that can be arranged.
It's only a problem
that Park and I are here
if we influence your
decision, so don't let us.
I won't say a word.
Dr. Kalu?
Yeah, um
as far as the VAD for
Jack, he's underweight,
so a high risk of complications,
infections, bleeding, stroke.
It's not a great option
for Eden, either.
Eden can go on ECMO
while we're waiting
for mechanical
replacement valves.
ECMO has risks, especially for
a baby with Turner syndrome.
And the longer she's on it,
the greater the risk of
serious complications.
The valves may not
get here in time.
Care to weigh in, Dr. Murphy?
Jack and Eden are
equally good matches
to the donor heart based
on size and blood type.
Anything else?
It's okay, Shaun.
Without this heart...
Jack will die.
Eden may also die without it.
But she has other options.
They are risky, but
they are options.
Jack should get the heart.
We'll put Eden on ECMO tonight.
And I'll contact Abbott about getting
the 15-millimeter valves ASAP.
Hey. I'm sorry. Can
we rain-check tonight?
I'm exhausted, and
Jerome promised
that we could watch a
nice crime procedural.
Sometimes you need
a case of the week.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Mmm! My favorite!
One cheddar brisket
with mild sauce
so little Steve's next meal
doesn't burn his mouth.
You are a treasure.
I am starving.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
Poor Eden, having to go on ECMO.
And poor Morgan and Park.
It's... been a day.
And how are you holding
up? Without Perez?
Everything that happens,
at home or at work,
he's the first person
I want to tell.
Mm-hmm.
And I can't.
Or I shouldn't.
I really miss him.
You can tell me everything.
If it's too surgical, I
may not understand it,
but I am excellent at nodding
and acting interested.
Mm!
I'm here for you. So is Asher.
What's going on?
Tell me. Babies are
terrible at gossip.
Asher and I were supposed
to hang out tonight,
just the two of us.
Do you need to check on him?
No. If he smells me, I'll
never get out of there.
He'll settle back down.
So you and Asher had plans...
He blew me off for Jerome
because he had a hard day
on Eden's case, which I get,
but I had a hard day, too.
Mm-hmm.
Steve's not settling.
Well, he can wait a minute.
You had a hard day, too?
It... It just seems like
everybody has someone except...
- Go.
- I am so sorry.
I-I will be right back. I swear.
Mm.
You didn't have
to do this, Shaun.
I am more thorough than
anyone else in this hospital.
Starting ECMO.
I just got an e-mail
from Gail on the board.
I'm suddenly a top candidate
for interim president?
You're welcome.
I don't want that job.
It's better... better
you than O'Brien.
You're a good manager, you're
you're well-respected,
and, you know, as
a diverse woman...
People aren't diverse.
I'm part of an
underrepresented group.
Right. That.
Makes you an ideal candidate.
Look. Gail loved the idea.
- I hate you.
- You're welcome.
Shh, shh, shh. Shh, shh, shh.
I am glad to see you, Steve,
but you are not
supposed to be awake.
Yeah, I-I fell asleep
during his afternoon nap.
We didn't wake up until 4:30.
You need to set an alarm.
The schedule is very important.
I know. I know.
Tomorrow I am doing
a heart transplant
on a 12-week-old baby.
Okay. You need sleep.
Yes, I do.
Go to bed. I'll
handle Steve tonight.
I-I don't think I can.
Shh, it's okay. What about your
noise-canceling headphones?
I fall asleep on my side.
I cannot do that in those.
Maybe you could go spend
the night at Glassman's?
No.
What about your office?
Can you sleep there?
We can save them
both with one heart.
It's called a domino transplant.
Jack's heart is failing,
but his valves are healthy,
so when Jack receives
the donor heart,
we will use his valves to
replace Eden's damaged ones.
A fresh homograft donor
means Eden won't need
multiple surgeries
or blood thinners.
One heart could
save both babies.
What are the chances
of valve failure?
Minimal. Jack's valves
are very functional
despite his cardiomyopathy.
The odds of success are high.
It's the best option we have,
for Eden.
And for Jack?
We would have to be very
careful while removing his heart
so as not to damage his valves.
That would mean
more time on bypass,
which means a greater risk
of bleeding or infection.
It's a lot to ask.
They can always say no.
What would you say?
You haven't eaten
anything in 24 hours.
I'm fine.
No matter what they decide,
we'll get through this.
Don't.
What, try to help?
Yes, exactly. It's
pointless and annoying.
You know, I get that you don't
think of Eden as mine yet,
and that's why you
haven't included me
in any of her medical decisions.
Not that I need that,
or disagree with any
of your choices...
Is pissing me off another
attempt to distract me?
I'm not trying to pick a fight.
I just want you to know
that I love that girl
like she's my own, and...
I'm as scared as you are.
And I wish you'd let
me help you because
we're in this together.
That's it.
And I really don't
want you to pass out,
so please eat or
drink something.
If our baby can save your
baby's life, we'd be honored.
"I'll love you forever,
I'll like you for always.
"As long as I'm living,
my baby you'll be."
Oh, my God. What a tear-jerker.
We need to find one of
Daddy's medical journals.
Reminder.
Nap time in five minutes.
How do I un-sync the baby
app from our speaker?
Oh, no. You should not do that.
I set it up so you can
remember the schedule.
When it's just me and
Steve home during the day,
I like to be a little
bit more... flexible,
go with the flow.
I'll just... I'll
just unplug it.
It has a battery in
case of power outages.
Lea, when I'm at work,
I like knowing what you
and Steve are doing.
It makes me feel like I am
still a part of his day.
And when Steve gets
off his sleep schedule,
I have to go sleep
at the hospital,
and I miss you both even more.
Aw, we missed you,
too. How did you sleep?
Not well. But I came up with a
very good idea to save both babies.
I have to go prep for my
surgery now. I love you.
Dr. Lim, we have a
meeting to review...
One minute, Shaun.
Gail, of course, diversity and
representation should be considered,
but given this is
an interim position,
I think the top priority
is finding someone
who can hit the ground
running from day one.
And that means someone
who's done it before.
He's too modest to
sing his own praises,
but I think he's
the obvious choice.
Hmm. Compelling
argument. Thank you.
Oh.
And seniors are also an
underrepresented group.
Dr. Murphy and I will
start with Jack in OR 1.
Asher, you'll be with Eden
next door getting her ready.
Allen and Kalu, you two
will receive the donor heart
and prep it for transplant.
Then Dr. Lim and I
will put Jack on bypass
and start cooling
him to 25 degrees.
Given his age and underlying
medical condition,
he should not be on bypass
for longer than two hours.
Putting in Jack's new heart
will take about 90 minutes.
That leaves us half an
hour to remove the old one.
While Shaun is
transplanting the new heart,
I will be excising
Jack's valves.
We have zero room for error.
Prep your patients.
Exciting case.
Yep.
We're saving two babies at once,
and your commentary is "yep"?
I was agreeing with you.
With as few words as possible,
which you've been doing
for the last two weeks.
If you have a problem
with me, just tell me.
Okay.
Okay. I have a problem with you
and how you handled
Perez's case.
- That's completely stupid.
- You just said I should tell you.
I didn't say I would
agree with you.
You overrode our
patient's wishes,
and Perez is gone because of it.
Perez is alive because of it.
You don't know what would have
happened if you'd listened to him.
You made the decision
you thought was best.
Didn't matter what
anyone else wanted.
I'm sorry, but you
don't get to do that
and not deal with
the consequences.
The consequences?
I lost someone I
care about a lot,
and I miss him every day.
I'm really trying hard to focus
on the good things in my life,
the job I love,
the friends I thought I had...
But it feels like everyone is
moving on, and I'm just alone.
Spare yourself the
burden of punishing me.
Get her prepped, draped,
and under anesthesia.
I'll see you in 30
minutes, hopefully.
I had an extra set.
You don't have to be Catholic.
They can just be a reminder
that you're not alone.
Thank you.
There is a lot of scar
tissue to dissect through.
The cardiomyopathy has caused
Jack's heart to enlarge
and adhere to his chest wall.
This will take
longer than planned
in order to preserve the valves.
We inspected the mitral valve.
The atrial septum is intact.
The heart looks good.
Dr. Allen, connect
the pulmonary veins
to prep the left atrial cuff.
Dr. Kalu, you're with us.
Okay. Increase flows
and cool to 25 degrees.
Start the clock.
Come on, Peanut.
We went with the flow,
but now it's nap time.
Come on. Settle.
Oh.
Ohh! We were so close, Peanut.
I need to transect the aorta,
but there are thick adhesions
where it meets the valve.
You now only have an hour and 14
minutes to put the new heart in.
The annulus is at the
tip of my dissection.
If I nick that, the
aortic valve is useless.
Anterior retraction.
We're running out of time.
Jack's transplant
is at serious risk.
Metz.
Dr. Murphy, you need to
abort this procedure.
Shaun, ECMO is still
an option for Eden.
- You need to abort...
- Got it!
The valves are good.
Ready for the donor heart.
How is she? Ready to go.
Vitals are great.
Open her chest and
start her on bypass
while I recover the valves.
Scalpel. How do the valves look?
A little bigger than
we measured on imaging.
Makes the anastomosis
challenging.
But it can still work?
It has to.
Hmm.
Feeding time starting
in five minutes.
Shh.
It's not seating perfectly.
Let's try a purse string suture.
7-0 Prolene.
Got it. Saline.
There's a paravalvular
leak at the aortic.
How about pledgeted sutures?
In an infant this small,
that could cause stenosis.
We try again.
7-0 Prolene.
It's been almost two
and a half hours.
We need to get him off bypass.
The aortic anastomosis
is complete.
Unclamp the aorta
and start rewarming.
Now what?
We wait... and hope his
heart starts beating.
It's been almost three hours.
Do you think something's wrong?
The sutures are holding.
Now the little thing
just has to beat.
Start warming her up.
Decrease the flows.
We need to shock him.
Clear!
Again.
The surgeries were successful.
Both your babies are doing very
well, and you can see them soon.
Thank you.
You saved our daughter.
You are welcome.
I miss my baby.
I'm going home now.
All right. Let me just
jump in the shower.
And then I'm good to go.
Go home to your man.
It's okay.
Bless you.
- Tomorrow?
- Mm-hmm.
You're right.
This chorizo is...
What'd you call it?
Bussin'.
Right.
Definitely bus sin'.
I thought we could
share an order.
Tell me you didn't
forget the hot sauce.
- Hello.
- Hmm...
Why is Steve awake?
You look terrible.
Thank you.
Steve has been fed,
burped, changed,
and woken from his haphazard nap
by a speaker reminder.
How's Eden?
Very good. And Jack's
transplant was successful.
Mm.
Parenting can be very hard.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah. I've noticed.
There are many hard choices
about what works best.
People want different things.
I will try to
make room for your way.
The schedule is important,
but I will un-sync the
app from the speaker.
I put it out on the fire escape.
Thank you.
I really appreciate it.
But the only room I need
right now is the bedroom.
- Okay.
- Good night.
I'm borrowing your
noise-canceling headphones.
I love you both.
Are you kidding me?
You recommended me?
I was just following
your example.
See? You're a natural leader.
I'm old. I'm worn
out and I'm old.
- You're wise.
- I remember rotary phones.
You're vital.
You're experienced.
You're the most respected
doctor in this hospital.
Aaron, you have
institutional knowledge
and a... and a natural,
unexplainable gravitas.
Will you please stop being an
idiot and just take the job?
Stop being selfish and stubborn.
How am I being selfish? I'm...
Oh, you're together.
That saves me a stop.
Your recommendations
presented the board
with a very difficult choice.
So we didn't
choose.
You two are the new
interim co-presidents
of St. Bonaventure Hospital.
Congratulations!
This is not the schedule, Steve.
Mommy needs to sleep.
Daddy needs to sleep.
You need to sleep.
Please?
Please. We are both very tired.
Hey.
I don't know what to do.
I can't go inside because
Lea needs to sleep.
I've always been able
to get him down before.
Sometimes babies
just need to cry.
Hey. Um
why don't I take him?
Get some sleep.
It's okay. Just get some rest.
I will just take a short nap.
Take as long as you need.
Hey.
Hey. I got you. Hey.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
I got you.
Huh. I got you.
I'm Grandpa
in case you were wondering.