Previously on ER:
You get used to it. You'll be
sliding in the hall in socks in no time.
How long you gonna stay?
Kem's gonna go back and see
her family for a couple weeks.
Then come back here
and have the baby.
I don't want you to get
the wrong idea about Luka.
- He's a good guy.
- I'm not looking for anything right now.
Okay. I just thought
you should know.
Thank you. But independence
works pretty good for me.
Although I wouldn't
mind some regular sex.
They always pray
before they start eating.
You have to bow your
head. That's weird.
Just be respectful. Think
about something else.
- Like what?
- I don't know. Baseball or dinosaurs...
cannibalism.
Isn't his mom gonna set
something on fire tonight?
- Bananas.
- That doesn't happen every day.
Well, Austin's mom can
cook pretty much anything.
See, you're gonna have a great
time. Sorry. Late start. Hi, Austin.
I couldn't get Max going either.
I'm never gonna make yoga now.
Okay.
One for my pager, two
for the hospital, okay?
What are you gonna do tonight?
I don't know. Check
your sugar before bed.
- You gonna see Luka?
- I don't know. I guess.
- Bye.
- Enjoy your night of freedom.
Thanks. I will.
Man, your sister's hot.
Fourteen-year-old
female, ankle inversion...
I'm dying right now! I'm dying
every minute, every second, dying.
Every day I'm closer to death.
Negative drawer,
good pedal pulses...
splint and RICE.
Seventy-four-year-old...
Hold on. Past medical history?
On the 14-year-old?
Unremarkable.
Was she drunk or high? Does the story
match the injury? She sexually active?
- When was her last menstrual period?
- She came in for a sprained ankle.
Monoarticular joint
pain in a young woman...
could be the result of
gonococcal arthritis, staph...
- or a systemic polyarticular disease.
- Or she fell off a curb.
You're a med student. I don't
want to hear "history unremarkable."
This ER visit may be the only
time a 14-year-old sees a doctor.
Get a sexual history,
do some STD counseling.
Dr. Weaver. Arnie
Nadler, Human Resources.
- Oh, right.
- Hi. Arnie Nadler. Nice to meet you.
Mr. Nadler is visiting us
for a couple of weeks...
advising us on how to have a
happy and cooperative workplace.
Shorter hours, higher pay.
- Pardon?
- Just a suggestion.
I'm open to suggestions.
I'll be interviewing the staff
before issuing recommendations.
I'd love to pursue this conversation
with you when you have a free minute.
- Great.
- An HR consultant?
Risk Management sent him.
He's a mandated part of the
Romano lawsuit settlement.
- Which one?
- Hengstet.
- Who?
- Nurse with the weird dog and that hat.
- Sexual harassment?
- Hostile work environment.
We identify and assess
high-risk employee behaviors...
and implement
early-intervention strategies...
before they escalate into
psychological abuse or violence.
Have you ever been
in an ER before?
You know, Dr. Romano's
gone, and we all get along great.
In my experience, all work
environments could use help.
Especially when navigating the
twin dangers of anger and conflict.
- Morris. Morris, I'm gonna kill you.
- I'm sorry. Here, have one.
Don't put those there.
Thank you.
Idiot.
John?
What are you doing? I was
gonna make you breakfast in bed.
Did you lock Emily
in the guesthouse?
No. I gave her the day off.
She's convinced we're
gonna burn the house down.
Oh, let's. Then we can run off to
the jungle, live off sticks and berries.
Is my cooking that bad?
- Ow!
- Oh, let me do it.
They hassle you about
going into work today?
No. I think Luka has forced
everybody to lower their expectations.
If we show up without resigning,
Weaver thinks it's a good day.
We've got a whole
day alone together.
- What are we gonna do?
- I have a list.
This is everything I wanted to show
you in Chicago, but we haven't done yet.
Aw.
- Ice-skating in Grant Park.
- Yeah, that's one.
And the Art Institute.
Among others. So
where should we start?
I have an idea.
Would you do a sexual history on a
14-year-old girl with a twisted ankle?
- Depends on the girl. Why?
- Weaver.
I'm used to the squawk,
but she's condescending.
Belly pain in 3 has
been waiting for an hour.
Okay. Hey, you're getting big.
- You mind?
- Yeah.
- You want to try a dislocated shoulder?
- Yeah. Can I do the Hennepin maneuver?
Are you marrying, or will
that kid grow up a bastard?
Shut up, Frank.
But what is going on
with you and Chuck?
He's pushing to get
married, buy a minivan...
fire up the barbecue.
I don't know.
Dr. Lewis. How often do you find
yourself the subject of unwanted...
physical contact at work?
- What?
Can you do a fly-by on a swollen
knee? This guy's demanding pain meds...
- wants to see a doctor right away.
- Sure.
Is tactile contact
between employees...
something that is
encouraged or frowned upon?
How many bimbos
you got in this hospital?
Just the right number.
Miguel, this is Dr. Lockhart.
- Student doctor, actually.
- What does that mean?
Means she's studying
the latest medicine.
That looks painful.
How'd you do it?
I fell off a ladder. I
gotta get back to work.
- What kind of work you do?
- Hang dry wall.
It'll go away. Just give me some
Vicodin, and I can get off your plate.
We'll take good care of your knee
and get you home. When did you fall?
- What do you have?
- I'm not ready to present.
Knee effusion from a fall? Drain it,
pain meds and send him on his way.
- Told you. ABBY: I'm
not finished doing a history.
We've got 30 on the
board and 50 waiting.
We're backed up 18 hours,
and this is an easy case.
- Come on, next patient. Let's go.
- I'll get a setup for you.
Med students always
spend an hour with patients.
- She was doing a great job.
- Dr. Pratt, if you have a minute...
I'd like to talk to you later about
that incident with Dr. Morris.
It wasn't an incident.
It was a French fry.
- How does that feel? Is that too tight?
- No, it's perfect.
Oh, I love it. Seeing
your whole face.
- Are you colder now?
- Yeah.
Well, that is what
scarves are for.
That and kissing.
This is where you used to
skate when you were a kid?
No. There was another one
on the other side of Grant Park.
My grandfather used
to rent it out for us.
All right, you ready?
I don't know.
Whoa!
Yeah?
- So who's "us"?
- My brother and I.
Your grandfather would rent you
the entire rink just for the two of you?
- Yeah, and our friends.
- A lot of friends, I hope.
Usually. You know, I wasn't quite
as pampered as I make it sound.
No, of course not.
I still don't see anything.
Once the blades are in,
pull pressure straight down...
and the cervix
should come into view.
- Can you set up for cultures?
- Sure.
- So when did the bleeding start?
- Last night.
It's weird because I'm
usually pretty regular.
Sorry.
Dr. Kovac. Vulva hematoma,
multiple bruises and vaginal tears...
one at least 3 centimeters.
You'll need suturing.
Lido and 3-0 Vicryl.
Layla, there's some
vaginal trauma.
Is that from too much sex?
Could be from the kind of sex.
Has anyone forced
themselves on you?
- What?
- Did anyone touch you in a way that...
hurt you or that you
didn't give permission?
- No.
- Do you have a boyfriend?
Fiancé.
Dean. He's in college.
Do you and Dean...?
Does it ever get rough?
Well, we get a little
carried away sometimes.
- How old is that girl?
- Sixteen.
- What are you doing tonight?
- What?
A patient invited me to his
restaurant. I thought we can go.
- Does Alex like Korean food?
- Oh, Alex has a sleepover.
Nine victims total.
We're getting three more.
Gus Loomer, 50s, altered LOC.
GALLANT: Wearing a heart monitor.
- Pulse is irregular but in the mid-90s.
- How did it happen?
Plowed his Hummer
into two oncoming cars.
- One, two... KOVAC:
What do you want, Gallant?
Full trauma panel, lateral C-spine,
chest, pelvis and a 12-lead EKG.
Okay. Add a set of troponins
and talk to the patient.
Mr. Loomer, you're at County
Hospital. You were in a car accident.
I was driving. I must
have blacked out.
- Been having heart palpitations?
- I had a heart attack two years ago.
Call Cards to
interrogate the monitor.
See if they need help
with other traumas.
Okay.
How bad is it?
- We're still assessing your injuries, sir.
- No, no, no, not me.
- My Hummer. It's brand-new.
- Okay. C-spine is clear.
- Can you find out about my car?
- Not right now, sir.
Got three more victims on
the MVA, two of them critical.
- Is he stable enough to be moved?
- Yes.
- What's MVA?
- Motor-vehicle accident.
Gonna be a lot of crashes
today. It's icy out there.
He's hypoxic. He
could be retaining.
Hang a gram of Ancef
and update his tetanus.
- Sending him to CT?
- No. Belly is benign.
- We'll follow the serial crits.
- Good day to be driving a Hummer.
Sam, we need you to
get the Pedes airway box.
- There's a kid involved?
- Mom and dad too.
Damn shame.
- He doesn't know?
- No. He was unconscious at the scene.
- This is the dad?
- Lungs down...
- hypoxic, altered.
- We need the room.
- Can you move him out? LEWIS:
Duvata, bring Loomer to Curtain 2.
Oh, my God.
- What have we got?
- Kathy Shepard, A and O times four.
- Breath sounds clear, good radial pulse.
- Is my family okay?
We're working on your
husband and your son.
- Loss of consciousness?
- No.
- What about my daughter?
- What daughter?
- Morris...
- They never brought in a girl.
Is she dead?! Is she dead,
and you're not telling me?!
Distal perfusion
sucks. I can't get a line.
Draw up etomidate.
- What's his weight?
- About 25 kilos, same as Alex.
Oh, God. He's been scalped.
Exposed skull and galea
with a big hematoma.
Neck's broken, C-5 and 6.
We'll need the Gardner-Wells tongs
to stabilize the neck. Page Neurosurg.
Where's my mommy?
It's all right, sweetie.
Mark the placement
point for the tongs.
They're all beautiful.
Most of these are
over 100 years old.
They were built for the
doctors, lawyers and managers...
who went west
with the railroads.
This is my favorite
street in Chicago.
What do you think of this one?
It's lovely.
- Yeah? You like it?
- Yeah.
- What?
- I was thinking maybe we could buy it.
- Really?
- Actually, I may have already bought it.
I had to put a deposit down. There
were four other interested buyers.
We need to have someplace
to stay when we're here.
- What about your grandmother's castle?
- We can sell it.
What will your father say?
He might get a little upset,
but Gamma left the house to me.
I don't want to live there.
Are you sure?
It is a little bit more
space than we need.
Mm-hm.
We can get our deposit
back if you don't like it.
- I love it.
- Yeah?
Yeah.
They sent two to Mercy
and two to Northwestern.
Why would they split us up?
In big accidents, one hospital
can't take care of everyone.
There were 10 victims total.
We could only handle four.
No, that's eight. What
happened to the other two?
There were two
fatalities at the scene.
- What?
- Kathy.
- Oh, my God.
Kathy, we don't
know anything yet.
- Oh, God, Paul.
- Mrs. Shepard?
- What was the last HemoCue?
- Ten-point-two.
He has to get up to the O.R.
He's losing blood somewhere.
Ethan? Where's Ethan? Ethan.
What are you doing to him?
- Until it's anchored in the skull.
- No!
- Dr. Kovac?
- No! Take that off!
Stop it! Stop it! That's my son.
God, this isn't happening.
Oh, God.
Your husband has suffered
massive injuries to his chest.
Both lungs are collapsed,
and he's bleeding internally.
What about Ethan?
What about you? You
were in there with him?
Tell me!
Dr. Weaver will talk to you.
Please, what was that thing
they were screwing into his head?
Ethan has a broken neck.
- The tongs help prevent paralysis.
- Paralysis?
There's been severe
injury to Ethan's spine...
and his lungs, and
probably his brain.
- They're dying, aren't they?
- We don't know yet.
Where should I go now?
Sorry?
Who's gonna die first?
I've had this ice-cream cone for nearly
two hours now. It hasn't melted yet.
It's just one of the many wonderful
things about winters in Chicago.
My grandparents got
married here, and my parents.
- Is that a proposal?
- You want it to be?
No, I thought since breakfast in
bed didn't work out, we'd try for lunch.
- Are we gonna check in?
- We already have.
Beth Shepard. No. Kathy
Shepard's here at County.
I'm looking for
her daughter Beth.
- I should get a smaller set of sandbags.
- Stabilize the tongs while I add traction.
Can you tell me what
hospital she was sent to?
Abby, I need you to
hold the counterweight.
Layla's been waiting
three hours for a repeat crit.
Go on. He's stable.
I'll take three of your patients
if you take over for me in there.
No, thanks.
- How are you doing?
- Fine. When can I go?
As soon as we
get these results in.
Nurse, can I have
some orange juice?
Hearing that, did you feel
threatened or just uncomfortable?
I mean, would you
categorize his comments...
as hostile or
merely insensitive?
- Can I still have sex?
- Not for a couple weeks.
- What? Just tell your boyfriend.
- Fiancé.
Just tell him that he
needs to settle down.
If he really loves
you, he'll understand.
Dean loves me.
We're getting married.
You know, sometimes you can
love someone and not realize...
that they're hurting you.
He doesn't mean to hurt me.
But does he hurt you sometimes?
Did he hurt you last night?
I don't know.
What do you mean?
We went on a drive last
night with two of his friends.
We went to this
park near his house.
He tells me I'm sexy all the
time. He just likes to show me off.
Well, show you off how?
Sometimes he likes
to let them watch.
Do they ever...
do more than watch?
Layla?
Yeah.
Sam, we need you to
set up another IMED.
Get Duvata. ABBY: She's busy.
We're gonna figure this out, okay?
- Sam, now.
I'll be right back.
Dispatch RDC can't tell me where
Kathy's daughter went or if she's alive.
The father arrested twice. I don't
know how long he's gonna last.
Decreased on the right.
Pratt wanted that guy discharged.
- I'm busy.
Betadine. Let's do this again.
- It doesn't look good.
- Needle decompression and chest tube.
- Where are my pain pills?
- You can't be here. You have to wait.
- No. I got to see you now.
- Abby, get him out of here.
- Tachy at 124.
- We're still waiting on some tests.
- I don't need any tests!
- Abby!
BP's dropping again. This is
stupid. We're just torturing him.
Let's go.
Hi.
Was this on your list?
Several times.
I hope he has your nose.
You have a lovely nose.
What do you want him
to be when he grows up?
I don't care. As long as
he's healthy and happy.
Okay, I'm deciding between
Cy Young Award winner...
and the guy who cures cancer.
I think he'll be
astoundingly cute.
Well, nature likes
genetic diversity.
We should make him marry
an Asian or Hispanic girl.
You know what frightens me most?
That I could get
used to all of this.
Well, I'm not gonna be
renting out any ice rinks for him.
- No?
- Uh-uh.
That's what I ran away from.
- Good femoral pulse.
- All that epi kicked his BP up.
Sam.
Layla's pregnant?
I can't get his sats above 80.
- Did you call Social Work?
- Yeah. But they're slow as hell.
Sub-Q air in the neck.
- Let me tell her.
- Okay.
Haleh, I'll be right back, okay?
We do a pregnancy test on all
female patients of childbearing age.
Yours came back positive.
- I'm pregnant?
- Yes.
Do you use birth control?
I was on the pill for a
while, but it made me fat.
Oh, my God! This is incredible.
- Layla, do your parents know...?
- Dean's gonna go through the roof.
You can't use that in here.
You need to seriously consider whether
or not you want to keep this pregnancy.
Oh, Dean loves kids.
What you want now may not be
what you're gonna want in five years...
or next year, or
even in six months.
We need a SonoSite in here.
I'll be back.
You running some kind of scam?
I've been here nine hours
waiting on some tests.
I hear you. How come
Mr. Rivas hasn't been discharged?
Abby's still waiting
on some labs.
Mr. Loomer...
- Hey, can you take this to Trauma 1?
- Sure.
Miss Taggart, I would
love to sit down with you...
and discuss workplace
conduct when you have time.
- I don't, okay?
- Maybe later?
I won't then either.
Mr. Loomer, back to bed.
- What's happening in there? SAM:
Come on. You've a heart condition.
Is he dead?
Yeah.
- Damn shame.
- Come on. Get back to bed.
- I bought that car on a whim.
- You shouldn't be here.
Impulse buy, midlife-crisis thing.
But hell, it probably saved my life.
I could've ended up like
that poor schmuck in there.
You drove your
car into that family.
You were unconscious
on the scene.
Your Hummer slammed into
their car and went right over it.
I don't remember.
Is that Mr. Loomer?
Oh, God! I need some help here!
Shirt.
- What happened?
- Syncope.
Okay, quick look.
- V-tach.
- Okay, charge to 200.
Clear.
Sinus. Got a pulse.
Okay. Can you at least
tell me how serious...?
She's alive.
Okay. When can I call back
to...? Okay, fine. Thank you.
She's at Mercy Hospital.
Doctors are working on her.
- What's wrong?
- I couldn't get more specifics.
But I'm pushing for
a transfer here soon.
I just want to
know if she's okay.
Do you want to be
with your son, Kathy?
- Will you come with me?
- Sure.
Labs back on your knee effusion,
Miguel Rivas. AFB's positive.
Okay. I'm sorry. Can
you take Mrs. Shepard in?
- Of course.
- I'll be back in a minute.
- Pratt.
- What?
- Miguel's knee effusion is from TB.
I saw his old charts. He had
multi-drug-resistant TB 15 months ago.
- He stopped going to therapy.
- No coughing.
I did an AFB stain,
which is positive.
He's coughing. He's probably
infectious. Where is he?
I just discharged him.
We have to find him before
he starts coughing up TB all...
I gave him a prescription. Call the
pharmacy. I'll see if he's still there.
Miguel! Move this damn thing.
- Watch it! Watch it! ABBY:
Hey! Hold the elevator!
- Damn it.
Hey! Miguel, hey!
- Wait for the next one.
- Come on, man. Sorry. All right.
Hey, Alex. If you don't wanna go to
that sleepover tonight, you don't have to.
We could do something fun together. If
you still wanna go, then that's fine too.
I just realized that I'm the only
one who will get this message...
because I never showed you
how to use the voicemail. Damn it.
I am so disgusted with
you. You are such an idiot.
- I'm sorry, okay?
- How could you do this to me?
- Get rid of it.
- It's ours.
- Leave.
- How do I even know it's mine?
- I love you.
- Get out! You need to leave...
- right now!
- What's going on?
One of your buddies
from the gangbang squad?
- She knows?
- Get out!
- I told you she'd talk.
- We didn't make her do anything...
- she didn't want to.
- Tell it to the cops.
She lies, okay? You heard her.
If it was true, why would she still
be saying she loves me? Hold on!
- Let go of me.
- Look, she's just a stupid little slut.
Hey, how long's it
gonna take in here?
I've been here 12
hours, going on 13 now.
- Keep your mask on.
- Yo, nurse! I'm talking to you.
- Hey, Frank.
- Hey.
- Has my kid called?
- No.
- He was supposed to call.
- Maybe he's busy.
- Can you hold for a tap...?
- Weaver says not to see any patients...
- until you talk to her.
- Yeah.
- Wait here for her.
- I got it.
- I'm just the messenger.
- I don't trust him.
He didn't understand. He stopped taking
the pills when he stopped feeling sick.
I want Miguel in isolation.
If he can't take his meds...
- I want him handcuffed and force-fed.
- He just started coughing.
- You're gonna call the police?
- The guy's a time bomb.
Are we gonna throw all
of our TB patients in jail?
- Just this one.
- If this is how we treat people with TB...
they will stop coming
to this hospital.
- They don't all go out together.
- They hang out at the TB clinic.
Miguel will need
six months' therapy.
- You think you can do that?
- I want to try to make him cooperate...
with the health-care system.
- Hey. FRANK: You're
supposed to stay put.
- If you still want to talk...
- Maybe later.
Waiting for Weaver? SAM: Yeah.
Hey, don't hit her.
She's crippled.
- It never stops being funny, does it?
- Sam.
How's Ethan?
Pressure's holding.
Last gas looks better.
Mr. Nadler's recommending
your immediate dismissal.
He called other
hospitals you worked for.
- You had prior incidents.
- I never got fired from those jobs.
You left before they could.
I'm a good nurse.
You want me here, fine.
If not, I'll find another
job somewhere else.
Something tells me you've used that
speech before. It's clear to everyone...
that you have an
impulse-control problem.
The guy helped his friends
gang-rape his girlfriend.
- We'll probably get sued.
- Kid's in PEA.
All right. The director of
nursing will talk to you tomorrow.
For what it's worth, I
wish I'd hit him harder.
You know, it's a lot warmer
here in the summertime.
I like Chicago.
In the summertime, the
lake is full of sailboats. It's...
I can't live here, John.
My work, it's...
important.
I know.
- What terminal? CARTER:
United. Terminal One.
We could just disappear,
and no one would ever know.
Yeah, I'd like that.
Me too.
- The pills made me sick.
- If you stop taking the pills too soon...
you'll only kill some of the TB.
Bacteria that's left will get stronger...
and then none of
the medicine will work.
Abby?
Did you call the cops yet?
No, not yet.
You're wasting your time
with this guy. Call the cops.
- What are you doing?
- I'm getting out of here.
It's not that simple.
You can't leave.
- I'll take the damn pills.
- You need to go to the TB clinic...
- every day for observed therapy.
- I don't need that.
- Abby. Mercy for you on line one.
- Just a minute. Miguel, stop.
It's about that woman's
daughter, Beth Shepard.
Okay. Don't be an idiot.
Okay. Security, stop this guy.
Hold it. Come here, please.
Hey, come on. Come
on. Easy. Come on.
Get off!
Don't hurt him.
I don't want you to leave.
I don't want to leave.
Well, then stay.
I can't.
We'll be all right.
We love you.
Your Holter monitor records every
heartbeat and stores it for 24 hours.
Thanks.
It appears you had a
run of V-tach at 8:20 a.m.
Eight-twenty. Is that
about when I crashed?
Your arrhythmia
caused you to black out.
But upon impact, it seemed you
reverted to sinus almost instantly.
You mean the car
crash saved my life?
Yeah.
How long?
Forty-one minutes.
Hold compressions. Pace at 80.
No capture.
Another atropine and resume CPR.
PEA.
Mrs. Shepard, your
son has no pulse.
His brain has been deprived
of oxygen for almost an hour.
I think we should stop.
But it's still beeping.
It can take some time for the
electrical activity of the heart to stop.
- What about my daughter?
- I'll find out.
I thought my life was over
after my first heart attack.
I couldn't work.
I couldn't walk upstairs.
I couldn't have sex.
I felt like I was dead.
I never thought I'd get
married, have two kids.
I wasn't the type.
I always thought that stuff
would mean life was over.
But then...
I got pregnant.
Paul was so excited.
He was always more
excited about everything.
I thought my wife
was gonna leave me.
I mean, I thought she should.
But she didn't. She...
She made me get out
of bed in the morning.
I'll take any seat. I
must get to the gate.
- Amsterdam's sold out.
- Another flight. Anything.
I have a first-class
to Tokyo. It's $9000.
That car cost $110,000.
But she didn't care. She said, "Gus,
you spoil yourself. You deserve it."
So...
that's what I did. I went out and
bought myself my dream car...
took it for a drive.
I've been having these
dreams, fantasies.
Stretching out alone at night,
you know, reading a book.
Now I can.
Did I make this happen?
Why? Why should I be the lucky
one? Why should I be spared?
No one knows why
these things happen.
You have to believe there
is a reason you're still here.
Late start this morning.
Ethan wanted ice cream.
He always wants these
crazy things. Today I said okay.
Can you imagine?
Ice cream in winter.
She's in here.
Oh, sweetie.
John?
Hi. Can I get four
coffees, three chili dogs...
and in a separate bag, two plain
hamburgers and three plain yogurts.
Hamburgers and yogurt?
Susan can only eat two
things without throwing up.
Being pregnant sucks.
- You want to sit?
- Sure.
How are you handling a
nursing and student shift?
- Do you ever get any sleep?
- Not that much, no.
That's what you get
for switching careers.
Well, medical
school was the plan...
for a while, actually. I
just sort of got sidetracked.
The last thing I remember wanting
to be was an international spy.
I was 15.
Then I got pregnant.
Fifteen? Wow.
Oh, I was, like, one of those girls
who gives birth at her prom. Total denial.
By the time I figured out
where the clinic was, I...
I didn't have any money. Alex's
dad never kicked in his half.
I couldn't get a waitressing
job because I was too young.
I took double shifts at
Baskin-Robbins to save up the dough.
Did he go with you?
He was at a gig.
Right.
First time I went...
I sat in the waiting room.
They called my
name. I never got up.
Second time, I was too late.
I look at Alex and I...
The place I went to had this
calendar on the wall with a picture of...
Strawberry Shortcake.
I just stared at
it the whole time.
- You have a nursing shift?
- Yeah. You're finished?
Yeah. Oh, here.
- Thank you.
- See you tomorrow.
See you tomorrow.
- Hey.
- How's your arm?
- Oh, it's okay.
Alex having fun
at his sleepover?
Too much fun to come
to the phone when I call.
Yeah. Sleepovers are tough.
I mean on parents, not kids.
I had a boy and
a girl in Croatia.
Miss Taggart...
do you have a minute?
I'll talk to you tomorrow.
This is a document drawn
up by our legal department.
It says you agree to be
admitted for treatment.
And after that, visit the TB clinic
every morning for six months.
I'm not signing anything.
You don't have a
Social Security number.
Hey, I've been living and
working in this country for 10 years.
Good. So you know if you
get arrested for a felony...
la migra's gonna
kick your ass out.
Oh, where's Dr. Carter?
Sandy's gonna kill me.
Dr. Weaver, we need you
to sign off on a TB admission.
TB on a knee effusion? See, that's
what I meant by doing a thorough exam.
- Good catch, Pratt.
- Dr. Weaver...
- That was Abby's catch.
- It doesn't matter.
- Dr. Weaver.
- What do you want?
A month in Door County
with my French horn...
but I'd settle for five minutes
of your undivided attention.
This place is a disaster. I've
never seen anything like it.
I've seen your workers
engaging in bullying, hostility...
- violence, inappropriate touching...
- Come on. We have a good staff.
- They do their best.
- You have lunatics on your hands.
Doctors yelling, nurses
beating up patients.
- You need to fire people immediately.
- Fine. You're fired.
- What?
- Don't come back tomorrow.
You'll break the
terms of the settlement.
So sue me. Again.
What else is new?
You're late.
- Night shift started 20 minutes ago.
- Yeah, I'm sorry.
- Where were you?
- I was at the airport dropping off Kem.
- Oh, yeah? Where'd she go?
- Kisangani.
- She have to get back to her program?
- Mm-hm.
She has 200 HIV
patients' lives to save.
Good for her.
That's Sandy. She can't
believe I left her alone...
with a screaming
baby for 12 hours.
- How long will she be gone?
- I hope just a couple weeks.
Hey...
- did I show you the new pictures?
- No.
- He's pointing his finger, huh?
- Yeah. He does that all the time.
He came out of the womb doing that.
It's like, "I've got a point to make."
- He's got his own personality already.
- Yeah. They all do. You'll see.
- Hi.
- Hey.
I was gonna see if
you'd had dinner yet.
Maybe we could get something.
Come on in. Let me get my coat.
- Wow, nice place.
- Yeah, it's okay.
So...
- where do you want to go?
- I don't know.