Cristina?
Owen's at the hospital, and I...
- Forget it. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- Come on.
Come on.
Well, that's...
that's kinda weird.
Oh, he's asleep. Get in.
Most surgeons
grew up being freaks.
While other kids played outside,
we holed up in our rooms...
Mm.
Memorizing the periodic table,
huddling for hours over
our junior microscopes,
dissecting our first frogs.
Almost all of the
surgeons in your program
have been cleared to operate.
The remaining cases will
be referred to Dr. Wyatt,
and she'll clear those people
when she feels they're ready.
What about Cristina Yang?
What's the timeline there?
Dr. Perkins felt that we
should assign Dr. Yang
to something low-stress
for a few months...
research, admin duties.
Administration? That's
the best you can do?
Put her on my service.
She's not on anyone's
service, Derek.
She'll be in the hospital, she
just won't go near a surgery.
Well, you do that,
and she'll leave.
She will not come
back to this program.
- Put her on my service.
- I already tried it, Shepherd.
Hunt's right. She's not ready.
Well, she wasn't ready
before. Maybe now she is.
I think we should
give him a shot.
Well, especially if
nothing else is working.
She crawled under a table
in the O.R. two weeks ago.
Thank you.
If she goes, I go.
That's insane.
I think they're
talking about you.
It's gonna be OK. I mean,
they... they... they can't
kick you out of the program
for being traumatized.
I don't care what they do.
Dr. Yang, you're with me.
What? N-no.
I'm with you.
You're with somebody
else. We're walking, Dr. Yang.
Derek.
Hey.
Where could I find Dr. Shepherd?
- You have an appointment?
- I don't.
Uh, could you just point me
in the direction of his office?
I'm sorry.
She has that look on her face
because the last time someone
walked into this hospital
looking for Dr. Shepherd
- without an appointment,
he shot him.
- Mark! Oh.
Oh, my God!
- Hi, Amy.
- You still look hot.
And you, uh, look
a lot more grown-up
than when I last saw you.
- You can say "hot," you know? 'cause I am. I'm hot.
- No, I can't,
because in my mind, you're
still Derek's 12-year-old sister.
- Huh.
- So what are you
doing in Seattle?
Uh, Derek's an ass
who won't return my calls.
Derek's an ass who got
shot and won't return my calls,
so I brought him a present
or a bribe or a peace offering.
- Whatever. I brought him that.
- Imagine how - surprised and relieved we were
when we grew up and found
out there were others out there
- just as freaky as we were...
- You brought him Brett Favre?
No. I brought him a brain tumor.
Same microscopes,
same dead frogs,
same inexplicable urge to
take human beings apart.
- Talk to Cristina.
- She's in the middle
of a nervous breakdown.
- I can't push her.
- In two weeks, my landlord
is gonna hand keys to a
Swedish couple with a truckload
- of Swedish furniture,
and I said I'd be gone.
- Teddy, can you...
mention it to
Owen, like casually,
"Hey, how's the
apartment search going?
No pressure, but Callie
and Arizona have a life."
"You're crowding them,
and Arizona can't handle it."
Oh, my God. Are...
Teddy, are you OK?
Um...
Andrew's leaving.
Oh. Oh, no, you
didn't. She got attached.
Oh, no. No, no, no.
You were supposed to be
smart and cool and G.I. Jane.
I know that. I know that.
Instead, I got attached
to the trauma guy who swoops
in and swoops out a month later.
I'm such an idiot.
I'm not G.I. Jane.
I'm Attachment Barbie.
Oh, you poor thing. Come here.
Come here, come here, come here.
You know what would
make you feel better?
What?
Telling Owen to get off his ass
and get his traumatized
wife out of our apartment.
Meredith is a much
better doctor than me.
- No, she's not.
- I am, too. Sorry, Cristina.
Oh, no. No offense
taken. She... she is.
- I'll take my chances.
- OK, how about we compromise?
- Why don't you page me
when you've got something?
- I've got something.
Oh, come on.
- Amy?
- Well, if you'd pick
up the damn phone,
- I wouldn't have to stalk you.
- Yeah. Why didn't you
call your sister?
- Sister?
- Meredith, Cristina,
- this is Amy.
- Amelia.
He's the only one who
gets to call me Amy.
- Um, nice to
finally meet you.
- Likewise.
Amy... Amelia... is
also a neurosurgeon.
- Another one? You Shepherds
grow them like weeds.
- Who's this, your husband?
- Derek, this is Tom.
- Todd.
Oh, best of luck to you both.
No, we met on the plane. He
has a probable pituitary tumor.
Did she say you
had spongy hands?
Yeah.
- Yeah. Were your hands
on her breasts at the time?
- Yeah.
So this was a mile-high hookup?
That doesn't change the
fact that he's a very sick man.
- If he has symptoms,
it could be a tumor.
- Not just "could." It... it is.
All right. Well, this fine
lady will find you a surgeon.
Derek, she's your sister.
- You can buy her
a cup of coffee.
- I have a lot of sisters,
and if I bought them all coffee,
we wouldn't have anything.
- Derek...
- Todd needs a workup. Will you take care of it?
- I can do it.
- Yang's on my service. Why don't you just go
have a good day with Amy,
OK? She's a laugh a minute.
Can you hold the
door open, please?
Thank you.
Easy.
OK.
Karev, what are you
waiting for? Get on.
I-I just remembered.
Dr. Hunt needs his lab results.
I'll... I'll meet you up there.
This patient takes
priori... Karev, what...
I can do it.
No, uh, Dr. Kepner has a
couple of patients in the E.R.
Go help her.
- Is Dr. Webber going up? I-I need an extra hand.
- He sent me.
Oh, uh, I thought you were on
Dr. Shepherd's service today.
He took Cristina.
Why? I mean, why?
You don't think she's
OK, do you? 'Cause I don't.
I mean, she was in
the house this morning.
Did she spend the night?
Because she's married.
It's a little weird
for someone to...
April, don't talk
about Cristina.
Just mind your own business.
I'm sorry. Um, I was
just... I was just concerned,
but I will try not to be.
I swear to God, Jerry, if
you don't get out of the car,
I'm gonna break the glass
- and drag you through
the freakin' window!
- No!
Um, look, ma'am, this
is an ambulance bay.
It's for doctor and
patient vehicles only.
Well, if my idiot husband
would ever get out of the car,
- you'd see he was a patient.
-
- Jerry, unlock the door.
- Just take me home, Tess!
- This was a big mistake.
- Um, sir.
If there is something
wrong with you,
you should let us take a look.
We can help.
Really? Can you
help me with these?
Uh, yes. Yes, we can.
But we can't do anything
until you get out of the car.
You'll have to open
the door for me.
OK. Um...
I need a-a chair. Oh, OK.
Oh, my...
I'm sorry.
People are great, aren't they?
Real sweethearts.
OK.
I am so, so sorry.
You will apologize to him.
- Profusely.
- And you will stay by
his side all day...
- Yes.
- Even during lunch.
I don't think I'll
be wanting lunch.
Yes, yes, I will.
Fine. Go get Dr. Sloan.
Decreased breath
sounds on the right side.
I wasn't trying to
hurt your feelings.
There's a few things
I don't talk about,
- and Cristina's one of them.
- Um, so is there any chest pain
or is it just
difficulty breathing?
Uh, it's... it's kinda both.
- It's cancer.
- It's not cancer.
Ooh, it's cancer or it's, um...
anxiety about the wedding.
- Oh, when are you
getting married?
- Two weeks.
Well, we're gonna need
to get a chest X-ray,
so is there any chance
that you could be pregnant?
Oh...
- Mnh-mnh. Not pregnant.
- You're sure?
- She's sure.
- Mm-hmm. Really super sure.
Shut up.
Um, uh,
I am a virgin.
Yeah. Uh, we're
waiting for the wedding.
Danny's had sex before.
It is important to him
that you know that.
I didn't say anything.
- OK. They think we're freaks.
- No, we don't.
- No, not at all.
- No, they think you're a freak,
and I'm just very,
very understanding.
Dr. Sloan, Dr. Bailey
needs a consult
in room 11-35.
I'll be right over.
Look away.
What?
- Stop staring at her.
- I can't.
Her last words to you
were, "Leave me alone,
leave me alone, leave me
alone," only louder. Look away.
Maybe she just needs
a little more time.
I'll try to look away.
Thank you.
Did it hurt?
Getting shot? Oh,
you're amazing.
Well, did you feel the bullet
or did you just feel pain?
I feel pain now because
you won't stop talking.
And we have images.
- Yeah, there it is.
- Dr. Yang, what's
the best approach
- on a tumor like this?
- I don't know.
Y...
It's a pituitary tumor,
so your, uh, access
would be coming in from?
You go in transnasally.
Can we book an O.R.?
What's the chance of me
finishing a thought today?
Not great. Um, there's
some compression,
so I'd like to get in
sooner than later.
Dr. Yang, can you
book an O.R., please?
You'll be scrubbing in.
You know, if she wants to
do it, you know, be my guest.
- Dr. Yang, book an O.R.
- Fine.
OK, that's my patient in there.
You're gonna let what's-her-face
with the learning
disability scrub in?
Why don't you
just shoot the guy?
Don't talk about shooting
people in this building.
Don't criticize my surgeons.
Leave your patient. Go home.
Um, Mr. Adams,
sometime in your history,
you contracted H.P.V.
There are various
types of the virus.
This one generally
causes small warts.
But in rare cases like yours,
there's an immune deficiency
that allows the warts
to get out of control.
We went to a dermatologist
in Pullman four years ago.
They were a lot smaller then.
- He removed
a bunch of them, but...
- They grew back.
Then we saw the guy again,
and they grew back again.
They're always gonna grow back.
And that's why we
should just go home.
Well, if you don't
do anything about it,
they're gonna continue to grow.
You'll become
completely disabled.
We need to do surgery.
You can't just
scrape the stuff off?
No. Um, each one of the
warts has its own blood supply.
So we need to cut
and stitch each one.
So basically, I'm gonna
go from looking like a tree
to looking like
Frankenstein, right?
Super.
Well, we'll be doing skin
grafts at the same time,
which will help with your
appearance and function.
That said, you're
right, it's not a cure.
The warts will recur, but if you
schedule surgeries regularly,
we might be able to
keep them under control.
Do you see? It's
what I told you.
They can't help.
So a couple of years
with me is, what...
a waste of time?
We never go out, Jerry.
We sit in that damn house,
day after day, month after month.
I want us to see a movie,
to go out to dinner,
I want to see... people.
Um, if the two of you
want to discuss it, we can...
No.
There's no more discussion.
You're having the surgery,
'cause if you don't,
I'm gonna leave you.
And you got nobody
else... no friends,
even your brothers
have given up.
I'm it. I'm all that's left.
So you're having the surgery.
Hey.
Got a bronchial obstruction.
Nice.
You think it's bad if I write
my own name on your board?
I mean, I did
bring in the patient,
and they gave me privileges.
Shepherd and Shepherd.
Classic.
What's going on?
You think I'm gonna
let you do to him
what you did to my
Mustang? I don't think so.
She's your sister. I...
you're being like this
because she crashed your
car a couple of years ago?
I totaled my mom's car.
People make mistakes.
Right. When you
totaled your mother's car,
were you high on pain pills?
- No.
- Did you steal your
mother's prescription pad
so you could feed
your addiction?
She stole your prescription pad?
Yeah, and then when she
went home, she O.D.'ed.
She was dead for three
minutes. I saved her.
That's what she put my mother
through after losing my father
and raising five
kids on her own,
so, no, I don't trust
her in my O.R., OK?
Hey, you paged me.
Is everything OK?
I have to get away from Shepherd
for, like, ten minutes.
He's like the K.G.B.
He's everywhere.
He's trying to help.
Yeah? Well, make him stop.
Would you love me
if I wasn't a surgeon?
I would love you if
you were a plumber.
But would you love you
if you weren't a surgeon?
I don't know.
Maybe.
I can't sleep when
you're not there.
Then I'll be there.
Chief.
Karev.
Oh, hey.
Um, can you talk to Cristina
about getting her own place?
Arizona's about to move
in, and it's kinda crowded.
They want to move out. It's just,
they haven't gotten their act together.
And, uh, if I ask her
about it, I'm a bitch.
But if you ask her about
it, you're her best friend,
inquiring about a healthy
next step in her married life.
Cristina's career is
hanging on by a thread.
She can't look at an O.R.
without breaking into a cold
sweat, she's a newlywed,
and last night,
she slept in my bed
because Owen was in surgery,
and she was afraid to be alone.
You really want to put
her out of her house?
Did you talk to
her about Cristina?
We're monsters.
Hmm?
A virgin... at 27?
Yep.
Well, maybe she was waiting
for the right person to come along,
someone special,
someone who really got her.
It's sweet. It's...
- It's idealistic.
- It's smart is what it is.
If you don't sleep with 'em,
you... you don't get attached.
Y-you sleep with them,
and then you get attached
even when you don't want to,
even when you specifically pick
someone that you are sure
that you couldn't
possibly get attached,
and then boom... you're hooked.
Graspers.
Is that the mass?
Yep.
Is it a tumor?
No, it... it looks
like... a foreign object.
All right. I got it.
What the hell is that?
- A condom?
- Yep.
Wait, and she aspirated it?
A condom in her
lung? I'm gonna gag.
And her fiancé
thinks she's a virgin.
- So I...
- OK, here we go. Here we go.
- Check it out.
- Ew. Ew. Ew.
OK, now I think I'm gonna gag.
Oh, look at Grey. It looks
like she's gonna heave.
She's looked like that all day.
I mean, I kinda
wish I was in there.
What?
Seriously, how often does
a case like this come along?
About as often as
27-year-old virgin brides.
She could still be a virgin.
Just 'cause she's 27, I
mean, it's... it's not impossible.
- Hey.
My wife is sleeping in your bed.
Yes, she is, with
Meredith, technically.
She's sleeping with Meredith.
- I'm on the other side
of the bed.
- That... I'm sorry.
- Don't you find that
a little strange?
- Mm-hmm.
Did you see E.T.?
- The movie? Yeah. Years ago. Why?
- Remember the kid... Elliott?
- Mm-hmm.
- He and E.T. had this
weird and disturbing bond.
If he got sick, E.T. got sick.
If E.T. got drunk,
Elliott would get drunk.
That's kinda like
Cristina and Meredith.
Meanwhile, you and I are like
the, um, the government
guys in the white hazmat suits.
You know, we're trying to
steer 'em in the right direction,
but in the end, we
just don't understand.
And you're OK with that?
I fish. I'm building a house.
I've recently taken up golf.
That helps.
I'm looking out for her.
Thank you.
So, Karev,
how old were
you your first time?
15. School nurse,
back of her car.
15? That's impressive.
When I was 16, she taught
me how to drive that same car.
Sophomore in high
school, Paul Waxman,
had absolutely no
idea what he was doing.
Mm.
Junior prom, Sarah
Richardson and Penny Caraway,
together.
I knew exactly what I was doing.
19.
- 19?
- Mm-hmm. I was very
focused on my studies.
It was my Chem T.A. He was
a whole head shorter than me,
but... man, he was smart.
Hey, April.
I'm not talking about this. It
was a private... private memory.
What happened, did the guy die?
- Alex.
- Oh, did it last,
like, three seconds,
- so you don't know if it counted?
- - No.
Mm-hmm.
Uh...
It was on the beach at
sunset. It was beautiful.
Sunset?
- Yeah.
- Really? Weren't
there people there?
Oh, on the beach? Man,
you get sand up in places
- you don't want to get sand.
- Mosquitoes.
- Mm-hmm. Yeah.
- Ha! You're a virgin.
- No, I'm not.
- Oh, my God. You are!
She is.
- Oh, my God. Do it. Do it. Do it to her right now.
Alex, go deflower
her. Do it. Do it.
It was... it was on the
beach at sunset, OK?
OK, leave her alone.
April, the beach at
sunset is very nice.
There's a gallery upstairs.
Have a seat. You can watch.
OK, you know what, smart boy?
You can pretend like we
aren't related, but we are.
And something happened to you.
What is it that you
want from me, Amy?
OK, can you imagine for a second
that this is not all about you?
Two men in my
family have been shot,
one of them didn't
survive it, and even that
I can't talk about because I
was 5, and I barely remember it.
- Don't make this about Dad.
- We can't make it
about anything!
You won't talk about Dad.
You won't talk about this.
I'm sorry this is hard for you.
It's been hard
for a lot of people.
Now I have an operation
I have to go do. Go home.
No, I'm not going
anywhere. He's my patient.
- I'm helping you.
- I don't need help. I have an
exceedingly capable resident.
Really?
Uh, sorry I'm late. There's
a long line at the cafeteria.
You're right. Crack team.
Fine. You can stay.
Dr. Bailey, how can you tell
which is horn and
which is finger?
If there's no bleeding,
I'm still cutting off the horn.
If there's a lot of bleeding,
I'm probably
cutting off a finger.
Sometimes this job is
very simple, Dr. Avery.
Oh.
I can do that if you want.
She's fine. Right, Dr. Grey?
Right.
Ugh.
What?
Nothing.
Danny, uh, could
you wait outside
just for a couple of minutes?
- Why? Is... is everything OK? Is she...
- Oh, no.
Whatever you have to tell me,
you can say it in front of him.
OK. Um...
Gretchen, you've...
Um...
Oh, OK. Gretchen, wh...
Uh, what... what
happened is, um...
The blockage in your lung
was a condom.
Apparently, you inhaled it.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
So the good news is
that we've removed it,
and you should be
feeling much better.
- What?
- Danny, Danny...
Wait a minute. I've...
I've... I've waited two years,
- and you been having sex
with someone else?
- No, no, no, no.
Plenty of people use
condoms to protect against
sexually transmitted
diseases when they're doing...
other sorts of things.
We don't.
Danny, please!
Danny, don't! Danny.
OK, you see how I'm
removing the tumor gently?
Not really.
OK, irrigate and suction.
Good. Good. OK. Can you see now?
Yeah, I can.
OK. You should be able
to see a little bit better now,
because I'm gonna be doing...
Oh, damn it. Oh, no.
It's bleeding too much.
- The carotid?
- Could be. OK. Backing out now.
OK, Dr. Yang, I need you to do
- some nasal packing, please.
- Uh, no. Um, um, you can do it.
- It doesn't have to be pretty. Just pack it in there.
- No, I-I can't.
- Yes, you can. Just do it.
- No, stop, stop. Please
stop it. I just...
You do it.
Pass me gelfoam and thrombin.
Give me suction.
All right. We're gonna
have to open him up.
What happened to you, Karev?
Uh, patient wasn't
critical, so I took the stairs.
Y-you do that all day?
Yeah. It's good exercise.
What's the big deal?
Well, the big deal is,
you're... you're sweaty
and you... and you smell.
And you're not
going into my O.R.
- What the hell's
the matter with you today?
- Nothing, I-I...
Karev, you stink.
Now go take a shower.
Oh.
- What?
- I thought I had
some normal skin here,
- but it's already starting
to grow warts.
- What does that mean?
It means, Jerry's not
going to get his skin grafts
anytime soon.
He's gonna have a
lot of open wounds.
So he was right.
He is gonna look
like Frankenstein.
Maybe I should
go update the wife.
You know, prepare
her for the worst?
I mean, if... if I
were her, I would...
- I would want to know
sooner than later.
- You're not going anywhere.
Which is fine, because
I'm... I'm fine right here.
I'm... I'm just saying, if... if,
you know, if I were the wife,
I'd want to know
sooner than later.
Later it is, then.
I need my mother's
engagement ring back.
Can I have it, please?
Danny, please don't do this, OK?
- If I could just...
- She didn't cheat on you.
- Yeah?
- She didn't.
She told us she has a
friend named Jeanette
who threw her a
bachelorette party.
- Yeah.
- Sometimes
at bachelorette parties,
there's a section of the party
known as the Tupperware segment,
only it isn't really Tupperware.
It's intimate items,
and there's someone
who shows you how
to use all of these items.
So the instructor was
instructing the attendees
in techniques for, um,
applying a certain apparatus
to something that
might s... simulate a...
She put a condom on a
banana with her mouth
and accidentally inhaled it.
Gretchen?
I choked, OK?
And I thought
that I swallowed it.
Obviously I have no
idea what I'm doing.
I just wanted you
to have a good time
on our wedding night.
And will you please
stop laughing at me?
I'm gonna love our
wedding night, OK?
No matter what,
I'm gonna love it,
because I love you.
Stop it.
You got it?
Yep.
You sure? Because I can get it.
You know, I do
this for a living.
I know. I just want to
make sure you got it.
Done. Wow.
Would you look at that? I
have impressed even myself.
So you're done. I can go?
I am done.
How did she get
past her internship?
- Shut up.
- Derek, come on. She's a dud.
She wasn't ready,
and I pushed her.
Yeah, she wasn't ready
because she's a dud.
Cristina Yang saved my life.
She saved my life.
I owe her everything.
Get out.
Get the hell out.
12 pounds.
EBay, here I come.
- Dr. Grey.
- I'm sorry.
You are doctors.
If you're going to be
doctors, caregivers,
you need to be able
to handle anything
the human body throws at you.
Oh! Oh!
Oh! Oh, God!
Look right there. A spider.
It's a spider. Oh! J... no, no.
Come on. Somebody do
something, please. It's a spider.
That?
Yes! It just crawled
right out of that horn.
- Quick, kill it! Kill it!
- I... it...
Thank you. Thank you.
Oh, thank you. Oh, thank you.
Oh, thank you. OK. OK. Whew.
Dr. Hines to Labor and Delivery.
Dr. Hines, Labor and Delivery.
I wouldn't have picked you...
to be a part of my life.
Professionally? Sure,
if you didn't think my
field was so uninteresting.
But personally?
We wouldn't have
picked each other.
But now we're family.
And that means I
worry about you.
You're flaming out.
And as someone
who cares about you,
it's not OK.
As someone who's seen a
lot of residents come and go,
but very, very few
with your potential...
it is not OK.
I can barely remember it...
the whole procedure.
I...
I took a bullet
out of your chest,
and... and all I can
remember are...
bits and pieces,
and the bits and
pieces I do remember,
uh, come back at very
inconvenient times.
So, um, end of story, OK?
Karev.
Uh, y-yes, sir.
You laid in a pool of your
own blood in that elevator
and almost died.
That's why you're
taking the stairs.
Now someday you're
gonna have a critical patient,
and you won't be able
to run up the stairs.
So... you and I...
are gonna take that elevator...
right now, together.
And you're gonna stay
on it until you're not scared.
You're just bored.
We're gonna have to
do the surgery in stages.
We may try stretching the skin.
But right now, there's not
enough normal skin to cut from,
which means
we may have to revisit
the idea of skin grafts later.
How much later?
That depends on how
much normal skin we find.
About six months to a year.
Still, in the meantime...
he's still gonna
look like a freak?
He'll look better than he did.
But there will be
substantial scarring.
So...
I'm not even gonna
get a few months
where he's gonna
look halfway normal,
where he might want to go out,
where he might want
to do something besides
wall himself up in
our house all day?
You're both just gonna
have to be patient.
You met my husband, Dr. Sloan.
You really think he can do that?
I haven't touched
him in four years...
haven't kissed him,
haven't held his hand.
He won't let me.
I love him so much, but...
I need to live a life, and
he wants to be a hermit.
And I think...
love isn't enough anymore.
Is that possible...
that two people can
really love each other,
and it just... isn't enough?
Mr. Donaldson
had a heart attack,
so his arteries won't be
quite as clean as mine,
but you'll get the basic idea.
- Now... you opened me up. Where did you make the incision?
- I don't know.
Yes, you do.
Um, when I say
that I don't know,
I'm not making it up.
I-I... literally, I
don't remember.
OK. Well, fortunately,
I have some details.
You started here
at the sternal notch
and went south 6 inches.
- OK, you know what? This is stupid.
- No, it isn't.
What's the worst that
could happen, you kill him?
Oh, ha ha, funny.
Take the scalpel.
Median...
sternotomy.
Good.
What happened next?
Don't worry. I'm
leaving the premises.
We were in the
back of the store.
Dad had just given
you two pennies,
and you always hid
them behind the counter
in this big crack
in the floorboards.
You said you were saving
them so you could buy a town.
And then the two guys came in.
We could hear them talking,
but you weren't paying
attention until Dad yelled,
and you looked up.
They had already pulled the gun,
they had already
taken the money,
and now they wanted the
watch that Mom gave him.
He wouldn't give it up.
There was a gunshot.
You... lunged forward.
I remember.
I was trying to get to him,
but... I couldn't move.
That's because I was
holding you so tight
that you couldn't budge.
I put one hand over your
mouth so you wouldn't scream
and wrapped the
other one around you
and just held on for
dear life, prayed to God
that you'd be quiet and
you wouldn't say anything.
You were so little.
I think that's what I've
always wanted all these years,
is you just to stay...
little and...
quiet and safe.
But you're not
any of those things.
You're loud and fearless,
and it scares the
crap out of me.
How am I supposed to call you up
and tell you that
I've been shot?
I can't tell you about my pain.
I don't want you to
know that pain exists.
Oh.
I can't believe that you
keep brandy in your locker.
- A patient gave it to me.
- Oh, yeah?
You sneak in and take a swig
every time you see a spider?
Every time I see a spider
crawl out of a human limb, yes.
- And it is a phobia.
- Mm-hmm.
OK? It is not... hey.
Give me back my bottle.
Oh, no, no, no, Teddy needs it.
- She's pathetic.
- That's right.
- Mm-hmm.
- You finish it,
I'll hurt you.
We're gonna live in a frat
house forever, aren't we?
Hey, no. Meredith's
is a frat house.
Our place is just that
off-campus apartment where
the burnouts go to buy pot.
Did you tell him good-bye?
I've kinda been avoiding him.
I'm afraid if I see
him, I'll start to cry,
and then he'll think I'm
some kind of crazy stalker.
Uh...
Uh, let's go buy
Bailey a real drink.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, let's go do that.
Excuse us.
- Hi.
Hey.
You gonna have dinner with me?
Maybe we should just
settle for a peck on the cheek
and a wave good-bye
and keep it simple.
Yeah, that sounds, uh,
incredibly... dissatisfying.
I like you more
than I wanted to.
And, uh...
and I knew what this was.
I don't know what my problem is.
Well, I've got a couple
of thoughts about that.
I thought I was the one person
that you weren't gonna analyze.
Well, I'm not entirely sure
it requires a professional.
I mean, either I'm
wildly attractive,
and your formidable
reason is no match for my...
incredible magnetism.
Or... you, uh,
fall for men who
aren't available...
engaged...
or only in town for a few weeks.
You're making some
lousy choices, Altman.
You deserve a little more.
Nobody chooses to be a freak.
Most people don't even
realize they're a freak
until it's way too
late to change it.
Come on. Just admit
it. You're still a virgin.
- No, I'm not.
- Hey, there's no shame in it.
- Really?
- No, there's shame.
- A lot of shame. Tell her, Mer.
- I, um...
I was gonna say something,
and then I forgot
to stop drinking.
Has anybody seen Cristina?
OK. So today only one person
looked at me like a psycho
who might run
down the hall naked,
and Dr. Bailey screamed
like a little bitch baby
over a spider,
so I'm feeling pretty good,
you know, for a crazy person.
Well, nobody gives a crap if
you're crazy. We're all crazy.
Yeah, look at April.
She's still a virgin.
Yeah, well, Mark
gives a crap, OK?
He stares at me
like I'm a menace to myself
and everyone around me.
- Wait. You're still a virgin?
- Stop. OK?
Just stop.
I'm a virgin. Yes. So what?
It's not something
I talk about, OK?
We all have things
we don't talk about.
Alex, you've been
afraid of the elevator
for, like, a month, but
I never said anything
because it's none
of my business.
And, Jackson, you wake
up every night screaming
because you have
nightmares. And, Meredith,
you don't talk about
Cristina because you're afraid
she's never gonna be
the same Cristina again.
And, Lexie... for God sake,
Mark never thought you
were a psycho. He loves you.
That's why he stares at you,
because he can't keep his
eyes off the woman he loves.
Of course, he's never
gonna say anything 'cause
he doesn't feel like he can.
Look, we all have
stuff we don't talk about.
I am a 28-year-old
virgin, mainly because
I wanted my first
time to be special,
and then I waited too
long, and partially because
I'm pretty sure guys
find me annoying.
I'm a virgin. That doesn't
make it drinks conversation.
We all have stuff
we don't talk about.
Oh, April. I'm liking
you more and more.
Thank you.
You're not on call tonight?
No. No, I'm home all night.
Good.
Come here.
How was your day?
I think...
I could be happy
being a plumber.
Mm. Mm. Mm.
- I...
- Whoa.
Mm.
- Aah!
- Whoa!
- We have to get
our own place.
- Yeah.
But no matter how much of
a freak you end up being...
chances are, there's still
someone out there for you.
Unless, of course,
they've already moved on...
So what time do you
have to be at the airport?
Not for another couple of hours.
- Mm.
Because when it comes to love...
even freaks can't wait forever.