Today's forecast, hey, mid 70s!
Unseasonably warm and
clear in the Pacific Northwest.
It's gonna be a
great day, Seattle!
He doesn't know
that. He's an idiot.
It sounds like it's a
good day to get outside.
For all he knows, it could
be the worst day of his life.
Why is that on?
Thanks, Len. Next up...
Oh, um... I wanted
to see the weather.
I have to fly today.
You've been saying
that for two weeks.
Well, only because
Link McNeil kept getting
close to getting a heart.
I really wanted to
see that through.
I can't put off Zurich anymore.
There is a staff
meeting on Monday,
and if I'm not there, it'll be
a terrible first impression,
and I'll lose control
before I start.
So, this is goodbye then?
Last night wasn't enough?
No. No.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Owen, no, no. You
made me late already.
No. Meredith made you late.
You were out drinking
till 2:00 in the morning.
Well, 'cause that
was our big goodbye.
Oh, we are not having
a big goodbye here.
I'm gonna be at
the hospital later
to check on my last conduit kid.
We have a big goodbye
here, and then I'll see you there,
and I'll feel all,
"Duh, bye, again."
No, no, no, no, no.
I got to go. I got to go.
You know how people say,
"Who knows? I could get
hit by a bus tomorrow?"
That seems pretty far-fetched...
Oh, crap. Oh, crap!
Oh, no! My phone is dead!
Until you have a friend
who got hit by a bus.
And I need a European
charger. Cristina...
Oh, no, now I have
to go to the stupid mall!
I'll see you later.
The point is,
we never know what
kind of day is coming.
How is everybody?
So, Zozo's in her
room getting dressed,
and this little guy just
pooped, so there's that.
How was your flight?
Rough, but... Mwah.
We have a place to live in DC.
We got the townhouse
in Foggy Bottom.
We got it? We close in a month.
I just need you to
sign the paperwork.
What is today? Is today
Tuesday? Today is Thursday.
Oh, good. Then
Amy's got my surgeries.
I can sleep in all day. Okay,
but first, that guy
has a foggy bottom,
and I can take a
look at these tonight.
Hey, you want to look
at the brochure again
and remind yourself
how much you love it?
Oh, it's pretty!
It's the freaking
Batmobile is what it is.
It's either this or a boat.
Everybody at the
practice has a boat.
Are you really a boat guy?
How should I know?
I never had a boat.
Ooh. Are you looking
to buy a road-penis?
It's that or a boat.
Oh, no, you don't
seem like a boat guy.
What are you here
for? My first anoplasty.
Wow. Is Lebackes grooming you?
Are you gonna be
Dr. Junior Butthole?
Oh, no! That's
what they'll call you.
I won't hear them 'cause
I'll be squealing away in this.
Congratulations,
Lil' Butthole. Thanks.
Any thought on who will fill
the three empty
seats on the board?
It's only one seat, actually.
Shepherd and Grey
will keep their seats.
They'll telecommute
from DC for meetings.
Yang says she won't have time.
I think she just
wants a clean break.
So that just leaves
her seat open.
Morning, gentlemen.
You'll be happy to know
that former bubble
boy, Braden Morris,
had his first follow-up
with his pediatrician.
He is healthy as a horse.
I have a consult,
if you'll excuse me.
You can stay. You should...
What's up?
Disappointing news, actually.
The Foundation cut our budget,
so we are unable to continue
funding your genome lab.
Oh, well, who's
gonna fund it, then?
We're shutting
it down, actually.
It's simply not producing the
results that other projects...
Did you not just
hear what I said?
I gave an immunodeficient
child deactivated HIV.
And saved him!
And almost got the
hospital sued in the process.
And almost lost your
license and landed in jail.
So is that really where
you want to plant your flag?
Yes!
And so should you!
Hey, two years ago,
I was wiping your butt
and changing your diaper,
and now you want
to do this to me?
No, no. I will not stand for it.
It's budgetary, and it's done.
Won't stand for it!
Hey, have you talked to Leah?
Oh. Yeah.
She's still on her couch, still
depressed, eating everything.
Has she said what
she's gonna do?
Won't even talk
about it. Catatonic.
What are you doing?
Just finished an aneurysm
clip with Dr. Shepherd.
Shepherd or Shepherdess?
Shepherdess.
"Shepherdess"? Really?
Sorry. It's just very confusing.
I kind of like it. Shepherdess.
Oh, well, before, it was
just "Shepherd's little sister."
Edwards, do you
like working on neuro?
Yeah. Don't ever
say that to me again.
I emailed Dr. Yang twice
about the conduit babies,
and her only response
was, "Not your problem."
I'm the head of
cardio. I'm her boss.
And the way that she
talks to me sometimes...
Look, Dr. Pierce, I...
"Maggie." "Margaret."
"Maggie" is fine.
Dr. Yang will be
coming in later today
for a final checkup
with her conduit baby
before she... And
then she's leaving?
For good? Yes.
Yes, she will be gone
by the end of the day.
Is that it?
Yes. I have a patient in pre-op.
It's that way.
I'm getting it. Mmm-hmm.
Chief, can I talk to
you? Mmm-hmm.
You are. Privately?
Do you have a minute to
go into, like, a trauma room?
Spit it out, Kepner.
I'm pregnant.
I know it's sudden
and it's soon,
and I know it
makes your life hell,
but I will work until
it falls out of me.
Kepners are built
to have babies, sir.
We've dropped
them in fields. Kepner,
I'm happy for you.
I'm thrilled.
Congratulations. Thank you.
It was earlier than we thought,
but my mom always says
that if you wait for the
perfect time to have a baby,
- then you'll just die...
- If you're
just joining us... childless.
We have breaking
news... Turn that up.
Of an enormous explosion.
It happened only minutes ago
at Seattle's Mall of the Woods.
We are getting reports
of massive fatalities.
Oh, my gosh! Explosion!
And scores of people injured.
Oh, my gosh!
Officials have not
yet determined...
Page all available
surgeons. Clear the ER.
Bring them to me. Discharge
all patients who can be.
Cancel all elective surgeries.
Admits... Get them upstairs.
I want a security
lockdown on this floor.
I want all available beds
and gurneys down here.
Call blood services. I want
all the O-neg they have.
The concern right now and
what we're all wondering is
is this an act of terrorism?
So it's chemical?
I'm not saying that.
Some patients are presenting
with blisters and rashes,
but the cause is not yet known.
This could be nothing,
but we are taking proper
decontamination precautions.
The main message
here is that we are
fully equipped to
treat the injured.
If you're coming to the hospital
to look for a loved one, if...
If you've... If you've
lost someone, then...
Please stay clear of
the emergency entrance.
Come straight to
the main entrance.
Thank you. MAN:
One more question!
Chief Hunt? Hmm.
Ray Pelletier,
Homeland Security.
There are some patients
we need to talk to.
Follow me.
Okay, take this one
to trauma four now.
Kepner, how are we?
Good. We've taken
in over 30 injured.
More on the way.
Triage areas are laid out.
Reds here, yellows here,
greens in the
hallway. And upstairs?
We've started rotating
ORs, one surgeon in each,
with steady turnover.
Okay. Talk to these men.
Help them find who
they're looking for.
And, Kepner, get a mask on.
Oh, God. Yes, sir.
Thank you. Thank you.
This way, guys.
Hi. You've reached the
phone of Dr. Cristina Yang.
I'm...
ORs one through
three are general.
We're gonna need more.
Neuro's in four,
and cardio is in five.
Who's in the cardio OR?
Pierce, the new cardio chief.
Okay, you guys, uh,
Kepner needs help
with triage downstairs.
Karev, you see
Yang this morning?
No, wasn't she with you?
Yeah, she said something
about going to the mall.
You got to be
freaking kidding me.
We don't worry until we're sure
we have something
to worry about,
but if you see her,
you let me know, okay?
Don't tell Mer! Yeah.
Your airway looks good.
This cut will need
to be stitched up.
And the blisters?
What is this? We don't know yet,
but we're running
some tests, okay?
I can't find him. I looked
all over down here.
I looked outside.
I can't find him.
Who?
Leo. My boy.
Our little boy. He was with me.
We were buying shoes when...
Marilyn, I'm gonna
give you some sedation.
Just try to breathe, okay?
What does Leo look like?
He's 10. Brown hair. It's long.
It's too long. He won't cut it.
Brown eyes. He has braces.
If he's here, we'll find him.
So, you said you're 31
weeks pregnant, Leanne?
Uh-huh. Homestretch, huh?
I'm actually
expecting a baby, too.
Is the baby gonna be all right?
We have to do
surgery on your arm,
but if your baby
goes into any distress,
we'll need to do a
C-section, okay, Leanne?
No, no, no, no, it's too
soon. She's too little.
No, your baby's
gonna be just fine.
It's not my baby. Sorry. What?
It's someone else's
baby. I'm a surrogate.
Can you please try
to let it get to term?
It's their baby.
We will do what we can.
And they're a super-nice couple,
and they trust me,
and it'll kill them,
and I really like them.
Leanne, we're gonna take care
of you now, okay? Don't worry.
One, two, three!
Let's get her to the ICU.
Turn the room over. Let's go!
Right away, Doctor.
Next!
When did you get here? As
soon as I found out. You okay?
I'm fine. You
want to switch out?
No. You want to switch out?
Derek, you want me to
take over your service,
let me take over your service.
Next patient,
please. A 26-year-old.
Left frontoparietal
subdural hematoma.
Burr hole's not gonna do this,
so what you're gonna need to do...
I'll see when I get in there.
Make a path, people!
Coming through!
I got it.
What are you doing here?
Isn't it obvious?
Actually, I came
to visit my son.
Apparently, I'm going
to be a grandmother.
Webber, we need
to open another OR.
Can you go up to six?
I'll start throwing
patients at you.
Yeah. On my way.
It's a weekday, right?
Shouldn't you be in class?
What were you doing at the mall?
Where's Nicky?
Where's my friend?
Nicky's gone, Mike.
It's just me and you.
Now, you want to talk to me?
What was in your
friend's backpack?
Mike!
His eardrums are ruptured.
He may not be able to hear you.
Okay, he's coming
with me. Get his clothes.
You can't take him anywhere.
We have to watch him.
You said he isn't
badly injured, right?
What I said was, so far, his
work-up has been negative,
but internal-blast
injuries take a while...
Okay, so, you're saying he
was likely very close to the blast.
No, what I'm saying is... Right
next to it? Was he running...
We need some help in here!
You got it, Doctor. - He's okay.
He's tachycardic.
Abdomen's rigid. We got to
get him to the OR. Right away.
Ma'am, we don't
know if this is over yet.
If he dies on your table
before I question him,
- we have nothing left.
- And if he isn't the guy,
you have a dead
civilian on your hands
whose care you obstructed.
Move! Ma'am, please!
It's "Doctor." You're
the boss out there.
I'm the boss in here.
Get out of my way.
Let's let 'em by.
I need some help here! Now!
What happened? He
was walking and talking,
and he just went down.
His airway is clear.
No breath sounds.
I can't feel a pulse.
Get a crash cart, chest
tube, and chest tray now.
How long's he been
down? Almost a minute.
Crap. Has he been sprayed down?
- No, sir.
Spray him down now! - I'm on it!
Everywhere! Get him everywhere!
That's it.
Hold it. Hold it. Stop.
Damn it.
Damn it. I need that chest tray!
Get me a chest tray now!
Got it. Here. Here.
Oh, my God.
Thank God you're here.
Of course I'm here.
Hunt said you went to the mall.
No, I didn't have time. I
was... What are we doing?
Sudden loss of vitals with
penetrating injury to the chest.
You're gonna have
to open him up.
Shouldn't you do it? No,
you're there. You got it. Go for it.
Oh, my God. What?
I was gonna go to the mall.
Diane, officials are seeking
to question these men
seen entering the mall minutes
before the explosion occurred.
Of course, the
biggest question is,
"Could there be more
attacks on the way?"
That's right. In fact, some
people are wondering
if this could be a
terrorist strategy
to send victims to the hospital
and then target
the hospital itself.
Alana, should you even be there?
I know, right? It's an
intensely dangerous situation.
What did she just say?
Turn that TV off!
No, no, I did work here,
like, two weeks ago.
No, she's okay. Let her through.
What can I do?
Yellows, reds, and
greens in the hallway.
Assess and treat what you can.
Okay, but I don't
have privileges.
I can't operate. Whatever
needs to be done, do it.
And if you see a 10-year-old
boy with brown hair,
brown eyes, and
braces, come find me.
Let's go! Let's go! Let's
go! MAN: Coming through!
Next! Him?
He's got peritonitis, probably
from a perf in the bowel.
Head CT shows a probable TBI.
I called neuro for a consult.
Okay.
Okay, oh, Bailey, DHS
wants to speak with him.
He's a possible suspect.
So, you page me when you finish.
Got it.
Transradial amputation.
Below the elbow, at least.
Why would they hit a shopping
mall? There's nothing there.
Except people. Regular people.
They want to scare us.
It's the scariest
thing we can think of.
Has that rash shown up
on any of our doctors yet?
Not yet, which is good.
It means it might
not be airborne.
The news said they might
be targeting hospitals now.
Oh, Edwards, shut
your mouth, please.
I'm just saying.
Whoa. Oh!
Oh, did her water just break?
The baby's in distress.
Late decels on the
fetal heart monitor.
We need OB down here, stat!
And page Dr. Robbins.
Tell her we might be
delivering a premie in here.
- On it.
What are you doing here? I
thought you had a big meeting.
They blew up Seattle,
Mer. I can't leave.
You should. No one has
a beef with Switzerland.
So, we're going to DC.
Um, we sign papers on
the townhouse tonight.
It's nice. It's gonna be good.
What are you doing?
I'm happy for you.
People do this.
Are you? Happy for me?
I got to go to the OR.
Alex gave a kid an
emergency thoracotomy.
Watch my finger.
I can't see out
of it. Is it gone?
No, no, it's definitely there.
It's orbital compartment
syndrome. Glove me.
Hey. Are you okay?
You have a little blood behind
your eye, and I'm gonna release that.
This is gonna sting a little.
Okay.
Now look at his finger.
Now open for me.
I'm starting to see something.
I can see.
Thank you!
Thank you so much. You got it.
Ross! I need you in the OR!
Hey! Does that kid have braces?
Hey, hey, listen. Yang, I
just got a call from UNOS.
They've been trying to reach
you. Oh, my phone is dead.
A heart's become available
that's a match for Link McNeil.
Now?
We tell them to do it
at Seattle Pres, right,
because there's no...
No, no, no, send it here.
No, I got to do it here.
Tell the McNeils to come.
Center of the crisis at
Grey Sloan Memorial.
Byron, what can you tell us?
What have you
learned at the hospital?
Right, Diane,
there's concern now
that the skin reactions on
patients we're hearing about
could possibly be
caused by radiation
from a so-called
dirty bomb. Damn it.
And the fear is it might
not be as easily treatable
as an attack from chemicals...
as we previously thought,
but the fact is...
The fact is, you don't know.
Oh, here's the Chief of Surgery.
You are lying to them now.
You are saying anthrax.
You are saying radiation.
Nobody else is.
The fact is we don't know
how bad this is, okay?
So stop wondering out
loud, report what you know,
and stop scaring
people for no reason.
What... I mean,
who let you in here?
Get out. Stop.
Turn off the camera.
Well, we seem to
have lost Byron there.
Tensions seem to
be running pretty high,
as one would expect in
such a dangerous situation.
Stay with us for
complete coverage.
We will be right back.
I'm ready. Where's the OB?
No show, but I
prepped her for them.
Decels are really frequent.
You need to get that
baby out of there now.
Well, where the hell's the OB?
The baby's down to
60 beats per minute.
All right, Avery,
you're gonna help me.
Fifty beats and sustained.
- I need a 10 blade.
Okay, hang on, sweetie.
Let's get you out of there.
She'll want a stapler.
We've isolated
the hilum. Stapler.
How are you gonna cope with it?
With what?
The boredom.
Making buttholes will
be your whole career.
How will you not stick
your head in the oven?
Screw you. I'll cry
about it on my boat.
Get a reload ready.
- Yeah, right.
You just saw a kid,
knew he had a hemothorax,
reached in, and fixed it.
You know, you're never
gonna do that again.
Saving kids with Ping-Pong balls
or making an end stoma
with an appendix. Stapler.
How did you even
know I did that?
You think I wasn't
paying attention
to you proving me wrong?
I mean, I thought
you were competent...
Well, no.
When you got here, I
thought you were an imbecile,
but you got competent,
like a decent handyman.
But eventually, I had to
accept that you were good.
Good hands, and you
think fast, act faster.
I mean, you'll never
be as good as me,
but you're very, very good.
Okay, let's get
ready for the leak test.
Irrigation? Thank you, Shane.
And you're putting all
that talent in a drawer.
So maybe you are an imbecile.
Oh, God, what a
relief. I'm still right.
Dr. Yang, did you schedule
a pediatric heart transplant
to come here today?
Oh, hey, yes. Good.
Are the McNeils here?
Why? Why would you
think that we could do...
Don't worry about it.
He's not your problem.
It is my department,
and I'll decide
what should be
sent out to other...
I'm a little busy
here, so can you just
tell me where I can
do the transplant?
I've just finished in OR three.
You can do your transplant in there.
- Great!
Can you see if Link
McNeil is here yet
and prep him for me? Thank you.
I'm gonna miss you.
Seriously, though.
Link McNeil. Today?
I just need something
to feel finished.
Shane can close for me.
Are you sure you want
him to close this kid?
I taught Shane how to close.
There won't even be a
scar, will there, Shane?
Nope. Mmm-mmm.
Suction.
Avery, I'm cutting the uterus,
so pull up on those clamps.
Got it.
Okay, now reach in here
and pull away from me.
You got to... You
got to pull harder.
Tug it, Avery!
Okay, yeah. There. There.
Ooh, ooh. Okay.
All right, I got it.
Clamp and cut the cord.
Okay. ARIZONA:
All right, you got her.
Okay. You're okay.
Okay. All right.
You're okay.
I got you.
How long till we can have him?
I have to get him to recovery
to make sure he's okay.
Doctor, I don't
think you understand
the nature of what's
happening here!
Do you want him healthy
enough to answer your questions?
Yeah.
Right.
Thank you for your time.
Wait. What just happened?
Situation's changed. He's
no longer a subject of interest.
That's all I can tell you.
But what about him?
Don't you think you
owe him an apology?
Doctor, you have a very
tough job keeping people alive.
I do, too.
Dry-cleaning fluid?
The CDC report says
that's what's causing
the patients' blisters.
There was a big dry
cleaner at the mall.
Victims were laying
in puddles of the stuff.
Prolonged skin exposure
can cause rashes.
So it wasn't a chemical
attack? It was just a bomb?
Dr. Hunt, you'll
want to see this.
And we will be bringing
you more information
as it becomes available.
We repeat now, investigators
have determined at this hour
that the Mall of the Woods blast
was caused by a
gas-main explosion.
Officials say they found
no evidence of foul play
and that fears of a terrorist
threat were unfounded.
Thank you, Jesus.
Seattle Power officials say...
Yep. Second that. The
gas main ran directly
under the mall's east end.
All right, Chief, what's next?
How does this change
what we're doing?
It changes nothing, Kepner.
There was still an explosion.
The wounded are still
wounded, and people are still lost.
Hey. I think I found
your brown-haired kid.
Ross and Karev were
taking him into surgery,
and he's just on his
way out. Oh, thank God.
I need to go tell
his parents. Go.
Dr. Hunt.
Sabine, what are you doing here?
They told us there's
a heart for Link.
Today? They told
you to come here?
I know, but Dr. Yang
told us to come right over.
You spoke to her?
You spoke to Dr. Yang?
Yes. She told us to come.
Should we go somewhere else?
I know that there's so many
people here that need help...
No, no, no, no.
Link is gonna be fine.
Everyone's gonna be fine.
Come with me. I'll
help you find her.
Dr. Hunt! We
need you here, stat!
They dug her out.
Coded twice in the field.
Penetrating trauma
to the abdomen.
Okay, we need
take her straight up.
Let's call ahead,
and let's clear an OR.
Take Mrs. McNeil.
Help her find Dr. Yang.
And, Murphy?
Thank you for coming in.
He's still intubated.
He's had his left lung removed,
but Dr. Yang says
he'll recover just fine.
That's... That's not him.
That's not our son.
Four by fours.
April, where do you
keep the four by fours?
Oh, hi. You're here. Hi.
What's wrong?
It was a shopping mall.
Didn't you hear?
It wasn't terrorists.
But that's what we thought.
We live in a world where that is
the first thought that
crosses our minds.
I don't think I can do it.
I don't think I
can raise a child
in a world where they could
die going to buy new shoes.
I remember when
I was 10 years old,
sitting in a restaurant with
my father, getting waffles.
I loved waffles.
I didn't like eggs. Still don't.
This was 1960,
in Texas, in a town so small
it probably has forgotten
its own name by now.
And I remember
some ignorant young
men telling us to leave,
dumping my father's
food in his lap,
throwing hot coffee on him.
Was I scared? Yes.
I begged him to
take me out of there.
Do you know what
he said to me? What?
"Not until after you finish
your eggs, young lady."
What did they do? What happened?
Nothing.
They went on to
bother somebody else.
He wasn't afraid, so they
didn't have any power.
April, there's always gonna be
stupid people.
There's always
gonna be accidents.
But that's not what defeats you.
It's the fear.
Now, if you had told
me on that day in 1960
that I would have the
job that I have today,
the child that I have,
I would have
laughed till I cried.
It seemed beyond impossible.
But this is the way the
world changes, sweetheart.
Good people raising
their babies right.
Now, come on. Where
are the four by fours?
We got things to do. Okay.
We got work to do!
Did more come in?
No, it's slowing down.
What are you still doing here?
What time is your flight?
I can't leave, Meredith.
They just bombed Seattle.
No, they didn't. No one did.
It was an accident. Gas main.
So, no different than
a train derailment
or a ferry-boat
crash, so you can go.
When I heard it was the mall,
you know what I thought of?
I thought about the time that
Callie and I played hookey
and we bought all the
furniture for the firehouse.
What time is your plane?
Two hours.
But Link McNeil has got a
heart, and I have to do that first.
No, the new head
of cardio can do that.
You don't have the time.
Plus, you'll have to re-scrub.
What... So there's that.
Meredith!
You have been
stalling for two weeks.
You know what? I have to...
I have to finish something here.
Nothing feels finished.
None of it feels finished.
Owen and I...
We split over something
that hasn't even happened.
And we never even split up.
And...
And you and I are not finished.
George is dead,
and Izzie is gone,
and it is supposed to
be you and me and Alex.
And now nothing is finished.
I am not finished.
You don't feel finished
because this isn't
the end for you.
There is no finish line.
There is no end point.
You just have to
go. I know. I know.
I know, and I'm...
And I keep trying to,
but I don't know
how to just do it.
You got to help me, Mer.
Dr. Yang, the donor
heart was delayed in traffic.
How long? Can't say.
Let's go.
Okay? Okay.
Derek.
Goodbye.
Any more come in?
Not for a while.
It's not fair.
Webber was wrong.
Maybe you just need to...
Really, Shane?
I hung on his
every word all year.
All of us did.
He's the greatest
teacher I have ever had,
so maybe if it were
someone else saying this,
I wouldn't believe
them, but Webber?
I got to find what I'm good at.
And I will.
You will. Good luck.
Oh, hey, hey, hey, hey,
hey, everything's okay.
What happened?
There was an explosion.
But it's over, and
you're fine, okay?
You're gonna be just fine.
The patient in
bed four is awake.
Thank you.
I would have thought, you know,
now that you're Minister
of Education or whatever
that you could tell
the stupid board...
I don't control
the budget, Bailey.
Well, did you at least
fight for me to keep my lab?
No, I did not.
Now, when it came
time this morning
to decide who
would staff the ORs,
who had the
stamina and the talent
to run patient after
patient, it was a no-brainer.
I mean, some people
belong behind a microscope,
but you don't.
You are a surgeon, Bailey.
It is what I trained you to be.
And anything else would
be a waste of your time.
And before you continue
trashing the board,
you ought to know that
Yang is leaving a seat open,
and I'm recommending you,
which the board
will agree is also
a no-brainer.
Oh.
Well, that's...
Dr. Bailey, Dr. Webber,
I just wanted to...
She doesn't have
time for long goodbyes.
She has a plane
to catch. No, Mer...
Well, you should go, then.
Yeah, don't stand
around here talking.
Go, be a surgeon. That's
what we trained you for.
Can I come with
you? Shane, not now.
I'm not kidding.
Take me to Switzerland.
I can help you.
You're in the middle
of your residency.
And my teacher is leaving,
the one I want to learn from to go
do the work I want to be a part of.
I want to be in charge of my
education, and I choose you.
You can say no,
but I will badger
you until you say yes.
Yes.
I quit.
Respectfully. And
thank you for everything.
Really.
Yes!
Want to grab anything
else on the way out?
CT machine?
What...
Thank you.
Proud of you.
Go. MEREDITH: Okay, now.
Come on. Let's
go. We have to go.
Wait. Wait. Wait here.
Cristina, we got to go!
Lap pads, more suction.
Get in there, Warren.
I know. Clamp it.
And make it pretty later.
Where's this
bleeding coming from?
Get underneath for me.
Clamp.
Good. Clamp.
Okay. That's good. Go ahead.
Let's go. Now.
Or you never will.
Wait. You already
called me a cab?
No.
Wait. Wait. Is that
for Link McNeil?
Yeah. I need to find Dr. Yang.
I'm Dr. Yang.
No! You need to find Dr. Pierce.
You can go to the nurse's
station, and they will direct you.
Meredith, no! I
can't just leave them.
Yes, you can. They
are in good hands.
Pierce is gonna do it,
and Sabine knows she's
gonna do it. She consented.
Owen is here, I am here,
and we're gonna follow
up with Link post-op, okay?
Get to the airport
as fast as you can.
Wait, Meredith. What?
What do you need, an "I
love you" or something?
I love you.
Call me when you get there.
You okay?
I just feel bad.
Did you lose someone?
No, no, I didn't
lose a single one.
That's why I feel bad,
'cause I feel so good.
This is the thing, Meredith.
This is what it feels like.
It feels like... Candy.
But with blood.
Only so much better. And Derek,
I mean, I was
still in his shadow,
but I didn't even care.
And the only thing that
would have made it better
was if his shadow was
gone, so you guys can go.
Have fun. Be happy.
What the heck?
Cristina, what are
you doing here?
I can't go.
Yes, you can!
We have to finish.
You're gonna miss your...
We have to dance it out.
That's how we finish.
What are you doing?
What, you gonna call someone
to make me leave or what...
I'm finding a song.
Okay, ready? Wait.
We'll call each other
at least twice a month,
and we'll text all the time.
You hate texting. Text me.
And don't let Owen get all dark
and twisty. Take care of him.
And Alex. Take care of Alex.
He needs to be mocked
at least once a day,
or he'll be insufferable.
Don't get on any little,
tiny planes that can crash
or stick your hand in a body
cavity that has a bomb in it
or offer your life to a gunman!
Don't do that.
Don't be a hero.
You're my person.
I need you alive.
You make me brave.
Okay.
Now we dance it out.
You love this song!
I got to go.
You stay here, okay?
Okay.
You are a gifted surgeon
with an extraordinary mind.
Don't let what he wants
eclipse what you need.
He's very dreamy.
But he is not the sun.
You are.
They're asleep.
Did you get those signed?
Meredith, you'll
talk to her tomorrow.
Knowing you guys,
you'll talk every day.
No, it's not...
I don't think I can sign this.
Sorry, I know you're wiped,
but I need to have those
on the plane by 7:00.
No, I don't...
I think I need to stay here.
Dr. Torres?
Um, the baby's parents are here,
and they were wondering
if Leanne was up to...
Yes, yes. Please, yes.
Yeah? Okay. Yeah, come in.
Hey, Leanne.
Are you okay?
Is she okay?
Do you guys love
her? Is she all right?
She's beautiful. She's perfect.
Thank you.
We're so glad you're okay.
Are you okay?
Yeah. That's just...
It's really sweet.
Yeah.
It's really amazing.
I wonder why they
wanted a surrogate.
I wonder if... I wonder
if she couldn't...
She really helped them.
She really likes them.
That's really amazing, right?
Guess what. I
delivered a baby today.
And the good news is,
if the OB doesn't show
up for ours, then I get...
Hey.
Our baby will be fine.
He'll be fine, or she will
be 'cause she'll have us.
Hey, of course she will.
You know, my mom always
says that's how the world changes.
Good people raising
their babies right.
Wait, is that...
Is that a thing?
I thought that was just my mom.
I love you.
It went perfectly.
Link's heart is responding
well, and so is he.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
My pleasure.
Now, I know from Dr. Yang
that you've heard the whole
anti-rejection spiel before...
I don't want to get too excited.
Yang's body isn't
even cold yet, but...
No, you can...
You can be excited.
You got a place on the board!
I will make policy,
not just hear it.
I will make changes.
You can keep your genome lab.
We can have a genome theme park.
And...
It's just...
What?
Webber picked me.
Ugh.
Boy, get in there
deep, deep, deep.
Oh, yeah, I got you. I got you.
Ow! What is this?
What is...
It's from Yang.
Alex, what?
It's Cristina's shares
in the hospital.
She's leaving them to me.
What?
She left me her seat on
the board. Can she do that?
I don't know.
She did.
I took the job!
And you were supposed
to be stepping back.
You said, "Take this
year and make it count.
"And I'll make sure you
can do it." And you lied!
Sorry. I lied.
It's a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity.
So, you got this thing,
and I gave up that piece.
And I found a way
to make it work
with my job, my
kids, and my research
with less help from you, and
I did it. You're not a victim.
I'm killing myself just
as much as you are.
And then you wanted more
pieces. I'm flying back and forth...
And more pieces...
twice a week...
You can't just drag
us away so I can come
live in your shadow. "Shadow"?
You have a job.
You're gonna be working
at James Madison.
Right, that's how my
father got his first job here.
They wanted my mom,
so she had to call the
university and pull some strings
and find something
for Thatcher to do.
It's called a trailing spouse.
This is not like that.
This is exactly that.
And it's not what
I signed up for.
You know what?
You're being selfish.
Well, I have to be, Derek,
because you believe
that your career is more
important than mine.
At this moment in time, it is!
No, not at this moment. Always.
You will always be
that hotshot surgeon,
and I will always be that young
intern who fell in love with you.
If that's how you see yourself,
that's your problem. I
can't do anything about that.
That is not how I see
myself. That is the issue here.
DC. You can do your surgeries,
you can do your research,
you can do the portal veins.
There is nothing you can do
here that you can't do there.
But I don't want to!
We're not just talking
about my job, Derek.
We're talking about my life.
I grew up here. I
made my family here.
I helped to rebuild
the hospital here
that has my sister's name on it,
my mother's name, my name.
I live here. My life is here.
I don't want to leave.
Whenever we think
we know the future,
even for a second,
it changes.
Dr. Pierce, rough day, huh?
Seven traumas,
two of which had
right ventricular perfs,
topped off with a
pediatric heart transplant.
Other than that,
how you settling in?
It has been the weirdest
two weeks of my life.
I don't know anyone.
No one knows me.
I haven't had one conversation
that wasn't related to work.
Well, you know me now.
No.
God, I sound like a
kid crying at camp.
No, it's not... It's not that.
It's something else.
I was adopted.
Two years ago, I
looked up my birth mom.
I had to go to the
court for the records.
She's dead now, so I
could only get her name.
But she was amazing.
She was a surgeon here.
Her name is all
over this hospital.
That's not why I took the job.
I mean, it's a little
bit why I interviewed,
but it's just so weird.
What was her name?
Your birth mother.
Ellis Grey.
Did you know her?
Sometimes the future
changes quickly and completely.
And we're left only with
the choice of what to do next.
You're asking me to
choose between this job
and my family?
I am simply saying I
am not going anywhere.
I am staying here.
We can choose
to be afraid of it.
To stand there, trembling.
Not moving.
Assuming the worst
that can happen.
Or we step forward...
Yes?
Dr. Yang?
They're all ready for you.
Into the unknown...
Let's do it.
And assume it will be brilliant.