.
- I had a daughter.
My memory of her was
my, uh, my greatest weakness.
- Well, today it seemed like
a source of real strength.
- It's nice to see you again.
- It's good to see you too.
- When I get outta rehab,
I--I'm gonna go somewhere.
Get a fresh start.
- Are you sure
Med is the best place for you,
given your history?
- You mean my addiction.
- Welcome back, Dr. Asher.
- Milena, I used to be a cop.
I guess I'll never be able
to shake it.
- Stefan's brokering
a meet tonight.
If he's not there,
my case takes a big hit.
- If Stefan spikes a fever,
anything off,
you bring him back.
- You got it.
- GSW left lower chest.
- Oh, man. Stefan.
Never should've let him go.
- It feels like you're mixed up
and you don't know
what uniform you're wearing.
♪
- Dylan, hey.
What's the status on Stefan?
- Guy got shot.
Gonna check on him now.
- If you wanna give me a ring
when you do--
Forget that.
I never should've
listened to you.
- El Rabioso got a read
on the meet and he jumped him.
- Yeah,
because I discharged him.
- This wasn't your fault.
- It sure feels like it.
- Dylan, no.
- Had I insisted
on him having surgery,
he wouldn't have been
out there.
- Guys like Stefan,
you know, sooner or later
they're either gonna get busted
or shot.
It's just part of the life.
- Yeah, well, it's not my life.
Not anymore.
- I'll be out here another 30
if you change your mind.
- Dr. Asher, good news.
Your drug test came back
negative.
You're cleared for work.
- Sounds good.
I'll be out in a minute.
- Let's plan on doing it again
next week.
We'll make it a regular thing.
- Uh, wait a second.
Ms. Goodwin said
it was just pro forma,
once a month.
- I'm sure she did.
But it's my ED, not hers.
♪
- Can't stay out
of my hospital, can you?
- I love doctors.
- Yeah, lucky you.
What happened last night?
- I don't know.
I heard shots and I felt pain.
- Uh-huh.
Chest tube output is minimal,
but steady.
What do you think?
- Could have
a retained hemothorax.
Maybe a chest CT.
- Hmm, dial it up.
- I've got
a dislocated shoulder in five.
Can you take a look?
- Sure.
Soon as I put these orders in.
- And once you do,
I think it might be better
if I take you off that case.
- What?
Did I do something wrong?
- No, no, no.
Just something about
that patient.
- What? Maggie, I'm his doctor.
- Dylan is his doctor.
- I am too.
Whatever it is, I've got this.
- We've got incoming.
You're going to Baghdad,
Dr. Scott, Dr. Taylor.
- Courtney, talk to me.
- I've got a 27-year-old male.
Gunshot wound to the shoulder.
Vitals are stable.
Police got a statement
at the scene.
- I'm Dr. Scott.
This is Dr. Taylor.
We're gonna take care
of you today.
All right, I need a CBC, BNP,
and tox screen.
On my count. One, two, three.
- Exit wound?
- Nothing.
All right, man.
Can you tell me your name?
- Hector.
What happened to you?
♪
All right,
let's get a chest X-ray
right upper arm and shoulder.
Dr. Taylor,
can you handle this?
- Got it.
- All right.
Hey.
- How's Stefan?
- Not why I'm here.
I think there's been
a retaliation shooting
against El Rabioso.
Goes by Hector.
He just rolled into the ED.
Damn.
- He just recognized Stefan,
and I'm pretty sure his buddy
got a message out.
- You think
they're bringing the war
to the hospital?
- Yeah.
I do.
♪
.
- So Tara's gotta be what?
Middle second trimester?
- All I know is she's going
to her third-trimester checkup
tomorrow.
I asked to come along,
but you know how that is.
- Our daughters.
They're an independent bunch,
right?
- Remember that '70's song,
"Hard Headed Woman"?
- Mm.
Perfect description.
- Right?
- How's your hardheaded woman?
- Anna's great.
Adorable as ever.
Constant source of anxiety.
A new boyfriend
I'm not so sure about.
- Uh-oh.
- Uh-oh is right.
- Oh, I have to go.
I'll talk to you later.
You understand I've got staff
and patients to protect?
- Of course.
But we have
two rival gang members here.
And the El Rabioso are gonna do
their best
to make sure Stefan doesn't
leave this hospital alive.
- So why can't you have
uniformed officers
standing guard?
- Because this is part
of an undercover operation
that's been in the works
for three years.
We have officers inside
both gangs
and we're only weeks away
from a major takedown.
If they see uniformed officers
or get wind
that police are watching now,
they'll go underground.
- And if this goes down,
what happens
to your undercovers?
- We try to get them out
in time.
But if they get made,
all bets are off.
We'll have
plainclothes officers
at every entrance.
We really need your help
with this, Ms. Goodwin.
- And if I don't extend it,
I imagine you'll charge me
with obstruction of justice.
- Look.
We're not so different.
I'm in the healthcare business
too.
- I don't need you
to school me.
- Ms. Goodwin,
regarding Stefan,
I think we can accommodate.
- All right.
You're the doctor.
I'm relying
on your clinical judgement.
You are not to interfere
with my staff's ability
to provide care
to our patients.
Is that understood?
- Loud and clear.
As soon as we ID him,
we'll get him out.
- See that you do.
Because if you don't,
I'm calling the 21st
and getting some uniforms
in here,
regardless
of the repercussions.
Where's Stefan?
- In CT.
Any way to move him out
of the hospital?
- Uh, not till I get
a better idea of his injuries.
-  All right.
Do what you need to do,
but give him an alias
in the system
and keep him out of the ED.
I want your people checking
hospital IDs.
- You got it.
Team lead, prepare to copy.
♪
- Hi, Hannah.
If I, uh, would've known
you were coming back,
I would've bought you
a houseplant.
I know I, uh, kinda went
radio silent on you.
Sorry about that.
- Must've been some decision,
coming back here.
I mean,
couldn't have been easy.
Given our relationship.
The last time around,
we--we got into some
pretty unhealthy patterns.
- Um, my coming back here
is not about you or us.
It's about me.
This job, this position,
it's everything
I've worked for.
It's everything I want.
- Glad to hear it.
- Look, I know
that we have history, Will.
But...
it is history.
- Dr. Halstead?
Your patient in six
says she's leaving.
Ivy Clark. 16 years old.
Had a seizure this morning.
- Thanks.
Hi, I'm Dr. Halstead.
Everything okay?
Anything I can help with?
- Everything's fine.
But this was a mistake.
- We're just going to leave.
- Okay, but, uh.
Ivy, I hear you had a seizure
this morning.
- It's over.
I'm ready to go home.
- I understand, but, you know,
we really should figure out
why this happened.
Seizures can have a lot
of different causes.
- I know why it happened.
Stage 2 glioma.
- She has brain cancer.
And it recurred
three months ago.
- I am sorry to hear that.
If her oncologist is here
at Med,
I'd be happy to give them
a call.
- She's not actually seeing
an oncologist.
She's chosen not to treat it.
- Even though stage 2 is
incurable,
there are medications
that can slow the tumor's--
- Dr. Halstead, we have
been through all of this.
So again, we're sorry.
Thank you for all your help.
♪
- What's going on?
- A teenager doesn't want
to treat her cancer.
Parents are going along
with it.
- A teenager?
Really?
- Yeah.
- I need a doctor in here!
- Get me a gurney
and 2 of Ativan.
- She doesn't want
any medicine.
- It's just to stop
the seizing, okay?
And I also need a CT scan
to make sure we're not missing
something.
Do I have you permission?
She's a minor,
so you have the authority
to make this decision.
- Okay.
♪
- Call Radiology.
Tell them we're coming up
for a head CT stat.
There you go.
♪
- CT shows a small hemothorax.
Blood must be coming
from his lung,
so it should stop soon.
I'm gonna keep an eye out
on his output
once we're back in the ED.
- Actually,
I'm taking him to the ICU.
- Why?
His blood loss is minimal.
- Uh, there's a police issue
with this guy,
so there's risk involved.
I'm taking you off the case.
- First Maggie, now you.
Listen, whatever it is,
I can handle it.
- Dr. Taylor, I'm concerned
that this might not be safe.
- Okay, but if he goes south,
you're gonna need
an extra set of hands.
I'm coming with you.
- All right.
I'll read you in.
- Morning.
Did you see that our 6:30
this evening was canceled?
- I did.
So why don't you and I
grab some dinner instead?
Come on, we've never been
on an actual date before.
- A date?
- Yeah.
- Isn't
that something adolescents do?
- Well, not exclusively.
- Crockett,
I see you all day already.
- Well,
then see me a little more.
Hey, come on. It'll be fun.
- I'm a vegetarian.
People don't find
that much fun.
- What do we got?
- Claire Stone. 32 years old.
Hemorrhaging
from her transplanted uterus.
- Transplanted?
- I got it five months ago.
Please help me.
- We're gonna try.
Brittany, call Dr. Blake,
please.
- I'm her sister, Beth.
- Okay, hang two units of PRBC
and two more of FFP
and infuse a gram of TXA.
Claire, I am Dr. Asher.
This is Dr. Marcel.
- I called her husband.
He's out of town.
- Okay.
- Here we go, guys.
Nice and easy on my count.
One, two, three.
- Okay, I need
a transvaginal ultrasound.
Hold.
- You got it.
Hang in there, Claire.
- Okay.
- All right, Claire,
scooch on down.
Put your feet in the stirrups.
Beth, you mind stepping out?
- No, I want my sister to stay.
- Okay.
How long's the bleeding been
going on?
- Every month since
the transplant,
but never this bad.
- You can stop it, right?
- I'm gonna take a look
right now.
A little pressure.
All right, any underlying
medical conditions?
- Just the scarring
in my original uterus.
They called it
Asherman's Syndrome.
- Is that acquired or genetic?
- Acquired.
- I can have kids.
- Do you know anything about
your donor?
- Just it was someone who died.
- Dr. Marcel?
- Yeah?
I'm seeing a severe thickening
of the endometrial stripe.
- Well, what does that mean?
- The lining of Claire's uterus
is too thick,
causing her
to bleed uncontrollably.
- Can you fix it?
I can't lose this uterus.
- Let's give the medicine
some time to work.
- And if it doesn't,
can you do another transplant?
- First let's send Claire
for a hysteroscopy
to get a closer look.
And then
we'll have a better idea
of what we need to do.
- Okay.
- We'll be right back, okay?
- Yes.
- Hang tight.
- Dr. Blake.
- Cadaver uterus.
- Mm.
Makes sense
she's having trouble.
A uterus from a cadaver
can be unpredictable.
It's much better to get one
from a living donor.
How bad's the bleeding?
- Yeah, pretty heavy.
- What do you think?
If she does need
a hysterectomy,
could you do another
transplant?
- Yeah, it's certainly
something to consider.
- I don't like it.
Prolonged bleeding makes her
a poor surgical candidate.
And I'm not gonna give her
another cadaveric organ.
- But she's young
and otherwise healthy.
Maybe it'd be worth
working her up
just to keep our options open.
- Uterus transplant
is elective surgery.
I'm here to save lives.
We're not doing it.
- Dr. Marcel?
- Sorry, it's not up to me.
♪
- Disappointed?
- Yeah.
- Mm.
To be honest,
I agree with Dr. Blake.
- Really?
And is that
because of the medicine
or because of your feelings
about me?
- I don't know.
Maybe a little of both.
♪
- Where's Stefan?
- Oh, he got a bed upstairs.
- Oh,
I didn't get a transfer order.
And since when does
a doctor come down
to get a patient's personal
belongings?
- It's no big deal.
Don't worry, Maggie.
Everything's fine.
- I'm sorry.
Ms. Goodwin is busy right now.
- And I'm sure she would want
to see me.
Sharon?
- Uh, it's okay.
Come on in, Maggie.
- What's going on?
- We've got a situation.
Someone might be trying to kill
one of our patients.
- Vanessa's patient.
♪
.
- Marisa?
- Where've you been?
- Personal matter.
Everything okay?
- Controlled chaos.
Same as always.
- Yeah, got it.
- Hey, uh,
how is that young woman
who had the seizure doing?
She back from Radiology yet?
- Uh, yeah.
Just came back down.
I'm on my way to talk
to her family now.
- You mind if I tag along?
- Sure.
- Family dynamics surrounding
a minor with cancer
are complicated enough already.
No less a minor
who doesn't want to be treated.
I just wouldn't mind getting
a beat on where
everybody stands, you know?
- Yeah, good idea.
Mr. and Mrs. Clark?
This is my colleague,
Dr. Charles.
- A psychiatrist?
- I understand
that you're going through
a very difficult time.
And I just wanted
to introduce myself
and let you know
that we're here to help
if you need us.
- Your daughter is sick,
and undergoing chemo seems like
the right option.
I know Ivy doesn't want that.
But she's only 16.
So I need to know
how you'd like to proceed.
- We support Ivy's decision.
- And the side effects
from the chemotherapy
and the radiation were...
horrific.
- And her doctor says
she only has a year to live.
With treatment
maybe she has one more.
And to spend it like that--
- But that's the thing.
New treatments
are constantly being approved.
And any extra time we could
give her, I mean,
could make a big difference.
- The odds of that happening
are so slim.
And she's suffered so much.
We've decided
to stand by what Ivy wants.
- No procedures.
No tests.
Only medicine for discomfort
and pain.
That's it. Nothing else.
- Okay, well.
At least, uh, looks like you're
both in agreement about this.
Yeah.
Yeah, we talked it through.
- Okay.
Well, I'll be back
to check on her soon.
- Did you bring Ivy's tea?
It's time for her to have it.
- Yeah, Ben.
I'll go make it.
Could I get some hot water?
- Course.
Just out of curiosity,
what kind of tea
is Ivy drinking?
- It's called Hoxsey tea.
It's an herbal mix Ben found
for people with cancer.
- Um, just on the other side
of that door is a tea station.
Help yourself.
- Okay, thank you.
- You've heard
of this Hoxsey tea, right?
- Yeah.
- It's a bogus folk remedy
like apricot pits
and antacid diets.
- Yeah, I think the FDA
debunked it a couple years ago.
- They're giving this snake oil
to their daughter
instead of actual medicine.
I don't know.
This could be medical neglect.
We might need to get
a court order to treat.
- I think it's probably
a little early
to force a needle
into somebody's arm.
Let me have a quick chat
with Mom first.
- All right, but I can't keep
her under observation forever.
So once she leaves,
there's no chance to treat her.
♪
- You, uh, you getting
everything you need?
- Yes, thank you.
- Good.
I know this has been
a very rough day for you guys.
How long have you been giving
Ivy that tea,
do you mind me asking?
- Oh, just since
the cancer occurred.
I know it probably
doesn't do anything,
but it makes Ben feel better.
- Just--just Ben?
And me too.
I guess.
It's the only thing
Ivy'll agree to.
It's the only thing I can do.
Do you have children?
- I have two daughters.
One of them is actually
very close to Ivy's age.
- Then maybe you understand.
I have to honor her wishes,
don't I?
It's her life, after all.
♪
- Claire, your bleeding hasn't
slowed the way we'd hoped.
- I'm afraid we're gonna have
to remove
the transplanted uterus.
- Oh, no.
- No.
You have to fix it.
- We can't.
- Then please, give me another.
- Unfortunately,
that's not possible here.
- But you do have other options
to have a child.
- I know.
Adoption.
Surrogacy.
All I ever wanted was
to carry my own baby.
Feel it inside me.
- Claire,
I'm--I'm really sorry.
I wish we could help you.
- I've had four miscarriages.
I've gone through five cycles
of IVF, please.
There are other hospitals
in Chicago.
Could you call them?
See if someone out there
will do it.
- Would it help
if I donated my uterus?
- Beth, no.
I could never--
- Claire, please.
- No.
You'll get married someday.
You'll have a family.
They'll find me another uterus.
And we'll both have kids...
and raise them together
like we always talked about.
Please,
call the other hospitals.
♪
- We still have a little time.
Run serial hemoglobin checks.
Let me know
if it gets below seven.
Claire, I'm not optimistic,
but I'll make some phone calls.
- Okay.
I know some people
at Lakeshore Memorial.
I'll make some calls too, okay?
- Okay.
♪
- I understand.
That was Dr. Scott.
They're afraid that Stefan
might still have a bleed,
so they're taking him
for an angiogram.
- Yeah, they're on the move.
- Man, you all right?
- Uh, chest is killing me.
- Push 10 of morphine.
- This'll help.
We're gonna figure this out
very soon.
- Zoom in on three.
Can you ID that man?
♪
- I got a Paco Ramirez,
a known El Rabioso.
- Any of your people nearby,
get them in there.
- Guys, I need you
in the surgery hallway now.
♪
- Uh, I forgot.
Uh, they rescheduled this
to 3:30.
We should probably take him
back to his room.
♪
- Dr. Scott.
- What's going on?
Are we good to move?
- Can you hold off
on the angiogram?
- Yeah, he's stable.
I think so.
- Then take him to PICU.
You'll be safe there.
Badge-entry only.
And wait for the all clear.
- Uh, yes, ma'am.
♪
- Sir?
Excuse me, sir?
Sir,
I really need to see your pass.
Just been assaulted by a male.
Hispanic. 5'10".
Black jacket and jeans.
Silver necklace.
Headed westbound past
the cardiac cath lab!
Stop!
We're all calm here.
♪
.
- So you know what, I, uh,
I don't think we're looking
at medical neglect here.
- Well, then we have nothing.
I gotta let her go.
- We tried.
- Dr. Halstead?
- Yeah?
- Well, Ivy's old records
just came in from East Mercy.
- Oh, thanks.
Dr. Charles?
- Yeah?
- Look at this.
Ivy's tumor.
It's not getting bigger.
It's shrinking.
- Hey, Ivy.
You want, uh, Trini to give you
some more Zofran?
- I'll be better once I'm home.
- Well, we got your CT records,
your old ones, and, um,
it seems your tumor
isn't getting bigger.
It's getting smaller.
- Smaller?
- It is shrinking.
- Oh, my God.
The tea.
- Yeah.
It's working.
- Whoa, hold on.
I wanna avoid jumping
to any conclusions.
This tea has been
widely discredited,
and none of its ingredients
have proven
to have
cancer-fighting properties.
- Well,
but it's getting smaller.
Ivy, this is great.
- Why do I keep throwing up?
- I'm not sure.
Do you have some of that tea
I can send to the lab?
See if it's causing any
of this?
- Sure,
I've got a packet right here.
- Ivy, I don't like this.
I wanna send you upstairs
for an endoscopy
to figure out what's going on.
- Ivy.
- Why's there blood?
- What's happening?
- Must be a Mallory-Weiss tear
in her esophagus
from the vomiting.
Get two units of blood
and plasma
and 10 milligrams
of Reglan now.
Ivy?
Okay, she's lost
too much blood.
We need to get her upstairs
to cauterize the vessels.
It's a simple procedure.
But if we don't get her up now,
she could die.
Do I have your consent?
- Yes.
Anything.
- Tell endoscopy we're coming
up right now.
♪
- She's gonna be okay, right?
She has to be.
- Honestly, buddy,
I don't--I don't really know.
- Okay, that tea,
she's gotta keep taking it.
It's working,
so she can't give up.
- We're gonna do everything
we possibly can.
That I can assure you.
- Somebody, help.
- Pressure's dropping.
- Okay, start norepinephrine,
hang two units of blood,
trigger the MTP.
- Pulse is thready.
- Transplant?
- I'm so sorry.
We're out of time.
We have to get you upstairs
for a hysterectomy.
Okay?
Okay, go! Go, go, go.
- Dr. Asher?
Let me donate my uterus.
- You do realize
that this procedure
is not reversible?
You would not be able
to have children of your own.
- I never wanted kids
to begin with.
I never wanted to be a mother,
but it was so important
to Claire, I couldn't tell her.
It's just not fair that I can
have kids and she can't.
Please.
- Okay, Beth, you need time
to make a decision this big.
- There is no time.
Once you remove
Claire's uterus, that's it.
Isn't it?
Unless you can
give her another.
- We don't know
if you're a match.
And I don't know if I could get
our head of transplant surgery
to agree.
- This is
my sister's only chance.
You have to try.
♪
- Hey, Pamela.
You got a sec?
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay, so they're taking
Claire up to surgery.
We have a live donor.
Will you do the transplant?
- Crockett, transplant medicine
is about saving lives
when people have
no other option.
She does.
- I don't pretend to understand
the bond between a mother
and a child, but you do.
You and Avery.
Now you have the chance
to give that experience
to someone else.
♪
Pamela.
- All right.
Fine, I'll do it.
♪
- Hey.
- Heard about your close call.
You okay?
- Yeah, uh,
I'm pretty sure they knew
I was leaving the ICU.
- El Rabioso probably has
someone on the inside.
Okay, like a girlfriend,
or a relative,
or some hospital employee
feeding them info.
- Listen.
Stefan is stable now,
but he might have a bleed.
I don't know how much longer
we can stay put.
- I hear you.
Dylan, these guys are here
to kill Stefan.
That's all that matters
to them.
And I don't wanna put you
in any more danger.
You send up flares
at the next sign of trouble,
all right?
I'll pull the plug.
- Ain't gonna happen.
All right. I'll stay in touch.
- Hey.
Jeffords said you went to bat
for us.
Thanks.
- Yeah.
What's up?
- His pressure's dropping.
- All right,
hang another unit of blood
and turn up the Levophed.
- Okay.
♪
.
- Getting ready to clamp off
the donor.
Should be to you in 15.
- Dr. Marcel, where are you
with this uterine artery?
- Getting close.
- Help us with the pressure,
Marty.
- I'm playing catch-up here.
Lot of bleeding.
- You guys okay?
- Ah, Claire's in V-fib.
- Damn it.
- Starting compressions.
- She's been coagulopathic
all day.
Gimme the paddles.
- Charging to 200.
- Clear.
- Epi, 1 milligram.
- I can handle this.
Do it, Marty. Charge to 200.
- Charged.
- Clear.
- Okay, we got sinus rhythm.
- Beth's uterus
is still connected.
We can close her up
and forget this ever happened.
- No, no, no.
Keep moving forward.
We can pull Claire through.
- This is why we don't do
elective transplants.
Plenty of other ways
to have a baby.
New gown and gloves, please.
- Well,
I guess we're proceeding.
♪
- Marisa.
Have you seen Dr. Taylor
at all?
Has she been down?
- Mm, no. Not in a while.
Sorry.
Is everything okay?
- Oh, no.
Everything's okay.
Just trying to keep tabs
on my doctors.
Well, if I see her,
I'll let her know you're
looking for her.
- Thank you.
♪
- Just got that lab analysis
of that tea.
No contaminants.
Nothing that
would cause seizures,
or this amount of nausea,
and definitely nothing
that would cause Ivy's tumor
to shrink.
- I--I had another test run
on Ivy's blood.
- Oh, my God.
- Yeah.
- But if she doesn't know,
this is assault.
So Ivy,
we got some test results back.
And we now understand
what's been going on.
Why your tumor is shrinking.
- Yeah, so your symptoms today
are consistent with your cancer
but they are also consistent
with the side effects
of chemotherapy.
- Specifically a drug called
Temodar,
which unfortunately,
can easily be obtained
over the internet.
- So what are you saying?
- Well, we believe that there
is a strong possibility
that somebody has been...
giving Ivy
an oral chemotherapeutic
without her knowledge.
- What?
What are you talking about?
Did you do this?
- Honey, no.
- Mona?
- No.
No.
- Hey, hey, Ben?
Can I just take a quick look
at your hands?
- What?
- Just indulge me.
Um, lemme look at your hands,
please.
Yeah, see, um,
the redness,
peeling on your fingertips.
You know, those look like
chemical burns to me.
And Temodar pills are caustic.
I'm just curious,
is there any chance
you could've been breaking them
up and putting them
in Ivy's tea?
- Ben.
Tell me.
- I didn't know what else
to do.
- You gave me drugs?
- You can't die, Ivy.
I love you.
You can't die.
I'm sorry.
♪
- His chest tube has stopped
putting out blood.
♪
What?
- His pressure's dropping.
- His jugular's distended.
- I thought the bullet went
through his lung,
but what if it got the apex
of his heart?
- Then that's where the bleed
was all along.
And now he's clotted off
his pericardial sac.
He's in tamponade.
- Ms. Goodwin,
we're going to the OR.
If the hospital isn't secure,
we'll need a police escort.
All right, I gotta go.
- He's in PEA.
We gotta get him to the OR now.
- No time.
We gotta drain him here.
- But we don't have
an ultrasound.
We'll be going in blind.
- We don't have a choice.
He'll need a syringe.
- Kenneth,
clear a path to OR 12.
- Copy that.
- I'm getting my people
on alert.
- All right.
Tell Dr. Latham to scrub up.
He's got a case
coming in any minute.
Thanks.
- Sats are in the 40s.
- Okay, pulling back.
♪
- Try again.
Okay, rhythm's back.
- Yeah, for now.
But the sac's
just gonna keep filling up.
We gotta move.
- Hello?
- Dr. Scott,
you're going to OR 12.
Escort's waiting
at the PICU door.
- All right. On our way.
♪
- Hey, I'm here to give you
guys a hand.
- That's Hector's friend.
- Police. Don't move!
♪
.
- Hey.
- Beth?
- Hey, Claire.
- What happened?
- We were able to perform
a transplant.
- Really?
How?
- Your sister gave you
her uterus.
- What? No, no.
- Don't be upset, Claire.
- Please, it's gonna be
all right.
- You shouldn't have done it.
Why did you do it?
- Because you deserve
to have kids.
Because you're gonna be
a great mom.
- What about you?
- I never wanted what you
wanted, Claire.
All that about us
raising our kids together,
that was your dream, not mine.
- Oh, Beth.
- Don't be sad.
I'm gonna be a great aunt.
I'm gonna spoil your kids
rotten.
♪
- Is that really necessary?
- Ben is a part of our family.
He and Ivy
have been sweethearts
since they were little kids.
- I hope you understand
that, uh, legally,
we just had no choice
and had to report this
to our hospital's
administration.
But they're just gonna
process him.
And after that
it's completely up to you
if you wanna press charges
or not.
- No, we're not gonna do that.
- I know today was agonizing.
But the chemo's working.
Ivy's having side effects,
and they are hard to manage,
but with the right dose--
- Dr. Halstead.
Our daughter is going to die.
No matter what.
- She's already partway
through the course.
Who knows what kind
of treatments will come out
if we give her the time.
- Please.
No chemo.
We're gonna take her home.
♪
It's what Ivy wants.
- We completely understand.
- Thank you for everything.
- Yeah, take care.
- Man.
Whoever said love hurts
sure knew what they were
talking about, huh?
- Yeah.
- You know what I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna go home
and hug my daughter.
You all right?
- Yeah.
I'll see you.
♪
- Come in.
- Hey.
- Look, I just wanna say
thank you
for doing the surgery.
I know you didn't want to.
Thank you.
- It's fine.
- Good night.
- Crockett?
- Yeah?
- You made an appeal to me
that I knew what it was like
to carry a baby, but...
the thing is, I didn't.
I used a surrogate.
- Oh.
♪
- I don't talk about it
because...
people make assumptions.
They judge.
We really wanted a child.
And my husband was older
and more established.
And I was just an intern
trying to get my career
off the ground.
And I had fibroids,
which would've made
the pregnancy more complicated,
so...
♪
Since we had the means...
I guess today just brought up
a lot of old feelings for me.
Maybe a little bit of regret.
- Yeah, sure.
♪
Okay.
- Hey.
- Yeah?
- You wanna get some dinner?
- Yeah, I do.
♪
- There you go, Rambo.
Okay?
Just wrap you up.
- I'll do that, Dr. Archer.
- Okay.
Yeah?
- Good night.
- Dr. Scott.
I'm told that Stefan's surgery
is going well.
- Oh, glad to hear it.
- You know, I don't know
how you got involved
with this case,
but I've got a feeling
that it wasn't a coincidence.
No need to share.
Just try not to forget
that the coat you're wearing
these days is white, not blue.
That should do it.
Good night.
- Night, Ms. Goodwin.
♪
- Dr. Asher.
- Look,
I know you weren't on board
with the surgery today, but--
- It was a difficult procedure.
But we pulled it off.
I think we can take that
as a win.
Good night.
♪
- Hey.
I, uh, I heard about your arm.
How is it?
- Uh, nothing serious.
- Yeah.
- What about things
on your end?
- All good.
We weren't compromised.
And, um...
Dylan, look, I'm--
I'm sorry for putting you
in that situation.
It, uh, wasn't what you wanted,
and it wasn't fair.
Well, just wanted
to say it in person.
I should go.
- Did you mean it?
When you said you were willing
to blow the whole operation
'cause of me?
- Yeah, I meant it.
Hey, uh, you don't have to go.
♪
Whoa, uh...
this could be dangerous.
- I'm okay with dangerous.
♪