Colleagues date all the time.
It's not a big deal.
Yeah, but it is to me.
There's no rush.
It's fun sneaking around.
I didn't know you
were a Chicago boy.
Born and raised.
Just been away a lot of years.
Must be nice, being home.
Public shaming is a way to
get companies' attention
and move them to act.
It's not our lane.
We don't get involved
with insurance.
I'm not sure that's
the kind of impact
I'm trying to make.
Whoa, heads up, coming through!
Good job, Haley,
you're doing great.
You're doing great, Haley!
Baby one is almost out!
Get ready to give me
everything you can,
and push as hard
as you can, okay?
- What do you need from me?
- Twins, four weeks early.
Neo's on their way down, but I
need eyes on baby number two.
- Got it.
- Okay, ready?
Here it comes. Give
me one big push.
There you go! There you go!
Almost out! He's out!
A quick breather.
Baby two is head
down on its way,
baby three right behind it.
- Baby three?
No, no, no, no,
twins. Not triplets.
One down, definitely two to go.
Haley, when was your
last ultrasound?
Uh, I had one my
first trimester,
another in my second,
and I was on my way to
see my doctor next week.
Well, you would have
gotten a big surprise.
- Triplets? Twins.
- Two cribs, two car seats.
I have seven
brothers and sisters.
Trust me, the more the merrier.
Okay, you ready for round two?
- Come on, baby.
- Yeah.
Okay, deep inhale.
Exhale!
Push!
- Coming through.
- Whoops. Sheesh.
Home sweet home, huh?
There he is.
Welcome back, Dean.
We missed you.
Yeah.
I appreciate the
low-key welcome.
I was a little
worried people would
make a big deal about it.
What, like with a
"congrats on the
new kidney" banner?
No.
We just delivered
surprise triplets.
Kind of stole your thunder.
My lucky day.
So look, the whole
kidney thing, dialysis,
and the house calls
and the Sean stuff.
You were a saint,
even when I tried my hardest
to push you away, so thanks.
Wow, look at you,
practicing gratitude.
- Something wrong with that?
- No, I like it.
It's just not
normally your style.
Oh, really?
Mm-hmm.
That guy's scoping you
out at six o'clock.
Wyatt from pharma.
Talked a few times.
Seems like a nice guy.
Those weren't his babies
you delivered, were they?
- Hey.
There he is. Welcome back, Dean.
What do we got, LJ?
High-speed motor vehicle crash.
Car hit some black ice,
skidded off the road.
Victim's Mark May, GCS
8, and hypotensive.
Gave him a unit of whole
blood on the flight.
Okay. Here we go.
Thanks, guys. We
got it from here.
Got a rail coming down.
- You want to hop on the chest?
- Yeah, you got it.
Hello, hello.
BP 102/96.
Breath sounds bilaterally.
Crockett, it's almost showtime.
- Got to make a decision.
- Thought we made it.
You host, I handle the menu.
- Oh, Lord.
- Pelvis feels loose.
- Ultrasound coming in.
- Mm-hmm.
I'm thinking barbecue now.
Fast looks good.
He's not bleeding
into his belly.
- He's bleeding from somewhere.
- BP just dropped 95/60.
Hang another unit of
blood and trigger the MTP.
Jimmy, that's you.
Mike, let's get some X-rays.
- Chest and pelvis, please.
- Yep.
So, uh, 11th-hour menu change?
- Seriously now?
- It's the middle of winter.
T-bones and fillets just sound
better than catfish and cod.
Clear.
Good.
Resetting for pelvis.
Clear.
Chest is good, but
his pelvis is busted.
Open-book fracture,
probably bleeding into it.
All right, let's
put them in a binder
to close down the pelvis until
I can get in there and pack it.
- That's still you, Jimmy.
- Yep.
Nice and easy, guys.
I got his head.
Log roll on my count.
One, two, three.
Easy, easy, easy.
Maggie, what do you
think? Surf or turf?
Uh-uh. Don't put me
in the middle of this.
Easy on your end.
To me.
- I got his head. Go.
- You got it.
- Got it.
- Yep. Put him down.
I'll call the OR and let
them know that you're coming.
Yep.
I'm telling you.
Barbecue's the way to go.
Okay, well, we'll
figure it out later.
Dr. Archer, good morning.
I'm Zola Ahmad, your
new senior resident.
I'm not stalking you.
I just wanted to introduce
myself first thing.
Yeah?
You mean before I'm caught up
on your renegade antics
of the last few weeks?
Yeah, kind of. Too late?
Yeah, too late, too late.
Look, I may
have crossed a few lines
and stepped on a few toes, but
you know what? There is no but.
The renegade is
out of my system.
I am no longer going
to be a headache.
Well, you know what, Dr. Ahmad?
You caught me on a good day.
I'm gonna give you the
benefit of the doubt.
Tabula rasa. Clean slate.
- Mm.
- Don't dirty it up.
Look at this.
D-E-N-N-I-S. Dennis.
Okay, that's your name,
but I'm not sure where
you're going with this.
I've been Denny's, Dentist,
Ennis, everything but Dennis.
- Denny's?
- Until today.
Maybe 'cause everyone now knows
I'm the big boss's boyfriend.
You're ridiculous.
Ah, what you meant
to say is "charming."
- Mm.
- Or was it "handsome"?
Go with me here.
"Charmingly handsome."
I like that.
Sharon. What is it?
My grandson, Isaiah,
is being brought into
the ED by ambulance.
Lungs are clear.
BP's 110/76. Heart rate's 115.
- That's... that's good, right?
- He's... he's breathing okay?
His heart's fine?
Bert, let's step to the hallway.
Give the doctor
some space to work.
- It happened so fast.
- Yes, yes.
Well, we're gonna
straighten it all out.
Bert, what happened?
I fell on Isaiah.
He fell asleep.
Does that mean he's okay,
or did he just cry
himself into exhaustion?
Shh. I don't know, honey.
Let's wait and see
what the tests say.
Dr. Ripley has ordered
a skeleton survey
to check for fractures
and a rapid MRI in
case of a head injury.
And Dad just fell on him?
They were playing.
Your father's legs
got tangled up.
He couldn't really
explain the details.
How is he? Dad?
Dr. Ripley is examining him now.
Hey.
Yeah.
It's okay. It's okay, baby.
Mama's here.
It's okay.
This is the
bravest face I've got.
Yeah, I saw you checking
me out just now.
Earlier this morning too.
Hmm. Yeah, I think that
was you checking me out.
Huh.
Not the first time, I might add.
I guess we should get
dinner tonight then.
Right? Settle the whole
who's-been-checking-out-who
once and for all?
Hmm?
Yeah, that sounds fun.
I'll, um, give you my number.
Until later then.
Mm-hmm.
What was all that?
Wyatt just asked me out.
Wow, face-to-face.
That's confident.
Boyfriend material.
Mm.
- Or boy toy.
- Easy.
Let's not get carried away.
I don't know.
There's research that
shows your brain knows
the kind of
relationship it wants
as soon as you meet someone.
So what do we think
of the new resident?
- Who? Zola?
- Yeah.
I like her. She's fun.
You're not a fan?
Cautious optimism,
emphasis on cautious.
Mm. Shocker.
You didn't warm up to
me for a few months,
but look at us now.
- Bosom buddies.
- What's good, guys?
- Hey.
- Sean.
I thought you weren't supposed
to be at the valet stand
until next week.
Well, that was the plan
until this morning.
I came in to turn in my uniform.
What happened?
I got a new gig.
Recovery coach at
a rehab center.
- Oh.
- Wow.
Way to go. Proud of you, son.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks. Thanks, Dad.
It's been a long road,
but it's all beginning
to fall into place.
All right, well, I'm
gonna go give notice.
How about that?
No evidence he hit his
head or lost consciousness,
but his left knee is
swollen and loose.
X-ray's negative.
It's not a fracture.
- A ligament injury?
- That's my guess.
Ordered an MRI, techs will
be by in a bit to take him.
All right. Thank
you, Dr. Ripley.
Of course.
How's Isaiah?
Well, he's getting
X-rays and a rapid MRI.
Tara's with him.
The doctor said two-year-olds
fall all the time,
that they're built
for bumps and bruises.
But I fell on him, Sharon.
It's not the same thing.
It was an accident, Bert.
Doesn't change where
we are right now.
Any vomiting, Floyd? Diarrhea?
No, but I'm bloated
morning, noon, and night.
Nauseous most of the time too.
- Appetite?
- Zero.
I know it don't look like it,
but this spare tire's
lost a lot of tread.
How would you describe
this pain in your abdomen?
Dull, sharp?
Um, mushy?
Is that a thing?
In here, we call it
"diffuse tenderness,"
but I like your way much better.
So this mush, when did it start?
Uh, best recollection,
two, three weeks ago.
It was after visiting Memphis
but before rolling
into St. Louis.
- Oh, you're on the road.
- Where are you headed?
Eh, don't know. I'm wandering.
Uh, I lost my job
a few months ago,
and I'm just using my severance
to zigzag the US of A.
Where'd you get
this scar, Floyd?
- Prior surgery?
- A week after I was born.
It's been so long, I can barely
remember what it's called.
A misrotation?
Malrotation.
Bingo, that's it.
Yeah, came out my mama with
my insides all over the place.
Doctors had to put it
back in the right spot.
You think that's why
my gut's a mess now?
I don't think so,
but I also don't
have any theories,
so I wanna run some
tests and go from there.
CBC, CMP, LFTs, and a KUB.
Yes, Doctor.
Uh, that's a lot of initials.
And hospitals like to
charge by the letter.
Well, we'll get an
estimate on the cost
and see how much your
insurance will approve.
I'm already in my pocket
just visiting the ED.
If insurance ain't gonna pony up
for the rest of the tab,
I'm just gonna have to keep
grinning and bearing it.
Well, you came here
for help, Floyd.
That's what you're gonna get.
Thank you, Doctor.
Dr. Archer, incoming,
going to treatment six.
Jordan Moore III, 32,
got lightheaded and fell down a
flight of stairs at his office.
Initial GCS 13, now 15.
Witness said he was
out about 30 seconds.
Been lethargic
since we got here.
All right. On my count. Ready?
And one, two, three.
All right, got him.
- Take it easy with this guy.
- All right, Jordan.
I'm Dr. Archer.
This is Nurse Doris.
Do you know where you are?
Oh, man, I'm going.
All right. I'll
take that as a no.
All right.
Lungs are clear.
Okay, Jordan, you are
in the ED, Chicago Med.
You fell down some
stairs, buddy.
My dad. My dad.
We'll call him, hon.
- Okay, belly's good.
- Let's take a look at that arm.
Mm-hmm.
Jordan, I'm gonna
open your shirt, okay?
Well, damn.
Anterior dislocation
of the left shoulder,
CBC, CMP, cardiac labs.
Mike, give me the iPad.
Give me a 12-lead
EKG and a panscan.
All right, Jordan, we are
gonna start doing some...
What's happening to me now?
Please help. I don't wanna die.
All right, all right, all right.
Dr. Ahmad.
Floyd's HMO isn't gonna cover
the labs that you ordered,
so he's passing on the tests.
I expected as much.
I've never been
pleasantly surprised
by an insurance company.
Me neither, which
is why I reached out
to his primary care physician
to get him seen there.
- Oh, good call.
- His HMO should cover that 100%.
Yeah, but unfortunately,
his PCP's in Kentucky,
and their next available isn't
until the first of the month.
Insurance companies... the
only thing that they're good at
- is getting in the way.
- Amen.
But we have to work with them.
Do we, though?
Three weekends now, I've traded
drunk underage college kids
who have registered
under fake IDs,
made-up names,
made-up addresses.
Admin sends the
bills. What happens?
It bounces back, and the
hospital eats the cost.
Exactly.
So what if we register
Floyd under self-pay
with a different
name and a different
- no.
- No.
- We can't do that.
- Uh-uh.
- What am I saying?
- It's fraud.
It's called fraud.
I know. Yeah, I know.
Can you just forget I said that?
Mm-hmm. Sure.
It just sucks that all
we can do for Floyd
is make him an
appointment with his PCP.
All right. I'll sign
off on his discharge.
Hold on. Let me think
on it for a bit.
Maybe there's something
more that we can do
that won't cost Floyd
a small fortune.
Yeah, sure.
Jordan.
I'm Dr. Archer.
Yeah, I, um...
I remember.
Well, vaguely.
Thanks for bringing me back.
I thought that was the big one.
No, no, no. Your heart's fine.
Your cardiac tests were normal.
Your troponins were
a bit elevated,
so your heart was
under some stress,
but nowhere near the
level of a heart attack.
Yeah. Yeah, this time.
Next time, though.
Men in my family just
drop dead out of the blue.
Both my father and his father
died of heart attacks when they
were the same age I am now.
- No warning at all.
- Well, I'm sorry to hear that.
I certainly can
understand your concern.
But I assure you, it
was no heart attack.
Then why'd I collapse?
It's most likely from
a transient abnormal
heart rhythm.
It's not uncommon.
They're often harmless.
They're blips.
No.
This wasn't a blip.
I know what I felt.
It's the family curse,
and now it's my turn.
Damn it.
I eat
right. I don't smoke.
I don't drink. I
exercise like a maniac!
I
see a GP, a cardiologist!
I am on top of my health,
and yet here I am!
Okay, okay, okay. Breathe.
Breathe, Jordan.
Come on, breathe.
Hearts don't just skip a
beat at random in my family.
All right? They give out.
Well, on occasion, and I'm
not saying this is you,
but sometimes transient
abnormal rhythms
are caused by cardiac miswiring.
Yeah, so I can repeat
the EKG and get an echo,
and we can go from there.
I'll try anything.
I just want answers.
I'm terrified.
All right. All right.
- Hey, Marcel.
- Hey.
Hey, I'll see you guys tomorrow.
How'd surgery go for our MVC?
Smooth sailing.
Packed his pelvis, got the
bleeding under control,
embolized in angio.
Ortho has to go back
in to reduce and fixate
the pelvis, but a couple
of months, some rehab,
he'll be good to go.
Oh, that's great.
And knowing that he's on the
mend means we can settle up.
Barbecue versus Cajun fish fry.
Cajun fish feast.
I'm not an amateur.
And I'm not just a
helicopter pilot.
- Grill master extraordinaire.
- If you do say so yourself.
- So we dug in here?
- Yep. How you wanna handle it?
- Best of three?
- Uh, no.
- No, one and done.
- Let's go.
Rock paper, scissors, shoot.
And barbecue it is.
Lucky break.
Oh, please, dude,
I'm a surgeon too.
I know the first instinct
is to throw scissors.
Oh, hey, Maggie, you got a sec?
Only if you walk with me.
Look, I just received
my general surgery
credentials here at Med.
Mm-hmm.
Also applied for my trauma
surgery fellowship in July.
- Nice. Good luck.
- Thanks.
You know, in the meantime,
I'll be around
the ED more often,
so if I can ever
help out, hit me up.
Will do. Are you
flying anywhere today?
No, shift just ended.
- Treatment 7.
- Scrubs are in the locker room.
Welcome to the
team, Dr. Johnson.
Okay, no problem.
And that's scheduled
for tomorrow.
Ah, great. Caught you.
All of Isaiah's
tests were negative.
No fractures, no head injury.
Then he's not hurt?
- He's fine.
- Oh, thank goodness.
Whew.
Excuse me, Ms. Goodwin.
Dr. Washington. Thank you.
So, ladies, Wyatt
just texted me.
- Oh, no.
- Mm-mm.
Uh, that's, uh
- yeah, that's his...
- Oh!
- Penis?
- Yeah.
Yeah, no, I was expecting
"Made reservations for 7:00."
Instead, bam, full frontal.
Mm-mm.
- Your first D-pic?
- Uh, yeah.
Yeah.
Why, you've gotten one before?
- One? I'm to at least five.
- Oh, I've got...
What? Okay.
Well, then, so, what
was he thinking?
He sends this to me and
I'll just start swooning?
I think some men
are still cavemen.
Is that portrait mode?
Hmm.
Ooh. You see that?
Underneath the shaft,
next to the frenulum?
Some kind of lesion?
Syphilis?
It's hard to tell. It could be.
Disease is on the rise because
of penicillin shortages.
Flashing his junk like that?
Gotta assume that
he's sexually active.
Means he could be spreading it.
Oh, he's gotta get checked out.
Yeah.
That means that I actually
have to respond to this
and get him to
take it seriously.
What... what do I type?
Just keep it clinical.
I don't know.
I think you have to
speak his language,
make sure that he
really gets the message.
- May I?
- Mm, yeah.
Unfortunately, I'm
fluent in alpha male.
"Nice pic."
"Meet me in the ED. I want..."
"I want to see that
thing in person."
Oh. Good luck with that.
Hi. Dropping off
from Odyssey Labs.
Odyssey?
You sure you're in
the right place?
Doris, I got it.
Thank you very much.
Are you looking for
me, Maggie Lockwood?
Yes.
- Where do I sign?
- Right here.
Thank you.
Now, please get out
of here quickly.
Floyd's now got a
low-grade fever.
Says that his bloating and
nausea has gotten worse,
and there are no tests
this hospital can run
anywhere near his price range.
That's okay.
I took care of his blood work.
Lab results? How
did you get these?
I outsourced Floyd's tests
to the lab contracted to
his insurance company.
Everything's covered by his
HMO and nothing out of pocket,
leaving Med out of the loop.
Shady!
But no fraud or lying.
So?
His EOS is a little high.
- That's it? Elevated EOS?
- That could be from anything.
Simple allergy all
the way to cancer.
And the only way to narrow
it down is more tests.
A CT to start.
We're right back
where we started.
I just... I can't let him
just walk out of here.
I need to make
this right somehow.
Yeah.
You see something?
- Oh, it's bad, isn't it?
- No.
Try and keep still, Jordan.
Oh, God!
Oh, this is it.
- My chest is getting tight.
- All right, come on, Jordan.
Just deep breaths.
Deep breaths, come on.
I can't breathe!
Two of Versed.
All right, we're gonna give
you something to calm you down.
In the meantime, I want you to
breathe with me, Jordan, okay?
Four seconds in, come on.
Okay, four seconds out.
Jordan? Ah, he's coding.
- Damn it, no pulse.
- Need a hand?
All right, yeah. Bag him, okay?
Crash cart! Yeah, yeah, a V-fib.
Start compressions.
All right, charge to 200.
All right, clear.
Still no pulse.
All right, again.
200. Milligram of epi.
Clear.
No.
All right, again.
200. Milligram of epi.
Clear.
Pulse is back. ROSC.
All right, let's replay.
Ultrasound's a little fuzzy.
He was clearly
moving around a lot.
But overall, heart looks good.
Yeah, wall motion is normal.
Then why the arrest?
I'm wondering
that myself.
He still tachycardic?
Yeah, heart rate's in the 130s.
Given it just hit
190, I'll take it.
Hey, I was thinking, uh,
your patient going from
panic attack to full arrest
in the blink of
an eye could mean
there's a heart signaling
or conduction issue.
Yeah, those are at
the top of my list.
I'll run some more tests.
Uh, appreciate the help.
Yeah.
Dr. Archer?
CT's waiting for
you on line three.
Got Floyd's CT.
Wait, how?
Tech ran it off
book. We cut a deal.
What kind of a deal?
The kind that gets things
done without red tape.
No fraud, no lying, promise.
Come on, fire it up.
Calcification and inflammation
on the abdominal wall.
Seriously, nothing else?
A normal scan is a good thing.
Yeah, of course.
But just doesn't explain
any of his symptoms is all.
We've been sneaking
around all day,
and we haven't gotten anywhere.
Well...
All right, uh, I just got
a call from radiology.
Seems a CT tech
didn't close down his
window when his shift ended,
and he left up
images of a patient
who's not listed on the log.
You can't go to CT
without bloodwork first,
and yet, not one test
run through our lab...
Well, actually, that was me.
- Oh, that's wonderful.
- So what she has is catching?
Dr. Archer, I can explain.
My patient, Floyd, he's
got a really crappy HMO.
His preventative care was
literally preventing his care.
I've seen that movie before.
It doesn't have a happy ending.
Yeah, well, at this rate,
neither does your career.
You've already flamed
out of two hospitals,
and you're doing your best
to flame out of a third.
I hear you. I overstepped.
Okay, and we get it.
We won't dig the hole
any deeper, okay?
Archer.
What was that about?
What was that about? Uh
it was about Dr. Ahmad trying
to make a good first impression.
You know, I missed
everything about this place
during my recovery
except idiot residents.
And there he goes.
Goodbye, Dr. Gratitude.
All right, can we get somebody
to take this thing down, please?
I know you're still
feeling crummy, Floyd.
But all your test
results were negative,
so it makes me think
you're just fighting a bug
you picked up on the road.
Gonna just let it
run its course then.
I wish I could have
been more help.
Oh, you tried.
Confirmation with your
primary care physician.
What's another
three weeks, right?
Thanks, Doctor.
Dr. Archer looking for me?
No.
I think he's going
out of his way
to avoid both of us for now.
Sorry about today.
I shouldn't have led off
by using an outside lab
for Floyd's bloodwork.
I set a bad precedent.
It was inspiring, but
I made my own choices.
Mind If I pry?
Oh, you're wondering
why, aren't you?
I'm actually wondering who.
From the start,
you were willing to commit
insurance fraud for Floyd.
A leap like that makes me think
treating him was really
about someone else.
Shirleen Watkins.
Hmm. Is she a relative?
Not blood, but
definitely family.
I was a surprise baby.
The next closest sibling
to me was nine years older.
I was in grade school.
They were adults.
My parents were great,
but they were just old.
You know, almost 60
and working full-time.
I was alone a lot.
Shirleen was our neighbor.
She was 24, super cool.
But my junior year
of high school,
- she came down with something.
- Mm.
We thought it was just a cold.
I was already
interested in medicine,
so I told her to see a doctor.
She had just started a new job.
Insurance hadn't kicked
in, so she put it off.
By the time her
insurance was active,
the runaround was so ridiculous.
Weeks were wasted before
she was able to
make an appointment,
- and by then, it was too late.
- What was it?
Lung cancer.
Oh.
She died six weeks later.
If not for the insurance BS,
then maybe she'd
still be around.
I'm sorry, Zola.
I was 16.
It still burns.
Oh, careful.
We don't want anybody else
to get any more X-rays today.
Oh, but the tickle monster
has been unleashed,
and he loves little
boys named Michael!
That's Isaiah, Dad.
- Knock, knock.
- Hope I'm not interrupting.
Hey, Isaiah. How
you doing, buddy?
Uh, so Bert, your MRI
shows a tear in your ACL.
We got two options for
you... rest and rehab,
or surgery to reconstruct it.
But you can't do that until
the swelling goes down,
so you don't have a
decision to make now.
Okay. Thanks, Doc.
Meantime, ortho will
be down in a few
to fit you with a
knee immobilizer,
just to give you
some added stability.
Immobilizer? Is it big?
I need to be able to drive.
It's bulky, but it's
your left leg, Bert.
You use your right
with the pedals.
You'll be able to drive.
Oh, yeah. My right
leg.
Your
father, without fail,
left is right, push is pull.
Thank goodness we
have revolving doors.
Well, I got to
imagine you had enough
of the ED for one day.
I'll get the discharge
paperwork going.
Nice meeting you all.
See you later, buddy.
- Thank you, Dr. Ripley.
- Yeah.
Now, now, where were we?
Oh, yes, I remember,
tickle monster!
Psst.
Well, here I am.
All of me.
This way.
Oh.
I can't believe it.
I get to play doctor
with a real doctor.
Oh, not so fast.
The doctor will be
with you in a moment.
What?
All right.
Hi.
I'm Dr. Ripley.
I hear you have a
lesion on your penis.
Floyd!
Here you go.
He went for deep dish pizza
right after being discharged.
Shortly after, he started
vomiting and couldn't stop.
Fever jumped to 102. Abdominal
pains also got worse.
Oh, it hurts so bad right here,
and the pain started
jumping up to my shoulder.
Don't press so hard!
Sorry, Floyd. I gotta
get a good look.
His gallbladder is inflamed
with pericystic fluid.
With the fever, it could
be acute cholecystitis.
- It needs to come out.
- I'll call surgery. Brandon!
No. Page Crockett.
Likely have to be open because
of his malrotation scarring
- from when he was a baby.
- All right.
You got it, Doctor.
- I can't afford an operation.
- It's an emergency now, Floyd.
Everything's
covered by your HMO.
So your father's gonna
be out of commission
for a while with his knee.
I know some nurses who might
want a part-time nanny.
Oh, that's okay.
I actually started putting
feelers out last week.
Really?
I think that Isaiah is getting
to be too much for Dad.
Last few weeks, he's been off.
He's forgetting things
and misplacing stuff.
The last few weeks? Or forever?
I know he's quirky,
but it's getting worse.
He keeps repeating himself too.
Tara, your father has
always been a broken record.
I mean, how many times
has he told the story
about meeting Michael
Jordan in the DMV?
So you think it's
just Dad being Dad?
If the shoe fits.
You keep me in the loop
with that knee, okay?
You got it.
Love you.
Everything's fine.
Okay.
Is it syphilis?
No, actinic keratosis.
Oh, thank God.
Wait, is that still an STI?
No, it's a patch
of rough scaly skin
caused by UV exposure.
Based on the pic you sent me,
pretty clear you like
to bask in the sun.
Yeah, I guess I should
have worn sunscreen.
Should have left
it in your pants.
Well, then we wouldn't have
this great origin
story about how we met.
For real, you think that
we're gonna still date?
Yeah, it's a clean
bill of health.
Something to celebrate.
Hard pass.
I can't speak for all women,
but for me, getting blasted
with a closeup of your business
is a giant red flag.
- Oh.
- Bye, Wyatt.
Prepare for takeoff.
Seeing big brother and going in!
Difficulty in the air! Oh, no!
He's coming down
for a crash landing!
So I didn't have a heart attack.
I went into cardiac arrest.
- And they're different?
- Yes.
So a heart attack is when blood
flow to the heart is blocked
and is starved of oxygen.
Cardiac arrest is when the
heart suddenly stops beating.
Your arrest was caused by
a rare type of
arrhythmia called CPVT,
catecholaminergic polymorphic
ventricular tachycardia.
Heart starts beating so fast,
it essentially shorts out.
It's genetic.
- It's genetic?
- Yeah.
So that means my father
and grandfather had it too.
It's very likely.
It would have been easily
missed in your grandfather.
That era was the dark
ages for cardiac care.
So an autopsy, would have
looked like a heart attack.
As far as your
father is concerned,
your family history
now established...
So the family curse
is a strain of bad DNA
getting passed down?
Well, stress exacerbates
the condition,
and there's no shortage
of things to stress about
when you're in your 30s, right?
So it stands to reason
that CPVT presented itself
to you, your father,
and your grandfather
around the same age.
Is there a cure?
No, but it can be controlled
with beta blockers and an
internal defibrillator.
How long have internal
defibrillators been around?
Almost 45 years.
So if the doctors would
have figured this out,
my father could have had one.
And probably my grandfather.
Dr. Archer, if you hadn't
cared enough to keep digging,
I'm pretty sure I wouldn't
have been around much longer.
I'm very grateful.
Should have been thinking
gallbladder from the start,
especially when Floyd said that
he dropped a bunch of weight.
There was no vomiting, pain
was limited, no jaundice.
Plus, the CT didn't
see any gallstones.
Hey, hindsight's 20/20.
We're getting Floyd fixed
up. That's all that matters.
Well, if it's my
last case at Med,
at least I'll be
leaving on a high note.
Hey, Dean's no choirboy.
And he's definitely not
a fan of bureaucracy.
He gets it.
So you think all's
well that ends well?
I won't get fired?
Whatever happens,
you're a good doctor.
Appreciate that.
Gallbladder coming out.
Lat.
Abdominal wall feels
really inflamed.
Yeah, I saw that on CT,
a lot of calcification.
No, I don't think
that's the case.
Feels like something else.
Stomach is adhered to
the abdominal wall.
Scissors?
Thank you.
Ooh.
What are you seeing?
Not sure. Hemostat.
Ooh.
It looks like some
kind of bristle.
Oh, my God, I think I
know where that came from.
Nice going, distracting that
boy so he could get an IV.
The brother was a lot heavier
than you thought, though, huh?
Like an anvil.
I might have to learn
some magic tricks.
Easier on the upper body.
It's good thinking.
Check this out.
I have no clue what I'm
looking at here, man.
Oh, well, that is a nylon
bristle I just fished out
of the abdominal wall of
Zola and Maggie's patient,
Floyd, just like the
kind on barbecue brushes.
Oh, man, Floyd was in
Memphis a few weeks ago.
Shortly thereafter is
when his pain set in.
- A lot of barbecue in that town.
- Oh, yeah.
The bristle could have
fallen from a brush,
ended up in the meat, and
eroded through his stomach,
and migrated to
his abdominal wall.
Sounds about right.
Magic bristle theory? Really?
Oh, it's not as farfetched
as you would think.
Zola found a bunch
of documented cases.
One patient even died.
They found a bristle
during autopsy.
Okay. Guess we're
hosting a fish fry.
- Feast, Johnson.
- Feast.
- When is the shindig?
Saturday.
What, are you coming?
I don't know. I was
thinking about it.
Okay.
- What's up?
- Why wouldn't Maggie be there?
She's going through a divorce.
I heard everything
went well in the OR.
Your patient take a turn?
Nope.
Just hiding out, I guess.
Hmm.
The CT scan.
What'd you trade with the
tech to get him to run it?
My Ventra card.
His commute's on me for a while.
ICU lounge, 20 minutes.
I wish I could have
seen Wyatt's face
- when Mitch walked in.
- Oh, this is fascinating.
I just clicked a
link to an article
detailing how there's
still Neanderthal DNA
floating around the population.
Variants are associated
with a variety of traits:
Neurological, immunological,
and... get this
dermatological, where
they've been linked
to the development of
sun-induced keratosis.
Shut up.
- So Zola was right.
- Oh, my God.
Some guys really
are still cavemen.
That's hilarious.
And utterly depressing,
because now there's
actual science
that states that
dating is not for me.
Well, I bet the numbers are
still on your side, though.
Yeah, Google estimates
40,000 single men in
Chicago in your demographic.
So you've gotta click
with at least one of them.
Mm?
Yeah.
Maybe.
Get back to you.
- Hey.
- Hey, nice surprise.
So how was your grandson
and the ex-husband?
- Oh, they're both fine.
- Catastrophe averted.
And I'm sorry about that
deer-in-the-headlights stare
I gave you this afternoon.
It was just so much happening.
I didn't have the bandwidth
for worlds colliding.
Of course not.
It wasn't the time or the place.
And I'm the one who
should be apologizing.
Even though it's not a
shortcut to anywhere,
I sometimes cut through the
ED hoping to run into you.
And today, it was because
I wanted to be supportive,
but I really didn't know how.
You see, it's that
kind of honesty
that's gonna really
make me fall for you.
I'm done for the day.
You wanna grab dinner?
Wish I could.
I still got a few things
I gotta finish up with.
- Okay.
- But we still on for Friday?
- Oh, I can't wait.
- Aw.
Mwah.
- See you.
- All right.
Dr. Archer, I am so sorry...
I know, I know.
Yes, you're sorry.
You're sorry.
All right, you got
caught up in the moment.
It'll never happen again.
We're way past
apologies, Dr. Ahmad.
Primer for you for class.
- Class?
- Mm-hmm.
Medical ethics course.
Eight hours every
weekend for ten weeks.
I signed you up.
You start Saturday.
If I were you, I'd take notes.
So I'm not fired?
Not today.
That's something
to be grateful for.
Ma!
Tara, what are you doing here?
- Where is Isaiah?
- Michael's watching him.
I need to show
you something now.
I know you said
everything's fine with Dad,
but I was looking through
footage on the nanny cam
in Isaiah's room,
and I saw this.
Take a look.
He goes to leave the room,
but he opens the closet door.
And he's just standing there.
He doesn't know where he is.
Something's wrong with Dad.
Damn.