Radiologist, contact 53 1 7.
Amber. No.
Why not? Amber's
a stripper name.
Find me one stripper
named Amber Hartig.
Or not. Okay.
- Non-stripper names.
- Um, Desiree?
Bambi? Kandy Kane?
Max.
Maxine.
Max Hartig. It's a
cute name, isn't it?
If you’re a professional
boxer, maybe.
Can you believe we
made this little creature?
I know. It's incredible. It's the
most amazing thing we've ever done.
I almost ran the
marathon last year.
If we're lucky, you won't inherit
your daddy's sense of humor.
Hello. Say “hi" to Bear.
She hasn't even eaten
anything. Why is she spitting up?
Well, honey, we can't bug
them again. Could you...
Okay, okay.
I'm sorry. It's our first kid. We're
both a little panicky, I guess.
Well, you gotta ask the pediatrician
next time. I just deliver 'em.
- Is she spitting up?
- Yeah. Second time in an hour.
Oh. If you lived
underwater for nine months,
you'd have a lot to spit up too.
Is something wrong?
A little lethargic.
Well, we didn't
think— - She's hot.
Is she, uh...
The baby's seizing!
Get the crash cart!
- What's-What's wrong?
- Need some help in here!
Oh, God. Is she all right?
- I. V. access?
- No. Ativan.
What's going on?
The M.R.I.'s back.
And? It's what we expected.
The accident caused
serious damage.
It's amnesia.
I'm sorry.
I just can't believe it.
Enjoying our lounge, House?
Just came in to get milk for
my coffee, which you're out of.
- Flat or sparkling?
- Sparkling.
- Splat.
So, the Hartigs?
Their baby gets a fever. What,
don't tell me— the kid had a seizure.
Yep. The parents, of
course, start freaking,
and I have to deal
with that for an hour.
Like it was your fault. She
was perfect when I delivered her.
If you wanna blame someone, blame
the pediatrician. So, how is the kid now?
Bowel obstruction. She's
under observation. She'll be fine.
The pediatrician
will take all the credit.
Exhibit A: Baby Girl Hartig.
Term baby, 42 hours old.
Went into seizures six hours ago,
brought into the intensive care...
diagnosed with obstruction
of the small bowel.
I'm still amazed you're actually
in the same room with a patient.
People don't bug me
until they get teeth.
Exhibit B: Baby Boy Hausen.
Another term baby, 48 hours old.
Brought into the NICU three
hours before the Hartig baby.
Fever of unknown origin,
101 degrees, trending upwards.
Wow, that is amazing.
You hung out in the OB/GYN lounge all
morning and heard about two sick babies.
- It's—It's eerie.
- Don't touch that.
All right. We have an infection
spreading in the hospital.
These kids have totally
unrelated illnesses.
They fell sick within
four hours of each other.
They had the same delivery
rooms, maternity rooms
are neighboring, so
transmission's possible.
- They have the same symptoms.
- The Hartig girl has a bowel obstruction.
No matter how close their beds are, I'm
pretty sure kids can't share a blockage.
What does bowel
obstruction on a chart indicate?
Normally I'd say it indicates a
patient's bowel is obstructed,
but I'm pretty sure you have
some deeper truth to impart.
It means that some random
doctor of indeterminate
skill thinks that the
patient's bowel is obstructed.
- Okay, you're upset because
they threw you out of their lounge.
- Look at the X-ray.
It's a normal gas pattern. If you want, I
can get you a key to the oncology lounge.
Air in the colon.
We're getting TiVo.
If it's air, no
bowel obstruction.
Even if it is air, it could have
been there before the obstruction.
No. Something's
infected both these infants.
And you're the only one who
put this together because...
Because I'm the only one
who looked at both kids.
I want them isolated. I want
the maternity ward shut down.
Because you're better at
reading an X-ray than a radiologist.
Radiologists always
over read babies' X-rays,
especially if they're asked
to rule out a pathology.
- He read into it what he wanted.
- Which is exactly what you're doing.
You're finding a cluster because you
think it's interesting to find a cluster.
Two plain old sick
babies would bore you.
See, this is why I don't
waste money on shrinks,
'cause you give me all these
really great insights for free.
Shrink. If you would consider going
to a shrink, I would pay for it myself.
The hospital would hold a
bake sale, for God's sake.
We have an epidemic!
Two sick babies is very sad,
but it doesn't prove an epidemic.
How many do?
Get up. We're going hunting.
For what?
Wabbits.
Hi. Bye.
He's screaming. He's fine.
Good-looking baby.
Oh, sorry. Wrong
room. We'll see you later.
Twelve rooms, right? That's it?
Yep. We've definitely
checked the whole floor.
Good news. No epidemic.
Tragic, huh?
Overflow rooms, third floor.
This imaginary infection
has spread to the next floor?
We were just gonna call.
Did he get hot all of a sudden?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'll take
care of that for you.
Almost there, honey. Don't
worry. We're almost there.
Excuse me! Hi. Hi.
Intake sent you up here? Yeah,
my wife's contractions are less than...
Okay, Intake messed
up. I am very, very sorry.
Nurse Alpert will arrange
for an ambulance...
to take you to
Princeton General.
The maternity ward is temporarily
closed. We have to leave?
Yes. I am very sorry.
Why are you doing this?
You will be there
very, very soon.
Happy now? No.
But I am interested.
Three sick babies, and a
fourth showing early symptoms.
- How bad?
- Spiking fevers.
B.P.'s plummeting. They're
barely able to keep systolic up.
At this rate, they
could be dead in a day.
Where did this come from?
Two delivery rooms,
four different maternity
rooms. No common personnel
and no common equipment.
- There's got to be something in common.
- Yeah.
That would be the difference
between an epidemic and a coincidence.
I'm putting a team together.
We're gonna start swabbing.
What's she gonna swab? Every respirator,
sink, vent, drain in the entire hospital?
- That'll take months.
- Needle in a haystack.
It's worse than that, We don't even
know it's a needle we're looking for.
- Then why'd you let her go do it?
- Because the hospital is her baby,
and her baby's sick.
If she doesn't solve this
soon, her head's gonna
explode, and I don't
want to get any on me.
So let's figure out
what's in the haystack.
- Differential diagnosis, people.
- Parasite.
- It's spreading too quickly.
- Next?
- Virus?
- The kids are too sick, and the blood tests
showed no lymphocytosis.
And they're not responding
to acyclovir or ribavirin.
If it's some other virus, we'll
never find it in time anyway.
Which leads us to
bacterial infection.
It's not responding
to broad-spectrum
antibiotics, so we've
got something resistant.
- The usual suspects?
- MRSA. It's always MRSA in hospitals.
Maybe contaminated
food or water source.
Pseudomonas.
V.R.E.? "H" flu.
Okay. Those are the big ones.
Cultures will take 48 hours.
Might as well be postmortem.
We'll start them on vancomycin for the
MRSA and aztreonam to cover the rest.
Let's get M.R.I. 's, check for
abscesses or some occult infection.
I'll be in the clinic. Grab me if you find
something important... or unimportant.
We did an M.R.I.
on all the babies,
and, unfortunately,
we didn't find anything,
so we're starting them on the
strongest antibiotics that we've got,
and we're hoping that
that will take care of it.
But he's so tiny.
How sick is he?
His fever's up to 103.5, and
his blood pressure is 80 over 40.
How, um— How bad is that?
Uh...
It-It's low. The heart
needs to circulate the blood.
If it's weak, the oxygen isn't getting
to the liver, the kidneys, the brain.
Um, I have to ask you something.
Judy— No, no, Kim. Let me.
Um, I had a cold last month,
and I told the doctors about it.
Honey, this has
nothing to do with you.
Kim's right.
Your son was born healthy.
He caught the
infection after his birth.
There's no reason to think
that he caught it from you.
But you don't know. I mean,
you don't know how he got sick.
Pretty standard question— "How
sick is my child?" You couldn't answer.
I answered. You rattled
off numbers— B.P., O₂ sats.
It's not what they need
to know. What they need
to know is the future.
You got a Magic 8 ball?
No, just eight years
of medical training.
Look, I realize it's tough to
break bad news to families.
Not as tough as hearing it.
And I guess being the poor
guy dying is the toughest of all?
No.
It's easier to die than
to watch someone die.
Well, we're checking the
vents. It could be airborne.
Somebody get the sinks,
too, and underneath them.
I'll get it.
How many med students have
you got swabbing the decks?
What else are they gonna do?
It's not like they're delivering babies.
You find anything yet? Uh, yeah.
About half the antibacterial gel
dispensers are empty or broken.
That's bad, yet diagnostically
completely insignificant.
Well, if the staff can't wash their hands,
it's no wonder an infection has spread.
Hey! Tie clip! Sorry?
We have an epidemic in this hospital,
and your tie is becoming a petri dish.
Put on a tie clip or
take the damn thing off.
My joints have
been feeling all loose,
and lately I've been
feeling sick a lot.
Maybe I'm over-training.
I'm doing the marathon, like, 10 miles a
day, but I can't seem to lose any weight.
Lift up your arms.
You have a parasite.
Like a tapeworm or something?
Lie back and lift up your sweater.
You can put your arms down.
Can you do anything about
it? Only for about a month or so.
After that it becomes illegal to
remove, except in a couple states.
Illegal? But don't worry.
Many women learn to
embrace this parasite.
They name it, dress it up in tiny clothes,
arrange playdates with other parasites.
- Playdates?
- It has your eyes.
But that's impossible.
Well, I assume you
weren't getting your period.
Maybe that should
have given you an inkling.
But I'm on this birth control
implant. Yeah, I know.
I saw the scar on your
arm. And my doctor said I
might not get any periods
at all if it was working.
Mm-hmm. Interestingly enough, you also
don't get any periods if it isn't working,
which is why you were supposed
to get regular pregnancy tests.
Oh! I'm gonna send a nurse in
here to schedule your prenatal care.
You're due in about five months,
so start planning the shower.
Um, Doctor?
Please, me and my husband
wanted to have a kid soon,
but, oh, God,
like four months ago,
we had this really big fight.
He moved out. I
did something stupid.
One-night stand? Ex-boyfriend.
Well, I'll schedule
you a paternity test too.
I can't let my husband know.
Does the old boyfriend
look like your husband?
Yeah.
Then just have the
kid. He'll never know.
The most successful
marriages are based on lies.
You're off to a great start.
Well, you look cheery.
What's going on?
The Hartig and Chen-Lupino
babies, their kidneys are shutting down.
And the urine
tests show no casts.
Which means the antibiotics
are causing the kidney failure.
You're the nephrologist. Which
one did it? We'll take 'em off that one.
- Don't tell me
both vancomycin and aztreonam.
- They both can cause this.
There's no way to know
which one it is. No test.
We can't take 'em off the antibiotics
though. They'll die of the infection.
If we leave them on both the
antibiotics, they'll die of kidney failure.
So, we take our best guess then.
Which drug's causing the kidney failure?
It's like I said, it's always MRSA in
hospitals. Take them off aztreonam.
I still think it's the pseudomonas. I
vote to take them off the vancomycin.
There's no point in guessing.
Take one kid off vancomycin,
the other off aztreonam.
They have the same disease. You
want to give them different treatments?
What the hell are you doing?
- Therapeutic trial,
to find the cause of the infection.
- That's wrong.
We have four sick kids at least.
- Who knows how many more
haven't started showing symptoms yet?
- We have a duty to these two.
If these two have different reactions,
we'll know how to save the rest.
So you're condemning one of these
kids to die based on random chance?
I guess I am.
So you're going to flip a coin?
That's how you decide
which baby lives?
Can I borrow a quarter?
Do you want to get sued,
lose your license, House?
Well, generally I'd applaud that,
but my job is to protect this hospital,
so I strongly advise you to
come up with a medical rationale...
why baby "A "should get
medicine "X" and vice versa.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Hold on there,
slick. We didn't all go to law school.
Your advice is that I should
use medical reasons to make
medical decisions? Hmm,
that's not gonna be as easy.
Any medical justification. It
doesn't need to be a good one.
Well, "Hartig" sounds
Jewish, so does aztreonam,
so we'll take the Hartig
kid off vancomycin.
How's that?
- You can't experiment on babies.
- Doctors experiment all the time.
- On adults, with their consent.
- Fine. I'll get the parents' consent.
Their informed consent.
They have to know the
other kid is getting
a different treatment.
Sorry. Can't do that. It
would be unethical for one
patient to know about
another patient's treatment.
They have a right to know.
If they know, they won't consent.
That defeats the whole purpose.
That's their right.
Two more babies have
just become symptomatic.
I defer to your legal wisdom.
Which takes precedence— six dying
babies or a missing consent form?
You can't do it.
Do what you think is best.
Your daughter's kidneys
are shutting down.
Your son's kidneys are failing.
So we're going to take
her off the aztreonam.
We're taking him off vancomycin.
Uh, but what— what made
her sick in the first place?
- What do you think is causing it?
- It seems to be a germ called pseudomonas.
We think it's MRSA—
Methicillin-resistant staph aureus.
It's a very resistant form
of a very common bacteria.
We're hoping the
aztreonam will clear it up.
Vancomycin is the best treatment for
MRSA, so we're gonna keep giving it to her.
Is it gonna cure her?
Your child is very sick.
You need to know that.
This is a Hail Mary pass. It
might cure her. It might not.
So-So, that'll cure him?
We'll know in 24
hours if it's working.
What did you tell them?
I told them the truth.
They seemed relieved. Did you
tell them how sick their son is?
I explained what was going
on. Allison, their baby's dying.
If the parents weren't in tears by the time
you left, you didn't tell them the truth.
That's not how I see it. Do
you want them blindsided?
Want them coming up and saying, "My
God, my baby died. Why didn't you warn me?"
So now it's about worrying
about them yelling at us? No.
It's about getting them prepared
for the likely death of their child.
If their son dies
tomorrow, you think they'll
give a damn what I
said to them today?
It's not gonna matter.
They're not gonna
care. Nothing's gonna
be the same ever again.
Just give those poor
women a few hours of hope.
Dr. House! Oh, no.
Dr. House, this is
my husband, Charlie.
Who told you
where my office was?
Jill, come on. He obviously
doesn't want us bothering him.
Ooh, I was trying to hide it.
Look, Doctor, this is about the
mono that you said you thought I had.
The mono? Yes.
You know, shouldn't
Charlie be tested?
You know, the
test. The blood test.
Right.
Yeah, I'm sorry. I—I
sometimes forget patients.
I thought you were this idiot who
doesn't know how to use birth control.
I can't have mono. I don't
even feel sick or anything.
That's very often
the first sign.
Call my office in the morning,
and I'll schedule you for blood tests.
Thank you.
I'm not even tired. Oh.
Find anything yet?
Oh, just some baby formula being
stored under a sink with a dripping faucet.
Tap water contamination. You
thinking pseudomonas infection?
I was. I wasted a couple
of hours chasing it down.
But, of course, the formula hasn't
been anywhere near the babies.
Huh. Whatever idiot
stored them there...
All right, we'll figure it
out. Just-Just calm down.
I am calm. Let me know
when you're gonna need it.
Oh, come— I warned you.
I did that calmly.
Hey. Hi.
She any better?
Uh, her fever has been
stable the last hour.
We're not gonna make it, are we?
Sorry?
Me and Ethan.
Our next-door neighbor,
her little boy died
in a car crash,
and she and her husband split up,
like, four months after the funeral.
It's just, uh, what
always happens, right?
Uh, what happens to patients after
they leave the hospital, I don't know,
but try not to get
ahead of yourself.
Dr. Chase, activity
on the monitor.
How long? I don't
know. It just started.
Pulse? Fluid, wide open.
Do we have an
arterial line? Not yet.
Let's get a B. P.
You can't come in
here. Is my baby dying?
- Mrs. Hartig— - Is she dying?
- Ma'am, you'll have to leave.
It's not your baby.
Ventilate.
B. P. 60 over 20.
Heart rate's 180.
Start the levophed.
Still dropping.
50 over 10.
I can't hold B.P., even
with three pressors.
I'm losing pulse.
V-fib.
Shut the blinds.
Charging. Set.
Clear.
Still V-fib.
Charging. Clear.
- Charging.
- Chase.
Time of death—6:57 p.m.
The aztreonam doesn't work.
Double-cover all the other
babies with vancomycin.
I'll do it.
Cameron, tell the parents.
Tell them their child
probably saved five lives.
- But Chase should—
- Chase is busy.
You're the attending.
Make sure she does her job.
I asked you to make sure she
does her job, not do it for her.
She froze up. She felt sorry
for the parents, so she shut up.
You felt sorry for her, so you opened
your mouth. She has a problem.
She needs to deal with it. If you hadn't
bailed her out, she would have done it.
Great. Then she wouldn't
have slept for two weeks.
Maybe she should be thinking
about a different specialty.
Lab work? Research?
- Yeah, what is it?
- The Hartig baby—
she's getting sicker too.
The vancomycin
isn't working either.
Vancomycin doesn't kill
it. Aztreonam doesn't kill it.
What the hell is this?
It's a superbug. It
could be V.R.S.A.
There's only been two reported
cases ever in the United States.
One of the kids, the
Hausen baby, had a skin rash.
It could be scalded-skin
syndrome, which would
be a sign of V.R.S.A.
Then these kids are dead.
This is our fault.
Doctors overprescribing
antibiotics.
Got a cold? Take
some penicillin.
Sniffles? No problem.
Have some azithromycin.
Is that not working anymore?
Well, got your levaquin.
Antibacterial soaps
in every bathroom.
They'll be adding vancomycin
to the water supply soon.
We bred these superbugs.
They're our babies,
and they're all grown up,
and they've got body
piercings and a lot of anger.
On the other hand, maybe
antibiotics had nothing to do with it.
Did you notice how low his B. P. was
at the end, even with three pressors?
Heart damage?
Go home. There's nothing
more you can do tonight.
Baby Boy Chen-Lupino.
Time of death—6:57 p.m.,
Thursday, December 2, 2004.
This is a cross section of the
Chen-Lupino boy's myocardium.
Fibrosis,
lymphocytic infiltrates.
There was no sign of
lymphocytosis in the blood tests.
Yes, well, we all had plenty of
good reasons to think bacterial.
Nobody is scolding you.
Unfortunately, all those
clever reasons were wrong.
It is a virus
infecting their hearts.
Then we're screwed. We
can't chase down a virus.
There's a thousand possibilities.
We could run gels, antibody tests.
A thousand of them? The
kids don't have enough blood.
Chase, you're the
intensivist. How many could
we do before we risk
exsanguinating the kids?
You're talking vials, not stick tests?
I wouldn't take more than five or six.
Okay, so we have to narrow
the thousand viruses down to six.
Now, the autopsy's shown
us what the virus does.
So, let's go. What do we know?
That ribavirin and
acyclovir don't knock it out.
- Cross out the herpes viruses.
- Also adenovirus.
What else? What
else? Keep talking!
Well, i-it only
seems to hit children.
The mothers aren't sick, so— -
No toxoplasmosis, no rubella.
Cross out the entire
TORCH syndrome.
- You didn't find any lung damage?
- No.
- None of the paramyxoviridae.
- Cardiac scarring, people.
C.M.V.
Enteroviruses too, I think.
Eleven. Influenza A.
Flu A.
Yes?
And?
I'm putting R.S.V.
down as a yes.
That makes eight.
- Eight vials of blood is pushing it.
- Pushing it? Well, we love that.
Get the antibody kits,
start testing the sick kids.
All right, I'll look into whether there
are any antivirals for these eight.
Wait a second. The kids
on the floor who didn't
get sick— are any of
them still in the hospital?
They got moved to the fifth floor, but
they're probably all checked out by now.
No, the Limpert boy had a bit of
jaundice. He's checking out today.
I want to test his
blood too. Why?
Because we need all the
information we can get.
The healthy kid can
be our control group.
I'll just tell his parents he can't check
out because he has the smallpox.
Stephen Morgan, contact
Hospital Administration.
Dr. Paul to the Recovery Room.
All done. All done.
What did we get?
Well, the sick babies all
tested positive for echovirus 11.
Great. And C.M.V.,
and parvovirus B-19.
- Three viruses?
- But what's weirder,
the healthy kid we tested,
he's positive for echovirus 1 1
and C. M. V. antibodies as well.
They're infants.
They have their mother's
blood, their mother's antibodies.
So we've just learned
nothing? Uh-uh.
We have half the picture.
The healthy kids survived
because their mothers'
antibodies saved them.
If the mom had C.M.V.
in the past, she'd have the
antibodies for C.M.V. The
kid would be immune from it.
So, we test the sick kids' moms
for echovirus, C.M.V. and parvovirus.
And whichever they
don't have the antibodies
for, that's what's
killing their kids.
I'll test the mothers.
Dr. Kent's office, one.
Echovirus 1 1.
It's an enterovirus. It
lodges in the intestinal tract.
Enteroviruses cause diarrhea and
flu-like symptoms in adults, maybe a rash,
but for newborns,
it can be deadly.
It's damaging her heart.
Well, is there
anything you can do?
Viruses are more difficult to
treat than bacterial infections.
We still haven't found a
cure for the common cold.
So, you mean
there's no vaccine or...
There's a company in
Pennsylvania developing an antiviral.
It got positive results
in a lab setting.
We managed to
get our hands on it.
Imagine not being able
to touch your own baby.
Can I get your guys' help
with something? Sure.
Your daughter, her— Maxine.
That's her name— Maxine.
We need someone to hold Maxine up off
the bed while the nurse changes her sheet.
Sure. Okay.
Shh, shh, shh.
Look at you. Hi.
Hold still.
That's it.
Hi. Easy. Shh.
There you go.
Hey, Foreman.
Got a minute?
So, pulmonary resistance has stabilized
for the two kids, but, uh, B.P.'s still...
No news then. How's Cameron?
Dr. Cameron? Sure.
Let's start with her and then move
on to all the other Camerons we know.
I'm sorry. I'm just not used to you
asking about someone's well-being.
I can understand how the
question would surprise you.
I don't quite get how
it would confuse you.
Why do you wanna know? Why do
you wanna know why I want to know?
Just curious. Me too.
You don't get curious.
I'm the most curious man in
the world. Not about trivialities.
Well, then this
must not be trivial.
How is Cameron
handling everything?
Just fine.
Great. Glad we talked.
Your husband is definitely
the source of your mono.
Oh. Wow!
Oh, thank God.
Wow. I'm gonna be a mom.
Whoa!
Thank you so much. I gotta
get you a gift or something.
Sometimes the best gift is the
gift of never seeing you again.
Okay. All right.
But, Dr. House, you've
been so awesome.
I mean, I really
totally trust you.
Do you think you— No.
Could do the prenatal— No.
Or deliver the baby?
That would be "no."
Okay.
Wow.
Chase, take a look at this.
Oh, God. It's good news.
No. It's great.
Thank you.
Hi. She's doing great.
Hi, little girl.
Hello.
They all gone? Hartigs
are checking out right now.
You look tired. Thanks.
It's no wonder. You've had a
hard time the last couple of days.
And you haven't?
Not like you.
Anyone who's that awkward...
either has no experience
with death or too much,
and I'm pretty sure
it's not the former.
Chase told me about that idea you
had, the parents holding the baby.
Where'd you get that?
Did you lose someone?
Did you lose a baby?
You can be a real bastard.
Unfinished business?
I'm in the haystack.
Ah, because now you know
you're looking for a needle.
Right.
If I tell you to let it go, it won't
make any difference, will it?
Enteroviruses are
spread by humans.
Fecal or oral usually.
It could be respiratory
secretions though.
So Cuddy got stool samples from the
whole staff. Just wait till they come back.
That won't do it. Why not?
The shedder, whoever he is, he's so
virulent, he must have been symptomatic.
Cuddy would have
noticed him. Hmm.
And the babies didn't share
any common personnel.
- That's what's weird.
- Yeah, yeah. That's what's weird.
Transition Team to O. R. 2.
Can I help you?
You saved my life. I
just ran some tests.
Your will and determination
are what saved your life.
I know who I am
now. Yes, you do.
And I know who I am as well.
Naomi, I love you.
Hey, seriously, man. You're
not supposed to be here.
I'm performing a
delivery. You are?
A patient whose prenatal
care I've been handling.
I just took her on a
couple of minutes ago.
Of course, I'll need one of
you two guys to supervise.
When's she due? Late March.
That's five months from now.
Thank God these
chairs are comfortable.
That's some bad hat, Harry.