I've decided to not
tell Ben about the accident.
There's no benefit
to him knowing.
I don't wanna
make it any worse.
Mazel tov.
Congrats on your
big news, buddy.
I'm so happy for you guys.
I'm pretty excited.
Asking Dayton for
$10 million right after
I helped rescue him
kind of feels like
a quid pro quo.
I think you're setting
your sights too low.
I'm gonna do something
even better for Chicago Med.
The people who
need us the most never even
make it through our doors.
When did we decide
that's the way it is?
It can't be.
I'm not gonna let it.
Ms. Goodwin.
Dr. Choi, I'm on my way
to the cleaners to pick up
my dress for your wedding.
Can I walk you
to your car?
Sure. What's on
your mind?
Well, April and I have
always talked about
bringing health care
to underserved communities.
Mmm-hmm.
And as you know,
so many folks use our ED
for their primary care,
and we'd like to get
to them before they
need to do that.
And one way, we thought,
would be to have
a mobile clinic.
That's a great idea.
Yeah. I got a small
inheritance from my dad,
and April saved up
some money.
So we bought a mobile
eye clinic we're refitting
for general care.
Oh?
And this is something
you could do part-time?
Full-time.
Ms. Goodwin,
after our honeymoon,
we'd like to start going out,
treating people.
Dr. Choi, are you
giving me notice?
Yes, ma'am.
Believe me, this wasn't
an easy decision.
Is your plan to put
my ED out of business?
I'm certainly gonna try.
Good for you.
That was beautiful.
Really. So, so beautiful.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Can I ask you a question?
Have we...
Have we met?
You seem so familiar to me.
Yes. From the hospital.
I'm Liliana.
I clean your office.
Liliana.
Of course!
Oh, my God,
I'm so sorry.
No. Please, I understand.
You only see me in my uniform,
and most of the time,
you're not there
when I clean.
Still, I'm very embarrassed.
No, please!
Anyway, you, Liliana,
are a wonderful singer.
Thank you.
Absolutely wonderful.
Thank you so much.
Okay. So thank you.
Maybe I'll see you tomorrow.
At the hospital. Okay.
Good night.
We are deeply grateful
to Jack Dayton,
who has made
a most generous
gift to our hospital,
this advanced surgical suite,
which he calls O.R. 2.0.
Mr. Dayton?
Thank you, Ms. Goodwin.
O.R. 2.0 is the fruit
of years of development
by Dayton Corporation
and partners.
I've entrusted it
to this hospital
because, well, Chicago Med
has always been
on the cutting edge
of medical care,
and it has the surgeons
with the talent and skill
to put O.R. 2.0 to good use,
doctors like
Crockett Marcel here.
That's very kind, Mr. Dayton.
Thank you.
With the help of Dr. Dupre,
who headed
the beta-testing team,
I'm still learning all
the bells and whistles
here, so bear with me.
But, I can tell you
a few things.
The O.R. 2.0 platform
integrates robotics,
immersive computing,
advanced sensory detection,
artificial intelligence,
all to make
the most challenging
and complex surgeries viable.
And the radiolucent
table allows
for accurate imaging
in any modality,
including X-ray and CT.
The numerous sensors
analyze every data point,
assisting the surgeon
in approach and technique,
even on the level
of suggesting
what instrument to use.
And the surgeon wears
these gloves while operating.
The sensors assess
the surgeon's efficacy,
hand accuracy,
and risk of complications.
For instance.
Please.
Okay.
There's a 10% chance
you'll have a major laceration
of the left anterior
descending artery.
Consider another approach.
2.0, to help Dr. Marcel,
can you show him a 3-D image
of the patient's heart?
Loading.
Oh, wow.
How much you think
that setup cost?
Gotta be north of 50 mil.
Surgery on a whole
other level.
Pretty soon, they won't be
needing us.
Yeah, right.
What, not impressed,
Dean?
Did you ever see
A Space Odyssey?
"I'm sorry, Dave.
Can't allow you
to do that." Right?
So what
are you, you...
You're really
doing this whole
mobile clinic thing?
Yeah. I told Ms. Goodwin
last night.
Hey, everybody, remember,
this afternoon in the
doctors' lounge,
cupcake party for Ethan
and his bride-to-be.
Mags, you don't have to...
None of that.
It's the least
we could do.
Dr. Halstead,
you and I are up.
All right.
Forty-five-year-old male,
Richard Evans.
Head laceration with
retained glass.
You're going to
treatment three.
Really, I'm fine.
You're bleeding
like crazy, babe.
Vitals are normal.
GCS 15, no LOC.
We're gonna take good care
of you, all right?
Thank you.
Okay, on my count.
One, two, three.
I was making
a vacuum chamber
out of an old bell jar.
I wanted to show the kids
how you can boil water
at room temperature.
Thank God I tried it
at home first, huh?
Richard teaches fifth grade.
I hooked up the jar
to my compressor,
and obviously,
it was not rated for,
what, 6,000 pounds of force.
Boom! Ow!
The jar imploded.
So stupid on my part.
Hold this for me, would you?
Yeah.
Well, it doesn't look
too serious.
A few stitches ought
to fix you right up.
We'll get a head CT just
to make sure.
Thank you.
Prep and drape, and get me
a lac tray, please.
Right,
Mr. Evans has an extensive
chart at Med.
Okay, thanks.
Yes, he does.
Richard, you've,
been diagnosed
with pancreatic cancer.
Yeah.
My surgeons
and the tumor board
ruled it inoperable.
And the tumor is inside
the pancreas
and has invaded the duodenum
and surrounding tissues.
There's no way to get it all.
They're just gonna
let him die.
Honey.
He's just such
a wonderful person.
His students love him.
I love him.
It's just not right.
I'm so sorry.
Thank you.
Page me when Mr. Evans
is prepped.
Will do.
Good morning.
I'm Dr. Archer.
Mr. Michaels, 65.
Took a spill coming
down the stairs.
He really
hurt himself.
He tore his pants,
and his hands
are all scraped up.
Mr. Michaels is complaining
of pain in his ankle
and right wrist.
Who's gonna
rake the leaves?
I will, Dad.
This is the second time
he's fallen in a week.
I gave him Toradol,
15 milligram.
IV for his pain.
There are his X-rays.
Doesn't look like
he fractured anything.
I agree.
What did you recommend?
Rest, ice, compression,
and elevation.
Very good.
Who's gonna rake the leaves?
I told you, Dad. I will.
Dr. Archer,
can I speak with you?
Yes, of course.
This is just like my mom.
What do you mean?
She died of Alzheimer's.
Thank you.
Dang.
Whole new O.R. suite?
That's quite a gift.
Yeah.
No strings?
Well, not that
I can see so far.
I mean,
that is really some...
Daniel?
You remember that piano
bar I was telling you about,
with the amateur night?
I actually finally...
I went last night.
Really?
This one lady, she got up and
she sang this song in Polish.
It was so beautiful.
No kidding.
Yeah.
And you know what
the crazy thing is?
She works here, at Med.
Get out.
Yeah.
What, nurse? Doctor?
Um...
You know, it was a...
It was a short conversation.
We didn't...
Uh-oh. Uh-oh.
I got to...
I got to get to the ED.
I'll catch you later.
Your coffee.
We lost my mom,
his wife, to Alzheimer's
a year ago.
And now Dad,
with how he repeats
things, and his balance.
It's just the way
it happened
with her.
I'm gonna
lose him, too.
Has he been evaluated?
No, I guess I haven't
wanted to know.
I completely
understand that.
How long were your mom
and dad married for?
Oh, gosh.
Right out of high school.
Almost 50 years.
Well, then, that's gonna be
a huge loss for him, right?
Yeah. It was terrible.
You know, I've never
seen him like that.
You know,
it's entirely possible
that he's still grieving.
You know,
he could be suffering
from depression,
not necessarily Alzheimer's,
and there are other
possibilities too.
I mean, I'm happy
to have a chat with him
and see if I can get
a better sense
what's going on.
Yes, please.
Go, go, go, go,
go, go, go, go.
Good.
Very nice.
This rate, we might be able
to send you home in a week.
Hey, how about that?
Yeah.
You getting out of bed?
Moving a couple
of times a day?
Uh-huh.
Good. Yeah.
Okay. Hey, keep working.
Excuse me, Jack.
Inoperable pancreatic cancer.
Inoperable.
Was inoperable.
But not with that new O.R.
Oh, come on. No.
The image guidance?
Real-time histology?
You could resect
the whole tumor.
No way.
I'm still getting used
to the technology.
You expect me to dive in
on a surgery like this?
I think it's
a great idea.
It's the perfect way to
demonstrate what
O.R. 2.0 can do.
Not if the man dies
on the table.
Guys, I need some time
to familiarize myself
with the platform.
There isn't any.
He's already got
lymph involvement.
We wait any longer,
he dies anyways.
You can do this.
Besides the guidance
you get from the Al,
Dr. Dupre will be
there to assist you.
She knows the system
inside and out.
Crockett, this man
has zero options.
Let's give him this one.
Spontaneous hemorrhage,
lower left leg.
Applied tourniquet
in the field to control
the bleed.
BP 90/32 after
500 milliliters fluids.
Heart rate 120.
Maggie.
All right, on my count.
Ready, one, two, three.
All right, let's get two units
whole blood in him.
On it.
He was in an accident
a week ago.
He had a tibial
pseudoaneurysm,
but it stopped bleeding.
Loosen the tourniquet.
Okay.
It ruptured.
All right, call the O.R.
Let them know
we're coming up.
Yeah.
All right.
Now, I have to emphasize,
this is an experimental,
high-risk surgery.
This is the first time
the platform is being
used on a patient.
If this
doesn't go well,
which is likely,
Richard will be robbed
of whatever time
he has left.
That's true, Richard.
You'd be taking a big risk.
And if I don't?
What do I have
to look forward to?
I get weaker and weaker,
more pain,
debilitation, until
I'm confined to a bed
with a morphine drip?
No.
I don't want that.
I don't want to put Vicky
through that.
It is not
about me, Richard.
Dr. Marcel, all my life,
I have been a science geek.
And here you are, offering me
the chance to be a part of
something groundbreaking,
that science has
made possible.
It's like being given
the chance to be the
first person on the moon.
And even if the worst
happens to me...
Hopefully you'll learn
something from it.
That's how science works,
isn't it?
Well, then, we just need
your signature on
this consent form.
You're a courageous
man, Richard.
No.
I'm gonna be asleep.
You're the courageous one.
Yeah.
That a picture of your wife?
Sarah.
We were in Maine.
Beautiful woman.
Jessica was telling me that
she passed about a year ago?
Yes. She's gone.
Sorry about that.
We went to school together.
Knew each other
a long time, huh?
Yeah. Yeah.
There was this tree
on her front lawn
that we used to go
and sit under and do
all our homework.
She was a lot better
at math than I was.
You know, I have
a daughter too.
I think about Jessica's age.
What year was she born?
Um...
1985?
Okay.
And then, how old
would that make her?
Uh...
Let me think, now.
'85 to...
You know what,
it's not important.
Look, I can't remember
what I had for breakfast.
You know, and my daughter,
she's actually always
giving me these, like,
memory quizzes, you know?
The other day she was,
"Hey, Dad, can you say
these random words
back to me in order?"
You know, like, cow,
window, umbrella.
Can you do that?
Say them back?
Yeah, in order.
Cow, window, umbrella.
Cow.
Um...
Umbrella.
Not easy, right?
No.
Ethan, April just brought
in her father.
Treatment five.
Her father? What?
Chest pains.
He insists that
you treat him.
It's crazy, right?
The day before
your wedding.
Ethan.
Hey.
Thanks God.
Marcia, hi.
What's going on?
Chest pains?
When did they start?
It's no big deal.
I saw him wince,
rub his chest.
He didn't want to tell me
what it was. I had to
pull it out of him.
They come and go.
I mean, so much trouble
for nothing.
Papai, chest pains
are not nothing, okay?
He wouldn't even let me
call an ambulance,
but I gave him some aspirin
on the way over.
Good.
He never complains.
He went a year
with that hernia.
Well, your heart
and chest sound good,
but April was right
about your chest pains.
We're gonna have to
give you a full workup.
Yeah.
Really?
Yes, really.
Let's start with an EKG.
Yeah.
Ethan, can I talk to you?
Yeah, sure.
Hey, we'll be right back,
all right?
Excuse us.
Do you think we should
postpone the wedding?
I don't know.
We might, but let's
see what the tests
show first, okay?
Okay.
Hey.
Yeah?
So your dad has
excellent recall,
going back to talking
about your mom
when they were kids.
So long-term memory
is intact.
I did notice some
short-term memory issues,
and he's having a little
difficulty concentrating.
It's just like Mom
all over again.
You know, she was such
a smart and funny person,
but eventually Alzheimer's
took everything away.
Just so you know, Jessica,
this is a cursory examination
that I gave him.
I'm not prepared to make
that diagnosis yet.
You said that what's happening
to him might be depression
because my mom died.
And it very well might be.
Yeah, and I read that
a lot of people
that have Alzheimer's
have lost a loved one,
just like my dad.
Well, that hasn't been
established as a cause.
Many Alzheimer's patients
haven't lost loved ones.
I think you want your dad
to have a full workup
with his internist, and a...
A neurologist who
specializes in dementia.
I've got a great list,
if you want a referral.
All right.
I'll get his discharge
paperwork going.
Hey.
Did you see?
You got a full house.
What?
The amphitheater.
Hey.
What's going on?
Who are all those people,
and why are they here?
Some are doctors,
some tech,
some media.
I invited them.
Why?
For the launch,
of course. 2.0.
No, no, no, no.
That surgery's hard enough
without having a bunch
of looky-loos.
Now, get rid of them.
Hey, Crockett. Relax.
They're friends, all right?
They're rooting for us.
For God's sakes, Jack.
Do you understand?
This is not a simulation.
There's a human being
on that table.
I know. And you're
gonna save his life.
And what if I don't?
What if he dies?
I'm not worried about that.
Well, you should be.
I am.
I know the tech.
I've been working on it
for years.
I promise you,
it won't let you down.
You know tech,
but you don't
know surgery.
Send them away.
No, I'm not
gonna do that.
Jack...
Crockett, this is not
who you are.
You're the man who
ran into that tunnel,
who saved my life,
who saved Nathaniel's.
Now, come on.
Have a little
faith in yourself.
Here's those referrals
I was telling you about.
My cell number's on there too.
Please call me any time.
He's seizing.
Dad!
Okay, let's get him back
in the room.
Need some help here.
Two of Ativan.
All right, Paul.
Don't worry. We got you.
Okay, Paul, we're just
gonna give you
some medicine
to calm this down
a little, all right?
Okay, on the bed.
One, two, three.
Head CT, Dr. Charles?
Why?
Although there was nothing
about headaches or nausea
in your father's history,
we should rule out a brain
mass or a bleed.
Has he complained about
any of those symptoms,
or pins and needles
of any kind?
No.
We should do the head CT.
If that comes back normal,
which I suspect it will,
we need to do a spinal tap.
Good to see you.
Good to see you too.
April?
Hey.
I'm sorry
about your father.
That's some stress
you don't need right now.
Hey. Good news.
His troponins
were normal.
There's no indication
he had a heart attack.
God.
That's such good news.
You two, congratulations.
There are
big changes ahead.
Thank you, Ms. Goodwin.
Thank you.
So, wow.
So you think
it was just
stress-induced?
You mean a panic attack?
There were no other
symptoms, no dizziness
or difficulty breathing.
Well, weddings
can be stressful.
Yeah.
But it's normal,
though, right?
Hmm?
To have, like, anxiety.
You feeling
anxious, April?
No!
I'm... Well, not more than
anyone else would be, right?
I mean, it's a big step.
Marriage. Like...
Yes. Yes.
Like Ms. Goodwin just said,
big changes.
Wait, you're not
having doubts,
are you?
No.
Not doubts.
I'm just...
Ethan, you've never
been married before.
I've never
When you asked if we should
postpone the wedding,
do you want to
postpone the wedding?
Of course not.
I'm so good.
So can you just get his
discharge papers going,
and I'll let Dad know
the good news?
Sure.
Okay.
Okay, pancreas head
and proximal duodenum are out.
Can we have a real-time
scan side-by-side with
pre-op, please?
Loading.
Nice work.
Okay, can I get a
vivo histology assessment
on the margins, please?
Margins are clear.
All right.
Time to start reconstruction.
Caution.
Do not sacrifice venous
return to the small bowel.
You need to preserve
the proximal arcade.
Yes, I'm aware.
My line of sight is limited.
The robotic scanner can
transilluminate the branches.
Okay.
I need more views
of the small
bowel vasculature.
Lucky break.
We have enough length.
Yeah.
Primary anastomosis
is possible.
Assessment is correct.
Okay.
Here we go.
Suture.
Suture spacing is too wide.
Risk for post-op
anastomotic leak.
No. I've done lots of
anastomoses this way,
without leak.
Risk for post-op
anastomotic leak.
Suturing too close risks
tearing the tissues.
Risk assessment re-evaluated.
Continue suturing.
Thank you.
Once I have exposure
to Grant's artery,
I'll have you...
Deflate the tourniquet?
Yeah.
And, I'm gonna need
to get proximal and distal
control of the...
God.
What?
You know what...
why don't you just go
ahead and start,
and, uh, I'll be in
in a minute.
What? Where are you going?
Call of nature.
You all right?
You were just there.
I'm fine.
It looks good on you.
Yeah?
Hey, you guys are all set.
Okay, great.
I got to head back to work.
Bye.
All right.
See you at the
church tomorrow.
You got it.
You ready, Dad?
Afonso!
The pain.
Dad?
It's back.
It's worse. I'm sorry.
No, it's okay, Papai.
It's okay.
Let's get you back in bed.
Okay. All right.
What's wrong with him?
All his tests were normal,
but there's something else.
I want to look into.
April, let's get a CT.
Okay.
I'll have Maggie let
Radiology know.
We'll be back as soon
as we get the results, okay?
Dan, you know
where Maggie is?
I got the cupcakes
for the party.
She's up in surgery.
I'll take those.
Surgery?
Oh, not her.
The guy she was
in the accident with.
What accident?
Last week,
when she got T-boned.
Oh...
Thanks.
Auto accident?
Ben.
You never told me
you were in an accident.
I wasn't hurt.
That's not the point.
You never told me you
were in an accident.
I didn't want to upset you.
Upset me?
Who were you with?
Who's the guy in surgery?
Was it Grant?
Is that why you didn't
want to tell me?
Was it?
No.
He was just showing me
his car and...
Showing you his car.
I go out of town,
he's showing you his car.
Ben, I know
how it looks, but...
Are you having an affair?
No! Never.
How am I supposed
to believe you?
Ben, wait.
Ben.
There's every indication
that we were able
to entirely remove
the patient's tumor,
and we're optimistic
for his future.
Now, bear in mind,
the patient's tumor
was considered completely
inoperable before O.R. 2.0.
And thanks to Mr. Dayton's
generosity, Chicago Med
is able to provide
our patients with
the best possible outcome
through a whole new level
of surgical intervention.
Thank you.
Dr. Dupre,
a moment, please.
What the hell
happened in there?
You had to override the Al.
It wasn't 2.0's fault.
It gave me bad advice.
That was because of me.
I was overly cautious.
I programmed 2.0 for someone
that was less proficient.
The risk threshold
was too low.
But you are
a very skilled
surgeon, Dr. Marcel.
The AI learns.
Believe me, you will not
have this problem again.
So Paul,
we think that we have
a much better idea about
what's been going on with you.
Is it what I thought?
It's not.
The lumbar puncture showed
elevated protein levels,
which means there's
inflammation present.
The good news,
there's no sign
of any infection.
So it looks like inflammation
is the cause of your
father's symptoms.
Inflammation from what?
The immune system
attacking the brain.
It's a condition called
autoimmune encephalitis.
Why? Why would
that happen?
We don't know.
It can be caused by a tumor,
but that's not the case
with your father.
And it's just one of those
medical mysteries
that just haven't
been solved yet.
The good news is that
it's entirely treatable.
We're going to give your
father high-dose steroids,
and this will reduce
the brain inflammation
and lessen
the immune response.
His balance?
His memory loss?
We think that they're
all gonna improve.
And, hopefully pretty
quickly too.
Hear that, Dad?
They're gonna
make you better.
Thank you.
Hi.
We know what's
causing your pain.
Okay.
You have a condition
called myocardial bridging.
That doesn't sound good.
Well, you actually
were born with it.
It's a condition where one
of your coronary arteries
runs through your
heart muscle, instead
of on top as it should.
Right, so when
the heart compresses,
it reduces blood flow
to that artery,
causing your pain.
Now, we can address it with
a procedure called unroofing.
It's where a surgeon cuts
through your heart muscle,
just to relieve
the pressure.
Heart surgery?
So I'm going to
miss the wedding?
No.
No, no, no, no, no.
This isn't an emergency.
You should schedule
the surgery soon,
but, we can wait till
after the wedding.
You're gonna be fine, Pai.
All right, I'm gonna go
text Noah and tell Mai.
Okay.
I'll be
right back, okay?
Hey, April.
Look.
I'm nervous too.
You are?
Yeah.
Here I am, asking you
to change your life,
leave your practice,
and I worry one day
you'll say,
"What have I done?
This whole thing is crazy."
I couldn't sleep last night.
I was just thinking, like,
what if...
I don't know, Ethan
realizes I'm not the
person he thinks I am?
What if in a couple of years,
he's sorry he married me?
No, no. Hey.
I don't want
to let you down.
I don't want to let
you down, either.
Well, maybe that's
a good place to start.
Hey, Maggie.
How's Grant?
He's fine.
The surgery went well.
Good. Your cupcake
party's starting.
Right.
What's the matter?
Ben.
He found out
about the accident.
Oh, no.
There's nothing
I could say.
He thinks that
we need time apart.
Oh, Maggie.
I'm so sorry.
I don't know what to do.
Hey, Sharon.
You got a second?
Yeah, sure.
So, you remember
the singer that I was
telling you about, who,
you know, I saw last night,
who works here?
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, she's with
the housekeeping department.
Okay.
Yeah, and...
I was thinking about
asking her out.
Am I completely
frigging crazy?
Daniel, you're
being impulsive?
You know, life full of
surprises? I don't know
what to tell you.
Well, tell me about her.
She, sings like a dream
and cleans my office.
That's all I got.
It's a little awkward,
though, don't you think?
Well, there is an unequal
power dynamic, but...
Exactly, and I don't
want her to feel obligated.
Listen, Daniel, you're...
It's not like
you're her supervisor.
Sharon, I think
it's too fraught.
It's too fraught.
You know.
Thank you. Good talk.
I appreciate it.
I'm gonna bag it.
Oh!
Okay.
Hey, Grant's coming around.
He's doing well.
That's good.
Yeah.
Hey, Dean, have you seen
a nephrologist?
Nephrologist? What are you
talking about?
Last week, you asked
my opinion on
an ultrasound.
The renal artery
was clearly stenotic.
Yeah, that was a patient.
Yeah, and today,
all those trips
to the loo.
Med-zone Nancy Drew.
Dean.
Tell me,
what's going on?
Yeah, I'm seeing
a nephrologist.
And?
Interstitial nephritis,
papillary necrosis.
There's more.
How? Why?
Those hits I took
to my kidneys,
I've taken too many NSAIDS
for the busted ribs.
It's stupid.
Well, how are you
being treated?
He's putting me
on a renal diet.
If that doesn't turn
things around, then I'll...
Dialysis?
Yes.
And then, well...
You know.
I'm so sorry.
It's gonna resolve.
Is there anything I can do?
Yeah, you can
keep it to yourself.
Of course.
Dr. Charles!
Hey, Liliana.
How are you doing?
Are you looking for me?
Did I miss something
in your office?
No, not at all.
Um... I was...
Hey, would you like to
get some coffee?
Get coffee? For you?
No, no, no, no. With me.
Would you like to
have some coffee...
Have some coffee with me?
You're asking me out?
Yeah.
Look, if I'm being
presumptuous,
I'm so sorry.
I don't know
anything about you,
your personal life.
You could be involved with
somebody, in which case...
No, I'm not.
You're serious?
Yeah.
Look, if I've gotten off
on the wrong foot
here, I really...
No, no, no, no.
I'd like to have
coffee with you.
When?
Any time you want.
I mean...
How about now?
What a good...
That's a great idea.
Let's have some coffee now.
I just have to change.
Cool. Okay.
I'll just...
I'll wait out here.
Good.
Since it is
your intention to enter the
covenant of holy matrimony,
join your hands and declare
your consent before
God and this church.
I, Ethan, take you,
April, to be my wife.
I promise to always
be faithful to you,
in good times and in bad,
in sickness and in health,
to love you,
and to honor you,
all the days
of my life.
I, April, take you, Ethan,
to be my husband.
I promise to be
faithful to you,
in good times and in bad,
in sickness and in health,
to love you,
and to honor you,
for all the days of my life.
May I have the rings?
Whoo!
Oh, my God. Sharon.
What?
The board
was just informed.
Jack Dayton has bought
controlling interest
in the Gaffney Medical Group.
What?
So I guess
he's in charge now.