Previously on "ER".
I guess a candlelit dinner
would not be an enticing offer.
You're offering me
a cardiothoracic spot?
Not officially until May,
but between you and me..
Hold on, hold on.
I'm covering the ER. Alright?
Fine. I'm finished here.
Peter's applied
for the Trauma Fellowship?
Yeah.
Hadn't you heard?
What do you think he'll do?
He'll be on the first plane.
Oh! Oh, my God.
I'm really sorry.
Ah, that's alright.
It's part of the game.
Being swatted by a ball?
No, it's called a hindrance.
It's a do‐over.
So I don't get penalized
or anything like that?
‐ No, I got in the way.
‐ Okay.
‐ So when do you go in?
‐ Noon. You?
Depends.
I may have a meeting.
About the Trauma Fellowship?
‐ Maybe.
‐ That's not very nice.
I mean,
I don't know when, actually.
Romano,
he keeps stalling.
Don't worry.
You're more than qualified.
'Oh!
Oh, I'm so sorry.'
Why do you have to stand there?
I've got to stand somewhere.
I didn't mean
to hit you, honestly.
Here, I have an idea.
Why don't you serve?
Okay.
You can't be enjoying this
very much.
Remember, the ball
has to bounce first.
Right.
Bollocks.
Blood pressure's fine.
‐ How are you feeling?
‐ A lot better.
Yeah, that happens once
you reach your second trimester.
I didn't gain any weight
in the first trimester.
Now, all of a sudden I've put on
two pounds in one week?
Get used to it.
I'll have Alice schedule
your midterm ultrasound.
Do you want to know
your baby's sex?
Oh, I haven't decided yet.
Well, just tell me
before we start
and we'll get
an alpha fetoprotein.
It's an indicator
of spina bifida.
‐ And Down's syndrome.
‐ Right.
‐ You think I'm at risk?
‐ No. AFP standard.
We typically only do amnio
when you're over 35
unless you have genetic
disorders in your family.
No.
‐ Cystic fibrosis? Tay‐Sachs?
‐ No.
‐ What about father's side?
‐ I don't think so.
Well, you should
check on that
but everything looks fine.
Very healthy pregnancy.
'Dr. Ross. Leave a message.'
Hey, Doug. It's me.
Uh, I‐I know we said
we shouldn't call for a while
um, but I needed
to tell you something.
I faxed it..
...and, uh..
...um, I really want you
to read it
and...sit with it
for a while.
Um..
...and then,
then we'll talk about it.
Okay.
I, um..
Bye.
♪ Semper fi do or die ♪
♪ Die for my brother ♪
I said die for my brother.
2 mgs of Ativan for the duke
here and hang a banana bag.
Kerry, I hear you have
a rule‐out AAA?
Yeah, Exam Four.
Oh, listen. Sorry, I had
to cancel the meeting‐‐
Hey, doc.
I'm one of a few good men.
That's good. Get a job.
Sorry I had to cancel
the meeting.
I had a perfed appy
that wouldn't wait
but I'll have
my office reschedule.
I spoke to Anspaugh.
He's gonna come back for it
after his seminar at 10:00.
Uh, it's a little past
my bedtime.
‐ Can I tell you something?
‐ I figured that.
He said you could present
your top three candidates
and I'll pass them along.
I bet you would.
I'm just trying to prevent
any further delay.
Very conscientious of you,
Kerry.
‐ Thank you.
‐ I'll be there.
‐ I appreciate that.
‐ Kerry, um..
‐ You mind if I call you Kerry?
‐ Oh, certainly, Robert.
‐ Here. Here, thank you.
‐ Hey, doc..
I know how much this
little project means to you.
Well, actually,
I guess I don't
but you would be smart
not to raid my surgical staff.
If you're referring
to Peter Benton
and Elizabeth Corday,
they both came to me.
Well, you can
send them right back.
I didn't realize that
you owned them.
Well, now you do.
Hire some hump
from the outside.
Make life
a lot easier.
Don't tell me you want
to see a picture.
No need to
see a picture.
Good, 'cause that
would turn her off.
Chuny, I don't need
to be fixed up.
‐ I'm not that pathetic.
‐ Who's pathetic?
Carter won't
meet my friend.
You met her.
The Urology nurse, Gina.
‐ Oh, yeah. She's nice.
‐ What's the matter, Carter?
Are you afraid she's touched
too many...you know.
Facial and abdominal trauma
coming in.
Little league umpire
got beat up.
One too many bad calls,
I guess.
What is this country coming to?
Little league?
You should see what happened
to the scoutmaster I treated.
Come on, Carter.
Just meet her.
‐ I don't date nurses.
‐ Just med students, huh?
No. I keep my love life
out of the workplace.
‐ Thank you very much.
‐ Since when?
I got a woman freaking out in
two. Something alive in her ear.
Carter. Jerry, page surgery.
I'll go meet the umpire outside.
Okay.
Hey, look what
the cat dragged in.
‐ What?
‐ You don't look so good, honey.
No, I'm just tired. I've been
working the night shifts.
Slept during the day,
didn't you?
Yeah, a little,
but I'm fine.
What the hell is that?
It's cool, huh?
Sound activated.
I picked it up
at Grossman's flea market.
Wasn't the "Macarena" in,
like, two years ago?
Three. I did it
at my college graduation.
Really?
Why don't you show us?
In your dreams.
My friend knows
how to do the "Macarena".
Oh, yeah.
♪ ..Macarena.. ♪
‐ Did you bruise?
‐ No, I don't think so.
‐ I'm afraid to check.
‐ I'm sure you'll live.
I didn't realize
that racquetball
was a full‐contact sport.
I guess it's not my thing.
Well, looked like you were
having fun there for a while.
Yeah, I was.
It was a bit too bizarre
bumping into Peter like that.
‐ How so?
‐ You weren't uncomfortable?
No. Should I have been?
I don't think
this is our umpire.
‐ You a doctor?
‐ Yeah.
Lance Carmichael, FBI.
We've got a woman
that's been shot.
Uh‐huh. What happened?
Gunshot wound
to the upper torso.
She's conscious,
but having trouble breathing.
Why didn't you call
an ambulance?
‐ Can't tell you that.
‐ Excuse me?
Active operation.
We had to abort
our medical protocol.
‐ What?
‐ Officially, we're not here.
Resps are labored,
pulse 130.
‐ I'll get a gurney.
‐ Ma'am?
‐ Can you tell me your name?
‐ Sorry.
That's
confidential information.
I'm trying to assess
her level of consciousness.
‐ Amber.
‐ Okay, Amber.
Why don't you tell me
how it happened?
That's also confidential.
Look, you want me
to help her?
Strictly need‐to‐know
information.
Okay.
Amber, can you tell me
where you got hit?
It felt like my chest,
but it hurts on the side.
‐ Uh‐huh. How long ago?
‐ Eighteen and a half minutes.
‐ What's your name?
‐ Dr. Greene.
‐ Social security number?
‐ What?
Got to run a check.
Get it out.
Just get it out!
Ma'am? You're gonna
have to hold still.
What is it?
I can still feel it
moving around.
I irrigated with Lidocaine.
It should be dead by now.
What? What should be dead?
Well..
...it looks
like a cockroach.
Ma'am, I can get it out.
‐ I can get it out.
‐ Oh.
I can get it out.
If you'll just hold still.
I don't want to puncture
your eardrum.
I'm suing the bastard.
‐ Who is that, ma'am?
‐ My landlord.
I complained three times.
I take a nap and wake up
with one in my ear.
I'm going to take him
for everything he has.
Well, until then..
...I'd sleep with earplugs.
I got it.
Alright.
We'll get that cleaned up.
You just...sit still
and I'll be right back.
♪ Semper fi do or die ♪
Lydia, can I get
a 19‐gauge angiocath?
‐ Sure.
‐ And some Valium.
‐ What you got, headache?
‐ I'm fine.
We need a secured area,
but more than one exit.
‐ Carter, is trauma one open?
‐ Yeah, what have you got?
We got a gunshot wound to the
chest, possible pneumothorax.
The metal may have slowed
the bullet down.
‐ Talk about a Wonder bra, huh?
‐ Bra saved her life?
‐ Do you need these people?
‐ They can help.
Essential personnel only.
‐ This is?
‐ FBI.
It's all very cloak‐and‐dagger.
I'm looking for
a few good men here!
You're going to have to stay
away from this patient.
I am. Mark?
Elizabeth and I can
take it from here.
We're gonna
need some nurses.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Relax, okay?
This happens all the time.
Just relax.
I think I upset the apple cart.
Get this guy out of here.
♪ Semper fi do or die ♪
‐ Hey, Peter, what's this?
‐ Bowel obstruction.
Tedious, huh?
Well, don't worry.
Another couple weeks
and you'll be out of the bowels
and into the seat of the soul.
Excuse me?
The heart, Peter.
You are serious about
the cardiothoracic fellowship,
aren't you?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Good.
'Cause I can't go in
and fight for you
and then have you not take it.
I thought you guys weren't
making your decision
until another two weeks.
Well, we're not, but the
posturing's already started.
Besides, I don't want
my guy going off to..
...waste his talents
as some glorified ER doc.
Well, uh, I wouldn't exactly
consider it a waste.
Peter, look, I know you're
confused with your son and all
and we can be flexible
about that
but you know,
let's get real.
You've worked too long
and too hard to settle
for patching up gang bangers
and drunk drivers
for the rest of your career.
Well, that's one way
of looking at it.
Good. So I need to know.
You're my guy?
Look, if you're asking me
if I'm interested
in cardiothoracic, yeah. Yeah.
Alright, say no more.
Pressure's good,
130/80.
I'm going to make
a small incision.
Will there be a scar?
We'll hide this one
under your arm.
There's oozing
at the point of entry.
Let's apply
another pressure dressing.
Curved Kelly.
Push another two of Versed.
‐ Easy on the painkillers.
‐ She's been shot.
She needs to stay
clearheaded.
I promise I won't listen to
anything her lips might utter.
‐ I got some fluid here.
‐ Blood?
‐ Nothing in the chest cavity.
‐ I don't know what it is.
It looks like saline.
Amber, do you have
breast implants?
You popped my boob?
Uh, the bullet did, but
the implant might have helped..
Sorry, this area
is off limits.
We need Merocel sponges.
We're out.
Get them someplace else.
Mark, I gotta stop
this guy's nosebleed.
That doesn't
sound serious.
‐ Are you a doctor?
‐ No.
Thora‐Seal.
I'll connect the tube.
Thanks.
Hold it.
And relax.
Did you just shoot that?
What?
Did you just shoot that X‐ray?
‐ Yeah.
‐ I was in the room.
‐ I said shooting.
‐ What's wrong with you?
'Wait, what's happening?'
He just took an X‐ray
while I was in the room.
‐ What's wrong with you?
‐ Hey, Carol, it's okay.
We've all been exposed
at one time or another.
I can't! You have
to be more careful.
She's very lucky.
No vital organ damage.
‐ When can we move her?
‐ We'll get her a bed upstairs.
No, we need to move her
to another facility.
One we can control.
Well, I need to monitor her
for a few more hours
before you can transport her.
Are you done with that?
‐ For now.
‐ I'll take it.
And we'll need all original
documentation of any kind.
Okay. The hospital keeps charts,
even on Jane Does.
We can't allow that.
Let me guess.
This conversation
never happened?
Crit's 44. Looks good.
I'll take that.
'Okay, how're we gonna
bill this?'
The bureau will be in touch.
I'm gonna have to call
my Chief of Staff.
Mark, we need the room.
Multiple MVAs coming in.
Alright, let's go.
Wait. What are you doing?
We got a traffic accident
coming in.
We're moving her
to an observation room.
Put them someplace else.
This room is set up
for trauma.
This is a national security
matter.
I don't have time
to argue with you guys.
‐ So who is she?
‐ I don't know.
‐ What she look like?
‐ A stripper.
I'm guessing
witness protection program.
Yeah, Jerry, a stripper.
That's a way
to keep a low profile.
Could be an undercover agent,
I suppose.
She don't look like
the undercover type to me.
Isn't that the point?
I'm guessing
mobster's girlfriend.
‐ Or a politician's.
‐ Maybe both.
Got a medevac coming in.
Boating accident in Berwyn.
‐ ETA?
‐ Five minutes.
Ah, it's gonna be
a long night.
Mark, can you take these?
I got a medevac coming in.
‐ Yeah, let's go.
‐ What do we got?
Peter, you're with me.
Come on.
Hey, you look like
you're feeling better.
Got my second wind.
'Shannon Mitchell,
16‐year‐old female.'
'Front‐seat passenger ejected
from the car. No seatbelt.'
'Complains of back pain.
Can't move her legs.'
Is her airway clear?
Yeah.
BP is 130/85, pulse 90.
My name's Elizabeth.
What's yours?
Shannon.
Shannon, I want you
to press your foot
against my hand just like
you're stepping on the gas.
I can't!
Possible spinal cord injury.
Let's be careful and go.
'They were on their way
to the prom.'
Hit a telephone pole
and rolled it.
Restrained driver,
second and third‐degree burns
to the bilateral hands
and forearms.
Pulled his friend out
after the gas tank exploded.
'Complains of chest pains.'
Where's Travis?
Did he make it?
We got partial thickness here.
Ten milligrams of Morphine
IV push.
‐ How's his buddy doing?
‐ Carter? Carter.
Oh, God.
Travis Mitchell,
18‐year‐old rear seat passenger.
'Head injury left him
unconscious in the burning car'
'and his friend
pulled him out.'
Seventy five percent
body surface area burned.
Mainly full thickness. Gave him
a liter of saline en route.
‐ What's his pressure?
‐ '94/68, pulse 130.'
‐ Did you find Melissa?
‐ He's waking up.
But he's asking all these
repetitive questions.
Travis. Travis,
my name is Dr. Carter.
Are you having
any trouble breathing?
Are you short of
breath at all?
‐ Where's Melissa?
‐ Who's Melissa?
She's my girlfriend.
She was in the backseat.
‐ Did she make it out?
‐ I don't know, doc.
There were three victims
and they hadn't cleared
the car yet when we left.
‐ 'I'll take the airway.
‐ What do we got?
Andrea Brodoff,
34‐year‐old female.
Rammed the boat into dock
with an attack of bad nausea.
Be careful. I have AIDS.
'Penetrating abdominal injury.'
What's her pressure?
95/60 after 800 CCs saline.
‐ What's this?
‐ 'Fishing pole.'
We had to cut it off
to transport.
Ma'am, does it hurt
on this side?
Yes!
‐ Who's this?
‐ This is Bruce.
He's fine.
He was wearing his seatbelt.
Mom wouldn't take off
without him.
Alright, let's go!
‐ Taking Bruce?
‐ 'I'll take him.'
Come on, Bruce.
Come on, sweetie.
‐ 'Solu‐Medrol's on board.'
‐ 'Can you lift your leg?'
‐ No.
‐ How about your knee?
Oh, my God!
What's happening?!
Babinski is positive.
‐ Is that bad?
‐ 'Okay.'
I want you to try and push
against my hand
with your big toe.
Alright, very good.
‐ Where's X‐ray?
‐ Coming.
Shannon, I'm gonna test the area
around your rectum.
It might be
a little uncomfortable.
‐ I won't be paralyzed, will I?
‐ Let's not worry about that.
I just need you to focus
right now, okay?
‐ Dr. Greene? Carter needs you.
‐ What is it?
Burn victim.
‐ Is that my brother?
‐ Who?
The burn victim.
Is that Travis?
Just relax, Shannon.
We're doing everything we can.
I'll be right back.
Four units, ABG
and carboxyhemoglobin.
What do you got, Carter?
I got full‐thickness burns,
maybe 80%.
At a 190 pounds,
I'm, uh, calculating
1700 CCs of Lactated Ringers
per hour.
‐ Sounds right.
‐ Yeah?
Alright, Lydia,
let's go ahead and do that.
How about vascular exam?
Good peripheral pulses so far.
Lucy, what do we do
during fluid resuscitation
'to prevent
constricting edema?'
Um, elevate the limbs
and, uh, do range of motion
exercises.
'That's right. Why don't you
start on the left leg?'
Is that my sister
over there?
‐ Yeah.
‐ What's wrong with her?
We don't know yet.
She was thrown from the car.
Is she gonna be alright?
She asked the same thing
about you.
Now really move it, Lucy.
He can't feel it.
'How's the debridement coming?'
'It's gonna take a while.'
'BP's 95/65.'
Alright, good bowel sounds.
Give me an ultrasound.
I'll be right back. Lucy,
why don't you come with me?
Go. I got this.
Find the kid's parents
and get them over here.
What should I tell them?
Tell them that their children
were in a serious accident.
‐ Don't get into specifics.
‐ Okay.
Lucy, burns like that
can be pretty brutal.
It's okay to bow out
your first time.
‐ Do you think he has a chance?
‐ There's always a chance.
Have you ever seen one
this bad survive?
‐ No.
‐ Doc.
We can't control
this environment.
Transport's en route.
I need you to clear her.
She has a chest tube.
She needs to be observed.
You provided
a valuable service.
We appreciate it.
We've arranged
for ongoing care.
I don't know what to tell you,
okay? She may need surgery.
I'm not going to release her
until I know that she's stable.
That's our problem.
Dr. Greene,
you got a sec?
Hold on, okay?
I'll check her in a minute.
I'm gonna need a blood alcohol
level on all these kids.
Especially this one.
He was driving.
He pulled his friend
out of the fire.
Yeah. He also ran the car
into a telephone pole.
It's early.
They're already drunk?
They were heading
from a pre‐party to the prom.
He said some parents
were serving beer.
Oh, geez. Alright.
Uh, how's the fourth one?
‐ Haven't found her yet.
‐ Mm.
You okay, Carol?
♪ Semper fi do or die ♪
♪ I die for my brother ♪
Central line kit's here.
‐ I got really sick.
‐ Alright.
I hit the throttle
too hard.
Let's get some O‐neg standing by
in case her pressure drops.
‐ Where's Bruce?
‐ Ma'am.
‐ Ma'am, just stay still, okay?
‐ He's in the lounge.
We're keeping a good eye on him.
It looks like blood
in Morison's pouch.
She might have
nicked her liver.
Alright, let's get
a gram of Cefotetan
'and draw pre‐op labs.'
It's the medication.
I can't keep anything down.
And then..
...the CMV just makes it worse.
‐ You have CMV?
‐ Yeah.
'Okay, let's type and cross
for four.'
'Call the OR.
Tell them we're on our way.'
‐ Oh, my God!
‐ 'What's wrong? What's wrong?'
‐ Whoa! Whoa, whoa!
‐ She's vomiting!
Roll her! Roll her!
Hey, hey, hey!
Carol!
'Carol!'
♪ Die for your brother ♪
Limited to L‐1. I don't see
any other involvement.
How are we doing?
She has some sensation
on the perianal area
and reflex contraction
of the sphincter.
Incomplete cord lesion
with a compression fracture
of the first lumbar vertebrae.
There's a small, bony fragment
impinging on her spinal cord.
Did you pump her
full of steroids?
1800 milligrams
bolus IV Solu‐Medrol.
You'll take her
to surgery?
If we can decompress it
she has a chance
at full function.
Let's do it.
Her mother sign a consent?
She's not here,
but I'll sign the order.
Okay, let's go.
If this girl doesn't feel
anything in 24 hours
she ain't gonna.
Dr. Greene, I think
I've got this sorted out.
The driver's date is the girl
with the spinal cord injury.
And her brother is
the burn victim and apparently
there's a fourth victim,
Melissa, no one can find.
And the parents of the driver
are on their way
and I spoke to some neighbors
who are staying
at the brother and sister's
house and apparently
their parents are staying
overnight in Milwaukee
but I have a call
into their hotel.
Okay, good.
Carter, how are we doing?
Compromised circulation.
His legs are cyanotic,
and I'm losing his pulse.
We've prepped
for an escharotomy.
Okay, go ahead.
Ten blade.
What's happening?
The swelling is constricting
your blood supply, okay?
So we need to make an incision
in the skin to release it.
You're slicing
my skin open?
Don't worry. You're not gonna
feel a thing, okay?
Lucy, why don't you go,
uh, talk him through it?
All the way down
to the subcu fat.
Did he start?
See? It doesn't hurt.
Will they be able to..
Will they be able to sew
this back?
We would do a skin graft.
Wait. You would or you will?
We will.
I got the medial aspect.
Okay, one centimeter
proximal and distal
to the circumferential burn.
Did you...did you find
M‐Melissa?
Not yet.
We're supposed..
We're supposed to be
at the prom right now..
...d...dancing.
Was there a theme at your prom?
Yeah. The '40s.
I was, uh..
I was gonna wear a zoot suit,
but Melissa..
...she wanted a tux.
Okay, that's one.
Halfway there.
Dr. Greene.
Uh, the FBI's
looking for you.
‐ Alright, they'll have to wait.
‐ Dr. Greene?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Todd Hoffman, FBI.
Did you treat a gunshot wound
to the chest
in the last six hours?
I told your other guys that
she's not ready to transport.
‐ What other guys?
‐ Right in here.
They were anxious
to get her out of here.
I'll bet they were.
And you believed them?
They flashed a badge at me
just like you did.
Why didn't you
put out an APB?
I need all the medical reports.
Well, they took everything,
I think.
‐ Everything?
‐ Who are these guys?
That's a need‐to‐know.
Do you have any idea
where they might be heading?
Uh, no.
They were acting like G‐Men.
How's that?
Well, they were asking
a lot of questions
and not giving out
much information.
‐ Jerry.
‐ Sorry. Sorry.
We're gonna have
to confiscate the tapes
from your surveillance cameras.
Yeah? Well, talk to security.
Jerry, put that thing away.
I don't want to see it
out here again.
Hey, Carol.
Carol!
Excuse me.
We're looking for my daughter.
She‐she was in the car accident.
Shannon Mitchell?
No, b‐but she was
in the same car. Melissa Harold.
I'm sorry, your daughter
hasn't been brought in yet.
A‐another parent told us
everyone was brought here.
The police and the paramedics
are still looking for Melissa.
‐ Where is she?
‐ They're st..
‐ They're still looking for her.
‐ Where?
I think that you should speak
with a police officer.
Reggie.
Come over here.
These are
Melissa Harold's parents
and they need information.
‐ Our daughter's missing?
‐ I'm afraid so.
But she doesn't appear to have
been trapped in the vehicle.
Doesn't appear?
The car caught fire, ma'am.
Hey. Are you alright?
I'm fine.
I'm sorry about before.
I'm just,
I'm having a bad day today.
Yeah. I'd say it was
a little more than that.
I'm really not
in the mood right now, Kerry.
Are you pregnant?
Who told you?
Nobody had to tell me.
You were upset about the X‐ray.
You didn't want to expose
the fetus to CMV.
It was instinct,
you know.
I mean, I don't mind
taking on the risks
of working
in a hospital myself, but..
It's perfectly
understandable.
How far along
are you?
Almost 15 weeks.
Good. You didn't
expose yourself
during the first trimester.
Feel free to opt out of treating
infectious patients
or doing anything that doesn't
make you feel comfortable
and we'll just deal with
the rest as we go along, okay?
Okay.
‐ Thanks, Kerry.
‐ Sure.
'Expose the spinous process
and lamina.'
There. There it is.
I can see the
bony spicule
impinging
on the spinal cord.
No wonder this kid
couldn't move her legs.
Let's rongeur
that little troublemaker.
So...have you thought
about what I said?
What was that?
About not wasting your life
on this Trauma Fellowship.
What? And miss out
on cases like this?
You're avoiding
the question.
Frankly, I don't think
I've a lot of options
at the moment, have I?
I'd consider you
for cardiothoracic.
I could sneak in
a late application.
I thought that
belonged to Peter.
Well, he didn't hesitate
to throw his hat
into your rice bowl, did he?
This fragment's
really embedded.
Careful.
Not a large margin
of error here.
You shouldn't be
out of bed.
He's gonna die,
isn't he?
It's too early to tell.
I need you to sit down here
and I need to take a look
at those dressings.
So...your X‐ray
shows that you have
a fractured rib.
Okay.
It's gonna hurt
for a few weeks
but it'll heal
on its own.
It's a brave thing you did
going back in there
for your friend.
It won't matter, will it?
We're doing everything we can.
They took my blood.
They think it's 'cause
I was drunk, don't they?
Your blood alcohol
level was .09.
I didn't mean
for this to happen.
Let me know
if you're in too much pain.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God! Justin!
You alright?
Is he going to be alright?
It's okay, mom.
I'm okay.
What happened?
It was the CD player.
I went to change the CD.
I totaled the car.
Pulse ox is dropping.
It's 93 on 15 liters of oxygen.
Any burns to the airway?
Yeah. He had some
singed nasal hair.
Good chance
of laryngeal edema.
What's the word
on the Burn Unit?
They had to call in
a registry nurse.
She should be here
in about an hour.
Okay. You should tube
while he's still got an airway.
Yeah, I was just waiting
for the parents to get here.
They're on the road.
They left half an hour ago.
‐ How about the sister?
‐ She's still in surgery.
You know, maybe you could
call the neighbors
to see if the parents
have a car phone.
It's up to you, Carter,
but I don't want to hear
you had to cric him.
Understood.
So what happens
if we don't reach them?
I tube him, and he dies
in the Burn Unit
within the next week.
They can still say goodbye.
I just wanted to give him
the chance to talk to them.
How is she?
Oh, good.
The pole nicked her liver.
We repaired the defect
with very little blood loss.
‐ Good. Thanks.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Hi.
I called family services
and they're gonna watch Bruce
until you can get someone
to pick him up.
How's he doing?
He's asleep.
Thank you.
I'm, um..
I'm sorry
about what happened downstairs.
You don't need to explain.
I understand.
It wasn't because
of the HIV status.
I was afraid
of the CMV.
Really, you don't
need to explain.
Is that yours?
Yeah.
Time for your medication?
Do you have it here?
They're at home.
Well, um, I can
get it for you here.
No.
Thank you.
Um..
Missing a dose could make it
harder to treat the HIV.
I'm done with them.
I'm sorry?
I'm not going to take
anymore medicine.
It's not worth it.
I can't function.
Andrea..
...I know
you're upset right now
but if you don't take
your medication, the chances‐‐
I know what it means.
Bruce is eight.
He needs a mother.
It is more important that he
have a well mother for now
than a sick one for longer.
'Good work, Lizzie.'
What do you think?
I give her 50‐50.
Robert, have you
got a minute?
Uh...sure.
You got her, Lizzie?
Yeah.
Look, I want
to do this now.
Where are you
on this Trauma Fellowship?
Well, like I've
already told you
I don't really see the need,
but if I'm the minority
I vote for the Georgetown guy.
Kerry?
Peter Benton's
the strongest candidate.
‐ Mark?
‐ I disagree.
Elizabeth Corday
brought us the idea.
She has passion
and certainly the talent.
Of course, she does,
but I don't wanna see
either one of them wasted
on this, no offense.
They both applied,
didn't they?
Well, it looks like
you're all of separate minds.
It's late,
and I want to go home
so I'm gonna
make this quick.
Peter Benton it is.
Thank you.
‐ How's he doing?
‐ Pulse ox 92.
Could you get
Dr. Carter?
Sure.
Travis, are you awake?
The doctor needs to put
a tube down your throat
to help you breathe now.
‐ Can you talk?
‐ Yes.
I have your parents
on the phone
and they're in a car
on their way here.
I thought you might
want to talk to them first.
How long?
They should be here
in about 45 minutes
but we can't wait that long.
How long's the tube
gonna be in?
At least a few days.
Are you ready?
Okay.
Mr. Mitchell?
Okay, you can talk to him now.
Okay. Okay, Travis,
it's okay, okay.
There you go.
Hey. Hey. Hey, dad.
I know. I know.
I can't believe it.
Did the doctor tell you?
It's‐it's pretty bad.
I don't think I'm gonna,
um..
...I don't think
I'm gonna make it
out to the lake this summer.
I don't know,
they‐they took her into surgery.
I haven't heard anything yet.
Hey, hey..
Hey, they have
to put this, uh..
...this tube in me,
so I'm not gonna be able to..
...talk for a couple of days.
Okay, I'll‐I'll,
I'll see you when you get here.
Hey...mom.
You....gotta hang in,
gotta hang in there.
I'm‐I'm okay.
I mean, just a little..
I‐I...I love,
I love you, too.
Pulse ox 89.
Draw up four of Versed
and ten of Norcuron
insert with the angular tip.
Number eight ET Tube.
Okay, Travis..
...you're gonna
feel a little sleepy.
When you wake up,
there's gonna be
a ventilator
helping you breathe.
Hey.
It's not
a very encouraging entrance.
I'm sorry.
You didn't get
the Trauma Fellowship.
Is it Peter?
Yeah.
Well, that's that, then.
I was looking forward
to working with you.
Yeah. Same here.
So now what?
Well, I guess I'm left
to ferret around
picking up scraps
wherever I can find them.
It doesn't mean Peter
was a better candidate.
Oh, I know.
How much more time
do you have on your internship?
Three weeks.
Well, you have
your license.
You can do
anything you want.
Except the Trauma Fellowship.
Just about anything.
How did the voting go?
I think you know.
Yeah. Romano didn't
want either of us.
Anspaugh was keen on Benton.
Don't tell me you were.
No, I wanted you.
But I'm not
really objective.
Really?
‐ You know what you need?
‐ What?
A milkshake.
When time do you get off?
Midnight.
Okay. I'll find you.
Is this more of
your bad‐day therapy?
It's free of charge.
I'm sorry.
What about the place
up the street?
No, you don't want
to go there.
Excuse me.
‐ Hey, who is that?
‐ Who?
‐ Over there, talking to Chuny.
‐ I don't know.
‐ She works in Urology.
‐ Really?
Carter, are you on
for a while?
Yeah, another six hours.
Got a social worker coming
from the HIV Clinic.
Needs to see
a patient upstairs.
‐ Surgical ward?
‐ Sure.
‐ Randi, did you get that?
‐ Uh, yeah.
‐ HIV Clinic to Carter.
‐ Goodnight.
ER.
Yeah, she's right here.
Carol...Doug.
I'll, uh, I'll get it
in the lounge.
‐ Hey, Chuny.
‐ What?
Is that the same friend
that you were talking about?
You're too late
now, Carter.
What, there was
a time limit?
I didn't think
you were that shallow.
No. I'm just reconsidering
your proposal.
‐ You snooze, you lose.
‐ Snooze, you lose.
What are we,
in tenth grade?
I set her up
with an Orthopedics intern.
An intern?
I'll tell you what,
if you're nice
I'll try to get her
to reconsider.
Adios.
Lucy, the pharmacy called.
‐ Your prescription is ready.
‐ Thanks.
‐ You're sick?
‐ No.
‐ What is it then?
‐ Nothing.
‐ Why are you on medication?
‐ Why are you so nosy?
‐ Who prescribed it?
‐ It's none of your business.
Yeah, this morning
I saw you were exhausted.
Then you pop some pill
and suddenly you are fine
‐ Now you're dragging again.
‐ I'm not on speed.
If that's what
you're asking, Carter.
So what is it?
Huh, what is it?
Ritalin. Okay?
I'm on Ritalin.
Ritalin? Since when?
‐ Fifth grade.
‐ What?
Yeah, my doctor tried to get me
off it in high school
and my grades dropped,
so I went back on.
You've been on it
ever since?
Well, there's never really been
a good time to stop.
Now. Now would be
I'm not an addict, Carter.
Lucy, you shouldn't still
be taking it.
‐ It's a stimulant.
‐ I don't take it to get high.
‐ I take it to function.
‐ You got ADD?
And it's never really
been a problem
until I started working
so many nights.
Ritalin is for
hyperactive children. You're 24.
And my doctor still
prescribes it
so I'm not doing
anything wrong.
You're just gonna keep
taking it forever?
I'll stop taking it
when things are less hectic.
Got news for you.
Things are never less hectic.
I'll think about it, alright?
But this really
is my business, Carter.
And I hope
you'll respect that.
'The signer's head leans
to the right'
'and rests in the upturned palm
of the open right hand.'
Hey.
I suppose congratulations
are in order.
Look, Elizabeth..
...you don't have to say that.
Peter, I'm just trying
to be gracious.
Thank you.
Peter.
Elizabeth, would you
excuse us, please?
Certainly.
Thank you.
You do lack
some qualities, Peter
but I always considered you
a man of your word.
I never said I'd take it.
You said
you wanted cardiothoracic.
No. I said
I was interested.
You missed your calling, Peter.
You should've been a lawyer.
I couldn't count on it.
I told you that I would be
pushing for you. I have been.
Thank you, but I'm taking
the Trauma Fellowship, okay?
Fine. Whatever, Peter.
I'm done looking out for you.
You wanna throw your life
down the toilet.
‐ That's your prerogative.
‐ Yeah, it is.
Just don't come crying
to me when you realize
what a mistake you've made.
‐ Were you serious?
‐ What?
The offer you made today,
were you serious?
Dr. Greene, some weird guy
dropped this off for you.
‐ What is it?
‐ Do I read your mail?
"Thanks for patching up Amber."
‐ 'Who's Amber?'
‐ Well, she's a stripper.
Whoa.
Must've liked you a lot.
‐ How much is there?
‐ Looks like about two grand.
Whoo! Party.
Look, Randi, get out
the phone book.
Look up FBI and have them
come pick this up.
Excuse me?
Uh, I'm Greg Mitchell.
Our son and daughter
were in an accident.
I'm Dr. Greene.
I saw both of them here
in the Emergency Department.
Well, where are they?
Shannon underwent surgery.
There was a broken vertebrae
in her back
that was impinging
on her spinal cord.
But she's gonna be okay?
There's a possibility
that she'll lose function
below her waist.
Oh, God.
Travis suffered
third‐degree burns
over the majority
of his body.
Third degree?
He's up in the Burn Unit.
They're doing everything
they can
to make him as comfortable
as possible.
But I have to tell you that
with burns of this magnitude
the survival rate is very low.
Is he gonna die?
He has a 20% chance
of survival.
Oh! Oh, God.
Oh! Oh, God! No!
No!
You're up.
‐ Where am I?
‐ The OR Recovery Room.
We operated on your back.
You were in a car accident.
'Do you remember?'
I thought it was a dream.
Can I do a quick test?
'I want you to tell me when
you feel something, alright?'
'Shannon?'
'Are you with me?'
Yeah.
There.
What does that mean?
It's no better.
It's no worse.
Let's see how
your big toe's doing, shall we?
I want you to wiggle it
just like you did before.
'Alright?'
Again.
'Is it moving?'
Let's just wait and see.
The swelling has
to come down first.
Lily, I took
Mr. and Mrs. Mitchell
up to the Burn Unit.
Could you go up
and show one of them
to Surgical Recovery?
‐ Sure.
‐ Thanks.
Um, Mark,
I wouldn't go in there.
Why?
We're giving Carol some space.
Doug called.
Carol?
Go away, Mark.
Did you tell him?
He's not coming.
Did you ask him
not to come?
Yeah.
I was very strong...and clear.
So he's respecting
your wishes?
That would be a first time,
wouldn't it?
You wanted him to come.
No.
I've had...hundreds
of conversations with him
in my head, you know?
What I would say,
what I would..
...do if he showed up.
I wouldn't let him charm
his way back in.
Not now.
Not because of the baby.
I would never feel secure
knowing that that's why
he came back.
Maybe he feels the same way.
I still expected him to come.
I've got to go home.
Hmm...you know what you need?
What?
You need a milkshake.
Elizabeth and I are going
to go get a milkshake.
Why don't you come?
No. I'm tired
and I'm gonna go home.
No, no, just, just one
one little milkshake, okay?
It was a date, wasn't it?
Look, no, it wasn't a,
it wasn't a date.
Well, um, we were just going to
drown our sorrows in ice cream.
'Come on.'
I don't wanna be
a third wheel, Mark.
How many times
have I been a third wheel?
That's true.
You do owe me.
That's the spirit.
Are you paying?
Of course I'm paying.
'Cause I'm eating
for two, you know.