If you're just waking up,
give yourself some
extra time to get to work.
I know they didn't
plow my street.
First major snowfall,
they always take three
days to get their act together.
Oh, God, it's freezing outside.
Hey, Dr. Weaver.
Any trouble getting in?
No, I didn't even
bother with my car.
I just took the El.
Hey, John, what are
you still doing here?
I thought you were off at 3.
Five-car pile up
on the expressway.
How many did we get?
Six out of eight.
Three went up to the
O.R., two to the SICU,
and one's waiting
on a monitored bed.
I spent the last four
hours catching up.
How'd our temp attending do?
Worthless.
Carter had to keep
the board running.
Thank you, Haleh.
Yeah, what happened to the
attending we had last week?
Took a job in the Bahamas.
I knew that guy was
too smart for this place.
Where do you need me?
I think we're
through the thick of it.
Those are the dispos.
I signed out the
rest to Malucci.
Will you, uh, give Mr. Phelps
a Bactrim and discharge him?
Yeah. Thank you.
And I think I am out of here.
Hey.
Uh, John, I'm sorry that I
put you on nights so soon,
but with Mark gone,
the schedule's a mess.
We all do our share of nights.
Have you heard from him?
Mark? Yeah.
No. They got there Tuesday.
I didn't want to call. I
mean, if it's good news,
then they'll... Yeah.
Well, I will see you at,
uh, 4:00 this afternoon.
Make it 5:00.
We'll cover for you.
Thanks.
Anesthesiologist is on his way.
How long?
A couple of minutes.
Jing-Mei, I'm gonna need
you to relax for a second, okay?
Okay.
Yeah, I know. I know.
Dilated at 4 centimeters.
Completely effaced.
Zero station.
Start the Pitocin
at two per minute,
and up it every 20 minutes.
Is it okay to come in?
Oh, John.
John, I'm so sorry to call you.
It's okay, it's okay.
I mean, I waited
as long as I could.
I didn't want to wake you.
Don't worry. I'm not working.
Jing-Mei,
I'm going to rupture
your membranes,
to help move you
along a little, okay?
When did you go into labor?
Midnight.
Where?
Home. I... I took a cab.
All done.
Oh.
You know, I thought I could
do this myself, but I can't.
I can't.
Hey, it's okay.
You don't have to.
Contraction? Mm-hmm.
Okay. Squeeze my hand.
Yeah, squeeze my
hand. There you go.
You're doing great, Jing-Mei.
You're doing great.
We'll get the
epidural working soon.
Have you taken
any birthing classes?
Mm-hmm. Lamaze? Bradley?
Which one?
Lamaze? Okay.
Take a good, deep breath.
In, in.
Don't touch that.
Peter.
Peter?
Yeah.
Listen.
What?
Voices.
It's Kynesha.
Talking to herself?
She's probably just watching TV.
Peter.
What?
You brought her here.
Go.
Mmm.
No, you don't know.
This girl stay uptight.
Can't be too uptight. Lets
you stay here by yourself.
Get mad every
time I turn on a light.
Place this nice, she
worried about the electric bill.
Sure has straight teeth.
Who are you?
Uh, I was just looking at it.
Where's Kynesha?
Hey, Dr. Benton.
Kynesha, who is this?
This is Tiny. Hey.
Tiny got locked out.
Her sister ain't
coming home till 7.
You went out?
No.
So somebody else is
wearing your boots now?
I went to check on my mom.
Tiny said she came
back, was looking for me.
Was pretty messed up.
All right. Um... You
live in her building?
Yeah. Grab your
stuff. I'll take you home.
Kynesha, you
better clean this up
before Cleo comes down.
Okay?
There, you have your coffee.
Now let's go.
Mark, I don't want to
keep this man waiting.
He's jammed us
into his schedule.
What is it?
The kid with the red hat.
What about him?
I saw another kid
wearing that exact hat,
three weeks ago.
I was buying groceries
for Thanksgiving dinner.
Now I'm in New York,
waiting for a miracle.
Well, maybe it's a sign.
Either that,
or the Grim Reaper
wears a red hat.
I didn't come with you
to hear talk like that.
I thought that was healthy.
Well, it's not.
I should just stick with denial?
I'd prefer guarded optimism,
until Dr. Burke maps the
brain, and gives us his opinion.
Yeah, and then I can
hear bad news twice.
If you really believed that,
you'd have called Rachel by now.
Just call her up, and
tell her over the phone?
No, you could have
flown out there for a day,
but you didn't.
Why?
I have a feeling
you're gonna tell me.
Yes, because deep down,
you really do believe
that this technology,
and this surgeon can help you.
And you don't want to tell her,
until you know
you'll be all right.
Yeah, or I'm desperate.
You've seen enough
patients in your time,
overcome illnesses
they shouldn't have,
to understand the importance
of a positive outlook.
Now, you have to
believe it's possible.
I think I'm a little nervous.
Well, me too.
Heart rate is 150
with Type-1 dips.
Is that a normal decel?
Yeah. It's good
cardiac activity.
I thought you got
high honors in OB.
I did. Excuse me.
The adoptive parents are
here. Can I show them in?
Yes. No!
They said they arranged
to be present for the birth.
John, do you mind?
Yeah. I'll talk to
them. I'll talk to them.
Hi. You're the adoptive parents?
Yes. James and Linda. Hi.
You're the doctor?
I'm a friend of Deb's.
Who?
Jing-Mei. I'm John Carter.
Is there a problem?
No, no. She's starting to push.
Baby's healthy. Could
be any minute now.
We should get in there.
Well, she's feeling
a little overwhelmed.
She said we could
be present at the birth.
I know. Uh...
But labor can be demanding,
and she really needs to focus.
We traveled all night
from Portland to get here.
I understand.
You can have a seat, right here.
Is she changing her mind?
About giving the
baby up for adoption?
No, I think she's a
little embarrassed.
Just wants a little privacy.
Look, we really
wanted to be there,
for the birth of our son.
I'll bring him right out to you.
I promise.
Hey, I heard Dr. Chen's
having her baby upstairs.
Malucci, Exam 1's
been here since 9:00,
with reflux esophagitis.
In a minute, chief.
Do you want to
send her flowers? No.
I could start a pool.
No. Leave her alone.
Why?
Randi, can you
just drop it, please?
Hi, Kim.
Hi. You have a
cyclothymic down here?
Yeah. A guy in Exam 3,
trying to set a new
world record doing sit-ups.
Got it.
Hey, I tried to call
you the other day...
Oh.
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
My machine's been acting up.
I need to get a new one.
Oh. I wish I'd
known that sooner.
I might have gotten
you something different.
Merry Christmas. Oh, wow!
Yeah. I happened across
a copy over the weekend,
and couldn't resist.
Hopefully you don't
already have one.
Well, thank you.
My pleasure.
Should I open it now?
Or later.
Okay.
You know, you should try
drinking water upside-down.
It always helps with me.
Yeah. Thank you.
See you.
You said one night.
It's been a week.
Look, I can't find her mother.
What do you want me to do?
Turn her over to
Social Services.
If her mother's been on
a drug spree for a month,
she needs to be in foster care.
Cleo, Cleo. She's 15 years old.
She doesn't want to
go in the system now.
Well, I'm not
adopting her. Are you?
No, of course not.
I hate the thought of her
being in my house alone.
Now she's bringing friends over?
I'm sorry. That
won't happen again.
Peter, she's manipulating you.
You know, I... I got a lead
on another halfway house.
I'll... I'll make sure
she gets into that one.
Two more days.
After that, she's out.
Cleo, I'm working on it. Good.
LFTs are back on Room
4. Bilirubin's a little high.
I need help, please! Help me!
Someone help me, please!
What happened?
A dog attacked my son.
He's bitten all over. I
can't stop the bleeding.
What's his name?
Oh, God! It looks worse.
Laceration through and
through. He cut his facial artery.
What's your son's name? Jeff.
He was crying,
but now he's quiet.
Jeff, I'm Dr. Weaver.
We need to secure his
airway. What's open?
Trauma 1. Come on.
Get him on a monitor.
I need suction, and
a Pedes intubation kit.
Throw up 40 of sux
and five of Versed.
- Cutdown tray, move.
- Pulse ox is 86.
Ten liters blow-by.
I need 4-by-4s, and
Merocel sponges.
Stats are dropping.
Get back, Peter.
I need to intubate.
I think I can
control it. What is it?
Uh, let me get
some suction here.
Ma'am, I need some room.
We have to ask you to step back.
Damn it. If only I can
tie off this bleeder.
Heart rate's up to
120. Pulse ox is 82.
He's not getting enough
oxygen. We have to intubate.
What are you doing?!
Why aren't you helping him?
Got it!
Blow hard. Three, two, one.
Okay, okay, now
one more should do it.
I don't want to use
suction. All right?
I thought you said
he was crowning.
He is. Just one more push.
Ugh... Oh, I can't.
Yes, you can. Just
one more push.
Come on. Now.
You're doing great.
Ten, nine, eight, push!
Seven, six.
Okay, the head is
out! You can stop.
Stop pushing.
Is it over?
Almost.
You did great. You did great.
It's a boy.
He's nice and healthy.
You want to hold him?
Wanna hold him?
No.
You sure?
Yes.
I guess this was more
than you bargained for.
Well, you did all the work.
No, I mean having
to see all this.
It was a blur.
Let's just say we're closer now.
Surprised you, huh?
I didn't tell you
about the father.
Yeah, kind of.
Are those the adoptive parents?
Yeah. You didn't meet them?
Uh, yeah. About two months ago.
They still want to
come in and see you.
What did they do when
you gave them the baby?
They cried.
They seem nice to you?
Yeah, they seem great.
Here we are.
Any nausea?
Um, yeah, a little.
All right. We'll give you
some ice chips until it passes.
Hey, you know, you
don't have to stick around.
Oh, I'm fine.
You have a night shift? Later.
Okay. Well, then
you should go rest,
crash in the, uh, on-call room.
We'll see.
All right. I'm gonna
change your pad.
Then we'll massage your
uterus, to firm it up a bit.
Oh, you don't want
to be around for that.
Not really. You okay?
All right, I'm gonna come
back and check on you later.
Okay.
Hey, John? Yeah?
Thank you.
You're welcome.
The, uh, whole thing
takes about an hour.
You'll be doing,
uh, language tasks,
as we map out
the speech centers.
Is Dr. Burke meeting us?
He'll stop by at some point.
Usually you meet the surgeon,
before he sends
you off for a scan.
Burke's one of the best
in the world. He's busy.
Uh, take off your glasses,
watch, wallet,
pager, cell phone.
Anything metal,
anything magnetic,
right in here.
Could you at
least call Dr. Burke
and let him know we're here?
He likes to be notified
when the renderings are up.
So as not to waste any
time with the patients.
Elizabeth.
Uh, don't forget the belt.
You'll have earphones,
and we'll talk by intercom.
Can I stay for the scan,
then? I am a surgeon, myself.
You can sit back there.
Uh, for the first run, we'll
ask you to name objects
you'll see projected
on fiber-optic goggles.
Do I get to shoot
down any aliens?
Will he have scars?
Surgeons will do everything
they can to minimize them.
What are you doing here?
I am so sorry. I was worried.
He almost died, Mona!
But he'll be all right?
You're putting that dog down!
He's a sweet dog. Mom?
What are you talking about?
Maybe this isn't the right time.
Jeff must have provoked
him in some way...
Provoked him? That
animal mauled my son.
You're putting him down. I
want that animal destroyed!
Shelly, I... You better
leave it alone for now.
Mom?
Are they gonna kill Winston?
I don't know, honey.
Why don't we find a place for
you to sit down? Here we go.
Oh. There's good hemostasis.
The repeat crit is 39.
Great, Peter. Thanks.
Yeah.
Hey.
You're not supposed
to be in there.
What's your name?
Taylor.
Well, come on out here, Taylor.
I hurt my foot.
If you come out here,
I can take a look at it.
I'm a doctor.
Okay.
Let's take a look.
Are you a patient here?
Let me see this.
Hey, you're supposed to
be up in the blood bank.
You having a blood transfusion?
I don't like needles.
Yeah, well, none of us do,
but sometimes we gotta use
them to make you feel better.
I'm not sick. Nicole is.
Who's Nicole?
She's my sister.
She has leukemia.
Ah.
Then you're donating
bone marrow.
I did that when I was little.
Now they want to
take all my blood
and wash it through a machine.
Mmm. Yeah, I see.
Every time Nicole gets sick,
I have to go to
the hospital too.
I tell you what.
You come with me, I'll
make your foot feel better.
You won't take my blood out?
No. Come on.
Come on.
Where are my shoes?
Jing-Mei, I didn't mean to
make you uncomfortable.
You should just think about it.
I have thought about it.
What's up?
John, I'm leaving.
Can you give me a ride home?
But you can't leave until
Dr. Coburn gets here.
I'll sign out AMA.
Just get the form.
We keep all postpartum
mothers for 24 hours.
Well, I'm not a mother.
I suggested she see the baby.
John, can we leave, please?
I think they observe
you for a reason, Deb.
I think you should
sit down and relax.
Well, I'll come
back for a blood test.
Don't run away
from this, Jing-Mei.
It's better for the adoptive
parents, better for you,
if you meet your son,
hold him, say goodbye.
I don't think I can.
Can what?
Say goodbye.
Last run is word fluency.
For, uh, each object,
name an action
that goes with it.
If, uh, you see a dog,
you might say, "bark."
Okey-dokey.
Okay, here we go.
It grows.
Sweeps.
Live in it.
Writes.
Blossoms.
Hey, Marty. Is this
the frontal GBM?
Baseline scans are up, but
not the functional renderings.
Well, Burke's not gonna
want to cut this one out.
I'll take him.
For the carboplatin trial? Yeah.
No, you had the
parietal GBM for that.
He's a good
gamma-knife candidate.
Best you can offer is
a 12-month survival.
We've seen up to 14 with
an intra-arterial protocol.
Yeah, and what an
enjoyable two months it is.
Hello? It slithers.
Okay, I'll be right up.
SVC Syndrome in the unit.
We'll duke it out
in tumor board.
Sticks you.
Page me when the
renderings come up.
Dr. Burke gets the first look.
No, he won't be interested.
Entomb.
Hang.
All done. I'll be right in.
How'd I do?
You did brilliantly, Mark.
Can I go home after this?
We'll see.
Cleo, you have a call on two.
Girl named Kynesha,
something about your car.
My car?
She was talking really fast.
Kynesha?
Just gone?
Did you see anybody?
No. Nobody.
I'll call the police.
Stay near the phone.
What happened?
Kynesha says my car is
missing, didn't see anything.
Chicago Police Department,
main number, please.
Always the diplomat, Peter!
What?
Dr. Duhlstrom just
called me, ranting.
Says you stole one of
his leukocyte donors,
and you won't give it back.
It was a little girl
that I found scared,
hiding under the stairs.
Finders keepers? Is that it?
She cut her foot.
I told him to send
her parents down.
If you hadn't hung
up on Duhlstrom,
you'd know that Dad is at
the airport picking up Grandma,
and Mom's a little busy
with the other daughter
who's puking her guts out
from chemo. So do me a favor.
Hurry it up, suture the
foot, and ship her upstairs.
Has anyone even bothered
to explain this
procedure to this girl?
They've done a few
hundred of these.
Well, she's scared right
now and feeling a little used.
Oh, that's... That's terrible.
The sister's a
little scared too.
She's scared of dying!
It's not like they're
trying to take out a lung.
Well, she has point tenderness
over the distal malleolus.
Okay. You want to play
ER doc, fine. I'll tell you what.
I'll tell the mother to
abandon her child upstairs,
come down, and
calm this kid down.
But if she is not strapped
in for leukapheresis by 2:30,
I'm strapping you in.
What did she say?
Okay. She said that
she would see him,
but she doesn't really want to.
Are you sure that you
want to force this on her?
We have three days until
she has to sign the papers.
And if she doesn't see him,
she might regret it, and...
then change her mind
about the whole adoption.
Okay. Well, she's waiting.
All right. Why don't
you bring him in to her,
and the Reeds and I will
follow in a few minutes,
so that Jing-Mei can hand
the baby back to Linda.
Okay.
I got him.
Ready?
Oh, Carter.
He's so beautiful.
Hey. Hey.
Hope it's like a jury.
The longer they deliberate,
the better chance I have
of getting off.
They could still be
waiting for Burke.
I'm starting to think
that he doesn't exist.
Maybe he only meets
people that he can help.
Mark.
I know, I know.
Positive. Positive.
That MRI tech sure
thought I was a goner.
He just runs the machine.
He can't offer a prognosis.
Come on. You know that
those techs can read a scan
better than most surgeons.
No offense.
Do you want to get
something to eat?
No. No. Nope. No.
I can't believe they
call it a tumor board.
Why? They discuss tumors.
I know, but...
You'd think they'd
come up with something
a little more esoteric.
Like what?
I don't know, uh, the...
"You're completely boned" board.
I heard they used to call
it the "poor bastard" board
but too many people
were showing up.
Someone told me that they tried
the "take me out back and
shoot me now" board for a while.
What, it didn't stick?
No, surprisingly.
Why not?
Too many letters, I guess.
Hm. Pity.
Elizabeth? Mm-hmm.
Will you have the
baby either way?
What?
If that man comes
out of that room
and tells me he
can't do anything...
that there's no
way I can beat it...
will you still have the baby?
Yes.
I got a 12-year-old in 4
that swallowed a
pair of toenail clippers.
I think he's gonna
need to be scoped.
Are you okay? The hiccups.
I thought they went away.
They did.
Teaspoon of sugar's
supposed to help.
It didn't.
Is Luka coming back
on the 26th or the 27th?
26th, I think.
Where'd he go? Croatia?
Yeah, he went to visit
his dad for Christmas.
Yo, my moms told me
if you stand on your head
and swallow, hiccups gone.
Thanks, Malik.
Hey, no problem.
Works every time.
Did you page me, Kerry?
Yeah. We got a bad
dog bite in Trauma 2.
Little kid who might
need to be plugged
into some outpatient therapy.
Sure. Did you open it?
What? The present.
No, not yet. No.
I'll go with you. Okay.
Do you want a shot of Reglan?
For what?
Hiccups. No, they'll go away.
What about my toenail clippers?
Malucci, get him.
Hey. Hey.
You're here early.
I was helping
Chen with her baby.
Was there a problem?
No. Well, she
didn't have a coach.
You were her coach? Mm-hmm.
How'd you do?
I did fine. She had
a rough time of it.
Should I...? She
doesn't want visitors.
I'll fill you in later. I'm
gonna catch some Zs...
Sweet dreams.
Dr. Carter! They told
me you were down here.
She's breast-feeding!
She gave the baby
back after seeing him.
Then we talked for a while,
then we went back to the nursery.
Then the nurse says she
wants to see him again.
She wants to breast-feed!
Man, slow down. What?
The nurse has to give the baby
back to her if she asks for him.
So she did.
My wife is frantic.
Okay. I'll... I'll talk to her.
Is my dad coming?
I'm not sure.
Your mom went to call him.
Is that a problem?
He's gonna kill me.
I was gonna put it back
without him knowing.
Put what back?
Is Winston gonna be okay?
The dog?
They're not gonna put
him to sleep, are they?
That would be very sad.
But any dog that would
attack you for no reason...
Excuse me.
I didn't mean to.
What?
To open my
Christmas present early.
I knew what it was.
A BB gun.
Did you shoot at the dog?
I was just trying it out.
Why would she
need to breast-feed?
It's not unusual.
Does she still have him?
She's changing
her mind. I know it.
There's no need to panic.
Why did we have to
force her to meet him?
Linda, she's
giving up her child.
There's a maternal
instinct she can't avoid
and shouldn't try to.
We'll give her some time
and have you rock
the baby in front of her.
Won't that make it worse? No.
She needs to know
at a very basic level
that the baby will be loved.
Can you talk with her?
Find out what's going
on, what she's thinking?
Yeah, I can try.
I can't lose another baby.
Deb?
What are you doing?
You know, they say
breast-feeding is good for them
in the first 24 hours.
It's mostly colostrum, which
boosts their immune system.
Deb, are you having
second thoughts?
I've always had second thoughts.
What's changed?
I saw his face.
I'm being selfish.
I have the money to raise him.
There's no reason why I can't.
There's a couple out there
who desperately
want to raise a child.
And you're giving
them a great gift.
What happens...
18 years from now?
He shows up looking
for an explanation.
Well, you tell him
the truth, you know?
You tell him that
you wanted to provide
the best home possible for him.
Do I tell him I was a coward?
That my bigoted parents
were more important
to me than he was?
Deb, I think that you gotta
take your family out of this.
Now, if you wanna keep
the baby, keep the baby.
But if you don't, or you can't,
then you wanna make sure
that he goes to somebody
who's gonna love him,
who's gonna want him.
And know that you're
not abandoning your baby.
You're creating a family.
Did you find it?
Four blocks away
with a burned-out clutch
and a busted headlight.
You lucked out.
They could have
completely stripped it.
Hello, Peter? My car
wasn't stolen by a thief
who doesn't know
how to drive a stick.
Kynesha and her friend
took the car out for a joyride.
What? I gave Kynesha's
friend a ride home myself.
Just Kynesha, then.
She's the one that called you.
So she's not
completely stupid. Cleo...
Get her in here now.
I wanna talk to her.
Why don't we just...?
Get her in here, or I'll
have the police talk to her.
Cleo, I...
Excuse me. Are you Dr. Benton?
Yeah.
I'm Melissa Walker.
You found my daughter.
She's in Radiology.
We just wanted to
get an x-ray of her foot.
Oh, God! It's nothing serious.
We just wanted to
rule out a fracture.
She has three stitches.
Did she fight you?
She's afraid of hospitals.
Yeah.
You know, um...
I think it might be more
than just the needles.
The leukapheresis requires
a big one in each
arm for five hours.
Taylor feels the only
reason you had her
was to help Nicole.
We love both of our daughters.
Of course you do.
If you had a child
dying of leukemia
and there was no
bone-marrow match,
what would you do?
We were planning to
have more children anyway,
but I am so tired of
having to explain this
like we did something wrong.
I was just telling you
that Taylor feels...
I know. She's my daughter.
And I love her,
okay? I love her.
Now, where is X-ray?
Mrs. Walker, I was just...
Where is X-ray?
Down the main hall to the right.
Thank you.
Hi.
Hi. Hi.
What's his name?
Michael. Michael Alexander.
Hey, Michael.
It's okay.
Shh. Shh. Shh.
♪ Baby of mine ♪
♪ Don't you cry ♪
♪ Dry your eyes ♪
♪ Rest your head ♪
♪ Close to my heart ♪
♪ Never will part ♪
♪ Baby of mine ♪
What did he say?
I may go to trial.
Thought you were gonna settle.
Yeah, so did I.
Rachel called.
She wants to come out
a day early for Christmas.
Mark Greene?
Dr. Burke. Nice to meet you.
You too. And you are?
Dr. Elizabeth Corday,
Dr. Greene's fiancée.
Oh, congratulations. Thank you.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I met some resistance
in tumor board.
Is that good or bad?
The oncologists and
radiation therapists
are having trouble
embracing the future.
Meaning?
Come over here.
They see a lesion like yours,
they jump to the
conclusion it's inoperable.
But it's not?
Not in my hands.
There's your tumor.
Now, as you were
doing verbal tasks,
there was increased blood
flow to language centers.
Those light up in orange.
As you can see,
while the tumor's
adjacent to Broca's,
it hasn't invaded yet.
That's not what the
neurosurgeon in Chicago said.
That's why you're here.
So you'll operate?
Mm. Yeah. We'll do
an awake craniotomy.
You'll be conscious and talking
while I map out Broca's
and resect the tumor,
but the real bonus
is my ability to insert
high-dosage chemotherapy
wafers into the tumor cavity
and use the malignant
cells themselves
to create a cancer vaccine.
Thank God for
second opinions. Yeah.
Those idiots on the tumor board
are satisfied with
12-month survival,
where most of the
patients on my protocol
are disease-free for
24 months and counting.
So when can you fit
him into the schedule?
How about December 31?
You can ring in the new
year with a load off your mind.
Brain-surgeon humor.
Right.
You okay?
Yeah, sure.
It's good news.
It's very good news.
You came to the
right place, Mark.
Dr. Carter! Wake up, Dr. Carter.
Multivictim MVA coming in.
Hell's Angel versus a minivan.
What?
Motorcycle hit a
minivan. Let's go.
Fortyish-year-old male,
closed head trauma.
Altered at the scene.
No helmet?
You kidding? This
moron was driving a hog
in the middle of winter.
Lost the IV.
Put another one in.
Cut the Gap collection off
him, get him on a monitor.
Ugh. Scissors can't
cut through this.
Use wire cutters.
Pupils are poorly reactive.
Check this out. This
ain't his first crash.
He's got brain
fluid in the right ear.
Let's get him in line for a CT.
That's a nasty scar.
That probably explains this.
Vicodin for pain, Hyzaar
for high blood pressure,
Lipitor for cholesterol. Yeah.
I've heard Hell's Angels
are on a pretty good diet.
Carter, Weaver needs you.
It wasn't a minivan,
it was a "van" van.
About a dozen kids got hurt
on the way to a
Christmas pageant.
Okay, I'll be right there.
Yeah, but that's why I wanted
to handle this thing in person.
Peter, she's not
your responsibility.
I know that, Cleo, but...
Look, I don't want
her bothering Jackie.
I just, I don't want...
Kynesha?
I'm sorry, Dr. Finch.
I didn't take your car,
but I think Tiny did.
Your keys was
missing, so I lied to you.
I was afraid you was
gonna kick me out!
I don't have nowhere to go.
Okay. Hank, can you
press against my hand?
Is my mom all right?
Abby, have you
seen this guy's mom?
Weaver has her.
Seat-belt injury.
CBC and UA here.
Dr. Carter!
What do you got? Be right back.
Nine-year-old MVA. Head
lac from broken glass. No LOC.
150 of saline in the field.
Open tib-fib
fracture on the right.
Hi, sweetheart.
What's your name?
Elise.
Elise? Does your neck hurt?
Yes.
Okay, let's go to Trauma 2.
What kind of costume is that?
Milkmaid.
What? Milkmaid.
You mean like "The
Twelve Days of Christmas."
We're missing our play.
What is this guy
still doing in here?
Oh, CT just called for him.
They had a code on the table.
Take her to Curtain 3 until
this room is cleared out.
Come on. CBC,
C-spine, right tib-fib,
5 of MS for the
pain, a gram of Ancef.
Don't worry, Elise, everything
is gonna be fine, sweetheart.
Oh, God.
Hold still. You
have to let me look.
It hurts!
I know. I know.
What do you got?
Three more from the van.
This is Eddie.
Cracked his collarbone.
Right with you. Yeah?
Hyper number one.
Seat-belted in,
no obvious trauma,
complains of belly pain.
Give these to Dori in Curtain 3.
Take him to Curtain 2.
Give me a set of vitals.
I already did. BP,
110 over 70. Pulse, 90.
What?
BP, 110 over 70. Pulse, 90.
Whoa! Slow down. Sorry.
You all right? Yeah.
Kids in Exam 4 need
their necks cleared.
Come on. Come on!
Does it need stitches?
I don't know. I
have to get an x-ray,
make sure there's no
broken glass in there.
Is my mom coming?
I need to talk to
you. Just a sec.
Now. Is my mom coming?
Yeah, somebody called her.
Here, can you hold this for me?
And press down,
but don't make it hurt.
Lindsay, can you? Yeah.
What?
I took two Vicodin.
I took two Vicodin. I...
Then I panicked and
ran in the bathroom
stuck my fingers down my throat.
You vomited them up?
How'd you sign 'em out?
I didn't. I didn't.
This biker comes
in with a full bottle.
Well, good. You
didn't actually...
I don't even know
what I was thinking.
I didn't plan on taking anything
I just saw them, and I...
It's okay.
Are you gonna tell Weaver?
I can't.
I think you have to.
Well, then, I'm done.
I mean, best-case
scenario, I'm back in Atlanta.
I mean, does it count? It
was never in my system.
All right, I'm off
in 10 minutes.
Let's go to a meeting.
I just started.
Well, you're sick. You threw up.
Tell Weaver you have to go home.
You have to be
on death's door...
Go convince her.
♪ Oh, the weather
outside Is frightful ♪
So you'll tell Rachel
and Jen now?
Yeah, I'll fly out there Friday.
You like it?
What?
The pizza.
Mm.
It tastes just like it did
when I was 8 years old.
It's weird how that works.
I wouldn't have been
able to remember
it if I hadn't tasted it again.
It's good, though.
You lived in New York?
Couple of months.
Dad taught me how to
skate backwards on this rink.
You never told me that.
You never came to
see me play hockey.
No, that you lived here, I mean.
Well, I can't tell
you everything.
I have to keep you interested.
You didn't sign
up for this, though.
It's called marriage, Mark.
We're not married yet.
You really believe that?
Didn't think so.
Hey, check it out.
There's a kid in another
one of those hats.
They must be on sale someplace.
Guess it blows your theory.
Yeah.
It was a good day.
♪ But if you really
Grab me tight ♪
♪ All the way
home I'll be warm ♪
Hey, Malucci!
I'll catch you later, chief.
Carter went home
sick. I need you to stay.
Come on, chief!
It's part of being a resident.
He's just tired. He stayed
up all day with Chen.
All the more reason
for you to lend a hand.
I just need you for
four more hours.
Damn these hiccups.
Okay, I got an 85-year-old
with abdominal pain,
headache and dizziness.
This sucks, man! Yeah, it does.
I saw the patient in 7.
She agreed to a
voluntary admission.
Thank you.
Hiccups.
Does it work?
I don't know. I'm desperate.
Now I'm listening to Randi.
Did you like it?
Yes.
First edition.
Must have been expensive.
Well, what's the point
of working like a maniac
if you can't spend
money on friends?
Friends.
I don't think we're in
the same place on this.
On what, Christmas?
No. Us.
I don't need any more friends.
Oh.
Okay. Okay.
I understand.
Do you?
No. No. I like you
and I respect you,
and I thought we
were really hitting it off.
That's the problem.
You're straight, and I'm not.
And I've done this before.
It didn't work out, and I
am not gonna do it again.
But I'm not asking
for that from you.
We're comfortable together,
we have a lot in common,
we have fun together...
That's why I can't
be your friend, Kerry.
You want me to get that?
Yeah, could you?
Room 914.
Yes. Hold on.
It's your mother.
She's sleeping right now.
Can I take a message?
I don't know. Okay.
She wants you to call her.
Put a "do not
disturb" on the phone.
Sure.
Thank you.