Previously on The Resident...
What happened in the
elevator stays in the elevator.
I'm taking your pulse
to make sure you don't
have an arrhythmia.
We are never gonna
have a normal life
if you keep overreacting
to every little thing.
- They found Julian's car.
- Did they find her body?
Still searching.
The landlady let me
in to get Julian's cat.
And you just took
her phone bill?
Look at the last number
that Julian called.
It was an office at the FDA.
Is Jessie being tested?
Stop going through
my stuff, Nic.
Quit lying to me! I'm
done trying to save you.
You want your pills? Take them.
♪ Please don't judge me ♪
♪ I am acting,
acting differently ♪
♪ And you know me, you know ♪
♪ Know what's inside ♪
♪ Please always love me ♪
♪ Even though I
lost my mind... ♪
I have a surprise for you.
I made a reservation.
To a place you've been
talking about forever.
Stop. No, you didn't.
- At Juniper Zest?
- Yes!
How did you get a
reservation on Valentine's Day?
Ah, anything is possible
when you call eight
months in advance.
I'll have to meet you
there. I've got that...
Family Day thing
at Jessie's rehab.
Right. Well, I'm sorry.
That won't be fun.
Mm, which part?
The part where you
hear endless stories
of people hitting rock bottom
or the part where we
do family trust falls?
Oh, my mistake. That
sounds like a blast.
Oh, God.
- Do you need anything?
- No, I'm fine.
♪ Please always
love me even though ♪
♪ I lo-I lo-I lost my mi-ind ♪
♪ Wake up, survive,
I will get better... ♪
Mina's been filling
me in on everything.
- Any word from Julian?
- How's your heart?
One thing I'm a little sick of
is everyone asking
me, "How's your heart?"
I hear that.
I found your shirt.
It was still in the
guest room closet.
- Why are those here?
- Don't look at me.
They're for Gertie
down the hall.
It's a thank you for
taking Julian's cat.
Aw, Gertie's a good woman.
She deserves flowers.
As for me, I told Micah no
flowers, no cards, no candy.
- I'll walk you out.
- So I take it
you guys don't have
plans for tonight, then?
Oh, I don't do
corporate holidays.
Oh, she's crazy. I think all
holidays are great holidays,
especially the ones
featuring chocolate.
Look, if you change
your mind about being
wined and dined
tonight, let me know.
- ♪ Please always love me
even though ♪
- Bye.
♪ I lo-I lo-I lost my mi-ind. ♪
- Micah has a key now?
- It was only logical.
Such a romantic.
Micah and I are right
where we should be.
No drama, no surprises.
So let the man take you to
dinner on Valentine's Day.
Oh, is this Dr. Devon
I see with Miss Mina?
Hi, Gertie. I was actually
just coming to see you.
Thank you again
for taking Julian's cat.
Oh, please. Needy Pete's a joy.
That's what I'm calling the cat.
Little kitty can't
stand to be left alone.
Here. Gluten-free, dairy-free,
- sugar-free, still delicious.
- Hmm.
Secret recipe.
You come by and visit with
Pete and me any old time, okay?
Not on Tuesday afternoon.
That's Pilates day.
Wednesday and Thursday is yoga.
Monday and Friday is tap class.
Guess what I'm
saying is call me first.
You got it.
Thanks.
Hmm, I think she wants
to be your valentine.
Hilarious.
You'd make such a cute couple.
Happy VD, boss-man.
What do I have today?
Uh, couple of meetings,
and tonight that
black-tie fund-raiser.
Do you need a date for that?
Lots of lonely,
desperate ladies today.
No, Grayson.
Look, don't say I'm the
one that told you, but, uh,
the 'rents are
back on the rocks.
What?
My mom's mad at my dad again.
Maybe you can get back in there.
Grayson, for someone
in my position,
tonight's fund-raiser is as
necessary as it is boring.
And consequently,
I'll be going alone.
However, you may not be aware
that I have a
long-standing tradition
of spending "VD" with
a scalpel in my hand,
so I need you to book
back-to-back surgeries.
I don't care what the
specialty is, make that happen.
- You got it, boss-man.
- Don't call me boss-man.
- You got it, boss.
- Nope.
I got your text.
You know the last
person Julian called?
I tried that number
again on the way to work,
and I finally got a
person on the other line.
It's an FDA agent
named Mark Truscott.
He was the last person
that Julian called.
- Did he say why she called?
- No.
Did it have anything
to do with QuoVadis?
No. She wanted advice.
She was thinking
about changing careers.
I guess that makes sense,
given what she told you
about things being off at work.
Yeah, but Truscott
scheduled a meeting with her.
And she never showed.
That's very odd.
I don't even think the police
are looking for her anymore.
It's like everyone has moved on.
Except me.
What do you think we'll
see the most of today...
Suicide attempts or
proposals gone wrong?
- Such a cynic.
- How do proposals go wrong?
You know, hot-air
balloon mishaps,
accidentally drinking engagement
rings in champagne glasses,
people doing stupid
things in the name of love.
See, that's why it's
better to do stupid things
- in the name of sex.
- Hear, hear.
Hmm.
You know you're supposed
to read those first, right?
"Wink, wink." High
literature indeed.
I ordered some
special ones online.
Just for you, Irving.
Um, I think HR would discourage
me from reading these out loud.
What are you doing?
Well, I figure if
I'm going to accept
a fortune from a
stale piece of sugar,
I should at least have
control over what it says.
Oh, look at that.
- "Real love."
- Yeah, don't bother.
Another one with the cynicism.
Listen, bruh,
instead of focusing on
resentment over what
we currently do not have,
let's use today
as an opportunity
to celebrate what's to come.
AJ Austin, doctor of love.
70-year-old female found
unconscious and asystolic.
A neighbor initiated CPR.
She's been down for
30 minutes. Still no pulse.
All right, stop compressions,
hold ventilations.
Gertie.
Time of death: 9:06.
She was fine an hour ago.
How did she die?
♪ ♪
I only stayed
there a little while,
but still, Gertie remembered
everything about me.
She delivered cookies
for all the holidays.
She acted like
everyone's mother.
Except in a good way.
She once told me that
the boys used to call her...
Flirty Gertie.
Dr. Okafor and Dr. Pravesh.
This is Gertie's niece, Nora.
It's nice to meet you
both. Is Aunt Gertie okay?
Uh, please, have a seat.
Gertie was found unconscious
in her apartment building.
Someone called 911,
and the paramedics did
everything they
could to revive her...
but your aunt died.
We are so sorry for your loss.
Damn it.
Of course. Of course she
died, today of all days. Damn it.
Now what?
Well, you were listed
as her next of kin.
Great. So who do I need to call?
Funeral home? Cremation place?
Chastain social workers
can help with all of that.
If there's someone
else you need to notify,
like other family members,
they can help with that, too.
There is no one else.
I'm her only living relative.
How long until the
insurance money kicks in?
Look, I know that she was sweet
to everyone else, but with me,
it was judge, judge, judge.
She hated every guy that I
brought home, every damn one.
But this time, I thought
she might like him.
He's nice, no kids, owns
a bike shop in Portland.
I don't make a lot
as a telemarketer,
so I was coming over
today to ask Gertie for money
to help me move to be with him,
and I don't know if she
would have said yes, but...
Doesn't matter.
This is giving me another
one of my headaches.
Where's the, um...
the death certificate?
We don't have the cause
of death yet to list on it.
She's gone. Say she
died from being old.
Calling the cremation
place to come pick her up,
so give me that
death certificate ASAP.
Your ortho consult's in Bay Two.
Chet Aiken, 26-year-old male,
single, motor vehicle accident.
Ugh. Boys and their cars.
Yeah. I had to put
him behind a curtain.
He was freaking people out.
License and registration.
They said a doctor
had to get it off me.
Well, that's true.
Looks like a clean impalement.
- Hold the door.
- Hmm?
- Think of England.
- What?
Mmm!
Sorry. Sorry, sorry, sorry.
Had to be done.
You're lucky you didn't
hit any bone or arteries.
- Do you have any neck pain?
- No.
You were the driver, right?
How fast were you going?
Um, I don't know. I couldn't
see the speedometer.
How did the door
end up in this position?
These look like
seat belt abrasions,
but they're on the
back of your neck.
Did the airbags deploy?
I don't see any facial
bruising or lacerations.
I-It happened so fast.
She was fine, but
my-my seat belt wasn't on.
You had a passenger?
Is she here?
No. She didn't want to come.
I mean, we didn't know
each other that well.
You weren't driving in the car.
Her profile was awesome.
Like, so awesome that I thought
I might be getting catfished.
Her name even
sounds fake pretty.
- Bella. Am I right?
- Mm.
And then I meet her,
and she's as hot
as she is online
and funny and smart,
and she asked me to get
coffee today, on Valentine's Day,
so, I mean, she must
like me, too, right?
She must like a part of you.
And then after coffee,
we ended up in my car.
But not-not out in the
open. We're not animals.
But one of us hit
the emergency brake.
We rolled down the hill,
and, bam, right into a fence.
It's just, I can't quite work
out the physics of the thing.
Well, the seat was here,
and-and... and she-she was,
she was strapped in, like...
And I... I was
more... I was like...
I am an idiot.
Mm, no, you're gonna be okay.
Hello. Dr. Hawkins.
I'm Andre. This is Otto.
How fast can you
get him admitted?
Oh, honey, don't be
so extra. It's just a virus.
Just give me some
fluids and acetaminophen.
Two years in med
school a century ago
does not make
you a doctor today.
- Says you.
- Got out while you could.
Good for you. Yeah.
What do you do now?
I'm a substitute teacher.
Middle school. That's
why he talks like that.
Oh, you low-key love it.
And I want out because we've
got lit Valentine's plans tonight.
Denied.
- Wha...
- We're saving our nickels.
It's too late. I
already made a rezzy.
- All right, what can you tell me
about your symptoms?
- Allow me.
He's been tired, weak, dizzy,
and some of his
joints are swollen.
Are you on any medications?
Oh, zero. I-I've been
sober for 20 years.
I don't even take an
aspirin for a headache.
- Stubborn old coot.
- Mind over matter, my love.
I like that. I'll be back when
I have your initial lab results.
Uh, Dr. Hawkins,
hold on, please.
We have a catastrophic
health care plan
with a high deductible.
- Joys of insurance, huh?
- Mm.
Don't worry.
I will only order tests that
are absolutely necessary.
Give the appy in OR
Three to someone else.
I want the partial colectomy
that's on the way in.
Yes, Dr. Bell.
I need to fast-track an autopsy.
Today I'm a surgeon.
Ask somebody else.
It's for a patient who
died very suddenly.
She was an active 70-year-old
with no apparent symptoms...
- 70? It was her heart.
- That doesn't make any sense.
We can't know that
until the autopsy.
She was a nonsmoker, she
participated in her community,
she was physically
active on a daily basis.
Why are you still talking about
an autopsy like it's a
forgone conclusion?
They cost thousands of dollars.
Unless the family wants
to pay out of pocket
or the coroner wants it
or her insurance authorizes
it, it's not happening.
It's not coming out
of Chastain's budget
because, trust me...
it's always their heart.
Dr. Okafor.
I understand the patient
brought into the ER today
was a friend of yours.
She was my neighbor.
- My condolences.
- Thank you.
You want to talk about it?
No.
Excuse me, I
need to make a call.
Hi, Micah.
I changed my mind about dinner.
See? I knew it.
Deep down, you
love Valentine's Day.
No. But I love you, and...
you love Valentine's Day.
And life is too short.
I don't want to be selfish
and just think of myself.
No, you're not being
selfish. You literally
think about everyone.
And I like where this is going.
So, we can have dinner
with all of the traditional
couples tonight.
Yes. It's a little late
for reservations... we might
end up at an all-night diner.
But if I'm with
you, it's all good.
Good news, Chet.
You're gonna be just fine.
We reduced your
wrist dislocation
and cleaned up the wounds.
We put you in a splint, and
as long as you keep it immobile,
it should heal quickly.
I'll write you a
prescription for antibiotics
so you won't get an
infection in that arm.
Thanks so much, Doc.
Oh, don't mention it.
We're a little backed up
because apparently this holiday
makes people do
oddly dangerous things,
but someone should be in
in a bit and get you in a sling,
and you can get out of here.
This is the kind of crap
that only happens to me.
I meet a hot girl,
I think she's into me,
and I do something stupid.
Well, to be fair, you did have
a slight technical malfunction
when you hit the
emergency brake.
- No one could've predicted that.
- Maybe.
But she wouldn't even
come to the hospital with me.
I mean, I should've had
car sex with a nice girl.
- You'll get through this.
- People like you don't get it.
I mean, you've never
done anything like this.
Well, maybe not
exactly like this.
You're severely anemic
and your sodium's low.
Looks like someone's getting
steak and spinach
for dinner, extra salt.
I already told you, Italian.
We have a reservation.
Otto... you're
also showing signs
of low kidney failure, so I
need to run some more tests.
You won't be able to
leave the hospital today.
On the upside,
cafeteria makes
a mean spaghetti.
I'll bring two bowls up,
we'll pretend we're in Italy.
Remember Rome,
when the Pope blessed
us in the streets?
You wish.
The Pope is not known for
his great love of our people.
Well, maybe it's a
blessing in disguise.
I can cancel tonight
and put that money
into that Alaskan tour
we always wanted to take.
I'll be back when
I have the results.
Oh, remember that
Caribbean cruise we went on?
Oh, how we danced.
Damn it.
No one cares about
the truth, not the police,
not this hospital.
Gertie's primary care physician
said she died of
atherosclerosis,
which she was
never diagnosed with.
Uh, it's because of her
age. We can't get an autopsy
because no one cares
what kills the elderly.
And now we're supposed
to give a death certificate
to the family that
says a lie. It isn't right.
The government bases their
stats on death certificates.
We might have to
work outside the system
if we want to get this done.
Would you consider donating
Gertie's body to science?
Chastain has a relationship
with a local university...
W-Why?
Well, you'd be helping
to educate future doctors.
Look, my head is killing me.
I'm not weeding through a
bunch of extra paperwork.
I just want her
death certificate
so I can get the money
and move to Portland.
If you donate her body, you
don't have to pay for a funeral.
And I'll get the
death certificate?
Where do I sign?
- What do we have?
- His oxygen levels are dropping.
He was talking about the Pope
and he wasn't making any sense,
and then he started
coughing up blood.
Oh!
Page Pulm and Thoracic.
Tell them he has
massive hemoptysis.
I need that airway cart now.
Step back.
Bronchoscope.
Thank you.
I need a double-lumen
endotracheal tube.
His left lung is hemorrhaging.
What are you doing?
I'm inserting this tube
to block off the bleeding
and to allow the good
lung to keep getting oxygen.
- Will he be okay?
- We just bought Otto some time
so we can figure out why
this bleeding is happening.
Let's get him to
Interventional Radiology.
- Oh, hello.
- Hi.
- Surprise.
- What?
- Mm.
- Ooh.
Mmm.
Ooh.
Hold on, hold on.
Someone might come in.
Oh, so let them.
It's Valentine's Day,
- and I'm getting some sugar.
- Wait, wait, wait.
Do you want to meet on
the on-call rooms on three?
Huh? I could sneak up there
and meet you in a few minutes.
Or we could walk
up there together.
Jess, come on. We're at work.
- And?
- And it's not professional.
So what? Other people
have relationships at work.
It's complicated, that's all.
I don't think it's
complicated at all.
You come to my
apartment, you make pasta,
we watch movies, and you
rub my feet, and you like it.
- Can you...
-
just a little less?
No, I cannot!
What, are you ashamed of me?
That's... No, of course not.
That's a crazy thing to say.
Okay. Well, then
let's go, right now.
Take my hand and walk
down the hall with me.
Hmm.
You know, no one thought
you were any great
prize either, Irving...
but I did.
Hey! How's it going?
Oh, you know, ball of fun.
Yeah, I bet. You doing okay?
Oh, sure.
Turns out, trust fall
thing... Not a joke.
- Oh. Anyone get dropped?
- No, but I thought about it.
You know what Family Day is?
It's a day for addicts
to blame their families
for their addictions.
I'm about to kick a
few people in the shins.
Well, that sounds about right.
There's more.
There's a group
thing in the morning.
I have to stay
overnight. I can't
come to the restaurant with
you, Conrad. I'm so sorry.
That's okay. We'll
do it some other time.
Oh, but you called eight
months ago to book a table.
I'll just give it to
somebody else.
Nic, really, it's just a
day on the calendar.
- Of course you need
to be there with Jessie.
- It sucks.
I know.
Door three closing.
I got to go. Another
session's starting.
- Don't kick anyone.
- I'll try.
Happy Valentine's
Day. I love you.
Happy Valen...
What in heaven's name? Chet!
Chet, are you okay?
Unlock the door!
Ow, she broke me again.
Bella, I assume.
Sorry. He said
he was good to go.
I said you had to be gentle.
It was nice to meet you.
Biopsy results are back.
He has an autoimmune disorder.
It's attacking his blood vessels
and it's what caused the
anemia and the kidney failure.
Polyarteritis nodosa.
It's treatable with medication.
Once we've got it under control,
you can go back
to your normal life.
Right.
Our normal life.
Andre, this is good news.
Otto will recover.
I know.
But...
that's not the only
thing going on here, is it?
He's talking about a
cruise we never went on.
And about Tijuana and
this casino in Vegas.
All things we said we'll do
someday, but we haven't yet.
Now, at first, I thought
he was joking or confused,
but then I called to cancel
the Italian place near our house.
It turns out, he never
had a reservation there.
It was a lie.
Or he forgot.
Or he was drunk.
His drinking...
That's why he didn't
finish med school.
I was young; I thought I'd
scored with this hot doctor.
Then he started lying
about where he'd been,
what he was doing.
Took me years to figure it out.
Then years for him to get sober.
And it was worth it because...
God, I love that man.
But now here we are.
I can't do this again.
Andre...
I don't think Otto is drinking.
Nothing indicating that
came up in his blood tests.
Then why is he doing this?
Tell me more about what he says.
How would you like to do
something epic and romantic
for Valentine's Day?
What do you have in mind?
Cut into my dead neighbor
lady to find out what killed her.
You're asking me to
perform an autopsy?
Since we technically
don't have permission,
we'll say it's for
your anatomy class.
So you want me to help
you steal an autopsy.
Sexy. I'm in.
Gather around the table.
Don't get in their way.
You know, I forgot how
easy it is to maneuver
when you're not trying
to keep someone alive.
And when you don't have to stop
to suction blood out of the way.
Are we late or something?
Did class already start?
Yeah, why wasn't this
field trip in the syllabus?
Shh. Let the
surgeons concentrate.
Look, they skipped the lungs.
In honor of the holiday,
we decided to start
- with the heart.
- I wanted to see the lungs.
My parents pay a lot of
money for my education.
Well, you tell your
parents congratulations.
Today, they got a deal.
Most students at your
level have never seen
a fresh cadaver dissection.
You, coupon cutter,
if this cadaver had
atherosclerosis,
what would the
arteries look like?
They'd be hard and narrow.
Correct. Now look
at these babies.
They are as wide
and free-flowing
as summer water
on a mountain range.
There's no plaque at all.
Explain, student.
This person did not
die of heart disease.
If atherosclerosis
didn't kill her, what did?
I intend to find out.
Hello?
Those candy hearts were
extremely inappropriate.
They gave me an
inappropriate idea.
See, this day is all about
couples, which, let's face it,
can be hell for the rest of us.
Now, I'm not
looking to couple up,
but I could use a distraction.
A distraction?
Mm-hmm. I'm not
in a thing right now.
I've never seen you in a thing.
You do like sex
with women, right?
Great.
Then my place, your
place, I don't really care.
Just be freshly showered,
bring your own birth control,
and no cuddling after.
It's a onetime offer, and I
will deny it ever happened.
So?
Congratulations.
You just sexed yourself
into a Galeazzi fracture,
and now I have to
operate on your arm.
I'm sorry.
Who does their
business in a hospital?
Do you have any idea how many
bacteria are festering in here?
One in 20 patients contracts
a health
care-associated infection.
What were you thinking?
Bella texted to see
if I was all right, so...
I thought that maybe we
could be a thing, after all.
The time for her to
ask if you were okay
was when you were
removed from her vagina
and put into the ambulance.
She didn't do that,
which means she is not
looking for a relationship with you.
But she said she never
had sex in a hospital.
There are love matches,
and there are sex matches.
You're saying that this
is only a sex match?
I'm saying this is neither.
And now we get a look
inside this woman's computer.
Don't you see inside
people all the time?
We're not neurosurgeons.
We don't often get the
opportunity to witness
the majesty that
is the human brain.
♪ ♪
So, as Dr. Okafor
dissects the brain,
she is using a technique called?
Fiber tract
dissection technique.
She's looking for evidence of
a disease process that
could cause sudden death.
Mystery solved.
Cause of death:
ruptured brain aneurysm.
Why did she have an aneurysm?
- Any guesses?
- She was born with it?
That's often the
case, but this woman
was 70 at the time of her death.
That is a long time to live
without knowing about
a congenital defect.
She may have
some other condition
which could cause
the aneurysm to form.
In an autopsy, we have
the luxury of a deep dive.
We found no evidence of
disease in the thoracic cavity.
Now we get to explore
further in the abdomen.
Let the party begin.
♪ ♪
Liver looks clear.
Kidneys do not.
What are those?
Cysts. A lot of them.
It looks like Gertie had
polycystic kidney disorder.
Can go undetected for years.
Brain aneurysms are
often complications of PKD.
It's a genetic condition.
Her niece Nora is
having headaches.
Oh, well, she
could very well have
- an aneurysm like her aunt.
- Yeah.
We need to get her into an
MRI machine immediately.
I'll alert the radiologist.
We need a stat read.
And if we're right,
there's a ticking time bomb
waiting to go off in her head.
Why am I back in this room?
Did someone else die?
Nora, the professor of the class
you donated Gertie's body to,
he found something.
Your aunt died from
a brain aneurysm.
He also found cysts on her
kidneys, leading us to believe
that she had polycystic
kidney disease.
We think you may have it, too.
- That's crazy. I feel fine.
- So did Gertie.
This morning, you said
you had a headache.
Which I got from you,
because everything
about this is terrible.
But then you had
another one later on.
- How often are you getting them?
- I mean, most days,
but my life is annoying. It
would give anyone a headache.
Okay, we need to do
an MRI of your brain
to make sure that's all it is.
So, I don't even have
the insurance money yet,
and now I have to spend it all
on some tests that I don't need?
This is what doctors do.
I don't like overtesting
any more than you do.
But in this case, your
life could be in danger.
This is the only
way to find out.
Well, my insurance is crap.
How much is that
gonna put me back?
Okay, we can talk
to billing about it,
but, Nora, listen to me.
If you have an
aneurysm in your brain,
it could rupture at any time.
We need that MRI.
Oh, fine.
Okay.
Grab your things.
That in there is one hot mess.
His wrist is the
least of his problems.
Yeah, I've made some
mistakes in my life,
but being that guy is one
I've managed to avoid.
So what's the rest
of your day like?
Oh, after this,
quick lap chole, and
then a fund-raiser.
Oh, Cupid Fights
Cancer in Midtown?
- That's the one. You going?
- I am.
Seems kind of silly
to take two cars.
It does, doesn't it?
This is Otto's MRI.
Uh, loss of brain volume,
the obvious atrophy.
You're looking at
damage caused most likely
by years of alcohol abuse.
These symptoms
are just surfacing now
after Otto's been
sober for years.
People don't realize
the damage from alcohol
can last a lifetime.
There's no surgery.
There's no medicine.
There's no way to repair this.
Dementia's only gonna get worse.
I'll speak with Andre.
First time in a
brain, Dr. Okafor?
A live one, yes.
Ah. The vessel
walls are so thin.
They are.
The patient's lucky you
caught this when you did.
It was about to burst.
Look, here's a second aneurysm.
That one is smaller. Less risky.
You know the surgical adage,
"See one, do one, teach one"?
I do.
Well, you just saw one.
Care to try doing one?
I would.
Hmm.
Isolating the vessel.
The surgery was a success, Nora.
You had two aneurysms,
and they've both been fixed.
And I won't get any more?
And now that you're
aware of your PKD,
you can go in for regular
screenings to minimize risk.
And it's all because you
donated Gertie's body to science.
No.
It was because of Aunt Gertie.
She was a good woman.
I will miss seeing her
in the building and...
Anyway, did you get
that death certificate?
I'm gonna need her money
to pay for this operation
and move to Portland.
It's called "confabulation."
He's getting things confused,
so his brain makes
up the reality for him.
But why is it happening?
We think it's a result
of brain damage
due to his past alcoholism.
Sometimes the damage
shows up years later.
He's having a hard time
differentiating between
what did happen and
what could happen.
But the most important
thing to know is that Otto
doesn't mean to hurt you.
We were saving
our nickels for Paris.
For Zurich, Bora Bora, Vietnam.
I know this is difficult, but
you can still be together.
Once Otto is stabilized,
he can go home with you.
Home. We were gonna
see the whole world.
I know. But if you
want to be with Otto,
you now have to find a way
to be with him in his world.
♪ ♪
Andre, why are we still here?
Did we go out for
Valentine's Day?
I-I can't recall.
Let me show you something.
♪ ♪
♪ Follow me into... ♪
Oh, it's so beautiful.
Did we go to Paris?
I-I can't quite recall.
We did go.
And it was beautiful.
- Oh, it's Spain.
- Yeah.
Vejer De La Frontera.
We sat near that fountain,
and we kissed for hours.
I remember.
It was so romantic.
♪ Next to you ♪
♪ Walking with a ghost ♪
Hawkins, I got your
text. What's good?
Eh, you know what's
happening in there?
Looks like a lot of money
spent on stock images.
That's a couple in love.
And when one
couldn't leave his world,
the other found a way to
make it better than reality.
Interesting.
Here.
Word on the street is
you're quite the romantic.
Well, I have been known
to write a sonnet or three.
What's this?
It's a reservation
for a very hot table
- at a very hot restaurant.
- Whoa. Wow.
I can't go, so you
should take someone.
You know, I hear
their scallop appetizers
actually make the angels weep.
Thanks, man, but I think
I'm gonna pay it forward
- and give it to someone else.
- Who?
Someone who's already in love.
♪ I am here alone next to you ♪
♪ Walking with... ♪
Jessica.
I want to show you something.
Before you say no, just look.
Really?
A crappy sign and
a mid-floor hookup?
Just because it
happened here once...
Jessica, wait.
I freaked out.
I thought maybe if I
went public with you,
people might think it was funny.
Because it's so funny
that someone would
want to be with me?
No. Because of me.
No one here has ever
looked at me that way,
like an option.
But I guess that's not true.
I could be with someone
else, just like you could.
But I don't want that.
Chastain maintenance
put that sign up.
They gave us 30 minutes.
♪ ♪
You told maintenance about us?
♪ Can you hear me? ♪
♪ Can you hear me... ♪
I'm gonna tell everyone!
♪ I am here alone next to you ♪
♪ Next to you ♪
♪ Walking with a ghost... ♪
Wow. Don't you look dapper.
I could say the same thing.
Could you? You'd say "dapper"?
N-No, no, I wouldn't,
I wouldn't prob...
I wouldn't say... I mean,
dapper wouldn't be the...
Shh.
♪ Can you hear a raven call? ♪
♪ Shadows on an empty wall ♪
♪ Distant even
though we lay close... ♪
Shall we?
♪ Hollow hands... ♪
Well, we don't want
to be late, do we?
♪ Can you hear me? ♪
♪ Can you hear me...? ♪
♪ If you can't feel me ♪
♪ If you can't ♪
♪ I am here alone next to you ♪
♪ Next to you ♪
♪ Walking with a ghost ♪
♪ Walking with a ghost. ♪
You were supposed to be at
the most exclusive restaurant
in Atlanta right now.
The restaurant I
have brought to you
is so much better,
you have no idea!
There's a band playing
the most romantic...
♪ I can dream about you ♪
Oh.
'80s pop songs.
- I'll take it.
- Okay.
We are serving
gourmet cuisine, starring
the string fromage,
uh, some sort of
processed meat stick thingy,
and two apples,
only mildly bruised.
- Very nutritious.
- Exactly.
And to drink, we have
the sparkling water.
Because I have to drive back.
But if there's anything
you taught me...
Everything tastes
better in a wine glass.
♪ How to hold me just right ♪
♪ Moving... ♪
- Happy Valentine's Day.
- Mm.
♪ I don't see under my feet... ♪
Mm.
With everything that's
going on with Jessie,
I wish there was
more I could do.
I know.
But you being here makes
everything a bit better.
♪ I can dream about you... ♪
And this, I mean...
Just about perfect.
♪ I can dream about you ♪
♪ You know how to
hold me just right ♪
♪ I can dream about you. ♪
Uh, for the record,
I called this place,
and they said
they couldn't even get me
in until next Valentine's Day.
Lucky Dr. Austin
gave us his reservation.
He says to try the
scallop appetizer.
All right.
You okay?
- You're all sweaty.
- I'm fine.
Your pulse is racing, too.
No, it's not. Please, stop.
Thank you.
Micah? Someone call 911!
He's had a heart transplant!
Wait, Mina. Wait, wait, wait.
Okay, so my pulse
may be racing a little,
and it is my heart, but it's
not because of my transplant.
Dr. Mina Okafor...
will you marry me?
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH