As doctors,
we rely heavily on data
to treat our patients
and minimize risk.
So when there is no data,
any move can be extremely scary.
- What are you doing
here this early?
- Getting stood up.
You?
- Couldn't sleep.
- ♪ I've decided to no
longer be contained ♪
♪ Oh, no ♪
- Enjoy.
We have to solely
practice medicine on a hunch,
relying on instincts and hope.
Sometimes it does
not go our way.
- Hey, why do you drive
slower than my grandma?
- I drive the speed limit.
If you need to whine,
maybe find a bus.
- Maybe we should
leave earlier then.
- Maybe someone should
stop staring at themselves
in the mirror all the time.
Why you hiding?
- I wanna scrub in
on one more surgery
before Altman fires me
for moonlighting at Joe's.
- She's not gonna fire you.
Helm took a stand for you.
- I didn't ask her to.
I have no idea what she said.
She doesn't even
know what she said.
She was in a rage blackout.
What makes her think she
can speak for me at all?
- Okay. Go.
Go, go, go, go, go.
Sometimes it does.
Before there was a
cure for diabetes,
scientists followed
their instincts
and gave sick children
an experimental
extract called insulin.
As terrifying as it was,
that risk has now saved
millions of lives.
- Ladies first.
- ♪ Know I'm
landing on my feet ♪
- Oh, I'm good.
But even if
your hunch is strong,
before taking the leap,
some part of you always worries,
"What if I'm about to
make a huge mistake?"
- Okay, great. Yeah. We'll
see you then. Thank you.
Okay. Luna's first auditory
verbal therapy is on the books.
I just have to reschedule
her audiologist,
find her a speech therapist,
get caught up on notes,
and deliver a baby.
- Can I help with anything?
- Um, you wanna deliver a baby?
- I was kind of hoping
for one of the other jobs.
- It's okay. I
got it. Thank you.
- Hey.
- Can you do a
consult in the ICU?
- Sure. I've got about 20
minutes before my next consult.
- Oh, you're gonna want
to reschedule that.
- Hey, uh, about this morning,
I... I get a ride into
work with my roommates...
- Don't care.
- Uh, okay. I...
Well, I... I thought you'd
yell at me or something.
- Yeah, I don't... I don't
care about the excuse.
I care that you did not show up.
- Right.
- So I'm about to tell
you a bunch of things
I need you to do today,
so I would suggest
you write it down.
Um, round on my post-ops,
then check with pathology
to see if Mr. Kane's
biopsy results are back in.
After that, I need you to review
tomorrow's patients' PT/INRs.
Tell me if anything looks off.
And then Sarah
Hawkins in bed seven,
when her blood sugar stabilizes,
turn off her insulin drip.
And put these notes
into the charts, 'kay?
And, Adams?
I hardly yell.
- Okay, the patient in
bed three can go home.
Just follow-up in the
clinic in two weeks.
Dr. Kwan?
Um, I... I haven't had a
chance to just say thank you
for stopping that patient
when he came after me.
- Oh, no, no, no.
It... it was nothing.
- It was not nothing. It
was very much something.
And I am grateful, so thank you.
- Maxine?
- Oh.
Call me Max.
Maxine makes me feel
like a grandmother,
which I am, of course,
but no need to
broadcast the fact.
- Are you looking for Jules?
- No.
And don't you dare
call her down here.
I don't want to worry her.
- Well, is everything all right?
- Well, I woke up
feeling a bit dizzy.
I'm sure it's nothing but at
my age, better safe than sorry.
- Well, let's take a
look. Come with me.
- But don't I need to check-in?
- Oh, no, no. You
are VIP. Come on.
Oh, finally.
Right over here.
- Sorry, sorry.
- What's with the
emergency meeting?
- We have an intern problem.
- Oh, is this about
Yasuda working at Joe's?
Because from what I understand,
it was only a couple
of weeks and it's over.
- Yasuda was working at Joe's?
- Yes.
- I thought Helm
worked at Joe's?
- And Yasuda.
- Why does any
surgeon work at Joe's?
- Because the system is broken.
And according to
these, they have to.
- What is this?
- It's the intern
surveys of the program.
I asked Schmitt to hand them out
and these are the results.
- "The lockers are from 1955."
- "Need low-fat oat
milk in the cafeteria."
- "More hypoallergenic
pillows in the on-call room."
- This isn't a spa, Altman.
I wouldn't put much
stock in these.
- Yeah, I didn't
until I read this one.
Uh, here we go.
"Our salary doesn't even equal
the average cost of
living in Seattle."
- Well, that can't be right.
- It is.
They included research.
- The patient was in a wingsuit
accident in Sun Valley, Idaho.
- Wingsuit? Like, skydiving?
- More like BASE jumping.
He slammed into a granite
wall at high velocity.
- I'd question his
personal choices,
but people like that
keep me in business.
Any major head injuries?
- Miraculously, no.
He was initially stabilized,
had wash-outs, and was
splinted at Boise General,
but they didn't have the
resources to do the rest.
- What'd he break? Femur?
Tibia? Humerus? Pelvis?
Yes.
- Don't worry.
Feels worse than it looks.
- So, you and Jules, huh?
She's quite the catch.
- It's not like that.
We're just friends.
- Friends with...
What'd they call it now?
"Benefits"?
- She told you that?
- You know us girls;
we spill the tea.
- Ms. Anderson.
It's good and not
good to see you again.
You feeling a little woozy?
- Well, it's not bad, really,
but after the last go-around,
I don't want to
take any chances.
- She's a bit tachy.
BP is slightly low.
- 'Kay, um, you know what?
Open your mouth for me.
Yeah, you're a
little dehydrated.
So as long as you're here,
we'll just run a few tests,
make sure nothing
else is going on.
- 'Cause I'm a VIP.
Exactly.
Uh, let's run a CBC,
CMP, urinalysis,
and give a bolus of IV fluids.
Uh, I'll come back and check
on you in a little bit.
If you need anything,
Dr. Kwan's your guy.
- Okay.
- So what else has
Jules told you?
- Nope. Can't tell you.
- But you just said...
- Sorry.
It's... what did she call it?
It's girl code.
- Sam Sutton, 44,
wingsuit versus
boulder, 24 hours ago.
GCS, 15, no evidence of TBI.
Has a left-sided pneumothorax
with a chest tube
placed at the other hospital.
Sustained multiple fractures
to all four extremities, ribs,
as well as stable
spinal fractures.
- Sam, this is Dr. Lincoln.
He is Chief of
Orthopedic Surgery.
- Do you mind if I take a look?
- Please.
- All right.
Have we ordered CT angio
on all four extremities,
check for blood flow?
- Dr. Hunt did this morning.
- All right.
Okay.
- Yeah, I can wait to
remove the dressings
until we're in the OR.
Is it annoying is if say
you are extremely lucky?
- Say it. He has,
like, 50 times.
- You tried to glide
through a 2-meter hole
in the side of a mountain.
- Oh.
Well, you could have
been right there with me.
Kwame was my copilot
in the Air Force
and now we're wingsuit buddies.
- Wait, you mean
a literal wingman?
- Except I prefer to go
around the giant rocks.
- How's it look?
You think I'll be back to BASE
jumping in a month or two?
- Uh...
- Kidding.
I know I'm lucky to be here.
But I did promise my nephew
I'd teach him how to ride
his bike this summer.
Like to make good on
that. What do you think?
- Um, I'll take a closer look
at your scans and X-rays,
but I gotta be straight with
you, the damage is extensive.
- If anyone can help,
Sam, Dr. Lincoln can.
He is the best.
- I'll do everything I can.
- Hey, Doc.
- Yeah?
- Can I ask you
something real quick?
- Of course.
- He's the surgeon who
operated on the Tank.
Should we get a second opinion?
- Dr. Lincoln is an exceptional
surgeon with a stellar record.
And the best of us
can have a bad day.
- Hmm.
Every time Sam's mind
takes him to a dark place,
it's his body that
ends up saving him;
marathons, martial
arts, diving off cliffs.
He needs his limbs and
I need him to live.
So don't have a bad day.
- I will do my best and
my best is pretty damn good.
Page me when those
scans are up, please.
- Yeah.
- Oh, um, Adams
gave me these, uh...
These notes that you scribbled
with, like, wedding stuff.
I... I spilled a little
bit of kombucha on them.
So if you wanted, you can
text me and when you...
I'm... I'm your new
Maid of Honor now.
Did he not tell you?
- He did not.
- Okay. Uh, well,
nothing to worry about.
I am not going to
do the blood thing.
In fact, I am not
going to do anything.
Unless you text me.
FYI, I am partial to cat emojis.
- Hey, do you think
they're gonna be in there
for a long time?
- According to the OR schedule,
they all cleared their
electives for the morning.
But it only takes five
minutes to fire someone,
so who knows.
- I just... I just can't
read Marsh's handwrit...
Do you know what this says?
- I'm about to lose
two jobs this week.
I really don't feel
the need to help you.
- How about for a liver
transplant recipient
on the fifth floor?
- I can't read that.
- Huh. I don't remember
assigning either of you to
the service that takes care
of patients in the hallway.
- Okay.
Okay, but how good are you at
reading Marsh's handwriting?
- "Check Prograf level
and stop Protonix."
- Thanks.
- How many bones did
he actually break?
- I've counted 75 so far.
He's got comminuted fractures
in all the long bones.
- Plus the rib and spinous
process fractures too.
- Yeah, we don't have to
worry about those for now.
They'll heal on their own.
- It's incredible that
his spine is still intact.
- Nothing's where
it's supposed to be.
It's like...
- He's a jigsaw puzzle.
A broken one, obviously.
But we can put him back together
one surgery at a time.
- Wait you're... You're
gonna do this in stages?
- Well, uh, we'll
need to reconstruct
his right femur first,
using cadaver bone to
fill in this defect here.
Once that's done, we'll wash out
and fix the left extremity
since its already open.
Then we'll go in the next day
and fix the left
femur and tib, fib.
And the right extremity and
digits can wait for last
since they're stable for now.
- Um, why not fix all
four extremities at once?
I mean, isn't there
risk of sepsis
from the open wounds if we wait?
- Well, if... If
you put him under
for an extremely
long period of time,
you're looking at a high risk
of anesthesia complications:
bleeding, clots.
- Life over limb.
- Exactly.
And if the bone and
tissue loss is too severe,
we may have to amputate.
- No. No way. I'm
not doing that.
- You're not doing what?
- I don't want one
of my arms or legs
to die waiting in line.
- Well, no. I'm not saying
that that will happen,
I'm saying it could happen.
I wouldn't be doing my job if
I didn't put all the risks
on the table for you.
Trust me, this is
the safer option.
- Compared to what?
- Is there another option?
- We could do all
the repairs at once,
but it is a much longer surgery.
- Which I strongly do
not recommend due to
the possible complications...
- But waiting also
has its downsides.
Muscle death from
such a severe injury
could lead to potentially
fatal consequences
or you could get sepsis
from the open wounds.
- Those are also
heavy complications.
- Yes, but we would...
- I was trained to assess major
risks and take them anyway.
So let's do this.
All or nothing.
- Wow. I think they're starting
Dr. Lincoln's
wingsuit surgery soon.
- Uh-huh.
- Mentioning it in
case you thought
maybe I could go
up there for a bit?
- No.
- To observe?
For my education?
There's, like, 91 broken bones.
- That's cool. But still no.
Ms. Anderson, uh, I'm afraid
your urinalysis came back
positive for a UTI.
- But I always pee after sex.
- And that's good.
But you can also get a
UTI from dehydration,
especially as we get older.
- I drink all the
time; tea, mint juleps.
- Those are diuretics.
They cause dehydration.
Yeah.
- I know. I'm just kidding.
Yeah, I admit, I could be
more diligent about water.
- Well, we're gonna put
you on an oral antibiotic
and some more IV fluids, 'kay?
Dr. Kwan will be nearby
if you need anything.
- Don't be mad at Adams.
- No, I'm not.
I probably shouldn't
have asked him.
- You definitely shouldn't have.
- Just wanted to go through
it with a friend who knows me.
- Well, I know you.
Unless you meant a friend who's
had their tongue in your mouth,
because I could be convinced.
Okay, quick. What's your sign?
- Taurus.
- Oh, that tracks.
Film or TV?
- Sleep.
- Fair. What's your
favorite crystal?
- What are you doing?
- I'm getting to know you.
- How's it going?
Anybody have a funny
joke, a good story?
- Uh, it's just a
little while longer.
We're making sure that
there's blood flow
in your extremities.
- Since I have a minute, listen.
I'm worried about Kwame.
He's my ride or die and...
I might die.
So I'm gonna give you
his wife's number.
And if I die,
I need you to call her.
If I die, I need you
to make sure that
she comes to pick him up
because he will be a wreck
and he won't be able
to drive himself safely
and he is too proud
to call her himself.
Can you do that for me?
- I'll take the number,
but hopefully, we
won't have to use it.
- How's it look?
- CT angio shows signs
of diminished blood flow
all over the place.
I'm still trying to
wrap my head around it.
- We need to get him in
OR as soon as possible.
Staged surgeries.
Then you tell him we
could do it all at once.
- It's what he wants.
- He wants to live, Hunt.
And staged surgeries
is how he lives,
one manageable piece at a time.
- If he loses his limbs,
if he can't jump...
In the Army, I was trained
to run on adrenaline,
risk, and terror, and
when I got home...
War makes you alive
and dead, Link.
And regular life
gets dull really fast
when you come home from that.
The thrill of being
a trauma surgeon is
the only thing that saved me.
Sam is not a daredevil.
He is a veteran
coping with trauma.
And even if he can
never jump again,
he needs the hope that
there is something out there
that can make him feel
more alive than dead.
- Get out.
- What?
- You're not an orthopedic
surgeon so get out.
- Are you refusing
to do the surgery?
'Cause the longer that we...
- No, I'm refusing to
waste more time talking to you
when I need to figure out
how to do the damn thing.
I will call you when I need you.
But, respectfully,
Hunt, get out.
- My first idea was
to appeal to Catherine
and to the foundation.
- Well, residents' salaries
are government-funded and
they always have been.
And, I mean, money may be tight,
but when you're in training,
you don't need a fancy car.
I mean, you eat a
lot of canned soup.
- Grilled cheese.
- Pasta.
- Cereal.
- See? I mean, we all did it.
And besides, a hospital covers
a resident's
malpractice insurance.
They have free parking,
meal stipend of up to $15 a day.
- Where can you get three
meals a day for $15?
- Cereal.
- Pasta.
- Okay, neither one
of you are helping.
Oh, shoot.
I got a 911 in
the ICU. Gotta go.
- Oh, hey.
I'll tell you another benefit
they have that we never got.
The hospital pays the residents
to have four weeks
paid vacation a year.
Uh, yeah, that started
when I was coming up.
My great-aunt died
and I asked for a week
to go help my mom.
- And did you?
- When I asked,
my attending asked me if I knew
why we were called residents.
"Because we live
in the hospital."
- Did you go to the funeral?
- I did not.
- Mm.
Did I know the
attending at that time?
- It was you.
But the one that got away...
That was Marshall.
We met in pre-law.
- You were a lawyer?
- Oh, heavens, no.
But a lot of good-looking
young men wanted to be.
No, I...
I preferred the literature
classes I took on the side.
So I ended up teaching
Austen and Miller.
Marshall, well,
he had a fire in his belly.
Confident and strong
and so handsome.
I never told him
how I felt, though.
- Why not?
- I was waiting
for him to come and
sweep me off my feet.
Too many romance
novels, I suppose.
Some days I still kick myself.
- Coming through.
- Trauma two,
Hang two units of blood.
- Check his pulse.
- How exciting.
- How's his airway?
- Go.
Go on. I'll be fine.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
Come back and tell
me all about it.
- Okay. I'll come right
back and check on you.
- Why am I quicker to
answer a page than you?
- I just saw it. What happened?
- You failed to
follow my directions,
that's what happened. I told
you to check her blood sugar
so you would know when to
turn off the insulin drip.
- Crap. I just hadn't
gotten there yet.
- Yeah, I asked you
to do that hours ago.
And because you didn't,
she went into
hypoglycemic shock.
- Is she okay?
- For now.
- No, no. Dr. Marsh, I...
I swear I was just...
- No, I don't want excuses.
I don't want 'em. I want
effort. I want change.
I offered to help you.
I sat with you and I gave
you advice on how to improve.
I have rooted for you
because I know you can.
So when you continue to
be distracted and late
and make careless mistakes...
- I'm trying.
- Try harder!
If you want me on your side,
then you need to grow up.
So get your meds right.
- My meds?
- You're clearly struggling
with your ADHD, so fix it,
or you risk losing your career
before it's even started.
- Two of my co-residents
were pregnant when I came up.
My chief told me if I
could keep my legs together
I would be asked to scrub in
at least five times a week.
Ooh, remember Davidson
from Vascular?
Oh, gosh.
- He once asked if I had
been a good girl that year.
And if I had, I should ask
Santa for some surgical skills.
- No.
- Ew, gross.
- At my intern orientation,
a senior resident played a video
of the people running with
the bulls in Pamplona.
And even on that grainy film,
you could see three
people get gored by bulls.
He said, "This is what your
internship is gonna be.
"Every day you're gonna wake up,
"you're gonna start to run,
and hope you don't
anger one of the bulls."
- We are not bulls! These
are horrible stories.
And they probably
don't even account for
half of what we experienced.
Yes, there is something to
be said for... for family,
and tradition, and adversity
making people stronger.
But if our interns
are experiencing
an ounce of the abuse
that we suffered, we...
- I yelled at Yasuda.
She dropped a retractor
and I kicked her out of
the OR and off my service.
- Well, you had a lot going on.
Doesn't make it okay.
- It doesn't, and that's
why we have to do something.
- Um, excuse me for a minute.
Hi.
Hi, you okay?
- Hey, have you seen Dr. Marsh?
- No.
- Do I have ADHD?
- Yeah, I see it.
- I forgot to turn
off an insulin drip
and a patient went into
hypoglycemic shock.
- And you still work here?
Do you know how many classmates
I've served fries to
while wearing a paper hat?
A lot.
It wasn't fun, but I did it
because I was determined
to be a surgeon.
And now I have made
it all the way here
and half of the surgical
chiefs are meeting about me
because I took a second
job to make ends meet.
But you,
you almost kill someone
but it doesn't matter
because you're related
to surgical legends.
- You're gonna be
working on this patient
until you retire.
- I heard. 91.
- Uh, 93.
I just found two more hairline
fractures in his pelvis.
- Everyone's talking about it.
- Great.
- Hunt said you're gonna
repair all four limbs at once.
- Yeah, I really wish
Hunt would shut up.
I'm the one who has to plan a
potentially 19-hour surgery.
I'm the one who has to consider
the risks of putting a patient
under anesthesia for
that amount of time.
I have to plan for every
possible catastrophe:
stroke, PE, heart attack,
and 50 other complications
screaming through my head.
And you'll be the one
who would lose a patient like
you lost Jermaine Talbott.
And then you would have
lost the Tank and this guy
with everybody watching.
- It's not an unlikely scenario.
- Okay, but in the scenario
where everything goes well,
what do you need?
- To grow an extra pair of arms.
Or three.
Two teams. One to help
me reduce and repair
the fractures in one extremity
and one to position the
next extremity ahead of time
and begin the wash-out process.
Plus, our best person to perform
vascular anastomoses
and rotational flaps.
Not to mention
someone to help me
place the osteoarticular graphs.
And a full anesthesia team
to care of the
resuscitation process
throughout the whole thing.
It's at least six surgeons.
- Well, you've got one more.
- Thought you had
to deliver a baby?
- I did.
Mae Ashley, 6 pounds, 8
ounces. She is beautiful.
'Kay. Who else you need?
- ♪ Hey, hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ My mind is in motion ♪
♪ My head is in the clouds ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ What is it you're
waiting for? ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ D-Day's knockin'
at your door ♪
- They still talking?
- Yeah.
Lincoln says it's important
to plan the work...
- So you can work the plan.
Yeah, I've heard it before.
I know that you're worried,
and I'm guessing it's related
to that football player,
Jermaine Talbott.
And you're thinking whether
another long surgery
on a guy who's supposedly
in shape could go south.
And I'm guessing
you're wondering if
Lincoln is the right
guy for the job.
- Uh...
you're not wrong.
- I know you better
than you think.
And if it helps,
my last ortho surgery
was an amputation.
And I think you know
I'm really hoping
I won't have to do that again.
- ♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ D-Day's knockin'
at your door ♪
- You were assigned to the ER.
- I know.
- You know and yet your patient
was wandering the halls?
- I know and it
won't happen again.
You're lucky I owe you one.
- Dr. Kwan, welcome back.
- Max, I'm so sorry I
was gone for so long.
- Even though you were
expressly told not to leave.
- Oh, don't be silly.
I had a terrific time.
I even ran into one
of my favorite people.
Benson, this is
my grandson, Hugh.
He's a doctor too.
- Ms. Anderson, I'm
Dr. Schmitt, remember?
- Hugh, tell them
about the time that
you helped save that man's
life on the airplane,
when he choked on,
what was it, a grape?
- I'll tell them.
Um, let's put her on
telemetry, get blood cultures,
and start her on
broad-spectrum antibiotics.
- She's more
hypertensive and tachy.
No, she's definitely septic.
Admit her to the ICU right now.
- Is she...
- She has delirium from the UTI.
- So your labs are looking good.
You're ready for takeoff.
To the OR.
Sorry.
- Me too.
You're giving Kwame
stiff competition
in the dad joke category.
- Hey, my kids
think I'm hilarious.
Mm-hmm.
- I'm getting paged to the ICU.
It's a 911.
- Well, go. I've got this.
How many kids do you have?
- Uh, three. And
one on the way.
And they love their Uncle Sam.
- And I have pitched
the name Sam every time.
Maybe if I don't make
it out of this surgery,
you and Kelly'll finally do it.
- Ah, don't say that.
You gon' make it.
- I plan to.
But I've been lucky enough to
have a life full of adventure
and if this is where
that luck ends...
- Hey, Griffith, can
you check to see if
the OR is ready? And
we will take him up.
- Absolutely.
- Thank you.
Hi.
- Excuse me, who are you?
- Oh, I am Dr. Wilson. I
am one of your surgeons.
It's nice to meet you, Sam.
- This may come
across as forward,
but I might be dying
in the next 18 hours,
so I'm gonna ask.
Are you single?
Remember, I might be dying.
So if you're not, you could lie.
- I'm single.
- Great.
Now I have something
to live for.
Excuse me.
Hi. Sorry to interrupt.
- It's okay. You've
got good timing.
- Yeah, we were just
talking about you...
- I have made mistakes.
I accept that responsibility.
I accept that there
will be consequences
when I don't do things right.
But right now, it feels like
the biggest mistake
that I have made
is not having enough
money to work here.
I wasn't born with
a silver spoon.
I don't have the family
pedigree to fall back on.
And my student loans are real,
and the risk of my
parents losing their home
if I can't make my loan
payment is also real.
And... and what? The promise
of an attending's salary
ten years down the line?
That doesn't do anything
for me right now.
I think you all know that I
bust my ass for this program.
And I will continue
to devote myself to
becoming an excellent surgeon.
But that devotion has to
include working a second job.
- Well, actually, it doesn't.
- I quit.
Can't fire me 'cause I quit.
- You're not getting fired.
You're getting a grant.
- We are starting an
emergency relief fund
for any resident
that might need it.
It's not gonna pay
off all your loans,
but it will help make ends meet.
And we would like for you
to be the first recipient.
- Unless you've quit.
- No.
No, I don't quit.
I rescind my quitting.
Thank you.
You have no idea how
much that means to me.
- Well, we kind of do.
Sometimes we just...
We need reminders.
- Yeah.
- ♪ I can't wish you away ♪
- I gotta prep for surgery but
I got your page, and what...
Max?
- ♪ Trying to get back
to who I was before ♪
- What the hell happened?
- ♪ But she's not
there anymore ♪
♪ She's not there ♪
- The cadaver graphs ready?
- Thawed and prepped.
Sam's ready too.
- Dr. Lincoln...
are you sure this
is the right plan?
There are so many risks.
And when we operated
on Jermaine Talbott...
- Griffith, we all
know what happened.
I'm sure Dr. Lincoln's replayed
that surgery in his mind
hundreds of times.
That was a complication that
could have happened to anyone
at any time and he
doesn't need an intern
questioning his skills,
professionalism, or his plans.
- Except it's not my
plan, Hunt, it's yours.
- Dr. Hunt, what I meant was...
- Griffith!
If you don't share my
confidence in Dr. Lincoln,
I suggest you keep
it to yourself.
- I'm sorry. I did
not at all mean to...
- Don't be sorry.
Jermaine's surgery haunts me,
so I can't imagine
what it's done to you.
Procedure went perfectly.
Post-op clot was the last
thing on anyone's mind.
But none of that makes it any
better for him or his mom.
But I need you focused.
I need your head clear.
I need you with
this patient today.
Because this is what Sam wants.
And we're his best shot.
- ♪ I feel the love ♪
- Millin's out.
Bailey sent me in to cover her.
- Your, uh, one last surgery?
- Oh, screw that.
I'm just getting started.
- ♪ Carry me off to a place ♪
♪ A place I've never been ♪
- Full house.
Could have sold tickets.
- All right. We're ready.
- Okay, everyone,
this is Sam Sutton.
He is a veteran and a hero.
And we thank him for his service
by keeping him alive today.
- Let's do this.
All or nothin'.
- This will be a very
long, complex surgery.
You will get hungry.
You will get tired.
Your feet will hurt.
And when that happens,
I want you to think about Sam,
because there is no
margin for error.
We will get through this
because we will get
Sam through this.
All or nothin'.
- ♪ I'm changing ♪
♪ This time it's
for the better ♪
- I'm Maxine's contact.
Why didn't you call
me when she got here?
- She said not to.
- She came into
the emergency room
and you didn't think to
notify her emergency contact?
- Okay, she was fine
when she came in;
just dizzy. We ran tests.
We started treating
her infection.
I got her everything she needed.
- Clearly.
- And then she apparently
left her bed and...
- What do you mean she left?
Where were you?
- She told me I could go.
- She said you could go
so you just took off?
Is she the patient
or the doctor?
I mean, wh... what, were
you stealing another surgery
or flirting with that nurse?
- Okay, what is
this really about?
- This is about an
81-year-old woman
who is now septic and delirious
because you didn't do your job!
I've got it from here.
- I'm not typically
one to judge,
but who was the
first fool that said,
"Maybe if I put on
a squirrel suit,
I'll make it to the other side"?
- Franz Reichelt.
He attempted to jump
from the Eiffel Tower
in a wingsuit in 1912.
I... I was really into
aviation when I was a kid
so I know weird stuff.
- Did Franz make his landing?
- Hit the ground headfirst.
Oh.
- ♪ How long before
the levee breaks? ♪
♪ Hold on till the
darkness fades ♪
♪ Cold sun ♪
♪ Trying to find
its way through ♪
♪ These days feel like
a cold steel cage ♪
♪ Reaching ♪
♪ Hoping to find
something I believe in ♪
♪ Show me something true ♪
♪ Day comes in like
a blade of light ♪
♪ Breaking down to
the wrong and right ♪
♪ Taking all that I got ♪
♪ Something's gotta give,
gotta give, gotta give ♪
♪ Can you hear the sound? ♪
♪ Oh, it's calling now ♪
♪ Mercy ♪
♪ Nothing left to lose ♪
♪ But to give in to mercy ♪
♪ Mercy ♪
♪ Lift me up ♪
♪ Take me higher ♪
♪ Lift me up, take me higher ♪
♪ Lift me up ♪
♪ Take me higher ♪
♪ Lift me up, take me higher ♪
♪ Lift me up ♪
♪ Take me higher ♪
♪ Lift me up, take me higher ♪
♪ Lift me up ♪
♪ Take me higher ♪
- ♪ Lift me up ♪
- ♪ Take me higher ♪
- Sam...
- He's out of surgery.
- You did it.
- Well, it's not over yet.
- He did.
Dr. Lincoln was able to
save all of his limbs.
I'm not sure there's another
surgeon who could have.
Sam is lucky
for multiple reasons.
And one of them is that
he was brought here.
- He's stable for now.
I'll monitor him closely.
But he still has a
long road ahead of him.
We can't say when but we
think with extensive PT
he will be able to walk again
and use his fingers fully.
- Ah, he will.
Sam, he's sort of the friend
who defies expectations.
- Hmm.
Well, he'll be back
to his room soon.
You can go see him.
- Thank you.
- Course.
Congratulations, Link.
You pulled it off.
- You ever put me in
that position again
in front of a patient,
we'll have a problem.
And Hunt.
- Hm?
- Thank you for your service.
- Yasuda, can I talk
to you for a minute?
Dr. Shepherd, I
am very grateful
for the grant money and
for not being fired.
But I just finished a very long,
very gnarly surgery
and I'm really not in
the headspace to process
whatever mistake you're
gonna say I've made.
- You haven't made
a mistake; I have.
I overreacted the other day
when I kicked you
off my service.
It had nothing to do with you.
You did not deserve it.
And I am a person who
believes in accountability,
so I apologize.
- I'm sorry too.
- For what?
- Nothing.
You make me nervous. I...
I meant apology accepted.
- Mm.
- Adams, you okay?
- Fine.
Listen, you deserved that,
but I should not have
called you out on your ADHD.
I'm sorry about that.
- Yeah, that, uh... It
kind of threw me off.
- You... you've never
had your meds adjusted?
- I don't have meds.
I... I don't have ADHD.
Or I, um...
I don't have a diagnosis.
- Ah.
- But I've been reading
up on it and, um...
- And things are starting to
come into focus a little bit?
I'm your program director.
I'm gonna notice some things.
Lack of attention to details,
hyperfocus,
uh, poor organizational skills,
improved performance when
complicated tasks
are broken down.
Adams, the signs,
they're all there.
Or maybe it just
takes one to know one.
Yeah.
Look, when I was
diagnosed in college,
I... I thought my chances of
becoming a surgeon were over.
But I went and I got
the help I needed
and now it's just
something I manage
like any other part of my life.
I always thought I was
just the black sheep.
You know, with this
program, with my family.
I never thought that I
might be neurodivergent.
- Yeah, well, typical
is just so boring.
- So what happens now?
- You go get checked out
and take it from there.
Easy.
- Dr. Lincoln. I was just
coming to check on his vitals.
- His H&H and electrolytes
are holding steady.
But I'm gonna stay by
his side, just in case.
- Understood.
That's a relief.
- Excellent work
today, Griffith.
- You too, Dr. Lincoln.
- Hey.
They told me you would be here.
Thought you could use a boost.
- Yeah. I'm just
realizing how tired I am.
Those are both for me, right?
You should go and rest.
I'm fine. I'll stay.
- 'Kay.
Want some company
till he wakes up?
- Yeah, I'd like that.
- Okay.
- ♪ Nobody heard the
hell that's behind ♪
Oh, my goodness.
The
experimental drug,
the impossible dream,
the fork in the road;
we face dozens of
choices every day
and have to weigh our options.
- ♪ Might hate me
now but hear me out ♪
♪ Hey, I only wanna know if
I should move out or stay ♪
♪ Whatever I did, just
say what you need to say ♪
Sometimes
you fail utterly...
- ♪ Nothing is wrong when
nobody's earned the blame ♪
- Dr. Weber.
What can I get you?
- I didn't listen.
I came here a
couple of months ago
to ask you to come back.
And when you shared with
me how difficult that was,
I didn't listen.
But...
I'm listening now.
What would it take
to bring you back?
- ♪ Hey, I only wanna know
if I should move out ♪
But to move forward,
you have to take
the leap of faith.
- ♪ Whatever I did, just
say what you need to say ♪
- Winston!
- No, I'm done for the day.
Do you need a consult
or can it wait?
- It's not a consult.
- Okay, great.
We'll talk tomorrow.
- Uh...
but it is something
that I wanna say now.
I owe you an apology.
I blamed you for Maggie
leaving even though I knew that
the truth is
complicated, and painful,
and, frankly, none
of my business.
But I took out my pain
and my sadness on you,
which has been
happening a lot lately.
You may be comforted
to know that
this is just one stop on the
Amelia Shepherd apology tour.
Even so, you are a
good man, Winston,
and marriage isn't easy.
I was wrong.
And I'm sorry.
- ♪ Hey, if this is the
end, why do we hesitate? ♪
You never
know where you'll land.