Surgeons are scientists
trained to believe
only in that which we can see and touch.
But that training doesn't always take.
How was it? Was he happy for you?
No. He was jealous.
It's the Harper Averys.
We're all jealous.
Oh, good.
Oh, my God! I'm so sorry!
I left some things here,
and I thought that you were
at the hospital.
It's no problem, Dr. Shepherd.
I'll just go put some panties on, si?
Probably a good idea, yeah. Yeah.
Si.
Yeah, I should probably
give these keys back, huh?
Mm.
Phew!
Wow. That French toast smells good.
You know, it's really good.
Yeah.
- Right?
- I'm gonna... I'm gonna take it to go.
I'll get the plate later.
- You can finish that first.
- Okay.
It's good. It's good.
See? See? You're mad.
I am not mad.
Then why are you taking the train...
I support public transit.
...when you can just ride with me?!
Because I can't count on you
- giving me a ride home, that's why.
- Ohh!
Look, I need to depend
on something in this world.
Miranda, just get in the car.
No, you do your thing.
I'm gonna take care of myself.
Wh... Wh... Wh...
As long as you're not mad.
I don't even know what day it is.
I don't know the last time
I changed my underwear.
Use the panty liners in the women's room.
They help.
The other day, I almost peed
in a supply closet.
Like, just for fun?
I couldn't find the bathroom.
Been here two weeks,
and I still don't know my way around.
Oh, God, I want to die.
You're welcome!
It's a private jet.
But private jets are bumpier
than regular planes.
All right, so pretend like
it's a roller coaster.
Or take a pill if you have to,
but you're going to that ceremony.
You're very bossy.
It seems like five seconds ago,
we were the interns
hiding in the tunnels.
Now you're about to win a Harper Avery.
What if I don't win a Harper Avery?
Then you're no better than the interns.
- Don't say that.
- Hey!
W... Slow down!
Sorry! Big trauma incoming!
Ooh. Trauma in the pit.
No, you have a plane to catch.
Aren't you curious?
Mer! Stop! Come on!
You're going to the awards!
How long do you think
you can pretend I'm invisible?
Well, it worked for you for years.
Blocked me on social media.
Yeah, because you moved
across the country,
and you didn't say goodbye.
Because you broke into my apartment.
Because you kidnapped my dog.
Because you wouldn't return my calls.
Look, Sam, we wreck each
other every time.
- I know.
- So what are you doing here?
You think I followed you here?
God. You give yourself a lot of credit.
Dean Parson, 40s male.
Status post blunt trauma
to the chest and abdomen,
shielded some kids when
a roller-coaster car came loose.
GCS of 10,
follows commands but nonverbal.
Pulse 120s, stable pressure.
Roller coaster? How are the kids?
Not a scratch. This guy's a hero.
Threw himself
between the kids and the car.
Okay, let's get him inside.
You two, come with me.
Hang in there, Dean.
Go, go, go.
What happened?
Rusty roller-coaster car
broke off the ride,
flew into a crowd at a county fair.
There's multiple injuries en route.
"Pretend the plane is like
a roller coaster," you said!
That's what you said to me!
Gregory Williams and Cleo Kim, both 26,
stuck in a crushed roller-coaster car.
Tried to extricate in the field,
but we suspect Greg has some
unstable crush injuries,
so we opted to do it in a more
controlled environment.
I told you
I didn't want to ride that ride.
I told you it was a rusty death trap.
Yes, Cleo. You were right, okay?
You're always right.
Now you're just stating the obvious.
I think I'm hallucinating.
Are you seeing what I'm seeing?
Seeing what?
George and Cristina.
What?
Are you seeing this?
How are you? Are you okay?
Get me out of this!
Get me out of this thing
so I can kill her!
I did not make you ride, Cleo.
"Ride for me. I'm too pregnant.
Let me live vicariously through you."
Seriously?
You're gonna blame me for this?
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
Oh, why are you gowning?
A major trauma just came in.
No, no, no. We have plenty of surgeons
that don't need
to be in Boston, Meredith.
What... O'Malley and Yang.
What's that?
Baby O'Malley and Baby Yang.
And there's a baby Izzie Stevens,
who's having a baby.
I mean, I definitely cannot
go anywhere right now.
What's the deal? She's afraid to fly?
Yeah, and afraid to lose.
I called your parents. They're flying in.
They wouldn't take, "We don't
know yet," for an answer,
so I made up some medicine.
What did you go with?
Minor blunt-force trauma
with no L.O.C. on the scene.
That's good. Sounds cool. Means nothing.
Are you guys doctors?
We're interns at Seattle Pres.
We are no longer interns
and haven't been for two weeks, Greg.
We are second years. Try to keep up.
I see another one of me, I'm leaving.
See, she seems stable.
Can't we get her out first?
No, not without jarring him.
I think we can open up his side
of the car
and just be ready
for crush syndrome symptoms.
All right, assess the damage
- and get me a timeline for extrication.
- All right, Doctor.
All right,
let's, uh, set up a crash cart,
get another I.V. going,
get him hooked up to our monitors.
Let's be prepared
when he comes out of this thing.
Okay.
Uh, wh-what are you seeing
so far, Kepner?
Uh, cuts and bruises,
couple broken bones,
some burns from the oil that went flying
when the roller-coaster car
hit the funnel-cake booth,
which perfectly describes
a recurring nightmare
I used to have as a child.
Uh, all right, let's re-route
everything minor to the clinic.
- Supervise the interns.
- Okay.
Make yourself available for quest...
- Ah...
- What?
Actually, Kepner, you stay here.
- We might need you on this.
- Okay, who's gonna...
Is that a roller-coaster car?
Yeah, it is,
but we need you in the clinic.
Uh, there were multiple injuries
when the car flew off the track.
Interns can't handle all that.
There is a major trauma in here,
and you want me to go
stitch up a clown's face?
Uh, clowns bring joy to children.
Scarred clowns lead
to traumatized children.
Go.
Dr. Bailey, how's that contest coming?
Hmm?
You know, I gave you over
$100 million about a week ago.
I don't know if you maybe got a name,
some judges, anything?
- Did you know?
- Know what?
When you handed me $100 million
and asked me to organize a contest
so that you could play, too?
- I know.
- Did you know that my husband
had secretly started training
to intentionally put his body
inside of burning buildings?
Right. So, uh, we'll talk this
over later, then.
Thanks.
You see that?
Free fluid in his left upper quadrant.
Splenic laceration?
Seems likely. Shepherd?
Pupils are equal and reactive.
He follows commands.
Okay, call the OR.
Tell them we're coming.
I want a head CT.
You just said
there are no focal deficits.
Probably just in shock.
We need to deal with his
life-threatening problem first.
Dr. Shepherd, I need a consult
on a head injury in the clinic.
Dean, I know that you're scared.
I know you want to talk, and you
can't, but we've got you.
He saved kids. He's a hero.
Get me that head CT.
Run ahead and book it.
Prep him to move! Let's go!
No. I'm fine.
Greg and Cleo are hurt.
No, Mom, the roller coaster
did not hit me.
Hey, um, would you let an intern
set a dislocated patella?
It's Izzie.
What?
You always ask about Izzie,
what she was like.
Well, that... that girl right there.
That... That's what Izzie was like.
Seriously?
Please don't say that word.
Oh, um, she's pretty.
Yeah.
And perky.
Yep.
Are you okay?
Yeah, it's just... weird.
Hey. Hi.
You were taking care
of my friends, right?
Yeah.
N-No, I mean, we just...
Your friends are okay.
They are? Like, okay okay?
No, I mean, they're...
they'll... they're like they were.
The same.
Oh, okay.
Well... I'm...
Ooh.
I just... I don't, um...
- Wait, do you need to sit down?
- Yes, please.
Oh, my gosh. Uh, we need a gurney!
Page Robbins!
Sorry I'm late.
I have Mer's dress and my dress
and Zola's dress and Zola.
Where's my mom?
That is an excellent question.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Well, the party is all here,
except the guest of honor.
Yes, there's a trauma in the pit.
And?
And Meredith felt
the need to get involved.
Wow. You totally called it.
My mom doesn't like to fly.
Right. I will go get her.
Crush syndrome can cause
arrhythmias and renal failure,
so we need calcium, bicarb,
and albuterol.
Look at them.
The way they're looking at you.
That's the "You're gonna die" face.
Shut up, Cleo.
That really isn't helpful.
We know that face. We use that face.
It's perfectly composed,
gives nothing away.
You should call your mom,
let her hear your voice one last time.
- I hate you.
- Hate won't get you into heaven.
You don't believe in heaven.
I'm not the one they're
looking at like that.
I-I can't... I can't breathe.
We need to get him out of there.
He's turning blue! Somebody do something!
His muscles are reperfusing.
Get ready to intubate and code.
Open up the airway kit.
No, no, wait, wait. It's not reperfusion.
It's his neck. He needs traction.
I got it. Got it.
Yeah, it's his neck.
Oh, God.
They really are all staring at me.
Am I gonna die?
It's not... unlikely.
They're staring at you, too!
Yeah, but I'm not the one
who has a lady doctor
attached to my cranium.
You're not gonna die
unless you keep talking
and moving unnecessarily.
Now, hold still.
Why are they all staring at us like that?
Because you look
exactly like our friends...
people we were interns with.
You look exactly like them.
- Both of us?
- Both of you.
Well, this is creepy,
and now I'm uncomfortable.
Even more uncomfortable,
if that's possible.
What's he like?
The... The guy that...
that I remind you of?
His name was George. He was a hero.
Was?!
Stop, Greg. What are you doing?
I don't want to be a trigger
for your memories.
I want to be me and him to
be him, so let's do that.
Stop looking at us!
We are not your friends!
It is uncanny, though.
Right?
I'm almost 30 weeks. It's a boy.
His name's Jasper, and he's perfect.
He was perfect at his 20-week ultrasound.
So I think I just passed out,
like, maybe from stress.
- You see that?
- Yeah.
What? Oh, my God, what is it?
So, Liza, you have a
chorioangioma, which is a...
A tumor. On my placenta?
Exactly. Are you a doctor?
A resident.
I've gone to every prenatal appointment.
I've had every ultrasound.
I've taken every vitamin.
They grow really quickly.
And at this size,
they can be very dangerous.
I think that you passed out
because you're having mirror syndrome.
So I'm mirroring the symptoms of my baby.
Yes.
So, he's... he's what? He's in distress?
He has hydrops.
His, uh, heart is struggling.
- Oh, my God.
- I think that we can remove the tumor
without delivering the baby,
but we need to do it right away.
And the good news is
if I do have to deliver,
you're at 29 1/2 weeks,
so the survival rate's really high.
Do you want us to call anyone?
No. I'm having this baby alone.
And my mom would just freak out.
And my birthing partner's
trapped in a roller coaster
that I made him ride.
So...
Will you stay?
Will you stay with me?
Little weird, but I'm gonna roll with it.
Hmm.
Grey, come on.
I'm a little busy here, Avery.
She can't move,
or my friend's spinal cord
will get severed by the fracture.
- Cleo! Shut up!
- Thank you!
I'm not your friend, remember?
You can't talk to me like that.
Except I can because I'm holding
his head in my hands,
and, by extension, the air in his lungs.
It's hard. I'm hot. It hurts.
So please shut up so I can
be still and concentrate.
Hold on a second. I'm gonna come
up there and help, all right?
I'm just gonna relieve
some of this pressure.
Okay, lean back into me.
Rest your arms. Okay? There we go.
Are we gonna miss the awards?
- Yeah, it's looking that way.
- What awards?
Wait, are you going to Harper Averys?
Wait. Oh, my God.
Grey? Is she Meredith Grey?
Yeah, and that's Jackson Avery.
Oh, my God, Greg!
You have surgical royalty
tractioning your head right now.
- Really?
- Bottom third of his class.
Whatever. Ignore him.
You're gods to me.
Dr. Warren, I have a patient
with intermediate partial thickness burns
from the funnel-cake oil
that flew when...
I don't need all the details, Dr. Bello.
Right. Um, we're out of xeroform.
Well, it's in the supply closet.
It's not. I checked.
Then you have to go to central supply.
Which is where?
He's trying not to scar my face!
Could you kindly support him in that?!
DeLuca.
Show Bello where central supply is?
How'd you get the idea for
the abdominal wall transplant?
From a hole in my bedroom wall.
You should not say that
in your speech if you win.
People, if we're not wheels up
in 20 minutes,
we will miss the show,
and we are the show.
We're almost there, Catherine.
Oh, my God, is that Catherine Avery?!
Oh, please.
Dr. Webber, we're good.
Okay.
Okay?
Okay, people, listen up.
We've got the traction tongs
and the pins ready to go.
We have access to remove this patient.
We are gonna lift him slowly
onto the gurney
while Dr. Grey continues
to secure his neck.
Once he is down,
I am going to start
to add on the weights.
Do we understand?
- Mm-hmm.
- Yes.
Now, on my count.
One, two, three.
Easy. Easy.
Okay. Easy.
I'm out of the roller coaster.
I'm out of the roller coaster!
Shh, shh, shh.
Tightening the screws now.
Adding the weights now.
Meredith, you can release your hands.
All right. He's breathing.
Thank God.
Okay, let's roll him for the CT.
Let's go, people!
Okay, I need a second.
I can't feel my arms.
I need a minute. Cleo, how are you doing?
All right. Removing the lap bar now.
Oh, my God, a puncture wound.
I need some gauze and
a non-rebreather now, please!
I didn't even know that was there.
My BP's plummeting. I'm losing volume.
Dr. Grey.
Call the OR! Let's hang some O-neg
while we check for type and cross.
Tell them she got penetrating
trauma to the right flank.
Okay, go. I have this.
No, no, no. You're the one nominated.
- You should go.
- I'm not gonna go anywhere.
If I win, just make a nice speech.
Where is that blood?!
Dr. Shepherd?
How's our guy?
Um, his wife is here with their kids,
and I-I don't know what to tell her.
Uh, well, was the CT clear?
Uh...
Um...
"Um," what?
- You skipped his CT?
- He was bleeding out.
If you were gonna skip a CT,
you should have paged me.
I made a call, Amelia,
and it was the right call.
His liver was actively bleeding.
I threw his spleen in the trash,
and he's still...
- Dr. Hunt?
- What?
She left.
It's a trauma.
I can page Owen if I need some help.
I'm saying you can still go win
your Harper Avery.
Pretend I'm your friend.
What?
I have too much promise to die.
I've got you. You're not Meredith Grey.
I want to grow up to be you,
so pretend I'm your friend,
the one I remind you of,
because you know her and you love her,
and I'm just the girl who's been
annoying you all day.
Please, Dr. Grey.
Save me like I'm your friend.
All right, let's go. She's not coming.
What do you mean she's not coming?
Well, she wants to stay here
and save lives.
Of course she does.
Zola, sweetie,
you tell your brilliant mama
that she's a big pain
in Dr. Catherine's behind.
How about you? Are you coming or staying?
Zola and I have work to do here.
Say hi to Boston for me.
Are you ready
for your first coronary bypass,
Dr. Grey-Shepherd?
Yes, I am.
We've almost got this, Liza.
You're doing great.
This is kind of a miracle.
What is?
That I was here when I passed out.
If this had happened anywhere else,
I might have just thought
I was overheated or overtired
and ignored it.
Then I might have died
or the baby might have died,
so it's like my own little miracle.
It's your own little miracle
that a roller-coaster car
flew off its rails and crashed
into a group of people
and crushed your friends inside of it?
When you put it like that,
I sound like an ass.
Yeah. A little bit.
See that? Small subcapsular hematoma.
We can keep an eye on that.
Dr. Hunt?
Nurse Linda? Amelia, what the hell?
Put this on.
You'll need it to protect you
from the radiation.
What radiation?
Skipping a head CT is not your call.
It is mine.
So you've left me no choice
but to bring the CT in here.
- Is this about this morning?
- What?
You seemed fine.
You ate the French toast.
Stop talking.
Amelia, there is no indication
that there's a head injury.
Zero.
I heard she had a brain tumor.
You think they didn't get it all?
I heard that.
Uh, CT shows
beading of a mesenteric vessel,
which means something's bleeding.
We'll find out exactly what
when we get in there.
And my neck?
You have a C5 fracture dislocation.
Now, as soon as we take care
of that abdominal bleeding,
Dr. Shepherd will do a spinal fusion.
And my friends?
They're both in surgery.
It was my idea to go to that carnival.
"Let's do something stupid," I said.
"We can't just work
every day of our lives," I said.
I pushed them, and now Cleo could die.
And Liza could die,
and, God, Liza's baby.
And I could die, too,
which no one probably cares about, but...
No one's dying today, Greg.
We'll take you up in a minute.
- I know.
- Sir.
I know how you felt about O'Malley.
Oh, these are not O'Malley tears.
I cried all of my O'Malley tears
over the real O'Malley.
I cried every day
for the better part of a year
silently in the shower.
No, these are
tears of rage... marital rage.
Okay, um, do you want to talk about it?
What is that?!
Uh, I think we both know what that is.
In the skills lab?
Th-This door doesn't even lock.
Hi.
I, uh, was just, um...
uh, g-g-getting a, um...
so I could... so I could
practice... things.
Okay, back to the pit.
Yeah, you need a plastic skull
in the pit?!
Do you, Dr. Bello?!
Don't you have a job to do, DeLuca?!
Uh, uh...
What the...?
I really hope there's not
a third one in there.
Almost done.
You see how easy that is?
He would have bled out
if we had waited for the CT.
And you're reading too much
into this man because...
It's okay. You can say it.
Dr. Hunt thinks
my decision-making is clouded
because my brother died
under similar circumstances.
But he's wrong.
- Am I?
- You are.
He has an expanding epidural hematoma.
Wait. What?
Wow.
Okay, let's get this thing out of here!
Prep for a craniotomy!
Monitors are on.
Pit's clear.
You need an extra hand in here?
I could scrub in.
Uh, if you want to be helpful,
you can go find Shepherd
and tell her we need her in here
to make sure this patient's
not permanently paralyzed.
I'm a general surgeon,
not a neurosurgeon.
And sometimes it's a good idea
to just do the job you're trained for.
- I know.
- Right.
You came into my flat
and didn't get up off the sofa
for three weeks.
I know.
You still love her?
How did she find you?
She got matched here.
It's a... coincidence.
Oh, Andrea, you're still
such an innocent bambino.
See there?
It's a simple procedure,
but not doing it would have killed him.
All this fuss for something
as little as one, two, three.
Okay.
"I told you so" is unbecoming on you.
Also, he'd be dead
if I'd done it your way.
Fair enough.
He's alive. That's what matters.
Go tell his wife and kids. Thank you.
Shepherd, uh, you're needed in OR Three.
Mm.
Amelia, I'm sorry if I implied that...
No. It's okay. You were right.
I mean, not about this morning.
French toast was excellent this morning.
But about Derek.
He was in my head.
He saved this guy.
He was that good.
You know, one could argue
I'm kind of saving him, too,
but I'm gonna let it go.
Yeah. I'm letting it go.
Suction.
I said suction, not retract.
I-I'm sorry. Here?
Where the blood is coming from.
R-Right. Got it.
Do we ligate or primary repair?
What do you think?
I think you should have gone to Boston.
What?
We're gonna ligate 'cause it's safer,
and it's a thing I could have done myself
while you went to Boston.
Kepner.
God, you're like Jackson.
He grew up with so much money
he never had to balance a budget
or check a price tag,
and he just takes it all for granted.
And you're like that with your talent.
You're... You're missing
the Harper Avery Awards
'cause you take for granted
that there's just gonna be another one.
You take your talent for granted,
and, you know,
some of us work really hard,
and we're just average.
You think I'm taking it for granted?
I'm not taking anything for granted.
I want that award so bad
I could pick you up
and throw you out a window,
especially right now because
my best friend's image
is splayed out in front of me.
Cristina Yang is the only one
who gets just how badly
I want that award.
And, Kepner, you're not average.
- Baby's having prolonged bradycardia.
- All right. Damn it.
Liza, we tried, but baby says
he wants to come out today, okay,
so I'm gonna convert to a C-section,
and I need Dr. Karev
to get his NICU team ready.
It's gonna be okay.
Oh, I'm scared. I'm scared.
Wilson, hold her hand.
I'm way past that.
I need someone to talk to me.
Please talk to me.
Okay, uh, what do you want to talk about?
Anything. Have you done this before?
- Are you a mom?
- Oh, God, no.
I mean, um...
Liza, I am. I'm a mom.
I have a... I have a daughter.
She's 7 years old,
and she's on a plane right now
coming back to live with me.
So she lives with her dad sometimes?
Uh, she's with her other mom sometimes.
Her dad, um...
What... What about her dad?
He died.
And I miss him all the time,
which is actually kind of unexpected
because I didn't
really like him in the beginning.
I resented him because
he was perpetually relaxed.
But he could make me laugh.
He could make me laugh when I was afraid
or freaked out or annoyed,
which actually is really,
really annoying.
If he was here right now,
he would say, "Relax, Robbins.
Your kid's coming here.
It's gonna be the greatest thing ever,
and you're freaking out
about paint colors.
You're gonna... You're gonna
take her to ice cream
and you're gonna let her pick
three different flavors,
and it'll be the best thing ever."
And he would be right.
Okay.
- Jasper is out, Liza.
- Aah.
Okay, good.
Now show me the inferior vena cava...
- Mm-hmm.
- ...and the aorta.
Wow. You are a natural.
You must get it from your mom.
My daddy, too.
I'm gonna be a brain surgeon like him.
You are?
I miss him.
Do you miss your mom?
Every day.
Want to know what my mom would say?
She would say,
"Even though your mom's not here,
she's always with you."
O'Malley's got a long road ahead.
- This isn't O'Malley, sir.
- I know.
And call me sentimental,
but it's nice to think of him.
Most of the interns
just blur together over the years,
but O'Malley... I can't forget.
And it'll be good to be able to save him,
to save this O'Malley.
Is he okay?
How you doing over there?
He's doing well on 50% O2.
So he's okay?
Yeah, he's gonna need some oxygen
and spend some time up in the NICU,
but you can hold him
for a minute if you want
before I take him up.
You ready?
Here he comes.
Thanks.
You think he's gonna make it?
I do.
I think he is going to make it.
Oh, no. So, you're threatening me now?
Is... Is that how you're gonna do this?
You turned away
from a career in anesthesiology
because you were bored
and you wanted to be a surgeon.
Now you're bored again.
Starting to sound like
a man with commitment issues.
Can't you just... Look.
Can't you just think of it like
I'm taking a fellowship year,
learning something new,
something that makes me happy?
You were my front runner
for Chief Resident!
Can't that make you happy?
I want a job where all this adrenaline
that's coursing through me
is a good thing.
I-I'm not saying I don't love surgery,
and I'm not saying that I won't
come back to it someday.
I'm saying that while I'm young enough,
I want to try this because I
don't want to live with a ghost,
- and neither do you.
- A ghost?
Yeah, the ghost of who I might have been
if I'd been brave enough to try.
Miranda?
Jackson called. Do you have a minute?
I do.
Alex, if you want to know how she is,
you should just call her.
You should call Izzie.
No.
No, it's okay.
I mean, I-I-I don't need to call her.
I know how she is.
I mean, she's, uh...
she's married with three kids,
and she lives somewhere,
I think, uh, kind of woodsy?
And she's a surgeon
and she goes to work every day,
so she refuses to hire help,
so her house is always a mess.
And it has Christmas decorations
all over it
because she won't let
her husband take them down.
It smells like muffins,
and she's... she's smiling.
When I picture her, she's always smiling.
I don't need to call her because
I want it to stay that way.
I picture her as happy as I am with you.
You imagined a whole life for her?
Oh, yeah. It's way better than wondering.
Mm-hmm.
All right, well, how is she?
She's good. She lost a lot of blood,
but we had to ligate
her transected IVC...
They were superheroes. Both of them.
I've never seen anything like it.
- Nobody asked you to talk.
- Right.
We're done here.
You can take her to recovery.
Hey, how's Baby George?
He's in recovery.
And Baby Izzie?
Oh, Baby Izzie has a baby.
Oh, that's so good!
Um, the Harper Averys
are about now, Dr. Grey.
I know. I know.
Well, we thought you might like
to be there.
What is going on?
Please welcome Dr. Catherine Avery.
Thank you so much.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
It is my distinct privilege
and honor to award
this year's Harper Avery
for Surgical Innovation.
This award is named for my dear friend,
who we lost this year
which makes this award
ever more meaningful.
Harper Avery was a very complicated man.
But his love
for medical innovation was pure,
and that describes this year's winner.
So, without further ado,
the Harper Avery for Surgical Innovation
goes to...
Dr. Meredith Grey!
Here to accept on her behalf...
Dr. Jackson Avery.
Thank you.
Incredible.
Knowing very well
that she might win tonight,
Dr. Grey opted to stay in Seattle.
A trauma came in,
and she knew that she was
the right doctor for the job.
That's one of the many reasons
that I'm so very, very proud
to call her my colleague and my friend.
Now, Dr. Grey has experienced
more loss in her life
than I think most of us would deem fair.
She lost her little sister, Lexie Grey,
who I know would love
to be here tonight with us.
She lost her husband, Dr. Derek Shepherd,
who knew with total certainty
that this night would happen.
And she also lost her mother,
Dr. Ellis Grey,
who won this award twice...
once as a resident...
and probably would have won a few more
if she hadn't been taken
from all of us so young.
The most amazing thing
about Meredith, though,
is that she takes all that pain,
all that loss,
and she turns it into drive...
drive to save lives,
to make things better,
and despite all that she's lost,
she continued to find joy in her work
as a surgeon, as a teacher, as a mother.
And she managed to share that joy
through her spirit of discovery
and of possibility and of hope
right in the face of darkness.
I am profoundly grateful...
for the lessons that I have
learned from Meredith Grey,
and it is my distinct honor
to accept this award on her behalf.
Congrats, Meredith!
Listen, I know that you said green,
but I couldn't... I couldn't
pick out which green.
So I think that you should pick it out,
and then we can paint it together, okay?
Okay?
I miss Mama.
Oh, I know.
I do, too.
But I am so, so happy that you are home.
- And you know what I got?
- What?
Three different flavors of ice cream.
Come on.
Okay. Stand there.
All right. One, two...
The third one... It's all for me.
This one's all for me.
That one's not for you.
We're good.
Oh, my God, you're everywhere.
Fine, Andrew.
I'll... I'll go somewhere else.
No, no, no, stop. Just, Sam...
You swear you didn't follow me here?
Andrew.
We're bad for each other.
We both know that.
- Really?
- No.
You don't see the similarity?
No.
You're just being stubborn.
Maybe I should text Burke
and send him her picture.
Meredith, there's no one like Cristina.
No one.
Fair enough.
Scientist or not,
most of us who've been at this a while
are forced to acknowledge
the mysteries of life.
You're driving?
I'm driving myself.
You can take the fire truck.
This day was epic.
I'm so tired I can't feel my teeth.
I almost stitched my finger to a person.
Scram.
Yeah. You heard her. Scram.
This is our beach.
We are forced to acknowledge
that certain kinds of magic exist.
Someone's calling.
- Ooh! Look who's calling!
- Uh-oh.
Hey, you're just in time
for the champagne.
Ready? Wait for it.
Whoo!
Yes! Yes!
What did she say?
Yes. She asked me if I feel different.
Damn straight, she does!
And that history and memory
and the ghosts of our past
are sometimes just as tangible
as anything we can hold in our hands.
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com