You. Give me that.
What are you talking about?
- Mrs. Miller?
- Shh. Your phone, young lady.
- I was just switching it to silent
in case someone called.
- No, you were cheating.
- Please. Like I have
to cheat— - Lady?
I said wait!
Give it here. Sure.
Love the blouse.
- I-I need to use the bunk room.
- The bathroom? Sure.
- In 19 minutes.
- Can't do it.
You got a friend in the
bathroom with the answers?
Fine. I'll get you an escort.
Don't stink up till I kill you.
Don't stand up.
D.X.D.T.
Hey, he's really sick.
- Eyes on your work.
- Are you all right?
- What is going on?
- Get some help.
The kid was just taking
his A. P. calculus exam,
when all of a sudden he
got nauseous and disoriented.
That's the way
calculus presents.
Severe bradycardia. Heart
rate's down to 48 and falling fast.
You know the kid?
No, he just came in.
Mom real good
looking? I... didn't notice.
Then it's a mystery.
Not why he's sick, but
why you care so much.
Gift shop's open. Buy him a card.
He's not responding to atropine.
Boys love fart jokes. Find
one with a good fart joke.
He's a teenager. It's drugs.
Tell those E.R. geniuses to give him
charcoal and naloxone. Stop following me.
His tox screen was negative.
He's still whacked out.
You don't care about the kid.
You just find his illness intriguing.
His CAT scan was clean. There's
no sign of infection. It's not diabetes.
And you don't care about him.
If that's what you wanna
hear, not in the slightest.
Me neither. May
as well be objective.
Maybe it's shigellosis.
Wouldn't account
for the bradycardia.
Viral myocarditis?
Wouldn't account
for the whacked out.
- So, what's the differential
for a negative tox screen?
- He was clean.
- Unless someone screwed up the test.
- That never happens.
Or he O.D.'d on
something we didn't test for.
1,4-Butanediol would
give you these symptoms.
- That's a new one.
- Copy machine toner.
Same punch as G.H.B. A little
pricier. Way more dangerous.
On the other hand, it is legal. I want
you to go to his house and find his stash.
I'll bet you know all
the good hiding spots.
Actually, I never did drugs.
Better go with him.
In case he gets high.
- How much atropine is the kid getting?
- One ml.
Make it two. In case he
needs his heart later on.
Matt, did you take
any drugs this morning?
Pencils down.
Can you squeeze
my fingers for me?
Did anyone give you anything
to help with the math test?
- Matt?
- I told you. He doesn't take drugs.
Ms. Davis, all parents think
that about their children,
and they're usually wrong.
I gave my mum a little
trouble when I was his age.
I turned out okay.
Even she thought so.
I know my kid. The fact that you
did drugs doesn't mean he did.
Did he go anywhere last night?
No, he was home studying.
- Any friends come over to help him?
- And bring him drugs?
Is that what your
friends did? Ms. Davis.
Look, I tested him myself.
The home kit. I took
some hair off his brush.
I didn't want him to know
about it, because I do trust him.
Then why did you test him?
All he did last night was study and
argue about his college interviews.
He wants to be himself—
No haircut, ratty old clothes.
That'll go over big.
Then we both gave up
and went to bed. That's it.
Has he ever had any problems
like this before? Any family history?
No, it's just me and Matt.
Diazepam. Ten
milligrams, stat. Right.
- What's going on?
- Just taking some precautions.
He's seizing. Help me hold him.
Stay cool, mate.
We'll calm you down.
This room is way too
clean for a teenage boy.
You know why House
thinks I'm a druggie?
This is gonna be a
racial thing, isn't it?
Same reason he thinks this
kid overdosed. When you're
a drug addict, you wanna
believe everyone else is too.
He's not addicted.
He has to take drugs.
The definition of an addict.
He's in pain. And
addicted to pain killers.
What a coincidence!
You really never did any drugs?
Now this is gonna
be a racial thing.
Deflecting a
personal question with
a joke. Gee, who do
I know that does that?
Yeah, I'm just like him. Except for
the angry, bitter, pompous cripple part.
Maybe we should all pitch
in and get you a nice cane.
You already have the
matching gym shoes.
Check this out!
Mom's not too careful with
the homemade tomato sauce.
When the top sticks out like that,
it's a sign of bacterial contamination.
This one's open.
I am extremely
disappointed in you.
I send you out for exciting
new designer drugs,
and you come back
with tomato sauce.
I bet you paid twice as
much. I got mine online.
Matt decided to make himself a
homemade pizza for a bedtime snack.
Source of botulism, as well
as a million other toxins...
that cause gastroenteritis, cardiac
symptoms and mental confusion.
I'm not so sure about gastroenteritis.
But mental confusion? Bring it on.
- Don't— But— - Mmm. Delicious.
- Do you have a death wish?
- I notice you didn't try to save me.
I figured you were trying to
make some kind of subtle point.
I was. The kid just started seizing.
Not a symptom of food-borne toxins.
Also not a symptom of drug
use. Not two hours after admission.
So what would make him seize, in addition
to all these other delightful symptoms?
- Pesticide poisoning.
- Carbamates.
Or organophosphates,
organochlorines.
- Lnhalation or absorption?
- Too soon to tell.
We should wash him down. The
poison could still be on his skin.
Already told the nurses.
Nursing supervisor
to the instrument room.
- I feel good.
- That's your complaint?
Your major symptom. I told
her this was a waste of time.
I notice colors more.
And music! I— I'm
really hearing music.
I'm 82, and I'm supposed to be
playing canasta with the other old ladies,
but now... when I see
a guy with a cute butt,
I can't stop looking at him.
Or... a sexy beard.
And you figure that enjoying
cute butts is a sign of disease?
It all started a month ago when Mark
rented Gone With the Wind for me,
but it had the wrong DVD in it.
Oh! Oh, right. I-I forgot.
This is all my fault.
Of course, he was too busy to bring
it back. Yeah, like I don't have a life.
So I watched it, and
it had this actor in it...
This kid called Ashton Kutcher.
Now... I think about Ashton...
all the time.
All... the time.
- Ah.
- You remind me of him.
Same bedroom eyes.
People are always mixing us up.
I-I-I suppose you— You
need to check my heart?
- No! No, no, that—
that won't be necessary.
- I told you.
But I am going to admit
you to the hospital for tests.
What tests? She's just old.
And you're just insufferable.
Your mother has had a sudden personality
change. It should be checked out.
I'll have a nurse come in and admit
her. I'm too handsome to do paperwork.
Anesthesiologist
to O. R. Room 4.
He's been on this
medication for over an hour.
Pralidoxime is very effective. It
just takes a little time for it to kick in.
And maybe you're wrong.
Maybe it's not a pesticide.
The blood work was pretty
conclusive. It's an organophosphate.
Oh, my God.
Move back. Ms. Davis,
move back, please.
We're at 30. Bradycarciac
arrest. Get me the pads.
What are you doing?
We're gonna beat his
heart for him. Set it at 60.
I can't stand this anymore.
We'll keep him on the pads
for another hour. Then what?
Let's see what happens.
Well, that's not my philosophy.
Especially when it
comes to my son.
And if something bad might happen,
I'd like to know what our options are.
The pralidoxime isn't doing him any
good. We're gonna have to wire his heart.
- Maybe we're wrong about the pesticides.
- I ran his plasma again, twice.
Are there any stronger treatments
for the organophosphate poisoning?
Oh, damn it! You caught
me. We went with the weak
stuff. I was just trying
to save a little money.
Actually, one of my
professors at Columbia
developed an experimental
treatment for the army.
- What's the success rate?
- They're targeted. There's a different
hydrolase treatment for each poison.
We'd need to know if Matt got
hit with Orthene or malathion...
- What's the success rate?
- Excellent, I'm sure. It's the U.S. Army.
"Be all you can be." Point is, what
are the kid's chances without it?
Minimal at best. The poison's
broken the blood-brain barrier.
I assume "minimal at
best" is your stiff-upper-lip
British way of saying
"no chance in hell."
I'm Australian.
You put the queen on your money.
You're British. Call your professor.
If we don't know what kind of
organophosphate we're targeting,
we don't know which
hydrolase to ask for.
- There's over 40 organophosphates.
- I'll get all of 'em.
- Get all of 'em.
- Great minds think alike.
- By the time they get here, we're
gonna know which one we need.
If we figure out how he got exposed,
we'll figure out what he was exposed to.
Well, the mom had
homemade tomato sauce.
Call me crazy, but I'm thinking
maybe... homemade tomatoes?
Front yard. Vegetable garden.
Kid's out there spraying,
sees a pretty girl,
hormones raging, spray
can goes off in his face.
- I'll check into it.
- I'll make the call.
I'll keep the kid alive.
For a while, at least.
I'll have lunch.
Through the
superior vena cava...
into the right atrium...
through the tricuspid valve...
and lodging to the wall
of the right ventricle.
Can you turn off the pad?
- Capturing?
- Getting a native heart rate of 36.
No, that won't do.
Let's get him to 50.
"The healer with
his magic powers!
"I could rub his
gentle brow for hours.
"His manly chest,
his stubbled jaw.
Everything about
him leaves me raw"...
- Psych ward's upstairs.
- "with joy.
Oh, House, your very name will
never leave this girl the same."
It's not bad for an 82-year-old. She
asked me to give that to her true love.
What can I say? Chicks
with no teeth turn me on.
That's fairly disgusting.
And that's ageism.
You better watch
yourself around this babe.
Here are her test results.
Impressive.
Yeah.
I found the pesticide.
It's disulfoton.
And it's empty. He used up the
whole can. Okay, I'll get Chase on it.
The poison's called disulfoton. This should
bond with it and neutralize the poison.
Then his nervous
system will start sending
the correct signals
to the rest of his body.
But there was no disul—
Well, that stuff in that can.
The label says
"disulfoton." I can show you.
But you didn't test it.
You said Matt sprayed with
it this morning before school.
Matt started that garden himself
for an environmental science class.
- They weren't allowed to use pesticides.
- Apparently he cheated a little.
It was orange peel oil. Totally organic.
He dumped that other stuff last winter.
The symptoms fit. There must
have been some left in the can.
If you're wrong, what will
this treatment do to him?
Well, theoretically, it could
increase the toxicity and...
But we're not wrong. Don't.
We're not wrong. I
can't let you do this.
Get a court order. Unless you wanna
see someone killed by sheer irrationality.
Maternal instinct is always
irrational. Doesn't mean it's wrong.
Actually, that's the definition.
It doesn't make her
mentally incompetent.
She's risking her son's life...
based on a teenager's claim
that he washed something.
How mentally
incompetent can you get?
That's a brilliant
legal argument.
Listen, have your
Harvard law dog whip up
some high-grade
legal-sounding psychobabble:
"Temporary insanity brought on
by acute panic distress syndrome."
I don't care. We have
to give him the hydrolase.
Her only sign of mental illness
is that she disagrees with you.
Some would consider
that a sign of sanity.
Not the kid. Let's ask him. Oh,
no, I forgot. We can't. He's dying.
Get the mother to sign off that
she's refusing this treatment.
Good-bye.
"I, Margo Davis, have
been informed of the risks...
"which may arise from my
refusal of advised medical care.
- I hereby release"—
- Who are you?
I work for the hospital.
"... the Princeton Plainsboro
Teaching Hospital and its employees,
"agents and otherwise,
for any adverse
medical conditions
resulting from my refusal.
It is not the hospital's
fault if my son kicks off."
Kicks off?
I punched up the language.
Mostly for clarification.
"I understand my doctors consider
my decision to be completely idiotic"...
Why are you doing this? "But I am
convinced I know more than they do.
I took a biology
course in high school."
I assume that's—Yeah.
"Besides, I enjoy controlling
every single aspect of my son's life,
even if it means his death."
Sign here, please.
I brought a pen.
Who are you? I'm the doctor
who's trying to save your son.
You're the mom
who's letting him die.
Clarification—It's
a beautiful thing.
Dr. Morell, contact the CAP lab.
She rethought her position.
Start him on the hydrolase.
No. We've got a problem.
Three. One, two, three.
Heart rate's 49. O₂
stat, 84 and falling.
Saline, atropine
and diazepam, now.
His name is Chi Ling. He
was admitted 12 minutes ago.
Identical symptoms as Matt.
Chase isn't sure he's gonna make it.
This one. Bag.
Matt's next-door
neighbor, by any chance?
They live 10 miles apart.
Apparently, they don't
even know each other.
We live in an apartment.
We have two bamboo trees.
No pesticides. Just dry
seaweed for fertilizer.
The second kid's heart
is almost as weak as
Matt's. We may need
to get it wired up too.
And I don't know how
long Matt's brain will
hold up. His heart's not
pumping enough oxygen.
How much are you
giving him? 80%.
Make it 90. We're risking
damage to his retina.
What the heck. Do it anyway.
He's a calculus student.
Probably likes having a brain.
I'll have Foreman take care of it.
- I'm the primary.
- Yeah, but the mom
wants to get rid of you.
And you know me. I'm a
people-pleasing kind of guy.
She complained? About
me? She went to the principal.
Told Cuddy you took drugs in high school.
This is gonna go on your permanent record.
I was trying to get
information. It was a strategy.
She also used the word
"slacker." You wanna come in?
Smoke a little weed?
Watch some MTV?
High school has no idea
what could have happened.
You sure that Chi didn't
sneak onto Matt's tomato patch?
Maybe they sniffed
disulfoton together to get high.
Same school, different grades,
different cliques, different everything.
They managed to get poisoned together.
They must have something in common.
Their classes aren't
even in the same building.
They don't even eat lunch
in the same lunchroom.
How do they get to school?
Unless you're with the board, the police
or the union, I don't care who you are.
Sir, we need to test the
bus for chemical residue.
And I need to pick up
the basketball team.
You got a problem with
that, call my supervisor.
Two kids were poisoned
on your bus this morning.
They're dying.
My God. The things he said.
Dr. House wanted your son
to get the medicine he needed.
- He was willing to do whatever
it took to make that happen.
- The wrong kind of medicine.
He didn't know that. At the
time, it was our only choice.
He would have known
if he had listened to me.
He listened.
He just assumed you were wrong.
To be honest, that's true
of most of our patients.
You're just as pompous
and superior as he is!
Uh, Matt is back row right. The
Asian kid, uh, first or second row left.
Okay. Look, I got this rash
in kind of my groin region.
It's, um, not a symptom.
Neither is being obnoxious.
Looks like you're in the clear.
- So who poisoned 'em?
- We're not sure yet
if it was done on purpose.
Oh, yeah? You oughta
see these little bastards
screaming and punching
each other all day long.
Did you happen to notice if anyone was
doing any spraying near the bus route?
Oh! Yeah, there was this truck down
by the pond doing something or other.
It smelled kinda funny too.
Oh! Dr. House!
Well, it took you long enough.
We've been waiting here...
Mr. Adams, would you
step outside for a moment?
Why? Because you irritate me.
He is my son, Doctor.
He's just a little
cranky from not eating.
Fine. Mrs. Adams, have you
had any recent sexual activity?
What?
Well, I—I don't suppose
fantasies count.
Oh, my God.
Unfortunately, I've
hit kind of a dry spell.
Only for the last— Oh,
I don't know—15 years.
You see? She's—She's confused. My
father died eight years ago. Heart attack.
Not in bed, dear.
Why do you ask?
Because you have
tested positive for syphilis.
That's impossible!
And insulting.
I don't think it's the first time
that Mom has heard this diagnosis.
"Cupid's disease." That's
what we used to call it.
When did you get it?
Uh, 1939. Prom night, I think.
He had a Chevrolet.
It was before I met your father.
But you said that...
You said Dad
was your first love.
He was.
We're talking about sex.
But I was treated.
Which suppressed it—
In your case, for 60 years.
But now it's back, and
the spirochetes that cause
syphilis are eating
away at your brain cells.
Oh! That's revolting.
It's not as revolting as
chlamydia. That's got seepage.
And it's the 2 1st century.
We've got flying cars,
robot dogs and penicillin.
High-dose regimen for
two weeks, you're cured.
- I can't believe this.
- Yeah, well, pinch yourself.
I guess for the next two weeks,
I'd better practice safe sex.
You'll be fine. Just
feed that cranky kid.
The county's worried
about West Nile, so they
sprayed ethyl-parathion
right next to the bus route.
Do you have the hydrolase
for ethyl-parathion?
Yeah. Only one problem. Matt's
mother faxed his records to the C.D.C.
She refuses to let us do anything
until she hears back from them.
Well, you're getting good
at this Godlike doctor racket.
Why don't you talk
her out of this lunacy?
She's not really a big
fan of mine. Or mine.
Well, only one man left in the
bull pen, and he throws like a girl.
I hate sports metaphors.
Give her the high, hard one.
We really think the
hydrolase is the only...
I'm thinking about
transferring Matt out of here.
Ms. Davis, your son is very
sick. He won't survive a transfer.
I'm getting a second opinion
from the Center for Disease Control.
Right. Look, when my
grandmother got sick...
What? You're gonna tell me some
tough decision you had to make?
- I know how hard this is for you.
- Maybe embroider the story
a little? Make it fit?
I can't imagine
being in your position.
Honesty. A kind of vulnerable
honesty. That's your thing. And the looks.
- Oh, boy.
- They send a single woman
to hustle the single mom.
Actually, they sent a doctor!
To tell you that if your son
doesn't get this treatment,
there's a good chance he'll die.
That's what House said about a
treatment that would have killed Matt.
You've gotta do better
than that. No, it's on you.
You need to do better.
Right now. Yes or no?
- I don't know.
- Figure it out.
Wait.
Nurse!
- Help!
- Okay. Coming.
- Seizing. Suction.
- Watch his head.
My son!
- Coming.
- Diazepam.
Got it.
- Suction.
- Ten milligrams.
Right.
He's not responding.
Another 10 milligrams.
You're killing him!
- You're killing him!
- Get her out of here. Get her outta here!
Come on, ma'am. Ma'am?
Their hearts are barely
pumping. Their lungs are shot.
Now they're
showing liver toxicity.
I guess Matt's mom won't nominate
us for any Doctor of the Year awards.
Only explanation is they got poisoned
by something besides ethyl-parathion.
Then the hydrolase would release the
neurotoxins instead of bonding with them.
The only thing they have
in common is the bus.
Except their symptoms.
Given their severity...
and the fact their cardiac
symptoms are getting worse
much faster than their other
ones, what does that tell us?
The poison was probably
absorbed through the skin.
They were admitted at 8:45 and
11:00. When were they poisoned?
Absorption through the skin?
Anywhere from three to eight hours.
In a case that bad, more
like one and a half to four.
So Matt was poisoned before
7:15. Before he got on the bus.
You're thinking each kid got poisoned in
his own house? Two separate exposures?
What do teenage boys do in
the morning, besides the obvious?
Wake up, go to the bathroom,
then the obvious, then
check their zits in the mirror.
- Do they both use the same acne cream?
- Because acne cream contains lanolin,
which could have
pesticides, and you're
thinking they both
bought the same product...
- It was contaminated. Shaving cream.
- Chi doesn't look like he shaves.
But he sweats. Deodorant
could contain lanolin.
Do these people have animals?
Chi has a dog. Matt has a cat.
Fleas. Flea powder.
Okay. Go to their houses.
Check for anything that
might have touched their skin...
between the time they got up
and the time they went to school.
I'm running low on tomato sauce.
Oh! Dr. House! Hello.
- I sent you home.
- Well, I came back.
I took a cab,
so my son wouldn't try
to chaperone us this time.
I'm sorry, but... the fact that
the sexual pleasure center...
of your cerebral cortex has been
overstimulated by spirochetes is...
It's a poor basis for a relationship.
I learned that one the hard way.
Doctor, um, these feelings
that I've been having...
Is it all because
of the syphilis?
Yes.
Then... here's the
prescription you gave me.
Well, it's not likely I'm
going to infect anyone.
No, but it'll kill you.
Well, gotta go sometime,
and...
I really don't want to play
canasta for the rest of my life.
I—I like feeling sexy again...
and... making a fool out of myself
with handsome, young doctors.
Do you think that I would
have given you this...
if it would stop you
from flirting with me?
Well, but if I'm cured— Then
all the spirochetes will die off.
But the little pieces
of your cerebral cortex
that have been
destroyed won't grow back.
You're brain damaged.
Doomed to feeling good
for the rest of your life.
Really? Well, thank you.
Georgia.
Yeah.
When I stop being contagious,
I'll come by for a checkup.
Yeah.
- Matt uses Sure.
- Chi uses Old Spice.
- No zit cream.
- Lucky kid.
Floral air freshener.
Doesn't matter.
When was the last time you heard
of a teenage boy using air freshener?
Pert shampoo.
Um, Johnson's over here.
Matt's mom would make
him use air freshener.
There are limits to a
mother's power. Even hers.
Just check.
Negative on the floral.
Matt's A.L.T.'s are up to 800.
If they get any higher,
we can toss his liver.
- Yeah.
- No matches on flea powder
or underarm deodorant.
- Or any other kind of deodorant.
- What about shampoo?
No to shampoo, bar soap,
dish soap, dish detergent.
How about laundry detergent? Maybe they
both washed their clothes this morning.
I'll check. You
know, if we cure Matt,
he can use his close brush
with death on his college essays.
- Admission guys love that stuff.
- That's how you got in, right?
Jailhouse diary?
Uh, TKO.
TKO. Liquid?
Liquid, 128 ounces.
- 128. Yellow jug. "Special"— -
"Environmentally safe formula."
It's the same. Bring
in the detergent.
So the detergent was
contaminated with pesticides?
Which soaked into their clothes
and got absorbed into their skin.
Hi. Uh, listen, the clothes
your son wore today...
- He washed them this morning, right?
- What?
Nice, respectful Asian
kid does the laundry.
My wife said he didn't.
Well, then I'm betting he washed
them last night without you knowing.
He doesn't even know
how to turn on the machine.
And those clothes were new. Nobody
washed them. His clothes are all new?
The ones he wore
today, yes. Never washed.
Now what?
What about Matt's
clothes? Were they new?
Uh, they're ratty
old jeans, I think.
They've been bagged
and taken downstairs.
"Davis." Yeah, they're Matt's.
And they're old.
And yet the label isn't
faded in the slightest.
Fake old. Hundred dollars
for the homeless look.
What? Kids aren't
pretentious in England?
Chi was wearing a different brand. How
could they both have been contaminated?
That is the question for the
ages. Meantime, get these tested.
I never bother to wash new
clothes before I wear them.
Right. Your wife does. She likes
you feeling nice and comfortable.
Hey, I'm a man. I don't
have time for laundry.
I'm saving lives here.
No, she doesn't
wash them either.
So your skin absorbs a little dye,
the odd chemical here and there.
You know me—
Mr. Living On The Edge.
Judging by the
self-importance of your strut,
you have identified the
chemical in question.
- Phosdrin.
- Hit 'em with the hydrolase.
- Chi's parents said yes,
but— - Mighty Mom said no.
Well, she's gonna feel like a million
bucks when Chi lives and her son dies.
Send Cameron. She's the only one of you
who's managed to talk her into anything.
Not this time. Matt's
mom won't make a move
until she gets that
opinion from the C.D.C.
Godot would be faster.
What is this?
Thought I'd hang out.
In case you change your mind.
Then I could give Matt
the medicine right away.
Don't worry. I've got time.
The C.D.C. promised they'd call.
I'm sure they will.
Maybe tomorrow.
Maybe the day after.
It takes time to
review faxed records.
Then they'll probably tell you they can't
make a decision based on faxed records.
This is Suzie.
She's never gonna
marry him. No money.
What makes you think
you're right this time?
Same reason as last time.
If you wanna see how the
other kid does first, that's okay.
Might help you. Although
there's a real good chance...
- What? Matt might kick off?
- That's a little blunt.
I was gonna say
"run out of time"...
or just kind of let
my voice trail off.
Hello? Yes, this is Margo Davis.
But you have his
records. I sent them.
Yes, I understand.
They can't help me.
They haven't seen him.
They can't make a
decision— Give it to him.
"The C.D.C. is unable to give
an opinion at this time, ma'am.
We're gonna have a doctor
in your area next week."
You fooled her with that?
House!
So I'm gonna be cured? As long as
you don't wear any more poison pants.
I'm sorry, Mom. I knew
the pants were stolen.
They were only five bucks. You're
gonna give me hell, aren’t you?
Oh, honey, I'm just
glad you're alive.
Let's get you home
so you can rest.
Maybe I am too hard on you.
You don't have to make
up that test till next week.
You can stay in bed and
work on your applications.
Some guy was selling pants off
the back of his truck near the school.
When he wasn't busy as
a clothing entrepreneur,
he did day labor at a
cornfield out on Route 1.
He used the same
truck for both jobs.
So he spilled pesticide on the
pants and was too lazy to clean up.
Real question is
why are you still here?
Why aren't you out there
making up with the joyful mother?
Why would I do
that? No reason at all.
If you don't care
about her. Or her son.
Oh, Dr. House.
The C.D.C. called.
- Again.
- Oops.
- Who are those guys?
- Oh, they're the arrogant jerks
that saved your life.
That's some bad hat, Harry.