What do you say now?
I don't know.
You said your dad wouldn't
be home for an hour.
I know, but it—You don't
know— Don't you love me?
Of course. You know I—
Then, come on. Let's do it.
All right.
Where are they? Nightstand.
Gentlemen, start your engines.
I so want this car!
Whoo-hoo!
Oh, my God! You're bleeding.
Look out!
What lie are they telling you?
I'll check on it. Okay. Yes...
Come on.
Okay, thank you.
Okay, pharmaceuticals
were delivered this morning.
But Shipping accidentally sent
the box with Vicodin to Research.
Hmm. That's a tough one.
If only we had some way to communicate
with another part of the building.
Sixteen-year-old M.V.A. victim.
He's been in and out of
the hospital for three weeks
with internal bleeding.
No one can find the cause.
Internal bleeding after a car
accident. Wow, that's shocking.
Let me talk to Shipping.
I speak their language.
It's been three weeks— Your hospital
doesn't have my pain medication.
Shipping says it's
going to be an hour.
This is Dr. Cuddy.
What's going on?
The crash didn't cause the bleed.
Right—the bleed caused the crash.
Blood got on the road, got all
slippery— Anyone here got drugs?
She saw his blood, she got distracted,
and she crashed his dad's Porsche.
- Dad'll love that.
- He was...
- Don't talk.
- It's gonna be an hour.
Thank God you took control.
- If you can't wait one hour to
get— - Kid's got hemolytic anemia.
Kid? How old?
He must have inherited it.
He's gonna die. My condolences.
Wasn't inherited. The problem's
outside the red blood cells.
This is impossible. A 16-year-old
does not get hemolytic anemia.
Give her back the file. You have
bigger problems to tend to, like my meds.
Elevated indirect bilirubin,
low serum haptoglobin...
- He's got meningitis.
- Uh, no.
- Artificial heart valve.
- No.
Get everyone in my office.
Kid's gonna be dead
in a matter of days...
if we don't figure out why his
red blood cells are disintegrating.
So, differential diagnosis,
people. Well, it's not environmental.
Dad hired a company to clean the
house, maid washed all the clothes...
and bought hypoallergenic
sheets and pillows.
- You want us to recheck?
- No.
If it's environmental, he'll get
better just from staying here.
- It could be an infection.
- No fever. No white count.
- Well, he's 99.2.
- Barely above normal.
But above. His body's
reacting to something.
We could account for the lack of
fever and white count if it’s lupus.
Drugs will fit just as much as lupus.
Meth will cause hemolytic anemia.
A lot of meth.
Also doesn't exactly
seem like the type.
Because his dad drives a Porsche?
Rich kids do drugs just like poor kids.
Didn't mean to offend you. Okay!
So it's infection,
lupus, drugs or cancer.
- Cancer?
- Why not? Great meeting.
Shouldn't we narrow it
down before we finish?
My leg gave us till 11:15.
I'll talk to Wilson about
lymphoma, A.N.A. for lupus,
radioimmunoassay for drugs,
and you test for whatever
you thought it was.
I've got a date
with the pharmacist.
That's already done, and...
Come on! Come on,
come on, come on.
Yeah.
Excuse me.
You know, there are
other ways to manage pain.
Like what? Laughter?
Meditation? Got a guy
that can fix my third chakra?
You're addicted.
If the pills ran my life,
I'd agree with you, but
it's my leg that's busy
calendaring what I can't do.
You're in denial.
Right. I never had an infarction in my
leg. No dead muscle, no nerve damage.
Doesn't even hurt.
Actually, it kinda tickles.
And chicks dig this...
better than a puppy.
It's not just your leg.
You wanna get high.
You're doing, what,
80 milligrams a day?
No. That's way too much.
Moderation is the key.
Unless there's pain.
It's double what you were
taking when I hired you.
'Cause you're twice as annoying.
I can't always be
here to protect you.
Patients talk. Doctors talk.
About how big your ass has
gotten lately? Not me. I defend it.
You got back.
You can't go a week without the drugs.
No, I don't wanna go without the drugs.
It'll hurt. No, you can't.
If you're just getting off
pain medication, it will hurt.
You won't be having a
great time, but you'll make it.
If you're detoxing,
you'll have chills, nausea.
Your pain will
magnify five, ten times.
You won't make it. Well,
I guess we'll never know.
I'll give you a week off clinic duty if
you can go a week without narcotics.
No way. I love the clinic.
You love the pills. Two weeks.
The pills don't make me high.
They make me neutral. A month.
You're on, mister.
Drugs could cause this? Cocaine and
meth are very hard on the blood system.
Has he had any erratic
behavior? No, but...
She was in rehab
in the ninth grade.
She's supposedly clean now,
but— She obviously cares for him.
Yeah, what she cared
about was the car.
Anniversary present for my wife.
We drove it up north to
watch the leaves change.
She was dead a year later.
Cancer. I'm sorry.
Mr. Foster, we're gonna
test Keith for drugs.
I—I don't do drugs.
It's not that we
don't trust you, but...
His hair will tell us any drugs
he's taken over the past 60 days.
It's kind of like
rings on a tree.
Negative.
- Have you been sick?
- No, nothing.
- Have you been out of the country?
- We went to China,
but we got all our shots before we left.
It could be an infection.
We're going to give him a
gallium scan just to be safe.
We inject a radioactive
isotope into his bloodstream,
and we check to see if there's
inflammation anywhere in the body.
Has he ever complained
of any joint pain?
Sensitivity to light? Rashes?
- No, no. Nothing.
- Any relatives who've ever
been diagnosed with lupus?
I don't even know what that is.
In simple terms, the body
becomes allergic to itself.
The immune system attacks healthy cells in
the circulatory system and destroys them.
Would it be treatable?
It can be manageable.
We can test for the antibodies.
Ninety-five percent of patients
with lupus have positive A. N.A.
Not cloudy. Negative.
What about bruising? Never complained
of tenderness under his arms or his groin?
I'm not sure he'd
tell me if he did.
I guess I don't really know
what's going on in his life.
- He's a teenager.
- Yeah.
What type of cancer
did your wife have?
Pancreatic.
It's his lymph nodes
we're concerned about.
We're going to do a biopsy
to check for lymphoma.
Can you feel this? No.
Good.
I have cancer, don't I?
We're just testing.
That's what they told my mom.
Definitely not cancer.
- Nothing?
- Nothing.
Negative for drugs. A.N.A. was
negative. Gallium scan was clear.
Yeah, I got that
from the "nothing."
- Where's his hematocrit?
- Thirteen.
Drops any lower, he's
not gonna have enough
red blood cells to bring
oxygen to his body.
He'll suffocate with his lungs
working perfectly. You okay?
Excuse me,
someone? Help. Please!
Polite for a dying kid.
How long has it been?
I'm fine.
There's something in
my eye. Up at the top.
Which eye?
This one. What's happening?
It's all right. Just
look down for me.
It's clear. There's
nothing in it.
- It's getting worse.
- Is it fuzzy or...
No, it's dark.
I can't see.
It's a retinal clot
in the left eye.
Coumadin would dissolve
the clot, fix his eyesight.
You can't use blood thinners.
He's got internal bleeding.
Fix the eye, you'd kill everything
else. Surgery's out for the same reason.
We have two hours
to figure this out. Either
we restore the blood
flow, or he loses the eye.
Forget the eye. Tell him to use the
other one to look on the bright side.
The clot tells us something.
Could help us figure out what he
has, which could mean he gets to live.
Differential diagnosis, people.
How does internal bleeding
suddenly start clotting?
It makes no sense.
They're opposing processes.
It can happen in lupus. Increased
platelet count can cause blood clots.
A.N.A. was negative.
It's not lupus.
This is true. But why
are you the one saying it?
What are you doing here? I
thought we'd ruled out cancer.
I was lonely.
Well, go see Cuddy.
She needs a friend.
That's funny. She said
you might need one.
That's why you're here. She wants you to
keep an eye on me. Make sure I don't cheat.
No, I wanted to make sure you don't
start firing shots from the clock tower.
I'm fine...
What's going on?
He hasn't had
Vicodin in over a day.
- Does your leg hurt?
- You ever been shot?
There's gonna be side effects.
Insomnia, depression, tachycardia.
Withdrawal symptoms.
Not applicable.
The only side effects I'm gonna have
are some pain and 30 days of freedom.
Am I the only one who's
concerned about a dying kid?
If it's not lupus, what else?
Most likely candidate for throwing
a clot is infection or cancer.
Checked the biopsy
twice. It's not cancer.
It's not an infection. Gallium
scan didn't reveal anything.
Okay. What hides
from a Gallium scan?
Cardiac. Right.
Clot flicks off, travels through the
arteries, then gets backed up in the eye.
I'm sorry. I wasn't paying
attention. What happened?
It's an infection in his heart.
Great.
Echocardiogram for the heart and
I.V. antibiotics for the infection, stat.
Is it my birthday?
I'm not lonely. My leg hurts.
- She's a real masseuse.
- She's $500 an hour, minimum.
She's hot, so she's a hooker?
What kind of pathetic logic is that?
The envious, jealous,
I-never-got-any-in-high-school
kind of logic. Hello!
She's a legitimate masseuse.
Come on.
God! She's beautiful.
Because she's beautiful, I should do
it? What kind of pathetic logic is that?
The envious, jealous,
I'm-married-and-I-can't-do-anything
logic. Hello.
Hi. Uh, listen, I'm sure you're really
good at whatever it is you do, but...
Déme su mano. Huh?
- Hey, no, no. Let go of my hand.
- She doesn't speak English.
Shh.
Ow!
Ow—Ahh.
Ahh.
Oh, my God.
Bueno.
Take off your clothes.
Not a fan of the Stroganoff?
I'm not hungry. Well, the
antibiotics can cause nausea.
So can the food.
Shouldn't you be
looking at my eye?
The blood clot
isn't life-threatening.
We're focusing on figuring
out the cause of your problems.
So the—So the blindness
will be permanent, won't it?
Thank you. Bye.
I had a massage.
Looks like you had a
masseuse. Help the pain?
I'm fine. I know.
Kid's echo was normal. No signs
of any vegetations on heart valves.
Never met a diagnostic
study I couldn't refute.
And the antibiotics
aren't doing anything.
So double the
dosage. 70 milligrams.
That'll box his
kidneys for sure.
Oh, you're right.
Save the kidney.
The guy we transplant
it into will be grateful.
Also, I have an idea for his eye.
Nothing we can do about his eye.
He's got a clot in the
retina— Put it in a memo.
If we remove some of the liquid
from the eye itself, the vitreous humour,
it might make some extra
room around the retinal artery.
If the artery expands, the clot might
move on its own. That's very creative.
Why didn't you
mention this before?
I didn't think of it before.
You should've.
This is going to hurt.
Your eye is numb.
You'll only feel pressure.
Give it a minute.
I can see.
I can see you.
I heard. Congratulations.
Don't. I haven't brushed
my teeth in two days.
I'm so scared they're not gonna
find out what's wrong with you.
No biggie. I'm fine.
I feel so bad about
all this. It's all my fault.
No. No, it's not.
But your father—he hates me.
He's just pissed about his car.
Help! Help! Help!
What's wrong?
A.S.T. is 859. We're
getting him to the I.C.U.
A.L.T. and G.G.T. are in
the tank. Our antibiotics...
Would not have caused this.
She must have given him drugs!
- I wouldn't do that!
- It's not drugs!
His liver is shutting
down. What?
What does that mean? It means
he's all better. He's ready to go home.
What? What do
you think it means?
You can't live without
a liver. He's dying.
What is your problem?
Bum leg. What's yours?
Hey, we don't have
time for this. Let's go.
His son's dying, and
you're mocking him?
It was a dumb question.
No, it wasn't.
You're right. It wasn't.
Is proving Cuddy
wrong worth all this?
- You know, House shouldn't even be here.
- Because he said something inappropriate?
If we sent him home every time he
did that, we wouldn't need this office.
He's in pain.
- What does the man
have to do to piss you off?
- He's been without pain relief
for over 70 hours.
- Exactly!
He's detoxing. Can't you
see he's out of his mind?
That's what they
said about Manson.
Do you wanna continue
talking about me,
or should we discuss what
the liver damage tells us?
I was born in a log
cabin in Illinois...
Hemolytic anemia
doesn't cause liver damage.
Add the fact he's
coughing blood,
you've got three of the indicators
of organ-threatening lupus.
It's moving too fast.
Could be hepatitis "E."
There's only been one case of
hep "E" originating in the U.S. since...
His history says he's been in and out
of the country four times in the last year.
You really think
he's got hep "E"?
No. I think lupus
is way more likely.
All right, then let's start him on
I.V. cytoxan and plasmapheresis.
No, we should rule out hep "E."
You just said it wasn't hep "E."
I said lupus is way more likely, but if
we treat for lupus and it is hep "E" —
He's toast. Exactly.
But there isn't a
treatment for hepatitis "E."
Either he'll get better on his
own or he'll continue to deteriorate.
Yeah. I went to
medical school too.
Start him on solumedrol.
- If he's got hep "E,"
that's only gonna make him worse.
- Not as much.
It's Goldilocks, people.
Won't hurt him so
much that it'll kill him, and
it won't hurt him so
little that we can't tell.
It'll hurt him... just right.
And if it does nothing—
We'll know it's not hep "E"
and can start treating for lupus.
Now watch me do it while
drinking a glass of water.
What do we tell the dad?
"We think your kid has
lupus, so we're gonna
treat him for hepatitis 'E.'
And, oh, yeah, if it
really is hep 'E, ' we're
not actually giving
him hep 'E' medication.
So it's gonna make him worse,
not better." Think he'll go for that?
- So you want us to lie?
- No.
- I want you to lie.
- Why me?
Because he trusts you.
- This is a mistake.
- This is a lawsuit.
Hep "E" is possible.
House always pulls these
stunts, and he's right more often...
He's delaying treatment
because of a one-in-a-million
chance that even he
doesn't think is the problem.
I don't wanna lie
to him. Then don't.
And get fired? Oh, like he's
gonna fire you. He loves you.
I've gotta do something.
- Kid needs treatment.
- Treat him for lupus.
That will get you fired.
You really think
House is losing it?
Yeah.
He's fine. He knows
what he's doing.
Okay.
We're recommending a
drug called solumedrol.
For hepatitis? Did that
show up on his blood tests?
The tests are never
100% accurate.
Well, then all the other
tests could be wrong too.
This could still be an
infection or cancer. Um...
They don't fit any of the
most recent symptoms.
Well, what, just hepatitis does?
I know, I know, I know—
You can never be sure.
When Wendy was in the hospital,
a doctor told us there was this
aggressive experimental treatment...
which might extend her
life by two or three years.
Well, we figured if there was
any hope at all that we could
have her with us a little
while longer, it'd be worth it.
Three weeks later, she was gone.
I don't think it's hepatitis.
I think your son has lupus.
I think it's broken.
What did you do?
Accidentally closed
the car door on it.
No. Door would've
broken the skin.
This looks like something
hard and smooth smashed it.
I want my lawyer.
The brain has a gating
mechanism for pain.
Registers the most severe
injury and blocks out the others.
Did it work? Well,
my hand hurts like hell.
Yeah. I feel much better. Huh.
Don't splint it.
I want to be able to bang it against the
wall if I need to administer another dose.
Just tape it up.
Why did you tell Cameron
to lie to Mr. Foster?
Make it tight. Answer me.
Nothing I can say is
gonna change how you feel,
and nothing can come out of your reaction
that is gonna change what I plan to do,
so I prefer to say nothing.
So that was just
you saying nothing.
Uh-huh.
- The guy is furious.
- And scared.
So what are you gonna do? The
father's insisting on the lupus treatment.
Yeah, Cameron told me,
and I told her to tell him no.
Well, you can't just sit
back and let the kid die.
Neither can the father.
So that's your plan?
You're gonna play
chicken with the kid's life?
Well, he's the dad.
I should win easily.
Take the week off.
Why, 'cause I lied to a patient?
I take risks.
Sometimes patients die.
But not taking risks
causes more patients to die,
so I guess my biggest problem is I've been
cursed with the ability to do the math.
I told him that we wouldn't
treat him for the lupus until...
- What'd he say?
- He said he wanted to transfer Keith
to another hospital.
He's not stable enough. He'd never make it
through the door. That's what I told him.
And that's when he caved.
Yeah. He agreed
to do it your way.
Two plus two equals four.
If it is hepatitis "E," we
should see a marked
decline in liver function
tests within the hour.
Why bother explaining it to me? It's
not like I have any choice in the matter.
If there's no hep "E," we'll start
treatment for lupus immediately.
Ouch.
- Keith? What's wrong?
- What's happening?
No, get off.
Keith, it's Dr. Chase.
Where does it hurt? Jules, no!
- He's hallucinating.
- Is this from the medicine?
We haven't started the medicine.
Keith, you're in the hospital.
Keith, there's nothing on you.
- Hey. Hey. Keith.
- Keith! Keith! Keith!
Hey. You okay, buddy?
Um, I think I wet the bed.
Oh— Don't worry about it.
It's fine. Let's get you up.
- Oh, God!
- He's had a major bleed.
- Bright red blood per rectum.
- I didn't—I didn't mean to. I'm sorry.
He's going into
hypovolemic shock.
- Pressure's 60, heart rate's 140.
- We need an angiography, stat!
Angiography revealed major
upper and lower G. I. bleeding,
severe hemodynamic
compromise and liver failure.
He's also hallucinating. Thinks he's
being tortured by someone named Jules.
Hallucinations are a
symptom of psychosis,
which is the fourth
diagnostic criterion.
It's official. This is lupus.
Who’s Jules?
Any mention of her
in the medical history?
It doesn't matter what he's hallucinating
about, it matters why! It's lupus.
Well, there's no
need to get snippy.
This kind of lupus takes
years to get to this point.
It's been a week. Yeah.
And a 16-year-old kid
shouldn't have hemolytic anemia
or be bleeding out of
every orifice, but he is.
We had an opportunity to
treat this. Instead, we diddled
around with hepatitis
"E," and now it's too late.
He needs a new
liver. We screwed up.
You're saying I screwed up.
- Yes.
- Then why don't you just say that?
- You gonna blame this on her?
- Did you agree with my recommendation
to treat for hep "E"?
- No, I didn't.
- And she made herself quite clear.
And then she went and lied to
the father. That's why you're angry.
Yeah. I trusted you.
You always trust me.
That's a big mistake.
Lupus is a bad diagnosis.
- It's the best diagnosis we've got.
- That doesn't make it good.
No. It just makes it this
kid's only chance to live.
Put him on the transplant list.
And make sure Cuddy knows.
See if she can do anything
to get him close to the top.
Cafeteria.
Stay away from the sushi.
And what happened to your hand?
Got stuck in a drawer.
Yeah, right. You're
going through withdrawal.
No, I am going through pain.
Pain causes nausea.
I took this job to work with
you, not cover your ass.
Your Vicodin.
And your solution
is to give me drugs.
That's interesting. No.
Now I'm covering my ass.
Take your pills
before you kill this kid.
Lupus is normally
treated with medication.
But in Keith's case, the
disease is too advanced.
Because you lied. Because House
wanted to play games with my son's life.
There's no way to really
tell what progression
the disease may have
taken— You're right.
And I'm sorry.
So what do we do?
He needs a new liver.
There are over 15,000
patients on the transplant list.
But how many are about to bleed
to death unless they get a new liver?
In Jersey? I'd say, uh, 20.
Two thousand patients die
each year because a donor
liver can't be found.
That's almost five a day.
So he's screwed.
I'll see what I can do.
- Could I donate part of my liver?
- Sorry. You're a different blood type.
So we just wait? I'm afraid so.
And hope for someone to die.
Who’s Jules?
Dr. House, you should get
back to your office— Jules.
- There's no Jules in the history.
- It was a hallucination.
Of what? Our cat.
- Does this matter?
- No. I'm sorry.
We'll continue the transfusions
and the treatment for the
anemia and liver failure
while we're waiting for a donor.
- How long can he wait?
- Not long.
- I don't think this is lupus.
- It's lupus. Come on, let's just go...
Your fourth diagnostic
criterion for lupus is psychosis.
This is just a kid
missing his cat.
He was being attacked by an
animal that wasn't in the room.
That's psychosis. There's a difference
between psychosis and hallucination.
So if he was imagining
a fake cat, it'd be
lupus, but since it
was a real cat, it's not?
- Take your damn pills.
- Psychosis requires...
There is no cat.
Jules is dead.
You have a dead family pet
and you never mentioned it?
Nice family history.
Family history's asking
about family members,
meaning people
related to the patient.
How did the cat die? Can
you get him outta here?
- Dr. House, come on, let's—
- What happened to the cat?
Old age.
- She was 15 years old.
- When?
About a month ago.
- Does this have anything to
do with— - Where'd she sleep?
With Keith. This
is not a cat allergy.
And it's not lupus.
Where is Jules?
Four years of college,
four at med school,
two years of residency,
another four of subspecialty
training, and where do I end up?
Talking instead of digging.
Come on. The
ground's frozen solid.
What's that?
Out of the way!
We have the liver.
Prep O.R. four.
All right, Keith, start
counting backward from ten.
Ten,
nine,
eight...
Scalpel.
Stop the gases.
What the hell are
you doing, House?
Saving a 16-year-old
kid from a lifetime of
immunosuppressant
drugs and a very nasty scar.
This kid doesn't
have lupoid hepatitis.
He has acute
naphthalene toxicity.
Naphthalene? Y-Y-You're
talking about mothballs.
Nope. Termites.
They create naphthalene
to protect their nests,
which I'm assuming
is rather large and
inside all four walls of
his bedroom at home.
And your assumption
is based on what?
The autopsy I just
conducted on his pet cat.
- Call Cuddy. And Security.
- You are not removing that kid's liver.
Now!
Have you completely
lost your mind?
No, but I have been
feeling a little sick lately.
Ah-choo!
There's no way we can do
this surgery now. Ya think?
You've already cost him
his liver. Don't kill him too.
Why are you so eager
to cut into a healthy kid?
Healthy? He's in the toilet. He
just needs some chicken soup.
I'm telling Hourani to re-scrub.
We're doing this transplant.
No, you're not.
You said it. If Keith's
symptoms had an environmental
cause, they would have
disappeared as soon as he got here.
They've only gotten worse.
If the food here wasn't one step below
Riker's Island, he would've gotten better.
- He's lost 14 pounds— - Sure.
This is nothing but a dietary thing.
Naphthalene is a
gas, a fat-soluble gas.
Kid breathes it in, it
gets stored in his fat cells.
Outside the hospital, his body
burned protein and carbs for energy.
And the naphthalene
stayed in fat.
But once the car accident put him in
the hospital and he started losing weight,
his body had to get its
energy somewhere else.
It started to burn fat.
The floodgates opened.
The poison poured
into his system.
So getting away from the
poison is what poisoned him?
Getting away from his dad's
meat loaf is what's killing him.
You wanna explain to me
why you stopped the surgery?
Oh, my God! My God.
- I want him locked up!
- Hey!
Take it easy.
Your cat did not die of old age.
It died of massive internal
bleeding and acute liver failure...
caused by naphthalene poisoning.
The exact same
thing your son has.
You lie to me, you
mess up my son's
surgery, and now you
expect me to trust you?
Give me 24 hours. We'll
pump your son full of calories...
That liver is going to
somebody right now.
We're doing that surgery.
You do the surgery, you'll
be killing a mother of four.
Father of three.
- I was guessing.
- Like you are now?
Naphthalene poisoning
is the best explanation
we have for what's
wrong with your son.
It explains the internal bleeding,
the hemolytic anemia, the liver failure.
It also predicts
what'll happen next.
If you do the surgery, he's gonna
lay on that table for 14 hours...
while his body continues to burn fat
and release poison into his system.
Either way, I did you a favor.
He's awake now. You've
got a chance to say good-bye.
I think you should
trust Dr. House.
Give the liver to the other guy.
Watch out.
I.N.R.'s down and his
red count is climbing.
Means you made the right call.
His liver is healing.
He's gonna be just fine.
You made it a week.
And won my prize.
Congratulations.
Cuddy's a sucker.
I would've done it
for two weeks off.
Yeah, it was a piece of cake.
You learn anything?
Yeah.
I'm an addict.
Uh—
Okay.
I'm not stopping.
There are programs.
Cuddy would give you the time.
You could get on a different pain
management regimen. I don't need to stop.
You just said...
I said I was an addict. I
didn't say I had a problem.
I pay my bills. I make
my meals. I function.
Is that all you want?
You have no relationships.
I don't want any relationships.
- You alienate people.
- I've been alienating people
since I was three.
Oh, come on! Drop it.
You don't think you've
changed in the last few years?
Well, of course I have. I've—I've
gotten older, my hair's got thinner.
Sometimes I'm bored. Sometimes I'm lonely.
Sometimes I wonder what it all means.
No, I was there.
You are not just a regular
guy who's getting older.
You've changed. You're miserable,
and you're afraid to face yourself.
Of course I've changed!
And everything's the leg?
Nothing's the pills? They
haven't done a thing to you?
They let me do my job.
And they take away my pain.
How'd it go?
He admitted he's
addicted to the narcotics.
Well, admitting you have a problem is
the first— And he says it's not a problem.
Maybe it's not.
What do I know?
What are you gonna do?
Nothing. Done enough damage.
Better hope he never finds out that
that was your idea. He'd never believe it.
That's some bad hat, Harry.