Susan.
Hey.
Good morning.
Yes, it is. I'd even go as far
to say it's a glorious morning.
Didn't your mother
teach you not to gloat?
What good's a vacation
if you can't gloat?
Just think. In eight
days, you'll be back here
slogging miserably through life
like the rest of us.
Yeah, but tomorrow,
I will be in Maui
with the sun on my face,
drinking a sea breeze.
I hope you burn.
Thanks for house-sitting.
My cat owes you big time.
I'll try to remember
to feed her.
Hope you recognize the
hospital when you get back.
I hear Anspaugh's got
a lot of changes in store.
Like what?
I don't know.
I'm philosophically opposed.
That's my new motto.
Change is not good.
Well, we're getting
more residents.
Maybe we won't
have to work as hard.
We'll work twice as hard.
What?
They're from Southside.
Their program is, shall we say
less than discriminating.
We're going to
spend half our time
trying to keep them
from killing the patients.
Okay, I'm coming!
Good morning, Dr. Carter.
I saw your car in the garage.
I didn't want you
to oversleep again.
Well, I'm not on for
another two hours
but thanks.
I brought you some Borscht.
Here, here.
They eat this for
breakfast in Russia.
Hmm.
Thank you for helping me
fix my tank the other day.
I hate this damn thing!
It's like dragging an anchor.
Just don't light that
cigarette around it, okay?
Oh. By the way
I've been feeling this
waxy buildup in my ear.
Would you mind
taking a look at it?
You know, ears really
aren't my specialty
but there's a
family practitioner
who lives on the second floor.
Really?
And he is so much
more qualified than I am.
Oh! Thank you, Dr. Carter.
I'll be back for that bowl.
Okay.
Isn't this exciting?
Yeah, like a junior
high assembly.
Here comes the
assistant principal.
Susan, I want you to
meet Margaret Doyle
one of our new interns
from Southside. Maggie.
Pleasure. Hi.
Wonder what med
school she went to.
Guys, come on. Saved you a seat.
You look like hell. Did
you pull an all-nighter?
Yeah, Price is sick so they
called me in at midnight...
Interrupted a very
promising date.
Morning, everybody.
Thanks for coming.
I'm due on
the surgical floor
in ten minutes
so I'm going to
make this snappy.
We're in trouble.
With the closing
of Southside hospital
we can expect an
increase of at least 30%
in our normal patient
load here at county.
To meet these demands,
we're going to be instituting
the efficiency standards
that made the Southside E.R...
No offense... The
best one in the city.
All residents
and attendings
will see an average
of 2.5 patients per hour.
Your patient quotient will
be checked on a daily basis.
The highest PQ wins a gumdrop.
The lowest has to wax my car.
What about the dead?
I'm sorry?
DOA's? Train wrecks
who croak on the way in?
Do we get points for them?
Yes, you do
but, uh, try not to kill
all your patients at
once, Dr. Greene.
We wouldn't want
to draw suspicion.
Now, who handles the scheduling?
I do.
Will you make
sure that I'm CC'd?
Chart review?
That's, uh, me too.
I want a daily
summary, and budget?
It's me.
Greene
aren't you
an attending here?
I'm patient ombudsman
I run the mentoring program
and I'm in charge
of staff morale.
Well, let's even
out the duties a bit.
Greene, you take chart
review. Get me a report by noon.
Can I suggest...?
People, change is
like a freight train.
You're either on board
or you're grit in the gears.
Same time Tuesday.
Oh. I think he likes you.
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.
It was ugly, the
ugliest thing I ever saw.
It was big like a
bear and fearsome.
Well, look what he done to me.
What's this?
Dante says a
kangaroo attacked him
in Humbolt Park.
That's a nasty cut.
Had a claw like a razor.
Smelled like an elephant's ass.
Exam six.
Jerry, who was
attending last night?
Um, Mishkin.
Well, get him on the phone
'cause I can't read
his handwriting.
It's like Sanskrit.
Stuck in chart-review hell?
I've been here an hour
and I haven't seen any patients.
Well, pick it up
or you'll be waxing
Anspaugh's car.
One down. Anyone got
the broken tib-fib in Two?
Actually, I'd rather
you stayed supervised.
Doug, did you meet, uh...?
Maggie Doyle.
Maggie, hey, I'm
Doug. How are you?
I was handling my
own cases at Southside.
It's your first day.
I'd like you to stick with Doug.
Jerry, get on the PA
and tell the idiot
with the red BMW
to get out of my parking spot.
Space 37?
Yeah.
Security told me
I could park there.
Space 37 is my space.
It's been my space
for the past three years.
Maggie, I'd like you to
meet Carol Hathaway.
She's our head nurse.
She also heads the
welcoming committee.
I'll move.
Good.
Who's that?
Intern from the Southside.
Intern? With a BMW?
I thought your car
was repossessed.
It's still my spot.
Before I do the stitches
I'm going to give
you some medicine
so they won't hurt, okay?
You know what?
I'll even let you choose
the color of thread.
I've got blue, purple, black.
Jeanie.
Uh, can I talk to you
for a minute outside?
Yeah.
I'll be right back.
You should call a surgical
intern to do the sutures.
I'm sure the interns have
more important things to do.
Have you told the
mother and the patient
that you're HIV positive?
None of your damn business.
All right.
This is just going
to hurt for a second.
Jerry, get these
charts out of my face
and get me a sick person to fix.
Actually, the board
is covered right now.
Kleinman's been turfed to neuro
Figueroa... has been discharged
and Nguyen signed out AMA.
Your labs on Otis
and Fenning came up.
Okay. Thank you.
You're cooking.
I heal 'em and deal 'em.
Besides, in...
46 hours and 18
minutes I will be in...
Don't say it.
Maui, Maui, Maui.
You're cruel.
I haven't had a day off
since Christmas.
Why don't you come with me?
Yeah, right.
You're kidding, right?
Uh, I-I don't know.
I mean, you have the time coming
and there's plenty of people
to cover for you.
What about your cat?
I can ask a neighbor.
Mark! This guy's crashing.
I'm coming.
We'll talk later.
Sure.
Good morning. How are you?
I've been better.
Me too.
So did you see
if the triage nurse
brought your chart back?
I don't know.
So what seems to be the problem?
Kidney stones.
I've had them in the past.
Woke up with the
same pain this morning.
It starts back here
and it works its
way around front
and then down.
Yeah. Sounds like a stone.
They're probably
going to want a cat scan.
Let's get you in a gown first.
Do you eat a lot of ice cream?
Yes, actually.
Drink tea?
Almost every day.
Why do you ask?
Well, calcium from the ice cream
combined with the
oxylate in the tea
forms calcium oxylate stones.
A simple ionic bond.
Makes sense.
Mr. Sidowski?
That's right.
I was in your chemistry
class at Saint Monica's.
Carol.
Hathaway.
Second row...
right near the window.
God, I can't believe
you remember.
I remember the good ones.
I always knew you'd do well.
There you are, a doctor.
Do you specialize in
emergency medicine
or surgery or..?
No. I'm a nurse, actually.
In the E.R.
A nurse?
Well.
That's wonderful.
What's the story?
They found him obtunded
at his board and care.
BP's 50/30.
Pulse weak at 130.
No tendon reflexes.
No response to pain.
This IV's blown.
His vein's too weak to hold it.
What's his name?
Johnson.
Mr. Johnson? Mr. Johnson?
He seems plenty gorked to me.
How old?
Eighty-nine.
Does anyone know what his
quality of life was like?
I'm calling his board and care.
Find out if he's
got a living will?
I don't want to get into
heroic measures if he's DNR.
I don't get a pulse.
He's bradying down.
You getting through?
They put me on hold.
All right, let's bag him.
Break out the atropine.
This is ridiculous.
It's a crime.
Every surgical intern
is in the OR today.
Everyone but us.
Benton let me spend
more time in the OR
as a med student.
Man, the man...
the man is a sadist.
Look at this.
Edson's double bypass?
No, but geez.
No, Keaton. That's Abby Keaton.
Pediatric surgeon.
She used to be at Southside.
Oh, man.
What?
Benton's going to try
for an elective with her.
No way. Mm-hmm.
He signed up for thoracic
with the new chief.
Then why did I see him reading
Essentials of Pediatric Surgery?
Benton and kids?
See, it's the most
difficult specialty.
It is impossible to get into.
It is exactly what he'd go for.
I don't buy it.
Benton's no Mr. Rogers.
It's a beautiful day
in the neighborhood
boys and girls.
Gant, cover med-surg today.
I heard that you signed up
for a thoracic elective
with Anspaugh.
Oh, Carter. Pre-ops
and transfers for you.
Any chance we might get into OR?
Today?
Maybe... possibly...
Call surgery! Tell them we got
a major chest impalement!
What happened?
A motorcyclist
hit a glass truck.
Start an IV. And set
up the rapid infuser.
Okay, let's move him.
Ready. And...
Go.
Oh! Watch out.
BP's 70.
He's getting dusky.
Try for a 16 gauge...
He needs more volume.
He's seizing.
Someone hold his arm.
Ativan, two.
Use both hands.
Get the needle in.
He's moving.
Wait, wait.
Okay.
Now. Now!
Rapid infuse the o-neg.
No breath sounds on the right.
Tension pneumo.
Damn. Connie? Hold his head.
Jeanie, grab hold of
this glass and watch
your hands.
Pulse ox is down to 70.
Jeanie?
Get over here now.
I'll get someone.
Jeanie?
Jeanie!
Malik, they need you in there.
I'm going to the lab.
I'll take them. Go.
Go.
Do you pluck your eyebrows?
Uh... wax.
They look good, girl.
You do it yourself?
No, I found this
place on Dearborn.
Time?
12 minutes.
More Epi?
I guess.
What's going on in there?
The board and care
found medical records
but no DNR.
Let's hear it.
He's got COPD.
Renal failure,
congestive heart failure
prostate cancer, diabetes.
Any family we can contact?
A son. They're
trying to reach him.
If I ever get this old, I want "do not
resuscitate" tattooed on my forehead.
Get this. His PH is 6.97.
All right, he's been
down long enough.
Time of death:
10:06.
Get a strip.
I'm going next door.
Mark.
He's got a rhythm.
It won't last.
BP's 50 palp.
Guess we better put
him back on the mask.
Tough old geezer, ain't he?
So she asked you
to come to Hawaii.
Yeah, but I don't
know what she meant.
Well, seems fairly unambiguous.
Well, if she
meant it as a friend
then that means
separate hotel rooms right?
Right, or you could
be sharing a bed.
Right.
All right. Well, you
get adjoining rooms
with a broken lock and
you see what happens.
You're not helping.
What do you think she meant?
Well, I think she meant
something a little
more than friendship.
Yeah, and how do
you feel about that?
Well, I'm...
You're interested?
Maybe. Get on a plane, Humphrey.
Well, what if that's
not what she meant?
Three hours divided by
seven patients is 2.33.
How's it going, Mark?
Three hours, one patient.
I'm on a roll.
Jerry, I'll take that
plantar wart in five.
You got it.
Neuro come down for Mr. Johnson?
Who?
That Gomer that
came back to life.
Oh, yeah, they
wouldn't take him.
They said he's a renal case.
Yeah, well then try renal okay?
We've got to get
him out of here.
Jawohl. Hey, your wart.
Oh, right. Thank you.
Could I have some more soup?
Whose patient is Johnson?
Why?
He stopped breathing.
They need you in two.
I'll take it.
Has anyone seen Jeanie?
She went on break.
More soup?
Shh. Quiet.
Of a sighting of a
kangaroo in Humbolt park.
Yep, you heard me.
Lydia, come here.
The mystery marsupial
was recently sighted
hopping along the
Kennedy expressway.
The Department of Animal
Control has issued a warning
that kangaroos can be dangerous
and have been known
to attack when threatened.
Soup?
So... you asked
him to go with you?
It just popped out.
Have you guys ever...?
No!
But you asked
him to go to Hawaii.
I mean, that's...
that's pretty bold.
Oh, it's stupid.
I mean, Mark and I are friends.
We work together
and I basically invited
him into my bed.
What did he say?
Oh, he was appalled.
He couldn't wait to
get away from me.
Oh, I'm such a fool.
Uh, how long is
Anspaugh going to be?
One never knows.
Dr. Benton.
Carter...
What are you doing here?
I just admitted a
woman with a lipoma.
She's going to need surgery.
A fat tumor? It can wait.
Hey, well, she
wants it out today.
All right. Well, then
go ahead and book
an OR, all right?
Can I assist, please?
Yeah, whatever.
Just get out of here, all right?
Solid.
Hey, this guy in the
picture with Dr. Anspaugh...
Is that, um...
General Schwarzkopf.
They were roommates
at West Point.
Judith, I'll be in neonatal.
Hey, uh, Dr. Anspaugh,
I chose cardiothoracic
as my eight-week elective.
Congratulations.
Means you're on my team.
Uh-huh. But I just
found out today
that Dr. Keaton's coming here.
Yes. Very, very
happy to have her.
Yes. I know... I
followed her work.
Do I sense a wind
shift, doctor, uh...
Benton.
Look, Dr. Keaton
is one of the finest
pediatric surgeons
in the country.
An opportunity to work
with her is hard to pass up.
Well, she may not
have a slot for you.
Well, I'd like to see.
I'll give you until 6:00.
So if I don't get the pedes
I'm still on for
thoracic, right?
Dr. Benton, if I don't
hear from you by 6:00
you get neither.
Jane, I'm Dr. Ross;
this is Dr. Doyle.
Hi.
I understand you've
been having some pain
when you urinate.
Yeah. I think it's
a bladder infection.
I had one before.
Uh, when was that?
Last year.
Okay. Any soreness
or tenderness?
Um, just when I
go to the bathroom.
Are you sexually active?
Have you ever had intercourse?
Oh, no.
Okay, well, we're
going to do some tests.
When we get those
back, we'll talk some more.
Okay?
Okay.
All right.
So what do you think?
Either an STD.
Or she's pregnant.
Based on?
Her sweater... cashmere,
probably Neiman Marcus.
Why does a rich girl
come to a county ER?
She doesn't want her
family doctor what's wrong.
Okay, so what do you do?
Dip her urine and do
a pregnancy test for starters.
Sounds good.
Sorry. The OR's are booked.
Dr. Benton sends
his apologies...
He can send
flowers for all I care.
You've got a breast
reconstruction
a thyroidectomy and a
hemicolectomy ahead of you.
This is important.
What is it?
It's a pheochromocytoma.
A pheo?
Her BP is through the roof.
If we don't go in soon,
she's going to stroke out.
All right.
Tell Dr. Benton he has his OR.
And tell him I like tulips.
Jeanie, if you have an
explanation, I'm listening.
I'm sorry. I haven't
been feeling well.
I got nauseous.
If you're feeling
ill to the point
where it interferes
with your work
you should let me know.
It won't happen again.
Everything else okay?
Yeah. Everything's fine.
How's Al?
He's, uh, he's holding his own.
It's difficult.
I'm sure it is.
Can I help you?
Uh, yeah. I need
to see Dr. Keaton.
You're too late.
Well, the patient's
still conscious.
Come back in three hours.
I need to talk to her.
You don't know Dr. Keaton
very well, do you?
Just by reputation. Why?
I guarantee
that if you go in there
right now, the only words
she's going to have
for you are "get out."
All right, look,
if I write a note
will you make sure
she that she gets it?
I'm not her secretary.
Leave it in her box.
Mr. Johnson, your father
was found unconscious
this morning.
He has what we call
multisystem failure...
Heart, lungs, kidneys...
And he may have
suffered a stroke.
That's like Alzheimer's.
No. But it's very serious.
Did you ever talk
with your father
about whether he
wanted to use machines
to keep him alive
if his body were failing?
Not a lot, no.
Were you and he close?
About a hundred miles.
I live in Boone County.
I smoke hams.
Your father is very ill.
In all likelihood
he may never
regain consciousness.
And we can use
a machine to keep his body alive
or we can give him
medication to take
care of his pain
and let nature take its course.
As next of kin,
it's your decision.
What do you think?
If it were my father...
I would try to make
him comfortable
in his final moments.
Okay.
So I'll get somebody
to bring you the papers?
You're going to help him, right?
I'm sorry?
You're going to make him better.
I'm not sure that we can.
Just don't let him die, okay?
All right, Carter, make the
incision below the costal margin,
straight across,
six centimeters.
Okay.
Now, just like carpentry,
measure twice, cut once.
Right.
Benton, you should have
told me you're doing a pheo.
Trying to keep all the
exotic ones for yourself, huh?
What are you talking about?
I'm doing a lipoma removal.
It's on the board,
"pheochromocytoma"
in big red letters.
Who the hell put it
up there?
That one.
Hey, Carter, Simon's
letting me do an Appi.
I'm going in.
No. It's called Gonorrhea.
It's sexually transmitted.
It is treatable, but we
have to do it right away.
Are you going to
tell my parents?
No. Whether you
tell your parents or not
that's up to you.
I would tell the,
uh, boy or boys
that you've had sex with.
I only did it once.
Then you need to tell him.
I... I can't.
Why is that?
Because he won't talk to me.
When I see him in the halls
he won't even look at me.
I feel really disgusting.
Sorry.
That's all right.
I wanted it to be special
and it was like I
wasn't even there.
He didn't even drive me home.
Hey Jane, guys
who are interested
in having sex with you
aren't necessarily
interested in you.
You know?
If you want it to be special
you're going to have
to wait for the right guy.
I would suggest
waiting a long time...
like until you can vote.
So, Mr. Johnson's in V-tach.
Paddles.
Why not?
Charge?
You pick.
200?
200 it is.
Clear.
Next contestant.
Do I hear 300?
300, sure.
300 from the stunning woman
in floral scrubs.
Clear. Clear.
I'll see your 300
and raise you 360.
Mark?
What a joke.
360.
Clear.
And he's back.
What a trooper.
Congratulations, Mr. Johnson.
You are the lucky winner
of a brand-new ventilator
at a cost of $5,000 a day
and as a bonus, your
very own chest x ray...
Perfect for decorating
the small sterile hospital room
where you're going to spend
the rest of your
brief, unconscious life.
She's still in there? It's 4:00.
She went back in.
She's got a four-year-old
with a Wilm's tumor.
Excuse me, what are you doing?
I'm just seeing if
she got my note.
Look, uh, when
Dr. Keaton comes out
please, please make
sure that she gets this.
Yes.
I'm Peter Benton, I'm
a fourth-year resident
and I'm interested in a
pediatric surgery elective.
I need to talk to
her about 6:00.
My pager number is...
3376. I can read.
Look, just make
sure she gets it, okay?
Okay.
So you always vomit
when you screw up?
Only when I get written
up by the Chief of Staff.
Yeah, well, ten
migs of Compazine
should get your
stomach back on its feet.
You missed a great appendectomy.
I could lose my residency.
Retracted the internal
obliques, clamped that sucker...
My career is over.
Ow! Sorry, sorry.
Dr. Benton.
What makes you think
you can assist
on a surgery behind my back?
Simon needed an intern.
I'm your resident.
You don't blink
without asking me.
This afternoon,
you're on bedsore duty.
If there's a boil, you lance it.
If there's a weeping decubitus,
you debride it, and if...
Anspaugh's leading
chief rounds in 20 minutes.
Don't be late.
Especially you, Carter.
He asked for you by name.
I can't believe
I spent four years in med school
and four years as resident
so now I can take orders
from a guy who smokes hams.
Other than that,
how's your day going?
Just got worse.
Who does this belong to?
Yep, that's mine.
Wear it. We lose
20 or 30 a year.
Who invented the stethoscope?
I have no idea.
Rene Laennec, 1819.
You can see I taught her well.
Keep hustling, boys.
You don't want to end up
with the turtle wax.
Oh.
Hi. Hi.
I haven't seen you much today.
Yeah, it's been
a pretty busy one.
So you've been, uh...
you've been busy.
Yeah, pretty much.
So, about Hawaii...
How much are the hotel rooms?
Rooms?
Or a room...
for me.
Um... yeah, I'll have
to check on that.
You'll let me know.
Sure.
Jerry! Jerry, turn on
channel five, quickly!
They've spotted him again.
He was at the railyard an hour
ago, I hope he made it through.
Remains unknown.
That kangaroo watch continues.
The kangaroo that
mysteriously appeared on
Chicago streets, was seen
entering this abandoned building
at the corner of
Kenzie and Maplewood.
That's six blocks from my house.
Armed fish and wildlife officers
have surrounded the building
in an attempt to
apprehend the animal.
They're not going to
shoot him, are they?
I hope so.
That thing looks
like a giant rat.
Jeanie?
You paged me?
Yeah.
Where's the patient?
There is no patient.
We need to talk.
About what?
About my working here.
I need to know if you're
planning to tell anyone
that I'm positive.
No, I'm not.
Look, Jeanie, I don't agree
with what you're doing.
But how you handle
your patients...
That's your responsibility.
Thank you.
But I do want you
to stay away from my patients.
And I don't want to be in
a trauma room with you.
That 13-year-old with the clap
has had her ceftriaxone.
You want me to
write her a scrip?
Ten days of doxycycline
and tell her to stay away
from insincere suitors.
You were good with her.
Thanks.
Listen, uh... Why don't
you grab some lunch?
I was on all night.
I'm kind of beat.
I'm going to sack
out for about an hour.
Sure, I'll round you
up when I get back.
That's not necessary. Thank you.
Susan, can you
push some Ketorolac?
Actually, I'm suturing a thumb.
Do you know where Mark is?
Mm, try the desk.
Hey, Malik, have you seen Doug?
Haven't seen him.
Where are all the doctors?
Um... are you available?
Sure.
Exam one.
In a minute.
Next, we have
a 73-year-old post-thyroidectomy
exhibiting both Chvostek's
and Trousseaus's signs.
Treatment?
Dr. Carter?
Saline diuresis, three
to six liters per day
plus Pamidronate.
A textbook treatment
for hypercalcemia, doctor.
Unfortunately, this
patient has hypocalcemia
and you've just
stopped his heart.
Rest in peace, Mr. Edmonson.
Next, we have a...
Man, he's gunning for you.
You okay?
I can't control the
muscles in my neck.
You're having a dystonic
reaction to the Compazine.
I am?
Yeah, muscle spasms
are one of the side effects.
So is lip smacking.
Help me.
The aortography on
this patient revealed
a small type "A" dissection
of the thoracic aorta.
Dr. Carter
differentiate between type "A"
and type "B" aortic dissection.
Type "A" involves
the ascending aorta and type "B"
the descending.
Correct.
Next, a traumatic amputation.
The patient is a
35-year-old female,
otherwise in good health...
How much longer do I
have to wait?
They're prepping an OR
for you know, Mr. Sidowski.
In two hours, you
will be stone-free.
I have some
questions for the doctor.
Uh, the surgeon will
be down in a minute.
He can answer your questions.
Excuse me. I'll be right back.
I had half a mind
to give him saline
instead of the painkiller.
Why?
He flunked me in chemistry.
You went to St. Mo's?
Yeah, you? Yeah.
You know what? I think
you were in my history class.
Mrs. Hester. Never had her.
You might be thinking
of my sister. So, listen...
What year were you?
'88.
Oh, see, I was '85.
Yeah, Mary's three
years older than me.
Check Sidowski's urine
output before moving him.
The last entry
was two hours ago.
Hey, Jer, Animal Control
cop got shot with a tranquilizer.
Where do you want him?
Exam four. Excuse me,
officer, how did this happen?
I was trying to hit
that friggin' kangaroo
that's running around
Ukrainian village.
My partner got in the way.
How about the kangaroo?
Hopped the wall.
He's still out there.
Mr. Johnson?
Do you recognize this?
What?
This was found at your
father's nursing home.
It's a living will.
It says that your
father did not want
any heroic measures
used to prolong his life.
A will? What I get?
No. What it means is,
we never should have
put him on the ventilator.
We've kept him alive
against his expressed wishes.
See this? Right here? This line?
Does that signature
look familiar?
Yeah, it's mine.
Yes, it is.
I got to go put the hams to bed.
Except this one.
This one's for you.
So you'll call me when
he wakes up, right?
My work number.
Bye, Pop.
What happened?
30-foot fall off an
I-beam. Head trauma.
Near amputation of the left leg.
I'll get some O-neg.
Eight units. And call
the reimplantation team.
Let's go, trauma two. Let's go.
Yeah?
Jane wanted to say good-bye.
Jane.
Thanks for helping me.
You've both been really nice.
Well, okay.
Be careful out there.
You, uh, need to get that?
Excuse me.
Uh...
Faint dorsalis pulse.
Decreased breath
sounds on the right side.
Set up for a chest tube.
All right.
What's going on?
30-Foot high dive
facial trauma, multiple open
fractures, tension pneumo.
He's not breathing.
Laryngoscope, now. Move.
Lacerated femoral artery.
Get me a vascular
clamp and suction.
Can't visualize the cords.
There's too much blood.
From where?
I don't know. Looks
like the nasopharynx.
Jeanie can pack the nose.
Get a 16 foley
and an umbilical clamp.
Peter can talk you through it.
I thought you were
staying out of my traumas.
It's not your trauma.
I was here first.
Pulse ox is dropping. 78.
Come on, let's go.
Thread the catheter
through the nose.
Let's move.
Can you visualize the balloon?
It's down there.
Inflate and retract.
Artery's clamped.
Can you come up here
and take over for Jeanie?
She's got it.
I think I've got it sealed.
Clamp it to keep it in place.
It's clamped.
Peter?
Bleeding stopped.
He's tubed.
Bag him.
Nice job, guys.
Good breath sounds.
All right. Let's get him
upstairs. Let's move.
Good work.
What kind of greens?
Yeah, romaine, spinach, alfalfa.
Right.
Who's he talking to?
Australian Embassy.
Unfortunately, there
was some confusion.
We intubated him first,
and then, we found the DNR.
Yes, I know.
Mark...
No, no, no, he never should
have been put on the ventilator
to begin with.
I just need the legal okay
to take him off.
Mark...
Absolutely.
His pulse ox barely registers.
There's not a single
functioning organ
left in his body.
He's got one foot
in the grave, okay?
This man...
Is awake!
I'll call you right back.
Mr. Johnson, do you
know where you are?
You're very sick.
You were found
unconscious at your home.
Do you understand?
You want me to take that
tube out of your mouth?
There is a risk of
respiratory failure
if we take you
off the ventilator.
Are you sure that
that's what you want?
All right.
What I want you to do
is to blow real hard
on the count of three.
Okay. One, two
three, blow.
Good, good.
You okay, Mr. Johnson?
Call me Jack.
The Compazine wore off
and now, I'm sick
to my stomach again.
What a day, huh?
I just want to go
home and go to bed.
So, tell me, how much longer
are we going to
put up with this?
With what?
With Benton.
What else we going to do?
I don't know if I can
take this abuse for a year.
Betty?
Betty, what happened?
Smoke inhalation.
There was a fire.
Was anybody hurt?
Just me.
What about your apartment?
It's gone.
Everything.
The whole building.
The whole building?
Yes.
My floor too?
Yes!
She's not here.
I think she went home.
Damn.
So there he was,
naked as a jaybird.
I mean, not a stitch.
So I said
"Son, what the
hell are you doing?"
He turns, looks straight at me
and says, "Fishing, Pop.
Fishing."
He's a sweet boy.
Just slow.
You want me to call him?
No.
I don't like him
driving at night.
We're going to transfer
you up to intensive care.
They'll make sure
you're comfortable.
Is there anything else I can do?
No.
I had a good spin.
Saw two wars...
Ten Chevys...
Boston, San Francisco
Paris, France.
Married a woman
who put up with me
and died as beautiful
as the day we met.
Can't ask for more.
Hi. Uh, is Dr. Anspaugh here?
He's not here.
He was supposed
to be here at 6:00.
He was. He left
about five minutes ago.
Uh, listen, um...
You have his pager number?
Sorry, I'm new here.
Yeah, beautiful.
Thank you.
Hey, you're Benton, aren't you?
Abbey Keaton.
I'd shake your hand, but
I've got pepperoni on mine.
Don's just letting me use
his computer till I move over.
Well, it's...
Sorry.
Uh...
It's a pleasure to meet you.
You know what, actually...
I've been trying to get
in touch with you all day.
I got your note.
So, you're interested
in pediatric surgery.
Yes, I am, very much.
Mm-hmm.
How do you feel about deep-dish
pepperoni and anchovies?
Well, um, I don't
eat meat, but, hey.
You could scrape it off.
Sit down.
Let's talk.
Gee, it's cold out tonight.
Yeah, it feels like fall.
You off?
Waiting for a break in the rain.
How long have you
and Al been separated?
Almost a year.
No chance of a reconciliation?
No.
Mmm.
Must be tough to
be sick and alone.
A good friend of mine
tested positive last year.
I think I'm one of the
two people he's told.
He's a lawyer.
Didn't want to
tell his coworkers.
Afraid he might lose clients.
It's got to be hard
to carry that around all day.
It is.
I'm glad you decided
to keep working.
It would be a real
loss to the patients
if you quit.
Is there anything you need?
No, I'm okay.
Okay.
It's freezing out here.
Well, good night.
Wait, wait. You're serious?
Yeah, yeah.
Aah!
I've given it a lot of thought
and I've decided
to be spontaneous.
What the hell,
I'm going to Maui.
Good for you.
You don't think I
misread the situation?
You don't invite
somebody to Maui
to play scrabble by the pool.
So how's that new intern?
Doyle? She's fine.
She's competent, does her job.
What do you think, keep her?
Sure, keep her. Why not?
Mark, I need your signature.
Oh, more paperwork
on Mr. Johnson.
Surprise, surprise.
Transfer orders?
Death certificate.
What?
He arrested in the elevator.
ICU never admitted him
so technically, he's
still your patient.
Hey, that's my locker.
Gotcha.
So do you get back to
the neighborhood much?
Uh, every night.
I'm still living
with my parents.
Really?
Yeah, same room I used
to share with my sisters.
I'm trying to save
money, you know.
You could always
sell the beamer.
It was a gift from my dad.
Bought it at a police auction.
Oh, he's a cop?
Third generation.
He wanted me to be the
first female commissioner
but I took after my ma.
Oh, she's a doctor.
Nurse.
I was going to be
until I got kicked
out of nursing school.
I never was very
good at taking orders.
See ya.
Jerry, I don't want that thing
eating out of my mixing bowl.
Oh, ma, I'll clean
it when I'm done.
Lewis, Weaver, Weaver.
Ross, Lewis. Greene?
Did you work today?
Yeah.
This it?
Uh-huh.
You mean to tell me you worked
a 12 hour shift and you
saw only one patient?
It was unusually time consuming.
What was the outcome?
He died.
On the other end of the scale
it looks like we have a tie
between Dr. Lewis
and Dr. Weaver.
Last patient, out the door.
Well, congratulations, Doctor.
You win the gumdrops.
Greene...
It's the uh, black
Cadillac Seville.
Front row, burgundy interior.
Don't forget the sidewalls.
Is he serious?
No.
I want to talk to you
about that invitation.
I'm sorry about that.
No, no, I... I...
I hope you didn't
misunderstand me.
I mean, we can
still get you a room
if you still want to come.
Oh.
But you can't, that's okay.
I wasn't really
serious about it myself.
Right.
So, uh, I'll see
you in ten days.
Sure. Don't worry about the cat.
Thank you.
Have a great trip.
Call me.
Yeah, from the pool.
Bye.