- How is Jacob today?
- Same as yesterday.
- Ava.
How is Jacob today?
- That's why I've been looking
for you.
Well, if it isn't
my daily lifesaver.
- Ah--oh, don't forget
that tomorrow
the daycare is closed
until 10:00.
- It is?
Uh, how am I--
what am I gonna do?
- Doesn't Luna
have a babysitter?
- Uh, you're looking at him.
Friends?
Yeah, you're looking at him.
- Sorry, Dr. Goodwin,
but tomorrow's
the "Breastfeeding Class
for New Moms."
- Right--whose idea was that?
- Yours.
- Yeah, it was mine.
I knew that.
Bye.
- Hello?
- Um, hi, this is, uh,
Max Goodwin,
not sure if you remember me.
We met in the waiting room
at New Amsterdam.
- Mm.
No, it doesn't ring a bell.
- Oh, uh, okay.
Sorry, nevermind.
- I'm kidding, I'm kidding!
How could I forget the doctor
who snuck me in
to my kid's surgery?
- Yeah.
Yeah, right.
Um--
so, the reason I'm calling
is that
it appears Luna has an opening
in her very busy schedule
tomorrow morning
and was wondering
if Bobbi would like to play
some competitive racquetball.
- Oh, wow.
Yeah, Bobbi would love that.
She's been working
on her backhand.
- Good, okay, great.
'Cause Luna has been
practicing her topspin, so--
- Actually, we have
this routine.
We've been spending
our mornings
in Madison Square Park
across from the dog run.
Around 8:00 a.m.?
- Uh, yeah--no, 8:00 a.m. is,
uh, perfect.
I will see you there--
we will see you there.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
- It's not as though
I haven't tried to tell him.
- It's not that hard.
You just say, "Max, Amy and I
are moving to San Francisco."
Boom.
Done.
Unless you were dragging
your size 12's for a reason.
- Woman...
you are way off base.
Am I?
- Yeah.
- Maybe you just prefer
subway rats and dirty slush
over wine country and winters
that feel like spring.
- Ah.
- Thank you.
- Oh, here we go.
About to show you how bad I
wanna go right here, right now.
- All right,
show me what you got.
- All right, look.
Yo, Max.
Can I talk to you for a second?
- Yeah, actually, you're just
the man I wanted to see.
Uh, can you cover
for me tomorrow
at the, uh,
"Pharmacy Formulary Meeting"?
- Look before we get into
all that--
- I know it's boring,
but I've been struggling
with this whole
single parenting thing,
and, um, I have an opportunity
to give Luna a playdate
with this other little girl,
and I just feel like
I need some time to, you know,
be a dad
and try to give her everything
Georgia would've wanted.
- Max, I--
- He'll cover for you.
He will cover for you.
- Really?
- You kidding?
Go be a dad.
- Yeah?
Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
- Amazing. I owe you, buddy.
Big time.
Thank you.
- Yeah, okay,
that was harder than it looked.
- You're weak.
- Morning.
Yikes.
Hey.
Sounds like Ashley's trying
to break her own record, huh?
- Nonstop screaming for
three days takes dedication.
- Right.
- I think she's determined
to make a point.
A thank you
from Nelson's family.
Isn't that so nice?
- Aw, yeah.
That is lovely.
And out you go.
Okay.
- If you'd read the card,
you'd know they were for
the whole department.
- I'm only making healthy
choices now.
For Martin, for my kids.
Healthy choices, Gladys.
Healthy choices!
- Okay, do you know what?
Just stop.
Rodney, look at me.
This is an emergency room.
Every time you guys update
the system this happens,
and it's unacceptable.
I need to be able to update
patient files.
I need to be able to check
lab results.
I need computers that recognize
the letter "H".
- I fixed the "H" thing.
- Rodney.
- Just give me another minute.
- I put Louise Galena
in Bay 28.
She definitely has cellulitis
and a severe fungal infection.
- Okay, we're gonna need
a Hematology consult.
Let's page Sharpe.
- Oh, uh, I wouldn't.
It's all connected.
Just to be safe.
- Go and find Sharpe in person
and drag her down here
yourself, and you--yeah.
- Almost got it!
- Thank you.
Thank you, thank you,
thank you.
It's very exciting.
It is a Phase Two trial
of a vascular endothelial
growth factor receptor
antagonist.
- How many patients
do you anticipate enrolling?
- Funding covers up to 40.
- And are there any
demographic parameters?
- Yes, I am looking for men
and women age 40 to 65
with naive tumors.
Do any of you have patients
fitting that criteria?
Fabulous.
Forward me their files,
and we will get started
on this bad boy.
- Okay, now we have
a lot to cover
so let's start on page one.
Using objective market and...
- Louise, hi.
I'm Dr. Sharpe.
- Hi.
- May I take a look
at your arm?
- Mm-hmm.
- Now that's pretty.
Is it a daisy?
- Daylily.
I like to grow them.
- There's fabric around
the infection sites.
Do you know what it is?
Pantyhose.
Sometimes I try
to hide my extra skin
by wrapping them up.
When I wear the right blouse,
people don't stare so much.
- They make compression
sleeves for that
that won't abrade your skin.
- I can't afford those.
I tried to leave it looser
this time.
- So this has happened before?
- Yeah.
- Okay, we're going to get you
started on some anti-fungals.
Have you feeling better
straight away.
- Know what would actually
make me feel better?
Taking my garden shears and
slicing these things clean off.
- We're gonna do
everything that we can.
Lauren.
Louise Galena just mentioned
self-harm.
- Minister Reid.
Brand new T-shirts, I see?
Very bright.
- Helps if people know
why we're here, Max.
- Yeah, didn't realize it was
our turn again so soon.
- You can always check our
website to see our route.
- Good to know.
- What do you say?
Have a little interfaith
prayer with us today?
We could use your help.
- I think I'll, uh,
stick to helping people
the old fashioned way.
- I think prayer's been around
longer than medicine,
my friend.
- Dr. Goodwin.
- Yeah?
- You want me to clear
these folks out of here?
- Aw, no, it's fine, Joe.
They're not hurting anybody.
- You got that right.
I heard after they showed up,
some guy who was in a coma
14 years woke up.
- I knew this day would come.
After all these years,
his eyes are finally open.
And he's looking at me!
He's squeezing my hand.
I can feel him!
- Those are reflexive actions
of his brainstem.
- I have been coming
here for 14 years,
sitting by his side,
waiting for him to look at me.
And he is.
People have been known
to wake up from comas, yes,
but that's not Jacob.
He remains in a persistent
vegetative state.
He's not in there, Annie.
- How can you say that?
I mean, how can you know?
Truly?
- This is the miracle
I've been waiting for.
My husband's back.
And now you have to make him
whole again.
- Oh, keep the change.
Thank you.
Hello.
So I see your prayer buddies
have returned.
- It does feel like they're
here more often, doesn't it?
Why?
What's that smile?
- What this thing?
- Yeah.
- It's nothing.
They irk you,
and I find it funny.
- No, I think it's great
they wanna help the sick,
I just don't know how they're
gonna do that from the lobby.
- Although, I gotta say,
right after they showed up
my patient Ashley
who's been screaming at the
top of her lungs for three days
miraculously stopped.
- You don't seriously think
it's from the praying, do you?
- I don't ask questions.
I just enjoy the silence.
Which has allowed me, actually,
to jot down a bunch of ideas
for our Pharmacy Formulary
meeting tomorrow.
they're some winners.
- Well, you'll be sharing them
with Reynolds
because I have a, um,
playdate.
- You have a playdate?
- Luna and her new friend
have a playdate.
Her mother and I will just
be there for supervision.
You know, make sure
nobody falls off a--
- Yes, Max Goodwin, I fully
support this next step for you.
This is good.
- Not a step, not a step.
Not stepping, just a playdate.
- Yeah, but it's got the word
"date" baked right into it.
- I know,
but play is the first word,
so I don't think it's a date.
- Semantics.
- I don't think it's a date.
- It's a date, it's a date.
- I think it's just playing.
- Boy, you do not stay
in one place for long, do you?
- Could've just paged me.
- It's not really an option.
We just admitted a 13-year-old
who's presenting with symptoms
of a heart attack.
He checks all the CDC boxes,
and you wanted to know if--
- When New Amsterdam
got our first case.
- Yeah, and Reynolds
is with him right now.
- Okay, thanks.
- Jackson has extensive damage
to both of his lungs.
I'm going to have to perform
what is called
a "Bronchial-Alveolar Lavage"
to determine the extent
of his injuries.
- So it's not a heart attack?
- No, CDC is calling it
"EVALI."
- I've never heard of that.
- That's because the disease
is only a few months old.
It stands for E-cigarette
or Vaping Lung Injury.
- Vaping?
- He's an honor student.
He's in all AP courses.
Have you seen him smoking?
- No, never.
- Well, kids have become really
good at hiding these things
sometimes in, uh, plain sight.
It's an epidemic.
- Jack?
- Will he be all right?
- This is an unknown world,
Mrs. Lowe.
- Even now, your son is one
of only hundreds of cases.
But we are gonna do everything
that we can.
- Um, hi, Alice, this message
is for Bobbi, actually.
Unfortunately,
Luna had something
very important come up,
and she can no longer make it
to the playdate tomorrow, so--
uh, sorry for the short notice,
I'm just--um, sorry.
- Looks like you could use some
positive vibes aimed your way.
- I have no problem
with you guys being here,
but I also have
a 13-year-old patient
with a disease that has
no known cure.
So if you and your group
really wanted to help out,
you could try donating
blood or volunteering.
- Max, these people
are donating.
- You know what I mean.
- But I don't think you know
what I mean, hmm?
I love science, medicine.
I believe in them,
but they can't explain what I
appreciate most in this world.
Love, music, heroism.
So we throw our anchor past
the senses into a deeper truth.
The intangible.
- Yeah, well, I guess when
lives are at stake,
I'm just more interested
in the tangible.
- Hey, Dr. G, did you hear?
- Hear what?
- They just told me
I was in remission.
What are the odds, huh?
- Big Mike, that's amazing.
- Give me some.
You mind if I sit in?
- No, man, please.
This is ridiculous.
- Unbelievable.
- Okay, okay, listen up.
I mean, we have already
cut screens
from patient interactions.
We don't need computers.
All we need is our wits
and some paper.
All right, come on.
Let's do this.
- Since I can't email
prescriptions to the pharmacy,
how are discharged patients
gonna get their meds?
- You'll write them down.
Maybe here on this pad.
And what shall we call
this amazing invention?
This pad on which
we write prescriptions?
- Um, he's got abdominal pain.
- And?
- Usually the computer tells me
what comes next
after I type in the symptom.
- Are you seriously telling me
that one of my residents
doesn't know what to do
about a tummy ache?
Okay, this is ridiculous.
How is there not
a single working pen
in this entire building?
- Here, try this one.
- Incoming!
- All right,
now we're in business.
Watch and learn.
All right, fellas,
what do we got?
- 53-year-old male
complaining of crushing
substernal chest pain.
- Okay, what's your name, sir?
- Ikaika Namakaokealohahaunele.
- With an "A" or an "E"?
- Ever since I was a kid,
I was big.
By the time I was 20,
I was about 375 pounds.
I could barely walk.
- That must've been
frustrating.
- People'd say I wasn't trying
hard enough to lose the weight.
That it was my fault
I was so fat.
- That's--
obesity is not
a willpower issue.
It's not.
- Mm-hmm.
I've, um, you know--
I've been there.
- So you know.
Then one of my doctors told me
obesity was a disease.
- Yeah.
- And like any other disease,
it could be treated.
- Yeah, that's correct.
- Well, I was ready to try
damn near anything.
So I started taking
this medication,
and I started losing weight,
and I felt healthier.
I really did, but they never
told me about these skin flaps.
Wasn't like I loved
my body before,
but at least
it was my body.
This makes me feel like
I'm wearing an extra coat.
People stare at me more now
than they did when I was fat.
- Louise, do you ever think
about hurting yourself?
- Hey, there are--
there are surgeries.
You know that right?
Where they remove
the excess skin--
- It's all I think about,
but it costs a fortune,
and my insurance won't pay
for it, so this is my life now.
- No, no, that is not the case.
I'm not giving up on you.
Okay?
Don't you either.
- Helen, hey.
- Hi.
Did any of your patients
get into Dr. Castro's
Stage Two trial?
- Only one.
- Hm.
Not a single one
of my eligible patients got in.
- None?
- None of Dr. Shoji's either.
Now if Dr. Castro's gotten
government funding
for 40 patients,
where are they coming from?
- I flew all the way
from Chicago for this?
- Sam, come on.
- Sorry, it's just--
- Your father's still in there
trying to talk to us.
Trying to communicate with us.
- But he's not.
I mean, why can't you see that?
He's gone.
- Mom, we know how badly you
want Dad to still be here.
We miss him too, but these
are just involuntary movements.
- I mean, at this point
we're all doing involuntary
movements.
- You haven't been here.
Neither of you
have been here enough
to see that these
are different.
- Are these different?
- No.
- Does our father show
any signs of--what is it?
Higher brain function?
- No.
- And you told us 14 years ago
that it takes more
than a beating heart
to declare someone alive,
so is my father alive?
- He has no cerebral
cortical function,
so I would have to say no.
- You listen to him, Mom?
Please?
He told us this 14 years ago.
He just said it again.
How much longer do
we have to be stuck
at this never-ending wake?
- Sam's right, Mom.
- It looked so real.
- We all want it to be real;
it just isn't.
- What would happen
if we were to, uh...
...To let him go?
- If we were to remove
his, uh, feeding tube,
his body would be deprived
of nutrients,
and within a few days
his organs would start to fail,
but I assure you
that he would not experience
any pain or suffering.
- ...90.
- 50 mils normal saline
at 24 degrees standing by.
- Initial BAL results show
lipid laden macrophages
consistent with
hot chemical burns.
Basically the same
as chemical warfare.
Any ideas?
- Not off the top of my head.
So let's see what
the CDC recommends.
- When's the last time
you had to look up
a treatment guideline?
- I don't know.
Not since I was an intern.
All right, the, uh, CDC
recommends this week,
let's see here--
"vent settings with low tidal
volumes and high P.E.E.P."
- That's temporizing, at best.
- Well, we're all
flying blind here.
Let me try to locate a, uh,
PCSK9 modulator.
A dose or two might knock down
some of the inflammation.
- Based on what evidence?
- Like I said, flying blind.
- He could hear us.
He knew what
we were talking about.
He was begging for us to stop--
- Mom, please.
- Annie, that was an expulsion
of air over his vocal cords.
Just a reflex,
like his eye movements.
- I can't believe I almost made
the biggest mistake of my life.
- Dr. Kapoor,
how long could he live if
she kept the feeding tube in?
- Conservative guess?
Another 20 years.
- I can't do this
another 20 years.
I can't.
Goodbye, Mom.
- You're leaving?
I don't--
I don't know what else to do.
- He's my husband!
- He was.
He was your husband.
And he was my father.
I swear it's like you both died
that day.
- Sam, your mother has--
- She's tethered herself
to this bed.
Never leaving the borough.
Never getting to know
her grandchildren.
14 years wasted and for what?
- I'm not removing
his feeding tube.
- Yeah.
Well...
- Well, despite the chest pains
and labored breathing,
your EKG came back normal.
So maybe there's
an environmental cause?
What do you do for a living?
- I work the L Train expansion.
- Oh, so we're both
in the Dark Ages.
- You wear a mask
in the tunnels?
- Nah, I don't like
the smell of my own breath.
- You exercise?
- Only if you count smoking.
- All right,
deep breath for me.
- All right, this could be
pulmonary edema.
We're gonna get you on lasix,
and then back to making
questionable health choices
in no time.
- Hey, doc, just remember,
if I drop dead, the L Train's
only gonna take longer.
- Duly noted.
Where's his chart?
- Whose chart?
- Who's got Ikaika's chart?
- Sorry, I was putting
notes on it.
- Is that a coffee stain?
- ...while getting coffee.
- Okay, new rule, people.
The charts don't come with you.
You come to the charts, okay?
Give me that.
- Valentina!
I've, uh,
I've been meaning to ask,
how's enrollment going
on your trial?
- Great.
Thanks.
- You filled all 40 slots?
- I'm only enrolling 15.
- Isn't it our goal to help
as many people as we can?
- My goal is not to help
40 people right now,
but to help millions later when
we bring a new drug to market.
- I just see people
who are suffering now,
and you can help them.
That's why I brought you here.
- Helen, you did not
bring me here.
And I don't appreciate
your tone.
In fact, now that I'm chair,
I don't even have to have
this conversation.
- No.
- Was not the answer
I was hoping to hear.
- We don't cover
brachioplasties.
They're cosmetic.
- No.
No, no, no.
This, uh, this is not cosmetic.
I mean, yes,
technically it is cosmetic.
You busted me,
but, uh, Louise--
her skin leaves her
with a whole host
of very real psychological
and physical problems.
- Sorry.
Her claim is rejected.
- Hardball.
I heard about you.
I can play that game.
May I?
Why don't I reword
Louise's diagnosis?
"Louise Galena has
Body Dysmorphic Disorder."
And that one is in the DSM.
So what do you say?
You wanna try this dance
one more time?
- Mental illness is not
justifiable reason
for cosmetic surgery.
If it were, they'd have to
cover every sad person
who thought a face lift
could cure their depression.
Brachioplasties are coded in
the system as cosmetic,
and there are no enhancements
or modifiers
that will ever change that.
- But this is--this is a life
or death situation, Larkin.
It is.
Louise is depressed.
She's angry.
She's struggling.
She came to us for help,
and we only cured her halfway.
We left he with rolls
of loose skin that chafe
and give her
necrotic infections.
And you're telling me
with all your knowhow,
there's nothing
we can do for her?
- We can cover meds
for the rashes.
- Dr. Kapoor.
Something's wrong with Jacob.
I only had my eyes closed
for a moment.
And when I woke
he was like this.
You have to do something.
You have to bring him back.
- Annie, there is nothing
I can do.
- Surely there's something--
he was improving!
- He wasn't.
Whether his eyes
are closed or open,
whether he's squeezing
your hand or sleeping,
Jacob is not here.
He never was.
- He's all I have left.
- Uh, got the modulator.
Almost to you.
- Jackson popped a lung.
- The ventilator was supposed
to keep him stabilized!
- He was stable,
and then he just crashed.
I can't figure out
what the hell changed.
- Hey, uh, what happened
to the prayer group?
- They left, like,
five minutes ago.
- Oh, there you are.
- I'm on my way out.
Can it wait?
- It's about Castro's
clinical trial.
I have some concerns.
- So I've heard.
- What do you mean?
- Uh, Castro already
came to me.
Apparently she has
some concerns with you.
She has concerns with me?
- Well, that you're having
trouble accepting your new role
in the department, and that
you're overstepping her trial.
- That's--all I did
was point out
that she's leaving
25 patient slots unfilled.
That's 25 patients we could
be helping, but we're not.
- Well, I hear you,
and I agree.
- I should jolly well hope so.
- But NIH is funding the trial.
They're paying us, and Castro
is in the driver's seat.
- Okay, so we just stand by and
watch her cherry-pick patients?
- No, we stand by
and let Castro run the trial
the way she wants
because those are the rules.
- I'm certainly glad to know
that we're all about
following rules these days.
Helen, that's not what--
- May I?
Your mother loves you
very much.
- She barely knows me.
Or my kids.
- She gave up everything
after Dad's accident.
My wife died
several years ago...
And I would have done
anything to bring her back.
I cannot imagine
if she was still breathing
in front of my very eyes.
As a neurologist,
I know your father is dead.
His soul is gone.
But even I would find it
difficult to say good-bye.
Your mother sees that...
And she's trapped between
life and death.
She wants to move on.
She wants to let go.
- So why can't she?
- Because she has
pushed you both away.
If she lets your father go,
once and for all,
she believes she will be
truly alone.
- We've reached a crossroads,
Rodney.
- Look, closing in.
No, like, for real this time.
- How close are we talking?
- Four keystrokes.
Just gotta pop in my ADMIN
password, and we're home.
Oh.
- Oh, you are so lucky
you're in an emergency room
right now, Rodney.
- Hey, help!
I need help!
- What is it?
- I can't see.
It's my right eye.
I can't see anything!
- Okay, okay, okay.
Uh, we're gonna need a CT
with contrast, and let's page--
no, no,
run and find ophthalmology.
- Mr. and Mrs. Lowe?
So...
your son's lungs
have failed,
and we had to put Jackson
on heart-lung bypass.
Will he be okay?
- Will he get...
- We just don't know enough
about the disease yet
to make any kind of prediction.
- Vaping's been around
for years.
How can you guys
still not know?
- The products
are always changing.
And they're not being tested;
they're not being regulated.
I mean, we're still learning
what the chemicals are doing
to his body and to his lungs.
I'm sorry,
I wish I had better news.
- What are you saying?
- I'm gonna do everything
in my power to help your boy,
but you need to be
prepared for...
- No.
- It's--
- No!
- Hey, uh, Mr. Reid.
Uh, I checked the website.
You're right, very thorough.
- Max, what are you doing here?
- Um, do you remember
the teenager
that I was telling you about?
He's, uh--
let's say his situation has
exceeded the limits
of, uh, modern medicine,
and he's just a kid.
Uh, he made an honest mistake,
and, uh, he's running out
of time, so I thought...
I thought maybe you guys
could--
- Pray for him?
- Put him in your minds,
or whatever it is that you--
Um, his name is Jackson Lowe,
and he could really use--
- A miracle.
- If you have one to spare.
- Max.
Doesn't work that way.
- Then why do you do it?
I mean, why else do you come in
my hospital?
Why do you come here?
- You know what miracles are?
They're the word
for the shoreline
between what we understand
and what we can't.
- Then what is praying
if not asking for some higher
power to do something helpful,
something useful?
- When we do it right,
prayer changes us.
Not the other way around.
Whether we're praying for
forgiveness, or gratitude,
or guidance,
we're not looking out, Max.
We're looking in.
And if you can find that
shoreline within yourself,
I mean really find it,
that's when you got a shot
at one of your miracles.
- Hey.
Hi.
- Sorry, I'm--
I usually save
my violent outbursts
for somewhere
a little more private.
- Hey, believe me,
there are way worse things
you can do alone
in a stairwell.
- All I was trying to do
was help more people,
and I'm the one who gets
clobbered for it?
- You get clobbered--
I'm sorry, by who?
Oh--
By the relentlessly unfair and
stupid system we all live in.
Ah, that.
- Yes, I'm very familiar
with its work.
Do you, um--do you remember
the patient you referred to me?
- Yeah, Louise Galena.
- Galena, yeah.
- So despite substantial
physical and emotional
suffering,
insurance,
in their infinite wisdom,
has decided not to cover
her skin removal surgery.
They're calling it cosmetic.
Cosmetic--
it's just, like--
If you had
a breast cancer patient
who needed a mastectomy,
insurance would cover that
plus the reconstructive surgery
after it, yes?
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah!
Because with cancer, insurance
pays to finish the job.
But Louise has been
just abandoned
halfway through a treatment
because even though obesity
is a disease,
it still isn't treated
like one.
- Then let's give her cancer.
- What?
Hello?
Up there?
I'm not really into this whole
praying thing, but, uh...
My parents did a lot of it
when my sister was sick, and...
Didn't do a lot of good,
but...
I could really use
a miracle down here.
And I know that's
not how it works.
Believe me.
But of all the...
chaos in the world,
all the unfathomable,
unspeakable things
that happen to people...
Can't one of them be good?
I don't have anything to, um,
bargain with,
or offer except maybe this...
Empty part of me that...
I'm willing to fill up
with something.
New.
Yeah, anyways.
Jackson could really use
your help.
We're in OR 7
if you need specifics.
There you go.
Hang in there.
- What are we missing?
- Who has Ikaika's chart?
- Something useful to add?
- No.
But he had some dizziness when
I took him to the bathroom.
- Whew, how about his pee,
right?
- What?
- It stank.
How'd you not notice that?
- Glass houses, my friend.
- Psh, no, my pee smells great.
- No, I mean you didn't notice
how swollen his neck was?
I read your notes.
You skipped right by it.
- How would you even
fit that in the notes?
- It isn't a computer.
You can write on the side.
- He's an elephant.
Let's get Ikaika on dialysis.
It's nephrotic syndrome.
- I think I speak for
a few of us here when I ask,
how is he an elephant?
- Well, a bunch of blind people
touching an elephant
when asked, will all say
it's something different.
The person at the trunk
will say it's a snake,
the person at the leg
will say it's a tree.
Only by combining
all of these observations
do we see it's an elephant.
Numb feet, swollen neck,
foul-smelling urine.
It's nephrotic syndrome.
- Huh.
- You had better get
the L Train done on time, okay?
Okay, Dr. Bloom.
That's it.
Just gotta reboot the system
and this whole place
will be back online.
- You know what?
Take your time.
- Oh, yeah,
that definitely looks like
a dysplastic nevi to me.
And there's one.
Yup, yup,
that one's gonna work.
- Ooh, that dot
looks super cancery.
- Maybe leave this bit
to the oncologist.
- Right.
- Is this really gonna work?
- Louise, patients
with more than 100 moles
are at far greater risk
of developing severe melanoma.
At this point, let's just say
I've lost count.
So I'm going to suggest
we skip the biopsy entirely
and have all
of the skin removed.
Just to be safe.
- And there's definitely
an insurance code for that.
- Does that mean...?
- Your procedure
will be covered fully?
Yeah.
I don't know what to say!
Thank you!
Ooh, thank you so much!
- Annie?
Tell her.
It's okay.
- We want you to be
a part of our life.
Your life.
- We just want our mom back.
- There are times when even
we find ourselves surprised.
- How did this happen?
- Could be the experimental
agent we used
to reduce the inflammation.
It could be his own body
fighting back the damage.
The CDC is still searching
for treatments,
and there are kids Jackson's
age who haven't been so lucky.
We may never know what helped
your son turn the corner today,
but sometimes
you just take the win.
Right, Max?
- Amen to that.
Uh, hey.
- Hey.
- Uh, sorry about earlier.
- It's fine.
- No, it's not,
so I made up for it.
- Well, I seem to have missed
the making up for it part.
- Yeah, well, I got a call
from our Insurance Liaison
about a patient who had 107
perfectly spaced,
atypical moles
spanning both arms,
requiring
reconstructive surgery.
She thought that sounded
a little suspect.
- Did you approve it?
- Sure did.
Told her today
was full of miracles.
- I hear you're
taking the morning off.
- No, I canceled my thing.
- What thing?
- I accidentally accepted
a date with a woman,
and I am--
not ready for that.
- Someone asked you on a date?
- Yeah, well,
she called it a playdate.
It was for the baby.
She's a mom.
- Oh.
Where was this supposed
to take place?
- Park.
- What time?
- 8:00 a.m.
- Well, that doesn't really
sound like a date.
- To be fair, she didn't
explicitly say it's not a date.
- Then why did you think
it was a date?
- Because I have no idea
what I'm doing.
Max, doesn't Luna deserve
to have a new friend?
And don't you?
-  Dreamcatcher
in the rearview mirror
Hi.
-  Hasn't caught
a thing
- Oh, look who's here.
It's Luna.
- Hi.
Hi, Bobbi.
- Hey.
- Hi...
-  $20 in souvenirs
Anything's worth trying
To stay out of your
nightmares
Few hours in
your dream last night
Always end up dying
You said because
of course I did
Oooh
Ooooh