Each of you comes
here today hopeful...
I have five rules.
Memorize them.
Can anybody name...
So, you might be thinking...
Rule number five,
when I move, you move.
I've been here before.
Trauma protocol...
This is familiar.
This is old hat.
Maybe you're wondering
why are we here?
But I promise
you're about to find out
that everything has changed.
What the hell are you doing?
You want to
swing? It feels good.
No! No, no, no! We
talked about this.
No, we mused about it.
And then we went to bed.
I think it's a great idea.
Let's open up the space.
Get a little light in here.
Or bad, it's a bad idea.
Who wants open or
sun? Bad sun. I hate sun.
I'm used to living with
someone who knows me,
who knows not to change the
channel during the commercials,
someone who knows not to
punch a hole in my living room wall.
You know, it's not
that big of a hole.
We can probably
just patch it right up.
I bet she tries to patch it up,
instead of trying to just
imagine the possibility.
But, I mean, it is
Meredith's house.
I mean, it's my house.
And I let her live there.
I should know better.
Why don't I learn?
I take in strays
because they're sad.
They're lonely and homeless.
The truth is strays
are flea-ridden creatures
who pee on your stuff.
Am I a stray?
I mean, she acts like
I'm some kind of animal,
when who does the dishes? Me.
Yep.
Who makes sure
the piles and piles
of dirty laundry are
fluffed and folded?
Me.
When she puts my clothes away,
I can't find my own
clothes in my own house.
I mean, they're probably
just in your drawers.
It's a problem.
What's her problem?
It's just... She's just...
She's just impossible.
Just impossible.
Hey, you excited?
About?
April. She's coming
in tonight, right?
Oh, um... Yeah.
I still think you should bow
out of this anatomy class
you signed up to teach.
I mean, pawn it off on
Grey or someone else.
You're not gonna have
time to teach a class
once you've been
appointed Chief.
Haven't been appointed yet.
Um, do you know her?
Uh, that's Dr. Tracy McConnell.
Chief Cardio at Hopkins,
Yale Grad, Yale Meds.
SAGES award recipient.
She's Catherine's
candidate for chief.
Dr. Webber.
Hey. It is such an honor.
I have been wanting
to meet you for years.
Your work with islet cells,
it's just absolutely inspiring.
Well, thank you. Thank you.
Oh, all right, I'm
sorry. This is Dr...
Dr... Yeah, Miranda
Bailey, of course.
Hello. Oh.
Uh, I'm afraid you
may have gotten
your times a little
wrong, Dr. McConnell.
Our presentations to the board
aren't until 4:00 p.m. today.
Actually, I asked
Dr. Webber if he wouldn't mind
taking some time this
morning to show me around.
You know, give me a little tour.
I wasn't invited on any tour.
Um...
You know where everything is.
Uh, don't you have
some surgeries, Doctor?
Nothing that can't be pushed.
Great. Mmm.
Sounds fun.
That's one word for it.
So, what time's
the thing tonight?
What thing?
For April. She comes
back tonight, right?
Isn't... Aren't we
doing a thing?
Big night, Avery.
When's Kepner getting in?
No idea.
Then what time's the thing?
There is no thing.
Should we clear Trauma One
to remove the giant
bug from Avery's ass?
Hey, I need advice.
Okay.
I got tickets for
this concert thing,
and I'm thinking
about asking Amelia,
but she and I, we don't
really go to things together.
Not that we couldn't,
but should I, you
know, ask her out?
What do you think?
I think you're over-thinking.
You're late.
I know. I'm sorry.
I got stuck behind a train
that just stopped forever.
I'm sorry. You said a crash?
I mean, I should have
done, like, turned around
but they shouldn't be
allowed to do that, right,
just stop on the tracks?
I really don't care,
okay? You missed rounds.
A pedestrian? Two pedestrians?
It's irresponsible is
what it is, of the train.
Two pedestrians
were hit by a train?
What?
Oh, my God.
And they're alive?
Yeah. Oh, my God.
Two girls were hit by a
train on their way to school.
Kids. Um...
They're just kids.
Jessica Tanner, 15 years old.
Moving train swiped her, then
tossed her down the embankment.
GCS is 15. Pressure's 100 palp.
Right side took all the
brunt. It's one big bruise.
There's a shortcut to school.
I take it every day
over the tracks.
She's tachy at 120.
All right, I'm gonna
need a Doppler
to check these
extremities for pulses.
I tripped.
You know, my foot, it got
stuck in between the tracks.
Try to stay calm, Jess.
Have you seen
the other girl? She...
She just showed
up out of nowhere.
She tried to push
me out of the way.
Somebody? I'm not
sure what to do here!
Oh!
Help get the other
patient inside.
Go. Torres.
Take a look at this. Oh...
Hey, it's gonna
be all right, Jess.
We're gonna take care
of you. Both of you. Okay?
Let's go. Go.
Hang two units of "O"
neg, check the pelvic binder,
and prep her for a
rapid-sequence intubation.
Any word on her
name? Her parents?
I don't think she had any I.D.
Did you look? Did
you check her bag?
Okay, where do you need me?
She needs an ex lap.
One of her legs was ripped
completely away from the other.
She has a wishbone injury.
The force of the train broke her
pelvis and split her insides apart.
I'm gonna need to stabilize
her pelvis and extremities,
but not before you guys
address her internal injuries.
Pupillary reflexes are sluggish.
She's gonna need a head CT to
rule out a traumatic brain injury.
All right, you got
a name for me yet?
No, but I found some textbooks.
Sophomore, junior, maybe. I'm
guessing she's about 16 years old.
Okay, hang on, hang on. Quiet.
Mom.
I want my mom.
Grey, we're gonna
need to intubate. Okay.
We don't have
much time. Go ahead.
Good. You're here.
She's got multiple
complex injuries.
She needs to go to
the OR for a washout.
Hemothorax on her right
side that needs to be drained.
Jess.
Have you seen
her, the other girl?
Is she still alive?
Jess, can you tell me her name?
I don't know her. So...
You have the same
hearts drawn on your arms.
I think you do know each other.
Her name's Aliyah.
And you two were
out there together?
Yes.
Your foot didn't get
caught on the tracks, did it?
Honey, tell me what
happened out there.
We just wanted to be together.
Dead or alive.
And this is one of our
state-of-the-art
radiology suites.
We have just installed
new data-processing systems
with simultaneous...
Simultaneous multi-slice
holographic imaging.
Yeah.
I mean, that kind of imaging's
the wave of the future.
Wave of the future. I
couldn't agree more.
Do you mind if I
take a look around?
Be my guest.
Thank you.
Is this the new SE-700?
Yes, we just had it upgraded.
Admit it. You like her.
She's a solid
candidate, certainly.
But so is Bailey.
Bailey knows you too well.
You all have been
together too long.
She doesn't push you, Richard.
Better than that.
But in a chief, you need a chief
who knows how to push back.
Are you implying she's soft?
Because Miranda
Bailey is anything but soft.
I'm saying that she's
too comfortable here.
We need someone who
will make us uncomfortable,
someone that'll walk in here
and push us to be the best.
We need someone
who will surprise us.
And you know it.
Instant access to case imaging
would really assist
with patient care.
You're only 15. You want to die?
It's more complicated than that.
You were standing
in front of a train.
We weren't suicidal. We just...
Okay, Jess, I'm gonna
tell you something personal
about myself, okay?
Okay.
I like men...
Romantically, sometimes.
And I like women, too.
It's a big, big part of my life.
Can I ask you something
personal about yourself?
Do you like girls?
Do you...
Do you like Aliyah?
I love her.
What were you
two doing out there?
It's not that we wanted to die.
This was just...
The only way that
we could stay together,
you know, forever.
No. No, Jess. There
are so many other ways.
I... Killing yourself
solves nothing.
My parents...
They're sending me away...
To a camp.
They come and get you
in the middle of the night,
and they take you to this place.
They change you.
They're gonna make me
change my mind about Aliyah.
No, they won't. There's no way.
Those places don't
work. They never work.
Your parents are doing this?
Please. Please,
you can't call them.
Please don't tell them that I...
They're the whole
reason why I'm even here.
Please. You can't call them.
Aliyah's a good girl.
She wouldn't miss school.
Why would she be
out on the train tracks?
This doesn't make sense.
She suffered extensive injuries.
She needs surgery. I
just need your consent.
She's... She's okay?
She's awake? She can talk?
No, she's unconscious.
She did ask for her mother.
Her mother's dead.
If I could just have your
consent for the surgery...
Yes.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
We're looking for our daughter.
Jessica Tanner. Can
you find us a doctor?
I'm a doctor.
I'm one of your
daughter's doctors, actually.
Well, where is she?
We want to see her
immediately, please.
They said she
was hit by a train?
Yes.
A train?
I think our daughters might have
been out on the tracks together.
Jess was with your daughter?
What's her name?
Aliyah.
I'm Dakhir Hamed.
You keep your damn
daughter away from our little girl.
No one's taken a tab.
Why hasn't anyone taken a tab?
I don't know.
Uh... What I do know is the labs
came back on the Wilbanks baby.
Everything looks good there.
My flier's perfectly placed.
It's clear,
aesthetically pleasing.
I mean, people have
taken tabs from other fliers.
I'm sorry. Why do you need a
roommate? You have a house.
Had a house.
Callie and I sold it.
Now it turns out I need a little
help in the rent department.
You'd be surprised how many
patients can't afford my fees.
I mean, what am I gonna do?
Gonna look parents
in the eye and tell them
I can't treat their teeny,
tiny, little sickly babies?
Hey.
Do you need a place to live?
Me live with you? God, no.
I just... Uh, I
already have a place.
Take a tab anyway.
I mean, someone
has to take a tab.
It'll make other
people take tabs.
It's like putting
money in your tip jar.
It just encourages tipping.
I just... I'm gonna go...
Check on things...
Away from here.
Clamp.
3-0 Prolene.
I could use a little
breathing room here.
A little more.
I can't move anymore,
or I won't be able to
zero the neuro monitor.
Everything okay?
She's just mad about the wall.
What wall?
Just stand and suction.
Not talking to you.
We did talk about
taking it down.
You talked about it. I
was drinking tequila.
Okay, you said it
was a good idea.
I should remember.
I was the sober one.
I said I would think about it.
But the words
that you said were,
"Let's take the bitch down."
That was the tequila talking.
So, when you said
this was my home, too,
that I should
think of it that way,
that was the
tequila talking, too?
Yeah, that sounds like
something tequila would say.
Can you suction over here, please?
- Mmm-hmm.
Hey, is it a load-bearing wall?
'Cause if it is, it can actually
bring the whole house down.
Yeah, Aliyah and I, we
like to pass notes at school.
The kind that you fold
a million different ways.
And I kept them, every single
one in a box under my bed,
you know, so I could re-read
them when I had bad days.
Bad days?
Sometimes kids at school...
People suck, you know,
like to tease us, throw things.
And the other day, I came home,
and my mom was in my room.
She had found my box of notes.
And she burned
them in the fireplace.
Uh, Jess' parents
want to see her
and speak to her surgical team.
They're here?
Tell them she's in pre-op.
They will have to wait to
see Jess until after surgery.
You're making Aliyah out to be
some kind of terrible influence.
Because she is. She took
advantage of our daughter.
Jess didn't know any better.
What are you talking about?
You don't know?
They think they're in love...
With each other.
They want to grow
up and get married.
What?
Honey, the doctors.
Uh, Jess has sustained multiple
fractures, including
two in her left leg
that need surgical
intervention immediately
or she could lose
use of her leg.
Unfortunately, she also
needs her belly explored
to evaluate the source
of her internal bleeding.
There's also blood in her lungs,
which required a chest tube.
Luckily, it seems to be
stable at the moment.
We're taking her up now.
We'll update you
after the surgery.
Bethany. Please, let him...
Shut up, Steven!
Shut your stupid mouth!
If you had kept your mouth shut,
Jess would be safe
at camp right now.
But you had to give her
the heads-up, didn't you?
It's okay. You had
to tell her all about it.
Torres, don't.
What are you doing, Torres?
I'm sorry, but I'm not sure you
understand what
those places are like.
I know that you're trying
to help your daughter,
but that kind of
camp is horrible.
It will not give her the kind
of support that she needs.
I realize that you
care about Jess, but...
Care about her? We love her.
She's our child. Our child.
Please, this
doesn't concern you.
Jess' fear of that place
is why she stepped in
front of a train to begin with.
No, we are not doing
this. She doesn't feel safe.
We are not doing this now!
You want to give
parenting advice?
Talk to Clueless over there.
You have no right to talk to me
about anything other than
my child's medical care.
She's right to feel afraid.
Those places are harmful.
They will damage her
mentally, emotionally.
They are tantamount
to child abuse.
Torres. You are out of line.
You are here for one
thing and one thing only,
and that is to attend
to my child's injuries,
to help my daughter.
That's it.
So you can either shut up
and do the job that you are
here to do, or I will get rid of you.
Sweetie, please.
Where do you think you're going?
Like you said, to
help your daughter.
That woman was
bullying her own child.
And, you know, don't even
get me started on the husband.
He is useless. Useless.
Poor kid's got no
one in her corner.
Mmm-mmm.
What would make someone do that?
I mean, why do
people act like that?
Karev?
Why are you asking me?
'Cause you're a bully.
His scar looks pretty nice.
I'm just gonna apply a little
more collagenase lotion here.
So, um, what is your
plan with April tonight?
So, she's gonna come
home from across the world
to what, a locked house?
Why do you think it is
that everybody thinks
they have a right to a
front-row seat to my marriage?
The show's closed.
I'm not selling tickets.
Dr. Avery?
What?
Your gastro flap harvest
is ready when you are.
That's great!
Um, can you come dress this?
Yeah.
You know if Kepner
wants a roommate?
Not if it's you.
Okay, what aren't you telling
me? You know something.
Why don't people
want to live with me?
I'm being paged.
No, you're not.
Nobody's paging you.
What, are you
telling me I'm wrong?
I watched you push
people around for years.
You bullied interns.
You bullied nurses.
Hell, you bullied George.
Don't go projecting
all your stuff on me
just 'cause you got
picked on as a kid.
Oh, no. Nobody
picked on Callie Torres.
Really?
Yeah, I was an easy target.
I didn't look like the other
girls. I didn't act like them.
I had to learn how to stand
up to people like Karev.
So I learned to fight.
Titanium screw, please?
Tell you what, though, once
you punch your first bully,
the rest start to fall
in line pretty quickly.
So you were both bullies?
What? No. Mine was self-defense.
People you two used
to call me "Li'l Maggot."
'Cause I was always
younger than you and smaller...
And smarter.
And my lisp...
You guys had a
field day with my lisp.
So I was "Li'l Maggot Pierth."
That's kind of cute.
No, it wasn't cute.
Not when I was begging
not to be pantsed in
the middle of the quad.
I mean, really think about that.
My pants were literally pulled
off of me in front of other people.
Or when I was screaming for help
after being locked
in the janitor's closet
and left there until the cops
found me the next morning.
You want to know
why bullies bully?
It's 'cause they can.
Maybe you got it worse at home,
or maybe you're just bullying to
keep from getting bullied, but really,
it's because people like me,
like this girl on our
table, are alone.
And small and vulnerable.
And pushing us around
makes you feel better about
your sad, pathetic, little lives.
But not you guys, though.
You're cool... Now.
So, after we helped
rebuild the hospital in Haiti,
I took a team down to Houston
to help the relief
shelters after the flooding.
Outstanding.
Um... So, why are you
interested in moving to Seattle?
I mean, it sounds like your
hospital's doing great work.
Oh, that wasn't
through the hospital.
I fund most of those
trips through my nonprofit.
It's a bit of a passion
project of mine.
Your nonprofit. Well, now.
Um, I started the
hospital's free clinic.
We're open
Wednesdays and Fridays.
She won't stop
bleeding. Damn it!
She's maxed out on pressors.
She can't tolerate
this low a MAP.
I'm clamping the hilum.
It's not working. Debakey.
Sorry, do you mind if I...
Come on, guys, she's crashing.
You don't think I know
that? Somebody page cardio.
You're gonna want to open
her up with a sternotomy.
I'm sorry. Who
in the hell's that?
Right, sorry. Hi. Dr. Tracy
McConnell, Chief of Cardio at Hopkins.
I'm on a tour. Now,
about that sternotomy.
Patient's chest is already open.
I don't want to make
another major incision
just a few inches
away. Where is cardio?
They're saying
Wexler and Hall are out.
- Pierce is in surgery.
- Find out how long.
Okay, I want to try
twisting the hilum. Towels.
You need to get control
from a higher angle.
Her pulmonary
artery is lacerated,
which means you
have about 90 seconds
before she bleeds
to death on that table.
I know that it seems redundant
to make another large incision
in an already-open chest,
but if you do, in under a minute,
you can have her sternum open
and get a clear
view of the field
from an entirely
different angle.
If the choice is between
giving her two chest scars
or letting her bleed to death,
I bet she would
choose the two scars.
Grey?
You're down to 60 seconds.
Okay, I need a saw
and a sternal retractor.
On it. OWEN: Prep
her for a sternotomy.
Right away.
Got it. Here's the bleeder.
Okay, I'll need 4-0 Prolene
and a pericardial patch, please.
Got it.
That was a hell of
a save, McConnell.
It's not my save, sir.
They did the hard work.
I just helped change
their perspective a little.
Well, I should probably go...
Hey. Why don't people
want to live with me?
Is it 'cause I have a kid
or is it 'cause I'm a boss?
Like people don't want
to live with their boss?
Hey, did you hear,
Dr. Torres stabbed
a white supremacist in the face?
Or a patient bit Karev and lost
his finger or his eye or some...
Shut up and speak!
What aren't you telling me?
Okay, have you
ever been assigned
back-to-back overnight
NICU shifts, Edwards?
And I'm not talking
for, like, a weekend.
I'm talking for months of
long, terrible, quiet nights
all alone in the NICU
watching over 27 incubators
full of fragile,
dying, little lives.
You know how hard that
is? Do you have any idea?
You are kind of a legend
with the interns and residents.
Go on.
You're one of the
Seattle Grace Five.
I survived a plane
crash. Big deal.
And a car crash. And a shooting.
You might be immortal.
You mastered one of the
most exclusive specialties
basically overnight, and
then you took Herman's job
and her eyesight.
Okay, that's... That's just...
You have screwed dozens of
interns, and you got them all fired.
You speak really fast,
like superhuman fast.
You have a weird name.
You know, that's not
true. That's not true.
I only slept with one intern,
and I have an awesome name.
I mean, what, man?
Like, what? What else?
I mean, what...
Do people have a problem
with the fact that I have one leg?
I mean, do people
actually go there
and talk crap about
a one-legged person?
Because that's just
discrimination against amputees.
They say you have two legs,
and you are only pretending
that one is amputated.
For the parking space. I...
We good?
Hey. Tell us something good.
Mer says Aliyah's
hanging in there.
Well, that's something.
Also, Jess might not
be going to that camp.
I may have made some calls.
Which one of you did it?
You called child
protective services on me?
Is this a joke? Is this
some game to you people?
If I want to send my
child to a beautiful camp
run by a lovely pastor
then I have every
legal right to do so,
and it is none of your business.
Do you understand? Stay
away from my little girl.
And stop filling her head
with your faithless,
inappropriate nonsense.
You repulse me.
You're disgusting!
Oh, crap.
My heart was pounding, and
there was a noise in my head
and then her face
was just coming at me
and I was like, "Ah!"
And then... Ow, ow!
My fist had a mind of its own.
'Cause I didn't even know
I was gonna punch her
until she was punched.
Oh, my God! I lost
control. I am a monster.
I would have paid money.
Cash money. Like 1,000 bucks.
Worth every penny.
It was beautiful.
Okay, what happened?
Yeah, we want details.
And would someone
page me, please,
next time Pierce hulks out?
Think it's funny? It won't
be when she loses her job.
I'm gonna lose my job?
You're not gonna lose
your job. She attacked you.
Kind of. Right?
Okay, you weren't
there. You don't know.
Oh, the lady deserved
it. She got bigot-slapped.
You know she deserved
it. It doesn't matter.
There's a right and a wrong
way for us to conduct ourselves.
Mmm. You know
what? Grey has a point.
Next time, leave the thumb
outside the fist when you clench.
That way, you avoid
bone damage. See?
Okay, bitch lady's fine
medically, no real injury,
but she is seriously pissed
and out for your head.
See? Oh, God.
Is it true? Callie
punched a homophobe?
Pierce punched a homophobe.
Ooh! Unexpected. High-five.
No. Yes!
Come on.
I have to go apologize to
that horrible woman, don't I?
What are you doing?
Scrubbing in on an
open cholecystectomy.
Yes, no, I can see that,
but what are you doing?
Why are you scrubbing in
for a three-hour procedure
when you have a presentation
to the board in 45 minutes?
The patient is in terrible pain.
I have the ability
to stop that pain,
so I'm going to do that.
So, what, you're just gonna
not show up for the presentation?
It doesn't matter if I do.
Look, I just spent the
day with Tracy McConnell.
She's chirpy and blonde
with a perky, little ponytail.
And she's...
Fantastic, smart, talented.
I tried really hard to
hate her, but I couldn't.
She's perfect. And
Webber's ready to marry her.
Hell, I might marry her, too.
No offense. She's a catch.
And we'd be lucky to have her.
Hey, she may be the new Idris.
Now, it's fine.
Okay, being Chief isn't
the only thing that I...
I mean, I've got my son that
I hardly see as it is. And you.
And I got this class that
I got to start teaching.
So, you know, it doesn't matter.
It's fine, really.
Miranda, that's... No.
Leave it alone.
Okay? Just... Leave it.
Hi.
Oh, hey. Uh, is the
room still available?
Did your friends put you up
to this? Did you lose a bet?
Or do you have a
thing for feet? Or foot?
What?
Uh, no.
Well, okay, hold on.
Why would you
want to live with me
instead of your intern buddies?
I don't, uh, have
any intern buddies.
They think I posed as
an attending on purpose
and they made up all this stuff
about me and it isn't even true.
Nobody wants to talk to
me, let alone live with me.
It's okay. Thanks.
Um... Hold on. Just so you know,
two months up front.
Yeah? Okay. Mmm-hmm.
Well... Well, we can maybe...
We can make this work.
Scrub out. I'll finish.
You can still make
your presentation.
DeLuca, will you escort Warren
out of my surgery, please?
But...
Okay.
Don't even think about
it. You do not know me.
Miranda, you are rolling over.
You are quitting in
the middle of the race,
and that is not okay.
Would you let me quit?
Would you let Tuck quit?
Would you?
What did you tell Tuck
when he wanted to
quit the French horn?
He was a terrible French
horn player, and still,
what did you tell him?
"You made a commitment."
"You made a commitment!"
And now who is first chair?
Tuck is.
Tuck is!
You don't quit.
You don't roll over.
You don't let anybody
take your chair!
Miranda Bailey,
what chair are you?
First chair. Yeah,
I cannot hear you.
What chair? First
chair? First chair.
First chair! That's right!
Jess' injuries were extensive,
but surgery went
better than expected.
Oh, thank God.
Uh, Bethany wanted me to ask,
do you know when Jess
might be discharged?
She's, I guess,
arranging for the camp
to come pick Jess
up from here, and...
What? What are you saying?
There were complications
during the surgery,
and Aliyah lost a lot of blood,
and her blood pressure
was very low for some time.
And we just won't know
if that caused damage
unless she wakes up.
So, she might not wake up?
That's what you're saying?
I'm sorry, is his
daughter going to die?
I can't discuss another
patient's personal information.
I'm so sorry.
This can't be... This
shouldn't be happening.
We wanted to give her a future.
We came to this country
when she was eight.
Two years later, my wife died.
My family, they said,
"Dakhir, you have no business
raising your daughter alone."
Maybe they were right.
What do I know
about raising a girl,
now a teenage girl, in America?
All I know is it's hard.
Aliyah doesn't confide in me.
Why would she?
In my community, we don't
talk about things like this.
Aliyah's mother would
have known what to say.
She always knew.
We came here to
give her a future.
And now...
Do you have a picture?
Excuse me?
Of your daughter?
Here's... Here's Jess.
You can't tell now with
the tube in her mouth,
but she has the best smile.
This is Aliyah maybe
a year ago now.
I took it at school
after a game.
You know, I never realized,
but I think that's your
daughter with her.
They look really happy.
I don't believe we were
introduced properly before.
I'm Steven.
Dakhir.
Your patient's been
out of surgery a while.
Did you wait to
update the family
until my patient was
out of surgery, too?
Because this hospital
is worth more than that.
Thank you. Thank you.
Bailey should be here by now.
Hi. Hello.
Sorry to interrupt, but
Dr. Bailey has a request.
I'm sure Dr. McConnell gave
you an excellent presentation.
Scissor. Watch that tissue.
She would be
excellent for the job.
But that's not the point.
The point is McConnell
and I offer different things.
She is new and shiny.
And she likes a good challenge.
I know. I spent the
whole day with her.
She jumps into new
challenges all the time.
And that's what this place is
to her. Her newest challenge.
Until she finds her next one.
And her next.
But that's not me.
See, I don't care if this place
is the shiniest or the fanciest
or if it's a beat-up
hunk of junk.
As far as I'm concerned,
it'll always be the ship
that made the Kessel
Run in less than 12 parsecs.
This is not a
stepping stone for me.
I believe in this hospital
and what it can do.
And I want to push
this bucket of bolts
to do the most impossible
things you have ever seen.
And then I'll do more
because this is my challenge.
There's a bleeder on the fossa.
Yeah. Clamp. Use the argon beam.
Avoid CBD.
Slowly.
Let me.
Good.
There.
This job was made
for me. Staples.
This job belongs to me.
Suction.
I've earned first chair.
Suture.
And every single one
of you already knows it.
Ready to close.
Well, damn it.
Dr. Hudson to OR 3.
Is Jess still at her
post-op x-rays?
Yeah, Dr. Torres
took her a bit ago.
Yeah.
You have some nerve coming here.
Bethany.
Mrs. Tanner, I would
like to apologize.
I was totally out
of line before.
To think I trusted you
to treat my daughter.
Bethany.
I am suing you and
everyone else we have met
in this godforsaken hospital.
Bethany, shut up!
No one is suing! No
one is pressing charges!
The person who should
be apologizing is you!
We almost lost our child today!
She almost died!
We are not sending Jess away!
This stops now. Do you
hear me? It stops now.
Steven, what are you saying?
This stops, or I am gone.
I will leave, and I
will take Jess with me,
and you will never
see her again.
I don't care if she's gay.
I care if she's loved.
I care if she's happy.
And that is what you
should care about!
What is wrong with
you that you don't?
So, we were able to stop
the bleeding, and she's stable.
So I thought you'd like to
see her because she is awake.
It's okay. It's okay.
I'm here, Aliyah.
You're okay.
Jessica is okay, too.
Shh. Don't try
to talk. It's okay.
I have something for you.
Jessica asked if I
could read this to you if...
When you wake up.
So...
"Dear my beautiful Aliyah..."
Well, I like her already.
Oh.
Sorry. You know, I, uh...
I thought...
Why aren't you at home?
Because I thought
you'd be at home.
Right, well, I just
assumed that...
It's fine. Just, um...
Go and sleep there
tonight. A real bed and all.
Right. Real bed. Yeah. Thanks.
I've been flying all day.
I'm exhausted. Dirty.
Okay.
But we can talk tomorrow?
I really want us
to talk, Jackson.
Good night.
Behold.
Everything the light
touches is yours.
You're stupid.
Congratulations, Chief.
This looks amazing.
This is amazing.
Now, I love that
you love feeding me,
but I can't keep eating
like this every night.
I'm gonna get fat.
What's wrong with
being fat? I used to be fat.
That's funny. No, really.
I mean, not just
roly-poly. I mean big.
I mean, it didn't
matter much till what,
I don't know, 5th
grade, maybe? 6th?
And then suddenly,
everybody seemed to care.
I got picked on a bunch.
I mean, stupid stuff, you
know? Names, pranks.
They shoved me in a
locker once, and I got stuck.
I was...
Well, I was the fat kid in class
and the screw-up at home.
And it sucked. I
mean, it was really hell.
So in the summer
after 8th grade,
when I basically spent three
straight months on my bike
riding everywhere,
all day, every day,
literally riding my ass off.
School started.
Nobody recognized me.
I toughened up. I mean,
I had to, you know?
Want more rice?
Who does that?
Who carpools to work with
somebody in the morning
and then leaves
without them that night?
I can't believe she...
She just left me.
I'm happy to give you a
ride. Actually, I did want to...
I don't even want to
go in there. I may lose it.
Not even kidding. I may...
What's happening?
You. Come here.
I...
Sorry.
Sit. Good.
I want you to stop
and take a closer look
at the body in front of you.
I live here, too, and
that means I get a say.
And I say you two need
to figure your crap out.
There's nothing
special about it.
It's just a body.
So, why are you here?
What's so different?
What's changed?
Sorry about the wall.
I...
Jumped the gun.
I'm sorry I said you had fleas.
Meredith! What?
I don't...
I don't know how to talk to
you. You are a lot sometimes.
I don't totally like you.
Wow. Okay.
But I don't have to,
because you're family.
I love you.
My answer is...
You.
The thing that has
changed is you.
I want you to throw
everything you think you know
about anatomy out the window...
And look at this cadaver
like you've never seen
a human body before.
Now pick up your scalpels.
Place them below
the xiphoid process.
Press firmly.
No regrets.
And let's begin.