You should put this on now.
My contractions are
still nine minutes apart,
and they're not...
not that bad.
They are now 8 minutes
and 45 seconds apart.
We should get pancakes.
Where's my sweater?
I don't want pancakes. I
want you to put this on.
Shoot... I forgot
my lucky socks.
The ones I wore last time
I was in the hospital...
when my brilliant
husband came up
with a miracle surgery
to save our baby.
Those are hospital socks.
They are identical to all
the other hospital socks.
I will get you another pair.
But they won't be my lucky ones.
- I'll go home and get them.
- N-No.
You need to stay
here. And put this on.
And get hooked up
to a fetal monitor.
I will get the socks.
Okay.
How long after we get there
will the surgery start?
You'll go straight
to the pre-op,
where they'll do a
chest X-ray and echo.
Oh, why waste time with
that? I need a new valve.
There's no mystery here.
We'll also need blood
and urine samples.
Huh. I can give
you that right now.
That's... not necessary.
Efficiency, boys.
Clearly, none of you have
been in the military.
Yeah. We're Oscar-Mike
from the nursing home,
but some dense fog put
us behind schedule.
Yeah. Make sure
the O.R. is prepped
and Dr. Park is at the ready
for Mr. Ermey when we get there.
On the double.
Your dad a Marine?
Brother.
Oorah.
Okay. Just make sure
your "dense fog" excuse
is only for your
critical care transport
and not dinner tonight.
Um, dress code?
To the nines.
Going tens.
Hello?
Danny?
You there?
You okay?
My knee's kind of messed
up, but otherwise okay.
Mr. Ermey? We've
been in a crash.
All right. We're
gonna get you down.
- Okay.
- All right.
- You got his legs?
- Yeah.
All right. Three, two, one.
Gotcha.
- All right.
- Take his armband off.
- Yeah, I'm all right. I'm all right.
- Watch your head.
Okay. I'm gonna unstrap you.
- Okay.
- All right. You ready?
- Mm-hmm.
- Three-two, one.
- -Oh!
- I'm good. I'm good.
- You good?
- Yeah, yeah.
Okay.
The truck came over the
line. I had nowhere to go.
Are you all right?
I think my leg's broken.
Okay. Stay up there.
I'll get to you.
Can you reach your radio?
We're gonna need at least
five more ambulances.
Got it.
Danny, you take the driver
of the pick-up truck.
- I'll get to the family.
- All right.
Dispatch...
It's gonna be okay, girls.
Okay, I'm Jared. I'm a doctor.
- What's your name?
- Uh, uh, Kenny.
I can't breathe.
Kenny, any pain in your
chest? Trouble breathing?
Uh, uh, I'm okay.
I'm okay. Help them.
All right. You sit over
there. I'll get to them.
Hey, girls.
I'm gonna get you out
of these car seats
so you can be with
your dad, okay?
- What's your name?
- I'm Bea.
- Okay, Bea.
- My sister's name is Ella.
Okay. Okay. All right.
Let's get you out of there.
It's gonna be okay.
Good job, Bea. Well done.
Ella, I'll be right
back for you, okay?
Good job. Now, you
go to your dad.
- There you go.
- I got you. I got you.
He's alive! He's alive!
But pulse is weak and thready.
Hey.
I'm gonna get you out
of here safe, all right?
Yeah, yeah. Don't
worry. I'm fine.
All right. Hold still, please.
Okay, Ella. I'm
Dr. Kalu. Are you okay?
My chest... I can't breathe.
Okay. Let's get you out of here so
you can be with your dad, all right?
Good job, Ella.
I've got you. That's it.
You're doing so well.
I've got you. Get
you under here.
Come on.
Okay. Good job, guys.
Good job.
No, no, no, no, no.
No. Hey! Hey!
Stop! Stop! Hey!
Danny!
Lea's in labor.
We're having our baby today.
Congratulations.
Morning, ladies.
Eden, clocking in today?
My trial had three participants
drop out at the last minute,
and every available
nanny within 90 miles
is either dumb,
lazy, or incompetent.
Mommy Morgan has very
exacting standards.
I'm willing to lower them
momentarily if you're available.
I just need a few
minutes to give my spiel
to a room full of
perimenopausal IBS patients.
I would, but I just
got paged to the E.R.
I'll stop by later.
Be professional.
At least five seriously injured
multi-vehicle collision
patients are inbound,
including Dr. Perez.
I'll take the first patient.
Then Dr. Park, then
Andrews, Wolke, and Allen,
in that order.
Senior doctors, when you have
stabilized your patients,
please circle back and
assist the residents.
Take a deep breath, everybody.
Driver of the last car of the
pile-up... head-on collision.
Conscious, has a pulse,
but not responding.
Suspected cervical spinal cord
and brachial plexus injury.
Chest hurts.
Where's my phone? I
need to make a call.
You'll get your phone
call soon, Mr. Ermey.
Get an eFAST and
assess for shock.
Let's fix that lac.
I need to drain the
hemopericardium.
Give FFP to control
the bleeding.
Fracture of the right femoral
shaft and left distal radius.
We got it.
- Hey, are you okay?
- I'm... I'm good.
Where's Perez?
Kalu is bringing him
in the last ambulance.
So, he's the least critical?
He's...
He'll be here soon.
Multiple rib fractures and
associated pneumothorax.
It hurts.
Hey, I'm Dr. Wolke.
We're gonna help you, okay?
Finally.
Still no purposeful
eye or limb movements.
Likely a high c-spine fracture.
Let's get her stabilized
for a trauma pan-scan.
Massive right-side
hemopneumothorax,
but she's holding
her own on vitals.
- She needs a chest tube.
- What does that mean?
- Is... Is she gonna...
- She's gonna be okay.
We just need to make sure that
you and the little one are good.
- If you could take a seat...
- I-I-I'm fine. Just a bruise from my...
Yes, I know you feel fine,
but we need to make sure.
I-It's okay, Bea.
Um, I-I-I got to call my wife.
She doesn't even know
any of this happened.
Abdominal ecchymosis,
peritoneal hemorrhage,
possible hemothorax.
You're bleeding everywhere.
Call up to O.R. 2 for
an emergency ex lap.
No opioids.
What?
Just promise me.
No opioids.
Okay.
Tell the anesthesiologist
opioid-free.
Ow!
Considerable
intraperitoneal fluid.
She has a perforation and needs
abdominal surgery right away.
No! Dad!
It's gonna be okay, baby.
Mommy will be here soon,
and we'll all play Scrabble.
We think you suffered
a neck injury,
but we need to get some images
so we can tell for sure.
Hey.
All stabilizing ligaments
have been completely severed.
Internal decapitation.
Have you ever worked
on one of these?
Never even seen one.
Why aren't you in
your patient room?
Oh, I had some last-minute
e-mails to send,
and my preggo-brain
forgot my laptop in here.
Did you get my socks?
Is there something
wrong with your room?
We could get you extra blankets.
What is this?
This is the cutest
hat I've ever seen.
Oh! I got one for each of us.
Shaun, I love them.
We should take it to Glassy.
We should go to your room.
I-I know things are...
difficult between
you two right now,
but his grandson is
being born today.
He knows.
He said, "Congratulations,"
and then he shut the door.
Mm.
We need to get you hooked
up to a fetal monitor.
The surgery went well. We
repaired Ella's bowel perforation.
Mommy, did you bring snacks?
We'll go to the
cafeteria together
as soon as we're done
talking to the doctors.
When can she go home?
Uh, there was some
damage to her spleen.
Uh, we'll need to monitor
that for the next few days,
make sure it doesn't get worse.
But I'll keep you updated.
I've got to be in the O.R. in 10
minutes for my valve replacement.
Order a post-op CT and
run serial hematocrits.
Mm. Sorry.
I'm not used to having
consultations in my kitchen.
I've never seen that much
separation between skull and spine.
Have you? Not in anyone alive.
I was thinking
occipitocervical fusion surgery
using a plate with
four-point fixation
and transpedicular and
translaminar screws.
You're gonna have to add
iliac crest graft
and Songer cables.
You're looking at over
two hours just to realign
and stabilize the
skull and the spine,
and then the real work begins.
Your odds of success
are somewhere
between minimal and nonexistent.
Well, marathons are pointless, but
millions of people run them anyway.
Feel like running?
I've been deemed "unfit."
You wouldn't be cutting.
You'd be consulting.
Flattering.
You're still one of the
world's foremost experts
on the brain and spine,
and my patient's head is
hanging on by a thread.
This one's scary. I
could use some help.
Sure.
I'm up for some...
color commentary.
You have another contraction
coming in one to two seconds,
and it is a big...
one.
They are now six minutes apart
and increasing in intensity.
We should have the nurse
check your dilation again.
Hi. Big day. Excited
for you both.
Everyone is busy because
of the accident...
Lim is prepping, Andrews
and Park are in surgery...
And I think my
patient is in trouble.
Her latest CT shows her splenic
injury is getting worse.
How's Perez doing?
They're just finishing
up his surgery now.
Your patient needs a
splenic artery embolization.
How long can she wait? There
are no attendings available.
She cannot wait.
Shaun...
you need to do the surgery.
I... should be here with
you, to give you ice chips
and hold your hand and
talk about the future.
Have you been watching movies
about people having babies?
I'm fine.
I have hours to go before
the Peanut makes his debut,
and how complicated
is this procedure?
It is quite straightforward.
I love you, and I'm so happy
we're starting our family.
But there's a little
girl who needs you.
Please, go.
Okay. Prep the O.R.
Do not have this
baby without me!
No opioids.
Thank you.
You want the itemized list?
Multiple displaced
rib fractures,
contusions on both lungs,
abdominal bleeding,
and a fractured pancreas,
which is as painful as it gets.
Danny, you need to let
me give you pain meds,
- real pain meds.
- No.
I've already got you on
acetaminophen, lidocaine,
gabapentin, and magnesium.
Your heart rate and
BP are still elevated.
You are at risk for a
heart attack or stroke.
No.
I worked way too
hard getting sober.
I can't go back to square one.
You need opioids.
What I need...
is to hear you tell me
about our dinner tonight.
Please.
Distract me.
The restaurant is
very romantic...
Tablecloths and
candles everywhere.
And the music isn't so loud that
it drowns out all conversation.
The trial starts Monday.
You'd only be in-patient
for three days,
then weekly check-ins
for six weeks.
I suppose I could
hire a dog-sitter.
But Lincoln doesn't
like new people.
Or tall people. Or men.
Can you excuse me
for just one second?
She's the sweetest girl.
She prefers to face
out, be involved.
Yeah. Better.
I'm almost done here.
I need to push my 2:00 p.m. to 3:00
p.m., my 3:00 p.m. to tomorrow.
So, is it three
days and two nights?
Or three days and three nights?
Sorry. A little
more head support.
No, not like that.
Just...
Here we go. Right there.
I need to go.
Lincoln's waiting.
No. Wait. Barbara,
it's... It's two nights.
Please go talk to him.
Shouldn't you be in a room
somewhere, having a baby?
Congratulations, by the way.
You two cannot be
in a fight today.
It's not a fight.
I know it's a big deal, but
can you please put it aside,
at least for today?
I got to go to the O.R.
This is probably the most
important day of Shaun's life.
He needs his father.
Oh, my God.
Either my water just broke,
or I just peed all
over your office.
Either way, it would be a first.
You have plenty of time.
Here, let me help you.
No, no. I'm married
to Dr. Shaun Murphy.
He has walked me
through the steps
of the birthing process
many, many times.
I can take it from here.
Please go talk to him.
I'll call janitorial.
I just...
Gail, always a nice surprise,
but you caught me on a busy day.
Well, sadly, I'm about
to make it busier.
The board's calling an
emergency meeting for tonight.
Okay, and what is the board
defining as an emergency today?
You, Marcus.
And how you're going to handle
the nurses' push to unionize.
I'm on top of it.
That's the problem.
The splenic artery
embolization went very well.
Your daughter should not
need any more surgeries.
She'll need to spend
the next few days
in the hospital until we
can remove her NG tube,
get her back on regular...
Honey? Wha...
- What's happening?
- Profoundly hypotensive.
-Kenny! Pulse disparity
-between arms.
This is likely an
aortic dissection.
We need to get him
to an O.R., stat.
Reasonably happy in this life...
Supremely happy with
You forever in the next.
Amen.
Danny, your BP's 211
over 130, heart rate 194.
You're having a
hypertensive crisis.
You need fentanyl. The
pain is killing you.
God, grant me the serenity
to accept the things
I cannot change...
He asked you not to do that.
He's not responding to the
antihypertensive drips.
Right, so up the dose.
He's tachycardic and
hypertensive because of the pain.
He's going into shock.
- He's not. He's praying.
- He's dying.
The courage to change
the things I can...
That prayer is what
starts every NA meeting.
He is clinging
onto his sobriety.
And the wisdom to
know the difference.
And wisdom to know
the difference.
He's admitting he
doesn't know what to do.
He's asking God to help him.
I'm helping him.
You can leave.
Accepting hardship as
a pathway to peace...
Living one day at a time...
Enjoying one moment at a time...
Forever in the next. Amen.
Forgive me.
Accepting hardship as
a pathway to peace.
We need to place the graft
to replace the descending
and thoracic aorta.
We need six more units of blood.
I did a full exam in the E.R.
I mean, the imaging was clear.
There were no signs
of dissection.
Trim the distal aorta.
It must have started small
enough to be undetected.
His blood pressure
gradually expanded the tear
until it ruptured.
Oh.
There's a false lumen.
It extends past the carotid.
The graft...
won't work.
Well, can you...
Can you have one
of your visions?
Come on, Shaun. There
must be something.
For his family.
He's lost more than
half his blood volume.
His brain has been
underperfused for too long.
Time of death...
4:36 p.m.
You might have mentioned you
were one of the organizers
behind the nurses'
unionization push.
Does it matter?
Not to me, but the
board feels differently.
Apparently, our
relationship is why
I haven't been coming
down hard on the nurses.
I can personally
attest that you've been
a total pain about
it the whole time.
Cute. They're
threatening my job.
I don't want you to
lose your job over us.
I don't want to lose
you over my job.
You know, Shaun and Lea are
having their baby today.
Yes, I'm aware.
Have you talked to him?
I said, "Congratulations."
Well, the alignment
looks much better,
but she could have
horrible stenosis.
Are you planning
on talking to him?
Beyond one word?
I'd decompress the C1
with a laminectomy.
You know, a crotchety,
old, wise man once told me
that hanging onto
my anger was toxic.
I'm not "crotchety."
You were right then.
And I'm right now.
He publicly humiliated
me yesterday,
as everyone in this room
is quite well aware.
Well, he's having
his baby today.
Pass me two 28-mill
pedicle screws, please.
- I'll take those.
- Right.
Old habit.
I saw your family
leave a while ago.
Are they getting a hotel?
You gave me fentanyl.
I did.
Was it a hard decision?
Overriding my wishes?
Honestly?
No.
You were on the verge
of a heart attack.
- Or brain bleed.
- Yeah, but not definitively.
I wasn't willing to risk your
life waiting for "definitively."
But you were okay sending me
back to certain opiate addiction.
I couldn't...
let you die.
I stopped by to offer
my nanny services.
But it looks like
you're all set.
I got all three
participants locked in.
Trial's starting on time.
Now I just need to tell
Andrews that I'm done.
Done?
With this job.
Look, you've had a long day.
But you'll find a
rhythm. And a nanny.
I can't do this job
as well as I want
and take care of Eden
as well as I need.
I've made the mistake of putting my
career ahead of the people I love before.
I'm not doing it again.
The nurses put a chair
next to the table for you,
if you would like to sit.
Is it okay to touch him?
Yes.
Just don't remove the sheet.
He was just here.
How am I gonna tell my girls?
I don't think I can do
any of this without him.
When my brother Steve died,
I didn't know how
I would survive.
He had always taken care of me.
But I did.
Because someone else
came into my life
who took care of
me and loved me.
Now he may be gone, too.
It is very hard to lose people
you thought would never leave.
But you will...
be okay because
you have no choice.
When we lose people we love,
we have to find a
way to keep going
for the people we still have.
Take as much time as you need.
I'm going to have a baby now.
Oh, you're back.
How's the little girl?
She will be okay.
Mm.
How far apart are
the contractions?
About two minutes.
Okay.
It is time to start pushing.
Are you sure?
I don't... I don't
feel anything.
That's because of the epidural,
but your prostaglandin
E1 and E2 levels
are at peak concentration
for stimulating
myometrial contractility.
It is time.
Oh.
I'll gown up and be right back.
I will refill your water
bottle and get an extra pillow.
Do you want a warm
or cold washcloth?
Either is fine, but
I-I need more time.
Delaying delivery can cause
excessive postpartum bleeding,
plus an increase in
bacterial infections.
I'll get one warm and one cold.
Shaun, wait. Come
here a minute.
I'm scared.
Really, really scared.
It is...
common for women to be anxious
about the birthing process.
For nine months, my whole
goal was to keep this baby
in my belly, safe and
sound and protected.
And now it feels like
I'm supposed to just
shove my own heart
into the world and...
And let it walk around
all exposed and vulnerable
and so, so tiny.
And I'm not gonna be able
to protect him anymore.
It will be okay.
Probably.
I am very excited
to meet our son.
I'm really excited, too.
Okay.
Okay, let's... let's do this.
You're two hours out
of surgery. Lie down.
When can I get back to the home?
I need to take your vitals.
Ehh.
Want us to call your family?
I got to call Martha.
- Wife? Girlfriend?
- Neither.
We take walks every morning
with about 20 other old
farts from the home...
All waking up to watch
the damn sunrise.
Not your preferred activity?
Doc, if God wanted us
to see the sunrise,
he would have put it at
a more reasonable hour.
You go because Martha's there.
I think it's time I told her...
she's the reason I
wake up in the morning.
Let's give her a call.
Thanks.
You're all right, Doc.
I went through my
patient record.
You made the right call.
Thank you.
But...
I'm going to need all the
help I can get to recover
without relapsing.
I...
need to go back to
Texas with my family.
I knew when I gave
you the drugs,
I might lose you.
And it wasn't a hard decision?
The decision was easy.
The aftermath is...
Well, I'm not going anywhere
until we have our date.
Are you free tonight?
The levator ani muscle is
undergoing a stretch ratio
of 3.26, which is normal.
Shaun, I need you up
here, not down there.
Why isn't he coming out?
The little guy is just
progressing slowly.
I think we need a
vacuum assist to help...
You want to vacuum
my baby out of me?
It is standard protocol
if a baby is stalled
in the birth canal.
I covered this in the
e-mail about instrum...
There were a lot
of e-mails, Shaun.
Okay.
Is it safe for the baby?
Mm.
Will he have a cone-head?
Only for approximately 48 hours.
Okay, mama. You ready?
Mm-hmm.
I am here for you.
You can squeeze my hand.
You're doing great.
He's almost here.
Oh!
Congratulations, Mom and Dad.
Ooh.
Oh, I can't believe you're
finally here, Peanut.
He doesn't look like
an alien at all.
His... head has a
very nice shape.
Yeah.
He is beautiful.
Dr. Murphy, would you
like to do the honors?
Yes.
I would very much
like to do that.
Hi.
Look at what we made.
Hello.
It is very nice to meet you.
I am Dr. Shaun Murphy.
I'm your dad.
You think anybody would notice
if we took this home with us?
I think you should leave it.
I wasn't really
going to take it.
Oh, sure you were.
But...
I don't think you should resign.
Because you don't have
to do it all alone.
You're the reason I
wake up in the morning.
So, whatever there
is to figure out,
all I want in the world is
for us to do it as a family.
I love you, too.
She has a dirty diaper.
And I have 30 lab
reports to review.
Thank you...
for saving my life.
You're very welcome.
I-I, um... I didn't mean today.
I meant when you made looking
for a foot in a lake fun.
When you sat next to
me in church, quietly,
knowing that was
exactly what I needed.
And, uh, when you trusted me...
even though I'm pretty
sure I didn't deserve it.
And, of course, today.
You make me believe
that I can do this.
You will be okay.
I'm gonna miss you.
Thank you.
I love a sunset
as much as anyone,
but isn't this a little
sentiment over science?
There's a case study
out of Alabama...
Internal decapitation.
They took the patient
out every night...
Sunset, beautiful
sky, and fresh air
to help stimulate the brain.
How long before
they got a response?
A couple days, but it worked.
Hey, how can you argue with a
thing called "Operation Sunset"?
Your family is coming.
I know they'd love to see
you smile, or even a blink.
Or you could just flip us off
because you're cold and
you're afraid of heights.
You've got your
methods, I've got mine.
Whatever works.
Shaun and Lea had their baby.
Do you want to go meet him?
I think I'll stay
here. Thank you.
I know that losing
surgery is devastating.
Don't let losing one great
love cost you another.
♪ You got wings, but they
won't get you off the ground ♪
♪ And you got low and got off
right before the station ♪
I wanted to give you a
heads-up, as a friend.
Uh-oh.
I've decided to resign.
Seriously?
Yeah.
♪ You are coming home ♪
♪ Oh, you ♪
Do you think
Dr. Glassman is coming?
Let's take a picture before
my adrenaline wears off
and I pass out.
I'll get the hats.
I would love the honor
of taking the
first family photo.
♪ Goodbye ♪
♪ 'Cause you ♪
♪ You are coming home ♪
♪ Oh, you ♪
Hi, baby.
- Okay.
- Take a good picture.
Hey, baby boy Murphy.
Smile for your big debut.
Three, two, one, cheese.
Beautiful.
♪ You are coming home ♪
Hi.
Hi, baby.
This is from Dr. Glassman.
♪ You got low and got off
right before the station ♪
♪ Now all you've got
to do is turn around ♪
How did he know his
name would be Steve?
Because he knows you.
♪ You, you are coming home ♪
♪ Oh, you ♪
♪ You are coming home ♪
♪ I will calm the
rivers in your mind ♪
♪ Though it might take a
little time, you know ♪
♪ But you're coming home ♪
Steven Aaron Murphy.
♪ You are not alone ♪
This is a gift from
your grandfather.
♪ Coming home ♪