Isn't it finally time
you admitted I'm
quicker, old man?
These young boys
always come out
both side of their mouth.
Uh, what you run the 40
in at the Combine?
Um, four. Four six.
TATE: That's good.
That's fast.
Four. Four two.
Ooh.
If you're even I'm leavin',
baby. You gotta keep up.
You know what I'm sayin'?
Got it.
I literally have no idea
what just happened.
Baby, now you know how I feel
when I come pick you up
from work.
Everybody running
around talking about,
"Let me get me 50 cc's of epi,
stat!"
And I'm like...
Fifty cc's of epi?
You trying to
kill my patient?
Baby. Mmm.
Doc in the house.
Looks good.
What's going on, man?
I'm good, man.
MAN: Hey, let me set you
up in the bedroom.
Yeah. Sure, sure.
Noah?
Hey.
What's up, man?
What's happenin', bro?
What's up?
Gotta get these fellas ready
for morning practice.
Gonna get your fast break
on point tomorrow,
I'm telling you.
Sounds good. Come on.
All right.
I'll be right back.
What's he doing here?
He said he wanted
to meet some players.
MAN: So, what's all this, man?
NOAH: All right, so, this is
my "Recovery Ultra," okay?
It's filled with
electrolytes
and anti-oxidants.
MAN: Yeah,
that sounds real good.
Um, but first, I wanna
get you guys started
with some B12, okay?
Babe.
(SIGHS)
I gotta go home.
What's wrong?
Nothing. I just have
an early shift
in the morning.
Okay. I'll drive you.
No, no, no.
You stay with your friends.
I just texted for a ride.
Honeymooners
with food poisoning.
Take 'em to four.
You can say it.
What?
You were right
about athletes.
Ah!
What happened?
KENNY: Help!
Get me a gurney.
Dr. Manning,
we're going to Six!
My stomach is on fire!
What's your name,
sweetheart?
It's Ellie Newman.
It's okay.
We're gonna take good
care of you, all right?
Get me a gurney!
MALE NURSE: On it, Maggie.
Get ready to
raise the head.
Let's start an IV.
On it.
Are you her father?
Uh, yeah.
She eat anything that
could've made her sick?
Um, no. She ate what I ate.
How old is your daughter?
Uh, she's 16.
Is she on any medications?
Any medical issues
we should know about?
I don't think so.
I don't know.
When did this start?
KENNY: Uh, last night.
Did you take any
drugs? Alcohol?
Were you at a party?
No!
I was just trying
on my prom dress.
Oh, baby.
BP is 133 over 88,
heart rate 112. Sat's 99%.
Give her 0.2
of hydromorphone.
No! No drugs!
Sweetie, you're in pain.
Let us help you.
No, I don't
want any drugs!
What?
She doesn't want
to end up like me.
FAST is negative,
i-STAT labs normal.
So, it's probably
not a surgical issue?
I'd like to put a scope
in her just to make sure
we're not missing anything.
Without pain meds?
We could try a non-narcotic,
maybe she'll go for that.
(SIGHS)
Hi, Ellie, Mr. Newman,
this is Dr. Rhodes,
our trauma surgeon.
I've asked him to consult.
Has Ellie ever
experienced this before?
A year ago.
How long did it last?
Maybe, like,
three weeks.
Your daughter
was sick like this
for three weeks
and you didn't know?
I was...
Strung out.
Yeah.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Ellie, we're gonna
give you a painkiller
that's a non-narcotic.
No, I don't want anything.
The girl won't even
take two aspirin.
Did you see a doctor
for your last attack?
He couldn't find anything.
He sent me to a psychologist.
But I'm not
making this up.
Don't worry, Ellie,
we're gonna get to the bottom
of this.
I don't know,
she's in a lot of pain.
Maybe it is psychological.
I'll page Dr. Charles.
Dr. Rhodes. Your sister's
on line two.
Yeah.
Right, tell her I need
to reschedule.
Like you did last week?
Yes, Maggie, like I did
last week.
Ms. Rhodes,
he's with a patient.
He said he won't be able
to make lunch today,
but he'll call you
back to reschedule.
Okay.
Hey, Maggie.
Do you by any chance
know of a good contractor?
For what?
I'm thinking about
turning the basement
into a man cave for Bert.
Oh, trying to buy him off,
so he'll stop bugging you
about retiring?
Something like that.
Yeah, I got a cousin.
Not too big a crook.
Text me his number.
I will.
Dr. Halstead.
Maggie.
I got a patient in two
that's from your
old hood Canaryville.
Thought you
might be interested.
Sure.
Vitals?
BP 164 over 90.
Heart rate 92, Sat 99%.
Okay, Mr...
Tucker.
You gotta be kidding me.
Ginger Spice
is our doctor?
ANDREW: No way.
Ginger Spice?
What they called me
back at De La Salle.
Well, how about we
get a real doctor?
Dr. Halstead is
a real doctor,
an excellent doctor.
It's okay, Reese. This is
how we gentlemen
relate in Canaryville.
Andrew, what's
going on with that leg?
Swelled up
during my truck route.
Pain won't let up.
Push on my hand
like you're
stepping on the gas.
Come on.
All right, how long
ago did the pain start?
About 12 hours.
Why didn't you
say something?
I would've had Pete
take over your deliveries.
Wasn't this bad at first.
WILL: You on any medication?
ANDREW: No.
Still smoke?
Been cutting back.
Alcohol?
Not much since this
one bumped me up to
Transpo Coordinator.
Gotta be ready to
cover any driver
who calls out.
Hey, you should ask
Ginger about the fight
we had in high school.
I caught him
staring at my girl.
How many times did I
knock you on your ass?
A hundred?
Sounds about right.
Ever had any pain
or swelling like this before?
Any shortness of breath?
ANDREW: No.
Okay, now we're gonna
start with some basic labs
and get
a duplex scan
of your legs.
And we'll take it
from there.
So, where you
livin' now, Ginger?
Gold Coast?
Not quite. I'll get
those orders started.
Were they always
like that?
The Tucker brothers
were very popular.
And they loved
sticking it to us
lesser mortals.
Go ahead and
order an ultrasound
of Mr. Tucker's leg.
April.
Hi.
How's my guy?
Better.
Much better.
Coming in for Eric's
check-up upstairs.
Cool.
Hold on. Hold on.
You got little hands.
See if you can
untangle these.
I can do it.
All right.
Please.
I just wanted to
make sure you're okay.
You left in a bit of a hurry.
Look, um, I don't know
if this was such a good idea.
What? What do you mean?
Last night was
just not my scene.
It's not mine
either. I'm...
Okay, it used to be,
but I got Eric now.
Things are different.
Just wanted you
to meet some
old friends, that's all.
Mmm-hmm.
Yeah. I don't know.
I have to get back to work.
Daddy! I did it.
(CHUCKLES)
Good job.
Bye.
(EXHALES)
It's a tough situation, man.
Sixteen years old,
taking care of herself,
and her
heroin-addicted father.
And doing it for years.
She said she was
trying on her prom dress.
I mean, could that
have been
some kind of trigger?
And maybe the pain
is psychosomatic?
Possibly.
I don't really know
enough to make that call.
We have to figure
out what's going on,
and the only way
we're gonna do that
is if we scope her.
We can't unless we
get her to accept
pain meds or an anesthetic.
Given her family history,
we have to take
her concern for
addiction very seriously.
Okay. So, what do we do?
Well, how about
good old-fashioned
topical numbing agent?
No. Worth a shot.
(ELLIE SOBBING)
That's okay, sweetie,
we will take care of them.
Dr. Choi,
April. Doris,
open that door.
Neela Desai,
32 weeks pregnant
and contracting.
Got it.
Let's rotate the chair.
Mommy.
Go with the nurse, okay?
Let's take them
to the break room
to get a snack, okay?
Okay, mama.
We're going to take
care of your mommy and
then we're gonna
come and get you. Okay?
(SCREAMS)
Okay. Let's go.
Go ahead, love,
take them to
the break room.
Lie back, so,
the doctor can
examine you, okay?
There you go.
Take this out, please?
Okay. You're in
good hands, love.
Okay.
I can't have this baby!
It's not due for
another two months.
Page OB.
BP 142 over 90.
That's high, probably due to
anxiety or the pain.
Just to be safe, I'm gonna
order some labs, okay?
Now, you're gonna
feel a little pressure.
She's bleeding
from the cervix.
Grab six-gram mag
bolus and call OB,
tell them we're coming up.
Wait. What's going on?
Ms. Desai, you may be
experiencing an abruption,
your placenta is separating
from the wall of your uterus.
The overall picture
suggests something
called preeclampsia
with HELLP syndrome.
What does that mean?
It means
that we need to
deliver this baby now.
No, no, no.
I know 32 weeks
is more premature
than we'd like.
But right now,
your baby is safer
outside of your
body than inside.
Yeah, I can't deliver
this baby premature.
This is not my baby.
I'm a surrogate.
I'm carrying this
baby for someone else.
I need to carry it to term,
or I don't get paid.
ETHAN: If we don't
deliver now,
this condition could be fatal
for both you and the baby.
Yeah, I need the money.
Ms. Desai, I don't...
No! No.
We just got out of
the shelter, okay?
I'm not putting my boys
through another
Chicago winter in one.
So, please, help me!
It was nice
talking to you.
How'd she do on
the psych eval?
In my opinion
Ms. Desai is competent,
capable of making
her own decisions.
Mentally, she's stable.
How can she be stable?
She's risking her
life and the baby's.
She has no
genetic connection
to that baby, Ethan.
Another couple's
fertilized egg is
implanted in her womb.
For her, it's about
making enough money to
take care of her kids.
Then, that's it then,
we have to respect
the patient's wishes.
We can't force her to deliver.
You expect me to just
wait for her to die?
I'll call her
surrogacy agency.
See if they can help
us find a solution.
Trucks are on their way,
just running a little late.
We're backed up with me
out of the office today.
Hey, let me call you back.
You finally figure
out what's going on?
The duplex scan
shows that
the swelling of
your leg is being
caused by a DVT,
a deep vein
thrombosis.
A what?
Okay, English, Halstead.
You've got a blood
clot in your leg.
So, how do you fix it?
Blood thinners.
Enoxaparin is
where I'd start.
No, hold on,
most of the time,
administering a blood thinner
like enoxaparin would
be the right answer,
but given Andrew's history,
I'm leery of doing that.
It could cause
intra-cranial hemorrhaging.
Bleeding?
Yes, in the brain.
I remember you
getting into your
fair share of scuffles
back in high school.
Is that still the case?
Only when the
Packers are in town.
When you've experienced
trauma to the head,
blood thinners are
more likely to make
your brain bleed,
cause you to stroke,
possibly die.
Whoa.
I'm gonna make sure
that doesn't happen.
For now, I'd like to get
a CT scan of your head
to establish a baseline,
and then we'll wait and see.
Wait, that's your plan?
"Wait and see"?
A nurse will be by to
take you for that scan.
Well, I hope you know
what you're doing, Ginger.
CLAIRE: Connor.
CONNOR: Hey.
Hey.
Looks like I need
to check into the ER
to spend any time with you.
Claire, I'm sorry.
It's just been
really busy around here.
You're avoiding me.
I'm not avoiding you...
It's because of Dad, isn't it?
You hate that I
don't hate him.
You're not being fair.
Listen, Mom's suicide,
I know you blame him,
but Mom had real problems.
That's not exactly
how I remember it.
That's because,
believe it or not,
Dad tried to shield us,
he kept us away
when Mom spiraled
into a black hole.
You don't remember, but I do.
Call me, Connor,
when you're ready.
Damn.
Noah.
Hey.
What were you
doing last night?
Just a little
entrepreneurship.
Big market for banana bags.
Noah.
What?
It's a legitimate business.
You are not a doctor yet.
You're not supposed to be
sticking needles in people.
Yeah, but I'm gonna be.
This is why we all worked
so hard to send you
to medical school?
So, you could keep
a bunch of party animals
from getting hangovers?
I'm just trying to
earn a few extra bucks.
Only way I can pay you back.
I never asked
you to pay me back.
I want to.
And what about
Mom and Dad?
Oh. So, you're just doing
this to help the family?
April, let me do my thing.
You are so full of it.
And you're mad at me?
All right, this is
gonna numb your
mouth and throat.
But you're still
gonna feel some pressure
in your esophagus.
It's the best we can
do without anesthetic.
Hopefully, you'll be able
to tolerate the scope.
Okay.
We'll use this.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Okay, here we go.
(RETCHING)
You okay?
Slow deep breaths
through your nose, okay?
Here, squeeze my hand.
Ellie, I'm gonna do this
as fast as I can. Sorry.
(RETCHING)
(ELLIE COUGHS)
It's okay. It's okay.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Nurse Doris is
gonna stay with you.
Just give us a second.
Thank you.
I have got to
talk to her father.
Mr. Newman, I can't
stand to see your
daughter in this much pain.
I need your permission
to give Ellie pain medication.
I don't tell Ellie
what to do.
It's sort of a deal we
have with each other.
I understand.
But we just need to
sedate her this once,
so we can perform
the endoscopy.
This will not turn
her into an addict.
Your daughter is
overwhelmed with pain
and depleted from vomiting.
She cannot make
the best decision
in this state.
But Ellie's a minor.
You are her father.
You can make this decision.
No, I don't know.
I don't... I don't know.
Ellie needs you to
step up, Mr. Newman,
to be her father.
(SIGHS)
Um... (SNIFFLES)
Okay. Uh, do it.
I mean, do what you
have to do. I guess.
Okay. Thank you.
Yeah.
(GASPING)
He can't breathe!
Help him, Halstead.
Help him!
Sinus tach?
One thirty-three.
WILL: Sat?
Eighty-six.
He threw a
pulmonary embolism.
"Embolism." What is that?
WILL: Get oxygen on him.
Okay, what is going on?
Need some help in here!
You know, you should have
given him the blood thinner!
Brian, you need to
step out of the room now.
He's my brother!
You are killing him.
Andy! Andy!
Get a crash cart in here!
Give me the bag.
BRIAN: What?
He's turning blue.
He's too big to lift.
I'm intubating here.
Come on, Andy, breathe.
Breathe, Andy.
Twenty of etomidate
and 100 of sux, now!
NURSE: Yes, doctor.
Breathe, Andy, breathe.
Come on, Andy.
Come on, breathe, just do it.
Okay. I'm in.
Call the MICU and
the pulmonary team.
Get 'em down here immediately.
What is happening?
Why isn't he breathing?
Clot moved from
his leg to his lung.
What did you do
to my brother?
Heart rate's up to 130.
BP's rising.
(ELLIE GROANING)
I'm afraid she'll
have a dysrhythmia.
Push 50 of fentanyl.
Yeah.
No! What's that?
What's that?
It's just gonna help you.
ELLIE: No!
No. Please!
NATALIE: Ellie.
Ellie, you have to do this.
ELLIE: Please!
It'll help us figure out
what's going on with you.
No.
NATALIE: It's okay.
It'll only help.
It's okay. It's okay.
(ELLIE SOBBING)
(PANTING)
Nothing?
No.
Maybe her condition
is psychological.
Dr. Manning,
a quick word.
Yeah.
I understand that you
gave Ellie a narcotic.
The numbing
spray wouldn't work.
Sedating her was the
only way we could
perform the endoscopy.
Was it worth it?
The endoscopy
was inconclusive.
I thought that
we concluded
that staying away
from narcotics was
Ellie's top priority.
Yes. But she's a minor.
She wasn't in any condition
to make decisions.
And what condition
was her father in?
Was he sober when
you asked his consent?
She was in so much pain.
It was the right call
to make.
I think it might have
felt like the right
call for you, doctor.
For Ellie,
gonna have to wait and see.
Our clients are people
who are desperate
to have children.
Ms. Desai is
helping a couple
realize that dream.
Her life is in jeopardy.
We'd like to
understand
the arrangement
your clients have
with our patient.
Well, she has
graciously allowed
our clients' baby to
develop in her womb.
In turn, they give
her a living stipend
for every week she
nurtures that child.
She specifically said
she needs the payout.
What's that?
In the spirit of
inspiring a
healthy baby,
our clients have
promised a bonus
should Ms. Desai
carry to term.
That's what she's
killing herself for.
Ms. Allen,
this contract seems to be
incentivizing our patient
to put her health at risk.
Is there any
way to alter this?
How so?
Well, perhaps,
she would
deliver the baby now,
if she knew she
was still eligible
for at least
a part of that bonus.
Unfortunately,
our clients
have stipulated
that they do not
wish to adopt
a premature baby.
It's their baby.
According to the law,
my clients are
under no obligation
to adopt this child.
Wait. Then who's
responsible for this baby?
If the bio parents
choose not to adopt,
Ms. Desai is welcome
to keep the child or
surrender it to the state.
"Welcome to keep it"?
Ms. Allen, this contract
seems to protect everyone,
but Ms. Desai
and that baby.
I'm sorry,
that is the arrangement
she willingly agreed to.
If you have any
further questions,
please feel free
to call my office.
Uh...
This embolism,
it happened
'cause of you.
She said you were supposed
to give him something,
but you didn't.
I am telling you.
I know your brother.
I saw Jimmy Doyle
knock him out cold.
I'm sure that happened
more than once.
Andy's too high a risk
for blood thinners.
No, you made the wrong call
and now Andy's got
this clot in his lungs.
You're an uppity bastard,
and you don't give
a rat's ass about us.
Back off, Brian. Back off.
I want a doctor who
knows what he's doing.
You want a new doctor?
Is that it?
Yeah.
A good one.
Okay, I'm done.
Noah showed me some
selfies he took
with Tate's friends.
God. I want to strangle him.
Noah or Tate?
Noah.
He's hooking
these ballers up
with banana bags.
Oh, very enterprising.
Tate's idea?
No.
He thought he was
doing Noah a favor,
giving out his card.
Still, what'd I tell
you about athletes?
Hey, Noah is what he is.
It's not Tate's fault.
Then what are
you mad at him for?
I don't know.
I'm... Oh, God, I'm not.
Tate.
Uh, how was his check-up?
Wasn't too bad. I mean,
he cried twice, but...
Did not!
I'm just playing.
'Course not.
You're too brave for that.
Hey, Eric, do you mind
if I have a really
quick word with your dad?
I want you to take
a seat for a second
right over there, honey.
(SIGHS) I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have
made this about you,
when it wasn't.
It's my brother,
I really did not like what
he was doing at that party.
I get you.
I really like
being with you.
(CHUCKLES)
I don't want that to stop.
Me neither.
Look, I was
just helping
Noah out because,
hey, that's your
little brother.
But I'll let my
guys know, no more.
No, that's sweet,
but if they wanna hire him,
they can go right ahead.
Noah is making his own way,
and I'm done fighting it.
Okay.
Hey, Eric!
How about an
ice cream sandwich?
If it's okay
with your dad.
I want an ice cream sandwich.
Let's get you
an ice cream sandwich.
Yay!
Under fluoro,
we'll get a
precise picture
of the clot burden,
then we can lyse it.
Let's get him
into the elevator.
What's happening?
Dr. Perrington is
taking him to the cath lab
for a clot buster.
If you're right about
Andrew's head traumas,
giving him a clot buster
is worse than giving
him blood thinners.
I gave my medical opinion.
The patient
and his brother
did not wanna listen.
Perrington's an attending.
It's out of my hands now.
Rough day?
Yeah. I just...
WILL: What?
(SIGHS)
I just... I can't
believe what I just did.
I have this teenage patient
who adamantly
refused drugs of any kind
because addiction
runs in her family,
and I just convinced
her heroin-addict father
to let me give her
pain meds anyway.
What was I thinking?
(EXHALES)
What?
Well, I hate to say it,
but going against
a patient's wishes
because you think
you know better?
Sounds like something
you'd bust my balls for.
All right, what's wrong
with this kid, anyway?
I wish I knew.
(PAGER BEEPING)
ELLIE: Spiders! Get away!
That's her.
NURSE 1: Dr. Manning.
NURSE 2:
Need some help over here...
ELLIE: (SOBBING)
Spiders over me!
MALE NURSE:
Okay. Relax. Please!
Ellie, what's happening?
I have spiders all over me!
Get it off! No.
Give me five of Haldol.
Page Dr. Charles.
Got you.
No! No!
Ellie, there's nothing there.
Please! Get them off.
NATALIE: Ellie,
there's nothing there!
What's going on? Hey!
MALE NURSE: Dr. Manning.
CONNOR: What's going on?
I don't know!
(SOBBING)
Okay. It's okay. It's okay.
NATALIE: Acute stomach
pain and vomiting,
but the endoscopy
comes back clean.
And she has
a psychotic episode.
You were right.
I never should've
given her the narcotic.
Although that
could not have caused
the hallucinations.
I'm at a loss. I guess
this is in your court.
And whatever
she's suffering from
must be psychological.
You know,
I'm not sure that I agree.
When you scoped her,
did you give her
a benzo or an opiate?
Fentanyl.
Huh.
An opiate. Was it effective?
Very. Why?
I got a hunch
that the stomach pain
and the psychotic episode
might be related,
and if that's the case,
whole thing would
in fact be
entirely physiological.
Excuse me for a second?
Sure.
So, do you mind
if I ask you a couple
personal questions?
Nope.
When did you, um,
start using drugs?
Well, um...
Just so you know,
only asking
because it might
help us figure out
what's wrong with Ellie.
Near as you can remember.
When did you start using?
Uh...
I'd say high school.
And did you experiment
with various things
or did you go
straight to heroin, or...
Oh, uh...
Nat.
Yeah.
I could use your
help with a patient.
What is it?
I can't get through to her.
I thought maybe you
could talk to her,
as a mother.
Dr. Choi.
Ms. Desai,
we can't delay this
delivery any longer.
No, please.
Ms. Desai,
I'm Dr. Manning.
I'm sorry you're
going through such a
rough time right now.
I know when
my water broke,
I was a mess.
I wasn't ready
to deliver, either.
I told Dr. Choi,
I can't have this baby now.
My boys are counting
on me to keep a roof
over their heads.
I understand. I have a son.
I would do anything for him.
But do you understand
what's happening in
your body right now?
The proteins from
your placenta are
poisoning your blood.
And at any moment,
you could have
an eclamptic seizure
that could kill
you and this baby.
Ms. Desai, your boys
would rather spend
100 Chicago winters
in a shelter
than a lifetime
without their mother.
Don't orphan
them for this money.
Neela, look at me.
Look at me. Neela.
Dr. Choi is gonna
take you up to OB
and you are going
to deliver this baby.
For your boys.
Okay.
ETHAN: Call OB,
tell them we're on our way.
(NEELA CRYING AND GROANING)
(SOBBING)
Halstead!
Why'd you dump us?
Dump you?
You dumped me.
Said you wanted
another doctor.
Yeah, so?
So?
All right,
do I look like a doctor?
Who cares what
I think? You're
the smartest guy I know.
Listen, I don't know
what it is that you want,
but Andy's in good hands
with Dr. Perrington.
She knows what
she's doing...
Hey.
What happened to
that stand-up kid
from high school?
What?
We respected you.
Funny way of showing it.
Hey, no matter how
many times we knocked
you on your ass,
you always got back up.
Ginger never stayed down.
Yeah, I don't care
about this other doctor.
I care about my brother.
And you know him.
God sakes, you even
remember the fight
with Jimmy Doyle.
You said he could get a...
What? A brain bleed.
And that could
kill him, right?
That's right.
Then shouldn't you
stop this?
Oxygen looks good.
Let's turn up the propofol.
Let's administer the tPA.
Wait!
What's going on?
I wanna make sure
we're giving Mr. Tucker
the proper treatment.
He's no longer
your patient,
Dr. Halstead.
He thinks what you're doing
could make his brain bleed.
Excuse me.
Your brother's CT was clean
except for old hygromas.
That means
the risk is very low.
I grew up with this patient,
seen him take
a lot of hits to
the head over the years.
Those hygromas
are indicative
of old subdurals.
He's at a much higher risk
than his CT shows.
We need to
implant an IVC filter
to prevent future clots,
but as far as
the current clot's
concerned,
I think we should hold off
and let him ride it out.
Dr. Halstead is a resident,
a doctor in training.
I'm an attending physician
and a board-certified
critical care specialist.
I'm telling you, your
brother is perfectly able
to handle this treatment.
He's not.
We're going with
Dr. Halstead, what he says.
All right.
How are you
feeling, Ellie?
You gave me drugs.
I'm sorry. I didn't
feel like we had a choice.
And what are these?
You had what we call
a delusional episode.
So, I'm going crazy?
No.
We actually think
that it might be related
to your stomach pain.
Did you change
your diet at all
in anticipation of
wearing your prom dress?
Yeah, a little. I...
I just started
eating salads at lunch.
Can you remember
your last attack,
a year ago,
had you also changed
your diet then?
I guess I...
I was going to
a volleyball tournament
in Florida,
and I wanted to, you know,
wear a bathing suit.
Why?
We believe you may
have a disease called AIP,
acute intermittent porphyria.
It's a genetic condition
that causes
severe stomach pain
along with episodes
of psychosis.
Carbohydrates actually
help control it.
And we think that
your latest flare-up
was probably helped
along by your
recent change in diet.
That's what's making me
feel like this?
NATALIE: We think so.
Long term, AIP can be
treated and managed.
In the short term,
an opiate will
help to ease the pain.
An opiate?
You don't have to worry.
We will carefully
manage your dosage.
(EXHALES)
As long as I don't
turn out like my dad.
Ellie, your father
helped lead us
to this diagnosis.
Again, it's a
genetic condition.
He probably has it,
and has very likely
been self-medicating
all these years.
You mean, that...
That's why he's an addict?
Well, more like
a contributing factor.
He probably experienced
the same pain
that you did when
he was your age,
and without proper
help or diagnosis,
he came up with his
own way to treat it.
ETHAN: The baby's in distress.
We've got fetal bradycardia.
It's not getting oxygen.
DR. PATCHEFSKY:
Almost there.
Baby's apneic, suction.
ETHAN: Come on. Come on.
She looks good.
Premature, but healthy.
Let's get her to NICU.
ETHAN: Wait.
(BABY CRYING)
It's a girl.
DR. PATCHEFSKY: Don't you
wanna see your baby?
I can't. I can't.
ETHAN: Ms. Desai...
No.
(BABY CONTINUES CRYING)
Take it away!
He's stabilized.
Not as bad as we thought.
Maybe we don't need to
push to the clot busters.
You were right.
Just glad he's okay.
Excuse me.
Dr. Halstead.
Just curious,
you planning on applying
for a job here when your
residency is complete?
First choice.
I'm on the hiring committee,
and if I were you,
I'd be looking
for other hospitals.
What's going on in there?
They look like
they're celebrating.
Yeah, we ran a PBG test
on Ellie and
confirmed the diagnosis.
We also did one
on her father,
and it turns out
he has it, too,
but he never knew it.
All her life, she just
thought he was an addict
who didn't care,
and now she sees
it was just
his way of coping.
SHARON: Any issues?
ETHAN: She was born
shy of four pounds
and her lungs
are underdeveloped,
but I think two
months in the NICU
will plump her up and get
her breathing properly.
That's good to hear.
I'm sorry, but I have
some unfortunate news.
Our clients have
pulled out.
What?
They don't feel
equipped to deal with
the complications
that come with
a premature baby.
This is a healthy baby.
She just needs
some extra attention.
I understand.
You know, my heart
goes out to Neela,
all she's been through.
But I'm not giving up.
I'm sure we can find
an adventurous couple
willing to take on
that little bundle of joy.
And maybe get a little
something for Neela, too.
Of course,
you'll get a fee as well.
I need to make
a quick call, excuse me.
Is this a happy ending?
Dr. Choi, this is
as happy as it's
going to get.
Mr. Newman.
Yeah. Hey.
Hey.
Very excited to hear that
you and your daughter
finally got a diagnosis.
That's good.
Yeah. That's great.
Hey, can you step
over into my office here
for a second?
You know, sometimes,
people get new perspective,
how they got into a
situation, they re-evaluate
getting out of it, you know?
And if that
were the case,
I just wanted to
offer my assistance,
you know?
Kicking heroin is
a tremendous undertaking,
and it really shouldn't
be attempted alone.
Um...
Yeah, um, you know,
I appreciate that. Thank you.
Yeah, I work with
these alternative rehabs,
you know, who use
psychoactives like ibogaine.
They've been having
extraordinary success.
I just wanted, you know,
to put that on the table.
(EXHALES)
Yeah, well, uh, you know,
(CLEARS THROAT) like I said,
I appreciate it and, uh...
You know, I think,
I think I got it handled.
You know, so, I'm gonna
have a smoke.
Okay, man.
Thank you.
Good luck.
Hey, just in case, you know?
(CLEARS THROAT) Great.
Thank you.
How's she doing?
I suggest you stay
as far away from me
as possible.
What you're
doing may be legal,
but it sure as
hell isn't right.
No reputable
surrogacy agency
would've ever given
Neela a contract like that.
This is an emotional process,
I can understand you're upset.
Don't you dare
patronize me.
What you do,
let's call it what it is,
human trafficking.
Maybe if we bring
that one down here.
And yes, I've been
thinking about it just...
Claire.
(CHUCKLES)
Well...
Um...
Any chance you're
free for dinner?
Yeah, I think I could
make that work.
Let me just
grab my coat.
(SIGHS)
Leave it to you to
find the nearest bar.
Homing instinct.
Let me buy you
a drink.
Okay.
What'll you have?
One of those fancy
fresh-squeezed cocktails?
With my med school loans,
I stick to beer.
Thank you.
Another for me.
And the same
for my friend.