Hmm. Interesting sign.
Thank you. Yeah.
Kinda dark. Kinda true.
Hmm.
Hear me out: same
sign, but in a wacky font.
Right? 'Cause nothing says
"You're doomed" like Comic Sans.
Nothing says...
You know, when Sharpe
was my oncologist,
I at least got pity laughs.
I won't be doing that.
Mmm. Well, this'll be fun then.
Uh, I'm gonna go, and maybe once
you've read that, you can call me.
Sit. Okay.
I can't help but notice
inconsistencies in your treatment.
Missed chemo sessions,
erratic radiation schedule.
That won't work.
Virginia, I've never seen
you with a patient before,
but I gotta say, very impressed.
This whole scary-principal
thing you got going on,
it's very effective.
But I am not your normal patient
because I have a huge hospital to run,
and so when it comes
to things like scheduling,
I gotta keep it flexible.
But you'll learn to love it.
Radiation is set for
this afternoon, 2:00 p.m.
Great. See? Easy.
As long as there's no hospital
emergency, then I will see you there.
Max, you are the emergency.
Radiation is set for
this afternoon, 2:00 p.m.
2:00 p.m., I heard
you. But listen.
No, you start listening.
Your treatment's
impact is cumulative.
Your brain is going to operate
at half the capacity
you're used to.
You're going to
be in a lot of pain.
And that is if the
treatment is working.
But you're not
letting it work. Why?
Why? Because I have
a million things to do.
I have a child on the way.
If I'm too far gone by
the time it gets here...
Dr. Sharpe said
you'd make excuses.
Did she? Really?
It's time to get ready,
Max. Yeah, for what?
To step down as
medical director.
We'll see about that.
Hang in there, Lyn.
Doctor? What you got?
An overprotective dad-to-be
who needs to chill out.
Her back's been sore and
she's had these awful headaches
and she's, like, forgetting things.
She nearly fainted at the coffee shop.
It's called having
a baby, Michael.
Vitals? Found
them right outside.
We didn't have time. All
right, we got it. Thanks.
How far along are
you? Thirty-nine weeks.
Do you have a birth plan? Yeah.
Any allergies? - No.
Complications? Just having
these really bad headaches.
Mom's blood pressure: 290/160.
Heart rate 130 and fetal
heart rate 90 and falling.
All right. Trauma One. We have
to do an emergency C-section.
- Call OB, but I'm not waiting.
- What, now?
What's happening?
What? Is the baby okay?
Michael? Just breathe.
Michael! MICHAEL:
Should I call her doctor?
Clamps and forceps, please.
We won't need the Metz.
Get them off the tray.
Your name's Michael
Archer? Uh, yes.
Lift your arms.
Turn around.
Your date of birth
is May 28th, 1988?
Patient intubated and sedated.
How we doing?
- Almost prepped...
- Guys, please.
I need to be in there. I
need you to lift your foot.
What are the last four
digits of your social?
0501.
And the other foot.
Fetal heart rate still falling.
Preparing to
sterilize incision site.
Let's go. - Let's go.
You cannot touch anything in
there unless we say it's okay.
You got it? Yeah.
Okay. Let's go.
PGA and polyglactin
910. Is she okay?
She's sedated to help
with the hypertension,
but we need to get your baby out
now for both of their sakes. Retractor.
- Richardson.
- Where's OB?
Okay, need a little help here.
Is everything okay? Got it?
Okay, hold it nice
and wide for me.
What's wrong? Doctor?
The cord? - I'm trying.
Doctor. Suction.
Just a little more.
Time of birth, 10:23 a.m.
You have a strong baby boy.
Give me those Apgar scores.
Yes, Doctor. All
right, I see that.
Birth weight, uh, 7.6 pounds.
Apgar of nine.
He's very healthy.
Let's close her up.
How's Lyn? She okay?
No signs of hemorrhaging
or excess bleeding.
She's still hypertensive.
Wanna hold him, Daddy?
There you go. Support his head.
Hi, Robin.
Hey, there!
Ta-da!
You amaze me.
I wear paper very well.
I'm not talking
about how you look.
I'm talking about how
you're tackling this.
All by yourself.
Freezing your eggs.
Lots of women do.
Lots of women aren't
chair of oncology.
I knew there was a
reason I invited you.
So, that nurse earlier,
thinking I was here to fertilize...
Oh, my God. I mean,
can you imagine?
We've only been
together a month.
So awkward. So awkward.
That said, I...
I know the biological
pressure you're under.
So what if...
That's not a reason to...
No, no, of course not.
I just... Here I
am, able to help.
Not helping feels... No, yeah.
I get it.
I mean, I have thought about it.
You have? Oh, no.
I mean, I've thought about it,
but I haven't, like, thought about it.
Right.
Yeah, it's just a lot to put
on this and on us at this time.
Hopefully we'll get there. Yeah.
I just don't wanna
lose our chance.
It's E-day, Helen. Ready to go?
Um...
Actually, I think I just
need a little bit more time.
You can have till 5:00 p.m.
Any longer, we'll miss
our chance to retrieve
any eggs at all,
fertilized or not.
I'll see you at 5:00?
Sandra Fall from
billing. How goes it?
Uh... My husband
filed for divorce,
and he's taking the
dog. Oh, I'm sorry.
Don't be. They
deserve each other.
Signature, please. Sure.
You know, I would sign just about
anything you put in front of me,
but out of curiosity,
what did I just sign?
Permission for
the hospital to sell
delinquent medical
bills to the highest bidder.
To do what now?
Orders from Karen
Brantley. Excuse me.
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
Forgive me, sorry. Yeah.
"Approval to institute
a trial program
"known as 'the asset
reclamation commitment.'"
ARC, for short.
Love a good acronym.
Oh, well, that's an
even better euphemism.
Asset reclamation.
This program sells our patients'
debt to collection agencies.
Yes, so that we may be reimbursed
for their delinquent medical bills.
The thing is, people come here for
care, and this is what bankrupts them.
This hospital currently holds
six figures in outstanding debt,
and we're steaming
towards seven.
It's time to do something
about it. Not this.
We found an agency that
can get five cents on the dollar
for our debt. That's
real money, Max.
Think of all the good
you can do with it.
What if I can do better?
Six cents on the dollar guaranteed,
and nobody goes bankrupt.
Just let me try.
Start with this batch.
You have 24 hours. Thank you.
Look at what Harper
made for cool Uncle Kapoor.
Oh, God.
What are you doing?
Is it an ashtray?
Oh, yes. Yes, Vijay.
My five-year-old daughter
made you an ashtray in school
for all your cigarette butts.
It's a paperweight, man.
Why does it have grooves? It...
I don't know. Maybe
it is an ashtray.
But you know, that... That's
the beauty of Harper's work.
The functionality of
each piece truly does lie
in the eye of the beholder.
My desk is really very messy.
I have four kids all dabbling
heavily in the arts, all right?
My desk is 99% paste
and pasta. Come on.
Plus, you can't pass
on a gift from a child.
Actually, it sounds that you
can't pass on a gift from a child.
Hey, Dr. Eagan!
You're still a big
smoker, right?
Bonjour from... Pain...
Good morning, Ella.
What would you like?
I would like to again apologize.
I never meant to imply
that you and my son...
$2.75.
Isn't he amazing?
I don't usually play favorites,
but your son is perfect.
Sabrina, would you
just give us a minute?
Hi.
Mr. Archer, I'm Dr. Goodwin.
Medical director of this hospital.
Is everything okay?
Your paperwork said
that Lyn is your surrogate?
She's also my best friend.
But you paid her
to carry the child?
Yes. Uh, we have a contract.
Yeah, I'm afraid that
surrogacy contracts
aren't valid in the
state of New York,
so by law the baby
belongs to the birth mother,
and we can't legally give him
to you without her permission.
Then just ask
her. She'll tell you.
What?
We thought delivering
the baby would relieve
Lyn's hypertension,
but so far it hasn't.
We're doing
everything that we can,
but she hasn't
regained consciousness.
Wait. I'm sorry, Michael.
I know this is hard, but the nurses
here are gonna take amazing care of him.
You can't be serious.
You're taking him now?
Michael, listen to me.
I'm gonna do everything
that I can to help you.
But right now, we
need to take him.
I don't need a shrink.
I have a contract.
I signed it. Lyn signed
it. It was notarized.
See, she wanted me to have
Robin. Well, I know she did.
But the fact remains that
this is a New Jersey contract.
I know that but, okay, here.
"The parties agree
that the jurisdiction
"for resolution of
any custodial dispute
"shall vest in the court in
the state of New Jersey."
Not New York. Jersey,
okay? Okay, okay. I hear you.
Slow down.
Michael, take a breath.
I'm sorry. It's okay.
No, no, no, I'm sorry.
I understand.
It's just, I mean,
that's New Jersey.
It's right there. I can see it.
Yeah.
Five miles west, I'd
be holding my son.
They won't let me hold him.
I guess you got kids?
Yeah.
My little girl made that
masterpiece right there.
I have zero idea what it is.
Everyone who looks at it sees
something completely different.
It's kinda cool, actually.
I see a little girl
that loves her dad.
Yeah.
What would you do if someone
tried to take her away from you?
Is this my cystic
fibrosis patient?
Dania Constantin, 12 years old.
Collapsed on a school field
trip with shortness of breath.
Hey, Dania. I'm Dr. Reynolds. We're
gonna take good care of you, okay?
I need the stat chest.
All right, let's go ahead
and get her to Trauma One.
Dania, are you all right?
I just got the call
from school. I'm sorry.
You have nothing
to be sorry about.
I'm so sorry, Mom.
Go ahead and give me a big,
deep breath. Deep as you can.
And out.
That's great.
Good job.
Is she having a CF exacerbation?
Don't be afraid to throw it at
me, Doctor. We've seen it all.
Mrs. Constantin, in a
standard CF exacerbation,
we'd see one impacted
area, maybe two.
But this is multifaceted.
Her platelets are down.
Low red and white cell counts.
Infiltrates on her chest.
So this isn't about her CF?
I believe something
else triggered this.
Arthroscopic shoulder surgery,
$4,650 still outstanding.
I'm real sorry.
I was in such a hole
from all the time I missed.
I just don't have the money yet.
No, that's okay, because
today I'm proposing
a new way to settle your debt.
Says here you're a plumber.
Yeah. Plumbers I've
met know how to barter.
Anything that you can
do for New Amsterdam,
we'll take it.
I'm an electrician
by trade. Perfect.
Wait till you see what
that last storm did to us.
What's the scam,
man? This is New York.
There's always a
scam. It's no scam.
Just barter and trade.
It's worked like
gangbusters for centuries.
So why don't we bring it back?
So I patch up the cracked drywall
around here and rip up my bill?
You patch up the cracked
drywall and you will have paid
your bill every bit as much
as if you wrote us a check.
This isn't charity.
This is just us recognizing
the real-world tangible value
of what our patients can offer.
So the question is,
"How can you help?"
It's a cocker spaniel.
Look at that.
Kids'll love it.
Cough if you need to.
Hi, thanks for jumping
in. It's my pleasure.
So, Dania, has anyone
been sick at school?
Not really. Any new pets?
Just my bacteria-covered
lizard monster.
His name is Lungy. She's
kidding. Cut it out, goofy.
You're on top of your
meds and your CPT, right?
Her father and I handle therapy.
Dania's in charge
of her own meds.
She's a model patient.
You're okay.
Honey, you're
okay. I'm right here.
Any recent travel?
I wish. We've had to cut back.
We're remodeling,
adding a nursery.
Did this new construction have
any leaks in the recent storms?
Oh, God.
You're thinking mold?
Aspergillosis fungal infection
could explain her symptoms.
Some of them. Her white
blood cell count's low.
You'd expect
high with infection.
But if it is black mold,
there's no time to waste.
Okay, we're gonna give you
voriconazole, ceftazidime and tobramycin.
If it's fungal,
that'll wipe it out.
But how could this happen?
We need to prep Lyn for surgery.
We should know in an
hour or two if the clipping
has lowered her
intracranial pressure.
Dr. Kapoor will
be overseeing it.
And our grandson?
Can we see him?
Uh, this is Dr. Frome.
I've asked him to consult on this
case in his role as a child advocate.
Forgive me for asking,
but you are aware that Lyn
was not the egg
donor for this baby?
Yeah, that since she
was just the carrier,
she and this child are not
genetically related in any way?
Yeah. Okay, good.
Um... I apologize for
having to discuss paperwork
at such a painful
time. I really do.
But if you'd take
a look, please.
What is this? That's a waiver.
Although Lyn and
Michael shared a contract,
surrogacy is still currently illegal
in New York, but the good news is
as Lyn's parents, you
can sign on her behalf
to allow the father
to take custody.
No.
Mrs. Sackhoff,
this baby's father
is sitting in my office
waiting to hold his son.
I am not giving him
to some stranger.
Mrs. Sackhoff...
Some man who pays
women to carry children?
Ma'am, I know this is
a complicated situation,
but this child is not yours.
He's the... He's the last
piece I have of my daughter.
He's our grandson, and
we're taking him home.
Thank you.
Help! Help!
She's in V-tach. We
need to defibrillate.
Found some blood.
Charging. Clear.
Going again. Clear.
She's back. Normal sinus rhythm.
You see this?
We were wrong.
This wasn't fungal.
I'm gonna get her
down to the OR,
find out where the
blood is coming from.
What is it? What's
wrong with her?
We're doing everything
we can to find out.
I'll be right back.
Advancing through the
pylorus into the duodenum.
I don't see it yet.
Why did I push for
the voriconazole?
All the signs pointed
in that direction.
Yeah, well now she's being
compromised by antifungal meds
she didn't need on
top of her cystic fibrosis.
There. Right there.
Bleeding ulcer.
Cauterizing now. Good find.
Well, I'll take the compliment when
we figure out what's hurting this girl.
It's the low white
blood cell count.
That's the piece
that's never fit.
You thinking a
myelodysplastic syndrome?
That's the best angle
we have right now.
Once she's recovered,
I'll obtain a bone
marrow biopsy.
We're missing something.
Dr. Stauton, who
are you waiting for?
Dr. Goodwin. He
has a session now.
Oh, no, his session
was rescheduled.
Rescheduled? By whom?
By Dr. Goodwin.
The cost of treatment
for multiple sclerosis
has tripled since
1993. I've noticed.
Yeah, big pharma just
keeps jacking up the DMTs.
Sadly our current system refuses
to limit these increases,
which is why I'm trying
a new thing where
we barter for your debt.
Like a yard sale? Kind of.
What are your skills?
What do you do?
I'm a painter. Mmm. Perfect.
Well, the lobby could use a
fresh coat. Not that kind of painter.
Uh, Less Sherwin-Williams,
more Georgia O'Keeffe.
Oh.
Huh.
So much for the
easy way out, huh?
I can't tell you how many gigs
I've lost because of my condition.
All right, Georgia O'Keeffe.
Here's your canvas.
I think I need to
buy a lot more paint.
Um, yeah. Then, well,
you better get to work.
But you're gonna be great.
Well, if it isn't my
former oncologist.
Aren't you peppy.
You sound surprised.
Well, after all your emo
misgivings about working
with Dr. Stauton,
I feared the worst.
Oh, she's been
a delight. Really?
Like a summer
breeze, that woman.
You do realize I
know her, right?
Yeah, you know,
it's not too late
to take me back, and
I would think about it
if I was you 'cause this offer
will expire in, um... Never.
Please, please
take me back. Max.
Yeah. Friends, colleagues.
Friends and colleagues is...
Clear delineation
till you get better.
Right, but she is so mean.
I mean, she's, like, crazy.
She's like a werewolf or
something. Okay, I'm on board. Fine.
So as my colleague, would
you take a look at this, please?
Mmm-hmm. It's my CF patient.
Everything's failing
at the same time
and we can't see why.
These numbers are atrocious.
That's the only place that
she's not overachieving.
She's top of her class, highly
involved in extracurriculars.
Volunteers in the community.
I mean no one deserves
such a nasty disease,
but such an inspiring girl.
Well, maybe she's
getting a little help.
What, you mean drugs? She's 12.
Yeah, sounds like she
has more on her plate
than most 12 year
olds can handle.
Hi.
Um...
Rohan just told me
this was a family piece
when he gave it to me.
But from the look on your face,
I'm guessing it
belonged to your late wife.
I don't know what's going
on between you and your son,
but I have no intention
of being in the middle of it.
But I certainly never
meant to hurt you, so...
I know we're not great,
but I hope you know
I'd never do that to you.
Hey, how's it going?
Uh, well, legal put in an emergency
injunction request for Michael.
They've all made statements
so now we're waiting.
Mmm. And Lyn? Still in surgery.
Yeah.
Frankly Lyn Sackhoff's
intentions are clear.
The contract's
claim is compelling.
However, the interstate dispute
here is beyond this court's remit.
So I'm bound to issue an
injunction I take no joy in making.
Until the conflict is
resolved by a higher court,
neither party may have custody.
The legal guardian will be the New
York Department of Social Services.
The baby is to be
placed in foster care.
Your Honor, uh, this
child's genetic father is here
begging to take him home,
as are the birth
mother's parents.
And this court's answer is
to send this wanted newborn
into foster care? JUDGE
HAYASHI: It's the law.
I'm sorry, Dr. Goodwin.
My hands are tied.
This isn't over yet. Our legal team
can file an appeal by tomorrow.
No, we'll lose. No,
you don't know that.
Max, do you think this
is the first case like this?
This is not unique.
And while we're appealing,
Robin will be in foster care.
Not for days, for months. I
know. It's unfair, and it's cruel.
Michael.
If you let your son
go to foster care,
you will be introducing him to
a world that is cruel and unfair.
Far more cruel than this.
So, what are you saying?
I should just give up?
I'm saying you should fight.
You should fight to
give your son the best life
that he could possibly have.
Even if it's not with you.
Did you find anything
in her bone marrow?
I'm afraid that's
not the culprit.
Sabra, um...
Is it possible that Dania's
been experimenting?
With drugs? No.
Opioids attack
white blood cells.
And if she's taking street pills,
the cutting agents could account
for all her other symptoms.
But Dania would never do that.
Are you sure? I
know my daughter.
Go ahead. You
won't find anything.
Those are all her
standard CF meds.
I told you, I know my daughter.
This was refilled two weeks ago.
There should only
be four pills left.
Dania stopped taking her
pancreatic enzyme pills.
Her body's not digesting fats.
Leading to a
vitamin A deficiency.
I'll go order the IV.
She stopped on purpose.
Why would she do that?
Oh, wow. Looking
great. It's... It's a horse.
No, it's a field of
corn? I don't know.
But you know what? Don't tell me
because I'm a big believer in the process.
Art is life. "Art is life."
Should I be getting medical
treatment at MoMA now?
Hey, did you rip
that out of the wall?
This came from your
"electrician" working in the hallway.
There's no need for
the "air quotes," okay?
Fran is fully bonded
and licensed.
But she was engaged under
your "bartering" agreement.
Again with the "air quotes."
So, your answer to our
debt issue is bartering?
Look, I promised to get
six cents on the dollar
for our debt within 24 hours. That's
what I did. Mission accomplished.
The only thing you've accomplished is
turning this hospital into a flea market.
Yeah, and who doesn't
love a good flea market?
Sorry, I'm not
seeing the problem.
The problem is you're
paying $4,800 to Fran
to fix five light fixtures.
The only people who
can justify a cost like that
are the military and the mafia.
On the books this looks
like money laundering.
We'll be audited. Yeah,
but if we just explain...
No, no explaining.
This is not how
you run a hospital.
This is over. End
it. I can't do that.
You can. You will.
This is a public hospital.
We care for people at the
lowest points in their lives.
And we do it no matter who
they are or where they're from
or whether or not they
can pay. That's the gig.
And yes, I understand
everything costs something.
But these people, they trust us.
And that trust is sacred.
So believe me when I tell you,
there is no way that I'm gonna
let you hound them for money.
The bartering you've done
today, I'll let it stand. Fran is golden.
Thank you.
But that will be the
end of this billing system
built on rainbows
and magical thinking.
Bills exist.
And it's my job to
make sure we pay them.
I want you to succeed, Max.
If we work together, I'll
be your greatest advocate.
But if you work against me, I'll
bury you before your cancer does.
What are you, five?
Just give me my keys
and I'll be on my way.
Sure, right after you finish
your course of radiation.
Yeah, well, I would, but my appointment
isn't for another several hours.
That's strange.
I could have sworn it was
supposed to have already started.
It was, and then I had
an emergency come up
requiring me to switch
it. So you switched it?
Correct, to later today.
Know any other patients
who go into the system
and switch their
appointments on a whim?
It wasn't a whim.
It was a real emergency
that I was dealing with.
So your cancer isn't
a real emergency?
I didn't say that.
Max, when you tell
me you missed radiation
because people need
you, I don't hear a good man
making a hard choice.
I hear somebody choosing to die.
Today you had a choice.
And you chose to die.
I'll ask you again tomorrow and hopefully
you will have your head in the game then.
Because frankly I don't know
how many tomorrows you've got.
Hear this.
People who treat cancer the way
you're treating cancer do not survive.
Do you want to die, Max?
No.
Radiation is expecting you. 3B.
3B.
Max.
This is how you get better.
I'm afraid the clipping
procedure has not relieved
Lyn's intracranial
brain pressure.
Is there a cure?
Surgery to place
a ventricular shunt
- in her head, but...
- Excuse me.
How is she?
We must prepare for the worst.
You, uh... You've raised
an amazing woman.
Thank you.
That's why I'm, uh,
withdrawing my case.
He can't grow up in foster care.
My son...
He needs to be with
people who love him,
even if that's not with me.
And if you do as good a job
with him as you did with Lyn,
then he's gonna be...
You hang in there,
okay? I'll see you soon.
Someone please tell Robin
that his daddy loves him.
Sweetie. Mom?
Why?
Why did you stop
taking your pills?
I didn't mean
for it to go so far.
Did something happen at
school with your friends?
Dania?
Is this about the baby?
What if you have another me?
Then I'd be the luckiest
mom in the world.
I'm so much work.
And when I stopped
taking the pills,
you didn't even notice.
I wanted you to see.
See what?
That if you're taking
care of the baby,
you can't take care of me.
Dania, do you know why I waited
12 years to have another baby?
'Cause you weren't
ready after me.
I've been ready since
the day you were born.
I waited until you were ready.
Until you could
advocate for yourself.
And, kiddo, look at your life.
You're amazing.
Am I in trouble?
So much trouble.
Come here, baby.
Think they'll be
okay? Yeah, yeah.
Me and my mum
fought all the time,
but we always made up.
Think it'll be the same
with your own kid?
How's that going?
Uh, it's a...
It's complicated.
You having doubts?
On so many levels.
Well, don't.
'Cause you would make
an incredible mother.
You were right.
The bracelet did
belong to my wife.
It was part of a set
of heirloom jewelry.
Mothers pass on
these to their daughters.
It's one of the only things I
kept of my wife after she died.
To remind me of her.
It's been incomplete
for the last two years.
Just missing the bracelet.
I'm so sorry.
All this time I thought that
Rohan had sold this for drugs.
At the funeral I accused
him of it and he denied it.
And I called him a liar...
At his mother's grave.
I see.
So seeing you with the bracelet
showed me how wrong I was.
How wrong I have
been about my own son.
I should have listened
to him, what he told me.
That he wanted something
of his mother's to cherish...
As much as he cherished her.
So give this to Rohan.
His mother would
want him to have it.
Please tell him that
his papa is sorry.
Hey. Oh, hey.
Ready?
Today you offered me
the most amazing gift
that I could ever hope for.
But I can't take you up on it.
I am crazy about you.
But we're not there yet.
And I really like where we are.
Totally agree.
Just, I got caught up
in the possibility of...
Us.
Me, too.
But there's no rush.
We can wait until we're ready.
Will you join me at my harvest?
It's cool that it turns me on
when you talk like a farmer, right?
Michael!
What you did back there,
Lyn's parents want to talk to you.
We just wanted
to hold onto our girl
in case she doesn't wake up.
But we need to honor what
she did while she was here.
And what she did,
she did for you.
Here you go.
Are you...
Yeah.
Thank you.
Hey, little guy.
Hi!
Um... I'll meet you
downstairs. Okay.
Now that is a face I've seen
on many a patient of Dr. Stauton.
I may have jumped the gun on
that summer breeze comment.
Yeah.
She prescribed an
attitude adjustment.
Apparently I need to
prioritize my treatment.
That's why I sent you to her.
The cancer has to come first.
She says I need to
focus on my cancer,
stop moving so fast,
but everything in me says
when I stop moving,
the cancer will catch up.
So just keep moving.
'Cause I'm not...
I'm not done yet.
I wanna leave something
behind, you know? I wanna...
Do something that matters.
But everywhere I look,
all I see is everything
the cancer is
trying to take away.
Then you're not looking
in the right places.
Almost done. What'cha think?
I'd say it's not a bad
thing to leave behind.
So today I wrote a song for you
'Cause a day can get so long
And I know it's hard
to make it through
When you say there's
something wrong
So I'm trying
To put it right 'cause I want
To love you with my heart
Sorry about that, sir.
Whoa! Whoa!
What's this? You
put it on your head.
Uh... Yeah, I do.
And all of this life
It's okay. It's okay.
Oh, my gosh! Look at you guys!
Whoa!
Oh, my gosh! Look at this one!
Holy cow!
For all that you claim
I will move with you