Hey, Catie.
I told you never to come here.
He loved her so much.
I just wish he
loved us that much.
You played his mom
in "Nick of Time."
It's great to see you.
Hello!
Please don't leave us.
I will not leave you.
Ripley, get out of there now!
Whatever happens,
I'm OK with it.
I need you.
Trust me, I am not the only one.
No! Mitch?
I love you too.
Dr. Lenox, we've
got an intake.
Josephine Tucker,
38-year-old female.
Suffered a seizure
30 minutes ago
and treated with
Ativan at the scene.
Heart rate's 110, BP's 131/77.
Respiratory rate and
efforts all over the map.
She's been in a coma
for the past 20 years.
22 years.
That's her mother,
Angela Tucker.
We're gonna take good
care of your daughter.
On my count.
One, two, three.
Call respiratory.
Let's get her hooked
up on high-flow
and order ABG analysis too.
On it.
Her urine output has been
less the last couple of days.
Darker too.
That's helpful. Thanks.
Sunset sign and
Cheyne-Stokes respirations.
What... what does that mean?
Mrs. Tucker, your
daughter's symptoms
are indicative of hydrocephalus.
A build-up of
fluid in the brain.
She's bradying.
Heart rate's in the 30s.
She's having another seizure?
Page neurosurgery?
There's no time. 1
milligram atropine IV.
Prep and drape her
right frontal scalp.
We need to place
an emergent EVD.
What is that? What's an EVD?
Dr. Lenox will drill a small
hole in Josephine's skull
and insert a tube
to drain the fluid.
It's the only way
to save her life.
Do we have your consent?
Yes. Do it.
Scalpel.
Drill.
Catheter.
Now page neurosurg.
Let's get labs and
a head CT, stat.
Is she gonna be OK, Dr. Lenox?
She's stable now, and
her breathing's improved.
We'll know more soon.
I'll wait with Mrs. Tucker
until neurosurgery gets here.
Good. Wait.
Aren't they handing out
Match Day envelopes soon?
You should go.
Oh, is that happening today?
Why are you stalling?
No, I'm not stalling.
I'm just avoiding the crowd.
Mm.
Cardiothoracic at Gaffney
is impossible to get into,
and for some insane reason
I put the University
of North Dakota
as my second choice because
it seemed realistic.
Which it is, because
it's a frozen hellscape.
Naomi, go get your envelope.
Hi.
Hey.
Thank you so much for
setting this up for me.
Of course. Yeah.
Let's just find Maggie
for you, get you started.
Yeah.
Hey, how's your
friend, uh, Dr. Ripley?
They were talking about him
on the news this morning.
Yeah, no, he's gonna be OK.
Oh, good. I'm so glad.
Yeah.
Listen, if you're
still up to it,
maybe we can have
that dinner tonight.
Um, yeah.
No, that'd be great.
- OK.
Maggie. Hey, look who it is.
- Ainsley.
- Hi.
It's so good to see you again.
Thank you so much for
letting me shadow.
Absolutely.
Gonna be learning from the
best charge nurse around, so...
Does he always lay
it on this thick?
Mm, you have no idea.
Ah.
All right, let's go
find you some scrubs.
OK.
Did you bring a
comfortable pair of shoes?
Uh, no, I didn't. But, um...
I love you.
Mom's here, Josie.
I'm right here.
Is that Nurse Goodwin?
Uh, that's Ms. Goodwin, yeah.
She's our chief of
patient services.
Chief?
She's the boss now?
She's my boss, certainly.
You know Ms. Goodwin?
Mrs. Tucker, Josephine's
hand is moving.
Is that normal?
Oh, my God.
No, I've never seen her do that.
Never.
What does it mean?
We will have to do
some tests to confirm,
but it indicates an
increased neuroplasticity.
She might be waking up?
Yes, it's possible.
Isn't this against
some kind of rule?
You're a hero, man.
What do you think you're going
to do, break your other ankle?
So, uh, what's going
on with Hannah?
Uh, we're, uh,
saving the big talk
till I'm back on my feet.
OK.
Doris asked me to
bring these up.
Man, you have got quite the
flock of admirers down there.
Oh, God. More flowers.
All right, that is my cue.
Oh.
Feel better, man.
Thanks, man.
How you feeling?
Other than the bum leg,
better than I have in
a really long time.
How are Sadie and Emilia?
Well, you know, I mean,
Sadie's got some adjusting
to do, obviously.
But you know, they're safe.
They're together.
I think they're gonna be
discharged this afternoon.
Wow, that's great.
Any word from the board
yet about your suspension?
No.
No decision yet.
Last thing I want
to do is set you up,
but I just can't imagine
that your heroics
aren't gonna spin this
in the right direction.
I mean, God knows I think
you deserve a second chance.
I don't know about deserve.
But, um, if I'm given one,
I don't intend to waste it.
I didn't really think I was
gonna make it out of there,
when things started
to go sideways,
till I heard your
voice on the walkie.
I know I haven't always made
it easy to care about me.
Caring about you, pal,
never been the,
uh... the hard part.
You know, you hear stories
about people waking up
from comas decades later,
but I've never actually
seen it happen.
Well, once she's out of CT,
maybe you'd like to say
hello to her mother.
Well, uh, I'm not so sure
Angela would want that.
What caused Josephine's coma?
What was the initial trauma?
It was a... a
terrible car accident.
As I recall, the roads were wet.
It had been pouring all morning.
Josephine's father was
driving her to school
when the car skidded and
flipped over into a ditch.
He died on impact.
Josephine's brain
was hemorrhaging
when the paramedics
brought her in.
Did she go straight to the OR?
Well, there was a
difference of opinion
amongst the doctors...
surgery or trying to
decrease the swelling with...
with medication.
What did Mrs. Tucker decide?
She couldn't decide.
She was paralyzed with grief.
I advocated strongly
for surgery,
perhaps too strongly.
They fixed the bleed,
but Josephine never
regained consciousness.
Angela couldn't possibly
blame you for that.
She was heartbroken
and distraught.
Well, I didn't
take it personally.
There you go.
You're OK, man. You're OK.
Mm-hmm.
Breathing is shallow.
What was his blood pressure?
88/58.
Liam. Hey, bud.
Is there any dietary
changes you've had recently?
Maybe something you ate
that didn't sit right?
Uh, I do all of the cooking,
and we don't really
eat out much.
OK.
Was anyone else in the
house feeling ill, or...
No.
No, Jessica and I are fine.
So are his older brothers.
Doris, let's get a
CBC, BMP, a tox screen,
a urine analysis,
and then call GI
for an endoscopy, please.
OK.
Hey, buddy.
I'll be back soon, all right?
Try to get some rest, OK?
- Thank you.
- Of course.
Really? Cheese curls?
Like many others, I've found
that high-sodium
snacks lift my energy
during mid-morning slumps.
You know, it's these kind
of oddities I look forward
to learning more about.
Does that mean...
I've been accepted
into Gaffney's
cardiothoracic
residency program.
North Dakota's loss
is Chicago's gain.
I couldn't have done
this without you.
You know that, right?
You're about to
become a surgeon.
Lose the humility.
Student Dr. Howard.
Dr. Hayes.
I hope you've heard
the good news.
Hot off the press.
I wanted to come down in person
to congratulate you
and welcome you aboard.
I am incredibly excited
for this opportunity.
I also wanted to invite you
to an informal
gathering tonight.
The cardiothoracic department
does a weekly get-together
at Bar La Rue, end of shift.
Blow off some steam.
I'll be there.
Cheesy curls.
- Mm.
- You?
Mind if I...
You're so generous
with your snacks.
- Oh, I'll take it back.
- No.
Your very detailed
email about Naomi
factored significantly
in our deliberations.
I just thought you should know.
There you are.
I just reviewed Josephine
Tucker's head CT.
- And?
- It's not good.
A brain tumor?
That's what's waking her up?
The neuronal progenitor
cells within the tumor are
firing electrical impulses
into the thalamus,
so it's almost like jumper
cables for her brain.
Uh, how long before
she's fully awake?
It can take weeks, even months,
if it happens at all.
Time that we
unfortunately don't have.
What do you mean?
The neurocytoma is 6
centimeters in size,
so it's disrupting CSF flow,
which caused Josephine's
hydrocephalus
and subsequent seizures.
So we need to resect
it as soon as possible.
Is that dangerous?
Uh, yes.
The tumor is in a very
challenging place to reach.
Will she survive the surgery?
We don't know.
But without the procedure,
there is no uncertainty...
she will die.
So the thing that's
waking her up
is also killing her.
Do you happen to know where
I could find Caitlin Lenox?
I think Dr. Lenox is
in with a patient.
Oh, speak of the
devil, literally.
Damn, you working out?
That's quite a firm
grip you've got.
What did I say
about coming here?
I wouldn't have to if someone
would stop ignoring my texts.
I'm working.
Plus, I found that
it's harder for you
to say no in person.
What did you do, Kip?
Upstairs neighbor
left a faucet running
and flooded my apartment.
I was hoping maybe
I could stay...
- No.
- Come on.
Look, it will be fun.
We will order takeout.
We'll watch "Newsies"
for the hundredth time.
A dancing Christian
Bale with some ramen?
Huh?
Fine. One night.
Totally.
Two or three at most.
I'll be super
low-maintenance, I promise.
I'm gonna go get my key.
Do not move.
Oh, hey, thanks, Catie-Cat!
Hey, you got a minute?
Shoot.
I've got a 12-year-old in
Treatment 4, Liam Russell.
He came in vomiting
blood this morning.
Oh, that's not good.
Pretty unusual for a
12-year-old too, right?
His labs came back and
his tox found traces
of ipecac in his system.
Oh, man.
Well, what are you thinking?
Maybe bulimia?
I mean, maybe, but it's unlikely
a kid his age would
know about ipecac.
GI scope him yet?
Yeah.
They found several small
tears in his lower esophagus.
Well, caused by
repeated vomiting.
So it's been going
on for a while.
It appears so, yeah.
Why don't I wait till Liam
wakes up, have a little chat,
see what I can suss out?
Yeah, that'd be
great. Thank you.
You bet.
Angela.
Hello.
Nurse Goodwin.
Sharon, please.
I understand Josephine's
surgery has been
scheduled for later today.
Well, she's in very good
hands with Dr. Abrams.
He's one of the best
neurosurgeons in...
Well, you'll forgive me if I
don't take your word for it.
I'm sorry.
It's been a...
it's been a day.
Uh, no, it's OK.
I understand.
I've waited 22 years
for her to wake up,
and now, just as
it's happening...
Well, I'll, um...
I'll let you be
alone with Josephine.
Ms. Goodwin, how's
Mrs. Tucker doing?
Every time I go in there,
she's just trying
to will Josephine
to open her eyes or
squeeze her hand.
Oh, I can't imagine it...
all these years waiting
for her to wake up,
dreaming of this moment.
You know, if only the tumor
had worked a little faster.
I mean, jump-started things
before it got so bad.
You mean if it was accelerated?
Yeah.
Why?
Liam, how are you doing?
I'm Dr. Charles.
Your, uh... your mom and
dad are doing some paperwork
with Dr. Frost
right now, I think.
OK.
So, um, this has
happened before?
This, uh... this vomiting?
Wait, why?
Why do you think
it happened before?
Well, because the doc who...
who checked out your throat,
he found some lesions
on your esophagus,
which usually, you know,
happens with repeated vomiting.
I threw up a lot today.
The thing is, you're not
gonna get multiple lesions
from just a single day,
you know, of vomiting.
Like I say, it...
it just suggests a
history of it, you know?
Sometimes I have to
throw up after I eat.
I just have a weak
stomach or something.
It's not a big deal.
You don't have to tell
my parents or anything.
OK, OK.
Um, so you are in seventh grade.
How's that, uh... how's
that going for you?
You like it?
It's fine.
Yeah.
You know, my daughter really
struggled in junior high.
I did, too, come to think of it.
There's so much pressure to
look a certain way, you know.
By the way, total myth
that only girls struggle
with that kind of thing.
I'm not bulimic.
Well, then, um, why are you...
why are you making
yourself throw up, buddy?
How do you know
I'm making myself?
Because we found a
drug in your system
that's, you know, used
to induce vomiting.
I am not here to
get you in trouble.
Not my job, OK?
I promise you, I just
want to figure out
what's going on so I can...
so I can help you.
There's something wrong with me.
I'm fixing it.
Oh.
I'm not stalking you, I promise.
Maggie asked me to
bring her some gauze.
Yeah, it's all good.
Gauze is right there.
It's a real trip seeing
you in doctor mode today.
Can't have been easy
for you to get here.
I'm... I'm sure your
parents didn't help.
Yeah, no.
But you did it.
I'm really proud of you.
You know, you were the
only person in my life
who encouraged me
to quit acting,
figure out what I
really wanted to do
instead of, you know,
what everyone else was
telling me I wanted to do.
Yeah.
I could just see your
heart wasn't in it.
Yeah.
I was always...
I used to feel like
you were the only one
who ever really
saw me, you know?
Like, past the veneer.
Used to?
I still see you, Jonathan.
Ainsley, I, um...
Oh.
I thought you wanted...
I... I don't really
know what I, um...
- I'm so sorry.
- No, that's OK.
Look, if you need any more
help, just get Maggie, OK?
- Of course.
- All right.
Similar to the neurocytoma's
progenitor cells,
the medicine that I'm
injecting, baclofen,
could theoretically
restore neurotransmission
between wakefulness
and awareness.
In other words, it's mimicking
what the tumor's
doing, only faster.
It's a long shot.
But it could allow Josephine
to wake up before surgery.
Emphasis on long shot.
There's a good chance
this won't work.
And as we've discussed,
introducing any substance
into the brain
intrathecally can increase
intracranial pressure,
so if Josephine's ICP
level rises above 40,
we need to take her to
surgery immediately.
I understand.
Mom's here, Josie.
I'm right here.
So you're saying that
Liam is feeling the need
to harm himself because
he's attracted to boys,
and this was his
attempt at, like,
some DIY conversion therapy?
He read about a form of
aversion therapy online where
they administer nausea-inducing
inducing medications to people,
then show them
same-sex materials,
idea being to condition
them to feel sick
when those attractions come on.
OK.
Well, what do we do now?
I mean, Liam's intentionally
harming himself.
Do we put him on a
psych hold, or...
The problem is he didn't
really see it that way, right?
He thinks he's fixing himself.
Those are his words, you know?
Not... not hurting himself.
And I mean, honestly,
5150 wouldn't be
the top of my list anyway.
It'll just reinforce this
idea that he's somehow,
you know, deserving
of punishment.
I mean, in a perfect world,
we'd find him a good shrink.
But, you know...
Yeah, which we would need
the parents' consent for.
But look, I can only
imagine Liam begged you
not to say anything
to his parents,
but at this point, uh...
We've got to tell them
about the ipecac, right?
I mean, it's on the blood test.
But there's no way I'm gonna
tell them why he took it.
It would be immensely damaging,
not to mention unethical,
to out the kid,
you know, without
his permission.
OK.
Then how do we tell his parents
that their son needs help
without explaining to
them the actual problem?
Very, very carefully.
I don't understand.
Liam's a happy kid.
Why was he doing this?
You know, I haven't quite
gotten that out of him yet.
Um, which is why, with
your permission, of course,
I would really like to
keep him here another day,
maybe two, you know, to...
Sorry, I'm confused.
You want to keep him here,
but you don't know
what's wrong with him?
I mean, do you
think it's some kind
of a suicide attempt
or something?
I mean, I know he got picked on
at school for a little while,
got teased a little
bit, but he's got
a solid group of friends now.
- No, OK?
That is not it.
We are not at all suggesting
that Liam is intentionally
hurting himself in a...
- Well...
In a traditional sense.
Traditional?
What are we talking about here?
We brought him in today because
he was vomiting up blood.
You really don't know why?
I'm sorry, we, uh... we don't.
But if I had to
guess at this point,
I would say that it might have
something to do with Liam,
I don't know, somehow
not feeling safe.
Are you saying he doesn't
feel safe at home?
Not necessarily, because...
because I don't know yet.
Well, I'm honestly not sure what
you're suggesting, other than
committing my 12-year-old son...
We are not committing...
When you have no idea
what's wrong with him.
If Liam needs to
talk to someone,
he can always talk to us.
He knows that.
We'll handle this as a family.
When can we take Liam home?
He needs to do another
round of fluids
to address his dehydration.
How long will that take?
A couple hours.
Fine.
As soon as that's
done, we're leaving.
Josie?
Please, baby.
Come on, Josie.
What is that?
Her ICP level is over 40.
50 grams of mannitol IV.
Come on, baby.
It's OK, baby.
Just give it a second.
It's not coming down.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Tucker.
We have to take
Josephine to surgery.
No.
Just another second, please.
Come on, baby.
I love you.
Angela, it's time.
I'll be waiting for you, honey.
I can take you to a
private waiting area...
Mr. Russell, how
are you doing?
Hey. Fine.
You mind if I sit for a second?
OK.
I just want to say that, from
my own experience, anyway,
like, watching your...
your kid suffer is
the worst pain
imaginable, right?
I mean, especially when
you don't know how to help.
I think, um...
I think Liam might be confused.
Confused, um, how?
Just about who he's,
you know, attracted to.
Growing up in today's world,
you're inundated with
all these images,
and you can't even turn
on the Olympics anymore
without it being shoved
in your face, right?
Yeah.
So I...
I just think he's
a little mixed up.
You know, Jessica and
I, we don't hate anyone.
It's just not a...
lifestyle that we condone.
Science, it... it actually,
it just doesn't support
this idea that, you know,
television or social media,
or anything, for that
matter, can, you know,
turn somebody gay,
can make them gay.
You know, it actually
tells us the opposite,
that, uh, when it comes
to sexual orientation,
there's just actually no degree
of choice involved whatsoever.
It's just... it's...
it's how we're born, you know?
It's just an innate part
of... of who we are.
I'll also tell you
that for a kid to feel
like their parents...
whose approval they seek
more than anything
in the world...
that their parents can't
accept who they are...
it can lead them to take
some pretty drastic action.
I don't want that.
I just love him
so much, you know?
That is very clear.
So then how do we help?
- Henry.
- Hey.
What's going on?
Uh, nothing.
I was just talking to
Dr. Charles here about
what else we need to sign to
take Liam home today, right?
Good.
Well, Liam's finished
with his fluids,
so we're ready to go.
Great.
Hey.
Would you mind some company?
You know, 22 years
ago, we sat together
in a waiting room
a lot like this.
I remember telling you
if it were my daughter,
I'd choose surgery, no question.
But I wasn't your doctor,
and it wasn't my child,
and I wouldn't have to
live with the consequences
of that decision for
the rest of my life.
I'm sorry, Angela.
I should not have
weighed in on a decision
that was yours alone to make.
Is she...
Josephine made it.
She's alive.
You know, I'm...
I'm not a conspiracy
theorist, but if I were,
I might suggest it seemed
like you all were trying
to collect a little extra
money from our insurance,
keeping Liam here.
I can promise you
that is not the case.
Well, anyway.
Liam, come on, let's get going.
Bye, Dr. Charles.
Great meeting you, Liam.
Jessica, stop.
Maybe we need to rethink this.
What are you talking about?
I'm just saying maybe we
should listen to the doctors.
Henry, you know why they
want to keep him here.
They want to fill his
head with ideas that
whatever he's feeling is OK.
Did you know that
he was doing this
to himself the entire time?
- No.
No, of course I didn't know.
I just knew that he was...
he was working
through some issues.
Of course I don't want
him to be in danger.
He's my baby.
But I am so proud of
how strong you are.
You knew something was wrong,
and you were trying to fix it,
and we're gonna get
you the help you need.
But it's not in here.
Now let's go.
He's not going anywhere.
What?
How could you let
our son hurt himself?
I... I told you,
I didn't know.
You knew.
I didn't know he was gonna
end up in the hospital.
You need to leave.
Not without my son.
Yes, without our son.
Now, what happens next, we'll
handle it when the time comes.
But right now, you
really need to leave.
Oh, right, OK.
Well, um, I'm... I'm
just gonna go home
and get started on dinner, then.
I'm your mom.
I know what's best for you.
I'm sorry.
I tried.
No.
Hey, buddy.
Hey.
There is nothing
to apologize for.
I love you, no matter what.
Nothing will ever change
that, do you hear me?
Yeah?
Man.
There you are.
Ainsley, she was stellar today.
She acclimated to
the chaos like a pro.
That's great to hear.
And I, um...
I appreciate you
letting her shadow you.
Of course.
So what's the real story there?
There's no story.
We're just old friends.
I saw your face when you
came out of the supply room.
You're not gonna
let it go, are you?
- I'm not.
- OK.
We had a thing.
A thing?
We were involved,
a long time ago.
How long ago?
Towards the end
of "Nick of Time."
Weren't you 15?
Almost 17 when the show ended.
And what was she, in her 30s?
God, Mags, I knew you
were gonna make this
a bigger deal than it was.
But look, I was not a
typical teenager, all right?
I was already living on my
own, working a full-time job.
I mean...
- OK.
That still doesn't make
it OK for a grown woman
to start a relationship
with a minor.
I don't need the
lecture, all right?
I know what the
textbooks say about it,
and I know technically,
it was wrong.
- Technically?
- Yeah.
OK? But having lived it,
it was not like that.
Maybe it wasn't
the best decision,
but it was my decision.
I knew what I was doing.
And whatever it was, it's
well in the past now.
I've moved on.
That is not what I saw today.
OK.
You're not being
honest with yourself.
Maggie, I'm not a
victim here, all right?
I'm just trying to be a friend.
No, no. Stop, stop.
You and I may joke
around at work,
and that's fun and all,
but it does not mean
that you know me, or her.
Drop it. It's not
your business.
Hey.
I'm supposed to tell you
that visiting hours are over.
Can't the boss bend
the rules a little?
Well, unfortunately,
ICU rules are ironclad.
I don't want her to be alone.
Oh, then I'll sit with her.
Don't you need to
be getting home?
Well, I live here anyway.
OK.
If you don't mind.
It'd be my pleasure.
Josephine, my name is Sharon.
I met you long time ago.
I did blame you for years.
But I also blamed the rain,
and Josie for oversleeping
and missing the
bus that morning,
and... so that her dad had
to drive her to school,
and I blamed her dad for not
getting the tires checked
after I reminded him to.
And when the pain
became unbearable,
anger was the only thing
that kept me going.
I understand.
But sitting in that
waiting room today,
the possibility of losing
Josie as real and as terrifying
as it was 22 years ago,
I realized I am so grateful
for every moment I've
had with my daughter.
And I have you to
thank for that.
I'll see you tomorrow?
I'll be here.
Uh, Angela!
Josie?
Mom's here, baby.
I'm right here.
She's squeezing my hand.
Three times.
That's right.
I love you too, Josie.
Hey, Catie.
Oh, hey, no way.
Gyuro?
Well, you said ramen,
so I got ramen.
And the DVD's in the
case under the soundbar,
and we're doing the singalong
version, so you know.
You made plans.
- I kind of made plans.
But we could put the
ramen in the fridge
and watch "Newsies"
when I get back.
When's that?
Not too late.
By midnight.
I'll be sleeping.
Mind if I hold on
to your key, then?
Here.
Uh, you should take the spare.
I think you should have it
anyways, for emergencies.
What's going on?
You're the only
family I have left.
We should take
care of each other.
It's what Mom would have wanted.
Oh, you big softie.
Shut up.
What was that?
Uh, nothing, Catie.
How long has that
been happening?
It's nothing, OK?
I just had a few too many
espressos today, that's all.
Kip.
Look, it's not like I
would do anything about it.
We promised.
I know, but if this...
But what, Catie?
Look, whatever time I have left,
I'm not gonna spend it worrying.
I'm gonna have fun.
You should try it sometime.
I have fun.
Oh, tough love, sis,
but when's the last time
you had plans on a Friday night?
OK.
You want to spend your time
partying, fine, go ahead.
I want to spend
mine being useful.
Doesn't mean that you
have to be miserable.
- I'm not.
- OK, fine.
But will you just
do something tonight
that involves you
leaving your apartment,
and maybe putting on pants
that aren't scrubs or sweats?
Or maybe taking them off
for somebody special.
Or not so special, you know.
Just somebody, anybody.
Thanks.
Dr. Ripley, how's your ankle?
Dr. Stano says I can
start PT next week.
Should be upright in
less than a month.
Well, I'm pleased to hear that.
The board convened today.
Turns out becoming
an overnight hero can
buy you some goodwill.
You've been reinstated.
Which I know you
recommended against.
Look, talk is cheap,
so let me just say
I'm gonna prove to you that
I've changed, Ms. Goodwin.
Well, after the day I've had,
I'd be remiss not
to acknowledge that
patience can be rewarded.
Rest up, Dr. Ripley.
We'll see you back in
the ED when you're ready.
I don't need him,
I need a drink
Let's turn this pain
into some champagne, baby
Like cheers, bitch,
it's been a day
Might take that last
flight out to Vegas
Dr. Lenox.
I... I didn't know
you were coming.
Well, here I am.
You look... wow, um...
- Let me buy you a drink.
- No, no, no.
It's your accomplishment
we're celebrating.
Let me do the honors.
What can I get you?
Two shots, Woodford
Reserve Double Oaked.
So bitch, I can't complain
I'm still bad, babe
Plot twist,
I'm doing great
Here's to your
future, Dr. Howard.
Ahh.
Come say hi to everyone.
Oh, yes.
Social time. Fun.
Glad you could
join us, Catie-Cat.
Oh, oh, no.
Do not ever call me that.
Who was the guy?
It was my brother.
What a relief.
Hey.
There he is.
Sorry, I was just
finishing up a few things.
Yeah. You ready for dinner?
Yeah, you know,
actually, I don't think
I'm gonna be able
to make it tonight.
This is about earlier.
Listen, I... I know that
was a little presumptuous.
I just... old feelings, I...
I got carried away.
- Right.
Yeah, it's just I
think maybe they should
stay old feelings, you know?
Like, forever?
For now, at least, yeah.
Are you mad at me?
No.
Uh...
Ainsley, whatever we had,
whatever it was, it...
Whatever it was?
You know what I mean.
Jonathan, what we had,
that wasn't a fling.
It was more than that.
I know.
Do you?
I listened to you.
We cried together.
You said it yourself... you
wouldn't even be here now
if it wasn't for
me, for what we had.
So listen, you can
leave it in the past.
That's fine.
But don't dismiss it like
it didn't mean anything.
You loved me.
I did love you.
And I loved you.
And I still love you...
OK, Ainsley. Hey, hey.
Just... I wish you a lot of
luck on your movie, all right?
That's it?
That's it.
OK.