.
- ¶ Oh, yeah,
candles burning low ¶
¶ Lots of mistletoe ¶
- Hey, uh...
two adults and one
furry little monster.
- Rawr!
- Here you go.
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you.
- Enjoy the show.
- ¶ Right outside my door ¶
- Hey, I'll get a seat.
Come on, okay?
- Hey.
Max, Max, Max.
- Honey, honey.
[gunshots]
- Gun!
He's got a gun!
Gun! He's got a gun!
- Lucy!
Lucy!
[panicked yelling]
- Bill!
- Max!
Lucy!
- Mommy!
- I got you, Max.
Come on! Let's go!
- Lucy!
[indistinct yelling]
- Get out of the way, lady!
- [grunts]
- Ow!
- Lucy!
- Bill!
- [muffled]
Mommy!
[panicked yelling]
- Max!
- Korean Spanish
fusion?
- Oh, yeah, the short rib and
chorizo burrito is delicious.
- What if you're
a vegetarian?
- Then I would go with
the tofu kimchi quesadilla.
- Can I have a garden
salad, please?
- Yeah.
What? You said get
anything I want.
- April, order up!
- Yes!
Pork and chili taco.
Mmm!
Gonna post this.
Yes.
Thank you, Dr. Rhodes.
- You are very
welcome, April.
Hey, Will,
you sure you good?
- Yeah, I brought
something from home.
- It's $65.50 total.
- Hey, thanks a lot, man.
- I'll grab you some change.
- Nope. No, we're good.
Thanks, man.
- Thank you.
- You brought
something from home?
I've seen your fridge.
What'd you bring, expired
yogurt and baking soda?
- All right, we get it.
He's rich.
- He's just new.
He's trying to be nice.
- What is that?
- It's some
cabbage kale thing.
I promised my mother-in-law
I would try it, so...
Oh. Ugh.
- [chuckles]
You got, uh...
Let me get you a napkin.
- Thank you.
Ugh.
- I think I'm
seeing something.
- Easy, April,
we're just friends.
No.
- If you say so.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
[beepers sounding off]
- Shooting in
a movie theater.
Mass casualties.
About to get crazy.
EMT four minutes out.
[ambulance siren wailing]
- Check that,
they're here.
- Let's go,
let's go!
Let's go, I need two.
- Another maniac going crazy
in a theater.
This the world we live in?
- Maggie!
Trigger disaster plan,
get ortho, neuro,
walk-ins can wait.
- Got it.
What do we got?
- 23-year-old male, trampled,
shoulder dislocation,
GCS 15.
- Trauma 7, yellow.
- Maggie!
- Talk to me.
- 20-year-old female trampled.
Scalp avulsion.
- All right, treatment 6.
- Thank you, Maggie.
- What do we got?
- Lucy Simms,
34, unresponsive.
Flaccid, agonal breathing.
Tubed her without drugs.
- Trauma 2.
- The boy hurt?
- He was never touched.
Mom was literally
a human shield.
Dad's in the
ambo behind us.
- Maggie, take him somewhere
until Dad arrives.
- I got him.
- On my count.
One, two, three.
- 2 epi.
- Pulse is weakened. Ready.
- I'm having trouble bagging.
Lot of resistance.
[heart monitor beeping steadily]
BP 70 over 40.
Heart rate 130.
Stats are dropping.
- No breath sounds
on the left.
- She's bradying down.
No pulse, she's coding.
[heart monitor flat lining]
- Milligram of epi.
[dramatic music]
[panting]
- No official
ID on the perpetrator,
but witnesses report
he looked to be
in his late teens
to early 20s
and was laughing as he sprayed
the theater with bullets.
- As soon as the labs
come back call me.
- Yes, Doctor.
- But from my vantage point
I can see paramedics.
- The police say
the shooter's in custody.
They're bringing
him here now.
Multiple gunshot wounds.
A civilian shot him.
A high school
algebra teacher.
He's on his way here too,
and the press is
gathering outside.
- "The media is the most
powerful entity on earth.
"It can make
the innocent guilty,
and the guilty
innocent."
Gee, who said that?
- Malcolm X.
- Right on, sister.
- Mr. Miller,
you're being lauded as
a hero for taking
down that gunman.
What were you thinking
in that moment?
- Uh...
I didn't think.
Um...
People were in danger.
I just acted.
- Excuse me, ma'am, um...
Is there someone I--
my wife is just--
- Excuse me, can I help you?
- Yes, uh--
I'm Bill Simms.
My wife, Lucy, was just
brought in here and
my little boy, Max--
- Okay, Mr. Simms,
I need you to take a breath.
- [sighs]
- Your wife is being
treated right now,
and your little
boy is fine.
I'm gonna take
you to him, okay?
- Yeah, okay. Thank you.
- Follow me, please.
- Yeah.
- Okay, this way.
[heart monitor flat lining]
- [panting]
- Slide over so I can
needle the left chest.
Hold compressions.
[air whooshing]
[heart monitor beeps steadily]
- Got a pulse.
Get a pressure.
- 100 over 78,
heart rate 120.
- How long was she down?
- 23 minutes.
- Last patient I had down
that long--it didn't end well.
- Let's get a chest tube in her
and then get her up to CT.
We'll take it from there.
- Can you take
a deep breath for me?
- [inhales deeply,
exhales]
- How about another one?
- [inhales, exhales]
- Were you part
of the crush?
Did you get the wind
knocked out of you?
Is that why you
passed out?
- No, I got dizzy
before anything happened.
- What about
the vomiting?
- I don't know why.
- Did you buy candy?
Or that horrible
buttered popcorn?
You know,
that's not even butter.
- No, I didn't
eat anything.
- Everywhere you go,
junk food.
When I was a teenager, I thought
I could eat whatever I wanted.
Of course, I got fat.
- All right,
well your heart's regular,
your lungs are clear.
How's the nausea now?
- A little better.
Maybe.
I don't know, I just
always feel kind of blah.
- What about that
meal I packed you?
Did you eat that?
I make her healthy options,
she won't eat them.
- They're gross.
Besides, they make
me feel bad too.
- Okay.
Let's run some tests and
see what comes back.
Food allergies,
infections--
these could lead to extended
periods of nausea.
Nurse will be in
to draw your blood.
Get me some baseline labs.
CBC, CMP, prealbumin,
mag, UA, HCG, a urine tox,
and I need Dr. Charles.
Thanks.
- What do we got?
- 17-year-old male.
GCS six,
multiple GSWs to the abdomen.
Two large bore IVs.
Tachy's at 160.
Pressure's marginal.
- Baghdad turned over?
- Yeah, it's all yours.
- Reese!
Stay with us.
[indistinct chatter
on EMT radio]
All right.
On my count.
One, two, three.
All right, check
for breath sounds.
- This the shooter?
- Don't know yourself
out over this one.
- Yeah, we got it from here,
thanks.
- Breath sounds
bilaterally.
[heart monitor beeping steadily]
- Can't even go
to the movies anymore.
- Doctor.
[heart monitor flat lines]
- No pulse. Reese?
- On it.
- He's bleeding
into his belly.
We need to clamp
the aorta to keep
whatever blood
he has left
going into his
heart and brain.
[heart monitor flat lining]
- You're gonna crack
the chest here?
- Yeah.
- It's futile.
What, are you just practicing
your thoracotomy?
- Actually,
trying to save his life.
[dramatic music]
¶ ¶
Aw, the heart's empty.
Pump the blood with
the level one now.
- Give me the tubing, I'll run
it through the groin here.
- All right.
Aorta's cross-clamped.
Clock starts now.
We have 30 minutes to find out
where he is bleeding from.
Call the OR, tell them
that we're on our way up
with an open chest
and a gunshot to the belly.
- Good luck.
- I'll let you write it up
in JAMA when he pulls through.
Let's go.
[heart monitor flat lining]
- Yeah, headed up with
an open chest, gunshot wound.
Thanks.
- She's not responding
to pain.
[heart monitor beeping steadily]
Pupils still
non-responsive.
[sighs]
No corneal reflex,
no gag reflex.
Not over-breathing
the vent,
failed the first apnea test.
- We get a miracle?
- Not today.
Catastrophic
intracranial hemorrhage.
Too many kicks.
- God,
this shouldn't have happened.
- What, you want a why?
People suck.
That's why.
[heart monitor beeping steadily]
- Maggie?
- Yup?
- Lucy Simms was
a registered organ donor.
Her husband
has given permission
for her to be taken
off the ventilator
and her organs harvested.
The Gift of Hope transport
vehicles will be here soon.
- I'll alert the OR.
- Thank you.
- Hey, it's you,
Rick Miller.
You're the guy that
took out the gunman.
Thanks, man.
- Thank you so much.
I will never forget you.
I'll never forget you.
Thank you.
[applause]
- Thank you, Mr. Miller.
- We need more
guys like that.
- Right.
[applause continues]
Mr. Miller?
If you would
follow me, please.
- Thank you!
- You're a lifesaver.
- Quick thinking,
cracking open his chest.
I would've used
the REBOA, though.
- And for a second,
I thought Dr. Zanetti
was about to give
me a compliment.
- The kid's alive,
that's your compliment.
Okay, let's pack him up,
see where he's bleeding from.
- Yes, Doctor.
- Open belly, open chest.
Kid's gonna have a hell
of a set of scars.
- Huh.
Serves him right.
- Keep the commentary
to yourself, okay?
- Sorry.
- Didn't peg you
for a bleeding heart.
- Didn't know you
were trying to peg me.
Bleeding's coming from
the portal vessel
high up in the liver.
- A year at Chiraq
and I've already lost count
of how many
Pringle Maneuvers I've done.
- Chicago and guns.
Winning combination.
- And making us all
very good surgeons.
[monitor beeping]
- Damn it.
The bullet decimated
the portal vein
and common hepatic artery.
We take the clamp off,
he bleeds to death.
We keep it on,
we sacrifice his liver.
- Well, then we can't let him
bleed to death.
[dramatic music]
¶ ¶
- Nurse will be with
you in five minutes.
- Dr. Charles.
- Poor fellow in here.
Agoraphobic, picked today
of all days to go to the movies.
- I know you're busy,
I just need a quick consult.
I've got a
16-year-old patient
emaciated, persistent nausea,
but her blood work's normal.
No food allergies,
she's not pregnant,
and her mom's all
over her about food.
She has all
the indicators of anorexia.
- Eating disorders
is so tricky to diagnose.
- I've seen it before.
My best friend in college,
she was anorexic.
Starved herself to death.
Her mom?
Just like this one.
- Terrible disease.
You pretty sure that's what
we're dealing with here?
- Mm-hm.
- Let's take a look.
- Great, this way.
- Ashley, Mrs. Cole,
this is Dr. Charles.
I've asked him to consult.
- I am so sorry
about the awful day
you've both been
having, but...
Ashley, I understand
you're not feeling well
and haven't been
for a while?
Some tummy issues?
- Yeah.
- So you and food not on
the best of terms right now?
- I love food.
I just can't eat it.
- Why is that?
- It makes me throw up.
- Any food in
particular, or...
- Everything.
- Well that's no fun.
- Makes me nervous just
thinking about eating.
- I don't blame you.
- Are you a
gastroenterologist?
- No, I'm a psychiatrist.
- But--
No, no--
This isn't that.
It's her body
that's in trouble.
- What if I were to
give Ashley something
to make her not feel sick?
Do you think you might
be able to eat then?
- I guess so.
- Yeah, FDA's just approved
a new anti-nausea drug.
Remarkable results
in clinical trials.
You should be able to
eat anything you want.
- Anything?
A hamburger with fries?
- She can't take
all that grease.
- The cafeteria grills
a pretty mean burger.
We could give one a try.
- Sure.
- Ashley.
- Mrs. Cole, could I get you
to go with me on this one?
- [sighs]
Okay, I suppose.
- Great.
I have some samples
up in my office,
I'll have them sent down,
and then we'll order
you that burger.
Nice to meet you both.
- Just hang tight.
Hey, what's the name
of that medication?
- I've got a board member
in my office in five seconds.
Page me at burger time.
- Well, there she goes.
- Something doesn't
make sense.
- What's that?
- Shooting in a movie theater,
and we've only had one GSW,
and that was the shooter.
Where are the rest
of the gunshot victims?
- You look very island-y.
Are you sure
you're not Jamaican?
- Yes, I am sure.
- Well, you look just like
the girl who cleans my house.
[sighs]
- Mrs. Kovach,
I'm Dr. Halstead.
Says you were
in the movie theater.
- Oh, no, I just said that
so I wouldn't have to wait.
You see all those
people out there?
- So, just the headaches, then?
- Oh, I get tired
sometimes,
and I cough a lot,
and I don't always remember
where I put my things.
Bring me a cup of
chamomile tea, will you, dear?
- Oh, I will let your
server know, ma'am.
150 over 90.
- Let's get a CBC, CMP,
EKG, and a CXR.
- You bet.
- Your symptoms are pretty
varied, Mrs. Kovach.
Once we get you
lab results back--
- Who is that?
- Dr. Choi?
- Perfect.
I want him.
- Excuse me?
- Oh, no offense, dear.
The Orientals make
the best doctors.
It's their math skills.
- So, did you ever lose
consciousness?
- Briefly.
I think, um...
I have a little headache
now, but it's probably
just from the adrenalin.
- All right, I'll talk
to my attending about
ordering a CT,
just to be safe.
[cell phone chiming]
- Oh.
My phone's been blowing
up with texts and emails
ever since my name
got in the news.
That's a tweet.
This morning,
I had 120 followers.
Now I have 96,000.
- I'm one of them.
That video of you getting
into the ambulance,
saying you didn't think,
you just acted?
It's trending.
- Mr. Miller.
There are a couple
of detectives here
that need to ask
you some questions.
Is he all right
to come with me?
- Yeah, just finished.
Just waiting
to get him to CT.
- All right,
Mr. Miller.
- Thanks.
- Mm-hm.
- Uh...
I already spoke with
the officers at the scene.
- We're just here to
clarify a few things.
- You said you saw
the gunman enter
the theater,
is that right?
- Yes, from the emergency
exit by the screen.
- And what was he carrying?
- Um, an assault rifle.
- You saw the weapon?
- Yes, he was, uh,
waving it around.
- Can you describe
the weapon?
- Uh...
I couldn't tell if
it was a Kalashnikov.
I couldn't see
the banana clip, you know?
I think it was an M16A1.
- Did you hear him
fire the weapon?
- Yes, that's why
I pulled my gun.
- Is it possible that
the shots you heard
were actually coming
from the movie?
- No.
What--
what's, uh...
what's going on here?
- Peter, the kid that you shot
is a prankster.
He thinks it's funny
to scare people.
He posts videos
on the Internet.
- I don't understand.
- He didn't have
an assault rifle.
He didn't have
a rifle at all.
He had a leaf-blower.
[dramatic music]
¶ ¶
- So, they're gonna
charge Mr. Miller?
- No.
The gun was legal, he had
a license to concealed carry.
He thought
his life was in danger.
The prankster, Peter Wallace,
is another story.
He could face
some serious time.
- If he lives.
- So, her name's
Gertrude Kovach.
72 years old, presented
with general discomfort,
fatigue, headaches,
forgetfulness.
- Dementia.
- No.
She knows exactly
what she's saying.
You sure you don't mind?
- No worries.
Always glad when
someone gets it right.
- Oh, good.
Finally.
- My assistant,
Dr. Halstead,
showed me your
blood work.
Your ACE and calcium
levels are high,
and your chest x-rays
revealed the lymph nodes
along your lungs
are enlarged.
It could be symptomatic
of something serious,
but before we go there,
let's do a biopsy
and see what comes back.
- Oh, thank you, Doctor.
I knew you'd be
the one to help me.
- You're too kind,
but humility is the solid
foundation of all virtues.
- Oh.
- Really?
Confucius?
You're Korean.
- All the same to her.
Hey, call me after
you do the biopsy
and make a diagnosis,
so I can take the credit.
- Ha-ha.
- Hey. You hear?
The kid at the theater,
the one who got shot,
he didn't have a gun,
he had a leaf blower.
- What?
- Yeah.
It was some
kind of prank.
[indistinct intercom voice]
[heart monitor beeping steadily]
- We have clamped the entire
blood supply to his liver.
It's keeping him
alive for now,
but it's a temporary solution.
He needs a liver
transplant to survive.
- Which he won't get.
Peter'll stay at the bottom
of the list, won't he?
How long does he have?
- A day, maybe two.
- He did a bad thing,
but he's not a bad person.
He's just a boy.
Please...
save my son.
- [sighs]
- Rumor's floating
around,
you're gonna
want to hear it.
- The kid, Peter Wallace,
he has a website for his pranks.
Look.
Look at this.
Like he's an escaped convict.
- Oh, nice little baby!
They got Peter Wallace-d!
- Knuckle-head.
- [laughs]
Amazing no one's popped
him before now.
- Check out my blow cam.
[wacky music]
- The leaf blower.
40,000 views.
- Wait a second.
Mr. Miller?
Excuse me,
can I help you?
- Um...
How's he doing?
Peter, the kid.
- I'm sorry, Mr. Miller,
we can't give out
patient information.
- Is he alive?
- Yes.
- [sighs]
An hour ago, everybody was
clapping for me,
and now, um...
[laughs]
It looked so real.
- There's one patient ahead
of you for the CT.
It shouldn't be long.
I'll come get you.
- Thanks.
I could swear he had a gun.
- This is so good!
Mmm.
- Honey, please.
Don't eat so fast.
- Mom, I'm fine, really.
[retches]
- She's gonna be sick.
- Here.
- [vomiting]
- I knew all that grease
would make her sick.
So much for your
magic pill.
- You okay?
Has it passed?
- I'm sorry Ashley's having
such a tough time, but uh...
her response has actually
tell us a great deal.
- I should hope so.
- Dr. Charles.
- Dr. Manning
will be right back.
- Okay, honey.
You're gonna be okay.
- What did you give her?
- A Tic Tac.
- A Tic Tac?
- Yes.
- You gave my patient a placebo?
- Yup.
- That's not ethical.
- Oh, balls.
Look--
nausea, no nausea.
I now have a much clearer
picture of what's going on.
I needed to get around mother
and see that girl eat.
- I could report you.
I should report you.
- Dr. Manning, have you ever
heard of "bias confirmation"?
- What?
- Bias confirmation.
Interpreting
information so that it
conforms to
one's preconceptions.
Look, you walked in and saw
a thin 16-year-old girl
with an overbearing mother,
who reminded you
of your college roommate.
Who, very tragically,
died of anorexia,
so voila, the patient
has anorexia.
- She has the indicators.
- She also has
the contra-indicators.
If the mother were
that overbearing,
she never would
have allowed Ashley
to choose that
particular meal,
and if Ashley were anorexic,
she never would have eaten it,
let alone with such gusto.
The mother is right.
It's Ashley's body
that's in trouble,
and that is
your department.
Thank you.
- Is it true?
Lucy Simm's liver is on its
way back to the hospital?
- The intended recipient
died in pre-op.
- Peter is an HLA match,
it can go to him.
- Yeah, there are names
ahead of him on the list.
- None of them
are in this hospital.
It has already
been three hours,
livers are viable
for less than 12.
By the time the list
gets sorted out,
the patient prepped, organ
shipped, it may be too late.
Lucy's husband can direct donate
to whomever he chooses.
Ask him to give
it to Peter.
- You're talking
about the man
responsible for
his wife's death.
- And he has done a horribly
stupid thing, I know,
but he's a kid.
Peter deserves a chance
to turn his life around.
- Dr. Charles.
We have a patient
that I think you might
want to have a chat with.
- Oh.
Thank you.
- I got--
I got mugged a few years ago,
so I started carrying
a gun for protection,
and I took the classes.
I passed
the background checks.
I'm not a vigilante.
I don't go out
looking for trouble.
- It was dark in that
theater, you know.
People were running
around yelling, "Gun."
I completely understand why you
thought he would have had one.
- That's right.
I did what anyone
would have done.
But tell them.
"My buddy pranked me with a
whoopee cushion, so I shot him."
"Another genius gun nut,
shoots first, and asks
questions later."
"Save the rest of us,
shoot yourself, hero."
Those are the nice ones.
- Oh,
the Internet, right?
I mean, people use it
to vent anonymously.
None of them were
in that theater.
- Yeah, well, uh--
People believe
what they want to,
and because I'm the only
one that had a real gun,
I'm the bad guy?
That--
that--
that kid did this.
I shouldn't be the pariah.
[knock at door]
- Sorry to interrupt.
Mr. Miller, your CT
results are negative.
You're fine.
The stitches will need
to stay in for a week,
but you're free to go.
- Thank you.
[whispering]
Could have waited.
We got a few more minutes--
- No. No.
Look, I got to go.
- You sure?
Um, why don't
you let me
call you in a mild
sedative, you know?
Something to maybe
help you sleep,
just so you have it.
- I'll be okay.
- Well, here.
Let me at least
give you my card.
My cell's on it.
Give me a call if
you feel like it.
- Really, I'm fine.
It's the world
that's messed up,
but, um...
if you want me to, okay.
- I'm here.
- Okay.
- Oh, there he is,
there he is, there he is.
Mr. Miller!
- Mr. Miller!
Mr. Miller, do you
have anything to say
to Peter Wallace's parents?
- No, no.
- Detectives have confirmed
you were the only person armed.
[indistinct yelling]
- I did what
I thought was right!
And I don't regret anything,
and I'd do it again!
Get out of my way!
- And there you have it,
Mr. Miller--
- Are you kidding me?
- Mr. Simms, I am not
condoning what he did,
but Peter Wallace
will die without a transplant.
If the liver doesn't
come from your wife,
he won't get one.
- Lucy and I met
at a Cub's game.
[laughs]
I heard this--this crazy
laughter coming from,
like, five rows
behind me and...
it just--
it just reached out
and grabbed me.
I'd look at her,
and it would just
make me happy,
and then,
this afternoon,
just watching the life get
stomped out of her...
you know,
his site has gotten more
hits in the last hour
than it's every had
before, I mean--
it's disgusting,
it's all disgusting.
So, no.
No, my wife's murderer
does not get her liver.
- I understand.
[somber music]
¶ ¶
- Can I at least talk to him?
- No, you cannot.
- There has got to be
something we can do.
- And we've done it.
Let it go, Dr. Rhodes.
[door opens]
He signed them.
- At this time,
I don't know what
the nature of those
injuries are,
but rescuers must be working
with blunt-force traumas,
fractures--
- We were right there.
- Honey,
put that away.
- Mr. Miller, you're being
lauded as a hero for--
- Your abdominal
x-rays are normal.
Ultrasound looks good too.
I'll call GI,
they'll want to schedule
an endoscopy and
probably a colonoscopy.
- Really?
- Tests are unpleasant,
but they're necessary.
I'm sorry.
- Ashley,
come on, sit up straight.
Slouching.
She's always slouching.
- Can't help it,
I'm almost a foot taller
than all my friends.
- Ashley, after you eat,
does your stomach
hurt less when you
sit with your knees
to your chest?
- A little.
- What about if you lay
on your side
and put your arms
over your head?
Will you do that for me?
- Actually...
this feels better too.
- You know what,
before I call GI,
I'd like to run
one more test--a CT,
and don't worry, it is
nothing like a colonoscopy.
[thermometer beeps]
- The boy who shot up
the movie theater, was he black?
- He didn't shoot up anything,
and no, he's white.
- Hm.
How about that.
- Biopsy's back
on Gertrude.
- Lymphoma?
- Not cancer.
Non-caseating
granulomas.
- That's good news.
You want me
to tell her?
- No.
I'm waiting for one
more test to come back,
and if the results are
what I think they are,
I'd like to deliver
the news.
- Okay.
- Hey.
I need a CT for 6.
- Noon?
- Yeah, that's fine.
- Hey, Nat.
- Yeah?
- I'm thinking,
I only live a mile from you.
When you go
into labor, call me.
I'll drive you here.
- Thanks, but...
you know it could be
three in the morning.
- Sleep's overrated.
- We're just friends.
- Mm-hmm.
"I want to take you
to the hospital."
- Liver's in.
We're up.
Abdominal wall's really swollen.
What do you think,
VAC pack closure?
Or a Wittmann Patch.
Always creative,
aren't you, Rhodes?
We'll do it my way.
Transplant surgeon's
got the easy end of this one.
I say that loud enough?
- I think they heard you.
- Good.
- Ashley's problem
is right there.
Superior mesenteric artery.
The fat pad that
supports it has shrunk,
and it's now constricting
the duodenum,
so food passing through
her stomach gets stuck
in this pressure point.
- Huh.
- You were right.
It is physical.
You still could've told me
you were gonna give her
a placebo.
- Long time since
my last GI rotation.
What are her options, anyway?
- Well, Ashley can wear
a nasal feeding tube
for the next few months.
Not the most attractive thing.
There's also a surgical option
which comes with some risks.
Knowing how the mother feels
about appearances,
I'm pretty sure I know
what the choice will be.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
- Ladies, on me.
- Reese, what do we go?
- Blunt trauma.
Open pelvic fracture.
Got a King airway and a 16-gauge
IV in the right AC.
Still got a radial pulse.
- Wait a second.
Oh, no.
- You know him?
- It's Mr. Miller,
the guy who shot the prankster.
- Go, go, go, go,
go, go, go.
On my count.
One, two, three.
- If he had a pulse,
I can't find it now.
Damn it.
- What happened?
- He stepped
right in front of a car.
[dramatic music]
¶ ¶
[heart monitor flat lining]
- Charge.
[defibrillator whirring]
Clear.
- Clear.
- Epi.
Charge.
[defibrillator whirring]
Clear.
- Clear.
- Another round of epi.
- Yes, Dr. Choi.
- We've done three.
- Charge.
[defibrillator whirring]
Clear.
[heart rate monitor
flat lining]
Any objections?
[hear rate monitor
flat lining]
- Call it, Dr. Choi.
Time of death, 22:47.
[somber music]
¶ ¶
- Mr. and Mrs. Wallace?
This is Bill Simms.
It was his wife--
- Lucy.
Her name was Lucy.
- It was Lucy's liver that
was transplanted into Peter.
- Thank you
for saving our son.
- What you've done
for our family--
- I didn't do it
for your family.
[sniffles]
I did it for mine.
Death isn't justice.
Can he hear me?
- Yes, he can.
- My wife--
my wife died because of you.
And now she keeps you alive...
And that's gonna haunt you
for the rest of your life.
- Mr. Simms, please.
- No, no, no, I can't--
Look, you
wanted a following, right?
Kids today,
everyone wants a following.
I'm gonna give you
a following every day
on every social media site
for the rest of your life.
I'm gonna be there to remind
the world of what you did!
You will never be able
to go anywhere or do anything
without people knowing
who you are!
You will never be able to hide!
- Not quite the happy ending
I was hoping for.
- Take the win,
Dr. Rhodes.
Take the win.
- Mrs. Kovach.
Hi, Mrs. Kovach.
We have some news for you.
- Oh.
Oh, where's Dr. Choi?
- He's with another patient
right now.
- Yes, your diagnosis.
- Yeah?
- Sarcoidosis.
- [gasps]
What's that?
- It's an inflammatory condition
that causes your immune system
to attack healthy tissue.
It's very treatable.
- Does Dr. Choi agree?
- Oh, absolutely.
- Oh,
then...
that's it, huh?
- Not quite.
Oh.
- Your diagnosis was intriguing.
See, sarcoids predominantly
affect a specific demographic.
You didn't seem to fit
the profile,
so I ran one more test.
- What am I looking at?
- A graph of your
genetic makeup.
You're part
African-American.
- What?
- Come on, sister,
put it here.
- Uh--
- Give it here.
We got to stick together.
[laughs]
- How'd she take the news?
- A little surprised.
- You're really getting off
on this, aren't you?
- Oh, come on.
Didn't it bother you?
The bigotry?
- What do you think?
But, you know, glass houses,
cast the first stone,
maybe it's not such
a great idea to get worked up
about other people's faults
if you happen to have
a couple of your own.
- Is this because of her diet?
- No, her growth.
No matter what you eat,
right now your weight
cannot keep up with your height.
- So she either walks around
with that tube in her nose
or she has surgery?
- Mm-hmm.
There are less risks involved
with the feeding tube.
- Honey, come on.
Can you see it?
Going to the Homecoming dance
with a tube
sticking out of your nose?
You know how kids are.
One day, standing out
will be an asset,
but not in high school.
Trust me.
- I'll take the tube.
- Honey.
- I want the tube.
- Is that all right?
- [sighs]
It's her life.
- Okay, great.
I'll send a GI resident down
to put one in.
- See you later.
- Hey, your transplant patient.
How's he doing?
- He's gonna make it.
I suppose you think he didn't
deserve to get that liver.
- Who am I to judge?
[melancholy music]
¶ ¶
- Bill Simms exiting
Chicago Med after deciding
to donate his wife, Lucy's,
liver to help save the life
of movie theater prankster
Peter Wallace.
What an amazing act
of forgiveness.
I don't know if I would've made
the same choice.
Bill Simms,
thank you for your example.
Coming up, we're gonna meet
a figure skater
from Hyde Park who may be
the USA's next great hope--
- Turn that off.
- Then we'll go behind the
scenes at the Shedd Aquarium
and meet the newest
additions to the--
- Witnesses saw Mr. Miller
place his cell phone
on the curb,
then step into
oncoming traffic.
On his phone,
a final message:
"It was an honest mistake."
A tragic to a tragic day.
- Think he killed himself
'cause he felt guilty?
Or because he was humiliated?
- I don't know.
I mean, does it really matter?
- The time we live in,
it's crazy.
- No. Look, The Crusades,
the Mongol Conquest,
World War I,
World War II, that was crazy.
We're actually living
in the most peaceful time
in human history,
but not that you'd know it.
You know, every dumb, mean,
stupid, vicious thing
gets a light shown on it.
The world would be
a much better place--
a much safer place
if people'd just shut up.
- [chuckles]
- I'm serious.
I hate these things.
Here, take it.
I'm done with it.
- Serious?
- I don't want it.
- I could use an upgrade.
[phone rings]
Ah.
- Give me that.
Hi, honey.
You're up late.
[phone ringing]
Aww.
You had a bad dream?
That sucks.
I'm so sorry.
Yeah.
Uh-huh.