You should be getting a raise.
You don't get a raise every
time you do something well.
You did something very well
and saved 1.75 million dollars.
- I'll talk to Dr. Glassman about it.
- No, you won't.
If any talking, or anything
else needs to be done,
I'm fully capable of
handling that my...
Hey! No, no, no...
- Hey! Hey, that's my car!
- You can pick it up at Tricky's Towing.
I'm picking it up right
now because this is my car,
I'm allowed to park here,
and you're a trespasser.
- Any time after 1.
- Shaun, tell him.
Mm...
This is not your spot.
Oh-ho!
Someone told a lie.
I just got a spot last week,
so it's kind of new to everyone.
So, yes, it is not my spot, but
that doesn't make it the wrong spot.
It'll be 250, cash or credit.
I'm not paying 250, I don't
have 250 to waste on th...
- If you get that raise...
- Shaun!
Would you just
stop for a minute?
- Not once I start.
- That's not a law,
that's just some bull
you bastards made up.
Three-fifty.
Hostile work environment fee.
Jeffrey Williams, 21 years old.
When he was 5, he
fell in love with baseball.
Dreamt of playing
with the Tigers.
By the time he was 8,
he was the best hitter in
Little League. Right, Jeff?
At 9, he led his team all
the way to the Divisionals.
Pura vida, Dannie.
- Retropulsion.
- What?
Her thumb moved.
- What does that mean?
- Nothing.
If it happened, it's a normal
response in dying muscles.
Or it could just be the result of
hypoxia or an electrolyte imbalance.
Or brain activity.
The E.E.G. showed no
purposeful brain activity.
Hook her back up.
Elias, over the last ten years,
Dannie's had thousands of tests.
- If there was any chance...
- Dr. Reznick, please. Now!
Ankylosing spondylitis.
Nasty little disease.
When Jeff was 10, the
inflammation was so bad,
the bones in his back
started to fuse together
into one big gnarly bone.
If you can't extend your
back, you can't use your legs.
If you can't unwind your
back, you can't use your arms.
Useless legs. Useless arms. Can't
even fit into a standard wheelchair.
I've had breakfast
in bed since I was 10.
And lunch and dinner.
Are you in a lot of pain?
Not compared to what it was.
I wish I'd met that rheumatologist
at the Baltimore Spine Clinic
seven years earlier.
They didn't offer surgery?
I've... I've been to
nine neurosurgeons
and they all said that
they couldn't fix me. So...
But thanks to Dr. Glassman, my
post-pretzel future is looking bright.
I want to move out of long-term
care, want to study engineering...
go to Europe.
Hell, go to a ballpark
and see the game.
Maybe with a girl.
I'd just love to be able
to hug somebody again.
I'm going to need two
residents to assist me with...
with the surgery.
What were you
doing ten years ago?
That's how long it's been since
the aneurysm in her brain ruptured.
And how long Elias has been
visiting, bringing her Peppermint Patties
and hoping for that special day
she opens her eyes and says,
"Hi, honey, did I sleep in?"
And I had finally gotten
him to give that up.
Give up hope?
Give up an impossible fantasy
that has paralyzed his life.
He used to have a
career, goals, a wife,
things he can have again
if we let him move on.
And by "we," I mean you.
You're going to tell him
the twitch meant nothing.
But she has elevated
levels of dopamine.
Which is a stress hormone,
likely produced by the
adrenal when it was shut down.
But it's also a
neurotransmitter in the brain
and may be associated
with increased brain activity.
We need to do a
SPECT C.T. of her brain
and full-body with radiotracers
to find the source of the dopamine.
You know about Elias, right?
The patient's husband who can't move
on and it's making everything worse?
Do you see an analogy here?
- No.
- No more tests, Shaun.
I'll ask Dr. Lim.
- I'm calling your bluff.
- I don't know how to bluff.
Your joint cuts
are nearly perfect.
"Nearly perfect" leaves him
with no feeling in his legs.
I kind of cracked
the vertebral body.
But I got the rest right.
That is perfect.
Welcome to my team.
Textbook.
You followed the video
demonstration exactly.
You didn't.
The third bone is the problem,
and you messed around
with the first one. Why?
My model was a bit more
severe than the one in the demo.
So I thought a three-column
reconstruction might be better.
Nice. Nice improv.
You're on my team.
I mapped out every screw placement,
osteotomy cut, and rod contouring.
Now, I've been... trying to
figure out why you're doing this.
I don't know. Change a
kid's life? Something like that.
I'm thinking you must be afraid.
- What?
- Come on.
You've been impulsive ever
since you recovered from cancer.
You quit surgery
to start a clinic,
married my favorite
barista after a few dates,
and I'm guessing none
of it made you happy.
I'm sorry.
We barely talk to each other
outside of the board meetings
and now all of a sudden
you can see into my soul?
I love my wife, I love my work.
Great.
And you still feel
empty, don't you?
I'm thinking you're scared
something's missing from your life,
so you keep reaching.
You take on a case no
other surgeon will touch.
As fascinating as all this is,
I don't think Jeffrey cares all that
much why we're doing the surgery.
He should.
Because your motives are affecting
your ability to properly assess
whether that surgery
is worth the risk.
Thank you for the input.
You were supposed to meet
me for lunch at 12:15. It's 12:23.
I'm not the first person
Tricky has shafted,
he's earned his name.
I'm gathering every
complaint I can find,
which I wouldn't be doing if
you'd back me up. So, no lunch.
Are you mad at me?
When you're mad at
me, you don't look at me.
Although, you are now,
so maybe you're not.
I turned to my boyfriend for
support and he hung me out to dry,
so let's just say I
am disappointed.
I told the truth.
This isn't about honesty,
this is about having my back.
We're a team now, Shaun,
working together for a common goal.
And right now, our goal
is to get my car back.
Then you need to pay $350.
I'm paying nothing. He is a pirate and
I'm going to expose him to the world.
No increased
dopamine-specific uptake.
It's not coming from the brain.
Which means it must've
come from the adrenal glands
when we shut down
their oxygen supply.
Move down to adrenals.
Impressive, to mourn
his wife for ten years.
He's not mourning her. He
can't as long as she's alive.
Dannie is stuck in limbo,
somewhere between life and death.
So is he.
If there are time limits
to being a good partner,
are there also ethical limits?
Should you support them even
if they've done something wrong?
You think maybe the
coma patient robbed a bank?
- Good alibi.
- What did Lea do?
Doesn't matter. Support her.
Whether you agree
with them or not,
the job of a good
partner is to be supportive.
As opposed to, say, resolving disputes
by running to the Chief of Surgery.
It's not coming from
the adrenals either.
There it is, but it's not
coming from an organ.
It's coming from a tumor.
Dannie has cancer.
We could say we're doing
a... kind of Humpty Dumpty,
only this time we're actually going
to put you back together again.
Don't get too excited though,
Dr. Andrews wants to
give us a little reality check.
If all goes well,
you'll have a restricted range of
motion, and be dependent on a walker.
If all doesn't go well,
there is a risk of paralysis,
and, given the potential
for massive blood loss,
there's a small chance you
might not survive the surgery.
But you have a great team
and one of the top
neurosurgeons in the world.
So, what do you say?
This is really happening.
Yes, sir. Tomorrow
morning. First thing.
I'm sorry, Dr. Glassman.
I can't... I can't do it.
She has a paraganglioma
abutting her vertebrae.
Her twitch wasn't a sign
of increased brain activity,
it was just a reaction to the
tumor irritating her nerves.
We can take her
off life support.
What about this
cancer? It's treatable?
The only treatment would be
surgery, and it's in a difficult location.
- But what happens if you don't remove it?
- It's malignant.
Dannie would die within
a couple of months.
- Then you have to operate.
- She could die in the O.R.
rather than here, with
you holding her hand.
We rechecked her
E.E.G. There's no change.
There was a change.
No... The thumb
movement was a change.
And the cancer and the
dopamine were changes.
Something else could change
and maybe that will wake her up.
Elias, her body is dying.
Only if we let it.
I gave up on her once,
I'm not doing that again.
I've got your discharge
paperwork here.
I'm sorry I wasted your time.
I thought I was ready for this
and I knew it was dangerous.
Hey, look, my
life isn't perfect...
but it's not so bad that I
want to risk throwing it away.
You ever hear of Gates Brown?
- Left field for the '68 Tigers?
- Yes.
My dad had his baseball card.
Your dad ever tell
you about his story?
First person to recognize
his talent was a prison guard.
He helped him get out of
prison a year early on parole
so he could play
professional baseball.
I think about Gates Brown a lot.
Whenever I have to
make a tough, really...
tough decision,
I think about how scared
he must have been.
About playing for the Tigers?
It's a dream come true. Real scary.
Getting out of jail early.
Facing a world he
hadn't been in in a while.
What if he didn't live
up to expectations?
What if he wasn't good
enough for the bigs?
But he kept fighting.
He kept pushing.
You wanted to have this surgery.
And you kept fighting,
and you kept pushing.
And doctor after doctor said no.
And finally you found
a doctor who said yes.
And now you stop?
That doesn't make any sense.
I don't think that you are afraid
that the surgery is going to fail.
I think you're afraid
it's going to succeed.
For the last several years, you
could have taken classes online,
worked towards your degree.
- You could have traveled...
- You don't think I've tried?
No. You tried. Okay. And you failed.
But, man, did you have a good excuse.
And now, you have the surgery,
and it's successful, but you still fail?
That's scary.
Because now, you gotta
look at yourself in the mirror.
And you have to ask...
"Was it my condition?
Or was it me?"
You know where I
celebrated my 10th birthday?
Children's Hospital.
Getting 13 steroid
shots into my spine.
By the time I was 11,
my entire social network
was R.N.s and M.D.s.
I've never had a job.
I've never danced with a girl.
I've never even
had a best friend.
I have no idea how to
live like a regular person.
So what?
So you'll suck at
it. Join the club.
Say no to the surgery if
that's the right decision.
But do yourself a favor.
Don't say no because
you're afraid to live your life.
I'm going to support you.
Thank you.
- I'm looking right at you, see?
- I noticed.
Let me have your phone.
Why?
I've created a couple
hundred Yelp accounts
to trash Tricky and maxed
out on my I.P. address,
so I need another one.
You're not allowed to do that.
He's not allowed to extort people.
So I'm just extorting him back.
Once I threaten to unleash my
arsenal, he'll hand over my car.
He might even detail it for me. I
won't have to actually post anything.
Thank you.
This last segment of tumor
is holding on to her
spinal dura for dear life.
Fine dissecting scissors.
I may be participating in fraud.
But I want to
support my partner.
If your partner wants
you to do something
that makes you feel
uncomfortable, shut it down.
Do not enable crazy.
Lea isn't crazy.
We're all crazy sometimes.
Just takes the right motivation.
There is an obvious
middle ground.
If your partner's doing something
wrong, help them see what's right.
Damn it, the capsule
ruptured and it tore the dura.
We have a C.S.F. leak.
We should try a graft.
Harvest some fascia
to reinforce the dura.
Dr. Lim...
Mm.
Tastes like my birthday.
Lab confirms the tumor wasn't
metastatic. You're cancer-free.
And brain function
is apparently fine.
All in all, it's been
a pretty good day.
Ten years.
I miss anything good?
No.
So why did I wake up?
We're running tests.
There have been cases of
anesthesia rebooting the dormant brain.
Yours was light, but
it still might have...
Let's just call it a miracle.
Last bone wedge.
Let's start
straightening him out.
You know, if you can talk
this kid into risking his life,
I'm thinking maybe you can
talk anyone out of any fear.
Been trying to talk you
out of those caps for years.
These caps save
lives. No fear in that.
I'm afraid to eat
a cheeseburger.
My mother, she was
very proud of her cooking,
and she told us we didn't need
to sacrifice taste to keep kosher.
At least not with
her in the kitchen.
And it's crazy, you know,
considering all the other ways
I've rejected her faith. But...
if I do eat one, it...
feels like I'm cutting my
last lifeline to my mother.
My mom taught me
how to play guitar.
We had our problems,
a lot of them, but...
everything seemed to be
okay when we were singing.
Since she died, I'm... I'm
afraid to even open the case.
It's the middle of your
shift. You miss me?
I had a bad morning.
My patient lived.
That is surprising.
You keep being competent,
you'll get used to it.
I need an ice cream infusion.
- The cafeteria has ice cream.
- Not Cherry Garcia.
Heard you lost out to a Firsty.
One bright spot in my day.
I did everything perfectly,
but it's still not symmetrical.
Nose job.
It's changing as you fix
it, you gotta change with it.
Andrews always said the first thing
you do with your plan is toss it out.
That's exactly why I
didn't do a plastics elective.
Or you're a blue-collar ex-cop
who's afraid to color outside the lines.
Your L3 vertebrae is perfect,
which means you're
not entirely without talent.
Look at the bones
you're not supposed to fix.
What are your instincts telling
you that this procedure manual isn't?
Huh.
Congratulations, you're
now as good as a Firsty.
I almost feel bad about
eating your ice cream.
BP's 82 over 50. Spinal shock?
SSEP and MEP waves are normal.
Check for buckling.
- No cord compression.
- Okay, pressure's still dropping.
Did we poke a hole in the canal?
Let's back out these screws.
Spine's not the problem, it's
his heart. It's in failure. Crash cart!
Sponges.
I know why Dannie woke up.
The paraganglioma
was filled with dopamine.
And leaking it in trace
amounts, that's how we found it.
But when the capsule ruptured,
the tumor released the
dopamine in very large amounts.
Her spinal tap showed over
1200 nanograms per liter...
which bathed her brain in dopamine,
which energized it and woke her up.
It was just a freak event.
A temporary freak event.
The dopamine's going to wear off
and her brain will shut down again.
Yes.
And the dose she'd need
to stay awake would be toxic.
If we don't replicate the surge,
she'll relapse into a coma.
And if we do, she'll die.
Your dopamine levels are dropping
quickly, and when they return to normal,
you'll return to your
comatose state.
- What?
- No.
She... Look at her. She's lucid.
She's talking and
laughing, she's fine.
I'm sorry.
That's it? There's no treatment,
no surgery, no medication?
- Elias, I wish we...
- No!
How long do I have?
Less than 24 hours.
But she could wake
up again, right?
I mean, you didn't
think she would this time.
You said she shouldn't have.
The series of events that coincided
to make this happen was so unlikely,
it is safe to say it will
never happen again.
- I want to see another doctor.
- Elias.
- There... There must be some way...
We have to face this.
Why? Because they say so?
Listen to me. You're right here.
Looking into my eyes
and holding my hand.
You're not going
anywhere, Dannie.
I promise.
Troponin's normal,
it's not a heart attack.
- Yeah, no signs of PE.
- No clots in the heart either.
Normal valves, no wall
motion abnormalities.
But he has S/D wave
fusion on RV inflow.
His heart's not
filling properly.
His legs are swollen.
His fluid's not returning
from his lower body.
His anatomy adapted to his
contortions. Nothing is where it started.
And now, moving to this new position
could be trapping his vena cava.
His spine and breastbone are
squeezing off blood flow to his heart.
The vein's compressed.
- Can we prop it open with a stent?
- Too much chest cavity restriction.
Jeff's body is not letting
us straighten him out.
We need to reverse the surgery.
All the king's horses...
About time Elias
took a bathroom break.
He never shuts up about you.
I know you love skiing,
both water and downhill,
and how you actually did
both the same day in Tahoe,
despite a water
temperature of 48 degrees.
I know your favorite
movie is Battlefield Earth.
So bad it's good, I get it.
And your favorite candy,
well, that, I got all on my own.
I also heard about the puppies.
How he couldn't decide between
the three of them and so he...
Brought them all home.
Yeah.
Are you trying to tell
me that I'm a lucky girl?
It's okay.
I know that I am.
I found my soulmate.
Do people still use
that lame word? Heh.
He's a wonderful man...
who has trouble
making tough decisions.
And he's going to
spend the rest of his life
sitting at your bedside listening
to a ventilator keeping you alive.
Which puts it all on you.
Screw's stuck.
I'll try a lamina spreader.
If we do a bone graft here,
we can re-fuse the T3
vertebrae to the way it was before.
It'll never be the
way it was before.
We cracked his spine
at 15 different levels.
He will be more contorted,
he'll be more in pain.
T-handle.
Pectus excavatum.
If you never heard of it,
don't feel bad, it's very rare.
A person is born with a big
dent in the middle of his chest.
Sometimes it's so bad that the
breast bone presses against the heart,
you gotta break away the sternum,
you gotta crack open the ribs,
prop it up with metal bars.
If you can do that for Jeff...
then we can create
enough space in his chest.
Close him up, let's
turn him around.
It's a DNR.
I don't want to be put
back on life support.
That's not life.
You gave her this?
But I...
signed it.
You remember...
our first Valentine's
Day together?
You gave me that...
that silver pendant
with the two little hearts?
I told you I was considering
that job in Boston.
And you let me go.
- You didn't need my permission...
- I know.
I know.
But you knew that it was
something that I needed to do.
And you also knew...
that I was scared.
Dannie, this isn't Boston.
I can't...
I can't let you go.
I know.
I think that's why I woke up.
Uh-huh.
- Hey.
Something that I've
always felt guilty about...
Costa Rica.
That was your... dream trip.
Your mother was sick.
Mm. Not very.
But you never complained.
You canceled everything.
Did you ever go?
How could I go without you?
Because you have to.
For both of us.
Let me have that thought.
Pura vida.
Dannie?
Want to try and stand up?
You got this.
No, no, no. Okay, I'm
afraid I'm gonna fall.
That's why you gotta try.
There you go.
Dr. Glassman...
It's after 6.
- You're open 24 hours.
- Not saying I'm closed,
saying it's after regular business
hours. There's a $50 fee for that.
I've created 336 of the
most scathing critiques
of you and your
sleazy operation.
So give me my car back or I'll
post them and shut your ass down.
I'm not buying it, cupcake.
You're no outlaw. And
I'm going to have to add
a $200 "unfair
business practice" fee.
I push this button, and you can
kiss Tricky's Towing goodbye.
Cash or credit?
This time, I'm not
lying. Shaun, tell him.
Cash.
This way.
I don't...
- Shaun!
- Drive away! Drive away!
Get back here!
Okay. Drive fast!
Oh, my God, Shaun!
Kick its butt.
So?
It's...
really...
really good.
That was tight, everyone
give it up for Travers!
Next up is... Claire.
Hey. You got this.
Okay.
Um... This is a song
my... My mother taught me.
So if you don't like
it, shame on you.
♪ You can hold my hand ♪
♪ If you need to let go ♪
♪ I can be your mountain ♪
♪ Though you're
feeling valley-low ♪
♪ I want a house ♪
♪ With a crowded table ♪
♪ And a place by
the fire for everyone ♪
♪ Let us take on the world ♪
♪ Like we're young and able ♪
♪ So bring us all together ♪
♪ When the day is done ♪
I got Jeff's post-op images.
Everything looks great.
Yeah.
What you did was phenomenal.
It's gotta feel pretty good.
Feels great.
Three patients I turned down.
This world needs more
people screwed up just enough
to think they can
do the impossible.
You owe me seven bucks.
- This costs six.
- Delivery charge.
I just increased
your rent by 20.
His face was awesome.
Mostly blind rage, with a
sprinkle of bewilderment.
And how about you leaping
into the car like the man of steel?
I hurt my knee.
Making what you did
even more spectacular.
I can't believe
you stiffed the guy.
I didn't.
I paid him $250, which
is what he was entitled to,
leaving him with no
reason to retaliate.
That is fair.
Lea...
you have been a bit...
crazy...
the last two days,
and I needed to help
you see what was right.
I have been a bit crazy.
But it wasn't really
about the car.
Two days ago, I found out...
Shaun...
I'm pregnant.
♪ While we're young and able ♪
♪ So bring us all together
When the day is done ♪