Hey, Dean.
How you doing?
I've had worse.
Hey, Maggie.
I just found
my old varsity jacket.
Of course, you always
wore it more than me.
This is my husband, Ben.
Hey.
I do seem to remember you
telling me
that you weren't
gonna have anything
to do with him.
What is going on here?
You're dressed like
one of my engineers.
Believe it or not,
we're out of scrubs.
So this is all your doing.
Just trying to help.
It's nice to have
a guardian angel.
You're here early.
Alarm mishap.
I'm gonna try to
grab some shut-eye
before my shift starts.
Got an empty bed?
Two's open.
I should warn you, though.
Drunk teenager vomited
all over that room last night.
But it's been cleaned.
Yeah.
Then I won't be surprised
by a pungent whiff.
Thanks for the heads-up.
Dr. Halstead, Maggie,
meet our newest member
of Emergency Medicine.
Justin Lieu.
Hello.
Hi. A new attending.
Terrific. Welcome.
Actually, Dr. Lieu
is a first-year resident.
Ah! My mistake.
Listen, I'd like him
to join your service today.
Sure.
I'll let you get settled.
Thanks, Ms. Goodwin.
Wondering why I'm so
late to the party?
I know I've got some years
on the typical first-year.
I spent a decade doing search
and rescue
before deciding
on med school.
Very cool.
Is this guy
bothering you?
What are you doing here?
I just remembered
it was your first day,
and I was, you know,
I was in the neighborhood.
What's up, Gallo?
Clearly, you two
know each other.
We have ambo coming in.
Dr. Halstead,
you're going to five.
Ready to get
your hands dirty?
Yeah. Catch you later?
Yeah, go.
Go on. Be useful.
Courtney, going to five.
What do we got?
Lydia Shaw.
15-year-old female.
Disoriented and confused.
GCS 13, BP 90/56.
Sinus tach in the 110s.
Afebrile.
Wait. Where am I?
She woke up this morning,
she couldn't tell me her name,
what day of the week
it was. Nothing.
Are you Lydia's mom?
Yes.
Danielle.
On my count.
One, two, three.
She's been complaining
of exhaustion and nausea
for weeks.
Okay, we got her.
Lydia, you're at the hospital.
I'm gonna listen
to your lungs.
Okay.
Lungs are clear bilaterally.
Danielle, does Lydia
have any conditions
we should know about?
Any medications she's on?
None.
She's never even
had the flu.
Dr. Halstead?
Okay, pitting edema
to the lower extremities.
What's that?
Just means
there's some swelling.
Stop it!
Why are you doing that?
I'm sorry, Lydia.
I'm just checking your eyes.
Almost done.
Sclera is jaundiced.
Dr. Lieu, how does
the liver feel?
Liver edge extends
past the costal margin.
I know.
All right. All done.
Let's get a CBC, CMP, coags,
LFT, chest X-ray,
ammonia level, UA,
and a right
upper quadrant ultrasound.
Okay, we'll be back
the minute we have an update.
What are you thinking?
Hepatic encephalopathy.
What, didn't
expect the intern
to know the answer?
I was second oldest
in my med school class.
It might have given me
a bit of a complex.
Yeah, well, I think
you're absolutely right.
All clinical signs point
to advanced liver disease
as the cause
of her altered
mental state.
But what would cause
an otherwise healthy
15-year-old's liver to fail?
Grabbed this from your locker
for you. You'll never guess
what's inside.
Tampering with
someone else's mail
is a federal offense, Doris.
Just open it, Maggie.
No!
Is he there?
Are you serious?
I can't believe April
kept it from me.
Surprised?
Thrilled.
I'm so happy for you guys.
Thanks, Mags.
Come in.
Uh-oh.
See, now why does my mere
presence elicit that
response in your doctors?
Take a wild guess.
Have a seat, Dr. Marcel.
You're not in any trouble.
Oh, good.
Listen, I'm sure you know
the board wanted
to update the OR suites
this year with MRI machines.
Yeah, it'd be
a real gamechanger
to have high-resolution
imaging available
during surgery.
Unfortunately, the supply
chain crisis took precedence
over fundraising efforts.
And now we are
fast approaching
the end of the fiscal year
and still
woefully short on funds.
A big-ticket item, for sure.
So we're hoping Jack Dayton
might consider contributing
the remainder.
Roughly $10 million.
Okay.
We have invited him to dinner
at the hospital tonight,
and it'd be great if you
could join us, Dr. Marcel,
given your close
personal relationship
with the entrepreneur.
I don't know
if I'd call us close.
Not like I socialize
with the guy.
Yeah, but you'd be able to
explain to him
the benefits of the technology
from a surgical perspective.
We know it's
last minute, but...
Asking Dayton for
$10 million right after
I helped rescue him?
Kind of feels like
a quid pro quo.
Exactly.
He is indebted to you.
Well, that's not
the way I see it.
My patients
don't owe me anything.
Look, I think it's great
you're approaching Jack,
and I hope he goes for it.
I'm just...
I'm not comfortable
making the ask.
We understand, and this was
by no means mandatory.
Okay.
But if you change your mind,
dinner's at 7:30
in the executive dining room.
All right.
What?
Hey, I need a second opinion
on a patient's
renal ultrasound.
And good morning to you.
Does this look like
renal artery stenosis
to you?
Did you forget
I'm an obstetrician?
I don't normally look
at these kinds of scans.
Just tell me what you see.
Okay. Velocities are higher
than they should be, I think.
And yeah, could be stenotic,
but it's hard to say,
seeing especially since,
as we established,
I'm not a nephrologist.
Okay, thanks.
How bad would it be if I got
a candy bar for breakfast?
No worse than
the decaf frappe
with whipped cream
that I just downed.
Please, can I just speak
with a doctor?
Please, it won't take long.
I'm afraid that's not
how it works.
First fill out these forms.
And I'm gonna need your ID
and insurance card
if you have it.
Forget it.
Hey there.
Is there something
we can do for you?
How do you...
How do you know
if something happened to you?
Do you think something
might have happened to you?
Let's take a seat.
What's your name?
I don't want my name
recorded anywhere.
Like, in your system.
No, just between us.
Gloria.
Hi, Gloria.
I'm Nellie.
This is Hannah.
Just talk to us like we're
one of your girlfriends, okay?
Tell us what happened.
Last night,
I went to this party.
It was at a big warehouse
in Pilsen.
I was supposed to meet
my cousin there,
but I couldn't find her.
There were just
so many people.
And then?
I don't remember.
I had a drink,
just one drink,
and that's the last
thing I remember.
When I woke up this morning,
I was still there,
at the warehouse,
in this room
I didn't recognize.
Was there anyone
there with you?
But my underwear was gone.
I don't know what happened.
We're gonna figure this
out together.
Come with us, okay?
So Lydia has
an autoimmune disease called
primary biliary cholangitis.
The disease, it destroys
the bile ducts and can
lead to liver failure,
which unfortunately is what
we're seeing in Lydia's case.
She's 15!
She doesn't even drive yet!
It is rare to see PBC
in adolescents,
although there have
been reported cases
of pediatric onset.
If her liver is the problem,
why is her brain
being affected?
When the liver
isn't functioning
how it's supposed to,
it stops filtering toxins
from the bloodstream.
And then these toxins
build up and travel
to the brain.
But the condition
is only temporary.
And with medication,
her cognitive function
will return to normal.
What about her liver?
Lydia is going to need
a liver transplant.
So how do we do that?
How do we find her
a new liver?
We'll get Lydia evaluated
for the transplant list,
the national registry,
but her fastest bet
would be a living donor.
What's pretty cool about
the liver is it regenerates.
So you can give someone
a portion of your liver,
and it grows back
to its original size
after the transplant.
I would give her mine
in a heartbeat,
but I'm a recovering
alcoholic.
As long as you've been sober
for six months,
that's not an exclusionary
criterion, okay?
We will want to run some tests
to check your liver function.
Of course.
Whatever you need to do.
I would give anything
to help my daughter.
Maggie.
This better be good.
Showing up at my job
unannounced is quite
the overstep.
Didn't you get my text?
No, my phone's been on the
charger all morning.
What is it?
I got to show you
something outside.
I can't, Grant.
I'm working.
Just five minutes.
That's all I'm asking.
I don't want to be a bother,
but you're the only person
who will understand.
Give me 20 minutes.
I'll take my lunch
break early.
Meet you out front.
Okay.
Congrats on
your big news, buddy.
Mazel tov.
Thank you.
I'm pretty excited.
Could have given me
a little more time to dust off
the old tux, though.
Damn.
Sorry about that.
You know, my dad's passing
crystallized a lot for me
about the man I want to be,
the life I want to have,
and an urgency
to get those changes now.
Makes sense.
It's probably why things
are so easy with April
this time around.
I guess I got
closer to the guy
she was holding out for.
Nice.
Hey, I need some help.
I got a guy in trouble
a few blocks away.
Hey, I'm Dr. Choi.
What's going on?
There's this
homeless guy, Buddy.
He kind of lives
behind my apartment building.
Something's wrong with him.
I called 911.
But they said the ambulance
is gonna take,
like, 20 minutes.
I don't know.
He doesn't look so good.
Can you take us to him?
Yeah, follow me.
Buddy!
Buddy. Hey, Buddy.
He's breathing, right?
Respirations are shallow,
but yeah, he's breathing.
How long has
he been here for?
Buddy's been a fixture
since I moved in,
so at least four years.
You notice any changes
in his behavior recently?
Buddy disappeared
for a couple nights,
maybe about a month ago.
I don't know where he went,
but when he came back,
he wasn't moving
around as well.
He just seemed
more out of it
than usual.
My name won't be on the...
It won't be attached
to anything?
It can all be
processed anonymously.
And you won't release
any of my information
to the police, right?
Mmm-mmm.
Not without your permission.
I forgot to ask.
How much is it gonna cost?
I don't have insurance or
anything, so...
Nothing. There's no patient
responsibility.
And we'll give you
a voucher for any
additional follow-up costs.
Would you like a Valium?
It can help calm your nerves.
No, no, no, I don't want
to black out again.
It's actually just
a mild sedative.
No!
Thanks, but no.
Okay.
We're ready to begin the exam.
Okay, Gloria?
Okay, so sit back a little,
put your feet in the stirrups.
And if at any point
you need me to stop,
if you need to take a break,
you just let me know, okay?
All right,
I'm putting my hand
on the inside of your thigh.
Next, I'm gonna
take a quick look at
the outside area first.
Here.
Squeeze as hard
as you need.
Okay.
Now you're gonna feel
the tip of the speculum.
You're doing really great.
So what do you think?
I know her liver's
on the cusp, but...
I've got to disagree
with you there, Will.
It's not on the cusp.
Not even close.
Well, what do you mean?
Danielle's liver function
is solid.
Yeah, now,
but the damage is done.
The liver's fibrotic.
Mildly.
It won't tolerate
a partial resection.
Well, that's a prediction,
not a fact.
A good chance
it'll fail to regenerate.
And then Mom will need
a liver transplant.
Maybe that's a risk
Danielle's willing to take.
But if Danielle ended up
needing a new liver
after we allowed
her to donate,
that's the kind of
bad outcome
that could get
a transplant program
shut down.
I'm sorry, man.
My, my, my.
My goodness.
Is that...
It is.
No!
What happened to
the peeling vinyl top that
used to flap in the wind?
Gone. That and
the cracked window.
Got the heating
and air fixed too.
Oh, my word.
You know,
I love this car.
It's the only reason I gave
you the time of day
in high school.
I've been restoring it
for years now.
You did
all this yourself?
For the most part.
Just got the leather seats
reupholstered.
The finishing touch.
Wow.
What do you say?
A spin around the block,
for old time's sake?
Oh...
Come on.
A quick spin.
My break's over in 30.
Yes, ma'am.
Do you happen to know
his full name?
Everyone just
calls him Buddy.
He's a friendly guy
but not all there.
How so?
Sometimes I'll see him
talking to no one,
and he repeats himself a lot.
It just seems like his
processing is kind of delayed.
Hey, I'm really sorry,
but I'm super late for work.
Look, we really appreciate you
hanging around while we got
him situated, okay?
Thank you very much.
So I found a partially healed
puncture site in his groin.
It looks like he developed
a postprocedural abscess.
I'm gonna drain it
and start antibiotics.
Wonder what the procedure
was for.
Or where it was done.
Hawley Community Hospital.
It's still in pretty
good shape,
so it must have been
a fairly recent visit.
Is there a name
on that bracelet?
William "Buddy" Foster.
Clip that off for me,
will you, Doris?
I'm gonna look up
that hospital
and then give them a call.
Hawley?
I mean, it kind of
rings a bell,
but I'm pretty sure
it's outside of Chicago.
I wonder how he
ended up there.
Any other family members
that might be willing
to get evaluated?
See if they're a match
for Lydia?
No, she's...
She's an only child.
Her father also had problems
with alcohol.
Smashed his car
into a tree two years ago
and died on impact.
We're so sorry.
With the transplant list,
how long do you think
Lydia will have to wait?
It is impossible to predict.
It can take just a few weeks,
or it can take months.
Years sometimes.
So just prepare myself
for anything?
Yeah. We'll check on Lydia
in a bit, okay?
Man, that's rough.
Worst feeling in the world,
I imagine.
Doing search and rescue,
you meet these parents
who are just
so desperate to help.
It's heartbreaking
telling them they can't.
Yeah, only adds salt that
Danielle's past
is what's preventing her
from donating.
Talk about a cruel twist, huh?
If it was any other organ.
I mean, her kidneys are
perfectly healthy.
Dr. Halstead?
Her kidneys are healthy.
I think you're
on to something.
You're staring.
I'm sorry.
I just never thought
you'd be riding shotgun
in this car again.
Well...
It used to give me
such a rush back in the day,
looking over and seeing
you next to me.
Still does.
Grant.
No.
Grant!
You're talking about
a paired exchange, right?
It won't work.
Both the donors need
to have healthy livers.
Well, not exactly.
It's called a trans-organ
paired exchange.
Oh, yeah.
I heard it discussed
at a conference.
Pretty new concept, right?
Only a couple have
been performed in the U.S.
It's rare, but this
kind of swap
is allowed under the
National Organ Transplant Act.
Uh-huh. Thank you.
So you're suggesting
that Danielle
donate her kidney
to someone on
the transplant list...
Someone already with
a willing donor
who was ruled out
for a kidney-specific reason.
And then they would donate
their liver to Lydia?
Like a paired exchange,
except with different organs.
Well, it's not exactly
like for like.
A liver transplant exposes
the donor to greater risk.
But if we can identify
a potential donor
recipient match,
walk them through
the added risk factors...
And we have to loop in legal.
The whole nine yards.
Of course.
I'm not trying to do anything
below board.
Okay, I think I have an idea
for a second donor.
Frank Sheraton. Late 40s.
He's in good health,
but due to a mild reduction
in GFR,
he couldn't donate his kidney
to his wife, Roberta.
She's been on
the transplant list
for three years.
Before we get
anyone's hopes up,
let's make sure Frank's
a match for Lydia,
Danielle for Roberta.
I'll pull up their charts.
Dr. Lieu, you want to
give me a hand?
Happy to.
All right.
We'll circle back in a bit.
Great.
Dr. Halstead, there you are.
What's wrong?
Maggie and a friend
were in a car accident.
The ambulance is en route.
Maggie, you should be
on a gurney.
I'm fine.
That's what I said,
but she refused.
Going to Baghdad.
Matt, talk to me.
Grant Young. 44-year-old male.
High-speed motor
vehicle crash.
GCS 15, BP 120/72.
Heart rate 110.
Large laceration on the...
To the left calf.
Active bleeding for
almost four minutes.
I initially tried
to control it
with pressure.
Hey, Grant.
I'm Dr. Halstead.
A piece of shrapnel
or something from the door
sliced the leg.
It looks arterial.
Thank you, Maggie.
I got it from here.
Come on, Maggie.
Let me look you over.
Come.
Gloria.
Hey.
You want to have a seat?
That's okay.
I prefer to stand.
Okay, sure.
So your labs came back
positive for GHB.
It's what's commonly known
as a date rape drug.
And while we can't make
any definitive conclusions
until your kit is tested,
there was evidence
that you sustained injuries
from a sexual assault.
What kind of evidence?
Bruising in your genital area,
a possible
fingerprint pattern.
What about STDs?
Your HIV, gonorrhea,
and chlamydia tests
all came back negative,
but you'll need to follow up
to do retesting in two
to three weeks.
Is it too early to know if...
If I'm pregnant?
Your pregnancy test
came back negative,
but you'll want to retest
in two weeks.
Is that it?
Is that everything?
Can I go home now?
Well, first we wanted
to talk with you
about some of the counseling
and mental health
services available.
All free of charge.
I really want to go home.
Forget it ever happened.
If you do
change your mind,
all of the information
and the phone numbers
are in here.
Both of ours included.
Thanks.
Gloria, you said initially
that you didn't want
to involve the police.
I don't.
Okay.
You do understand, though,
that without a report,
they're not able
to open an investigation,
so they're not able
to find the person
who did this to you.
It's not like I'd press
charges anyway.
I just...
I needed to know
what happened
for myself.
That's it.
That's enough.
No one else can know.
Gloria, I understand,
right now, this is
very traumatizing...
Okay, Gloria.
We hear you.
We'll get your discharge
paperwork started.
Hey. That's it?
I feel like we should
be having a more
substantial conversation
with her about reporting.
No.
Her unwillingness to show ID,
lack of insurance,
fear of the police.
I suspect that Gloria
might be undocumented.
Let's not push too hard, okay?
But I believe there are
legal protections for
undocumented immigrants
that report crimes
like sexual assault.
And while you may believe
in those protections, Hannah,
Gloria might not,
and we have to respect that.
Buddy, what we're trying
to figure out
is if you can remember going
to a hospital recently.
Yeah.
Yeah, I went
to the hospital before.
That's right.
And how'd you get there?
Real nice lady drove me.
She bought me dinner too.
Were you hurt?
No. Don't think so. No.
I wonder why she,
she took you
to the hospital, then.
Guess I needed to go.
A real nice lady.
She bought me dinner.
Okay.
Um, you know what?
We're gonna step out
for a second
and be right back.
Sure.
Yeah, all right.
Sit tight.
Sure.
All right, so I got
in touch with Hawley
Community Hospital.
It's about two hours north of
the city, in Wisconsin, right?
Buddy was there
a month ago.
Two-night stay for
a left atrial appendage
occlusion procedure.
Aren't LA occlusions done
to prevent stroke in patients
with a-fib?
Buddy hasn't flipped into
a-fib once since he got here.
It's an elective procedure
on an unhoused patient
in a different state.
How'd they expect him
to get back for his
follow-up stuff?
Or keep his
surgical site clean?
It's no wonder he ended up
with an infection.
At best, I think we're
looking at extreme negligence.
I think it's worse.
Buddy mentioned a lady
picking him up
and driving him
to the hospital.
Ugh!
A recruiter.
Probably gets a kickback
for every patient she finds.
Oh, my gosh.
I think we're looking at
Medicaid fraud.
It's not what
it looks like, Sharon.
Who said
it looked like anything?
No one's judging you.
Hey, I just wanted
to let you know
I sent Grant to angio
to see if there's
any vessel damage to his leg.
Thanks for the update, Will.
Of course.
How's your patient,
Ms. Goodwin?
Stubborn with a chance
of just fine.
Maggie, you want me
to call Ben for you?
No, no, no. That's okay.
Ben's away at a teacher's
conference in Florida.
I'll let him know
when he comes home on Friday.
Sure.
Hannah.
Hey, do you have a minute?
Yeah, of course.
What's up?
Her name is Chelsea.
She walked into the district
this morning to report
a possible rape.
A possible rape?
Blacked out at
a warehouse party last night.
She thinks someone
slipped something
in her drink.
Was it in Pilsen?
Yeah. How did you know that?
So I donate a lobe of
my liver to this young woman,
and the girl's mother
would give her kidney
to Roberta?
Exactly.
We've done the legwork,
and you're a compatible donor.
And the mother is a match
for you, Roberta.
Well then, yeah.
Absolutely. I'm in.
How soon can they operate?
Frank, hold on a second.
I think we have to ask
a few more questions.
We learned all about
kidney donation
when Frank was evaluated
to be a donor for me.
Donating the liver,
is this a similar undertaking?
Well, to be completely honest,
it's a bigger undertaking.
It's an open surgery with
a large abdominal incision.
And because of
the incision,
it is a harder recovery
than kidney donation.
Usually about twice as long.
Oh, then no.
Babe.
No.
We have to think
about the kids.
I am.
They need their mom.
We all need you.
Hey, remember,
I survived five skydives
and three bungee jumps.
You think I'm gonna let
a little surgery take me out?
Surgery is probably
the safest place for me.
And the fact that
this is gonna
help someone else out too?
Even better.
Let me do this.
Is this a yes?
Okay.
Great.
I understand that
the evidence
from Gloria's exam
would strengthen any future
case against the assailant,
but I really don't think
revisiting the topic
is going to change
her mind.
Well, I think we should try.
So you want her
to risk her future,
or her family's future,
for someone
she doesn't even know?
No, I'm not saying that.
Because that's
her dilemma, Hannah.
And you can promise her
till you're blue in the face
that the system
will protect her
and fight for her rights
just like they
fight for yours,
but I bet she's seen enough
evidence to the contrary
to know better.
I'm not suggesting that Gloria
do this for someone else.
I'm thinking of Gloria
and how it's gonna feel
to carry this trauma
for the rest of her life.
My college roommate, Annie,
was raped at a frat party.
She didn't know who did it.
Didn't report it to anyone.
And she said exactly
what Gloria said.
She just wanted to forget
it ever happened.
And so,
she put all her energy
into pretending like
it didn't matter,
like holding someone
accountable didn't matter.
And somewhere along the way,
I think she began to believe
it didn't matter.
That she didn't matter.
And she carried that feeling
as long as she could
before taking her own life.
Oh... Hannah.
I'm so sorry.
So no, I'm not,
I'm not insensitive
to the enormity
of what we are potentially
asking Gloria to do.
It's just I have seen
the other side of it.
The consequence of sweeping
a trauma under the rug.
Dr. Martin Grainer,
the interventional
cardiologist who did
Buddy's procedure.
I noticed that he was moving
around a lot,
so I started calling
some of these hospitals.
Yeah?
Lost privileges
in pretty much every
single one of them.
I mean, how the hell is
this guy still practicing?
You all right?
Yeah.
I slept funny. That's all.
They didn't feel like
they could prove
that he was fabricating
indications for procedures.
Hey.
That's the doctor
who treated Buddy.
Dr. Martin Grainer.
So Buddy's labs came back,
and his PSA
was through the roof.
Sent him for imaging,
and he has advanced stage
prostate cancer.
It's all over his body,
in his brain, his spine.
Nothing we could do
for him at this point.
So while this sorry
excuse for a doctor
is making up all
these bogus
medical problems...
He could have been treating
him for something very real.
See that?
You have a small
pseudo-aneurysm
of the posterior
tibial artery.
That sounds ominous.
It's not as
scary as it sounds.
It's a small pressurized
pool of blood
that can form following
injury to the wall
of the blood vessel.
That will likely resolve
on its own
without any need
for surgical intervention.
We'll just want you back
next week for an ultrasound.
That's a relief.
Definitely.
If you'll excuse me, I have
to check on another patient.
Thanks, Will.
Well, that's good news.
Yes, it is.
Look, I've just been lying
here, doing a lot of thinking,
and I crossed the line.
Plain and simple.
I'm really sorry, Maggie.
Riding around in that
old Monte Carlo,
I think we just both
forgot ourselves for a moment.
I guess I thought maybe
we could be friends, but...
There's just too much history.
Yeah.
I know that now.
I do.
Gloria, you are so brave
to come here.
And if you need
anything at all,
you've got both
of our numbers.
And I really hope
you consider attending
one of those support groups.
Yeah, I'll think about it.
Dr. Cuevas.
Nellie, I mean.
I was hoping I'd see you
before I left.
Before you go, Gloria,
I wanted to share
something with you.
It's not something
a lot of my colleagues know.
Something Dr. Asher
doesn't know.
I'm, um...
I'm undocumented.
My family
immigrated to the U.S.
before I could walk.
And as a DACA recipient,
I'm legally allowed
to work and live here,
but I still keep
my immigration
status close to the vest.
But I'm telling you
because I trust you.
And I trust Dr. Asher.
So if you ever want
to report what happened,
now or at some point
in the future,
Dr. Asher and I know someone
who will have your back.
Someone you can trust.
Roberta, Frank,
this is Lydia
and her mom, Danielle.
I don't know
how to thank you
both enough.
I should be thanking you.
You don't even know me,
and you're giving me...
Can I hug you?
Yes.
We'll give you all some time
to get acquainted.
I hope trans-organ exchanges
become more commonplace.
It would increase
the number of potential
donors significantly.
Yeah, and would allow
donors who were
previously ruled out
to still help
their loved ones.
Quid pro quo.
Yeah, and everybody wins.
Well, hey, if you guys
aren't above
grabbing a beer
with an intern,
first round's on me.
Definitely not above
a free beer.
What do you say, Crockett?
I'm gonna have to join
you fellas another time.
Cheers.
Hey, Gloria.
This is Detective Upton.
You can call me Hailey.
We can talk here,
if you want.
We can go outside for a walk,
get some air.
Up to you.
Here is fine.
Okay.
We'll check back on you soon.
I just hope they find
who did this before any
other women are harmed.
Gloria's statement,
the evidence from her exam.
They're gonna help CPD's
investigation tremendously.
Hannah, like I said
to Gloria,
I don't advertise my status.
It's your business,
nobody else's.
I won't tell anyone.
Thank you.
It is incredible,
what you've accomplished.
Going to med school,
becoming a doctor.
It hasn't been easy.
And with legal challenges
constantly on the horizon,
DACA's future and my future
always feels a bit precarious.
But surrounding myself
with good people really helps.
People I can trust.
Oh, Maggie. Come on in.
I have to head to this dinner,
but I'm glad you stopped by.
Okay.
So how are you feeling?
I've decided to
not tell Ben
about the accident.
For the time being, or...
Ever.
Are you sure that's what
you want to do?
There's just no benefit
to him knowing.
Well, I think Ben might
beg to differ.
Grant has just caused so
many problems in my marriage.
I just... I don't want
to make it any worse.
Well, I get it,
but I'm just...
I'm just wondering
how you'd feel if
the roles were reversed
and Ben didn't tell you
that he was in a car accident.
Sharon, it's just that,
I can't.
Look.
Look, give it a little time.
You had a terrible scare
today, Maggie.
You don't have to
decide this minute.
Look, I have to go,
but you stay as long
as you need.
All right.
Hello, everyone.
Jack, great to see you again.
Glad you could join us.
Yeah.
Kathleen, Dennis.
Hey.
So what changed your mind?
Well, I...
I might have been
a little overly concerned
with the optics.
This money could benefit
a lot of people.
Good to see you guys.
How are you?
Thank you.
Well, why don't you
make your ask now?
I just think we can get
the business talk
out of the way
so we can enjoy our dinner,
which looks delicious,
by the way.
So what's the ask?
Well, our surgical center
is ranked among
the top ten in the U.S.
Thank you.
We want it in the top five.
We have the best surgeons
in the country,
Dr. Marcel among them,
and what they've been
telling us they need
is updated technology,
starting with intraoperative
MRI machines.
Being able to take imaging
in the middle of a surgery
would allow us to constantly
recalibrate our approach.
It'd be the difference
between being able
to resect 50% of a tumor
and being able to resect
the whole thing.
How much capital
are you looking for?
Ten million dollars.
But of course,
we would welcome
a donation of any amount.
No, I think you're
setting your sights too low.
I'm gonna do something
even better for Chicago Med.
Please.
What's all that?
Buddy's belongings.
The guy he came in with
dropped off a bag.
Stuff he gathered
from the spot
where Buddy camped out.
Was this him when
he was a kid?
It looks
like him, right?
Yeah.
And that apartment
building in
the photo,
that's where we
found Buddy this
morning.
He was camping out
in the alley behind it.
I'll be damned.
Figure it's where
he grew up?
Yeah.
Maybe I shouldn't have
unpacked everything.
He's only here
to make a move
into hospice.
Were you able to track
down any family?
No.
You know, I'd love
to put the blame solely
on Dr. Grainer,
but more than one bad actor
failed Buddy.
What do you mean?
He's gonna die
from one of the most
survivable cancers.
With early intervention,
this was treatable.
It shouldn't be killing him.
Our system failed Buddy,
and it fails people
just like him every day,
because the people
who need us
the most
never even make it
through our doors.
Until it's too late.
When did we
decide that's okay?
That that's just
the way it is?
It can't be.
I'm not gonna let it.