During our
ER rotation in med school,
my roommate fell in love with
emergency medicine.
Avery.
Care to tell me
why you've pulled
all of my residents
from the ER?
Yeah, I just wanted to speed up
our free COVID testing.
But, I mean, hey, if you want,
I guess we could...
We could start turning
them away.
It's a great program.
Forget I asked, okay?
She loved being
on the frontline.
She felt that's where she had
the most impact.
But I knew, three days in,
emergency medicine
was not for me.
Most treatments were meant
to just tide patients over
until they could see
their own physician,
a specialist, or a surgeon.
And how is
her base deficit?
Same as I told you
five minutes ago.
And her inflammatory
markers?
Altman, we would not be here
without your tireless effort.
But you still have
two days off.
Enjoy them,
because you're gonna miss them
when you're back.
Okay. Thanks.
Uh, one more thing...
Goodbye, Altman.
And I thought,
"What's the point
of starting something
you won't get to finish?"
...closer, I saw it didn't
have a ball in its mouth,
it had an avocado.
No idea where he got it from.
You're gonna love dogs.
Oh, you're gonna love everything
about the outside. Mm-hmm.
The trees, grass,
rainbows.
Isn't that right,
Luna?
Wait, wait, wait!
Wait, wait.
Say her name again.
Why?
Because I think
she understood it.
Her face changed.
Yeah, Luna...
Luna.
Luuuna...
Luna!
For what it's worth,
she doesn't respond
when I say her name,
either.
Yes, she does.
She's a genius.
All right if I complete
my rounds now?
Or is she such a genius that
she can look after herself?
No. Go ahead.
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Wilson, Chief,
while I think these visits
do Luna the world of good,
I have about 15 other patients
and their very worried parents
waiting for me,
so if you don't mind...
Nyah nyah nyah
nyah nyah. Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
♪ Used to have a lover
that was mine, all mine ♪
No. Go back
where you came from.
I already have all the clothes
in the house.
Ellis thought her laundry went
under her bed,
not in the hamper.
He just ate.
Well, I ate a lot
when I was a kid.
Still do.
Okay.
Baby or laundry?
Neither.
I... I just want
everything to stop.
The whole planet,
it can just stop turning,
and we can all
just melt.
Is it for us?
Is what for us,
buddy?
The camping truck,
the camping truck!
♪ Over you ♪
♪ Darling, over you ♪
Dad?
Hey, kiddos!
Surprise!
Huh?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
COVID! And stranger.
Aw, we've talked on the computer
screen lots of times.
We're old friends.
Where are your masks?!
Where's my grandson?
That's what I want to know.
Oh, don't worry, honey,
we have been totally safe.
Two-week quarantine
from Colorado
while we took in
the scenery.
Dad packed for everything.
We didn't even have to shop.
Haven't spoken face-to-face
with another soul
since we left.
Mm. So romantic.
I guess I'll...
go get Scout?
Okay. Alright, I'll
do you one better.
We thought we could take
all the kids
to check out
Mt. Rainier.
Fun!
Can we go, please?
Uh, I'm sorry.
You're say... you want to take
everyone from here?
Those first few months
with a newborn...
Impossible without help.
Only if it's okay.
Okay.
Yes!
Yay! Come on!
Have I told you two
how much I love you?
Because I definitely
love you.
And we love you, too, hon.
We couldn't have asked for
a better daughter-in-law.
She is the mother
of my grandson,
and even if you haven't
gotten around to proposing,
I am gonna call her
what I want to call her.
I don't get why they're not
married, either.
Okay. Time to
hit the road. Zola.
I'll go get Scout.
I can't wait
to meet my grandson!
That's it?
I can go again if
you want.
You'll get a text in 30 minutes
with the results.
Thank you.
All right.
I've almost used all my kits.
I'm so sorry.
It's just that the... the...
The turnout's so high.
Relax, Schmitt.
We have more in the van.
If we run low,
we can go over
to the drive-through site
at Station 19.
They've got extras.
Oh.
Wow. That's amazing.
How did we get
more kits?
20 hours of virtual meetings
with the Fox Foundation,
convincing them it's the right
thing to do... that's how.
You don't just ask your mom?
Ready for you, sir.
Thank you. Why don't you
go ahead and have a seat?
How you doing?
Good.
One of our cashiers tested
positive at the store.
I feel fine, but, you know,
I figured I should make sure.
Good. Smart.
Okay.
Can you take your mask down
a little bit for me?
All right, one more.
Great. All set.
Yeah.
How many days
till I know?
Uh, well,
it's a rapid test,
so about 30 minutes
for your results.
Oh, wow. I won't be late
for my shift, then.
Thank you so much.
You're very welcome.
Thank you.
I wouldn't be the surgeon I am
without you, Meredith.
You taught me to push myself,
to innovate,
to see what's possible,
and to trust my instinct.
And right now, that's telling me
to change to OB.
Go with God?
Meredith wouldn't say that.
I have literally never known
what Dr. Grey is gonna say.
Ooh! Why don't you be me
and I be her?
Oh, how about
you be you and her
so that I can get back
to the testing tent?
She's my mentor!
I don't want to disappoint her
or Bailey or Dr. Webber.
This is stressful.
Well, so is
pissing off Dr. Avery.
Oh, crap... trauma.
I gotta go.
I had to go first!
Dr. Goldberg
to the ICU. Dr. Goldberg to the ICU.
Arthur Beaton,
14 months...
Hold up, Khan.
Chris, did you want
to wait for Hollie?
Or I can set you up with
a video-chat on a tablet?
No. Thank you.
It's... not a good time.
She has work, so...
go ahead.
Arthur Beaton,
14 months,
diagnosed with
multiple VSDs,
cardiomyopathy,
and heart failure.
He's currently on
day 12 of ECMO,
waiting for a transplant,
status 1A.
We thought this would only be
for a few days.
Do a lot of kids with his
condition stay on it this long?
It's unusual.
It means he's strong.
He's already held his own
through several procedures.
None of which have fixed
the holes in his heart.
We're hoping he can hang on
a little bit longer,
until a donor heart
comes through.
I'll be back to you
in a couple of hours, okay?
Chief.
Welcome back.
Mm.
So, uh, this is the car
that got stuck in a truck?
Yep, ran right up
the loading ramp.
They had to cut open
the side of the van. Mm.
Newlyweds, I heard.
Hell of a honeymoon.
Huh.
Shayne Riley, 45.
Unstable pelvis
and lower abdominal pains
after sustaining crush injuries
in an MVC.
Initially unresponsive,
but now alert and orientated
after saline boluses.
Shayne, you are
in good hands now,
and I'm not
just saying that
because Dr. Bailey here
is my wife.
But you are looking
really good, Chief.
All right, this is
Karissa Skolaski, 42.
Vital signs stable,
A and O times three.
Minor lacerations to the face,
arms, and legs.
Patient complains
of headache.
Let's take her
to trauma one.
Shayne?!
W-Where's my husband?!
He's right over there, ma'am.
He's being taken care of.
Oh, Shayne,
I'm sorry, babe!
I didn't mean it!
Wait,
can he hear me?
Uh, he's heavily
sedated, ma'am.
I can hear her just fine.
I'm just not talking to her.
Ever again.
Improving ground glass
opacities,
no pleural effusion
or pneumothorax,
and no signs of stroke
on head CT.
This is great news.
It's not great news?
Great news doesn't matter
if she's too weak
to stay awake.
Captioning provided by
ABC Studios and ABC, Inc.
And brought to you by: Ford,
Built Ford Proud
Karissa, you can't get up. We're
waiting on neuro to see you.
Okay? Just squeeze.
I'm fine, I'm fine.
But my boyfriend...
Husband...
Uh, he...
He hates needles.
He really hates needles.
He's being worked on
by excellent doctors.
Can you follow my finger?
But can't you put us
in the same room?
I really need
to talk to him.
When we were
in the accident,
I kinda said a thing,
and I feel terrible.
Well, you're in luck. They pay
me to help people who feel terrible.
Any loss of consciousness?
Dizziness?
I don't think so.
So, what?
You cheated on him?
You stole all his money?
You ran over grandma?
Okay, CT's calling for her.
Do you want to come?
Please and thank you.
Squeeze my hands, please.
I told the paramedics
to save me first.
Over him, my husband.
Yikes. Well, maybe you can
blame that on a brain bleed.
Can you please tell him
I'm okay?
Yeah.
Let's go.
You know
what else she said?
That except for her, no one
would miss me if I died.
She thinks I'm a loner
and no one cares about me.
A lot of people panic
on their wedding day.
I know I did.
Dr. Hunt knows that...
Does this hurt?
Ow! Yeah.
Don't people normally panic
before saying "I do"?
We'd already been married
four hours.
I'm not sure,
but your scan does show
that you have an open-book
pelvic fracture.
We're gonna have to do a CT
to make sure
there's no other
abdominal injuries,
but you will need a
surgery, okay?
Shayne, we're taking
Karissa to CT,
but she is stable
and she's feeling okay.
Let me guess...
She asked to go first.
No, she's very worried
about you.
Good.
Don't tell her how I am.
She doesn't get to know
anything.
Let's go.
I'm just gonna
not tell her anything?
She's terrified.
You know the rules.
It's not just me, right?
This is weird.
Super weird.
It's like we won
the lottery of silence.
Where do we even start?
By getting naked?
Okay.
Loving that.
Whoa, Amelia.
I don't think
you're grasping
the extent
of our freedom here.
There are no
baby monitors.
homework assignments,
no one's...
No one's hungry.
I'm a little hungry.
Then let's have sex
in the kitchen.
We can do whatever we want.
You realize that?
We can...
We can be loud.
Oh, do you remember
being able to be loud?
What's wrong?
Okay.
All right. Amelia...
look at me.
Oh, my, God. No, no!
No?
Get up, get up!
I-I-I thought you were crying
because my mom and Zola...
No, I'm not!
I'm... I'm not, just...
I just really need
to be crying right now!
Okay.
Marcel tested positive.
He needs to be home,
isolating.
I told him that, but apparently,
he lives with his family...
Six people in
a two-bedroom apartment,
including his grandpa.
He doesn't want
to get them sick.
Can't we just admit him?
Get him some care
and a place...
This is not a hotel,
Schmitt.
He can't afford to stay
anywhere else.
Okay.
Book him a hotel room.
On you?
Are you sure?
It's a matter
of public health, okay?
Anybody needs a room...
just book them a hotel.
No questions.
We got you a hotel.
Dr. Feldman
to the Step Down Unit.
Chris?
I had to
get out of there for a minute.
I understand.
You want to get outside,
get some fresh air?
Or there's a chapel.
So I can pray for
someone else's kid to die?
I lied earlier.
Hollie wasn't
on a work call.
She hasn't signed on to work
in weeks.
I don't know if
it's postpartum depression
or Arthur or the world...
Listen, it's...
It's been a terrible ordeal
for the pair of you.
She's so depressed,
she can't get out of bed.
When COVID hit,
seeing people lose
whole families in a week...
we knew
we had to be careful
'cause of Arthur's
heart condition.
And we were.
And in the end,
it didn't matter.
I'm still losing them.
The only thing keeping me going
right now
is the hope for a miracle.
Arthur gets a heart,
Hollie
comes back to life...
and we a family again.
And I know we can't have
our miracle
unless someone else
loses theirs.
Lives what I'm living
right now.
Gets shattered.
And I pray for it anyway.
'Cause Arthur...
He's your son.
I can't lose him,
Dr. Hayes.
We can't lose him.
Please.
How's she looking?
Squirmy.
Karissa...
Did I hear Dr. Wilson?
Is Shayne okay?
Uh...
Sorry, Karissa.
Um, patient confidentiality.
Confidentiality?
From his wife?
Wait.
Did he ask you
not to tell me?
That is also
confidential.
He's still mad.
My sisters said we were crazy
for moving so quickly.
They said three months is not
enough time to get to know
someone you're gonna spend
the rest of your life with.
Well, neither is six
years.
Scans are up.
Karissa, you have a very small
contusion on your brain.
It's benign
with a very minor bleed,
so minor I don't think we can
blame it for anything.
Sorry.
But we do have to keep you
overnight for observation.
I was wrong.
I was wrong that
no one would miss him.
Because
it's only been a few hours,
and I miss him so much
I could burst.
Hi.
Got your page.
What's up?
Can you think of
a salvage procedure we can do
on a 14-month-old
with multiple VSDs?
Another one?
We just did one
two weeks ago.
It's the same boy.
Arthur Beaton.
The one
we put on ECMO?
He's hanging on.
What about
a double pump EXCOR?
You know,
an artificial heart
that can take over
for the ventricles...
No, I know what it is.
Uh...
Arthur's chest cavity
is too small.
The cannulas would push up
against his vital organs.
We'd have to
leave him open
and leave him
on a vent.
He's been on ECMO
for 12 days.
I don't think
he has the strength
to withstand
a transplant,
and that's even if
we could find a donor.
So, then,
what do you suggest?
I think you should have
a very difficult conversation
with his parents.
It's time.
Aren't you supposed to be some
sort of genius or something?
Youngest cardio chief
in the country?
More innovative and published
than any of her peers?
So what?
You're just gonna give up?
We have been at this
for months.
We have done everything
we can for that boy.
At this point,
we're just prolonging his pain,
and his family's.
It's not giving up.
It's letting them go on.
I think it just hit me
that it's been months
since I've been able to feel
whatever I want
without worrying that I will
permanently scar a child.
I mean,
the constant pressure
of not ruining a life
is exhausting.
Are you mad
that I shouted no
and made you get up?
No, I'm not mad at you.
I'm mad at my mom
for bringing it up.
Are you... wanting
to get married?
After you shouted no
and made me get up?
No, not so much.
I meant, "No,
you're misreading the moment,"
not, "No, I don't want
to marry you."
So you do want
to marry me?
I wasn't saying
I want to marry you, or...
Or I don't want
to marry you.
I, um... haven't
thought about it.
I haven't had time.
Yeah.
I haven't had time
either,
but I've still
thought about it.
What have you thought?
I love you,
and I love Scout,
and I love us
together, and...
you know, marriage
is, uh, I guess
kinda how society
locks it all in...
Eh, but it doesn't
lock it in.
It doesn't lock it in!
Mnh.
And your parents' divorce
was hell.
It was hell!
And I-I swore that I'd never
put a kid through that.
Mm-hmm.
So...
I know that your mom
has big ideas,
and Zola has big
wedding-dress dreams,
but, um...
have you really
changed your mind?
I was a terrible wife.
You had a brain tumor.
I did.
But I'm not sure that
the sexy brain tumor
can take all the credit.
I still think I'm wired
for self-destruction.
Why do you think that?
Because, every day,
for a lot of days now,
I go to sleep thinking about
getting high,
and I wake up thinking about
and sometimes, in the middle
of feeding Scout,
I zone out...
and think about
getting high.
...and he won't let me
tell his wife anything.
It's their wedding day,
and he's already over her,
which is just...
It's just sad and messy and...
And it's not that
I am sick of adults.
Okay, I'm a little...
I'm a little sick of adults.
Adults are always here
on the worst day of their lives,
and I am so sick
of worst days.
And people being terrified of me
because I'm cutting them open.
But with moms,
they want you here,
even though it's scary
sometimes,
because you being there
means that they're getting
to meet their baby,
their dream,
and they can't do it
without my help.
And since, uh...
Since Alex left, um...
my house hasn't been
my happiest place.
So...
I want work to be.
And I think
that you get that.
And I am so grateful to you,
because you believed in me
before I believed in myself.
And I will tell you
all of this again
when you're awake.
Please, please be awake soon.
Please be well soon.
We can't take any more
worst days around here.
I've booked
18 hotel rooms.
The manager wondered if
you'd rather book a whole floor.
Well, we got
a lot of positives.
Tell him we'll take all the
rooms we can get. Thank you.
I think I've memorized
your credit-card number.
When did hotel stays become
part of the plan?
Well, people need
more than a test,
and quarantining isn't easy
for everybody.
And you realized that today?
Excuse me? You know
he's your boss, right?
I'm sorry. And,
technically, so am I.
I'm sorry. Schmitt,
give us a minute.
Well, don't fire her.
Schmitt!
Come here, please.
I assume that wasn't
your real question.
So would you like to tell me
what is going on?
You're booking up
hotel rooms.
So is Seattle Partners.
Okay.
I've heard of them.
A group of, uh,
community organizations, right?
Longstanding
community organizations
that have been providing housing
and wrap-around services
for people who test positive
for COVID
in low-income
neighborhoods.
Okay. So, the more the better,
so what's the...
Yeah, maybe in theory, but they
can't book their hotel rooms
at their discounted rates
because a local doctor
is booking them at full price!
And hotels are
kicking people out
to make room
for your new arrivals.
I got it.
I apologize.
I didn't... I didn't know that.
Great.
We'll just tell everyone
it wasn't on purpose.
That should keep them
real warm tonight.
Oh, I fell asleep?
I think
it's a defense mechanism.
Noticed you do that.
Do what?
Fall asleep when you are
emotionally overwhelmed.
Some people cry.
Some people talk.
Some people yell.
You... fall asleep.
All right, well, I'm not
avoiding my feelings,
if that's what
you're implying.
I just...
I-I process them better
while I'm unconscious.
Mm.
Okay.
Let's figure this out.
There's not much
to figure out.
I'm an addict.
You're an addict
in recovery.
So, what?
You need to hit up a meeting?
I've talked about it
in meetings.
A lot of us have.
This pandemic feels like
Satan has designed
the perfect set
of circumstances
to make sobriety seem
impossible.
Isolation, fear,
futility,
anger, hopelessness.
I mean, name a trigger,
it is stronger.
For the record,
I don't believe in Satan.
I'm just saying
it feels like that.
Also, what's weird is
I'm not even craving pills.
I'm just...
I just want to, like,
drive to a dispensary
and buy some weed
and smoke it.
Well, is that allowed?
To, um... To smoke weed
if that wasn't the thing
that you were addicted to?
Well, there's no such thing as
"allowed" in my program.
There are just
suggestions.
And, no,
it is not suggested.
Why not?
Because...
if I smoked weed,
it is very likely that I would
forget to not do heroin.
Well...
for the record...
I would marry you
in a hot minute.
Why?
Because most drug addicts
who crave drugs
just do drugs.
But you don't.
That makes you stronger
than most people.
And cooler.
And the opposite
of self-destructive.
So...
All right, Amelia...
Oh, my God. No, no.
Oh, my God!
Get up!
Got it.
Like, not ever
or not today?
Just...
Not when I'm confessing
my darkest secrets
and I have snot
rolling down my face.
Okay.
Is Luna okay?
Yeah, she's fine.
I just needed to see a
friendly face.
I'm about to ask a father
about taking his baby
off life support.
Oh, my God.
She's the best.
Doesn't judge.
Isn't selfish.
Isn't bitter or resentful about
the cards she's been dealt.
Oh, I hope she doesn't.
Become bitter or resentful.
I mean, I wouldn't blame her
if she did.
I spent a lot of my life
being angry
about the way that
I came into the world.
Took me a long time
to realize
that that anger
didn't serve me.
And the more I let it go,
the better off I'd be.
Letting it go was like...
breaking off the crusty
black pieces of my heart.
It hurt at first,
but with time, it just...
Oh, wow.
Wilson...
What?
Thank you!
The Cooper ligament is
completely destroyed.
Yeah, I think Stoppa
technique's our best bet. Agreed.
Uh, pick-ups?
What a wedding day.
Started with his bride
calling him a loser.
Can't imagine much worse.
Not... that I...
How are the kids?
If you ask me, he's lucky.
How so?
Well, he found out the truth
on day one
instead of
20 years from now.
No house, no kids.
Lucky.
Mayo scissors, please.
And how is Altman?
She'll be back
in a couple days.
That's not why I'm asking.
Respectfully, Chief,
the OR has heard enough
about my personal life, okay?
Mesh.
Thank you.
Hayes, you paged again?
You said there's
not enough space
for a total
artificial heart.
You paged me 911 after
I told you it was impossible?
His chest cavity
is too small. I know.
Too small because his heart's
taking up space.
But what if
we made space?
Sure, let's just
take out his heart.
Don't be ridiculous.
We'll leave
some of it behind.
You want to cut out
part of his heart?
The lower part,
the ventricles,
which are not functioning
properly.
So the answer is yes...
You want to cut out
part of his heart.
To create space for
a total artificial heart pump
to act in place of
what we removed.
Have you done this
before?
'Cause it sounds like
you haven't done it before.
We have used the device
on older children.
But in those cases,
we did not have to remove
both ventricles.
So you could do this
and it doesn't... work?
Why would you even
suggest...
'Cause Arthur's chances of
survival are exactly the same
as if we did
absolutely nothing.
I know this sounds insane.
But we are running out
of options,
and Arthur is almost
out of time.
You asked me
to save your son, yes?
I am telling you,
this is his best chance.
I need to call Hollie.
She'll want to see him
before...
Just in case.
Of course.
Your surgery went better
than we could have hoped.
Yep.
You may have
a couple months' rehab,
but everything looks good.
Months of rehab,
alone in an apartment
during a pandemic.
Oh, so that's it?
It's been, what, 12 hours,
and you're jumping ship?
Bailey, maybe we should
just let them...
Shayne, my parents were together
for over 60 years.
Look,
after my mom passed,
my dad and I were going through
their old photos,
I-looking for something
that we could post
with her obituary.
60 years...
is a lot of hairstyles
and fashion trends.
Anna mdad told me
that I should just pick,
because when
he looked at them,
all he saw was the woman
he fell in love with.
She was still
the same caring, nurturing,
kind-hearted person
she was the day they met.
Look, people are
who they are.
Karissa said some things
while you were trapped in a car
and she was terrified.
My guess is...
she's still the same person
she was when you met.
You might want to give her
a chance to prove that
before you just
throw it all away.
Is there any way
I can see her?
I'll get you a tablet.
I just got off
with Kelly Bernard,
who runs Seattle Partners.
No one is losing their bed,
nobody's losing a room.
She's gonna point me
in the direction of hotels
so I can sponsor
patient rooms
without getting
in anybody's way.
Oh, come on.
Do you have a problem with
all your attendings or just me?
'Cause I'm trying
to make this right.
I know you are.
It's just, this whole situation
pisses me off.
And, what, that's my fault? No.
No.
It's the whole system.
It's not designed to help the
people that actually need it.
Especially when
they look like us.
Right.
That's why I'm trying to help.
When I was a social worker,
I saw a lot of temporary fixes
that came
from a good place.
But they never get to the root
of the problems.
Hotel rooms are great
for quarantine.
But then people
have to go back
to risky jobs
and overcrowded homes.
I know
you're trying to help.
It's just that all this
is just...
Is... is too much.
And I'm just really over it,
you know?
Just over it.
♪ In my younger days,
I was a fighter ♪
I want to teach you to swim.
♪ In my younger days,
I felt the fire ♪
I want to take you
to hockey games.
♪ Things didn't go my way ♪
♪ I'd strike a match,
turn my back ♪
But if we don't...
get to do those things...
I want you to know
how much I love you.
How much your mom and I
love you.
♪ In my younger days,
I'd love 'em and leave 'em ♪
You've already given us
a lifetime of joy.
I'm so sorry, Chris,
but we really need to go.
♪ I'd trade my freedom
for a steady hand now ♪
♪ But I wouldn't trade
the lessons I learned ♪
♪ No, I wouldn't
change a thing ♪
♪ About my younger days ♪
What would our wedding
even look like?
Mm, rooftop,
French Quarter, New Orleans,
April or early May.
♪ Looking back,
I'm glad to see ♪
For someone who doesn't
want to get married,
you answered that
really fast.
It's a magical place.
Just don't go in June.
It's hot and smells bad
by then.
Mmmm. Magic.
It'd be fun.
The kids would love it.
And, Link,
I love you so much,
sometimes I feel like I'm gonna
have a panic attack.
So marriage seems
so obvious.
But...
But you're not sure.
And you're not sure.
♪ Taking life as it comes
ain't working out too bad ♪
I need you to not get high.
I mean it.
I need you to do whatever
you need to do to stay sober.
Because I'm not...
I'm not Owen.
I'm not equipped for...
Drama?
I'll just end up
sleeping my life away.
Okay.
I won't get high,
and you don't propose to me
in a semi-compulsory manner.
For how long?
A day at a time.
About all I can manage.
Okay, deal.
What's that face?
Well, that's the one
that says...
this house is still empty.
And, um...
you look incredible
by this fire.
And I'm pretty sure
these clothes
still come off.
♪ No, I wouldn't change a
thing ♪
Oh, my God.
Get up.
♪ About my younger days ♪
♪ Looking back,
I'm glad to see ♪
Hey, sleepyhead.
♪ I didn't get my way ♪
♪ In my younger days ♪
Mmph.
I'm sorry.
For what?
You had to put me
on a vent.
You had to make
that call.
I'd do it again
if I had to.
But I hope I don't.
I'm glad I chose you.
♪ The person I became ♪
♪ In my younger days ♪
We need to talk
about Wilson.
♪ We are raindrops in a river ♪
♪ One day,
we'll all be memories ♪
♪ To be lost is to be looking ♪
♪ The heart,
it is a lighthouse ♪
♪ Our minds are rocks
along the shore ♪
♪ I will not follow my mind
anymore ♪
That's it.
It's in.
All that's left is
to take him off bypass.
And pray that he maintains
his blood pressure
with this new pump.
♪ You're a giant
who walks among us ♪
♪ You have carried me this far ♪
Nothing's happening.
Give him another second.
♪ Teach me to step
over mountains ♪
Come on, Arthur.
Come on, come on, come on.
♪ Love is deeper than the
scars ♪
It's working.
Ah! We did it!
We did it!
Whoo!
We did it.
♪ Carry on ♪
♪ On, on, on ♪
Whoo-hoo! Whoo!
♪ No, you're never gone ♪
♪ Never gone ♪
You paged?
Have a seat.
Um, look, Dr. Avery, I'm really
sorry about earlier.
I... I just have a huge problem
keeping my opinions to myself,
especially when it comes to
underserved communities, so...
Well, sounds like
that makes two of us.
I want to help people...
especially those
who've been ignored
and shut out of the system
for far too long.
It sounds like you have some
ideas from your last career.
I'd like to hear them.
All of them.
Really?
You have
a deep understanding.
I have deep pockets
and a desire to help.
So, Dr. Ortiz,
if you had the power
to effect real change...
...where would you start?
Okay.
Well, access
to affordable healthy food
is a huge problem
in low-income neighborhoods.
Okay.
The car was closing in.
I had no idea
what I was saying.
I just... I, uh...
I was so worried about you
the whole way here
and then once we got here.
Do you know what
that was like for me?
I'm sure it was, um...
They wouldn't even tell me
if you were dead or alive.
Please, promise me
you will never
put me through that again.
I won't.
Thank God,
because that was hell.
I want an annulment.
I'm sorry.
What's happening? What?
You were right.
I-I didn't say anything
about an annulment.
Shayne, what the hell?
You said people don't change,
and you were right.
She hasn't changed.
Today wasn't any different
than any other day.
I just found her self-absorption
charming on every other day,
like I was drunk on
her sense of humor.
'Cause she's funny, too.
And I was lonely.
And then I was laughing,
and I wasn't lonely,
and so I thought I could
overlook, basically,
the rest of her personality.
Okay, then maybe we should
do this later. The...
No,
I want to do it now,
and then I want to be
done with it.
You're selfish, Karissa.
And you were
the same person today
that you were the day we met,
the same person who ate
all the trail mix
I'd packed for our hike
without offering me
so much as a peanut.
You're dumping me
over a peanut?
It's an example.
One of many.
You're the center
of your own universe,
and I'd rather be alone
than with someone
who isn't capable of
considering anyone but herself.
Well, now I feel
terrible.
I'm sure
it won't last long.
Thank you.
Mnh.
One way or the other,
surgeons get closure
with their patients.
You've got yourselves
a feisty one here.
He sailed through
every hour of it.
Never showed any signs
of giving up.
My man.
You're here.
You're still here.
I gotta call Hollie!
Of course.
Honey, he's okay!
He's okay.
And he's... bionic.
Just for a little while, Hollie.
Soon as a donor heart comes up,
we'll remove the machine.
Until then, Arthur's got his
very own little battery pack.
Hi, sweetheart.
Oh, my beautiful boy.
We're so proud of you.
Hi, hi.
You're our strong
little guy.
Mommy loves you.
We love you so much.
Sometimes we fix you,
sometimes we can't.
Hey, thanks for driving me.
I'm too tired to ride my bike.
Well, if I'm driving,
you're cooking.
Ugh, who knew sticking things
up people's noses
would be so exhausting?
Wilson,
you got a minute?
Sure, yeah.
What's... What's up?
Oh, I was hoping
you could tell me.
About...?
Quitting surgery.
I'm just gonna...
If you're serious about
changing specialties,
I... I want
to support you.
But I... I can't do that
if I'm in the dark.
But our intention is to find
a long-term solution.
Zola's reading
for 20 minutes.
And the others
fell asleep
before the animals saw
Toad's bathing suit. Mm.
And this guy's down.
How long can your parents live
in the driveway?
So my mom can keep
"accidentally" referring to you
as my wife?
♪ When the earth shakes ♪
What if we just...
do a check-in?
Every few weeks.
No judgment.
To just make sure we're still
good with our decision.
♪ Good or bad, nothing lasts ♪
Are we super broken?
Or are we super evolved?
Oh, definitely evolved.
Mm.
Yeah.
♪ Even when it feels like
the day will never come ♪
Which isn't to say emergency
medicine isn't important,
especially when something's
gone neglected too long.
♪ Seems like the light is gone ♪
Owen.
I just... I mean, I-I just
put the kids down.
I-I didn't know
that you were...
Actually,
I came to see you.
♪ I will see the sun ♪
You tried to tell me the truth
about your relationship
with Allison, and I...
I was awful to you.
♪ But a heartbeat ♪
And I am sorry.
I-I... I should have told you
years ago.
You told me
when you could,
and I should have been there
for you.
Because since the day we met,
Teddy, and every day since,
you've been there
for me.
You've listened to me.
You've fought for me.
So that thing
that you did on our...
...wedding day, it was...
I-I'm... I'm sorry.
I know.
I know you are.
We were friends first.
We've been friends
for years.
And you've never been anything
but there for me,
so when you...
So when you did this thing
that was so out of character,
I should have known
that you were going through
something bigger than me.
♪ Seems like the light is gone ♪
And that you just needed
a friend.
Owen...
I can be your friend.
I want to be
your friend.
And I don't know if I have
more than that in me.
But I can be your friend,
if you'll let me, Teddy.
♪ I will see the sun ♪
And I'd like to hear about
Allison, if you'll tell me.
♪ Ooh, I know ♪
You want some tea?
♪ I will see the sun ♪
Yeah.
♪ Even when it feels like ♪
Tea would be good.
♪ The day will never come ♪
♪ When everything is broken ♪
♪ Seems like the light is gone ♪
But try as we might,
some solutions
can only be temporary...
How'd she do today?
Her energy's low.
She's still
mostly sleeping.
She's listening.
♪ I will see the sun ♪
Even when you think
maybe she's not, she's...
Extraordinary.
Unstoppable.
Always has been,
always will be.
I pray to God
you're both right.
We evaluate you.
We think in the moment.
We do our best.
♪ I will see the sun ♪
And we hope like hell
we've done enough
to carry you through.
♪ I will see the sun ♪