Hey, Sam, have you seen Gates?
Uh... Who?
Gates. Is he working today?
How would I know?
Broken tib-fib is next in the O.R.,
meniscus guy needs crutches...
and hip lady can go to the floor.
- You look different.
Discharge Curtain
3, give him a Vicodin.
I'm with Sam, something's
going on with you.
Well, I kicked ass in my
overnight, what can I say?
I need you to look at
my bike crash guy in 2.
- Well, call Ortho.
- I'm looking at Ortho.
Not anymore, I am officially
done with my rotation.
The next time you see me, I
will be back on General Surgery.
Big plans for your day off?
Well, it is a big day.
Is it? What do you mean?
- What are you doing?
- Oh, I'm not sure.
If nothing comes up, it'll be my couch,
moo goo gai pan, and "Project Runway."
- Which is good enough.
- You're not caught up?
- Oh, it's awesome.
- No, don't tell me.
I'm gonna watch the repeats.
Cable guy should be
arriving in two to six hours.
- You don't have cable?
- It went out three weeks ago.
- You look nice.
- So do you.
We on for lunch? Switch day,
you're supposed to take me.
Oh, right. After Pete's surgery.
That's what I wanted
to talk to you about.
I promise, we'll do it soon.
Neela?
Are you decent?
I'm coming in.
Neela?
What is it?
There was a little mix-up.
Your shift in General Surgery
started 15 minutes ago.
Please, not today.
Come on. Dry
off, put clothes on.
We got a non-versive
waffle-iron waiting for us in the ER.
Ah! Six-two.
You're getting beat
by an old codger.
Hank, that's your granddaughter.
It's okay, Grandma,
I'm about "to..."
- Goal!
- I gave you that one.
Hank, calm down. I swear,
he acts like a child sometimes.
It keeps him young.
Sarah seems very happy.
She's with her old
group of "friends..."
she's doing well in school, even
in math, which is almost a miracle.
You've done a good job, Tony.
But wait till she's 16, starts
dating, ignores everything you say.
I'm already looking
into boarding schools.
- Game over. Beat by your grandpa.
- Come on, best two out of three.
Grandpa?
White meat is better. Says who?
FDA. Ever heard of them?
Jump in, Dr. Pratt.
Start with a cleansing breath.
All right, look, let's
try to relax, okay?
Names, Dr. Pratt. Use names.
All right, look, Ted, Jim...
My name's not Jim.
Don't call me Jim.
He's Jack Spratt,
he eats no fat.
That's the exercise.
Help Mr. Spratt reframe his
position using "I" statements.
- "L" statements?
- Mm-hm.
I prefer white meat
because it's healthier.
I prefer dark meat
because it tastes better.
- Okay, look, Mr. Spratt...
- I think I should be Mr. Spratt.
No, I've committed to this role.
- Sounds like your phoning it in.
- Excuse me, Mr. De Niro.
This isn't working.
Are you talking to
me? You talking to me?
Of course. What's your problem?
What's your problem?
- What's your problem?
Oop. I warned you.
- No food in the patient care area.
- Hostile work environment.
- Stop, I can't hear myself think.
- See what he did?
It's a J Code violation to
have food in the desk area.
Come on, Pratt,
help a brother out.
Okay, show me a brother.
- Hey, how was chief camp?
- Chief camp?
- Did you get a medal, wear a badge?
- No, it was a management seminar.
- Thank you, Morris.
- Mr. Yunji got kicked out of his band.
They said his blood pressure
medication was making him tone deaf.
He should discuss it
with his cardiologist.
I accessed the port for our cancer
patient. That line is impossible to flush.
Yeah. Have Interventional
Radiology take a look.
- Want a chest x-ray?
- Have IR deal with it.
- They're the ones who put it in.
- That's easy.
Oh, Frank, you shouldn't have.
They're for Sam.
What?
- "What a beautiful..."
- Excuse me.
Sam, you little...
You little minx.
Who are they from?
Um... The lady with the kid
who had that fistful of splinters.
- Red roses from a woman? You're lying.
- County General.
- Who are the flowers from?
- I'm never telling.
- Okay.
- I tell you about my love life.
Margot, sounded like a
howler monkey in bed.
Got it. We got a trauma coming in.
Why don't you make yourself useful?
It's bedsores guy from last week,
isn't it? I saw him giving you that grin.
Hey. Thought you were leaving.
Scheduling mix-up.
So much for my day off.
- Hey, pretty flowers.
- Oh, thank you.
New boyfriend?
No.
Hey, Frank, what's
the date today?
- April 17th.
- Already?
Did you pay your taxes, or are
you exempt because you're "from..."
across the pond?
Don't. Is this from Abby?
I kept bugging
her for a picture.
My God, he's getting so big.
You should get one of those.
- A husband or a baby?
- Yeah. Neela, over here.
What you got?
- You're still here?
Don't remind me.
"Sheryl Hawkins, restrained driver.
High-speed Mv C, car rolled three times."
Tachy to 120. Sat, 98.
- Five of MS, positive seatbelt sign.
- Does this mean we can have lunch?
Hi, Sheryl, I'm Dr. Rasgotra.
Do we need to call anyone?
My husband. He'll have to
pick up our kids after school.
- Number's in my notes.
- It's meatloaf day.
Call her husband and
meet us back here. Go.
One eighteen over 72.
He's got a small forehead lac.
How long you been on the 42s?
It'll be a year, May.
- Hey, is Lou Honeycutt still there?
- Let him do his job.
- And what is this?
- EKG lead, sir.
No, I don't need that.
We gotta monitor your heart.
- I'm not going to the hospital.
- You fainted, Grandpa.
I lost my balance.
You could have a condition that
could lead to your heart shutting down.
I skipped breakfast.
All I need is some food.
Well, he's got a
strong "pulse..."
blood pressure's good,
normal neuro exam.
Are we going in or not?
You ever send a woman roses?
Only if it's serious.
- Is it serious?
- No.
Well, either he's trying
to get you into bed, or...
He already got you into bed and
he thinks you need the reassurance...
"that" it wasn't just
a one-night stand.
- Okay. That's what I thought.
- Heh.
Hold up, I'll be right back.
Hey.
Hey, I've been calling you.
Yeah, I'm sorry, things
have been a little crazy.
I left you messages.
Everything all right?
Yeah, just work.
I'm running late, and I'm guessing
you should be inside saving lives.
- I'm waiting on a paramedic run.
- There you go.
Hey, look, you wanna
grab some coffee later or...?
I'm sorry, I have to go.
I was running late for my
art history class at UIC...
when this guy cut me off.
You're a professor?
Freshman.
College is a little difficult...
"when" you're pregnant
right out of high school.
Four kids, 23 years
later, here I am.
Your children must be proud.
Yeah.
My son, Chris, is a sophomore.
He loves the fact that
his mother's "fresh..."
Sheryl, everything okay?
- A little woozy.
- What's wrong?
She's tachy with a dropping
crit and we're standing around.
One-twelve, not that bad.
Well, it's too fast,
considering she's so calm.
We did that five minutes
ago. Ultrasound was fine.
Aorta seems a
little wide, doesn't it?
- You're hallucinating.
- See for yourself.
Where?
You were up all night,
you start imagining things.
No, it's subtle, but it's there.
With a rupture,
she'd be "dead..."
but a dissection with a slow leak...
- Dead?
Don't listen to her.
Sorry, I didn't mean to...
Morris, they need you in 2.
Okay, she's stable.
Lily will stay
and monitor her...
while you grab a cup of
coffee, or a nap or something.
Abdominal CT
with a contrast now.
If they make you wait more than half
an hour, bring her straight to the O.R.
Hey, are you okay?
Something's not right.
What the hell?
I read a study where
smelling one's "breath..."
you can tell what's
missing in their diet.
Well, stop it.
Make sure they're
getting serial crits on her.
Then we can go get a coffee.
- Why so persistent?
- No reason.
Neela, we need you for
a trauma consult here.
And check co-ags too.
And stop hitting on me.
- I don't need oxygen.
It's just a precaution.
- Hank, for God sake.
- You're making this harder on everyone.
I thought you were off.
- This is Sarah's grandfather.
- Spending the day together.
- Pulse ox, 98.
Fix her.
Sometimes, you can't fix
people if they're technically...
Shut up! Go away.
Why are you even here?
We don't want you here.
She doesn't want you
here. We don't want you!
Hello, sir, I'm
Dr. Rasgotra from Surgery.
Ow. I'm sorry,
it's the last one.
Looks like he's afib at 130.
Okay, there's an electrical
problem in the heart.
Causing a fast irregular pulse.
- You said his pulse was normal.
- It's possible to go out of afib.
We'll give medicine to slow the heart
and thin the blood to reduce the risk.
Twenty of dope?
- Yeah.
Neela, pressure's
dropping in here.
Go.
The head trauma was minor, all
the problems seem to be cardiac.
Thank you for your help.
Once you give me the
medicine, I can go home?
In a day or two. We gotta make
sure you didn't have a heart attack.
Sarah.
Look, this is very common.
- There's treatments that will fix him.
- Kathy's uncle died from a heart attack.
I know this looks scary, but
we're gonna be extra careful, okay?
- Okay?
- Okay.
- Six thousand heparin?
- Start a drip at 1400 an hour.
Heart rate's at 80.
You feeling better?
I guess.
- I'm gonna order a telebed, all right?
X- rays for Martin Sinula.
- This is Hank Riley.
- Sorry.
I got it. Your film's cooking.
Thanks, Sam.
- You get a special delivery?
- No. Uh, yes.
Thank you.
Wanna go ahead and
open your mouth for me?
Okay, good, now close.
- Blank films?
- Go ahead and open your eyes, sir.
No film. I have
a digital camera.
His head CT was normal.
Let's go see if
those labs are back.
- Sit tight, Mr. Sinula.
I'd rather lie down.
A bad concussion?
Fractured radius and ulna.
- Femoral head too.
- Yeah, and look at this.
Compression fractures of T12, L4
and 5, all in different stages of healing.
That's never good.
Your signature, please.
What is this?
I'm filing a grievance against
Dr. Morris and his aftershave.
- What's with you
two? I think it's love.
Have you smelled him? He's
like a violation of the Clean Air Act.
People in glass houses, Frank.
Hey, did you get my
labs back on Exam 2?
The Chem-20 machine
is down for an hour.
The Radiology Attending wants
you to call about the MRI in 3.
- Bettina?
- Some guy named Cohen.
Your squeeze
isn't working today.
I saw her walk in. And
don't say "squeeze," Frank.
So shoot the messenger. Oh.
That kid's been loitering a good
hour. The son of your broken bone guy.
- I got it.
- Thanks.
Oh, and another thing.
Golden boy called.
His flight was canceled,
he won't be in until tonight.
Brenner? He was at a
conference in South Bend.
If by conference, you mean fashion
show, and by South Bend, you mean Milan.
- I'm Dr. Pratt.
- Nick.
How's my dad?
Well, he's got multiple
fractures and a broken back.
That's pretty bad.
- Is your mom around?
- No, it's just the two of us.
Okay, would you have any
relatives that live nearby?
My aunt.
- Do you mind if we give her a call?
- I don't have her number on me, "so..."
Can you get it?
Come on, we'll walk you over.
You know of anyone who
might wanna hurt your dad?
Um, no.
He ever talk about
anybody bothering him?
Like at work maybe?
He lost his job
about a month ago.
- What about drugs?
- What?
His injuries are
consistent with violence.
Like somebody's
been hitting him.
- Yeah, if he owed somebody...
- My dad's not like that.
Can I see him now?
We're trying to help you.
- I'm sure you are.
Do you know who called 911?
I don't know, I was at school.
So everything was
fine before you left?
Yeah, fine. He was fine and
now his arms are all busted, okay?
I don't get it either.
Go in. He's in there.
We never said anything about
his dad's arms being broken.
Dr. Gates?
I hung a second
liter, I need Regulan.
All right, start with 10.
- Oh, God.
- Oh, my God.
- Take it easy, Hank.
- Any belly pain? All over.
Open up the saline, he
needs an abdominal CT.
- What's going on?
- It's possible that...
- Dr. Morris, what's happening?
- With afib, you get a clot in the heart.
A piece can break, travel to the belly,
block the blood supply to his intestines.
- I need something.
- Four of Morphine.
We should start with
two. Pressure's borderline.
- Lf we open up...
- Listen to the doctor.
Get him on a monitor. I want
him in the scanner in five minutes.
Don't worry, sweetie.
Mommy's gonna be fine.
I'll see you when I wake up.
Bye. I love you.
Thank you.
I really needed to
hear their voices.
Lucy, my 5-year-old,
is very worried.
You also have a 5-year old?
It was a surprise. A great
surprise, but a surprise.
Well, Lucy has
nothing to worry about.
You're getting the best surgeon
County has to offer, okay?
- Someone thinks very highly
of herself. I was referring to you.
Scrub in. You're
first assistant.
I've been awake for,
like, over 30 hours.
I'll let you do
the aortic repair.
How many residents
get that opportunity?
None. Neela, you have to do it.
Sweet. What a great way to
spend our last case together.
You're only going to Pedes
Surgery. I'll still see you.
Actually, I'm going
to Pedes ICU.
- What? Doing a non-surgical rotation?
- I wanted to talk to you about...
You're gonna spend the whole month
dialing dopamine and weighing diapers.
- You're letting him do this?
- It's his call.
- Well, that's crap. You had to sign off.
- Neela, I...
You only have five years here.
You need to make every month count.
You know I'm right.
Okay, let's talk about this
later. I'll see you inside.
- Have you seen my case of Groovitas?
- I don't know, ask Frank.
No, that's exactly
what he wants me to do.
We agreed, no food on the floor.
Groovitas is not food,
it's a liquid life force.
Have my first can at the start of my
shift, second one midway through my shift.
Uhhh. I can't do this. I can't.
I cannot work under
these conditions.
That's it. This is war.
What great war
wasn't fought with tape?
I don't know. Maybe
you misdialed.
I called twice, both times it was
wrong. So do you have an aunt or not?
Look, all you're doing is
asking stupid questions.
- So fix him up and let us go home!
- That is not gonna happen soon.
His x-rays show he's been beaten.
We need to figure out who's doing this.
You don't know what
you're talking about.
- When you fight, does it get physical?
- Sam.
- Do you lose temper, throw punches?
- We don't fight.
Come on, now.
It's you that's hurting
your dad, isn't it?
Just wait. Stupid bitch.
- Hey, what the hell was that?
- I'm just doing my job.
By berating the kid in
the middle of the ER.
Something's going on. I'm
trying to figure what the story is.
You do not storm into the
hallway making accusations.
If you have a problem,
you discuss it calmly.
- Or just run it by me.
- Somebody has to take the initiative.
What's that supposed to mean?
While you moved on to the next
patient, I'm the one who's in the trenches.
I deal with the family...
follow up to make sure
we didn't miss anything.
And now, I'm the one trying to
figure out what's wrong with this guy.
You learn that in chief camp?
Might wanna ask for your money back.
All right, back to work.
Mind if I sit down?
First of all, Nurse Taggart,
she had no right to accuse you.
She overstepped her
bounds and I'm sorry.
But some of what you told
us, it just doesn't add up.
Look, the last thing
any of us want...
is for your dad to come back here
in a month with more broken bones.
- Lf you know anyone who could have...
- Look, no one hit him.
You know that for a fact?
Yeah. He fell in
the kitchen, all right?
- I'm the one who called 911.
- Paramedics said it was anonymous.
Yeah, well, I disguised my
voice, tried to sound older.
Why would you do that?
Okay, about two years ago,
my dad was in a car accident...
and they made me
stay with a foster family.
I'm not going again.
So there's no aunt.
I was hoping if you thought I had
someone you'd just leave me alone.
And you say your dad was
just standing there and then fell?
Yeah.
- You gotta give me something more.
- Look, I don't know, all right?
I guess he has been
acting kind of weird lately.
He's fallen a couple of times.
Today was definitely the worst.
Look, he was making a
sandwich in the kitchen...
I hear a thud, I look
over and he's on the floor.
Just let me run a few more tests
and see what I can come up with.
Hey, wait a second.
You're not gonna
snitch to Social Services?
Let's just see what I can figure
out about your dad first, okay?
You had to tube him?
- Dropped his sats in Radiology.
- What are you talking about?
- We're helping your husband breathe.
- They read the scan?
- Big clot in the SMA.
Hank? Hank?
- No, we had to sedate him for the CT.
The scan shows a large clot blocking
the main artery to his intestines.
- What do you do?
- We need to...
Dr. Morris?
We need to restore blood flow to
his bowels. That means surgery.
- Surgery? Today?
- Not necessarily.
What about TPA?
No, I don't think that's
the best option here.
What's TPA?
It's a clot-busting
medicine that could help.
But if it doesn't, we've
delayed an inevitable operation.
That could cause a stroke or MI.
Surgery is the best option here.
If that's what you think.
Page Neela.
- I want a hematology consult too.
- You are wasting time.
- Not if it prevents...
Stop it. Just stop.
I want co-ags, serial crits and
neurovascular checks q-hour.
- Got it.
- And stay on the vent.
- Acidosis is the last thing she needs.
- Got it.
Why neurovascular checks?
To make sure she's perfusing
her extremities distal to the graft.
Still haven't forgotten what you said
about Pedes. I'll talk to Lucien soon.
- That's not necessary.
- The Pedes ward.
- Sabotage your career.
- He's not...
You need 10 months
of surgical electives.
- There isn't time to fool around.
- It's okay.
No, it's not.
You won't graduate on time.
When you're looking for
jobs, you'll be behind...
I'm not taking
it as an elective.
I'm switching specialties.
What are you talking about?
I don't wanna be a surgeon.
What did he say to you?
Dr. Dubenko's been
very supportive about this.
I told him I would work with
you, mentor you, and for what?
So he could eventually
squeeze you out.
Damn, it's the ER.
Stay here and call me
with Sheryl's next crit.
- Don't worry, I'll handle this.
- I'm not worried.
Harold Zelinsky, you
will be a great surgeon.
You're supposed to be. I'm not gonna
let one person get in the way of that.
- Is that for Hank?
- Yeah.
His K's 3.2, so Morris
wants 40 in the bag.
You okay?
Yeah, just, he's not the
best surgical "candidate..."
"but" I can't get
Becky to listen to me.
Well, you know what your problem is.
You don't know how to talk to women.
- Yeah, that's my problem.
- Mm-hm.
Well, I'd teach you, but it's
gonna take a really long time.
I'll put this up.
Onset of pain was an hour ago.
He's infarcting everything from the
duodenum to the transverse colon.
- We have to correct this.
- With surgery?
Well, we were discussing
TPA as an alternative.
I'm talking about local TPA.
Well, it's a good
idea in theory.
It might not work?
And we would lose valuable time.
Mrs. Riley, if we get Radiology
here, you can get another opinion.
If they have a good record with TPA with
catheter it might be worth considering.
But if we wait too long and his
bowel dies, he's at risk for sepsis.
What's sepsis?
It's an infection.
- I just wanna do what's best for Hank.
- Why don't we talk to Radiology?
- Enough, why won't you listen?
- Surgery is not the best...
You'll never change. You can't
ever let someone else be right.
Let's do a liter of saline
an hour for two hours.
- Hey, Dr. Pratt.
- Hey.
Any news?
His hormone's causing too
much calcium in his blood.
- That made his bones break.
- His bones are brittle.
It doesn't take
much to fracture.
- This is just gonna keep happening?
- No.
He can have surgery
to remove some glands...
and his bones will
be strong again.
- How long is he gonna be in the hospital?
- About a week.
I really don't wanna
stay with a foster family.
All right, tell me something.
How do you get to school?
My friend's mom.
She picks me up.
- What do you do after school?
- Bus tables at a diner.
Get home around 7.
You could take care of yourself
while your dad is in the hospital.
Seriously?
What about the social worker?
As long as you come in every day
and visit your dad and check in with me...
"I'll" take care of
the social worker.
- Thanks, Dr. Pratt.
- No problem.
Hey, what's going on
with Sarah's granddad?
- Eh. Could be better.
- All right, well, keep me posted.
I hope you're right about this.
Me too.
Sorry to hear about Julia.
Oh, thanks. I'm fine.
Seems that way.
Julia's plane hasn't landed in Bangkok
and you've already moved on to Sam.
Actually, she went to Nepal.
Whatever.
- What are you, jealous?
- Please.
- You go from relationship to relationship.
- Lf it doesn't work out, I move on.
Yeah, well, think about
someone other than yourself.
What does that mean?
- Sarah, maybe.
- You wanna go there?
You would rather be with the
wrong person than be on your own.
In the wake of these failed relationships,
it's a girl in need of stability.
I give stability. I help with her homework.
She can talk to me about anything.
About how there's a different
woman in your bed every month.
Mrs. Riley. The
surgical consent forms.
Before you sign anything,
please read it carefully...
and understand all the risks
involved with Hank's surgery.
I, "uh..." I'm not sure.
Well, there are always
potential complications.
This says brain damage,
death. You said...
Well, right now, the benefits
of surgery outweigh the risks.
But he could die,
this says he could die.
No, no, there's
gotta be a better way.
This is not how we were
supposed to spend the day.
We were supposed to be
out with our granddaughter.
Not stuck in this
godforsaken hospital.
I know it's a lot to absorb.
Maybe you were right.
Do the TPA thing, then
he won't need surgery.
Hank should have the surgery.
You said it wasn't
necessary. You said...
Becky, Dr. Rasgotra
is an excellent surgeon.
If she and Dr. Morris recommend
this, then we go for it and we trust them.
We'll all do everything we can
to make sure this turns out right.
Okay?
More traction on the pancreas.
- Where do we access
the SMA? Neela?
Neela, course the artery.
Neela.
Inferior to the uncinate process,
superior to the duodenum.
Exactly.
Vessel loops, help
me get distal control.
Oh, crap. Lap pads.
- Suction. Systolic down to 90.
Hang another unit. I can't
see a damn thing in here.
Did we nick the IVC?
We sheered some
venous tributaries.
Start with hematocrit 5-0
protein on a C-1 needle...
and cut into the
vessel wall. Let's go.
Was I acting crazy?
It was the calcium
talking, but no worries.
So when I get home, Nicky has
to wait on me hand and foot, right?
It couldn't hurt, just
to be on the safe side.
Yeah, sure, of course.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- Right after school.
- I just gotta be at work by 4.
- All right.
- Thanks again.
- You got it.
Never have I been
so happy to be wrong.
Sometimes go with your gut...
other times, you gotta
force yourself to be objective.
Yeah, I should've slowed down.
Yeah, and I could've taken
a few cleansing breaths.
I'm taking this new
management course.
So how's that going for you?
Well, I'm working
on conflict resolution.
So you got a few
weeks to go, huh?
Stop breathing so loud.
- Stop tapping your pen.
- Mouth-breather.
- Pen-tapping garden gnome.
- Garden gnome?
All right, guys,
guys, come on, now.
All right, wait, look.
Archie, Frank, just
tell me what's wrong.
- Morris is an idiot.
- One at a time.
- Frank's a hypocrite.
- Okay, look.
Starting your
sentences with "I feel."
- I feel like Frank is a big, fat
hypocrite. That's not what I meant.
I feel hurt.
Because Archie had a party
and he invited everyone but me.
That's very good, Frank.
Can I go again?
I feel...
like Frank is hypocritical, because
he told me he hated sushi and karaoke.
I didn't think you'd wanna go.
I could've grabbed a
burger on the way over there.
- What about the karaoke?
- I don't wanna do it.
I don't mind watching you
make an ass out of yourself.
I'm sorry. I'm so...
Come here, you
big lug. I'm sorry.
Can I buy you a cup of coffee?
- Yeah.
Keep his fluids at 125
and CBC in an hour.
Hey.
- Surgery is over, Hank.
- We got the clot out.
Neela. Can we talk?
All right, I'll buy you lunch.
I'll meet you in recovery.
Whatever you want.
I have 52 cents.
I haven't spoken
to Lucien either...
It was my decision to leave.
Lucien had nothing to do with it.
- What?
- I'm not cut out for surgery.
- Of course, you are, you...
- No, listen, I'm not.
I see how much you've given up.
And I admire that,
but I wanna have a life.
Harold.
I don't wanna end
up alone. No offense.
Oh, come on, you're young.
By the time I finish
my residency, I'll be 26.
If I wanna do a fellowship,
I won't be done until I'm 29.
Twenty-nine, Neela. You might
as well just put a bullet in my head.
You're over-stressed,
you just need a break.
Neela, it's over.
Was I not a good teacher?
Did we not spend time together?
We both did our best.
Well, was it something
I said or didn't say?
It's not you, Neela.
It's me.
So you think they can do the
pull-through at the same time?
They do everything they can.
- Just give me one minute.
- But it's a real possibility.
I see.
- Hey.
- Hey, Greg.
I didn't know you were on today.
I'm not, I'm just going over a case here
with Grant. You know each other, right?
- Grant Hayward. Oncology.
- Yeah, I've seen you around.
What were you talking about?
That Wilms kid we scanned?
No.
It's a crazy adrenal tumor. Took
up the whole abdominal cavity.
We're talking about me, Greg.
- You're not allergic to roses, are you?
- No.
These are really beautiful.
And kind of embarrassing.
I had a good time, I
wanted to let you know.
Yeah, well, I heard that the
other night, loud and clear.
No, you know, I like you.
You know, it's not just about...
- Keeping a full dance card?
- Right, it's not just about that.
Shoot. I was gonna use you and
abuse you and then throw you out.
Why would you do that?
Doctors have been doing that to
nurses for years. It's karmic retribution.
You want me to play
nurse? I'll try anything once.
- Hey, Archie.
- Hi, Archie.
Sam, I figured it out.
You're sending them
to yourself, right?
- You got me.
- Ha!
Good night, guys.
No.
Hey.
Everything okay?
Last weekend, my college roommate
had a baby shower for her third kid.
Who does that?
I don't know, somebody
desperate for attention.
Maybe Sheryl had it right.
I should have popped out four
kids and then gone to med school.
Kids? You want four kids?
Oh, I don't even know if I want kids,
but if I did, I couldn't have them now.
I don't have time to
do laundry, have sex...
Wait, meet someone,
then have sex.
You could meet someone.
You know, I turned down a
date last week so I could sleep.
The closest thing I have to a personal
relationship is Harold Zelinsky...
a 19-year-old intern,
and he just dumped me.
You have a personal
relationship with me, right?
We're friends.
You know what? Go
home. You're tired.
I'm 31 today.
It's your birthday?
Oh, Neela, I'm
sorry. I didn't realize.
Oh, don't worry, nobody did.
Here.
Happy birthday.
I'm sorry I don't have a candle.
Thank you.
No, don't eat it. That's
disgust... That's disgusting.
It's been out since
morning. Spit that out.
God. I can't do this.
You know, I fell asleep in
the shower this morning and...
Well, it doesn't matter.
But I realized, I'm going
through life as if everything's okay.
But it's not.
Come on.
Well, what are you doing?
Pity party's over.
- Here. What do you see?
- A happy family...
I see a mom who was this
close to dying from a torn aorta.
You made a critical diagnosis...
and performed a flawless
anastomosis of a bifemoral y-graft.
And in there...
I see a grandfather who could
have died from an ischemic bowel.
Thanks to you, he'll be
eating filet mignon soon.
- Yeah, but...
- I don't "care..."
how many babies people have
or how many dates you miss.
Very few people could have
done what you did today.
Hey.
You have a gift, Neela.
You have a gift.
The minute you start comparing yourself
to others is the minute that you forget...
you're doing exactly
what you were meant to do.
Your shift ended 15 minutes
ago, you should go home.
You look like hell.
Will he be able to
walk his horses?
For shorter distances
to start with, but yes.
Good. He loves that.
Maybe lay off the air
hockey for a little while.
He kept beating me, anyway.
Thanks, Neela.
Sure thing.
I get a colonoscopy,
and every year, it's fine.
I guess I was starting to believe
that it wasn't gonna happen.
Which is ridiculous, because in my
family it's not a question of if, but when.
If you get the surgery, you'll have
no chance of getting colon cancer.
So you'll be okay,
everything will be fine.
Until I develop a post-op
desmoid or hepatablastoma.
- Or thyroid cancer.
- Oh, you don't know that.
I was born with a defective
tumor-suppressor gene.
Colon cancer is
just the beginning.
Why didn't you tell me?
You showed your hand.
- I knew you weren't cut out for this.
- I can handle it.
Really? You wanna
change my colostomy bag?
That's touching,
but I don't think so.
Look, maybe in the past...
You weren't a hundred percent
committed when things were easy.
So don't try to tell me now all of
a sudden that you can handle it.
- I don't need your pity.
- It's not pity.
You shouldn't go
through this alone.
It was my choice to
end our relationship.
You don't have to call,
don't have to check on me.
- This is not your problem, Greg.
- Bettina.
I'm letting you off the hook.
I got you some food. I figured you and
Sarah must be hungry for dinner, huh?
Oh, thank you.
Listen, Hank is gonna
be here for a week.
So until then, I think Sarah would
love it if you would stay with us.
Thank you, that's very generous.
I'm sorry for how I treated you.
It's been a stressful day.
Not just today.
I remember the
first time I met you.
You were this messed-up vet back from
the war running around with my daughter.
Yes, I was.
Meg used to say you
changed, that you grew up...
"but" I didn't
believe it, not really.
Until today.
Thank you.
- How's he doing?
- Very well.
When we restored the blood
supply to his intestines they pinked up.
- That's a good sign.
- Thank you, Dr. Rasgotra.
Well, I'm about to go off duty,
so I'll check on him first thing.
- I'll be there.
- Okay.
Listen, about what you
said, me dating Sam.
Yeah, um, about that.
I said some awful
things, and I'm sorry.
To say I'm sleep-deprived would
be a massive understatement...
so I would just like to blame it on the
frontal lobe malfunction and call it a day.
- Lf it's okay with you.
- Sure.
Hey, Mayday.
Happy birthday.
Thank you.
Neela Rasgotra.
Oh, I know, I'm sorry.
And I was stuck at work.
Well, can they come tomorrow?
Well, how hard is
it to hook up cable?
Three weeks?
Well, I'll leave a
key under the mat.
Yes, I'm serious.
Look, I'm a doctor.
And I'm single. All I
have is "Project Runway."
Hello?
Subtitles by SDI Media Group