Previously on "ER."
I mean, a drink sounds great.
Can we also
eat something?
What are you
talking about?
‐ You went out with her, right.
‐ We had dinner.
We should embrace
our mistakes
and learn from them
to improve the system.
I'm going to put the microphone
holder right behind the ear.
I wanted to postpone
Reese's operation.
Are you coughing up blood?
That woman
has tuberculosis.
It's highly contagious.
There's something
about me that
just brings out
the worst in people.
Merry Christmas, Amanda.
'Gotta beautiful
snow storm last night'
'but it's a mess
on the roads'
'and you're gonna have
to dig the car out.'
'Absolutely, I guess‐‐'
I should really get up.
Me too.
Have you seen
my pajama bottoms?
You really should talk to
Kerry about the heat in here.
Ah, it was pretty hot
in here a minute ago.
Yeah, thanks.
So, I'll pick you up
tonight around nine?
Ah, I said
I'd think about it.
Oh, come on, my friends
are dying to meet you.
Girls night out.
I'd feel like
I was on display.
Come on, it's gotta beat the
hell out of baby‐sitting
a med student
on a Friday night.
Oh, Lucy's presenting
chief rounds tomorrow.
‐ It's a big deal.
‐ And Lucy is a big girl.
I'd rather spend
the night with you.
‐ But only with you.
‐ Mmm‐mm.
John, what is that?
Oh, that is a major drag.
‐ Hey.
‐ Sorry.
You were an easy target.
You've got quite an arm.
My grandfather
was a pitcher
for the Cincinnati Reds.
Must be in the genes.
Someone not notice that this
is an emergency entrance.
The snow‐plow comes in
and just kind of pushes the snow
from one side to the other.
‐ I'll give maintenance a call.
‐ Yeah, don't bother.
By the time they get here,
it will be spring.
Fresh snow always
reminds me of the year
I spent working
in Alaska.
You've done it all.
I try.
Hey, oh, oh.
You got something
on your back there.
Ooh, that's cold.
Oh, oh, oh, you think
that's funny, huh?
Oh.
You okay?
‐ I'm fine.
‐ I'm sorry.
I'm vibrating.
What?
‐ It's my pager.
‐ Oh.
‐ See you inside.
‐ Yeah.
So Mark said dinner plans
are, quote, "Optional."
Hmm, if everything's going well
with Amanda, we should vamoose.
Yeah, I hope
things go well.
He deserves it.
You think they've
slept together yet?
Not if they observed
the three‐date rule.
What's the three‐date rule?
First date, you go out.
Second date,
you get invited in.
Third date,
you close the deal.
Yeah, well,
if you recall
we closed the deal
on the first date.
Oh, yeah, I was never much
for rules, you know.
Hang on, hang on.
Call in a code white.
Get a gurney
and a crash cart.
Joi Abbott, fainted in the
cafeteria, tachycardic at 130.
I'm fine, really.
Her lips are dry,
it's probably dehydrated.
Exams two's open,
we got it from here, Doug.
Okay.
Ah, excuse me.
‐ Yo, can I help you?
‐ Yeah, who are you?
‐ Who are you?
‐ Who is this guy?
Doug Ross,
peds ER attending
meet Tony Fig,
transport dispatcher.
He's been turfed up here while
Jerry and Randi are both sick.
Hey, some dude from NASA
called wanting to know
if you got your phase two
application packet.
NASA, as in
the space program?
Yeah, probably NASA as in
trying to sell me a time share.
‐ There's no phone number.
‐ Said they'd call back.
Bet it was Jerry
making a crank call.
He's made two
from home already.
Doug, I DC'd the otitis media.
‐ We're free and clear.
‐ Hmm.
'Excuse me.'
For a nanosecond...
yes, officer.
What can I do for you?
Scott Pew,
thought it'd be cool
to bumper ski
on my patrol car
until I made a U‐turn
and he shot into a hedge.
‐ Hmm‐mm.
‐ Says he broke his arm.
Nah, it feels more
like his elbow
probably a proximal
radius fracture.
Here, I'm gonna sit you
right down here.
Could be a good
candidate for
our pain medication study.
That's a good idea, Jeanie.
I'll get his parents' consent.
Would you mind taking
a look at my hand?
I got a splinter when I pulled
the kid from the bushes.
Ah, I'm working in peds today,
I'll find you someone else.
I'm a kid at heart.
Okay, I'll meet you in
the suture room in a minute.
Okay.
I really need to go.
Could you be pregnant?
No, my husband and
I are separated.
When was the last time
you had anything to eat?
I don't know.
Lunch yesterday..
Your body's malnourished.
My son's upstairs
getting an MRI.
And if I'm not there
when he's done‐‐
Oh, we can call upstairs
explain what happened
I'm sure they'd
keep an eye out on him.
He gets scared
if I'm not there.
And we have to get
to the clinic.
We have a clinic here.
Ricky goes to
the genetics clinic.
Will you take
this out, please?
Joi, what's your son's
medical condition?
ALD, adrenoleukodystrophy.
‐ Advanced?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
‐ Are you giving him oils?
‐ It's too late for that.
We'll have your lab results
back in about an hour
if you'd like to
come back down here
when you're through upstairs.
Maybe.
Thanks.
Well, we tried.
I'm looking forward to our
double date this evening.
Oh, me, too.
If you don't mind me asking..
...have you and Mark
ever been intimate?
Me and Mark?
No, why?
Well, I just wondered if he
makes it a habit
of seducing coworkers.
He's been
so aggressive.
Oh, don't get me wrong.
I've never been as
satisfied with anyone
as I am with this man.
But when someone's that
inventive, you know
I sort of suspect
he's a Don Juan.
We are talking
about Mark Greene?
Last night,
on his fire escape..
I'll drop these at the lab.
Must have gotten
it from treating
that woman
in the projects.
‐ Any night sweats or fever?
‐ No.
A positive test
doesn't mean I have TB.
It just means
I've been exposed.
But you'll still
need a chest x‐ray.
And INH prophylaxis
for at least six months.
‐ I know the drill.
‐ Carter, I'm really sorry.
That's the risk
of being a doctor.
I'm glad you're negative.
Carter, Roxanne, line two.
Oh, thanks, Lily.
Ah, I have to cancel our
study plans this evening.
Friday night,
something's come up.
No problem.
Maybe you and Bernard
can review together.
Hey, what's up?
‐ You hated it.
‐ What? No.
I just haven't had time
to read it thoroughly, yet.
Do you think I have a shot
at getting it published?
‐ Well, it is controversial.
‐ And that's bad?
For you, right now,
oh, yeah.
‐ We'll see if Anspaugh agrees.
‐ Dr. Benton.
In there,
the patient's grandmother
requested you personally.
Yeah.
Ah, Dr. Parks,
this is a surprise.
Where's your interpreter?
I can do that.
My name is Gwen.
Oh, you can hear.
Grandma thinks
I have appendi‐‐
‐ Appendicitis?
‐ Yeah, that's it.
Okay, where does it hurt?
Around my bellybutton.
When did it start?
While grandma
was driving me to school
she had to pull over
so I could throw up.
Ah, tell your grandmother
I think you have
gastroenteritis.
Can you spell that?
I'm sorry,
stomach flu.
You're wrong.
There's no
localized tenderness
in the right
lower quadrant.
Grandma wants to do
the ultrasound.
I'll re‐examine her
in a couple of hours.
See if the problem
declares itself.
What did she say?
Uh, she said she wants
to do the ultrasound.
Fine.
I don't see a splinter,
but there is something.
Uh, good, I'd hate for you
to think I made this up
just so I could
spend time with you.
Oh, that smile is worth
a thousand splinters.
‐ Ow.
‐ Oh, easy. Got it.
Sorry, I didn't
mean to hurt you.
Well, you can make it up to me
by letting me take you out.
I didn't hurt you that bad.
You will
if you say no.
I don't think so.
So, you've decided
not to like me.
‐ I don't even know you.
‐ Right, right.
So we go out,
you get to know me.
‐ Officer..
‐ Call me Reggie.
Reggie, I'm just not looking
to out with anyone right now.
You know, if it's because
you're HIV‐positive
I'm cool with that.
You're cool with that?
Lucky me.
Whoa, whoa.
I didn't...I wasn't
talking about sex.
I‐I like to get to
know a woman first.
So, how about we cross
that bridge if we come to it.
Oh, Dr. Weaver,
I almost forgot.
‐ Your mom called.
‐ My mom?
Yep, this morning,
right before I left the house.
What did she say exactly?
Just that, uh,
she'd try again later.
‐ Am I supposed to get that?
‐ No, I got it.
‐ Did she ask for me by name?
‐ Your mom?
'County General, go ahead.'
'County, be advised of'
'a commuter plane crash
at Meig's Field.'
'Anticipating up to
14 trauma patients.'
'How many can you handle?
Over.'
We can take
three major, seven minor.
Do you have an ETA? Over.
'Negative, we're
waiting reports'
'from the scene, over.'
Alright, this is County General.
Clear on med nine.
Okay, everyone, we have
a mass casualty incident.
Implement disaster protocol.
Carol, set up
the curtains one and two
trauma two and three
for critical patients.
John, will you put IV stands
and gurneys in the hallway?
I need warm saline,
rapid infusers
and two units of O‐negative
available at every bedside.
I appreciate your
hard work but I..
...don't think it's
appropriate for publication.
How can we effect change
unless we create an open forum?
I support change, Elizabeth
but I don't believe your
paper is the proper tool.
You object to me
referencing my own mistake
because it paints
County General in a poor light.
No, it paints you
in a poor light.
It has a confessional
quality that concerns me.
I suggest you find
out the true motives
for writing this paper
before you become hell‐bent
on sharing it
with the world.
Nothing like
a multi‐victim trauma
to get the blood pumping.
I don't believe we've met.
I'm Dale Edson.
Third‐year surgical resident.
Lucy Knight, third‐year
medical student.
Working with
the esteemed John Carter
former surgical intern.
I didn't know that.
Wait until you do
surgical rotation.
You'll find that he makes
emergency medicine
look like child's play.
Here, let me help
you with that.
Thanks.
You ever been on
a riverboat casino?
Like in New Orleans?
Like in Elgin.
It's a stellar boat,
the Grand Victoria.
I'm heading up there this
evening to try my hand
at lady luck.
Would you like to join me?
I've never been
gambling before.
Lucy, don't you need to prepare
for chief rounds tomorrow?
Oh, right.
I probably shouldn't.
When you're through here,
check the O‐neg supply.
I can help you on it
during the drive up.
‐ I mean, if you want me to.
‐ That would actually be great.
Come on,
we got work to do.
This place won't
be the same without you.
Am I going someplace?
You don't have
to play dumb, Doug.
Matt Richmond phoned.
I downplayed you,
of course, I'm not an idiot.
Well, I am, because
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Who's this, uh, Richmond guy?
He runs an HMO,
headquartered in Portland.
They're looking for someone
to set up pediatric ER's
in their facilities
around the country.
Dr. Lee, blood bank's
on the phone for you.
‐ Oh, thanks.
‐ Don't worry, Amanda.
‐ I'm not going anywhere.
‐ Glad to hear it.
So you actually applied
to the space program?
My second year of residency.
‐ I made the first cut.
‐ What happened?
Uh, Rachel was just
barely out of diapers
and Jen was
starting law school.
I tried to defer,
but they wouldn't let me.
So that call from NASA
could have been for real.
Uh, I doubt it.
Trauma room's ready.
Great.
Thanks, you guys.
You two seem to be
moving right along.
She's kind of
playing hard to get.
Carter, Lucy and Lily will
handle minors in the main hall.
‐ Got it.
‐ Mark.
I've assigned you
and Carol to trauma one.
Kerry, you and Chuny
in trauma two.
Lydia and I will float.
'Come in, County General.'
Any critical peds,
Jeanie and I
will take them
in curtain three.
This is County.
Over.
Everybody hear that?
Critical peds, curtain three.
'Be advised, your facility'
'has been instructed
to stand down. Over.'
Command center,
we're prepared.
We're ready to
handle patients. Over.
‐ Stand down?
‐ Stop prepping.
'There were
no survivors on scene.'
'Repeat, no survivors.
Over.'
Copy that, dispatch.
Any messages for me?
And you are?
Dr. Weaver. "Weaver."
Yeah. One, sounded
kind of important.
‐ From my mother?
‐ Your dentist.
Okay, any calls for me,
business or otherwise, page me.
I got you covered.
Dr. Greene.
Overnight delivery.
Check out the return address.
NASA.
You deserting me?
No, of course not.
Got another, behind us.
Okay, I'll take this one.
‐ Amanda.
‐ Yeah?
42 year old female.
Blunt head trauma
from a collapsed chimney.
‐ Chimney?
‐ Possible LOC.
Complains of headache
shortness of breath.
Help me! Help...me!
‐ What's her name?
‐ Edie Harvell.
Don't worry, Edie.
You're in good hands.
Blunt trauma to the chest and
abdomen from falling bricks.
‐ 'Complains of abdominal pain.'
‐ 'Vitals?'
BP a 100 palp,
pulse 110.
'On my count.
One, two, three.'
Help...me.
Pupils equal.
React to light.
'Go...home.'
Tachypneic and tachycardic.
Edie, do you have
any chest pain?
Pain...every...where.
‐ BP's 130 over 82.
‐ Possible pneumothorax.
I want a CBC, a chem panel,
and send off cardiac enzymes.
'We've got to
rule out an MI.'
She's young for an MI.
Yeah, but I don't
wanna take any chances.
Do you mind checking on Kerry?
'Pressure's holding at 100.'
He's a psychologist,
said he was
treating your patient
when the accident occurred.
What were you
treating her for?
Agoraphobia.
Edie's terrified
of public places.
‐ Lungs are clear.
‐ Including hospitals?
Pulse ox looks good, 98.
I was using
a desensitization approach.
I got her to step outside
her house for the first time
in five years when
a chimney fell on top of us.
‐ It was freakish.
‐ Call CT.
Right upper‐quadrant tenderness.
Does she have panic attacks?
‐ Up to 30 a day.
‐ Great.
CT can take him now.
Okay, let's get him upstairs.
She has relaxation
music with her.
That may help.
EKG. Normal.
‐ Lips...numb.
‐ Edie, my name is Dr. Greene.
You're in a hospital.
Nothing bad can
happen to you here.
Hospitals...bad.
Let go of the Walkman.
Haleh, I want you to try
and find a Yanni tape.
Keep breathing.
Alright, yeah,
there's some fluid
around the edematous appendix.
E‐d‐e..
Mom.
'That's my mom.'
She was on a
field trip with her students
while grandma called her.
‐ Hey, what does this mean?
‐ "Father."
She says you're
the father of the deaf boy.
Oh, do me a favor.
Tell your mother and your
grandma...never mind.
Um, hey, hey,
excuse me.
Uh, listen,
she, um..
...uh, sheesh.
Ah, appendix.
Appendix, yeah, yeah.
Right.
I'm gonna have an operation?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But it‐it‐it's fine.
Wait!
Mom needs a signer.
Grandma's not a surgeon.
'I need to ask questions.'
The hospital needs
to provide one.
Yeah, yeah. That's...look,
I'll take care of it.
It's‐it's no problem.
Am I gonna be okay?
You're gonna be fine.
‐ Edie.
‐ What?
This mask will
help you breathe.
Okay, now just
inhale like this.
‐ No, no.
‐ Nice and easy.
‐ Mask off.
‐ No, no, no. Mask on.
Mask off.
Mark.
Bad news.
CT's down.
Oh, I'm not getting
through to her.
I don't wanna put her on
sedation until we rule out
an intracranial bleed
but we may have no choice.
Let me try something.
Okay, Edie.
'I want you to
close your eyes.'
No, I...can't.
Sure, you can.
Close your eyes.
And I want you to imagine
yourself as a little girl
'Someplace warm and safe.'
‐ It's...dark.
‐ No, it's not.
Close your eyes.
It's light
and it's airy.
And it's warm
and it's safe.
Can you tell me
where you are?
I...kitchen.
Uh‐huh.
Good.
And who's
with you there?
‐ Mom.
‐ Your mom?
She's baking something.
It smells really yummy.
Can you tell me
what she's baking?
‐ Cookies.
‐ "Cookies." Very good.
That's good.
'Sshh.'
'That's good.'
I'm sorry if I
offended you earlier.
‐ It's not what I meant to do.
‐ Don't worry about it.
I'm trying to think
of something to tell you
about myself to even
the playing field.
Reggie, that's not necessary.
How I'm broke,
or got suspended once?
‐ It's not that simple.
‐ Yeah, I know.
The truth is, there's nothing
in my life that compares to‐‐
No, no, no.
Wait, wait, wait.
Don't feel
sorry for me, okay.
I'm doing great.
Where did you learn that?
I did research on
phobias in med school.
Actually got published in
the Cornell medical journal
which is a pretty big
deal for a third‐year.
I'd love to read the article.
Do you still have a copy?
‐ Filed in a box somewhere.
‐ Mark, ambulance pulling up.
I'll take that,
besides, it's poorly written
endless psychobabble,
you'd be bored to tears.
I doubt it.
Carol.
Hey, I just got the labs
back on Joi Abbott.
Who?
The woman who fainted
in the cafeteria.
‐ She has microcytic anemia.
‐ Just give her some iron.
She'll be fine
in a couple weeks.
No, I doubt it.
Her son has ALD.
‐ How old is he?
‐ Eight. Why?
They usually don't make it
past the age of ten.
Well, when I pulled his chart,
he had an older brother
who died of it
three years ago.
Mmm, yeah, it's x‐linked.
Inherited from the mother.
It only strikes boys.
No wonder why Joi looks like
she's been through hell.
Simon says.
I can't believe
you paged me for this.
When a child acts
out it's usually
an indication
of a bigger problem.
If Reese bit a kid,
it's probably because
he was provoked.
Actually, this isn't
the first time
he's disrupted
the class.
Yesterday, Reese threw a fit
when it was sing‐along time
and he wanted
to continue painting.
Maybe that's because
he can't sing along.
I understand, but we
don't have the personnel
to let each child do
their own activities.
I already spend extra
time with Reese
talking to him and making
sure he understands.
Okay, okay, okay.
Listen. Listen, what do
you want me to do?
Perhaps you should consider
a special‐needs environment
where Reese can get
more personal attention.
I think it may be the
best for all concerned.
Good breath sounds bilaterally.
You're doing awesome, Robin.
Fetal heart tones
present at 140.
Okay, are you feeling
any pain here?
Only with the contractions.
Is our baby alright?
‐ So far, so good.
‐ 'Haemoglobin is 12.8.'
‐ What have we got?
‐ Robin Gambrell, 28 years old.
Restrained front seat passenger
involved in a two‐car MVA.
Full‐term pregnancy and
she's in active labor.
It was my fault.
I shouldn't have been
driving so fast.
Hey, they‐they just brought
in the other victim.
I think they
need you next door.
Okay.
I hope that guy's okay.
I never saw him coming.
Okay, we're gonna have
to do a quick pelvic exam
before we bring
you up to OB.
Mike, did you
hurt your back?
What?
Oh, no, I'm okay.
Don't worry
about me, baby.
Lydia, let's get a trauma
panel on Mr. Gambrell.
I wanna make sure he didn't
damage his kidneys.
Uh‐oh.
Here comes another one!
Okay, baby, breathe now.
Breathe through the pain.
'His name is Aaron Drane.
He's a private in the army.'
BP's down to 60.
Could be intra‐abdominal
hemorrhage.
I need the peritoneal
lavage kit.
‐ Prep the belly.
‐ Another two units of O‐neg.
‐ Squeeze it in.
‐ Heart rate's up to 130.
Hook up the adapter
to the syringe.
Okay, I'm in.
Pull back on the syringe.
Gross blood.
Oh, v‐fib.
'Crash cart.'
Charge to 200.
Clear!
Tony, do you know how
to navigate the internet?
My middle
initials are WWW.
I'm trying to
find an article
on the Cornell
medical school
journal website, and..
You got backslashes
instead of forward slashes.
Common beginner's mistake.
‐ Author's name?
‐ Uh, Amanda lee.
Subject would be phobias.
I got an A. W. Lee.
wrote something
called "Fearing Fear."
Could you print
that up for me?
Already did.
Listen, call down
to the library
and have them
send up any articles
by the same author.
Hey, for you, Dr. G.
One more time.
Charge to 50.
‐ Charging.
‐ Clear.
He's still asystole.
Me and some friends
were hanging out
after my shift, uh,
when Robin called
and told me that
her water broke.
I kind of freaked out.
That's pretty common
with first‐time dads.
Mike's been working
doubles so he can take
time off after the baby's born.
Yeah, I don't want Robin
going through this alone.
Hmm, sounds like you're
gonna make great parents.
That's a
good looking baby.
Placenta looks fine.
There's no abruption.
Thank you, God.
What's going on in there?
How's the other driver doing?
Everything's fine, baby.
Don't worry.
'"This time, with
the wind aft, and a good one'
the swallow fairly raced
to the island, with her wig‐‐"
Hi, Joi.
Oh, hi.
Sorry, I couldn't
make it back down.
That's okay, I decided
to come to you instead.
‐ That's nice of you.
‐ This must be Ricky.
I'm Carol.
‐ Hi.
He just started having trouble
talking a few days ago.
He used to be
such a chatterbox.
So, I got some
terrible disease, too?
No, but your blood test
confirmed that you're anemic.
So, I brought you these
iron pills, if you take those
three times a day,
you'll feel a lot better.
And I would like you
to come back to the ER clinic
in three weeks so
I can recheck your blood.
I'll try. It's hard for me
to plan that far ahead.
Time to eat.
I've got chocolate today.
Do you have
any help with Ricky?
My daughter Celia
plays with him sometimes.
'No, I was actually
thinking more medically.'
Uh...I take care
of all that.
You know, I could arrange
for some respite care.
Someone who could watch
Ricky a couple hours a day..
...while you
regain your strength.
I appreciate the offer but
Ricky's my responsibility.
Joi, if you don't start
taking care of yourself
you're not gonna be
very much help to him
or your daughter, either.
It's my job to
see him through this.
Good effort
in there, Amanda.
You win some,
you lose some.
Oh, you know, I was trying
to find your journal article
and I came up with this,
written by A. W. Lee
picture of
a 40 year old Asian guy.
Yeah, and who was
a classmate of mine at Cornell.
And not a very good one,
I might add.
People were constantly
getting us mixed up.
So, you wrote the article,
but they printed his photo.
Yeah, they printed
a correction in the next issue
but by then,
the damage was done.
‐ And this is on the internet.
‐ Yeah.
A global source
of misinformation.
Hey, Tony, why don't
you get the, uh, editor
of the Cornell journal
of medicine for me?
Mark, it's really
not necessary.
You should get credit
for your work, Amanda.
Where's Cornell?
‐ Yes, officer?
‐ I'm following up on the MVA.
I wanted to know
how everyone was doing.
Yeah, Mrs. Gambrell
and the baby
are doing fine.
Unfortunately, the driver
of the other car expired.
And, uh,
Michael Gambrell
the driver who
caused the accident?
Just some minor cuts
and abrasions.
We have some witnesses saying
he was driving erratically.
Did you get a blood
alcohol on him?
Uh, just a CBC
and a chem panel.
Can you get
a BAL off that?
I‐I really don't think
that's necessary.
It's standard procedure.
Now, I can take him
down to the station.
I'll add it
to his orders.
Appreciate it.
Just try
and relax, Mr. Wong.
Pulse ox 87.
I can't find
the radial artery.
Try a brachial stick.
Got a pulse.
Mr. Wong, I'm going
to stick you now.
Okay?
I'm getting blood.
You see? All it takes
is a little practice.
Ow!
‐ Lily, take over for Lucy.
‐ Dr. Carter.
Go to the suture room,
flush out the wound.
I'll be right there.
Lucy.
Well, sounds like
an astronaut to me.
It's not like I'm
gonna fly the thing.
So, what's a payload
specialist do, anyway?
Onboard experiments.
This guy I went to
school with is heading up
a medical team
for next year
and just wanted to see
if I was interested.
That's some pretty intense
physical training, right?
Are you saying, I'm not
gonna be physically in shape?
Hey, you know they let
John Glenn back up there
and he's what?
Like, in his late '70s.
Thanks, Carol.
Yeah, sounds like
the opportunity
of a lifetime, you know?
It's not like you have
Rachel and Jen to tie you down.
Tie him down?
It's not like I was
looking for it.
It just kind of found me.
Yo, Dr. G!
Those A. W. Lee
articles you wanted?
They're checked out.
All of them?
By who?
‐ Didn't ask.
‐ When were they checked out?
Didn't ask.
Did that editor from
Cornell return my call?
Nah.
Listen, check with
the library
and see what else
you can find out.
Donald, can I talk to you?
‐ I'm late for surgery, Mark.
‐ It'll just take a second.
You know anybody over
at the Cornell medical school?
Hmm, can't say that I do.
Why don't you talk to Dr. Lee?
That's her Alma Mater.
You never spoke to
anybody there about her?
I didn't see the need.
You saw her letters
of recommendation.
‐ They were glowing.
‐ Yes. Yes, they were.
An old army buddy
of mine who worked with her
in Atlanta said that she was
the best resident he's ever had.
Really?
That's good to hear.
‐ If there's a problem..
‐ No, no, no problem.
Sorry to bother you.
CT just called.
They're ready
for the freaky chica.
Why don't you stick with me?
I may need your
transpo expertise.
Lucy.
I'm so sorry.
It's okay.
It was an accident.
No, I should have
warned the patient
that I was gonna
stick him.
Like you said,
risk comes with the job.
‐ Uh, let me see.
‐ What do I do?
We're gonna send a sample
of the patient's blood
down to the lab
for a rapid HIV test.
Can we do that without
his permission?
Yes, since we already
have a sample.
Let me take a look.
And if he turns out
to be HIV‐positive
which I'm sure he won't
then we'll tell him
the test results.
And if he's positive I'm gonna
have to start prophylaxis.
Well, let's just take
this one step at a time.
Okay?
Okay.
Hasn't the interpreter
arrived yet?
The nurse says she's busy
another one is
driving in from somewhere.
Okay, we really shouldn't
wait on this.
She said okay.
Grandma wants to watch.
No. No. No.
That's not necessary.
Okay. Okay. Fine.
I love you.
'I love you both.'
Okay, we're gonna be
in and out of there
in less than 20 minutes.
‐ Don't leave.
‐ Don't worry, I'm right here.
‐ How does it look, Tony?
‐ Coast is clear, captain.
Alright, Edie,
why don't you
close your eyes and
imagine yourself in..
‐ How about outer space?
‐ What?
Yeah, you know, you're floating
around the galaxy
in the black expanse
and Earth is a tiny speck
in the distance, okay?
‐ Are there cookies?
‐ Cookies? Sure. Yeah.
You can eat cookies
in outer space.
Wash them down
with Tang.
'Coming through!
'I need blood now!'
Don't...make me.
‐ Can't...Can't...
‐ Let's go back. Go back.
We're gonna go back.
Alright.
Well, let's take her back.
We're gonna take you back.
Excuse me, we've been
waiting for over 45 minutes
and no one will
tell us about our son.
I'm sorry, I'm sure
the doctor's tied up.
I don't want your damn excuses.
I wanna know about my son.
Why can't we see him?
What's going on?
What's your son's name?
Aaron Drane.
He's a private in the US Army.
He was in a car accident.
Well, I'm not
aware of his status.
But let me see
what I can find out.
He was just home on leave.
He was driving
back to base.
Look, we're gonna
go back there.
‐ You can't stop us.
‐ Just wait one minute.
Excuse me,
Mr. Drane, uh..
Mrs. Drane,
I'm officer Moore.
I'm very sorry
to have to tell you this
but your son, Aaron,
was very seriously injured
and he died.
The doctors here did everything
they could to save him.
Hi, Amanda.
What are you doing in here?
I'm cutting out some fascinating
articles on Conn's syndrome.
Aren't those
hospital copies?
Yeah.
They were extras.
You know what? Unfortunately,
I have to cancel on tonight.
There's a killer migraine
that's like a freight train
running through my head.
Oh, have you ever
tried just pressing?
You name it,
I've tried it.
I think the best thing
for me is just to go home
and pull the covers
up over my head.
But Mark and I will
definitely reschedule, okay?
‐ Okay.
Oh, Dr. Weaver.
Um, Mike Gambrell's
blood alcohol came back.
‐ "0.086."
‐ Just over the limit.
‐ Not good, huh?
‐ No. Not good at all.
I am okay.
Nothing bad can happen to me.
‐ I am in control.
‐ That's it.
Just keep nice,
positive thoughts.
‐ That's good.
‐ I am...I am in control.
‐ I am okay.
‐ How weird is that?
‐ What?
‐ Uh, nothing. Nothing.
We're just gonna, uh,
wait for the next elevator
'cause this one's full.
Alright, there it is.
One inflamed appy
with fibrinous exudate.
You know, I've never
come across a deaf doctor.
Quite an amazing feat
that she's pulled off.
Alright, preparing to clamp.
How did she manage
a residency?
Especially a surgical rotation?
A mask on,
her hands occupied.
Don't worry.
She can't read our lips.
Yeah, but still,
it's rude to talk about her
when she's standing
right in front of us.
You're absolutely right.
My apologies.
Where you been?
Phone's been ringing
off the hook.
Helping Dr. G,
get a patient to CT.
And let me tell you,
it was no picnic.
Oh, he wanted
this Cornell call.
Wonder if maybe I
should run it up to him?
I'm heading that way.
I owe you one.
Look, he had
a couple of beers
with no intention
of driving
and then, his wife
called in labor.
He killed a man.
That's involuntary manslaughter.
Yes and he's willing
to take
full responsibility
for his actions.
He just wants to stay with
his wife through the delivery.
Look, I don't like this
any more than you do
but my job is to
arrest him now.
Yeah, but should
his wife and child
have to pay as well?
Alright, he can stay
until she delivers
but then I'm
taking him in.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Great news. Mr. Wong's
test results came back.
‐ He's negative.
‐ Are you sure?
I went to the lab myself
to confirm the results.
Thank you.
‐ Thank you so much, um..
‐ Don't thank me.
I'm the one that
got you into this.
Oh, well,
I appreciate you
sticking through it
with me.
I still want you
to get tested again.
Six months, just to
be on the safe side.
Absolutely.
Oh, man,
I'm so relieved.
Tell me about it.
‐ Done?
‐ You passed with flying colors.
I'll be right in.
Why don't you go ahead
and process those?
I am okay.
Yes, you are.
'And the scan confirmed that'
'there's no bleeding
in the brain.'
'Oh, Edie, if you want
me to unstrap you'
you're gonna have to
let go of my hand.
I thought you were different.
I thought you
understood the real me.
Obviously,
I was mistaken.
Amanda, what's going on?
Unstrap.
I'm a fine Dr. Mark.
I have what it takes.
I know that.
‐ Then why did you doubt me?
‐ No!
If this is about the
article, we can talk.
‐ Why is this door locked?
‐ The door's locked?
I loved you more
than any man
has a right to be loved.
What?
'I never expected
to feel like this.'
I hate feeling like this!
Amanda, I don't know
what you're talking about!
If you just open this door..
Please!
It's too painful for me
to be near you right now.
Can we talk about this?
No.
'Can't...can't breathe!'
It's okay, it's alright.
It's okay, Edie.
Just keep breathing.
Keep breathing.
Amanda, I wanna understand.
It's too late
for that, Mark.
It's over.
But I will never forget you.
'Amanda, wait!'
Amanda, wait!
Let us out of here!
'Dying!'
It's okay.
Okay. Okay.
They were locked
in there how long?
Over an hour.
The tech decided
to take a long lunch.
Have they found Dr. Lee yet?
‐ Missing in action.
‐ Get this.
Amanda Lee, also
known as Barbara Hardin
also known
as Janice Englehart.
She never even got her MD.
‐ She's not a real doctor?
‐ Unbelievable.
From what they
can tell she stole
A.W. Lee's medical
school transcripts
and used them to get
into a residency program.
Why didn't I
think of that?
It's not her
first time, either.
According to her
records, she also posed
as a lawyer
and an architect.
Do you know how many
patients she treated?
Hospital's gonna have a
liability nightmare.
Can't believe,
I thought she was
such a good doctor.
Certainly had me fooled.
Me, too.
Wonder if my Portland
job offer was made up, too?
What job offer?
‐ Edie?
‐ Oh, Dr. Greene.
I wanna thank you.
For what? Getting you held
hostage by a crazed lunatic?
Oh, I haven't..
I haven't felt
this good in years.
That's great.
Yeah, I mean, if I can
survive this hellhole
I can survive anything.
Can I call you a cab?
No.
No, no.
I think, I'm just
gonna walk.
Cervix is at
seven centimeters.
Shouldn't be long.
We'll get you
upstairs right now.
‐ Is that him? Is that the guy?
‐ Yes, yes.
Excuse me, I'm treating
a patient here.
That son of a bitch
killed my son.
Oh, my God.
I'm sorry.
You gotta believe me.
I didn't mean for this.
What are you waiting for?
Arrest him.
Baby's heart rate is slowing.
Okay, let's get in‐‐
‐ Mike, don't leave me.
‐ I'm right here, baby.
He just wants to see his wife
through labor, alright.
'I'll stay with him.
He only needs a few more hours.'
I would have liked
a few more hours with my son.
I've got to do this.
Mr. Gambrell, you should
go with the officer.
'You can post bail.'
Hopefully you'll be back
before the birth.
I‐I'm not leaving.
I think you have to.
No, he doesn't.
We're gonna take
very good care of her.
Yeah, uh‐huh.
Um...good pick up.
So how do you think
she's gotten away
with this charade
for so long?
Obviously, Dr. Lee's
a first‐class pathological liar.
ER, if you're sick,
we'll fix you quick.
Hey, Dale.
Listen, um..
Lucy's a good kid.
So...try to be nice.
John, I'm always nice.
She told me about
getting needle‐stuck.
The guy tested
HIV‐negative, right?
‐ Yeah, thank god.
‐ I'll say.
Means I got a chance at
scoring tonight after all.
Dr. Carter do you
have a lucky number
you want me to bet on?
No, thanks.
Not feeling
very lucky tonight.
I am.
Shall we, Lucy?
Bye.
'Yes, if I must.'
'I'm trying to
apprise the CEO'
about Dr. Lee
and he keeps
putting me on hold.
I thought you should know, uh
a patient died under
hers and my care today.
Well, that's just what
I didn't need to hear.
However, I...I don't believe
either of us made any errors.
Well, I'm sure
the hospital attorneys
will wanna speak
to you about it.
I've also been
thinking about
what you said
earlier and, um..
I intend to pursue
the publication of my paper.
Yes, yes, I'm here.
Can you hold one second, please?
Well, in light of
the Amanda Lee debacle
it's obvious none of us
are above reproach.
I admire your directness.
Alright, give me a list of the
journals you'd like to submit to
and I'll attach
a cover letter.
Thank you, Donald.
Yeah.
Where were we?
‐ How we doing?
‐ She's crowning.
Mike's not gonna
make it, is he?
No, but we're gonna get
through this, Robin, okay?
Now, take a deep
breath and push.
There you go.
I'm beginning to
guide the head out.
Deep breath...
and push again.
Mark's made some bad
choices in women before
but I think he
outdid himself this time.
I knew there was
something off about her.
I don't wanna
talk about it.
Can I just ask
you a question?
Was the fire escape
thing for real?
What fire escape?
‐ Never mind.
‐ Uh‐oh.
Think we should open it?
Hmm, too thin
to be a bomb.
What is it?
"This is for you,
it is a poem
"you inspired me to write.
"Because two bodies,
naked and entwined
"leap over time,
they are invulnerable.
"Nothing can touch them.
‐ "They return to the source.
‐ "There's no you, no I
‐ No tomorrow."
Octavio Paz,
my favorite poet.
There you go.
Looks like you inspired
her to plagiarize.
Just go.
So, dinner for three?
I'm gonna hit the gym first.
Carol...I thought
I'd missed you.
Hey, Joi,
is something wrong?
I've been thinking
about what you said
about respite care.
And my daughter has
her dance recital next week.
I mean, I know it
would mean a lot to her
if I was there.
Of course, I'll make
some calls first thing
in the morning
and find someone to help.
I appreciate that.
Hey, kiddo, how you doing?
‐ Fine.
‐ Yeah?
He's got a little
conjunctivitis in his left eye.
Oh, I meant to have the doctor
upstairs take a look
but there were
so many tests.
It's alright, I'll write a
prescription for gentamicin.
We'll get him
cleared right up.
Okay.
Well, this is getting
a little ridiculous.
I was coming by to see
how the Gambrell wife
and baby are doing.
According to Dr. Weaver
both mother
and daughter are fine.
Well, I'll call in and
have them tell the dad.
It's a shame, really.
He was not a bad guy.
He just made one
really dumb mistake.
Yeah, you're right.
It is a shame.
You have
a good one, Jeanie.
‐ Hey, Reggie.
‐ Hmm?
Look, I've got
plans for tonight but
you wanna catch
a movie tomorrow night?
Let me think about it.
‐ Okay.
‐ Goodnight.
‐ Hey, Dr. Weaver.
‐ Hey.
‐ INH.
‐ Oh, you converted, huh?
Hey, your mom, she, uh,
she never called back.
My mom's dead.
Uh, I‐I was adopted.
Possible that call
was from my birth mother.
Wow.
I, uh, I didn't know.
Yeah, well, probably
a wrong number
so, false alarm.
Have you been looking for her?
I put my name on the
internet about a month ago.
My parents,
my‐my adopted parents
have been gone
about a year now, so..
Well, I would think that there'd
be agencies that‐‐
Yeah.
Yeah, there are.
There are.
Go on,
it's Friday night.
Yeah, I'm gonna miss
my curtain if I don't move it.
‐ Have a good time.
‐ 'Hey, thanks.'
'Good, hey.'
Hey.
What's happening, Reese?
Huh?
What?
Hey, hey, hey.
You know who I am?
Huh?
Reese, you know who I am?
Who am I? Huh?
Can you say "Father?"
Come on, man.
Let me show you. Look.
Can you say "Daddy?"
'Huh?'
Yes, see what
I learned, "Daddy."
See, "Daddy?"
Come on, Reese.
Eh...never mind.
Yeah.
Hey..
Hey, man.
Hey, that's it.