♪♪
We are condemned
to useless labor.
Fourth circle of hell.
Charting goes a lot faster when
you eliminate all classic poetry.
Writing down what we already
know to be read by nobody.
I'm pretty sure Dante would
agree that qualifies as useless.
You're over two weeks
behind in your charting.
Oops. I missed.
- What are you, eight?
- Could an eight-year-old do this?
You'd better stop,
or it'll stick that way.
- You have a patient in Exam One.
- Yeah, but, see, I'm off at 12:00,
and it's already five of.
She's been waiting
for you since 1 1:00.
Melancholy without
hope. Which circle is that?
Hi. I'm Dr. House.
What seems to be the problem?
Show him your hands, Augustine.
- It-It looks like stigmata.
- Shah. Pius.
You must be all the talk
around the "holy water" cooler.
Been washing a lot of dishes
recently? I help out in the kitchen.
- Anything new in the kitchen?
- We just got a donation
of saucepans and pots this week.
I unpacked and washed them.
Should have spent your time
saving souls. It's easier on the hands.
This is contact dermatitis.
You're allergic to dish soap.
Nonsense. We've always used that
soap. Why is there a problem now?
I've been a doctor for
years. Why do I have to
keep assuring people
that I know what I'm doing?
A person can become
allergic to substances...
that they've had repeated
and prolonged exposure to.
The good news is—free samples.
Diphenhydramine.
It's an antihistamine.
It'll stop the
allergic reaction.
Take one every eight hours. It
might make you feel a little sleepy.
And get some of that over-the-counter
cortisone cream. Thank you, Doctor.
You want some
water? I have some tea.
Well, you just relax for a few
minutes. That stuff works pretty fast.
♪♪ Still out by 12:00.
How do you solve a problem
like dermatitis? What?
Doctor? I want to thank
you for your patience.
She talkin' to you? I don't know.
She's certainly looking at me.
Ah, it's good to get
a secular diagnosis.
The sisters tend to interpret their
illnesses as divine intervention.
And you don't? Then you're
wearing an awfully funny hat.
Ooh, boy. Excuse me.
If I break my leg, I believe
it happened for a reason.
I believe God wanted
me to break my leg.
I also believe he wants
me to put a cast on it.
Doctor! Something’s wrong.
Lift up your chin.
Sister, you're having an
asthma attack. I need you to relax.
Roll up her sleeve, please.
I'm gonna give you epinephrine.
It'll open your lungs
and help you breathe.
What happened?
Did she take the pill?
- Yes.
- It's probably an allergic reaction.
She's allergic to an
anti-allergy medicine?
You figure somebody's
out to get her?
- How are you feeling?
- Better.
I'll put you on some
steroids instead.
Is my heart supposed
to be feeling so funny?
It's called adrenaline.
It makes your heart beat fast.
But not this fast.
Get a nurse, please. Hold on.
Help! Somebody help us!
Somebody get in here!
Call a code and charge up a
defibrillator. She's got no pulse.
You diagnosed the patient with
allergies and prescribed antihistamine.
She went into
respiratory distress,
and you injected
her with epinephrine.
Presumably 1 c.c.
.1 c.c. That is the standard
dose. That is what I gave her.
People don't go into cardiac
arrest from .1 c.c. epinephrine.
She must have a preexisting heart condition
that got exacerbated by the epinephrine.
It's too bad you didn't
make a notation in the chart.
I can make it up right now.
The drawer has syringes with both dosages.
You could have reached for the wrong—
- But I didn't.
- Everyone makes mistakes.
This is why doctors pay through
the nose for malpractice insurance.
Relax. They're not gonna sue.
The worst they'd do is
whack my hand with a ruler.
- And the discipline board—
are they gonna whack your hand too?
- You're gonna report me?
- What choice do I have?
- Uh, how about not report me?
I can justify keeping her
here for a 24-hour observation.
If you haven't found an underlying
cause for the cardiac arrest by then,
I will have to
notify our attorneys.
Her hands were red and swollen.
Maybe she has a skin infection. Cellulitis?
That could manifest with tachycardia.
There's no history of fever. Results from
the C.B.C. didn't indicate an infection.
The eosinophils are mildly
elevated. Sed rate's up a
bit. Could we be looking at
a systemic allergic response?
It's not allergic. Allergies don't
cause cardiac arrest like this.
- Could be inflammation of the blood vessels.
- Vasculitis? That wouldn't give you
an elevated eosinophil count.
Churg-Strauss vasculitis would.
The blood vessels of the heart,
lungs and skin become inflamed,
causing the asthma, rash and heart
problems—covers all her symptoms.
You need a biopsy to diagnose.
Chest C.T. would be quicker.
The lady just
came in with a rash.
What the hell are those?
Candy canes.
Candy canes? Are you mocking me?
No. It-It's Christmas, and I—
I thought— Relax. It's a joke.
Isn't the prognosis for
Churg-Strauss a bit grim?
Yeah. Untreated, only 33%
of patients survive past a year.
Treated—five years. Then I
definitely suggest treatment.
If it was any other attending doctor,
I'd say that he made a mistake...
and gave her too
much epinephrine.
Saying you wouldn't
say it was my mistake...
is saying it was my mistake.
Everyone screws up. Your rule.
I think you fit within the
subset of "everyone."
I didn't screw up.
- Order a chest C.T. and start the sister
on prednisone—40 milligrams T.I.D.
- The sister?
Oh, didn't I mention? The
patient's a nun—Sister Augustine.
I hate nuns.
Who doesn't?
♪♪
- Sister Augustine?
- We weren't watching.
We were trying to see
if this is the bed control.
Oh. Uh, this one's
the bed control.
And that's the TV control.
I'm Dr. Cameron. This is
Dr. Chase and Dr. Foreman.
I haven't seen television
in over 20 years.
Do you consider it
the work of the devil,
or do you just not get
cable where you live?
- Um— - How are
you feeling, Sister?
I seem to be a little better.
They gave me some medication.
Prednisone. It's a steroid
to help with the inflammation.
Has Dr. House
figured out what I have?
Will I be okay? We're
not sure what's wrong yet.
You'll have a chest C.T. scan this
afternoon that'll help with the diagnosis.
Dr. House is giving her medication,
and he doesn't know what she has yet?
Trust, Sister Pius. It
all happens for a reason.
He doesn't know what he's doing.
The only problem that woman has is
that House grabbed the wrong syringe.
You don't trust him? I don't trust a
man who won't admit he might be wrong.
I notice you weren't
so quick to tell her she's
got Churg-Strauss and
only has a couple years left.
I don't tell patients bad
news unless it's conclusive.
Because you know
he might be wrong.
About Churg-Strauss. Not
about what happened in the clinic.
What about you, Chase?
You think he's infallible too?
All I know is, if House
didn't make a mistake
and Sister Augustine
has Churg-Strauss,
he'll be self-satisfied and our
lives will be good for a few weeks.
If House did make a
mistake, he'll be upset
and our lives will be
miserable for months.
There is that.
If Cuddy thinks I made
a mistake, the least
she could do is suspend
me from clinic duty.
She doesn't confuse making a
mistake with being incompetent.
Oh, here we go—lesson time.
I recognize that confidence
is not my short suit.
I also recognize that I am
human and capable of error.
So you might have
screwed this up? No.
So it's merely a theoretical
capacity for error. Good point.
Maybe there isn't one.
Maybe that's my error.
Most people who think as much of themselves
as you do like to talk about themselves.
Most people don't like to listen.
So, what's wrong with you?
Let me guess—inflammatory bowel.
Wow. Yeah. Is it that bad? Yes.
It's also written on your chart.
"Bloody diarrhea, gas, pain.
Took sulfasalazine,
but it didn't work."
- No. Then-Then I— -
"Next, tried steroid enemas.
Oral corticosteroids—
5-A.S.A., 6-mercaptopurine."
- I'm impressed.
- By my medical history?
By how well your
last doctor charted.
It's one thing to have to go
to the bathroom every hour,
but when the kids
sit on my lap, it's...
The store sent me home.
They're gonna fire me.
Can't you put me back on 5-A.S.A.?
Maybe it'll work this time. Not likely.
I'm giving you a prescription.
It's cheap, which is good,
because your insurance
company won't pay for it.
- "Cogaritis"?
- Cigarettes.
One twice a day.
No more, no less.
Studies have shown
that cigarette smoking...
is one of the most effective ways
to control inflammatory bowel.
Plus it's been well established
that you look 30% cooler.
- Are you kidding me?
- About the looking cooler, yeah.
- The rest is true.
- Isn't it addictive and dangerous?
Pretty much all the drugs I
prescribe are addictive and dangerous.
The only difference with this
one is it's completely legal.
Merry Christmas.
I was talking to the nurse—
Arsenio. Do you know him?
Not really. He can take
pictures with his phone.
Cool. That woman from
the lab was interesting too.
She studied astrophysics
before becoming a nurse.
You know the staff better than I
do. I love to hear all about people.
- Yet you live in a monastery.
- It's where I serve our Lord
and the world best.
Our Lord maybe. The rest of
the world, on the other hand,
- would probably get more out of feeding
the homeless or— - Healing the sick?
As an example, yeah. Did
you always want to be a doctor?
Always. You always want to be a
nun? My parents died when I was six.
I was raised in a foster
home run by the Church.
When I was 18, I went to the monastery,
where they let me take my vows.
I've known no other life,
and I haven't wanted to.
Okay, Sister. We need
you to lie as still as possible.
If you get scared,
just let us know.
As Jonah said from
inside the whale,
"When I had lost all hope, I
turned my thoughts to the Lord."
- Well, she's got God on her side.
- I don't believe in God.
You're not even
a little agnostic?
Is it supposed to smell funny?
Someone ralphed in there this
morning. We cleaned it up, but...
It's normal, Sister. It's
just a few more minutes.
Mm.
I believe in a higher order
that's in control of what happens,
but not one, anthropomorphic
entity called "God"...
that's concerned with the
everyday workings of you and me.
What else is there to control but
the everyday workings of you and me?
It's always about you, Foreman.
What are you talking
about— The trees, the fish?
Should they be the ones
that think it's all about them?
What about you, Chase?
Do you believe in God?
I believe Sister Augustine has no vascular
pathology, which means no Churg-Strauss.
Which means House made a
mistake. No, not necessarily.
It could be something else— thyrotoxicosis
or a carcinoid. I don't get you.
You don't believe in God, but you're
willing to put complete faith in one man?
Please. The smell.
Let's get her out of there.
I'm coming, Sister. I gotcha.
Please. The smell. I'm comin'.
I'm gonna be sick.
There's no smell.
No. God. Oh! It’s
Jesus. It’s Jesus!
He's coming for me!
He's burning me with his touch!
Let's get her on some Ativan.
The smells, religious visions— It's
symptomatic of temporal lobe swelling.
- We don't want her
to— - She's seizing.
- Jaw block!
- Help me get her on her side.
- Religious visions?
- Yeah. And next comes...
Patient tested positive
for herpetic encephalitis.
- What's that tell us?
- Her immune system
is severely compromised.
Oh, I know. Prednisone
compromises the immune system.
- Isn't that the medicine that you gave her
for that thing she doesn't have?
- Yeah, that— Hey.
- I'm thinking that's a trick question.
- Her immune system
is severely compromised.
Two doses of prednisone
wouldn't do that.
Are you hanging your
diagnosis on an adverb?
- In 10 seconds, I'm going to announce that
I gave her the wrong dose in the clinic.
- You're gonna admit negligence?
Unless you leave the room. If
you stay, you'll have to testify.
Five, four,
three, two...
So, there I was
in the clinic, drunk.
I opened the drawer,
closed my eyes,
take the first
syringe I can find—
So, what are the options for a
compromised immune system?
Mixed connective tissue
disease. It'd explain
why she was feeling
better on the prednisone.
Sure. She was feeling better right
up to the moment it almost killed her.
On the other hand, it
explains the symptoms—
Swollen hands, pulmonary
problems, cardiac problems.
It all fits. Except her
A.N.A. was normal.
- So redraw the blood.
- But the treatment is corticosteroids...
Prednisone—and we can't go
there because of the encephalitis.
Then we'll treat it with
something that modulates
the immune system
but doesn't suppress it...
Hyperbaric oxygen chamber.
There's no protocol
for putting a patient in a
high-pressure oxygen room
to treat auto-immune problems.
Oh, you people. Always
with the protocols.
Prep the nun and
discontinue the prednisone.
I am both amused and annoyed...
that you think I should be
less stubborn than you are.
You are aware of the
Hippocratic oath, right?
The one that starts,
"First, do no harm," then
goes on to tell us no
abortions, no seductions,
and definitely no cutting of those
who labor beneath the stone?
Yeah. I took a read
once. Wasn't impressed.
Hyperbaric treatments could cause
oxygen toxicity—lung and eye damage.
Every treatment has its dangers.
Which is why we only treat...
if we're convinced the patient
actually needs the treatment.
I'm convinced. You're not.
Question is, what are you
gonna do about it? Hmm?
I have an opening Thursday
at 3:00. Do you have a fourth?
Is he any good?
Can I call you right back? Okay.
What's up?
The pressure will force the oxygen
into your system, saturate your blood.
It will enhance white cell
activity, reduce the inflammation.
And that will help with this
mixed connective tissue disease?
We'll be doing about 10
treatments, and then we'll reevaluate.
The last treatment with prednisone
caused the seizures, right?
How confident is
Dr. House about this?
That you reacted so strongly
to the prednisone let us know...
that you had an underlying
problem with your immune system.
I guess it was a
blessing... of sorts.
So, who's your favorite
reindeer, Nurse Arnold?
Rudolph. I would've
thought it was Vixen.
What are you implying? Nothing.
But I saw you at the
Christmas party with Dr. Riles...
and Dr. Jorkins
and Nurse Crandall.
I was just doing some
Christmas dancing.
This is a chapel,
a house of prayer.
House of prayer? Huh.
That explains the
good reception.
Also why nobody's ever here.
I need to talk with
you, Dr. House.
Sister Augustine believes
in things that aren't real.
I thought that was a job
requirement for you people.
She's been known
to lie to get sympathy.
She's a hypochondriac.
So you're warning me that I may
be treating a nonexistent ailment.
Sore throats, joint pains.
There's always something wrong,
and there's never a reason for it.
Mother Superior
plays right into it...
Lets Augustine off work duties,
treating her as
fragile, special.
That must make you angry.
It bothers me.
It's not really in
Augustine's best interests.
You want some?
I shouldn't.
I guess you gotta be good at reading
people to be a good infirmarian, huh?
Mm. Mm-hmm.
So, we've got pride,
anger, envy, gluttony...
That's four out of seven
deadly sins in under two minutes.
Do you people keep records of
these things? Is there a "Cathlympics"?
They say you have a
gift. They like to talk.
- You hide behind your intelligence.
- Yeah. That's pretty stupid.
And you make jokes because
you're afraid to take anything seriously.
Because if you take
things seriously, they matter.
And if they matter— When
things go wrong, I get hurt.
- I'm not tough. I'm vulnerable.
- I barely know you.
And I don't know if I'm
right. I just hope I am.
Because the alternative is...
you really are as miserable
as you seem to be.
You know, from the way
you're looking at me right now,
I'd say you just
hit number five.
Lust.
Dr. Brown, I love you too.
How are you
feeling? A little weak.
- That's from the oxygen.
- My mouth is dry.
Okay. Well, uh, I'll get
you some of your tea.
Mixed connective tissue disease?
Her A.N.A. is barely elevated.
Thanks for checking up on her.
Good to know you got my back.
O₂ sat's down to 83. Pulmonary
problems, breathing problems.
Irritation from the
oxygen is typical.
She comes in with a rash, and
you put her into cardiac arrest.
That well just never
runs dry, does it?
If there was no underlying problem, why
is she still having the rapid heart rate?
Maybe from the herpetic encephalitis
caused by you giving her prednisone.
Her reaction is a
symptom, not an error.
There's always an explanation,
isn't there? Yes, there is.
And if this one
doesn't work, we'll find
another. But never one
involving you screwing up.
One that fits all the facts.
Look, we obviously have a
difference of opinion, and that's fine.
But, unfortunately, I've
used up all the time I
budgeted today for banging
my head against a wall.
I'm gonna do you the biggest
favor one doctor can do for another.
I am gonna stop you
from killing your patient.
You're off the case.
We're gonna treat the symptoms.
Not the underlying condition?
There is no underlying
condition. What's her status?
The sister's
breathing is labored.
Pneumonitis from the
hyperbaric chamber.
Put her on 40% oxygen until her O₂sats
increase. B.U.N. and creatinine's rising.
A.L.T. and A.S.T.
twice the normal range.
Could be from the hypotensive
episode. Let's follow them with labs.
She still has the rash and
joint pain she came in with.
Order a nonsteroidal
anti-inflammatory. When we were
looking at the differential
diagnosis with Dr. House,
we were considering— I don't need to
hear what Dr. House was considering.
All of this woman's symptoms can be
traced to Dr. House's considerations.
Okay.
Let's just get this
patient healthy.
I want her going out the
front door and not the back.
Hey, it's not like
I betrayed him.
Cuddy would have found out about
the hyperbaric treatments eventually.
You did what you
thought you had to.
Can't get enough
of this place, huh?
Came for my stethoscope.
So I shouldn't read too much into
the fact that you were looking for it...
in the drawer with the
epinephrine syringes in it?
Okay. Yeah, I'd like
to clear my reputation.
Oh, right. I forgot how much
you care about what people think.
Prescribing cigarettes
for inflammatory bowel?
That's, uh—They cause
lung cancer, you know.
You know why they have
ribbons for breast cancer,
colorectal cancer, prostate
cancer— And not for lung cancer?
They ran out of colors?
It's because people
blame lung cancer patients.
They smoke. They screwed
up. They deserve to die.
The reason people die
from lung cancer is guilt.
Huh. Well, guilt
does a lot of damage.
You said that with
great significance.
You're not here to find your stethoscope.
You're not here to clear your reputation.
You're here because you're having
doubts. You might have screwed up.
I'm here because, if I'm right,
Cuddy is killing that patient.
Okay. But if you’re wrong?
Then she's saving her. Fine.
You're gonna have to go through
every record of every patient...
who's been through this
clinic in the last two days.
And you're gonna have to hope
that those records can be trusted.
Which, by the way, yours can't.
These pills will help your kidneys
function a little better, Sister.
Get your wrist?
What's that?
104.
Is that good? It's fine.
You're a lousy liar, Dr. Chase.
I have to get this. Excuse me.
My mother's been
dead for 10 years.
But she's always
with you in spirit.
What do you know about
the nun? Which one?
The cute one. I
think she likes me.
- The sick one, obviously.
- Her parents died when she was a child.
She's been with the Church
ever since. What's she lying about?
- Why do you say that?
- I always say that.
And the old nun thinks the
sick nun is a big fat nun liar.
You know nuns. What do
you think? I don't know nuns.
You hate nuns. You can't hate
someone if you don't know them.
Know any Nazis? Maybe
I hate them on principle.
I have a theory about what
makes good boys good.
It's not because of
some moral imperative.
Good boys have the
fear of God put into them.
Catholic Church specializes
in that kind of training...
To make good boys
afraid of divine retribution,
so they'll do what
their daddies tell them...
Like, for example,
going into medical school
when it's the last
thing they wanna do.
What do you think?
I think, if she did have a
secret, her boss would know.
Did you paint or put in
new carpets recently? No.
Any way she could
have got access to drugs?
We lock all our
medications in the infirmary,
and we don't keep
prescription drugs here.
Why haven't you asked Sister
Augustine about these things directly?
I've found that when you want
to know the truth about someone,
that someone is probably
the last person you should ask.
Ah. And have you been
speaking to Sister Eucharist?
She ratted out her fellow
sister pretty quickly. Oh.
If I were you, I'd have her
repeat a year of nun school.
Well, becoming a nun
doesn't make you a saint.
Becoming a doctor
doesn't make you a healer.
And just because we live in a monastery,
and we spend most of our time in prayer,
doesn't mean we don't
find time for drama.
So, what is the
sick one's drama?
Sister Augustine lived in Catholic
foster care until she came to us.
- Tea?
- Sure.
Do all of you lie?
It's a good strategy; it's simpler
when you all tell the same lie.
She has not spent her
entire life as a good Catholic.
When she had a cardiac arrest, I
had to open her blouse to do C. P. R.
And I learned two things:
nuns can have nice breasts,
and she has a tattoo on
her shoulder— Of a skunk.
Now, maybe it's the
sacred skunk of Joseph,
but, as far as I know, Catholic
foster care and monasteries...
do not keep tattoo
parlors in their refectories.
We consider that
our life begins...
when we put on our
habits and take our vows.
- What happens before then— - Is
irrelevant to you, but it's relevant to me.
Sister Augustine went into foster
care when she was six years old,
but she left when she was 12.
She lived on the streets.
She got into drugs.
When she was 15,
she became pregnant.
Tried to self-abort.
She lost the child.
She became ill.
We took her in
when she came back.
If we had thought it was medically
relevant, we would have told you.
It's not.
This tea is delicious.
Local herbs?
Any change with the medication?
Yes. She's getting worse.
Lung function's deteriorating. B.U.N.
and creatinine continuing to rise.
She's starting to run a fever,
and the rash is spreading.
At this rate, she's not gonna make
Christmas. Maybe House is right.
Maybe there is an underlying
condition that explains the symptoms.
Something we haven't
considered. Like what?
It could be a metabolic
disorder. Specifically?
Might be genetic. Specifically?
I'm just saying— You're just
saying you think House is right.
Might be right. Of
course he might be right.
It might be the hand of God at
work. Don't say it's something else...
unless you've got
something concrete to offer.
What's this, hemlock?
I'm gonna do you the biggest
favor one doctor can do another.
I'm gonna stop you
from killing your patient.
It's figwort tea—
Great for that little
pick-me-up we're all
looking for in the morning.
Opens the lungs, increases the
blood pressure, stimulates the heart.
Unfortunately, if you then get injected
with even .1 c.c. of epinephrine...
Instant cardiac arrest.
- Still, what the hell, it tastes great.
- Sister Augustine...
Has been drinking it
religiously, so to speak.
And if you take the cardiac
arrest out of the equation...
All the rest of the
symptoms can be explained
by a severe long-term
allergic reaction.
Well, that's what Cameron
said in the beginning.
Yes, she did. Well done.
But your unwillingness to stick by
your diagnosis almost killed this woman.
Take a lesson from Foreman—
Stand up for what you believe.
Okay. Let's go figure
out how to save a nun.
Damned if you do,
damned if you don't.
Because it's been
untreated for so long,
it's gone from a simple "watery
eyes, scratchy throat" allergy...
to a whopping "I'm gonna
kick your ass" allergy...
Compromising her immune
system, diminishing her
ability to heal and breaking
down her organ systems.
- So, what's the source?
- The dish soap.
No. The symptoms persisted
days after the dish-washing episode.
It's gotta be something
she's been exposed to
here in the hospital as
well as the monastery.
What about the tea? It
caused her arrhythmia.
Could be, but
it's not definitive.
- We'll skin-test for allergens.
- Not yet. She's too reactive.
She tests positive to everything.
We need to stabilize her...
Isolate her from all possible
allergens— Give her system a rest.
Get her in a clean room. Okay.
Then gradually introduce
allergens and see how she responds.
When she reacts to something,
we'll know that's what's killing her.
There you go. No
television, no books.
- Not even my Bible?
- I'm afraid not.
This room has filtered
air, filtered water.
You even have silk sheets—
Very decadent and hypoallergenic.
You should be
feeling better here.
We'll be back to check
on you in a little while.
Can the other sisters
come in and pray with me?
It'd be better if you
don't have any visitors.
Once we isolate what's
causing your allergy,
then we can be
a little more lax.
I-I can pray with you.
I don't wanna die.
Why has he left me?
I was in seminary school.
They asked us once what
our favorite passage was.
I chose First Peter,
chapter one, verse seven.
"These trials only test your faith to
see whether or not it is strong and pure.
Your faith is being tested, as
fire tests gold and purifies it."
"And your faith is far more
precious to the Lord than mere gold.
"So if your faith remains
strong after being tested,
"it will bring you much
praise and glory and honor...
on the day of his return."
He hasn't left you.
The only thing in the way of you
knowing he's there is your fear.
You have a choice—faith
or fear. That's the test.
Choosing faith doesn't
mean I won't die.
But it will affect how you
experience your death...
and, therefore, your life.
It's up to you.
Why did you leave
seminary school?
That test.
You passed. I didn't.
We'll call you if anything
changes. Will she be all right?
As long as she's not
exposed to anything that
can aggravate her
allergy, she'll be fine.
I need some help in here!
Screw the procedure!
She's in anaphylactic shock!
No way. She's in a damn
clean room. You kidding me?
Get in here!
- . - 1 c. c. of epi.
- We've got to intubate.
I got it. Get the ambu bag.
I'm in.
Breathing's stabilized.
It's a clean room.
How do you get an allergic
reaction in a clean room?
Maybe it was the preservatives
in the I.V.? Checked that.
Latex tubing? Checked
that. Checked everything.
Well, it could be mast cell
leukemia. It can cause anaphylaxis.
I checked the blood levels, and it's not
eosinophilia or idiopathic anaphylaxis.
Maybe it's just divine will.
It's not my will.
You do realize, if you're wrong—
About the big picture, that is...
You're going to burn, right?
What do you want me to
do— Just accept it, pack it in?
Yeah. I want you to accept that
sometimes patients die against all reason,
and sometimes they get
better against all reason.
No, they don't. We just
don't know the reason.
I think the nuns would
agree with you on that.
I just wanted to say that I know
that you did everything you could.
I don't need verification from you
to know that I'm doing my job well.
That's your problem, not
mine. I was just being nice.
Yeah, well, you don't
need to always do that.
Merry Christmas.
Sister Augustine's
been extubated.
Good. She's requested to
check out, against medical advice.
She wants to go
back to the monastery.
Well, talk her out of it.
I think I may have
talked her into it.
Room's paid up for
the rest of the week.
Might as well stick around.
This illness... is
a test of my faith.
If it's his will to take me, it
doesn't matter where I am.
I can accept that.
Does anybody believe
anything you say?
You're not accepting.
You're running away.
Just like you always do.
You ran away from the
monastery to get laid.
You ran away from the real world
when getting laid didn't work out so good.
Now things aren't working
out again, so off you go.
Why is it so difficult for
you to believe in God?
What I have difficulty with is
the whole concept of belief.
Faith isn't based on
logic and experience.
I experience God
on a daily basis...
and the miracle
of life all around...
The miracle of birth,
the miracle of love.
He is always with me.
Where is the miracle in
delivering a crack-addicted baby?
Hmm?
Then watching her mother abandon
her 'cause she needs another score.
Miracle of love.
You're over twice
as likely to be killed...
by the person you
love than by a stranger.
Are you trying to talk
me out of my faith?
You can have all the faith you
want in spirits and the afterlife...
and heaven and hell.
But when it comes to
this world, don't be an idiot.
'Cause you can tell me that you put your
faith in God to get you through the day,
but when it comes time to cross
the road, I know you look both ways.
I don't believe he is inside
me and is going to save me.
I believe he is inside
me whether I live or die.
Then you might as well live.
You got a better shot
betting on me than on him.
When I was 15,
I was on every kind of
birth control known to man...
And I still got pregnant.
I blamed God. I hated
him for ruining my life.
But then I realized something.
You can't be angry with God and
not believe in him at the same time.
No one can. Not
even you, Dr. House.
How'd it go? She
has God inside her.
It would have been
easier to deal with a tumor.
Maybe she's allergic to God?
We've looked everywhere for an allergen
that could be causing this reaction...
except one place—inside her.
On her medical history, she didn't
mention any surgery. She had one.
Can we get her records? What hospital was
it at? She didn't have it at a hospital.
Order a full body scan.
What if she refuses?
Tell her I'm looking
for a miracle.
No Piercings. No fillings.
No surgical pins in
the arm. No implants.
It's clean as a whistle.
What's House looking for?
- What is that?
- Don't know.
Lock on it. Get a
3-D representation.
Oh, my God.
The copper cross—a form of birth
control pulled off the market in the '80s.
- So she's allergic to copper.
- Rare, but it happens.
Wouldn't she know
she had an I.U.D.?
She had an abortion.
I.U.D. must have been left in,
embedded in the endometrial
tissue where it couldn't be detected.
So, all we have to do
is remove the I.U.D.
Then the symptoms
should subside.
I got this I.U.D. when I was 15.
It-It's been more than 20 years.
Prolonged exposure to an
allergen with minimal symptoms.
But at some point. all it takes is one last
contact to cause a full-blown reaction.
Just like a balloon filled with
air— One last breath, it explodes.
The first time I got the rash was when
I was washing the copper cookware.
And all your subsequent symptoms
came from ingesting food prepared in it.
Dr. House found his miracle.
I doubt he'll
interpret it that way.
You told me your
favorite passage.
Would you like to hear mine?
"Celebrate and be glad,
because your brother was
dead and is alive again."
The prodigal son.
He'll be waiting for
you when you're ready.
We'll schedule your
surgery for tomorrow.
The sixth circle of hell.
Confined in a sweat box with a bloody
nose, and all the tissues are soggy.
I think that's the seventh.
No. The seventh is...
God, you must be fun at parties. I
think we both know the flaw in that theory.
How's the sister? Heart rate
is normal, kidneys functioning.
You know how it is
with nuns. You take out
their I.U.D.'s, they
just bounce right back.
Great. Told you
I didn't screw up.
You screwed up. I gave
her .1 c.c. of epinephrine.
Yeah, and if Cuddy hadn't taken you
off the case, you would have killed her.
You wanna come over
for Christmas dinner?
You’re Jewish. Yeah.
Hanukkah dinner.
What do you care? It's
food. It's people. No, thanks.
Maybe I'll come to your place. Your wife
doesn't mind being alone at Christmas?
I'm a doctor. She's
used to being alone.
I don't wanna talk
about it. Neither do I.
You did good with the nun.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Merry Christmas,
Dr. House. Dr. Wilson.
Good night.
That was sweet.
♪♪
That's some bad hat, Harry.