News at this hour.
An investigation's
underway into a fire
that claimed two
abandoned buildings...
Mayor Daley welcomes
tourists from Eastern Europe
and Dante the cat is
rescued from the parapet
of the Sears Tower.
WMAQ Sports: White
Sox beat the Brewers.
WMAQ Business:
Dow-Jones Industrials
start the day 14 points higher.
♪ All news, 67... WMAQ! ♪
53 degrees at 5:46.
I'm Pat Cassidy.
Now, WMAQ Traffic and Business.
Here's Captain Tom
Johnson in Jetcopter 67.
We're out east of the dumps now.
Dundee, most of the way
into the Kennedy merge.
47 minutes Lake-Cook into...
My, uh... my mother's not
getting enough exercise.
We're doing everything possible.
Why are you still
feeding her in her room?
We can't move every
resident into the dining hall.
No, I want her to eat
with everybody else.
She needs to be
around other people.
When she gets better, she
can participate in more activities.
She's not going to get better
unless you keep her mobile.
If your mother
were strong enough,
she'd get more exercise.
You promised hydrotherapy.
You said you had
a full-time staff.
We'll do more when she's ready.
What do I have to do?
Do I have to come down
here and supervise it myself?
Dr. Benton, your
mother broke her hip.
She won't heal overnight.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Mom, Chloe doesn't
have any insurance.
If you could spare a
couple hundred dollars...
Dr. Lewis?
I got to go, Mom. Bye.
Yeah?
Our chief resident in?
Uh, he should be
here any minute.
We have tourists tonight...
Joint Commission surveyors.
I need him for two
hours after his shift.
Rolando!
Yeah?
I love chaos, but
this is overdoing it.
I'm a little slow today.
I got a cold. I'm sorry.
Call a replacement, go home.
Is he a jerk?
I don't know yet.
Carter?!
Fadenhecht, Isidore.
Caught in a metal press.
Multiple lacs, B.P., 80/30.
Pulse 135, thready.
This guy's a mess.
How much blood loss?
500 cc's.
Okay, let's move him up slow.
He's busted up enough.
On three. One... two... three.
I'll order o-neg.
Mental status at scene?
GCS 344, complained
of back pain.
No kidding.
Stopped 18 minutes ago.
Cross table C-spine.
What size tube?
Give me a seven.
Call Respiratory. Put
him on a ventilator.
Pulse is weak, B.P.'s falling
Give me three, large-bore IVs,
normal saline, wide open.
Tube's in.
Bag him.
Dr. Ross, I'm not getting
a pulse down here.
Find a surgeon
before this guy loses his leg.
Call X ray.
Cross-check the C-spine.
Rolando, Dr. Ross is still
waiting on the surgeon.
I'm on with him now...
20 minutes is no good!
Carter, I thought you were
reorganizing my X rays.
Dr. Ross needs
you... Crush case.
He's in trouble, Peter.
He's absent femoral, popliteal
and dorsalis pedis pulses.
No cap refill. X rays back yet?
Not yet.
Flexed, internally
rotated and shortened.
What is it, Carter?
Uh, a fracture? Mm-mm.
Posterior dislocation.
All right, give me
some room here.
Carter, hold his pelvis down.
Doug, stabilize his neck.
Yep.
One...
two... three.
I felt a pop.
Good.
It's back in.
Distal pulse is back.
Well done, Peter.
Call Ortho.
You saved his leg.
Yeah, well...
legs are something
I can save today.
Captioning sponsored
by WARNER BROS.
Mark?
Hi. Hi.
How'd it go with Jen?
Oh, I never got there.
She didn't want me to come up.
Oh.
Uh, Wild Willie wants you
to stay after your shift.
Can't do it.
You want to earn points,
now's the time...
if you still want
to be an attending.
Mark?
She said I could
come up tonight.
I have to make a 7:30 train.
You know, I remember
when we used to fight.
We wouldn't talk
for a couple of days
but I always knew that
things would work out.
This time, I'm not so sure.
What do you use for
Legionnaire's disease?
Erythromycin. You
studying for the boards?
They're four months away.
I'm bad on tests.
Doug, got a kid coming in
with sudden hearing loss.
I'll take the baby in two.
Okay.
Carter, you decide
about next year?
I'm waiting on
that surgical sub-i.
What about the E.R. sub-i?
Mark would recommend you.
You think so?
Yeah.
He's studying again.
I heard they raised
the boards' failure rate.
What?
Carter, Dr. Benton
needs you in Four.
Yeah, it went up to ten percent.
What, seven
students fail last year?
Seven? Yep.
Dr. Ross? Mm-hmm?
Katie's got a problem.
Hey, Katie, what
can we do for you?
Come here.
Katie's kind of shell-shocked.
Shell-shocked, as in combat?
She can't hear a thing.
It's take-your-
daughter-to-work day.
She pulled her muffs
off on the firing range.
Katie, do you hear ringing?
What?
Come here.
You hear this?
What is that?
That's louder.
All right, Wendy, call ENT
for audiometry.
I want to rule out any
middle ear damage.
Okay, where do you work?
Great Lakes Naval Base.
I took her to morning
gunnery exercises.
I always wondered
why there's a naval base
on Lake Michigan.
Who's going to
invade, the Canadians?
It only happens
when he's eating.
Uh-huh. Hold still, Henry.
But not in the mornings.
Bounding pulses.
Every night, his lips turn blue.
Leonard, please, let him listen.
It's his heart, isn't it?
Leonard, don't start.
It's not your fault.
It's my family's genes.
They all have heart problems.
We need a chest
X ray and an EKG.
Go on, tell me.
Uh, I hear a murmur.
There you go.
It's his heart, isn't it?
I think so.
Girl coming in. Head trauma.
Page Benton, will you?
Fickle finger of fate
gets you every time.
Wanted my daughter
to be a doctor.
But you can't get
what you want from life.
She's a hostess at a
Hungarian restaurant.
You know, the capital is Budapest,
where Zsa Zsa Gabor was born.
Pushed her around,
locked her up for no reason...
Mrs. Dibble, Mrs. Dibble,
you need to stay in bed.
Why? What's wrong with me?
You stopped taking your lithium.
Malik, can you take
Mrs. Dibble to three?
Okay, let's go, Mrs. Dibble.
Don't touch me. I am coming.
Ooh, you're a big man.
You could be a body builder.
You're so handsome.
We could go to
my place for dinner.
We'd have a lot of fun.
Bi-polar.
They found her in Grant Park.
She was sweeping the sidewalks.
I feel lucky to have the
right brain chemicals.
You okay?
Fine. How's Chloe?
She wears all my clothes,
never washes the dishes,
forgets to feed the cat.
She's coming in
today for an ultrasound.
You sound so enthusiastic.
I'll help her out,
but she's not going
to run my life, Mark.
No, I'm not going
to do it, not this time.
Dr. Greene.
I need you for two hours
at the end of your shift.
Joint Commission survey.
I can't. It's a bad night.
It sure is.
It's going to rain.
I need you here.
I have personal business.
Personal? Since
when does a resident
have a personal life?
I'm sorry. I do tonight.
Well, I... I guess
I'll do it myself.
Screw him.
Do what you have to do.
We found her
passed out in the hall.
She must have slipped.
Are you her mother?
I'm her homeroom teacher.
She was bleeding
all over the place.
She's hypotensive,
Peter, 60 palp.
Let's take her and shake her
on my count: one, two, three.
Haleh, cut off this bandage.
She's breathing really hard.
Does she use drugs?
No, no, not Samantha, I'm sure.
Bleeding's controlled.
Does Samantha have
a history of seizures?
I don't know.
Pupils reactive to light.
What do you think, Carter?
Could be a blood clot,
bleeding in the brain,
uh, seizure disorder...
No posturing.
Let's get a head CT.
CBC, chem 7.
Haleh, run a blood sugar.
B.P.'s down to 60/nothing.
Arrhythmia, v-tach!
Oh, she's crashing!
What the hell is happening?
All right, come on, paddles!
Move!
One hundred.
Clear!
No. I hate psychiatrists.
You've put this off long enough.
A guy kicked his
daughter out a window
and I slugged him,
and he deserved it.
Go see the shrink, Doug.
I got past the residency review
and the guy didn't sue.
I need to close the file.
Allen Murphy,
room 607, 3:00 p.m.
All right.
Are you saving my
ass because it's your job
or because I'm so wonderful?
Why don't we just say
I'm sort of fond of you?
Ouch.
I tell you, I get
kidney infections.
As a urologist, you
should know better.
Why didn't you take Bactrim?
"Physician, heal thyself."
We never do.
Where do you practice?
Uh, Seattle. Evangeline.
We have a great E.R. there,
but the weather stinks.
Ah! T-That's it!
Flank tenderness right...
Temp, 98.9.
Get me 100 meperidine for pain.
Let's make the diagnosis first.
Doc, it hurts like hell.
Dr. Strong, I'm sure
your diagnosis is correct
but let's get a urinalysis
just to make sure.
B.P.'s still down.
Her glucose is
through the roof. 600.
Oh, God, it's not seizures.
Haleh, I.V. loading dose
regular insulin ten units.
Start an infusion
five units an hour.
Carter, come here.
The coma's not from head trauma.
Take a whiff.
It smells like fruit.
Diabetic coma.
She's in ketoacidosis.
The breathing is Kussmaul's.
Get a blood gas.
Run in a liter of
saline wide open.
Did she eat anything today?
We had a birthday party.
She had chocolate cake
and, I think, some ice cream.
Will she be okay?
Why is a diabetic
eating all that sugar?
I didn't know she was diabetic.
Oh, great.
Haleh, let me know
when the chem 7's back.
I want a potassium
every 30 minutes.
I can turn the
case over to Ross.
I said I want a potassium.
Carter, stitch her head.
What do you want, 6-0 nylon?
Seven and a half blood...
I have nightmares
that I'm getting married
in a peach wedding gown.
I kind of like peach.
You don't wear it every day.
Yeah. Why do nurses wear colors
and doctors wear white?
Because doctors
are pure and good.
Does that include me?
No.
A Linda Farrell called.
Linda Farrell. That
sounds familiar.
Uh, you used to date her?
Oh, that's right.
Dr. Greene, Rescue 64's
bringing in a bleeding drunk.
I thought he went home.
Oh, Mark, Tag and I
need a ring bearer
for the wedding.
We'd love to have Rachel.
Oh, that'd be great.
I'm not sure where
we're going to be in May,
if Rach is going
to be down here,
but, well, I'll have
to ask Jennifer,
but I'm sure it'll be fine.
Okay.
Susie! Hey.
Oh, my jacket fits nice.
You look great.
I don't feel so great.
I'm kind of scared.
Don't worry, it'll be okay.
I broke your blender.
I was trying to
make a milk shake.
Blenders break.
Why are you being so nice to me?
Because you're not going
to screw up anymore, right?
Let's find your room,
get you a full physical.
Vomiting blood.
B.P. 90/60.
Smells like he's been
putting it away all day.
What's your name, sir?
Screw off, bitch!
Just what I need today.
Let's move him
on one, two, three.
Aah! My stomach!
Chest X ray, EKG.
Mary!
That '66 Malibu.
Best engine Chevy ever made.
What's your name, sir?
Reicher.
I like that M-MG. '56.
That was a great car.
I like the Triumph myself.
Set up for endoscopy.
Who are you?
Where am I?
How much did you drink today?
Ah, stuff it, will you?
We'll need to sedate him.
Droperidol, 2.5 migs.
Set up the suction.
He'll need a Foley.
I'll do it. Uh,
you get the back.
I'm going to puke!
Don't do it on the floor.
We're going to get you a basin.
Suction on, give me the scope.
Okay, is he, uh,
doped up enough?
He seems pretty out of it.
Running it wide open.
All right, this is a test.
Are we looking at a
peptic ulcer, varices
or Mallory-Weiss?
Peptic ulcer. Varices.
You're both right.
Get the bi-cap, let's
cauterize the bleeder.
Mr. Reicher, can you hear me?
You're going to be fine.
You drank yourself into an ulcer
and now the taxpayers
are going to buy you out of it.
Mark, is he stable?
They need you on seven
for residents' meeting.
I'll finish this.
All right, thanks.
We have to get
Radiology down here.
Blood sugar's 95.
Did you take care of me today?
Yes, and you
should be lying down.
I'm getting my medicine now.
Do I look old to you?
No, you don't.
I feel old.
I feel like nothing good
is ever going to happen to me.
I'm sorry.
I've been begging
Psych to take her.
It's hard to be happy.
You can't try.
It comes or it doesn't.
Blood pressure's normal. PH 7.3.
Run a rhythm strip.
Give her 20 milliequivalents
KCL over an hour.
We got ahold of her mother.
Good.
Well, at least her
heart is steady.
Looks like she didn't
take her insulin today.
Looks like she
didn't take it all week.
Run a potassium
every 30 minutes.
Let me know.
Peter, she's not
a surgical patient.
You don't have to do this.
Just keep me posted.
I think it's the flu.
He told me to go home.
Can you come in?
Hurry.
Ronson's discharged.
Loomis to X ray.
Excuse me. I'm looking
for Lewis Reicher.
Oh, we have a Lew Reicher.
My husband... is he all right?
Maybe we reached
the wrong family.
No, he's my husband.
Did he talk about his cars?
He likes to talk about his cars.
Mrs. Reicher, your
husband's fine now,
but he does have
a bleeding ulcer.
The paramedics
found him on the street.
That's where he lives.
Don't ask me to explain.
I can't explain it
to my daughter.
I sure can't explain it to you.
Your husband's
been moved upstairs,
if you'd like to see him.
I brought him
some clean clothes.
Could you see that he gets this?
Sure. But he's awake,
if you want to talk to him.
I just wanted to
see if he was alive.
So Chloe's staying with you?
Not for long.
Is she okay?
Yeah. Considering
she's been living
on Twinkies and popcorn.
Hmm.
The mother of your
diabetic's on the way in.
Oh! Thank you.
Dr. Strong's urine test.
Seems he belongs
to a different species.
He signs his name
"Dr. Lyle Strong,"
then follows it with "MD."
What is taking so long?
This pain is killing me.
I'm sorry.
Your test results aren't good.
What?
You know the
differential diagnosis.
You have an aplastic
bi-cystic renal neoplasm.
No, no. It couldn't be that.
You're right, because
there's no such thing.
The blood in your urine
was from a chicken.
There's some kind of mistake.
But your story's so good,
we ought to give you
any painkiller you want.
But then you'd only
be back for more.
What'd you do, read
medical textbooks?
I... I'm a doctor.
You're a drug addict
looking for Demerol.
Connie, what do the cops do
if you're trying to
get drugs like this?
Mr. Strong, stop!
Mr. Strong!
Is that the new spring fashion?
Henry may have a
hole between his aorta
and pulmonary arteries.
He turns blue
because he's not getting
enough oxygenated blood.
I knew it.
My whole damn family.
It's not genetic, Mr. Offenbach.
Everything's genetic.
He said it can be
corrected. It can be, right?
Open heart surgery
will close the hole.
Eight weeks old
and they have to
cut his heart open.
It's a common operation.
Well, then, do it
to somebody else.
I'm sorry.
Shh.
I wanted everything to be okay.
It's not your fault.
It just happens.
Doug.
Hey, buddy.
Do I have to call you
Dr. Ross in the hospital?
You can call me
anything you want.
How about air head?
Wise ass.
Do you work Saturday mornings?
Sometimes. Why?
Well, um, could you get, like,
12 Saturday
mornings off in a row,
and some Tuesday and Wednesdays?
Is this a test?
Well, my little league team...
We need an assistant coach.
It's 18 games and
two practices a week.
Well, give me a schedule.
I should be able to
make most of them.
Is that okay?
Yeah. Great.
Dougie.
My name is Doug.
You never call a grownup Dougie.
Oh, and since when
did you grow up?
I just closed a
huge deal in Neuro.
Want to celebrate with me?
Uh, oh, uh...
Jake, this is Linda.
Linda, Jake.
Hi.
So, celebrate?
What happened
to what's-his-name?
Brian. Boston. Business.
I'll buy you ribs
at Carson's. 8:30?
I can't.
Why'd we stop seeing each other?
I miss you a little.
All you had to do was marry me.
I don't miss you that much.
Yeah.
I got to go.
Bye.
Do you go out with
her or something?
I used to.
But not now.
Listen, Jake.
You know what flirting is?
Yeah.
That's what she was doing.
People do it all the time,
and it doesn't mean a thing.
Okay?
Okay.
Guess I was
hoping for a miracle.
I'm glad you still visit her.
I like her. She's tough.
Anyway, it's on my way to class.
Keeping surgeon's hours?
That's what Al says.
How do you keep a
marriage together?
I couldn't do it.
When I get through
the physician's assistant course
we'll have a normal life.
I get a break at 7:00.
You want to grab dinner?
Uh, I, I don't know.
It's just dinner.
Okay.
Dr. Benton, can you see Charlie?
They brought him
from the Friends School.
Yeah.
That's a fine-looking woman.
Married, huh?
So, what's the problem?
My leg feels funny, and
my arm, I can't move it.
Have you been sick lately?
I had the flu.
All right.
We drop a lot of people.
Get ready.
Okay.
Doesn't look surgical.
I'll work him up,
but find Dr. Ross.
When'd your leg get sore?
This morning.
Maybe a little last night.
Have any headaches?
From the flu.
I'm still sort of sick.
Yeah, it's going around.
Have you fallen in
the last few days?
On Saturday.
I tripped over
my little brother.
Yeah, they get in
the way, don't they.
Does your head hurt?
No. Just my arm.
And my back a little.
The diabetic girl's
mother's here.
Possible left-side
hemi-paresis onset 24 hours.
This is Dr. Ross.
He's going to take
good care of you, okay?
Thanks.
He's really nice.
Yeah. He's a prince.
Carter!
Your tests are okay, Chloe,
but you need to
start eating more.
I never ate right.
Put that down, please.
Oh, I've been
screwing up so long,
maybe I can't ever
do anything right.
This time, you'll try harder.
All right, open wide.
Come on. Ahhh.
Chloe, can't you listen
to me for one second?
Look at it this way:
I may not be a doctor
but I'm giving Mom a grandchild.
That'll make her happy.
Yeah. Just what she
wants... To be a grandmother.
She'll be thrilled.
Okay. An O.B.'s coming
down to do an ultrasound
and then you're
going to go shopping
for baby stuff, all right?
Shop till I drop. Cool.
I know I shouldn't
eat ice cream.
You should've taken
your insulin today.
And yesterday,
and the day before.
What are you talking about?
You took it, Sam, didn't you?
Mommy, it wouldn't...
Oh, Sam.
I'm tired of being sick.
I don't want to be different.
I'll go blind.
I read it
in the encyclopedia.
It's not fair.
You, uh...
you have
an illness.
You want to pretend you don't.
Where's that going to get you?
Hmm?
I don't know.
You have to accept
the way things are.
So maybe you won't be
exactly like everybody else
but if you don't
take your insulin...
you'll die.
I'll be back to check on you.
The way you talked to her...
That was great.
2:30. I have to do a hydrocele.
Push down, like on a gas pedal.
Okay.
You like to drive,
there, Charlie?
Yeah. I just got my license.
Hey. Squeeze my hand.
Harder.
I'm trying.
Mm-hmm.
All right, Malik here's
going to take you for an MRI.
You know what that is? Uh-uh.
It's kind of like an X ray,
only you lay in this big tunnel
and they take pictures
of the inside of your head.
Why are you taking
a picture of my head
when my leg hurts?
Because I'm the
doctor, and that's what
I want to do.
Malik, can I talk to
you for a second?
He didn't have any
strength in his hands.
No, he didn't.
Find his parents.
Have Radiology put him ahead
of anybody who's not critical
and tell Benton
to look at the MRI.
And get a neuro consult.
Head's okay.
It's a good position.
Looks like a little girl.
Oh, a girl. Wow.
How's the weight?
Look at her move.
Look at... look at her hand.
Weight's a little
on the low side.
Is something wrong?
You have to
improve your nutrition
and take pre-natal vitamins.
Remember, you're
eating for two now.
Come back next week, we'll
take another look, all right?
Thanks, Janet.
My pleasure.
Susie...
What?
Look at her.
I'm looking.
I told you I was
going to have a girl.
I'm going to name her Susan.
She's mine.
That's my baby, Susie.
Mine.
Carol?
No, I will not type up
your requisition forms.
Where's Doug?
Getting his head shrunk.
When will he be back?
About a half-hour. Why?
We got the MRI back on that kid.
Tell Doug to meet
me in Radiology.
Uh-oh.
Yeah.
So what do we do
now, stare at inkblots?
God, no. I don't know
a thing about them.
Sit down, will you?
So...
you slugged a guy in the E.R.
That was dumb.
What?
That was really stupid.
Uh, you're a shrink.
Aren't you supposed to
talk about my neuroses?
I know all about your neuroses.
You're a reasonably normal
guy with sloppy impulse control.
That's what it's called?
Yeah.
Take my advice.
You want to lose your temper?
Go pop a guy in a bar.
Are you suggesting
that I hit someone?
I'm suggesting you
don't do it at work
or they'll fire your ass.
My report will say
you had a bad week.
You're a pediatrician, thus,
you're particularly
sensitive to child abuse.
Now, say you'll
never do it again.
I'll never do it again.
Good. Or you could
really mess up your life.
Thanks for stopping by.
Dr. Murphy, I have been
a little unhappy lately.
Well, join the club.
Try therapy.
Might help.
Oh, and, uh, have a nice day.
Dr. Greene?
Hi. I was wondering, uh...
Dr. Lewis said
you might be willing
to recommend me
for an E.R. sub-i.
Thought you wanted surgery.
I won't get it, and I want to
consider an E.R. residency.
Carter, you might've noticed
that a recommendation from me
might not be very
helpful right now.
I'd like it anyway.
Sure. You bet.
Yeah?
The MRI shows an aneurysm
at the juncture of the
basilar and vertebral arteries
in the brain stem.
How old's the kid?
Sixteen.
I'd say you better find
this kid's parents quick.
We're looking.
So that explains the paralysis.
The aneurysm is pressing
down on the spinal tract.
I'd say it could
blow any minute...
or it could go in a week.
Well, nothing like
a specific diagnosis.
Hey, Seymour.
Seymour Lassally, Doug Ross.
Doug took the case in.
Hi. What do we got?
I have an astrocytoma at 4:00.
Whoa! That's a huge aneurysm.
When did paralysis start?
Yesterday.
We can't do this, Peter.
He could die in 20 minutes.
Dr. Ross, the operation
requires hypothermia.
You have to cool him
down so the brain'll survive,
and shut off the
heart-lung machine.
Get lucky and
he'll come out okay,
but, uh, it's not for us.
Dyer over at
Mercy's done it a lot.
Call him and get
the kid over there.
You're going to pass this up?
Mike Dyer is good,
fast and confident.
Call him.
He jumped right over and bit me.
Well, it's minor.
You'll be fine.
The neighbor said
he had all his shots.
Could he have rabies?
There hasn't been a
rabid dog in Cook County
in 20 years.
Mm-hmm.
You're sure about the rabies?
Yeah.
You're sweet.
I'm going to tell all my friends
to come here in emergencies.
Any word on the kid's parents?
The mother's on the way.
I see it's raining
finally. Uh-huh.
15 miles? Where's he doing it?
Yeah. Thanks.
Carter, give me your car
keys. I need your keys.
Thought you were on call.
They paged Dyer from
Mercy. He didn't answer.
They won't take the
aneurysm without his approval
and he's out jogging.
Come on, your keys.
GSW to the chest coming in.
What's Benton doing?
Out looking for Dr. Dyer.
It's about his mother, though.
Because if he can't
make her better,
then he'll fix everything else.
Carter, you took too
many psych classes.
Get somebody from surgery
down here to cover for Benton.
Shouldn't you be out of here?
Uh, 20 minutes.
So, this, uh, woman
that had the dog bite,
I think she was
was hitting on me.
It been known to happen.
Not to me.
Did she smile a lot? Yes.
Play with her hair? Yes...
Touch you? On my arm.
She was hitting on you.
Hope I'm not sending
out a signal or something.
I mean, you know, I
mean, me and Jen...
You've been moody lately.
Women love to save moody men.
Mark, GSW to the chest.
Susan? Yeah.
On your right!
Call Radiology, stat!
Why don't you intubate.
I'll check his lungs.
Vitals?
Lost 500 cc's.
B.P. 50 palp. Pulse 140.
Six units o-neg ordered.
All right.
Let's go on my count.
One, two, three.
All right. Let's roll him.
Entry wound...
Upper left chest.
Exit... below scapula.
Second entry wound...
Abdomen.
Exit... left flank.
Let him die.
Who is she?
Get her out of here!
Let's get a chest tube started
and let's get a surgical
resident down here.
I'm his mother.
Let him die.
Ma'am, you have to wait outside.
Let him die. Es el diablo.
Somebody get her
to the waiting room.
- Es el diablo. Es el diablo.
- He's in fib!
Paddles, 200.
Charging.
Clear?
Clear.
Three hundred.
He's still in fib. Hit it.
Charging.
Clear?
Clear.
He's back.
Sinus rhythm.
100 migs lidocaine I.V. push.
Tension pneumo.
16-gauge needle.
Got it. Chest tube.
Mark, do you want
to make that train?
I got to put in a chest tube.
I'll help Susan. You go.
I'm here. You go.
All right. Thanks.
Two milligrams a minute?
Seven and a half gloves.
Betadyne here.
Drape him, please.
Lidocaine? Don't need it.
He killed two boys
today, another last month.
You did no good for anybody.
Murphy found you charming.
You must've turned it on.
I don't turn it on.
It's just there.
Kind of like a force of nature.
Doug, this Little League thing?
Yeah, it's great, isn't it?
Yeah.
Now what did I do?
Was I supposed to say no?
Jake really likes you.
I'm glad. You're good for him.
And?
And if you're not
serious about me,
I can handle it.
I don't expect men to
move in and stay forever...
Especially you,
with your history.
Me? Mr. Commitment?
But if you're going
to leave Jake...
I need to know, Doug.
Not for me, but for Jake.
What's our future?
Six months, at least.
Diane, I don't know.
I hope we're
together a long time.
Maybe... grow old together.
Maybe.
I can hope.
Can I make the
station in 38 minutes?
Mark, it'll be okay.
This will be the night
that Amtrak goes on strike.
Watch Garrison
inFour, hypocalcemia.
The girl in three, orbital
fracture from softball.
Try and get a consult.
The back pain in six...
Mark... could be
a herniated disk...
I can read the board.
Yeah.
Bye.
You're Benton's
student, aren't you?
Uh, yeah.
John Carter.
Where is he?
I think he's in surgery.
I need his charts.
Joint Commission's
breathing down my neck.
I want him the
second he gets back.
I'll tell him.
Jerry, is Dr. Benton back yet?
No. Still out in the rain.
Probably smashed up your Jeep.
Can you get his
charts together for me?
You really want that sub-i, huh.
Just get them for
me, Jerry, all right?
Are you Mike Dyer?
Who the hell are you?
Peter Benton. I'm a resident
over at County General.
I have an MRI I
want you to look at.
You're joking.
It's in the car.
Carol, what's the diagnostic
code for diabetic ketoacidosis?
250.11.
Facial laceration repair?
120-52.
Why are you doing that?
Round up some residents.
You never get to see this...
Woman hit by lightning.
Dr. Benton's charts are done.
I'll see them later.
Come on, Carter.
Nesbit, Leslie.
Struck by sideflash
lightning on 23rd Street.
Full arrest on scene.
Bystander started
CPR in seconds.
What's she had?
Two amps epi, two
milligrams atropine.
Look at this, Carter...
Feathering burns.
Lichtenberg's flowers.
Yes. Very good.
She's cyanotic.
Hyperventilate her and
get Respiratory down here.
I'll bag her.
Handle it, Carter.
Okay, get ready to
move her on my count:
One, two, three.
Asystole. How
long since last epi?
Seven minutes.
All right, Carter.
Give a high dose,
uh, five milligrams.
Get a CBC, Chem
24, cardiac enzymes.
Pupils fixed and dilated.
Doesn't matter. You get that
temporarily with lightning strikes.
Where the hell is everybody?
They should be
in here seeing this.
I got a weak pulse.
Sinus rhythm.
Put her on a full cross...
Dopamine, 400 milligrams
of 500 D-5-W.
Let's get a cross table
c-spine, then a chest.
Let's order a head
CT, noncontrast.
Right.
Well done.
Good teachers.
Who?
Dr. Benton
Dr. Greene, Dr. Lewis.
Which one's the best?
They're all good.
They teach diplomacy, too.
What do you want
to do with this patient?
If X rays are okay,
then I get the CT
and we'll ship her
to the ICU.
Yes. Shooting!
They picked up your
mother at O'Hare.
She's on her way to Mercy.
What'd she say?
I didn't talk to her.
Well, it's just that...
you know, since she and
my dad have been divorced,
she works and all, and I
know she's going to be worried.
Yeah.
I don't just have
the flu, right?
No.
You have an aneurysm.
It's like a little balloon
in a blood vessel in your brain.
It doesn't sound good.
It's not.
Why am I going
to another hospital?
It's a complicated operation.
Complicated?
Like I could die?
Yeah... you could die.
But that's not going to happen.
Hmm?
I'm going over there alone?
Don't worry. You'll
be in good hands.
All right?
All right.
Dr. Benton, your
charts look good.
Thank you.
This student of
yours is terrific.
So you found the neurosurgeon.
Yeah. Oh, uh... car keys.
My charts?
Dr. Swift wanted
them, so I finished them.
Yeah, well, uh... thank you.
Excuse me?
I, uh, said
thank you.
I know.
I just wanted to
hear you say it twice.
I'll see you in the
morning, Carter.
What happened to you?
I had to run an errand.
Huh. Still interested in dinner?
Yeah.
Is this cool or what?
Yes.
Does she really
need six pairs to start?
Aren't these cute?
Well, these are nice.
Maybe we can take
some of the others back.
Forget the bows.
Keep the patent leather.
Chloe, how much did
you put on my credit card?
I don't know, like
$100, maybe $150.
Chloe, this is easily $300.
Suz...
I'm going to be
somebody's mother.
If Mom could do it, you can.
At least I didn't
drink sangria all day.
Yeah, or smoke
four packs of Luckys.
And we turned out okay.
And Mom didn't
have you to help her.
It's going to be
all right, isn't it?
Yeah, it's going to be fine.
Three plus three is six.
And four plus four is eight.
And six...
Daddy, I don't have
any more fingers.
Well, I do, okay?
Hold up six.
Hey, banana fish,
it's time for bed.
But Daddy's here.
Well, Daddy can't stop you
from falling asleep
in school tomorrow.
Go brush your teeth.
If I get a story.
Mmm... well...
Daddy'll read you a story.
Go brush your teeth.
Go.
Jen?
It's been a long day, Mark.
Should I turn
around and go back?
I just... I can't do this.
We need to talk about Rachel.
I miss her.
I need to see her more.
You live two hours away.
I'll move up here.
Mark... it's over.
No, I mean, I'll
get a place here.
I'll commute.
I want to raise my daughter.
You'll commute?
I'm not going to get
that attending job.
I'll try to find a job here.
If that's what you want to do.
Look, uh, can I
stay here next week
while I'm looking for a place?
It's not a good idea.
Can I stay here
tonight on the couch?
Daddy, aren't you coming?
I'll be there in a sec.
Get under the covers.
Please.
Okay. Okay.
Thanks.
Daddy!
Why don't you go read to Rachel?
Yeah.
So she stood up, and
she started to applaud.
In the middle of graduation?
The whole medical
school was staring at her.
When I graduated from
college, my father danced.
What's wrong with that?
On a table.
I hope my kids don't sit
around laughing at me.
Better than hating us.
You don't hate your mother.
Just 'cause your mother's great
doesn't mean mine was.
So, uh...
she's never going to
get any better, is she?
There won't be much improvement.
And there's not a damn
thing I can do about it, huh?
No.
I, uh...
I wouldn't be getting
through this thing if it...
if it wasn't for you.
I think Peter Benton can get
through just about anything.
He used to think so.