Mobilize with Kocher maneuver.
Divide at pylorus.
Transect stomach TA 90.
I.D. ligament of Trietz.
Come on.
My Billroth II's been canceled.
Good morning to you too, Peter.
Is there a problem?
I believe your patient
developed a fever.
No, no, no.
I mean, is there a problem
with me in this department?
Ever since I left
Dr. Vucelich's study,
I've been underutilized.
When you were
working with Dr. Vucelich,
he monopolized
most of your time.
Now you're back with
the teeming masses
and there's lag time
while a schedule plays catch-up
to your change of fortune.
I see.
What do we got?
30-year-old male
had a bad Valentine's Day.
Threw himself on the El tracks
in front of an oncoming train.
Did a good job on himself.
How are his vitals?
Sinus tach at 150, BP's 50 palp.
Bilateral hemothorax,
rigid belly, head trauma,
near amputation, right forearm
deformed fracture, left femur,
open fracture, lower
right extremities.
Okay, you put in
the other chest tube.
I'll do the DPL.
Oh, that's a deal. 36 French.
All right,
we need four units of
O-neg on the rapid infuser.
Pupils are unequal and sluggish.
We need a head CT
to rule out a bleed.
No time. Positive tap.
Do those burr holes blind.
No way. I need a CT first.
All right, let's shock him.
I wish I would
have thought of that.
200!
Clear!
Clear.
All right, we got a rhythm.
Sinus tach at 160.
Lidocaine 100 IV push.
Dopamine 400 and
500. Start it at 10.
All right, we got a pulse.
Okay. I'll take him.
You, stick with me.
You do the burr
holes up in the O.R.
If you don't, he's toast.
He's not stable.
Yeah, well, he's as
stable as he's going to get.
Let's move.
Uh, Peter?
We have some other
sick people down here
if you want them too.
Wow. What'd he
have for breakfast?
Something hard to digest.
Oh, Suz, did you forget?
I'm not on till 11.
We can sleep in.
Yeah...
Oh, you're soaked.
Yeah, okay.
Oh, boy.
Yeah.
Yes?
Good morning, Ms. Lewis.
It's Ms. Pearline
with social services.
Who?
Ms. Pearline.
I'm here for your home visit,
for the adoption.
What?
Well, I, uh...
I worked really late last night.
Well, you could reschedule,
but it will take
another four to six weeks.
Uh, no, no, no. Come on up.
Just come up slowly, please.
Good morning.
Actually, good night.
Hey, Dr. Ross.
Still got that extra ticket
to the Bulls-Spurs
game next week?
Well, Jerry, I do
have two tickets,
but they're not extra.
The ones your dad gave you?
Mm-hmm.
I thought you threw those out.
Well, I was going to,
but they're mid-court,
about 10 rows up.
Well, you guys heard
about all the excitement
here yesterday, right?
Scottie Pippen came
in. What excitement?
Here?
He did not.
Yeah, I... Actually, he did.
Brought in a kid
from his Cabrini
Greens tutoring program.
They'd had a basketball clinic.
Kid took a charge,
broke his collarbone.
Nice try, Jerry.
Lot of details.
Almost believable.
It's the truth. Look.
I got his autograph.
You know what that's worth?
It's I-N, not E-N.
No, it's E-N. It was him.
Who else was on?
The kid's mom showed up,
so Scottie split pretty quick.
So nobody else saw him?
I'm heading upstairs.
Can we watch?
My God.
Conni, haven't you
had that baby yet?
Oh, you won't have me
to make fun of after today.
Thought you were
working up to your due date.
I have, and then some.
Doc's gonna induce if
nothing happens by Monday.
I'm going up to OB
for a non-stress test.
I feel like a damn elephant.
An elephant's gestation period
is two years.
Oh, shut your mouth.
Okay, my interview
is not till 4:00.
Benton'll be done
with the Billroth
by 10:30.
I'll find him. I won't beg.
I'll be dignified.
I'm not getting a fair shot
at this internship,
I'll tell him,
unless he rewrites my
letter of recommendation.
90 applicants for six slots.
How did you even see it, anyway?
It was on his desk, and, oh...
"Has put forth a
consistent effort."
That's what he says about me.
"Has acquired solid...
"Technical skills".
I told you that part.
Several times.
You know, I know he and
I have had our differences,
but I've worked
my butt off for him.
Where the hell's our train?
John, how soon after intercourse
can you get a pregnancy result
by a blood test?
Seven days.
Did I tell you about
the other applicants?
Harvard, Yale,
Stanford, Hopkins.
I got the home court
advantage, but still... still...
Wait a sec. Did you
just say "pregnancy"?
You think you're pregnant?
How's that possible?
We've been really
careful. I know.
Did you miss your period?
No, not yet. I'm just obsessing.
You don't need this today.
I know. This whole
interview thing
is nerve-racking enough.
I'm sorry. Do you want
to draw some blood?
No, it can wait.
I'm just being paranoid.
You worry about your interview.
Okay, okay, we need some help.
What happened?
Hey, we need some help here.
Don't tell me your water broke.
Sprinkler system went
berserk on the fourth floor.
It's raining cats and dogs,
and we can't shut it off.
Need a hand here, quick.
Jerry.
Yep, yep.
The whole west
wing is getting soaked.
Labor and Delivery
and the Nursery?
NICU and Postpartum.
All high-risk women
are going up to the sixth floor.
Everyone else is down here.
How many?
Eight, I think,
all in active labor.
Oh, boy. All right. Chuny.
Okay, we're gonna
need some dry gowns,
some warming lamps.
Also, uh...
You've got to change.
Blow dryers, if you can
round any of them up.
This is a new one.
This really sucks.
Dr. Ross? Yeah.
This one's pretty ripe.
Is there any time
between your contractions?
No. None.
All right. Uh...
let's get a pelvic bed
set up in Trauma 1.
Somebody call Mark.
Coming through.
ICP's 14.
Final ligature.
Spleen's out. Suction.
So I guess if you're
looking to kill yourselves,
the El tracks'll do the job.
All right, we're dry.
Send it to Pathology.
What do you want to tackle next?
Let's run the small bowel
for perforations.
How's the arm look?
Bad as the rest of him.
Think you can save this guy?
We're chasing our tails here.
Damn.
He's hemorrhaging.
It looks arterial.
All right, let's open him up.
It's your party,
but this is a teaching
exercise now.
What do you mean,
teaching exercise?
There's not a life to save here.
You want to bet?
Sternal saw.
Run up to Labor and Delivery.
Take some galoshes and
an umbrella if you have to,
but find me an extra stash
of preemie and
term-sized ambu-bags,
and infant ET tubes.
Make sure we have
some bulb syringes.
You got it.
Christy, your baby's head
is engaged in the canal,
but the membrane
isn't ruptured yet,
so we're gonna have
to do an amniotomy
to rupture it.
What's the presentation?
Station two plus, fully
effaced and dilated.
I'll be right back. Yeah.
He went to buy film.
He won't even know where I am.
We'll find him. Just relax.
Taking an incubator.
Blankets.
Chuny, you were on yesterday.
Tell Dr. Ross Scottie
Pippen was in here.
Oh, yeah,
and so were Jordan and Rodman.
Jerry and Conni and I
beat them three on three.
It's a monsoon up there.
All our fetal
monitors are trashed.
How many do you have down here?
A few. We'll rotate.
Well, high risks went up to six,
which is where I have to be.
I'll just send down a
couple of residents.
We can handle it.
Who's attending?
Good. Push, push. That's it.
You know Mark Greene?
Oh, yes.
Membrane ruptured?
We had to do it for her.
Was the head engaged?
Yes.
All right. Don't want
a cord prolapse.
Okay.
Now, when you get the urge,
I want you to just
go ahead and push.
Okay?
Okay, good.
Ooh. Seeing a head here.
All right, here it comes.
Now take a deep
breath. Deep breath.
Push.
Patient in Exam 2 is ready.
I'm on my way.
Mrs. Wilson, you have
a beautiful baby boy.
Fundus is firm.
Placenta's coming.
Activity, two, pulse, two,
grimace, two.
One laceration.
Dr. Greene, will you suture?
I think I can handle that.
Apgar, nine.
I'll check again in five.
Use 2-0 chromic.
Interrupted suture
for the muscularis layer,
interlocking for the mucosa.
We can manage from here, Janet.
You got other fish to fry.
Just don't take any chances.
You run into any trouble,
run them straight to us.
Six East for all C-sections,
understood?
Uh-huh, and we're going
to need another bassinet.
They'll be sending them down.
No, we need another one now.
She's having contractions again.
What?
Why?
I hope you're ready
for an encore, there, Christy,
because you're
having another one.
Oh, my God. I don't believe it.
She came in just before
the sprinklers went.
Nobody had a
chance to monitor her.
I had an ultrasound months ago.
I got a hold of the head.
No, no, no. Make that the tush.
This is a breech?
I'll deliver.
No, no. I'm okay.
I got a good hold here.
What's wrong?
Well, it looks
like your second baby
wants to be different
so he's going to
come out butt-first.
Now, just push.
Get the feet out.
Okay, good. Good, Christy.
Good, good.
Push. Push. All right, good.
Push.
All right, that's good.
That's really good, Christy.
Keep going. Keep going. Push.
Good.
Okay.
Those are the shoulders.
Okay, now, just relax, okay?
Because I've got to get
a good grip on the head.
Flex the head.
All right, now, push gently.
Nice and slow.
Good, good, good.
Good. Excellent.
Nice, nice.
Nice work, Mom.
Oh, there.
Look at that.
Oh, my God.
Two of them?
Pretty smooth, Mark.
You'd think
you delivered a
breech every day.
Page me if you need me.
Okay.
Doug?
You can suction.
Mom, relax.
The place was a pigsty
and Susie has this
bruise over her eye
from pulling the highchair over.
The more I explained
it, the phonier it sounded.
I'm sure you were
the best adoption candidate
they've had all month.
I don't know.
They're sending this
guy over this week
for work-site interviews.
Please lie.
Can you take this girl in 3?
We prefer to be
called "women" now.
Yeah, well, you
judge for yourself.
With my last two,
I had Pitocin and an
epidural with no complications.
I'd love to pit you, hon, but...
With the shortage of monitors
we can't be sure
if your baby's having distress.
I'm in distress.
If I wanted a natural
childbirth I'd have stayed home.
What are they gonna
come up with next?
Natural dentistry?
Okay, Ms. Amayo...
Uh...
Tina.
How are you doing?
It hurts.
Okay, I'm going to put
these on you for a reading.
Did they tell you about
the monitor upstairs?
I don't know.
There was a lot of stuff.
Yeah.
Oh, good. A doctor's here.
Sorry, Tina.
They didn't have X-Men.
I'm Dr. Lewis.
I was just explaining
the monitor to Tina.
It's been a crazy day for her.
So your daughter's 13?
She's not our daughter.
We've only known Tina
for a few months.
We're adopting her baby.
She called us
when the contractions began.
Her mother was...
out.
Did you find my mama?
She's still not home.
I'll try again
in a little while.
And who examines that?
Your urine specimen?
Yeah.
We send that to the lab.
And you'll alert them
about my abduction?
Well, uh...
Not that I expect
them to have tests
to identify alien life.
No, probably not.
But if they do find
something unusual,
maybe the FBI or
NASA will listen to them.
They certainly
don't take phone
calls from the victims
of extraterrestrial
insemination.
You're pregnant by aliens?
It was so humiliating.
I bet.
Oh.
Here's one more to go...
Okay.
And this goes with it
for a pregnancy test.
You ready for another look?
Oh, could we do two
more laps, please?
I want to be at least
four centimeters this time.
She's very goal-oriented.
Walk on.
I hate men like that.
It gives you false hope.
It's safer to believe
that guys like that don't exist.
Oh, finally. Fresh recruits.
I thought this shift
would never end.
What's the EBL?
Five liters.
Carter, want to scrub in?
I would, but they
asked me to give a tour
to the visiting candidates
of the hospital.
Stiff competition.
Mm-hmm.
I had a couple of hours to kill
before my interview,
you know, at 4,
so I thought I'd come by.
Hey, I was hoping
that you managed
to get a final draft
of my letter of rec out.
One draft. Sent it last week.
Great. Great.
Great.
Thanks.
Nice work.
Peter, word's gotten around
this is where the
resurrection is.
I have some students
who want to watch
you raise the dead.
They'll have a good
view from there.
They'll benefit from learning
how and why you decided
to pursue this hopeless case.
"How and why"?
Hmm.
I saw this guy.
I knew I could fix him.
I went to work.
Pressure's 110/75.
Good call, Kerry.
She's abrupted.
Any time.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Whatever.
You know, he said he was
going to send some tickets.
Jerry, are you still telling
that Scottie Pippen story?
It's not a story.
Shh. Here she comes.
Hey, Conni.
Hey.
The beet soup, huh?
That's what they say.
I don't know. Crazy.
It's put a lot of
women in labor.
It was in the newspaper.
What has?
The beet soup
over at Doc Magoo's.
Induces labor.
Oh, come on.
Yeah, I read that.
It's not that far-fetched.
A lot of plants
have ergot alkaloid derivatives.
And what do those do?
Make the uterus contract.
Susan...
Yeah?
I've been monitoring
Leah Russell. Uh-huh.
A few things don't add up.
She hasn't been able
to give us a urine sample.
Her chart shows
she's had two previous births
but she told me she lives alone.
She's nervous, underweight...
You're thinking drugs?
I checked with a few hospitals,
and as a teen,
she gave birth to
two crack babies.
One she lost at six months.
One was taken away at birth.
Lead the way.
Oh, boy. Here we go again.
Hi, Dad.
I hate this part!
Try to save your breath, Monica.
If you don't get a vasectomy,
I swear
you're having the next one.
Oh! How big is this kid?
All right, all right.
Ease up on the pushing, okay?
There's the head...
Would you please shut up?
She has to go through
this herself soon.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
That's it.
Look at that one.
She's a 10-pounder.
I take it back.
Hon, you scream all you want.
Suction?
Baby's lethargic. Apgar three.
Hold on. Hold on. Okay.
No, no, no. Okay. All right.
Let's bag her.
Is something wrong?
Ma'am, did you test positive
for diabetes during
your prenatal care?
What's... what's...
what's wrong?
Start CPR, right now.
I'm gonna intubate.
Prep an umbilical line,
and heel stick a glucose.
Please?
What is it?
This never happened
with my other kids.
You may have developed
gestational diabetes
during your pregnancy.
Bolus her with
two cc's per kilo.
Is she breathing?
Weak respiratory effort.
Give her a 10 cc infusion of D10
and stick her for
another glucose.
Why isn't she crying?
Your baby's been intubated.
Okay. Just try and lie back.
Try and lie back, Monica. Relax.
Jeanie tells me
you're having trouble
giving us a urine sample.
Yeah, I tried.
Well, I suggest you try again,
because if you can't
produce a sample,
we're going to have
to put a catheter in you
to get one.
Why do you even need it?
So we can do a tox screen.
You do those on white women too?
We do those on
everyone who has a history
of drug or alcohol abuse
so I suggest you cooperate.
Let me know the results.
You looked me up.
Shall we?
You had to tell her?
She's the doctor.
Well, I was just tripping,
because I was busted before.
I was a kid then,
but now I'm clean.
Let's find out.
Pulse ox 98.
Yeah. That's
what I want to hear.
Come here, you.
Look at that.
Oh, Dr. Greene, thank you.
Thank you.
Wait. I didn't get it.
Do that again.
Oh, thank you!
Dr. Ross?
Yeah? Get over here.
No, no, no, no.
Oh, come on, come on, come on.
Nurses too.
This is the doctor
that saved our little Renee.
I love you.
Here. Me too, Doc.
Okay.
I love you.
You know what?
I love that doctor too.
All right. I want a
copy of that one.
Okay, I'm going to take
little Renee up to NICU.
And have them check her out.
Congratulations.
I got it on tape.
Oh.
Pleased to meet you.
John Carter.
Ken Matsumitsu. You're from...
I'm the local guy. You're...
From Boston.
Ken's the Howard Hughes
Fellow at Harvard this year.
Oh. Congratulations.
John Carter.
Pleased to meet you.
Andrea Zucker. Stanford.
Ah, California.
Explains the tan.
No, actually,
I just got back from Senegal.
Did 10 months in a clinic there.
Oh.
This is Martin Fisher.
How are you?
Martin Fisher.
Published in Nature last month.
That's me.
Okay, guys.
We can all go home.
Did you read it?
He cloned tyrosine
kinase receptors.
Wow.
Well, shall we, with the tour?
Her back is killing her.
What can I do?
Tina, roll on your side.
When the contractions start,
press down on her back.
Give her some relief. Like this?
Yeah. Good, good.
Is she doing okay?
Yeah, thanks to the two of you.
I just hope she's not
depending on us too much.
What do you mean?
She needs a mother herself.
We can only adopt a baby.
We can't take her too.
Give me the bullet.
Allow me.
I'm Dr. Anna Castiglioni,
Internal Medicine,
in my 34th week.
I have a scheduled
induction for Monday.
My membrane
ruptured 40 minutes ago.
I'm fully dilated.
I'll take the express elevator
to Labor and Delivery.
I'm sorry, Dr. Castiglioni,
but L & D has
maintenance problems,
so we're taking all admits
in here today.
You have your hands full?
Yes,
but I think we can
handle one more.
All right, on my count.
One, two, three.
Sorry. I think you
left this behind.
Stage three
carcinoma of the breast.
I had a mastectomy
six years ago.
The cancer flared up again
last spring.
I was started on a
CMF chemo regimen
and slated for radiation when
I found out I was pregnant.
Are there any
implications for the fetus?
The ultrasounds look fine,
but methotrexate
is contraindicated
in the first trimester,
so I won't rest easy
till I see this baby.
Well, it shouldn't be long.
The angels were
watching over her.
If I'd had the radiation,
she would have
gotten a toxic dose.
You suspended
your own treatment?
For the first trimester.
I've been on a modified
regimen since then.
It wasn't a hard choice.
I've got a matter
of months left.
My baby has her
whole life ahead.
You're right, Doctor.
You are fully dilated.
All right, let's call Coburn.
Tell her we got
one on the way up.
Dr. Coburn? Oh, no.
Please. I have worked
too hard for this delivery
to have Janet Coburn
anywhere near it.
You're old friends, huh?
Still,
all the high risks
have to go up.
I'm not considered high risk.
Dr. Lopez was going to induce me
in the birthing center.
Hello?
Is Ferdie there?
I hope you're
calling your husband,
because this baby
is on her way.
My husband's already driving in.
Hello? Fernando.
You'll never guess where I am.
Let me hand you over
to Dr. Mark Greene.
It's my OB.
Break it to him gently.
He's going to be jealous.
Man, look at this.
Standing room only.
So you got Humpty Dumpty
back together again, huh?
Getting there.
Marathon surgery.
You run the 20K too?
Not since med school.
How's it look?
Massive crush injury.
We should amputate.
This guy's gonna live. He
might as well keep his arm.
It's longer than a long shot.
Look, it won't hurt to try.
Well, she'll thank you.
Patient's mom.
She works over in recovery.
Said to tell you, "God bless."
Okay, spectators.
No intermission.
We're going straight
into the next act.
Pulse ox 97.
I owe you an apology.
Your tox screen
came back negative.
I told you I kicked it.
People don't think you can,
but I did.
You must be a strong lady.
Not strong enough
to take much more of this.
Oh! There she is!
Ooh, ooh, my, my! No, Sonya.
Don't look at me. I'm a wreck.
Oh, looks like this baby's
giving you a real workout,
girlfriend.
That's for sure.
I brought you some candy.
We're pretty crowded.
We have to limit visitors.
But I'm her sister.
Birthing coach...
and sister.
Okay.
Just don't stay too long.
Oh! Look at you!
Jeanie, have you seen Harper?
Not recently.
She sent out blood tests
for the woman in Exam 2.
Ah. The alien abduction.
Yeah. This is so odd.
Oh! I want my mama!
We're here with you, Tina.
Blow. Blow. Go on.
It hurts.
Yes, that's because
your baby's coming.
Hurts...
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Next door.
Got it, got it. Blow, okay?
You're doing great, Doctor.
You're doing great.
There's meconium in the fluid.
Amnioinfuse
500 cc's normal saline.
Look, you push,
I'll run the procedure.
Do exactly what she said.
Since then,
I've had the most
awful nosebleeds.
Harper. There you are.
Dr. Weaver.
Whatever possessed you
to run a pregnancy test
on this visibly
gestational woman?
I...
had a lapse.
I don't know what
I was thinking.
Until the hypnosis,
I thought I was absent-minded.
Maybe they've gotten to you too.
Maybe they beamed up
the entire lab,
because Ms. Clarke's
pregnancy test
came back negative.
Oh, yes.
I told you
this was no ordinary conception.
It's not.
It's pseudocyesis,
and a classic case of it.
Ms. Clarke's pelvic
exam confirms the labs.
She's not pregnant.
But look at her.
Distended abdomen
from hyperventilation
due to "contractions."
She's got a colon full of gas.
That's what they always say.
Those creatures blew
their interstellar filth
into all my cavities,
and it's hibernating there.
Yeah. Good choice.
The whole father-
in-waiting thing
has changed since
the Ricky Ricardo days.
It's nice to preserve
some traditions.
Excuse me. Just a sec.
I mean, I know how
you feel... Excuse me.
Hey, can't you see we're...
Hey. Jerry, right?
Uh-huh.
I just want to thank you again.
Oh, you're welcome.
Uh, can you stay here
for just one minute?
One minute.
How is the fetal heart rate?
140, good variability.
I'm not progressing.
You can do it.
Dr. Ross...
I'm busy in here, Jerry.
He's here! Scottie Pippen!
Jerry.
Okay. Okay. I'll bring him here.
Where did he go?
Who?
Scottie Pippen.
Is he kind of a tall guy?
Yeah. You could say that.
He said to tell
everyone, "Thanks."
Like they're gonna believe that.
I can't. I can't.
Yes, you can!
You are. Hold your breath.
Use it
to push the baby out.
I'm gonna die.
No. No, you're not.
You're doing beautifully.
Okay, Tina.
One more time, and
then you're there.
You said that before.
I know. You are doing
such a hard thing,
and you are doing a great job.
I've seen grown women
who can't hang
in there like that.
Really?
Really. I'm so proud of you.
Okay, come on.
Bear down. Bear down!
Bear down!
Come on, bear down!
It shouldn't be long now.
Did your friend leave?
Yeah.
Can I go to the bathroom?
Sure.
Let me help you.
I can do it.
What's wrong?
Get this damn
stuff away from me.
Your friend bring this?
Damn.
Am I ever gonna kick this stuff?
I've been clean for two months.
But you did use crack
during your pregnancy?
Yeah.
I mean, not too much
after the beginning.
I have to let the doctors know.
Help my partner.
He was electrocuted.
Grab that gurney!
Come on!
Here. Lie him here.
He's soaking wet. What happened?
We were up in OB,
working in standing water.
A 220 line fell.
It must've been hot.
Yeah. Here's the entrance wound,
right palm.
Exit wound on the foot.
Let's try Trauma 2.
Need a room!
Yeah, we'll move next door.
In here.
Careful of the baby.
Can we crowd in?
15 liters O-2,
by mask.
Start him on an IV. Saline, TKO.
Pulse ox.
Get him on a cardiac monitor.
Got a good vein here.
Lidocaine 100 IV push.
What about you?
How are you doing, sir?
Oh, when I knocked
him away from the ladder,
I guess I got a little jolt.
Well, sit down here, sir.
We're going to take care of you.
Here you go.
She is perfect.
Look at that.
Picture of health.
Hello, beautiful.
Hello.
I didn't think it
would be so hard.
That's why they call it "labor."
I mean,
I didn't think it would
be so hard to see her
when I know...
I love you.
I will always love you.
Shh-shh-shh-shh.
The easiest birth
I've ever seen.
We don't usually
give extra credit
on the Apgar,
but when they come out
reciting Shakespeare...
Well, he takes after his mom.
Couldn't have
done it without you.
Yeah, we're still
trying to figure out
how to clone your husband.
It could happen.
Little Thomas here
is a chemistry experiment.
In vitro fertilization.
A miracle baby.
Dr. Ross?
Hmm?
We set up a full OB on six.
We're going to start
transporting the
postpartum women
and their newborns.
We've got one more
close to delivery.
Okay,
so that's eight
mothers to transport,
and nine healthy newborns.
That's a nice ratio, Dr. Greene.
Moms did all the work.
Dr. Ross, this is Mr. Wilson.
His wife had the twins.
Oh, hey, hi.
Dispatch called.
I was on the Berkeley run.
It was snowed in out there.
Took them three hours
to get a relief driver,
almost three more
to get me back in.
Well, you want to see your kids?
I sure would.
Come on.
Here you go.
Boys, I'd like you
to meet your father.
I'm sorry I wasn't
here for you guys.
That's not how it's going to be.
I'm going to always
be here for you
whenever you need me
and sometimes when
you think you don't.
I'm your dad
and that's my job.
To be there.
You're gonna be a great father.
They say
it's all about the
kind of start you get.
She's crowning, Dr. Ross.
The crack baby?
Mm-hmm.
Okay. Excuse me.
Push, push, push, push. Good.
Good. Yes.
You have a little girl.
Is she okay?
She's beautiful.
Is she breathing?
Oh, yes, she is.
Apgar seven.
Head circumference
may be on the small side.
What does that mean?
It means, ma'am,
that your daughter,
for the moment,
seems fine,
but that you were doing crack
while you were pregnant,
which can cause
developmental problems.
Learning problems
we may not know about
for months, maybe even years.
I'm going to take
her up to NICU.
But you're bringing
her back, though, right?
You're giving her back to me?
I'll get to have her?
Yes, you probably will.
So even though my family
was predisposed to law,
I was the black sheep
and decided to go into medicine.
Shoot. Can I try again?
The point, Mr. Carter,
is to tie the knot
without pulling the clip away
from the magnet.
I know.
Mr. Carter, can you
run through the steps
of an adrenalectomy?
Uh...
sure.
Identify the mass by CT.
Make a Kocher incision.
I almost had it.
What if that had been a patient
and your inept technique
caused uncontrolled
arterial hemorrhage?
I, uh...
I would repair the damage
and...
proceed.
Good answer, Mr. Carter.
It may not be
possible to tie that knot
without dropping the magnet,
but you didn't lose your cool,
and that matters.
That, and your academic records,
your board scores,
and your letters of rec.
Quite frankly, I...
Carl Vucelich sent
his standard glowing report...
Still didn't fix the typo
in the second paragraph.
But it's Dr. Benton's letter
that gives us the most...
pause.
I am at a loss to explain...
You're one of the first
students to survive Dr. Benton.
But to have him use words
like "solid"
in connection with
surgical technique...
High praise from Benton.
Not to mention "full knowledge
of anatomy and
diagnostic tools."
That's tantamount to gushing.
Are you sure he wrote this?
He did.
Well, you're a most
impressive candidate,
but we have many
impressive candidates.
One last thing.
Tell us why you
want to be a surgeon.
It's not a trick question.
Hmm. No. Um, hmm.
I, uh...
I see people with
injury or disease...
and I know that
I can fix them...
So that's what I want to do.
Oh, excuse me, nurse.
How soon before they move her?
Oh, it shouldn't be too long.
Oh, you probably
have time, Harris.
I'm starving.
I was just going to run
to that diner across the street
and get her something to eat.
I loved that beet soup
I had there last night.
Do you know what that lady
in Curtain 1 just said?
What?
I'm out of here.
You're not going to join us?
Nope. Sorry. I got
to see someone.
Join who?
Leslie! Leslie!
Oh!
He's beautiful.
You two finally
have your family.
I am so sorry that I missed it.
Thank you, Harris,
for everything.
We're making you
two the godfathers.
Too good to be true.
Re-check his crit in 30 minutes.
Don't forget,
15 mgs per kilogram per minute.
Page me stat
if his systolic BP
drops under 100, huh?
Carter, what are you doing here?
Brought you dinner.
Tofu, brown rice,
veggies on the side.
Thanks.
I know it's been hard lately.
I just want to thank you
for setting the bar high,
and for everything.
For being a good example.
The interview went okay, huh?
It's hard to say. I think so.
Is that guy going to live?
Yeah, I think so.
It's just...
now that I've seen her...
she's so pretty.
Yes, she is,
but it's also a
huge responsibility.
Not that much.
I have a baby
and it is an impossible job.
You never think you're
doing well enough.
My mom will help.
I'd pay you guys back someday
for the pre-natal stuff.
We don't want the money, Tina.
You shouldn't change your mind
right now, where
everything's so emotional.
Tina!
My baby! Oh, look at this!
We tried to find you, Mama.
Oh, it's a boy or a girl?
A girl.
Oh, that's lucky!
She's just like
you. Lots of hair.
I think she knows me.
She's got your eyes, huh?
Oh, yes. Yes.
Oh, yes, pobrecita.
Yes.
Oh, look at that.
I want to keep her.
Well, of course you do, baby.
Mira, look at
that itty-bitty face.
Yes, mi pobrecita.
Excuse me.
Is there another Hotel Dupree
around this area?
No. It's the only one.
Problem? No, no.
It's just not quite
the dive I expected.
Uh, I'm here to see
a guest. Ray Ross.
Oh, well, Mr. Ross
is in the bar...
Why am I not surprised?
But he isn't a guest.
Mr. Ross owns this hotel.
Hey.
Doug.
Oh, what a surprise.
Yeah.
You found me.
You left your number, Ray.
Oh, yeah.
Come on, have a drink.
Listen, Ray,
I just wanted to give you these.
You know, I was going
to play along, Ray,
you know, like Mom
and I always did.
You know, take your...
your gifts
that drop out of the blue,
and I decided, uh, no, you know?
I'm not going to let
you get away with it.
Not this time. So...
you're not my father.
A father is someone
who was there
and you never were.
I know. I'm sorry.
You and your mother
deserved better.
Well, she did.
No, you did too.
Hey, Jimmy? Yeah?
I'll have a bottle
of Maker's here.
Right away.
Look, I'm beat.
I delivered eight
babies today, so...
Oh, yeah, sure.
Oh, yeah, I understand.
Boy, the night you were born...
I swore I was a changed man.
Your mother must have told you
how you came
into this world, huh?
Well, it's a hell of a story.
She must have told you
about the skates, huh?
She didn't tell you
about the skates?
We were up at the
cabin, and the lake was...
The cabin?
The one that the bank took back?
Yeah, well, that was, uh...
that was a mix-up.
Anyway, you weren't
due for another two weeks
and there your mother was.
She went into labor...
Right.
And the lake was frozen over
and the doctor was afraid
to drive across
the ice, you know?
So there's your mother, huh?
Strapping on skates
between contractions.
I swear, I thought
I was going to have
to deliver you myself.
Where is everybody?
You're the last
one to clock out.
Well, it's my last
day for a while.
Good luck.
Excuse me.
Do you have
any beet soup tonight?
Oh, you want the...
beet soup?
Surprise!
Oh, they got you good!
We did, didn't we?
I hate you guys.
I hate you.
Congratulations. Any day now.
We are so happy for you.
And happy it's not us.
Well put.
Here you go.
Little Susie liked it.
I hope you do.
One order of beet soup
and we can rush back
for Conni's delivery.
I wish! I wish. Oh!
That's a good shot.
What, are you out of breath?
No. No, no. Get out of there.
Ah,
you're getting slow
in your old age.
Come on, give me a break.
Give me a break.
No, you can't spin it.
All right, watch this one.
You better guard...
Aah!
Okay, rematch. Two out of three.
What do you want to play for?
Uh...
tickets to the Bulls game.
One for each of us, all right?
You're on.
Let's go.
Come on.
All right.
Okay, are you out of breath yet?
You need to sit down?
Ready?
Men are up. Men are up.
That's a score, champ.
Ready?