Get them off!
Get them off of me, please!
Get them off of me!
They're on me!
Robin Charles, early 30s.
Delusional and combative.
Lacerations on the soles
of her feet.
Treatment Six.
She's on 4 milligrams
of risperidone.
Nothing given in the field.
Vitals?
No.
Too agitated.
Couldn't get her hooked up.
Get them off of me!
Are we set? On my count.
One, two, three. Gentle.
Robin, do you know
where you are?
Do you know who I am?
Help me! Help me, please!
We need to sedate her.
Five of olanzapine,
50 of Benadryl.
Two of Ativan.
Two of Ativan!
Get them off of me.
No! No! No! No...
Dr. Rhodes?
So, you, um, starting
to figure out
why I didn't want her
leaving the hospital?
She was rational.
She was lucid.
I warned you.
Robin was fine, okay?
Suddenly, she just...
Suddenly, look at her now!
This is on you. You did this.
I gave her 5
milligrams of olanzapine
and she responded well.
So, we're gonna
titrate up to 10 a day.
Past that,
Med isn't the place for her.
Robin belongs in a long-term
locked facility.
Dr. Latham.
Go, Dr. Rhodes.
We'll text you if
there's any change.
Go.
Okay.
Thank you.
Daniel, you should go home
and get some rest.
You have to take care
of yourself.
Are you taking your meds?
Well, at least go up
to your office and lie down.
You see this?
Mandatory penis examinations.
"Under Illinois State Law,
all male emergency
department workers
"are required to have
a yearly penis exam,
"to be administered
by Dr. Stohl.
"Please contact him
directly."
Want me to prep you
a treatment room?
Graduation week.
Childish pranks,
not to mention
the binge drinking
and the stunts.
Every year, we have an ED
full of morons.
Youth, Dr. Stohl.
Yeah.
No. No, there are no exams.
No, it's a practical joke!
Dr. Shore,
Dr. Halstead, don't forget,
Keoni's luau tonight,
my grad party.
We'll be there.
Absolutely.
Great.
Mai Tais and poke.
Mmm-hmm.
Piña colada for me.
See you later.
Hey.
You and Nina look happy.
Yeah.
Hey, you two need to know
that Robin Charles is in Six.
What happened?
Psychotic break.
Oh, my God.
You're up.
Incoming. Poly trauma.
Go, go, go, go, go.
Twenty-two-year-old male.
Peds versus auto.
GCS 12, BP 100/70,
heart rate 125.
Got a student ID.
Kid's name is Marwan Haddad.
Hit-and-run.
The car dragged him,
like, half a block.
Sexton, FAST his belly.
On it.
Need X-rays.
Chest and pelvis.
And left lower leg.
Probably a Tib-Fib fracture.
Let's move him.
One, two, three.
Poor breath sounds
on the left side.
Christina.
It's okay.
It's okay. I'm Dr. Manning.
This is Dr. Halstead.
We're going to take
really good care
of you, okay?
Christina.
Easy. Easy.
Belly's clear.
He's shocky. I'm intubating.
Bilateral rib fractures.
Bilateral
pulmonary contusions.
And hemothorax on the left.
Sexton, chest tube.
On it.
Doris, hang two units
of O-neg on the level one.
Got it.
We got a medical history?
No. I spoke to his roommate.
Marwan's a Syrian refugee.
He's here to go to school.
That's about
all the guy knows.
His parents are on a plane.
They're flying in
from Germany,
to go to his graduation.
Poor guy.
Chest tube's in.
Good work.
Can you imagine?
Kid survives
cluster bombs in Aleppo,
just to come to Chicago
and get hit by a car.
Let me know when
he wakes up, all right?
I want to get a statement,
figure out who did this.
Absolutely. Thanks, Jay.
Yeah.
Dr. Rhodes,
I have news for you.
Oh, I should say
"Good morning."
Good morning, Dr. Latham.
If I'm not mistaken,
you don't seem to be
your usual self.
Tired?
No. I'm all right.
Thanks.
Okay. Good.
Did you page me?
Yes.
You remember
when I told you that
you weren't
my first choice
for this fellowship?
Yeah.
It was a South African woman
from Groote Schuur.
Well, the hospital has
allowed for another
second-year CT fellow,
so she's here,
joining our team.
Dr. Rhodes,
meet Dr. Bekker.
Ava.
Connor.
I'm sure
you two will enjoy
working together.
I'll leave you two
to get acquainted.
He's very odd. Asperger's?
Dr. Latham is
a great surgeon,
teacher and friend.
Oh. Loyal. That's sweet.
You know what, Dr. Bekker?
I'm not sure we will
enjoy working together.
Leah?
Okay.
Mr. Kellogg,
I'm the charge nurse.
Is Dr. Charles
ready to see me?
I texted him I was coming.
He may not be
checking his messages.
He had a family emergency.
He told me that I could
see him any time.
He promised.
I'm sorry.
But I can have one of
his residents see you.
I'm not talking
to some underling.
Is Dr. Charles here?
Yes.
But I don't think he's
going to be available.
You tell him that
I'm not going to be
treated this way.
I'm going to stay right here
and wait until he comes out.
Okay.
Hey. Get me a cup
of coffee.
The vending machine's
right there.
April, about last night...
No. It's just as much
my fault.
It never happened.
Dr. Choi, April, you're up.
Cesar?
Don Crocker,
47-year-old male.
Shortness of breath,
chest pains.
You're going to
Treatment Four.
Passed out on the stairs.
Neighbor found him.
I'm lucky.
BP 90/70.
Heart rate's at 110.
Twelve lead in the ambo.
All right, Mr. Crocker,
I'm Dr. Choi.
We're going to take
good care of you,
all right?
Okay.
Let's transfer on my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
Twelve lead shows a STEMI.
Activate the team.
Mr. Crocker,
you're having a heart attack.
Aspirin?
Yeah, 81 milligrams
and four of morphine.
Mr. Crocker, is there
anyone we should call?
Friends? Family?
No.
Someone at work?
Work from home.
Most days don't even
leave the apartment.
So, no one?
No.
Mr. Crocker, you've got fluid
backing up into
your heart and lungs.
That's why you're having
difficulty breathing.
April, let's give him
10 milligrams of Lasix
and place a foley.
We're going to get
the excess water
out of your system.
Okay.
Mr. Crocker?
He's lost consciousness.
I've got a pulse.
Take him up to the cath lab.
I'll intubate him there.
Page Cardiology.
Ready?
Yeah.
Why'd she do it?
Mmm.
Cut her hair.
A woman changes
her hair like that,
it's a big deal, right?
It means something.
Absolutely.
Yeah. So?
Well, don't ask me.
Oh, my God. What?
Are you coming to
my party tonight?
I don't know.
I haven't thought
about it.
Okay. Well, it won't be
the same without you.
All right.
Look, I'm busy, okay?
Okay.
But you are coming
to my party.
Hey.
Hmm?
Glad you took my advice.
She's sleeping.
At least let me buy you
some breakfast.
Cup of coffee, maybe.
Dr. Charles?
I have been reviewing
Robin's history,
just to make sure
we haven't missed
anything and...
Well, uh,
some of her symptoms,
they're not consistent
with a psychiatric disorder.
Dr. Reese...
Let her finish.
Two days ago,
when Robin came
to the hospital,
she was running
a mild fever, 100.2,
and her BP was elevated.
Now, at the time,
we didn't think anything
of it...
That's 'cause it's
a very mild fever.
And, of course
her BP was elevated.
She was on a forced hold.
She was agitated.
But when Robin was
brought in today,
it seemed
she was experiencing
visual hallucinations.
Now, auditory hallucinations
indicate a mental disorder,
but visual hallucinations
should be considered organic
until proven otherwise.
I think we all wish
that Robin had
a treatable physical
condition rather than...
I want to check
her ceruloplasmin levels
and run an FTA-ABS
as well as an MRI and EEG
to rule out sclerosis
and epilepsy.
Of course. Do it.
What's the matter with you?
She's trying to
make me feel better.
And bless her,
but she's grasping
at straws. Come on.
Are you so blinded
by your fear
that Robin inherited
her problems from you
that you won't even
entertain an alternative?
False hope, Sharon.
Come on. I don't need any.
You don't know that.
Where's the Daniel
who leaves no stone unturned
when diagnosing a patient?
Where's the Daniel
who never gives up?
Don't you think
your own daughter
deserves that much?
Thanks.
Hey, what are we
looking at?
He needs a new valve.
Ava Bekker, CT fellow,
Ethan Choi,
Chief Resident of the ED.
So, we crack his chest,
replace the valve.
Well, we don't need
to crack his chest.
Uh, Mr. Crocker's
been assessed
as intermediate risk,
and Transcatheter Aortic
Valve Replacement, TAVR,
is now FDA approved
for patients at that level.
We get excellent results
with open aortic
valve replacement.
With TAVR, you're just
inviting complications.
I don't agree.
Why put the patient
through a long operation
and a long pump run?
He can have
a functional heart again
in under two hours.
The less invasive,
the better.
Exactly.
Excuse me.
You're an emergency
medicine resident.
Why are we even talking?
Excuse you?
Because I value
Dr. Choi's opinion.
And I think you'll find
that Dr. Latham will
back me on the TAVR.
Fine.
I'm sorry you got
brought into this.
I didn't know about Robin.
I'm sure you want to be
with her.
Yeah. I'm all right,
but thanks.
This won't take long.
I'll let you know
how he does.
Thanks, man.
Mmm-hmm.
What level of oxygen
is he on?
100%.
Left upper lobe is
segmentally collapsed.
Probably plugged up
from a clot in his airway.
Yeah. Let's get
a bronchoscopy.
Yeah, clear out
any obstructions.
Hey, I never asked,
why'd you decide
to cut your hair?
Time for a change.
Oh.
I'm looking
for Marwan Haddad.
Oh, are you family?
We go to school together.
Oh, well,
he's being treated
right now.
Why don't you wait
in the lobby
and I'll tell you when
you can see him, okay?
Oh, Dr. Choi, take a look
at this girl in Two.
Probable distal
radial fracture
and concussion.
This young genius tied
a rope around a rafter
and tried to swing across
the school cafeteria.
What?
You'll see.
Oh, by the way,
I'm missing
my coffee mug.
Some cretin obviously thought
it would be amusing
to steal it.
I'll make sure to look out
for it, Dr. Stohl.
Thank you.
Closed distal radius
fracture.
Monkey suit.
Uh-huh.
Of course.
Swinging from the rafters,
gotta have a monkey suit.
So stupid.
No.
You should've seen
people's faces
when they saw you.
It was so clutch.
Senior prank.
We're graduating
from high school.
We'll need the Ortho
resident to see her.
I'm afraid we're going to
have to cut this suit
to set your arm.
No! It's a rental.
I'm sorry.
Your friend
lost consciousness
when she fell?
Yeah. I was
kind of worried.
Concussion is always
a concern.
I want to get a CAT scan,
head and neck,
just to be sure.
Don't worry. You'll be
out of here in no time.
I'll call Ortho.
Oh, Dr. Choi, you're coming
to my party tonight, right?
Uh...
Thanks, but I'm not
gonna be able to make it.
Early call tomorrow.
You sure? One Mai Tai.
Sorry.
Okay.
The valve is in position
and open.
I'm injecting dye now
to check it.
Fluoro.
Left coronary artery
looks good, but I'm not
seeing the right.
Could be occluded.
Can you get the wire in?
Let me try and cannulate
the right coronary artery.
Can't, the lumen's blocked.
There's no flow
on the right side.
Seeing right side
ST changes.
Calcium deposit
must have broken off
from the old valve
and occluded the RCA.
His heart is dying.
We've got to
open him up now.
What we should have done
in the first place.
And we're already making calls
to find her another bed.
We'll keep Robin here until
we can get her transferred
to a long-term facility.
We'll take good care of her.
I've dialed back
on her sedation.
Robin? Honey?
Get away from me.
Get away.
Get away from me!
Make him go!
Dan, Dan, Dan,
we got this.
You were right.
The tests I ran,
there's no indication
of any organic
medical condition
I'm sorry.
Robin's showing dyskinesia.
Did you notice that before?
The jerky movements?
Yeah, I assumed it's from
the antipsychotics.
Yeah. It could be.
Did you order
a paraneoplastic panel?
For auto-antibodies? Why?
Could we just run one?
Of course.
Graft is in place.
Let's get him off of bypass.
Unclamping the aorta.
Let's get his heart
beating on its own.
Defibrillate.
Clear.
Sinus rhythm.
Cut to 2 liters.
Hold on.
His right heart
is ballooning.
Back on full support.
Marty, what's he on?
Dobutamine at eight,
dopamine at five.
Give him
a milrinone loading dose,
epinephrine bolus
of 50 micrograms
and start inhaled nitric.
That's not
going to cut it.
His heart isn't coming back.
He's not leaving
this room without ECMO.
Won't that just set him up
for complications later?
Why do all the residents
in this hospital
think they can offer
their opinions?
No ECMO.
His heart is strong enough
to come back on its own.
I disagree.
Noted,
but this is my case.
All right,
cut to 2 liters.
The heart's
coming back.
Septum is midline,
SVR acceptable.
Pressure's holding.
Good call, Dr. Rhodes.
Yeah.
Let's decannulate.
His sats are down to 80.
There's his latest X-ray.
No improvement.
How much vent support
are we giving him?
Maxed out.
He's on bronchodilators,
and he's still not getting
enough oxygen.
Seventy-five percent.
Mmm.
If we don't correct
his hypoxia,
we're looking at
anoxic brain injury.
Mmm-hmm.
Let's get him up to the ICU
and put him on
cardiopulmonary support.
Right.
Your patient
has a friend here.
Girlfriend, maybe.
Oh, good.
I'll go talk to her.
Okay.
Thanks, Nat.
How long you been waiting?
I don't know,
about an hour.
Typical.
They lie to you here.
Stand up for your rights.
Hi. Are you
Marwan's girlfriend?
Is your name Christina?
Yes.
How do you know my name?
When he first came in,
he called out for you.
Do you know anything
that may help me treat him?
Any medical history?
Medication?
We haven't known
each other that long.
Okay.
We're taking Marwan up
to the intensive care unit.
If you want,
you can come wait up there.
All right. I'll have someone
come grab you, okay?
Dr. Stohl. I, uh...
I found your mug.
Where?
Thank you.
I'll, um, call Maintenance
to get it down.
Hello?
It's a joke.
There are no inspections!
It's a joke!
Get me Maintenance.
Here's
the paraneoplastic panel.
Wow.
Look at that.
You were right,
Dr. Reese.
It is objective.
It's physical.
Well done.
Where's the tumor?
There.
It's so tiny.
All that.
Page Dr. Latham.
Good news.
Your CT was negative.
You're gonna be fine.
See? I told you!
It isn't that.
She never does
anything wrong.
Straight A's, all Honors.
She got into Harvard.
Well, we'll start
the discharge paperwork.
Parents on their way?
Yes.
The school had trouble
getting a hold
of them, but yeah.
Hey.
So, what's with you
and Dr. Choi?
Nothing. What are you
talking about?
Oh, come on, April.
I'm your brother.
No. There's nothing
with me and Dr. Choi. Noah!
I just broke up with Tate.
You think I'm gonna jump
into another relationship?
Let me just say,
maybe Dr. Choi is no
all-pro football player,
but he is one hell
of a doc.
With decent
earning potential.
I'm just saying.
Maggie, where's Robin?
Let me call you back.
They took her upstairs.
She's getting a scan.
Doctor...
I saw Robin's scheduled
for surgery.
She has Anti-NMDA
Receptor Encephalitis.
It's very rare.
Dr. Charles had the idea
to test for it.
Some auto-immune response...
Gone awry.
Robin has
a mediastinal teratoma,
a benign one,
but her body's attacking
the tumor,
and it's also
attacking her brain.
Yeah, and the resulting
inflammation is what's caused
her psychiatric symptoms.
So, when
the tumor's removed...
Hopefully the psychosis
should resolve itself.
Wait. What's going on?
Come on in.
I'll remove the teratoma
via mediastinoscopy,
a minimally
invasive procedure.
Shouldn't take
more than 90 minutes.
You're gonna be okay.
I love you.
Dr. Latham,
I would like to assist.
Absolutely not.
Given your relationship
to the patient,
it would be inappropriate
and ill-advised.
I do not want you
in my OR.
It would still
be your surgery.
I just want to be there...
Dr. Rhodes, my understanding
of human behavior
may be limited,
but you are not acting
in the professional manner
that I am accustomed to.
Like any other friend
or family member,
you will sit
in the waiting room.
Dr. Bekker,
ah, will assist.
As soon as your
parents get here,
you can go.
How can I explain
what I did?
I don't even
understand it myself.
I do.
You got into Harvard.
Sometimes we work so hard,
hold ourselves so tight,
when we finally reach
our goal,
we go a little crazy,
swing from the rafters.
I don't know.
Listen to me.
You're gonna go to
a fantastic school.
Get a great job,
and 10 years from now,
you'll just think of this
as a happy memory.
Uh, Noah says you're not
coming to his party?
I'd really like it
if you did.
Should be done soon.
I was wrong to take Robin
out of the hospital.
I'm sorry.
Well...
I have certainly
been wrong, too.
Seeing the whole thing
through the prism
of my own fears.
Since I was a kid,
I always wondered
if there was something
I could've done
to stop my mom
from killing herself.
I obviously
couldn't save my mom,
but I was sure as hell
gonna try and save Robin.
At one point, I considered
bringing that up.
Decided it probably wouldn't
have been helpful.
Yeah, probably not.
Well...
She's not gonna want to have
anything to do with me
after this is all over.
That's for sure.
Any word?
No, not yet.
Everything okay?
Yeah.
She did well.
The tumor's out.
Now, we just have to rid
Robin's body
of the antibodies
with plasmapheresis.
Should take two hours,
and hopefully
she'll be okay.
Hey, Reese.
I've been looking for you.
I thought you might
want this back.
It was a gift.
Why would I want it back?
Oh, you know,
when people break up,
you give stuff back.
It's a Rubik's Cube, Joey.
Not a diamond ring. Keep it.
One more thing.
I'm dating Valerie.
I just thought
you should know.
I'm glad
you found someone.
Thanks.
Christina?
How are you doing?
We are doing
everything we can
for Marwan.
I'm pregnant.
We didn't mean it to happen.
We thought we
were being careful.
We were going to get married
after graduation.
Nobody knows.
You haven't
told your families?
We were going to tell
his parents tonight.
I am so sorry you both
have to suffer like this.
Dr. Choi?
Mr. Crocker.
They did have to
open your chest,
but you came through
just fine.
Oh, thank you.
Sure.
For caring.
Hey.
Hey. How's Robin?
She's good. Thanks.
Uh, you saw Mr. Crocker?
Yeah.
Pretty young to have
that kind of heart trouble.
Could be genetics, or...
He said he's alone, right?
He's not married.
No friends. No family.
None.
Loneliness puts you at risk
for heart disease.
That for real?
Yeah.
I think we all know
that love can hurt, right?
But loneliness?
That'll kill you.
What is it, Natalie?
Look at his X-rays.
Diffuse airway disease.
Even with CPS,
his lungs are getting worse.
Fast.
This poor kid.
What, are his parents
just flying here
to bury him?
Why can we not figure out
what's wrong with him?
We've been so focused
on his injuries.
Maybe there's
an underlying condition,
not related to the accident,
that we don't know about?
When Marwan got
his bronchoscopy,
his tidal volume dipped.
It shouldn't have.
Right.
The paralytics
should've relaxed
his chest wall.
So, why are his airways
still so constricted?
Why can't he breathe?
What if it's as simple
as Marwan's got asthma?
That would make sense.
He needs steroids.
But, Natalie,
if we're wrong,
they'll put him at risk
for infection and myopathy,
and that could
wind up killing him.
Well, we are out of options.
If we don't do
something now, he will die.
Candace, 125 milligrams
of solu-medrol IV.
Dr. Halstead,
Dr. Manning?
The patient's parents
are here.
They just arrived.
Great.
Hi.
Hello.
Thank you for
taking care of him.
How is he?
He was seriously injured,
and our main focus right now
is his lung function.
Tell me, is Marwan,
by any chance, asthmatic?
Yes, yes,
since he was a child.
It comes and goes.
His X-ray is ready.
Please, come with us.
Bilateral consolidation's
markedly improved.
His airway pressures
are coming down.
What does that mean?
It means
we think your son's
gonna be all right.
Thank you.
Mmm-hmm.
Candace, let's start
weaning him off
cardiopulmonary support.
You can stay
with your son.
Marwan's recovering.
You should go
introduce yourself.
I don't know.
They should know
who you are.
Are you good?
Yeah.
Some days,
I really love my job.
Asthma.
Astute diagnosis, Doc.
Hey, don't give me
all the credit.
I wouldn't have gotten there
if it wasn't for you.
You're the genius.
Marwan's awake.
I got a statement from him.
Ah, great.
I'll go check on him.
Thanks, Nat.
Mmm-hmm.
So, it's, uh, Noah's
graduation party tonight.
Yeah.
Should be fun.
Natalie asked me
to go with her.
You mind?
No. Of course not.
You sure?
Yeah.
All right. You know,
I'll tell her I pass.
You need to get
your act together.
Hey.
Is it time to go?
Nina, I haven't been
fair to you.
You deserve someone
as committed to you
as you are to him,
and I haven't been
that person.
This is about Natalie,
isn't it?
You lied to me, Will.
You said there was nothing
between you.
I don't know if
she has feelings for me.
But I have feelings for her,
and I can't go on pretending.
All this time? Pretending?
Nina, I care about you...
Get out of here, Will. Go!
I'll get my stuff
out of your apartment.
Sooner the better.
There are balloons
in my office?
Hundreds of them.
I can't get in.
Oh.
I'll call housekeeping.
Maggie...
Do people hate me?
No, Dr. Stohl.
It's quite the reverse.
Then why?
You know the saying,
"You only hurt
the ones you love."
A tumor?
Yeah.
Reaction to your antibodies
caused your
psychiatric symptoms.
So, I was crazy,
but I wasn't crazy?
Yeah,
something like that.
You should know something.
It was your dad
that came up
with the diagnosis.
Robin, he's hardly left
your side.
You should talk to him.
Hi, sweetie.
Honey. Um...
Robin, I, uh...
So, I think we can
call today a draw.
Didn't realize we were
in a competition.
Come on.
You know, you're quite
the gossip magnet.
Your mother
committed suicide,
you drove
your girlfriend crazy,
and you murdered
your attending,
Dr. Downey.
Well, then, you'd better
watch yourself, hadn't you?
I like dangerous men.
Whoo!
I want you.
Come on.
April.
Dr. Choi.
Ethan.
You're still here?
Mmm. Five minutes,
and I'm gone.
So good to hear
about Robin.
Yeah.
Well, we made it through
another year, Daniel.
Gonna get
a new bunch of residents
to drive us crazy.
Le plus ça change, baby.
Le plus ça change.
Good night, Sharon.
Good night.
Dr. Charles.
Mr. Kellogg?
I've been here all day.
You haven't answered
any of my messages.
I'm very sorry
I've had a, uh...
An unusual day.
Is there any way
we could talk first...
Liar!