Previously on ER:
We belong together,
Sam, Alex and I.
Sam knows that.
- Two weekends a month...
- Not enough.
- At the discretion of the Lopezes.
- I get to see my son at their discretion?
- Does that make sense?
- The worst thing...
is violate the judge's order as
we go into a custody hearing.
Remember a kid with
high blood pressure?
Tell him to get to the clinic...
- sometime before he's 30. CHEN:
17-year-old with pulmonary edema.
- Elgin? WOMAN:
There's no heartbeat.
Not genetic. It
was just bad luck.
Ow! Ow, ow, ow!
I haven't started yet.
Okay, little pinch.
Hey, you put in your
schedule request yet?
- Yeah, why?
- Because Alex has his teacher-parent...
thing next Monday,
and I'm on all week.
- I can swap Friday.
- Find another nurse.
Can't have one of our interns
changing bedpans during their residency.
Yeah, I'm still waiting
for my board results.
Call the USMLE.
It's multiple choice, for
God's sake, not rocket science.
Okay. All done. All done.
You are God's gift to
nursing, you know that?
- So Monday for Friday?
- I thought you were starting.
Yeah, well, not till I pass my
boards. I can't quit my day job.
- Morning.
- I thought you'd left already.
Orientation doesn't
start till this afternoon.
Figured I'd take
care of loose ends.
Return my microscope to the histology
lab, hand over supply-room keys...
- and sell my textbooks.
- This is your last day of freedom.
Why don't you read the paper,
go to the movies, sleep in?
Right, do as I say, not as I do.
- You find a place yet?
- I'll have a look while I'm there today.
- Are you a doctor?
- No, but...
Yes, actually, she's
just not on duty right now.
I got my hand slammed in a car door.
I'm supposed to get a dose of morphine.
If you just wait there, I'll
take care of that for you.
Refer to yourself properly. You'll never
gain any confidence with your patients.
Doesn't feel quite earned yet.
Fake it till it does.
- Where did you match?
- University of Michigan, Ann Arbor.
Well, we'll miss you,
but I hear it's quite nice.
Yeah, a.k.a. rich and easy.
Unlike my friend Abby, who's decided
to stay at County and do God's work.
Just like the rest of us
suckers. Hey, check this out.
The doctor is in.
Five-speed automatic, 340
horsepower, 5.7-liter Hemi...
V8 with MDS and ESP.
I'm assuming those
are good things.
Man, this is tight.
What'd you drive before?
- Nothing. I finally got the prize.
- So you won this?
What? No. Paying for
it out of my own pocket.
Not everybody gets
money from Mom and Pop.
- Really.
- Jing-Mei, take a look.
- I'm sorry, I'm late.
So are you leasing
this or did you buy it?
What do you think? I'm
still a resident, remember?
Hey, get that beast out
of here. This is a hospital.
Which is convenient because
if you ding this, you die.
- Hey, is this the intractable vomiting?
- Seventy-five, end-stage colon cancer.
Liver mets, fever
and abdominal pain.
I'd better go. There's a
patient I wanna check on.
Call me. Let me know
how it goes. Hold it.
BP's 92/64. Looks
pretty jaundiced.
- Who's your oncologist, sir?
- Don't have one.
Says that chemo wasn't working so
he signed himself out a few weeks ago.
- What about your primary-care doctor?
- Fired him. I wanted to die at home.
Called 911 anyway.
Guess he changed his mind.
- Need any help?
- Yeah, I do. Thanks.
Hey.
Thanks.
You stay in your
seat. Stay in your seat.
I need you to sit down
in your seat, okay?
- But, Mommy, I have to go.
- I know, honey. Just hold on. Okay?
I think my battery's dead.
Come on, lady. Move it!
- I think I have cables in here somewhere.
- It's okay. I got it.
- Dr. Carter, I was sorry to hear about...
- Thanks.
Wife says to let us know if
you need her to bring dinner.
We will. Okay,
we've got eye pain.
We've got swollen ankle,
excessive coughing, headache, gout...
- You all right?
- Headache. Yeah. How is Henry?
Haven't seen him all
week. We're in court today.
- Helps to keep busy.
- Yeah.
Okay, Chuny, fluorescein, saline
bullets and a Wood's lamp, all in Exam 4.
You got it.
We need paramedics. There's a
woman wedged between two cars.
She's awake and alert.
Yeah, State and 14th.
- Can you feel me touching
your legs? LINDA: No. No.
- Where's Michael?
- Are you having any trouble breathing?
- Get me out!
- How's the boy?
- I don't know. The door's jammed.
- I'll be right there.
Michael!
Okay, help is coming.
Just hang in there, okay?
That guy came barreling
through the cones.
- It's crazy.
- There's a first-aid kit in my trunk.
- Hurry.
- I'll get it.
Help me get it open. Come on.
- Michael.
- Hey, where do you think you're going?
Somebody stop him, damn it!
- Temp's up. One-oh-two-point-eight.
- No septic workup, though, right?
I don't need a workup.
I need ampicillin.
We can't give you anything
until the doctor examines you.
Now, is there anyone...
- you'd like us to call?
- No.
- Hi, Richard. I'm Dr. Chen.
- It's Mr. Gould.
Doesn't anybody teach
manners anymore?
Looks like you're a little
jaundiced, Mr. Gould.
- Any advanced directives?
- Yeah, DNR, but he wants antibiotics.
Sir, it's entirely possible these
symptoms are due to your colon cancer.
Antibiotics will do
nothing to help that.
I'm not ready.
We can figure out why you have a fever
or we can just treat you for your pain.
I said, I'm not ready!
Okay.
CBC, lytes, liver panel, blood cultures
times two, Zosyn 3.75 piggyback?
- Thought you were a nurse today.
- Abby's a nurse every day.
That's why she's
gonna kick ass as a doc.
How'd you score on the
boards? I never heard.
- Me either.
- Oh. Pretty close to the wire, isn't it?
Yeah. Listen, Dr. Chen,
is everything okay?
Um, give Mr. Gould two
liters of saline wide open...
10 of Reglan and four of
morphine once the pressure's up.
Hey. Where you been? Pardon me.
I took a few days off. My dad had
10 different doctor appointments.
- Nice car, by the way.
- Wait a minute. What happened there?
- Nothing, really.
- It doesn't look like nothing.
My dad's not sleeping well,
so I'm not sleeping well...
and I forgot to turn on a light
and ran into a door. Excuse me.
Dr. Pratt.
Damn, how many times I
gotta say goodbye to you?
I wanted to say bye to Elgin.
He's going home today.
Were you planning on it?
- Planning on what?
- Seeing him.
- Yeah, sure.
- Because he asked.
I get the impression
he looks up to you.
- Figured he was smarter.
- He could use a positive male figure...
in his life right about now.
Yeah, well, I'm
nobody's role model.
- Is he all right?
- Don't worry.
- They're taking care of him.
- Sir, clear the area.
- I'm a doctor.
- If this blade breaks you'll kiss metal.
- Please.
- Get your ass out of there!
Okay. Just hang on.
Okay, put direct pressure
on anything that bleeds.
Four of morphine and
one more liter of saline.
Get me the biggest
BP cuff you've got.
- How are you doing, Linda?
- Need to call my husband.
We will, but we need
to get you to a hospital.
Bolus saline on the pressure
bags. What's her BP?
108/70. Look, doc, we've protocols to
follow and you've broken most of them.
- Ten liters of O2. Let's go.
- Sorry, it's just us in the rig.
Oh, please, don't leave me.
- You can follow us...
- in your car if you want.
- I'm going with her.
Excuse me. Looking
for a kid named Elgin.
- Down at the end on the left.
- Thanks.
- Hey, what's up, man?
- What's up, doc?
How you doing?
Good. Just waiting on my mother
to come get me. My cousin's driving.
So, what have we
learned from all this?
Five a day, exercise some
and find myself a job...
at a vegetable stand
or something, I guess.
Good man.
Well, all right, then.
Take care of yourself.
Yo, doc, you got an
office somewhere?
Me?
We don't really have a doctor. I was
thinking maybe we could come see you.
Yeah, look. I just
work in the ER.
People come in, I see them once,
twice tops. That's it, you know?
Well, maybe we could
hook up something then.
The family clinic can help
you with whatever you need.
Just give them a call.
Tell them I sent you.
Stay on your meds.
- Guess he just got spooked.
- Midshaft clavicular fracture.
- That's a dangerous sport.
- He's usually steady...
except for that time
he refused to jump.
There's minimal
tenting. You're very lucky.
- This is not gonna need surgery.
- Broke my leg in two places.
Immobilization, Motrin for pain?
CARTER: Yep. Month in a sling.
The good news is
that will heal on its own.
But I'll miss the
Lamplight Classic.
- Get her a follow-up with Ortho.
- Be right back.
Wish I was that
fearless when I was 15.
- Is that fearless or is that reckless?
- She is fearless. I was reckless.
Hey, look, I didn't
wanna bug you earlier...
because you've heard
it from everybody, but...
Hey, Taggart, that juvenile
delinquent of yours is MIA.
- What?
- School called. He's a no-show.
Probably just out lighting fires
and torturing small animals.
- Alex playing hooky?
- More like his dad is.
Hey, it's me. Pick up.
Come on. Anybody home?
She's got it rough
with him, doesn't she?
Which one, the kid or the ex?
- Both.
- How are you and Kem doing?
- You'll get through this.
- Hey, Peaches and Herb...
multiple MVAs one minute out,
including a woman nearly cut in half.
Got control of the major
bleeders, but she's tachy.
We need Trauma, Ortho
and Vascular here now!
Thought you were working nights.
- I am.
Give her another five of morphine
and as much O-neg as you can get.
- Who do you got?
- Seven-year-old male...
unrestrained, tachy at 138. BP, 102/56,
multiple lacs to the scalp and face.
- It hurts.
- Hi. I'm Dr. Carter.
We're gonna take very
good care of you, okay?
- Who are you?
- My name's Abby. What's your name?
Antwan Coles, 20-year-old driver of
vehicle number three. Airbag deployed.
Vitals are good, but he's definitely
altered. Think I smell a little ETOH.
- How you doing, Antwan?
- Need to get me out.
No sign of head trauma.
Pinpoint pupils, shallow
resps, bradycardia.
- Push two of Narcan.
- Right here?
Yeah, unless you need
some practice intubating.
- You been shooting up, sniffing?
- No, nothing like that.
Pulse ox down to 82.
PRATT: Just give it a second.
Ah! PRATT: Come on. Let's go.
- You gotta back me up, brother.
- I'm Dr. Pratt.
You're under suspicion of DUI,
and you sure as hell ain't my brother.
I can't feel my legs.
- Got a flash.
- Am I paralyzed?
You received a lot of pain
meds, and you're in shock.
It affects your sensation.
- I'm in.
- Guide wire's ready.
- How's she doing?
Pelvic fracture by exam,
small fluid in Morrison's.
And hypotension. AP chest
and pelvis are on the way.
I'm Dr. Corday. I'm
a trauma surgeon.
You're bleeding internally.
We'll take you to the O.R.
What about my son?
Uh, I'm sorry. I don't know.
Michael's in good hands, Linda.
Distal pulses before
the cuffs were placed?
Ask Kovac. He examined her.
I couldn't tell. Take down
the cuffs, she bottoms out.
Wait till you're in the O.R.
Gram of Ancef, 200 of gent and
DT, if you haven't already done it.
- Why were you in the field?
- Good Samaritan.
Systolic's 74, pulse, 130.
Another unit of O-neg
and get the rapid infuser.
Got it. CORDAY: Page
Ortho down here 911.
Shallow resps,
good femoral pulses.
- You need the infuser?
- No. It's yours.
Tachy at 165, sats are only 84.
- Mommy!
- She's right next door, honey.
I can't get the
labs. He's thrashing.
Belly's soft. Give him
two more of morphine.
Michael, we're gonna
make you feel better...
- but you got to settle down, okay?
- Daddy, Daddy, Daddy!
He's on his way. Run
in a liter of warm saline.
Let's get this mask
back on you, buddy.
- Michael? Michael!
- BP's 74/37. He's bottoming out.
All right, we need to intubate.
Four-point-five uncuffed, 2 Mac Blade.
Come on! What are
we waiting for? Let's go!
Five cm lac over the deltoid.
Must've hit the doorframe
when he was trying to leave.
You don't know that.
- You don't know nothing, bitch.
- Hey, watch your language.
- No Attendings here?
- Got their hands full.
Urine tested positive for opiates.
Woke up cold with Narcan.
My guess, heroin by nose.
Get a CT, check for
bleeding or fractures.
Can I go after that?
Dog, you caused an accident.
No, an accident is when bad
things happen for no reason.
You were high
and ran into people.
Sew him up. Let
the cops sort this out.
- Decreased on the left.
- This one of the MVC patients?
- Mom's next door.
- Blunt chest trauma...
hypotensive, hypoxic
secondary to a tension pneumo.
- How old?
- Seven. Get an 18-gauge angiocath...
- and chest tube tray.
- Pulse is 78. He's bradying down.
That's gonna get worse till we
get compressed air off his chest.
- C-spine, chest, ab and pelvis?
- No, he's not stable.
Pulse ox, 84.
- I'll assist Dr. Carter. Ten blade.
- I got it.
- Dr. Weaver?
- Ten blade.
- You'll be late for court.
- I don't need any help with a chest tube.
- Good breath sounds.
- Systolic's drifting down.
- Another liter of NS.
- We need more O-neg.
- Is my husband here?
- Not yet.
Can you assist Dr. Carter?
- Ortho's here. We need bleachers.
- Get X-ray back to check line placement.
- Is he in trouble?
- No, it's just...
I'm afraid he's too
emotionally vulnerable.
Need an intubation tray.
- What, are you saying that he can't...?
- Do it.
- Wow, pretty ugly stuff.
- She can hear you. She is conscious.
Diastolic's dropping.
What happened
to Dr. Chen's face?
We might salvage with a BKA.
Which will be a nonissue when she
bleeds out from a massive hepatic lac.
Tube her, get her to
the O.R. for an ex-lap.
No. I wanna wait for my husband.
A laparotomy and a BKA.
We're double-teaming.
- What's BKA? What are they saying?
- You need surgery.
And receive
placement assistance...
anywhere in the USA.
Don't wait any longer to
enter the exciting world of...
Lost the pulse.
- That's P.E.A. Epi, 3 cc's.
- Starting compressions.
- Come on. CHEN: Abby,
check the Thora-Seal.
- That's not it.
- Maybe the tube's kinked.
- Or in a false tract.
- No, it's not it.
18-gauge angiocath and
another chest tube tray.
The mediastinum's not
widened. There's no crepitus.
- Holding compressions.
- V-tach.
- Charging to 40.
- Normal heart, no chronic lung disease.
- It doesn't make any sense.
- Clear.
- Still V-tach.
- Okay, come on. Needle. Let's go!
- Sinus at 58.
- Too slow. Another round of epi.
- Abby, that Gould guy's asking for you.
- Who?
- End-stage cancer with the antibiotics.
- Did you tell him I'm busy?
No, I wasn't gonna
deal with his ass.
Come on. Who's in and who's out?
- I'm in.
- Come on, .6 of atropine.
- You called?
- When am I getting my own room?
- It's noisy. It stinks.
- You'll get it when one becomes available.
- Don't patronize me.
- I'm not.
Fever's down. What do you need?
I dealt with a million
smart alecks like you.
Think you know
everything, you know crap.
Okay. Well, then, I'll be
back to check on you later.
- I was a teacher. Junior high. 37 years.
- I bet you were the kids' favorite.
- Weaver's on line one.
- Can you take a message?
She's in her car.
Hi, Dr. Weaver.
Have you called the USMLE
for your board results?
I haven't had a chance.
- Well, are you going to?
- Yeah. Fine.
- Fine.
- Okay.
- I'll be back.
- Whatever.
Frank, you have the number
for the USMLE around anywhere?
Do I look like 411? Here.
Let your fingers do the walking.
Excuse me, nurse. My
family was in an accident.
- Sinus.
- Weak carotid.
- It's better than nothing.
- 500 of NS, another HemoCue...
and let's get some
warm blankets.
- Heart rate's dropping. 48.
- Damn it!
- Starting compressions.
- All right, epi. Let's go. Mark time.
Michael?
- This the father?
- Yeah.
- What happened?
- Holding compressions.
He suffered severe trauma
to his chest in the accident.
His lung's collapsed, and
it's compromising his heart.
- We lost the pulse.
- Oh, my God.
- Let the doctors work.
- You have to do something.
- Pericardiocentesis needle.
- Not in tamponade.
I know.
Hey!
Open up!
You're home early.
What do you think you're doing?
We're watching TV. Why?
Because Alex is supposed
to be in school, that's why.
- Dad said it was okay.
- Well, it's not exactly his call, is it?
- I'm out of here. Later.
- I'll speak to you soon.
Can I speak with you a minute?
You can't do this. You can't pull
him out of school when you feel like it.
I wanted to take
the kid with me...
- You're high.
- What?
You smoked dope in front of him?
No, I went outside. I took a few
rips when he was watching TV.
- And it's no big deal, okay?
- Maybe not to you, but to me it is.
The reason I kept him out
was I wanted to take him...
Where? To an arcade or a movie?
- Or your dealer's house?
- To my interview, okay? Interview.
- All right?
- What?
He got, like, the
coolest job ever.
He's gonna manage this building and
they're gonna give him a place to stay.
Yeah, it's on upper Dearborn. It's
two-bedroom, two-bath, fully remodeled.
So now I can live with Dad too.
The judge will ask questions about
how you plan on caring for him...
while you're at work.
Meaning I'm less of a parent
if I have to hire a nanny.
- The Lopezes are retired...
- They're elderly.
They may not be alive long enough
for Henry to get to high school.
And can offer a
larger support system.
So now I'm being penalized
for not having a big family?
This is a conservative judge.
Her idea of what represents
the best interests to the family...
is pretty basic: two parents,
a man and a woman.
Unless she's planning to take the children
of every single parent in Chicago...
and place them with a heterosexual
couple, she's a hypocrite.
- I don't disagree.
- It's a myth.
This idea that there's some perfect
setting that everyone gets raised in.
You need to outline how
you're gonna provide...
a stable, consistent
lifestyle for him.
They brought him.
Sit back down.
If you interact, it could get volatile,
and that's not gonna help you in court.
He's grown.
You okay in here?
Who was that guy?
He's just some guy who had
a business proposition for me.
Look, Sam, just so you know, I
wasn't planning on staying, okay.
It just all kind of
fell into my lap...
which makes me think it
was supposed to happen.
You know, this manager
job is no great shakes...
but it'll keep me here
and, I don't know...
maybe I can go to night
school or something.
You know what Alex
said to me the other day?
What?
He said, "I love you, Dad."
Anyways, um...
I've got a bunch of furniture
with a buddy in Dallas...
and I figure I'd leave today, and
come back maybe this weekend.
Hey, maybe when I get back,
you and Alex can help me paint.
Sam.
Okay.
I'll see you soon.
- Hey, buddy.
- Hey.
I'm gonna take off. You
wanna walk me to my car?
Why can't I just go
to Dallas with you?
Because you got
school, that's why.
- You have to stay in bed.
- Need to use the restroom.
But you're dehydrated, and
your blood pressure is low.
- Let me get you a bedpan.
- Can't a person die with dignity here?
- I want a toilet!
- Okay, okay.
You have to let me help you.
Hold on.
So, what have I got, a week?
Three days, huh?
Never mind. Doesn't matter.
What subject?
Algebra.
Thirty-seven years.
Taught over 4000 13-year-olds.
What the hell for?
Well, I'm sure
you had an impact.
Oh, right.
And at the end, you're
alone, and you get cancer.
- I'm here.
- Yeah, only because you're paid to be.
- More laps and suction.
- BP's down to 78/40.
Ligate the femoral proximal
to the popliteal artery.
I can't control the
damn SMA bleeder.
Periosteum's shredded up to the midshaft,
and the perforating arteries are gone.
Dr. Kovac, you came after all.
- How is she?
On a scale of one
to 10, probably a four.
Repaired the spleen,
still oozing from the liver.
- Maxed out on dopa and Levo.
- Make that a three.
- Anything I can do?
- There's barely anything I can do.
Perry, start neo at
100 mics per minute.
That'll screw up
her distal perfusion.
Yes, well, the brain and heart
outrank the extremities, don't they?
- This is crazy.
- Atropine's in.
- He's got two chest tubes.
- Hold compressions.
- Pulseless.
- There's a huge air leak.
- He's got another pneumo.
- That's his third.
- Resume compressions.
- He's coding on and off for 40 minutes.
- Betadine and a 10 blade.
- Still P.E.A.
Another chest tube is not going
to fix it. His injuries are too severe.
- Somebody needs to talk to his dad.
- Well, think! I don't know!
- Another epi?
- No.
No.
Pulseless.
- I'm calling it.
- Whoa, whoa. Wait, wait, okay.
We're pumping air in faster
than the chest tube can suck it out.
- What are you doing?
- Bypass the left.
Stick it all down
the right lung.
He's lacerated his left
mainstem bronchus.
Resume compressions.
Even if he did, he's been
deprived of oxygen too long.
Just give it 10 seconds.
Okay, hold compressions.
Got a pulse back, 82.
CHEN: Sats coming up.
Okay, call CT and Surg.
Let's redline him upstairs.
We saved him.
Mr. Pryor?
We think your son has a tear in his
airway and is gonna need surgery.
But he's gonna be okay?
The injury's very serious,
but we hope to be able to fix it.
- Do you know anything about my wife?
- Just that she's in the O.R.
Someone can take
you to the waiting room.
- Can I be with her?
- Um...
- Well, she is being operated on.
- She'd want me there.
- Dr. Carter, you got a minute?
- Uh, no, not really.
- It's about Jing-Mei.
- Can you give me a second?
Can you just have
a seat right there?
Yeah, did she seem okay to you?
No, neither one of us are
having our best day. Why?
- There's this bruise on her face.
- I saw it.
She says it was an
accident. I don't know.
She seeing somebody?
I don't think so. She's
focused on her dad.
- Think it was him?
- Maybe. Probably.
Look, I'd get into it myself, but
things are complicated between us.
- I don't think that she'll listen to me...
- Pratt, your DUI homeboy's back from CT.
- I'll talk to her.
- Thanks.
So looks like in addition to being high
on H, you were also legally drunk too.
How you think your boy
out there is gonna feel?
- You know what he says to me?
- What?
He said because it's my third
strike, I'm gonna have to do 25-to-life.
I'm 20 years old, doc.
- You hit a woman and a kid.
- Yeah, but life?
What, you think that's right?
I think it's the law. Hey.
Lido and a 4-0 Vicryl.
I ain't got nothing
nowhere anyway.
I mean, what the hell
am I supposed to do?
I don't know, go to
school, get a job maybe.
Yeah, right, man. Who
the hell's gonna hire me?
- You grow up in Winnetka or something?
- Cabrini-Green.
- So I don't wanna hear excuses.
- Oh, okay.
I guess that makes
you one lucky son of a...
Hey! It ain't about luck.
You know what? You right.
It ain't about luck.
I guess it's about not looking
back once you're gone.
Doc.
Mom? When are you making dinner?
- Mom?
- I'll deal with the clothes.
You put all the stuff that
you wanna keep in these.
- What?
- We're moving.
- No!
- Come on. Hurry up.
- I don't wanna go.
- You don't exactly have a choice.
- I'm not going.
- Yes, you are.
- I like it here.
- Yeah, so did I.
- You're just being a bitch.
- What did you call me?
I'm sick of moving
because you're screwed up.
You know what I'm sick of, Alex?
I'm sick of pretending
your dad is a good guy.
I'm sick of keeping quiet about the crap
he's done and the stuff that he hasn't.
I'm sick of him tracking us
down every time he loses a job...
so he can buy you
presents to make you think...
he's actually a father because
he's not. He's a user, a loser...
and I am not gonna let
him turn you into one.
Now get your ass in that
room and start packing!
Last one. Cover with ABD
pads. I'll write post-op notes.
- So you saw the whole thing happen?
- Yeah, her car broke down.
- I stopped to help.
- She's lucky.
- Most people would've carried on driving.
- We've got an audience.
Must be the husband.
I'll go talk to him.
- How soon before she wakes up?
- That's hard to say.
- Mr. Pryor?
- Yes.
I'm Dr. Kovac.
I was with your wife at the scene of
the accident and during her surgery.
I'm gonna check
back in with you later.
Is she gonna be all right?
She suffered massive internal
injuries, and she lost a lot of blood.
- Oh, God.
- But we were able to stop the bleeding...
and we're confident that
she's gonna pull through.
But, uh, her legs
were severely injured...
and orthopedic surgeons
were not able to salvage them.
- What?
- We had to amputate.
In both legs?
I'm sorry.
Yeah, I took it a couple
weeks ago. Lockhart, Abigail.
I mean, I should've
gotten them by now, right?
Aren't you supposed to send
them to my home address?
We sent them to
your work address.
You're kidding.
Yeah, I will. Hey, Frank.
If I received a letter
here, would you tell me?
Hell, no. If a letter came, it
would be filed alphabetically...
in the mail drawer with everyone else's
crap. As if I didn't have enough to do.
Excuse me. I'm
looking for a patient.
Last name, Gould.
Let's see if he's awake.
Mr. Gould?
Who the hell is that?
It's your former student.
Hey, Mr. Gould.
Ed Minyard? I had
you for algebra.
In both '73 and '74.
Flunked you because you didn't
follow directions on your final.
Yeah, that'd be me.
- What are you doing here?
- I teach at Larchmont now.
Math, which is kind of karmic.
Someone called the school,
told us about your situation.
I've reviewed all the written testimony,
and I have follow-up questions.
Mr. and Mrs. Lopez, I
understand you're both retired.
Yes, Your Honor.
Can you describe your
physical condition currently?
My wife and I are both in
good health, Your Honor.
A statement from your
physician would verify this?
Yes.
Dr. Weaver, just to clarify.
Both your parents are deceased
and you have no siblings?
That's correct, Your Honor.
I'll take this under
submission, and parties
will be notified of
my decision when...
Your Honor?
I love my son.
Mr. Brooks, does your client
wish to address the court?
- No, Your Honor, she...
- And I loved Sandy very much.
- Kerry, please.
- Together, we decided to have a baby.
We chose a sperm donor, got
pregnant, had a miscarriage...
and together, we tried
it again. And that time...
thank God, we succeeded,
and we had Henry.
I was there when he
was born. I cut his cord.
We made our way through every
cold, every rash, every colicky night.
We fed our son and
changed him and bathed him.
We were a family,
whether any city, or state...
or country gives
us that recognition.
And we still are.
You'll be notified
of my decision.
- Is that it?
- Yeah.
All right, I'll be right back.
- ER.
- Yeah, can I speak to Dr. Kovac?
Yeah, just a minute.
For you.
- Hi, this is Dr. Kovac.
- It's Alex. Could you come over?
- My mom's freaking out. She...
- What are you doing?
Hello?
Surgery said that the
lung repair went very well.
He has my ears.
I was hoping he'd get my eyes.
Everything else was Linda.
That's probably a good thing.
You have kids?
No.
Honey?
I'm here, baby.
So is Michael. He's
right next to you.
What happened?
They had to take
your legs, honey.
But you're gonna be okay.
You're gonna be good.
J, K...
- It's empty.
- Look under N.
- For Lockhart?
- For "Nurses."
Doctors' Lounge is on the third floor,
where I'm sure you'll be spending...
little or no time if you
know what's good for you.
My office is on the second floor, where
hopefully you'll spend even less time.
And in keeping with
orientation tradition...
some of our departing
third-year residents...
will escort you
to a local eatery...
where you will eat, drink
and pride yourselves...
on having matched at one of
the finest hospitals in the country.
So I'll see you all tomorrow
morning bright and early.
All right, who likes Mexican?
Make sure Dr. Goodman
sees me before he leaves.
We need the PPD
results from his file.
- Excuse me.
- Dr. Rasgotra.
Would it be possible to
speak with you privately?
Transitional internship
leading to Dermatology, right?
Right this way.
Ha!
Ha, ha! Ha.
- Good news?
- Yeah. I passed my boards.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Oh, God.
Sorry, I'm just...
- You going home?
- Yeah.
- Give Kem my best.
- I will.
Hey, Abby.
I never had a doubt in my mind.
Yeah!
So, what can I do for you?
I, uh, I don't know how
to go about this, but...
I never actually made
this choice for myself.
I mean, I told my parents in third
grade that I wanted to be a doctor...
and ever since then,
it's been assumed.
It's a good thing I never
said I wanted to join the circus.
I don't think I can do it.
I've been thinking about
it the whole way here...
and for the last
year, actually, and...
Are you withdrawing from
this residency program?
I'm sorry.
You're really leaving
us in quite a lurch.
What are you gonna do, then?
I'm not sure.
You understand you can't get
licensed without an internship.
I know.
You went to MIT after all.
- Yes.
What did you always used to say?
"Math is the true universal language."
"And love is for suckers."
Mr. Gould, this is Dori. She's
taking care of you tonight.
- Hi. ABBY: He's waiting
on a bed in Medicine.
You might wanna give them another call.
- Young lady?
- Me?
- Will you be my nurse again tomorrow?
No, I won't. Uh,
but I will be here.
Just ask for Dr. Lockhart.
Alex, come on. Get
in the car, please.
Alex, please. Come on, we'll
get something to eat on the way.
Sam! ALEX: Luka!
What happened? What's going on?
- Look.
- What are you doing?
- Alex and I have to leave.
- What?
- It's complicated.
- I don't understand.
- No one does.
I can't let it happen. I
can't let him get to my kid.
I'm sorry.
- I don't wanna go!
- Wait. Why are you doing this?
Sam, talk to me. Hey.
Sam!
Hi.
Hi. We're running
low on ibuprofen.
Is that right?
I know it's none of my business.
You know, I was just
trying to give him a bath.
Was it an accident?
He doesn't know what
he's doing anymore.
Did you talk to anybody about
it? Because I think you should.
I'll be okay.
Wait. Hold up.
Hold up. Jing-Mei.
Look, call his nurse. Ask her to
stay an extra couple of hours...
so I can take you to
dinner and we can talk.
Jing-Mei, I'm
still your friend...
whether you wanna
believe that or not.
Pratt.
Cops need you to sign
off on your DUI ghetto kid.
- He's medically clear, right?
- Sutured and good to go.
She should have been here
by now, man. What time is it?
- Just about 5.
- What's up, doc?
- Did he get his discharge instructions?
- Four hours ago.
Can't get in touch with my
mom. Phone ain't working.
You need a ride?
- I got the Chrysler outside.
- For real?
- Zero to 60 in 5.6 seconds.
- Let's go.
Yo, this is one nice ride, man.
This is the best I've been in.
- Hey, is your safety belt fastened?
- Like this song right here?
Wanna turn it up, bro?
Hands don't even
have to leave the wheel.
How many speakers you got?
Eight with a subwoofer
and 380-watt digital amp.
You're gonna blow them out...
not to mention our
high-frequency hearing.
- What'd you say?
- The lady wants it down a notch.
- Is that better?
- Thank you.
All right, all right,
keep your shirt on.
Hey, jack off! Try to
pay attention to the road!
- What's your problem? Get out of here.
- Pay attention to this.
- Oh, nice.
- All right, we're out of here.
See you, suckers!
Feel that Hemi power,
baby. It's a beautiful thing.
Do you wanna slow down now?
Pratt, slow down.
There, everybody
happy now? Okay, good.
Greg.
- Son of a bitch!
- He's shooting at us!
Get down! Come on. Hold on.
We gotta get out of here!
Hold on!
Where is he?
We gotta get away from him!