Previously on ER:
- We're closing down.
- It's only temporary.
How do you know? Old boys run
around here, checking for cracks...
and now we're
having some dinner.
Probably just wants
to boost morale.
How are we affording a
fancy place? It's not Ladokern.
- Finally get things sorted out with Neela?
- There's nothing to sort out, man.
Neela, I want you to say hi to Mae Lee
Park. She's our new surgical med student.
- Hi, nice to meet you.
- I've heard a lot about you.
I can smell a wedding a mile
away, Archie. It's like a sixth sense.
It's in your eyes. You have the
glow. I can't wait for the glow.
I can't wait to try on
wedding dresses with...
Hope!
If you tell
anyone I'll kill you.
Oh, man, what you swinging at?
We're closed.
Yeah, I work here.
Then you ought to know the ER
is shut down until further notice.
I'm an R3.
I left something in
my locker. You mind?
Go on. You might need this.
Yeah, just a second.
Come on, Mayday, we're
gonna miss the canapés.
- What are you doing here?
- I thought we'd go together.
Oh.
Or not. Wow.
You look, uh... Wow.
Listen, I know things have
been a bit crazy with me.
- And our relationship is undefined, but...
- Yeah, we should talk.
Ahem. Yeah, maybe...
I don't know, maybe
we could talk at dinner?
Yeah. Uh...
Let me just get my stuff.
Why are we here so early?
Well, I'm the chief.
I thought I should
be here first.
Were the chief.
Well, consider this
my last official act.
The department dinner is here?
Yup.
Haven't been in a neighborhood
like this since I tried to score crack.
- Budget cuts are getting serious.
- Come on, it's different.
That's for sure.
See this? Pretty cool, huh?
Is this a restaurant?
No, no, it's a rental space.
- A patient told me about it.
- Oh.
And was she, by any
chance, a porn star?
- He is a music producer.
- Oh.
So it is a drug den.
Since when did these
things get so formal?
- It's fun, people like to dress up...
- Good evening.
Dr. Kovac,
Dr. Bobeck's in back...
and she needs you to make a
decision about the centerpieces.
- Hi. Big night, huh?
- Hi.
What's he talking about?
Hope is here. She
helped set everything up.
What do you mean,
"helped set everything up"?
What do you think?
Yay, yay, yay!
A wedding. ABBY: No.
- You the bride?
- Nope.
- Sophie, her dad's the caterer.
- No.
- She's your flower girl.
- Like hell.
Abby.
You're kidding me, right?
You gotta be kidding me.
- Can we just please talk?
- How do I get out of here?
You're just nervous.
It saves you the stress.
- Do you think I look unstressed...?
- The cake's coming up.
- Where you want it?
- Check with Hope.
How could you imagine
I'd wanna do it like this?
Planning was freaking you.
It's ripping off a Band-Aid.
Oh, man, you really know
how to melt a girl's heart.
This is something we both want.
- Oh... Luka, it's crazy.
- We can do something for families later.
- Tonight is for us.
- Yeah, and a bunch of people from work?
- Our friends.
- What about the food, the music?
It's like getting married
in a Meat Loaf video.
- I took care of everything, Hope helped.
- It's like a labyrinth.
Hey, hey, hey.
I love you, you love me.
Let's make it forever.
Let's get married.
ER rocks.
Party like New
Year's in Mozambique.
Looks like somebody
already started.
Mm-hm. Which way is the bar?
- Back there. MARQUEZ:
I hope they got margaritas.
I need me an apple martini,
something strong and stiff.
I'll race you to that martini.
- Oh, there's the bar.
- Luka...
- Give me 10 minutes.
Hey, hey, 10 minutes. Let
me show you what I've done.
If you don't like it, I'll
take you home. I promise.
Come on.
One foot after the other.
- Looks like a Victoria's Secret ad.
- Oh, it's so pretty.
I love the way ER
people do things.
Is something going on
we don't know about?
No, you guy... Hi.
Not there. PRATT: Hope...
- I'm gonna set you up here.
- Morris.
What's the deal,
bro? What's going on?
Well, tonight is the night.
What are you talking about?
Abby and Luka,
they're getting married.
- You were right.
- I told you.
Abby and Luka
is getting married.
- Seriously?
- Dr. Kovac and Dr. Lockhart?
- Yes, siree.
- That is so dope.
- A surprise wedding, how novel.
- Doesn't sound like Lockhart.
- Does Abby know?
- It's awesome, isn't it?
We're just running a bit behind.
We've hit an itty-bitty snag.
- Do you need help?
- No, thanks.
- Small case of cold feet. Ha-ha.
- It's a logistical issue.
We will be sealing this deal
within the hour. Excuse me.
I know what you think.
That this is a manipulation that
makes me question our relationship?
Maybe it's a symbol
of how much I love you.
How well I know you, how
deeply we're meant to be together.
Jeez.
What kind of ring
do you think I got?
I have no idea what
kind of... It's not bad.
I don't wanna
ruin the surprise...
but there will be no Celine
Dion, Air Supply, boy bands.
- Not even Menudo?
- The food is international.
- Name the country, we got it.
- What am I gonna wear?
- I'm supposed to wear this?
- You mentioned it.
I was half asleep and you
were flipping through a magazine.
You thought I wasn't
paying any attention.
That's not gonna fit.
- Hope sized it off your other things.
- Hope, Hope, Hope.
Her cousin's a tailor.
She's got him on standby
if it needs any adjustments.
Croatian sensation pulls
a rabbit out of the hat.
I just wanted to
make the wedding...
that I thought was
gonna make you happy.
- Ha. Luka.
- Oh, no, don't say no.
Not now, not after everything.
It's too weird.
It's too sudden.
You just wanna just do it on
the spur of the moment like this?
If there was ever anything
that was not rushed into...
it's you and me promising
to be together forever.
You know, Ray... Thank you.
Weddings are great
opportunities for guys like us.
Weakens a woman's defenses.
Sure.
You ever think
about settling down?
- Sometimes, I guess.
- Hmm.
You?
- Me? Ha-ha-ha.
- Mm-hm.
No, never.
If I did, I would never admit it.
- Hi, guys. Hey.
Well, the bar's right there.
Yeah, but, you
know, I said more half.
Ahh. Bartender, give
my friend another.
The energy is
sagging. Do something.
Here, have a drink.
Mm.
Timing, momentum, flow,
they're crucial to an event like this.
Calm down, everybody's
having a good time.
It is sagging, damn it.
- Lapel, lapel, lapel.
- Don't tell me to calm down.
- Thank you. Okay, this is easy.
- I'm sorry. Sorry.
Excuse me, do you have
a playlist that I can see?
Bum-bum-bum-bum
Look, it's sweet, it really
is, and I love that you did it.
But this should be something
that we plan together.
Something we both want.
- What else do you want? I'll get it.
- Luka...
We could put this off forever.
Always gonna be reason not to do it.
We want it, we deserve it.
So let's stop stalling
and dive in the ocean.
Jump into the pool.
- It's been seven years, Abby.
- I know how long it's been.
- Look, I just...
- Hey, let's just do this one thing.
That's fast and easy and right.
Let's get married, right
here, right now, tonight.
And what about Joe?
We can't get
married without Joe.
My secret weapon.
Save the best for last, huh?
This is pretty kooky, huh?
Them getting married like this.
Yeah, it's pretty
kooky. Heh-heh.
- How's it going down there?
- Oh, they're getting ready.
What's this?
It's for you.
Heh. I know, I started doing a little
bit of recording again on my own.
It's got some songs
I've been working on.
Really? That's great.
There's one about you
that you'll have to figure out.
Plus a few others I burned.
Some songs we used to listen
to when we were roommates.
I'm sorry, Ray.
About what?
I thought I was coming
alone, and he just turned up.
I didn't know what to do.
No offense...
but not knowing what to do
has become your baseline.
This isn't easy for me, Ray.
I've had a pretty
hard time ever since...
Losing Michael.
- I still haven't quite...
- Yeah, I know.
I mean, Tony was new.
There's no history.
Didn't make me think
about things from before.
Maybe I rushed into it because
it made moving on easier.
So I feel like history to you?
Well, I couldn't separate
you from Michael.
I couldn't be with
you and not feel guilty.
What about now?
Now?
I'm not sure all that
matters anymore.
Meaning?
Ah! There you guys are.
Neela, Abby needs to see you
before the ceremony, come on.
Okay.
- I gotta go.
- Okay.
Okay.
- This is so nutty.
- Tell me about it.
- It's great, everyone's so excited.
- I have to ask you a question.
What do you need? Something
borrowed, something blue?
Chuny has a scarf, it's
aqua, but might do the trick.
Can you just sit down
for a second? Sit down.
Sorry.
First, I know this has been
a really rough year for you.
And I don't think I have been
around as much as I should.
- And I feel bad about that.
- Oh, you don't have to.
But you have always been
a great friend to me, so...
So I was wondering...
if you didn't mind, do
you think you could lead...
and stand up there with
me when we do this?
You mean, like be
a maid of honor?
Well, I hate to put that kind
of conventional term on it...
but yes.
I'd be honored.
Thank you.
Your first job is to figure
out how I put these in my hair.
- Hair?
- Yeah.
It's a Croatian thing, I don't know.
They belong to Luka's mother.
Okay.
Okay, stop it, don't start now.
Oh, God.
I know.
Whew.
Come in.
- There he is, dead man walking.
- Ha-ha.
Very funny.
You're not getting
cold feet, are you?
I could find a back
way out of here.
I'll have you at a gentlemen's
club in under 20 minutes.
Pratt... I'm just
teasing you, man.
So Hope said you wanted to
talk to me, said it was important.
We've had our moments, Pratt.
And I haven't always liked
the things you've done...
or the way you've done them, but
I've always respected your reasons.
Thanks.
I had to supervise you...
which wasn't always
easy for either of us.
But I think we've managed to reach
a place where at the end of the day...
we're also friends.
Yeah, I feel the same way.
Would you stand up for me?
Wait, you mean, like...? Heh.
Be my best man.
Anytime, anyplace.
- Don't lose that.
- No.
It's go time, my brother, are
you ready? Because it's go time.
Let's do it.
Oh... Your tie's crooked.
- Let me fix that.
- I'm fine.
- Leave me alone, stop pointing that...
- Okay, sorry, I'm just emotional.
I'm emotional.
Everything's good,
everything's under control.
- There's just one minor change.
- Change?
The justice of the
peace couldn't make it.
- Someone else is doing the ceremony?
- Very experienced. It will be lovely.
Okay, go. Go, go, go.
Go, go.
Okay.
- Ready?
- No.
- She'll be fine.
- Take this.
- I don't...
- You wanna make Sophie cry?
I'm sorry, but I'm
really not ready.
Why do you have to be a whiner?
- Why do you have to be a crybaby?
- Okay, sweetie. Ahem. Come on.
Go, go, go. ABBY: No, no.
Just don't...
Welcome.
I understand from my
notes, "Luka and Abigail..."
Um... It's Abby.
Have no patience for the normal
rituals, which I find a little meshuga.
But, hey, if that's how you
want it, we'll get right to it.
Today, you become a man. No,
sorry, bar mitzvah this morning.
Kid was such a schnook.
Here. Marriage is an important
step, a great responsibility.
Uh... A coming
together of souls.
Yada, yada. Yada, yada.
Any readings?
No, no, no.
No readings? Oh.
Come on, readings
are a nice touch, classy.
- I've got one.
- You do?
Yeah, it's a Punjabi tradition.
- Oh.
Um...
- That's beautiful.
- Thank you.
What is it?
It's about love,
faith and devotion.
It's kind of a blessing.
Alrighty.
Next thing.
Any ex-lovers wanna say something
about why these two shouldn't be married?
- Okay, moving on.
- Okay.
- Vows.
- No vows.
Can you just skip ahead to
the I-now-pronounce-you thing?
No vows?
You have vows?
Be my wife.
I offer myself with all
my faults and strengths.
We'll help each other
when we need help...
and work together
to raise our son.
I choose you as the
person I will love and honor...
for the rest of my days.
Abigail?
Well, it's not really fair,
because you got to practice.
- Abigail. Abigail?
- It's not fair, because he got to...
It's Abby.
Um... Well, okay.
Okay.
First of all...
First of all, I love you.
I do.
And you've helped
me through a lot.
And we got here together
with a beautiful little boy.
And I was thinking of
a poem before, actually.
Before, when I
was getting ready.
And I think it starts:
I carry your heart in my heart
I am never without it
Anywhere I go, you go
I'm probably messing...
the whole thing up...
but I think the end goes:
And this is the wonder
That keeps the stars apart
I carry your heart I
carry it in my heart
So I guess what I'm saying is...
let's just try to love each
other and persevere.
Jeez. Hmm.
For two people who
wanna cut to the chase...
you sure know how to go on.
Rings.
Humor me.
By the power vested in me by
Cook County and the state of Illinois...
I hereby pronounce
you husband and wife.
Step on the glass
and kiss that girl.
Attention. Attention, please.
Quiet. Shut up.
I have been asked to kick off...
the party portion of
tonight's festivities.
Thank you, thank you.
And I'd just like to say...
that this is clearly a
marriage made at County.
Aw.
Because if we worked
at Northwestern or Rush...
there'd be better food
and a lot more booze.
The top shelf
stuff, right, Lucien?
Relax, big guy.
Hey, you know, I'm not
saying that Kovac is cheap...
but he did try to get Murray, the
roach-coach guy to cater this thing.
Anyway, the kids have rested up
and are ready for their first dance.
So I give you...
Abby Lockhart, Luka
Kovac, married couple.
It was so beautiful.
What you said, it really added
an ethnic spice to the ceremony.
I was just trying to do my part.
What did it mean?
Uh... I wasn't really prepared.
Don't be so modest,
you were great.
Oh, it meant:
"I went to the market
to buy some meat...
but the butcher wasn't
there, so I got fish instead."
It was the only Punjabi I
could come up with in a pinch.
Okay.
Let's just keep that
between ourselves.
Stevie Wonder, huh?
I told you, I hear
everything you say.
I know, sweetie.
Just try to go to sleep, if you need me
or just wanna talk to me, call me, okay?
It doesn't matter what time, just
call me and I'll be here, all right?
Okay.
I love you too.
Bye.
Missing the first dance.
Eh.
Sarah called, she's
having a rough night.
Is she all right?
She's a tough kid, mostly.
Sometimes she's just a kid.
Are you all right?
Yeah, yeah.
I'm happy for
them, this is good.
This is a beautiful night.
I'm fine.
Tony.
I just don't get it sometimes.
You know, I don't...
Why did she do this?
I mean, I think I'm handling
it fine most of the time.
But then other times, I
get so damn angry at her.
I mean, how could she
leave a beautiful kid like this?
How could she mess
with our minds like this?
- How could she lie to us?
- It's okay.
- It's not okay. It's not okay.
- It's okay to be angry.
It is? She's dead.
I'm angry at Michael.
Still. I'm not sure
I'll ever get over it.
I...
I haven't been a good
friend. I know that.
I screwed up, and I
wanna make it right.
I wanna make it better.
Can I have another chance?
Tony...
I don't think this is the
time or the place for this.
It seems perfect to me.
I...
Maybe we should talk
about this another time.
- We can go for coffee this weekend?
- Coffee?
People get back together over
dinner. They break up over coffee.
I just need to get back inside.
All right, please.
Listen a few minutes.
You're having a
good time. Lovely.
Twinkle toes, you did
a great job out there.
All right, just give
a few seconds.
Listen, first and foremost,
I have to thank Luka...
- for inviting us all here today.
- It's not like we had a choice.
I think I speak for everyone,
including Frank, when I say...
that it is an honor and a privilege
to be here on your special day.
- Hear, hear.
Now, you guys know me. I've
never been married before, so...
But he's dated women who were.
Leave your mom
out of it, Morris.
What's the difference between
an ER nurse and a Porsche, Sam?
Okay, okay, okay.
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
All right, listen.
I can't believe you guys
save lives for a living.
But really, I've had the great pleasure
of working with Abby and Luka...
both of whom I consider friends.
And I see them working together,
sharing a life, sharing a family.
Tonight's been a great night,
and I know... We all know.
That this can't last forever,
but I think we all do agree...
that the love between you
two will, and I know it will.
And hopefully, with some luck...
maybe some of that love
will rub off on all of us here...
and help us find
someone as special.
Someone to spend the
rest of your lives with...
as friends and as lovers.
To Abby and Luka.
And love and
friendship. Hear, hear.
DJ, you know what
to do, come on now.
Oh, here we go. Marquez?
Hey, baby.
Who are you talking to?
The hottest nurse in the ER.
Don't take a plate away without
making sure the guest is finished.
And make sure that there are no empties
and don't forget to crumb the tables.
And you, button
your vest up, please.
- Hope.
- What are you doing here?
- No, you should be out there.
- Hope.
- The bride cannot be back here with...
I want to thank
you for all of this.
You do?
Yes.
Oh.
You're not gonna hurt me?
No.
What's wrong?
You're just so beautiful.
Okay.
Luka.
Hey, have you seen Abby?
Congratulations, Luka.
You're a lucky guy.
- Thanks.
- No, really, Abby's great.
- I know.
- Don't ever hurt her.
- Excuse me?
- I mean it.
Okay.
Chuny.
Anybody ever told you, you
is the hottest nurse in the ER?
Yeah.
No, no, no,
seriously, I'm sorry.
You're great, you'd
never hurt her, I know that.
What was I thinking?
But if you did, I would hunt
you down like a cheetah.
Hello.
Lucien, having fun?
Yeah, it's fun.
It's a lot of fun.
I went to a Surgery
wedding, it was such a bore.
All they did was
talk, talk, talk.
ER weddings have spunk.
Yeah.
- They're serving coffee now...
- What about you, are you having fun?
- Yeah.
- It is fun, isn't it? It's a lot of...
Fun.
Uh... I have to go
to the bathroom.
I'm looking for...
Pardon, I'm so sorry.
Has everyone gone bonkers?
Hey.
You all right?
- I always cry at weddings.
- Oh.
I'm alone.
Oh, well, it's all right.
I just wanna say...
I appreciate all the
mentoring you've done.
Have I done that?
And I totally admire you a lot.
And...
I just really wanted
you to know that.
Really, really know it.
Yo, there's some freaky
stuff going on in here, man.
Yeah, probably
something in the water.
Timmy told me I was the
hottest nurse in the ER.
What do you want from
me, a second opinion?
Hi, I'd like a dry dirty martini
and a tequila sunrise, please.
Hey, Ray, what's shaking?
Dry and dirty?
I should've figured
that one out.
Actually, I prefer the tequila sunrise
because of all the pretty colors.
Asshole.
Gates, what are you doing? Save
some liquor for everybody else.
Another one, please,
vodka and cranberry.
Ray, there's a party going on here,
everybody's having a good time.
So anytime you feel like jumping
in, just get off your little stool, and...
Bartender, hot coffee for him.
Keep it coming, fast and black.
- Thank you.
- You're a real prick, you know that?
- Problem?
- Not yet, but soon.
What's your damage, Ray?
My damage is you walked into
our ER like you owned the place.
I don't appreciate that.
Nobody else does.
Ray, I realize that
you don't like me.
But sooner or later, you're gonna
have to get used to living with me...
because I ain't going nowhere.
You wanna leave a mess
wherever you go, that's up to you.
But there are two things I will
not let you screw around with.
- That is patients' lives and...
- And what, Ray?
- And her.
- Hey, I care about her, you little...
- Wrong time.
- Bet you almost have yourself convinced.
- Oh, yeah?
- But you're the only one who buys it.
- Come on, Ray.
- No.
Wait, let me just say, Ray, you know
that thing you guys had in the past?
- It's over, finished, done.
- Tony.
- You don't know how to take care of her.
- Ray, please.
Well, Ray, at least I'm trying.
That's right. That's right.
- Like you took care of Meg, huh?
- Oh.
Hey, let it... Let it go.
Let it go, he's drunk.
Oh, that's it, come on.
Gates. NEELA: Stop it.
Cut it out!
Stop it.
Stop that. RAY: Come on.
- Come on.
- Hey, screw you.
- Go, go.
- Come on, come on.
Hey, come on, come on.
What the hell is wrong with you?
- Okay, I'm good. Get off me.
- Trying to ruin it for Abby and Luka?
Just get the hell
off of me, man.
Hey, Ray, what's going
on with you, man? Huh?
I think you get it,
Greg, you know?
Every time I think I'm turning the corner,
I feel like I know what I'm doing...
- I end up falling backwards again.
- It's a wedding...
you're drunk, and
you're hooked on a girl.
Just go, you'll feel
better in the morning.
- I don't wanna go home.
- Well, you're done here, okay?
So just catch a cab.
- Pratt.
- Go home, Ray.
I'm not kidding, go home.
You know what I
love about you, Gates?
Just when I get worried that
maybe I'm being tough on you...
you prove what an ass you are.
Me? I was perfectly civil till that
alcoholic O.C.reject went off on me.
You should've kept walking.
Well, Morris, as my role
model, Kenny Rogers once said:
"Sometimes you have to
fight when you're a man."
Oh, that's deep.
That's... Gates.
I'm not going back. I
just wanna talk to her.
- Neela.
- Not right now, Tony.
- Can't you see she's upset?
- Chuny, I just wanna talk to her, okay?
It's all right. I'm fine,
Chuny. Thank you so much.
Okay.
I'm sorry that happened.
Abby and Luka are in the other
room, they don't know about it.
- There's no excuse.
- No, there isn't.
I wasn't looking for trouble,
he wouldn't back down.
Right, and there was no way for
that to end without him backing down.
What do you mean?
Well, with men, you have to win.
And with women...
Well, with women, you have to
feel like you've done right by them.
Even if all you're doing
is causing them pain.
Or at best, wasting their time.
Is that what you think
I'm doing? Wasting time?
You know, I think we both got into
this because we knew it had no future.
It was just a bridge from one
part of our life into another.
- I think it's a lot more than that.
- No, I don't love you.
And I don't think you love me,
and I don't see much chance...
of that changing anytime soon.
So that's it?
We're done?
Yeah.
- Because Ray couldn't get over you?
- No.
Because...
You can stand there as if you're
listening to what I'm saying...
and still believe that
none of this is your fault.
Have you got any bourbon?
- Yeah.
Can you make it a double?
- You okay?
- Yeah, yeah, I just...
Wish that hadn't
happened though.
- You did a really good job tonight.
- No, no, no, you did an awesome job.
They look so happy.
I got them the honeymoon
suite at the Ritz for a few nights...
but they can't use
it on account of Joe.
Yeah, I can see that.
It's too bad. I really don't
want the room to go to waste.
Yeah. I don't either.
Really? You don't?
No, of course not.
Are you suggesting what
I think you're suggesting?
Oh, it's go time.
It's...
Can I get that on record,
please? Say it... Say that again.
No.
So you quit your job and
get married in the same week?
- I'm a new guy now.
- Is that so?
Being chief was gonna just
mean spending less time...
with my wife and baby.
Well, I have to admit, I don't think I
could've planned a better wedding.
- You don't?
- I don't.
Uh... Abby, it was a
really nice wedding.
Luka, what I said before
about hurting Abby, I meant it.
I'm not really sure why I'm here,
but I'm very happy to be invited.
I don't really
know these people.
Okay, let me just put this down.
- And... No, no. Okay.
- Oh, there's Morris with that thing.
- Yup.
- Come on in, Morris.
- Here we go. Here we go.
- Hey, we just wanna say...
congrats to our
fearless leader here.
Yes. Yeah, and we wish him
a life of contentment and joy.
- And love.
- Yes, yes.
What else? Oh, oh.
Sleeping with only one woman.
- Ever again.
- Forever.
Without end.
Everybody's real nice. I hope
they'll be real happy together.
I do. Even the bride.
Ray, can you call
me when you get this?
I thought we could go out for
breakfast or coffee or something.
Listen, I'm sorry about tonight.
It's a pretty amazing night.
I guess it just makes you look forward
to a time when you get to be as happy...
as Abby and Luka
are right now, so...
Good, good job.
Okay, Ray, we gotta go.
Hey, dude. Dude,
can you get this for us?
Thank you.
Abby and Luka.