Let's get back
to Phil and Diane.
Phil's been having a
hard time finding work,
and Diane wants him to talk to her
about his fear, his disappointment.
And Phil wants Diane to trust
him, that they'll get through this,
ideally without having to
keep discussing feelings.
Not your exact
words, but am I wrong?
And most guys out
there are the same way.
But, ladies, if you're
feeling frustrated, remember,
it's not our fault.
We were raised to be
strong, not emotional,
to deny vulnerability,
not embrace it.
And you know what that makes us?
Dinosaurs.
Nobody needs us to
hunt wild animals for food.
Nobody needs us to cut
down trees to build shelter.
They need us to evolve.
To catch up.
Since the 1960s, women's
roles have shifted radically.
And as their roles have changed,
so have women.
Well, they've become tougher,
more demanding
of us, their partners.
And who can blame
them? Who can...
Who can...
For expecting us to
do the...
Joe!
Joe. Joe.
We need an ambulance.
You want? I'm good.
Your limp's almost gone.
It pains me to interrupt
the collegial banter.
It pains me even more
to listen to it continue.
38-year-old man spikes a fever and
collapses during a speaking engagement.
ER checks out blood volume,
cardiac function and
autonomic reflexes. All normal.
Our patient makes a living telling
men to behave more like women.
Surprised you didn't throw psych
symptoms into the differential.
Either way, could
be a cerebral AVM.
ER did a head
CT, no sign of AVM.
Decent thought, though.
The patient's philosophy
makes perfect sense.
Its only flaw is
that it's impossible.
Evolution doesn't work that
way. You can't talk legs onto a fish.
If we're gonna go
extinct, we're gonna do it
drinking scotch and
driving muscle cars.
Am I right?
Am I... Thank you.
Cephalic fibromuscular
dysplasia? Doesn't explain the fever.
The patient's talking
about compromise.
If you don't think that's possible, you
don't think relationships are possible.
Anyone in this room in a
position to disprove that?
This guy's just
playing to his audience.
Women are by far the biggest
consumers of the self-help industry.
He could have a
pulmonary embolism.
Clot in his lung increases
right ventricular afterload,
drops the blood
flow to his brain.
We should do a
pulmonary angiogram.
Patient lacks major
risk factors for a PE.
Doesn't rule it out,
just makes it unlikely.
Maybe we start with a D-dimer?
Less invasive than the angiogram.
Good idea.
Fine.
Now, I am hereby
searching for a number two.
Which is why I'm
eating a lot of bran.
Also, I want a team leader,
someone to fill Foreman's old job.
Why? You're right.
We don't need any more structure.
It's not like we had a near-fatal stabbing.
Well, if it isn't the
old ball and Ukraine.
Who's that?
His wife.
Dominika.
House, you survived prison.
And you Atlantic City.
Where they also had gangs and
pruno, but slightly less recidivism.
I start Ukrainian
food truck business.
After gambling, win, lose,
everybody likes a little knish.
You're here
and I seem to remember
throwing out a bunch of
certified letters
from Immigration.
I'm assuming
there's a connection.
Our green card
interview is in four days.
They come to the apartment.
They ask questions about marriage,
vacations, family history, what
side of the bed each sleep on.
We've never taken a vacation, I
don't like your family, and on top.
I hear Kiev is lovely
at this time of year.
And your mother, who may or may
not be dead for all I know, misses you.
Can it be that genius doctor is afraid to
take on a silly government apparatchik?
I would say more not interested
than afraid, but why quibble?
Then I go to plan B.
Make you an offer
that cannot be refused.
How long have you
been doing seminars?
The marriage counseling,
just the past couple of years.
Before that I did
corporate coaching.
Can't imagine the same
advice works for both audiences.
Guess you shifted
with the market.
There's nothing cynical
about my husband. He and I...
It's okay. I get it.
What guy thinks men
should be more like women?
A macho jerk who got a big
wake-up call courtesy of three drunks
who beat the crap out of me
outside a sports bar in Milwaukee.
I'm guessing that explains the
broken wrist in your medical history.
Those morons did me
the biggest favor of my life.
I realized I'd
sacrificed my health
because I couldn't back down
from an argument over football.
Meeting Marlene was the
final piece in the puzzle.
She changed my career, my diet.
She gave me a whole
new direction in life.
We'll need to know exactly how
you changed your diet and when.
Need my apartment key back.
If you're breaking up with me,
can we at least talk about it first?
Maybe if you weren't
all nag and no shag...
I don't sleep with married men.
I'll get a copy made. You're
an ex-con. If you get caught
perjuring yourself to Homeland
Security, you'll end up back in jail.
That'd be troubling if there was the
slightest chance that we'd get caught.
You barely know each other
and you've got about five minutes
to remake yourselves into
a convincing married couple.
And why?
Dominika gets her green
card. What's in this for you?
This is what men do for the
women they pretend to love.
Also she's paying me
30,000 bucks once we pass.
Apparently, knishes
sell like hotcakes.
Lab results.
Afraid you're gonna have
to finish your nag later.
I said I think
it's stupid, right?
Then I think I'm done.
D-dimer came back normal.
Rules out pulmonary embolism.
And our patient's a true believer
about the follies of masculinity.
He underwent a spiritual
overhaul three years ago.
He also went off
gluten and red meat.
Unfortunately, that doesn't
explain any of his symptoms.
One of those
points is not absurd.
What's absurd about
a change of heart?
What this guy believes is
making him a better person.
He's going against
his baser instincts.
Base, meaning foundational,
meaning things we're
biologically programmed to do.
Yeah, it's perfectly natural
that he stopped doing that stuff.
That's the kind of lapse that could take
you out of the running for team leader.
I feel surprisingly
okay with that.
It comes with a 50
buck-a-week raise.
I'm in.
You don't want to do that. You
might need your dignity later in life.
You didn't.
And she could be on her
way to living the dream
unless the rest of you
nut up and give her...
This spiritual overhaul.
Did it come after a
physical overhaul?
A major injury of some kind?
Bar fight.
But there's no way a broken wrist
explains... Adams, come with me.
You, too.
You guys get a
copy of that made.
Did those dudes bend
your ball-sack like Beckham?
Three years ago. The bar fight.
This is Dr. House.
He has a theory.
Dr. Adams, would you mind?
I asked you a question. I
assume you know the answer.
Yeah. I took a couple of
serious knees to the groin.
But what...
What has gotten into me?
Dr. Chase.
Just pick it up.
Do you know what's
wrong with me?
Nothing that the Golden Girls couldn't
have handled in 23 hilarious minutes.
You had a hot flash.
Those guys kicked your guys
hard enough to do lasting damage.
You didn't even look when presented
with two reasonably attractive tuchi.
Yeah, I said it.
I was listening to my doctor.
People generally listen with their
ears, leaving their eyes free to wander.
I'm guessing that your testosterone
level is just below Bieber.
Do a blood test to confirm,
then start hormone replacement.
It's no wonder that you
think women are so great.
You've basically been
one for the last three years.
Tests confirmed House was right.
Low testosterone
explains all your symptoms.
They should go away
with replacement therapy.
We're gonna give
you a fairly high dose.
Over time, your personal
physician may reduce it a little.
Just need you to turn around.
Will the shots
increase his libido?
Are you worried about that?
No.
Have you been
unsatisfied? No. No, it's just...
It's usually me
that initiates things.
Sometimes I think maybe
you aren't that attracted to me.
Are you crazy?
With these injections, you will
see an increase in sex drive.
Great. Yeah.
All done. Okay.
Something's wrong.
I think I peed myself.
Is that from the testosterone?
Couldn't be. I don't think
you're going home just yet.
It's not a plumbing problem.
Means it's probably neurological.
And?
And name Dominika's
three brothers.
Volodymyr, Oleksiy and...
The low testosterone is
off the table as a symptom.
Guy got his nuts cracked three years ago.
Don't need to look much further than that.
So his hose just
happens to spring a leak
at the same time he's in the hospital
for a totally unrelated problem?
Fjodor. It's Fedir.
If low testosterone means I
can't get sick with something else,
then punch me in
the junk right now.
I would if it weren't redundant.
Is Fedir the one
who married Mykola?
Mykola is Dominika's uncle.
How is it you can retain every
detail of our habits and personal lives
and none of this?
I find it hard to remember
things I don't give a crap about.
Ergo, Dominika has one
brother, and his name is Al.
Maybe the testicular damage
set the stage for something worse.
Multiple sclerosis causes incontinence
and progresses faster in men with low T.
Way to stay on point.
It's that kind of leadership that's
putting you at the head of the pack.
There is no pack.
She's the only applicant.
Well, that's settled, then.
Have your underlings do an LP
and get a cranio-spinal MRI to
check for plaques associated with MS.
I will go tell Foreman
about your promotion.
Wait. Wait.
So nobody cares
about the job until I apply
and suddenly it's the last limited
edition lightsaber at Comicon?
Just seems like it should go
to someone with more seniority.
Meaning you.
I said more, not most.
Meaning you or Taub.
House is a dictator. Second-in-command
is a meaningless position.
Doesn't look meaningless
on my resume.
It doesn't have to
be meaningless at all.
The right person could
turn it into something,
get the department
running smoothly.
I wonder who that
right person could be.
House is the head
of the department.
It's only fair that a woman should
hold the other position of authority.
Yeah, let's go affirmative action on
this, because then I'll definitely win.
This is what House wants. Wind us up
and watch us fight over an empty title.
Which would make us extra stupid
because of what we've just been through.
We should let him choose
whoever he wants and move on.
So if these proteins are in my
spinal fluid, that means I have MS.
The proteins may indicate MS.
There's no one definitive test.
That's why Dr. House
ordered an MRI as well.
This is anesthetic.
It's a scary diagnosis,
but advances are being made.
Several drugs
approved just this year.
To be honest, at the moment
I'm feeling a little more worried
about the
testosterone injections.
It's making me feel different.
Kind of amped.
I went through this big life
change, and it felt really meaningful,
but what if it was
all just chemistry?
Loss of testosterone
could have been a factor.
But think of it as a catalyst.
It got you to re-evaluate.
Now you know what's important.
You can choose
to hold on to that.
Right?
Certainly worth trying.
Deep breath, stay very still.
Just tell House to drop
the whole team leader thing.
That's the only
way it'll go away.
I don't think it's
such a bad idea.
A little more structure in
your department couldn't hurt.
Yeah, House is doing this
because of his great love of structure,
not because he wants
us to turn on each other.
So, don't do that.
It makes sense to have someone in
there with a little more accountability.
As long as it's not Adams.
She sees the whole thing as an opportunity
to remake the department in her image.
Or Park, for obvious reasons.
And Taub's got the
kids. He's pretty busy.
Are you seriously angling for
a job that you mocked as fake
the whole time I had
it? I don't want the job.
You just don't want
anyone else to have it.
This'll be great.
Your grandmother
is kind of sexy.
This is Taras Shevchenko,
the greatest Ukrainian poet.
Is he the guy behind There Once
Was a Man From Kremenchuk?
Help me move coffee table.
Well, then, where
will we have coffee?
And by coffee, I mean scotch.
Coffee and booze are artificial
high. For me, high is in exercise.
Dance-aerobics. Fun
and good for the butt.
Amy Grant?
I know, but there's a hot girl jumping
up and down in my living room, so...
Aww!
You have a limited amount of time
to learn a ton of uninteresting facts.
Welcome to my wheelhouse.
You brought a protractor?
You never know when you
might need to make a pie chart.
Looks like someone is currying
favor for the team leader position.
Yes.
We'll be using a basic alphabet
technique with a mnemonic multiplier.
In high school, they called
me the Bookie Monster.
Pop quiz.
Where did you get
the candlesticks?
On three. One, two, three.
Morocco. Denver.
Drink up. It's gonna
be a long night.
You really think this guy's gonna
Hulk out once the hormones kick in?
Some male lizards do
push-ups to attract mates.
When scientists gave
them extra testosterone,
they did push-ups
until they died.
Same drive you took advantage of
to get Chase to carry a box of
files down to your car yesterday.
Periventricular and subcortical
white matter are clean.
So you're saying masculinity
is ingrained and irrational.
I'm saying it's
pointless to try...
By extension, you're also saying
femininity is enlightened and rational.
It's the way we should all be.
Guys just aren't capable of it.
Brain stem and cord are clean.
Is it okay if I scratch my nose?
Go ahead.
I guess he doesn't have MS.
Something's wrong.
Is it your hand?
No, it's my eyes.
I'm seeing double.
Smile. It's your honeymoon.
So, what causes double vision
on top of all the other symptoms?
It's not a brain tumor or we
would've seen it on the scans.
Eye exam didn't offer
anything conclusive.
Let's do some winter shots.
Wardrobe change.
Thyroid eye disease in
conjunction with Graves.
Thyroid level's normal.
Check it out.
Simpson traded this in exchange for
me helping out on some of my days off.
Quite the display of
initiative and leadership.
But you're way too smart to
fall for a blatant bribe like that.
Or a blatant flaunting
of cleavage like those.
What happened to not
letting House get to you?
You're like lemmings marching off
the cliff of competitive humiliation.
All I'm doing is my job.
House has indicated that
he considers me attractive.
There's nothing wrong with me
using my strengths to my advantage.
With an argument like that, maybe you
should just drop down to your knees and...
I mean, unless that's
not your strength.
Big hug, big man.
It's cold out here.
At the risk of derailing this
very productive photo shoot
and bickering session,
what about myasthenia gravis?
Extra-ocular muscle
weakness leads to double vision,
atonic bladder
leads to incontinence.
Could've been triggered
when his T got really low.
Ooh, little one.
He'd be a good pick.
Smooth.
You let the rest
of them compete,
tear each other to pieces,
then you swoop in with the save.
Start the patient on
IVIG and plasmapheresis.
Can you handle that, please?
- I need a minute.
- Make it quick.
We're due in Memphis.
You think you want
this, but it's a bad idea.
I was gonna go Dollywood, but
I'm not sure I can pull off that wig.
Everybody was playing nice, and in
your world, nice doesn't solve cases.
But after what happened, a
little bonding is a good thing.
We still have
ideas, we still argue.
Maybe it could work better
if we appreciate each other.
That's impressive. You said that whole
thing without once moving your lips.
The ones you're not moving.
I get it. I won't play along
with your stupid games,
so I'm no longer a man. Clever.
Actually, you won't play
along with my stupid games
because you're no longer a man.
Still clever, though. Studies
have shown that raising kids
lowers testosterone
levels in men.
The more involved you
are, the lower it gets.
Right, having kids
has neutered me.
Or maybe it's helped
me finally grow up.
How are you feeling?
As long as I keep my
eyes closed, pretty good.
Really good, actually.
I've got energy,
I feel confident, clear.
Testosterone does
tend to perk you up.
Hey, hon, I brought
you a burger. Really?
You're in the hospital.
Eat whatever you want.
You are the best wife ever.
I'm not just saying that because of
how great your ass looks in those jeans.
I'm sorry, that was a little...
No, it's okay.
A girl likes to know she's
appreciated. Come here.
So, I think we should talk to Leading
Lights about seminars and DVDs.
You sure? You were
worried about the commitment.
Yeah, there's no point being
in business with them halfway.
You okay with that?
It's good to finally
have a decision.
Okay.
Fedir is the brother she
worries about the most,
ever since Luba passed.
Sorry, this was the closest we
could find to the cold, soulless offices
of a government bureaucracy.
If you're not using
your office, I will.
Does Dominika still communicate
with her high school friends?
Vasyly, yes, Oksana, no.
Not since she kissed Pavlo.
'Cause that bitch knew
that Dominika liked him.
Wrong. Oksana is
a slut, dead to me.
The right answer
is the wrong answer.
No husband would pay that much
attention to his wife's friend dramas.
Haven't you been
divorced three times?
In between those
divorces, I was married,
non-fraudulently,
for 12 years total,
which is 12 years longer
than anyone in this room.
Move.
So are you going for
this team leader thing?
Probably.
You deserve it. You have
way more experience than me.
You're giving up?
I wish. I still have a
lot of med school debt.
And my parents need
help with their mortgage.
So, I could kind
of use the money.
As of an hour ago, I'm just
seeing one of everything.
Looks like you guys were
right about... We'll be right back.
"I could use the money"?
You want to game me,
you've gotta do better than that.
Chase... You
want to be a leader,
you have to know how to
manipulate. You can't just spill...
I think the whites of
his eyes were yellow.
Everything okay?
Jaundice.
There's something
wrong with your liver.
Liver function tests confirm his
enzymes are totally out of whack.
So much for myasthenia gravis.
Can we hurry this up? I have a
government to defraud at noon.
If you need to
leave, you should.
I'm fairly confident our
patient's got sarcoidosis.
Wow, you said that
with so much authority.
Did anyone else get chills?
Just until I realized
our patient has
no sign of parenchymal
lung abnormalities,
which makes
sarcoidosis a long shot.
And bookkeeping isn't gonna
get you any farther than the boobs.
Though in fairness, the boobs
were really, really helping.
I still think it's
myasthenia gravis.
Did you miss the recap? We
treated for that, the liver tanked.
But his vision got better.
The liver problems
could be a sign of celiac.
He's been back on gluten
since he's been in the hospital.
Yesterday he had a burger.
That would've kicked his celiac
into gear, causing the liver problems.
So your theory is that he
has two unrelated diseases.
And he's already
got low testosterone.
I seem to remember something
about House hating coincidences.
It's true.
I think it's Lyme disease. One
single disease named Lyme.
Without a rash?
10% of cases
present without a rash.
Lyme disease it is. Start
the patient on antibiotics.
I have to get home before
my fake wife gets real annoyed.
Something bothering you?
I asked the nurse for an extra
pillow. That was half an hour ago.
Sorry, things can
get pretty hectic.
It's a pillow. I mean,
how hard can a pillow...
Listen to me, I'm being a jerk.
Testosterone can give you a shorter
temper even when you're not sick.
You noticed and adjusted.
That's a good thing.
Hey.
Just got a call from our lawyer.
You changed our
counter to Leading Lights?
You deserve proper billing and
a salary bump in the second term.
We talked about this. We decided it
wasn't worth potentially blowing the deal.
It'll be fine.
I've got to get some work done.
These are such pretty
flowers you buy for me.
Every Friday from
Japanese florist,
on corner of Edison and Conway.
There's just one more thing.
With this ring,
I thee wedded.
You left it here when you
skipped town with your boyfriend.
You kept the rings?
Actually, I tried to trade them to
a hooker for unspecified favors.
But it turns out she
doesn't accept zinc.
Like modern fairy tale.
Dr. and Mrs. Gregory
House? Yeah.
Nate Weinmann, U.S. Immigration.
Welcome to our home.
Give him time.
When I was 14, there was
a girl I wanted to impress.
So I jumped off the roof of
her house. Broke my ankle.
Joe's basically going
through puberty.
It'll take him a
while to adjust.
I tracked down a video from one of
Joe's business coaching seminars
from before I knew him.
I'm hearing a lot about
the value of compromise.
But we don't live on Sesame
Street. We live in the real world,
the business world.
If you're not a
winner, you're a loser.
If you aren't
comfortable with that,
go open a pottery studio.
I never would have gone
out with the guy in this video.
Do you remember the
last time she visited Vasyl?
Uh... Let me see.
That would be August?
No, no, July.
I remember. It was right
after our half anniversary
and I forgot to put
a gift in her suitcase.
And I never heard
the end of that one.
House specialty.
I made up this pun.
Thank you.
Honey, why do you do this to me?
You know I'm watching my weight.
Then maybe you stop eating cheese in front
of open fridge in middle of the night.
This is delicious. Thank you.
So, everything
looks good in here.
I'm just gonna step out and
get a corroborating interview
from one of the
neighbors. Neighbors?
It's middle of the day, I
think everybody is at work.
Yeah, then they're at work.
I just got a form to check off,
and you will be on your
way to permanent status.
Excuse me, sir. Do
you have a minute?
How can I help you?
Do you know Dr. and Mrs. House?
Of course. They've been my
neighbors about two years now.
Lovely couple.
I see them almost every night.
They seem always to be together.
Great. Thanks for your help.
Cheerio.
Hey, what are you
doing? That's my door.
Handing out menus
for a new Chinese place.
You're that guy that plays noisy video
games with House on Saturday nights.
There's a simple explanation.
Be at my office
tomorrow at 10:00.
The patient's shown
zero improvement.
Because he's only been
on the antibiotics overnight.
Or because he doesn't
have Lyme disease.
Where are you?
HOUSE: Just chilling
at U.S. Citizenship
and Immigration,
waiting on my fraud interview
with my wife and my attorney.
No big. House.
Hang up.
I still think it's myasthenia
gravis plus celiac.
His change in diet
has to be significant.
We just need to do an
intestinal biopsy to confirm.
With his low platelet count, a biopsy
puts him at risk for an abdominal bleed,
which puts him at risk of death.
Either you're done or you're
walking in there without a lawyer.
I know, it sounds like a phone,
but it's a timer. To remind
me to pee before our meeting.
Hello, old chap.
You need to save yourself.
I was up last night, trying to
find another angle, but I can't.
Tell Immigration you
were in love with Dominika,
but your marriage fell apart. And that's
why you haven't been living together.
She'll be deported. Permanently.
House, I know you like Dominika, you
have fun with her, but you got caught.
There's no getting out of this.
The best you can hope for is
that you don't go back to jail.
Tell my team to skip the biopsy
and give the antibiotics more time.
They're ready for us.
I drew a line in the sand and I
won. We should be celebrating.
Do you need a few minutes?
I'd rather keep getting better.
That's just it.
You won. You made a demand
that could have blown up the deal
and you never even asked me.
The deal didn't blow up, they caved.
Joe, you say it in your seminars.
Process matters just as much as results.
Are you seriously busting my chops
because I made one little move without you?
How about stepping aside
and letting me be the man in
this relationship for a change?
I really can't talk
to you right now.
I don't know why I said that.
Just, I got so angry.
Hopefully after this dose,
you'll start to feel better
and we can get you home.
But I'd like to do
one more test.
The testimony of one
angry, near-sighted neighbor
shouldn't outweigh all other
evidence. Photos, utility bills...
Yes. Because your clients
would never fake anything.
We acknowledge the neighbor thing
was a mistake, but that doesn't mean
that all the other documentation
should just be thrown out.
Look, look, I get that it's your job to
act like there's a case here, but shut up.
USCIS will be denying Ms.
Patrova's green card application.
You'll be referred to Immigration
Court for deportation proceedings.
And we're gonna inform your
parole officer about evidence of fraud.
So, unless anybody has
anything else to add...
Please, I am begging, do
not send him back to jail.
Maybe we have not lived
together all these months...
Mrs. House, I have to
advise you not to continue.
This man and I, did
we marry for love?
No. But this past week,
we have a lot of fun,
working really hard to fool
U.S. government. Right?
Don't answer that.
Way ahead of you.
It was fake,
but it felt real.
Maybe because it become real.
This man.
My husband.
I want to stay with him, but if I cannot,
please send me away and let him be free.
I love him.
I didn't buy a word you said.
But a judge might.
I'm gonna let you stay.
But for the next six months,
I'm gonna hold on to this file.
And our investigators are gonna show up
unannounced at 6:00 a.m., 11:00 at night,
and they better find the two
of you sitting on the couch,
watching NCIS, eating ice
cream from the same spoon.
Or both of you will be sent to places
far less pleasant than New Jersey.
What you just said in there...
Don't worry. I am much too
smart to be falling in love with you.
I will be needing
extra shelf in bathroom.
Abdominal biopsy showed flattened villi.
Looks like you were right about celiac.
You do remember Chase got
stabbed doing a test House didn't order.
Good comparison, since both
patients were tweaked on steroids.
You only did this to score
points over Chase and Park.
We were right. I proved it
and the patient didn't bleed out.
Why are you being
a jerk about this?
Let's go see if House is back.
Patient's having
trouble breathing.
So much for celiac.
His breathing is stabilized,
but his lung function is at
60% and his liver is tanking.
And he has major symptoms of
celiac without actually having celiac.
Could be Whipple's.
Doesn't explain
the incontinence.
Intestinal lymphoma?
Doesn't explain
the double vision.
Any time you want to jump in.
Is dance-aerobics even a thing?
I hear it's good for the butt.
What about a
parasitic infection?
Strongyloides is known to
damage the small intestine...
In this country he's about as
likely to get that as win Powerball.
Someone does win
Powerball. Every week.
The patient went to Puerto
Rico a few months ago.
One of the few places in the
U.S. you can pick up strongyloides.
Treatment is ivermectin.
We give that to someone with liver
problems, he could have seizures, or worse.
Do it.
I'm hearing a lot about
the value of compromise.
But we don't live on Sesame
Street. We live in the real...
I was wondering if maybe we
overlooked a symptom, or something.
Makes perfect sense if you're the
patient, and pantywaist is the symptom.
Adams and I both thought
the patient could have celiac,
but only she was willing to go out
on a limb and run the test. I gave up.
Now you're in here watching
a motivational speech.
Even your attempt to get
your balls back lacks balls.
World, the business world.
If you're not a
winner, you're a loser.
His voice, it's
lower than it is now.
If only there was a good reason for
a professional speaker to be hoarse.
Go open a pottery studio.
Good point.
It's not a good point.
It's a decent point.
You're doing it again.
You got any other videos,
other seminars? A couple.
When you see a weakness,
that's a time for strength.
A lot of people say, "I feel bad about
it." The other guy made a mistake...
You bailed too early.
Now I get all the credit.
That kind of thinking
is what makes you...
Chronic hoarseness is a symptom
of a condition called silent thyroiditis.
But I'm not hoarse.
Exactly. But you
were, three years ago.
Silent thyroiditis
comes and goes.
And it, in turn, is a symptom
of Polyglandular
Autoimmune syndrome, type 3.
Which makes this
is a really bad idea.
PAS-3 attacks the body's
own endocrine system,
moving from gland to gland.
It started in the thyroid, then,
probably helped along
by your low testosterone,
moved on to the gut. TAUB:
Where it caused celiac disease,
or it would've, if you
weren't on a gluten-free diet.
I was right.
This is incredibly relevant.
Eventually PAS-3
attacked your thymus gland.
You developed myasthenia
gravis, which landed you in here.
Then you started eating gluten,
which only made things worse.
So, am I gonna be okay?
We'll treat the various
conditions with high-dose steroids.
Assuming they
respond, you'll be fine.
And the testosterone?
Kicked in the nuts
is kicked in the nuts.
Over the past week, you have
all had good moments and bad.
No one candidate has prevailed.
So now we embark upon a
contest of medical strength,
stamina and skill.
Can we just get this over with?
If the competitor representing Australia
would like to take a point deduction,
he should by all
means continue yapping.
Your glee is on the verge of
making this not worth it for any of us.
Can I at least light the torch?
Hurry.
I declare open the games of the
number one number two competition.
Je dclare ouvert...
All right. Ready, set, suture!
T-time.
What happens if I don't take it?
Or at least, go to
a much lower dose.
Are you having side effects?
No, I feel great.
Faster, clearer.
More like myself.
But my marriage and my career,
they're both built on me
being somebody else.
Low testosterone can cause
depression and problems sleeping.
It's also been linked to conditions
such as osteoporosis and diabetes.
It will make your life
harder and more dangerous,
on top of all the
meds you'll be taking.
I'll take that risk.
I'm a better man without it.
Well, this certainly has brought
more structure to the department.
Really, I'm just excited
for the wheelchair race.
You were smart not to enter.
Never in, never lose.
And since you no
longer have stones...
I'll split the 50
a week with you.
Deal.
Honey, I'm home!