Clear!
Continue. Charging, 360.
Charging, 360.
Clear!
Continue. Charging, 360.
Clear.
Come on. Come on!
Asystole.
I'm gonna call it.
Any objections?
Time of death, 18:20.
He was looking
at me.
He didn't want to die.
Just shooting hoops.
Some guys drove by
and popped him.
I'm sorry about that,
Dr. Choi.
Goodwin just paged.
She wants to
discuss your request.
Hey, I'm taking off.
You coming?
No. I just got to wait
for Rita to get here,
but you go ahead.
All right.
See you tomorrow.
Yeah. See you.
Aren't you taking off?
Nah. Pulling another shift.
Malpractice premiums are due.
Maybe it'll be an easy night.
Don't jinx it.
I look at her as just
another patient.
But clearly she isn't.
If there is a bad outcome,
does this thing become
an international incident?
We have consent
from all parties.
The State Department's
been apprised.
You know, there is
a potential upside to this,
as long as you pull it off.
So, all right.
Let's keep it under wraps.
Everyone involved
signs a non-disclosure.
Yes, ma'am.
Dr. Halstead,
incoming times three.
One, two, and three
are all open.
Desmond?
15-year-old male,
extremely combative.
Trashed our ambo
on the ride over.
I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
No way
to get vitals.
Managed to stick him
with 5 of Versed
but no effect.
Looks like PCP maybe.
Got two more
in the ambo behind ours.
10 of Haldol IM.
The other two like this?
I think they all
took the same thing.
All right.
They're here.
Wheeler, stay with him.
Clarke with me.
Okay, watch his feet.
Got it.
"Easy night." She jinxed it.
Cesar?
15-year-old boy.
He seized on the ride over,
but responded well
to 5 of Versed IM.
We intubated en route.
All right. ABCs.
Check the tube placement,
get a quick exam.
Ativan drip,
then send him for head CT.
Got it.
Watch the lines.
Coming back.
Courtney?
Gave her 5 of Versed
in the ambo,
but didn't stop the seizing.
Have her on oxygen,
but couldn't
give her much else.
All right, Maggie, CBC, CMP,
and blood gas on all three.
Send blood and urine
for a tox screen.
Copy that.
On my count.
One, two, three.
Let's get an IV in
and an NPA.
Yes, Doctor.
All right,
I need an 18 catheter.
On it.
Get an NG tube.
All right.
He's 90 over 60.
Heart rate might be low.
Okay, let's move him.
Okay, here we go.
She's protecting
her airway.
Thank you.
Okay, we're in.
Sat of 97%.
All right.
Let's take advantage
of her postictal state
and get her head scanned.
Hey, bring Ativan with you.
Mmm-hmm.
Here we go.
Watch your back.
Look alive,
Dr. Halstead.
It's a broad presentation.
Are we sure they're all
on the same thing?
Till we get tox screens,
who knows?
I hope you don't mind that
I'm dating your boyfriend.
No, of course not.
Why would I mind?
Can we still
be friends?
Sure.
I'll be your maid of honor.
So, what do you think?
Well, I don't understand
why that woman doesn't mind.
Her friend betrayed her.
Hmm.
You sure she doesn't mind?
She said she didn't.
Um...
So, after reading
the material I gave you,
you told me that
you suspected...
That I'm on
the autism spectrum,
that I have Asperger's.
Right.
So, how'd you feel
if I told you
that I thought
that your diagnosis
could very well be correct?
Relieved, actually.
My whole life,
I've never understood
why people treated me
the way they did.
I felt there had to be
something wrong with me.
Not wrong.
I mean, it's just
different wiring, that's all.
Is there anything
we can do to change
that wiring?
Well, our wiring
is pretty much our wiring,
but there's a whole bevy of
strategies out there.
I mean, medications,
um, social skills training
to help you recognize
body language...
There's also a new therapy
called TMS,
but I'd probably
recommend you going
the traditional routes first.
TMS?
Transcranial
magnetic stimulation.
It's so far FDA approved
only for depression,
but there is
anecdotal evidence
that it can benefit people
with spectrum disorders.
I only mention it because
we have a machine here
at the hospital.
Well, I will do
some research.
I am needed in the OR.
Yes. Um...
Dr. Charles, this has all
been very comforting.
Thank you.
Of course.
Hey, Maggie.
Hey.
Rita just called.
She came down with the flu.
We're gonna be
short tonight.
I know what that means.
Another shift.
Well, think how much money
you'll be making.
Ms. Goodwin?
Yes?
The patient's arriving.
Okay.
Bring her up
through the loading dock
and use
the service elevator.
Sure.
Loading dock?
Uh... I'll tell you later.
Okay.
Crows!
Get them away!
5 of Haldol, please.
They're in the...
It's all right.
We're taking care of those.
They're in the house!
No, no, no.
We're taking care
of those.
of those right now.
There we go.
Okay.
You know, two out of
three patients in here
end up developing delirium?
From a fever?
She has pneumonia.
Well, it's
a contributing factor,
but it's also
the ICU itself.
Bright lights,
the endless beeping,
constant prodding
and poking.
I mean,
the woman's exhausted.
Hey, Hank, could we maybe
turn the lights down
in Ms. Novak's room?
Maybe quiet the monitors
a little bit?
Also, I don't think
you need to be
going in and out of there
every 20 minutes, okay?
The woman needs some rest.
Sure.
Thank you.
I spoke to my mom today,
told her I was
a psych resident.
What, just now
you're telling her?
Well, yeah.
I knew how she'd react,
and I was right.
She laughed.
She said I was
the last person
she could ever imagine
being a psychiatrist.
Wow, real vote of
confidence there.
Mmm-hmm.
Do I get to meet
your mom someday?
You seeing
what I'm seeing?
Yeah.
We need a CT surgeon now.
Page Dr. Latham?
He's in surgery.
Get Dr. Rhodes.
He's not on call.
Tell him
it's an emergency.
I'm puzzled by this chart,
Dr. Wheeler.
Did you do a rectal exam?
I didn't think in this case
it was necessary.
It's always necessary.
It's a part of
the physical exam,
and it's expected.
I've seen
too many things missed
because feckless residents
don't do a complete physical.
What's the troll
still doing here?
Doesn't he have
a bridge somewhere
to go home to?
How's your boy?
Still out.
All right.
CTs were all negative.
No swelling, no bleeds.
Tox screens
are also negative.
Rules out usual suspects,
heroin, meth, cocaine.
Then what?
Some synthetic cannabinoid.
What's your patient's
heart rate?
Slow. 50.
Bradycardia. Rules out MDMA.
Mmm-hmm.
See a lot of that
in the field.
You think we're looking
at spice?
Spice?
It's fake weed.
And it could be mixed
with a number of things.
Flakka, krokodil.
Right.
None of that would show up
on a tox screen either.
Nope.
I hope one of them
comes to and tells us.
Meanwhile, stay with
the standard OD protocol,
benzos and fluids.
Got it.
Oh, yes. Very nice.
Charity event at
the Art Institute.
Hi, Maggie.
Robin.
You concur?
Atrial septal defect.
But you feel
it's an emergency?
Well, the patient's
already anesthetized.
For just a CT?
Is she mentally compromised?
No.
Wait. This doesn't
look right.
The ribcage.
Pectus carinatum.
Is she deformed?
Come meet her.
Okay.
I'm really sorry
about this.
It's okay.
I'll wait in
the doctors' lounge.
Come find you
in a little bit.
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, here he is. Dr. Rhodes.
Thank you for coming in.
This is Mr. Hseih
from the Chinese Embassy.
Dr. Rhodes.
Mr. Woodfield,
the director of
the Chicago Zoo.
Doctor.
And the chief veterinarian,
Dr. Evans.
Uh, zoo?
Your patient.
Meet Su Lin.
So, this was your idea?
Dr. Choi volunteers
at the zoo.
Normally, we wouldn't bring
an animal in here,
but we couldn't
diagnose without a CT.
Well, that's fine,
but I'm not a veterinarian.
She needs
a cardiothoracic surgeon.
You've done this
procedure many times.
Oh, yeah, I have.
On human beings.
Same plumbing, just bigger.
Crack her chest
and plug the hole.
I can't... No,
I can't just crack
her chest.
She'll lose too much blood,
and what am I supposed to
transfuse with?
Do we have panda
in the blood bank?
So, how do we treat her?
Um...
I guess I would have
to take her up
to the cath lab
and close the defect
with a balloon.
Okay. Then do it.
Really?
Are we sure that
we're all comfortable
spending our time
and the hospital's resources
to save an animal?
Dr. Rhodes,
zoos rent pandas
from the Chinese government
for a million dollars a year.
Why? Because people
love pandas.
So, if we save this one,
it's a public relations coup
for this hospital.
One which will lead
to much-needed donations
to save human lives.
And there's an issue
beyond that.
I've learned that there are
less than 2,000 pandas
left in the world.
Connor.
We should do whatever we can
to keep her alive.
One parrot,
and he's Dr. Dolittle.
Okay.
Let's get Su Lin
up to the cath lab.
Thank you.
Hi. I'm Dr. Wheeler.
Do you know
where you are?
Do you understand?
Can you tell me
how you got here?
Help!
Grab him.
No!
Get away!
I got you.
5 Versed, 10 Haldol IM.
Got it.
I'll kill you!
All right, get the restraints
back on this kid.
What's wrong with him?
Delirium can sometimes
be a sign of
kidney failure.
Happens with these drugs.
The kids' parents
are on their way in.
There's nothing
good to tell them.
Okay, I'll be right back.
She's doing much better.
Very good.
Well, been a long day.
I'll see you tomorrow?
Mmm-mmm. I volunteered
to be on call tonight.
Really?
Mmm-hmm.
Wow. I applaud
your work ethic.
But, um, why?
This patient.
I'm afraid that
once the nurses
change shifts,
our instructions
won't get passed on.
You know, I think
that our excellent staff
will probably follow through.
I mean,
aren't you exhausted?
It's not a problem.
Coffee beans?
Mmm-mmm.
Robusta espresso beans.
If I eat five an hour,
I can go all night.
Got it.
You know, Dr. Reese,
I know your mother
might have some doubts
about your future
as a psychiatrist,
but I, for one, do not.
I mean, not even a tiny bit.
I'm just saying,
you have nothing
to prove to me.
Well, it's not that.
I just wanna make sure
our patient gets
the treatment that she needs.
Oh. Okay.
You know,
I've been meaning
to mention,
I recommend to
all of my residents,
as part of their training,
that they undergo
some form of psychotherapy.
Is that something
you'd ever consider?
Me?
No.
Well, I mean,
the idea being that
it might
benefit you professionally,
you know,
to see what it's like
to be on the other side.
I mean, it certainly
benefitted me.
I really can't see
myself in psychotherapy,
Dr. Charles.
Okay. Well, just a thought.
See you in the morning.
Sorry, Robin, but it looks
like it's gonna be
kind of a long night.
Tough case?
On the DL...
Yeah?
The patient
is a panda bear.
A panda?
Mmm-hmm.
Atrial septal defect.
Can you fix it?
Well, that's the idea.
You know, there are
less than 2,000 pandas
left in the world.
Somebody mentioned that.
Connor, what you are doing,
it is so great.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Very sexy.
Alpha CT surgeon
with a soft spot for animals.
I'll call you a cab.
No. What?
Are you kidding me? No.
I am sticking around.
I love pandas.
Okay.
Yeah.
I gotta go change.
This is weird.
Four West needs me
to come down and declare
a patient dead.
What?
Nobody likes that job,
so they dump it on
the on-call psych resident.
You.
Are you clear
on Mrs. Novak?
Yes, I'm clear.
All right.
It's a formality.
We need a doc to call it
and tell the family.
Haven't you ever
done this before?
No.
I'll help you. Here.
First thing,
introduce yourself
to the son.
I'm Dr. Reese.
I understand you're
the patient's son.
Okay.
I...
Uh...
I am here to check
on your father.
I'm afraid he's passed.
Time of death, 22:05.
I am very sorry
for your loss.
That was terrible.
I was terrible.
Hey, what are you doing?
Mmm, hospital called.
I got to go back in.
What? Why?
'Cause they're swamped.
They need me.
Can't they get
someone else?
No.
But it's so late,
and you already worked
a full day.
Yeah. I'm used to it.
I don't mind.
Shouldn't you be
taking it easy?
I mean, you know,
the baby.
Really, Tate?
We're gonna do this again?
How many times do
I have to say it?
Pregnant women can work.
What about
pregnant women with TB?
The drugs knocked it down,
and you know that.
I'm so sick of you
bringing up this work thing.
I worry about you
and the baby.
Well, stop. I'm good.
And the baby's good.
I'll see you
in the morning.
I think you're
a little posterior.
How's it look on fluoro?
Give me a view at 120.
One sec.
Right there. That's it.
All right.
We're almost there.
Hold on.
Heart rate's spiking.
Damn. I can't continue
if she's this tachycardic.
We got to slow
her heart down.
You gonna cardiovert?
No, all this fur,
we'd never get enough contact
with the skin.
Marty, give her 6 mg
of adenosine.
On its way.
Mean arterial pressure of 70,
60, 40.
No pulse.
Heart's arrested.
She's gonna
come back, right?
Humans do.
But this is the first time
that I've given adenosine
to a panda.
Got a pulse.
MAP back up to 50,
60.
Connor, no good.
She's still in SVT
and her pressure's down.
All right,
we've got no choice.
We've got to try
to cardiovert her.
Shave her!
Sync. Clear.
Still SVT.
All right. Charge to 150.
Sync.
Sinus rhythm.
All right,
we're stable enough.
Let's proceed.
Shouldn't you people
be working?
They're treating
a panda in the cath lab.
So much for non-disclosure.
How's it looking?
Dr. Rhodes just deployed
the ASD closure device.
I always learn so much
watching him.
Oh.
Hey, there.
Oh, hey, Dad.
Hear there's a panda
in there.
Yeah. ASD repair.
Mmm. Of course.
Wow. Looking sharp.
Connor and I were
at a charity event
when he got the call.
Good thing you got
your mom's looks.
That's all I can say.
Have a good time.
Hey, Dad?
I'm gonna be here a while.
How about a coffee?
Oh.
Yeah. Yeah, I got some time.
We're still
waiting on test results,
but we suspect
it's some type of OD.
Hey. Sorry to call you
back in.
No. I'm fine.
Tate's not, though.
Oh.
Girl, my work
is a problem for him.
I really thought
we were past it,
but he won't let it go.
Well, every couple's
got stuff they got
to deal with.
You're needed in two.
No way I'm gonna
stop working.
Hmm.
Mom? Dad?
I'm sorry.
Oh, Rudy.
BUN is 130.
Creatinine is 6.
You look at his output?
Renal failure.
I'm afraid
Rudy's going to need
emergency dialysis.
Put a temporary
dialysis catheter
in his left subclavian.
Okay.
Um, I'm sorry, folks.
We're gonna need you
to wait outside.
Thank you, April.
Yes.
Are you in?
No.
Must have hit the lung.
Pneumothorax.
Let's get a chest X-ray.
Oh, no.
All right.
Let's see if
this lung is down.
Yep, it is.
Okay.
No, I'll do the line.
I don't know
what happened.
Prep a chest tube.
Really, I thought
I had it.
Hey, it happens.
The lung will be fine.
You'll get it.
How's my son?
Um...
Dr. Halstead will
give you an update.
So, uh, how's this
new apartment?
Mmm. It's fine, except for
my upstairs neighbor.
He practices clarinet
two hours every night.
And it's always
the same two songs,
Summertime and Moondance.
Well, of course,
you know your mother and I's
first date was
a Van Morrison concert.
Hard for me to imagine
you two dating.
We had some very happy times,
especially when
you first came along.
You don't remember?
Mackinac Island?
All that
saltwater taffy?
No.
Frickin' paradise, man.
Walking on the beach.
When you were four, you...
You found this pebble
that you were
absolutely convinced
looked like a bunny.
A bunny?
Yeah.
You and your bunnies, man.
Loved your bunnies.
Robin, I'm so very sorry
I was an awful father.
I know, Dad.
I know that,
but to tell you the truth,
I never really felt that way.
Okay, all right.
I will admit that
I was angry, yes,
but it's just because
I wanted more of you.
I remember I used to read
my Nancy Drew mysteries
and imagine that I was
your detective.
You know,
following you around,
helping you solve cases.
Like how did my patient
develop a fixation
with doorknobs and stuff?
Yeah, yeah.
Something like that.
Actually, I'm surprised
that you,
my brilliant
psychiatrist father,
never figured it out.
Epidemiology is
detective work.
So, you see, Dad,
it's all about you.
I'm all about you.
You carry that around
with you?
Always.
Uh, we need you to
pronounce a patient.
Where's the doctor
who ran the code?
No code.
Patient had a DNR.
This is Dr. Latham's patient.
Why didn't you call him?
The family's in there.
He'd have to tell them.
So?
You know Dr. Latham.
He's a robot.
Creeps people out.
He'll just make them
feel worse.
Oh, great.
Second time tonight.
Dr. Latham.
Why is that resident in
with my patient?
I'm afraid
the patient has died.
Uh, Dr. Reese is
informing the family.
Why wasn't I called?
We didn't see
the need to bother you.
It's no bother.
It's my responsibility.
Guess we should have,
Dr. Latham.
I don't think
that's very funny.
A word, Doctor?
Mmm-hmm.
Can you explain
what that was about?
They didn't call you
because they don't think
you're very good
with emotionally
distraught people.
Huh.
Thank you
for your candor.
Mmm-hmm.
Well, the boy
has stopped seizing,
but he's got cerebral edema.
Rick. That's his name.
Hopefully, mannitol will
bring it down.
When Rick wakes, if he wakes,
we'll do cognitive tests.
But I'll tell you,
he's gonna have deficits.
Deficits?
Yeah, like walking, talking,
bladder and bowel control.
And the girl? Janna?
EEG shows
she continues to have
subclinical seizures.
We had to put her
in a barbiturate coma.
Possible she doesn't
wake up.
Never wakes up.
Renal failure.
Deficits. Coma.
Wheeler?
They're just kids.
What's the matter
with you?
Hey.
Wheeler, are you drunk?
Their lives are over.
Hey!
Are you drunk?
ED docs.
You're through tonight.
Let's get him
in the lounge.
Oh, God, wait!
Beautiful.
Thank you.
Let's go.
Excuse me.
So, normal BP
for a panda is 150/85.
She's down to 110/60,
and her heart rate's
twice what it should be.
Grab me the echo,
will you?
Yeah.
Here you go.
Thanks.
She has an effusion
around the heart.
Yeah.
Low-pressure bleed.
Damn, I must have nicked
the right atrial appendage
during the occlusion.
All right, we've got
to relieve the pressure.
And we shouldn't
open her up.
No.
Can't risk
the blood loss.
Yeah.
Okay, I'll needle her,
put in a drain,
and hopefully the bleed
will stop on its own.
Give me
the PERIVAC Kit.
Yes, Doctor.
Thanks.
All right.
Keep your fingers crossed.
Dr. Charles.
I looked online
at the therapies
that you mentioned.
I've decided to try TMS.
In some cases,
patients experience
profound changes
immediately after
one treatment.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Some cases.
Most of those,
a single treatment caused
only temporary change.
Fifteen minutes,
half an hour.
Even with
multiple treatments,
there's no guarantee
of prolonged change.
TMS. is not a magic bullet.
Still, it's encouraging.
It's very encouraging,
but there's also
the possibility
that in success,
your experience of TMS
could be
somewhat overwhelming.
Are you ready for that?
I am tired of
living in a world
I don't understand.
Very well.
I will refer you
to my colleague
in the morning.
I want you there.
You know that I can't
prescribe treatments
for doctors that work
in the same hospital.
You referred me.
I don't see why
you can't observe.
Well, when you put it
that way,
I don't see
why I couldn't, either.
Good. Let's start tonight.
Tonight?
If you don't mind.
It's 3:00 in the morning.
I'm not gonna call
Dr. Weyland at 3:00 a.m.
I'll pick up the cost.
That's not the point.
Dr. Latham, are you sure
that you don't wanna
go home and sleep on this?
Just think about it
a little bit?
Dr. Charles, please.
Hey.
How's she doing?
About the same.
No worse.
So, you volunteer
at the zoo, huh?
Yeah.
How come?
You'll laugh.
Just try me.
All right.
A few hours ago,
I lost a kid who was shot.
Another one.
So much of my work,
stabbings, shootings,
it's dark, man.
Worst of human nature.
But animals...
Not to say
they don't kill each other,
but they don't do it
out of malice.
They're innocent.
They're light.
How do you feel?
Awful.
All right.
I'm not letting you
drive home.
Why don't you go lay down
in the on-call room?
Oh, God.
Right in front of the troll.
Am I finished?
No.
It's not up to him.
You are gonna have to
go to therapy,
sign a contract saying
it won't happen again,
and if it does,
you will be fired.
My parents...
How am I gonna tell them?
Hey, Wheeler,
it's not the end, okay?
You can get past this.
How is he?
Oh, physically okay.
Just hungover.
So, what did Abrams mean
by "ED docs"?
Sad fact. Among the staff,
highest rate of alcoholism,
ED docs.
Battle fatigue.
The session lasts 24 minutes.
Every 20 seconds,
you'll receive a pulse,
which lasts
about two seconds.
Ready?
Yeah.
You okay? Is it tolerable?
Yes.
Mrs. Novak.
Hold compressions.
Still VF on the monitor.
Charge, 200.
Clear.
She's gone.
She's dead?
Your patient, right?
Yes.
Do you wanna call it?
Did you follow
my instructions?
Of course.
Then what happened?
Respiratory failure.
She had pneumonia,
you know.
Are you gonna call it?
Time of death, 4:02.
This wasn't
supposed to happen.
It's nobody's fault.
Wasn't supposed
to happen.
So, uh,
how are you feeling?
Any change?
Uh, not that I can tell.
Yeah? No headache?
No.
Okay.
I hope you don't mind that
I'm dating your boyfriend.
No, of course not.
Why would I mind?
Can we still be friends?
Sure.
I'll be your maid of honor.
So, um...
Anything striking you
differently?
That woman does mind.
She says she doesn't,
but she clearly does.
Yeah.
She's being sarcastic.
You, um, didn't pick
that up before.
No.
Looks like you could be
an excellent candidate
for this therapy.
It's like I've been blind.
Blood has
stopped draining.
BP and heart rate
have normalized.
We've dialed back
on the sedation,
see how she responds.
No, no, no.
We're not shooting
a panda in my hospital.
She's coming around.
All right!
Looks good.
Well, we don't need a bear
roaming the hospital.
Marty, put her back under.
Right.
Congratulations, everyone.
Dr. Reese,
how's our patient?
She died.
They all died.
All of them.
Three in one night.
Oh... That's terrible.
I'm so sorry.
It's too much, you know?
It's all too much.
We need to get you
a little sleep.
No. No, I, um...
I'll do it.
Dr. Charles,
I want to do it.
I need it.
Do what?
Therapy.
I can't handle anything.
I'm no good
at anything. I'm...
I'm a fraud. I'm just
gonna disappoint you.
Come here.
Oh, it's okay.
That's not gonna happen.
That's not true at all.
It's okay.
Excuse me.
Have a good day.
So, we're gonna
have to round
on Wheeler's patients.
I'll take half,
you take the other?
Okay.
And good job last night.
Thanks.
You hung in there.
You should consider
Emergency Medicine.
I will.
Morning.
How'd it go?
The usual.
Good.
I guess I'm gonna
start those rounds.
Yeah.
April!
It's not that easy.
I know how much
your work means to you.
I'm sorry.
Tate, we keep having
the same argument.
We won't. Not anymore.
I mean it.
I am the way I am.
If I don't make you happy...
You do, April.
I don't wanna
change you. Okay?
Let's go home.
You can scramble me
some eggs.
And now I'd like to introduce
you to Dr. Connor Rhodes,
who performed the procedure.
Dr. Rhodes.
Thank you very much.
Good morning to everybody.
Su Lin was suffering
from an atrial
septal defect, which...
Hey!
I'm okay.