Paranoia...
gives you an edge in the OR.
What I realize is that Peds is the
only specialty where I could do it all:
Cardio, General, Ortho.
It's like the whole
body is your canvas.
The fact that it's a small canvas
makes it even more challenging.
I have no idea if you have
someone on your service.
But I would love to
witness your artistry.
You got this?
You gotta like kids.
- I love kids.
- OK. I'll see you on rounds.
Great.
He lost a huge chunk of flesh.
I see down to his mandible.
We'll need Plastics
and an ENT consult.
Left IV looks like it's clotted
off. I need a 16-gauge.
Whoa! What's going on?
It's four in the morning.
Is everyone on call?
It's the merger. Everyone's
scared to go home.
Don't think the chief
meant people couldn't sleep.
Hard when your
job's on the line.
One of you, get as much
type-specific blood as they'll let you have
- and meet us in surgery.
- I got it!
Surgeons play out worst-case
scenarios in their heads.
I talked to Callie last night
about the residents at Mercy West.
She said they don't suck.
You're safe 'cause of Derek,
Izzie's safe 'cause of cancer.
Alex is Bailey's new favorite.
Even George'd have been spared
'cause he's Owen's guy.
Cardio has been a revolving door.
- No one's got my back.
- So Arizona is your cover?
She's merger-proof.
She keeps kids alive.
No one likes a dead kid.
They're under
anesthesia half the time.
How bad can it be?
You're ready to close,
you got the bleeder.
You know it, but there's that
voice in your head asking...
Sloan and Shepherd are
scrubbing out of surgery in OR Two.
Grab 'em before they leave.
Let me know if you
hear about the merger.
Nurses are always the
last to know, first to go.
What if you didn't?
What if the patient dies and
you could have prevented it?
Oh, Alex.
What do you think? Looks
real, right? My mom sent it to me.
- Well, what are you doing here?
- Working.
Iz, we talked about this. You're
supposed to take another three weeks,
- resting up.
- I have to come back now
before I don't have a
job to come back to.
- Iz...
- I have to show
I'm not gonna die.
Unless I sit alone in that
trailer, then I am gonna die.
- I'm gonna die of boredom.
- Izzie...
Seriously, looks real, right?
If you didn't know I have cancer,
you wouldn't know I have cancer, right?
So you check your
work one more time
before you close. Paranoia
is a surgeon's best friend.
- Karev, what do you got?
- 16-year-old helmeted
dirt bike victim.
GCS 15 reported
before intubation.
OK, on my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
I'm gonna scrub in.
So he announces the merger
and shuts himself in his office
- all day and refuses to talk.
- This merger won't affect us.
- It's financial restructuring.
- What do you think it is?
Cutting personnel. Prepared
to lose all the good people?
I'm not. He's good to
go. I'll write a consult later.
I'm gonna talk to Richard now.
You're tired, you're angry,
you'll say something
you'll regret.
Get out of here for a while.
Go to the driving range.
- I have surgery in an hour.
- Take a walk.
- Grab Meredith, take a walk.
- Meredith won't leave
the hospital.
None of them will.
Everyone's awaiting word.
Look, don't tell me
Lexie's not worried.
Is he in here? 'Cause
I've got the blood!
No, Lexie's worried.
I think you missed a spot.
You can't tease me
about the blood thing,
because it's not funny.
If it gets back to the chief, I
may as well pack my things.
Stop worrying about the
chief. All this is in your head.
Really? 2002, Milwaukee. Third
Street Hospital merged with St. Anne's.
Thirteen residents were let go.
2004, Nashville Women's
absorbed Memorial.
Nine residents were
fired. 2006, Albuquerque.
- OK.
- Nineteen residents.
Whoa, stop. You need
to pull yourself together.
You deserve to
be here. Act like it.
OK.
I meant later, you know,
after you went home
and got some sleep.
You know, we should get
some sleep before rounds.
Sleep is for wimps. Sleep
is for Mercy West residents.
Let's fit in another
trauma before rounds.
Don't say anything
about the wig.
I'm back. Yes, I am early,
but whatever. I'm back.
I've been gone so long, the
first trauma that comes through,
it's mine. Got it?
It's amazing, right?
- What?
- What's amazing?
- The wig.
- It looks so real,
I couldn't tell.
Always wanted to be a redhead,
so I thought now's the time.
What's wrong with your hair?
It's peach fuzz chemo hair.
I wanted to put my patients at
ease, make them comfortable.
She looks like a
Stepford wife. Tell her.
She can't handle
it. Just don't stare.
- MVC, who do I have?
- I got it! I can do it!
I'm not your chief
resident. Figure it out.
- Karev, let's go.
- Oh.
- You're back.
- I am.
- My mom's whole church
prayed for you.
- Thank you.
- It looks really real.
- I know, right?
- We need to talk.
- I'm busy right now.
- Are you making cuts?
- I said I'm busy.
If you're making
cuts, consult with me.
When appropriate, I'll
consult the people I need to.
I'm not people. I
saved your ass.
When Jennings came
to me, you were done.
- Out of loyalty to you...
- You came to me
so you'd look like a good
guy before you stole my job.
- Are you making cuts or not?
- I said when I'm ready to tell
my staff about decisions I'll be
making, I will! When I'm ready!
So don't come barging
in here like I owe you!
I don't owe you a damn
thing! You work for me.
I'm still the chief of
surgery at this hospital.
Then start acting like it.
Jodie Crowley, 60-year-old
driver who lost consciousness
and hit a parked
car. Vital signs stable.
Complains of abdominal pain.
It wasn't a parked
car. They hit us.
- Sir, who are you?
- Who am I? Who are you?
- He's my son.
- Go in the waiting room.
No! He needs to stay with me.
He's a paranoid schizophrenic.
OK.
All right, let's put her
on a gurney on my count.
One, two, three.
Listen. They're trying to get
to me through you. Believe me.
Tom, they're not real. Look
at me. Look at me, honey.
Did you feel dizzy or
light-headed before the crash?
- No, I felt fine.
- Abdominal tenderness. I feel a mass.
I've had it for quite a while.
Maybe that caused
me to black out.
They're trying to hurt
her. She won't believe me.
Tom, look at me. You
know I wouldn't lie to you.
No. No! You have to believe
me. Someone has to believe me.
Aliens have
impregnated my mother.
The chief was spotted five hours ago
in the cafeteria again. Apple and yogurt.
Then he met with
Dr. Shepherd, brief and heated.
Drew the blinds.
Probably sleeping.
Speculation. We have no proof.
You'd make a good lawyer.
If this doesn't work out.
Ouch.
- OK, Dr. Yang,
ready for rounds?
- Yes. Oh, um...
Continue with your
course of treatment.
Keep me updated
on new developments.
- You don't look ready.
- No, I'm ready.
I looked over your patient charts. I
notice you have a shockwave lithotripsy
scheduled for kidney stones
this morning. I was... um...
I've never done one.
I'm looking forward to it.
OK. Now, you're ready.
- Oh.
- Come on, let's go.
OK, how long have
you had the growth?
Can you cover the clock?
The number five bothers him.
Yeah. Can you get
something to cover the clock?
Are those cameras?
Tommy, what do we
need from the store?
- Why won't they leave me alone?
- Do we need fruit?
Yeah, why won't
you leave me alone?
What kind of fruit do we
need? Tom, what kind of fruit?
Um... Apples, pears...
- strawberries?
- Make a list.
Could you give him a
pencil and some paper?
He needs something to
distract him from the voices.
Ma'am, the growth.
Oh, uh... Yeah. I'm sorry.
I've had it for a while.
I've been meaning to get it
checked, but, as you can see,
my son's illness
is a full-time job.
Karev, I need you to get
Mr. Crowley's wrist X-rayed
- while I get her up to MRI.
- Can't one of these fetuses
baby-sit?
- If that's a triple-A,
I want in.
- I can do the wrist.
- Dr. Karev has more experience.
- The patient is paranoid,
and hyper-vigilant. He'll pick up
that Dr. Karev doesn't want to be here.
He may interpret that as
Dr. Karev being out to get him.
I aced my Psych clerkship.
- How'd it go with the chief?
- Hey.
- Richard's not talking to me.
- What? Why?
I don't know. He's
just... He's not himself.
- What's he doing?
- He's hiding out. How you holding up?
You've been up
for, like, 36 hours?
Forty-eight. I'm good, actually.
I feel like... it's
all gonna be OK.
We're all gonna keep our jobs and
be amazing people, live amazing lives.
Unstable childhood.
I get calm in a crisis.
- This is a crisis, right?
- I don't know.
I don't know what this is.
Oh, look who's coming.
Oh, um, Dr. Yang,
have you seen Sage?
She's six.
Light brown hair. Blue eyes.
She had a tumor
removed from her belly
so she has a
bandage on her tummy.
Hey, check under the
bed. Maybe she's there.
Her labs are better
than expected.
Uh, she's not under the bed.
Huh. Whoa. I... Maybe
try the bathroom.
Maybe she slipped in there.
How'd she do last
night, she sleep?
She did. I didn't.
Bathroom's clear.
Wait, shh. Shh shh shh.
I think that there's something
coming from your pocket.
Is Sage inside your pocket?
No, no. She's hiding here.
Gotta look in your pocket first.
No, I don't. I
found you already.
I need to check
your incision site.
Don't touch it. It hurts.
I bet that Mr. Bear would
like to see Sage's scar.
- Wouldn't you, Mr. Bear?
- Oh, um...
Yes, I would.
Dr. Stevens.
Surprised to see you back
so soon. You look great.
- Thank you. So do you.
- How you feeling?
- I feel great. How do you feel?
- What I meant...
I know what you mean. I
feel fine. I'm ready to work.
Here is Mr. Trinidad's
latest pre-op labs.
I told him you'd say
hello before the surgery.
Unless there's anything
else I need to know,
I was gonna get
his consent form.
That pretty much covers it.
- Unless anybody has questions.
- Can you tell us about
the merger?
Because I'm having a baby. I
mean, my wife is having a baby.
Resident Megan is having a baby.
I mean, am I gonna lose my job?
Right now, I'm concerned
about my patient.
You should be, too.
- I just got my hair cut.
- Oh. It looks nice.
The nurse out there with
the red hair is laughing at me.
You tell her I just got it
cut, they cut it too short.
- That's why my ears
are sticking out.
- She's not laughing at you.
How's that feel?
It feels like my
hand is falling off.
Feels like...
they put something in it
to make my hand fall off.
Like snakes or something.
You don't have a nametag.
Um... Oh, I... I guess I don't.
The other doctor had
a nametag on her coat.
- I had to change my lab coat.
- Think I'm an idiot?
You're working for them.
Got my mother, you're
trying to get me. Stay away!
I keep telling you
people! Stay away from us!
I called security.
They're on their way.
Where's Psych? I asked
you to page them an hour ago.
I paged them twice.
Wanna see the log book?
I wanna know how a paranoid
patient got out of the ER.
Where were you?
I stepped away from my desk
to deal with another patient.
Normally, being a punching
bag for doctors is part of the job.
There's a merger,
we're all being looked at.
I'm not about to go down
for a mistake that wasn't mine.
So, if you'll excuse me,
I'll page Psych again.
OK, Mr. Trinidad, your
shunt revision is pretty simple.
Shouldn't take
longer than an hour,
but I do need to go over the
possible complications with you.
Dr. Stevens, could
I have a word?
Give me a minute until I'm done.
I'm sorry. This'll
only take a minute.
Excuse me.
- What?
- How are you holding up?
- Fine.
- Take your meds?
- Not yet, but I will.
- Supposed to take them at nine.
- It's only a little after nine.
- It's 10:15.
Run down to her
locker and get her meds.
Are they in your purse?
- Yes, but you don't
have to get them.
- Yes, you do.
- No, you don't! Alex!
- I swear to God,
if you don't go and
get her pills now,
I'm gonna hurt you
and I'm gonna like it.
You can't do this. You
can't treat me like I'm sick.
My patients need to have
faith in me. What are you doing?
- Your wig was crooked.
- Ow!
I'll stop hovering if you
stop acting like an idiot.
Your next pill is at 2:00.
You can't take it on
an empty stomach.
OK.
Tyler Lee, nine years
old, came in with renal colic
three days ago that has not
resolved. We're going to perform
extracorporeal shockwave therapy
today to break up stones in his ureter
- so they can pass.
- No, we're not.
- Oh, uh, yes, we are.
There was no blood in
his urine this morning.
Just in case, we should do
the procedure. Just in case?
You want to do a surgical
procedure on a nine year old
even though it's
no longer indicated?
- No. Of course not.
- OK.
So Dr. Yang, wanna tell the
good news to Tyler and his mom?
It seems as though your son's
stones may have passed on their own.
- He doesn't need surgery?
- No. Looks like
he healed himself.
Can you believe that?
On your first day in Peds.
- No, I can't, actually.
- Does this mean I can eat?
Yeah. Dr. Yang will
get you something.
An abdominal aortic
aneurysm, 8.7 centimeters.
This has a 75 percent
chance of rupturing.
- She's a ticking time bomb.
- I'm surprised she woke up,
let alone got into a car.
OK, cancel all of my elective
surgeries this afternoon
and book an OR. We need
to get her in there ASAP.
OK, Jodie, we're done.
I'll meet you downstairs
to go over the results.
- Have you seen Tom?
- I thought he was with you.
He was, but he left.
He attacked me and left.
He...? You told me
you could handle this.
No, it's under control.
Don't worry. I called security.
I thought maybe his
mom would have an idea...
His mom has a triple-A. The
last thing she needs to know
is that her mentally ill
son is loose in the hospital!
I know this is bad.
This is really, really bad.
I'm gonna stop listening because the
words you are saying are hurting me.
- Find him!
- Yes.
- You look crazy.
- This is partly your fault.
You're the one who
told me to go act
like I deserve
to be here. I did!
Now, I lost a schizophrenic
and I am gonna be fired
unless I find the schizophrenic!
You're not gonna
find him back there.
You do not get to be charmed by
this, because this is not charming!
This is me getting
cut from the program!
You're already amazing.
I'm just starting out!
OK? I've never stapled a bowel
and I've never resected an esophagus!
- I am not amazing yet!
- All right. Let's just breathe.
And again. Good.
Look at me. Security is on this.
You have become a crazy
person I do not recognize.
I want Lexie back.
- Can I get Lexie back?
- Stay away from me!
- Oh, God, that's him.
- Just...
Where's my mother? What
have you done with her? No!
Sir!
Mrs. Crowley, there's evidence
your son may have suffered
some injury in this fall.
We don't think it's bad,
but we need to do an
ultrasound to make sure.
He's been sedated, but I need you
to wait here until we're completed.
- All right?
- I never should have
left him alone.
- I knew it. I knew it.
- OK, Mrs. Crowley,
I need to talk to you
about your test results.
The wall of your aorta
is dangerously thin
and could burst at any moment.
And when that happens,
it will most likely kill you.
I'm not mincing my
words now because
I need you to
understand the severity.
I need to take you up
to surgery right now.
I can't. I can't have
surgery right now.
I can't leave Tom.
He's injured, he's upset,
this has been a rough
day on him. I can't. No.
- It'll have to wait.
- Isn't there someone
you can call?
No. My ex-husband left
when Tom first got sick
and friends have
fallen away. It's only me.
We have services.
We can arrange...
I can't just leave
him with a stranger.
I need time.
To hire someone and train them,
to know that if he's watching
TV and holding his head
a certain way, it means
the television is talking to him
and he needs to be distracted.
He likes shopping, but they
can't take him to the place
on Lee Road because he
thinks they're out to get him.
They have to go to the
place on River Road,
but they've gotta park in the
back because underground parking
makes him upset, and it
goes on and on and on.
So no, please.
I need time.
A week. I've made it this long,
I can make it another week.
I'm not sure that you
have another week.
I need you to think
about yourself right now.
I have a mentally ill son.
I don't get to think of
just myself anymore.
Hey! Whoa, what
are you doing here?
I was just, um...
Uh... I just stopped by
to get some old case files.
- For what?
- Um, this job opening
in Portland.
- Oregon?
- Yeah.
The merger. I mean, the chief
already got rid of me once, so...
Yeah, no, that's smart,
smart of you to have a backup.
Hey, I'm working with Cristina.
She's interested in Peds.
- No, she isn't.
- Yeah, she is.
- OK.
- Did she say something to you?
She doesn't have
to. She's Cristina.
Help me out here. I don't
know what that means.
I shouldn't say anything.
She's my roommate.
And you're my girlfriend.
Girlfriend trumps roommate. Fine.
She's Cristina. She's
all about Cardio.
So she's probably
sucking up to you
to get through the merger.
Is she good with the kids?
- She's sucking up.
- Yeah.
- Nice pin.
- His name is Mr. Bear.
- He eats children.
- Not having fun in Peds?
My kid wants chocolate
pudding badly. This is the last one.
My triple-A got cancelled. You
guys got any surgeries I can get in on?
I'm on post-ops and
she's babysitting.
I can't stand it any longer.
Can't you go to the chief and use
your dead mommy to get answers?
We don't need dead mommy.
We are going to be fine.
I let a crazy man escape and
he fell down a flight of stairs.
- Is it surgical?
- Don't know. I got kicked off the case.
So then I went to
watch a surgery.
I figure I can't screw that up.
The second I get to the
gallery, the shunt starts bleeding.
I left before Shepherd
could blame me.
- Shepherd's shunt went bad?
- They converted to
open craniotomy.
Something I'll probably
never get a chance to do.
- She can't handle a craniotomy.
- Even he sees it.
He's not talking about
you. He's talking about Izzie.
I really admire you.
In case I get cut and
don't get a chance to tell
you. Plus, you're really pretty.
You can have the rest.
And you and I, we
were getting so close.
I need to speak with
Dr. Stevens, please.
- Alex, I'm in surgery.
- Izzie.
Alex, leave.
Dr. Shepherd, could you
please tell Dr. Karev to leave?
- Karev.
- She gets tired
walking to the mailbox.
She can't handle
a five-hour surgery.
I know what I can handle.
No one's gonna think less
of you if you walk out of here.
- Walk out now.
- Have this conversation
outside.
No. I'm not leaving. Alex!
You paged me. What's going on?
You have to tell the
chief you need me.
That George was your guy,
but he died so you need
a new guy and that's me.
- OK? Right now. Go, go, go.
- Come on.
- If anyone's safe, it's you.
- Be casual but firm. He likes you.
- Cristina!
- I played hide and seek today
and didn't go to surgery because
a nine-year-old miraculously peed
without blood. I
can't do this anymore.
Tell Dr. Robbins you don't
think Peds is your thing.
What's the big deal?
The big deal is that the
chief is in there making a list.
- You don't know that.
- Who stays and who goes,
- and I can't be
on that "goes" list.
- You'll deal with it.
If I am? There can be no "if".
I have to be on
the "stays" list.
That list is everything,
that list is my future,
- my salvation. The list is life.
- Calm down.
Schindler's List? You're comparing
this merger to the Holocaust?
- I'm Jewish. I'm allowed.
- You're irrational.
- So this is a no?
- This is a no.
- Somebody page Sloan stat!
- Right away, doctor.
OK, Elizabeth, take me
through exactly what happened.
I was doing a crash
C-section on this 32-weeker.
Had the incision done
in five minutes flat,
but I must have cut too deep
because when I went in to
take the baby, I pulled the arm...
- Oh, my God!
- Get me the umbilical cord.
- Umbilical cord?
- Just get it!
I got it. I got the
umbilical cord.
Get me five centimeters of it.
- What's going on?
- Arm got damaged
during a stat C.
I'm gonna use the
umbilical artery if it's viable.
It looks a little dry.
- Looks like it's gonna work.
- She's stable.
Let's put it in antibiotic solution
and move this party to the OR.
I'm sorry, I just... I wanted
to make sure you were OK.
Are you OK?
I injured my spleen,
and they're just waiting to see
if it stops bleeding on its own.
Good.
I'm glad. You seem...
Well, you seem
better and I'm glad.
Anyway, I should... I should
go. I'm not supposed to be here.
It's all right. They
got me in restraints.
I wouldn't be able to hurt you
even if the voices told me to.
It's a joke.
Schizophrenia humor.
Um... There's this thought
that I'm trying to get it out,
and I keep thinking that
they planted a camera
in my stomach
during the ultrasound.
I was gonna wake my mother
and have her talk me down, but...
She's tired.
Here is... your spleen.
See? And this bright spot
right here, that's blood.
That's not supposed
to be there. But...
no camera.
- No camera.
- Mm-mm.
I can leave this up if you want.
So that when the
thoughts come back,
you can look and see
that they're not real.
They're just scary
thoughts. They're not real.
Thank you.
A little more suction.
It's 2:00, Izzie.
- Oh, my God.
- No more fighting in my OR.
Go deal with this.
- I hate you.
- Shut up.
OK.
God...
- Thank you.
- Shut up. Get back to work.
Has Mrs. Crowley
agreed to the surgery?
No. She's gonna go
home and she's gonna die.
- What's that boy
gonna be left with?
- He needs surgery.
Does he need a transfusion?
Is there active bleeding?
No, his crit's stable. I
know we don't operate
unless there's an active
bleed, but it's so close and if we
operate on him, maybe
she'll let us operate on her.
We can keep them
together through the surgery,
through recovery, they'll
be together. Maybe you think
this is bad, I'm proposing
unnecessary surgery,
maybe you'll tell the
chief, he'll think it makes me
a bad doctor, but it
makes me a good doctor.
- Stop talking.
- Are my words hurting
you again?
No. You're right.
It's a good idea.
How does this happen? Was
Chen just not paying attention?
She made a mistake.
Wrong time to make a
mistake, with the merger.
You people need to stop with
doom and gloom merger scenarios.
I read that the hospital's
revenues went up last quarter.
Except for elective procedures
which went down 13 percent.
You mean elective
procedures like plastic surgeries.
- You're saying
I'm gonna get fired?
- No one is safe.
- I'm safe.
- How can you be sure?
Hey! We're about to
reattach a baby's arm.
We need to stop thinking about
the merger and think instead
about this girl throwing a ball,
holding a spoon
and waving bye-bye.
No, I'm not letting
you cut me open.
You're gonna put a camera in
me. You're... You are one of them.
- OK, Mrs. Crowley...
- No. He's scared. He said no.
Tom, you need this surgery.
And you will feel better
after it. And your mom...
Your mom's surgery
will save her life.
OK. Look...
Tom, look at me. Look at me.
I am not an alien. I
am not one of them.
My name is Miranda Bailey.
I have a three-year-old son.
And I would do anything for him.
Just like your mom
would do anything for you.
Now, she needs
you to do this for her.
Otherwise, she will die
and you will be alone.
Look, see? Red.
Red blood.
See, I'm human.
I am a doctor and I want
to help you and your mom.
But you have to trust me.
OK. I think we're there.
If it pinks up, we've
done our job right.
Releasing the bulldog
clamps. Here we go.
That's how I know my
job is safe, Dr. Yang.
Because I reattach babies' arms.
It's not a good idea to
piss off your attending.
I didn't know he was
upset. I'll apologize.
- I wasn't talking about him.
- Sorry?
I like kids and I like their parents,
and I like to see them smile.
I like going to get them pudding
and playing games with them
because it makes attaching
their arms way more fun.
I don't like being used.
- I wasn't...
- I like being
lied to even less.
What do we need from
the store, sweetheart?
Tell me what we
need from the store.
Apples, pears, strawberries.
Pears, apples...
- What if I don't make it?
- You don't worry about that.
OK? Let me do that.
Let's go.
OK. Bleeding's stopped.
Let's close up.
- Stevens, scrub out.
- No, I'm fine. I'm your resident.
Someone else can close up. You've
been on your feet for five hours.
- You look exhausted.
- I'm not.
You're dripping with sweat.
You know what?
Just take my wig off.
Just take it off! Take it off.
Just pat down my head.
OK. Just put the cap back on.
Thank you.
I'm fine.
Isobel Stevens spent five
hours on her feet in surgery today,
not because she was ready,
but because she's scared.
She's scared for her job, and
she was scared to show weakness.
You don't have to talk to me.
But you need to
talk to your people.
- They need to hear from you.
- Don't tell me about my people!
I have been here for 30
years, Derek. I know my people.
I have spent every hour
of the last three days
trying to save
every job I could.
But tough choices
had to be made.
HR is sending an e-mail to the
first round of people to be let go.
- Richard...
- Derek, I'm tired. I'm going home.
- What's going on? You paged.
- Check your e-mail.
- For what?
- HR.
If you got cut, you'll
have an e-mail.
I didn't get one, but I've
been calm through this crisis.
I have been calm. But if one
of us gets cut, I will not be calm.
- No e-mail.
- I'm fine.
- I'm good, too.
- Good! See? I knew it.
- I knew none of us'd get cut.
- Yet.
There's gonna be another round.
OK. So I'm there in the
spleen repair with Dr. Hunt,
and he's got the cautery and
he's moving it back and forth,
fixing bleeders. And then
he just... hands it to me.
Like it's the most normal
thing in the world to do.
Like I repair spleens all
the time. And so I do it.
I repair the spleen on my own.
And I realize if we
just focus on our jobs,
we focus on our patients,
we're gonna be fine.
Megan got cut.
- I didn't, but she did.
- What? How?
The chief sent out an e-mail.
He fired three
quarters of our class.
We're having a baby.
Terry, it's been a
pleasure working with you.
- Thanks.
- Sorry about everything.
- Hey, hey.
- What did I do wrong,
- so I can learn?
- You didn't do anything wrong.
This is about the money.
I've been here seven years.
All my friends are here.
I'll find another job,
but... seven years.
You have no idea.
If...
If you need a job recommendation,
anything, just call me, OK?
Hmm.
- Rough day?
- I need some sleep.
- OK. Let's go home.
- I can't. I just got
kicked off Peds.
- I'm totally screwed.
- Cristina...
I can't sleep. I can't.
I can't leave if
she's not leaving.
We're all susceptible to it.
The dread and anxiety of
not knowing what's coming.
No way.
Are you serious?
I'm gonna go to the chief.
I'll tell him you're the
best second-year resident.
I'm safe.
I didn't get cut,
Mark. I'm safe.
It's pointless in the end.
I hate, hate, hate this merger
because I hate long
distance relationships.
I don't believe in them. So
you can't move to Portland.
When I mentioned it this
afternoon, you didn't seem to mind.
You were like,
"Move to Portland".
I didn't know I was
allowed to mind.
I didn't know if we
were girlfriends.
But then you said girlfriend.
You called me your
girlfriend. So I need to know.
Am I your girlfriend?
Yeah.
OK. Good.
You're not moving to Portland.
No. What you are gonna do
- is go to the chief and beg...
- I'm not gonna grovel.
Uh, yes, you are. Seriously,
you don't want to mess with me.
Because all the worrying...
and all the making of plans for
things that could or could not happen...
it only makes things worse.
I forgot he was dead today.
For a few hours in
surgery, I forgot I had cancer
and I forgot he was dead.
But George is dead.
And you do have cancer.
I want you to keep
doing what you love.
You're a great doctor.
And you have a fantastic
future ahead of you.
But you gotta step up and
start taking care of yourself.
You gotta take your
meds, you gotta eat,
you gotta pace yourself.
Because I can't be your nurse.
I can't.
So walk your dog.
Or take a nap. Just,
whatever you do,
- stop worrying.
- I don't have time for games.
I have to get back
to the hospital.
She's right. She has to go back.
We're not talking about the
hospital. We're playing baseball.
And drink beer. Drink your beer.
- What more do you want?
- How can I drink when all
- my friends just got fired?
- Sorry, I'm leaving.
- No.
- You need this.
Put this on. That's right.
There we go.
- Here. Here.
- No... No!
- Now, hit the ball!
- I don't wanna hit the ball.
- Oh, my God!
- Batter, batter...
What are you...?
Stop thinking about
what's gonna happen.
Focus on what's
right in front of you.
Now, hit the ball!
Oh, my God! I hit it!
I hit it! Oh, my God!
- Oh, my God! I hit it!
- Wait, wait.
Because the only
cure for paranoia...
- I hit it!
- Now you like baseball.
Unbelievable.
Here we go, let's go.
Is to be...
here.
Just as you are.