Previously on ER:
Officer on deck.
- Me. I'm the chief.
- Yeah, Chief Pain-in-the-Ass.
- Welcome to County, Inez.
- Thanks.
I don't need anything from you. I
never have. Don't come back anymore.
But I couldn't leave
without seeing you.
I need to think
things out by myself.
- Where you going now?
- To look at an apartment before work.
So that's it? We
don't talk about this?
Sam's moving out.
Oh.
Why?
I have a feeling it's our
communication problem.
You're watching
the sunrise movie...
on WMAQ-TV, Chicago's Channel 5.
What did you say
your name was, again?
I didn't.
No, I guess you
didn't, at that, did you?
Morning, Zoila.
I think you at work.
First Thursday of the month. It's
when Samantha told me to come.
I'm running a bit late. You
don't have to clean up today.
- But Samantha say...
- Samantha doesn't live here anymore.
Um, I'll have her call you.
All these was at the lobby.
- The dishes.
- Hmm?
You're gonna get cucarachas.
Currently, patient throughput is
8.7 hours. Now, the problem is...
- Dr. Weaver, can we...?
- Not a good time, Morris.
If they need to be admitted to the
hospital, that goes up to over 19 hours.
Certainly room for improvement.
That's where Caduceus
Systematics come into the picture.
- Houston, we have a problem.
- One moment.
Why don't you...? Here,
take a look at these.
Hey.
Keep it down, doctor, I've
got grant officers with me.
Grant officers?
They're considering funding
a pilot study here at County.
Kudos to you.
Now, what do we do about this new
nurse czar, Eve something-or-other?
Peyton. She met with the Emergency
Services Committee, and we all loved her.
- Is it her job to slow the floor down?
- I thought that was your job.
My point being, the nurses
are in there, just yakking away.
- They're entitled to a staff
meeting, - Not unless I say so.
We say so.
Not unless Dr. Weaver says so.
Exactly. Who's the
Attending on today?
- Supposed to be Susan.
- That's not gonna happen.
So it's true? She's leaving
for a tenure position?
Not yet, she's just interviewing.
Isn't Kovac coming in?
- He's running a little late.
- What else is new?
- Dr. Weaver?
- Hold down the fort.
When's the last time
anybody even saw a nurse?
- Malik did an EKG for me six minutes ago.
- Just let them have their powwow.
No. Chief say powwow over.
Guess he hasn't met the
new nurse manager yet.
As part of the upcoming JCAHO
site visit, any individual practitioners...
- I need you to step out.
- What?
Can and will be asked
questions by the surveyor.
I need you to be
familiar with this booklet.
Shut up.
- I need a nurse, okay?
- I'm sorry.
Dr. Morris, is it?
Yeah, I...
I have a patient with an
abscessed tooth. Needs IV penicillin.
You need one of us to
administer IV antibiotics for you?
That's what nurses do.
Oh, I'm sorry, I wasn't aware
of any literature on the benefits...
of IV antibiotics
in dental infections.
- Literature? PEYTON:
As far as I know...
oral antibiotics are still
the standard of care.
Yeah. Yeah, I know that.
Oh, good. Then maybe
you can educate the nurses...
about inferior
alveolar dental blocks.
What?
Doing a study to track patients is the
best way to determine how to improve...
Uh, hey, Tony, can you give
my friends here a tour of the rig?
Sure thing, Dr. Weaver.
- Your shift started 40 minutes ago.
- Morning, Kerry.
- There's no Attending on the floor.
- We seem to have a shortage.
- Don't make me look for you.
- Can we talk about this later?
Okay. No, I need
to know that I...
Sir, stop where you are, sir.
I need a gurney here!
So did you straighten
those nurses out, chief?
They're autonomous
professionals.
If they wanna have a meeting,
we're in no position to question.
- She spanked you raw?
- It was a blur.
Can't find a femoral
pulse through the eschar.
Got a carotid, two plus.
- Need some help?
- We got it.
Can you check on my
guests? They seem freaked.
Hey, Sam. We need a nurse here.
- Inez, you go too.
- Hey.
Unidentified burn victim.
No history, walked himself in.
Do you want me to start
an IV or check the BP?
- Yeah, fine. WEAVER:
Access, vitals, fluids, let's go.
What's up with the camera?
- Sending Michael a care package.
- To Iraq?
Figured I'd include photos of everyone.
Is there anything you wanna send?
Sure. Like what?
Well, something you think he'd
miss, something he can't get there.
Exactamundo.
- Oh, a movie? That's not a bad idea.
- Yeah.
Let me put it this
way: It ain't Disney.
I know you're not
sending him porn.
- Just a three-way, nothing dirty.
- I like the way you think, Frank.
I'm not mailing this. He'll
get in trouble, I'll get arrested.
No. I buried it inside some nature
snoozefest about snow leopards.
That'll get it past
the Army hounds.
This cannot be a good idea.
Listen, dear, I've been to war. I
know how horny a guy can get.
Thanks, Frank, that'll do.
K.J., I need you to
make a run for me, man.
Again? I just got back
from getting her that camera.
Hey, hey, hey, no
slouching, right? Like a shark.
Now, take this $20.
The generous Dr. Pratt.
Catch me in a minute.
And help restock that cart.
What are you doing? We
still getting together later?
I had a case upstairs,
thought I'd stop by.
Oh, what case?
Eleven-year-old Latin Queen
recovering from a stab wound.
- Knife missed her heart by an inch.
- How's she doing?
Says she made one mistake.
She should've stabbed the bitch first.
Aren't they so cute at that age?
You got anything for me?
- I always got something for you.
- I meant work.
- Ah.
- Mm.
No GSWs yet, but
the day is still young.
I saw Charlie Pratt at Ceasefire.
He said he stopped by here last week.
- How'd it go?
- Quick.
It was quick. I mean, we
really have nothing to talk about.
Okay. So I'll see
you for lunch, then?
- Definitely.
- All right.
Lungs are wet. He's very tachy.
- I need that line, please.
- I'm working on it.
Morphine and fluids.
We need access, Sam.
- I know.
- No ID, doesn't know what happened.
Worry about ID after
you've got him on monitor.
And start a Foley to
document renal function.
Got it. Eighteen-gauge
in the left antecube.
A liter wide open.
Feet and perineum
are clear of burns.
- Sam, what are you doing?
- I'm gonna hang saline.
I can see that. Why?
Because fluid requirements
are 4 cc's per kilo.
You're familiar with
the Parkland Formula?
Yeah.
So you must know that lactated
Ringer's is the preferred crystalloid.
- Excuse me?
- Oh, Dr. Kovac, I'm Eve Peyton.
- Our new nurse manager.
- It's Kovac.
Sats are down to 78.
This is a bad time to start
pimping the nursing staff.
- Worst times are the best times to learn.
- Didn't Yoda say that?
- Suction.
All right. You've got this.
Eve, why don't you come with me and
I'll introduce you to the bean counters?
All right.
Did you call that woman?
Yes, your daughter's on her way.
Oh, hey, hey, you might
wanna check in on Penny.
Penny Nicholson?
If at first you don't succeed...
I believe that
would be my kidney.
- Hi, Penny.
- Nice to see you again.
- I'm Dr. Rasgotra, Mr...?
- Trimbody.
- It's my stage name.
- How apt.
I do elementary
school health shows.
"The Respiratory Rumba."
"Hygiene, Goodbye BO,"
"The Heart is a Lonely Beater."
- We get it.
- Discomfort after a fall.
I slipped on a puddle of Jell-O
in the cafetorium in the middle...
of my number on the reproductive
system, "Ova Here, Ova There."
Breath sounds are equal.
Check for splenic tenderness.
All right.
Take a deep breath, sir.
She was about to feel
my liver, wasn't she?
I mean, come on, you're not in the
fifth grade. My spleen is right here.
There's no need
to get excited, sir.
- Ms. Nicholson is a medical student.
- It's right in front of you.
- The entire human anatomy.
- Actually, sir, it's not.
You have no genitalia.
- Ready?
- Hmm?
- You blocked it.
- What's that for?
Michael's care package.
I'm getting photos of everyone,
plus anything people wanna send him.
Frank's giving him porn.
Ah, the gift that
keeps on giving.
What are you gonna send?
Well, I made this mix
CD, but I don't know.
"Weekend in New
England." "Mandy."
Michael's got a weak
spot for Barry Manilow.
Very weak.
I could send him a menu from
Gibson's, or a Cubs program.
Or I've got some
pressed flowers I could...
You'll figure it out.
Yeah. Here, sign this for him.
The lighting in here is brutal.
That's all you got from
him? No family, no address?
The guy was in pain, okay?
Well, I'll go up with you
in case he wakes up.
Maintain the PEEP
around 10 and tell the unit...
they'll need central
monitoring on this guy.
You didn't even get a name?
He really wasn't
up for an interview.
- Nice way to start the day, huh?
- Yeah.
How's the new place?
It's okay. You know,
we're getting used to it.
Oh, here. Some of
it's a few days old.
Oh, thank you.
Are you gonna take Alex to
that soccer game on Saturday?
- If you still want me to...
- Yeah, no, I think...
- No, I mean, I wasn't sure that...
- I think...
- No, maybe you should.
- Yeah.
Think it'd be good
for everybody.
Well, okay.
I was thinking...
I've been thinking.
We let things get away from us,
but we don't have to leave it like that.
- Luka...
- No, a lot happened fast.
Too fast.
Maybe we should just take our time,
make sure we know what we're doing.
I don't want this to be one
more thing I messed up.
We're pretending, Luka.
I don't wanna pretend anymore.
Sam, do you have that...?
Your piggyback. Yes, right here.
How much did you drink?
I'm fine, let me out of here.
All right, sit down
and relax, okay?
- How old are you?
- Sixteen.
- Pretty stupid.
- I got a 2200 on my SATs.
You work for the
county. Who's stupid?
Two liters of saline.
Send off a BAL, and don't light a
match around our little genius here.
That's why they
call me the whiz kid.
Oh, yeah.
Okay, go with God.
Oh, yeah, look at that.
This is an 18 French
Foley catheter, Erik.
What's it for?
I'll need you to
remove your pants.
- Labs are back on your UTI.
- Thanks.
- How's your burn guy?
- In ICU.
- Any leads?
- Cops are looking into it.
He just walked
in here like that?
High tolerance
for pain, I guess.
Okay, well, let me know
if you hear anything.
Robbie Beckwith, 11,
blunt face and head.
He's on a motorized
scooter, hit a lady on skates.
- They're unloading her right now.
- I'll get that one.
- Robbie, can you squeeze my hand?
- Maybe Pratt should take this.
He's altered and he
had no helmet. CT?
Chuny, where's Pratt?
With a new-onset seizure in 2.
Guess it's you and me.
Yeah.
- Trauma panel, C-spine, chest and pelvis.
- And facial CT?
After the plain films.
Yankauer, please.
My mom. I want my mom.
They called her.
She's on her way.
You lost a couple of teeth, Robbie.
Wear a helmet from now on, okay?
- Promise.
- Need anything here?
Probably just gonna tube
him and get him to CT.
- I'll call for a vent.
- We may not need it.
- You're not gonna tube him?
- I don't know yet.
Well, I've got three
nurses here for the traumas.
I can float in a
fourth if you want.
There's a lot of bleeding
from the nasopharynx.
I can't visualize the source.
He's getting wheezy.
Okay, he's gonna
need help breathing.
That's all I was saying.
I'm going in with Abby on
a diffuse abdominal pain.
Show her how to
secure the airway.
- Really?
- Yeah, I'll be next door.
7-0 ET.
Sux is onboard.
Pulse ox 99 on 2 liters.
- Pupils equal and reactive.
- What happened?
- We were Rollerblading.
- My first time.
She got dizzy and rammed
into some kid on a scooter.
- No breakfast.
- I tried to catch her, but I...
Why are you
wearing those in here?
We left our shoes
at the rental place.
- Good breath sounds bilaterally.
- Have you ever had any seizures?
- Any heart problems?
- No, I'm healthy.
- You on any medication?
- Nothing, just multivitamins.
HemoCue's low, 6.9.
You ever been anemic before?
- No.
- Luka.
- Is that a burn?
It's probably from
the scooter's tailpipe.
Okay. Belly CT,
ultrasound, 2 units of O-neg.
Call Surgery and hold an O.R.
- What's happening?
- She's losing blood.
- But I'm not even cut.
- No, it's internal.
- You good in here?
- Hemorrhaging?
He needs that lac looked at.
Yes, he does. Come with me.
I'll be back soon, Stephanie.
Hey, how do you like those
things? They hurt your knees at all?
That Morris guy, what's he do?
He's chief Resident.
No, seriously.
- Ton of blood, cords are swollen.
- What if you can't get through?
- Plan B.
- What's Plan B?
- Set up the fiber-optic.
- How long will the paralytics last?
Look it up in the PDR.
I got the scope, but the
light source, I gotta find one.
Morison's is
clear. No free fluid.
Fiber-optic light
source in here?
I saw it in Exam 3.
- How's it going in there?
- It's going.
- First unit of O-neg is up.
- No hemothorax.
- Is that good?
- Yes, it is good...
but it still doesn't
explain the blood loss.
- I'm here.
- Blunt abdomen, severe anemia.
FAS is negative. DUBENKO: BP?
Hasn't dropped yet. She's tachy
but maintaining a systolic of 110.
- Any pain there?
- Not really.
Extra red top, please. You.
- Here you go.
- Microscope?
Obviously, there's an
occult bleeding source.
Dr. Kovac, normally
this might be the part...
where we argue over whether
you were hasty in calling me down.
I'd question the accuracy
of your assessment.
We'd play mind games in a
futile attempt to one-up each other.
But you know what? I'm
just not in the mood today.
Why? I don't know.
Lack of sleep? Stress?
Maybe you people
have just worn me out.
Yet even then...
Dr. Lockhart, what do you see?
- Microcytic hypochromic anemia.
- And is that an acute condition?
- No.
- No, it is not.
It is a chronic condition, the
differential of which includes?
Iron deficiency, thalassemia,
sideroblastosis, lead poisoning.
Are any of those surgical?
Anybody?
New nurse?
Next time, please consider
the innate skills and abilities...
that I suspect led
us to be doctors.
Dust them off and put them
to use before you summon me.
Good luck, dear.
Was it something you said?
- Light source on high.
- Sats are 92.
All right, here we go.
This is Mrs. Beckwith, Robbie's
mom. I've explained the situation.
- Is he in a coma?
- No, ma'am, he's just sedated.
Oh, I told him be careful on
that thing. To wear a helmet.
- Turn up the suction.
- Has Dr. Kovac been in here?
He left to work on that lady.
Sam, cricoid pressure.
Got it.
Is he coming back?
I'll go update him. Here, Penny.
- You're sure you've never been anemic?
- Positive.
Ever had an ulcer? SAM: Luka.
- What is it?
- You might wanna look in on this.
- Not right now.
- PVC's on the monitor.
Okay, is the first unit in?
- No, IV's infiltrated.
- She's only got 50 cc's.
- She needs some blood.
Anything from your medical
history we need to know?
Anything else you can think of?
Nothing important.
I mean, I tested positive
for BRCA1 last year.
- But I'm tumor-free.
- BRCA1?
Genetic mutation
that indicates...
an increased risk of
breast and ovarian cancer.
Try an 85 percent chance, but
I know I don't have cancer yet.
- I cannot get an IV.
- Neither can I.
Okay, set me up for a central
line. Betadine and sterile gloves.
- Sats are in the low 80s.
- Did Dr. Kovac say how long?
Damn it. SAM: Actually,
he didn't say much.
- Let's get those sats up.
- Is he not breathing right?
- Maybe you should crike him?
- Too young. Not in children under 12.
Line is primed and ready.
- Dr. Kovac.
- Guidewire.
- Cordis introducer.
Dr. Pratt needs a more experienced
physician to help him get the fiber-optic.
Wire is passing,
100 of lidocaine.
Pratt is experienced
with airways. He'll get it.
Anything unusual you
might have ingested?
He needs you in there.
- Multifocal PVCs.
- This woman is decompensating.
- And that child is hypoxic.
- Run of four.
Because to fix it, we
have to know what it is.
I didn't take anything.
- There should be an Attending in there.
- I'll be in as soon as I can.
Okay, then.
- Where's your difficult-airway box?
- It's over there.
Do you work with pottery or stained
glass? Those have heavy metals in them.
Excuse me, Miss Peyton?
I have a Ph.D., so if you'd
like to get formal, call me doctor.
Open the crash cart.
Stephanie, what is it?
I've been going to
Mexico for treatments.
To prevent cancer?
A three-day juice fast
with herbal enemas.
And some natural medicine
to boost my immune system.
Lead poisoning. Send a level.
Okay, BAL, 35
milligram, IM for chelation.
Why didn't you say
something sooner?
I was scared. I didn't know
what it would do to my coverage.
- What's going on?
- Laryngeal mask airway.
Tip of the cuff on the palate,
and guide with your index finger...
until you feel the resistance
of the hypopharynx.
And inflate.
And bag.
You might wanna educate about
the LMA as a rescue device...
in can't intubate/can't
ventilate patients.
- Sats are coming up.
- It's working.
Thank you. Thank you.
Take it from here, doctor. I'm gonna
go find a bedpan that needs emptying.
I didn't even know we
had LMAs on the floor.
Been on order since
July, arrived last Friday.
As part of my orientation, I went
through the supply lists, item by item.
Sounds like something
Weaver would make you do.
Actually, I did it on my own.
Is there some sort of history
between you and Dr. Kovac?
Uh, nothing to worry about.
It's a nurse-doctor issue. If I
don't worry about it, who will?
It's a personal thing.
Won't come up again.
Sam, is our kid up in CT?
- Yeah, he's with his mom.
- Hey, since when do we have LMAs?
Since last Friday,
from what I'm told.
Man, I hope I didn't blow it.
- Kovac shouldn't have left you.
- I told him I had it.
Hey, Dr. Pratt. Got it.
All right, we all set
up? Let's go find Neela.
I wasn't a feminist, I'd call
that new manager a bitch.
She's all up in my stuff,
writing everything down.
Are we getting evaluated, Sam?
I guess so.
Beware the Blood Countess.
A pizza? You wanna
send a pizza to Iraq?
- It's a deep-dish. Mikey loves it.
- I understand that, but...
We got the dry ice, we
got the waterproof shroud.
- It's gonna be a week in transit.
- It will?
I could look into
flash-freezing.
It's all good. Just, you know,
take the picture, come on.
Well, all right. Say cheese.
- Cheddar.
- So should I...? PRATT:
No, don't worry about it.
I'll take care of everything.
I got this.
What's with you? This thing
won't make it to Baghdad.
- What were you thinking?
- Hey.
CT's on the line. Your scooter
boy's heart rate dropped.
Is Stephanie okay? They said
that I still can't talk to her yet.
How deep into
this thing are you?
What?
Oh, um...
We only met a few nights
ago, at a JSpeedDate.
- But we really hit it off.
- J what?
It's for Jewish singles.
You go around each table, chatting
for a few minutes with each person.
- See who responds to whom.
- Oh.
- Are you Jewish?
- No, no, no.
I had a crush on
a Semitic girl once.
That's a holy prayer
that you just said.
Yeah, yeah. I spent a
lot of time at synagogue.
I guess you could
say stalking her.
Those rabbis,
man, they hit hard.
I think I really like her.
- Ow!
- Sorry about that.
- Oi.
- Aah!
Diffuse brain edema. Facial
CT shows a Le Fort II fracture.
Okay. NORMA:
What does that mean?
Need surgeries to fix
the bones in his face.
- I'll put him back on monitors.
- And set up for a formal trach.
What's that, trach?
We need to put a
surgical airway in his neck.
All right. We're gonna need 12 of
Decadron, IV push, and 60 of mannitol.
Okay. Number
eight sterile gloves.
- Betadine and Steri-Drape.
- One percent with epi.
CT report.
- Norma, you need anything?
- 410 blade to Dr. Pratt.
My husband. We're separated.
- Do you need me...?
- Yes, he's been called.
Do you have a washroom?
Chuny, I'll get that. You show
Mrs. Beckwith where that is.
- Vertical incision.
- Come with me, ma'am.
- Bring you back when they're done.
- Cricoid cartilage to sternal notch.
I'm glad you found time
to supervise your Resident.
Cauterize here
for the hemostasis.
There's no excuse for
what happened earlier.
- I was with another patient.
- She's less critical.
- Not by my assessment.
- Then it was wrong.
Ready to divide
the thyroid isthmus.
Two Kellys.
Kid with severe head
trauma takes priority.
Shouldn't need a
nurse to tell you.
Shouldn't need a doctor to explain it's
not always clear who the most critical is.
Then next time, you call in a second
Attending or get a more senior Resident.
Hey, I'm an R-4.
I thought I had it.
You and I need to talk about which
nurses you're willing to work with and not.
That way, this won't
have to happen again.
Number 6 Shiley.
- Hard to come up with right thing.
- People sending Michael loser presents?
Well, Pratt thinks he can send him
a pizza, and Chuny got him these.
- But I meant from me.
- Well, what's your current plan?
Well, I wrote him a poem.
Are you sure you want me to...?
Scented.
It rhymes.
- Is it too high school?
- Yeah, it's kind of cheesy.
- I'm an idiot.
- No, you're not.
Look, you're his
girlfriend, right?
Well, I guess, yeah.
Well, Neela, a man at
war has certain needs.
You're beginning
to sound like Frank.
I get that a lot. Meet me in
the Family Room in 10 minutes.
- Dr. Kovac.
- I'm tired of fighting with you.
- There's issue between you...
- It's my job to assess where I'm needed.
- I understand that.
- As for me and Sam, we're a couple.
I mean, it's not a problem.
All right, then.
Look, normally I try to
resolve internal issues...
as calmly, as
civilly, as possible.
And you probably don't understand
that, because in this case...
well, I didn't.
Look, from now on, I'm just
gonna focus my attention...
on determining how the
nurses should be utilized.
That sounds good.
Nice. Don't be so serious.
Try to relax a little
bit. Have some fun.
- It just feels too weird.
- It's okay, it'll be fine.
Come on.
Oh, grab those lollipops.
You're kidding, right?
No. Come on.
This guy's asking for you again.
Secret of my success, Chuny,
always leave them wanting more.
Done. Done. Dead.
And done.
You don't need
the bra. Take it off.
No, I can't.
It'll be fine.
Like this?
Nice. More open.
Oh, I just feel weird.
Do my legs look okay?
Yes. You have the
gams of a patriot.
Now, make love to the camera.
That's great!
Excellent.
Smile.
Perfect.
Hi.
Thank you.
Where's your Roller-date?
Lou. He said he'd come
back with pizza and sneakers.
Seems like a sweet guy.
So your lead levels
came back critical.
Is that from my treatments?
It's probably from the
herbs you were taking.
You're gonna need a series of
injections, but the anemia should resolve.
More importantly is what
you're doing about the BRCA.
- What I'm doing?
- Yeah.
Can you hold onto
this for a minute?
If you like, I could get an oncologist
to come down here and talk to you.
No. I don't want that.
You okay?
I saw an oncologist
when I first found out.
And what made you get tested?
My doctor recommended
it, on account of my mother.
Is she positive too?
She beat cancer once when I
was little, but it came back to get her.
I watched her getting
smaller and smaller all winter.
And then, as soon as the leaves
began to go green, she passed away.
It was right before
my senior prom.
Just 44 years old.
I'm sorry.
Did the oncologist you
spoke with mention anything...
about prophylactic surgery?
- You mean having my breasts removed?
- And an oophorectomy.
I'd never do that.
That's why I tried Mexico.
I wanna fall in love.
I wanna have a child, a
family, while there's still time.
Then you might wanna
consider just the mastectomies.
- And wait for the ovarian...
- Just the mastectomies?
Would a man even
wanna look at me then?
There have been advances
in reconstructive surgery.
And you need to
protect yourself.
Can you promise me that giving
up my breasts would protect me?
It would decrease your chance
of getting cancer by 90 percent.
And I would lose months of my
life to recovery with no guarantees.
And the clock is ticking,
and I'm not getting younger.
So tell me which poison to pick.
The cancer risk or the surgery?
Well, I can't.
But maybe an oncologist could.
- Mr. Beckwith? BECKWITH:
Are you Doctor...?
Kovac. Yeah,
please, come with me.
Where is he? Can I see him now?
I'd like to talk to you
about his condition.
Is my wife here?
- She's in with Robbie now.
- Is he awake? I wanna see him.
- You will, soon.
- I told her not to get him that thing.
She's always making me out to be
the bad guy, spoiling that kid rotten.
Why don't we go inside so I can explain
to you where we're at with Robbie now?
I'm not going. I know
why you take people there.
- Sir, please...
- No, my boy is not dead!
Robbie?
- Mr. Beckwith.
- Robbie.
- Where is he? KOVAC:
Sir, can you just calm down?
Where is he? Robbie? Robbie!
- Robbie!
- Mr. Beckwith!
There's swelling in his brain.
We hope it's gonna go down soon.
We had to put an
emergency airway in his neck.
Oh, buddy, what did
you do? What did you do?
I'm sorry, Jack. I'm sorry.
No! No! BECKWITH: Oh, God!
Security! NORMA: No!
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it!
Get off me! Get...
No.
I didn't want that floor to
be without an Attending.
That's all right. My shift
starts in 35 minutes anyway.
- Your shift?
- Yep.
Till we get new faculty, it's just
you, me and the moonlighters.
Hey, doc. Wife doesn't
wanna press charges.
- How about you?
- No.
When she leaves the room,
we'll let him go inside, see his son.
Hey, that burn victim who
went up to ICU, how's he doing?
He's hanging in there.
The guy's such a mess, he
can't even tell us his name.
- How you doing?
- That floor came out of nowhere.
Hey, I signed out to Morris.
He's our mini-chief, right?
- Just go.
Neela, you L-train-bound?
- In a minute.
- All right, I'll walk out with you.
- What are you doing?
- Found it in Sutures.
It was wrapped in
a death-kit shroud.
- It's kind of soggy.
- Frank, that was for Gallant.
Hey, try Lou Malnati's.
They overnight.
So, Neela, I feel you should
know that I minored in photography.
- So if there's anything you need a hand...
- Shut up.
What's he talking about?
- Nothing.
Okay, different tack. As Chief
Resident, I think I need to know...
what you and Abby
were doing in that room.
And by know, I mean see.
You know what, Morris?
Just because you're so cute.
Sebaceous cyst abscess.
On somebody's ass.
Oh, that was my
fat guy in Curtain 2.
Weighing in at an
easy 400 pounds.
Looks like it's leaking, Morris.
You might wanna check that out.
Ew.
I won't have to
sleep up here, will I?
No, we have a bed for
you on the third floor.
We both know what
they're gonna say.
The safest thing would be for
me to have the double mastectomy.
Well, I know it's a sacrifice...
but it's not as though you'd have
to live without breasts forever.
It won't be the same. It
won't feel like my body.
Well, the things you want,
you can't have if you get cancer.
So if you were
me, you would do it.
Well, sometimes, we want life
to stay the same, but it doesn't...
it changes, and if I were you, I hope
I would be brave enough to change.
Hi, Abby. Is this
Miss Lowenstein?
- Yes, it is.
- Dr. Geary can see you now.
I'll check on you tomorrow.
Thanks.
Someone picking you up?
Erica's dropping off Alex.
Heard you had a little
throwdown with a patient.
Not a patient. The
scooter kid's father.
Yeah, Robbie.
He was having some
purposeful movements.
Yeah. More than I can
say for myself today.
I shouldn't have left him.
It was the wrong thing
for the wrong reason.
- We'll figure it out.
- Yeah.
Let's start again tomorrow, huh?
Tell Alex I'll be seeing him
for that soccer game tomorrow.
He's gonna be real happy.
Hey. What, are you off?
No, coffee. I got
six more hours.
Hey, walk with me.
Okay.
Is something wrong?
You're sleeping with him?
I was. It's over.
It's never over, hon. Trust me.
I don't think it's appropriate
for you two to work together.
- What?
- Since I can't control physician shifts...
- I guess I gotta rejigger yours.
- Rejigger?
- I took a look at the schedule...
- Come on, wait.
And it seems to work out if you
work Tuesday and Friday nights...
and pick up a third
shift Saturday or Sunday.
That's two less than I'm doing, which
I can't afford, and I'll never see my kid.
- I'm doing you a favor.
- Doesn't sound like it.
I could do what any
manager would do.
How do you feel
about ICU or Recovery?
- Geriatrics always has openings.
- Threatening to transfer me?
I am giving you a choice.
I'm an ER nurse.
Right. So be here Friday,
8 p.m., ready to work.
- Hey.
- Don't you have work?
Nope, 48 hours off.
- Oh, lucky you.
- Yeah.
Thanks.
Oh, there's more in the fridge.
Well, who's the other one for?
Having a sleepover.
Hi. I ordered a Caesar
salad and a root beer.
That should be right out.
- Thanks.
Hey, sailor. New in town?
Have a seat.
No, I have to get going.
I took our BRCA
lady up to Oncology.
Yeah?
It was sad.
She was telling me how
she's at this point in her life...
where she's worried that
some of the things she wants...
she's never gonna have.
She could never
imagine feeling that way.
It's sad.
You must miss it.
Drinking.
Wow.
You'd be a terrible sponsor.
Yeah, I could never give up.
I'd miss it too much.
Well, you might wanna think
about suspending it for the evening.
Need a ride home?
No, but I think you do.
- I do?
- Mm-hm.
- You're not driving like this.
- I'm not?
No.
Ray, I can't concentrate!
Help yourself to something.
- Wow.
Didn't take you long to
embrace the bachelor lifestyle.
No. It's like riding a horse.
Or living in a barn.
Can't get him out of my head.
Who?
That guy.
What a mess.
All melted of flesh, but even
so, enough will to keep walking.
Body ruined, but
still desperate to live.
And he's alive.
Yeah, I wonder if I...
If I were hurt like that...
If you'd keep on walking?
If anyone would know who I was.
I would.
Probably.
You know, you might wanna
think about getting a housekeeper.
Because it's really
disgusting in here.
In a charming sort
of way, of course.
Do you want a coffee?
You're watching the movie...
on WMAQ-TV, Chicago's Channel 5.
Probably don't want a coffee,
but I got you a black coffee and...
It's about time we
got out there, huh?
There's plenty of time.
Yeah, but they'll be
here any damn minute.
I think Sam's
right. We ought to.
- Yeah.
- What about after?
What about after we do it?
- Hmm?
- What do we do then?
Then you live with it.