Adam, eyes here.
Follow my finger.
Adam, show me a bicycle.
Eyes here.
No, buddy, that's a ball.
Adam, look at me.
Are you hungry?
Show me what you want for lunch.
He's still drawing those lines
instead of looking at the cards.
More juice?
If he wants more juice,
he has to ask for it.
Adam, buddy, eyes here.
He's tired, Dom.
He wouldn't be if we
stuck to the schedule.
Show me the juice, buddy.
I think we've reached the
point of diminishing returns.
He has to ask for it. Adam.
He's choking.
That's impossible.
It's mac and cheese.
Ten-year-old boy who
screams for his life for no reason.
He's autistic.
Severely autistic.
Can't talk, can't
make eye contact.
Screaming is probably
his way of communicating.
And he went to three different
doctors who all said just that.
So, clearly that
can't be the answer.
His brain can't
filter information.
It's a constant assault on
his senses. I'd scream, too.
Or it's something
medical-sounding, like dysesthesia.
Parents are convinced that there's
something wrong with their son.
Since when did we start believing
parents? Or anyone? Where are we going?
Elevator.
Dad was on Wall Street, Mom
was a partner in an accounting firm.
When their son was diagnosed
with autism, they both quit.
So they're over-protective and scared.
That's all the more reason to discount...
They study this kid.
Heard him scream a million times,
but in ten years of caring for him,
this is the first time they've
brought him to a hospital.
ER checked his throat.
No obstructions, nothing.
Which means the only
symptom was a scream,
which is diagnostic of nothing.
Kid clutched his chest, BP was
elevated, maybe there was chest pain.
ER said the heart was fine.
Don't be so quick
to dismiss pain.
Where are we going? Down.
Stool sample to
check for parasites,
blood culture to rule out
infection, and ANA for lupus.
Because he screamed?
Could also be an
environmental reaction.
An allergy. Dust, wheat, pollen,
a toxin or something
he ate. Check the house.
And run a lung ventilation scan.
Lungs are in the
chest, too, right?
I had a date last
night, she screamed.
Should we spend a hundred
thousand dollars testing her?
Of course not. This
isn't a veterinary hospital.
Look, if you don't think
this kid is worth saving...
That's not what I'm saying.
That's too bad. It
was a good point.
Kid's just a lump with tonsils.
You know what
it's going to be like
trying to put an autistic
kid into a nuclear scanner?
I don't envy you guys.
I want my old carpet back.
We're going to have to do this later.
A kid in the clinic had an accident.
Generally, when people
are on the phone...
I want my old carpet back.
It was stained with blood.
Yeah, my blood, which
makes the carpet part of me.
I want it back. I want
to be buried with it.
You think you can get me
to do anything you want,
regardless of how stupid it is?
It's my office.
It's where I work,
where I think, where I save lives,
allowing you to brag to rich people,
so they'll give you more money
to spend on MRIs and low-cut tops.
I want it back the way it was.
It's identical to
the old carpet.
Except without the
hazardous biological waste.
I shall not return to my office until
every patented, durable micro-fiber
has been restored
to its rightful place.
Inspiring.
If you don't want to work in
your office, work in the clinic.
If you don't want to work in the
clinic, go home. And don't get paid.
Attica! Attica!
Attica! Attica! Attica!
Attica?
He just needs
to finish this level.
We only have the scanner
for the next half hour.
After that... Trust me,
you don't want to move
him until he's finished.
The sooner we do this test, the
sooner we can get you guys home.
Adam, do you think that...
No.
Ten minutes. Tops.
If he has a vascular
disorder, he might not have...
He might not have ten minutes?
I don't have ten minutes.
No! No! You don't want
to do that. Adam? Adam?
I used Metamucil
like the doctor told me
and finally I was able
to use the bathroom.
But I saw something in
the toilet I couldn't identify.
I wrapped it in tissue paper,
so you could take a look.
Can't you sedate
him or something?
I could if I didn't want the
test results to mean anything.
Painkillers, exercising,
we even did that puncture
thing, nothing works.
Then this morning, I get
up, my back feels great.
I figured I'd better get
down here, right away.
Big shocker, Dad's depressed.
Save your time.
SSRIs don't cause chest pain.
Wow.
Every minute of
every day is booked.
When he eats, sleeps,
plays his handheld.
Not much of a life for them.
They chose to have a family.
You don't get to decide what
your kid's going to be like.
Nobody chooses this.
It's funny, you get a
normal kid, the parent works.
You get a special
kid that costs more,
you quit and turn the
backyard into a therapy circuit.
Yes, if only you
were handicapped.
All the good times you
could have had with Dad.
Hi, Doctor House.
Hello, girl whose
name I don't remember,
but whose dad I treated, so I
don't really know why she's here.
Ali. I think I caught what
my dad has. The rhino thing.
Right.
Does that hurt?
Little.
It's in my chest, too.
Of course it is.
Kind of had access through
the shirt, but this'll work.
That feels good.
Exactly when did New Jersey
run out of horny 17-year-old boys?
About five weeks ago.
It's been very lonely.
The...
The ventilation scan was
normal. Time to send him home.
Can't leave right now.
Well, congratulations.
You are the proud owner of
your very own "rhino thing."
A rhinovirus? You can't
leave because she has a cold?
I can't leave because
Cuddy says I can't leave.
All the tests are normal.
Okay, don't start with
me. We're backed up.
I know this is hard for all of
us, but thanks to Doctor Cuddy,
I don't have an office,
so I have to work here.
What did she do to your office?
It's unusable.
So whatever's bothering
him, it wasn't his lungs.
What about the kid's house?
There were some pesticides and some
alcohol, but the tox screen was negative.
Which means there's nothing
physically wrong with this kid.
We already had that
discussion. We get a fecal smear?
Should we do this
someplace else?
No, Cuddy says I
have to work here.
No, I said you can work in your
office, or you had to work here.
And since I can't
work in my office...
Is this your master plan?
Disrupt hospital business
until I replace your carpet?
Devious. Saw it in a
James Bond movie.
Fecal smear! Talk to me.
Get out of here.
Put back my carpet?
No. Get out of here.
Fecal matter. Is there a
sample we can look at?
The parents have a smear
kit. The kid is constipated.
Do what you want. Not
replacing your carpet.
Go up his rear and get a smear.
Which reminds me, I
kind of feel like a bagel.
Carpets.
Need a stool sample.
We should probably wait until
he's finished playing that level, huh?
I actually think he's
a bit better today.
He seems more like his old self.
It's possible that
he was never sick.
I guess, we
could've overreacted.
Adam? Adam? Adam? Adam?
So what makes fluid fill
the lining of a kid's lungs?
Why are we in here? Is
this some sort of power play?
Yeah.
So, you stuck your finger in the
kid and gave him a pleural effusion?
Have you ever considered
getting a manicure?
I took the stool sample
after his lungs failed.
Or do you really have a
problem with the carpeting?
Change sets you off...
I said it was a power play.
If someone answers yes to option
A, you don't move on to option B.
If there's a pleural effusion,
we have to rule out heart failure.
Why now? Why a power play now?
I smelled weakness.
Get the kid an echocardiogram.
That's funny. It
says, "James Wilson."
That's a strange typo.
The fluid comes back and exudates,
get him on broad spectrum antibiotics.
Thank you for
coming. No problem.
Thought you wouldn't mind
sharing offices for a while.
You share stories, feelings,
toys, you don't share offices.
That is so not Zen.
It was a gift.
Some doctors get those.
So, you want
mornings or afternoons?
You couldn't make Cuddy miserable,
so you're going to make me miserable,
so I can make Cuddy
miserable on your behalf?
Yeah.
What makes you think I
can make her miserable?
'Cause you're
good at that stuff.
I'm nothing compared to you.
Is there anything
you'll throw out?
That's a gift from an
eleven-year-old patient of mine.
She and I both knew it was a piece of
junk, and that's what made her laugh.
So you gotta
keep it until she...
She already did.
Adam, I need you
to stay still, buddy.
It's okay. It's okay. I got him.
There we go.
What? What is it?
Is his heart okay?
No.
Echo suggested a conduction
abnormality, EKG confirmed it.
Still doesn't explain the effusion.
The pleural fluid was an exudate.
We should be looking for something that
explains both the heart and lung problems.
An infection, parasite, cancer.
Microbiology showed no organisms
in the fluids, so forget infection.
It's not a power play.
Doing a differential in the clinic
makes sense, piss Cuddy off.
Same thing with Wilson's
office, works indirectly.
But now we're in office space
because you don't want
to be in your own office.
Which means this has
nothing to do with Cuddy.
You really are obsessed
with your carpets.
Which means... What
are you doing here?
I have this room
booked from two to three.
Two, East Coast Time?
I thought you meant Pacific.
Which is stupid of me, I guess.
What about parasites?
Stool sample's negative.
It's two o'clock.
Oh, well. We should go
then. That just leaves cancer.
Get a lung biopsy.
It took a half an hour to get the
mask on the kid for the lung scan.
I'm sorry. Was there
somewhere you needed to be?
House, can we talk?
Carpet? Never.
Nothing to talk about.
Your girlfriend called the clinic
15 times, looking for you today.
Lot to discuss,
china patterns...
House. She's a stalker.
Right.
Couldn't be that she finds me interesting,
attractive, has to be that she's insane.
She's called you 15 times. Your
mother's not that interested in you.
Well maybe I'd be
better adjusted if she was.
I'm notifying security.
Is this about the carpet?
Do you think I'll back
off if you block all my fun?
You better not be having fun.
I'm having fun.
I'm not having sex.
She's dangerous.
She's not dangerous.
She's pretty. She's pretty.
Men are stupid.
I'm with you so far.
I'm notifying security.
Give her a break. She's not
dangerous, she's insightful.
You can't stop our love!
Hey, you got a minute? Yeah.
We have a ten-year-old
with pleural effusion
and conduction abnormality,
but no heart failure.
Was there protein
in the pleural fluid?
Yeah. That's why
we're thinking cancer.
Non-Hodgkin's probably. So
we want to do a lung biopsy.
Lung biopsies usually come back negative,
so biopsy a lymph node under the arm.
That's probably something
an oncologist should do, right?
There's nothing real
tricky to it. It's a biopsy.
Still, just to be
safe. You mind?
For the love of God, can't
somebody shut that kid up?
People are trying
to work around here.
Why don't you show him
a teddy bear or something?
Who are you?
Somebody you'll
never send a gift to.
This is Doctor House,
your son's doctor.
High test, please.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Out of Vicodin?
What are you doing?
Eating the red berries.
He trusted you.
No, that wasn't trust.
That was self-preservation.
No. That was huge.
It was like a conversation.
A monkey's afraid to eat the red berries
until he sees another monkey eat 'em.
Monkey see, monkey
do. That's all it was.
Your kid's still just as messed
up as when we admitted him.
That was sensitive.
You have pretty hair.
Hope is all those parents
have going for them.
No, hope is what's
making them miserable.
What they should do
is get a cocker spaniel.
A dog would look
them in the eye,
wag his tail when he's happy,
lick their face, show them love.
Is it so wrong for them to
want to have a normal child?
It's normal to
want to be normal.
Spoken like a true Circle Queen.
See, skinny,
socially-privileged white people
get to draw this
neat little circle.
Everyone inside
the circle is normal.
Everyone outside the
circle should be beaten,
broken and reset, so they
can be brought into the circle.
Failing that, they should be
institutionalized, or worse, pitied.
So, it's wrong to feel
sorry for this little boy?
Why would you feel
sorry for someone
who gets to opt out of the
inane courteous formalities,
which are utterly meaningless,
insincere, and therefore, degrading?
This kid doesn't have to pretend
to be interested in your back pain,
or your excretions, or
your grandma's itchy place.
Can you imagine how
liberating it would be
to live a life free of all the
mind-numbing social niceties?
I don't pity this
kid. I envy him.
No cancer because
these aren't lymph cells.
Then what are they?
Liver cells.
Wow, liver cells under his arm.
Wonder what he's got where
his liver's supposed to be?
Anyone got a clue how liver
cells got into the kid's armpit?
Make yourself at home.
So, you think maybe Gray's
Anatomy got it all wrong?
Lymph system circulates
fluid, not organ cells.
Cancer cells break into the
lymphatic system all the time.
But we're not talking
about cancer cells.
So what's the difference between
cancer cells and liver cells?
Why can one pass through
walls, but the other can't?
Cancer cells are damaged, it
lets them grow into blood vessels,
go wherever they want.
So if the liver cells
are damaged...
The liver isn't damaged.
The tests were normal.
So if the liver
cells are damaged,
it's theoretically possible they
passed into the lymphatic system.
Liver failure could also explain
pleural effusion, even the heart issues.
The liver cells are fine.
He was immunized for Hep A and
B, and do you really think this kid
is having unprotected
sex, or sharing needles?
Daddy does seem the
type to use a rubber.
So it's not viral. That just
leaves a lot of booze-irrhosis.
Our 10-year-old boy does not
have a drinking problem, or cirrhosis.
House, when we echoed his heart,
we got a piece of his
liver. There was no scarring.
Cirrhosis explains the
symptoms, heart problems, lungs...
Look up cirrhosis in the
dictionary, it means scarring.
Parents aren't doing
or dosing this kid.
How would you know that?
The kid can't talk. Why do
you think I took this case?
He's not going to
give away the ending.
They quit their jobs for him.
Yes, they are everything
you'd want in a parent.
Unfortunately, their kid
is nothing you'd want.
When a baby is
born, it's perfect.
Little fingers, little toes,
plump, perfect, pink,
and brimming with
unbridled potential.
Then it's downhill. Some
hills steeper than others.
Parents get off on their
kids' accomplishments.
Bend over and relax.
Cute.
They'll annoy you with
trophy rooms and report cards.
Hell, they'll even
show you a purple cow
and tell what a keen
eye for color their kid has.
But this kid, he doesn't smile,
he doesn't hug them,
he doesn't laugh.
His parents get nothing
but the right to brag that their kid
picked orange juice out of a lineup.
So you figure they slip the kid a
mickey so they don't have to deal.
Do a biopsy to
confirm cirrhosis.
Don't try to pawn it off on Wilson,
he's going to be busy with Cuddy.
My parents love me
unconditionally. Get out of here.
Don't you think the
restraining order's a little much?
He's not actually going to have
sex with a 17-year-old patient.
I didn't think he
was going to ask me
to dig a bloodstained carpet
out of a dumpster, either.
It might be easier
in the long run.
Are we stopping here,
so House doesn't find us?
Unless you want to make out.
You want me to
surrender to House's coup?
No, no. You pro-actively
give him what he wants.
I defeat him by
surrendering to him.
He'll never see it coming.
Look, I'll pay for it myself.
What is it, a thousand
bucks to carpet a room?
Actually, it's 400.
Not doing it.
Liver biopsy?
They're doing it now.
How's it going?
Like a biopsy.
Needles, cells, screaming.
What did you find
in the stool sample?
You were too busy
bothering Cuddy.
But as discussed, it was
negative for parasites.
Can we get out of here?
I didn't ask what
you didn't find,
I asked what you did
find in the stool sample.
Stool
and traces of iron, zinc,
calcium carbonate. Can we leave?
What's the matter?
You afraid of the man?
Yeah.
Too late.
Leave my stuff alone.
You have a meeting with a Guggenheim
in 15 minutes. You're wearing that?
I'm going to count to three and
then I'm going to fire you. One.
Calcium carbonate? That's
an anti-diarrheal, right?
Two. Think that's significant?
Think hard poops is significant?
Two and a half.
Never threaten unless
you're ready to deliver.
Makes you look weak.
Thank God you
don't have children.
Doctor Cuddy.
Take a message.
Your patient is being
rushed to cardiac ICU.
Wow. That's like the one thing
that would get me out of here.
I'm sorry, you
can't come in here.
What's going on?
One, two, three.
He's in V fib.
Charged.
Clear.
Charging, clear.
He's stable for the moment.
First-degree atrial ventricular block.
Okay, what else do we know?
His liver's damaged. Pleural
effusion compromised his lung function.
Biopsy was
negative for cirrhosis.
Parents didn't poison their son.
It's not his liver, his
heart, or his lungs.
It's the calcium
carbonate in his stool.
Kid was constipated.
Parents probably just overdid it.
Or they didn't do it at all.
Calcium carbonate
is also what's in chalk.
So he ate some chalk.
It isn't toxic, it sure didn't
cause the pleural effusion.
Forget the chalk.
You just said it
was about the chalk.
Yes, and then I said,
"Forget the chalk."
You must be very
confused. The kid's got pica.
You take him to a buffet,
he's going to eat the table.
Or lead paint.
Level of lead in the blood was
normal. His tox screen was clean.
We're not looking
for typical poisons.
We're looking for anything
that he could put in his mouth.
Matches, spiders, bricks.
Pressure-treated wood
used to contain arsenic.
Even better.
Hansel, get samples of the
Gingerbread House. Bag everything.
Hey.
You could get into a
lot of trouble being here.
I wanted to see you.
Yeah, I got that.
So did everyone else.
They think you're a stalker.
One could argue those people
might be jealous of your attention.
Yes, I actually
made that argument.
You going home? That's the plan.
In Iceland, the age
of consent is 14.
I'm surprised that tourism
isn't a bigger industry up there.
Today I'm jailbait,
but in 22 weeks,
anybody can do anything to me.
Will I be so different
in 22 weeks?
Twenty-two weeks is enough for
an embryo to grow arms and legs.
It's just a line.
An arbitrary line drawn by a
bunch of sad, old men in robes.
Yeah, who cares
what judges think?
I didn't think of you as a guy who followed
rules just because they were rules.
You are over ten
years younger than me.
I said, "Over."
Gotta go! House.
Doctor Cuddy.
Do you happen to know the
way to the Icelandic consulate?
This young woman, a stranger
to me, was just asking directions.
Security was going to call the
police. I don't want to do that to you.
Go home. She needed a ride.
She got here on her own,
she can get home on her own.
Now.
If I see you on hospital grounds
again, I will call the police.
After that look, I'm feeling a
little frisky. Looks like you're up.
I'm ovulating. Let's go.
The frisky, it went away.
House, this isn't a game.
If I leave her alone, can
I have my carpet back?
No.
If I forget about my
carpet can I have her?
Jimsonweed. I found a small
patch of it in his backyard.
Jimsonweed contains
atropine, poor man's acid.
Our kid's been tripping on "Lucy
in the Sky with cubic zirconium."
Explains the pleural
effusion, the heart arrhythmias.
Meeting here will do
nothing to upset Cuddy.
I'm not trying to upset Cuddy.
I'm trying to figure out what's
wrong with the patient. Continue.
I'm done.
Jimsonweed doesn't
explain the screaming.
You've obviously
never had a bad trip.
I would've thought you'd try to
accomplish two goals at once.
Why can't you be more like
the other age-inappropriate girls
who have a thing for me?
Just accept me for me.
Continue.
Treatment for jimsonweed
OD is physostigmine.
Kid's got heart issues.
The two don't mix.
We'd better make sure
that's what he's got.
Serum from the lab in
Patterson is three days minimum.
He won't survive three days.
What time does he wake up?
7:35 a.m.
Then what? Walk me through it.
7:40 to 7:50 he goes to
the toilet, washes his face.
What does this matter?
I'm trying to prove
he ate the plant.
His schedule has nothing
to do with jimsonweed.
There are two possibilities.
Either the parents saw him eat the
plant or the kid has unsupervised time,
and eats plants instead
of playing with blocks.
Even if you find 15
minutes of free time outside,
it doesn't mean he
spent it eating a bush.
So, what do we do? Nothing?
Wait for the kid to tell us? What?
Where are you going?
To talk to him.
Ever see your son eat a bush?
I haven't.
I've only ever seen him eat...
Adam, you ate
something at your house.
Something that made you sick. I
need you to show me what you ate.
He can't answer you.
Neither can you.
This is your backyard.
You may know it as Mel's
Diner. This is your sandbox.
Your jungle gym.
And under it is this.
I need to know if
you ate this, Adam.
He doesn't know what you want.
Adam, you have to tell
me because if you don't,
game over. You'll be dead.
What the hell are you doing?
Show me what you ate.
Adam, show me what you ate.
Adam? Honey?
Adam!
Come on in, brothers and sister,
welcome to the
house of the Lord!
House, come on. The Chapel?
We have been blessed with
the miracle of a new symptom.
Brother, can you testify
as to why this poor child's
eyeball rolled back into his head?
It's consistent with jimsonweed
poisoning, ocular paralysis. I'm sorry.
The wicked shall deceive ye
because they have turned
from the Lord and are idiots.
His ocular muscle didn't
paralyze, it pirouetted.
MS? It is easier for a wise man
to gain access to heaven...
Will you stop doing that?
Just say, "Not MS."
A stroke, bleed in the brain.
We'd be seeing other symptoms besides
a single eye misalignment. Like a coma.
And you've already testified.
It's a tumor.
And all the imaging
just missed it?
It's a micro-tumor.
It started in his lung, which
caused the pleural effusion.
Then it metastasized to his
liver, which made it slough cells.
And then it went to his
brain behind the eye,
which caused it to
roll back into his head.
So, he had three tumors
and we missed all of them?
What's the opposite
of a miracle?
I have a better chance of finding it,
now that I know exactly where to look.
So, unless you
have a better idea,
I'm going to go CT his head and
then, if I have to, remove his eye.
You remove this kid's eye,
he's only going to be half as
good at not making eye contact.
Hello?
I have sad news for
you. She doesn't love you.
You're ugly when you're jealous.
She showed up at my house
last night. Came on to me.
She's even more
perfect than I thought.
House, she's sick.
You say, "Sick," I
say, "Freestylin'."
The girl will have sex
with an invertebrate.
Come on, you're not that bad.
She has a problem.
You're not doing her any
favors by indulging her.
How could you lie like this?
Do you not have room
in your heart for love?
You don't believe me.
I didn't believe the kids when they
said that Susie was sleeping with Johnny.
I didn't believe them then.
I don't believe them now.
I don't care that Susie
married Johnny. She's mine.
She has a mole on her right
breast, just below the nipple.
No, she doesn't.
You've seen her breasts?
It was a medical exam. I
was listening to her heart.
It went, "Greg-House.
Greg-House. Greg-House."
Fine. I'm lying.
But she did come back.
She's locked up in my office.
I was hoping you could
talk to her, put an end to this.
Listen to me.
Do you have any
idea what you'd have
to look forward to if
you stayed with me?
Nine chances out of ten,
we'd both wind up in a jail.
You're only saying
that to make me go.
I'm saying it 'cause it's true.
Inside of us, we both know
that you belong with Victor.
Is there a Victor in your class?
If you're not with someone
your age, you'll regret it.
Maybe not today, maybe not tomorrow,
but soon, and for the rest of your life.
What about us?
We'll always have Fresno.
I'm no good at being noble,
but it doesn't take much to see
that the problems
of two little people
don't amount to a hill of
beans in this crazy world.
Someday you'll understand that.
Now, now, here's looking at you.
Damn.
Was there an earthquake
when you were in Fresno?
What?
I ask all my girlfriends that.
Yeah, a little one.
Damn.
What? What?
What is it? It's not love.
You have spore in your brain.
Coccidioides immitis.
California's full of them.
They get an earthquake,
they get released into the air,
you breath it in,
you get a cold.
Turns into sinus congestion, aches,
weakness, milky tears, and sometimes
loss of inhibition and judgment.
Damn!
So, loving you,
wanting to have sex with you
was all just the spores talking?
You'll probably live.
Damn!
Hey! Don't touch his eye!
This is an appendectomy.
Like I said, don't
touch his eye.
Why isn't he in surgery?
Some emergency bumped him.
We've got another
room in ten minutes.
You're not taking him in.
Kill the lights.
He was seeing them all the time.
What are you looking for?
He was telling us
what he was seeing.
Telling us exactly what was wrong with him.
Drawing them for us over and over again.
But nobody knew
how to speak autistic.
When I asked him what
he ate, he even told me that.
What are you talking
about? What was he seeing?
Hello, my pretties. It's
not a tumor, Foreman.
It's worms swimming in his eye.
Animal makes potty in the
sandbox, boy plays in the sandbox.
Boy eats the sand.
You can probably tell
where this is going by now.
Stool samples were
negative for parasites.
Raccoon roundworms are not
excreted by their human host.
Cameron tested the sand.
All of it?
Worms spread from his
gut to the rest of his body.
They attacked his lungs, that's what
made him scream and caused the effusion.
They invade his liver, sending dead
liver cells coursing through his system.
They attacked his eye and
the muscles surrounding it,
making his eyeball
do a back flip.
Laser photocoagulation
to fix the eye,
and a high dose of
benzimidazole to kill the worms.
Wait a minute, that's it?
He's going to be okay?
Good news.
He's going to be with
you for a long, long time.
I'm going to read you something.
"Asperger Syndrome is a
mild and rare form of autism.
"It is typically characterized by
difficulty establishing friendships,
"and playing with peers, trouble
accepting conventional social rules,
"and they dislike any
change in setting or routine."
Or broadloom.
It doesn't say that last
part, but you get my point.
House doesn't have Asperger's. The
diagnosis is much simpler, he's a jerk.
Why do you think
he took this case?
Because he believes
these parents?
Because he wants
to help a young boy?
He sees himself in this kid,
and he's trying to help himself.
He doesn't want
this, he needs it.
You're not autistic. You
don't even have Asperger's.
You wish you did.
That would exempt you from
the rules, give you freedom,
absolve you of responsibility,
let you date 17-year-olds.
But most important, it would
mean that you're not just a jerk.
At what point does a person endlessly
lecturing someone make him a jerk?
First tongue kiss is an
eight on the happiness scale.
Child being snatched back from
the brink of death, that's a ten.
They're clocking in at a
very tepid six point five,
because they know what
they have to go back to.
Listen,
thanks.
You saved his life.
Yeah, I know. See ya.
That was so good.
That was a ten.
All change is bad?
It's not true, you know.