We ask a lot of our patients.
We put them to
sleep, cut them open,
poke around in their brains
and guts with sharp instruments.
- We ask for their blind trust.
- The blue one.
When in doubt, always go
with blue. It brings out your eyes.
Thanks.
The hospital, the
staff, they love Richard.
To them, I stabbed him in the back
to get the job. They'll be mad at me.
- Just like you are.
- I am mad.
That doesn't mean I don't
think you'll do a great job.
I think you'll be
a very good chief.
Irony is, trust is hard for surgeons
because we're trained, from day one,
that we can't trust
anyone but ourselves.
The only instincts you
can count on are your own.
Either of you know what
this big meeting's about?
- I heard there was a coup.
- Webber's out,
Shepherd's in. True?
- We know what you know.
- Bull.
Your sister's married to the guy.
Expect me to believe you don't know?
Don't you have your own
loser friends to talk to?
Also heard Shepherd plans to clean
house. Maybe he'll start with you.
I'm safe. The guy's my roommate. You're
the ones who should watch your backs.
- Why? What do you know?
- Simple math.
Shepherd hates the merger.
You're from Mercy West. You're toast.
Derek's not gonna fire people just
because they're from Mercy West.
He's not like that.
He's loyal and fair.
Tell that to Webber.
The only skills you can
count on are your own.
Until, one day, you'll leave the
classroom and step into the OR.
I think we've almost
got the tumor out.
At this rate, we'll be
finished early, Grey.
You might be able to catch the
end of Shepherd's big speech.
She's tachycardic!
You're surrounded by
others. A team of others.
I don't understand what happened.
Everything appears to be in order.
There's no bleeders. I
don't see any bleeders.
OK, I don't see a
reason why down here.
So why is her heart rate
going through the roof?!
- Check her anastomoses.
- It's intact! Everything is intact!
What? Is...? Wait, wait,
wait. Did I just feel movement?
She's awake. Dr. Bailey,
the patient's awake.
A team you have to rely on...
whether you trust them or not.
What the hell did you do?
What the hell did you do?!
Get her back to sleep right now!
OK, I know you're scared
right now, but it's gonna be OK.
Everything is going to
be OK. Just try to breathe.
Pushing 150 propofol.
- Hey.
- Think he's gonna
give a big speech?
- I don't know.
- So... about the other night...
- I don't wanna talk about it.
- What the hell is he wearing?
- He looks good. Chiefly.
He looks like an undertaker.
- I promised him we'd clap.
- Oh, now?
I wanna thank you all for
being here. I know you're busy,
so I'll try to make this quick.
As you may have heard,
I have been appointed the
new interim chief of surgery.
It's my personal goal to make this
transition as smooth as possible.
- I know we've had
a rocky few months.
- Here it comes.
- Mistakes have been made.
- He's talking about the merger.
- Shh!
- - I intend to right those wrongs and...
- Told ya.
- Bring this hospital back to its former glory.
Former glory? Undertaker
needs a speech writer.
- We are screwed.
- Yes, you are, sucker.
- Check it out. Chief Webber.
- And, um...
What I meant... Uh...
by that is... What I'm trying
to say is I wanna thank you
for your support, in advance.
That's all. OK, let's get back to work.
Avery? I need you to round up my
charts and bring them to room 2214.
Yang usually comes
in early to do that.
Yang's not on my
service today. You are.
Karev, I hear that
you're the future of Peds.
- Excuse me?
- Birdie named Bailey
whispered in my ear. I want
you to work with me today
- so I can see if she's right.
- What'd she say?
You're the best
babysitter in the hospital.
Shut up.
You don't think Peds is hardcore?
You can say that to my face, Avery.
- No. No, ma'am.
- Mm-hm.
Don't let the roller skates fool you.
Peds is nothing but hardcore. Rounds.
In ten.
Peds. Who's the sucker now?
I heard that...
Sloan was released
from the hospital in LA.
That's good. Is she, uh...
Is she coming back soon?
Mark? This is some kind of joke?
You're not even gonna look at me?
Torres, I have a hip decubitus
ulcer I need you to check out.
Mature. Really mature, Mark!
Basically, you have two
options available to you.
Sign these, you're agreeing
to an early retirement.
You'll take an early pension.
Your license to practice
medicine will no longer be valid.
You'd walk away from this
hospital, effective immediately.
- No strings attached.
- You're not gonna sign that.
You're gonna sign this.
Which says that you are
voluntarily enrolling yourself
into the Physicians
Rehabilitation Treatment Program.
Go to rehab, Richard.
You'll sober up.
You get out, you
have your job waiting.
Pending board approval.
I need some time to think.
What is there to think about?
You aren't considering
quitting, are you?
Sorry to interrupt,
but chief...?
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
I'm sorry. Dr. Shepherd. There's a
situation that needs your attention.
Excuse me.
The patient was
open on the table...
She had appropriate anesthetic.
- There is no way
we should be liable.
- Stop. Stop!
- Just take a deep breath. You check on the patient.
- OK.
This can happen.
It's happened to me.
Any luck at all, she
won't remember a thing.
- She won't remember to sue us?
- Exactly.
OK. How was that?
That was good, right?
- Very chiefly. Lose the tie.
- Good. What? The tie.
Mr. and Mrs. Wilson? We're
here to update you on the surgery.
We completed your tumor resection.
I was able to resect the entire thing
- off of your abdominal wall.
- Which is a good thing.
- Things went very well.
- Really?
How about the part when
I woke up on the table?
How well did that part go?
Where I could smell my own
burning flesh, how was that?
When I was lying
there unable to speak
while I could actually feel
you butchering my insides!
I couldn't move! I was awake and
couldn't move and you had no idea!
How well did that part go?
Here's what we do. I'm gonna
check the anesthetics themselves.
You draw a CBC, a chem 18 and
let's do some genotyping studies.
Oh. Here's what we do?
We? Did you not hear her?
The girl is traumatized. The only
thing we are doing is getting sued!
- Because of you.
- Where do you even get off
speaking to me like that? You have
no idea what went wrong in that OR.
Here's what I know. I
know that you're new here.
I know you probably still
have a chip on your shoulder
'cause your parking space
at Mercy West was better.
And I know you're an anesthesiologist,
which means you make buckets of money
logging reasonable
hours, sitting on your behind
and flipping through Architectural
Digest while somebody on the other side
of the curtain does the real
work, and gets sued for it.
- Excuse me...
- I don't what
they did at Mercy West,
but here at Seattle
Grace, we expect to be able
to trust the gasman, trust him
to do his job so we can do ours.
We expect the gasman
to stay awake at the switch,
no matter how long and
boring a procedure might be.
We expect the gasman to stay focused
enough to keep the patient unconscious!
How long would you say
Brad's been having the pain?
- Off and on for months.
- - Brad, is the pain constant,
or is it worse at
times, better at others?
It's usually bad in the mornings,
like right after breakfast.
Which, I might point out, is
when he has to go to school.
But I feel it at
other times, too.
Right, like when you
have a Spanish test
or have to give a
presentation in history class.
- Stress can exacerbate
abdominal pain.
- Please, don't encourage him.
- He's faking
so he can miss school.
- I am not!
Abdomen's soft, non-tender,
not rigid. Bowel sounds are good.
Still, I'd like to cover all the bases.
Dr. Karev, how would you proceed?
- We could try
a triple contrast CT.
- Let's do it.
Brad, this is gonna cost
us thousands of dollars
and insurance only covers
part of it. You know that, right?
I'm not faking it! I'm not
faking it, Dad! I swear!
Dr. Altman? I noticed
you have Avery assigned
- to all your
surgeries this morning.
- I do.
Um... So there's no room
for me on your service?
You've been on every one
of my cases since I've arrived.
This is a teaching hospital. It's only
fair I give other residents a chance.
Yes, yes, of course.
I understand. Um...
Do you think you'll have room on
your service tomorrow, or the next day?
I... I... I don't
know. I just...
I can't today,
Cristina, OK? I just...
I can't.
Um, Leslie? Hi.
This will only take a moment.
We just need to examine your...
- Hey, careful!
- I don't want you to touch me.
- Leslie.
- I mean it.
Don't let her touch me.
OK, uh, I know that you've
been through a lot today,
- but if we don't check...
- I remember.
I remember you
screaming in surgery.
- You were panicking.
- - She's getting tachycardic.
Panicking.
With your hand inside
my body. You just...
Dr. Bailey, her
incision site is bleeding.
- She ripped it open.
- I mean it! Don't touch me!
- OK!
- I don't want you to touch me!
- Grey, redress the wound.
- Don't touch me!
Use the dressing to apply
pressure with one hand.
Grab as much gauze
as you can with the other.
OK. See that tape? You're
gonna need a nice, long piece.
Uh-huh.
- Hey. Need some help?
- No. I'm good. Thanks.
- OK, never mind.
- I need to talk
to you about Mark.
- Could you not rip those?
- He isn't speaking to me.
He barely even looks at me.
And I know that we broke up,
but we still work together and
I'm gonna be a plastic surgeon.
- You're not gonna
be a plastic surgeon.
- Still.
OK. We're gonna have to
see each other every day.
He's best friends with my
sister's Post-it husband.
- I don't know what to do.
- I know. He's not
exactly being fair.
- No, he's not being fair!
- Seriously,
go easy on the cast padding.
At least, he could be civil. I had
a one-night stand, OK? Big deal.
Right.
- Not like he didn't
sleep with Addison.
- True. More than once.
- What?
- Hm?
Nothing. I didn't say anything.
More than once? More than once?!
Ha!
What about that?
That spot? See it?
Oh...
- That was lint.
- Doesn't make sense.
No kid wants to be the loser
missing class to go to the hospital,
- I don't care how lame you are.
- I loved the hospital
when I was a kid.
No school, lots of cool
medical supplies to play with.
OK, yeah. So let's
go over it again.
He presented with severe
but intermittent abdominal pain.
- No discernable pattern.
- Labs were normal. No fever.
- Soft abdomen on exam.
- We're missing something.
- Chronic mesenteric ischemia.
- Ah! It's a stretch for a kid,
- but if he had
vascular problems...
- It fits the symptoms.
- It doesn't show up
on the scans.
- But the problem is,
the only way to get
an accurate diagnosis
- is try an
exploratory laparoscopy.
- So?
Brad's father didn't
want us to run a CT.
You really think he's gonna
agree to exploratory surgery?
Hey.
Teddy is blackballing me. She's
not saying that's what she's doing,
but I think that's...
I don't want to talk about Teddy.
Do you want to talk about Teddy?
No.
I heard he had some
kind of mental breakdown.
- I heard it was drugs.
- No way. Prescription or...?
Go practice medicine. Now.
Richard. This, sitting
here, this isn't good.
This isn't helping things. Just
sign the paper, go to rehab.
- Sign the paper.
- Who the hell do
you think you are?
Who do you...?
You are not my boss.
And you are not my chief. You may
have stolen my office out from under me...
You're in trouble and
I'm trying to help you.
I helped you! I
didn't get you fired!
You got fired the minute
you took your first drink!
- Get out of my face!
- No. You're not gonna do this.
You're not ending your
career to get back at me.
I did what I had to
do, and nothing more.
You look me in the eye,
and you say that again.
I wanted the job.
I wanted the job, I admit that. I
didn't want to end your career.
Well, that part's not up to you,
is it? You did what you had to do.
But this part is up to me.
- So get out.
- No!
Stop it! Both of you!
People are watching.
Get back to work.
- The gasman
would like an apology.
- What?
Leslie Wilson's
cytochrome P450 results.
The type she has means she
metabolizes anesthetic drugs too fast,
way more rapidly than you or me. No way
we could have known that before surgery.
- So this is why she woke up?
- It is.
You don't have to get down
on your knees and apologize.
But I would like something heartfelt.
Something in the neighborhood of,
"You were right and I was
rash and kind of mean."
Maybe throw in a, "Turns
out you're a hell of a doctor."
It wasn't our fault.
That's... That's good news.
She's gonna need a second surgery.
Her incision site won't stop bleeding.
- She might
have internal bleeding.
- OK.
It's not gonna be easy, but now
I know how to keep her under.
She won't let me touch her.
Oh.
I'm good with patients.
They always trust
me. I... I... I've never...
I don't even know how to...
She won't let me touch her.
- Why are you walking like that?
- I got a burn.
- Where?
- Go away.
We're both doctors. No
need to be embarrassed.
I'm not embarrassed! I'm just
waiting for Meredith. Now, go away.
- I let you treat my tick. Come on.
- This is not a tick.
Today sucks. Mark sucks.
Yang got burns
on her girl parts.
I do not... It's not
on my girl parts.
They're on her ass.
Look how she's walking.
- Don't you two have patients?
- How did you get
burns on your ass?
- You paged?
- Mer, come.
The rest of you, bye.
- Oh, my God!
- Not so loud.
How did you...? What did...?
You have grate marks
burned into your ass.
Vent marks. But same difference.
I was busy having sex. Will
you please just dress the wound?
Owen's being very caveman-like.
It's hot, vaguely
disturbing, but mostly hot.
I think he might still be a little
upset I offered him to Teddy.
- Alex!
- Hot cross buns.
- Oh! That's gonna blister.
Will you get them out of here?
Bailey's paging me. Lexie,
will you finish this for me?
- Oh, my God. I hate you.
- I'm
taking Alex with me.
- What?
- Let's go. Come on.
- Ugh.
- Is this a sex injury?
- Oh, my God.
- It is.
I used to have sex
injuries with Mark.
Mark was really awesome at
leaving you with good sex injuries.
- Please don't cry on my ass.
- I'm sorry.
Please don't cry.
- Hey. Are you...?
- Busy.
Dr. Altman, I pulled
everything you asked for.
It's here in numerical order
according to room number.
Numerical order?
- Is that not how...?
- It's fine.
Yang always orders them according
to priority, most urgent to least urgent,
but... it's fine. It'll
work. Follow me.
No. Just no.
You are not cutting open our son
with no evidence that there's anything...
- Dad.
- No! Listen to me.
That is thousands of dollars we're
talking about on what, a hunch? Huh?
He's got a nervous stomach
and crappy grades, that's it.
I hated school, too,
Brad. OK? I got it.
Your mother and I, we
have jobs and we go to them.
You have school, that's your
job. No surgery. It's insane.
Just no. No!
You think it's right for
them to take him home?
- It isn't.
- Shh. Brad, I'm teaching.
- You think he's faking?
- No.
- What are you gonna do?
- I'd like
to push his dad's face
- into a wall. No offense.
- Yeah, no, that'd be good.
Barring physical violence, what
are you gonna do? This is Peds.
Your patients can't
advocate for themselves.
So in addition to surgery, a big
part of the job is advocating for them.
You think you can do that?
Yes, this is
exploratory surgery,
and yes, Brad's scans
look clean, but if we're right,
if he has mesenteric ischemia
and you take him home?
The blood flow to his
intestine will slowly stop,
killing the tissue, causing
Brad to become septic,
forcing his body into such intense
shock that by the time you realize
what's happening and
you call an ambulance,
the chance of Brad getting back
to the hospital alive is next to zero.
You think he's
faking? I get that.
So the only real question
is, how sure are you?
How sure?
I understand your hesitation.
But we don't have a choice.
You need a second surgery.
Haven't you put her
through enough for one day?
I can make some calls, see if we can
get you transferred to another hospital.
A transfer takes time,
and the longer we wait, she's at
greater risk for infection or blood loss.
I know you're scared. But the
dressing I did earlier is only temporary.
- It needs to be fixed properly.
- It was like being in a coffin.
Alive in a coffin.
I couldn't talk,
I couldn't move.
The thought of your
hand back inside me...
Sweetie. You don't have to do
anything you don't want to do.
- You can do it.
- What?
You were there.
You stayed calm.
You were kind.
Oh. Dr. Bailey is far
more experienced.
She's not touching me.
You have to promise
me she won't touch me.
You can do it.
She can't.
- Hey!
- Hey.
What do you think of the present I
got from Hunt for becoming chief?
From Hunt, huh? I was
gonna get you one of those.
The deluxe version, the kind
that keeps score. Not, you know,
- the cheaper one.
- That's my chair.
I know. I like it. It
makes me feel powerful.
That was quite a scene in
the conference room earlier.
- You saw that.
- The whole hospital did.
What happened there? How'd
you dethrone the chief? And why?
- I can't talk about it.
- Not even to me?
- It's not my story to tell.
- Heads up.
Looks like I'm facing
a lawsuit. First day out.
- Patient wakes up on the table.
- You know Lexie slept
with Alex Karev
while I was in LA dealing
with my sick daughter?
According to Meredith, you
were doing more in Los Angeles
- than dealing
with Little Sloan.
- She dumped me.
Which is why you went back
to sleeping with my ex-wife?
- You slept with his ex-wife?
- Wait a second. You're remarried.
- What do you care?
- The Karev thing is forgivable,
- considering.
- Not to me.
- What?
- Is that a hickey?
- Uh, it's a... It's a birth mark.
- It is, it's a hickey.
Cristina and I have been...
- getting along.
- You two are good together.
Not like me and Lexie. Way
better than Yang and Burke.
Yeah, I never understood those
two. They were too monosyllabic.
You know, I made a bet she'd never
make it down that aisle. Won 50 bucks.
- What aisle?
- You haven't heard that story?
- That's a good story.
- It's not your story to tell.
Bailey's letting me operate on a
post-op internal bleeding patient.
By myself. Do you
think I can handle it?
I think I can.
Derek tells me you're
thinking about quitting.
I think if my mother
were here to see this,
she would kick your ass
for even considering it.
These loops of
bowel look clean, too.
- Nothing.
Crap. I bullied them into totally
unnecessary surgery for their kid.
It wasn't unnecessary.
By not finding anything,
we're one step closer to finding
out what isn't wrong with Brad.
Which means we're one step
closer to finding out what is.
At least, that's what you're
gonna tell his angry parents.
- Me?
- You bullied them into surgery.
You take the heat.
More suction, please.
- BP took a dip.
- Damn it. He's getting unstable.
Bolus him with a liter
and let's get him closed.
We may not have found the problem,
but there's absolutely something wrong.
You know, there isn't anything
that says you can't operate.
Once she's under,
she would never know.
I'm not operating on a patient who
doesn't want me to operate on her.
If she wants a resident
doing her surgery,
she gets a resident
doing her surgery.
I wouldn't let you operate unless
I thought you could handle it.
- I could perforate her bowel.
- You won't!
I'll be with you the whole time.
Dr. Webber was mentoring you.
There's no reason why I can't do the same.
The chief wasn't exactly
mentoring me because of my talent.
Richard Webber is not a man
who wastes his time on just anybody.
Last time he mentored a surgeon, it
was me. You think I don't have talent?
Well, hurry up and finish scrubbing
in. You got a patient waiting.
Do you really think
Shepherd's gonna cut all of us?
- What?
- The Mercy Westers.
Do you think we're all
gone? Just tell me if you think
I need to start
looking for a job.
Is there a reason
our son is in ICU?
Figure out what's wrong?
- Not exactly.
- Why does he have
a tube in his chest?
You said you were
doing abdominal surgery.
Brad became briefly
unstable in surgery.
So we had to put in a central line
which got a little kinked, so his lung...
- Alex!
- Are you saying you cut
into our son for nothing
and caused more damage?
- Blood. Blood.
- What?
There is a lot of
blood in the chest tube.
Get a chest tray
and some gloves!
He's already put
out 700cc's of blood!
- What's going on?
- You need to leave right now!
- Like hell we're leaving!
- Somebody tell us
what's going on!
He's crashing! Page
Cardio and Robbins.
- We can't wait
for Cardio. Crap!
- What the hell is going on?
I need to open him up. Scalpel!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
Get away from our son!
Please get away from our son!
He's bradying down!
More suction, please!
There! I think I got it.
- Let me in. What happened?
- He put out
two liters of blood
in the last five minutes.
I think I found the source
because the bleeding
started to calm down.
Jump on. We're moving to the OR.
- Page Cristina Yang.
- Right away, Doctor.
Wait. Wait, hang on. Hang on!
- It's Teddy. It's Teddy!
- So?
- You're not on her service.
- No, but...
Don't go. She has
another resident today.
Stay here with me.
Don't go.
Please.
All right.
- What's going on? How is he?
- He's critical.
He has a ruptured
aortic arch dissection.
Hardly ever catch them, but Karev
here may have worked a miracle.
Nice work, Karev.
Damn it.
Where is Yang? I need
a second set of hands.
- You want me to scrub in?
- Dr. Altman, I'm available.
- She's waiting for Yang.
- Yeah, I know.
Believe me, I know
I'm not Cristina Yang.
You've made that clear,
but if you give me a chance...
I have very good
hands. I can do this.
I can help.
Cannulate the femoral artery and vein,
then we're gonna cool him down fast.
We have 30 minutes to complete
this repair or this patient is toast.
The bowel looks fine.
Good. Just check the anastomosis
and keep going. Everything still good?
BP's stable, BIS level's
45. She's sound asleep.
Just like the last time you
asked. Two minutes ago.
Anastomosis looks
clean. Bowels intact.
- Good, get a new mesh.
- And so you know,
I don't read Architectural
Digest in the OR.
That magazine I read earlier?
That was the Journal
of Clinical Anesthesia.
- In case you were wondering.
- I wasn't.
Ready for the mesh.
Suture, please?
Get a good bite of fascia.
Actually, I don't like the
sitting down part of my job.
It's not great for the back,
and I like to keep in shape.
So I can lift my big
buckets of money.
I yell when I'm scared.
Some people
whimper or duck, I yell.
When she woke up, it was one
of the scariest moments of my life.
So I yelled. And then I yelled
some more. It's what I do.
- Was that an apology?
- Closest thing
you're gonna get.
Hey.
- Ooh! Nice skin graft.
- Thank you.
- So I was talking to Lexie.
- Why?
When? Why are
you talking to her?
- No, she came to me. And actually...
- Don't do this.
You're my friend, not
hers. Don't take her side.
I'm not picking sides. I'm just
saying she made some good points.
She dumped me and
jumped into bed with Karev!
She doesn't get to
make good points!
Don't you think you're being...?
What? Mad? Offended? Disgusted?
Hypocritical? Sexist? Immature?
She dumped me! Not
the other way around!
She dumped me for wanting to step up
and be responsible with my own daughter.
You know how big
a step that is for me,
and you know how much I
wanted to take that step with Lexie.
I'm not the one who's immature!
And you made me
wreck my skin graft!
Leslie's out of surgery.
- How'd the repair go?
- Just fine. No complications.
- Meredith did an excellent job.
- Good. That's good.
Good news.
- How's the lawyer?
- Lawyer's still here.
- Drooling.
- Damn it.
Tough first day, chief?
- Tough first day.
- You know,
nine times out of ten,
you can make a lawsuit
go away if you apologize.
People like to feel heard.
They like to feel respected.
And they like to hear an apology.
That's what Chief Webber would do.
He'd walk right into that woman's
room the minute she got out of recovery
and he'd apologize.
- Dr. Altman.
- When I page you,
- I expect an answer.
- I know. I'm sorry. I was just...
I had a ruptured aortic
arch dissection, and...
- An aortic arch dissection?
- I thought, at the very least,
I could rely on you
to act professionally.
Everything OK?
Dr. Altman, I'm
sorry. You're right.
It won't happen again. I
should've responded to your page.
No, wait. I... This
wasn't Cristina's fault.
I detained her
for a trauma thing.
Oh, really? Now you have
something to say to me?
You know what?
Forget it.
- What?
- What are you
trying to do to me?
I'm... Cristina... I'm...
Come on!
- His heart ruptured?
- This is unbelievable.
- How could you not find this?
- His heart symptoms presented
as abdominal pain, which is
an extremely rare presentation.
It's almost impossible
to diagnose.
But the most important
thing is that Brad is doing fine.
Fine?
You call him being hooked up
to tubes and... You call that fine?
Dude, seriously, we're the
only reason your kid's alive.
- Karev...
- If you'd had it your way,
you'd have been home
when Brad's aorta ruptured
and he'd be dead right now.
- Think about how much school
he'd be missing then, huh?
- Karev! We're done.
Excuse me. Follow me right now.
Go away, please, Bailey.
I don't want you
to see me like this.
Uh, all due respect, chief, everybody's
been seeing you like this all day.
And I don't know details. I don't
know what's going on with you.
But you can't sit here
anymore. Not like this.
I can't give them this.
Shepherd. Jennings.
If I do what they want me to do,
it's like saying that they were right.
Right about doing this.
- Right about me.
- Saying they're
right about what?
They want me to
say I'm an alcoholic.
Well, are you an alcoholic?
Yes.
But if I sign these papers,
I have to stop drinking.
And go to rehab.
And I don't think
I'm ready to do that.
Drinking, it feels a little
bit like all I have left.
You are better than this.
I've seen you be better.
Look, the way to win,
the way to beat them,
is to stop fighting
them. You go get better.
You be the man that I've
always known you to be.
You be the chief.
Be the chief.
If you want to work in Peds,
you can't get emotional.
- You said it was
part of the job.
- There is a difference
between advocating for tiny
humans and berating terrified parents!
You're good with kids, I can see that.
You've got great hands, great instincts.
We already knew that. You're
as good as anyone I've seen
when it comes to advocating for
patients. But until you've been a parent,
until you've stayed up
nights with a screaming infant
or dealt day in and day
out with a terrorist toddler
or raised a lying teenager,
you don't get to judge parents.
You have to
advocate for the kids.
You don't get to
berate terrified parents.
- You clear on that?
- Yes.
Good. Then you go
apologize to that family.
Karev?
You saved that kid's life today.
How'd it feel?
Feels great.
- Hardcore, right?
- Yeah.
Welcome to Peds.
I know it's been a long day and
you're all anxious to get home,
but I feel like we got off on
the wrong foot this morning.
I don't expect to win
your trust overnight.
But I want each of you
to know you have mine.
Which is why I felt it was important
to personally come in here and...
apologize.
Mrs. Wilson, do
you have a moment?
I want to clear some things up.
I'd like to offer each
of you your jobs back.
There are gonna be
cuts down the line.
But you both deserve
a fighting chance.
- Oh, my God.
- Thank you, Dr. Shepherd.
Thank you. Thank you.
I am neither pro
nor anti-merger.
From this point on,
everyone has a clean slate.
I'm not focused on the past.
I'm trying to understand you.
You've been trying to
screw me into submission.
- I was not.
- You've been trying to screw me
into submission. And I let you
because the sex was so good,
- and your ego was hurt.
- I'm trying.
I am trying to understand
you. I am trying to know you.
I am trying to... love you.
And I don't know how. I don't know
how, 'cause you don't give me anything.
The vent burn was you
branding me? Like I'm chattel?
I'm trying!
I don't know you. I don't know you
'cause you don't give me anything.
- I give you everything.
- Burke.
- What?
- Burke. Preston Burke.
You were engaged. There was almost
a wedding. Why didn't that happen?
No. No, I'm not...
We're not doing this.
See? You give me nothing!
Maybe... Maybe I was trying
to screw you into submission.
Maybe I was
trying to... connect.
I'll try anything, I'll try anything, but
you have to give me something back.
- Well, Burke is irrelevant.
- Like I'll be
in three years time?
- That's not fair.
- I'm trying to love you.
Why won't you let me?
Burke...
Burke was, uh...
He took something from me.
He took little pieces of me.
Little pieces, over time.
So small I didn't notice.
He wanted me to be
something I wasn't.
And I made myself
into what he wanted.
One day I was me, Cristina
Yang, and then, suddenly,
I was lying for him and
jeopardizing my career
and agreeing to be married and
wearing a ring and being a bride.
Until I was standing there in a
wedding dress with no eyebrows,
and I wasn't Cristina
Yang anymore.
And even then I would've
married him. I would have.
I lost myself for a long time.
And now...
that I am finally me again...
I can't...
I love you. I love you
more than I loved Burke.
I love you. And that
scares the crap out of me.
Because...
when you asked me
to ignore Teddy's page,
you took a piece of me.
And I let you.
And...
that will never...
happen again.
I'm looking to the future.
- You feel better?
- A little.
This really isn't
gonna work for me.
To all the promise this
hospital has to offer.
I plan to honor Richard
Webber and his legacy.
Not undo it.
Thank you, Richard.
I'm sorry.
Which is why I'm both
humbled and honored
to be your new chief of surgery.