.
- Merry Christmas.
- What happened,
that was just for fun.
- I'm sorry for the stress
that I caused you
for wanting you here.
- I understand why you did it.
You had a daughter
and you wanted to meet her.
Maggie Lockwood
is my biological mother.
- For every Vas-COM catheter
the hospital ordered,
Dr. Cooper
received a percentage.
- I mean isn't this
kinda like kickbacks?
It's illegal.
- We can go to the FBI now.
- The board does not feel
that is in the hospital's
best interests.
- Matthew Cooper,
Jessa Rinaldi,
you're under arrest.
- Any and all fallout
lands on me.
- Believe me, Sharon,
there will be fallout.
- There she is.
- Sharon Goodwin.
Dr. Matthew Cooper
is out on bail.
Vasik Lab
is denying any knowledge
of the alleged fraud schemes.
- That it was the work
of their rep, Jessa Rinaldi.
Government even have a case?
- Listen, I have no comment.
- There are reports
of impending civil actions
from families and patients
affected by the Vas-COM.
- You've been named
in any of these suits?
- I said no comment.
- Excuse me.
Excuse me for a second.
Excuse me.
- Thanks.
- Yes...
I use--used the Vas-COM
for cardiac monitoring
on some patients.
- Eleanor Holt, now deceased,
was one of those patients?
- Yes.
- The hospital uses
multiple cardiac monitoring
devices, correct?
- Yes.
- Still you opted
for the Vas-COM?
- It was promoted
as a better option
than the competing devices.
It was getting talked up
a lot by other doctors.
- Anyone in particular?
- I've only been at Med
a few months.
I know some faces
but not many names.
- Was one of those faces
Dr. Will Halstead?
Why don't we come back
to that question?
I've already gotten a statement
from Dr. Halstead.
- How's that 15 minutes
going for you?
- What? Of fame?
That was the last thing
I was thinking about
when I called the FBI.
And now
all that hoopla out there.
I'm worried
about the hospital, Daniel.
The feds are seizing files,
computers.
They're interviewing
board members and staff.
- Look, it's a little crazy
right now, okay?
But the dust
will settle, you know?
It always does.
- Sharon.
Just heard an interesting fact.
It turns out whistleblowers
are entitled to a reward.
Six, even seven figures.
How 'bout that?
- Always a pleasure, Roger.
- You got the chart?
You up to speed?
- Yeah. Lawrence Givens, 50,
end-stage renal disease.
No longer tolerating
hemodialysis.
Grafts keep clotting.
But he only has one kidney
to begin with.
- Yeah. He donated the other
to his father 25 years ago.
He also has kidney disease.
Turns out it's a genetic issue.
Autosomal dominant
polycystic kidney disease.
Lawrence has it too.
- Yet the doctor
still took his kidney.
They missed it.
Either a misdiagnosis
or the screening
didn't pick it up.
- Oh, man.
Chart says Lawrence has a son.
- Luke, he's 19.
He hasn't been tested
to see if he also
has polycystic kidneys.
- Okay, so if he doesn't
have the disease,
he could be a possible donor.
- I've thought about
testing him a few times
and always shied away.
- Why?
- It's complicated.
Hi, Luke. It's Dr. Blake.
- You remember Dr. Blake,
don't you?
She's helping
fix Daddy's kidney.
- I want to help too.
- I know you do. I know you do.
- It's good to see you again,
Luke.
This is Dr. Marcel.
- Hey, Luke.
Pleasure to meet you.
- Luke, honey,
let's let the doctor
speak with your dad.
Come on.
All right, there we go.
Okay?
- Look, I can hold out.
I know there's
a donor somewhere.
I mean, I've gotta be on top
of the transplant list.
- You are
but time is running out.
I think we should consider Luke
as a possible donor now.
At least test
for polycystic disease,
make sure he doesn't have it.
- I want to be with Daddy.
He needs my help.
- We're gonna help him.
-  I don't know.
- You need a new kidney,
Lawrence.
And I truly believe
that Luke is your best,
and possibly,
last chance to get one.
- Okay.
.
- Luke wants to help
his father.
I can get behind that.
- Believe me,
I want to also
but his developmental ability--
I mean what are we talking
about here?
- Look, it's not ideal,
but we don't have
a better move.
And Luke needs his dad.
I've known Lawrence
for a long time now
and Luke is always
his first concern
and he gave us the okay.
- Okay.
So we're on
safe ground legally.
What about morally?
- All right.
I'll take it
to the ethics committee.
Get their opinion.
- Negative CT
and clinically improved
for the patient in five.
He can be discharged.
Want me to put it through?
- I've got it. It's okay.
A flu in two and
dislocated shoulder in seven.
- Can't believe you're her mom.
How'd you keep that so quiet?
- Easy, I didn't tell you.
- Ha.
So...who's the dad?
- Why don't you turn over five?
- Good morning, Will.
Oh, hey.
Another article
in the Trib this morning
about your takedown
of corporate greed, yeah?
- Yeah. My email's blowing up.
- Well then, I guess
you won't be needing this, huh?
I thought you might want
to cut out the article
and use it in your--
your scrapbook,
you know,
put it on your trophy display?
- I didn't do it
for the accolades, Dean.
- Hey, um, I got your back
on this one.
I mean, you--you went
out on a limb for justice
and you won. Proud of you.
Truly.
- Spent the morning with feds
and they wanna talk again soon.
Thank you very much.
- Hey, I'm sorry, Stevie.
Really. I didn't--I didn't mean
for you get caught up in this.
- Then why didn't you read me
in on what was going on?
Especially when it came
to Eleanor Holt.
If I'd known what you knew,
I might have treated
her differently.
- Halstead, Hammer, you're up.
You're going to treatment 3.
Chart's in your tablet.
- Mr. Sanon, I'm Dr. Halston.
This is Dr. Hammer.
- Hi.
So I can see you got a bum arm
and a lump on the head.
What happened?
- Um, he doesn't speak English.
I'm his son, Emmanuel.
- Okay.
He says he's okay
with me doing the talking.
- Great. French?
- Haitian Creole.
I've been in the U.S.
a few years.
My father was finally
able to join me.
He got out this past summer.
- So, Emmanuel, what happened?
- Last couple of months,
he's been a little off.
Dizziness, confusion.
But Chicago moves a lot faster
than rural Haiti.
- Yeah. Culture shock
must be staggering.
- Yeah. That's why
I didn't think much of it.
But recently
he's been clumsy too.
Today, he missed a step
like he didn't know
where it was,
fell down the stairs.
- Lungs are good,
heart seemed normal
but can't rule out
a syncopal episode.
- Let's get a chest X-ray,
a 12-lead EKG, cardiac labs,
CBC, BMP, and a head CT.
- Um, he is asking
if his fiancée, Fabienne,
can come to the hospital?
- Of course, yeah.
Give the nurse her number.
- Okay. Merci.
- You're welcome.
- We'll check back soon.
- How you holding up?
- Uh...been better.
Put colleagues
in an uncomfortable spot.
Not what I wanted.
- I hear that.
FBI speak to you yet?
- Yeah.
Told me you made it very clear
that I was working
on your behalf.
- I did because it's true.
We're gonna get through this.
- Peter, really?
Shutting me out
of budget meetings?
- Well, the board
can't fire you.
You're the hero.
- And this is their plan
to put me in purgatory?
- What do you expect?
There's stink
all over Med right now. We're
getting hammered
by the press,
donors are fleeing,
doctors are getting poached
by other hospitals.
Had three more
resignations today.
These are department
heads, Sharon.
- Silencing me is not
gonna clean up their mess.
- I suspect the board
knows that.
- Suspect?
Look,
as a Sharon Goodwin ally,
I'm out of the loop.
But if I had a guess,
they're gonna come at you.
And I doubt it's gonna be
from head-on.
- What'd they say?
- The ethics committee's
comfortable with moving ahead
with Luke as a possible donor.
Look, do the tests.
See if he's even a candidate,
then we'll go from there.
- Sharon Goodwin?
- Yes.
- Randall Shentu.
- Can I help you
with something?
- Oh, I assumed
you'd be expecting me.
Nobody told you?
- Why don't we talk
in my office?
"The Shentu Group,
health care consultancy?"
- We provide hospitals
with practical guidance
to navigate the ever-evolving
healthcare landscape,
whether it be regulatory,
operational, fiscal,
or reputational management.
- You got a lot going on
after your name.
President, CEO, MD, JD.
Impressive.
Why are you here, Mr. Shentu?
- Board told me
you don't mess around.
They've brought me on
to help Med
through this challenging time.
To establish a culture
of transparency with vendors,
device companies, reps,
and especially patients.
- You mean Med's business
shouldn't happen
behind closed doors?
- Exactly. Well said.
- I hope so.
It's been my mission at Med
since I started here
as a nurse 35 years ago.
- I'm sorry.
I meant no disrespect.
And I need to acknowledge
your leadership.
Exposing Dr. Cooper's
abuse of the Vas-COM
was brave, admirable.
I'm not here
to be an obstructionist,
but right now Med's in trouble.
And, uh, if it gets worse,
ultimately, it'll be
the patients that suffer.
I don't want that.
- Then we have something
in common.
- Mm.
- I'm gonna take you
at your word.
- That's all I can ask for.
Thank you.
I look forward
to working together.
- It was nice to meet you,
Mr.--
sorry, Dr. Shentu.
- Randall. Please.
One more thing.
An ED resident upstaged Santa
to announce that the ED
charge nurse was her mother?
Do I have that right?
- Dr. Vanessa Taylor
and Maggie Lockwood.
- Wow, talk about left field.
Can only imagine your surprise.
.
- Hey, Luke.
I'm Dr. Marcel. We met earlier.
Luke, I'm gonna take
some blood from your arm.
Gonna feel a little pinch,
but before you know it,
we'll be all done, okay?
- Where's my daddy?
- He's in his treatment room
right across the way.
- I see him.
Sleeping.
- That's right.
- He's tired, honey.
- I don't wanna be here.
- It's okay.
- I understand. Ready to do it?
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay, Luke.
Can I see your arm?
Here you go, bud.
I'm just gonna...
roll your sleeve up, all right?
- Don't wanna.
- We're almost there.
- Cold.
- I know.
I'll pull it right down
when I'm done, okay?
Okay, this is a tourniquet.
- No. Tight. It hurts.
Take it off.
- I can't do that quite yet,
all right?
Just hang in there
for me, okay?
- I don't like it. It's cold.
- Okay.
- What's that?
- This is just a wipe
to clean your arm.
That's it. That's it.
Just hang in there
for me, okay?
- No shot! No shot!
I don't want a shot!
Daddy!
- Right, need a hand?
- No, no. Shutting it down.
That's it. We're done.
All right, bud. We're done.
- I want my daddy.
- Okay, all right.
- Daddy!
- Come on, sweetie. Come on.
- Saw your patient's chart.
Wasn't that his best shot
at a kidney?
- Yeah.
You got a plan B?
- No.
- Take a deep breath
for me, Claudia.
Can you tell me what happened?
- I was in class.
I couldn't really concentrate.
And my teacher let me
go to the water fountain.
- Okay.
Bilateral breath sounds,
heart's good,
regular rate and rhythm.
No murmurs.
- I was really thirsty
but when I leaned over
to get a drink,
I just got really dizzy
and I fell and hit my head.
- Did you lose consciousness?
- I don't know.
I just remember
sitting on the floor
with the school counselor,
Ms. Jones.
- BNP, CBC, bolus a liter
of saline and a 12-lead EKG.
- Is my mom coming?
- I called her, no answer.
I left a message.
- We'll keep trying
your mom, Claudia.
Be right back.
- She okay?
- Gonna run some tests
but all signs
just point to Claudia
being dehydrated.
- Oh, that's a relief.
I've been worried
about her lately.
Her grades have slipped,
absences have gone up.
I tried reaching out
to her mom.
We've been looking for a time
to sit down.
This is Claudia's backpack.
I know I shouldn't have
looked inside but I did.
Found this.
What are they?
- Furosemide.
It's a diuretic.
It's sometimes used
as a diet pill
to lose water weight.
"Sarah Rey?"
- Claudia's mother.
- Anel's cardiac labs
and EKG were normal
so unlikely he blacked out.
X-ray of his arm showed
a distal radius fracture.
Page ortho.
Should be down soon to cast it.
Is that his CT?
- Not good.
Check out the hippocampus.
- Diminished in size,
significant atrophy,
but there's no evidence
of a bleed or stroke.
- No.
Makes me think
it could be Alzheimer's.
Could explain the confusion
and the visual-spatial issues.
- Yeah, but Anel's only 45.
- Yeah, he might be
one of the 5 to 6%
that develops symptoms early.
Tell ortho to hold off
on casting the arm.
Let's get
a neuro consult first.
- Scott, need extra hands.
- Keith Varig,
35-year-old male,
unrestrained driver,
high-speed MVC.
GCS 8, BP 100/60,
heart rate 124,
grossly deformed left femur,
intubated in the ambo.
Apparently, a truck kicked up
a rock on the Eisenhower,
flew across the divider,
smacked through
this guy's windshield,
hit him in the head and
sent him right off the road.
- Or somebody's got it in
for him.
All right, come on. Let's go.
All right.
Transfer on my count.
One, two, three.
Watch his bag. All right, good.
- Multiple lacerations
to the face, neck, and arms.
Likely closed femur fracture.
- Belly's distended. I do not
like the way it feels either.
Quick fast, please.
- Bilateral breath sounds.
Kathleen, let's set up
for a chest X-ray.
- Free fluid
all over the belly.
Heavy internal bleeding.
Vitals?
- BPs dropping 90/55.
Heart rate's on the rise, 136.
- Let's trigger the MTP.
2 units blood,
2 units plasma, stat.
- Clear.
X-ray up.
- Wow. Chest X-ray's clean.
Lungs up, no hemothoraces.
- Yeah, lucky us.
One less crisis.
This guy's still
trying to die though.
Okay, Hank, call the O.R.
Tell 'em we're coming up.
Come on.
Let's move, people. Let's go.
- Look, my feeling just because
the ethics committee says
we can use Luke as a donor
doesn't mean we have to.
- So there's another option?
- It's not a great option
but yes.
Peritoneal dialysis, PD.
It's a slower type of dialysis,
puts less strain
on the vascular system.
- Slower.
- Well, given your
clotting issues
from regular hemodialysis,
PD's the next best alternative
until the kidney
becomes available.
Doesn't sound too pleasant.
- It's not but it buys time...
to keep working
that transplant list, right?
- This, uh, this PD, it--
it won't involve Luke?
Ever?
- No.
- Then let's do it.
- Sharon.
- Yeah?
- I just got a call from HR.
They're asking me about
my relationship with Vanessa.
What's this is all about?
- Randall Shentu.
- Who?
- Compliance officer
the board brought in.
- You think they're gonna
call Vanessa in too?
- I imagine so.
- We were finally getting
to a good place.
- I'm sorry, Maggie.
- Here. Is that better?
- Uh, sure.
- I'm sorry. Lawrence.
I know it's uncomfortable, man.
- Dr. Marcel?
- Yeah.
- Speak outside?
I'll be right back.
- Peritoneal dialysis.
- Yeah.
- He's dying, Crockett.
We had a path towards
possibly saving him
and you've blown that up.
- Luke couldn't handle
the blood draw.
What happens
when it's time for surgery?
That'd be torture.
- We could help Luke
with his anxiety.
- What? Sedate him
because we're inconvenienced
by his emotions?
That's not a solution.
- Neither is PD.
It's a stopgap at best.
Transplant organs
don't grow on trees.
Sometimes we have
to go get them.
- Yeah, well, not like this.
And Lawrence agrees.
- Well, you better hope
that decision
doesn't cost him his life.
.
- Is everything okay?
- He's asking about
a prescription
for him and his fiancée,
Fabienne,
for their, um, wedding night.
- Oh.
- Uh...
how about we talk
about that later?
- Merci.
- Okay?
Um, what did
the neurologist say?
- It's his opinion
and ours as well
that your father likely
has early-onset Alzheimer's.
- Okay.
Wow.
Um...
- Okay.
- Um, so...
how long until he's not
him anymore?
- Hard to say.
Likely a few years
but maybe more,
maybe less.
- There are medications.
One, Donepezil,
we'd like to start today.
And going forward, neurology
will devise a treatment plan.
- But there's no cure?
- No.
I'm sorry.
With Alzheimer's,
the best that we can do
is slow it down.
- He's asking
about his fiancée?
The nurse reached her.
She'll be here soon.
Merci.
- Vitals had been stable
but now BP's crashing.
Down to 94/60.
Heart rate's rising 130.
- He's bleeding again. A lot.
- 2 blood, 2 plasma stat.
Re-trigger the MTP.
Call the O.R.
We're going back in.
We'll reintubate there.
- Am I gonna die?
- Your injuries are severe.
You sustained
incredible trauma.
I've already
had to take your spleen
and a good deal
of your small intestine.
You're still
bleeding internally.
I'm sorry to be so blunt-- -
No, I get it.
My family,
my parents, my sisters,
they're in Minnesota.
- Yeah, I called 'em.
They're on the way.
- His family, how long
until they get here?
- They're three hours away.
- Call 'em back.
They need to drive faster.
- But you knew Vanessa Taylor
was your daughter
before you visited her
at the medical school's
residency fair, correct?
- Yes.
But I spoke to many other
students that day,
not just Dr. Taylor.
- How many of those students
are now employed
by the hospital?
- None.
- Which makes it appear
as if you had
an ulterior motive
when you visited the fair
in the first place.
- I wanted to meet my daughter.
But I had nothing to do
with her being hired
by this hospital.
She earned this
on her own merit.
- But that's not
the issue right now.
We're talking
about appearances.
- Claudia Rey, 13,
in the eighth grade,
treating her for dehydration.
CT confirmed that her
head injury was superficial.
But, look,
I could use your help.
- Tell me.
- I don't want to call DCFS.
- Okay.
- Claudia passed out
because she was using diuretic
as diet pills,
mom's prescription.
She says mom
gave 'em to her but
I just don't know
if that's true or not.
- Where is mom anyway?
- Still trying to get
ahold of her.
Three calls, three voicemails.
- Yeah.
Daughter in the hospital,
no sign of mom.
I mean, it's not a great look.
- I mean, notifying them
might be protocol,
but once that ball
gets rolling, it's--
look, I just want to get
mom's side of the story
before I start something
that I can't undo.
- I get it. I mean,
you really wanna be sure
before you make that call.
- Yeah. Okay.
Uh, I'm gonna keep trying mom.
And once she arrives,
do you mind talking to her?
- Why don't we talk to
her together?
- Okay, Keith.
Let me scrub in and then
we're gonna get started.
- I'm finally gonna
get what I deserve.
Ten years ago,
I was at a bar.
I was drunk.
A guy hit on me.
I saw red.
I punched him
and I walked away.
Later, I found out
that when he fell,
he hit his head.
He died.
No one knew it was me
so I didn't tell.
I murdered a man.
And now it's time to pay.
A life for a life.
- Everything all right?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Pushing meds,
20 of etomidate.
- Oh, fun.
Got another morning meeting
with the feds tomorrow.
- Dr. Halstead, Dr. Hammer,
I think something's up.
I was just in Mr. Sanon's
treatment room.
Overheard him
with this fiancée.
I speak French so it's not
a one-to-one to Haitian Creole,
but I'm pretty sure
he was explaining
that his son said the fall
was just a balance issue.
That meds called
Donepezil will take care of it.
- Emmanuel didn't tell
his father.
- Yeah, looks that way.
- Nancy, do you know
where Emmanuel is?
- Waiting room.
- I didn't tell him
and I'm not going to.
- Emmanuel,
I know Alzheimer's
was not the news
that you were expecting today.
I'm so sorry.
But lying to your father
is just--
- I'm protecting him.
You can't understand.
In Haiti, all my father knew
was poverty, hardship, and war.
But now there's freedom,
joy, love.
He finally
has everything to live for.
And I won't take that from him.
- Emmanuel,
the disease will progress
so you--you can't keep it
a secret forever anyway.
- Why not?
Let my father live
a few years in ignorant bliss.
When the time does come,
he won't even remember
this day happened.
Please.
- No. No way.
Anel should be
the one to decide
what's best for his life,
especially when there's
a time clock on it.
- When the truth
may do more harm than good,
therapeutic privilege gives us
some leeway to hold back info.
I mean, plus I imagine
Emmanuel knows his father
better than anyone.
We should consider his opinion.
- Is it his opinion or yours?
Seems these days,
you're the one who's in charge
of what people should
or rather shouldn't know.
.
- Fabienne doesn't know either,
does she?
Keeping the diagnosis secret
affects her life too.
- I'm doing
what I think is right.
- Okay, Emmanuel,
I get that you want to preserve
your father's happiness
but he and Fabienne
are engaged.
She needs to know
her future may not be
what she's envisioning.
Please tell her.
- So Claudia's gonna be okay?
- Yes. Her latest labs
came back normal.
Small bruise on her forehead
but she's now hydrated
and feeling much better.
- I had my cell in my pocket,
but I was on shift.
There's a strict phone policy.
I didn't know
it was the hospital.
- Don't worry about it.
We, um, we found you
and you're here
and that's what's important.
- Um, Claudia told me
that you gave these to her.
- I've struggled with my weight
my entire life.
I was raised on fast food
and huge portions.
And before I knew it,
I was raising Claudia
the same way.
I tried to break the cycle
with lean recipes,
meal prep, organic,
but I--I work two jobs
and can barely make rent.
Eating right
takes planning and money.
- Must be frustrating
feeling like,
you know, all those--
all those healthy options
are not available to you.
So could you tell us
about the pills?
- I found them on the internet.
I was just trying
to get to spring
and nicer weather
so we could walk again.
- Right.
- I've been Claudia,
the overweight teenager,
and kids can be cruel,
especially when you get
to high school
and I just wanted to spare her
that pain but I'm failing.
- No, I don't see that.
I see a mom
who's doing the best
that she can.
- You know, we have
a couple of excellent
educational programs
here at the hospital.
The one I'm thinking about,
Exercise and Nutrition,
both online and in-person.
Is that something you think
you might be interested in?
- Yes. Thank you.
- I can put together
some info for you.
- Can I go back
and be with Claudia now?
- Yeah, of course.
It was very nice
to meet you, Ms. Rey.
- So, holding off on DCFS,
that was the right call.
- Mothers and daughters have
been on my mind a lot lately.
- Well, came in handy today.
Good work, Doctor. Keep it up.
- Thanks.
- Fabienne?
Hi.
I'm Doctor Hammer.
I'm hoping Emmanuel told you
about Anel's diagnosis?
- Yes.
It was a shock.
- I understand.
I want to respect your space
and I apologize
for overstepping...
but Emmanuel has chosen
not to tell his father.
How do you feel about that?
- Conflicted.
I love Anel.
Keeping a secret from him
is not the way
I want to begin our marriage,
but I agree with Emmanuel
that he doesn't need to know.
- Oh. Really?
- Anel is reunited
with his son.
His world, at last,
is at peace.
Telling him it's only
a fleeting moment
will destroy him
far faster than the disease.
That's not the marriage
I want either.
I support Emmanuel's decision.
- But he's made it
for both of you.
That's not fair.
- It won't be easy,
I understand,
but I'm prepared.
- In our culture,
nothing is more important
than family.
Emmanuel knows this because
his father instilled it in him.
What's not fair,
even more than the diagnosis,
is that Anel will never know
what Emmanuel is doing for him.
He would be proud of his son.
- The damage was extensive.
It was a very difficult
surgery.
We couldn't awaken Keith
after the surgery and...
we gave him a CT,
found that he had suffered
a hemorrhagic stroke
while he was on the table.
- He's not gonna wake up?
- There are no
brainstem reflexes.
Neurology will run
an apnea test to confirm
but the stroke was massive
and catastrophic.
- Keith's gone?
- I'm very sorry.
- Keith spoke to me
before he went under.
- What did he say?
- Well, he said...
that if he were to die,
he would want his organs
to be donated.
- Yes.
Yes, we'll donate.
- Um...
if you'd like to spend
some time with Keith.
- Damn, man.
That's what he was saying?
- His exact words:
"a life for a life."
- Well, my plan B
isn't working.
- Well then, new plan.
Got a patient on life support,
no chance of recovery,
blood type O-neg.
Kidneys being HLA tested
right now.
Here are the preliminary
numbers.
The family's agreed
to direct organ donation.
If the kidney matches
your patient, it's yours.
- Yeah, I think this'll work.
- Okay.
.
- Look, I should've
run PD by you
before making the switch.
You're right.
It was a Hail Mary
and it could've ended badly.
I get it if after today you
want to drop me from your team.
- Not drop you, Crockett,
strangle you.
- Mm.
- The truth is
I believe in you.
Hell, I even like you.
Maybe that's because
you piss me off.
- Thank you.
I guess.
- Look,
I'm not opposed to you
wearing your heart
on your sleeve,
but you and I are strongest
when we work together,
got it?
- Got it.
And I like you too.
- Let's go save
Lawrence's life.
- Vanessa.
I've been looking for you.
- Sorry,
I'm just taking a moment.
- I had to sit down
with HR today.
They're digging into
how I met you and ultimately
how you ended up in Med.
I'm so sorry.
I keep on getting in the way.
I never wanted
to be a distraction.
But over and over, that's--
that's what I've been.
Anyway, uh,
they're probably
gonna reach out.
- I don't care.
Let HR call.
- You're not upset?
- You know, when--
when I first started at Med, I
was just--
I was just so intimidated.
The early hours,
the ten-year binder,
the...Adderall, that was--
that was just me trying
not to feel like an imposter.
Like I belong.
But I know now I do belong.
And I wouldn't have figured
that out if it weren't for you.
All you've been is supportive.
- I don't know what to say.
- You don't have
to say anything.
Just know that I am so grateful
that you're in my life.
I don't care who knows.
- You know,
when I went to the FBI,
I really thought I was
doing right by this hospital.
And now, I don't know.
- Whoa, whoa, hold on.
For what it's worth,
I, for one,
am absolutely positive
that you did the right thing.
- I appreciate that.
- So positive in fact,
that I am gonna take you out
for an incredibly expensive
dinner right now.
Let's go.
- Just so you know,
the Vas-COM business,
sneaking around,
playing nice with the enemy,
it sucked,
but I needed
to protect patients.
I had to help.
And if I had to do it again,
I would.
So I'm sorry
I didn't fill you in.
I wish I could have.
- No, you were doing
what you thought was right.
Yeah, I get that now.
- So we're cool?
- Yeah, we're cool.
Um, hey.
The device rep, Jessa,
did you sleep with her to get
the information you needed?
- No.
Absolutely not.
- Good.
- Congratulations.
Another W.
- Thanks to your
11th-hour heroics.
You saved us
from an impossible choice.
Deus Ex Machina.
- Dues--
oh, "god from the machine."
I like that.
Goodnight, Pamela.
- Night, Dean.
- Crockett.
- Avery, hey.
What? Another follow-up?
- No, I'm working here
just like you.
- Oh.
- My firm's been meeting
with patients and families
affected by the Vas-COM.
- Oh, that's right.
Well, you got a case?
- Oh, yeah. Good one.
- Nice.
- Speaking of,
my mom filled me in
on your big win.
- Ah.
- Way to kick ass.
- You say so.
- Are you refusing to
pat yourself on the back, huh?
That's pretty sexy.
What do you say,
dinner then my place?
- Oh, not tonight.
- Yeah.
Yeah, sure. I get it.
Single in the city.
I know how it works.
- Yeah.
- Well, okay.
I'll see you around.
- Yeah, see you around.
- So what are you thinking?
- I don't know.
The duck, gnocchi,
Spanish octopus.
- Mm, you got
a tough decision to make.
Me on the other hand,
I have no such issue.
- The Wagyu strip.
- How'd you know?
What about the--
the tasting menu?
- Ms. Cooper.
I'm actually glad
I ran into you.
There's something
I've been wanting to say.
- I'm not interested.
- You come at me
as hard as you want, okay?
It doesn't matter.
- Come on.
- I'm gonna win.
You're gonna lose.
- This is neither
the time or the place,
all right?
- That's it.
Enjoy your dinner.
.
♪