There's a moment
I've noticed in the OR...
♪ I can feel you
walk around... ♪
...especially when a patient
is going south.
♪ ...my head again ♪
♪ I find it comforting ♪
You're working so hard,
you lose yourself.
♪ And that's troubles me ♪
All of your problems.
♪ I lie awake ♪
Your relationships.
♪ And wonder where you go ♪
Career goals.
Your fears.
♪ When everything
gets quiet and cold ♪
They all just fade away.
It's not even you
and your patient.
It's you and yourself.
- ♪ I lie awake ♪
- Your hands.
♪ And wonder where you go ♪
Your skill.
♪ When everything gets quiet
and cold ♪
You might call it
muscle memory...
or being in the zone.
♪ Those little fleeting moments
we hold ♪
But whatever you call it,
it's rare...
♪ When everything gets quiet
and cold ♪
...and you never want it
to end.
Captioning provided by
ABC Studios and ABC, Inc.
And brought to you by: Ford,
Built Ford Proud
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 17  Episode 13
Episode Title: "Good as Hell"
Aired on: April 22, 2021
♪ Everyone around me
is on their knees ♪
- Hey.
Are the, uh...
Are the kids okay?
Yeah, they're great.
It took a little longer
to get through the park
'cause of the protests,
but Mom had French toast ready.
How was, uh, therapy?
- Virtual.
- Yeah.
Is that
why you're out here?
Making sure
that I did it?
No.
I'm here to make sure
that you're done, 'cause
I have something to show you.
♪ I can tell you
all my secrets ♪
- Come on.
- ♪ But don't call it a weakness ♪
♪ Got my reasons ♪
- Hey.
Didn't your shift end
a while ago?
Yeah,
I went to check on Mer.
Still no change.
She'll get better.
Just like Jennilyn did.
You didn't even know
Jennilyn.
She's my favorite
ICU nurse.
It might be
my first official day here,
but she and I...
We go way back.
I'm just glad I didn't miss
her big
post-COVID sendoff.
She is one of us.
Here she comes!
Ladies and gentlemen,
Jennilyn's going home!
Whoo!
- Whoo!
- Alright!
Whoo!
♪ Living on my faith ♪
Hey, excuse me.
Hey,
did we miss it?
No,
you're just in time.
Ah.
Six weeks
in the hospital.
Our tenth official discharge
this week.
Ah, I remember the day
I hired her.
I will never get sick
of this.
You okay?
♪ Living on my faith ♪
That should be
Meredith.
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Living on my faith ♪
♪ On my faith ♪
I hate ER days.
Everything's so urgent.
What are we watching
tonight?
Whatever you want.
I'll be with Nico.
Movie nights are sacred,
Levi.
Movie nights are new
since your sex friend
disappeared.
Don't deprive me
of mine.
I have to talk to Bailey
about OB today,
and I know that Webber told me
everything I need to say,
but still... Bailey.
You have to talk to Bailey
every day.
I'll cancel my plans
when you actually do it.
Hey.
Uh, you forgot this.
Oh, well, uh, could've just
gotten it later.
Oh, it was kind of
in the way.
Well, it wouldn't be if you
gave me a drawer or something.
Is the sex still good?
It's amazing.
See how supportive I was of you
just now?
Bye!
Okay, Felix, and how's
your range of motion been?
It's still stiff
when I throw.
I thought I'd be back to pitch
this fall.
Hey. Teddy hasn't returned
my calls.
Have you talked to anyone
from the hospital?
'Cause I...
Sorry. It's just,
I had a dream about Mer.
I'm going.
Sorry, Felix.
Um, you know,
it's still early days,
you're only four months
post surgery,
and it was
a decent-sized tear.
This is the last season
to get scouted by a D-1 school.
Huh.
Why are you still here?
Right. I'm gone.
Uh... yeah, Felix, it's gonna
take a little bit more patience.
It's...
It's gonna be...
I'm so sorry.
Felix, is it?
Um,
a-are you right-handed?
Yeah.
Amelia.
I know this is weird.
I'm... I'm a surgeon, too,
and I just, uh, wanted
to check one thing with you.
H-Have you noticed
that your left arm
feels stronger
than your right arm recently?
I guess so.
Kinda?
Why?
What the hell?
If this is
a neurological issue,
it could end more than
just his career
if it goes untreated, so
I'm...
Hey. I just want to to over a
couple maneuvers with you, okay?
Okay.
Meredith's vitals
have been stable for days.
Her X-rays have shown
a remarkable improvement,
and her oxygen requirements
have gone down.
Which is why
she should be awake
for more than two minutes
at a time.
Why isn't she?
What is it?
Her labs this morning showed
elevated liver enzymes.
It might just be a side
effect from the medications,
but we do want to order
some new tests.
And we'd also like to get CTs,
both chest and abdomen.
It might seem extensive,
but...
Well, let's do it.
We're seeing more and more
patients in the same position.
It seems like they're finally
out of the woods,
and then
some new problem arises
and they just...
they just crash.
We can't let this happen
to Meredith.
Were you in pain?
You know, the worst part
was knowing
they were
getting it wrong.
I didn't want
to leave you,
but I knew, you know,
at a certain point...
I came
to the hospital.
I know.
You could hear?
Not through my ears.
Dying is exhausting.
You know that point
as a surgeon...
you've done everything
for your patient.
I could try and will them
to fight,
will them to live,
but I never understood
the level of exhaustion.
There comes a point
where the desire to rest
overrides the desire to live.
You got that.
You gave me permission
to go.
You told me it was okay.
You got me.
You gave me everything I needed
until my last breath.
Do you need more time
to think about it?
No.
Okay.
And your answer is...
I just told you.
No.
Bailey...
I didn't come
to this decision lightly,
and without
your recommendation,
I may have to redo
my entire intern year.
Only if you were
changing specialities,
which you are not doing.
That is not your decision
to make.
It's not.
No. It's yours,
and you made it
when you signed a contract
as a general surgery
attending.
It's got a few more years on it,
last time I checked.
Bailey, you can't...
I-I need this.
And I need surgeons,
Wilson.
I'm losing them
to, uh, sickness, exhaustion,
hell, murder,
or in Avery's case,
just suddenly taking
a leave of absence.
Y-You need to think
about the hospital.
I can't afford to lose you
right now,
especially
when Meredith...
Look, we can, um, revisit
this topic
after this thing is over,
but for right now,
my answer is no.
Okay.
Felix is headed in.
Mm. Great.
Uh... Is he set up for his MRI
in case he beats us there?
Yes. You know,
I would have caught
- that right-sided deficit.
- Yeah, I know you would have.
We had just started.
I was focused on the shoulder.
Yeah, I know you were.
Not to mention
I kept getting distracted.
All my fault. I got it.
I'm ready.
No, we...
We can't leave.
Maggie's not here yet.
Oh, well,
that means you can't,
but I can,
and I should.
Or, you know,
I could call Koracick
and you could stay here.
Well, this was my find.
Oh, I'm sorry. You wouldn't
want somebody waltzing in
and stealing your patient? W...
Please don't take this
from me.
I have not operated
in over a month.
Oh, and this sudden need
to operate has nothing to do
with your sister
still being unconscious?
Nope.
I just
really miss cutting.
Got it.
- Okay.
- I-I'm still coming.
Hey.
Great to see you, Maggie.
Thanks for all the help.
Um, everybody's eaten.
Hi?
I take it this is a new hobby?
Should have started
with the plow stop,
but my kids wanted
to learn the moonwalk.
I was killing it
until I hit that railing.
My mom
would never do that.
She's a total worry...
Dr. Schmitt, order tib/fib X-rays
and page me when they're done,
please.
Okay, Erika, I'd like to
do an abdominal ultrasound.
Oh. Nice.
I've lost 50 pounds
in Q-tine.
Check out these abs.
Damn.
That railing ate me alive.
- Yep.
- Oh.
Okay, let me know
if this hurts at all.
50 pounds, huh?
Tech lawyer. Boatloads of money,
but... tech lawyer.
Sedentary job,
sedentary life.
Then COVID hit, and I figured,
if the world's ending,
I might as well be happy.
I was so tired of being tired,
you know?
So, I quit that job
that I hated,
spent time with my kids,
started working out,
then I started my own business
making peanut brittle.
Ooh. Try some.
Ooh.
No eating
in the hospital.
Um, so, Erika, it looks like
you have some bleeding
under
your abdominal muscle,
so we'll need to do a CT
to evaluate how severe it is.
Alright, page me
when she's ready, Schmitt.
I won't tell
if you won't.
And I know we've only
technically met on the phone...
but I'm marrying
your sister,
so how about you wake up
and give me a "Congratulations"
or something?
I mean,
I heard you were tough,
but I didn't think
you were cold.
I want you closer.
You're worried
about the kids.
If you get closer...
I'll never leave.
I think
that's the theory.
Your dad died
when you were young.
Yes.
And it almost ruined me.
But it didn't.
Kids survive.
And struggle
makes them stronger.
Sometimes. Sometimes,
it makes them stronger,
and sometimes,
it makes them...
Amelia.
She's doing great,
by the way.
- I know.
- And she named her baby...
I know!
Oh.
People love you,
Meredith.
People need you.
I'm tired.
Your body's tired.
But your soul...
Your soul won't even
let me near you.
You're still fighting.
Have you seen
the last...
one or two years?
Yeah.
Was that hard for you?
It's harder watching you
be lonely.
I want to say
you're beautiful,
but it's... shallow.
Say "pretty on the inside."
That's what I tell Zola
to say.
"Be pretty
on the inside."
You're pretty on the inside,
Meredith Grey.
- How's Grey?
- Not getting better.
She won't stay awake, and her
liver enzymes are elevated.
Any sign
of acute infection?
No, but that
doesn't mean anything
because
this stupid disease causes
every complication
in the book
without any consistency
whatsoever.
Well, it's still
relatively new.
There's information coming out
every day, and...
Yeah, vague information.
We have no idea
how this disease
is gonna affect these patients
in the long-term.
I mean, there could be
permanent lung scarring,
vascular damage,
neurological issues...
Eh, oh, no, please,
keep... keep going.
Tom, I didn't...
I'm... I'm sorry.
That's...
I'm sure that you're fine.
Alright.
She's all set.
Okay. Great. Thanks.
Tom, I'm sorry.
I...
Hey, Doc,
you're just stating facts.
Don't be sorry.
Okay.
What happened?
Carolyn Hexton.
Cardiac arrest.
When I talked
with her yesterday,
she didn't even
need oxygen.
Yeah, and then she started
having arrhythmias,
and then she went
into V-fib.
37 years old.
Kindergarten teacher.
She ran 10ks
for charity.
I thought she'd be going home
this week.
Yeah.
So did she.
We all did.
I got to call her family.
Hello, Mrs. Hexton.
This is Dr. Hunt.
No. No, um...
No. She...
Uh, she's, uh...
Um, there were
some complications.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Hexton.
Could you give me one moment,
please?
Dr. Seip.
Dr. Tracy Seip to Recovery.
Please tell me
you're not eating in...
I'm not! I'm not!
I'm just, uh... I'm smelling.
I-I miss smelling things.
Smell things after work
in the comfort of your own home.
My home smells like
unwashed laundry.
It's impressive, huh?
Leaving a successful career,
getting in shape,
being there
for your family.
She really made lemonade
out of, um...
a-a very deadly virus.
Must be nice.
You think she should be doing
something different?
I think if I suddenly started
baking snickerdoodles
and going base jumping,
do me a favor
and throw a big net over me.
It's peanut brittle.
It's... It's actually
a-a lot harder to master
than snickerdoodles.
Scans are up.
Mm. Mm.
Okay.
Deep breaths, buddy.
She told me to drop everything
I was doing and rush to the ER.
Well, Dr. Shepherd has a
tendency...
...to, uh, raise the stakes
of any situation.
MRI results will be back
in a second.
You look worried, and he keeps
telling me I'm gonna be fine.
Dr. Shepherd,
baseball is Felix's life.
It's what got him
into junior college,
and it's his only hope
of getting
into a Division I school.
What would you do
if suddenly,
you couldn't be a surgeon
anymore?
You paged Koracick?
No. Radiology did.
Uh. Be right back.
He has a meningioma,
C6, 7.
Let me look at it,
please.
That is
a nasty little tumor.
We'll have to do an intricate
multi-level decompression.
Start with a wide excision,
but that will destabilize
his cervical spine,
so he'll need hardware.
Forget
about his pitching arm.
Any slip, and you risk
making him a paraplegic.
I mean, but there's a lot
going on with your sister
and our lives.
It's been a long time
since...
I'm not that rusty,
thank you.
You can go, Tom.
Alright,
one millimeter off...
I said you can go, Tom.
And, uh,
if you want to help,
you can comfort the patient
while I book an OR.
How we doing today?
Oh, you know,
just thinking
about how selfish it is
to follow my dreams.
I meant Luna,
but, uh, good to know.
Luna's trending upwards,
so Luna is a bright spot
in a sea of unfettered misery.
What's all this
about dreams?
I want to switch to OB,
but Bailey said
it's a bad time.
Ah,
she's not wrong there.
Thank you.
Listen, everything
will sort itself out
once Grey's
back on her feet.
If she gets back
on her feet.
Well, I thought she was
on the mend.
We all did.
Well, how bad is it?
Her liver enzymes
are elevated this morning,
and her creatinine
is worse,
so her kidneys could be failing,
and nobody knows why.
God, it's just one thing
after another, isn't it?
This is my way of remembering
that there is more to the world
than just misery
and death.
At least,
I hope there is.
I'll get out
of your way.
Tell me
you found something.
Meredith's chest CT was clear.
However,
her abdominal CT wasn't.
We found a filling defect
in her IVC and hepatic vein.
And is that clot
in her liver?
Yes, which explains
why she can't stay awake.
Her body's fighting a build-up
of ammonia.
It's a small clot, but
if we don't treat it quickly,
then there could be
fluid build-up,
which will just wreak havoc
on her liver.
Can you do, uh, an IR shunt
or thrombolytics, or...
A TIPS procedure should be done
in the IR suite, for sure,
but I don't think
I should do it.
Why not?
Because Dr. Altman's here,
and because Dr. Grey
is Maggie's sister,
and if anything...
Dr. Altman...
are you sure
you're up to this?
It's a simple procedure.
I know what it is.
I'm asking, are you...
I will book
an IR suite.
Altman...
...are you sure?
Meredith doesn't have time
for this conversation.
Hey.
Webber send you
to check in on me?
No. No, he told me
what was going on
and asked me if we thought
you were okay to operate.
And? And I told him
you were fine to operate
and there was no one better
to do it.
Thank you. And I also told him
that if something goes wrong,
either something
within your control
or something
outside of it,
I'm not sure
that you'll recover.
I lost a kindergarten teacher
today.
I had to call her family.
I broke down on the phone.
I don't know if they knew
that I was crying
or if they thought
that I was choking,
but I was pretty much
doing both.
Never in my career
have I... cried
while delivering news
to a family.
It is unprofessional,
and honestly,
it is embarrassing.
And after all we saw in the war,
all that loss,
and this kindergarten teacher
that I barely knew
just... broke me.
Because, uh...
Because COVID.
Yeah.
You've been through a lot,
Teddy,
and you just came back,
and it is Meredith.
If something goes wrong...
I might not recover.
Can you page Dr. Ndugu for me,
please?
Dr. Shepherd, I've worked
with a lot of neurosurgeons.
None of them
were as good as you.
One millimeter
in the wrong direction,
and I end
this kid's career.
That's what Tom said.
That is what he said,
and that's what I said.
But you are
Amelia Shepherd.
So you got this.
What's she doing?
She's getting ready
to crush it.
Did something happen?
Yeah, you'll be
joining me. Okay.
She's not just your family
or Maggie's.
She's mine.
She's everyone's.
So, she's gonna have
two of the finest
cardiovascular surgeons
in the country,
and we're
not gonna think about
what she means to us
or to everyone.
We are gonna help each other do
what we know how to do,
and we will watch
each other's every move.
No ego. There's no question
that's too stupid to ask.
It's just about the work,
and we are going to remove
this clot.
Deal.
Okay, then.
Here we go.
Ultrasound?
♪ Wake up miles 'round ♪
Ellis draws this picture
of us.
I'm in a wedding dress.
Uh-huh.
And then
you're in a suit.
I showed her the Post-it Note,
but she just...
Hates it.
She feels robbed.
Well, she gets that
from my mother.
♪ Midnight ♪
Oh.
♪ Downtown ♪
You hate weddings.
I hate weddings.
But I would give this to her
if I could.
What do you want me
to promise?
To torture yourself less.
♪ Locked up in stables ♪
♪ Where we arrived ♪
♪ It's tangled cables ♪
I don't want
to leave the kids.
I don't want you
♪ Where we unwind ♪
Hey, Zola.
Your math teacher said you
signed out of class early today.
Are you okay?
♪ I told you I'm sorry ♪
What's wrong?
I'm mad.
At someone at school?
At everything.
♪ You don't know heartache ♪
Hm.
♪ Until you know none ♪
Did you see the news,
about the protests?
Yeah.
When my teachers try to talk
about it,
they get really weird
and seem scared to say anything.
That happens.
Do you want to go
to a protest?
I could take you.
I don't want to go
without my mom.
She'd be mad, too.
But she doesn't even know
what's happening.
She says she works
at the best hospital
with the best doctors.
She does. We do.
Then why isn't she home?
You know Dr. Fox?
She told me
to try something
when I'm really upset
that really helped.
What?
Screaming.
I'm serious.
It'll wake up the baby.
It's okay.
It's time for his bottle anyway.
Come on. Come on.
Okay.
Come on.
Shake it off. Ready?
One, two, three.
Your CT shows what's called
a rectus sheath hematoma.
It's when you have bleeding
under
your middle abdominal muscles.
Banged myself up good,
didn't I?
And your
blood counts are a little low,
so we'll need
to watch you overnight
to make sure the bleeding
doesn't get worse.
Well, your tib/fib
fracture should heal nicely
without surgery,
but we're gonna need
to put you in a cast
before you're discharged,
which you'll have to be in
for about six weeks.
Mm, I can make brittle
from a chair.
Must take a lot of peanuts to
make what you made as a lawyer.
I-I'd need a factory
for that.
Yeah.
You think I'm crazy,
don't you?
I didn't say anything.
There was this poem I read
in high school.
This lady stood
near a cliff,
afraid to get close to the edge
for a better view
because she thought
she might fall.
But then
someone pushed her.
Was the poem
about murder?
No, because she didn't fall...
She flew.
The cliff was a metaphor...
It's what
we're afraid will happen.
There's so much
the world tells us we need
that we don't really need.
Couldn't see it
until I took the jump...
Isssh...
beautiful...
Shhhhome...
Uh...
Oh.
Pulse is thready.
Hematoma's expanding.
She's actively bleeding.
Let's get her to the OR.
We're coming up
to the OR!
Stent looks patent
after the procedure.
And liver enzymes?
The creatinine?
Already improving.
Then why
isn't she waking up?
It takes time. We have given
her time. We have given her time,
and every test
and every treatment.
We removed that clot
perfectly... perfectly...
And she's still
not waking up,
and she's still not improving,
and she's still not going home.
Why isn't she?
Altman, there is...
I'm sorry.
I-I can't.
I have to take a walk.
More suction.
Ah, there's the inferior
epigastric artery. Mm.
Hemostat.
Yeah, looks like she'll live
to skate another day.
2-0 silk.
You know how a pearl is formed,
Schmitt?
Should I?
It all starts with one
very irritating grain of sand.
The oyster
doesn't like it,
wants to keep its shell
pristine.
So,
to get rid of the sand,
the oyster coats it with
the inner layer of its shell.
Then we're gonna tie off the
collateral while we're in there.
Good.
Perfect.
But that just makes
the sand bigger.
And even more annoying
to the oyster.
So, the oyster just keeps adding
layer after layer,
until... a pearl.
Lap pads.
So, I'm the sand,
and you're trying
to transform me?
The story wasn't about you,
Schmitt.
The pandemic is the sand,
and it's pushed its way
into all of our homes,
but it doesn't mean
it has to ruin everything.
Maybe it is an opportunity
to transform.
Maybe Erika here has
the right idea.
I guess that's what
Jo Wilson's doing, right?
Now, why would you bring up
losing one of my best surgeons
when I just got
to my happy place?
Goodness.
Goodbye, tumor.
You two
really are co-dependent.
She ask you
to chaperone?
Nope.
Just living vicariously.
You here to chaperone?
No.
Don't tell her
I said this,
but Shepherd's fun to watch
in there.
Elegant,
focused, confident.
Pippen to my Jordan.
What do you hear
about Meredith?
Uh, I don't.
Uh, I... don't.
I largely try to avoid that
entire wing of the hospital
because... God.
When is it
just too much, Lincoln?
When do we get to scream
at God?
When do we get to open
a bottle of Scotch
and pour him
a giant God-sized glass,
push it across the table, and
when he's too drunk to smite us,
just scream...
"What kind of
a sick joke is this?"
I don't get how kids still
get cancer during all this.
What kind of a sick joke
is this?
Is she awake?
No.
What if we did
something wrong?
You didn't.
What if we caused the clot
to break off
and now she's having
a massive stroke?
Teddy, there's nothing that
indicates any of that, okay?
Then why isn't she awake?
Teddy, breathe, okay?
Just... Just breathe.
Listen, hold my hand.
Can you feel my hand?
Okay. Just feel that
and just concentrate on that.
Concentrate on the weight
of my hand on your hand.
Good.
No. No. No.
Owen, please...
Teddy, no.
Listen, I'm here.
I am here with you.
Okay?
But you need to feel this,
Teddy.
Just feel it.
Dr. Webber,
maybe you should go.
Why? Because
it's only my first day,
and I want to try something that
could very well get me fired.
Absolutely not.
Well,
at least hear the man out.
I've heard.
Zola is
already traumatized.
I am not bringing her
to the hospital.
We need to do something,
Maggie.
Hearing her daughter,
feeling her?
Maybe it could help. Winston,
if your mother or my mother
could have stayed and lived,
they would have stayed
and lived,
but people
don't just decide.
It's not a choice.
Our mothers
were terminally ill,
but Meredith...
we have fixed the only thing
we found that was wrong.
It's too much
to put on a child.
All she'll know is that
she's coming to see her mom,
which she wants to do anyway,
and Meredith's negative now.
It's safe. Maggie, you
know good and well
that there is a psychological
component to recovery.
I've seen it
again and again.
I have, too.
Well, don't you think
it's at least worth trying?
Maggie, whether it works
or it doesn't,
at least Zola
gets to see her mom again.
Let me call you back.
Hey.
I want to go.
I want to see Mommy.
You got it?
All of it?
All of it.
And my arms?
You show us.
Oh.
Alright,
you get some rest.
Okay.
I need Scout.
I know. We haven't even
been gone that long.
I miss him, too.
Ooh, no, my boobs hurt.
I need to nurse or pump.
Or both.
And let's go.
Hmm.
Bandage is clean and dry
and intact.
No evidence of bleeding.
How's your pain, Erika?
Nothing I can't handle.
How long
until I can work again?
Well, you'll be back
in brittle business in no time.
I meant work-work,
not brittle.
At least,
if anyone's hiring.
To the job you hate?
To the job that keeps me alive
and in one piece,
and keeps my kids fed.
Quarantine was
a nice vacation,
but I can't live
in the clouds.
I need
to be realistic.
God,
what was I thinking?
That this world
had more to offer.
Oh, Erika.
You know, that...
That feeling
that you have to keep going
no matter what,
that it's all
on your shoulders...
It's something
that we're taught as women,
as Black women.
And I'm guilty of it.
And the pressure
to keep this place running?
I never used to
take any breaks.
let down my guard.
I never...
I never took breaks.
And then I had a heart attack
in my 40s.
"Rest" is not
a dirty word.
Rest is... not laziness,
no matter
what you're told
or how many times
you're told it.
Rest...
Rest is love.
Rest is peace.
Rest is a beautiful model
for your children.
And I was...
forgetting again
until I met you.
♪ Oh, this... ♪
So, don't be too quick
to give up on your joy.
You can... make it
your revolution.
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Yeah, me ♪
♪ In awe of you now, hmm ♪
Hey.
It's the smallest one
that we have.
Who's it for?
The less you know,
the better.
♪ This show no... ♪
Eh, and don't worry...
I won't tell anyone
it's from you.
Fine with me if you do.
♪ Lifting my spirit
like a Holy Ghost ♪
♪ All this ♪
♪ All this love, love ♪
♪ No ordinary love ♪
♪ Ordinary love ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la-la-la-la ♪
♪ Ah-ah, la, la, la,
la-la-la-la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la,
la-la-la-la-love ♪
♪ La-la, la-la, la-la, la-la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la-la-la-la ♪
♪ Ah-ah, la, la, la,
la-la-la-la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la,
la-la-la-la-love ♪
♪ La-la, la-la, la-la, la-la ♪
♪ I need you in my arms ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
Now, go on.
She's waiting for you.
Hey, if you change your mind,
it's alright.
It's okay
if you're scared.
♪ No ordinary love ♪
Mommy?
♪ Yeah ♪
It... It's me.
♪ Your kiss ♪
I'm here.
♪ A sky full... ♪
It's Zozo.
♪ ...of stars ♪
♪ Hmm ♪
I miss you so much.
♪ No ordinary love ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
I got your page.
My answer is no.
Did you forget
that you already told me that?
No. I will not be
making you keep a job
that no longer
fulfills you.
What about all of the...
The surgeons that you're losing?
Do you want me to change
my mind?
No.
Look, all non-emergency
surgeries
are non-existent anymore,
and if I have to hire
a new general surgeon,
I will,
but that's not your problem.
That's mine. I will help
you find anyone to...
Eh...
Thank you. Thank you.
Just love it, Wilson.
Love it
with every part of you.
Hey.
How's the, uh,
peanut brittle woman doing?
Heard you had to rush her
into surgery.
Nico, I think you're standing
on a cliff and you're scared.
Sounds a little crazy because
you're never scared of anything,
but me having a little space
in your apartment...
It's not
the end of the world.
Doesn't mean
I'll never leave.
It doesn't mean
that we're getting married.
It just... It means
that you're carving out
a small amount of room
for me.
Huh.
Well, move in with me.
You're right. I guard
my own space out of habit
because it makes me feels safe,
but safe from what?
You?
I love you, Levi.
So just...
move in with me.
Oh, I just... I just remembered
I can't come over tonight.
Jo is really sad
about Jackson leaving.
She is? What?
Yeah, and I-I promised her
that I'd hang out.
But... great talk.
Levi!
See you tomorrow.
Hey.
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Bailey said yes!
Great. What are we
watching?
Wait, what happened
to Nico night?
Oh, he's, uh... he's busy.
He's standing right over there.
Yeah, yeah.
I said, "What are we watching?"
Whoa!
Easy there, kiddos!
Oh, alright.
Yeah. Cool fort.
You got room
for one more?
What's the password?
- Uh... Rainbow Donkey?
- Nope!
I'm gonna go check
on Scout.
He just ate.
Little thing was out
in about 10 seconds.
I'm sorry, was I supposed to
keep him up?
Uh, Mom? What...
What are you doing here?
Did Zola wake up Mommy?
What? She went to try
and wake up Mommy.
Did something happen
with Meredith?
No change
in her mentation.
Sorry.
Well, it's something.
And no matter
what happens,
you did something,
and I'm grateful.
I want her to live.
I haven't met her yet.
And she's...
she's not
just Maggie's sister.
She's Dr. Meredith Grey.
So she lives, right?
Please God.
Those moments,
when everything fades away,
you're at your best.
♪ I can feel warmth on my skin ♪
But there's a problem with
disappearing into the work...
You can't save every patient.
It was Richard
and Winston's idea.
What?
♪ The winds are changing ♪
♪ The whispers of the angels ♪
It's a good idea.
And when I was checking
Ellis' homework,
she was actually doing
pretty well.
I'm scared.
I don't know why.
Me, too.
I need this year
to get better.
Me, too.
♪ The darkness won't hurt us
any longer ♪
What happened?
Is she okay?
Yes.
Yeah, she's the same.
What?
Why...
Why'd you bring Zola?
I couldn't think
of a better idea.
Oh, my God.
I can't breathe.
♪ I'm ready ♪
I'm so sorry.
I-I should've told you.
You were in surgery.
I need her to live.
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
Oh, my God.
Please,
I need her to live.
What?
Did something happen? What?
- Shh.
- Uh...
All of it.
Just all of it just...
All of it happened.
And if surgery
is all you have,
no matter how great you are,
eventually,
you're going to disintegrate.
It's not time yet.
There's no pain here.
Mm.
You want to know
a secret?
I even miss the pain.
You have to go.
I'm so tired.
It's not your time yet.
♪ Falling in, falling in,
don't want to get out ♪
Our kids need you.
♪ Down, down,
down, down the river ♪
You have to go.
Mom, Ellis keeps coming
into my bed at night,
the way I would come
into yours.
At first, I thought
it was annoying,
but now, I tell her she can come
in my bed whenever she wants.
And sometimes,
I let Bailey come in, too.
But he sleeps on pillows
on the floor,
but I always cover him
with a blanket.
♪ I'm ready ♪
That's so nice of you,
Zozo.
Mommy!
♪ Oh ♪
Hi.
♪ I'm ready ♪
♪ Yes, I'm, yes, I'm ready ♪
As nice as it is to lose
all your worries,
you also lose the good.
I love you so much,
Mommy.
We love you so much.
You're awake.
♪ Ah ♪
♪ I'm ready ♪
And if you hope to have any
kind of life worth living...
We love you, Zozo.
...you're definitely
going to need the good.
♪ I'm ready ♪