Previously on ER:
- Why you working the night before boards?
- Supposed to be Morris. He has them too.
You get stuck on the test:
Squeeze this, the answer will come.
That was so cool,
defending us to Moretti.
We were just discussing
different teaching philosophies.
Yours is better, which is why
there's no way I'll present to him.
My girlfriend, Lacey, her
homecoming dance is coming up.
Help me. I'm a virgin.
I'm not a nun. I'm a woman
who happens to be a chaplain.
- You been going to meetings?
- Yes.
It's like I'm actually
trying to screw things up.
A third straight day of
unseasonably hot weather...
reaching into triple figures has
resulted in sporadic power failures.
Soon they'll be blaming
this on global warming.
All those years of plastic cups and
Styrofoam are coming home to roost.
So because I've used spraycan
deodorant my whole life...
now I'm supposed to feel guilty about
the resurgence of the malaria in Kenya?
You talk so crazy, Frank.
I read it in the paper.
I read that cow farts are
gonna be the death of us.
Cow farts?
We eat too much livestock, which
release gases into the atmosphere...
- killing the ozone.
- Thank you, Al Gore.
I would rather drop dead right
now over a bone-in rib eye...
than live forever
on organic spinach.
The truth is very inconvenient.
I don't know about the rest of
you, but I have gotten smart.
I hooked up with a
tight, little sex machine.
Energy-efficient to the tune
of 40-plus miles per gallon...
and draws babes to
Archie like bees to honey.
Oh, that made me throw
up in my mouth a little.
Me too. ABBY: What about Hope?
Didn't you take an oath
of fidelity or something?
She's saving starving kids in Venezuela,
you're out here cruising for chicks?
Hope, Hope, Hope? Oh, that Hope.
Yeah, we broke up.
No, you didn't.
You did? I'm sorry.
- No, no big deal, it was very mutual.
- That's good.
Except it was her idea,
I begged her not to do it.
But I'm fine with it
now, it's all good.
- Lady for you on three, chief.
- Hope she chokes on a mojito.
Your ex-wife. Something
about your son.
Oh, all right. I'll
take it in there.
- He was married?
- Poor woman.
Oh, the very person
we're looking for.
Vroom, vroom, vroom.
- What's he doing?
- Oh, don't forget the clutch, dummy.
You said I could teach
him to drive your car today.
- I did?
- Yeah, you did.
No, that was before I
hooked up my new wheels.
- But...
- You have new wheels? Cool.
No, no, not cool.
I'm not gonna let some prepubescent
intern ding up my chick magnet.
Is it? For reals?
This car makes a statement.
And that statement is "I
am bringing sexy back."
- Sweet.
- Hello?
He's got his homecoming.
He wants to drive his date.
- Give the kid a break.
- What...?
Had to pull strings to get this. You
can't buy one of these babies yet.
I'll get you the number
of that new PACU nurse.
- The one from Nashville?
- I heard she was in the circus.
She does look flexible.
All right.
Okay, fine.
Now, let's see.
What are you doing?
A walk-around, make sure
it comes back the same.
- God, you're so anal.
- Pristine, beautiful, unblemished.
- Thank you, Dr. Morris.
- Now, let's run down a few things here.
- Harold, the brake.
- Hey, wait a minute.
Harold, Harold.
Be careful, Harold.
Stay aware of your surroundings.
It's all about peripheral... Uh!
What we're talking
about here is pain.
Proactively treating it right here
in Triage with you guys, all right?
Most of you know how to
use the Wong-Baker scale.
Any kid coming in, we
assess the pain from zero to 10.
Any score above zero,
we give them analgesia.
Put it on your charts.
Docs will be checking.
- Someone's been Moretti-sized.
- Mm-hm. Gates drank Kool-Aid.
- How old?
- Three months.
- She's been like this for hours.
- Okay.
- Fussy, crying.
- Probably the heat.
- Chuny, you take her back?
- I got this.
- Come on, follow me.
- It's never been this bad before.
- All right, here, check this out.
- Guys, stop goofing around.
- Victim of auto versus pedestrian.
- Possible blunt head trauma.
The car didn't hit me, I
walked into it. I told them that.
- What's with the backboard?
- Patient resisted treatment.
- I don't meet trauma center criteria.
- What do we have here?
- Combative on scene.
- I wasn't.
- Little bit, little bit.
- Because I don't need any of this.
- He might need a head CT.
- Definite possibility.
What? No, no, and I don't
need spinal immobilization.
No, you need an x-ray,
sir, before you take this off.
No, the hell you do,
and stop calling me sir.
Could be a distracting injury.
I'm gonna distract
your face with my foot.
Look. Huh? Huh? I'm fine.
All this wasted energy is seriously
inflating my carbon footprint.
- So are you refusing medical care, sir?
- Yes, yes, I am.
You're gonna sign a form indicating
you're leaving ER against medical advice?
You're wasting valuable
time and resources...
on this silly, little
comedy routine.
Stupid doors.
Next time that happens,
give him a Foley in the field.
Make sure your grandma follows
up with the clinic visits, okay, Jeffrey?
And a happy
L'shanah tova to you.
Oh, nice try. Jewish New
Year was two months ago.
- Oh, I got you your musicians.
- My what?
You said you wanted help brightening
up the place, alleviating the misery.
So, Ken and Willow
Monterey, this is Dr. Gates.
Oh, hello, thanks for having us.
This is our first time in the
ER. We're super excited.
We mostly perform in Pedes.
Love bringing joy
to the little people.
But this gives us a chance to
dig a bit deeper into the old set list.
Oh, good.
All right, well, make
yourself at home.
Where'd you find them, God Camp?
Oh, man, I almost forgot. Is
it...? It is. Today is the day.
- What day?
- D-day or Independence Day.
- Starting to sound like Stupid Day.
- Don't push me, Sam.
It's hot, I don't know
where my smart car is.
Greg and I get our
board results today.
I'm worried about him. I'm not
sure he hit the books hard enough.
- Hey, Vin Diesel, where's my car?
- Parked around the corner.
Gotta go to a laparotomy.
- Zelinsky, did you damage that vehicle?
- No, not that I know of.
Well, yeah, a little.
- What? NEELA: Tiny
ding on the fender.
- Miniscule.
- Gives it character.
- Personality.
- You'll hardly notice it, I gotta go.
Air conditioner broke
down at nursing home.
Victims with hyperthermia
and dehydration.
Another five coming in the van.
It turned our place into
Kentucky Fried Old Folks.
How you doing, sir?
I did not survive a pogrom, a
gulag and a bris in a back alley...
just so I could be
baked like a strudel.
This is J.J. Perkins, 80 years
old. ALOC, history of hypertension.
Previous MI, temp high of 104.
- Mr. Perkins.
- Thirsty.
Positive O sign. Not good.
Is he okay? We're roommates.
Hey, Grady, get some
more wheelchairs.
Power shortage, my ass.
The engineers are selling off
the energy to the highest bidder...
just like they
did in California.
You know who's
getting it all? The Pakis.
Hey, where'd they put my buddy?
Do you think our
apartment's too hot for her?
I can't say yet.
Any vomiting or diarrhea?
No, none of that.
Does anything help to calm her
down, car rides or noise machines?
She doesn't like
any noise, really.
Even music.
Well, I can't say I blame
her for that right now.
Our doctor thought it might be
reflux, so she ordered the scope test.
- Uh-huh. And?
- Everything came out normal.
Do you think it could be colic?
Well, we have to rule
out some other stuff first.
- How are you guys holding up?
- Um...
It's been kind of hard.
With the heat and the brownouts.
She just seems so
unhappy all the time.
It gets easier.
It does.
I'm gonna run this by
my supervisor. I'll be back.
Now, the next time that
the power goes out...
don't go using jumper
cables to juice up the a.c.
Where I went wrong was I had
the widescreen and massage chair...
hooked up to the same battery.
See you.
Three-month-old, intermittently
crying times three months.
The kid's whole life?
If it's been that long,
it's not an emergency.
The kid looks okay,
afebrile, alert, fontanel's flat...
no signs of injury,
and the exam's benign.
Of course it is. Exam's always
normal with babies like this.
I'll check it out
as soon as I can.
I got to take care of
this. Where is Gates?
No, more importantly,
where are our board results?
Oh, they're not in yet.
But the Vegas odds are
10-to-1 you both failed.
Tell Gates get rid
of Captain & Tenille.
We're healing people,
not driving them to suicide.
Are you nervous
about the results?
No. Are you?
No.
- You get those old folks all fixed up?
- Moretti ordered evaporative cooling.
I got Javier babysitting.
All right, let me know
if you need any help.
Patient was in his usual
state of excellent health...
until 1 p.m. today when he
got up from the living room...
Okay, stop. I'm bored and lost.
- You're gonna put him to sleep.
- But that's the history.
Yes, presented in
the most obtuse way.
- What do you think is wrong?
- Dehydration.
Okay, spit it out, so
Mussolini doesn't eat you alive.
And can you please
shoot me or shoot them?
I really don't care which.
- How's it going?
- It's weird.
- Hi.
- This music seems to be soothing her.
That is weird.
My supervisor's on his way
over. Okay, Grady, one more time.
Sixty-five-year-old man, syncopal
episode after skipping breakfast and lunch.
- I know what you're thinking.
- No chest pains, palpitation, headache.
That's what I'm talking about.
- Please, make them go away.
- I'm with her.
What do you want me to do?
Get rid of them. ALL: Yeah.
Guys, what they're doing
is a nice thing, okay?
And some people
actually like it.
Oh, yeah, what people?
Frank's not people.
I'll see what I can do.
Grady, break room. It's
time to present, come on.
Hey, here's an update, folks.
Green Line is down. Scattered
looting on the West Side.
We got two x-ray machines out.
The temperature in
the O.R. is 84 degrees.
And...
Oh, that's right, boys,
the test scores are in.
- What? MORRIS: What?
Why didn't you say so?
Stop playing games,
Frank. Here you go.
Hey.
You got us waiting like this.
So did the Medical Board make
another deadly error in judgment?
- Yes, they have, Frank, I passed.
- Yeah.
Congratulations.
Morris? Come on, baby.
Yeah, it's good, it's all good.
They passed, Morris and Pratt passed.
- My man, good stuff.
All right, after work,
drinks on me and Morris.
You stole her, didn't you?
- What?
- She's mine.
- Says who?
- Says me.
- Yeah, well, she came to me.
- Damn power.
I keep telling
you, it's the Pakis.
Oh, that's not nice, honey.
Chuny, how's Mrs. Lidner?
Down to 99. She's perking up.
Chest x-ray clear,
no hypernatremia.
Hey, you should see
this, J.J. It's very good.
What's it called again?
Grumpy Old Men.
- How's Mr. Perkins doing?
- Oh, he's fine.
Hey, he's better.
Leave him alone.
Minimally responsive.
Tachy to 130, having
some ectopy on the monitor.
Hey, we were hot and thirsty.
We don't need any
more witchy medicine.
Shh. MORRIS: Temp?
The cooling blanket didn't help.
He's still at 103.
Mr. Perkins?
Don't do that. What
are you doing to him?
- Neck's stiff, are we missing meningitis?
- Increased muscle tone.
Let's go, Trauma 2.
Blood cultures, two
milligrams Ceftriaxone.
- Get head a CT.
- You're not a doctor.
I want a real doctor.
You're just some quack.
- Calm down.
- He's gonna be all right, right?
Of course. Relax.
Is that it?
Worse when I press?
Or let go?
The same. DUBENKO: CT?
White count is 11.2.
Mildly inflamed appendix that
doesn't fill with oral contrast.
- Looks like early appendicitis.
- Oh, jeez, I need surgery?
Take it out laparoscopically,
you'll be back home.
Might we be jumping the gun here?
An alternate diagnosis to consider.
- It could be epiploic appendagitis.
- Rather unlikely, doctor.
- So in terms of the laparoscopic...
- He hasn't been vomiting.
He's got a normal white count.
No single sign, symptom or test confirms
the diagnosis of appendicitis, okay?
- As I was saying...
- Just hold the phone.
- CT isn't impressive.
- Dr. Zelinsky.
- Harold.
I'm onto something, he'll get
better with rest, nonsteroidals.
- He won't need surgery.
- So I don't need surgery?
That's not what we're saying.
His CT lacks all of the predictable
findings to support your theory, okay?
I don't want an unnecessary
operation. Are you sure?
Very sure. Dr. Rasgotra will
be back to consent for surgery.
- I'll see you in the
O.R. NEELA: Okay.
Thanks, Mary.
Dr. Dubenko, I'm interested in
why you think that the CT shows...
no signs of an
ovoid pericolic...
Shut up now.
Go round.
Drinks at Ike's on Morris
and Pratt. They passed.
- Wow, great.
- Uh-huh.
- I'd like to discuss Zelinsky's progress.
- Yeah, about that...
- Tomorrow, not now.
- Tomorrow?
I don't wanna say anything cruel,
which I'm at risk of doing at this moment.
So we'll talk about
Dr. Rain Man tomorrow.
Can you help me out
here, please, a little?
You want me to
fire the volunteers?
Yes, in a nice way.
Look, they love them in Pedes.
They're a hit in Oncology.
Why do you ER types
have to be such snobs?
Just do what God would do.
Cast these people out.
Nice, the mocking use of religious
imagery always works with me.
I'm just trying to speak to you
in a language you understand.
Bye.
Still having ectopy.
Three hundred amiodarone IV.
So chest pain in 3 should've
had an EKG and troponin.
But the resident
canceled the orders.
He's breathing. Sats okay.
Hey, Dawn, bring them in.
- What resident?
- Lockhart, did you sign off on it?
Must've been Pratt. I'm
sure there was a good reason.
What are you doing to J.J.?
Shh.
Mr. Lefkowitz, did Mr. Perkins
have any new pills at the home?
Always giving us pills. You
can't poop, they give you a pill.
Complain about the
government, you get a pill.
Can you be more specific?
Try to get people to vote for
Obama, they got a pill for that too.
Papi, listen. Did they
give J.J. anything today?
He got feisty, because
it was so hot in there.
Does this look
familiar? How about this?
Maybe this, it was yellow.
Bingo, Haloperidol.
I bet he's got neuroleptic
malignant syndrome.
- Interesting theory.
- Dantrolene, a hundred milligrams IV.
I'm pretty sure
what we have here...
is a beautiful, healthy little
girl with a bad case of colic.
That's what the
pediatrician said.
Is there nothing you can do?
No medicines you can give her?
No, you just
have to wait it out.
But it's too hot to keep
her all wrapped up like that.
A book said to do that
when she gets fussy.
Not in this weather. Feel the
blanket, she sweated right through it.
That's normal. She gets all
worked up when she feeds.
Well, just hang in there.
A nurse will be back with your
discharge paperwork. Abby?
Do me a favor. Get some kind of referral
for new parenting group or something.
That's it? You don't wanna
do any more workup?
For colic? No, why?
- There's no need, it's classic.
- Well, it's not classic, actually.
When I worked in OB, we did a lot
of anticipatory guidance about this.
Colic doesn't usually
start until six weeks of life.
- Baby's been fussy since birth.
- Hasn't killed her.
But the sweating when
she feeds could be an...
It's a million degrees outside.
Her parents keep her wrapped up.
I have a feeling...
Look, this is a long-term preexisting
condition with no signs of abuse.
Let them follow up
with the pediatrician.
And, Abby, relax, okay?
You're now talking to a
board-certified attending.
You still have to
take the oral boards.
Nothing but a mere technicality.
See you at Ike's?
So we done with them?
- The Birk baby?
- Um, yeah.
Hey, wait, no. Sorry.
Hold on, I just wanna
check one more thing.
Hey, you coming out tonight?
It's Brownout Thursday at Ike's.
- Drinks half price if you bring a candle.
- I thought Pratt and Morris were buying.
Only a round. Cheap bastards.
- Come on, let loose for a night.
- I'll think about it.
Your a.c. is putting out air at
77 degrees through this duct.
You mean, it's working?
But it's 62 degrees
at the compressor.
That's a lot of waste.
Hey, Frank, what's going on?
Oh, the green Nazis are here.
Oh, you must be
the energy manager.
Ethan Mackiner. And you are?
Sam Taggart, charge
nurse. I spoke to your office.
We made sure to change all the
incandescents for compact fluorescents.
- We're down to 30-foot candles.
- That's very green of you.
Just doing our part.
Maybe you can show me
where the utility access is.
Sure. Come with me.
I'm going out back and burn
some tires with kerosene.
You good with that?
I'm leaving these for Sam.
You're out of here already?
What about the party?
God, it's like junior
high around here.
Hi. Bye.
Shift over already?
Pratt's up to speed on my stuff.
Your intern presented to me.
Did he forget to kiss the ring?
No, in fact, Grady
was letter-perfect.
Which I'm sure had absolutely
nothing to do with you.
Absolutely nothing.
Doctor.
- Doctor.
- Yeah.
I understand you've been
canceling my preemptive orders.
In selected cases, I have, yes.
On what criteria?
A 20-year-old with epigastric
pain from ibuprofen...
doesn't need CBC,
chem panel, UA.
He needs to be sent
home with some antacid.
That's an exception.
I mean, the system is the
system, and the system is working.
Yeah, not for me.
I didn't go to med school to
check boxes and push paper.
When are you gonna stop
with the end-runs, huh?
Huh? I mean, what is it?
Feel comfortable with Dr. Pratt
because you've worked with him?
Or is this just like the
path of least resistance?
Or is it simply you
just don't like me?
What?
You know, it doesn't matter.
- What, if I like you or not?
- No, forget it.
No, I don't like you.
You know what?
You do whatever the
hell you want, okay?
And I hope it all
works out for you.
Folks, local power grid
might be going down.
But don't worry, we're prepared.
Somebody gonna make
a toast or something?
Nobody's saying anything until
my partner in crime gets here.
Oh, and by the way, I know
I'm still on, so this is 7 and 7.
Minus one of the sevens.
Can you guess which one?
Hey, here he is. ALL: Hey.
I can't stay long. Somebody's
gotta mind the store.
Well, then allow me.
We are gonna talk later. I
saw what you did to my car.
- Is he mad at me?
- No. He is.
Fair amount of failures as well.
But I think it's important that we all
reflect and appreciate the milestones.
So I would like to be the first to
congratulate Dr. Pratt and Dr. Morris...
who will become newly-minted,
soon to be board-certified...
Attending emergency physicians.
This chaplain thing is
really more of a hobby.
My true passion
is hustling pool.
I see.
You know, I gotta tell you.
To be honest with you, you don't
really strike me as the chaplain type.
And why is that?
I don't know, you don't look the part.
The way you dress, your vibe, your tat.
Oh, I have lots of tats.
- Oh, yeah?
- Mm-hm.
What is that one?
It's a labyrinth. It's a pretty
common symbol, actually.
In the Native American
culture and the Vedas.
The Minoans use it too.
It represents
life's real journey.
The spiritual journey
to the inner self.
Reminds me every day that I
have to constantly be seeking.
And how easy it is to get lost.
Have you been lost?
Haven't you?
So, what other tats you got?
- Harold was just trying to impress you.
- I thought we weren't gonna talk now.
I don't understand
why you don't like him.
- He's unshaped, he's immature...
- Smart.
That's not enough.
He's a little rough
around the edges.
But instead of getting hung
up about the presentation...
we should start commending
him on the insight.
And by we, I, of
course, mean you.
He's not ready to be a
surgeon on my team, Neela.
Lucien, he wants
to be here so badly.
And I believe he can do it.
You really wanna
mentor this kid?
Well, if you agree
not to kick him out.
Give me a month?
It's not just about turning
him into a doctor, Neela.
It's about turning
him into an adult.
Do you understand that?
Oh, hey, guys, looks
like I'm getting kicked out.
Check you on the flip side.
Okay, you got a month.
It's weird to think of Morris
and Pratt as the top of the heap.
I still remember when Mark Greene
and Doug Ross were running the place.
Who?
- Hey, Sam.
- Hey.
I came over as soon as I
was done with my evaluation.
- This is Chuny.
- Hi.
- And Dawn.
- Hey.
- Nice to meet you.
- Need anything from the bar?
- No, I'm good.
Apple martini.
Coming up.
Hello?
- What?
- What's up with the fine brother?
He wanted to see if I wanted
to have a drink after work...
What about your hunky beat cop?
- You sly dog.
- No, no, no, it's not like that.
Just...
You know that time in your life when
you're in your teens or your early 20s?
You know, when you
get to look around...
see what you like and
what you don't like?
You mean, like positions?
No, like, well, I
never had that.
And I think I should.
So now is my chance.
You know what I mean?
- Oh, yeah, we know what you mean.
- Mm-hm.
The boy in the blue
wasn't hitting that buzzer.
Guys, that's not true.
Apple martini.
I miss something?
Let's hope you don't.
Excuse me. Hey, hey, hey,
is this where the party is?
Hey, you made it. - Hey, girl.
Hey. ABBY: Hey.
Abby, what's happening? - Hey.
It does not look
very festive in here.
- Better.
- Oh, no, no, no.
- Do I have to?
Frank.
I love Frank.
Frank never misses a party.
- Yeah.
- Where you been?
Nowhere.
Sam. SAM: Yes?
You look fantastic.
- Oh, I do?
- You look so hot.
Oh, yeah.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
You're getting some, aren't you?
You are.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Who's he? Who are you?
Ethan, Ethan Mackiner. I work
for the county as an energy...
Rowr.
Hello.
Look at his eyes.
He's very sincere. Hey.
Congratulations.
- All right, let's get you some coffee.
- Oh, no.
Thank you. No, thank you, boss.
It's a night to
celebrate, right? Right?
Tonight is a night
to celebrate, right?
- Am I right, Chuny?
- You are right.
What...?
What is Chuny short for, anyway?
Nothing, just Chuny.
Actually, my real name is Ethel.
- Get out.
- I'm serious.
Frank, put that hat back on.
Abby.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Uh-oh. Surgeons are here.
You guys better be careful,
because you are outnumbered.
And if there's a throw
down, we will kick your ass.
Oh, is there gonna
be a throw down?
You never know, Lucien.
You never know.
Heads up.
Nice.
- Um. Who wants a drink?
- No, I'm good.
Anybody?
What's up? It's
a party, cheer up.
- Is she all right?
- Yeah, just blowing off some steam.
Hey, hey, hey.
Hi.
I didn't expect to see you here.
Oh, well, yeah, I...
I had a babysitter, so I just
figured, you know, what the hell?
Can I get something, please?
Hey, look, about before...
You shouldn't do that, you know.
What?
What you've been doing.
What have I been doing?
Playing a tyrant,
and then flirting.
Flirting?
Yeah, you should stop that.
Okay.
I was not aware
that I was flirting.
I'm not stupid, you know.
No, I know, I never
said you were stupid.
Okay, good, because I get it.
And you come in here on your
white horse, and you just figure...
What?
What do I figure?
Nothing.
You just figure.
- Abby, hey.
- Hey.
I just got paged back on the Birk
baby. She's been screaming for an hour.
Parents are threatening
to sign out AMA.
- Who?
- The baby we saw.
Oh. Yes, sorry. That's her prerogative,
their prerogative, their prerogative.
You were supposed
to discharge them.
Now, instead, they're waiting on studies
someone ordered without my permission.
Studies that this
kid doesn't need.
Now, do you have any
idea who could've done that?
Was it me?
You know what?
Let's take this outside.
Okay.
Okay, if I ordered tests, I'm sure
I had a very good reason, Greg.
- Even if you don't remember it?
- I remember it, I just...
What's the big deal? Chest
film shouldn't take this long.
It does when half the x-ray
machines in the hospital are down.
You totally disregarded my
instructions to send these people home.
Okay, power trip, what do you
want? I'll go over there, discharge them.
What? No, you can't be serious.
It's your party.
Cry if you want to.
- I'll take care of it.
- No, no, no.
- What? Get off me.
- You're not going in the ER like this.
Like what?
- Hey.
- Like what? Huh?
What?
You know, I don't know
what your problem is...
but you should really take
a cab home right now, really.
Whatever.
Both guests of honor are
gone. This place is kind of dead.
I know a little blues place
over by Northwestern.
I know where we can go.
There's a place. Salsa
nights on Thursdays.
Now you're talking.
Hey, hey, hey, Abby.
We're getting ready
to go somewhere else.
You wanna come?
No, I'm just gonna finish
this and get out of here.
- You sure?
- Yeah, but have fun.
Did you drive here?
- No.
- Okay.
I got his attention.
Oh...
Thank you.
- Everything okay?
- Yes, work thing, we fixed it.
- So where's your husband? He's in...?
- Croatia.
Croatia?
- How much longer is he gonna be there?
- Oh, you have to ask him that.
Because he was supposed
to be home weeks ago.
It's hard to...
It's complicated to balance the whole,
you know, the kids and the spouse.
You wanna hear about a
complicated life? I will make you cry.
- Really?
- I'm not kidding.
Really?
Sorry.
- Look, what you said before, when you...
- Yeah, forget about it, I...
Listen to me. I'm an asshole.
I know.
- You're not, you're not.
- Well, just forget about it, really.
- All right, all right.
- Okay?
- It's a good thing about Pratt and Morris.
- Yes.
- It's good.
- Here's to Pratt and Morris.
Yup, Pratt and Morris.
- Sorry, sir. No problem.
- Sorry about that.
We ain't closing for no stinking blackout
either, all right? Next round's on me.
Damn.
Power's back.
This family shouldn't
even be here.
Well, plan was
chest x-ray, an EKG...
and then discharge if the
studies are normal, right?
That was Abby's plan, not mine.
How's she doing?
She's been sweating and breathing
really fast ever since I fed her.
- She's retracting. MORRIS:
And really diaphoretic.
No fever, her temp's normal.
You guys better check this out.
Heart's big.
Lungs are wet. She's in failure.
- What's the sat?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
- I'll do one now.
So all this started happening
after she had a bottle?
Sweating with feeds is
a sign of heart disease.
- What's going on?
- You're confusing us.
Tell us what's going on.
Heart's not pumping strong,
fluid's backing up into her lungs.
- She doesn't have an IV?
- She was going home.
- Get me an IV kit.
- And where's the EKG Abby ordered?
- I haven't done it yet.
- We're moving to 1.
- I don't know your name...
- Tiffany.
- That EKG was ordered hours ago.
- We didn't have neonatal leads.
- I called Central supply.
- Central takes forever.
You can't wait for
them. Run to NICU, run.
- Get those leads and get back here.
- Where did you find that one?
You don't wanna have a glass of
water, a cup of coffee, something?
No, I gotta go.
- I gotta go.
- Yeah.
What happened?
How did I get here?
Well, I mean...
Look, why don't you stay for a little
bit? Don't drive right now, it's late.
- I don't think you should go, wait.
- I gotta go.
- Wait a minute.
- I gotta go to Joe.
What are you doing? Don't.
All right, sorry.
Dr. Morris?
Is she...?
- Sure the leads aren't reversed?
- I checked three times.
- Look at the lateral leads.
- Oh, damn.
Call Cards. We're on our way up.
Blood flow to your baby's heart's
been compromised. We're not sure how.
An EKG shows the classic
pattern of an acute MI.
- An MI? What's an MI?
- Your daughter's having a heart attack.
- Let's go.
- Oh, God.
We're taking her to cath lab.
We're gonna do everything.
You told us to go home.
You said we should go home.
Why did you tell us to leave?
He told us to go home.
I don't know, officer.
I don't know.
Okay. It's okay, she's home now.
- Doris, I'm really sorry, I'm so sorry.
- It's almost 3 in the morning.
I know, I'm really sorry.
And you can go now.
But he...
He slept the whole
time, right? He just slept?
Are you okay? What's the matter?
Here you go, just take that.
Take that and take that.
And you can go now. Take that.
Maybe I should stay.
You're worrying me.
No, I'm okay, hon. I'm fine.
- I can call my mother, tell her I won't...
- Oh, my God, please get out of here.
Hi, hi.
Hey, Joe.
Hey, buddy.
How you doing?
We're gonna go
see your daddy, huh?
It's gonna be okay.
All right, sweetie.
It's all right.
It's okay. It's okay, honey.
It's okay.
Hey, taxi.
I'm going to O'Hare.
International. Ow!
Lady, you can't hold
the kid like that in here.
It's okay, just go.
Go.
Croatia, please. Zagreb, Dubrovnik,
whatever, just get me there.
- Ma'am...
- Do you go through London or Frankfurt?
- London, but...
- London it is.
- Ma'am, there are no flights...
- Just get me a ticket.
- The blackout, it's affected our flight...
- Give me a ticket.
- It doesn't have to be for right now.
- Calm down.
No, you need to do your
job and sell me a ticket, okay?
Ma'am, you need to relax
before we can do anything.
Don't understand
what's so hard about this.
I have a passport and
I have a credit card.
I'm not a terrorist. Do
I look like a terrorist?
- She's been drinking.
- Why'd you have to be bitchy?
Okay, you can't call me a bitch.
- I didn't. TICKET
AGENT: You did.
- I said bitchy, not the same thing.
- Okay, here's how this is gonna go.
You won't be getting a ticket...
or boarding a flight as long
as you keep behaving like this.
I want you to sit over
there, get yourself together...
so I don't have
to call security.
Got me?
Keep the urine alkaline and
recheck labs in another six hours.
I'll let the ICU know.
You'll have your
roommate back tomorrow.
He doesn't trust lawyers,
accountants, anybody with a degree.
But he appreciates what you did.
Oh, yeah...
As doctors go, you seem
to be a pretty decent one.
So thanks.
Hey, just got back
from the cath lab.
Baby was born with an
anomalous left main coronary.
Blood was getting
diverted into the GI tract.
The heart gets shafted, which
explains the fussiness after feeds.
She was having
angina. They can fix it?
Well, she's in the O.R. now.
Cards said the prognosis was good.
- Guess we got lucky.
- Yeah, we got lucky.
I don't remember any questions like
this on the boards. Coffee's on you.
Looks like we
survived the blackout.
Yup, the news said
Commonwealth Edison...
has got it all under control.
I failed, Greg.
What?
Oh...
- Why didn't you say something?
- I was ashamed.
It happened so fast. Everybody
was so psyched for us.
Look, man, the only thing that this test
measures is how well you take the test.
It doesn't mean you
can't keep working.
You just have to
take it again, come on.
Well, in the meantime, maybe
we can keep this between us?
- Not tell anybody?
- Yeah, if that's what you want.
- Oh, man.
- Especially Abby.
She coached me a little on the side.
I had some family stuff a while back.
- I kind of feel like I let her down.
- I'm sure she wouldn't see it that way.
But, okay, we won't tell anyone.
Thank God for Abby, huh?
She saved that kid's life.
Yeah, thank God for Abby.