Previously on New Amsterdam...
His name was Muhammad.
He asked me to marry him.
You broke up? Brain aneurysm.
I still miss him.
I told you about the songs I'm
writing? Well, I'd love to make a demo.
I was wondering if you
could... Give you money?
I don't think it's a good idea.
I have plans with Ella.
Ella? Thanks for introducing us.
I've been taking a little bit
more Adderall than prescribed.
I think that I need to report
an impaired physician.
Don't forget to go over the rib.
The vein, the artery and
the nerve run under, okay?
All right. Here we go.
What you got?
EMS notification,
diabetic coma on the way.
Ooh, sounds interesting.
I thought you had a VIP patient.
Ah, that's after my shift.
I've got time to take one more.
Of course you do.
Allison Medrano, 68-year-old
fishing boat captain
with type two diabetes. Rescued
by Coast Guard, unconscious.
Finger stick blood sugar, 745.
She's received 10 units sub-Q
times four, but she's still unresponsive.
Found these in her pocket.
Diabetes meds prescribed
by a Dr. Jessica Medrano.
She's a primary
care doctor here.
This could be her mom.
Let's page Max and Dr. Medrano,
and let's get her into Trauma One.
What are you doing?
Do you see that man?
He's my son.
And you hiding all the
way over here because?
If you believe two people are
together for the wrong reason,
it's your responsibility
to... Oh, no, no, no.
No. No. I'm gonna
stop you right there.
See, as a rule, I
don't do family drama.
So, if you wanna talk about
that, I recommend you talk to Iggy.
Iggy is busy all day, and
there is no family drama.
Then why are you hiding?
Because I need
to see if my son is...
No, no. No family drama, man.
Look, my only advice for you,
stay out of your boy's dating life.
Hey, you want a coffee, Vijay?
Blood pH of 7.19.
Blood sugar still over 700.
Injecting 10 more
units of insulin.
Mom. Hey.
Can I get some water?
Uh, absolutely.
Uh. Casey? On it.
Ms. Medrano, you're at
New Amsterdam Hospital,
and I will be happy to answer
any questions you might have.
Where's my boat?
Except for that one. I... I
don't know what that means.
Ah, she's captain
of a fishing boat.
Seriously?
What? You expecting
a peg leg and a parrot?
No, but, uh, that'd be cool.
I just didn't realize there were
any of you left in New York City.
There's not. Industry
moved on, she didn't.
Huh.
Fishing boat captain in
New York City. That's...
That's a throwback.
What an interesting job.
Mmm-hmm.
Excuse me.
He, uh, does that sometimes.
Nourishment Consultant,
Media Distribution Officer,
pneumatic tube repair?
What do these people even do?
Aren't you the Medical Director?
Aren't you supposed to know?
Oh!
Hello.
Has anyone here
ever met a chiropodist?
Of course you haven't,
because they don't exist.
But 100 years ago, there
was a whole department
full of them cutting
people's toenails.
But the field evolved and
chiropody was absorbed into podiatry.
Chiropodists became obsolete.
Why are we talking
about chiropodists?
Because you're firing us?
No.
We're talking about chiropodists
not just because it's a
really fun word to say,
but because I'm willing to bet
that right here, at New Amsterdam,
there are people whose jobs
are obsolete, bogus, wasted.
Jobs that aren't
really jobs at all.
But just because your job is
obsolete, doesn't mean you are.
Wait. Are you firing us? No.
I wanna find people whose
talents are being wasted
and give them meaningful work. I
wanna give them jobs that matter.
Every time a patient
walks out our doors,
our people should
feel like they contributed
to that patient's
success. And no...
I am not firing anybody.
Every department is
gonna try this experiment.
Just for one day, stop working.
Just sit there, stand
there, don't do anything.
And if nobody misses what you do
or needs you to do
something for one whole day,
then your job may be obsolete.
Clearly not talking
about those people.
But if it is you, come to me.
I wanna find you a new job.
A job that inspires you, a
job that makes a difference,
a job that makes you an integral
part of New Amsterdam's mission.
Dr. Panthaki?
Dr. Sharpe.
Fancy meeting you here.
Yeah. Well, no.
No?
Uh, I came here to see a patient,
and I thought I'd stop by and say hi.
I walked by your office, but
they said you were on the floor,
so here I am,
casually bumping into you,
accidentally on purpose.
I see.
I can also accidentally
on purpose leave.
No, I'm glad that you
decided to stop by.
Accidentally on purpose.
And would you consider
joining me on an adventure?
An adventure?
It's a small adventure.
Do you like Radiohead?
Yes. Love them.
Then we'll need to be on a train
from Penn Station in a few hours.
Why? Where are we going?
Philadelphia.
So, we'd be staying overnight?
We would be.
You know, yeah, no, I can't
do that right now, with you.
Okay. I mean,
I want to eventually,
but I'm just...
Helen, I'll make you a bootleg.
Well, I'm still not 100% sure
as to why Ms. Medrano
collapsed on the ship.
Did her blood sugar spike
before or after her fall?
That's the million
dollar question.
So, this must be some VIP for
you to drag me all the way up here.
It is.
So, who's the patient?
You are.
Yeah. Hey! Dora!
Hold on.
I just wanna take in this
momentous occasion.
What... What occasion?
The day you chased after me.
I wanna remember
everything. What I was wearing.
Where I was standing...
You haven't texted me.
Nope. Or paged me.
Did you miss me?
Well, I just figured
by now people would...
People would admit that they
were getting paid to not work?
That's not exactly... And that
they would ask you for work,
when they could just
keep on doing nothing.
That's not really in the
spirit of what I'm trying...
If it was me, no
way I'd tell you.
Max.
What's going on
with, um, you know?
She's with Iggy.
I think I'm gonna be sick.
You did the right thing.
As a doctor, sure. But as a
friend, I absolutely did not.
You absolutely did.
As a doctor, and as a friend.
All right. Feel free to sit.
I'm fine.
Okay.
All right.
So, it says here
you went to Whitman College.
Yep.
All the way up in Walla
Walla, Washington, huh?
Did you like it?
Loved it.
Why there?
Well, I guess it's because I
thought that they would prepare me
for a career in
lifesaving medicine.
One which I would love
to get back to right now,
unless you're gonna tell
me what this is all about.
Okay.
Somebody reported that you
have a problem with Adderall.
Sharpe.
I'm not at liberty to
discuss that with you.
Please.
So, do you?
Do I what?
Do you have a
problem with Adderall?
No. Okay.
Do you have any idea why
someone would suggest that you do?
Look, I spoke to Sharpe
about a personal matter,
a minor personal matter,
and she has blown it
way out of proportion.
Right, well,
can you tell me about
the personal matter?
No.
Why not?
Because it's personal.
And because quite
frankly, this whole ambush
is unbelievably insulting, and
I'm done pretending like it isn't.
I wouldn't do that.
I have been empowered
by the hospital to determine
if you've been operating
as an impaired physician.
And if you have a problem with Adderall,
I will tell Max and he'll report it
to the medical board.
So, what, if I leave,
I'm suspended?
No, if you leave, you're fired.
Dr. Reynolds. Dr. Goodwin.
I need a consult.
What's the case?
Allison Medrano, let's just call
her a "non-compliant diabetic."
Hemoglobin A1C off the chart?
Yeah, and I wanna make sure her collapse
wasn't due to a silent heart attack.
Okay, I'll stop by after
the rounds. Thank you.
Oh, by the way, heard about
your speech this morning.
You got someone for
me in your department?
No, everyone in my
department is on overdrive.
But did you know there's a guy in
the basement who still prints X-rays?
X-rays?
Went digital a decade ago.
Well, that's why you
should check on him.
Hello?
Need an X-ray?
Does that thing still work?
What, the XR180? Oh, yeah.
And I like to keep it nice
and shiny, just in case.
When was the last time someone
ordered an old-fashioned X-ray from you?
Uh, 2008, give or take.
So, you just been
down here since 2008?
Doing what?
Am I about to get fired?
Do you like your job?
Oh. I used to.
I loved it, actually.
Everybody needed me.
Docs used to say nobody handled
radiograph paper better than I did.
I'm Max Goodwin, I'm
the Medical Director here.
Oh, nuts.
I am gonna get fired. No.
No, I'd like to
find you a new job.
A job that makes
you feel needed again.
Would you be interested?
It's like you can
see right through me.
It's an X-ray joke. X-ray joke.
It's great. What do you say?
You know, with technology being
what it is and me being as old as I am,
I think I'm just gonna
ride it out until retirement.
I mean, if you're not firing me.
Rohan.
Papa.
You came all the way down here
and won't say namaste to your father?
I didn't wanna bother you.
Bother? No, no.
I want to apologize
to you, beta.
For what?
I, know I've hurt
your feelings before,
when I refused to
support your music.
I should have been
more supportive of you.
That doesn't mean that you
use Ella to get back at me.
What?
Yeah, she doesn't need to be
dragged into our family business.
Is that what you
think is going on?
That I'm using her? I
am trying to protect her.
Excuse me.
I'm hanging out with Ella
because I actually like her.
Not that it's any
of your business.
I think you are
misunderstanding me.
No, I'm understanding
you just fine.
And I know it's hard for
you to comprehend, Papa,
but the reason I could stay
sober for a year was that
I didn't have to
deal with this. I...
I didn't have to deal with you.
Jessica, you should move
back to Sheepshead Bay.
Mom, I'd love to,
but my job is here.
You know, most parents would
be proud their kid's a doctor.
Well, there's something
to be said about tradition.
Our family has a tradition...
Of diabetes, heart
disease, lung cancer.
People gotta die of something.
Allison Medrano, I need
you to get back inside.
Who the hell are
you? Your doctor.
Since when? Well,
since you had to be
evaluated for heart disease.
Dr. Medrano. Dr. Reynolds,
thank you for taking
care of my mom.
I don't need taking care of.
We're gonna do a full workup,
but I need you to get
back inside first, all right?
Yeah, yeah. Mom.
Mom! Hold on. Hold on.
I need a stretcher out here!
Okay.
You get what's
ironic about this?
No. Help me out.
I have a prescription
for Adderall.
I mean, the risk would be in
me not taking my medication.
You know, I'd be, like,
mid appendectomy,
getting distracted by
how the appendix looks
like a giant shrimp.
So, you find it ironic
that you've been placed in jeopardy
by a tool that helps you succeed?
No. No, I find it ironic
that I'm being persecuted
by a psychiatrist for taking a
medication prescribed by a psychiatrist.
That was harsh. I know
you're not persecuting me.
It's okay. It's fine.
It's just...
I've got ADHD.
I've taken Adderall, as
prescribed, since I was 12.
It's a nonissue.
Yeah.
And you've never taken more
than your prescribed dose?
I'm sure I have doubled
up by accident, okay?
Double shifts, the days,
they can just run in together.
But you've never
taken it just to...
You know, just to
get through the day?
No. Hard no.
You sure about that?
You can't run an ED
propped up on pills, okay?
It's unethical and
I wouldn't do it.
So, your drug use has never
led to the harm of a patient?
Oh, you know what?
I've killed thousands.
I just... I get high and I start
stabbing people with my scalpel.
This isn't personal, Bloom.
I'm not trying to insult you.
You're asking me if I've ever risked
a patient's life because I'm stoned.
Yeah, and you haven't
answered the question.
Because if I had, we
wouldn't be here right now.
I would have turned
in my license, okay?
No, I have never harmed a
patient because of Adderall.
Do you remember LaDavius Powell?
LaDavius Powell?
That ring a bell?
It's a patient of yours that
came in, allergic to Cephalkem.
You prescribed it anyway.
If your nurse hadn't
have caught the mistake...
No, that's not the whole story.
So... No?
Earlier you assumed that
it was one single doctor
that voiced concern.
That's not the case.
Multiple people have complained
that you're having problems.
You're making mistakes
on your patient reports.
Your reaction time has slipped.
Your behavior has been erratic.
And this mistake you made
with LaDavius Powell could have
very easily cost him his life.
And now, you've sat there
and looked me in the eyes,
and you've lied to me about it.
What part of the
story am I missing?
What have I got wrong?
You said, in your own words,
if your drug use ever led
to the harm of a patient,
you would turn in your license.
So, what are you waiting for?
It's okay. I've got this.
Right.
Oh, boy. She was smoking.
Collapsed with a blood sugar of over 700.
It took 100 units of
insulin to bring her back.
So, it's the high blood sugar.
Well, we still don't know
why it keeps spiking.
What if it's the smoking?
Yeah, smoking's bad for you.
What if she has a carcinoid
tumor being stimulated by nicotine?
Just now when she
collapsed, she was smoking.
On the boat when she
What if the nicotine from the
cigarettes is squeezing the tumor,
making it kick out huge
amounts of glucagon,
and that is what is driving the
blood sugar through the roof?
Well, I did a CT on AI's abdomen
and her chest, and no tumor.
But all of her
symptoms point to it.
Except it's not there.
So, do exploratory
surgery and find it.
Who does exploratory
surgery anymore?
We do when we know
something's wrong.
Mr. Harris.
Pardon me? Ah, you're from
the Med Co-Op Group, right?
Actually, I'm just...
Uh, I've been
here for nine years.
I kept you waiting that long?
No.
Uh, I heard your speech today.
I think I've got one
of those obsolete jobs.
So, uh, what's your
job? To sit there.
Before the arm showed up, I sat
in a booth and checked badges.
I was the guy you
said good morning to,
asked about the traffic
down from Westchester.
Always packed on the FTR,
no matter what time of day.
But go down Second
Ave before 7:00 a.m.,
not so bad. Good to know.
But since the arm, people
don't even notice me.
I wanna do more than
sit in a chair all day.
I know I can do more.
See, you're exactly
who I'm looking for.
Uh, Dr. Goodwin...
No, you are the reason
I started this
search. Dr. Goodwin.
Yeah? You're in her way.
Sorry. So what's my
new job gonna be?
I have no idea.
So, now what?
Well, now I'd like to
hear about your life before
your Adderall use began.
Are you seriously asking me
to talk about my childhood?
Or I could just file
my report right now.
Fine.
Well, my mom was a disaster,
my sister, worse, and
my dad was a saint.
There you go.
Okay, well, how was
your mom a disaster?
She was an alcoholic.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, well, "boo-hoo," right?
She was, uh...
She was part of this...
This tacky nouveau riche
Upper East Side crowd.
Everybody knew she drank.
But it didn't matter,
'cause Jeanie was so fun.
Her parties were fabulous.
Yeah, but then the
party ended, right?
Yeah.
That it did.
Then she'd start complaining.
About how Mr. Benson
wouldn't flirt with her,
or how the Dover sole was dry.
Always something.
And she'd get mean.
Was there physical abuse?
No.
Would she get sick
after she drank?
Yeah?
Who'd take her to
bed? Who'd clean up?
That'd be me.
What about your
sister? She help?
I didn't need help.
Someone had to clean
her up, so I cleaned her up.
How old were you the
first time that happened?
I don't know.
Ballpark.
Seven, maybe.
Oh.
You've been taking care of people long
before you became an ED doctor, huh?
Yeah.
Well, that's the silver lining of
having Hurricane Jeanie for a mom.
You learn how to
be good in a crisis.
Yeah, I bet.
Sounds like your dad left
you in quite a tricky situation.
I didn't say that.
No.
You didn't say
much about him at all.
My dad...
My dad took a two-bit
dermatology practice
and he turned it into a
million-dollar business.
That's amazing.
Yeah, he was gone a lot,
but when I called,
he always answered. Every time.
So, you can dial back the
Freudian horse-crap, okay?
There's nothing Freudian about
saying that he neglected you.
He was an amazing dad.
He wasn't the alcoholic.
He wasn't the one
pissing on the carpet.
vomiting on himself.
No, he was the one who left a
second-grader alone to deal with it.
Because he knew what
you already told me.
Someone always
has to clean it up.
You just described him as an
emotionally closed-off workaholic
who was in complete denial
that his personal life was on fire.
Who does that sound like?
Dr. Goodwin. Yeah?
I've been emailing the powers
that be at New Amsterdam
about my useless job for
years. And nothing. No response.
I don't even feel bad
about taking a paycheck
for doing nothing anymore,
but you should know that
because I tried to contact someone,
New Amsterdam legally
can't take that money back.
I wouldn't even try, but
what's your obsolete job?
Tech. Cool.
In the accounting
department. Ah!
Whenever FlashPay has
any kind of software update,
it's my job to install it
on every single computer
throughout the whole hospital.
That sounds like a very important job.
It was five years ago, when New
Amsterdam still used FlashPay.
Now only one person in
the whole hospital uses it.
Who's that? Me.
When I update it
on all the computers.
I'll find you a new job. Great.
So, what'll that be? No idea.
Systolic 140, pulse ox 97.
Popcorn on a stick.
- Lap sponge.
Wet wrap the whole tip.
You see anything?
Nothing. We visualized
the entire abdomen.
Yeah.
I can't believe we let
Dr. Goodwin talk us into this.
He thought a carcinoid
tumor fit all her symptoms.
Well, he was wrong.
Fresh ESU pencil on the tray.
I'm gonna run the bowel.
All 23 feet of it? Yep.
Then you're crazier than he is.
Hey, man of the hour.
Your son is the sweetest.
We have been
having the best time.
We're gonna go to
Battery Park tonight.
Yes.
About Rohan...
It appears I may have hurt
my son's feelings this morning.
Oh.
Unintentionally, of course,
but I wanted to clear things up
before you heard
his side of the story.
There are sides?
Not exactly. It's just...
I was looking out
for you, you see?
Uh, trying to protect you.
Why would I need protecting?
I was concerned that my son had
taken an interest in you simply to...
To hurt me.
Why would you think that?
Because of a
disagreement we had.
Or because you don't think
your son could be interested
in someone like me?
Well, no, I just...
Because you actually thought
the only reason Rohan would
ever be interested in me is if he
was using me to get back at you?
No, that's not what I meant.
Well, you must have meant it on
some level or you wouldn't have said it.
I fear there has been a
profound misunderstanding here...
No, I think I heard
you loud and clear.
Hi. Welcome to Pain
de Vie. Excuse me.
Hi.
I'll get a small latte.
Sure. Is whole milk okay?
You know, this is why
no one likes therapists.
You're taking my
life and you're...
You're twisting it around.
Okay, well, then help me
out. Tell me a different story.
Help me understand.
All right, how about this?
Dad saved himself from
an impossible situation.
No, he was not perfect,
but I never doubted
that he loved me.
So, you can come at me all day, but
I'm not blaming him for my mistakes.
I'm not blaming him
for your mistakes, either.
He did the best he could,
for as long as he could.
Did you hear me? I'm not
blaming him for your mistakes.
Okay, so why the hell are
we still talking about this?
Because you went to Whitman
College in Walla Walla, Washington.
You literally could have
gone anywhere else,
but you went all the
way across the country.
Family psychological histories
are a lot like genetic ones,
and you have the
gene for running.
So, I'm asking you,
what are you running from?
You're right.
I'm like my dad.
We both ran.
And yeah, he was
running from my mom.
But I am not running
from, I am running to.
I'm an ED doctor.
I run to crisis.
I mean, I run to help people.
And yeah, you know what?
My childhood, it sucked.
But it made me who I am.
And this hospital
is lucky to have me.
Okay.
Thank you for that.
Do you think you can get
your Adderall under control?
Yes.
And do you think that
practicing medicine
is the best thing
for your recovery?
I know it is.
Okay then.
Get back out there.
You're clear.
Go show them how it's done.
Lauren?
Lauren.
I didn't know what else to do.
No problem. I was cleared.
Clevidipine infusion rate,
one milligram per hour.
Balfour retractor standing by.
She is so stubborn.
Show me a kid who doesn't
think their parents are stubborn.
She's overweight, diabetic and
spends most of her time chain-smoking,
eating fried foods and drinking.
Hmm. And she has no
intention of ever changing.
That's problematic.
That's a recipe for disaster.
I'm the only one
telling her to stop.
The rest of her buddies
out in Sheepshead Bay,
they all have the
same bad habits.
Maybe they all
need a little attention.
They need a swift
kick in the pants.
You know, I go out
there often as I can,
prescribe them what
they need, but it's just...
It's not enough.
Found it.
Yeah, I can feel an
abnormal nodule right here.
I'm gonna cut it out,
send it to pathology.
Is it crazy I'm happy
Dr. Reynolds found a tumor
in my mom's bowel?
No, you're not crazy.
Come with me. You
gave me an idea.
- Thank you all for coming.
- He is canning us.
Hmm?
It's just like that
scene in Goodfellas
when they tell Joe Pesci
he's gonna get made
and he's all excited and dressed up,
and then he goes in the room, and whack!
They whack him. I
am not whacking you.
I'm hiring you. All of you.
We're opening a new
clinic in Sheepshead Bay.
And since you're
all on payroll already,
this will actually be the first
profitable thing I've done.
Sheepshead Bay? New
Amsterdam runs satellite clinics
all over the city, but we've
neglected this part of Brooklyn
and the people who live there.
And that ends today with your help.
Sounds great, but I'm kind of
over the parking attendant thing.
Good, because you'll be
running our reception area.
Greeting people, making
sure they feel at ease.
That I can do.
Anna, you'll be installing
our new computer systems.
Linux or DOS? No idea.
And, Jessica, you'll be caring
for the community who raised you
and who needs you now.
Thank you, Max.
Hello. I hope I'm not too late.
Everyone, meet our
new radiology department.
You're gonna need the suture kit.
- Yeah.
Ask me again.
What are you running from?
I told my mom that
I was going to NYU.
That I'd be here
in town, close by.
Dad had died the year
before, and things had gotten...
I didn't even tell her
that I applied to Whitman.
I didn't tell
Vanessa, my sister.
And I knew.
I knew
that they wouldn't
be okay without me.
I mean, I protected Vanessa.
She thought I was a rock star.
But she was 12.
I mean, I couldn't... I
couldn't take her with me.
I wanted to,
but I knew if I didn't go,
then I was never gonna get out.
One night, I...
I tucked her up in bed,
and I left.
I left my little sister.
She, uh, she's in rehab now.
Again. Fourth time.
That is not on you.
I could have saved her, you know? I
mean, I could have saved my mom.
You were a kid.
That is not your job.
Then whose was it?
I mean, I was all they had,
and then I just... I just left.
Listen to me.
There are people all over the
world with families just like yours.
All over the world.
And many of them,
most of them,
they never get out.
You saved the only person that
you could save. You did not fail.
What you did was an
act of incredible strength.
I don't feel strong.
You only need to be strong
enough to do one more thing.
I need help.
Okay.
We can do that.
Okay?
Were you really clearing
me to go back to work?
And let a drug addict
loose in the ED?
God, no.
You kidding me?
Oh, wake me please
When this is over
Oh, when the ice Is melted away
And the hunger returns
I will feel the same but older
Hey.
I wasn't expecting to see you.
Because I cut you off at the
knees? I came on too strong.
It's a personality defect.
No, you didn't, and it's not.
It was spontaneous and fun
and completely lovely.
And that's what made it
utterly terrifying for me.
I haven't wanted to take a
chance on something, um...
On someone in
a really long time.
I mean, I used to be a
person who took chances,
and I really wanna
be that person again.
You don't have to explain.
No, I want to.
You make me want to.
I have baggage.
And it comes with
me wherever I go.
And to be honest, I'm so tired
of dragging it around with me.
Is that an overnight bag?
Yes.
I have literally brought
my baggage with me.
But only 'cause there's a
Radiohead concert in Philadelphia.
Any interest in going with me?
I took care for longer
At least something beautiful
Out of all the windows in all
the hallways in this hospital,
you had to stand
in front of mine.
Get your own window.
I needed your advice
today, my friend,
but you were busy.
Yeah, I mean, that
happens sometimes.
As a result,
I managed to
lose my only friend,
and my only son.
I'm sure it's not that bad.
It is that bad.
Oh.
Okay, sorry.
So, what do I do now?
Iggy, I need you to help me.
Okay.
Where have you been?
And what have you done?
How's the VIP?
Not feeling very important.
Well, you are.
To me, to everyone.
It's gonna be hard,
but when you make it,
your job's gonna be
right here waiting for you.
My job means
everything to me, Max.
I know the feeling.
Moving pictures
Silent films