♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
What do you mean,
you're not charging him?
I'm not charging him.
Sorry.
I heard you.
But what do you mean,
you're not charging him?
Look, mister--
Dr. Freedman.
Dr. Cooper Freedman.
This is Dr. Charlotte king.
The man you should be charging
is Lee McHenry.
Do you know the case?
Okay, we'd like
another lawyer--
someone who knows what
they're doing, someone good.
Ms. King's first statement
to the police
was that she was robbed--
not raped, robbed.
She lied to the police,
which taints her as a witness.
The rape kit wasn't processed
until two weeks after
the alleged rape,
which taints the evidence.
Ms. King failed to identify
Lee McHenry in the first lineup.
The second lineup came only
after a Dr. Sheldon Wallace,
from your practice,
spoke to Lee McHenry,
so that's also tainted.
And, Ms. King,
I mean no disrespect,
but you're a sex therapist with
a history of meeting strange men
from the Internet for what can
at best be described
as fetishistic
sexual encounters.
I know the case.
Mr. Freedman, I graduated first
in my class from Stanford.
I have a 90% conviction rate
here in the D.A.'s office,
100% on rape,
so I'm pretty damn good,
which is why I can say to you
without hesitation
that there is no way this office
is going to charge Lee McHenry.
I'm sorry.
Have a nice day.
This is
the ribbon cutting ceremony
of the new hospital
in western India.
This was also the day
that Olivia sat up on her own
for the first time.
Maya and I skyped.
That's incredible.
That's
quite an accomplishment.
The hospital, I mean.
But Olivia's great, too.
Yeah. And here,
the foundation is delivering
a boatload
of mosquito nets to Tanzania.
Wow.
Boatload. It's an actual boat
loaded with mosquito nets.
That's so cool.
Actually, that's where I was
when I found out about,
uh, Betsey's aunt
abandoning her.
Um...
This is Laos, and here,
we were able to deliver
enough vaccine
to immunize 2,000 children.
Wow.
Yeah, and that's where I was
when I found out
about Charlotte.
Yeah, a lot...
Has happened
since you've been gone.
Uh, oh.
I have a patient.
It was great
to see you, Nai.
Yeah.
All right.
What was that?
Nothing.
You look amazing.
- I mean, for someone...
- You do.
Who's trekked across
three continents...
Oh, you know, I just--
I'm all "eat pray love,"
you know?
I'm--i'm, uh, very zen.
Zen?
Does that mean
you're now all right
with Addison sleeping
with your ex-husband?
Amelia!
Filter.
Sorry. I'm working on it.
Well, I for one am glad
to have you back, so...
Thank you.
All right, truth--
how is Charlotte?
Rape-y and weird.
Filter.
Charlotte... is doing
the best she can.
Hey.
Emily wendal
is back in the E.R.
Damn it.
Again?
What,
who is Emily wendal?
You should come, too.
Hey, um... the guys
are playing poker tonight.
You want to do a girls' night,
get all of us together,
catch up?
Uh, yeah, yeah, I'm in.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I'm glad you're back.
I missed you.
Are you okay
with her screwing Sam?
Filter.
Yeah.
Got it.
Okay.
I don't know. I'm gonna try
to make some phone calls,
see if there's anything
I can...
How do they
not charge the bastard?
What will be will be.
Charlotte...
You seem fine.
Are you...
Are you okay with this,
with them
letting that guy walk?
I'm right as rain.
Okay. Good.
I just want to make sure
that you feel
like you're in control
of what happens.
This is your case.
You know, you have
the right to feel safe.
I'm in the driver's seat now.
Of course you are.
And I know
recovery is a process,
so it's okay
if you're not fine.
But we will get through it,
together.
You know, it's a marathon,
not a sprint.
Right.
And we can go back there,
we can
make the D.A. charge him.
I don't know how, but I will
think of something.
It's always darkest
before the dawn.
Emily wendal presented with
hypertension and early labor.
Treated with labetalol.
Blood pressure stabilized.
Her history includes
preeclampsia and drug addiction.
Every ten months,
right on schedule.
I heard Emily's back.
What, is she famous?
She's a frequent flyer.
Gets knocked up every year
or so,
then shows up in the E.R.
when she's close to term.
Hey, I don't have
any cash on me. Do--
I do, I do, I do. Technically,
it's my turn, right?
'Cause you did the last two,
and Charlotte did
the one before that.
Wh-wh-why do we need cash?
We give her 50 bucks,
she gives up her baby.
What?
It's--
well, no, no, I mean, first I
offer her rehab and therapy.
I give her the lecture
on sobriety, blah, blah, blah.
And then you lecture about
safe sex, offer to put in one of
those implant-y birth control
things that go in her arm,
blah, blah, blah,
she will refuse,
then you will deliver the baby,
and then Pete,
because she only likes Pete,
will give her $50,
and she'll give us the baby.
Well, she likes me
because I've helped her get
clean, what, like, three times?
Yeah.
Not that it ever lasts
more than a week.
Anyway, it shouldn't take
too long.
I'll get social services
on the phone,
let 'em know
we got one coming.
Okay, I'll get the paperwork
for her to sign.
So you want
to examine her first,
or you want me to do
my shrink dance first?
What?
Cooper. Hey.
Naomi. Welcome back. Hey.
I am so sorry I couldn't come
when I heard about Charlotte.
How you holding up?
We, uh, we're good.
Yeah?
Okay. Dealing.
Yeah.
Oh, my god.
Look, Justin Taylor.
Yeah?
I haven't seen this kid
in, like, three years.
I thought he had moved
or something. He's...
He's one of the good ones.
He used to make me
these great mix cds--
Dr. Freedman.
It's me, Justin.
I brought you
this playlist.
Oh, yeah?
All sick indie bands,
including death finger's
new track.
Awesome. Thank you.
Hey, how'd you get here?
I took the bus.
And your parents,
do they know you're here?
I-I didn't want to bother them.
They're busy, you know, at work.
Okay, okay.
Justin, I'm concerned
because you've gained
a lot of weight
since the last time I saw you--
a significant amount of weight.
I know.
I keep getting bigger,
and it's gotten harder
to get around,
like, a lot harder
just recently.
Okay. Can you
get on the scale for me?
It's okay.
It's just you and me.
How much?
You've gained 282 pounds.
Oh, man.
It's okay. It's okay.
We just need to talk about it,
okay? Come on.
And how many weeks along
are you?
Uh, eight months maybe.
How many weeks is that?
I'm not so good with math.
Or prenatal care.
Are you taking any
prenatal vitamins this time?
Getting exams at any of those
free clinics we told you about?
I've been busy.
The ultrasound puts the baby
at 37 weeks.
Heartbeat's strong.
But your pressure is still
a little on the high side,
so I'd like to keep you
overnight for observation.
Because the baby is breech,
we'll have to do
a c-section tomorrow.
Okay.
Looks like you get three hots
and a cot this time, Emily.
So I will tell Dr. King
to hold off d.C.F.S.
For picking up the baby
till tomorrow.
No. I don't want
d.C.F.S. To come.
I didn't ask you to do that.
Look, those other times,
I was an addict.
I-I didn't have a place to live.
I had issues.
You had issues?
You can't take away
this baby.
I got clean a month or two
before I even got knocked up,
and--and I've been trying
to quit smoking.
I swear.
Do any drug test you want.
Look, this baby, it's gonna be
healthy, and I want to keep it.
Emily,
that is not a good idea.
I'll do whatever you want.
Please.
I want to keep this baby.
Dr. Montgomery, please don't
let her take away my baby.
No one is gonna take away
your baby. Okay?
I'm gonna help you.
Hello, Mr. and Mrs. Taylor.
I'm Dr. Bennett.
How is it possible
that he is this fat?
Uh, well, we--
we are concerned.
Justin is diabetic,
and he has high blood pressure.
And that puts him at risk
for even more
serious medical complications.
He's lazy and he doesn't
want to lose weight.
I have no control over
what he does or doesn't do.
You're his parents.
That's your job.
What Dr. Freedman means
is that
Justin needs proper nutrition
and exercise
and medication compliance
to get his health back on track.
We sent him to fat camp,
we hired a nutritionist,
and we got him a trainer.
Could it be a thyroid condition
or a tumor on some gland?
We ran tests and ruled out
any underlying causes
for the weight gain.
I don't want
to get any bigger.
I don't feel good.
He sneaks food.
I find candy wrappers
under your bed all the time.
- He's trying, Bruce.
- Look, could we just stop
and try to be constructive?
Are you still
gonna be saying that
when he's 600 pounds,
Dr. Freedman?
I mean, i-I'd put a lock
on the fridge
if I didn't think
he'd eat it off.
Justin?
Are you okay?
I feel a little dizzy.
Justin.
Justin!
His pulse is sky high.
Yeah.
I'll get oxygen.
Okay.
Get me an I.V. Cart
and call an ambulance, please.
Here.
People can change, Violet.
I know you believe that.
Why not Emily?
We have tried, Addison,
again and again.
But it won't take
because she doesn't want it to.
Ten minutes after I get her
clean, she goes out to score.
I-I beg a shelter
to find a bed for her,
and she never shows up.
The best thing would be
if she stopped
having babies altogether.
We should tie her tubes.
You're doing her c-section
tomorrow. You could do it then.
I am not gonna sterilize a woman
without her knowledge.
I need her consent.
Well, it's the only way
to keep her
from coming back pregnant
in a year.
Okay, okay, look,
Emily is a disaster.
No one wants to see
her coming back pregnant,
but Addison is right.
She has to sign off
on the sterilization.
Just because Emily's made
bad decisions
doesn't mean that we take away
her right to have children.
Why are we only
discussing her rights?
What about David's rights?
Who's David?
Her firstborn.
Eight weeks premature.
He went blind
from being on a ventilator.
He's been in seven homes
in six years.
Turns out he's not only blind.
He's autistic.
Brad was second.
He's severely disabled
due to fetal alcohol syndrome.
He's in a home
for special needs kids.
Then there's April, who's--well,
she's still in foster care,
'cause who wants a crack baby?
And then...
There's Daniel,
who survived for 16
excruciating days in n.I.C.U.
Before he succumbed
to short bowel syndrome.
I signed
his death certificate myself.
You think she wants
this baby?
She doesn't want this baby.
She has an angle.
She always has an angle.
She's not gonna change,
Addison. Tie her tubes.
Without her consent, I can't.
I'm sorry.
I won't do it.
Justin. How is he?
Um, his blood sugar spiked,
which caused
profound dehydration
and electrolyte
abnormalities.
He's gonna wake up, right?
Uh, well, yeah. He's--
he's a little bit disoriented
and confused, but he should
respond to treatment
within the next 12 hours.
- We're gonna bring down his blood sugar, but slowly.
- But he'll be all right.
- I mean, he's not gonna die.
- Well, that depends on what you're willing to do.
He's a teenager with the health
of a 70 year old.
He could stroke out
at any minute.
- He's at risk for a heart attack.
- You coddle him too much.
You always have.
I love him.
I'm not like you--
the way you look at him
with such disgust.
I mean, how do you think
that makes him feel?
Of course he eats.
He needs comfort.
What he needs is discipline.
You make him think it's okay
to inhale all the crap he wants.
Okay, why don't--
why don't we go into the lounge
and discuss this?
I don't want to talk to you.
And I don't want you
around my baby.
I'm going back to work.
You're leaving?
Hey. Is everything okay here?
Yeah. I was just
checking up on Emily.
Your tox screens
came back negative,
and you don't have
any s.T.D.S.
I told you
this baby was healthy.
I've been thinking,
after the delivery,
you should tie my tubes.
Did you come up with that idea
on your own?
I've just been going over
the basics, the anatomy--
did he also explain that
this is a permanent choice?
That's the point, right?
Emily, there are other forms
of birth control that
would preserve the option of
having children in the future.
We went over
all the options.
This is her decision.
Sorry. I have to get back
to the E.R.
If he pressured you
in any way, i--
he didn't.
What he said makes sense.
And I want to give this baby
and me the best possible shot.
So do it, Dr. Montgomery.
Tie my tubes.
You think Pete bribed her?
That's what they do
with Emily.
They give her money to get her
to do what they want.
Well, that's one way
of helping.
What, you think
she should keep the baby?
I mean, do you think
that she wants to change?
I would like to help Emily
improve her life.
So you think Pete, Violet,
and Charlotte couldn't,
but--but you can?
I'd like to try.
Is this for your sake
or for hers?
What's that supposed to mean?
W--
what?
I'm supposed to filter.
Oh, just say it.
Okay. This is
the baby thing, right?
She told you she wants a baby,
and you didn't say anything,
and even though she told you
not to say anything,
she's mad that you didn't
say anything, and so now sh--
ah. Filter.
I have got to get
my own life.
My 15-year-old patient--
Justin--
gained 300 pounds
in 3 years,
and mommy and daddy were
too busy to notice.
So you're blaming
the parents?
You wouldn't?
Well, in all fairness,
Justin is the one
putting the food in his mouth.
Well, no, I get
that he's eating,
- but the parents let it get too far.
- So did he.
Whoa.
Shrink mind meld.
Creepy.
Give me back my fries.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Hey, there she is.
There she is. Hi.
Oh, hey. Hey.
Oh, hey.
How's she doing?
Sweetie.
Yeah.
Hey. How you doing?
Oh, first day
of the rest of my life.
Feel good?
What doesn't kill you
makes you stronger.
You saw that, right?
It's not just me? You saw that?
The clichés--
she only speaks in clichés.
She's got a million of 'em.
And the smiley thing?
Well, she's certainly...
Chipper.
But Charlotte's not
a smiley person.
Exactly.
Well, it's a--it's
a coping mechanism, Coop.
Okay, but she's not coping.
What do I do?
Mm-hmm. Where's
your mind meld now, bitches?
How much did you pay Emily
to get her tubes tied?
She said yes to $250.
I would've gone higher.
Pete, completely unethical.
There are nonprofits
in all 50 states
offering drug-addicted women
financial incentives
to have their tubes tied.
Yeah, but we don't work
for those organizations.
We're doctors.
And there are three million
cases of child abuse a year.
Drug and alcohol abuse
are a contributing factor
in most of them.
Usually you're more practical
than this.
Emily isn't just
some statistic.
She's a woman, okay, who could
wake up ten years from now,
still clean and sober,
and wish that she could
have another child.
Okay, look, I fully recognize
that what we're doing is
unethical, possibly illegal.
I understand that. But you
know me. You know Violet.
She's the one
that can't stop herself
from helping criminals,
pedophiles, you name it.
If the two of us are saying
that Emily is a lost cause,
doesn't that
tell you something?
- Yes.
- Hi.
Hi, baby.
I didn't realize
this was a play date.
Oh, I gave Maya
the night off.
Aren't you?
You're so smart.
She is super smart.
Yes. Yes, you're so smart.
Are you tired, too?
A little--
well, it's because you're gonna
run the world someday.
I know.
It's true.
All right, it's my
turn. My turn, my turn, my turn.
That's your auntie vi. Yeah.
Oh, I miss
Lucas being this little.
Is Charlotte coming?
No.
She declined, but gracefully.
Yes, she's speaking
in bumper sticker slogans,
which either means
she's internalized
the help
that we've been offering her...
Or we need start
planning escape routes
in case she goes postal.
Okay, okay, my turn again.
Come on.
All right.
Yes, the sweetest girl.
Hi. Hi.
Hi. There you are.
There you are.
Hi, sweetie.
Oh, she is so gorgeous.
Yes, you are.
You are gorgeous, little girl.
Okay, that's it.
Where you going?
No offense,
but I did not come here
for "the vagina monologues."
What?
Oh, not
"the vagina monologues."
Did you ever think
we'd be these women--
passing around a baby
like it's good drugs?
Being the kind of women that
women like Amelia run from?
I was always,
always this woman.
I want a baby.
Yes, I do. I do.
It's probably
not gonna happen for me, though.
No, it's not.
I have bad ovaries
and one sad--
Yes...
One sad, lonely egg,
and Sam...
No.
Go for it.
"Eat pray love."
I don't think Sam wants
any more children.
Have one without him.
I want to have one
with him.
I do. Yes, I do.
Well, the man makes
really good babies.
My turn.
Come here, sweetie.
There you go.
There you are.
Yeah. Hello, sweetie.
Hello.
I was good at it, too.
Hey, come on, guys. I told you
not to light 'em.
Come on.
They're Cuban.
Well, we certainly wouldn't
want to let Castro down.
I could have
an asthma attack.
I will be the first to stick
an epipen in your thigh.
Oh, god. Fine.
No cigars. I'm dealing.
Hello, men.
Why are you here?
Uteruses next door
be crazy.
Any objections?
♪ no lovelorn
prince would ever dare... ♪
Why are you looking at Cooper?
W-Why is she looking at Cooper?
Cooper told me
to stay away from him,
which is all I'm going to say,
because for once...
You are filtering.
I am filtering.
Ah.
You got money?
Hard cash.
♪ Ambivalent in c ♪
Welcome to the game.
So what are we talking about--
chicks, boobs...
Chicks and their boobs?
We were talking about cigars.
Before that, we were
talking about babies.
What?
Addison wants a baby.
Which isn't surprising, the way she took to Lucas.
- What do you want, Sam?
- I want to make Addison happy, but, uh,
I've already done
the daddy thing.
So does that make me selfish?
Am i--am I self--
am I being selfish?
No. Life sucks...
Sometimes.
You don't want another kid.
Addison wants a kid.
I want a kid. Charlotte's
too damaged to want a kid,
or too damaged to have a kid,
or too damaged to have the sex
that makes a kid.
Oh, my god. You are men--
hot, interesting men.
Please be dirty and manly
and sexist.
Give a girl a break.
I beg of you.
♪ Better ♪
♪ whoa, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ oh, oh ♪
♪ oh ♪
Hey.
How was your night?
It's always darkest
before the dawn.
Yeah, I know.
You used that one already.
What?
Try happy days are here again
or time heals all wounds.
Or how about every cloud
has a silver lining?
But not it's always darkest
before the dawn.
You can't use it's always
darkest before the dawn
because you used that one
already.
And damn it!
You used that one already!
Charlotte.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry. Please.
I-I didn't--
I didn't mean it.
I'm so...
Please.
Sweetie, I'm sorry.
Mm.
♪♪♪
Hey.
♪ ...to tell me
that I'm not alone ♪
Mm.
♪ ...someone to pick up ♪
Are we gonna
talk about this?
Talk about what?
The baby thing.
♪ Or all that you need ♪
♪ with someone... ♪
There's nothing
to talk about.
Addison--
no. I gotta get
to the hospital.
I have a c-section to do.
Addison--
not now. Okay?
Just...
If you're gonna take babies
away from me,
just... not now.
♪ Ships on the shoreline ♪
Okay.
♪ Are sailing away ♪
♪ I wish ♪
♪ I had more time ♪
♪ with more words ♪
♪ to say ♪
♪ and who am I kidding? ♪
♪ I'm back in a bar ♪
♪ and the ships on ♪
♪ the shoreline ♪
♪ mix into the stars ♪
The D.A. won't prosecute
Lee McHenry.
Did you know that?
How do you feel about that?
Charlotte doesn't care.
She doesn't seem to care
about anything.
I wasn't
asking about Charlotte.
I want to know
how you feel.
♪ ...the shoreline ♪
Uh...
♪ Are sailing away ♪
You know what?
I'm good.
♪ ...as rain ♪
Cooper,
if you want to talk,
I'll keep it confidential.
Nope. I'm great.
Are you?
Yeah.
Always darkest
before the dawn.
Right?
♪ Sailing away ♪
♪ oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ sailing away ♪
♪ oh, oh, oh ♪
She's beautiful, isn't she?
Yes, she is.
♪♪♪
I didn't tie her tubes.
Addison--
shh.
Addison,
she signed the consent form.
She didn't want it.
You did.
You wanted this for her,
and I...
We can't just pay someone
to tie their tubes,
or at least I can't.
We'll get another doctor
to do it.
You'd do that to me?
Really?
To you? Uh, pardon
the shrink in me, but--
Violet, she wants
to turn her life around
because of this child.
She told me that.
She can do it. She just needs
help and support,
which is what the shrink
in you should be giving her.
You're just banging your head
against the wall.
Yeah? Well, it's my head.
Talk to her.
Do this for me.
♪ I wish I... ♪
Okay. I'll do it.
♪ More time ♪
♪ and more words to say ♪
♪ but I'll ♪
♪ be ♪
♪ right ♪
♪ as rain ♪
Hey.
Where's my mom?
She had to leave
for a little while,
but your dad's
in the waiting room.
Is he mad at me?
No. No, he just
had to make some calls.
I got this friend.
Something bad happened to her,
something that shouldn't...
Happen to anyone.
And the thing I want most
in the world
is to help her feel better.
But she won't talk to me.
She won't talk to anyone.
I can tell she's in pain.
And I really think
that if she just opened up,
everything would change,
because then
she wouldn't be alone.
And the two of us together,
we could figure out what to do,
you know?
Well, I'm your friend, too,
Justin.
I want to help you, too.
If I keep eating,
I'll get bigger...
Which is what I wanted.
But now...
It is out of control.
Why would you want that?
I just...
I just don't want
to get touched anymore.
Dr. Freedman.
...his blood sugar slowly
so that he comes out--
ugh!
Cooper!
What are you doing? Stop it!
Coop! Would somebody
please help me? Stop it!
Get off of him!
Cooper, get off of him!
Let go of me!
Get your hands off me!
Let him go.
You son of a bitch!
What the hell is wrong
with you?!
Not your smartest move,
Coop.
That bastard
has been abusing Justin.
You can't hit people,
no matter what.
Really? So after what
Bruce has been doing,
you're okay
with just doing nothing?
Bruce is on the phone
with his lawyer right now.
He's gonna slap you
and the hospital
with a major lawsuit.
Oh, crap.
I do not
need this right now.
Okay.
Okay, okay.
I'll go make nice.
I'll clean it up.
It's gonna be fine.
Cooper--
I'll handle it.
Don't worry, sweetheart.
I'll--I'll fix it, okay?
Charlotte?
Charlotte, are you okay?
No.
But I'm trying to be...
For Cooper.
He needs me to be okay.
But he hates me now,
or resents me, or...
I don't know.
Charlotte, I am so sorry
this happened to you.
Nothing like being raped
to make your day
all shiny and bright.
Charlotte, I'm gonna
tell you this ahead of time
because I don't want you
to be surprised,
but, um, I'm gonna hug you.
Stand up.
You don't need to do--
Charlotte king,
I am going to hug you.
Stand up.
I won't let him touch me.
It's okay.
He's gonna leave me.
No, no, no.
He is not going anywhere.
And if he does,
you'll have me.
Well, according to the D.A.,
I like my sex kinky.
You gonna go all lesbian
and dress up...
In latex for me?
Absolutely.
It's okay.
You're okay.
Okay.
Hey.
These pain meds are good.
Thanks, doc.
Would you like to see
your baby?
Is Dr. Wilder here?
Is he coming?
Emily, um...
Dr. Montgomery
didn't tie your tubes.
What?
She doesn't think
that she should tie your tubes
just because Dr. Wilder
paid you money.
I've got rights.
I signed a consent form.
You gotta do it.
I need that money.
Violet, what--
Okay, what if I paid you $250
for no reason?
Would you still
want your tubes tied?
Would I get another $250
if I did?
No.
You still want the surgery?
Do you?
No!
What if I offered you $250
to give me your baby?
She's a healthy baby.
She's a good one.
She's a good baby.
Violet. That's enough.
Come on. Let's go.
She's worth way more
than $250.
$500. I'll sell her
for $500.
I think we're done here.
Hey, where's my money?
Where's my money?!
Look, I know
you don't understand this.
I know you think
I'm being callous
and unfeeling and awful.
But I have been dealing
with Emily
for six years.
I believe people can change.
You know I do.
But that woman...
Addison, she makes me
believe in hell.
She makes me need to believe
in hell
so that she can go there.
But I am...
Sorry... I mean.
Dr. Freedman--
no, no, I-I don't want you
anywhere near me or my son.
I'm having you arrested.
Fine, we can share a cell,
because I am telling the police
what you've been doing to him.
You should leave,
Dr. Freedman.
Justin, Justin, I promise you,
he will never touch you again.
No, it's--it's not...
I-I didn't mean
it was my dad.
Justin,
don't worry about this, baby.
It's okay, honey.
I'll take care of it.
It's okay, baby.
I'll take care of this, okay?
I'll fix everything.
Pam?
He's just confused.
It's all these medications
that they have him on.
Pam, sit down.
Uh, you can't--
sit down.
Are you serious?
How could--how could you
do that to our son?
He loves me.
Bruce! Bruce! Bruce! Come on.
Call security! Security!
Okay, okay, okay. Okay.
Justin,
this is Dr. Wallace.
He's a therapist,
and, uh,
he's here to talk to you
about, uh...
Your feelings.
I don't want
to talk about it.
Because talking about it
got your mom arrested?
It was my fault.
That's not true.
What your mother did to you,
no one should ever
have to live with that.
But we can talk about that.
We can talk about
anything you want.
You want me not to be fat.
Fat was your protection.
That was smart,
and it was brave,
but, Justin, you don't
have to be protected anymore.
All right? You're safe.
I don't know how to stop.
Dad, I'm sorry. I--
don't. Please.
I-I didn't know, Justin,
what your mother...
I didn't see it.
It's okay.
Don't tell him that.
Don't Bury it.
Tell him the truth.
Why?
You're my father.
You're supposed to protect me.
Why didn't you protect me?
♪♪♪
I love you.
And I failed.
And I hope that someday...
♪♪♪
Can you forgive me?
♪ stop me ♪
♪ if you've heard ♪
♪ this one ♪
This is your baby.
You can hold her
if you want.
I can teach you
how to feed her.
I can get you to a shelter,
get help from social services.
Or...
I have $1,000 cash.
You can take it and...
Sign these papers
relinquishing parental rights
to your baby.
♪ Fall endlessly ♪
Can I get more?
No. $1,000
or I walk.
♪ Nothing is how... ♪
Give me the money.
You don't even want to see her?
She's amazing.
Give me my money.
♪♪♪
♪ Here on the ground ♪
♪ the stars fall ♪
♪ fall endlessly ♪
Addison.
♪ Back here at home ♪
She's so little.
Yeah, I know.
She has no one.
That's not true.
The woman from social service
is bringing her new parents
to meet her.
♪ Being here... ♪
This could be our baby.
But it's not.
But it could be.
♪♪♪
You want to have
this conversation now?
Okay.
♪ It's on our side ♪
♪ and your word ♪
We can't move according to
your biological clock.
It's too fast.
We just got started.
You gotta give me some time.
♪ And here on the ground ♪
♪ the stars fall ♪
I am believing you.
♪ Endlessly ♪
♪ yeah ♪
Believe me.
♪ And back here at home ♪
♪ nothing is ♪
♪ how it's supposed to be ♪
♪ all except for you ♪
♪ being here ♪
♪ With me ♪
Sitting alone in a dark room.
I used to do that.
Then again, I used to down
narcotics like candy, so...
Come here.
Can I say that I'm glad
we're friends again?
I may be easy, Cooper,
but I am not a whore.
Go home.
Go home to Charlotte.
And we will pretend...
That this never happened.
♪♪♪
♪ you spend your whole life ♪
♪ Just to remember ♪
♪ the sound ♪
♪ When the world ♪
♪ was brighter ♪
♪ before we learned
to dim it down ♪
Whatever it is,
I can help.
My girlfriend gets attacked.
She wants to go home,
I take her home.
She wants to go to work,
I drive her.
I found out she wasn't
just attacked, she was raped.
She tells me she doesn't want
to I.D. the guy,
I say,
"okay, don't I.D. the guy."
I'm cheerful, I'm attentive,
I make breakfast for her
every morning.
My job right now
is good man in the storm.
I get that. I'm good with that.
I want that.
♪ Our resignation ♪
But the Charlotte
I fell in love with... is gone.
She doesn't exist anymore.
The laughing, the sharing
in the good and bad of the day,
holding each other--
that's all over.
It's like...
It's like she's dead.
It's like Charlotte is dead,
and I have
the good-man-in-the-storm job.
I am the fiancé of the victim.
My job is to hold up the corpse
that was once Charlotte
and smile.
♪♪♪
Can you help me with that?
♪ Flowers are lasting ♪
♪ and we're reborn untested ♪
Is it the hospital?
Oh! It's bizzy.
Bizzy. It's three hours
earlier here.
♪♪♪
What?
♪ All revelations ♪
♪ come to us ♪
♪ in recovery ♪
♪ cry wolf ♪
♪ cry mercy ♪
♪ cry the name of the one ♪
♪ you were raised
to believe ♪
♪ ah, ah ♪
♪ cry a heart ♪
♪ cry yourself to sleep ♪
♪ cry your storm ♪
♪ of tears ♪
Hello, Addison.
Bizzy.
What's going on?
♪♪♪
I need your help.
♪ ...you ♪
♪ if it helps you ♪
♪ breathe ♪
♪♪♪