No one ever imagined
we would make it this far.
♪ I guess all the mountains that
I moved just weren't enough ♪
♪ And all those nights
I walked you home ♪
♪ From crowded bars
when you were drunk ♪
Incision-less surgeries,
4D imaging,
mechanical organs,
stem cell therapy...
♪ And I just wonder what
it'd take to make you stay ♪
♪ 'Cause when you said jump,
I said how high ♪
♪ But when I jumped,
you said goodbye ♪
Every medical innovation
seemed impossible,
unimaginable
until it was achieved.
♪ I would've walked through hell ♪
And luckily, we haven't
stopped making advancements.
Your recent COVID test
has come back negative,
your ABG's improved,
your RSBI
looks promising,
and oxygen requirements
have decreased.
If you keep this up,
I may just try weaning you
off the vent later today.
Because
the other side of the unimaginable
is death.
And the pain
that comes with loss.
Dr. Altman?
♪ Without you here tonight
Bailey said
you'd need some help
covering the COVID ICU
since...
- since we lost...
- Yeah, uh... uh, o-okay.
- Thank you.
- ♪ Nothing I can do
♪ 'Cause
you don't wanna try ♪
And that side
never stops coming.
We need some good news,
Meredith.
Please, just...
- we really need some good news.
- ♪ I would've walked through hell ♪
♪ To find another way
♪ I would've laid me down
- ♪ If I knew that you would stay ♪
- It's you again!
♪ I would've crossed the stars
♪ To keep you in my life
♪ But now I'm falling hard
♪ Without you here tonight
Captioning provided by
ABC Studios and ABC, Inc.
*GERY'S ANATOMY*
Season 17  Episode 08
Aired on:
March 18, 2021
Episode Title:
"It's All Too Much"
You going in today?
Day off.
Hey, if I say something,
can you not judge me?
Because we're friends who bang,
not friends who judge.
Mm, I have wrapped my head
around the concept,
yeah.
I need joy in my life.
Val died,
and DeLuca...
I can't even say it yet.
And I physically have
no more room left in my body
for sadness.
So I am switching specialties
to OB
and all I need from you
is encouragement.
You thought
I would judge you for that?
I literally spend all day
every day at work
wanting to
walk out that door
just to go off into the woods by
myself hiking for three months
until there's a vaccine.
There's not gonna be a vaccine
in three months.
I'm sorry...
you just said no judging.
I know,
but that's just ridiculous.
Wait, so, you for real
about switching specialties?
Yes.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
What was that?
In lieu of confetti.
♪ I walked outside and got
kissed with a gentle breeze ♪
♪ The sunshine and roses
gave me everything I need ♪
- ♪ I feel alive
- You okay?
No.
The kids loved Andrew.
He used to
play his guitar for them
and teach them songs
in Italian.
He brought gelato
to every birthday.
And every half-birthday.
Which all three of these kids
now think is an actual thing.
I'm just so sorry.
For all of you.
Aunt Maggie!
It's your turn!
Okay, Zozo.
I'll be there.
Know what?
I think this crowd could benefit
from some new East Coast moves.
Ndugu moves.
What do you say, Zola?
- Gimme a shot?
- Yeah!
- Alright. Make room.
- ♪ Lucky today
Unh!
- ♪ I'm feeling lucky today Hey!
- Yeah?
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh
- Ooh, ooh! Come on!
- ♪ Yeah, yeah, I'm feeling... ♪
And I just wish I had the chance
to thank him for it.
Do you think
that was okay?
It's a video tribute for someone
whose brother got murdered.
Nothing's "okay."
But funerals
no longer exist, so...
Do you want me
to record yours?
I'm, um...
Yeah, just, um...
No.
And, uh, later today,
I need you to meet a team...
...from county
at the loading dock.
We're giving them PPE.
They're wearing trash bags
over there.
Mm.
Do we have extra PPE?
We have more than others.
Which is extra.
When was the last timeyou were home?
Hunt! Yeah, Altman.
Come in.
Meredith's stable.
I'm actually gonna try to
reduce her vent settings today.
I'm hopeful.
Hunt,
how are we with beds?
The normal COVID floor
capacity's at 80%, ICU is okay.
Morale is pretty low
with DeLuca...
It's hit everyone
pretty hard.
Well, I expect
DeLuca's autopsy results
by the end of the day.
You asked for his results?
Why?
Andrew DeLuca
was one of our own.
Obviously,
something went wrong.
I want to know what that was.
That's all.
Bailey, I already told you
every step of what happened.
Well after I could have done
something to change the outcome.
Shut the door
on your way out.
Yes?
Yeah.
Alright.
Dr. Connor to the ICU.
Thank youfor coming with me.
I wouldn't miss it.
I have privileges,
right?
My department,
my world.
Dr. Gruber to the OR.
- Helm, what do we got?
- Dr. Gruber to the OR.
Byron Gibbis, 52, found
passed out on his front porch.
He's febrile, tachycardic.
I also heard a big murmur.
Rapid COVID was negative,
no signs of head trauma,
but I did order a pan scan.
Let's add a cardiac CT.
Um, do you work here?
Dr. Winston Ndugu,
cardiothoracic surgeon
from Tufts.
He's got Osler's nodes.
Oh, my God.
My God.
Byron, I'm Dr. Maggie Pierce.
You're at Grey-Sloan Memorial.
You were found unconscious,
and an ambulance...
- Get away from me!
- Okay...
No, I'm serious.
Everybody back up, okay?
I'm not getting COVID.
Where are my clothes?
- Sir, please just...
- Everybody here is sick.
Oh, God.
Okay, Byron,
I know that this is a shock
and I know
that you're scared,
but if we don't get
a look at your heart,
you may not make it home.
We have all been tested.
If you need a mask
or if you need a face shield,
we can get you
whatever you need.
But, please, just stay.
I was so good.
I didn't go anywhere.
Let's get you ready
for CT.
One minute I'm sad,
'cause I think about his sister
and his family
and what a great guy he was.
Next minute,
I'm filled with guilt.
Then I'm filled with rage.
That a person could
Do that
to another human being.
I'm scared. Hopeless.
Sometimes numb.
I can always go back
to guilt.
Guilt is my go-to.
My go-to is numb.
Wow.
Did you just describe
exactly what was wrong
with our relationship
in only five words?
I think maybe
I just did.
I just...
DeLuca. I...
I-I just can't
get my head around it.
What is this?
Looks like whiskey.
Mm, what was it doing
on the top shelf behind
the fancy candlesticks?
What were you doing
on the top shelf
behind the fancy
candlesticks?
Are you drunk?
It's 9:00 in the morning.
Plenty of people get drunk
at 9:00 in the morning.
Yeah, well, not me,
Amelia.
I live at home
with four kids.
Sometimes late at night...
...I have a drink in the garage
and I play my guitar.
We're in a pandemic.
You drink in the garage?
Do you hear yourself?
Do youhear yourself?
Hiding alcohol
is an objectively bad sign.
Or it's a sign that I'm trying
to be respectful of you.
If you have a problem,
you can talk to me.
I'm, like, literally
the best person in the world
- you could talk to.
- Do you know stressed out I am?
All the time?
And now on top of everything,
if it wasn't hard enough,
now I have to make sure that
I don't accidentally mention
that their friend Andrew
was stabbed to death
by somebody
who sells children for sex.
Okay, that is all of us.
That is not just you.
And not all of us
have to drink to cope.
You don't have to,
or you don't get to?
Because I get to.
Because I'm not an alcoholic.
I'm not in recovery and...
Y'know what?
I can't be here right now.
- You're leaving?
- Yes.
Because I don't want to say
something that I might regret.
Because I love you
and because I'm a good guy.
But sometimes, Amelia,
you drive me insane.
And... And this is
one of those times.
So, yes, I'm leaving.
And I'm taking this
with me.
Oh, and, uh,
just so we're clear...
I'm coming back.
Because
I'm not a bad guy!
No pressure, Grey, but we really
need you to pull through this.
This place
can't stand another loss.
Are we ready?
I'm gonna lighten
her sedation...
...and then gradually
turn down all of her settings.
And if she tolerates it,
then we'll move forward
with spontaneous
breathing trials.
Dr. Altman, I'm more
than able to handle this
with the
respiratory therapist.
Maybe you should
get some rest.
I know how closely
you worked with Dr. DeLuca.
Which has nothing to do with
getting Meredith off the vent.
Come on, Grey.
Come on, Grey,
you can do this.
You look just like Ellis
just now,
the way you're looking
at your feet.
So serious.
Then she gets that
worried little brow.
This is torture!
You're right here,
and I can't...
It's torture!
It's a torture
of your own devising.
You were always good at that.
Good at what?
Torturing yourself.
I don't do that
as much anymore.
You never got to meet Ellis.
We didn't even know.
I wish
you got to know her.
She looks just like you.
She breaks the rules
just like you.
And she's quick to anger.
And quick to laugh.
And she's smart and pensive
and stubborn, just like you.
Hates pink and purple,
loves brown and green,
and... and gets enraged
at the thought
of anybody wanting to
cut down a tree.
Is... Is this thing clean?
People say you can't get sick
from surfaces, but you can.
We thoroughly disinfect
the entire room
in between patients.
- Sir?
- Just... I need a minute, okay?
Can I leave my face shield on,
please?
- Sure.
- Oh, God.
If you'd like,
I can stay with you.
- I can hold your foot or...
- No, no, no, no. I don't want
anybody touching me.
Nobody touches me, okay?
Osler's nodes,
so... endocarditis.
Yes, but what is
the underlying cause?
He denies
intravenous drug use,
there's no indwelling catheter,
no diabetes...
He said he hasn't left his house
since lockdown, right?
May I?
- Hey, Byron.
- Yeah?
Have you had any trouble
with your teeth lately?
I had a... a popcorn kernel
stuck in my teeth,
and I picked it out
with a paperclip
and... and now my gums
are a little sore,
but I-I'm not going
to the dentist.
I'm not gonna lay there with
my mouth open for 20 minutes
inhaling somebody's
spit droplets.
- No way.
- Bingo.
Dental infection, which led
to bacterial endocarditis.
Aortic valve abscess almost
completely blocking the valves.
Helm, order some antibiotics
and book an OR.
I thought of it.
You just said it first.
Oh, yeah, I believe you.
100%.
Were you looking
for me, dear?
Yeah, I was.
Yeah.
You know, I built my life,
my sanity,
my sobriety...
around the surrender
to a higher power.
I mean, for me,
it's the belief
that there's some purpose.
That there's
a... a bigger plan.
Something that if
I got all the way above it
and could look down on it
like, um...
- like a jigsaw puzzle, okay?
- Mm.
That somehow it would...
it would make sense.
My faith is rooted
in the trust
that there's a... a meaning
and a wisdom
that I'm just not elevated
enough to see or understand.
A faith that
whoever made this puzzle,
it makes sense to Him.
- And it's beautiful.
- Mm.
Today,
I'm... I'm struggling.
I'm struggling
with my faith.
to trust anything.
And I just cannot
see any wisdom in this.
I live
with stage 4 cancer.
A cancer
very few people survive.
I just got the results
from my latest scan,
and... nothing has grown.
It makes no sense.
Everywhere we look,
someone is dying
that was healthy yesterday.
It makes no sense.
"Puzzle"
is the right word.
You can look for the pain,
the lost, the unbearable.
Or you can look
for the beauty, the grace...
the miracle.
And nothing grew?
Nothing grew.
Okay, so, I know
that people buy and trade
and get rich
and then just lose everything.
But what exactly
is the stock market?
It's a good thing you already
know how to live out of a car.
Why? Well, questions like that
make me think you're
gonna end up back in one.
Uh...
who is it?
It's Jackson Avery!
I'm here for a quick bang.
I...
Jo!
Shut up.
Bad time?
Oh, crap.
Hey. Really bad time.
Um, I brought whiskey.
Oh, we're day drinking.
Ah!
Sorry, dude.
I didn't realize, uh...
No, no, it's cool.
Guess you're aware of our...
situation, then.
Yep. Sweet deal.
Here.
Oh, no,
I'm on, uh, call.
Oh! Dibs.
Okay. Cheers.
Happy...
all-our-friends-are-dying
day.
I told him we'd move as fast
as was safely possible.
His echo showed
his ejection fraction at 64%,
so hopefully his heart is strong
enough to have a good outcome.
Who cleans his teeth
with a paperclip?
Isolation makes people
do crazy things.
We're not meant
to be alone.
People physically
need people.
Oh, no, no! Don't...
Don't... Don't touch me!
Just back away!
Please, everybody, back away.
- Dr. Pierce!
- I'm sorry. I can't be here!
- I can't do this. I can't! Get away from me!
- Dr. Pierce. Dr. Pierce.
- Dr. Pierce! A little help?
- I can't be here! I can't be here!
- Oh, God.
- I can't! I can't be here.
I can't.
I need to get out of here!
Okay, call security.
I'm gonna go to the elevator.
- You go to the OR board.
- I don't know where that is.
- It's...
- Did anyone lose a naked man?
Because he went that way.
Oh.
Byron?
Hey, Byron.
I'm... I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I can't do this.
I can't be here.
I...
Oh, my God, my masks.
I'm not wearing my masks.
Honey, you're not wearing
anything.
My best friend, Rory,
he was healthy as a horse.
Never worked a day job
his entire life,
he didn't smoke,
he didn't drink,
he... he ran triathlons.
He got the virus,
he was dead in a week. A week!
Wife and kids didn't
get to say goodbye to him.
Do you know
how many people
they're projecting die
from this?
- Hundreds of thousands.
- I know.
And if you
want to walk out of here,
I'm not gonna stop you.
Wait, what?
But I will follow you.
Because your heart's
only gonna get worse,
and I owe it to you,
I owe it to my oath,
I owe it...
I lost someone, too,
Byron.
Not COVID.
But I know that pain,
and I know how unfair it is
and how enraging it is.
But I think...
I think we owe it
to the people we lost
to live the lives
that they can't.
Even when it seems hard,
and even when we're afraid.
Byron, you have a problem
that we can fix.
We can fix this.
But you have to let us.
I don't want to die.
I don't want you to die,
either.
Okay.
Let's get you
a gown first.
She didn't even know
that she was pregnant.
And then
we saved her baby.
And then...
she died.
It's like,
during a pandemic,
shouldn't all the other
tragic crap take a break?
You're seriously
gonna quit surgery?
I need some good things
in my life.
And babies are good.
You realize OB
is all about moms, yeah?
Yeah, who are happy
because they're having babies.
Not having my own
any time soon...
Fingers crossed.
...or maybe ever,
so I might as well hang out
with some others.
I got like 15 of them
at home.
- Hang out with those.
- It's so unfair!
You and Amelia
didn't even want a baby,
and then you got one
and neither of you died.
Oh, poor you.
You're young and single
and dating a plastic surgeon.
No, we're not...
not dating. It's just sex.
- And you can still work.
- Oh.
Last time
my life sucked this bad,
I quit medicine
and moved to Venice Beach.
Ah, yes.
The bike shop, right?
Heaven.
Jackson wants to
run away to the woods.
Oh, nice.
Can I come?
No, that would defeat
the purpose.
What is
the purpose?
- You kidding? Escape. Outta here.
- Mm.
Escape from pain and rage
and responsibility.
Escape from humanity.
I mean,
trees don't murder people.
- Trees are not racist.
- Mm-hmm.
Trees do not
politicize a disease
and convince
millions of people
not to protect themselves
and others
by using a simple piece of damn
fabric on their faces, so...
Trees don't even
have faces.
You know what?
Maybe you can come.
Ohh!
♪ Oh
Uh, primary repair
of the stomach...
...diaphragm, splenectomy,
and repair
of ventricular injury...
all intact.
Ultimately died
from coagulopathy.
- Like I told you.
- Well, now we have it in writing.
Which will make
the M&M go smoothly.
The M&M?
Bailey, what in the hell
are you trying to prove?
It's Andrew DeLuca.
He gave five years of his life
to this hospital.
We own him due diligence.
What about what you owe to your
doctors that are still here?
The ones who've sacrificed
their lives to fight a pandemic,
who hardly sleep or eat
or even shower,
who see their families
on screens...
Their faces are full of bruises
because of the damn PPE,
and now you want them
to sit in front of a computer
and be grilled
on whether they messed up
trying to save
one of their own?
Let them grieve,
for God's sake!
You are causing me harm.
You are causing harm
to Hunt and Altman.
DeLuca was a victim
of a horrible crime,
and he lost
too much blood.
No mistakes were made,
no stitch was missed.
And the mere suggestion
that any of us
didn't do everything possible
to save his life...
...it's a pain
I wouldn't put on anyone.
I want you closer.
Could you please
just come here?
Do you remember when
you were trying to teach Zola
how to ride a bike?
She got so frustrated
because she couldn't,
and she threw it down,
and she goes, "Mama, you do it."
And you couldn't stop laughing,
and she got so mad.
Well, I was trying
not to laugh.
So am I.
I can't do it for you.
It's your beach.
Zola's amazing,
isn't she?
I mean,
she's just so brilliant.
She writes me letters
in her journal.
Did you know that?
Well, what is that?
What is that face?
Would you start a surgery
with a face like that?
No!
No.
You would relax.
It hasn't been that long.
Maybe we could decrease
sedation a bit further,
at least run another ABG.
And hope she doesn't go
into cardiac arrest
while we wait
for the results?
I'm turning the settings
back up.
Grey's staying
on the vent.
How's the book report
coming?
That was
one of my favorites.
That's what grownups say
to convince you
to finish your homework.
You got me there.
I'm supposed to write a whole
page about living forever.
Mom says it's impossible.
So what's the point?
Your mom is pretty smart.
If I made a medicine
where you could live forever,
would you take it?
I don't know.
Uncle Link said,
"Heck yeah."
That sounds like him.
Me, I don't know.
I think the fact
that we can't live forever
is one of the things
that makes life so special.
Impermanence.
I think if we could
live forever,
we'd spend so much time
losing the people that we love
instead of holding tight
while we still can.
Impermanence.
I like that word.
Me too.
If I had the medicine,
I'd give it to my mom right now.
Me too.
Hey,
you want to call her?
Alright.
Hello there.
Can we have a minute?
Of course.
Hi, Mommy.
I miss you so much.
I love you.
Um, I've been writing
a page about living forever.
How are you doing?
It didn't work?
Altman wants to try again
in a day or so.
When I lost my wife,
um...
...the therapist,
she said that
there's no wrong way
to process the loss,
the grief.
But there is.
Over a bloody computer screen,
it's...
...it's wrong.
Dr. Lyon,
call the blood bank.
Ohh!
Oh!
You know the rules.
Who deserves it?
Deserves what?
Rules to what?
"Make it Sadder."
We tell our sob stories,
and whosever story is saddest
wins the last shot.
"Make it Sadder"?
That's fun?
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
Okay. Alright.
I'll be the judge.
Alright, go.Okay.
Alright.
I am currently raising
four children
in a hellscape of a world
where people
don't listen to science.
My parents are going ahead
with their second wedding
even though
there's a pandemic,
so they'll probably
get sick and die.
And, uh, my last shred
of me-time...
sneaking an occasional drink,
which was already
pretty pathetic,
I know... is now ruined.
- Strong. Yeah.
- Mm, alright.
I had plans the weekend
that everything shut down.
I had crawled out
of my depression,
and I was all set
to start over by...
going...
...going on dates.
- Oh, yeah.
- Aww!
Okay, yes, yes.
You guys,
I even bought outfits, okay?
Hang on. Okay.
Ah! Okay.Alright.
Let me show you.
What do we have?
Oh, this is cute, right?
The perfect thing
to declare someone dead in.
Oh, what about this?
This, for the, um,
career girl
that just spent, um,
seven hours
making more room for bodies
on the morgue truck.
Or...
How about this?
This, for... for
the funeral of a co-worker
who got stabbed to death...
who doesn't even
get a funeral.
Okay,
Jo wins the last shot.
No, no!
Yes. No way. Unh-unh.
- Unh-unh.
- Thank you so much.
She has an entire loft
all to herself!
Mnh-mnh.
- Hold on.
- Ahh!
What's that?
It's Richard.
The memorial for DeLuca
is tonight.
Alright, I'll drive.
Let's, um, get ready.
Orderly to 6 East.
Hey. Uh, just moved
Mr. Cabrera up here.
Another complete white-out.
- How's Meredith?
- Um, uh...
It... It didn't work.
And I'm questioning
why I even thought it would.
Well, DeLuca's autopsy results
came back.
We did everything
that we could.
I know that.
And he's still dead.
Your kids call every day
on a video chat.
Don't know
if you can hear them.
Don't even know
if you can hear me now.
♪ There's a million things
You look perfect.
♪ I can't control
Maybe... Maybe
it's none of my business,
Grey,
but I'm begging you.
Fight.
♪ There is one thing
that I know ♪
That's up to you.
But if you're asking me,
you should hear him out.
They need you, Grey.
The little one...
- Ellis.
- She looks just like you.
She got
all your expressions.
She doesn't smile
easy or often,
but when she does, sweet Jesus,
it lights up the room.
What did you do
to make her smile?
You shoulda seen it...
she smiles and she smiles,
and it gets bigger
and bigger until...
Boom!
She just bursts out laughing.
What did you do
to make her laugh?
Then her brother gets annoyed
because she's laughing so hard
right in his ear.
That's Bailey.
And then the oldest one
comes in,
and she takes the tablet
and says they're hogging it
and that she needs
time with you, too,
because she's the oldest
and she's your favorite.
Zola.
Then I hear a click and a lock,
but we're in darkness.
Can't tell who has it,
'cause I can't see a face.
But then I hear a voice,
and it's the oldest one.
And she's
sittin' in the dark.
She's in her closet.
That's where she goes
to write letters to her dad.
And she says,
"I'm really sorry, Mum.
Didn't mean for things
to get so violent.
Ellis can be
truly infuriating."
They need you, Grey.
I know.
They need you to fight.
♪ My thoughts don't drift
-♪ When you're around
- We all need you to fight.
I don't know that I can.
It's... so warm here.
The water is so cool.
I feel so relaxed.
And there's no pain.
I watched my kids
lose their mum.
You don't want
that for your kids, Grey.
There are people getting better
here every day.
You could be
one of those people.
♪ Nothing is forever
I believe that you could.
'Cause I've heard the stories a
bout other fights
you've already won, so...
- ♪ You're my anchor in the ocean ♪
- So I'm asking you to fight.
You fight, Grey.
♪ Tides will change ♪
- ♪ The sea can't help it ♪
- It's okay. I'll be right here.
♪ Nothing is forever
♪ When it feels like
I'm in constant motion ♪
♪ You're my anchor
in the ocean ♪
Dr. Webber
set something up for DeLuca.
A memorial.
I'm not a great Jew.
I cheated
at my bar mitzvah.
I was too busy trying
to ignore Lenny Rapkin's shins
that I didn't learn Hebrew,
so I just wrote it out
phonetically and read that instead.
I skip half the High Holy Days
and repent for it at Yom Kippur.
And if I'm honest, I...
go back and forth
about believing in God,
which is actually very Jewish,
but...
It's the traditions
that I find helpful.
When a loved one dies,
we have...
rules about how to grieve
and move on.
Protocols.
We force ourselves
to sit in the pain.
We cry.
And we laugh.
And we eat a lot.
And it doesn't bring
the person back,
but it does
start the healing.
Chief, your mom died.
My mom makes me crazy,
but I'm gonna fall apart
when she dies.
And you have people
you can be with.
People who love you and miss you
and need to grieve with you.
This pandemic
has taken so much.
Don't give it that,
too.
♪ There's a light
♪ A certain kind of light
♪ It's never shone on me
Hey.
Oh, sorry.
Um, I'm about to head back in
to check on Mr. Gibbis.
He's sedated and stable.
You gonna go
to the memorial?
I thought bad things
about him.
When he was sick, I thought,
"Great, more surgeries for me."
I had no compassion.
And now he's just...
dead.
And we can't hug.
And as a rule,
I hate hugs, but...
♪ What good does...
...I haven't physically touched
anyone without gloves
in over two months,
and I-I feel like
I'm turning into that patient.
Another week of this and...
I'll be running through
the hospital naked.
♪ You don't know
what it's like ♪
Stand up.
And turn around.
I'm sorry?
Just trust me.
♪ To love somebody
♪ The way I love you
♪ You don't know
what it's like ♪
Thank you.
♪ Baby, you don't know what it's like ♪
Spread out, please.
We may be outside, but we still
need to maintain our distance.
♪ To love somebody
♪ The way I love you
Richard.
I'm...
I need to
take some time off.
I'm not sure how long.
But I-I need to go home.
However long you need.
Everybody, can I have
your attention, please?
Thank you.
I appreciate
you all being here tonight.
Grey-Sloan is a family.
And Andrew DeLuca
was a member of that family.
And his death,
however brave...
Well,
it's still heartbreaking.
We can't honor his life
like we might have in the past,
but we can still honor him.
Dr. Perez?
♪ There is a man,
he runs right to me ♪
♪ He wraps his loving arms
around me ♪
♪ He knows
♪ He knows my pain
♪ Oh, he knows my pain
♪ Oh, he gives me life
♪ And I don't know
if that is for me ♪
♪ It's darker than I thought,
in all its broken glory ♪
♪ My soul
♪ Just wants to go home
♪ He's calling me home
♪ And there was a light
♪ Oh, there was a fire
♪ She came through
in the night ♪
♪ She entered like an angel
♪ Hold on
♪ She's just memories
Hello.
Uh, my name is Andrew DeLuca,
and I'm thrilled to be
applying to the surgical
residency program
at Grey-Sloan
Memorial Hospital.
A bit about me.
I am Italian,
but I grew up in Wisconsin.
A lot of doctors
in my family,
including my big sister,
Carina.
Um, I grew up stealing
her game of Operation,
so I guess you can say
it's, uh, been a dream of mine
for a very long time.
The idea of doing my training
at Grey-Sloan
and... and learning
from surgical legends
like Richard Webber
and Miranda Bailey
and Jackson Avery
and Meredith Grey...
uh, well, it just doesn't
get any better than that.
I think the reason I want to
become a surgeon
is that
I've always had
this insatiable desire
to help people.
And I think I get that from
my mom, who I lost too soon.
And, uh, she had
this really giving heart,
and she always pushed me
to do as much good as possible,
so I guess
I'm doing this for her.
Now, you should be warned,
I can be relentless at times,
and very stubborn.
But I promise that,
if I match with you...
Speaking Italian...
I will give you
the very best of me.
Thank you.
Alright.
Meredith: At all costs,
we avoid
negative experiences.
We ignore pain.
We steer clear
of the unfamiliar.
We lie when asked
about how we feel.
♪ Steady as a rock
♪ I stand, I wait
We shouldn't do that.
I stopped by
the hospital for, um...
I watched.
♪ But eyes that can't erase
I won't keep booze
in the house anymore.
That's not what I need
from you.
♪ Hands that hold
What I need from you
is no more secrets.
It's just...
we have this baby together.
We have this whole life
together, so...
I want to really know you.
Deal.
I reek of whiskey right now,
or I would hug you.
I will hold my breath.
♪ Ohhh
♪ So, send me into space
♪ And cut me free
Because I've learned something
from these last several months.
Teddy?
- ♪ And like a satellite
- Hey.
- ♪ Just look for me
- Teddy.
I'm gonna take you home,
okay?
Okay.
The body
can only take so much.
...Captions by VITAC...
Sync corrections by srjanapala