Dr. Hirsch, please
pick up extension 350.
Dr. Hirsch, extension 350.
I apologize for how
late he's running.
- It's okay.
- I'm sure he'll be with you any moment.
I can wait.
I'll see you in two weeks.
Judy will give you all your pre-op
instructions before you leave.
- Thank you. BURKE:
You've come to the right place.
- Mark, you look good.
- You too.
- How was your flight?
- Uneventful.
Yeah, the best kind.
Elizabeth with you?
Not this time.
See this area? It's called
"ring enhancement."
It encircles the cavity where
we removed your tumor.
Could it be inflammation
from a vaccine?
No.
What about a side
effect from radiation?
The spec MRI shows a
peak of creatine and choline...
with a depressed NAA, which
rules out radiation necrosis.
I'm afraid it's definitely
tumor re-growth.
Don't you need a biopsy?
Spectroscopy was conclusive.
How soon can you operate?
I can't.
Not this time.
The tumor invaded the areas of the brain
that control speech and motor function.
If I start digging around in there now,
the side effects would be devastating.
You wouldn't be able to
walk, talk, feed yourself.
Which is exactly what'll
happen as the tumor grows.
Some of the cells must've
been radiation-resistant.
So what are my options? I mean,
other than sticking a shotgun in my mouth.
Your best bet now is
stereotactic radiosurgery.
The Gamma Knife's safe and
effective. And they can do it in Chicago.
And if it works?
- The average is four, maybe five...
- Years?
Months.
So I'm back where I started.
You should've been
dead a year ago, Mark.
You got married, saw
your daughter be born.
I'd say that was
time well-spent.
Dad?
Dad, don't you have work today?
I'm up.
- I made you some coffee.
- Thanks.
You want some breakfast?
No. I'm good, thanks.
I'll be down in a minute.
- Elizabeth called. You were showering.
- Should've come and got me.
- Did she leave a number?
- No.
How am I supposed
to call her back?
She wanted you to bring some things
for Ella to work. I wrote them down.
Oh.
I can get all that stuff
and put it in a bag.
- No, no, no. I'll do it.
- I don't mind.
- How'd it go?
- What?
The conference in New York.
Oh, good. You know, the usual.
Boring.
So everything's set for
staying tonight at Kelly's?
Mm-hm. Yeah.
Are you sure you
should be doing this?
- This?
- Working a double shift?
- You seem a little tired from your trip.
- I'll be fine.
Iverson in 4 needs about
another hour of monitoring.
Dunn, also in 4, is probably
gonna need a walking cast.
The foot x-rays are pending.
Dr. Lewis is crashed out in 3.
- Susan?
- Yeah.
She... She worked a
double, so don't wake her up.
And last but not least is the lovely but
kind of spooky Miss Armstrong in 2...
who's waiting on a Psych consult
before the sewer people come get her.
- What sewer people?
- She's crazy. Hence, the Psych consult.
And there's a bad burn
trauma coming in, so have fun.
- Right.
- He called again.
- Ugh. Randall?
- Five calls in 18 hours.
Sounds like a stalker.
- You want me to talk to him?
- No. Thanks.
- What are you looking at?
- Theresa Matthews.
Comatose for a year following an
MVA. Mom takes care of her at home.
Called 911, thought her
daughter was in discomfort.
- How could she tell?
- My question too.
Dr. Kovac wants you to meet him in
the ambulance bay with Tartaglia's x-rays.
- Really?
- He said it was an emergency.
- Tartaglia from last night?
- The one with the whiplash.
- Just telling you what he said.
- More information might've helped.
- Am I talking to you?
- Knock it off and help me find it.
- Is that it?
- Yeah.
Who's your friend?
Would you mind telling
me what's going on?
He was gonna give me a ticket.
- Excuse me?
- I told him I had an emergency.
Oh, so you used me
to get out of a ticket.
It would have been a big ticket.
I'm glad you could pull
me away from patients...
so you could
avoid traffic school.
I owe you one.
Nice car. Did he get
the leopard-print interior?
- You off?
- Not till 10.
- What did you do to deserve that?
- I asked.
This way, I'm never
home when my neighbor is.
He's out on bail?
Till the trial.
Then I get my life back.
- How's his wife?
- She's good.
Safe.
How are you?
How's the eye?
Good. I think my Good
Samaritan days are over, though.
You probably saved her life.
Steady midnights, that can be
tough. You getting enough sleep?
Yeah? Eating okay?
- Feeling depressed or anxious?
- I have to get back.
- Call if you want to talk.
- I'm good.
Coffee and pie on me
if you change your mind.
Hey. What does a girl have to do
to get a cup of coffee around here?
- Mark?
- Hey.
I just worked two shifts. I'm
supposed to be the zombie.
- Little slow getting started this morning.
- How was New York?
Well, I didn't see as many
Broadway plays as I'd hoped.
And my tumor's back.
Oh, God, Mark, I'm sorry.
I do Gamma Knife today.
- Today? What are you doing here?
- It's best to stay busy.
- How's Elizabeth taking it?
- I haven't told her yet.
What? Why not? Mark, you
shouldn't be going through this alone.
I'll see her this afternoon.
- What time's your treatment?
- 1:30.
I'm gonna go home and get
some rest. But after, I'll come by...
- You don't have to.
- I want to.
Dr. Greene, Dr. Weaver
needs some help.
All right, I'll let you
go. Bye. Good luck.
- What patient?
- She's got an elderly woman in CHF.
An explosion
trauma just rolled in...
and there's an MVA with a
possible spinal injury 10 minutes out.
- They need you in Trauma 2. Burn victim.
- Okay.
- I'm firing that new guy.
- What new guy?
Jerry.
Jerry was here
before you, Frank.
So was the Neanderthal
man, but he didn't last either.
- You can't fire anybody.
- Either he goes or I go.
You... You! You'll be
hearing from my lawyer.
- What'd I do?
- Mark, coffee.
Mr. Nevinger, did you pass out?
- No.
Full trauma panel, portable
C-spine, chest and pelvis.
Start a second IV with LR.
Add an ABG with
carboxyhemoglobin and a CK.
Sats, 94. Pulse, 120. Can I
give him something for pain?
Titrate 10 of morphine. But watch
his pressure. Keep him above 90.
Carbonaceous materials
on his nose and lips.
He's not moving much air.
He's in too much
pain to breathe.
- How much fluid?
- One liter per hour for the first 8 hours.
I'll ask my super. I think there's
a waiting list for my building.
There's been an old lady
who's been sick on my floor.
I don't want to live in an
apartment where somebody died.
All you need is some Lysol and
some air freshener, and it's all good.
Are you moving? ABBY: Yeah.
The freak who hit
me moved back in.
You can stay at my place
till you find something else.
Thanks. I don't know
if that's a good idea.
- Why not?
- Yeah, Abby. Why not?
Don't you guys have
something to do?
You shouldn't have to leave
your own place. He should move.
He'll be in jail soon.
I just don't know if I want
to live there after all this.
- What's with the car?
- Like it?
- It's kind of flashy.
- You only live once.
Well, not if you keep
driving like a maniac.
- You look kind of tired.
- Yeah. I was up late.
Oh, really? What's her name?
- Who?
- It's a joke, Luka.
- No, seriously. If you need a place...
- Thank you.
Stay as long as you need. You only
have to sleep with me on the weekends.
- Excuse me?
- It's a joke, Abby. It's a joke.
Who called for a consult?
Burn patient. Trauma 2.
- What doctor?
- Greene.
- Make it stop hurting.
- We're trying, Ian.
- How's his PO-2?
- Eighty-nine on 10 liters.
- Borderline.
- I don't want to tube him yet.
Why not? He's hypoxic.
He needs intubation.
Then I can assess
him for escharotomy.
Dr. Greene, his wife's here.
That's why I've been waiting.
Keep an eye on him.
- Mrs. Nevinger, I'm Dr. Greene.
- Can I see him?
- The surgeon's in with him now.
- The surgeon?
The burns caused constrictive
tissue-swelling around his chest.
He may need a procedure to
relieve that so he can breathe easier.
- You have to do an escharotomy?
- Maybe.
- You in the medical profession?
- Yeah. I'm a nurse at Mercy.
- Is he intubated?
- Not yet.
What's the surface area?
Over 50 percent.
Oh, God.
Do you know how it happened?
He was in the garage painting some
new furniture for our son's bedroom.
Did he have a heater
on in the garage?
No. He paints cars. He knows he
has to be careful around that stuff.
Well, we're gonna do
everything we can. Okay?
Repeat the blood
gas in 20 minutes...
and have a fiber-optic
scope standing by.
Elizabeth.
- How is he?
- In need of intubation.
I brought the things
you asked me to bring.
Thank you.
What are we doing?
I miss you and Ella. I
need you to come home.
I can't.
You have every right
to be angry with me.
But staying in a hotel
isn't gonna solve anything.
Mark, I'm not
trying to punish you.
I'm just trying to do
what's best for Ella.
Don't you think it's best for her
to be with her mother and father?
- Yes, I do.
- So when are you coming home?
I don't know.
Aaron, how many
lights do you see?
One. There's nothing wrong with
my eyes. It's my arms and my legs.
Okay, Aaron, I need
you to lay absolutely still.
No sign of cranial nerve
impaction or blowout fracture.
Bilateral TM's clear. No blood.
Does it hurt when I press
here or just the sides?
Both. WEAVER:
Foreface is stable.
No dental fractures. - Ah!
Okay. We're gonna leave
the collar on for a while.
Let's tape down his head
and use sandbags to stabilize.
- Can you feel this?
- No.
- How's he doing?
- It's too early to tell.
- Can he tell me what happened?
- It was a sledding accident.
Yeah, his dad got smashed...
and was pulling him and his friend
on a sled behind a snowmobile.
Smelled alcohol on his breath?
No. But he seemed
out of it. Maybe drugs.
Lungs are clear bilaterally.
Normal heart tones.
- You going somewhere?
- What?
That's the third time
you've looked at the clock.
- Aaron, can you feel this?
- No.
- What about now?
- Anything?
- No.
- Why can't I feel my arms?
- Just relax. We're trying to help you.
I'm gonna go speak
with the father.
Prep the Solu-Medrol,
hold the scanner.
Okay, give me a reflex hammer.
Mr. James, I'm Dr. Greene.
I'm treating your son, Aaron.
He got hurt.
He has no feeling
in his arms and legs.
We're sending him
for x-rays and an MRI.
We'll have a better idea...
once the neurosurgeon's had
a chance to assess his injury.
This is all my fault.
You were pulling him and his
friend behind a snowmobile?
I knew it was wrong.
- You been drinking?
- You mean booze?
No.
I told them.
- Told who?
- Aaron and Chris that we shouldn't.
But they kept bugging me to.
Well, that's where
adult judgment comes in.
- Hey, idiot!
- Is there a problem?
Yeah. My son's got a broken
arm thanks to Dumb and Dumber.
- You could've killed them!
- It was an accident.
- Settle down, sir.
- I'll settle down after he's arrested.
Look, he shouldn't be allowed
to operate a motor vehicle.
He's only got half a brain.
I'm serious. His wife even
left him because he's lost it.
Let's go over
here and talk, sir.
- Sorry about that.
- It's okay.
He's kind of right. I would've
never done this before I was stupid.
Here, sit down.
What happened?
July 17th, 1997.
It was very hot.
I took off my hardhat so I could
wipe the sweat off my forehead.
And a pipe fell loose from
the fitting above me, and boom.
- Head injury?
- My brain doesn't work like it used to.
- Does Aaron live with you now?
- Sometimes.
We're buddies now. We
don't fight like we used to.
- He's gonna get better, right?
- I hope so.
Dr. Greene, Mrs. Nevinger's wondering
about an update on her husband.
- I'll be back to tell you about your son.
- Thank you.
- Get a red top on Mr. James.
- Sure.
- Nobody's telling me anything.
- He's still in with the surgeon.
Why don't you sit down
here, and I'll find out.
Oh, Abby. District
attorney's office called.
Your subpoena's been revoked.
- Revoked?
- Trial's been canceled.
What?
- Why?
- I don't know. Some legal snafu, I guess.
You know about lawyers. They're half
as smart as doctors but twice as sneaky.
Ian, your wife's here.
She wants to come
in and see you.
Is she alone?
No. Your sons are with her.
I don't want them
to see me like this.
I'm gonna have to put a tube down
your throat to protect your airway.
Once I do that, you won't
be able to talk to them.
I don't care.
Your urine tested
positive for amphetamines.
Want to tell me why?
I've been working two jobs.
Sometimes I need a little
help to keep me going.
How do you take it?
Do you smoke it?
Did you light up with all
those fumes in the garage?
I wanted to finish the dresser.
Birthday's on Saturday.
Hey, where have you been?
Elizabeth.
I was down in the ER.
Let me guess. A rule-out
appy on a corpse?
- No.
- Well, you're lucky.
I'm starting to think "ER"
stands for "everyone's retarded."
Honestly, it's a wonder they all
find their way to work every day.
Excuse me, Dr. Corday. Your nanny called,
said they're just leaving the hotel.
Thanks.
That sounds kinky.
- Do you need something, Robert?
- Yes, actually.
Your buddy Benton left us with
eight delinquent operative reports.
He said he was stopping
by sometime this week.
He wouldn't be caught dead
here. They are now your problem.
- I'm not the operating surgeon.
- I don't give a damn.
I want a dictated note on every
chart before our JCAHO review.
I'm being paged to the ER.
If I don't have them by tomorrow,
I'll report him to the medical board.
Someone is very popular today.
Oh, Jerry, give me a break.
I could have one of my
buddies on the force...
do a background
check on this Randall.
- Isn't that nice to know.
- Now, what's that supposed to mean?
It means that the continuing invasion
of personal privacy by law enforcement...
is appalling, not
to mention immoral.
Well, you have nothing to worry
about if you don't have anything to hide.
- Malcontent.
- Psycho fascist.
- Now, that's it!
- Settle down, you two.
- You wanna start something, tough guy?
- Bring it on, gramps.
Gramps? Who are
you calling gramps?
Guys, stop it. Both of
you, stop it! Hey. Hey.
Ah!
- Look what you did.
- You did it.
- Will you both shut up?
- You okay?
- Can I get a doctor here?
- What happened?
Dennis Cooper, 32. Multiple GSWs to the
chest. I got his 8-year-old daughter too.
- Was she shot?
- No.
Dad arrested about a minute out.
No BP, but good pulse with CPR.
All right. Somebody page Corday
and open a thoracotomy tray.
Spreader.
Okay, crank it open. Suction.
- What do you need?
- No. It slipped. I need to reset the lip.
- I could use a subclavian.
- Eight French cordis introducer.
Gallant's with the daughter.
Paramedics don't think she's
injured, but she was covered in blood.
I've got it, Kerry.
- Open up the pericardium.
- Pick-up.
What's her status, Gallant?
She has a couple superficial abrasions.
No evidence of any penetrating injuries.
I don't think any
of this is her blood.
Hey, who is your friend?
The first officers on the scene
found her hiding under a table.
By the looks of it, she saw everything,
including who shot her father.
So, what's your name?
- I couldn't get her to say.
- Her name is Brianne Cooper.
Brianne, I'm Dr. Weaver.
And we're trying to make
your daddy better, okay?
- Okay.
- All right.
- Now, are you hurt?
- I don't think so.
Did you see who
shot your father?
- Do you mind?
- I need to know.
Yeah. And I need to make
sure that she's all right.
- Wait outside until we're finished.
- Her father is known...
Outside means outside.
- Should I call DCFS?
- Mm-hm.
Don't worry, Brianne.
You and your daddy are safe here.
Nobody's gonna hurt you now, okay?
- She wasn't hurt.
- Physically, no.
But she's showing signs of
post-traumatic stress disorder.
You have to wait until the
psychiatrist is finished with her.
- How long will that take?
- Look.
Some girl just saw somebody
put five bullets into her father.
Yeah. And I need
to know who did it.
Her father's a well-known drug dealer
and a murder suspect in his own right.
If whoever did this finds out she was
the only witness, they may finish the job.
- What about her mother?
- She's a junkie and a possible suspect.
All right. Post an officer outside
her room, and I'll try to speak with her.
Okay, fine.
We did the best we could, but the
bullet passed through Mr. Cooper's aorta.
- How's the little girl?
- She's still in shock.
- You like me to speak to her for you?
- No, I think I should do it. But thanks.
Sorry about the delay.
I got a little backed up.
No problem.
The whole procedure only takes about
40 minutes once we get started, okay?
This frame provides
reference points...
so we can pinpoint the tumor
with 201 separate gamma rays.
Hope you're a good shot.
Well, the machine's
accurate up to .3 millimeters.
- What if I sneeze?
- Just try not to.
It could vaporize all the brain
matter in your skull cavity.
Kidding, Dr. Greene. You won't be able
to move once we lock the frame down.
- Any last questions?
- Nope.
All right. See you
in a few minutes.
Just try and relax, Dr. Greene.
I'm ready.
- Has anybody seen Dr. Greene?
- He left.
Already?
- Did he say where he was going?
- Sorry.
- We have an appointment.
- I can page him.
You should take it easy
for the rest of the day.
No problem.
A few people report
headaches, nausea and vomiting.
What about seizures?
Less than 10 percent experience
seizures in the next 24 hours.
But you're on Dilantin...
and we gave you some Decadron
to reduce the risk of brain edema.
- Is there someone to drive you home?
- I took the El.
- Is someone staying with you tonight?
- My daughter.
It would be better
if it's an adult.
Rachel's a teenager.
Well, just have her check on you,
and call if there are any problems.
Call Dr. Sanders and tell him I
can't see his patient until Monday.
Yes, doctor.
Reschedule Jenna
Kline for Thursday.
Fax Dr. Horton Brook
Yeung's MEG results.
I'm Dr. Greene. My
daughter has an appointment.
- Ella.
- Yeah. My wife should be bringing her.
You just missed them.
What does that mean exactly?
In the interest of
legal efficiency...
- we cut a deal. ABBY: A
deal for what? For jail time?
No. One year parole, 40
hours of community service.
Community service?
- This guy attacked me.
- This is his first offense.
He's pathological. I've had to
call the police on him before.
He has no prior arrests. We're also
insisting he undergo mandatory therapy.
Oh, that's great. So, what, he counts
to 10 before he hits somebody now?
- This is the best we could do.
- The best you can do?
Let's not overlook that someone
beat the hell out of Westlake...
a couple hours after
you were attacked.
- What?
- But...
you didn't know
anything about that, right?
No.
Wiggle your toes.
Fingers.
- I'm not paralyzed?
- You are showing signs of improvement.
It's only gonna get better as the
swelling in your spinal cord goes down.
You are lucky.
Put this behind you.
Your dad is gonna
be glad to hear this.
You know, the police
think that he was drinking.
My dad doesn't drink.
They're pretty angry
about what he did.
Pulling you behind a snowmobile,
your dad should know better.
- He does.
- Then what happened?
It wasn't your dad's idea to pull
you behind the snowmobile, was it?
It was Chris' idea. We were
just trying to have a little fun.
Elizabeth?
- Where were you?
- I'm sorry. Something came up.
- More important than our daughter?
- I was there. I just missed you.
I talked to the doctor.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Yeah. Well, any long-term effects
remain to be seen, don't they?
Dr. Greene, Ian Nevinger's
sats are down to 78.
I'm down for a GSW. You better
hope you can still intubate him.
- You still awake in here?
- A little.
Brianne, I have some bad news...
about your father.
The surgeons did
their best to help him.
But one of the bullets hit
his heart and damaged it.
They couldn't fix it.
He died.
I know it's hard...
and you feel really sad.
But it's very important
that you talk with the police.
No.
They just want to make sure
they find out who did this...
so that they don't
hurt anyone else.
Did you see who
shot your father?
Yes.
And do you know who they were?
Will you tell the police?
I can't.
Honey, you don't
need to be afraid.
- Was it your mother?
- No.
Then who?
Me.
You.
You shot your father?
He fell asleep on the couch and
left his gun on the coffee table.
Why did you shoot him?
Brianne...
was he hurting you?
Honey, was he doing things
to you that he shouldn't be?
He wouldn't let me watch TV.
So you shot him?
He said if I turned on the TV
while he was asleep, he'd shoot me.
So I shot him first.
He can't protect his
airway much longer.
- Can we go in before you intubate him?
- He'd prefer if you didn't.
This is the last chance
we'll have to speak with him.
He doesn't want you to see
him in his present condition.
I've seen worse.
- This is your husband.
- Yes, he is.
- If they stay here.
- Okay.
Brendan, watch your brother.
I have to talk to the doctor.
Carboxyhemoglobin's 30.
- I said no.
- I said yes.
You're gonna be okay, Ian.
How's my hair look?
You might want to get
a wig till it grows back.
Maybe I can get an Afro, huh?
Haleh, suction.
I can do that. I'm an RN.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't talk.
Burn unit have any beds?
- Holding.
He's gonna need a
Swan-Ganz catheter.
- Are these his labs?
- Some of them.
He tested positive
for amphetamines?
- Were you smoking up?
- It was an accident.
You lied to me. You told me you'd
stay clean. You promised me you'd quit.
I did. PAM: Was it good?
- Did you get nice and stoned?
- I just wanted to finish the dresser.
No, Ian. You just
wanted to get high!
- Pam... GREENE: Let's
get the heliox started.
- Chuny, have you seen Mrs. Nevinger?
- No, sorry.
What's going on?
We're trying to decide what to do
with Aaron. Can't reach the mother.
The father's blood
alcohol level was negative.
Yes. But what he
did was still reckless.
I don't want to split up this family, but
the father is as much a kid as his son.
The boys talked him into it. They
should take some of the blame.
- You need to talk to them.
- I did, and they didn't say anything.
Hey. Did you talk to the
social worker and the police?
- Yeah.
- What did you tell them?
What do you care?
- You worried about getting in trouble?
- No.
What is it, then?
- You want your dad to get arrested?
- Maybe it'll smarten him up.
What?
My dad's always doing stupid stuff
and saying things that are embarrassing.
Every teenager thinks
that about their parents.
Yeah. But my
dad's really a moron.
Well, you won't have
to worry about that...
once Child Services puts
you into a foster family.
- He could've said no.
- Could he?
You think your father likes
what happened to him?
He lost his wife.
He lost his job.
He lost himself.
You're the only
thing he has left.
And he still thinks that
you two are buddies.
We are.
Well, then you need to grow
up and start acting like one.
- Are the cops still here?
- They might be.
- Well, can I talk to them again?
- I'll see what I can do.
And could you tell
my dad I'm sorry?
No, but you can.
Why are you still here?
- I'm on till 8.
- You shouldn't be on at all.
- Do you have a headache?
- Just... Just a little stress.
Yeah. That and several
hundred beams of radiation...
zapped into your
brain this afternoon.
You need to go home.
There's just a
half an hour left.
- Did you tell her?
- Who?
Mark.
You said you were
gonna talk to her.
Does Rachel know?
Mark, they're
gonna figure it out.
Let them figure it out.
So you're gonna
keep this a secret...
act like nothing's wrong
until you pass out in public?
The moment you tell them,
they start treating you differently.
They start giving you that look.
What look?
That look. That look like you're
half-dead, like you're already gone.
Believe me, I've seen it before.
Yeah. Well, you're still here.
Good night.
Oh.
- What is it?
- Nothing.
- Mark.
- I'm just a little nauseous.
- That's it. I'm taking you home.
- No. I am not going home.
You have two choices.
I am taking you home right now or I'm
ratting you out to Weaver. What'll it be?
You'd better not
vomit in my car.
The burn unit's ready
for Nevinger, Dr. Corday.
- Haleh, do we have Marcaine?
- Right in front of you.
Right.
Can you take him up? I don't want
to lose his airway in the elevator.
- Who?
- Nevinger, the surface burn.
I thought he was intubated.
He's stabilized on a heliox,
but he's drifting down again.
- He's Dr. Greene's patient. Ask him.
- Dr. Greene went home.
- He did?
- Half-hour ago.
It says "Corday" on the chart.
Fine.
Mr. Nevinger, how's
your breathing?
Did you find her? CORDAY: Who?
My wife.
She isn't here?
Dr. Corday, sats
down to 9 percent.
Point-eight of Pav, prep
20 of etomidate, 120 of sux.
Mr. Nevinger, we're going to
have to intubate you for transfer.
You might not be able
to talk for a few days...
but your wife will
be able to talk to you.
I let her down.
Tested positive
for amphetamines.
Promised her.
All you need to worry
about now is getting better.
8-O ET tube.
Even if I live, she'll leave me.
Oh, I'm sure that's not true.
Wouldn't you? I
mean, look at me.
Things might be difficult for
both of you for a while, yes.
But you just need to
give her some time.
- Could you find her?
- Meds are in.
Tell her I love her, I'm sorry.
Yes, of course.
- Yankauer tip and a 3-mac.
- Got it. Bag him.
No. I had Debbie
pick up the kids.
Okay.
Thanks, Evelyn.
No, I will. I will.
Yeah. Bye.
Mrs. Nevinger? I'm Dr. Corday.
I helped work on your husband.
They told me you were in
Chairs. I was afraid you'd left.
No, I'm leaving now. I just
called Ian's mom. She's coming.
I didn't tell her about
the drugs. I should.
I should let the boys see him. Show
them what drugs did to their father.
They'll see that soon enough.
Assuming we're still
around when he gets out.
We've just moved your
husband up to the burns unit.
Look, I know what
he did was wrong...
and obviously you have
some things to work out...
but he really needs
you right now.
Yeah? What about me?
What about my sons? They really need
a father, but they don't have one now.
Yes, they do.
No. They have a drug addict in a hospital
with burns over 50 percent of his body.
He's still their father.
He's still your husband.
You do know that he could succumb to
infection and die within the next week?
That is not my fault. I begged
him to stop using drugs.
- I'm certain he's sorry for what he did.
- Is he?
Mrs. Nevinger, he's
in unbelievable pain.
He'll be permanently disfigured.
He'll never look like the
father your sons remember.
I think he's suffered enough
punishment, don't you?
You two can go home. You're
both suspended until Monday.
- For what?
- For fighting.
- We weren't fighting.
- I was told you two got into a fistfight.
I'm afraid somebody's pulling
your leg, chief, so to speak.
Yeah. I love this old guy.
Dr. Chen, did you or did you not witness
these two getting into an altercation?
- What altercation?
- You were knocked to the floor.
No. I tripped over a phone cord
earlier, but that was my own fault.
Hey, knock it off, you two.
Carter. Just the man I want to
see. Look. I got six patients for you.
- Not on for eight minutes.
- You're here.
- But I'm eating.
- Well, too bad.
Jing-Mei?
Randall.
I've been calling you all day. Did
you...? Did you get my flowers?
Yes. Thanks.
So are you off?
You know, actually, I have...
- Aren't you covering Dr. Greene?
- Yes. Yes, I am.
Well, what about after that?
Look, Randall, you're
a nice guy and all...
but I just don't think this is
gonna work out between us.
Well, I had fun.
Yeah. Sorry. I've
gotta get back to work.
Can I call you?
No.
Bye.
Don't tell me you just
broke up with that guy.
It was hardly a breakup. I
mean, we just went out once.
- One date and he buys flowers?
- Can you believe it?
You give a guy hand-release during
Harry Potter and he wants to marry you.
You okay?
Thank you.
Hi.
- Hi.
- Can I help you?
Nope.
- Hey, Abby?
- Hey.
- Come on in.
- No, I...
I just wanted to say hi. I
didn't know you had company.
No. Just a couple of friends.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- You need a place to stay, let me help.
- It's okay, really.
- Please? For me.
I need you.
They're kicking my
ass in Pictionary.
Come on.
Three lap cholys, two inguinal
hernias, LeFort Ill reduction...
vagotomy and a
pancreaticoduodenectomy.
I only assisted on the LeFort.
Daniels was the primary.
Well, Daniels has
moved to Las Vegas.
Growing demand for
breast implants, apparently.
Yeah. Well, I guess I should've
moved further away myself.
This doesn't have to
be so clandestine, Peter.
You won't burst into flames
if you step inside the hospital.
I know. I just wanted
to make a clean break.
Yeah. Well, finish those
and you'll be free of us.
Oh, and you owe
me $27 for Xerox.
How's the baby?
Normal background
rhythms, low amp activity.
All right, make
sure you get SSEPs.
You seem to be holding up okay.
Yeah.
What?
I think I may have
left my husband.
- You think?
- Well, I moved out. I'm living in a hotel.
What happened?
I've never made demands
on him, not real ones anyway.
The only time I ask him to
put his family first, he can't do it.
- Back up. You lost me.
- He won't send Rachel away.
It's like he has to
prove he loves her.
- You want him to prove he loves you.
- Yes. No.
I don't know.
I don't know if I'm protecting
my daughter or just angry.
- Look, Elizabeth, I'd be angry too...
- At Mark.
You see, I think I do blame
him for what happened.
And I think I've found a way to avoid
being with him because I blame him.
He's different.
It's like he's...
It's like he's disconnected
from us somehow.
Or maybe it's me, you know?
I just don't have the
energy to figure it out.
What happens if he sent
Rachel home tomorrow?
Usually this time of year...
Chicagoans are tired
of cold and snow...
wondering if winter
will ever end...
You're out of mustard.
- I told you, I'm not hungry.
- You have to eat.
That's right. Starve
a cold, feed a tumor.
You need to keep
your strength up.
I need to take a nap.
Well, I'll help you upstairs
if you have some soup.
No, I mean right
now, right here.
What if Rachel comes
home? She'll see you're sick.
She's sleeping
over at a friend's.
Mark, you have to have someone
watch you following Gamma Knife therapy.
- Oh, great.
- What?
I can't close my eye.
I've heard of cowboys who
sleep with one eye open.
I'm glad you
think this is funny.
Okay.
Hold still.
You'll have to start
using artificial tears.
Yeah.
How's that?
It's good. Thanks.
Don't let the soup
get cold, huh?