♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
Naomi's okay with it?
Yes.
With you and me,
she's okay with it?
Yes.
You told her
we were sleeping together,
and she's fine with that?
Sam.
No, I'm just saying.
Her ex-husband
and best friend
doing all kinds of pervy,
hot, nasty, sexy...
Okay,
she was surprised, yes,
but, you know,
we drank some wine.
We did what we do,
and in the end, she was fine.
I mean, it's okay.
She's okay.
If you say so.
Sam, why can't you believe
that she's okay?
Would you be?
Running's for idiots.
Oh, it's so good having you
living here again.
It makes my mornings 100 percent
more interesting.
And the evenings? Whew.
Yeah,
they're pretty awesome too.
Whoa. Hey, could you hold that?
Whew.
Where you going?
Fifth floor.
Me too.
First visit?
Yeah. I've, uh,
been avoiding this.
Don't worry. You're gonna love
everybody in there.
Oh, sorry.
Hey.
You cannot be here.
Who needs cereal when you can
have chocolate cupcakes?
You take my husband and all
I get are chocolate cupcakes?
Wha--? Uh...
Wow, as far as guilt gifts go,
you kind of cheaped out
a little.
No, no, Nai. That's not
what this is. I, uh...
I didn't mean to, um...
I'm kidding.
Oh.
Good.
I'm fine, Addison.
I'm okay. I'm fine.
We're fine.
Mm.
Okay.
Well, um, thank you
for being so understanding, Nai.
Well,
I'm not doing it for you.
With Dell and Maya and William,
I'm just, uh--
I'm letting it all go.
I'm just-- I'm done carrying
around all my anger.
Sam:
Get the hell out of here.
Pete: Easy, Sam.
You got some nerve
showing up like this.
I need to talk to you.
What's going on?
It's the guy that hit
Maya and Dell.
Hagen:
I am so sorry.
No. No. You don't get a chance
to be sorry.
He doesn't get a chance
to apologize.
Is that--?
That's the guy.
I would give anything
to take it back, but I can't.
Look, I made a deal with the
prosecutor. I'm being sentenced.
I'll go to jail. I deserve that.
But I just wanted--
I don't know.
If you could forgive me?
Sam!
Hey!
As far as I'm concerned--
Addison: Let him go. Sam.
--You shouldn't even be alive.
Let him go right now, Sam.
Cooper: Sam.
Someone call 911.
Hagen: Oh, my chest.
Addison: Get the oxygen.
Take slow, deep breaths.
Breathe. Breathe.
Sam, I know you're upset,
but to choke this man...
Do you--?
Do you know I'm upset?
Yes, of course,
I understand, but...
Sam:
Because you should've been
choking him with me.
Why?
Instead of standing back...
What do you expect me to do?
I expect you to back me up.
Back you up?
She's your daughter.
Of course.
I want you to remember.
Naomi:
I went through the same thing.
Sam:
Remember her in that bed.
What's that about?
Chickens coming home to roost.
What if you killed that man?
We...
Can somebody translate?
The guy who killed Dell
showed up to apologize.
And Sam took matters into his
own hands literally, like:
Well, good for Sam.
The guy should've just crawled
into a hole and disappeared.
Give the guy credit
for having the guts
to walk through the door
and face all of us.
He had to know the reception
he was gonna get.
Pete:
If he almost killed my kid,
I'd make sure he rotted in
prison for the rest of his life.
Don't you have things to do?
Charlotte: I don't think so.
I'm kind of clear.
Naomi:
I hate what he did
every bit as much as you,
but that doesn't mean
you can go and attack him.
Why are you defending him?
I am not defending him, Sam.
But he did come here
to apologize.
Apologize?
Apologize for killing Dell
and almost killing our daughter?
What kind of apology--?
Sam, I don't know!
I don't know. You didn't give
the man a chance to speak.
I spoke to the hospital
and, um,
Troy hagen is stable,
but his EKG does show signs
of new changes.
Sam, are you okay?
I don't know what that guy needs
to say to make you feel good
about him getting drunk
and driving into Maya and Dell.
He killed a man.
He doesn't get my forgiveness.
Maybe you can calm him down.
Sam, can we please--?
Some things don't deserve
to be forgiven.
Man:
What do we have?
Forty-five-year-old teacher,
passed out in the middle
of a school play.
Now he's complaining
about persistent chest pains.
It looks like an acute mi.
What's your plan?
He needs to go up for bypass.
I've got a stab wound
to the chest to deal with.
Get him to the or.
If you need any help--
I'm good.
You sure?
Absolutely.
Okay, thanks. Let's go.
Child:
When is he coming back?
The kids refused to finish the
show. They're really worried.
We're gonna do the best we can,
sir.
Okay, so I guess this means
no dinner?
Oh, no.
We were to meet
Derek and Addison
at the restaurant
in 20 minutes.
Oh, well, there's Addison,
so I guess Derek's
at the restaurant by himself.
You're doing a bypass
on your own.
Yeah. I just got it.
Yeah?
Well, I just picked up
a bilateral oophorectomy.
I don't start cutting
for a couple hours.
Maybe, uh, I can watch?
All right, you guys have fun.
I have a baby-sitter
and Derek made the reservations.
I'm having dinner
with your husband.
I'll try not to steal him.
Apologize to Derek for me?
Naomi: Okay.
Bye-bye.
What's wrong?
Do me a favor.
Take this to radiology.
Ask them for a ct angio
before the or.
Sure.
Thanks.
All right, come on, guys.
Is it worse than you thought?
Uh, it might be.
I just-- if there's a chance
I'm not gonna make it,
I need to talk to somebody.
We can do that for you.
Do you need a priest?
I've done some bad things.
And every day I tell myself
that I'm gonna stop,
but I can't.
Mr. Yates.
I know they're only children,
but I can't help myself.
I need to touch them.
I try, but I can't stop.
And I'm so sorry.
Hey. Are you okay?
I will be.
I was with that guy
on the elevator.
He seemed nice.
I had no idea.
Maybe this is not a good time.
No, please, distract me.
Okay. You should hire me.
Don't beat around the bush
on my account.
Well, you've got
a nice little practice here.
The baby thing is covered.
You've got shrinks
for the screw-ups.
Specialists to handle everything
from heart attacks to hernias.
What you don't have
is a neurosurgeon.
I'm listening.
I graduated
top of my class at Harvard.
I did my residency
at Johns Hopkins.
I have published
enough research
to single-handedly wipe out
several forests.
I'm the real deal, Naomi.
I'm a kick-ass,
world-class catch.
Did Addison coach you
on how to sell yourself?
No, we haven't discussed it yet.
But you are the big boss now,
right?
Look, Amelia, you obviously have
impressive credentials.
But this practice
is about cooperative medicine,
not solo surgeries.
You could go anywhere you want.
Why here?
I like to cut.
I won't deny that.
But...
I think that this would be
a good environment
for me to broaden my skill set.
Don't give me
the rehearsed answer.
I have nowhere else to go
where I'm not alone.
Derek forgave me, but...
I have nowhere else to go.
Oh, hey.
I just wanted to let you know
I ordered us the new bed today.
I hope you like it.
Don't see why I wouldn't.
Well, you know,
it's a lot firmer.
It's basically
just a wooden plank.
I don't know
if that's your thing, but...
Oh, yeah,
and we're getting a dog.
A mastiff, 160 pounds,
very drooly.
Gonna sleep in the bed with us.
Dog whisperer, whatever
you've gotta say, spit it out.
Because I have to get
to the hospital
before hagen's heart Peters out
or Sam rips it from his chest.
Why are you house-hunting
without me?
Pull up your bra strap, Coop.
I hired a realtor
when you kicked me out.
Then we got engaged,
so I told her to look
for something bigger.
It's a house, Charlotte.
It's kind of a big deal.
Okay, but we need to move.
What's wrong with the loft?
It's too grungy. Your neighbors
are freakishly chipper.
And it'd be nice
to sleep with you
in a place
that wasn't a fond memory
for half the tramps in L.A.
You know that's not fair.
I went out of my way to make
that place feel like ours.
I took down
all the vintage Houdini posters.
I let you re-do the bathroom
the way you like.
I'm doing cartwheels.
Can we at least agree
it's something
that we should consider
together?
Fine.
Seeing a house in the palisades
tomorrow, 8:00.
Stop whining
and you can join me.
This guy, he's got a piece of
phosphorous stuck in his thigh.
He's screaming like hell
because that stuff burns.
A bullet wound in his back--
Pete's got his hand on my shirt
and he's trying to drag me out
of the hut.
Pete:
The hut was on fire.
Ugandan rebel army
was about to get there--
it was Eritrea. And I wasn't
gonna leave the guy.
Uganda. And it was either leave
you there or let you get shot.
Can somebody tell me
what happened to the guy?
We got him out.
We stabilized him,
then together we carried him
four miles
to the nearest refugee camp.
You know, Violet,
I like you.
You're beautiful, you're smart.
What the hell are you doing
with this guy?
I haven't figured that out yet.
Would you stop flirting?
Get your own wife.
This is ridiculous. You've been
in town running your clinic
for, what, six months,
and this is the first time
we've met?
Gibby is impossible
to nail down.
The guy doesn't even have
a cell phone.
Never found much use for them
in the jungle.
Excuse me.
Come in. Come in.
Dr. Gibson, it's my husband.
We were making dinner and he had
bad pains in his belly.
It's getting worse.
Rock hard.
Could be a perfed appy.
I'll call an ambulance.
No, wait.
Give me a hand. On three.
One, two, three.
Take him down there.
What are you doing?
Saving his life.
Come on, gibby. We can drive him
to the hospital right now.
This is insane.
You could lose your license.
You could be sued
for malpractice.
Or I could save his life so his
wife doesn't become a widow,
so his kids don't lose
their father.
The belly's full of pus.
I could really use a hand.
Okay.
Pete.
Just until we get him
stabilized.
And then I'm out of here.
I promise.
Uh, I'm tired.
Sam, you had a right
to get angry today.
I know.
I mean, he hit Maya.
I don't wanna talk about it.
Sam--
I'm tired.
Good night.
Hey. What do you think,
diplomas behind the desk
or on the side wall?
So this is one of the things
you were gonna catch me up on?
Pretty cool, huh?
Can you hand me that box?
Sure.
Hey, I hope I didn't keep you up
last night.
I was nervous
about Naomi's decision,
so I just got up
and watched a movie.
Uh, no, I was at Sam's.
I didn't even know
you were in the house.
So, um, how was Seattle?
I had sex with Mark Sloan.
That man has skills.
Face like an angel,
hips like the devil, huh? Ha-ha.
Right?
Right.
Anyway,
it's all turning around for me.
I mean,
Derek and I are back on track
and I am starting
this fantastic new job.
New job.
What?
It's just a little weird
that Naomi didn't mention this
to me.
We usually-- we make these
decisions as a group.
Oh, she probably figured
you wouldn't mind.
I mean, you don't, do you?
No, of course not.
First earthquake,
that house just tumbles
right down that hill.
Being on a hill is what gives it
those amazing ocean views.
It's gonna have
an even better view
when it lands
in the actual ocean.
You're just punishing me
because I started looking
without you.
You're not listening,
Charlotte.
I don't wanna look at all.
Well, I hate your place, Cooper.
Because it reminds me of all
the things I screwed up,
all the fights we had.
You not letting me in the front
door after you found out
I was building
the practice downstairs.
Standing like an idiot with the
corn bread chicken casserole
in your bedroom,
trying to make up
after I tried to force you
to elope.
Fighting over
that damn latex jumpsuit
after I bought you
into the practice.
And we can't move forward
if that's staring me in the face
every day.
You never told me
any of this.
Well, now you know.
So...
Amelia works here now.
Yeah, I know. I hired her.
It's a little weird that you
decided without telling me.
Well, you decided to sleep
with my ex without telling me.
Wow.
Seriously?
Well, you know--
babies are tiny terrorists.
I'm dying
from sleep deprivation.
Lucas was up five times
last night.
Where was Pete?
He was operating. In a house.
His friend runs
a neighborhood clinic
and he sees no problem
with performing emergency
surgeries there.
I-- that cannot be legal.
Probably not the biggest concern
his patients have.
He's doing surgeries in a house.
Well, I didn't say I agreed
with it, but I get it.
The people he treats probably
don't have money or insurance.
They're scared of trying
to navigate the system--
even a county hospital
is better equipped
to deal with emergencies
than someone's living room.
We're talking surgery
in an unsterile environment.
The risk of staph infection
is huge and--
because nobody ever got
a staph infection in a hospital.
Okay. Fine. Well, what about
if something goes wrong?
Gibby doesn't have the resources
to deal with that.
Things go wrong
in hospitals too.
And I'm minding my own business.
I know you're mad
that I stayed but--
that guy could have died.
But he didn't and he's home
recovering with his family.
So that justifies
what you did?
I helped a friend
save a guy's life.
Gibby is helping himself.
Look, I know.
I know he's trying to do
something good here,
but there's--
there's better ways.
There's safer ways
of doing that.
Only none of them feed the god
complex that he's got going on.
The patient has cad
with crescendo angina.
My plan is to cool him down,
then do a three-way bypass.
I'll schedule an or
for you.
I called in Campbell
to handle Mr. Hagen's case.
She's gonna do a cabg.
I don't wanna know.
Okay. I respect that.
You want me to leave this up?
What? No.
Are you sure, Sam?
Yeah, I gotta go.
Hagen did ask
to speak to you.
I told him I'd pass it along.
I told you
I don't wanna deal with this.
Addison:
What is it?
Sam:
Double lumen on a aortic arch.
A dissecting aneurysm?
Yeah.
A different surgery
altogether.
Are you gonna get
your attending up here?
No. I'm gonna scrub in.
Are you sure?
He's a child molester.
What?
He thinks that he's gonna die,
so he wanted to get it
off his chest.
He's a pedophile.
Sam.
I'm doing the surgery.
I can handle it.
Hey.
Hold still.
One more minute.
Hey.
You're back.
And with gifts.
I noticed you were running low
on supplies.
Oh, thanks, man. You're a
lifesaver. Last night too.
I hope that didn't rock the boat
at home.
It'll blow over.
Listen, I've been thinking about
your setup here
and I've got some contacts
at surgery centers.
Let me see what kind of deal
I can work out for you.
Pete, most of my patients
don't even have cars.
None of them wanna be part of
a system that's failed them.
I'm fine with what I got.
One surgery goes wrong--
I don't remember you
being such a worrier.
What's wrong
with that little girl?
I don't know. I haven't had time
to check her out yet.
This is triage, man.
You know the game.
The sicker ones go first.
Hi.
Can I look at your arm?
It's popped out of its socket.
Here. It's okay.
There. Okay?
Okay.
Okay. Who's next?
Troy hagen's
refusing treatment.
But he has unstable angina.
He's gonna die
if he doesn't have surgery.
Seems to be the point.
Well, it's his choice.
Maybe he's trying to skip jail?
He's not. He feels like
he doesn't deserve to live.
Well, has anyone asked Sam
to talk to him?
Asked Sam to talk to who
about what?
Someone has to convince hagen
to have surgery.
Why?
I thought you guys
were all into helping people.
Oh, screw him.
I get that you're
emotional about this.
I mean, the guy made a mistake.
Does that mean
that he deserves to die?
Isn't the question whether
we have to go out of our way
to help him live?
Hey. Where have you been?
Hey.
I've been calling you
for hours.
I was at the clinic
with gibby.
I was treating patients.
You missed
three appointments.
I know.
I'll ask them to reschedule.
I've decided to volunteer at the
clinic one afternoon a week.
Pete.
There were 20 people
in his waiting room
and more standing outside.
People who have nowhere to go,
who need help.
You help people here every day.
It's not the same.
Our clients have money, they can
pay for the care we give.
These people have nothing.
They need me.
I get it.
And it's noble.
It's just too risky, you know.
For gibby, for the patients,
for you.
Okay, spare me the sermon.
I don't wanna give you
a sermon. I just--
I want you to think
about what you're doing.
I know what I'm doing,
Violet.
I thought you'd
already be cutting.
Hey. I'm heading in right now.
Well, I'm glad I caught you.
Um...
I wore this cap for my first
solo surgery, so it's good luck.
Well, I'm already scrubbed in,
so could you?
Sure.
You okay?
Yeah, yeah. I'm fine.
Sam.
Hmm?
You can do this.
Yeah, I know I can.
I've done grafts
on a hundred pig hearts.
It's not what I meant.
I have a daughter, Addison.
A daughter who's younger
than those kids waiting.
It's irrelevant.
Irrelevant?
You're his surgeon.
Only thing
that should concern you.
Your job isn't to judge his
life.
Your job is to save his life.
That's all.
Right?
Hey. I--
you need to convince Sam
to talk to Troy hagen.
I thought we weren't talking
about Sam.
No, I can talk about Sam.
You don't get to.
But, uh, you do need
to straighten him out.
This is not something that is up
for discussion with him.
I know Sam and--
no, no. I know Sam.
You're just sleeping with him.
I'm sorry.
You really wanna be with Sam?
You need to be with him.
You got to be his sounding
board. His conscience.
You need to kick him in
the behind when he needs it.
You've got a stubborn man
on your hands, Addison,
and it's not okay to just walk
away when things get hard.
Step up.
Hey, you're not gonna tell Pete,
are you?
What? That we're having lunch
on a non-prescribed day?
I'm gonna keep Charlotte
in the dark.
I don't even think Pete
would care now.
All he's thinking about
is how to get back to the jungle
where he can perform open-heart
surgery with a pen-knife.
You hate the jungle.
You don't like grass.
I think he's struggling
with the path not taken.
Wait, I thought he already
took that path
and then got off, didn't--?
Well, being around gibby
has obviously tapped
into something, you know.
He's so--
he's so happy and re-energized.
And, no, I want him to be happy.
I do. I just--
not at any cost.
Pete's no dummy.
He's making a choice.
Just like Charlotte who's just
deciding she hates my apartment.
We're on to you now?
She wants to move.
It's your bachelor pad, Cooper.
You can't blame her.
No more than you can
blame Pete.
So, what are we gonna do?
Well,
you're the shrink.
What would you tell
a patient?
I would say you have to confront
your problems.
Be honest. And then, you know,
whatever happens, happens.
People pay you for that?
Hey.
Wow, that looks like
not even a little bit fun.
Yeah. It's just this
foundation paperwork.
I-I don't even know
where to begin.
Much more interested
in just looking
at pictures of Olivia.
Aww.
Okay, that baby has my ears too.
It must be me.
I have baby ears.
Let me see. No.
Did you need something?
Well, I just wanted to make sure
that you were okay.
Oh.
Having Troy hagen show up,
yeah, that really threw me.
Yeah.
And I miss William.
But I was talking more about
the whole Sam and Addison thing.
And I know from having to watch
Violet and Pete,
and Charlotte and Cooper,
that it can make work
a little awkward.
I'm fine. You know, Sam and I,
we had our shot.
And seems only fair
that he and Addison
should have theirs, so I'm fine.
Well, that's an admirable
position to take.
I don't wanna be someone
who can't move forward.
Sure. Sure.
But sometimes what we wanna be
and what we actually feel
can be two different things.
I'm not proud of it,
but once when no one was around,
I licked Pete's bagel.
Okay, I'm a little proud of it.
My point is that you should
give yourself permission
to use whatever kind
of a coping mechanism you need.
Screaming, crying,
maybe even a dart board
with both their faces.
Do whatever you need to do.
Trust me, I'm licensed to give
that kind of advice.
Violet:
What are you doing?
Gibby called.
He has an emergency.
Call an ambulance.
Let them deal with it.
That's not the way this works.
That's exactly
how this works.
When you have an emergency,
call 911 and they take you
to the hospital.
I knew you wouldn't understand.
Then talk to me.
Explain to me why my husband
would risk everything,
his practice, his medical
license, his family,
because some old ghost
from his past asked him to.
I miss this kind of work, okay?
The rush of it.
The way it makes me feel.
I knew you wouldn't understand.
Hey, hey, hey.
I used to work
with inner-city single moms.
I used to counsel rape victims.
I ran a suicide hotline.
I do understand.
But I didn't break any laws
doing it.
Don't wait up.
Why are you lurking?
I'm not lurking.
I do not lurk.
About the--
this whole Troy hagen thing...
I don't wanna
talk about him.
What, Addison?
Why did you quit
doing heart surgery before?
Why?
I'm not discussing that.
Sam.
Just leave it alone.
No.
That patient, that pedophile,
and now Troy hagen.
Just shut up, please?
Shut up.
What did you do, Sam?
Doctors choose to do nothing
all the time.
You know it, I know it.
It's the dirty little secret
of surgery.
Doctors choose to do nothing.
Wait. When the patient
is brain-dead
or is gonna suffer
or is too far gone--
doctors choose to do nothing.
They choose to do nothing
for the right reasons, Sam.
Tell me. It's okay.
Just--
what did you do?
Okay, he's off bypass.
He's in fib. Lost his pulse.
Dr. Bennett?
Sam: Starting cardiac massage.
He's still in fib.
Internal paddles ready.
Dr. Bennett?
No pulse with direct massage.
You're losing him.
Should I page Dr. Warren?
Sam:
No.
Asystole.
Dr. Bennett?
Internal paddles ready.
It's over. We should stop.
But--
we should stop.
Sam:
Time of death, 20:13.
Woman:
Dr. Mendville, 8662.
Dr. Mendville--
what the hell happened in there?
Keep your voice down.
Sam-- Sam, tell me.
I made a judgment call.
I made a call.
It was a bad call.
You don't know that.
Not for sure.
Nobody knows that.
You know that.
Look me in the eye.
Tell me that you didn't just--
Addison, I made a call.
Leave it alone.
I'm done.
What--?
I quit.
I let everybody think that
I froze because it was easier,
but I made a choice.
You let him die.
You knew.
You knew I let him die.
I didn't wanna believe it
and then you quit surgery,
so I guess I just kind of
let it go.
Not everybody
deserves our help.
No, not everybody deserves
our respect. But our help?
There's nothing you can say
right now
that's gonna make me feel
any worse than I already do.
Sam.
That surgery was 12 years ago.
You're a different--
you're a different man now.
No, it doesn't matter.
Yeah, it does matter.
It matters for you, for us.
And hagen, look, somebody else
is gonna do that surgery.
And whatever happens,
it's not on you.
No, it's all on me.
I'm just asking you
to talk to hagen.
Murderer to murderer?
Pete:
What happened?
Girl took three bullets
to the abdomen.
We were sitting in the car
and, uh, these guys pulled up
and I told her to get down.
The bullets were for me.
I get control of one bleeder,
two more open up.
She's bleeding faster
than I can fix them.
You can save her, right?
I mean, you gotta save her.
We've gotta call an ambulance.
No,
that wasn't part of the deal.
What? Deal? Deal?
Gibby:
Alex and his friends pay me
some money from time to time.
You're taking money
from gangbangers?
Keeps the office going.
Would you hand me
a 3.0 vicryl on a driver?
So you look the other way
with criminals
because they're the ones
that can pay?
Gibby:
For every Alex who can pay,
I can treat a hundred patients
who can't.
Don't tell me I'm doing
something wrong.
You're risking peoples' lives.
Now ours.
We used to do that
all the time.
Back then you didn't
cry about it.
Well, back then we didn't have
a choice. Now we do.
Her pressure's dropping.
She needs blood,
platelets, ffp.
Do something.
Gibby: I don't have access.
That's why she needs to be
in a hospital.
We can cross-clamp her aorta.
Try to maintain cns function.
Alex: Put down the phone.
Listen to me.
Your girlfriend has
about five minutes
before she bleeds out
on that table.
And there is nothing, nothing,
that we can do here
to change that.
Put down the gun.
Let me save her life.
Yeah,
I've got a teenaged female.
Multiple gunshot wounds.
I need an ambulance.
Hey, I was just coming
to find you.
I talked to Sam--
"you're selfish, Addison.
"You always have been.
"The tunnel vision
that makes you a great surgeon
also makes you a crappy friend."
What--?
Please let me finish.
Sheldon told me to do this.
Just please.
I just-- let me finish.
"You're a cheater. And while Sam
and I aren't married anymore,
"you knew what you were doing
was wrong,
"and so you lied to me.
"Every day, you didn't tell me
about the two of you, you lied.
"Because you knew
telling the truth would be hard.
"And you're a coward.
You're my best friend,
"but when I look at you now,
I just wanna slap you
across the face."
Okay, I'm finished.
You sure?
I think so.
Feel better?
Kind of.
You wanna know why Sam
quit surgery 12 years ago?
He let a pedophile die
on his table.
What? I--
he made a decision
and it's been eating away
at him ever since.
And seeing Troy hagen, it just
brought it all back for him.
Nai, I know you're mad at me.
I know that we are--
I can't help him.
He needs you.
I see it on your face when
you're here. You feel it.
That thing.
The reason we help people.
That girl would have died
on your table.
Maybe. Maybe not.
But now everything I've built,
they're gonna take it away.
Because you went too far.
You disappoint me.
I've got nothing
to prove to you.
And if I hear
about another clinic,
if I find out that you treat
another patient,
I will personally call the cops
and shut you down.
Sam.
Hey.
I talked to Addison.
She told me.
She told you what?
I know what happened.
Hmm?
I know.
Sam.
Sam. Look at me.
I am.
Please, just look at me.
I understand.
No, you can't.
No, Sam, I do.
But you should've told me.
Because after that,
everything changed.
Maybe not all at once, but--
but just enough.
Yeah.
Well, I'm sorry. Ahem.
I know.
I don't know
if that matters anymore.
Oh, it matters.
It matters to have someone
to listen to you
and try to understand.
It matters.
Sorry.
You okay?
Yeah.
Violet:
You miss it.
Doctors without borders.
The adrenaline.
Yeah.
Listen, I've been thinking
about trying to pick up
some emergency-room shifts.
Get back to critical care.
If we can make it work
with your schedule and Lucas.
We'll make it work.
I know you don't wanna hear
an apology.
No. I don't.
Whatever I say--
it's not gonna change anything.
Have the surgery.
Live.
And do better next time.
What, that's it?
That's all any of us can do.
Should I be worried about
what just happened in there?
Hagen's gonna have
the surgery.
Thank you.
Oh, uh...
Tell Campbell to take another
look at the films.
The patient has
a pseudo-aneurysm.
If Campbell didn't see it,
hagen would have died
on the table.
Hey.
You got a busy day tomorrow?
Not really.
Good. Because I had the realtor
set up some appointments, so...
Why? You tattled to Violet
about our fight
and she told you
to make nice?
No.
If you're unhappy here,
we'll move.
But the truth is,
I don't see what you see.
Every time I walk through
that door with you,
I remember the first time
I brought you here
and how excited I was.
And the bedroom, it doesn't
remind me of makeup casseroles
and catsuit tug of wars.
It reminds me
of the first time we had sex.
And for me,
now that you're here,
everything just feels right.
How about we make a new memory?
Mm-hm. Mm-hm.
Mm-hm.
Hey.
So Sam convinced hagen
to have the surgery.
I heard.
Thank you.
I'm gonna be out of the office
for a few weeks
on foundation business.
Can, uh, can you ask Sam
to check in
on Maya and Olivia for me
while I'm gone?
Sure.
Okay.
Nai, are we ever gonna be
friends the way we were?
You know that night,
the night he quit surgery?
He didn't tell me
what happened.
We had never had secrets
before that.
That was the beginning
of the end of us.
I'm sorry.
Take care of him.
Addie.
Yeah?
This isn't the beginning
of the end of you and me.
Hey.
God, you're much later
than I thought.
Yeah.
I had a nice dinner
with Derek.
That's good.
How did the surgery go?
I lost the patient.
Oh, Sam.
I'm sorry.
Come here.
I'm okay.
I'm gonna go take a shower.
Come here. Come here.
This wasn't your fault.
I know.
Okay? You hear me?
Mm-hm.
It was not your fault.
I'm sorry.
Am I a good man?
Yes.