Surgeons aren't
complacent people.
- Fifty!
- - We don't put our feet up.
We don't sit still.
Whatever the game is...
we like to win.
And once we win,
we get a new game.
Today... feels
like the day to me.
I think, by the close of business
today, I've got cartilage in a bottle.
- What's with you?
- You,
Derek, you're all, "Don't screw
the nurses and the drug reps."
You did a psych rotation,
you know what happens when
you tell someone not to
think about an elephant.
You spend a lot
of time thinking...
I walk around the hospital trying
not to make eye contact with women.
I'm... lonely. And unhappy.
I don't see how
this is a solution.
Find a grown-up who wants
what you want and date.
- Like a grown-up.
- I don't know what that means.
Oncology's kept you busy. Two
rounds of chemo, brachytherapy,
two rounds of
external radiation.
Not to mention coenzymes,
shark cartilage, milk thistle.
- I'm open to pretty
much anything.
- Except surgery.
That's because
surgery's not gonna work.
We'd like to hear
all the options.
Well, your scans will
be back any moment.
Let me tell you what you'll see.
My tumor's the
size of a football.
Audrey.
It's wrapped around my organs.
And if you try to
cut it out, it'll kill me.
That's what you'll see.
We push ourselves.
Residents, attendings.
It doesn't matter
how much we achieve.
If you're a climber, there's
always another mountain.
Dr. Hunt! These are your scans.
I was just looking around.
- That's quite a tumor.
- Huge.
Probably nothing to be done.
Mind if I take a stab at it?
Well, it sounds strange
to you, I'm sure, but...
I only have a few
years left in the game,
and there may not be so
many big tumors left for me.
Of course. You're welcome to it.
What are you doing?
Thanks, Hunt. You're a good egg.
I'm sure you've got
work to do, Dr. Yang.
Mmm-hmm!
- Chart?
- Oh!
Oh!
- What are you doing?
- What?
This is a monster case,
and he just stole it from you
with some crap about
mortality and old men.
He's playing you.
What are you doing?!
All right.
Dr. Webber?
Dr. Webber, I'd like to keep
Audrey Taylor. She was my case.
- You gave it to me.
- You swiped it.
- Cristina.
- Got Harper Avery
written all over it.
When Dr. Avery was here,
he did mention that I needed
to dive back into my research.
This case would be perfect...
This thing is a monster.
At best, it's damage control.
I'll be operating by
the seat of my pants.
On the contrary, a tumor like
this calls for a methodical analysis
- of the scans, a careful plan.
- Right. Old school.
Old?
Wow. I didn't see that coming.
I did not mean your age.
I meant approach. Let's
not make this personal.
You just did, Ginger.
And you're right.
I've been resecting tumors
since you were in diapers.
In my experience, they demand
something a little more elegant
- than "by seat of your pants."
- This is my patient.
Good morning.
Why are we arguing?
- Wow. Big.
- Whose patient is this?
- Mine.
- Work on it together.
Harper Avery is
an individual award.
- Ah! I see where this is going.
- A case like this
needs an aggressive approach...
Sloppy. It requires
methodical analysis...
Some would say outmoded.
- Outmoded?
- All right.
Nothing wrong with friendly
professional competition.
Come up with
plans, I will choose.
Dr. Yang, Dr. Grey will assist.
- Yes!
- I'm with Webber!
What? He's got it in the bag.
"I'm with Webber?" Why'd you
push me to do it in the first place?
Now you'll know what your
plan is and what his plan is.
Wait. You're gonna spy on him?
That's... That's cheating.
You're adorable
when you're slow.
You have a dark, dark mind.
- Here.
- Thanks.
- Hey. You working tonight?
- Uh... No.
I'm going to a yoga class.
Nothing about that
statement makes sense.
Tuck's with his father, and
the fascist vegan next door
gave me a yoga
class for Christmas.
No, you're having
dinner with me.
The fascist vegan thinks that yoga's
going to make me a better person,
which is unlikely,
but if I don't go,
I'll have to hear
about it every day.
"My back kinda hurts,
but the breathing...
I've never breathed like
that before in my life!"
That's what people say
after their first yoga class.
Tell her that, have
dinner with me.
Come on.
Try it. "My back kinda
hurts, but the breathing...
- I've..."
- "Never breathed
like that in my life."
- More conviction.
- "I've never breathed like that
- in my life."
- There you go.
- What?
- This, um...
This patient, I can't
find the heartbeat.
- So call the morgue, 40-watt.
- He's not dead.
He's sitting up, he's talking.
You're lucky you
have a famous name.
Take a deep breath, sir.
Having... trouble doing that.
Oh, grow up, Todd.
When he was nine, they
removed his right lung.
Now the other one's
crapping out on me.
Maybe you're having an anxiety attack
because I asked you to move in with me.
- I can't find his heart.
- Oh, yeah? Me neither.
- No, I really can't.
- Who's the 40-watt now?
I can't... I can't...
Get a stat chest
x-ray and page cardio!
- There she is. By your kidney.
- My heart is by my kidney?
That's why it was hard
to hear your heartbeat.
And without a second lung in your
chest cavity, your heart sort of drifted.
It's called
postpneumonectomy syndrome.
The shifting caused
bronchial compression.
That's why you
weren't able to breathe.
I'm the biggest
bitch in the world.
Can you put it
back where it goes?
Yes. We're gonna use saline
implants in your chest to keep it in place.
Implants? Like
what they use for...
Fake boobs.
You wanna put...?
I can't have...
No. I'm a guy.
OK? I'm a guy's guy.
- You won't actually see them.
- Yeah, but still.
Come on, you know what I'm
saying. I mean, how am I supposed to,
- you know...
- What, pick up women?
How do you explain your boobs to the
next chick dumb enough to date you?
Molly.
- Do I have a choice?
- Do you like to breathe?
So, yes, there is
a surgical option...
We're still figuring
out the best approach.
The risks with this
surgery are very high.
The tumor has compromised
the organs to the point
where anything
we do to remove it...
Will kill me.
Audrey, you're not
even listening to them.
It doesn't make sense. I
just want one more month.
I'm not gonna risk
dying before that.
One more month?
Our daughter is getting
married, in a month.
And I would like
to see her do that.
I would... I would
like to see her
on the happiest day of her life.
Mrs. Taylor, if we
don't try surgery,
you might not make
it through the month.
Then...
I look forward to hearing...
what you come up with.
- Hi, I'm Dr. Grey.
- Hi.
He's really hot and his
stomach hurts so much.
He was fine. We were
playing at the zoo one minute,
- and he was fine. Please.
- OK.
- Noah, does it hurt over here?
- Ow!
- It's OK, baby.
- Page Dr. Robbins, stat.
Right away, doctor.
Hey. Do you have a
minute? I got a question.
- Sure.
- I want to talk
about breast implants.
Really? Good for you.
You know, it crossed my
mind the first time I saw you,
but I didn't think you
were the type to go for it.
No! Not for me.
- For my patient.
- Oh...
Oh!
- Of course.
- Hey!
Can I steal him
for a quick consult?
Yeah. He's all yours.
Yeah, I was just...
She's what you're looking for.
She's age appropriate,
probably wants kids.
- Ask her out.
- I'm not sure
that's gonna work.
Great, thanks. As you were.
Teddy, sorry about that.
Your breasts are fantastic.
I wouldn't change a thing.
- The patient.
- Um... He... Uh...
He's got postpneumonectomy
syndrome.
I wanted to use the
implants to stabilize his heart.
Of course. Let me take a look.
So asking you out tonight
is probably a bad idea?
You think?
- What?
- Mark Sloan just asked me out.
Huh?
- Cool.
- No. No, not cool.
Mark Sloan.
Exactly. Why not have
a little fun? Mark is like...
candy. Eat it and
forget about it.
Right? Come on. Know what?
This might be the best idea I've had.
Will you have to resect
part of the diaphragm?
Most likely.
Or I might let you
do the resection.
- Really?
- Yup.
That, or kick you off the case.
Depends on how much
you leak to Dr. Hunt.
I've been doing this a long time, Dr
Yang. You're working for the other side.
Now, there is another option,
if you would like to
realign your allegiances.
Like be a double agent?
We can keep looking for more
resections for you to perform.
So think about it.
Take your time.
It's a big tumor.
- You rang?
- Yeah.
I'm this close to making
headway on my cartilage,
but I keep getting 42
intern questions an hour.
Can they rotate through
your service for today?
- Sure!
- Thanks.
- What is with you?
- Nothing.
Is it the guy? It's the guy!
- He bought you coffee?
- No.
Think I smile like
this for coffee?
He's making me dinner.
He's cooking? Wow. You ready?
What, for food? I
think I can handle it.
- No, for sex.
- What?
- No! Grow up.
- Give me a break.
- How many dates have you had?
- This'll be three.
Oh, yeah. Third
date is the sex date.
And he's cooking
for you. At his home.
Where he keeps his bed.
I barely know the man.
You're gonna know
him a lot better tomorrow.
There's nothing magic
about a third date.
It is possible to
eat and go home
and not lose your
pants in the process.
Oh, OK.
But if it does go that way,
am I supposed to sleep over?
Oh, no. No, sex on the couch.
Walk of shame to the car
under cover of darkness.
- Do I wear a dress?
- Uh-uh. Casual.
Like you don't expect it's gonna
happen, but you're ready for it.
How ready?
Like... you've prepped
the surgical field.
The su...
- Oh! Torres!
- There is a Ukrainian woman
who works at the manicure
place across the street.
- She will take care of you.
- You...!
- Mm-hmm.
- Oh!
You sure it's OK to give him this much
medicine when we don't know what's wrong?
- It's not gonna hurt him.
- He needed a painkiller, Jim.
I'm telling you, he needed it.
Upright chest and
KUB are negative.
Go get him set up
for a CT with contrast.
How could this have happened?
Say it. You think I
missed something.
Honey, I don't.
Yes, you do. Just admit it.
OK, fine. Fine! How do
you miss a fever this high?
Guys, this isn't gonna help.
Kids get sick.
It's no one's fault.
Yes, it is. It's my fault.
- Kelly, don't.
- If you'd been with him,
I'd blame you. I would kill you if
you had him and this happened.
OK, I need to get him this CT.
I've also added an IV
antibiotic because he's septic
and I want to make sure
we've covered everything.
Maybe he ate
something off the ground.
I was watching him!
- Audrey Taylor's latest LFTs.
- Thank you.
Dr. Altman, I set aside
some saline implants
for your postpneumonectomy
patient. Have a couple on hand.
Size-wise, you won't really know
what you need until you're in there.
Can you scrub in,
place them for me?
Sure.
You know, I was...
Well, I may actually be
free tonight after work.
- Really?
- Yeah.
That's fantastic.
There's a new Italian restaurant
I've been meaning to try.
- You and I can...
- Joe's is probably fine.
- For dinner?
- No!
I mean... Well, you know...
- For a drink, and then...
- I was asking you to dinner.
So that we could talk.
Get to know each
other. That sort of thing.
Oh, that's... that's
not... I thought that...
You know,
I'm not available for dinner.
I'm... I'm sorry.
Sloan? Sloan,
what are you doing?
- Apparently, nothing.
- Teddy...
Teddy's not one of
these women that you...
You can't just treat her like...
This may come as a shock to you,
but it looks like I'm the respectful
adult in this particular situation.
So how about you talk to her
about how she treats people?
How genius is this?
Mark Sloan and Teddy.
Are you serious?
I just said that.
Shut up! Are we so well matched
we have all the same thoughts?
Kinda creepy,
but it's kinda great.
I'm just saying.
Teddy needs someone to come
in and clear out the cobwebs,
and put a little
spring in her step.
- Yeah, and father her children.
- Yeah.
What? No, Mark?
Yeah, he wants a wife and kids.
- I told her he was a candy bar.
- What?
I didn't know!
First she said no,
then she said yes.
- That's good.
- And then she said no again.
Because she doesn't want to have
a meal with me. She just wanted sex.
Who treats people like that?
Like an object. A piece of ass.
- I think you do.
- I've changed.
Dr. Sloan, Altman says if
you're scrubbing in, it's at two.
Thanks, Karev.
You're a good man.
- Hey.
- Not here.
Sloan's going all psycho
killer on me. Smiles, crazy eyes.
I don't know what
the hell he's gonna do.
What, I'm still his
property? I'll talk to him.
Don't. I gotta
operate with the guy.
You mess with him, he
might stab me with a scalpel.
- Mark's trying to kill Alex.
- What?
I mentioned sleeping
with Alex was a bad idea.
No, it's not a bad idea.
It's happy and easy.
You know how much
mental energy Mark took up?
I'm telling you, ending it is the best
thing that could have happened to me.
And for him! You know how much
happier he'd be if he could just move on?
Looked to me like he was
trying to pick up Teddy.
Sure, he'll sleep with
her. He slept with Addison.
He'll screw anything that moves, but
I'm supposed to check into a convent?
Why is he hanging on like this?
You're just that
good, Little Grey.
There's no getting over you.
Oh!
You clear the room every
time. You clear the room.
Grey, Audrey Taylor's
getting a new set of scans.
Have a look and see if there's anything
we need to include for the presentation.
- How's the plan coming?
- Good. I think if
I clamp the aorta
and vena cava above and
below the liver and porta hepatis,
I should be able to
carve out the tumor.
Interesting.
What's the word
from the other side?
From Dr. Webber?
Uh... Not much. He...
- He's still kind of flailing.
- Flailing? Really?
Yeah. It's sad.
You know, old guy.
End of the road.
Mmm-hmm. Webber doesn't flail.
I'm gonna go and see if I can
help him come up with something.
- He flipped her.
- We have to get those scans
- before she does.
- Yeah. Let's go.
Dr. Bailey, I'm
about to consult.
Would you like to join me?
- Lunchtime.
- Yes.
But in all the years I've known
you, I've never seen you eat.
- I do things at lunchtime.
- What things?
Errands! To the
dentist, get a haircut.
No, not a haircut. I'm going out!
Does that require interrogations?
Is that the kind of chief you want to
be, the kind of man you want to be?
- No.
- I didn't think so!
Take a deep breath.
Hey, doc, my parents
got married really young.
They hated each other
by the time I was born.
Sorry to hear that.
Molly thinks
shacking up's all cute,
but I don't think you play around with
something like that. People get hurt.
- You don't need to explain.
- You think I'm a turd.
And you're getting ready
to slice me open with a knife.
I'm sure you're not a turd.
I think we found our problem.
Noah had a cyst on
his liver and it ruptured.
- That's what's causing pain.
- Why would he have cysts?
They can be
congenital or infectious.
They're usually benign,
but they can rupture
with pressure.
Pressure?
What kind of pressure?
You mean like a fall?
- Did Noah take a fall today?
- No.
The truth is it doesn't matter
what caused the rupture.
- What matters is we operate right away.
- - Oh, my God.
Oh, my God! We
were doing bear hugs.
We were... I... I hugged him.
I hugged him hard.
That's when...
That's what did this?
- Noah? What's happening?
- Grey, get an OR.
We're going now.
I've done this 300 times,
and it's still not working.
I went to Eugenia.
Hmm?
She held up two postage
stamps and asked me
if I was looking for
the 44 cent or the three.
You don't have to tell
me which you picked.
I left! Let me tell you something
about my surgical field.
I prep my surgical field
with soap and water.
I keep my surgical field
the way God made it.
I don't need a member of the
Ukrainian KGB waxing it smooth
so it can be mistaken for the
surgical field of a five-year-old girl.
I am a woman. And a woman
was meant to have something
on her surgical field.
If a man can't deal with a little
something on the surgical field,
a little nature, a little God,
then that man has no business
getting near my surgical field.
Fine! I'm not putting a gun to
your head. Let freedom ring.
Damn it! This is not
supposed to be liquid.
What if I'm not
cut out for this?
What if I'm no
longer patient enough
or stupid enough to
deal with this crap?
Come here. Come here. Come here.
You can do this. You
can do this. You can.
This cyst was massive.
We have to do a cholie 'cause
of the intrabiliary pressure.
Should I update his parents? It's
gonna take a lot longer than we said.
Yeah, sure. Good idea.
- What do I tell them?
- Doesn't matter.
- I'm sorry?
- Until you can say he's awake
and he's fine, they
won't hear a word.
They'll just hear white noise
and see your mouth moving.
But go. It's good
for them to see you.
Try to keep your face happy.
Jackson Avery.
- Put him on our team.
- You stacking the deck again?
You're a spy. Don't
think I don't know.
Who started that boulder
rolling down the hill?
OK, I'm Switzerland in this
moment. All I'm saying is
that whoever gets the
surgery should use him.
- Use me for what?
- He's a liability.
Avery is not gonna give the
award to his own grandson.
He won't be named a
contributor. It'll just get mentioned
- that he worked...
- No, I won't.
On a tumor the size of a possum!
- What's going on?
- They're fighting over me.
Or more, the idea
of me. I don't...
- He's Harper Avery bait.
- Derek's waiting for us.
OK. Heart is back where
it came from. Dr. Sloan?
Two C's.
You're just gonna eyeball it?
- This is what I do.
- If you say so.
Syringe.
Whoa! What? Are you
afraid I'm gonna stab you?
There's no needle.
He's hypotensive.
Your implant's on the vena cava.
- There's too much fluid.
- No, there's not.
I just need to reposition it.
Relax.
Thank you.
An abdominal entry
is a shot in the dark.
The tumor has shoved everything
out of place, the anatomy's a mess.
I'm proposing a
thoraco-abdominal approach.
- You want to go in
through the chest?
- It's risky, yes,
but not as risky as "I'll open up the
abdomen and take a good look around."
- Snap.
- You may end up seeding
- the tumor in the lungs.
- That is a danger, yes.
Impressive proposal.
It's very... Hmm. I think I feel more
comfortable with Dr. Hunt's plan.
He doesn't have a
plan. He has an attitude.
It's more improvisational,
but given our situation,
I think it's our best bet.
Thanks, all of you.
Richard...
I'm sorry. It was a good plan.
Hunt's just makes
more sense to me.
Yes, because that's the way
you'd do it. That's your style.
Let me tell you
about your new job.
You manage surgeons.
Your job is to help
them do what they do,
the way they do it.
Not to get them to
do what you would do.
It takes vision, Derek.
And you don't have it.
- BP's still low.
- Dr. Sloan.
When people rush
you, does it usually help?
It would be nice if
we don't let him die.
I feel the same way.
And you thought we
had nothing in common.
- Pressure's coming back up.
- Imagine.
Dr. Sloan...
- nice work.
- What, that?
It's just a hobby.
Professionally,
I'm more focused on
my work as a male escort.
We will isolate the tumor
from the blood
vessels that supply it.
And then try to extract it.
That's the plan? You'll
try? Is that a plan?
I wish that I could
be more specific,
but until we know what
we're dealing with...
No, no, no! That's not a plan!
- That's a death sentence.
- Audrey.
Mrs. Taylor, if this works,
it is not just a month.
- It is a long time.
- It's a gamble!
It's a huge one! You are gambling
away my daughter's wedding!
I'll call Kim right now. She'll
get a justice of the peace
and she and Scott can get
married right here in this room
- and we can stop bothering...
- Don!
You don't even like weddings!
The salmon will be too dry.
The flowers will
make you sneeze.
Kim will be angry at you
because women get angry
at their mothers
at their weddings.
- That's how they handle stress.
- Stop it!
Do you think she cares
about her wedding?
- Her mother is dying!
- Don...
They're trying
to offer you a life.
A whole long life.
No, they can't guarantee it.
They're not gonna know what
they're gonna find. And it's a gamble.
But how can you not take that
chance because of a wedding?
There will be grandkids
and... and arguments
and God knows what else.
She'll need you for those.
And I'll need you.
Your husband's right.
And so is Dr. Hunt.
He can't foresee what
he'll find in surgery.
But he'll solve
that as it comes.
That's the plan.
And it's a good one.
He did great.
He's just coming out
from under anesthesia,
and he's gonna be in
pain from the surgery,
- but he's gonna be fine.
- Is this gonna happen again?
It's possible that he'll
develop cysts in the future.
- You have to keep an eye out.
- This was... I hugged him.
Do I not hug him?
Do we not wrestle?
You don't throw
him on the ground.
He's a boy. He likes to
wrestle. It's not like I initiate it.
Of course you hug
him. And you wrestle.
You live your lives. And if he
happens to be in any great pain,
- you know...
- So there isn't any kind
of preventative thing...?
- Please let her finish!
- It's OK.
I was done.
Are you ready to see him?
Somebody paged me here.
Condoms.
I'm building
cartilage from Jell-O,
- and you paged me for...
- Condoms.
- They have them in the clinic!
- No, no.
Am I supposed to bring them?
Oh!
Right. Yeah. Yeah... The
guy brings the condoms.
Anyhow, I pegged you
for the diaphragm type.
I have a diaphragm.
Diaphragms prevent pregnancy.
They don't protect against the
raft of sexually transmitted diseases.
You are a physician. Am
I explaining this to you?
I got it, I got it. OK, look.
Guy brings the condoms,
but sometimes they fail to provide them
on the third date as a sign of respect.
"I never imagined this would
happen so soon. I wasn't prepared."
So you should bring them. Always
bring them. Why trust the guy?
Right, right. All
right. All right.
- Torres.
- Hmm?
Come on.
- I can't.
- You can!
Walk into the clinic and take
some condoms out of the box.
Don't make me ask you twice.
I'm having trouble
telling liver from tumor.
Yep, you and me both.
Clamp.
Sorry you didn't end
up on the winning team.
Sucks. You made a
ballsy play, though.
- Thoraco-abdominal entry?
- I do what I can
to keep it fresh.
- Bring in the CUSA.
- - Hang another unit of FFP.
More lapse. More, more!
- You need some help?
- Where's Webber?
- You want me to scrub in?
- I need Webber. Where's Webber?
I helped Altman
save her patient.
I don't know why I bother.
She thinks I'm a piece of meat.
Plenty of women
dying to settle down.
You gotta move
on to the next one.
Try what's-her-name in Derm.
Dinner and
conversation. Can't wait.
- Who said dinner? Lunch.
- No. Lunch is not romantic.
You don't want romantic,
you want daylight and public,
so you can get to
know each other.
That is the least sexy thing
- I've heard in my life.
- You've had sex.
- You want a baby.
- No way this works.
Is it really possible
that you're this insecure?
You're not just a sex machine.
Don't get me wrong, you've got
skills, but you're a good person.
Why do you think Little
Miss Muffet fell for you?
- Lexie left.
- 'Cause she was too young!
It was about her, not you.
Wow. You really don't
believe any of this, do you?
Listen, you're a good guy.
You're worth getting to know.
In daylight.
It's not gonna work, Dr. Hunt.
The chest isn't an
option anymore,
- this is what we've got.
- I'm not pitching my solution.
I'm saying we
should think a minute.
I've isolated the blood
supply and mobilized the liver,
but I can't get enough
exposure to get to the tumor.
What if we lift the liver
up, give you more visibility?
That'd help with the periphery, but
I'd still have to deal with the vessels.
I wish we could just
take the damn thing out.
Well, why not? Let's
take the liver out.
I can clean off
the tumor ex vivo,
you can work on the
vascular supply in the cavity.
- Will it work?
- No one's ever tried that.
She's crashing.
If you're trying
something, now's the time.
Hunt?
- OK, extracting the liver.
- More lapse.
Suction, a lot
of suction. Hurry.
Surgery went great. Everything
is back where it should be
- and Todd's gonna be fine.
- Oh, my God. Thank you.
- Do you think I should see him?
- He's still groggy...
I mean, do you think he wants
to see me after I stormed out?
How did he seem?
Did he seem upset or...?
I just... I love him.
I was a little crazy. He practically
had a heart attack or whatever.
I acted a little crazy.
When you feel like you love
someone more than he loves you,
it can make you a little crazy.
It can make you a lot crazy.
You know, Webber really
came up with the idea
to take out the liver.
Maybe if Owen agreed
to take his name off it...
Will you give it up?
Hunt was more than halfway done
by the time the
idea even surfaced.
- There's no Harper Avery.
- Waste.
No, it's not a waste.
It's what my grandfather had in mind
when he came up with the stupid thing.
Find some way to keep
surgeons motivated.
Make them take
it to the next level,
even if they're already
at the top of their game.
That's exactly
what it did today.
This message was brought to you by
the Harper Avery Foundation of America.
Donations to the Foundation
can be made at www...
You're kind of a
bitch, you know that?
What? It was inspiring.
Mrs. Taylor's gonna
need a post-op note.
I'll do it.
Good work today,
Grey. We're a good team.
You know, we're not a team.
Cristina and I are a team.
I watched you today
watch Teddy and Mark.
She's my friend. And Mark
Sloan is a public health hazard.
You were jealous.
It took a long time to make her
happy, and she's finally happy.
And if you mess with
that, I will turn on you.
That's a team.
Maybe you should leave
this to the bioengineers.
I tried it. They
said it won't work.
Maybe that's
'cause it won't work.
They're just not
invested in it like I am.
Holy... It... It's not liquid.
- Arizona, it's not liquid!
- Oh, my God!
Oh, my God! Do you
know what you did?
I don't know. I don't know.
I gotta... I gotta do it again.
I'm on fire! And
it's not just this.
Everyone came to me for
relationship advice today.
And I gave them sane
and healthy advice.
Whether they take it or
not, I am seen as someone
sane and healthy
enough to give advice.
When I lived in the basement,
when I married
an intern in Vegas,
I wasn't seen that way.
You're amazing.
We're amazing.
We're the stable couple now.
We're the one
everyone wants to be.
I can just see us ten years
from now in a big old house
with kids running around,
giving sage, sane advice.
To Mark Sloan, who
will still be single.
I'm in it for all but the kids.
What?
No kids. And by
no, I mean yikes!
No to the kids.
You're joking, right?
You're in pediatrics.
Yeah. Exactly.
This kid Noah comes in
today, he's fine one minute,
then his mom gives him a hug
and he lands in my OR, nearly dead.
- But you saved him.
- Yeah. But his parents?
They're... They're a mess.
They'll never sleep well again.
Mm-mm...
But the big house, I'm in.
And can we have
dogs? And chickens!
I have this weird
thing for chickens.
I'd love to have
dinner sometime.
If you're still up for it.
I'm not taking you to dinner.
Oh.
I will take you to lunch.
Saturday afternoon,
in broad daylight.
We'll eat at a public place,
and maybe take a walk
on a crowded street.
We'll get to know each other,
and see if we have an interest
in the same kind of future.
Because I want to build a life,
and a family, and I'm
not wasting my time
on someone who
doesn't share that interest.
I'll pick you up at noon.
OK, then.
I used to grill.
You're out in the air,
you got a slab of beef,
it's a masculine activity.
But you ever try
to grill in Seattle?
I haven't.
You're standing
around in the rain.
In a raincoat with the hood up.
Let me tell you, there's nothing manly
about a hood and a soggy slab of beef.
OK, here's the thing.
I don't do things
because there's a timeline.
I don't do things because
it's the third anything.
I may have been out of
the dating game for a while,
but I don't play by anyone's
rules other than my own.
So whatever expectations
you walked into
this evening with...
- Are you lecturing me?
- No, I'm...
No, you are. You lecture people.
I think most people
are scared of you.
So nobody's willing to interrupt
you once you get on a roll.
But I'm not scared of you. So
the lecture thing's not gonna work.
We gonna have to
have a conversation.
Don't worry. Ask me a question.
Then I'll answer, then
you get another turn.
Go ahead.
Are you under the impression
that we're going to have sex tonight?
- Because if that's the case...
- Ask the question.
Don't answer the question.
I'll answer the question.
No, I'm not assuming
we'll have sex tonight.
You're a grown woman. Neither of
us is looking for something trashy.
So I kinda thought third
date was a little early.
- What do you think?
- Me, too. I...
Can I make a statement
or just questions?
A statement is fine.
I...
Uh...
have never had sex with
anyone other than my husband.
Former husband.
So it's not something
you get into lightly.
No.
Neither do I.
What else?
When do you think
is the right time?
I like to think we'll
know it when we see it.
Probably somewhere
between date eight and date 12.
Oh... No concern we'll
end up just friends?
Is that what you're looking for?
- No.
- Me neither.
Look, um...
I don't want to be your friend.
I have enough friends.
They take pictures
of mountain climbers
at the top of the mountain.
They're smiling,
ecstatic, triumphant.
Richard, I understand
your patient's doing well.
Hunt's patient.
He says he couldn't
have done it without you.
- I'm sorry I didn't...
- Don't.
You were doing your job.
- It isn't easy.
- True.
I'm not necessarily
all that good at it yet.
- No, you're not.
- Really?
You couldn't give me
one kind word? Not one?
They don't take
pictures along the way.
'Cause who wants to
remember the rest of it?
We push ourselves
because we have to.
Not because we like it.
Hey. How was Mark?
Did he do anything?
He was totally cool.
I think he's into
Altman, though.
Teddy? Come on. He's trying
to make me think he's moving on.
No, it looked real. He
wants to take her to lunch.
He's all like, "Let's take it slow
and get to know each other."
I think she went for it.
Hey.
- You OK?
- Yeah.
Mark's moving on.
Like, really.
OK. Well, that's good, isn't it?
Isn't that what you wanted?
No, it's... It's great.
It's... That's...
That's perfect.
It's...
It's perfect.
The relentless climb...
Oh...
the pain and anguish of
taking it to the next level...
nobody takes pictures of that.
Nobody wants to remember.
We just wanna remember
the view from the top.
The breathtaking moment
at the edge of the world.
That's what keeps us climbing.
And it's worth the pain.
That's the crazy part.
It's worth anything.