Morning.
I don't know...
Hey!
Hi, Dad.
Oh, sorry, Mom.
I've got to go.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
what'd I do?
Nothing.
You are perfect.
Bye, honey.
Bye. See you
this evening.
How are you feeling?
Fantastic.
They're giving me
the steroids in the infusion.
So I feel like
I could run a marathon.
Look what I found.
Remember that trip
we took to
Mackinac Island
when Robin
was three?
No cars,
nothing but horses.
I remember that
Rainbow Brite t-shirt.
Mmm-hmm.
Nothing but saltwater
taffy and ice cream.
What a trip. That was
a great trip.
No, it wasn't, Danny.
You were horribly depressed.
You stayed in the hotel room,
laid in the bed,
and stared at the ceiling.
I kept telling Robin that
you wouldn't come down
"because Daddy
didn't feel good."
Hmm.
I mean, I remember maybe
a couple of dark days.
But, on the whole,
didn't we have...
Danny, what
are you doing?
I just thought you'd like
to see these pictures.
That's all, you know?
I know you were trying
to rewrite history
to paint a pretty picture,
aw, of a happy marriage
and it wasn't
always like that.
It's pure fantasy,
Danny.
I know Med is not
a for-profit organization...
But
this report?
If my board saw
numbers like this,
they'd be calling for
a vote of no confidence.
Mr. Rhodes, you can see
that one reason
for our fiscal issues is
the ED's Hybrid Room
which you
only partially funded.
I think the rest of the board
would agree with me
that my contributions
have been more than generous.
No, in fact, what I'm seeing
is a lot of your pet projects
not working out so well.
Let's look
at the refurbishment
of the VIP wing.
A lot of empty beds there.
After Dr. Downey's death,
we became less of a...
a destination hospital
for our CT patients.
We're still in the process
of re-branding.
But in the meantime,
since you were
such a vocal advocate
of the Hybrid OR,
Sharon,
it seems only fair that
you should find cuts
in other departments
to make up for
some of our losses.
Well, I will certainly
take a look.
But I'd hate to put us
in legal jeopardy
or lose our reputation
as the premier
medical center
of the Midwest.
Well said, Sharon.
Very, very well said.
We certainly
would not want that.
Mom, seriously, I'm fine.
That's not what
you said this morning.
You could hardly
get out of bed.
Jenny Simpson, 17,
abdominal pain.
Hi. I'm Dr. Manning.
This is Dr. Choi.
Hi.
Mom and Dad?
Evie. That's
my husband, Joel.
Hi.
This is
so unnecessary.
It was probably that
sketchy salad
I had last night.
Remember I said
it smelled weird?
Jenny's been in pain
since we left Fort Wayne
three days ago.
Hoosiers, huh?
Winter getaway?
College tour.
Jenny got into
Northwestern.
Perfect SATs.
Wow!
Congratulations.
Jenny, are you
feeling any nausea?
I mean, a little,
but I'm better now.
I don't know why
you guys are freaking...
Oh, honey.
We thought
maybe appendicitis.
No rebound tenderness.
BP 100/62.
Heart rate 103.
I told you, it's just
food poisoning.
All right, well,
I'd still like to do
a quick ultrasound
just to see if I can get
a visual on
the appendix, okay?
An ultrasound?
Mmm-hmm.
It'll just
take a second.
No, I don't want that.
Honey.
I want to go.
Jenny, appendicitis
is serious,
but it's easily treatable
if we catch it early.
But I have to take
a look to do that, okay?
Jenny.
Okay. I guess.
Great.
Well, good news is
it doesn't look
like appendicitis.
So what is it?
Well, it's hard
to tell just yet.
But I would like
to run some tests
just to rule a few things
out if that's all right.
Oh, of course.
Absolutely.
Monique, CBC, BMP,
coags, and a quant hCG.
Mmm-hmm.
We'll be back
to check in
once we get
the test results in.
Thank you.
Did you see
how scared she got
when I mentioned
the ultrasound?
Yeah, she was
pretty defensive.
You thinking
what I'm thinking?
Pregnancy?
Thinking an endometrium,
but I didn't see an embryo.
Well, she could've had
a miscarriage or an abortion.
But whatever it is,
she is definitely trying to
keep her parents in the dark.
Yeah, but I don't think
that's going to be possible.
Heads up, Maggie.
There's probably
going to be
more spending cuts
coming down.
More?
Gwen hasn't met her goals
and she's feeling the heat.
We're already
short-staffed.
We're using those
cheapo central line kits.
What more
does Gwen want?
Speak of the devil.
Oh...
She's got a big fish
coming into the VIP wing.
Ooh.
Wow!
Man, I love it.
Thanks.
It's a lot easier
to manage.
Hey.
New hairdo?
It looks good.
Uh, so we still on?
Drinks for tonight?
Um...
I'm sorry.
I can't. Something came up.
"Something"?
Yeah.
Uh, tomorrow, then?
That's not going to work,
either.
This weekend?
Can I let you know?
Yeah. No big deal.
New hairdo? Hmm, hmm, hmm.
Women don't do that
for no reason.
I'm guessing
there's a guy.
You're suddenly
an expert on women.
Too bad, Choi.
I'll be using what's called
the "David procedure"
to resect
your aneurysm.
It will allow us
to preserve
your native valve.
Our Chief of CT,
Dr. Latham,
is going to be assisting
me on the operation.
Do you have any
questions, concerns?
No concerns. My people
did their research.
You were
at the top of the list,
just under
the late Dr. Downey.
Dr. Rhodes was
Dr. Downey's
star protégé.
I'm aware.
I wanted to
let you know,
Mr. Montero,
that as you recuperate,
we can offer you
spa-like amenities.
Massage, facials.
With your doctor's
permission, of course.
We also have a concierge
at your disposal.
Here is a list
of all our
personal services
and our menu options.
You can almost forget
you're in the hospital.
Why is Dr. Rhodes scheduled
to operate on Mr. Montero?
It's out of my hands.
Dr. Rhodes is
on the trauma service.
I'm the attending in CT.
Mr. Montero's case
should've come to me.
Dr. Bekker,
Mr. Montero specifically
requested Dr. Rhodes
and Mr. Montero
gets what he wants.
Jenny Simpson's
test results.
What's going on
with you and Phillip?
Are you seeing him?
You know, like,
"seeing him" seeing him?
Mmm-hmm.
I thought it was
headed that way.
He is a lovely guy,
Maggie.
But so is Big Red.
It is way more complicated
than that and you know it.
Ethan.
Jenny, where are
your parents?
They went to get coffee.
We have to
ask you something.
Jenny, we got your
blood work back
and it indicates
a pregnancy.
No, I'm not pregnant.
Let us explain.
I'm not pregnant.
We understand
how hard this is.
But your test results
and your symptoms
shows that maybe you had
a miscarriage or...
No. No, I didn't.
I don't want to talk about it.
Jenny, in order for us
to treat you properly,
we really need to know
what happened.
Please,
we are not here
to judge you.
No.
We want to help you.
The whole thing was stupid.
So stupid.
When I found out
that I was pregnant,
I didn't know what to do.
I'm finishing high school
and I'm going to college.
I understand.
So I went online
and I read about these pills.
And what were they?
Mife... something.
Mifepristone?
Did you take
the follow-up pill,
misoprostol?
I couldn't get it.
Not without a doctor.
Jenny, that's why
you're in so much pain.
Without the second pill,
you haven't fully aborted yet.
Help me.
Please.
Just don't tell
my parents.
They'll hate me
and they'll never forgive me.
Please.
I think you might be
underestimating them.
No, I know them and
you can't tell them.
Jenny, I'm sorry...
We're not
going to tell your parents,
but I am going to
give you the second pill
so that you can expel whatever
is left in your uterus, okay?
Thank you.
Yeah.
Nat, she's a minor.
We can't give her medications
without her parents' consent.
Yes, we can.
Dr. Manning?
Have you found out
what's wrong with
our daughter?
We were actually
just discussing that.
Unfortunately, we're still
waiting on some test results.
The best thing
you can do right now
is just be patient.
Wait, that's it?
You have no idea?
I know how frustrating
this must be,
but I promise you,
we are doing
everything possible
for Jenny.
I'm sure that you are.
Come on, hon.
What do you think
you're doing?
I'm honoring
the patient's wishes.
And lying
to her parents?
I did not lie to them.
You withheld
the truth, Nat.
They have a right
to know. A legal right.
That's Jenny's call.
If you have a problem with it,
take it up with Goodwin.
Dr. Lanik, FBI medics
have landed.
April, you're up.
FBI?
Special Agent
Sam Pearson.
Low-speed
motor vehicle collision.
GCS 10, LOC on site,
nasal airway in place.
Hey, I know this guy.
Let me work him up.
Self-starter.
Who am I to interfere?
Okay, on my count.
One, two, three.
Hang in there, Sam.
I got you.
What's the story?
Air bags deployed,
but his chest got
most of the impact.
He's not protecting
his airway, gotta intubate.
20 of etomidate, 100 of sux.
Get an X-ray in here.
Meds are in.
Heart rate 124,
BP 132/88, sats 95.
I'm in. Bag him.
Good breath sounds
bilaterally.
Let's get that
chest X-ray.
Yes, Doctor.
Clear.
Chest shows multiple
rib fractures
and bilateral
pulmonary contusions.
I need a CBC, CMP,
blood gas, and coags.
I'm seeing PVCs
on the monitors.
Got it.
Is he going to be okay?
Ingrid.
He's in rough shape,
but stable for now.
Were you with him?
Yeah.
Let me check you out.
No, I'm fine. I'm fine.
Just...
Just keep my partner alive.
Dr. Manning boxed us
into this situation.
You want to talk
about boxed in?
The only reason
we're in this situation
is because Jenny
had no options.
The family lives
in Indiana.
Where she would need
parental consent.
And she was afraid
to talk to them,
so there was
nowhere else to go,
so she went online
to find medication.
This generation's
back-alley abortion.
We don't make the laws,
but we have to obey them.
Jenny's a minor
and that means
we have to tell her parents
before we treat.
No, her pregnancy test
is still positive.
Therefore, under the law,
she is emancipated.
She was pregnant.
Not anymore.
Technically,
she still is.
Ms. Goodwin.
I'll admit
it's a thin argument.
Emancipation covers
a woman's decisions
regarding her pregnancy,
but my understanding
is that Ms. Simpson
has already made her choice.
So we betray
this girl's trust?
Well, that's not
what I'm suggesting.
We have to obey the law
and tell her parents.
That's not
exactly right, either.
If we had provided
a medical abortion,
which we didn't,
then, yes.
The State of Illinois says
we're obligated
to inform the parents.
But since she obtained
the medication herself
out-of state,
I'm not so sure.
So you intend to keep
the parents in the dark
based on a technicality?
No, because
our patient asked us
to keep it confidential.
Look, I would suggest you
continue to treat her
according to her wishes
until our lawyers
make a determination.
Thank you, Ms. Goodwin.
Why are you here?
I'm scrubbing in
on your surgery.
No, Dr. Latham
is assisting.
He reconsidered.
So just like that,
he pulled out?
What did you say to him?
Really, Connor?
Why wasn't I
consulted?
Don't worry.
It's been made
very clear to me
that Mr. Montero
is your patient.
I'm only here
as your humble assistant.
By the way, I had
my last HIV test.
I'm clear.
I'm glad to hear it.
Since you were the one
who so carelessly cut me,
I thought you might be.
How is she?
Cuts and scrapes.
Nothing serious.
Ingrid.
How's Sam?
Wait and see
right now.
Can I get you
anything?
No.
Haven't seen you
at the dog park lately.
It's... work.
I'll keep you
posted on Sam.
Where are we?
The PVCs were all unifocal,
but his airway pressures
are bad.
PaO2's at 50 and
peak pressure's at 55.
All this from a car crash?
They said he wasn't even
going that fast.
He shouldn't be this sick.
Crank the O2 and increase
his PEEP to 12.
See if we can improve
his oxygenation.
Okay.
These bruises...
They don't look like
they're from an air bag.
They're too extensive.
The air bag shouldn't
have touched his legs.
We still waiting
on those CT scans?
Radiology's been
slammed all morning.
Get him moved up.
Don't take no
for an answer.
These injuries
just don't add up.
You got it.
Proximal anastomosis done.
I'm working on the distal now.
Temp's coming up.
33 degrees.
We need to move faster.
Look, I realize that,
but the graft
is coming down unevenly.
If I keep tugging,
I could tear the aorta.
A suggestion?
What?
Try pulling on
the non-coronary commissure.
I think that'll move the graft
into the proper position.
Okay.
That did it,
thank you.
Of course.
All right, let's finish
the anastomosis.
No, I haven't told him,
but I don't feel good
about it.
Don't you think he has
a right to know?
I've gotta go.
I'll talk to you later.
You need something?
No.
Okay.
Help! Dr. Manning! Dr. Choi!
Oh, my God.
Help her!
I feel dizzy.
Jenny, keep looking at me.
Keep talking, okay?
Mom...
You'll be okay, honey.
Mommy is right here.
I don't feel good.
Oh, God.
What is happening
to my daughter?
There's so much blood.
It's a gynecologic
hemorrhage.
She's passing
retained tissue...
We need to
control the bleed.
Monique, hang a unit of typed
and crossed-matched blood,
give her 0.2 milligrams
of Methergine IM...
Mmm-hmm.
...and I need a stat
CBC and coags.
Wait, we need
your parental consent.
Ethan.
To start the transfusion
and administer the medication.
Whatever you need to do.
Go ahead.
I may have
distorted the graft
with that last stitch.
I'm doing this backhand.
Do you have a better angle?
I think so.
Dr. Rhodes's phone.
Take a message.
All right, last couple
of stitches then
we're coming off pump.
Dr. Rhodes?
I said take a message.
Dr. Rhodes, he says
it's an emergency.
All right.
Look, I'm in the middle
of an operation.
What?
Is this some kind of joke?
How do I know that?
All right.
All right. All right.
What do you
want me to do?
What is it?
Okay. Yeah, okay.
Yeah. Look...
No, I won't hang up.
I promise.
I have to leave.
What?
Finish the anastomosis.
Check the competency
of the valve.
Connor, no!
You've done this before.
You'll be fine.
That's not...
No!
I'm not hanging up.
I promise.
All right, we have
a patient on the table.
Let's get back to work.
I just left
the operating room.
I'm headed out now.
You finished already,
Dr. Rhodes?
No, I'm still here, okay?
I won't hang up.
Dr. Rhodes?
No, I'm still here.
I'm still here.
The elevator is really slow.
Look, I'm moving as fast
as I can, man, I promise.
Can I talk to her?
Okay, okay, okay.
I'll do whatever you say.
All right,
I'm leaving now.
Just, please,
don't hurt her.
Robin, it's Dad.
Can you... can you call me
as soon as you get this?
My bank is on the corner
of LaSalle and Van Buren.
I'll be there
in 20 minutes.
Trudy, it's Dan Charles.
I need to speak
to Hank Voight immediately.
What the hell is going on
with Dr. Rhodes?
What do you mean?
Halfway through
Mr. Montero's surgery,
he left the OR
and the hospital.
What?
You know how important
this patient is to us,
and if his outcome
is less than perfect,
I will fire Dr. Rhodes
and that'll be the least
of his problems.
I'll sue him and then
I'll bring him up
on charges.
I know there is a reasonable
explanation for this.
If this blows up, Sharon,
he won't be
the only one
without a job.
I'm heading east on Lake.
You're late. You said
you'd be there in 20 minutes.
I can't help the traffic.
Are you playing
games with me?
I am doing
the best I can.
Whatever happens to Robin,
that's on you, man.
Just don't touch her!
Move! Move!
Since your patient,
Jenny Simpson, is a minor,
legal is concerned
about liability.
Of course they are.
Bottom line,
if you feel the need
for any further
medical procedures,
you must obtain
parental consent.
Good, thank you.
This isn't right.
I'm sorry, Dr. Manning,
but you've given her
Methergine.
Yes?
Yes.
So let's hope she passes
any retained tissue
and that should
take care of it.
Hi.
Could we have a moment
to examine Jenny?
Oh, of course.
When are we
going to know something?
Honey, let them
do their job.
Come on.
Thank you.
How are you feeling, Jenny?
Not good.
Well, I'm going to do
an internal exam, okay?
So I just need you
to lift up your legs
just like that
and then just
let them fall open.
Perfect.
I apologize,
this is going to be
a little
uncomfortable, okay?
Thank you.
All right, you ready?
You okay?
What is it?
Well, your body
hasn't expelled
all the tissue
related to the pregnancy.
The medication
we gave you was
supposed to help,
but, unfortunately,
you're still bleeding.
It means you're
going to need a D&C,
dilation and curettage,
a surgical procedure
to remove the tissue.
But we do need
your parents'
permission for this.
No. You can't tell them.
We have to.
Jenny, your temperature
is elevated,
which means you could be
developing endometritis,
which is
a very serious infection.
It could be
life-threatening.
No! No! No!
Jenny, I know you're afraid
of what your parents will say,
but they love you
and they would
never want to lose you.
So I'm going to go
talk to them, okay?
Wait.
My mom...
Ask my mom to come in.
Okay.
Mrs. Simpson,
Jenny would like
to talk to you.
Oh...
Um...
Why don't you go get
a cup of coffee?
I think this is
mother-daughter talk.
No, it'll be okay.
Agent Pearson's CT results.
Is something wrong?
Sam's CAT scan.
Bilateral diffuse
pulmonary whiteout,
bilateral subclinical
pneumothoraces,
sternal fracture,
subcapsular
liver hematoma...
What does all that mean?
Looks like blast lung.
These injuries
were not caused
by a car crash.
Ingrid, what really happened?
Tell me.
Will it affect
how you treat him?
Of course it will!
What happened?
Okay.
We... there was an explosion
and Sam took the brunt of it.
What kind of explosion?
A meth lab.
What are we
talking about, then?
Acetone peroxide?
Red phosphorus?
Yes.
What else can you tell us?
Ingrid!
For God's sakes, Will,
isn't that enough?
Convert him
to lung protective
ventilation.
Drop the tidal volume
to four cc's per kilo
and up his rate to 28.
On it.
You... I knew it.
I knew it
all along.
You had no right
to keep this from us.
It was Jenny's wish.
Well, of course
she didn't want us
to find out.
She knew it was wrong.
What she did was murder.
Mrs. Simpson,
you should know that Jenny
didn't want to tell you
because she was afraid
you wouldn't love her
anymore.
No.
No, no, no.
Listen, no matter
what your beliefs are,
that's your daughter,
and she's very sick.
Look, can I give
the consent for the D&C
without my husband?
Yes.
Do whatever you have to do
to save my daughter.
Just don't tell Joel
what happened.
I don't want this
to destroy my family.
But doesn't he have
the right to know?
He's her father.
Actually...
Actually, he isn't.
And, no,
I never told him.
All right, I'm here.
Ginny! Ginny, hi. Hi.
Hello, Dr. Rhodes,
what can I do for you?
I need to take $50,000
out of my money market
account in cash.
Cash?
Yes, and, please,
I am in a bit of a hurry.
It'll take a few minutes.
I'm not sure the tellers
have that much on hand.
I may need to go
into the vault.
Ginny, whatever it takes,
just please do it. Thank you.
All right, did you hear that?
It's going to take a while.
No, no, no.
I... I... I didn't call them,
I swear!
No, no, no,
they can't be outside!
I didn't call them!
Please! Please!
No, no, no! Don't hang up!
I am getting you the money!
Hello? Hello, you there?
You... hello?
No, no, no, no, no!
No!
No, no, no!
I told you
not to call the police!
They saw you!
They're going to
kill her!
They're not.
You don't know that.
Yes, I do.
Dr. Rhodes.
Robin was never kidnapped.
No, she was.
I heard her.
I heard her scream!
It wasn't her, buddy.
No, it's a scam.
Dr. Rhodes, it's a scam.
A scam?
When I finally reached Robin,
she had no idea
what I was talking about.
You spoke to her
and she's fine?
Was never in any danger.
Watch out.
BP 92 over 56.
Heart rate 48.
Sats 73 and dropping.
He's bradying down.
Bilateral tension
pneumothoraces.
Two needle kits?
Yeah, gotta decompress
his chest.
What's happening?
Air's leaking
into his chest
from his lungs.
Now, his lungs
can't inflate.
Second needle?
Sats and heart rate climbing.
Set up for bilateral
chest tubes.
Otherwise his lungs are just
going to collapse again.
Right.
We'll need to
send him up to the ICU
and get him on ECMO.
Is this because
you didn't know?
It didn't help, Ingrid.
Evie?
What's happening?
Where are they taking her?
They'll explain.
We're starting your daughter
on broad spectrum antibiotics
and we're taking her
up to surgery.
Why?
We were unable
to stop her bleeding,
and also we were concerned
she could become septic.
Oh, God.
The procedure to address this
is simple, very low-risk.
In all likelihood,
she'll be able
to go home
with you tomorrow.
Okay.
I'm still not clear.
This procedure...
It's to remove
degenerating tissue
that's trapped
in her uterus.
Her uterus?
That's right.
Okay, as long as
she's going to be all right.
Yeah.
Do you have
any further questions?
No. No.
Okay.
Then why don't we have
someone take you up
to the waiting area?
Monique, take Mr. Simpson
upstairs to join his wife.
Sure. This way, sir.
Thank you.
Robin.
Hey.
Oh, my God.
Oh, it's okay.
I'm fine.
I was just so worried.
No... Dad, you know
I go swimming
during lunch.
Do I know that?
I don't think I know that.
Yeah, well, maybe
you should listen.
How were they even able
to pull this off?
I mean, they must've
known so much about you.
The cops said they
must've hacked my email.
Apparently, this sort of scam
has been happening a lot.
I'm really sorry.
I've got to get back
to the OR.
Oh, I'm fine,
Connor. Go.
Okay, thank you.
And change
your passwords.
Dr. Rhodes?
Ms. Goodwin, I will explain
everything when I can, but...
right now, I have got to
get back to the OR.
There's no hurry.
Mr. Montero?
Did fine.
They're closing him up now.
That's good.
Since you ran out
in the middle of the surgery,
I'd say it's very good.
And now you have time
to tell me what happened.
Hey.
Sam is stable, on ECMO.
That'll take
the strain off his lungs,
so they can heal.
He's got a long road
ahead of him,
but he should pull through.
Good.
And, look, I'm sorry.
Even if I had known earlier
what caused his injuries,
I don't think
it would have made
a difference.
Thank you.
You can go and see him.
Okay.
You're still
not gonna tell me
what happened?
We're fortunate
Dr. Bekker was able
to take over
for Dr. Rhodes when
he became incapacitated.
She is a brilliant surgeon.
And she's proven herself
a worthy successor
to Dr. Downey.
Thank you.
You're most welcome.
I think we can all agree
that thanks to Dr. Bekker,
we're on our way
to becoming
a destination hospital
once again.
I heard what happened.
That's awful.
But Robin's okay?
It was just a scam?
Yeah.
So cruel.
Well, thank you
for stepping in.
Of course.
I'm going to go
write up my notes.
Looks like it all
worked out well for her.
Yeah.
Dr. Choi, Dr. Manning,
I thought Jenny
might be hungry.
And I wanted to thank you.
The OB said
she's gonna be fine.
Yes, everything
went well.
Yeah. She's a good girl.
Mr. Simpson.
Take care.
I will. Thanks.
That man's being lied
to by us, his wife,
his daughter.
I don't get you, Ethan.
You believe that everyone has
a right to make decisions
about their own body.
It's not that.
It's the dishonesty.
Listen, some people
don't want honesty.
They find
living with a lie
to be a lot easier.
Not me.
April?
April, it's Ethan.
Ethan, what are you doing?
If you're seeing another guy,
just tell me the truth.
You have no right
to come to my apartment
demanding anything.
You keep making excuses.
You cut your hair.
My hair? So what?
Just be honest with me.
I can handle it.
You're going to
wake the baby.
Emily.
Why don't you come in?
Hey.
They're probably not going to
extubate him for a few days.
You should go home,
get some rest.
Okay.
Will, it wasn't
because of security
that I didn't tell you.
I trust you.
Then, why?
I just didn't want
to burden you with it.
Ingrid.
I'm not really good
at letting people in,
but I do know...
sometimes burdens
are easier to bear
if they're shared.
You can tell me.
Tell me.
That raid on the meth lab?
The suspect
was supposed to be alone,
but he had his kids with him.
They're twins, girls,
six years old.
And, um, rather than
surrender, he lit a match.
Uh...
After the explosion
when the smoke
started to clear,
I could see that
Sam was down.
And then I, um...
I just saw bits of them
everywhere.
And then in the middle
of all it...
I saw a little girl's toy,
a pink unicorn.
It was perfect.
There wasn't
a scratch on it.
I got you.
Bernie just needs some time.
So April said
I could stay with her.
But what's he doing
at his wife's?
He left her.
He did.
But he misses her
and he misses his daughter.
So we talked about it
and thought it would be good
if they spent some time
together, and, you know,
just work things out.
Work what things out?
He has a baby.
Your baby.
She knows that.
Obviously, you're
fine with this.
They're doing the best
they can, Ethan.
It doesn't sound
that way to me.
See? This is why
I didn't want him to know.
Okay, come here.
Don't you want
to meet your nephew?
Come here, Em.
Come on.
His name is Vincent.
Vincent.
After Grandpa.
Mmm-hmm.
You know, I did cut
my hair because of a guy.
Vincent likes
to pull on it.
Yes, I got that.
Hey, Ma?
So Dad has had
a bit of a rough day
and wants to know
if we can all go out
to dinner together.
So why isn't he
asking me himself?
Oh, I wouldn't want you
to think that I was being
manipulative.
Oh.
Tell him I like steak.
Not for nothing,
you were absolutely
right this morning
about Mackinac Island.
Okay, now, you're being
really manipulative.