♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
Charlotte?
Charlotte.
Close the door.
I don't want
anyone to see me.
Pete:
Okay. Okay.
It's okay.
Shh, shh, shh. I got you.
Pete:
Shh, shh.
Is that Dr. King?
Is there anything that we can--?
Pete: I got it.
She needs to be admitted--
I've got it.
He took my wallet.
That's what he--
he robbed me.
Can you lie back for me?
I would've just
given it to him, but he--
I don't know,
he just kept hitting me.
I need you to lie back
so I can take a look at you.
I'm fine.
My hand hurts. I got robbed.
He took my wallet. I just--
I need a bandage
and I'll be good as new.
Charlotte, your hand is broken.
So's your wrist.
Maybe your nose.
Possibly your eye socket.
Oh.
Let me examine you.
I can't take medication.
Pills. You know that.
I know.
I need a gown.
Okay.
And a nurse to get me into it.
All right.
Get Sheila.
Not one of those nosy bitches
out there.
Sheila.
She knows how to keep
her mouth shut. She's on four.
Okay. I'll go get Sheila
and I'll be right back.
But, Charlotte, please...
Please, lie back.
There's a nurse named Sheila
on four. Go get her.
One of you call the police.
And all of you get back to work.
Sam:
You don't ask your bride-to-be
about strippers.
They don't like it.
Besides, strippers are--
there are germs.
I'm not gonna do anything
with the stripper.
It's a rite of passage.
Get the stripper.
Every man should have a woman
dance on a table for him
before he takes the plunge.
Hell, you want me to take
my top off and dance now?
Because I will.
Oh, I'm drunk.
I know I'm drunk because
I just considered
doing very bad things to you.
Things that involve spankings.
I like you.
I like everybody.
Okay, back up.
"Okay, back up."
I hate being
the designated driver.
Amelia:
Yeah, well, even with three
drinks in me,
I can still
kick your ass at pool.
Price:
Two unis found him.
He was wandering the streets,
shouting to himself.
In L.A.? Heh. Shocking.
Heh. I know, right?
But here's the deal.
He had blood on his clothes.
And you didn't take him to the
hospital? You and I both know--
not his blood.
He had scratches on him, a
pretty good bruise on his face,
but it wasn't his blood.
We tried to talk to him,
we tried to help him.
He kicked one of the unis.
They had to arrest him.
Because there aren't any actual
criminals in L.A.
I was sleeping, you know.
Shelly, I'm trying to do
a good thing here.
He's a messed up guy.
Now, maybe he witnessed
something,
maybe he did something bad.
But you're on the 5150 team,
so do your job.
Evaluate the guy.
Price:
His name's Lee.
That's all we could get.
Do me a favor.
Turn off the cameras, huh?
He was about 5'8" or bigger.
Blond, maybe. Maybe brown hair.
I don't know.
He had on jeans or khakis.
I don't know for sure
what he was wearing. Ow.
Sorry. Are you positive this
guy's not still in the building?
Security did a sweep
floor to floor.
Does that mean you're sure or
are you just saying you're sure?
Addison, what are you doing
here? You're not on call.
I had a mom who thought
that she was in labor.
It was a false alarm.
And then I heard.
Is there anything else you can
tell us? Did he say anything?
Pete:
She's told you everything.
He didn't say anything.
See? Now find the guy.
Policeman 1:
We have to complete the report.
Pete:
Report.
Policeman 1:
And the forensic nurse
needs samples.
Pete:
Screw that. She's injured.
She needs medical attention.
Policeman 1:
There's a process here.
Pete:
She's been through enough.
Policeman 2:
Now you're getting
in the way of us doing our job.
Pete:
Your job is to find the guy.
There's a violent criminal
out there.
I'm sorry.
Okay, everybody out. Move.
Ma'am--
Addison: I said, out.
Pete:
Come on. Let's go. Out.
You too.
I haven't finished. She needs--
Pete.
Life's a bitch, ain't it?
Let's get you cleaned up.
Hey. What are you--?
Cooper:
Violet!
You're in a bar with a baby!
Are you loco?
Have you gone la cuckoo?
Why don't you people
answer your phone?
What's wrong?
Coop, wait.
Okay, thank you.
I have everything.
I just need
to bag your clothes, okay?
That's the worst of it.
Charlotte, it means a lot
that you called me.
I know that
we haven't always...
I'm here for you,
whatever you need, okay?
Nurse:
Underwear?
What?
I have a dress,
a bra, two shoes,
but there's no underwear.
Oh.
I don't wear underwear.
They just get in the way.
She doesn't. I think it's gross,
but to each his own, right?
I guess.
You'll need the HIV cocktail,
the morning-after pill,
std prophylaxis and a pelvic.
Right?
Right.
I don't think I want you
down there one-handed.
I just need to examine you for
any internal tears or injuries,
then I'll do a rape kit.
I'll collect pubic hairs,
pelvic washings, blood samples--
no rape kit.
I wasn't raped, I was robbed.
Charlotte--
no rape kit.
what you and I know,
those cops out there,
they don't know.
They know I was robbed.
Now, you can't tell anyone.
No rape kit.
I'm so sorry, Charlotte,
but I have a legal obligation--
I called you.
Okay. It's okay.
No rape kit.
He took my wallet.
He didn't take anything else.
No rape kit.
No rape.
Hey. How is she?
Pete:
She's with Addison.
She's okay considering--
what the hell happened?
A guy beat her up,
stole her wallet.
Where are the cops?
Cops are on it.
Okay. What the hell happened,
Pete?
I mean-- I mean, where is she?
I mean, where is she?
I need to know.
Whoa, hold on. Hold on.
Easy. Easy. Come over here.
Come over here.
They were in a bar.
The nanny's coming to pick up
Lucas. Can you--?
Oh, yeah, yeah. Go.
All right.
Are you sober?
Below the legal limit.
Charlotte took a blow to her
eye socket and vomited.
Could be a concussion--
I'll get a ct of her head and
facial bones, do a neuro exam.
Sam: It's okay.
Cooper: It's not okay.
Charlotte is hurt and I'm not--
Sam: You're drunk.
Okay, Charlotte's hurt
and I'm drunken.
Sam:
Calm down. Calm down.
Charlotte's hurt.
Yes.
Okay, I'm gonna kill somebody.
I'm gonna kill somebody.
Pete: Come on, Coop. Calm down.
Cooper: Let me go!
Guys, come on! I'm calm.
Calm down.
I'm calm. I'm calm. I'm calm.
Sorry.
Ow!
Sam:
Coop.
What the hell happened?
Can you tell me
what you were doing?
You were on the streets.
You seemed confused, they said.
Were you nervous?
Is that why you kicked the cop?
You're clean, you're well-fed.
You're not homeless.
Is someone missing you?
Do you need me
to help get you home?
Or away from home,
or, uh...?
I'm not a cop.
I hate cops.
They call me Shelly, and I hate
guys that call me Shelly.
I just wanna make sure
you're okay.
I'm on your side.
I had a bad night.
That happens.
Cooper:
Ouch.
Sobering up?
I can hang another bag.
No, I'm sober.
I need to get to Charlotte.
You need to let the bag finish.
I need to get to Charlotte--
Addison: Hey.
Pete: How's she doing?
What room is she in?
You need to prepare yourself.
She doesn't look great.
I can handle it.
What room is she in?
524e.
Uh--
okay.
Hell of a night.
Hoo. Yeah.
It's good you were here.
A woman who's been attacked
is usually more comfortable
with another woman.
Yeah.
Addison?
Coop.
Coop, come here.
Come here.
I'm okay, Coop.
Okay.
I'm okay.
It's gonna be okay.
It's important you don't move
while the ct--
I know how a ct works.
Sorry. Of course you do.
You know you're gonna need
stitches.
Yay for me.
I could page somebody
in plastics.
I don't wanna involve plastics.
Less people that know your
business, the better. I get it.
I could do them.
I got a gift with sutures.
Never leave a scar.
It's freakish how good I am.
Thank you.
Plus, you get the good drugs
that go along with stitches.
No drugs for me.
God Grant me the Serenity
to accept the things
I cannot change.
The courage
to change the things I can.
And the wisdom to know
the difference.
I thought you seemed
like one of my people.
Well,
it takes one to know one.
I've been
drinking a lot lately.
No pills, but, um...
Drinking.
Which is a gateway.
You been going to meetings?
No.
You need to take your butt
to meetings.
I'll go with you.
I know the best ones.
Thanks.
No problem.
Now remember, don't move.
The nanny said she'll watch
Lucas as long as we need.
We should pay her more.
She's probably a lawyer
in her country or something.
Heh. Violet.
No, I'm saying
she takes care of our son.
She keeps him safe. We should
pay her everything we have.
The world's a dangerous place.
Hey. I was just texting Naomi.
She's freaking out,
but she told me
to tell you that she knows
you have everything covered.
Yeah. Is she coming home?
She can't.
She's stuck in Zurich
doing some money thing
for William's foundation.
Mm. Um,
should we call Sheldon?
I tried.
He's working at the precinct.
Unreachable.
I'll tell him in the morning.
Oh, okay.
What?
Hoo.
Nothing. It's just that Nai and
Sheldon always know what to do.
Addison?
What?
Hey. Addison.
Nothing, it's just, um...
It's just been a hard night.
Mm.
Oh, Addison.
I'm so grateful it wasn't you.
Don't say that.
You don't know
what Charlotte's going through.
I'm sorry, but i--
with everything-- Maya--
I don't know if I could handle
any more bad news.
Right.
I get that.
I gotta go.
Yeah. Right.
Amelia's doing a ct on Charlotte
and she needs me.
Uh, Addison--
right. Okay.
I'd really like it
if you told me
what you meant when
you said you had a bad night.
It was bad.
That's all I wanna say about it
right now, okay?
Okay.
Hey, can I ask you something?
What's your last name?
McHenry.
That's a good name.
Hmm.
Have you ever thought of, uh,
I don't know, hurting yourself
or hurting someone else?
I just wanna go home.
I know you do.
And i-I'm sorry, but you can't.
Not yet. Not until you tell me
what happened tonight.
There's no hurry,
I don't want you to feel rushed,
but you can't go home until you
tell me. You understand?
This room is gross.
Yeah.
It smells like urine.
I don't like it.
Who hurt you, Lee?
Amelia:
You ready?
You can't take anything
for this pain?
She's allergic to local
anesthetics and she's in n.A.
Charlotte:
I'm fine. Just do it.
How many more?
You're doing great, Charlotte.
It's a guess, but maybe 50.
So now how many more?
Go get a cup of coffee.
No, I'm not leaving her.
Charlotte: Cooper.
I could use some coffee.
Uh-uh.
Charlotte: Really, I could.
Look at me, Cooper.
It's okay.
You go, come back with coffee.
A latte. Please.
I'm gonna start again.
You ready?
Yeah.
Violet:
Pete said
there's no neuro damage.
Good. That's good.
I called the cops.
There's no news,
but I'm gonna stay
on top of them.
Call them every day.
And I checked
our home security system.
We have a doorman,
but I'm gonna hire somebody
to watch the apartment
because maybe that'll
make her feel safer.
People never feel safe
after an attack.
I mean, you hid in the closet
when the doorbell rang.
So I'm thinking an armed man
outside our apartment door
would give her some
peace of mind. Right?
What do you think that costs,
like 50, 60 bucks an hour?
I can cover that.
And maybe she'll need
a bodyguard,
you know,
like a 24-hour-a-day person
to go with her everywhere
for a while.
Cooper.
I'm supposed to protect her.
I know it's the 21st century
and you women
have all surpassed us
in lifespan,
academic achievement,
intelligence and...
You know, well,
everything else, but...
When I was a kid,
my dad taught me one thing.
He said, "you find a woman,
"you marry her,
you get her pregnant,
and you spend the rest of your
life taking care of her."
Maybe that's cro-magnon
or something, but...
I mean, I'm her man.
I'm supposed to keep her safe.
Well, I have been where she is,
and I can tell you
that you
don't have to be tough,
you just have to be there.
Okay?
Okay. Now come here.
You know,
and for the record,
cro-magnon is a relief
sometimes.
Sometimes cro-magnon
is really hot.
Right?
Do you know what this is?
It's your file.
It's not thick, it's just
a couple of pages,
so that's good, okay?
Okay.
What's it say?
No criminal record. Dishonorable
discharge from the Navy.
That was a long time ago.
I know.
I know. It's just that
it's in your file, so...
I have a job now. I have a
girlfriend. I'm normal now.
Can you tell me about
your girlfriend?
We had a fight.
A fight. When? Tonight?
She was screwing this guy
in our bed and I caught her.
Well, that sounds like
quite a fight.
She was throwing stuff
and, uh, I was yelling.
And then she hit me.
Hmm. You were angry.
No, I wasn't. No.
No, she's-- she's my whole life.
My whole life.
She's my everything, you know?
She's real sweet, a good person.
I just don't understand
why she would...
You felt betrayed.
You know what that
betrayal is called?
A stressor. It adds stress
to your life.
A lot of stress.
Yeah.
Stress about covers it.
You have a lot of blood
on your clothes, Lee.
Where'd that come from?
Hey.
I'm sorry,
I didn't mean to wake you.
I wasn't really asleep.
I don't think I'm gonna be
sleeping much ever again.
Charlotte--
don't.
He could do this
to someone else.
Charlotte,
if you don't report this...
There are other women
to think about here.
I said, don't.
There's no shame.
It's not your fault. You need
support, counseling. You need--
if you try
to keep this secret,
it is going to eat you alive.
I know it.
You ever been violated?
Anybody rape you lately?
I'm trying to help.
No, hey, let me tell you
what it's like.
You know those
made-for-TV movies
where some woman's always
crouched down naked in a shower
holding her knees and sobbing
because when she closes her eyes
she can still feel
the guy's hands on her?
How, when they show the attack,
the woman's eyes
go all blank and still?
She goes to some other place
in her mind
just to deal with the horror
of what's happening to her
while some Lilith fair song
plays?
It is nothing like that.
It's dirty.
And sweaty.
And he licks your face.
And he wipes himself off
in your hair.
And when you try to scream, he
punches you so hard you see god.
And then he goes at you again.
Ripping stuff
you didn't even know you had
because he enjoyed it so much
the first time.
I know you're trying to help.
But if helping me means
that everyone,
that Cooper,
is gonna be looking at me
the way you're
looking at me now,
please, do not help me.
I'm gonna...
I'm sorry.
I'll go.
Let's do something
about your pain.
You know how I feel
about hoodoo.
Where does it hurt most?
My soul.
My hand.
And my face.
Okay.
Then I'll start there. Sheila.
Sheldon:
I understand you don't wanna
discuss the blood.
I don't. You can't make me.
Would you mind if I talked
to your girlfriend?
Maybe called her?
No, you can't do that.
How come?
Emasculating bitch.
Always trying to--
emasculating bitch.
How come, Lee?
It wasn't just about
the cheating, was it?
She's an emasculating bitch!
Lee, what did you do
to your girlfriend?
I didn't do anything.
If she's hurt--
Not to her.
Then whose blood is it?
Not hers.
Turn the cameras back on.
Pete helped her with her pain.
Cooper's in there with her now.
You should see if she'll talk
to someone. A psychiatrist.
Mm, I gotta be honest,
I don't wanna go in there.
It's kind of like nam for me.
Right now, Charlotte
is Vietnam and I'm a vet.
The war rages on.
Can you believe this happened
to someone we know?
Again?
I think we're cursed.
When I became a doctor,
I thought it would all be
fat babies and happy moms.
Thought I was gonna be able
to help people.
Not this. Not any of this.
We help people.
Yeah, but what's the point when
we can't even help ourselves?
Hey. There you are, Addie.
Do either of you guys want
a bag of over-processed,
partially dehydrogenated crap?
No thanks.
I'm good.
What time is it?
Four A.M.
ugh.
I've got surgery
tomorrow morning.
Do you think--? Is it rude
if I leave and go home?
What's the etiquette?
What?
I wanna stay, but--
I mean, I don't think anybody
would mind if I went home.
Oh, you--? You wanna go home,
Sam? Fine. Go. Go.
Go rest your head on a pillow.
Sleep the sleep of angels.
Amelia: He's saying he's tired.
I know what he's saying.
He's saying it doesn't matter
what happened to someone else
because it didn't happen to him,
so he's good, he's out.
What's going on with you?
Sit down. You're tired.
Nothing. I...
You're right, I'm tired.
We're all tired.
It's nothing.
I'll go.
No. I will.
Yuck.
I need to write a memo.
What?
A doctor was attacked
on hospital grounds.
People are gonna be concerned
for their safety.
Someone else can do that.
I'm chief of staff.
You don't have to worry
about it right now.
I'm chief of staff. Of course
I have to worry about it.
Everyone will understand.
I don't want them to understand.
I'm the boss.
You're the victim--
you ever call me the victim
again, this marriage is off.
You hear me?
Okay.
Off.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Where you going, Cooper?
I'm just walking.
Coop, where you going?
You shouldn't.
I am.
You don't need to see it.
Yeah, I do, actually.
Cooper.
Shut up, Violet.
Cooper--
stop talking.
She fought. She fought him.
She's 90 pounds soaking wet,
but she's a fighter.
Sheldon:
Whose blood is it? Was someone
else an emasculating bitch?
Someone that looked like
your girlfriend?
I mean, come on, Lee,
in the end,
they're all bitches, right?
She told me to wait my turn.
Who?
I just wanted some help
and she told me to--
she wasn't nice.
She had it coming.
Yeah, of course she did.
She had it coming!
What did you do to her?
I hit her.
I hit her hard and she fought.
She was a bitch in heat
and she fought.
But I gave it to her.
I gave it to her so good.
Who'd you give it to, Lee?
They're all the same. You hear
me? They're all the same.
Guard!
They're all the same.
Get him off of him. Get him off.
Lee: They're all the same.
Price: Get him off of him.
I can wait.
I'll wait it out.
I love you.
I can't tell you.
Are you breaking up with me?
That's funny?
No.
Oh, my god.
I needed that.
Sam, I love you.
You know that, right?
Well, I do now.
What is it
you're not telling me?
I can't.
Talk to me.
If I start talking,
then I'm not gonna be able
to stop, and this--
this is not something
I can talk to you about.
I need you to trust me.
Do you trust me?
Yes, I trust you.
Then, please, don't ask. Just...
Tell me everything
is gonna be okay.
Everything is gonna be okay.
Just be here.
Don't leave me alone.
Okay.
You should be in bed.
Help me get these on.
You don't need
to put them on--
my ass is swinging in the wind.
Help me.
Fine.
I'll do it,
I'll do it, I'll do it.
Untie this gown.
Get me in that shirt.
Charlotte--
I wanna go home.
Please.
I don't wanna
be in this hospital.
Cooper:
Okay, okay.
Charlotte:
Thank you.
Look at me.
For loving me.
Take me home.
Thanks.
So was he telling the truth,
or was he, you know, crazy?
Both.
Oh.
Are you gonna hold him?
Well, we could arraign him
on assault.
I mean, he kicked a cop,
he attacked you.
If he makes bail, even if you
say to hold him on a psych eval,
he'll be out on the street
in 72 hours.
He raped someone.
Yeah.
There's a woman out there
that he raped.
We can put his DNA in the
system, but there's no victim.
I mean, to hold him,
to charge him,
someone's gotta
file charges.
We gotta get a case.
Joe, the man's a rapist.
Ain't life a bitch, Shelly?
Pete:
We should get you a wheelchair.
I'll walk out of here
on my own steam
unless I'm in a body bag
or a coma.
Charlotte:
No!
Don't you people have
somewhere to be?
Don't let me fall.
I won't.
No.
No!