Previously on Grey's Anatomy...
I'm married to a guy who
almost beat me to death.
- You do this everywhere you go?
- Do what?
Turn the place against you.
She's really gonna let you do
a whole surgery with no help?
The resident gets to
be the primary surgeon
on their own
case... start to finish.
What did I do?
Did I kill that boy?
You are the attending!
This is your loss.
You could have friends
here, if you wanted to.
Bailey, who is this woman?
I do not support this.
Then you no longer have an O.R.
You're suspended...
effective immediately.
I don't do reunions.
High school,
undergrad, med school...
Alex, you've got five
minutes. I mean it.
I know.
I can't be late. I have
two consults this morning.
So many teeny-tiny socks.
I can't be late, either.
It's my first day back.
And none of them match. Why?
I don't need to make
superficial conversation
with a bunch of people
I barely remember.
Mer. Mer!
- Hey. I just, I need
to grab my lunch.
- Sorry. Go.
Hey, you know, maybe tomorrow
I can pack a lunch for you,
seeing how I have all
the time in the world now.
I told you to think of
this like a vacation.
These are folded all wrong.
Vacation or prison?
Ooh, sorry. Too soon?
Hey, you don't get to act tired when
you got a full night's sleep in my bed.
You made me take the room.
Yeah, when I thought you
were gonna be here for one night.
- I didn't think you'd move in.
- I haven't moved in.
I do not live
here. I'm crashing.
No, you crash on a
couch. You live in a bed.
And you're living here. I
crash on the couch, and it sucks
because I woke up with a
Cheerio stuck to my face.
You can have my bed because
I'll be dead from boredom.
Can that happen?
Can your hypothalamus
just curl up and...
stop working from
lack of stimulus?
No. I mean, technically, yes.
Hey, how can she suspend
you? Don't you own the hospital?
Oh, she can. I
checked the by-laws.
Checks and balances...
This is how bored I am.
Alex, car, now.
- I want my bed back.
- I do not live here.
If I want to keep someone in
my life, I keep them in my life.
The band is back together again.
Or maybe it's just that I don't
know how to get rid of them.
Anyone?
- That's a kidney.
- Mm-hmm.
And here?
That is a very sick kidney.
Hold on. Are we gonna
do a kidney transplant?
Technically, a kidney
recovery and a transplant.
So, who thinks they're
ready to run lead on those?
I'm not ready.
That is the right answer.
- It is?
- Mm-hmm.
Okay, great. I am not ready.
Put your hand down, intern.
None of you are
ready, but you are ready
to do as much of it as you can
under the extremely close
supervision of an attending
with the reminder to
pass it off if you need to,
which means you'll be that
much closer to being ready.
The donor will be in O.R. 2
supervised by Dr. Webber.
That'll be you, Warren,
with Cross assisting.
- Yes!
- Thank you, Dr. Minnick.
No.
Edwards and Wilson,
you'll be in O.R. 3 working
on the boy with Dr. Karev.
- The boy?
- Yes.
The kidney recipient
is a 16-year-old
in chronic renal failure
from interstitial nephritis.
He's required dialysis
three times a week
while waiting for a
donor, and he just lost
his last access site,
so today is the day.
The donor is...
The boy's mom. She's
giving him one of her kidneys.
The organ procurement
led by Dr. Warren will...
It's a kid. Are you okay?
Yeah, I don't have
much of a choice, do I?
It's Karev. Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Welcome back, Karev.
My name's finally on
the O.R. schedule again,
and I'm not even allowed
to do any of the surgery.
Yeah, welcome to phase two.
Prep the patients and run labs?
That's resident scut. Sucks.
Well, the good news is
I'll be right there with you.
Yeah, you're right. It sucks.
So, how long will my
kidney last in there?
It should last up to 15 years.
Oh, so, definitely
through college then.
Perfect, it'll be like a
guardian angel kidney.
- I will be watching over you...
- Mom!
Like your conscience... I'll
be whispering in your ear,
"Christopher, do your homework.
Christopher, change your sheets.
“Christopher, put down
the Jägermeister...”
You got to interrupt
her. She'll never stop.
I'm not the one in
charge. They are.
If you don't have
any more questions,
then Dr. Edwards and I
will see you in surgery.
Uh, just one thing... Tell
my son it is mandatory
to kiss his mother before she
goes under the knife for him.
- Stop!
- It's mandatory, dude.
Thank you.
Doctors Karev and
Webber will be in in a minute
to prep you for surgery.
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
Thanks.
That was good, but don't
be afraid of taking the lead.
Embrace it. Be assertive.
Dr. Schiavo, extension 2217.
Riggs finishing up the
cardio consult at bed 5,
but I think it's gonna be...
Make it hurt... They
make... They make it hurt.
Ma'am, can I help you?
No. No help.
There's no help out there.
They come and they go
and they crack the whip.
Who's uh...
- I...
- No help.
Do you need something, ma'am?
Ma'am, you can't be back there.
- Snakes...
- You might need
to call security.
There's no snakes here.
- There's no... There's no snakes...
- Okay,
- we're gonna get you
over to someone.
- Did you do this? Did you?
Did you... did you...
Whoa.
No. My son's name
is Chris, Chris Daniels.
He's in surgery today
to get a new kidney.
Let me see if I can
find what room he's in.
- Thank you.
- Hi, I'm Dr. Wilson.
I'm one of Chris' doctors.
Oh, hi.
I hit so much traffic on
the way over here, and I...
So, he's not in surgery yet?
Well, if he is then I'm late,
because I'm his surgeon.
Good. Okay. So, I
haven't missed it?
No, you haven't missed
it. I can take you to him.
- Yes, please. Thank you.
- Yeah.
BP looks good.
You're ready to go.
Well, we need to
start prepping you, too.
I know, but...
can't it wait just
another minute?
I am not ready to leave him.
- He is my...
- Don't say it, Mom!
My baby!
Chris, Cynthia, you
about ready for surgery?
You can start his
prep in the O.R.
Thank you, Edwards.
Hey, guys. Good news. Guess
who I found looking for you?
Dad?
What the hell?
Cynthia, look, I just
wanted to check on Chris.
How did you know where we were?
He posted it online.
Today's "kidney day."
I had no idea he was
even getting a new kidney.
You need to leave,
Ken... right now.
- Cynthia, I swear to God...
- All right, now that's enough.
- That's enough.
- I'm so sorry, sir,
why don't you...
- Hey!
- Chris is my son, too.
Now, I let you do a
lot of stuff without me.
Let me?
He is my kid, too. I
have a right to be here.
- I just want to know he's okay.
- Get out!
Chris, buddy, talk
to your old man here.
Dad, go.
Get the hell out of here.
- Okay, let's go now.
- This is my son.
- Get out!
- Look, I understand...
I have a right to be here.
You hear me? I have rights!
Hey, why don't we sit down?
Why'd you bring him here?
- I'm sor...
- Why would you do that?
Cynthia, do you
want to sit down?
- Hey, big transplant today.
- Don't talk to me.
- I'm mad at you.
- Oh, God, did you go?
Yes. Now I want to
eat there every night.
I told you. Did you
have the steak things?
I had two, and then
the dessert tray came.
I'll come look, but I
think that you're right
to delay your patient's ACL
surgery until after she delivers.
Thank you for the
consult, Dr. Robbins.
I do not know how you do it.
I don't know how you
can be polite to her.
- Oh, I know. She's the worst.
- Yeah. I couldn't do it,
not after the way she
screwed Webber over.
Yeah, right. Got to go.
All Minnick did was take
a job she was offered.
No, she stole that job.
But you're rather
familiar with the concept
of job stealing, aren't you?
Uh, Kepner, are you up to speed
on the big resident transplant?
- Yes. Yes.
- Good.
You are running the
show. I have to leave.
- Are you up for that?
- Yes. I... yes.
Uh, where are you going? I
thought you were running the show.
Camp David for a summit meeting.
Wait, actual Camp David?
Well, she's gone.
Maybe you can
steal her job, too.
You paged me for
a temp pacemaker?
Yeah, she needs a permanent
one, but can't get consent, so...
Well, you need
approval? You got it.
What is she,
intoxicated or something?
Jane Doe, no I.D. She's
confused and disoriented
- to the time and place.
- Ma'am,
can you tell me your name?
No, no names.
Names are for
hats, not for cats.
You put the snake in the hat.
We did ask that.
I'll tell Grendel. Grendel
has all the patterns.
She sees the patterns.
She sees the patterns,
I see the patterns.
- You don't see the diagram...
- Okay.
- Because I see the diagrams!
- Okay, okay, ma'am.
You don't know the diagrams.
You don't know the diagrams!
We're gonna give you
something to relax you, all right?
Two I.V. of lorazepam.
-CBC, chem one and
a tox screen, -Okay.
- And call psych.
- So...
how old is that pacemaker?
That is the Ford
Pinto of pacemakers.
Right.
Okay, ma'am, we're gonna
take that old pacemaker out
and give you a brand new,
shiny one. How's that sound?
For the snakes?
It's for the snakes.
- Yeah.
- For the snakes.
Your BP is through the roof.
We've got to get that
down before surgery.
We're gonna give you a little
something to calm you down, okay?
He's downstairs
in the waiting area.
He's asking for updates.
You can't make him leave?
I'm so sorry. He never mentioned
that you were divorced or...
They're not.
They should be, but they're not.
I left with Chris
almost a year ago.
And you should
have done it sooner.
- He hit her.
- Chris!
- What?
- What? It's why we left.
I didn't have a job.
Chris was sick all the time,
and I thought I
could make it work.
But the day that
he went after Chris,
we left that night, and
now he's showing up
pretending that he cares,
pretending that he is a father?
Mom, it's all
right. We'll be fine.
Okay, I just want you to focus
on why you are here today.
I can't believe him.
Today was supposed
to be such a good day.
And it is. It still is.
Think about Chris.
- Hey.
- Thank you.
- Hey, thank you.
- Hey, Dr. Hunt?
Make that man leave.
Did something happen?
Listen, do you need
me to call security, or...
I just... I need him
to go away, please.
Okay.
Excuse me, sir, um, you've
been asked to leave the premises,
- so if you can follow me...
- I'm not bugging anyone,
I'm not hurting anyone.
- I have every right to be here.
- Sir, do you want me
to call security?
- Because I need you to leave.
- Oh, this again!
You're gonna threaten
me with... Sir, sir!
Do not touch me!
First scrubbed... I
make the first cut.
You okay?
What do you mean, am I okay?
The thing with the
husband. Are you...
I'm fine.
Let's use the pelvic
brim as a landmark.
Mm-hmm.
Dividing the ureter...
- How we doing?
- Very well.
Cross, can you
enlarge the incision?
Yep. Got it.
A whole, healthy kidney.
Nice work, guys...
like seasoned pros.
More like very good
residents who are learning
an advanced procedure and
still needing help and guidance.
Which you are clearly giving
them. Nice work, Dr. Webber.
Good news...
Warren and Cross have successfully
removed their patient's kidney,
which will soon be
your patient's kidney.
- So, who wants to...
- I'll get...
I'll get the kidney. I have
crossed the sterile field.
I'll get the kidney.
Okay.
The wires on the
pacemaker's stuck.
DeLuca, laser.
Can't you just pull them out?
No. It's scarred
into her tissue.
Why are we not better at
taking care of the homeless?
Gotcha!
So, now what? We hand
her over to Social Services?
How will they find
out who she is?
Fingerprints, I imagine.
- She doesn't have a record.
- I don't know.
Maybe dental records?
She doesn't have a home,
you think she has a dentist?
I don't know.
They'll figure it out.
Okay, but what if they don't?
She didn't just
come from nowhere.
Someone's probably
looking for her, right?
Is she just gonna
go back to the street?
Nope.
'Cause I just found
out who she is.
Call the company, get them
to trace the serial number.
That will tell us who
you are, Ms. Doe.
Warren and Cross did fine
work with the renal vein graft.
It should be an
easy anastomosis.
Got it, sir.
All right. Well, what's next?
- Irrigating here...
- Good hemostasis...
Should we close?
Her systolic BP's 200.
Was it malignant hypertension?
No history of high
blood pressure.
Okay, well, you know
what, stop. Nobody move.
Bolus of diltiazem, fast, and
let's pull up an image now.
Did we do something wrong?
Uh, I-I can't see.
Enlarge the image and
show me the right kidney.
There. Behind
the bowel. Damn it!
The vessel's prepped
for anastomosis.
Pocket for
implantation is ready.
Go time.
Stop!
- Did you attach it?
- Geez.
- Webber, what the hell?
- Did you attach the kidney?
No, no. I'm... I'm
holding it, I'm holding it.
Put it back on ice.
The mom's remaining
kidney thrombosed.
It's dead.
We now have only one
good kidney between them.
Call UNOS. Tell them you need
Chris moved to the top of the list.
We already told them he
lost his last dialysis port.
Tell him he's on the table
now with two residents
pouring saline down
his open abdomen.
What kind of timeframe
are we talking about?
Not long. She's
in renal failure.
- What happened?
- The donor's remaining kidney
had a major stenosis.
And when we tried to
open it up, the entire vessel
dissected and clotted off.
So, where does this kidney go,
back to the mom or into the kid?
- Well, it was already
in the kid's O.R.
- What's the legal on that?
The mom signed the
paperwork. It's past the red line.
- It belongs to the kid.
- No, it doesn't.
Not until it's put into him.
- It was about to go in.
- So, there's no formal protocol?
Not that I know of. I mean...
this is not a thing
that happens.
- This is...
- This is a first.
- So, no rule book.
- Where's Bailey?
She left. She said she
was going to Camp David.
- What does that mean?
- I don't know.
She said she had
a summit meeting.
She said I'm in charge.
Invite me inside for coffee.
For coffee?
We are going to sit
down over a cup of coffee,
and we are going to figure
this out like smart women.
- Over coffee?
- Over coffee.
Do you have coffee?
I'm not leaving until
you invite me in.
- Well, I don't have milk.
- I don't take milk.
We give the boy the kidney,
and then his mother's
on dialysis, maybe for life.
Well, people are surviving for far
longer. They both have a chance.
We just close up
the kid, he's screwed.
- He has no access...
- And then we just close up
the mom, and then we've
given her a debilitating condition.
- We have to give it back to her.
- The kid's at a dead end.
The mom is healthy.
She can go on dialysis
until we find a donor.
But is that what
she signed on for?
She signed up to
save her son's life.
At the expense of her own?
She came in here
perfectly healthy.
If you found the stenosis a minute later,
we wouldn't even be talking about this.
- The kidney
would already be in him.
- Yeah, but it isn't,
and if we don't put it in someone
soon, it's gonna die and no one gets it,
so who's it going to?
- Why are you asking me? I'm not deciding.
- Just answer the question.
Where do you think
the kidney should go?
Out of my jurisdiction.
But in 5 years, in
10 years, it won't be.
So what would you do?
Look, if we can wake up the
mom and ask what she wanted...
We can't. She would
need to be awake
long enough to be competent.
The kidney would
not last until then.
I know, but if we could,
she'd say give it to her son.
Right?
No doubt. Give it to the kid.
Any parent would
say the same thing.
Sure, any parent
with two good kidneys.
She's only got one. She
might want to hang on to it.
Yeah, if she's a monster.
- I'd want to hang on to it.
- And that makes you a monster.
You're the monster.
So, we give Chris the kidney,
and then the 16-year-old
has to take care of
his mom or she dies,
and we've saved his
life, but left him an orphan.
- He wouldn't be an orphan.
- Yeah, he has a father.
A father who used to beat
the crap out of his mom
and probably him.
That's who we'd
be sending Chris to.
You were right. The company
had her records right there.
She was a minor
at the time, so...
Tell me her name again.
The patient's name
is Claire Nolan.
- This is her mother.
- Okay. Good work, DeLuca.
See? Problem solved.
- You're very impressed
with yourself.
- A little bit.
- Ms. Nolan.
- Yes? Gwen.
The police said someone
found my daughter.
Yes. We just have
a few questions
before we take you to her.
Did you call Tim? My
ex-husband... Is he coming?
He's on his way. Please.
Did your daughter have
a history of mental illness?
No. That's...
- Why does that matter?
- Just prepare yourself...
It'll be a bit of a shock
when you see her.
Well, it's already a
shock. It's been 12 years.
I never thought
anyone would find her.
Well, you may have a
hard time understanding her.
- Wait, what?
- Well, her speech is...
very disorganized.
- She's possibly delusional.
- She's alive?
Claire's alive?
Are you telling me
my daughter's alive?
Did I say he's 16?
I know it doesn't change
anything, but he's 16,
and he is open on a table.
- Anything?
- Nothing.
I'll try Seattle Pres again.
This kid doesn't have another
option. We just lost his donor kidney.
- We need another one right now.
- What do you mean?
- You talking about my son?
- Hold on.
- You're talking about Chris.
- You were told to leave.
What happened?
What happened to
Cynthia? What is it?
I can't discuss their
conditions with you.
Don't you tell me that.
That is my son up there,
and you have to tell
me what is going on.
Answer me.
- Kepner, we need an answer.
- I know!
Dr. Webber, prep
the mother for dialysis.
I will call UNOS myself.
Karev, start the
anastomosis on the boy.
Wait! Stop.
We might have
another option, but...
But?
- Wilson.
- Jo, what is it?
The husband.
The son of a bitch
wants to give his kidney,
but we can't do that, right?
Right?
So, people are really embracing
this new method of teaching.
Some say it's actually fun.
Today you would
have been performing
a mother-to-son
kidney transplant.
You don't have to sell
me on the method, Bailey.
- People like it. I get it.
- Good. Then we can stop
all of this stubbornness
and the insubordination.
- It's not insubordination.
- Well, it's not cooperation.
Look, I made you
my Chief of General
because I wanted you
to be my right hand.
- So, you want a Yes Man?
- No.
I want someone who will lead
with me but follow when I lead.
Even if I think you're
leading the wrong way?
I shouldn't speak up when I
think you're making a misstep?
You don't want
that in a right hand?
- I'm not making a misstep.
- I disagree,
but you don't want to
hear a dissenting opinion.
Well, you never
offered me your opinion.
You just shut Minnick out.
I didn't have time to
offer you an opinion.
You just showed
Richard the door.
How could you do that?
I didn't want to do that. I...
I wanted him to stay
right where he was.
I wanted Minnick to add value,
but she wouldn't work with him.
So, you sided with Minnick
and tossed Richard aside?
No.
Look, I had a
choice to make, Grey,
and I didn't want
to make it because,
yes, Dr. Webber
built this place.
But I have to keep building it.
So I do that by asking
myself 100 times a day,
"What would Richard Webber do?"
But how did Eliza Minnick
win you over so quickly?
When I saw this program,
this better way of teaching,
I asked myself again, "What
would Richard Webber do?"
And he would have embraced
this, Grey, you know it.
The answer was so clear. I
couldn't ignore that choice.
But you made the wrong choice.
Look, you can serve under
Chief Webber if you want to,
but that doesn't change the
fact that he is not your chief.
I am. And as your chief...
I am ready to...
lift the suspension if you
feel you can come back.
- I want to.
- Good.
But I can't.
Not until he does.
Okay, there's a
difference between loyalty
and stubbornness, Grey.
I do not want to be reinstated
unless Richard Webber
is as Residency Director.
Minnick goes.
Thanks for the coffee.
We can't do this. We can't
put his kidney inside her son.
If his tests show he's a
match, we're absolutely doing it.
But it's wrong. His wife
would never agree to this.
- She would never accept this.
- To save herself and her son?
She wouldn't say
no out of spite.
She might like any
other option, though.
- Well, I don't see
any other option.
- He's right here.
And our obligation
is to our patients.
- But what about her?
- No one should get to make
this decision for her.
- Our patients are still stable.
- What about the residents?
Fairly stable. Is he a go?
- Yeah, it looks like...
- No!
We can't! We can't do this.
Wilson, we have no other choice.
Don't say that. You
don't get how she will feel
to wake up and find out
that he controlled this,
that he made a decision
while she was asleep.
He decided to get into her life.
She had no say, no
control, no choice, nothing.
He can't do that. He can't.
We have to try something new.
- We have to find...
- There's no time.
I'm sorry.
If his tests come back and
he's a match, we're doing this.
Do you want to go in?
She was in college at U-Dub.
It'd had been a couple weeks,
and we hadn't heard from her.
They found the door to
her apartment wide open.
It looked like an abduction.
There were press conferences.
We walked through the
forest with flashlights.
It was all we thought
about for years.
It ended our marriage.
It ended our lives.
Well, it's early for me to
make a definitive diagnosis,
but I suspect you're right.
Claire suffers
from schizophrenia.
Gwen, how old did you say
she was when she disappeared?
Twenty.
That fits, I'm afraid.
Late teens, early 20s is
when it starts manifesting.
It's possible it got so bad
that she just left
everything behind.
Do you want to go in, let
her know that you're here?
- Why don't you sit for a minute?
- Okay.
We had a funeral.
Everyone came to the funeral.
She has a grave stone.
Kepner told me what's going on.
You were supposed
to get him to leave.
I thought I did.
But now I'm glad I didn't.
His son's gonna die
unless he gets a kidney.
I'm not excusing
what he did, I'm not.
But maybe... maybe this is
his way of coming out of it,
of being a better person.
Maybe he's sorry.
Maybe he's changed.
The dad's a match.
You don't need to be involved.
You can sit this one out.
No. I'm not gonna sit it out.
You just got to
let it go, okay, Jo?
I know.
Don't... Jo!
Wait. Hold on.
You're not the hero here.
You don't get to
take this as a win.
This is the least that
you can do, the very least.
- I'm doing the right thing.
- I don't think so.
I think you want an excuse to
worm your way back into their lives.
I'm not.
I swear.
I can't take back the
stuff that I've done.
But I can do this.
I just want to do
something good.
If you really want to do good,
never tell them about this.
You do it anonymously
and walk away.
They never have to
know it was your kidney,
and they never have
to see you again.
Oh, my God, he's
an abusive husband?
Yes. So now, he's
their only hope.
The kid is getting his
dad's sleaze-ball kidney.
- Well, you're doing
the right thing.
- It feels gross.
Yeah, but the choice
that keeps everyone alive
is the right one.
- That is wise.
- I am wise.
And you're pretty
rude, actually...
rude and obstructive,
and I am fed up with it.
This is so fun.
- That woman is a menace.
- Mm-hmm.
And what I hate is her smugness.
She doesn't have the
experience to be that smug.
And she hides her total
disrespect under this bunch of perky.
- Yeah, she's confident.
- She's overconfident.
- She's a menace.
- God, yes.
- Gwen, your ex-husband is here.
- They found her.
- Gwen, they said she's alive?
- She is, but, Tim...
I can't believe it. I
can't believe she's alive!
Tim... she might not
know who we are.
We're not sure.
It's unclear as to what she's
responding to in the real world
and what's just
happening inside her.
She might.
We're her parents. She might.
You ready?
Claire? Claire, it's Dr. Pierce.
Pierce? Pierce. Pierce.
Needles pierce.
There's blood in my arms.
And snakes... I can see them.
You can't... You had it.
- Claire?
- There's snakes in my...
Hi, honey.
No. No, no, no!
- No!
- I need five of Haldol!
It's Mom.
It's Mom and Dad.
You can't have the
blood in my arms!
You can't have it!
Okay, let's... let's just
give her some space.
- You can't have it.
- You're safe.
Okay, Claire. Okay.
It's okay. She's
gonna be all right.
Ready for anastomosis.
Dr. Karev?
Nice jobs, Edwards.
I'm here if you need me.
Dr. Bradshaw, call Recovery.
Well, this looks like
the residents pulled
it off without a hitch.
You missed a few hitches.
I went and talked to Grey.
Yeah? She coming back?
No, she is not.
Bailey, you...
you are ridiculous.
You're not just costing
Meredith time and money,
you're costing yourself
and the hospital.
Oh, no, not me. You are.
She chose you.
Dr. Guyer to Radiology.
So, I'm gonna start
her with a gradually
increasing dose of haloperidol.
After she stabilizes,
there's newer
medications we can try.
Hopefully that'll stop
the disorganized thoughts
- and help her communicate...
- Well, will she know us?
What if she doesn't?
What do we do?
After she's released and
stable, it'll be up to her.
Sometimes people don't
like the way the meds feel,
so they go off and end
up back where they were.
We just don't know.
I'll make sure your
family is given information
about services and permanent
supportive housing programs.
You can go back in and...
and sit with her
until she wakes up.
We'll wait, if that's all right.
Okay.
We'll come back and check in.
I just...
Schizophrenia's a
difficult disease, but...
with treatment,
it can be helped.
What do you mean?
Well, I just don't get it.
I would just be
happy she's alive.
How is this not a happy ending?
You're right. You don't get it.
I want to.
They gave up on her.
They just buried an empty
box in the ground and moved on,
had lattes, saw movies.
They just lived their
lives, and all the while,
their daughter was out there
walking around in the rain,
in pain and alone.
And they will never
forgive themselves for that.
And they shouldn't.
- Hey!
- Hey. You busy?
Yes, I was just about to
paint a wall and watch it dry.
Well, Karev and I talked
the "surgeons of tomorrow"
through a kidney
transplant today.
And?
And you being here
instead of there is a waste.
I mean, also, it's your choice.
It's also stubborn.
- Bailey spoke to you?
- She did.
Meredith, go back.
Don't waste another
day, not for me.
I want to, but every
time I try, I keep hearing
my mother's voice saying
"Meredith, it's Richard."
Well, that's very nice,
but we both know
that your mother would
never put me before her career.
True.
But I'm supposed
to do better than her.
Isn't that the point, be
better? I can't be like her.
Go get your job.
Good night.
Dr. Bailey, please.
My transplant was a success.
- Thanks for asking.
- You mean Minnick's transplant?
Yeah, Minnick's transplant.
Never seen residents learn
the way that they did today.
It was inspiring.
Oh, hey. I was just texting you.
It's not fun. You
know, this is...
- It's not fun.
- I'm sorry. I don't understand.
I don't like pretending
not to like you,
and I don't like listening
to the awful things
that people have
to say about you...
What do they say?
Because I know
that you're not awful.
And they should know.
They should know that.
- Arizona...
- Because you're nice,
and you're smart, and
you're funny, and you care.
You care about the students
maybe even more than I do.
And you have this brilliant way
of making your
victories their victories,
and you're good for this
place, and you're good for them,
- and they should know that.
- Arizona, stop.
- I just think it's not...
- I need you to stop...
so I can kiss you.
- Oh.
- Stop.
Claire...
how are you feeling?
I'm just gonna check
your bandage, okay?
I... I wasn't...
I wasn't gonna put
in... in the order.
They switch you on,
and they switch you off,
and they've got...
diagrams... and
conditions, and...
Claire, we're monitoring
your pacemaker...
and it's working beautifully.
And we've put you
on some medication
to calm you down. It might
make you feel a little groggy.
Okay.
I... you can't...
you can't feel...
You can't feel the
snakes in the hat.
Nobody can feel the snakes.
Hi, Mom.
Hi.
Hi, sweetie.
Hi, Claire-Bear.
Can we sit with you?
You can... you can sit.
You can sit, but
you can't tell...
I can tell.
They crisscross, the...
The snakes are in the cart.
They told me...
So, I...
I still have a kidney?
And Chris... He also h...
has a kidney?
Yes. Chris received
a different kidney.
A perfect, healthy
living-donor kidney.
But... how?
From... from who?
It was an anonymous
directed donation.
It's a perfect match, and
Chris is responding really well.
I can't believe it...
That people are...
are that good...
That they can be so good.
Thank you.
Well, it looks like she's
responding to meds.
That's good.
The family has you to thank...
for that pacemaker idea.
Oh, you would
have thought of that.
Yep, looks like they're
getting their little girl back.
Are you...
Do you want to talk?
Hmm?
Oh, no. I'm...
I'm great, just...
Happy ending, right?
Night.
Hey, Wilson.
How you doing?
You okay?
Do you need me
to do anything, or...
Hey, hey, hey...
I don't do reunions, but
I can see why people do.
Thank you.
They can make you feel like
you haven't felt in a long time.
It's comfy, it's familiar, it's
kind of like coming home.
What?
Nathan was so sad today.
We had this patient
who turned up
after being missing for years.
And we called her family.
I think it brought up a lot of
feelings about his fiancée.
Megan.
I've never seen him like that.
When Derek died,
there was one day,
just one day, where I
didn't know where he was.
I pretended everything
was going to be okay,
but inside, I was going crazy.
I guess it's like that
for Nathan every day.
You see how people turned out
if they realized their
hopes and dreams
or if they have lost
their hopes and dreams.
Yeah.
You get him.
Well, I don't know about that.
Or maybe you see that they
have found what we all should find...
brand new hopes and dreams.