Bye.
I want to be alone with my wife.
I'm a selfish SOB.
I never got you to Rio.
There was always
one more problem at the stores.
You deserved better than that.
I love you.
I always have.
I'm ready.
It's okay.
I know...
Somebody
help her.
Help her!
Fifty-four-year-old woman
with acute respiratory failure.
No anaphylaxis, lung
issues or tracheal lesions.
Tox screen was clean for
coke and amphetamines.
I will give you 30 reasons, one for
each pound that caused the apnea,
which inflamed the epiglottis.
Why's our rainbow coalition
missing Brown and Bi?
Thirteen's with the patient,
and Kutner's dog's sick.
He should be in by lunch.
No apnea because no sleeping
problems when she's sleeping.
She's spent the last six months
caring for her husband
who's dying of heart failure.
Reason 31, whatever
whacked the husband's heart
is also whacking her airway.
And, oh, good, I thought maybe Kutner
was home nursing the rib you broke
when you elbowed your way
in for credit on the last patient.
I contributed. And the patient's
illness wasn't caused by her husband,
unless lung cancer
is contagious.
Interesting.
Not about the patient,
that was kind of dull.
I thought maybe you were lying to
cover for Kutner, which sounds noble,
except you're doing it
out of guilt, instead of love.
She visited her sister in
Hawaii about six months ago,
just before her
husband got sick.
Could've picked up melioidosis
from one of the islands.
Would have jumped
to the husband,
finished off him and his
lame immune system.
No tumors, no
drugs, no bacteria...
Leaves viral. Varicella zoster.
Start her on IV
fluids and acyclovir.
Can't. She's demanding
to be released
so she can get
home to her husband.
How sweet. They
can die together,
instead of separately,
40 years apart.
She claims he got stronger as
soon as she stopped breathing.
The mind can heal the body.
Seeing his wife in distress might
have actually slowed down his death.
Or he just had an
adrenaline surge
when he saw his chance
to hit the singles market.
Send her home. We don't need to.
I had an idea, all by myself.
Eddie?
Found him
loitering in the lobby.
You're still with me.
Where the hell
else am I gonna go?
And now, with your permission,
we'd like to try to
make you better.
The pageant starts in an
hour. You have to do something.
There's something
wrong inside her head.
It's like she has no idea
what's going on around her.
I thought she was
just flirting with me.
I could fix it, but it's
gonna cost you $3.75.
Well, I'm not just gonna
give you my coffee.
Think of it as Costa
Rican sober juice.
She's drunk?
That little minty scent hiding
beneath the rose petal perfume,
and the cherry
blossom moisturizer,
and the morning dew hairspray...
You sneak into Mommy's bathroom
and gulp some of her mouthwash?
Gotta be perfect.
You spit it out?
Mommy doesn't.
Treatment worked.
Charlotte's breathing's back to
normal. She's being discharged.
She can resume her vigil over her
husband. He's started fading again.
Win some, lose some.
And, strictly speaking, since
he's not my patient, win some.
Oh, look at the time.
It's half past Taub
was lying about Kutner.
He probably went
to a comic book fest,
spent the night at some Wonder
Woman's lair. I'm sure he'll...
Find out what, or
who, he's doing.
Either way, Cuddy's gonna want me to
write it under "Reason for Termination."
Is that Kutner? Charlotte.
O2 sat and S-T are
normal. It's not her airway.
You're okay.
Yeah, don't worry
about me, she's in pain.
Pulse is rapid and
regular, no fluid in her lungs.
What's happening?
I don't know.
Kutner. It's Foreman and 13.
Where are you going?
House didn't ask us to
find out where he wasn't.
If you wanna climb a
fifth-floor fire escape...
This might be faster.
Kutner!
Man-boy heaven.
Surprised he ever leaves.
There's nothing on his
calendar. His pager's still here.
Oh, God.
Need an ambulance at
410 Willis, apartment 5C.
Twenty-eight-year-old male, single
gunshot wound to the right temple.
No pulse.
Alert Princeton-Plainsboro,
have a trauma unit ready.
His pupils are dilated,
his head's swollen.
Still no pulse. Come on, Kutner!
Let me try.
He's cold.
Eric.
He didn't say
anything to any of you?
Family problems? Bad
relationship? Financial pressures?
His parents were shot
right in front of him.
Parents are ancient history.
Not to someone
who actually cares.
He didn't slit his wrists and
peacefully drift away, he shot himself.
He didn't leave a
note, that means panic.
Which could've been pre-empted if
the idiots who worked alongside him
for 80 hours a week
had seen this coming.
You're blaming us?
I'm just trying
to figure it out.
We would've helped him if
he'd reached out to us. He didn't.
We should've picked
up on something.
This isn't our fault.
Something like 25%
of suicidal people
show no outward
signs of depression.
No, 25% of suicidal
people have friends
who didn't notice anything
and don't want to feel guilty.
Killing yourself also
kills all other options.
Makes Kutner an idiot.
So pity, yes, but guilt, no.
If that's what you
want to tell yourself.
We still have a patient.
Actually, two. One worsening,
one who should be worsening.
You can't be in denial about
Kutner and the husband.
It is possible Eddie's
body is willing itself to live.
Well, call the tabloids.
Tell them you just witnessed the miracle
of slightly increased kidney function.
Maybe we should pass
this file off to another doctor.
And the next one, too?
And the one after that?
How many files till it's
okay that Kutner's dead?
Cardiac enzymes means
she didn't have a heart attack.
No vision problems means
no mitochondrial disease.
Could be a metabolic
disorder. Acidosis.
Blood pH was normal.
Polyserositis would inflame the
membranes near her epiglottis
and the heart's pericardium,
causing the chest pain.
I'm sorry.
I've hired a grief counselor,
who I'm sure none of you will see.
And I'm offering time off, which
I'm sure none of you will take.
But just know it's available.
Polyserositis fits. Start
her on indomethacin.
If you'd rather not
deal with this case...
I'm fine, despite
what Wilson will say.
He hasn't come to you?
Pretty sure he has
Mah-jongg Tuesday mornings.
I assume he thinks that I
will work through this better
if I don't have to keep flicking
his wings off my shoulder.
You didn't even have an inkling?
I know his fantasy football team
cratered, figured he'd gotten over it.
Well...
Sorry for your loss.
Thanks. It's not my loss.
Then I'm sorry
you don't think it is.
Patient's membranes aren't
going to heal themselves.
Taub went to run the treatment.
We'd like to go see
Kutner's parents.
I'll join you.
Polyserositis damages the protective
covering around tissue and organs.
The indomethacin is simply an
anti-inflammatory, but it should fix it.
Just make the pain stop.
Charlotte.
Close your eyes.
Now.
Pretend you finally
made it down to Rio.
You're on the balcony of
some fancy hotel.
You never talk like this.
Yeah, just shut up
and let me do this.
And you're on that balcony, and
you are watching the Mardi Gras.
It's called Carnival.
And I don't want
to go without you.
I want you to.
And I want it to be everything
you've ever dreamed of.
Sorry to interrupt, but I'd
like to run one more test.
On you.
This is the first day
we got him. He was six.
Sweetest little
boy you ever met.
Must have been scary,
going through a trauma, and then
being handed off to a new family.
We kept telling him to
call us Richard and Julia,
but it was always
Mr. and Mrs. Kutner.
Then, on his ninth birthday,
we gave him a chemistry set.
Lawrence always
loved blowing things up.
And he said, "Thanks,
Mom. Thanks, Dad."
That's who we were from then on.
He was pretty special.
We were lucky to have him.
You spent the
most time with him.
He spoke so
highly of all of you.
Do you have any idea...
I wish we did.
We all... HOUSE:
It was his name.
He was conflicted.
Didn't know where he fit in.
Being ripped out of his
world and stuck into yours.
We encouraged him to
hold on to his heritage.
It's hard to still be
Lawrence Choudhary
when everyone sees
you as Lawrence Kutner.
It was his idea
to take our name.
You should have said no. House.
All his Anglo name gave him was the
illusion that he was someone he wasn't.
You were being
emotional, not rational.
You didn't understand him.
We loved that boy,
you son of a bitch.
You wanted to make him
happy by shutting out his pain.
When he looked happy, you
assumed the pain had gone,
but it just got buried deeper,
leaving him tormented about who
he was, until finally he put a bullet...
House.
Go back to the hospital.
I'm sorry about your son.
Indomethacin had no effect, she's
still in pain. Rules out polyserositis.
I ran a hormone panel on Eddie.
His prolactin's above normal.
Means he's actually improving.
Body chemistry changes
for all sorts of reasons.
Stress, fear, why not love?
Maybe he's going into
some sort of remission.
You haven't asked if I learned
anything relevant from the Kutners.
If you had, I'm sure
you'd have mentioned it.
Or you're just afraid
there is something relevant,
which would mean you
could have saved him.
I don't buy that suicide
is always a cry for help.
Sometimes you
just don't want help.
Good thing you got some,
or you'd have tried
again and gotten it right.
She doesn't have Wegener's.
Kidney function's normal.
It's not byssinosis, it's
not mitral valve stenosis.
Nothing fits.
If it doesn't fit any diagnosis,
that just leaves one diagnosis.
I'm Dr. House.
You have hypertrophic
cardiomyopathy.
His heart is too weak,
yours is too strong.
Good news is it's fixable.
We induce a massive heart
attack and kill off the extra muscle.
You want to give
me a heart attack?
It's only dangerous if
your heart is normal-sized.
But since all the...
Are you serious?
No.
This is actually very annoying,
and I'm getting really bored
of lying to patients
to scare them
into telling me the
truth. She's faking.
And, yes, if she keeps faking,
I'm going to eventually do
something that will kill her.
How could she be...
The windpipe thing?
That was real. The
treatment made her better.
But good for her was bad
for you, which was bad for her,
so she made herself
bad. It's all so simple.
She figured that the sicker she
was, the longer you'd hang on.
Charlotte?
We haven't been
this close for years.
I wanted to hang on to that.
Oh, please.
People hate reruns.
It's my leg. I
swear, this is real.
Do you pinky swear or you
just plain swear, because...
How can she fake that?
She can't.
So, what can shred an epiglottis
and make muscle disappear?
Mr. and Mrs. Kutner.
They caused Kutner's
death, why not Charlotte's?
Mourning period's over.
Foreman's sense of irony is back.
I was wrong about
the ethnic reason.
Step one, change your name back.
Step two, if step one
fails, move to Bangalore.
Step 14, if step 13
doesn't work, kill yourself.
So, what now? You gonna
insult your way through his rolodex
till you find someone
with an answer?
I've been polite to the friends I've
called, all of whom were useless.
They weren't useless, they just
didn't know anything more than we did.
Tomato, tomato.
MS. Weakens myelin sheath,
compromises nerve conduction.
I'm talking about Charlotte,
the one who's still alive.
You two, stick her in
an MRI, confirm MS,
and you, run the echo on Eddie
that you're planning
to do behind my back
to see if his heart's improving.
Did you let me hire a pervert?
Well, it'd be
hypocritical of me not to.
Kutner's police background
check from when he started.
He was charged with
indecent exposure.
Kutner streaked at the
Penn-Dartmouth football game.
Precisely the kind of thing
you'd expect him to do.
It's okay.
You should be upset.
He thought like you,
pushed boundaries like you.
If he thought like me,
he'd have known
that living in misery
sucks marginally
less than dying in it.
Just a few more minutes,
then we'll get you back to Eddie.
What's it like, 30 years
with the same man?
Great for me, good
for him, I hope.
What, you don't
think he loves you?
I think he always
loved me, in his way.
Just not in a "spend time
with me" or "show emotion"
or "any affection
for me" sort of way.
Why did you stay?
I didn't need him to feel about
me the way I did about him.
Love doesn't...
Charlotte?
I've heard stories
of cancer patients
going into
spontaneous remission.
You think this might
be that sort of thing?
It's unlikely, but
you never know.
If I just had a little more
time to be with Charlotte.
Try and do better by her.
Yeah, maybe.
You don't think I mean it.
I think you mean it now.
I think it's much easier to mean
it than to do anything about it.
Chamber walls are
barely moving. I'm sorry.
He needs a friend.
I can't deal with
this and House.
You need a friend, too.
You couldn't give
a crap what I need,
you just want someone
to take care of him.
He told Kutner's
parents it was their fault.
Ruptured spleen.
Means it's not MS.
What are you doing here?
Waiting for you to fix her spleen, so
we can biopsy it for rheumatoid arthritis.
I'll do it. Go home.
She's not your patient.
And Kutner wasn't my friend.
Kutner wanted to
die, Charlotte doesn't,
so in a contest for my
concern and interests, she wins.
Okay, either you're a
cold-hearted bastard,
or you're too
miserable to face it.
Go home and cry.
It's not rheumatoid
arthritis, her liver's scarred.
Whatever she's
got, it's spreading.
For the record,
I'm uncomfortable violating
a dead colleague's dignity.
It's only violating if
we find something.
Good to see you.
What are we looking for?
He was hiding.
Why?
Shame? Fear? Are you okay?
It's okay not to be okay.
"Colonial Warrior
Blaster. Number 101."
He spent months
tracking this down.
He had passions.
He was obviously in pain.
Does it really matter why?
He hung the bad with the good.
His loss beside a reminder
of what he'd gained.
Means he was
open about the pain.
Should mean that if it got
worse, he had no reason to hide it.
Here's how we're
gonna handle this, House.
We're going to leave here and
go to the closest bar and drink,
tell stories about the time
Kutner almost blew up an OR,
and pass out in our own sick.
Sound like a plan?
What am I missing?
You've got that look.
You figured this out.
You're not here because
you care about Kutner.
You're here because
it's a mystery.
You're here for the puzzle.
What if I didn't miss anything
because there's nothing to miss?
He didn't kill himself.
He was murdered.
Epiglottis, muscle,
spleen, and now her liver,
which is operating at
20% and deteriorating fast.
Autoimmune hepatitis?
Did you page Foreman?
He took up Cuddy's
offer of time off.
Normal thyroid
means no hepatitis.
Could be amyloidosis. Amyloid
build-up hits the organs, tissue...
Her muscles wouldn't
have atrophied.
You run the echo on the husband?
Heart's still failing. The
improvement was only temporary.
I prefer the less subtle answer.
"You were right, House."
So, less time proving
why hubby isn't dead,
more time proving why Kutner is.
Motives for murder.
House, it was a suicide.
The police have
already investigated.
They investigated what they
saw, not what they didn't saw.
Talk to friends, classmates,
pizza delivery guy. Draft Foreman.
He can make calls
through his tears.
No.
Is that, "No, I'm not
calling my boyfriend
"who apparently called my boss
instead of me to say he wasn't coming in"?
'Cause it's really not fair to have
that much subtext in one syllable.
We all want to know
why Kutner did it,
but we're not gonna
waste time chasing ghosts.
You're not remotely curious?
Only why a man who
embraces the rational
is suddenly pursuing
the irrational.
She could have Alpha
1-antitrypsin deficiency.
Run her AAT proteins.
I'd like to be with Eddie.
It's too soon
after your surgery.
You can ask if someone gets
your organs if you die, right?
Even if the donor bank
turned them down?
Individual donors can
bypass the registry,
but there are a
lot of other factors.
Blood type... I've
given him blood.
It's not just... Please.
If I go before him, I want
you to give him my heart.
This isn't over yet.
For me.
But it is for him, isn't it?
Yes.
Remy Hadley. I
also answer to 13.
I sometimes sleep with you.
I know I should have called.
I just need some time.
Alone?
I've worked through a
lot of bad stuff in my life,
always done it solo.
So I should go?
I'm sorry.
Okay.
IT's been trying to close
out Kutner's email account.
Apparently, someone's
still logged on to it.
Wasn't hard to figure out
that his password was "Kutner."
He did what they
tell you not to.
He wasn't murdered.
But his parents were.
And the guy who killed
them is coming up for parole.
He's coming up for parole,
he's not out on parole.
Kutner testified at
every one of his hearings.
Guy wouldn't be the first
to see the clock ticking...
He was killed by his own gun.
Which he bought years ago,
obviously for self-defense.
In the temple, cops
found residue. Right.
A murderer would never try to make
it look like suicide, that'd be unethical.
You haven't asked
about my patient.
You're waiting on
AAT protein results.
Means you checked up
to see that I'm still on it.
You want to transfer the case,
but you won't because you think it's
the only thing that's holding me together.
Well, relax.
Either I'm right or I'm wrong.
We'll know soon enough.
Find what's
killing your patient,
and then I'll find
you another patient.
What happened?
Nurses found her like this.
She broke into the cart,
injected whatever she could grab.
Dumb way to look
worse for Eddie.
She wasn't trying to look worse.
She was trying to kill herself.
She's stable,
but whatever was left of
her liver is definitely shot now,
and there's no change in Eddie.
So, thanks to her idiotic move,
she's dead in 24 hours if
she doesn't get a new liver.
It was selfless. She loves him.
How does that disagree
with what I just said?
Test was negative
for AAT deficiency.
Myelofibrosis fits, but
testing takes at least 48 hours.
We should try a partial
donation from a live donor.
Damage is too severe.
She needs a whole new liver.
No diagnosis, no
liver. No liver, no living.
What do you know?
It is myelofibrosis.
Says so right here.
Who wants to tell Cuddy?
How many times have you
lied to the transplant committee?
Just twice.
How many times has it worked?
I don't quite see
how that's relevant.
Cheese it, it's the coppers.
We're not just gonna leave them
to die while you fixate on Kutner.
Technically, he's
not our patient,
so I'm really only
leaving her to die.
We've already explored
the usual options,
shouldn't we at least
explore unusual ones?
Absolutely. Don't worry, this
is why God gave me two ears.
Kutner would say we should
just come clean with Cuddy.
Wow, if only he
were here to say that.
I'm sure Cuddy would
be bound to fall for the old,
"Hey, the dead guy won't
mind that we're wasting..."
I need an incurable romantic
to talk to an incurable romantic.
Kutner wasn't murdered.
You deduce that by removing your
sunglasses to the strains of a Who song?
Suicide means you could have
helped him, murder lets you off the hook.
Needs a liver. Has a liver.
He can make a partial donation.
The faster he agrees, the
faster she gets to not die.
Partial won't be enough,
she needs a whole liver.
And he'd never
survive the procedure.
Nice symmetry, huh?
He dies on the table, you
give her his whole liver.
If he's gonna do this,
he's gonna do this for love.
Thought he should talk to
someone who spoke the language.
You want me to die on the table?
We don't want you to.
Your wife needs you to.
My heart?
Is still dying.
You have a couple days at most.
But this could buy us
enough time to save her.
When can I say goodbye?
You can't.
If she knew what we were
planning, would she be okay?
She'll resent me.
She'll be alive.
Nothing else matters.
You can't do the transplant.
Only if he said no, but your
urgent hovering means he said yes.
His fingers have nodules. I think
his doctors misdiagnosed him.
Or you sprinkled too much
wishful thinking in your tea.
Obese man with lung cancer. Two
easy explanations for his heart failure.
Nodules could mean something
else, something curable.
Go back to the ER.
My thanks to you
and your cold feet.
What's going on? I'm giving
you a shot at a cool result.
Better yet, a chance to
prove other doctors idiotic.
Except you're wrong.
You figure that out by
taking off your sunglasses
to the strains of a Who song?
The guy who killed
Kutner's parents
died of an aneurysm
two months ago.
Kutner hid from everyone.
You didn't get a chance
to save him. No one did.
Run the test. Find out if you
have a chance to save Eddie.
Bad news.
Love can't save you.
On the other hand,
mold can.
Your heart failure was
caused by a fungal infection
called cardiac blastomycosis.
Started as nodules
in your lungs,
which every doc, except
one, mistook for cancer.
It's very rare, very curable.
I'm starting you
on itraconazole.
But how come I was getting
better without the medicine?
Your emotional state
bumps your catecholamines,
which help raise
your prolactin...
My emotional state?
Three months of treatment, you'll
be back to your buff, chiseled self.
I don't want the treatment.
Do the transplant.
You'd be trading the
certainty that you'll live
for the uncertainty
that she'll live.
I was ready to die anyway.
Now you get to be
nicer to your next wife.
If you won't do it, release me.
And when I get hit by a car
and show up in your morgue,
you can give her my liver then.
You're basically asking
us to commit murder.
I was yesterday, too.
There's a difference when he has
20 years to live instead of two days.
Not really, not legally.
That's your way of
convincing us to do this,
by saying it's no more immoral?
The idiot is gonna do
this with or without us.
This way, we can
protect the organ.
We should be protecting him.
So we strap him to the
bed, wait till his wife dies?
I'm not doing this.
I will.
We've already had
one pointless death.
Eddie? What's going on?
I don't know. He just
came and got me.
Your husband has
a curable disease,
but he wants to die so
he can give you his liver.
Are you okay with that, or would
you rather he take the treatment?
You son of a bitch.
Eddie, don't.
You have to let me do this.
Charlotte, can you hear me?
She spiked a fever. LP shows
her white cells through the roof.
She's infected everywhere.
I should fire you.
I just did what
you failed to do.
Convince Eddie to
live and let his wife die.
Infection means
we have a new clue.
And a full two or three
hours to figure it out.
Sarcoidosis. Hits the
spleen and the liver.
She'd have lung issues.
Scleroderma inflames the tissue.
No skin or GI problems.
What is she hiding?
You don't know that...
Either we have all the
clues and we're idiots
or we don't have all the clues.
Possible exposure.
People, places.
Both.
Bad lie.
Did you really think
the beaches in Hawaii
were just like the
beaches in Rio?
The disease-bearing sand
flies are completely different.
She's never been to Rio.
Who'd you go with?
Why are you doing this?
I don't actually need
to know who it was,
I just need to
know that you went,
so we can know that you
have visceral leishmaniasis.
But since Lancelot there
was ready to die for you,
he might want
the answer to both.
Last year.
It was nobody you knew.
Rio was supposed to be ours.
I got tired of waiting.
I'm so sorry.
Start her on antimony.
Have Cuddy find her a liver.
They were all ready to die.
But for guilt, not love.
You can't feel that
much guilt without love.
New York Mercy's medevacing
a liver. It should be here...
Tell them to turn around.
Charlotte's treatment isn't taking.
We diagnosed it too late.
Everyone's heading
over to Kutner's funeral.
You're welcome to ride with me.
I'm going to stay
with Charlotte.
She bought you some
time to save Eddie,
it'll give her death
some meaning.
No, it won't.
I was wrong about
you. No, you weren't.
You're in pain.
And you're romanticizing. Again.
You worked with him
every day for two years,
and you never saw this coming.
No one saw it coming.
But you see everything coming.
This has never been
about what you missed,
this is about why you missed it.
You're terrified that you're
losing your gift, losing who you are.
And I'm terrified of
what you'd do then.
Unless you feel there's
more to do here to cure me,
don't you have
the funeral to go to?
I'm taking a ride
Off to one side
It is a personal thing
Where? When I can't stand
Up in this cage
I'm not regretting
I don't need a better thing
I'll settle for less
It's another thing for me
I just have to wander
Through this world alone
Stop before you fall
Into the hole that
I have dug here
Rest even as you
Are starting to feel
the way I used to
I don't need a better thing
Just to sound confused
Don't talk about everyone
I am not amused by you
'Cause I'm gonna lose you
Yes, I'm gonna lose you
If I'm gonna lose you
'Cause I'm gonna lose you
Yes, I'm gonna lose you
If I'm gonna lose you
I'll lose you now for good