From the looks of that rock,
I'm guessing you didn't
tell Ethan.
No, I didn't,
and I would appreciate it
if you didn't
mention it again.
Mention what?
I want us to try
to get pregnant again.
I'm proposing opening
a safe injection site
at the hospital.
Preventing deaths would
save the hospital money
in the long run.
Allow drug use
on our premises?
"A PR nightmare"
is how I'd put it.
There's another way.
An unsanctioned site?
But they're illegal.
You could lose your license.
You in?
I'm in.
Did you get any sleep?
Nah, got busy
around midnight
and never let up.
I did a lot of counseling,
though, and set up that
rehab consult.
Great. And I just heard back
from our new hookup
on clean needles.
Get me a Narcan inhaler.
She OD'd. Hang in there.
It's okay. You're okay.
What...
You overdosed.
But you're gonna be all right.
Overdosed...
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
No. Oh, my God...
What's your name?
Val.
Okay, Val.
Let's get you into a bed,
and you know, maybe later,
we can have a talk.
Okay.
All right.
This is why we're here.
You realize I could do this
myself, right?
True, but Dr. Patchefsky
did say IVF is a team effort.
So any negative effects
from the hormones?
Headaches, mood swings?
Are we counting
the growing urge
to pump my teammate
full of hormones?
I hope not.
I'm doing great, babe.
Good.
Maggie, good morning.
I guess.
What's the matter?
My oncologist.
She says I'm not responding
to the radiation the way
she'd hoped.
We have to add a course
of hormone therapy.
Oh, Maggie...
It's fine. I guess
that's how it goes.
Well, I'll call someone in.
You take the day off.
No, really, I'm fine.
It's only one day.
There'll be others.
Yeah... Oh, no.
What's up?
We've got a school bus crash.
How bad?
They need doctors
over there right now.
Dr. Marcel,
Dr. Manning,
I need you to hop
on an ambo
and get to mass cas
MVC school bus.
How many passengers?
Thirty to thirty-five.
I'll get the packs.
Guess I'm gonna be here
for a while.
Keep me posted.
Will do.
Natalie, hey! I need you
over here, guys.
What happened?
We got two kids
in the front seat.
It's gonna be tricky
getting them out.
Why? What's wrong?
A bunch of rebar flew
off this truck,
went through the windows.
Luckily, most of the kids
were in the back.
Help. Help us.
Help us! Please, help!
Okay,
hang on, bud.
We're coming.
Oh, my God.
Help us, please.
Get us out.
Okay.
Getting cold.
I know. We're gonna get you
out of here right now.
Are we good?
Yeah.
You're doing great.
I'll be right back, okay?
Hang in there.
Lieutenant,
a word please.
Henry's got good pulses
in his neck,
but Kate's bleeding
into her belly, fast.
Normally,
I'd cut the bar
in between,
but they're
pinned together
pretty tight.
So what do we do now?
Slide her down
a couple inches,
make some space?
No, she's already shocky
from blood loss.
Moving her could shear
the vessel wide open.
Just let me know
what works for you.
We'll make it happen.
Can you give us a moment?
He's right, there is no
other way to move them.
Yes, there is.
We get more blood
to up their reserves,
then we cut them out together.
What? But we don't know
where the rebar
is in Henry's neck.
One wrong move
and we could tear
into a vessel.
Maybe, but if we slide Kate,
we'll lose her for sure.
Look, you are gambling
a kid's life on a Hail Mary.
Natalie, we got
two kids here.
If there's any chance
of saving them both,
I'm taking it.
All right.
Doctor.
Someone you should
take a look at.
I gotta get to work.
All right.
What's wrong?
He's got a fever, pale,
short of breath.
Hi. I'm a doctor.
I'm Mike.
How long have you
had a fever, Mike?
I don't know.
A few days?
You've got a pretty
significant heart murmur.
It's very likely
you could have something
called endocarditis.
Give me a break, man.
Have you had it before?
Yeah, I've had it.
I got my valve replaced
last year.
I need to take you
to the hospital.
No. I'll just end up
back here.
We can find a way
to treat your addiction.
Forget it. Nothing helps.
We have resources
to help you.
Babe. Please.
Mike, you know better
than anyone.
If we don't fix
your heart valve,
it'll kill you.
Let me take you in.
All right, first wave of kids
are coming in.
Dr. Choi, you're up.
On it.
Alice Winston, 12-year-old
with shortness of breath
and chest trauma.
Respiration's at 24,
heart rate 83, sats 92%.
Hey, Alice, I'm Dr. Choi.
You're gonna be okay.
We're gonna take good care
of you, okay?
All right, let's transfer her
on my count.
All right, nice and easy.
Ready? One, two, three.
Good.
That sounds like it hurts.
Hey, Alice?
Any dizziness, nausea,
blurry vision?
No.
Good, that's good.
Any pain anywhere else?
Alice.
Sweetie, are you okay?
I have a feeling she has
some broken ribs.
Is it bad?
We'll get some
X-rays right now,
but other than
a little heavy breathing
from the stress,
she looks good.
Okay, okay.
Oh, thank God.
Hey, Alice.
I'm gonna give you
a little more medicine
for the pain.
Does that sound okay?
You're a champ.
I'll be back in just a bit.
Hey.
April, Dr. Marcel
is bringing in two traumas.
Be on standby.
Dr. Marcel?
Can someone else do it?
April.
Please, I...
I'm really messed up.
I don't want to,
but I can't stop
thinking about him.
Okay, but whatever
you're feeling, you've got
to get over it.
You hear me?
I know.
Thank you.
Gary.
Thought I recognized you.
Maggie, right?
Mmm-hmm.
Taxotere, Adriamycin, and...
Cytoxan, right?
Yeah! My old chemo regimen.
We know each other
from the infusion center.
Mmm...
So what's going on?
If I remember, you
were having trouble
finding a match
for your bone marrow
transplant.
Took eight months,
but we got one.
A woman,
scheduled for next week.
That's great!
So what happened today?
He passed out.
You have severe anemia
from the leukemia,
and it's giving you
intermittent dysrhythmias.
I'm gonna get you some blood,
and then we're gonna see
how you respond.
Great. Thank you.
Okay.
Excuse me, Dr. Reid.
So, how bad is it?
We need to move
the transplant up
as soon as possible.
Okay, I'll call the donor.
See if we can get her
in today.
I'd see if we can get her in
in the next hour.
Dr. Halstead.
I have assessed your
endocarditis patient,
and I've decided not
to perform
the valve replacement.
But he has plus-four
aortic regurgitation.
He won't survive
without a new one.
But he's already infected
and destroyed two
healthy heart valves.
Every indication is that
he will do so again.
Not if he stops using.
I don't see any evidence
that he will,
and heart valves are
quite costly both in time
and resources.
And there are
too many children
from the bus crash
who require
my attention.
Dr. Latham, I think
beneath the addiction,
Mike may be depressed.
So if we can treat that,
it might push him
in the right direction
so that eventually
we can get him off drugs.
Then the new valve
would be safe.
Dr. Charles.
Dr. Halstead has a patient
who is a heroin addict.
I'd like you
to evaluate him
for surgery.
Oh! Be happy to meet him.
Thank you.
If Dr. Charles clears
your patient, then I will
schedule the procedure.
Thank you.
Hey, um,
you wouldn't have
happened to have come
across this patient
at your friend's
safe injection site,
would you?
I did, and I know
you think it's a bad idea.
It's illegal, buddy.
We're doing
a lot of good there.
Yeah, well,
you're not gonna be
doing any good anywhere
if you lose your license
and go to jail.
We can talk
about that later.
Please, just go talk
to Mike.
Blood's in.
Stay with me, okay?
Just hang in there. Hey.
WOMAN ON POLICE RADIO:
Do you need civilian vehicles
to get out of the way?
There's still time
to change our minds.
No. We're doing this.
Hey. You ready?
Yeah?
Yeah.
Okay, we have to keep
these kids perfectly still.
There's no movement,
shifts, nothing, all right?
All right.
You're doing great.
Let's get them out.
Okay, easy, guys.
You ready?
Nice and easy.
Here we go.
Careful. Slowly.
You all right?
Okay. We're gonna
get you out, okay?
Ready?
Yeah.
Thanks.
I hope you're right
about this.
Open the Hybrid Room.
We're coming straight in.
Need an extra gurney.
How do they look?
Boy's stable.
Girl got three units
in the field, GCS 11,
BP's 80 over palp.
All right, start her
on the MTP,
four plasma, four blood.
Right away.
Let's get two FAST scans.
You're okay, bud.
You're all right.
What are you doing?
Just taking a quick look,
okay, bud?
I can't get a window.
Must be in the kidney.
She's got a ton
of free fluid in there.
What about him?
Rebar got the jugular.
You gotta be kidding.
How bad is it?
We won't know
until we lift him off.
Hell of a move,
bringing him in
like a shish kebab.
We need some Betadine
and a lot of Kerlex.
Dr. Manning.
Kate? Hey, Kate,
stay with me.
Is she okay?
She's unconscious.
We need to move them.
All right, buddy.
It's time to get you off
this thing. You ready?
Am I gonna die?
No, hey, no.
No, you've got
a whole hospital of people
who just want
to take care of you, okay?
Okay.
All right. My count.
One, two, go.
That hurts.
You're doing great, Henry.
Keep him steady.
You're okay, buddy.
You're okay.
Little more.
Okay, he's off. Gauze.
Get me some gauze.
Okay, yep,
he's still bleeding.
All right, let's get him up
to CT, see how bad it is.
All right, if it's just
the vein, he could be okay.
It's gonna be okay.
All right? Okay.
All right, Dr. Marcel,
let's scrub in. We've got
a lot of work ahead of us.
Hey, Doc.
What do you think?
Well, it's tricky, you know,
because active addiction
tends to mask
whatever underlying pathology
might be present.
Sure.
I mean, he could very well
be self-medicating, but what?
Is it depression,
is it bipolar,
or, you know...
Yeah, understood.
And we can figure that out
later, but right now,
a diagnosis is what's
gonna save his life.
It's not quite
that simple, though.
You understand his heart
is a ticking time bomb.
Every minute we let go by
increases the chances
he's gonna die right here
in front of us.
I wanna help him, too,
but in order for the surgery
to be successful,
he's gotta be willing
to get clean,
and right now,
I'm just not seeing
a whole lot of evidence
that he wants to do that.
We're doing
everything we can.
The doctors are still
examining the victims.
Any word on our son,
Henry Chase?
We heard they brought him
in with Kate Lawson.
She's our daughter.
They're best friends.
Henry is being evaluated
in radiology, and Kate
is still in the OR.
They're still operating?
Oh, my God.
Could you just let us know
when they're out?
We just wanna see them.
Yes, of course.
I'll let you know
as soon as I hear something.
Thank you.
Dr. Reid.
Did you schedule
the transplant?
Oh, Gary's donor
has the flu.
Her temp is 100.3.
But that shouldn't affect
her bone marrow.
The cutoff is 99.9.
But Gary has a rare HLA type.
No one else in the system
is a match.
Well, hopefully the donor
will get better soon.
The longer we wait, the more
unstable his rhythm gets.
It's only half a degree.
Can't we just
make an exception?
I'm sorry, but no.
We can't.
Maggie, we got two more
coming in from the bus.
Okay.
Hey, what's wrong?
The girl with
the broken ribs, Alice.
Her pain's under control,
but her breathing
just keeps getting worse.
Anything abnormal
in her labs?
No. X-rays showed
a few mild opacities,
but nothing that
should be causing this.
Mmm.
Yeah, hi.
Has Alice had
a fever recently?
Runny nose, sore throat?
No. No.
Any history of asthma
or pneumonia?
No, nothing.
No.
Her sats are down to 87.
Want me to put on the mask?
Yeah, and call
for a nebulizer treatment,
too, just in case.
Anything that could
cause any sort of
breathing trouble at all?
Family history,
asbestos exposure, mold?
She did smoke cigarettes
last year.
But only
for a little while.
We caught her
and made her quit.
Is that true?
Yeah.
Either way,
this really isn't
what we normally see
from a smoking
related illness.
So we need to keep looking.
Right.
If that was our daughter,
her smoking history's
the first thing I'd be
telling the doctor.
I'm sure they're just
embarrassed.
I mean, they probably
feel like they've got it
under control.
Yeah, I guess.
It just makes me wonder
if there's anything else
they're not telling us.
Dr. Halstead.
He's tachycardic in a-fib.
Doc, my chest
is killing me.
Want me to push Cardizem?
His pressure's dropping.
Milligram of morphine
and Versed, synchronize
and charge paddles to 50.
Mike, tear on your valve
must be extending
into the electrical system
of your heart.
I need to reset your rhythm.
Okay, let's go.
Charged to 50.
Clear.
Rhythm's back.
Start him on
an esmolol drip.
They giving me a new valve?
I'm working on it.
It's just taking
some time.
Hey, Doc.
Whatever it takes. Please.
I don't want to live
like this anymore.
Hey, you seeing this?
He is running out of time
and needs our help.
And believe me, Will.
I wanna help.
Then do it.
Do what?
You want me to just,
like, make something up?
Look, I appreciate that
the clock is ticking here.
So if you want me to try
and talk to Dr. Latham...
And tell him what?
You know what?
Forget it.
All right.
Kidney's free.
Oh, man.
Got the lateral cortex,
and three centimeters
into the hilum.
Maybe we should salvage.
Nah, there's
too much damage.
We're gonna have
to take out the whole thing.
Sure hope we're not
wasting our time here.
Dr. Marcel,
there's an emergency
in the CT scanner.
It's your other patient
from the bus.
I'll handle
the boxed kidney, okay?
Go check on the boy.
Sats are down to 81.
His hematoma's expanding.
He must've started to bleed.
It's compressing his airway,
let's get a tube in fast.
Let's get etomidate and sux.
Getting a lot of resistance.
His sats are down to 72.
It's not going through.
Sixty-eight,
give me a cric kit.
No, we're not gonna put
another hole in his neck.
Crockett.
Got it.
Okay.
He's still actively bleeding.
Damn it.
I'll call the OR.
Dr. Halstead.
I'm puzzled by this order.
Yeah?
Your patient was written
for antidepressants,
but it's not
from psychiatry,
it's from you.
Yeah, right,
I totally forgot
to tell you,
Dr. Charles was
gonna write it,
but he got pulled off
on an emergency.
Yeah, with the bus crash
it's been just crazy
down here.
Ah...
Of course.
Very well, then. I'll let
the OR know that Mr. Monroe
will be coming up immediately.
Thank you, Dr. Latham.
Five...
Hey, Maggie.
Hey.
Can I get you something?
I just forgot to ask
if you're still
with that guy.
Vincristine... Leucovorin...
Ben.
And yes, I am.
Seems like a good guy.
Anyway, I just wanted
to say thanks.
I know you've been
fighting for me.
Well, you can thank me
after the transplant.
I'm not done yet.
I'm sure you're not,
but you know how this goes.
One day your numbers are bad,
and you're crushed.
Then they get good again,
and you can just
beat the world.
Up and down, over and over.
But this time,
it feels different.
I don't know if I've got
another "up" left in me.
Gary.
You don't talk like that.
Uh-uh.
You may not know this
about me,
but when I put my mind
to something,
I get it done.
So you just stick with me.
Hey.
Where am I gonna go?
That's right.
Doris.
Hmm?
How do Gary's labs look?
Lower than when he got here.
Hmm.
Come here.
What?
I'm gonna draw
your blood.
What?
She can't breathe!
Sats are down to 74.
We need to intubate.
Fifteen of etomidate,
seventy of sux.
Alice, sweetie,
I'm gonna have to sedate you
so we can put a tube in
to help you breathe, okay?
Wait, wait, wait, you mean
the machine is gonna
breathe for her?
She can't do it
anymore on her own.
We don't have a choice.
Meds are in.
There you go.
Alice?
I'm in.
Sats up to 83.
Why is this happening?
I don't know.
Order a new round of tests.
We're gonna figure this out.
I need to get some air.
How'd she do?
The surgery went well,
but then again,
eight units of blood,
so she may end up
with deficits, or not
even wake up at all.
Just gotta wait and see.
I assure you,
as soon as we
know any answers,
I will let you know.
Is that Dr. Marcel?
Uh...
Why didn't you
separate Henry and Kate
before bringing them in?
My brother's a doctor.
He says you never move
people together like that.
Kate was in bad shape.
We didn't have a choice.
What do you mean?
Well, keeping them together
was the only way to save her.
She was gonna die.
Wait, so you endangered
our son?
How could you?
I didn't have a choice.
Not if they both could have
a chance to live.
No, you did have a choice.
And you have no right
to make it.
I understand. I do.
And I'll speak with you
after your son's surgery.
Okay?
If you'll excuse me.
I tried to keep them calm.
Yeah.
No, they're right.
I'll come back to answer
their questions as soon as
Henry's carotid is tied off.
What? You're gonna
tie it off?
But he wouldn't have normal
blood flow to his brain
for the rest of his life.
Why not reconstruct?
Reconstruction is long
and risky. He's already
lost a lot of blood.
So?
So, it makes him
a poor candidate
for prolonged anesthesia.
Well, I know what it means.
I just don't understand
why you're suddenly
trying to play it safe.
Because I've already done
enough damage today.
I'm not gonna do any more.
Crockett. Hey.
That boy deserves
to come out of this with
the best outcome possible.
So you need to go in there
and do everything that you can
to make sure that happens.
Okay?
What's going on here?
I'm checking
the staff to see
if there's a donor
for Gary.
Maggie, we've got an ED
full of injured children.
Our staff
is needed in there.
I know.
And that's why I'm going
as fast as I can.
Maggie, we can't have this.
But if we...
If we don't find a donor
for him today, he's gonna die.
After battling cancer
for a year, every day,
and then to have
a cure right there,
right in his hands,
and then to have it
taken away?
I've got a hospital
full of patients
who need care.
Everybody.
Back to work.
Excuse me.
My little boy's in there.
He was on the school bus.
And I hope someone
would do this for him.
Where do you want me?
Right here.
What the hell
is wrong with you?
What did you do?
Dr. Charles,
I already lost an addict
that I helped get hooked
on opioids. I'm not
about to lose another.
You let this get
way too personal, Will.
Never a good idea.
For God's sakes,
isn't it personal?
You lost a brother to drugs.
What's that got to do
with anything?
You've been there.
Okay, you should know
that we can't
endlessly deliberate
over every patient.
Enough!
You have a lot of nerve
bringing up my little brother.
But since you have,
not a day goes by
when I don't miss him
or wonder what I could
have done differently,
but what I never do
is bring that to work
and let it affect
my professional judgment.
Okay, how we doing?
Carotid's mobilized.
Ready to tie.
Okay,
silk tie on a pass.
Dr. Marcel.
Open a patch. We're switching
to reconstruction.
You sure? He's pretty
coagulopathic.
I'm sure.
Adjusting
the upper clamp.
He's bradying down. Crockett.
Give me a three-inch shunt.
Dr. Marcel, if we just
tie the carotid off...
Give me the shunt.
Come on, come on. Shunt.
Shunt.
Rate's down to 42.
Thirty-six.
Crockett.
I'm in.
Rate's back up, 63.
Let's get started
on this patch.
Mr. Walker, there's no vaping
allowed in the hospital.
Oh, sorry.
I didn't know.
Let me ask you something.
Does your daughter vape?
What? No.
Well, I mean, she did,
but just to get her off
the cigarettes.
You know.
Doctor?
What's going on?
She's been vaping.
Mind if I look at this?
Sure?
I don't think you're gonna
find anything. She stopped
vaping six months ago.
She's 12 years old.
Do you have any idea
how dangerous that is?
It's better than smoking.
That causes cancer.
She only did it
for three weeks. She did
it long enough to quit.
I mean,
it's totally safe.
Vaping's not addictive
like cigarettes are.
Oh, my God.
Are these yours?
No.
She must've gotten them
from school or
from her friends.
We had no idea.
Oh, my God.
Let's wait and see
what the last few tests show.
We'll be back
in a little bit.
Ronnie? Any luck?
No.
You do realize you found
almost 40 potential donors?
We usually don't get
that many in a month.
Wait.
It's a match.
We got a match.
Are you sure?
Maggie...
This is the one.
Oh, my God.
Thank you so much, Ronnie.
We've got a match!
Clear.
Oh, my God. Gary?
Doris, I'll take over.
Come on, Gary.
Charging to 200.
We'll get you through this.
Clear.
Come on. Let's go!
Charge to 200!
Come on, Gary.
I'm sorry, Maggie.
Charge it!
Maggie.
No.
Time of death is 17:36.
It'll be okay,
little man.
Dr. Marcel,
I'm sorry about before.
Thanks for saving our son.
Yeah, of course.
How's Kate?
We don't know yet.
Crockett.
Kate's waking up.
Kate, sweetie,
do you remember
where you first saw me?
The bus?
Yeah, good. Really good.
Can you wiggle your toes
for me, sweetheart?
That's good.
Can you squeeze
my finger? Tight.
Like that?
Yeah, just like that.
Hi.
Did you get
the other tests back?
I'm afraid they
were all negative.
So, it was the vaping.
We call it EVALI.
E-cigarette
or vaping-associated
lung injury.
She must've
already had it,
but the bus accident
pushed her over the edge.
So how long
till she gets better?
I wish I could tell you,
but we don't know
if she will.
What do you mean?
This condition
is so new,
we're still
figuring it out.
Your daughter may begin
to breathe again on her own,
but she may not.
Never?
It's possible.
But the truth is,
some people
don't survive.
Oh, my God.
I'm very sorry.
Those poor parents.
And Alice.
Yeah.
All day long, I just...
I had a feeling
I wasn't being
told the truth.
Hey, I'm sorry
about today.
And for bringing up
your brother.
But you know what?
It was all for this.
I just, um,
caught his girlfriend
trying to pass that to him.
Right now? Here?
Yeah.
What...
Oh, my God.
It's a long road, Will.
No shortcuts.
Hey.
Quite a day.
Yep.
Risky call.
But you did it.
Yeah, well,
didn't do it alone.
Crockett.
You were so adamant
this morning on the bus.
I've never seen you
like that before.
What was going on?
Nothing.
It was a choice.
A choice no one else
would've made.
Why did you?
Because no one should have
to lose a child.
No, of course not,
but it was still...
I'll see you in the morning,
Dr. Manning.
Hey, Maggie?
Oh, hey.
I heard about Gary.
I'm so sorry.
And I'm sorry for making
a difficult day worse.
Oh...
I've got something
I want to show you.
Come with me.
What's this?
We were able
to match some
of the donors you found
with other patients waiting
on the transplant list.
All these people?
Yeah. And there are
more on the way.
You saved a lot
of lives today, Maggie.
Hey. Ready
to do it again?
Listen, Sean, I'm sorry,
but I don't think
I can do this anymore.
What...
What's going on?
Just not cut out for it.
Will, we have all
had these moments.
Doctor, there's someone
here to see you.
Hey.
Hi.
I met you this morning.
When I was foaming
on the ground.
Yeah, I remember.
Um...
I'm new here, and...
This place is a godsend.
Anyway, I just wanted
to say thanks
for saving my life.
I'm gonna try
to turn things around.
Good.
I'm glad to hear that.
Yeah.
Okay.
Ooh...
Hey, Uncle Dan.
Practice always end
this late? When do you
do your homework, man?
I'm a psych major.
You can basically make it
all up as you go.
That's funny.
You, uh...
You hungry?
Is that a question?
Come with me.
All right.
So, you checking up on me?
Eh...
No. Not really.
Maybe. Sort of.
I don't know.
All right,
don't worry.
I'm still clean.
The team checks
my pee every month.
I loved my dad,
but I'm not gonna
end up like him.
You know how proud I am
of you, right?
Yeah.
Do you?
Good.