No, I'm not saying
that you made it up.
I believe
you heard something.
Do you?
'Cause it really
doesn't sound like it.
I'm going to
take the next one.
No. Dad, no. Come.
We have rats.
Or we don't.
We've had two exterminators
go through everything.
"We?"
Yes, "we," Dad.
We are cohabitating,
and we do have rats.
Oh.
We'll talk about this later.
Yes, we will.
How about that snow, huh?
Springtime in Chicago.
I know what I heard,
okay?
We just have to
get an exterminator
who knows what he's doing.
Hey, Maggie?
Mmm-hmm.
I want to FaceTime
with Owen before his nap.
I set an alarm on my phone
for an hour from now,
but if I get swamped,
can you remind me?
Sure.
He was already asleep
when I got home last night
and still conked out
when I left this morning.
I've hardly
seen him lately.
Don't worry.
I'll remind you.
It hurts like hell, I know.
We're gonna get you upstairs
and the surgeon
will fix the holes
the bullet left
in your intestines.
They'll take good care of you.
Dr. Choi, incoming.
Trauma Two's open.
Elliot Gallagher, 17.
Got beat up at school.
Multiple facial trauma,
chest wall contusions,
GCS of 15
with a history of
loss of consciousness.
Elliot, I'm Dr. Choi.
Can you tell us what happened?
Those guys, they caught me.
Make sure his parents
are notified.
Let's transfer on my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
Elliot, can you take
a deep breath for me?
Again.
Does that hurt?
No.
Good breath sounds.
Let's get him off the board
and get a chest X-ray.
Right away.
Lungs are up and
no broken ribs.
Looks like
they're just bruised.
Let's give him 50
of fentanyl for pain.
On it.
Turn your head
side to side.
Chin to chest.
Good. C-spine's clear.
Elliot,
follow the light for me.
Your right eye doesn't look
the same as your left.
I think the orbit's fractured.
Your nose is also broken.
I'm going to
quickly realign it.
Pain meds should
be working by now.
Hope they caught
the boys who did this.
I deserved it.
You gotta castrate me.
What?
I want you to castrate me.
Please.
Are his ankles swollen?
Just look down and check.
Damn it. Yeah, all right.
I'm on my way.
Everything all right?
Not really.
That was my brother.
He's with my dad.
The man's stubborn
beyond all belief.
He's had mitral valve regurge
for, like, the last 10 years.
Man, faulty valves
are tricky.
Yeah, and I don't like
what Jay's describing.
I gotta get
to the L station.
Why doesn't your brother
bring him in?
Dad hates doctors.
Did I mention he's stubborn?
Well, don't you
have a car?
I sold it.
Hey, look, man,
waiting for the L train's
just gonna slow you down.
Why don't you take mine?
Actually,
I'd like to take you.
I'll get my coat.
All right.
I think about sex
all the time.
You're 17.
It's really not
that unusual.
Sex is for procreation.
That's all.
Huh. So, how did you
come to that understanding?
My parents.
The reason those
guys beat me up,
I, uh, was climbing
on a dumpster
by the girls' gym,
and was looking in
a window to the shower.
That sounds to me like
grounds for disciplinary
action, maybe,
but, I mean, not a beating.
I mean,
certainly not castration.
Blonde girls. It's, uh...
It's blonde girls.
I follow them.
There's this one girl,
Lacey.
She's blonde.
I sit behind her in trig.
One day, I...
I cut this off.
She didn't notice.
I'm afraid of
what I'm going to do.
I was looking up
castration online.
They can do it with drugs.
That's what I want.
Chemical castration.
I don't want to hurt her!
Or anyone.
Elliot is very troubled.
Poor kid is just consumed
with sexual thoughts.
Aren't most kids
his age?
Yeah, but he's been raised
to believe that sex is wrong
unless it's for procreation.
And repressing
his natural urges
is triggering
aggressive impulses,
which he's
struggling to control.
Aggressive?
He fetishizes blondes.
Stalks them.
We're talking about
a sexual predator?
Not a psychopath.
I mean, he has a conscience.
I mean, I think
he could definitely
benefit from therapy,
but I'm not
ruling out those meds.
Chemical castration,
really?
It's temporary, Ethan.
Raping somebody isn't.
We would need
the parents' consent.
Dr. Manning, a three-year-old
with a bilateral
lower extremity paresis
and gingival lesions
in Treatment Four.
Hey, you want to give
me a hand with this?
Sure.
Hi, I'm Dr. Manning,
and this is Mr. Clarke,
a medical student.
Hi.
He's gonna be assisting me.
I'm Amelia.
This is my son, Troy.
Hi, Troy. I hear
you're not feeling well.
Troy is speech-delayed.
He only says a few words.
Okay.
I'm gonna check you out.
Okay, buddy?
When did this
start happening?
A couple weeks ago,
he woke up limping.
When it kept getting worse,
I took him in for X-rays,
but they didn't
show anything.
The doctor wanted
him to rest for a week,
but it isn't
getting any better.
They've been okay at work,
but I gotta get Troy well.
I understand.
This morning,
his gums started bleeding.
Hey, let me check
your chompers, bud.
Ulcerations.
Hmm.
He looks quite thin.
Um...
Has his appetite
been affected?
He's always been
a picky eater.
I've got one like that, too.
All right, we'll get
a copy of his X-rays.
The leg pain and weakness
could be coming
from a lot of things,
so we'll get a CAT scan
of his spine and
some blood work,
and, hopefully,
we'll get some answers.
All right.
Chocky.
Not now, sweetie, okay?
Chocky, now.
He wants some
chocolate milk.
I think we have some of
that in the cafeteria.
I'll have some sent in.
We'll check back
in a little while.
All right,
here are the rest of them.
Why all the dolls?
As part of
my psych residency,
I have to teach
high school kids
the responsibilities
of having a baby,
so hopefully, they'll
exercise a little caution.
The sound circuit
is adapted to
convert audio data
into analog audio
output at the speaker.
Oh, man, too bad you can't
do that with a real baby.
Okay, can I see it?
Mm-hmm.
Peripheral port is coupled
to the micro-controller
and connects to
the host computer?
Uh-huh. So I can monitor
how the kids are doing.
It's ridiculous.
What? Why?
These are cool.
No, I have no
maternal instincts.
I have no connection
to babies.
I have no intention
of having one.
I'm right there with you.
Good luck.
Robin?
Oh, hey.
What's looking good?
I can't decide.
This is where you grew up,
huh?
Yep. Played a lot of
ball on this street.
Everybody knew everybody.
All the grandmas
would sit on
the front porches.
They were like the original
neighborhood watch.
Up there,
Mrs. Riley hated noise.
She used to throw
a pot of boiling
water out at us.
Caught Jay on
the foot one time.
A little different
than the Gold Coast, huh?
It's nice.
Hey, Pop.
What are you doing here?
I called him.
Wasted trip.
I don't need you.
Are you kidding me?
You missed two days of work,
and you never miss work.
Pop, this is Connor Rhodes.
He's another doc at Med.
Told you
I don't need this.
Come on.
You can barely talk.
I'm gonna take
medical advice
from someone
who wet the bed
till he was nine?
Never changes.
I gotta get back
to the district.
Thanks, Jay.
Don't let the door
hit you on the way out.
Mr. Halstead,
I'm seeing some things
that tell me that your heart
isn't working very well.
Your fingertips are purple,
you're having
a hard time breathing,
and your energy
seems depleted.
Had this heart thing forever.
It's never been a problem.
Do you mind if
I have a listen?
If it'll get you two
off my ass.
Apical holosystolic murmur
and the lungs are wet.
In English?
It means that
your heart has been
compensating for
the faulty valve
for a very long time,
and now it can't keep up,
so fluid is backing up
into your lungs.
It literally means
you're drowning
in your own blood.
We need to get you
to the hospital.
I'll call an ambulance.
Like hell you will.
I'll be damned if
I'll have the neighbors
see me hauled out of here
in an ambulance.
Mr. Halstead...
No.
If we're going, I'm driving.
No, no, we'll drive.
I got it!
I'll call the ambulance.
No!
Just move your asses.
April, I got a patient walking
into the ambulance entrance.
Can you get
a wheelchair ready?
Walking in?
Uh-huh.
It's Dr. Halstead's dad.
Hey, you're going
to Treatment Six.
Yep.
Problems getting
an ambulance?
No, problem
with the patient.
I don't need that.
I got it, I got it.
Okay.
Easy on the bed.
Damn it, I got it.
All right,
let's get him hooked up.
Will, you wanna get
him on oxygen?
Yep. Pop...
Yeah?
On a scale of one to 10,
how bad is the pain?
I've had gas that hurt worse.
All right, T-wave inversions,
ST depressions.
It looks like he's
having an NSTEMI.
Let's give him 81
milligrams of aspirin
and a dose of nasal nitro.
Let's get cardiac labs,
CBC, CMP, coags,
and a chest X-ray.
He's gonna need a formal echo,
but in the meantime,
let's get a quick look
at the heart
with the ultrasound.
Clear.
Bilateral pleural
effusion and congestion.
Yeah. You see here?
Mitral valve is wide open
and the LV is dilated.
Mr. Halstead,
it's just like we thought.
Your heart is
working way too hard
to compensate
for your bad valve.
First time I've ever heard
of hard work
being a bad thing.
You got a fix?
We will.
We're gonna get
you an angiogram,
and it'll give us
a full picture of your heart,
and then we're
gonna figure out a plan.
Let's get him up
to the cath lab.
Don't worry, Pop.
We can beat this.
Who the hell's worried?
All right, let's go.
Will?
My dad, his heart.
He needs a cath.
I'm so sorry.
Let me know how it goes.
Natalie?
Head lac in Treatment Two.
I'll shoot you the chart.
And don't forget
to FaceTime Owen
as soon as you're out, okay?
Oh, thank you.
The three-year-old.
Test results are back.
CT was clean, blood work
indicates mild anemia.
Nothing to explain
the limping or the lesions.
Maybe we're dealing
with lead poisoning
or some sort of tox?
Yeah, um, let's do
a tox workup and
look for heavy metals,
and get a babygram
while you're at it.
Okay. It could
also be abuse.
Let's not go there yet.
Can I help you?
It's our son, Elliot.
They said he was in a fight.
We got here as quick
as we could.
We got a call
from his school.
Okay, Dr. Choi.
He'll take you to him.
Dr. Choi, Stan Gallagher.
This is my wife, Debbie.
What happened?
Elliot got into
an altercation at school
and suffered
an orbital blowout fracture.
The eye surgeons want
to get him to surgery.
He's right here.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my poor baby.
Elliot,
who did this to you?
He's still a little
groggy from the pain meds.
Why don't we let him
rest while we talk?
The bracelets
you're wearing have a sensor
which registers when you feed,
bathe, or diaper the baby.
If you shake the baby
to stop its crying,
it will shut down
and register as being abused.
Are you a real doctor?
Sometimes I wonder.
Uh...
Anyways, recent
studies have shown
that talking, reading,
and singing to babies
is crucial for
early brain development,
80% of which occurs
during the first
three years of life.
These dolls record
the amount of time
you spend doing
these activities,
so, obviously,
the more, the better.
Need anything, Dr. Reese?
Uh, no, I'm fine,
Mr. Sexton.
Any questions?
I don't get it.
We're supposed to
be talking to a doll?
Or reading or singing.
Mm-hmm.
Any other questions?
What operating system
are the dolls on?
I don't know, and really,
why is that relevant?
I have PE today.
What should I do
with the doll then?
That is a problem you
will have to deal with.
The point of this is
to understand the impact
having a baby would
have on your life.
I will see you all
at the end of the day
to check on your dolls.
So, a kid got beat up.
What does he need
a psychiatrist for?
Well, Elliot was
caught peeping on girls
in the shower at school.
Oh, my God.
Wait till I get him home.
But much more troubling
are some violent impulses
that, so far,
he hasn't acted upon.
And there is
something we can do.
Elliot wants us to
give him a medication
that would turn
off his testosterone.
This would significantly
decrease his sex drive
and make it
much easier for him
to control these impulses.
But we do need your
permission to do it.
"Turn off his testosterone?"
What exactly are you
talking about?
The medical term is
"chemical castration."
What?
It's completely reversible.
The idea would be
to combine it with
traditional therapy
with the hope of ultimately
weaning him off
the medication.
No. No way.
Elliot could very well
be on the verge of acting out
on some very
disturbing impulses,
including rape.
He would never do
anything like that.
You people are sick.
Again, this was
your son's idea.
Elliot is torn up
about this.
He's scared
he may not be
able to stop himself.
This is ridiculous.
Fix his eye,
and we're taking him home.
Where's your dad?
The restroom.
He shouldn't be
up after his cath.
He couldn't use a bedpan?
Practically
threw it at my head.
I'm here if you need me.
I won't.
So, Mr. Halstead,
the results of
your cardiac cath
show that your heart
has been under
stress for so long
from the mitral
valve regurgitation
that it's basically giving up.
This is why I told you
to get it checked regularly.
We knew about the regurge,
we could've gotten
ahead of this.
Yeah, so what?
I'll fix it now.
Well, there's another
issue, unfortunately.
Your left anterior
descending artery
is 80% blocked.
Now that is
the largest artery.
It supplies half
the heart with blood.
The question is, am I done?
I can do a surgical
replacement of the valve,
and while I'm in there,
do a bypass for
the blocked artery.
Are you talking
open heart surgery?
It would involve
opening your chest, yes.
Now, if you wanted
to go non-surgical,
a cardiologist
could place a clip
on the mitral valve
to try and
control the regurge,
and do angioplasty
to open up the blocked artery.
Do you have
a good cardiologist?
We do.
But I strongly recommend
that you let me operate.
The long-term results
of surgery are much better.
Mmm-hmm. Exactly.
I'm going non-surgical.
Pop...
Hey, if you don't like it,
you don't have to be here.
Fine.
I'll set it up.
Yeah.
Hey.
Now, you know I should be
cracking his chest, right?
So, why did you give in?
Hey, you're the one who gave
him the non-surgical option.
No, I laid out
his choices, Will.
I pushed for the surgery.
Not hard enough.
You're his son.
You should be the one
trying to convince him.
He won't listen to me!
My dad considers me
something of a disappointment.
Oh, yeah, he didn't even
want me to go to college.
Says a real man
goes right to work.
He doesn't give a damn
what I have to say.
So why don't you get Jay
to try to talk to him?
It won't help.
No, Jay and him
have their own history.
Everything's
coming back normal.
Maybe we're dealing
with some sort of
weird vasculitis.
Henoch-Schonlein purpura
or Kawasaki disease?
Or possibly
infectious disease,
or rickettsia like
Rocky Mountain Fever.
Chocky, now!
It's okay, baby.
We'll get you some chocky.
Uh, the chocolate milk
never came?
No, the cafeteria was out,
and he won't drink the plain.
Well, you can't fault a kid
for knowing what he likes.
Is there
something else that he likes?
Graham crackers.
When I get home at night,
all he wants
is chocolate milk
and Graham crackers.
It's hard not to
give in when it's late
and I'm tired.
Let me go see
what I can find.
Uh,
you said he's picky at night.
Is he better during the day?
I'm pretty sure he
eats other things.
Pretty sure?
He has a couple sitters.
The neighbor's kid,
the woman upstairs.
It's possible
they're not as firm
as they ought to be.
I can't afford day care.
I understand. Um...
I'm going to send a nurse
in to draw blood
for one more test.
Mr. and Mrs. Gallagher,
I need to get Elliot
up to pre-op holding.
The eye surgeon will be
calling for him any minute.
We'll be in the
waiting room.
I'm guessing your
parents told you
they wouldn't approve
the chemical castration.
No.
But my mom read me
Thessalonians 4:3.
"God's will is
for you to be holy,
"so stay away from sexual sin
and immorality."
Both Dr. Charles and I tried,
but since you're
still a minor...
Yeah, I figured.
All right, whatever.
Look, I'll talk
to Dr. Charles
and see if we can come up
with some other options.
All right,
numbers look good.
Breathing great.
Feel like I could
pitch nine innings.
It's what every team wants.
A 60-something starter
with a bum ticker.
At least nobody had
to cut my chest
open to fix it.
Admit it, kid, I was right.
You got that fancy degree,
but I'm still the one
calling the shots.
I didn't say this course
of treatment wouldn't work.
I was more concerned
with the long term.
That right?
'Cause to me, it looks like
you're back-pedaling so much,
you're gonna start sweating.
Oh, believe me,
that is the last
you'll hear about it.
Yeah.
Well, since you made me
miss the end of the game,
let's see if I can
find some highlights.
I guess I should
start with an apology...
And for
the foreseeable future...
The cleanest, whitest white...
Yeah.
Hey, Dr. Charles,
you got a second?
Uh...
Yeah, kind of.
Okay.
I'm worried about Robin.
She's not acting like herself.
Hmm.
She is convinced
that there's rats in my condo,
but I haven't seen
them or heard them,
and no exterminator
can find them.
Rats can be pretty clever.
Not that clever.
And, aside from that,
lately, there are times
when I find Robin just
staring off into space.
Well, I mean,
that's not that odd.
I mean,
I do that all the time.
It must be a family trait.
I think it's more
than that.
How so?
Like I said, she's
not acting like herself.
I just feel like there's
something off with her.
Well, I mean,
there is that new
living situation.
Cohabitation can
be awful stressful.
Dr. Charles,
I hope you realize
I wouldn't have come here
if I didn't think
this was important.
And you know what?
I appreciate that,
but I was supposed to be
on a conference call,
like, two minutes ago,
so can we
pick this up later?
Yeah, you bet.
Well, thank you
for your time.
Thank you.
Did you find anything?
We did.
Based on Troy's limited diet,
we checked his
vitamin C levels.
The results show
a significant deficiency.
Well below normal.
Troy has scurvy. It's what's
causing his symptoms.
I don't understand. Scurvy?
Isn't that something
sailors used to get?
It was, historically,
but anybody with
prolonged dietary
deficiencies is susceptible.
Well, how is that possible?
We were surprised, too.
It's not something we see.
It's been all but eradicated
in developed countries,
because it's
easily preventable
with a balanced diet.
You mean he's sick
because of what he eats?
More like what
he doesn't eat.
It's a parent's job,
Ms. Bohlen,
to make sure their children
get nutritious foods.
Excuse me?
This never
should have happened.
You should have been
monitoring Troy's diet.
That's easy for you to say.
You know nothing
about my life.
I work two jobs
to support my son.
I am gone from 6:00 am
to eight at night.
You have no right to judge.
I would do anything
to protect him.
Excuse me.
Please explain
the course of treatment.
Mr. Halstead,
I'm Sharon Goodwin,
Executive Director
of Patient and
Medical Services.
I thought
I should say hello.
Well, how you doing?
Well, better question
is how are you doing?
Other than a lack of
sports channels in this place,
I'm feeling pretty all right.
You know,
we think quite highly
of your son around here.
Kid's got you snowed, huh?
You look a little pale.
Are you sure
you're feeling okay?
I'm fine.
Page Dr. Rhodes.
I'm concerned
about your breathing.
I'm going to
increase your oxygen.
What happened?
He's throwing runs of PVCs.
Give me the ultrasound.
How are you feeling,
Mr. Halstead?
Like I just told her,
I'm feeling fine.
I don't think
you're doing as well
as you say you are.
Why don't we have
a look, huh?
Half the mitral
valve clip came off.
It's flopping around.
We need to get you to surgery.
Can you fix it?
Like before?
No, we can't.
We need to operate,
and quickly.
If the other half comes loose,
the clip could end up
in your brain
or somewhere else
you definitely don't want it.
Wait.
This is not up for discussion,
Mr. Halstead.
No, just...
Just don't tell Will.
I don't want to have
to hear him crowing.
We won't, but I'm afraid
he's going to find out anyway.
Yeah, okay.
Sorry, hold on.
Hey, what's up?
I can't find my wallet.
Oh.
Let me get it.
Uh...
My coffee, her yogurt.
Come on, let's sit down.
I think someone stole it.
Oh, my God, now I'm going to
have to cancel my credit cards
and get a new
driver's license.
That it?
Oh, thank God.
The old side pocket.
Is everything okay, honey?
Damn it,
Dad, I know that look.
You're trying to shrink me.
We're just talking.
We're having some coffee...
No, we're not just talking.
You never just talk to me.
It is always
a psych evaluation.
Robin, come on.
Just because you
are a head case, Dad,
does not mean that I am.
Stop looking for things
that aren't there.
Thank you for
your participation.
Thank you. Uh, Marla,
would you hang back a sec?
Uh, sure.
Your score,
very impressive.
Thanks.
You fed it regularly
at two-hour intervals
and verbally interacted
a total of six hours.
You said more is better.
Uh...
How did you have time
to do anything else?
Multi-tasking.
You hacked your doll.
What? No.
Okay, just because I am 26,
don't think I am some
old fool.
This score is impossible.
Marla.
Yeah, I hacked it.
Don't worry, Mr. Halstead.
We're going to get
that mitral valve fixed.
Damn.
The kid was right.
Not so much a kid anymore,
is he?
No.
Did you know
he put himself
through college?
I told him...
Told him it was
a waste of time,
and damned if I was
going to pay for it.
Well, I'm sure
you're very proud of him.
That doesn't even
begin to say it.
He made something
of his life.
He's a better man
than I am.
I don't think he
feels that way, sir.
And I'm sure that he wouldn't
want you to either.
We need to get started,
Mr. Halstead. Are you ready?
Yeah.
I spoke to the surgeon.
Everything went great.
Once the dressing is off,
your vision should
be back to normal.
I'll be back in
a bit to check on you.
Hey.
I went off
on that boy's mom.
Oh?
But it was really about me.
I wasn't mad at her.
I was mad at myself.
Am I a horrible mother?
Yes, you are.
Nat, you're just
having working mom's guilt.
Relax, man,
Dad's too stubborn to die.
Any word?
Not yet.
I heard you were there
when he went back
into failure.
Thanks for jumping in.
Well, it's good to
flex the nursing muscles
every now and then.
He did great.
Brand new mitral valve
is fully functioning.
Shouldn't give him
anymore problems.
Told you.
Thanks, man.
You got it.
Nice work, Dr. Rhodes.
Thank you.
I'm gonna head
back to the house,
'cause he's probably
gonna need some stuff.
All right?
See you, Jay.
Yeah.
Thanks, Connor.
If my dad hadn't
pulled through...
Yeah.
I gotta say, man,
what you guys have,
it's pretty great.
Are you serious?
All we do is fight.
Yeah, well, me and my dad,
we barely even talk.
That doesn't
sound too bad to me.
Take my word for it, Will.
You got a
good thing going.
Elliot?
Elliot, what are you doing?
She looked cold.
Step away from her.
Now.
Elliot!
Elliot! Elliot,
open the door.
Page security!
Elliot!
I need a gurney
with soft restraints
and some ABD pads.
Get me some ice and 50 mics
fentanyl IV now,
and page Urology.
Just relax.
Elliot, Elliot.
Just relax, buddy.
The procedure to
repair the testicles
is complicated,
but the urologist
is optimistic.
How did this happen?
What did we do?
You know, in my experience,
there's actually
very little to be gained
from looking backwards.
The important
thing to focus on is,
what do you do now?
Hey.
I just saw Natalie.
She told me your dad's
in the hospital.
Yeah,
mitral valve and blockage.
He should be awake now.
I'm headed up.
Will, I'm glad
he's doing well,
but how come I had to hear it
from Natalie and not you?
Yeah, sorry.
It's been a little crazy.
You had time to tell her.
Listen, why don't you
come with me?
If Dad's up for it,
I'll introduce you.
No, just let me
know how he's doing.
I will.
Yeah.
Am I interrupting?
Actually,
I'm glad you're here.
I have something to show you.
Proof that we have got rats.
I picked up some
of their droppings.
I don't understand.
They were here.
Weren't they?
Honey, I'm saying this
as a dad, not a shrink.
I would just feel
a whole lot better
if we could get somebody
to, um, you know,
take a look at you.
What do you say?
Okay.
So, did you flunk her?
No, I couldn't.
She was overwhelmed.
She's taking all
these AP courses
and doing all that
extracurricular stuff
that you gotta do to
get into a good college.
Man, I hear you.
Math club?
A lot of better ways
to spend my time.
Mmm-hmm.
And the thing
is I did it, too.
I hacked my doll when
I was in high school
'cause I was overwhelmed.
Nice.
I mean, to tell you
the truth, Noah,
the real reason I
don't wanna have kids
is it's too hard.
How is anybody
supposed to do it all?
No, you'd be good at it.
Why do you say that?
I watched you.
You're like that girl,
cagey, resourceful.
You can't hack
a real baby, Noah.
Yeah, you're right,
all right.
And what do you mean,
you watched me?
You know.
Hey.
I heard your dad's
doing well.
Yeah, I'm sure he's making
the nurses miserable.
They can handle it.
I better get up there.
Okay.
We're waiting for a bed,
then we'll transfer
Troy upstairs.
We're gonna get you
feeling better soon,
okay, buddy?
It takes a few weeks
to get back to normal,
but his prognosis is good.
He should have
a full recovery.
You waiting
for a thank you?
One of our social workers
is gonna come in
and talk to you
about nutrition,
help you with Troy's diet.
And I'm sorry.
I know it isn't easy
holding everything together.
And, to tell you the truth,
every day,
I worry if I'm doing
right by my kid, so...
Okay.
Thanks.
All right.
Hang in there, champ.
Hey, Pop, how you feeling?
Like I took one
on the chin.
You kind of did.
Maybe now, if something's
cooked in bacon grease,
you'll think twice?
You know, in fact,
we need to have a talk
about all the junk food
you eat
and the beer.
What?
I mean it. When we get home,
there are gonna be
some changes.
Thanks, kid.
Yeah.
I love you.
Love you, too.
Who is that?
Can you say hi?
Hi.
Yes.
Oh...