Previously on The Good Doctor:
Can we just hold each other
for a little bit?
Deal with your crap
before this is who you really become.
I am sorry for making you meet me
after hours like this.
I'm always available for my patients.
Come on in.
Your dad's been diagnosed
with pancreatic cancer.
You're not like other people.
You're like a spoiled little baby.
Shaun? You okay?
We have to be at the airport
at 7 a.m.
When you're taking
the first flight out of Casper,
you don't need to be
90 minutes early.
Mm.
Or maybe you do.
You wanna talk about last night?
I think we should.
Why?
Because you were in
a pretty bad place,
- which is totally understand...
- I feel better now, thank you.
I'm glad I could help you.
But I also think
we shouldn't tell anyone
I stayed here.
People might get the wrong idea.
Okay.
We slept together.
Did you use protection?
No, we did not...
have sex. We just slept...
together.
Held each other.
I was upset and Lea comforted me.
Lying...
in bed with her, it felt...
different than it does with Carly.
Well, maybe that's why
you invited Lea
instead of Carly in the first place.
Mm.
- Lea and I are just friends.
- Yeah, she's made that very clear.
Sometimes you learn
more about someone
by what they do than what they say.
Because who knows what she wants?
But more importantly, what do you want?
I don't know.
Well, you better figure it out soon.
Sex or no sex,
the wheels are in motion and...
someone's about to get run over.
They had Mallomars. Let's roll.
Shaun, you're back already?
Why wouldn't I be?
I like being here.
Shaun.
I'm really sorry
to hear about your father.
- How are you doing?
- He died.
And the seat was very uncomfortable
on the flight, so I couldn't sleep.
And they only had the salty peanuts,
and not the pretzels I like.
Yeah, life sucks.
We need a doctor!
We were mountain biking and she fell
down a rocky slide. Her leg...
We'll need an X-ray and an MRI.
Let's also get you something stronger
than this ice pack for the pain.
No. They gave me Vicodin
when I had my wisdom teeth pulled,
I was sick two days.
- We have other painkillers.
- Really, I'm fine.
Look, I made it through childbirth
without drugs,
- I can make it through this.
- That hurts less than childbirth?
Tender and bloated.
We should get you admitted,
get an X-ray.
That's all right.
All I need are laxatives.
Intestinal blockage could be fatal
if we don't treat it.
Please, I'm unemployed
and I don't have insurance.
How about this?
We skip the X-ray, give you the meds,
but in exchange,
you agree to stay here
till you've had a bowel movement,
and we have peace of mind.
Deal.
Shaun, you're back.
Hello, Carly. It's good to see you.
I missed you.
Morgan and I have a patient
with a comminuted leg fracture.
We need a rush on a CBC
and coagulation panel.
Shaun, I'm sorry about your dad.
Why didn't you return
my calls or texts?
I was... very busy.
You had time to text me.
I wasn't sure what to say.
Shaun, I know you don't always
understand people's feelings...
but a part of you had to understand
ignoring me would be hurtful.
I'm not sure what to say now.
My patient is getting an MRI.
I need to get back to them.
Are you going to take the samples?
Hey.
PTSD?
It's an interesting topic.
Organizing notes
for a potential case report.
Nice. Look forward to reading it.
I started seeing a therapist.
Good.
- I hope you find it helpful.
- Mm.
She thinks I, uh... I might have PTSD.
Sounds a bit excessive.
You've definitely dealt
with some childhood trauma.
You think she's right?
I think doctors make
the worst patients.
Hmm.
The best patients are the ones
who ask a lot of questions,
and keep an open mind.
We gave him laxatives,
and right away tried to leave.
Ended up passing
out and vomiting.
I'm fine, I can take
care of this at home.
Okay, we need to get him to Radiology.
We need an abdominal CT, stat.
No, you can't keep me against my will.
Wherever you need to be, it can wait.
- You need help now.
- What are you transporting?
Painful constipation,
nervous agitation, refusing scans.
You're obviously packing drugs.
The balloons have either created
a complete obstruction,
or one of them burst.
Please, I just wanna go home.
- Luca, we're doctors, not cops.
- He definitely sounds like a cop.
We won't call the police, I promise.
Whatever is wrong, let us help you.
How's Carly?
She wasn't upset about you ghosting her
- while you were with Lea in Wyoming?
- She said it was hurtful.
You got off easy.
Is this your weird way
of breaking up with Carly
to get with Lea?
- I don't want to break up with Carly.
- But you do wanna get with Lea.
- I didn't say that.
- Not out loud.
And you're making a big mistake.
Carly's smart, pretty,
and the fact she's willing
to deal with your stuff
means you should thank whatever God
you pray to that you ever met her.
While Lea is, well, a flake.
She's not a flake.
She showed up on your doorstep without
even a heads-up she was coming back.
Then she needed to move out,
but then she moves in.
Not to mention the
"Let's get drunk on tequila
and teach you how to kiss,
but I just wanna be friends" nonsense.
She's...
not a flake.
There is traumatic avulsion
of the ligaments.
She's going to need surgery.
We hammer a long rod
through the medullary canal
to hold the two ends of the break
together.
It's a broken leg.
Can't you just put a cast on it
or something?
You'll be asleep. You won't feel anything.
I lied...
about the Vicodin making me sick.
My husband doesn't know.
I'm an opioid addict.
I've been clean for 10 years,
but one dose could send me
right back.
Do whatever you need to do
to fix my leg,
but you can't use any narcotics.
Not even an epidural?
Strongest thing
she'll let us give her is Tylenol.
Ketamine. What about ketamine?
It's non-narcotic
and can create a dissociative effect.
It's mind-altering
and potentially addictive.
Hypnosis has been shown to be effective.
Only when used in conjunction
with narcotics.
Studies say playing
the patient's favorite music
can help manage pain
in certain surgeries.
Yeah. We hammer
a nine-inch rod through her tibia,
but she's listening
to the soundtrack from Hamilton.
- I said, "certain surgeries."
- Okay. That's the answer.
- Music?
- A different surgery.
Some other way
of putting her leg back together.
An external fixation?
We put two pins
through the proximal tibia.
Another two in the distal end
of the bone beyond the fractures.
Healing will take much longer,
and there's an increased
risk of infection
- and permanent deformity and...
- And small pins
are less painful than a huge nail.
I'll get her prepped.
I got laid off.
I needed money
and this was just a one-time thing,
but it was a mistake.
A stupid mistake.
This works best if you don't talk.
Our plan is to attach a metal frame
with pins into your leg.
It'll stabilize the fractures
and we can do it
without narcotic anaesthesia.
I know she's worried
about an allergic reaction,
but aren't there any other drugs
you can use?
Given your wife's medical history,
this is the best strategy.
Don't worry, sweetie.
Remember,
I'm strong like Wonder Woman.
Right?
There's over 50 balloons
lodged near the ileocecal junction.
They'll need to be surgically removed,
and we need to alert Vice-Narcotics.
No. The only reason
he agreed to treatment
is because we promised
we wouldn't do that.
I didn't promise that.
Neither did Dr. Melendez.
We don't call the police
on overdose victims or addicts.
He's got probably two kilos
of what I'm sure is heroin
in his gut.
He's not an addict, he's a dealer.
I know you feel for this guy,
but hospital policy is clear.
Take a few more deep breaths for us.
Just two more to go.
Kerry, we need you to keep your leg still.
- BP is 190 over 110.
- Push IV beta blockers.
- Wait, no!
- No, they're not narcotics.
We need to reduce the pressure.
Oh, my God.
Back to 150 over 80.
- Kerry, how are we doing?
- Better.
We'll get this last one in
and you'll be good to go.
No, you promised me.
Yeah, you value honesty
and morality over all else.
If you leave this hospital now,
you will die.
I'll take my chances.
Do you know what'll happen
when one of those balloons bursts?
You'll start feeling weak, get cold.
Soon you'll have secretions
filling your lungs and airway.
You'll try to scream for help,
but nothing'll come out.
Can you get the release paperwork?
I'll be back in a few minutes.
Luca, I understand
where you're coming from.
You're a doctor.
Last job I had, I was a busboy.
I grew up in a trailer.
A bunch of them, actually.
My mother wasn't the type
to save for a rainy day...
but we never gave up.
Even when you think you're alone,
you're not.
I want to help you.
You just have to give me
a little more time.
One hour.
If I can't figure out
how to treat you
and keep you out of jail,
you can walk out the door.
One hour, and then I'm gone.
Okay.
You'll have discomfort
the next few weeks,
but all you need right now is rest
and you should be able to...
- Mommy!
- Hey.
Oh, my gosh. That's so cool.
Everyone says their spouse
is the strongest person they know...
but I have actual proof now.
Told you. Wonder Woman.
This is absurd.
If this was a tumor,
we'd take it out and toss it.
- This time it just happens to be drugs.
- Yeah, because cancer is not a felony.
You can't toss out the drugs
with medical waste.
He's not a gangster
or a hardened criminal.
He's just a scared guy
trying to survive.
You're assuming anything
he's told you is true. And even if it is,
not everyone who needs money
becomes a drug mule.
You can't imagine what it's like
to grow up in that kind of poverty.
Shouldn't you be judging this guy
the harshest?
You made it out just fine
without breaking the law.
That's not exactly true.
My mother used to go on these trips.
I would come home from school
and she'd be gone.
Sometimes hours, sometimes days.
I didn't have any money.
So when I needed supplies
and food from the store,
I would sneak them away
in a backpack.
One day, the bag broke,
and all of the soup and oatmeal
that I had stolen
fell out in front of a security guard.
And she looked at me,
at my face, at my clothes.
And helped me pick them up
and let me go with a warning.
If she hadn't given me a break,
I wouldn't be standing here as a doctor,
discussing this with you.
Maybe there's a way to save Luca
without ruining his life
or breaking policy.
Shaun.
You need the elevator,
use the elevator.
What am I doing wrong?
I never know where I stand with you.
One minute, we're sharing
deep personal fears with each other,
and the next, you're running away
because you can't stand to touch me.
Be honest,
is there anything going on with Lea
that you're not telling me?
- Say something, Shaun.
- It's different.
Like you, Carly.
When I'm around you...
I want to be impressive to you.
I don't feel like
I have to impress Lea,
like I do you.
We will have to keep
whatever medical waste we collect
during your surgery in the lab
for testing,
but we will discharge you before
the pathology report comes back.
At which point, we'll be obligated
to alert the police.
How do I know you're not gonna call
the cops after you put me to sleep?
You'd be a moron not to trust
Dr. Browne at this point.
She's gone way beyond the call
to save your ass.
- Okay.
- Say thank you.
Thank you.
Dr. Murphy, how about
you head home for the night?
We still need to monitor Kerry.
And it's easier for me
to avoid Carly here
than it is for me
to avoid Lea at home.
Okay. I'm only gonna respond
to the first objection.
You've had a long week
and it's important you get rest.
Morgan will take point.
How did you know your wife
was the right woman for you?
Personal advice?
I thought that
was Dr. Glassman's domain.
Dr. Glassman is divorced.
He seems happy with his marriage now,
but I have no way
of knowing for sure.
You're better than him.
For this.
I knew I wanted to be with Isabel
the first time we spoke,
freshman year biology class,
and I have not wavered in that resolve
in the 27 years since.
But how did you know?
It was a feeling I had
in the pit of my stomach
every time I was around her.
I felt...
- Nervous?
- Excited.
It's a cliché,
but my heart sped up
every time I saw her.
Still does.
Not quite in the same way,
but...
Now, if you don't mind,
I need to get home to that woman.
Hey, you.
- How was the first day back?
- Confusing.
Problem with a patient or Carly?
If you don't wanna talk about it,
we can just hang.
- Let's just hang.
- Copy that.
Commencing a hang.
Um...
Shaun?
Hmm?
- What's up?
- This will just take a few seconds.
- Hello.
- It didn't work.
Kerry's leg is swelling up.
I think she has compartment syndrome.
You need to get back here.
We'll have to do the surgery
we've been trying to avoid.
We'll have to make multiple incisions
to relieve the pressure,
then replace the external frame
with an internal nail.
If we don't act soon...
you could be facing amputation.
Okay.
- You'll need to be sedated.
- No. I can take it.
Kerry, you had a blood pressure spike
during the fixation procedure.
Without anaesthesia,
you could have a hypertensive crisis,
a risk of stroke, or heart attack.
Post-op, we can help you
manage the dosing. And if you relapse,
- we have counsellors that...
- No!
I remember waking up
all those mornings, cold and alone,
wondering if I could ever
be happy again.
If I deserved to be happy.
Any amount of pain
is better than losing everything again.
My husband, my daughter...
How long can you keep secrets
from the people you love
before they stop
being the people you love?
Every relationship has secrets.
But this, it doesn't have to be
one of them.
Drug addiction is a disease.
You have nothing to be ashamed of.
It happens because of the choices
you make.
When you have lost everything,
but you still manage to find someone
who makes you wanna get up
and live another day,
you do whatever you can
to hold on to them...
even if it means burying
a piece of yourself in the process.
If we can't convince her
to change her mind,
- maybe her husband can?
- Impracticality isn't cause
for breaking doctor-patient
confidentiality.
This isn't impractical,
it's irrational and barbaric.
We're not permitted
to reveal any secrets to the husband,
but we can tell him that.
Last one.
- What's wrong?
- It's too adherent to the intestinal wall.
We could use Potts Scissors
to dissect it free.
Let's give it a try. Nurse?
Your idea,
only fair you do the honors.
Check it for perforations.
- It's intact.
- Vitals are stable.
Take the specimen container to the lab.
Dr. Browne, you're leading closure.
There's been some complications.
We need to perform
an additional surgery.
- What do you need to do?
- I can't tell you.
I'm unable to go into further detail,
it violates your wife's confidentiality.
Confidentiality?
Haven't you been telling me
everything?
Again, I'm unable to go
into further detail...
Hey.
- Hey.
- What's going on?
Why can't the doctors talk to me?
Kerry, obviously there's something
going on you don't want me to know.
- Are you dying?
- No!
No, it's... It's nothing like that.
Hey.
Then what?
Whatever it is,
I want to be able to help.
Please.
I'm an opioid addict.
I've been clean for a decade, but...
That's why I never take painkillers,
and that's why
I can't let them use anaesthesia.
Why didn't you ever tell me?
You don't know
the kind of person that I was...
who the drugs turned me into.
I tried quitting so many times,
but it never stuck,
until you.
Meeting you saved me.
But...
if I relapse,
I know I'll drive you away.
Hey. Hey.
How could you ever think
I'll stop loving you?
The woman who knows the lyrics
to every Boyz Il Men song?
The woman who rushes home to watch
those stupid home makeover shows live?
The woman I'm raising
our daughter with?
The woman who will steal from you.
The woman who will lie to you.
- Who will hurt you.
- No.
The woman you won't be able to trust.
No.
Just do what the doctors tell you.
Take the meds.
I will be there for you,
no matter what happens.
I love you...
and I know you mean that.
But I'm not as strong
as you think I am.
- Baby...
- I just can't.
I'm so sorry.
We'll start prepping you for surgery.
"I like your laugh.
I like your smile.
I don't usually look at eyes,
but I think yours are pretty.
I like your breasts."
You can keep going if you want to.
"I like spending time with you.
I like that you are kind.
I like that you are patient.
I like that you're my girlfriend."
Are you going to break up with me?
No. I am not planning
on breaking up with you.
We had a fight. Couples fight.
But...
I'm worried, Shaun.
I'm flattered
that you want to impress me,
but that is not worth anything
if you feel like you can't talk to me.
You're right.
I have to tell you everything.
I got...
very upset...
in Wyoming.
Lea came in...
to comfort me, and we hugged,
and laid down on the bed.
And we fell asleep hugging.
That's everything that happened.
We struggled with lying together
for weeks,
and you...
did it in one night with Lea?
Yes.
But she's a close friend
- and she wanted to be there for me.
- Please, just stop talking.
Shaun, I... I just...
I need some space.
I can't be around you right now.
Shaun?
I wanted to be honest. Carly said
she wanted me to talk to her.
Lea said not to tell what happened.
Lea was right.
- Take a breath, sit...
- I can't.
I have surgery in a few minutes,
and...
I can't focus, and I feel sick,
- and is everyone going to leave me?
- What? What are you talking about?
My dad didn't want me.
My mom chose him over me.
Carly now hates me.
- Lea will get tired.
- Shaun.
- You'll get sick of me.
- What?
I do everything wrong.
Everyone will go away!
- Look at me.
- I make people upset!
Shaun! Oh, my God.
I make them angry!
I make them hate me!
Shaun, look at me, look at me.
Right here. Look at me here.
Don't ever say that about yourself.
Don't ever say that!
You hear me?
You're gonna get through this.
You're gonna go to surgery
and get this done.
- How?
Because you're an extraordinary
doctor, that's how.
And that's what you do.
That's what you do.
Hey, hey, hey. Hey.
I could not be more proud of you.
You hear that?
And I could never get sick of you.
You're not getting rid of me, pal,
okay?
I'm right here.
I'm right over here.
Okay? I gotcha.
I'm going to be late to surgery.
Can you let me go now?
Yeah, okay.
- Okay.
Numbing cream applied.
Are you ready?
We were able to remove
all the balloons,
so you should be out of here
in 24 hours.
It'll likely take another 48 hours
to get the contents tested.
The lab's very busy.
I know I've been a pain in the ass.
I've just got used to people
screwing me over.
You're the first person
that's made me feel...
I don't know, seen.
Maybe I'll find a way
to pay it forward, right?
Reamer's in the intramedullary canal.
This will make space
for inserting the nail.
- You're doing great, Kerry.
- Inserting into canal.
Here comes the nail. You ready?
- BP's spiking.
- Push beta blockers.
Hang in there.
Two-twenty over 170.
She's having a tachyarrhythmia.
Screw it,
we have to push fentanyl.
- Nurse, help Dr. Murphy.
- No.
It's helping distract her.
- You sure, Dr. Murphy?
- Yes. Please hurry.
It was a good day.
It must be very gratifying,
saving lives.
I think I might have done
a little more than that today. I...
I think I might have changed one.
Last time we met,
you mentioned that your mother
would frequently berate you
when you were young.
What kind of things would she say?
Do we have to get into that
right now?
Can't I just have a good day?
You know, enjoy feeling okay
for once?
Claire, I believe you've fallen
into destructive patterns
precisely to avoid confronting
your feelings about your mother,
her death.
Feelings that need to be confronted
if you hope to get better.
They're reviewing the security video.
Someone faked a seizure,
staff responded,
and another person
broke into the storage locker.
Do you think Luca...
The only thing missing
was his specimen.
Is someone questioning him?
Luca's gone.
- What will the police do?
- Nothing.
We have a fake name
and the knowledge
someone stole balloons
with unknown content.
♪ If I weigh in ♪
♪ You'll give me a reason to say it ♪
She definitely is a Wonder Woman.
You were right the first time.
She's totally irrational,
needlessly endangered her life.
But I understand why.
♪ To these motions ♪
♪ Scattered with our words
never spoken ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ All the circles that we move in ♪
My mother used to say
I'd end up like her.
Putting my faith in the wrong people,
getting taken advantage of.
That no one
would ever truly love me, except her.
There are worse qualities in this world
than trying to see the best in people.
If you're a good person...
every now and again,
you're gonna feel like an idiot.
And today, you were wrong.
And I am still grateful
that I work with you.
♪ Dreadful silence ♪
Thank you.
♪ Waiting for the moment to break it ♪
♪ I've been slipping ♪
♪ But I think that I'm going to make it ♪
Have you had enough space yet?
♪ I lost you in the smoke ♪
♪ And I've tried patience ♪
♪ But we've just overgrown ♪
Shaun, do you remember
the first time we met?
♪ Ooh ♪
I was checking on a biopsy
to see if the tumor margins
were in the artery walls.
Yeah.
And you said,
if I didn't do it right then,
you would toss a rock
through my window.
Yes.
I thought it was cute
how much you cared.
And when you started working in Path,
I realized...
this guy may be the most
genuine person I have ever known.
You told me the truth.
That is a good thing.
It's why I like you.
It's why I don't wanna lose
what we have.
♪ Ooh ♪
You hurt me.
And...
I worry something like that
could happen again.
♪ That we move in ♪
♪ Remind me of the love ♪
I wanna be with you, Shaun.
But I don't know how this works
if you're still living with Lea.
♪ Then why are we still suffering? ♪
You...
want me not to live with Lea?
♪ Ooh ♪
I know that's a lot to ask.
And if it's too much...
I understand.
♪ I thought love was true ♪
♪ But loneliness ♪
You don't have to answer right away.
♪ Love's been running out
Maybe ♪
Take some time.
♪ I'll find solitude without you ♪
♪ All the circles ♪
♪ That we move in ♪
♪ Remind me of the love we've wasted ♪
♪ If we're searching for the same thing ♪
Okay.
♪ Then why are we still suffering? ♪
Okay?
I want to be with you.
♪ Ooh ♪♪
I love you, Carly.