On an operating table,
a person is at his most
vulnerable, naked, exposed.
I do not need another sister.
Get out.
I mean, she's a lying liar.
I would know if my mother
were pregnant when I was five.
My mother was not
pregnant when I was five.
Get out.
She's, like, psycho,
like a stalker.
I'm being stalked. Alex,
this is criminal. I mean, you...
What's your problem?
Get out! I'm naked here!
Okay, so what? I've seen it
before. No big deal. I'm in crisis.
Okay, fine.
Your junk is spectacular.
Jo is a very lucky girl.
Can we get back to me now?
Why are you making that face?
Mer, I realize that I said I
would take over as your person.
Maybe that means I
have to buy your tampons
and act like your husband's
hair is special and crap.
But I have a very important
presentation to make to the board today
to get a job, which I need
because I got fired by Dr. Butthole!
I have been practicing all
night. I am sleep-deprived.
I need to shower.
Alone. And focus.
You didn't even
hear what I said.
No. And I don't care.
The new cardio chief thinks
she's my biological sister.
She what? Wait.
What? That's insane.
Thank you.
He's in the shower,
and she's in the bathroom
with him while he's in the shower.
So, go in there with them.
No! I am not going in there.
You're the girlfriend.
No. Yeah, I am, but I'm not.
They're this little
team together.
They are war
buddies, and I don't fit.
And then they look at
me... Well, she looks at me
like I'm just the stupid,
naked girl in Alex's bed.
So go be the stupid,
naked girl in Alex's shower.
I am a doctor.
I am a surgeon. I
deserve respect.
You're a girl in her pajamas with
her ear to the door of a bathroom.
How much respect can
anyone give you right now?
She stole my Alex.
You know what? I
miss Cristina Yang.
When Cristina Yang was
here, nobody stole my Alex.
Oh, my God. You're
scared of Meredith Grey.
No, I'm not. Are you? No.
Hey.
Hi, Dr. Grey.
Tell Alex I'll be downstairs.
And if anybody
asks you, I am sick.
Skin is not a very tough
armor. It's soft, easily broken.
Okay, I'm only here
to give a speech
on residual limb
health, and that is it.
That is it.
Yeah, I got to pull back, okay?
We have a kid. Arizona
is starting a fellowship.
We're trying to
have another kid.
I am stretched out far too thin.
I completely understand.
I said no already.
I know that. You're just gonna
meet a couple guys. Come on.
Navy SEALs, Green
Berets, Army Rangers.
Wounded warriors from the
most badass specialized ops forces
in the U.S. Military.
But you're too busy to help
our nation's heroes, so...
I do not like you.
Then I directed the RFA needle
to where the blood
supply entered
the abnormal
parabiotic tissue mass.
To interrupt the blood
flow to the abnormal fetus.
Yes. Then I removed
excess amniotic fluid.
Nice. And then she
delivered full-term?
She did,
months after I completed the
operation that I'm telling you about.
Why are you not taking notes?
Oh. Sorry. I thought we
were just, you know, talking.
And I thought you
were my fellow.
I am. Completely.
No, I'm so excited
to be your fellow.
I just need a little
time to get up to speed,
you know, like four...
Three weeks.
Yeah, 'cause I have
a lot of cases on my...
Dr. Robbins, for the
purposes of this fellowship,
we are not peers.
And four weeks is 10% of
the average gestational age.
In that amount of time,
a fetus's lungs become
a fully-functioning organ.
Everything in utero
happens at hyper speed.
And the sooner you get
up to that speed, the better.
Get a notepad.
Avery, I've got a
backlog of some cases.
Amy's doing a
great job, but there's
some stuff I got
to get on top of.
So, you need help?
I need you to reschedule
this meeting for tonight.
No.
Oh. Are we rescheduling
the meeting? If so, thank God,
because Callie and I have
an appointment tonight,
and apparently, I've
already started my fellowship.
We are not
rescheduling the meeting.
Tomorrow work for you?
No, tomorrow's bad. Thursday?
Listen to me speak, all right?
We are voting on a new
member of the board.
It's happening
tonight. Understood?
Derek!
Derek, why is there
suddenly an order
for carbamazepine in
Eric Schneider's chart?
He needed a good
anti-convulsant.
Mmm-hmm. And I had already
written him one for valproic acid.
You can't go around
writing orders on my patients.
I'm doing my job.
No, you are doing my job.
I am chief of neurosurgery.
If you have a problem with that,
you should take it
up with the board.
Until then, I will call
you when I need you.
What happened to the two
diverting loop ileostomies I had today?
You're welcome.
I rearranged your cases so
you had the easiest day possible.
You are going up against
Karev, so I figured you'd want
plenty of time to practice
your board presentation.
I don't need to practice. I need
my schedule back the way it was.
You sure, though?
Karev's pretty tight with
some board members.
So am I.
Well, Meredith Grey was in the
bathroom with Karev this morning.
Well, not that tight.
That's what I'm saying.
Look, Edwards...
I am going to walk in
there and tell the truth.
I deserve this.
And if any one of them has
the misguided impression
that there is any choice
at all in this matter,
I will set that person
on the righteous path
before he or she can
reveal him or herself
as a moron.
Oh. Pileup on I-5.
Trauma coming in.
Hey, why are they paging
me? Isn't Grey on the pit today?
She's sick.
If my mother were
pregnant, I would have known.
Adoption agency made a mistake?
And randomly put the name
"Ellis Grey" on a birth certificate?
I don't think so. Pierce
has got to want something.
Maybe she thinks
there's money to inherit.
Oh. The only thing you inherit
in this family is Alzheimer's.
Whoa. Dark.
Good one, though, huh? Yeah.
She's not my sister.
You know who you
should ask about this?
The guy who was banging
your mom back then.
I'm not asking Richard Webber.
All I'm saying is, he's
got skin in the game.
Disgusting.
He's the only living person
who would know if it's true.
Richard Webber is like
a second father to me,
and if he knew that I had
a sister, he would tell me.
Paged to the ER?
Yes. You?
Mmm-hmm.
Sounds big.
I told her last night.
Oh.
How'd it go?
Could have gone better.
Give me some room,
please. Everyone...
What the hell is this?
What's going on?
37-year-old male
rear-ended a lumber truck.
Anyone who is not
treating this patient,
please move out of the way.
Hey! You heard the woman.
This is not a spectacle
for your amusement.
Holy...
Cool! Edwards!
I'm sorry.
Get a close-up! What?
No way!
Is that really a branch?
We need to get this man on
his back in less than 60 seconds.
Got to work faster.
One more inch to the
right, he'd be D.O.A.
How you want to proceed?
Ultrasound's negative
for fluid around the heart,
so I would do a laparotomy.
Yeah?
His airway is compromised.
He needs a chest
tube and intubation now.
Yeah, we're almost
done here, okay?
It'll be safer on his
back. No, there's no time.
I'll have to go in
nasally. 7-0 ET Tube?
Here you go.
Charlie, I hate
to tell you this,
but your day is actually
about to get a little worse.
Hold the work!
Hold on, Charlie.
Hold on. Almost
there. All right.
Okay. Go ahead.
Okay, push 100
of propofol, please.
Pushing.
22 to go.
Well done, Doctor. Sorry?
I said, "Very good!"
Uh, okay. He's clear.
On his back on my count.
One, two, and three.
You want to give me a
robot leg, like the Terminator?
Robotic, more like the
Six Million Dollar Man.
Uh, actually, it costs
a little more than that.
But the project is fully funded,
all expenses paid.
The leg will be free.
A free $6 million robot leg?
Listen. I've been through
three prosthetic legs.
Each one hurt
more than the last.
Why is this so...
Well, the leg is
entirely painless.
Free, pain-free robot leg?
Sounds made up.
It was made up, by Dr. Torres.
It is cutting-edge technology.
Dr. Torres is a genius.
You'll be amazed at this...
Okay, let's just slow
down for a minute.
We still have to run
a number of tests
to make sure you're even
a candidate for the study.
But, again, the
program is fully funded.
Unbelievable.
Major Hunt was right.
He's been going
on and on about you.
Yeah, I bet.
I told him how busy
I am. He knows.
He knows my plate is
full. He just doesn't care.
I am an attending with an
entire service of my own.
Herman and I have shared
dozens of patients before.
Oh, and now he's just bringing
this guy to my lab, right?
Like I'm gonna say no to a guy
who gave up his leg for our country.
She has me reviewing
journals and doing skills labs.
I have a case report
that's due by 4:00.
I'm sorry. Excuse me. I have a
neuroblastoma to remove at 4:00.
Wait.
Is this your way of telling
me that you're canceling
our meeting with the
surrogacy agency tonight?
What? No! No. I
will figure that out.
Okay. I just...
Say something to help me.
You own a hospital. You
are raising a beautiful girl.
You save babies. You're
gonna save more, right?
You can do this, too.
If anyone can, you can.
Oh.
Oh, okay.
Um, listen, I will meet you at the
agency with a smile on my face.
And we will get
ourselves a new baby.
A.B.C.'s intact.
I need to assess his GCS.
If you'd be quiet,
he's trying to talk now.
Sir, can you tell me your
name? What's your name?
Steve. Forget your
helmet today, Steve?
Ahh, it hurts.
I'm giving you
something for the pain.
You might start
to feel sleepy now.
It's a depressed skull fracture.
It is pretty deep.
We're gonna need a CT.
And because of the
position, probably an angio.
I can make that decision if
you'll give me room to look.
Amy, I don't think
he's gonna make it,
and it's gonna get
ugly, so let me do it.
Ah. Because only
you can save him now.
Screw you. I've got him.
Maybe you can both take
him, like a team, or a family.
I have him. Kepner, you'll
assist. Let's take him up to CT.
The African outreach
program has given 34 kids
excellent outcomes and a
chance they never would have had.
And it gave me something, too.
Starting that program gave
me a sense of ownership
and a level of passion that
I didn't know I could have.
I have this passion
for this hospital.
I look forward to... Mer. Huh?
Yeah, it's great.
You're gonna vote on this.
I don't want to blow this.
And it's Bailey.
Bailey did deliver my
baby and save my life.
What have you ever done?
Why aren't you
at your own house,
drinking and having
bitch baby tears
about your fake sister
with your husband?
Derek doesn't know.
He doesn't know?
I can't talk to him right now.
Come on. He gave
up the job in DC.
He's staying, and
you're still mad?
You won. No.
I never asked him to stay.
This wasn't a compromise.
I didn't win. He
forfeited, so we both lost.
So you're not talking to him?
He's walking around
like he's a martyr,
waiting for me to be
grateful. I am not grateful.
My career is just
as important as his.
I'm the sun. I'm the sun.
And he can go suck it!
I'm the sun.
All right. We're done.
Hey!
You can sit here and get
drunk and then vomit and cry,
and I can never get any
prep for my presentation done,
or we can do
something about this.
You want to do
something about this?
It's so light.
It's a 100% titanium
body and 13 sensors.
But before we can get
you in a leg like this,
we need your muscles and
nerves to interface with the sensors.
So, this
electromyogram will show
spikes when your
muscles contract
and then go flat
when they rest, okay?
All right. Go ahead
and flex for me, Jeff.
When this is done,
I get to keep it?
Well, it's all funded,
including follow-up, so...
Yes.
Sorry. I know how that sounds.
It's just, all I wanted was
to be a Ranger, you know?
I still dream about
it all the time.
Pack on my back,
running, my team.
Then I wake up
and get out of bed.
I try to stand, and
I forget about it.
So, you know, when
you say "free robot leg,"
I think I'm still dreaming
of running with the guys.
Jeff, are you still flexing?
Yeah.
Can I take a
picture of it? Yeah.
My mom is gonna freak.
Jeff, flex harder for me.
What?
I should be seeing readings.
What's going on?
Uh, we're just having
trouble with the EMG.
No, no. It's not the EMG.
Jeff, I'm...
Dr. Torres, can I talk
to you for a moment?
Excuse us, Jeff.
That was inappropriate.
Inappropriate?
You were about to
reject him from the study.
Yes. You saw those readings.
Look, the way his
amputation was performed,
there's no way this will work.
Okay, it's a crappy
amputation, Owen.
Probably because it was done
in less-than-ideal circumstances.
He is a soldier, Callie.
I know that, okay?
I feel bad about
that, all right?
I care about that. I really do.
You know who doesn't care?
You know who doesn't give
a damn about his service?
The robot leg.
All the robot leg cares about
is that the nerves in his leg
aren't communicating
with his muscles,
which means they
can't communicate
with the sensors
in the prosthesis,
which means the
robot leg won't work.
Then you can find a way
to help him. Just figure it out.
I'm sorry. Are you not
listening to me, Owen?
Are you deliberately being
obtuse? I just told you his nerves...
Just fix it.
I just told you I can't!
Fix it! That is an order!
An order? Who are
you? General Patton?
I'm your chief of surgery.
On the surgical floor,
you are my chief.
In my lab, funded by the money
that I procured, I am in charge!
Are we clear? No,
you don't get these
guys' hopes up
and then leave
them with nothing.
No, no, no. No, I didn't
do that, Owen. You did that.
You're the one out there running
your mouth at the rehab center
about, "Free, pain-free Six
Million Dollar Man robot legs!"
I'm about to go in there and
crush his dreams because of you.
We're gonna pull on
my count. We ready?
One,
two,
three.
Easy.
Okay, Kelly clamp.
Apply pressure. Got it.
More suction. I
need to see or feel.
Okay. MAGGIE: Whoa.
That's got to be the fastest
splenectomy I've ever seen.
Yeah, this isn't my first rodeo.
I'm hope I'm that fast someday.
You will be.
In about 4,000 rodeos.
So, I hear you and Hunt had
a little episode in the hallway.
He told on me.
You can write me up all
you want for insubordination,
but I stand by the
fact that I do not
take orders
regarding my own lab.
And Hunt can kiss my...
I'm not asking you to
take orders in your own lab.
What I'm asking is maybe that
you not have a screaming match
in the middle of the
hallways of the hospital,
because when members
of the board cause a scene,
I have to stop practicing
medicine, which I love doing,
and become a hall monitor,
which I don't really love doing.
I got to come down
here and lecture
you about
responsibility and honor
and crap I really don't want
to be lecturing you about.
You know, I'm down to three
procedures a day, okay, if I'm lucky?
Not even long procedures.
I'm sucking fat, lifting boobs,
butts. Butt implants are huge.
I just want a good,
intense, smart surgery.
You know, like the ones
where your feet hurt,
where your feet hurt because
you've been on them for hours.
Or your mind hurts because
you've had to improvise and paint.
Surgeries of joy.
But no, I can't have those,
'cause I run the board.
Grey calls in sick. Your wife tries
to give up peds surgery on me.
And boy Shepherd's
in a pissing match
with girl Shepherd,
which they won't admit.
And Yang screws us
with Bailey versus Karev.
And I think Richard has the
hots for the new cardio god,
Maggie or whatever?
Which is gross,
'cause she is 12.
So, now you and Hunt are running
around screaming at each other?
I don't get to be a
surgeon. I'm a hall monitor.
I will stop screaming
in the hallways.
All right, what's wrong?
Hunt's got this bug up his butt
about a candidate for
my robotic limb project,
and as much as he
wants it to happen,
those nerves are not
communicating with those muscles,
and there's nothing
I can do about it.
I can.
Targeted muscle reinnervation.
I create an alternate traffic
route for the nerve signals.
It's like, if there's
construction on the highway,
you pick a side street, right?
I can dissect a nerve
at its current location
and rewire it
wherever you need it.
Connection established.
You are wasted
as a hall monitor.
I know!
Well, I am done here.
Lung crisis averted.
Okay. Partial gastrectomy
and splenectomy done.
We can start the
diaphragm repair.
This was, I have to say, the most
fun I have had since I got here.
Well, you've done
some very good work.
Me? You. That was amazing.
What was that? A
15-second splenectomy?
Well, 20.
Eighteen. I might have
stolen a peek at the clock.
Well, it was inspiring.
I'm glad I was here.
Thank you all. I will
check on him in post-op.
The bowels seem to be intact,
but we're gonna run
it again just to be sure.
Bailey, you have this?
Indeed, we do.
I need your username
and password.
This is illegal.
We're just logging
into the hospital system.
To get Maggie
Pierce's personnel file
to get her date of
birth, which is illegal.
Yeah, so is pretending
to be someone you're not.
Now, put in your password.
Once we figure out
when she was born,
there's got to be
something we can use
to prove that your mom
wasn't pregnant at the time.
You know, photos or
a video or something.
You can call Pierce's bluff.
You're a very different
person than Cristina.
Cristina and I would
just be dancing by now.
Yeah. I know.
Here we go. Look at that.
Pierce's birthday,
November 22, 1983.
So, basically, your mom
would have been knocked up
around spring of '83.
What was going on
in the spring of '83?
What?
That's when she
tried to kill herself.
So, that's done.
Maybe you want to
practice your speech on me.
Or maybe I want to focus on making
sure Mr. Hays is stable post-op.
But Karev...
Okay, Edwards, I
am afraid of snakes.
I'm afraid of large spiders.
And while it might
not be rational,
I am occasionally afraid
there might be a shark waiting
for me in a public swimming pool.
Why would there be a
shark waiting for you...
I said it wasn't rational. I
am afraid of those things.
What I am not afraid
of is Alex Karev.
You shouldn't be. You should
be afraid of everyone else.
Say more.
Alex Karev is the closest thing
Meredith Grey has to a brother.
He lives in her old house.
He started a program that
brought a daughter into her life.
Robbins is Karev's mentor.
Torres is married to Robbins.
So, whoo! Team Karev.
Jackson Avery,
friend of Alex Karev.
We used to double-date.
Speaking of which, Avery has a
history of making wrong choices.
Oh. Hey, Dr. Herman.
Sorry I don't have that
case report in to you yet.
I've got this
neuroblastoma on this baby,
and the mom got really overreactive,
and so I had to reassure her.
Dr. Robbins, in fetal
surgery, every patient you treat
will come encased in a mother,
a mother whose
heightened state of concern
is a biological and
evolutionary necessity.
If you lack the
basic skills to...
No, I don't. I don't. No. No.
Moms are kind of like my
thing. I'm great with moms.
I actually teach other people
how to be great with moms.
Yeah. No. You can ask anyone.
I need your start paperwork.
Right. I just need to
get caught up on that.
I am great with moms!
I know!
It was right after that
she moved us to Boston.
I mean, I was five. All my
memories of Boston are so hazy.
Do you remember your
mom getting suddenly fat,
then suddenly not fat?
Alex, that whole
time was just a blur.
Everything that happened
after she tried to kill herself
was just a blur for me.
I don't want to talk
about this anymore.
Let's just keep
working on your speech.
I'm not working on my speech.
I'm going through the
emergency room admits
for Seattle Grace
in June of 1983.
What? How?
We computerized
this, like, two years ago.
How are you on the
board and I'm not?
Wait. Right there.
There it is.
Well, don't click on
it, because I'm not...
I'm not sure I'm
ready to see this.
Are you ever
ready for this stuff?
"Patient admitted with wrist
lacerations and loss of blood."
Scroll down. Scroll down.
Beta-HCG came back positive.
She was pregnant.
Look in the notes.
"Advised patient of pregnancy.
"Patient was unaware of
pregnancy when admitted."
She's my sister.
I owe you an apology.
Were you going to give me
one, or is this just a heads-up?
I'm sorry, okay? We're okay?
No! Come back here!
Come back and
say a bunch of crap
to make me understand
why you were yelling at me
and giving me orders and
generally being a big old ass.
No, we're not okay.
I need something to be...
Good. To...
I need something to feel right.
Okay, I'm not depressed.
I'm not... My
heart is not broken.
I'm not grieving.
She's not dead. She's out there.
She's living out her dreams,
and I know she's happy,
and that makes me
feel proud for her.
But there is this other feeling
that doesn't completely
feel fair or right or good.
She goes on, day in and
day out, happy, without me.
But every morning, I
wake up, and there's this pit,
this feeling here that...
Maybe my dreams are over.
Maybe I had my dreams
and they're over now.
And I'm gonna
be this single guy.
No wife, no kids, no family.
She was my family.
And now she's someplace
else, and I let her go,
and it's good that I did. I
mean, it's better for her.
But for me...
So I need something to be good.
I need a reason to
get up every morning,
to not crawl back into that cave
that I was in before I met her.
I mean, you know she saved me?
You were there. You
remember how I was.
I was...
Dark.
That war made me dark.
And that darkness,
it is still in me.
She just lit it up.
So, I just thought,
maybe to beat back that
darkness, I would do some good.
I'd just do something good.
I'd go be with those
guys who'd remind me...
I just need
something to be good.
That's why I dragged
you to that rehab center.
That's why I, um...
Wanted you to help.
That's why I pushed
too hard, and that's it.
I'm not gonna talk
about it anymore, okay?
So, just say that we're okay.
Okay? Okay.
Great. Owen?
For God's sakes, Callie.
No, I was just gonna
ask if you wanted to...
I was just gonna ask if you
wanted to watch Jeff's surgery.
Jackson's doing a little
targeted muscle reinnervation.
He's moving the nerves to where
they can talk to
the robot sensors.
Want to watch?
How's our motorcycle guy?
My motorcycle guy? I
fixed him, like a boss.
Like your boss, actually.
Amy, you're an excellent
surgeon. You have nothing to prove.
Oh, I know I don't.
But if you try and fight me over
the leadership of this department,
you will lose. My resume
will kick your resume's ass.
I am better than you.
Oh, my God, Derek. There
is no limit to your narcissist...
I have been playing this game
longer than you at a much higher level.
That is all there is to it.
Bite me.
Where did she go? Dr. Shepherd?
I'm Dr. Shepherd.
Yeah, I know. Ms. Dr. Shepherd.
Her post-op CTs are back.
Let me see them. I shouldn't.
Kepner, I am Dr. Shepherd.
Uh, so, we repaired
the subdural bleed, but...
That is a big aneurysm.
Yeah. It's grown. It's way
bigger than it was before.
Okay, book an OR. And scrub in.
Okay. I'll let her know.
No, with me, Kepner. You're
gonna scrub in with me.
It's her patient.
Well, it just got
too big for her.
Tell her or don't tell her.
Just prep an OR. And scrub in.
Okay. So, now what
are you gonna do?
Go talk to her?
Well, I called Richard,
and he's coming over.
Is that okay?
Yeah, sure.
It's just, you know...
We've got this
board meeting thing,
and I don't want to rush
you, but I got to go get ready,
and you got to be
at this meeting, too.
Alex, you're prepared.
Your speech is great.
Why are you so...
Because I want this, Mer.
You know? I don't
just need a job.
Yang thought I could
do something bigger,
and for the first time,
I feel like I can, too.
You know, I feel
like I should really...
Like I have something to offer.
And I'm scared to death,
and I don't want it to
go like crap, all right?
Take all the time you need.
Thank you.
When did you know?
I found out the night
I met Maggie Pierce.
You didn't know?
Ellis didn't tell you?
Believe me, don't you think...
When Pierce asked
about your mother,
I felt like I was
being hit by a car.
And when she asked about you...
I...
When was that?
The night of the mass casualty,
the mall explosion.
That was a week ago.
So, you knew I had a sister
and you had a daughter,
and you didn't tell me?
You didn't tell her. I tried.
What the hell is wrong with you?
Don't you think I want to?
I tried. I tried again today.
Well, when are you
planning on doing it?
I would have liked
to do it 30 years ago!
I would like to
have been a father!
To know my child!
To have a say!
But your mother stole
that chance from me.
Gown and glove me.
I don't believe you.
I don't believe you!
Suction. Amy, you
don't have to scrub in.
I want to be sterile
when I come over there
and stick that
bovie in your eye.
Kepner, move! You're on my list.
You have put me
in an awful position.
Amy, he never had
a good prognosis.
I went endovascularly
to fix the aneurysm,
but he starting
re-bleeding. I can see that.
Fibrin glue.
Now, why is that
suction not working?
Okay, can somebody
change the canister?
Got it.
Amy... I see it.
One hundred of mannitol,
125 of Solu-Medrol.
He's gonna herniate. He
may not have time to herniate.
He's in florid DIC. He's
not clotting anymore.
Knox, check his pupils.
Fixed and dilated.
There's no gag reflex.
He's probably
already brain-dead.
The next thing I heard, she
had moved you to Boston.
She never said a thing to
me about being pregnant.
I had no choice in the matter.
She knew, and she left.
I'm sorry.
It's just...
We had an amazing day today.
And she's someone I'd
very much like to know.
So, she came here
looking for answers
about her biological mother.
You are her answer.
You have to tell her.
Don't make her wait.
I mean, Ellis made the decision
for you. Don't do that to Pierce.
So, you're re-routing the deep
peroneal with the biceps femoris?
Exactly.
You know, if you
made this process
part of the initial amputation,
you could cut out the
second surgery altogether.
Ha! Yeah. Add what?
Two, three minutes
to the initial surgery?
That could make a world of
difference. That's a great idea, actually.
Thanks.
Avery, did I mention
that Hunt and I
are starting a special
project with veterans?
We are? We are.
We are taking a chunk
of my research money
and focusing it on
prosthetics for vets.
Free, pain-free, right?
Right. Right.
That sounds great.
That is good for the
hospital. Good work, guys.
You want in?
I mean, unless you're too busy
with butt implants, hall monitoring.
Yeah, well, I guess
you would benefit
from having a good plastics
guy who knows nerves.
Ew.
Ew. That was so weak.
Did you see him
trying to pretend
he already had friends
on the playground?
Yeah, don't pretend that you
have friends on the playground.
Aw. He tried to be cool.
Don't try to be cool. It's sad.
Don't try to be cool.
Shut up.
Adding on this reinnervation, it
revolutionizes the whole thing.
I mean, the potential for control
these patients can have is...
It's incredible.
I mean, I could change the
way the world does amputations.
Sounds like you
really want to do this.
I do. I do!
And I know it'll
take so much time,
and we'll be
stretched so, so thin.
But I really think that...
So, wait.
So, are you saying that maybe
we should wait on this baby?
What? No. No, no.
Why would you say that?
No. Because you just said it
was gonna be too much to juggle.
And you're supposed to
say, "It's not a problem.
"You can do it, Callie.
We can do it all."
You're supposed to support me
the way that I've been supporting you
ever since you decided you
needed to start this fellowship.
But what if we can't?
I mean, what if we can't
do anything and everything?
Are you saying
you don't want to...
Are you saying you
don't want a baby?
'Cause, then, what
are we doing here?
Why are we
meeting with this lady
who's gonna help us find
someone to help us make a baby
if you don't want a baby?
Don't put words in my
mouth. This was my idea.
Yeah, but you
don't want to carry it,
and then I couldn't, and
you still didn't want to carry it,
and then we find this,
and then you find something else
to do. Oh, my God. It's so obvious.
I can't believe it.
Say it.
Just say the words.
You don't want a baby.
Hi.
35-Year-old male admitted status
post-ejection from a
motorcycle without a helmet.
Head CT revealed...
What?
I'll do the op note if you want.
You gonna steal this part, too?
Stealing? No, I'm
just trying to help.
This guy was a lost cause.
Whether he was or wasn't,
he was my responsibility,
and I didn't need your help,
and I don't need any
more of your bullying.
Bullying? I am
trying to be nice.
Look, I get it!
You were king of all neurosurgeons,
right hand to the president.
And now you can't have that,
so you need to be king of the
hospital and kick around the peons.
You of all people
should understand
that this was the
future of neuroscience.
I mean, this is what we
would've dreamt of in med school
if we'd thought it was even
possible that it could be done.
Then you shouldn't
have given it up.
But the least you can do is
stop stomping around here
punishing people for
a choice you made.
I didn't make a choice.
Meredith made a choice
and backed me into a corner.
And because I love my
kids and I love my wife
and I want to do what's
best for her... I do.
I want to give her everything.
But something like
this will not come again.
This is it. This
is as high as I go.
I have never taken a step
back in my career ever.
I've never felt like this before,
and I feel like she forced me.
Okay, well, I know the feeling,
because it is happening
to me right now.
I'm not trying to...
No, I know that you're not
trying to, but you are, Derek!
You are doing it to me.
And Meredith, you say that
you want her to have everything,
but not if it interferes with
you having your everything.
And it is not fair, and
I am saying no, too,
because you have to live
with the choices you make.
I am trying to.
I am trying.
I know.
We're all trying.
It's just, no one
wants to give up.
Or give in.
And no one should.
Right?
Hey, time for the board meeting.
Hmm. Okay.
How's our masterpiece doing?
- Good. He's good.
- Great. You coming?
Yeah, no, I'm just
gonna be a minute.
I'm just reviewing his chart.
Want to make sure
everything's perfect
since they are gonna be
teaching this in med schools.
I know, right? It's crazy.
Yeah.
Let's go.
I'll make sure that
she gets there.
All right, fine. Don't be late.
And actually, the three of us,
we should, you know, meet,
get together, talk
about timelines, protocol.
Yeah, I'll fill you in
on the funding stuff,
and we'll figure out
a subject pipeline.
Okay.
You okay?
Yeah. I just...
I need something
to be good, too.
Okay.
All right.
How sobby do I look? One to 10.
Hmm...
Six.
Okay.
So, how'd it go today?
Did Meredith help
you with your speech?
Oh. Not really.
If this doesn't work out, I
hear RadioShack's hiring.
She must have helped some.
I mean, you guys were at
the house together all day.
Yeah, well, she's got
a lot of stuff going on.
Do I have pit stains?
What kind of stuff?
Oh, nothing. Don't
worry about it.
You sure I look okay?
Yeah. You look great.
Dr. Karev.
Dr. Bailey.
I'll tell them
you're on your way.
Pierce?
Hey! Dr. Webber!
Did you check in on
our impalement patient?
He is doing great!
I need to tell you something.
I should have told you sooner.
Okay.
Ellis Grey and I
knew each other.
Very well.
We had a relationship...
Oh, my God. Oh,
my God. Stop talking.
It's funny, but that is
the first thing I thought
when we first spoke and you told
me that you'd known my mother.
I thought, "What if it's him?"
But then you
never said anything.
And then days went by, and
you still never said anything,
so I thought it couldn't
possibly be true,
because what kind of person
would do something like that?
Would let me sit there
and talk like an idiot
and never speak up?
No one decent. No one honest.
A coward.
The only reason that you
would do something like that...
Is if you'd known
about me all along
and never wanted me, either.
No. No, that's not
true. That's not...
Why should I believe you?
Why should I believe
a word you say to me?
Well, this must've been
a nightmare for you,
me showing up here like this.
Don't worry, it has
been worse for me.
Good night, Dr. Webber.
Surgeons are bred
to be invulnerable.
It's very hard to
lay ourselves bare.
Hey. How are you feeling?
Hey. Uh, not great. Weird day.
You don't have a
fever. You still sick?
No, I wasn't sick. I am
a little drunk, though.
You're drunk? Yes.
I was at Alex's...
Okay, Meredith, you got to
help me. I'm trying to understand.
Okay, listen, this crazy
thing is happening...
You said you had to stay here
to make the most of your career.
Just listen to me.
Wait, so, I gave up the
brain mapping initiative
so you can play hooky and
get drunk with your friends?
This is why we're
staying in Seattle?
Because we know exactly
how deep some injuries can go.
But vulnerability isn't
the opposite of strength.
It's a necessary part.
We have to force
ourselves to open up,
to expose ourselves,
to offer up everything we have
and just pray that
it's good enough.
I'm sure you did fine.
Sure are taking a long time.
Alex?
Otherwise, we'll never succeed.
Congratulations.
I... Wait. Karev?
Bailey?
Hey! There she is.
Hey. Congratulations.
Oh, my...