Sean's being paroled.
That's great.
I just want him
to have a fair shot.
I want to do it right
this time, Dad.
And I've tasked
Dr. Grace Song here
with finding ways to make
your jobs more efficient.
We're deciding how to use
tech so that it's empowering.
I wonder if you might train me
on that new EMR program.
The longer
we don't talk,
the bigger the divide
between us becomes.
Maggie, you lied to me.
I'm not gonna give up on us.
Hi.
You've reached Ben Campbell.
Leave a message
after the beep.
Hey, um.
I know this is the third
message that I'm leaving.
And I really want to respect
the space you asked for,
but if you can text me
and let me know that
you're all right,
it's getting pretty
brutal out there.
And... Okay.
Love you.
Bye.
You hurt?
Injured?
Mmm-mmm.
Stay to the right
and settle in.
Someone will swing by
with a blanket soon.
Hey. What's our count?
Pushing 60.
Sixty? And it's
not even 10:00.
Hey. How long are we supposed
to keep letting people in?
Well, the worst of the storm
is still ahead of us.
The weather center
is expecting
70-mile-an-hour winds
and at least
ten inches of ice.
If we don't open our doors,
most of these people
won't survive the night.
I understand, but,
look, pretty soon
we're just gonna be
standing room only here.
Well, we're setting up cots
and the entryway
for the overflow.
What about our patients?
I'm short doctors,
and everyone I do have
is coming off a double
with no end in sight.
Well, I just got word
from the governor's office.
The National Guard
will be making runs,
picking up
essential medical personnel
who can't make it in.
Look, I know this isn't easy,
Dr. Archer,
but I promise,
reinforcements are coming.
All right.
You don't believe in omens.
Hey, Mags, let me know
when my OR is ready.
I'm gonna grab a coffee.
You've been on your feet
for 72 hours now.
Might want to make
it a double.
Tell me about it.
Dr. Halstead,
we've got incoming.
You're going to Baghdad.
Can you give Dr. Song a hand?
I'll see what I can do.
Thank you.
So Dayton's got you
in the trenches with us
grunts tonight, huh?
He's concerned
you're running
out of ammo, yeah.
We're going to Baghdad.
Where's the ambo?
The tires started
spinning out
in the driveway.
Nina Simonds, 53 years old.
Carbon monoxide exposure
from lighting
an old gas stove.
Fell from a third-story window
trying to vent the apartment.
That's her nephew, Lucas.
No complaints.
Tubed in the ambo
for GCS of five.
Gross deformities
on the left arm and leg.
Eighteen-gauge in each arm.
Total of 500 milliliters
of normal saline.
Heart rate 120,
BP 104/78.
She's hypotensive.
She's bleeding
somewhere.
Two units of blood on
the rapid transfuser and
an X-ray, chest and pelvis.
On my count. One, two, three.
Thanks, guys.
Okay?
Yep.
We were getting dizzy.
She was just trying
to let in some fresh air.
Okay. Good to know,
Lucas. Don't worry.
We're gonna take good care
of your aunt, all right?
Doris?
Hey.
Let's get you
looked at, okay?
Lungs are
clear bilaterally,
but pressure's fallen
to 90 systolic.
Okay. Let's get an ABG,
two grams of TXA.
And, Dr. Song, fast her.
On it.
I don't see any fluid.
Me neither.
That's weird.
She's already sucked down
two units of blood,
and her pressure
hasn't budged.
X-ray.
Chest looks good.
Mike, get her pelvis quickly.
Open-book pelvic fracture.
It's completely shattered.
She's falling.
Okay.
Let's get a binder
on her pelvis now.
We need to lock it down
before she bleeds out.
Let's go.
You set?
Don't wait for me.
Tighten it.
Looks closed.
Pressure's coming up.
Let's get another X-ray
and keep pushing blood.
That was close.
So it looks like
the storm took out
the West Loop substation.
Anyone experience
disruptions to ventilators,
monitoring equipment?
No, no, no,
everything kicked over
to emergency backup.
All right, good.
Let's all get back to work.
I'll keep you informed
as we get updates.
Maggie, let's start getting
everyone who's stable
into the entryway.
They can hunker down
there for the night.
All right.
1979, You remember that one?
God, I remember that one.
4 degrees, 22 3/4 inches.
Wow.
Yeah. But then
there was 2012.
16 1/4 inches,
10 below zero.
Cold, very cold.
But tonight
is much colder.
You know what then?
It's really good
that you came in
when you did.
Yeah, good.
No, good for sure.
Felix, tell me how are you
doing with your lithium?
Are you
taking it regularly?
Yeah, pretty much.
Pretty much?
Okay. Well, then,
let me ask you.
How are you dealing
with the change of seasons?
You know, the shorter days,
the darker days?
Are you holding up okay?
It's never easy.
I try, but...
Hi.
Hey there, Felix.
How are those
toes feeling?
Slowly but surely
getting better,
as the saying goes.
Slowly but surely.
Great. Great.
Dr. Charles, can I speak
with you for a moment?
Be right back.
Yeah.
I've got a cot ready
for him in the entryway.
He's already got a bed.
I can't tie up a room
all night for some
frost nipped toes.
Thing is, though, Mags,
Felix is bipolar II
with history
of noncompliance.
I just don't think
that's an ideal situation
for him out there.
Well, we don't really
have a choice.
We have patients
with greater need.
Okay.
Excuse me, Dr. Archer.
Yeah?
Twenty-six-year-old male
with an eye injury,
possible orbital fracture.
I can put in the orders,
but I thought you might
want to see this one.
What? Why?
Sean?
Oh, hey, Dad.
Hey. Are you hurt?
No, I'm fine.
It's Clint, my roommate
from the reentry center.
I heard a lot
about you, Mr. Archer.
It's Doctor.
Right.
So what happened?
I was picking up
some essentials
before the storm hit,
you know, eggs,
milk, and such.
Got jumped leaving
the Mariano's over on Wabash.
Is that right?
Yeah.
It must have been,
like, ten dudes.
Didn't have a chance.
Sean was nice enough
to pick me up
in his four-by.
Well, that's my boy.
Let's see what's going on.
Can you see out of it?
Yeah, but kind of blurry.
It's really swollen.
All right, well,
keep ice on it
and get a CT.
Can I talk to you
for a minute?
Okay. What are you doing?
City's on lockdown.
He needed help.
Well, then get somebody else
to bail him out.
You got no business driving
around in an ice storm,
especially after curfew.
All it'll take
is one violation
to land you back in county.
He's my friend.
I couldn't just leave him
out there to freeze.
Sean...
Dr. Archer.
You have an OB patient
in treatment six.
Where's Dr. Asher?
She couldn't get her car
out of the garage.
Don't go anywhere.
Let's add a tox screen
to those labs.
Hi. You must be Katie?
Uh-huh.
Hi. I'm Dr. Archer.
This is Dr. Hudgins.
I see you're experiencing
mild contractions
and some dizziness.
I almost fell off the ladder
undressing my Christmas tree.
Hmm.
Well, I like
the festive spirit, Katie,
but Christmas in February?
I know. I'm a little
behind schedule.
I've been a bit preoccupied.
When is your due date?
Not for another seven weeks.
I was hoping he'd hold off
long enough
for my husband
to get back from Auckland.
Your contractions
could just be Braxton-Hicks.
So there's nothing
to worry about.
But I see that
your blood pressure
is slightly elevated.
What does that mean?
Hopefully, it's just
a response to the pain.
But we could be looking
at preeclampsia.
Oh, God.
Well, hang tight.
Stay warm.
Before anybody jumps
to conclusions,
I'm gonna have lab work
done and OB weigh in.
Thank you.
Nina Simonds'
latest scans.
As you can see,
binder's holding pressure
on her pelvis,
but she's still leaking
blood from the left
iliac artery.
So she needs surgery.
Ideally, yes.
But the second we open
her up, we'd release
the pressure.
And she'll bleed out
and likely die on the table.
So we take her to IR,
embolize the vessel.
Okay. But even
if we can reach
the artery,
and that's a big if,
the second we do,
she'd go into
hypotensive shock.
So we give blood
and resuscitate.
Which would require
continued use of massive
blood products.
We'd gut our supply.
Until the storm
blows through,
there's no telling
how long it'll be until
we get re-upped again.
So how about
we cut to the point
where you're recommending
a course of action?
Look, I don't want
to be a downer here, but...
I ran
an algorithmic simulation
with inputs
from patients with
a similar trauma profile.
It puts Nina's odds
of survival at 7%.
So what are we gonna do?
Honestly, nothing.
My recommendation would be
to transfer her to ICU
and make her comfortable.
You're kidding.
If it was any other day,
I'd say go for it,
but we have an obligation
to prioritize blood products
and other
precious resources
for patients who have
the most favorable outcome.
And unfortunately,
that's not her.
That kid lost
both his parents
in a car accident.
His aunt's all
he's got left now.
I feel you.
But it's not clinically
relevant, is it?
I just thought you should know
before we orphan him again.
I'm taking her to IR.
And if you don't want
to help, that's fine.
I'll find somebody else.
I've been trying
to reach Ben.
It's his bowling night,
and I'm worried
that he's out there
in the storm.
I never thought that
it would take him this long
to come around.
I'm starting to think
that it's never going to.
Well, you know
what they say.
Absence makes
the heart grow fonder.
Just give it some time.
Felix, how are those
frost nipped toes?
Here.
Felix?
He's been stabbed.
Stay with me,
Felix.
Okay, I got three
clean points of entry
to the lower
right quadrant.
I'm gonna fast him.
I don't get it.
Why was this guy
moved to the entryway?
He was being
treated for frostbite.
It was frostnip.
And we needed
the room.
What the hell's wrong
with this thing?
I'll take a look.
No, no, no, forget it.
We gotta get him
up to CT anyway.
Let's get him upstairs.
All right, let's go.
Let's move.
Thank you.
Hey. I heard Felix
got stabbed.
What happened?
CPD's
been notified,
but their entire department
is underwater.
So it's going to be
a few hours before
they can even get here.
Jack.
Yeah?
What are you
still doing here?
We got delayed finishing up
the OR 2.0 sensory upgrades,
and then I couldn't
get the helicopter launched
before the storm hit.
So I... I was told
there was a stabbing.
It seems awfully calm.
Well, we're trying
to keep it quiet.
As far as anyone is concerned,
we had a medical emergency.
Okay. Then what happens now?
My team is pulling
the surveillance footage
as we speak.
But in the event
this is an active situation,
I think we have to call
a code silver,
evacuate the building
before anybody else
gets hurt.
I'd really prefer
not to do that.
A code silver
would require us
to lock down the hospital
and kick all of these people
back out onto the streets.
Then what are we
supposed to do?
Well, we can start
by quietly notifying essential
staff of the threat.
And if everyone
could have just a little
situational awareness,
we'd give Chief Madsen
and his team time
to review
the surveillance footage
and ID a suspect.
I don't know, Sharon.
We might have a lunatic
loose in our hospital.
I think we should
call the code.
Jack, these people
don't have anywhere to go.
I get it, but I'm not
gonna have this whole thing
blowing up in my face.
Shut it down.
I am not letting you
send people out there.
And that's it.
Yeah, we've got
a couple more pickups,
and the roads are a mess,
so I'd say about
an hour or so?
What are her liver
and kidney function numbers?
Creatinine at 1.
PC ratio of 200.
Mild contractions,
and her blood pressure's
persistently higher
than 140/90.
Okay, she could
be preeclamptic,
but we're a bit shy
of where we'd want
to induce right away,
33 weeks.
Admittedly, I'm a little
out of my depth,
but I am open to ideas.
Give her a shot
of betamethasone to help
mature the baby's lungs
and magnesium
to prevent seizures
in case we are dealing
with preeclampsia.
I'll be there
as soon as I can.
Okay. Got it. And, Hannah,
be safe out there.
I'll be there before
you know it.
We got Clint's
imaging results,
which confirmed
an orbital fracture.
I'm just waiting
until ophtho can get down
and do a consult.
Okay, yeah. So is there
anything else?
Yeah, um,
his lab results.
All right.
Hey, with me now.
So do you mind telling me
what's really going on here?
What? I don't know...
Clint's lab work.
Amphetamines,
benzos, opioids.
I mean, that guy's got
an entire pharmacy
in his bloodstream.
Okay. Okay.
Look, Clint called me
for a ride
because he relapsed
and he got into some trouble.
Are you using again?
No!
No, tell me the truth.
You know,
this is exactly why
I didn't tell you the truth
about why we were here
in the first place.
When are you ever gonna
have some trust in me?
When you stop making
bad decisions.
That's when.
I swear I'm clean.
You don't believe me,
give me a drug test.
Maybe I will.
Advancing the catheter.
I'm barely keeping
her pressure up.
I'm working as fast as I can.
Having some issues.
All right, give an amp
of calcium and bicarb.
And keep going
with the blood products.
Lost pulse.
She's arresting.
Starting compressions.
Push a milligram of epi.
Push it.
Epi's in.
Pulse is back.
I have ROSC.
All right.
Let's keep going.
No. I think
we're done here.
What?
I tried.
The pelvic binder's
in the way, and the
hematoma is too big.
It's distorting the anatomy.
I can't pass the wire.
What if we loosen
the binder?
No way.
As soon as you remove
the pressure, she'll bleed out
on the table.
Well, come on.
We have to think
of another way.
Gave it our best shot.
Sorry, Will.
Security's still
investigating.
In the meantime,
we're just telling people,
you know,
just keep an eye out
for anything suspicious.
Wow, a stabbing.
Okay, will do.
Dr. Charles, can you confirm
this pharmacy dosage, please?
Thank you.
Dr. Marcel.
Yeah?
So?
Not good.
A CT scan showed that
part of the knife broke off
and is lodged somewhere
in the middle of his liver.
So he's gonna
need surgery?
Yeah, but he has
three tracts in the liver.
From the surface,
it'll be challenging
to know which one
has the retained blade.
And, well,
if we go in blindly,
then he could
bleed excessively.
So I'm...
I'd like to go up to 2.0.
I'm hoping
the enhanced imaging
will give us
the roadmap we need
to make the repair.
Okay.
I'll call upstairs
and let them know
that you're on your way.
You get another
cup of coffee.
Yeah.
Liver injuries
are brutal.
Poor Felix.
I know it's chaotic tonight,
but how does something
like this happen?
Doris, please.
This is not helpful.
What happened?
Pressure is falling.
Oh, man.
Hang with me.
Hang with me, Katie.
All right.
Reflexes close
to absent.
Diminished urine output.
All right. Let's hold
the magnesium.
Give 500 cc fluid bolus
of lactated ringers.
And let's repeat all her labs,
including a mag level.
Copy.
Where the hell
is Hannah?
This doesn't look good.
No, we gotta
get him out of there.
Yeah.
Hey.
What's your name?
Paul.
Paul, take a few
deep breaths for me.
Okay. Are you okay?
Are you in pain?
No.
No?
No? Do you think
you can walk, Paul?
I think so.
Okay.
Good, 'cause we're
gonna get you out of here.
Grab an arm.
Yep.
On three. One, two, three.
Here we go.
We gotcha.
Gotcha.
I'm dizzy. I gotta stop
for a sec.
Okay,
let's put him down.
Yeah.
I think there's a blanket
in the back seat.
Stay with him.
Keep him on his side.
Watch his neck.
Will do.
We gotcha.
Hey, Paul?
Hey.
Did you get hit?
I don't think so.
Okay, good.
Hang tight for a bit.
I'll be right back.
I think I took some shrapnel.
Oh, let me see.
We got to stop
the bleeding.
I have a tourniquet
in my vest.
Hold pressure.
Watch your hand.
That should do.
I'm gonna get you
to the hospital.
Not in that, you're not.
What?
Where are you
taking her?
Up to the ICU.
Dr. Davis couldn't
access the vessels,
just like you said.
I'm sorry, Will.
Auntie N!
Woah, woah,
easy, buddy.
Auntie N? Is she gonna
get better?
We're gonna do everything
we can for her.
It's my fault.
Lucas, why would
you say that?
She was lighting
the stove
'cause of me.
I was cold.
That's why she fell.
Lucas, there you are.
Let's go back to
the doctor's lounge, okay?
I'm so sorry.
It's all my fault.
Will, wait a sec.
What if we take her back
to the hybrid room?
And if we can loosen
the pelvic binder, maybe
we can find the vessels.
I thought of that.
Dr. Davis was not on board.
Then I'll do it myself.
One person said
they saw a guy in a red
T-shirt leaving the area.
But there were some
inconsistencies with
their account.
How about
security footage?
Cameras never
came back online
after we shifted over
to the backup generator.
Remind me to jump
down IT's throats
over that, please.
But what
can we do now?
We need to find out
who did this Felix.
If I had to hazard a guess,
I'd say whoever did this
already exited
the hospital.
At the moment,
our top priority
needs to be ensuring
the safety of our
patients and staff.
Were you able
to get in any extra
security personnel?
They're trickling in.
I wanted to talk to you
about how best
to deploy them.
Why don't we do a walkthrough?
I'll fill you in
if I get any more
information.
This is unacceptable.
It is.
But, look, we're gonna have
to accept the possibility
that we might never
find out who did this.
Yeah, but Felix wouldn't
even have been
in the entryway
had I not insisted
on turfing him.
Look, you've been
on your feet for,
what, 20 hours?
What do you say let me
pass the brick off to Doris
and you get some rest?
No, I'm gonna
power through.
Doctor's orders, then.
Daniel.
Margaret, I'm not
messing around here.
I'm worried about you.
You need some sleep.
Thank you.
Still can't tell where
the retained fragment is.
2.0, rotate the image
to feature the right
hepatic lobe.
What's this?
Intentional motions
are at 74% efficiency
compared to your
normal metrics.
What are you
talking about?
You're too fatigued
to continue operating.
You're kidding, right?
I've done hundreds of cases
far more exhausted than this.
It's recommended
you have another surgeon
complete the operation.
There is no other surgeon.
I can take over.
I just started my shift
a few of hours ago.
I'm plenty rested.
You're not qualified.
You're a junior resident.
I need you to
override the system
and give me my image.
I can't.
Uh, Mr. Dayton upgraded
the code to make it
impossible to override.
Then get Jack
up here to do it.
You're wasting
your breath.
He doesn't want
anyone operating
at a capacity below
the system's threshold.
This is ridiculous!
I feel fine!
I can do it.
Damn it.
Under your supervision,
of course.
2.0, transfer primary surgeon
to Dr. Tanaka-Reed.
Focus on
the right lower lobe.
Your show.
Katie's platelet count
dropped to 70,000.
And her LFTs doubled.
Mag level was seven.
All right, we're gonna
need to induce labor.
All right,
start her on oxytocin
and restart the mag
at one gram an hour
as long as she's doing better
and her reflexes are back.
Oh, uh, any ETA yet
on Dr. Asher?
Just got off with OEMC.
Seems she encountered
a trauma in the field.
What kind of trauma?
He didn't have
any details.
Only that the guard vehicle
was disabled
and they were
having difficulty
finding transport.
Thought it might be
another hour.
An hour? How is she
gonna survive out there
for that long in this cold?
All right,
you know what?
I'm gonna pick her up myself.
Where'd they say
she was at?
Canal and Lumber.
I'm sorry, Dr. Archer,
but Katie's delivering.
Right now? She's only
one centimeter dilated.
I want you staying on this guy
until Hannah gets back here
safe and sound.
All right. You got it.
You think
this is serious?
Why? You got
big weekend plans?
Actually, I do.
My fiance and I are supposed
to have cake tasting.
I'm getting married
next month.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Well, don't worry.
I'll make sure
you're fixed up in time
to walk down that aisle.
How you doing
back there, Paul?
I don't know.
It hurts pretty bad
when I breathe.
Okay, let me take
a look at you.
Okay.
Where's the pain?
My side.
Your side? Give me
your flashlight.
I'm gonna lift up
your shirt.
Okay, it looks like
the shrapnel
might have penetrated
your chest well.
Hold that for me.
Do you have
any medical supplies?
Uh, no,
but there's a toolbox
under your seat.
Hey, that bag,
hand it to me.
Okay, here.
All right, Paul.
You have a hole
in your lung.
I'm gonna stabilize
your breathing
with an airtight patch.
That's your patch?
Yes.
Here we go.
It's going to conform
to your body contour
to create a better seal.
All right.
Now take a big
inhale for me.
That better?
Mmm-hmm.
Okay, good. Good.
Good, good, good.
There we go.
The cavalry
better get here soon.
Yeah.
This is all the blood
we have left.
Do you think
we should use it?
We don't have a choice.
All right.
A-line pressure's down.
I don't think
we're gonna make it.
I only need
another 30 seconds.
I'm almost there.
All right.
Come on. Come on.
Come on, Nina.
I'm in.
Launching the coil.
Pressure's coming up.
All right.
Let's get her
up to the ICU.
BEN ON PHONE:
Hi. You've reached
Ben Campbell.
Leave a message
after the beep.
I...
Are you all right?
It is so cold.
What happened?
I slipped on the ice.
Okay. Come on.
Let's get you inside.
Okay.
Oh, my God.
You're frozen.
How long were you
out there for?
I don't know, a couple
of hours maybe.
Okay, stay right there.
Stay right there.
Let me take a look
at your ankle.
No!
Okay.
I'm gonna go
get a wheelchair,
and we're gonna get your
ankle all fixed up, okay?
Okay, stay right here.
It feels like
there's a boulder on my chest.
Okay.
All right, when you feel
that pressure building up,
I want you to just
pull that flap back, okay?
Try that for me.
Hey. Is that EMS?
Looks like a civilian.
Sorry. I got here
as soon as I could.
Were you looking for us?
I was in the ED
with a friend of mine when
I heard you needed a lift.
I'm Sean. Sean Archer.
Wait. Dean's son?
That's right.
Huh.
Okay.
Well, let's get these guys
in your truck.
Okay.
Katie, I know delivery
didn't go exactly
as you'd planned,
but your baby looks
healthy and strong.
Isn't he?
I was so worried.
Because he was born
prematurely,
we're gonna have to have him
evaluated up in the NICU.
It's a perfectly
normal protocol.
Nothing to be
concerned about.
Okay.
And what about
the preeclampsia?
Well, in most cases,
it's resolved
by giving birth.
We'll keep an eye on that,
but in the meantime,
I'll have you transferred
upstairs where you'll be
a lot more comfortable.
Thank you.
Thank you both.
Sure.
Can you believe it?
That was my first delivery.
I can, actually.
It's such a rush.
Yeah.
Dr. Archer,
just spoke to OEMC.
Hannah's on her way in.
She should be about
15 minutes out.
Thank you, Doris.
And I also
need a consult,
Dr. Archer,
for treatment five.
Patient's name is Heidi.
She fell and twisted her ankle
trying to enter the hospital
over on Polk Street.
Who do you have?
Dr. Hudgins here
would be happy to help.
Great.
Absolutely.
Let's get an X-ray.
That's Kathleen.
Hi.
We're gonna get you
all patched up and back
on your feet, Heidi.
I promise.
Stop smiling so much.
It's creeping me out.
X-ray.
Okay, Heidi.
Unfortunately,
it is broken.
I don't think
you'll need surgery,
but I'll inject
a numbing agent until
ortho can weigh in.
In the meantime,
let's get you out
of this parka and under
some warm blankets, okay?
No! Stop!
Stop handling me!
I can do it myself.
Okay.
Everybody, all night,
just hovering over me,
just crowding my space.
Zach, can you,
come out here
for a second?
Yeah, one second.
I just gotta draw this up.
Zach.
Get away from me!
No! No! Let go of me!
Can I get some help over here?
Patient armed!
Okay, sweetie.
Pushing five of haldol.
Right here.
No.
Okay, sweetie.
Why won't anyone
leave me alone?
Okay. Okay.
Daniel, do we know why
she stabbed Felix?
Because he was
talking too much
and in her personal space.
What, she stabbed a guy
for being a close talker?
She's a seriously
ill person.
Diagnosed with paranoid
schizophrenia when
she was a young woman.
Last time she was here,
she was on thorazine,
but that's, like,
ten years ago.
I'm pretty sure
she has not had any kind
of consistent care since.
Without her meds,
she's gonna be very volatile.
Well, hopefully, she'll get
the kind of help she needs
moving forward.
In a prison-affiliated
psych ward?
I wouldn't count on it.
Hey, Jack.
You got a minute?
Yeah, of course. Excuse me.
Look, we need to...
We need
to talk about 2.0.
Yeah, let's.
Now, I'm told
that it delivered another
tremendous success.
Success?
Yeah.
2.0 walked an inexperienced
surgeon through
a complicated procedure.
Yeah, I'd chalk that up
as a win.
Sure, the patient
had a good outcome,
but 2.0 glitched again,
Jack, big-time.
Come, walk with me.
Now, I'm listening,
though, sir. Keep talking.
Well, this new feature,
locking surgeons out
because of some preprogrammed
metric of fitness,
it's got to go.
2.0 is a tool that was
designed to help surgeons,
not keep them
from doing their job.
I think it needs
to be disabled.
Listen, I gotta disagree
with you there.
Now, look, I was told
that you had some difficulty
with this thing
earlier, yeah?
Uh...
I couldn't
get it to work. Yeah.
Mmm-hmm.
Well, maintenance
took a look at it, and...
Yeah, it turns out
that it was working
just fine.
Well, it wasn't working
when I tried it.
Look, regardless,
it was an emergent situation.
I was in a rush.
Or could it be
that maybe you were more
fatigued than you realized?
Now look, it's common
for all of us,
maybe even top surgeons,
to underestimate
the effects of fatigue
on our reflexes and judgment.
But isn't it great to have
a tool that can take all
the guesswork out of it?
Okay, 40-year-old
male involved in
a motor vehicle crash.
Blunt trauma.
Possible head injury.
Penetrative wound
to the left flank.
Applied an occlusive dressing.
All right.
Take him to Baghdad.
This way, guys.
This is Corporal Parker.
Twenty-eight years old.
National Guardsman.
Isolated arterial hemorrhage
to the right leg.
Applied a tourniquet
about 90 minutes ago.
Vascular surgeon
is waiting upstairs.
Okay.
How you feeling?
Good.
Yeah, much better
now that my patients
are stable and in hospital.
How did you get here?
I was worried about you.
Hey, Dad.
Sean.
I gotta move my truck.
All right.
I'm not sure we would
have made it if he didn't
show up when he did.
Did you know
that he spent a year in Alaska
driving a snowplow?
No, I didn't know.
You got a good kid
there, Dean.
Nina, can you hear me?
Hi, Nina.
I'm Dr. Halstead.
Can you hear me okay?
Good.
Come on. Come on in.
Auntie N,
you're all better now.
You're gonna be okay.
I'll give
you two a moment.
Which one of you two drongos
is responsible
for blowing through
our entire blood supply?
I'm sorry. Who are you?
The surgeon
who just performed
a miracle cardiac bypass
with only two units of blood.
Justin, take it easy.
Hey, we were
all strapped today.
You ate through 40 units
on a single trauma.
Now, if my patient wakes up
with deficits because of this,
that's on you.
Don't worry about him.
He's a prick.
No, he's right.
It was a bad call.
How can you say that?
I mean, look what
we did for that kid.
That's my point.
I shouldn't have
let my decision-making
be influenced by this kid
or anyone else.
I should have followed
the data like I always do.
Doesn't sound very
compassionate.
I mean, remember,
we're treating
real people here.
Sticking to the data,
remaining objective,
that's how we save
the most lives.
That's what makes us
objective and compassionate.
Hey.
How's Paul doing?
He's making a full recovery.
And Corporal Parker?
He's just out of surgery,
and he'll be up and around
and walking in no time.
Listen, uh,
about earlier, I...
Oh, no.
I'm guessing the roads are
pretty ugly out there, huh?
Well, I've seen worse,
but... Yeah.
Well, in that case,
I haven't put
my snow tires on yet,
and I was wondering
if I can get a lift home.
Hey.
Pretty impressive sleuthing
there, Maggie.
Not to mention stepping in
before Zach got hurt.
Is your arm okay?
Yeah.
And guess what?
Felix is no longer critical.
Crockett is confident
he's gonna be okay.
That's good news.
Yeah, it is.
Isn't it?
Yeah, uh...
Things haven't
been that great
between Ben and I.
Sorry to hear that.
You want to, uh...
You want to go get
a quick coffee or something?
No.
Actually, no.
I just want to go home
and crawl into bed.
I hear that.
Thank you.
Of course.
Yeah.
Ben?
Maggie.
I'm sorry
it took me so long.