Previously, on
"The Resident"...
Hawkins,
what's your problem?
This is the pharmacist
who filled
the fake prescriptions.
Hey, what are you doing?
Phoebe agreed
to wear a wire for us.
Someone must've found out.
We got a good look
at the killer.
- How's Padma?
- Depressed about AJ.
What if I offer
to be the sperm donor?
- You can't be serious.
- Why not?
Because I couldn't handle that.
Mom?
If it's not too late, I would
like to be your sperm donor.
Yes, yes, yes!
But there is a condition.
So if we're going to do this,
I don't want to just be a donor.
I want to be a father.
♪ It's alright, it's alright ♪
Carol meant the world
to all of us.
I know.
Thanks for coming.
♪ It's alright,
it's alright... ♪
You're so lucky to have had
such a wonderful mom.
Not everyone gets that.
Yeah, yeah.
I'm holding onto that.
Even though he knew
this day was coming,
doesn't make it any easier.
Nothing makes this easier.
Hey, have you seen Cade?
I thought she might be here.
No. She...
she has some things to work out.
I hope everything's okay.
AJ, I'm so sorry.
I wish there were
something I could do.
Thank you.
Um, we should find some time
to talk about the baby.
Maybe sometime tomorrow.
Of course.
The sooner the better.
I want to thank you all
for coming.
You know...
you guys are...
my only family.
At least for now.
When we buried my father here,
three years ago,
my mother wanted
to plant a tree
to mark his grave.
She told me
that even after death,
she would always want
to be by his side.
♪ It's alright,
it's alright... ♪
Bell?
♪ It's alright, it's alright. ♪
*THE RESIDENT*
Season 05  Episode 20
Episode Title: "Fork in the Road"
Aired on: April 26, 2022.
Job well done.
I'll be fine.
Call me when you're off.
I'll meet you here this evening.
Glad you're back.
FBI?
As long as I decide
to stay at Chastain,
- they've given me an armed escort.
- Good.
You need that protection.
Yeah, but it's not exactly
a long-term solution.
What are you doing?
We have to get to work.
Woke up in the middle of the
night wondering about my will.
It was written
a very long time ago
and needs to be updated.
Funerals do have that effect.
- I should probably update mine.
- Well, it turns out
that if I drop dead tomorrow,
everything I own
- goes to my ex-wife.
- Feel free to leave her that boat.
Lord knows
I'm not maintaining it.
It's serious.
You are not about
to drop dead, I promise.
People younger than me die
on the treadmill every day.
I just need a trust
that benefits
you and Jake and Sammie.
And because Georgia doesn't
recognize common-law marriage,
your part in this could be,
you know, pretty complicated.
I have everything I want.
Leave it all to them.
Well, I don't want to do that.
Okay, let's get married then.
So, this is the way
you ask me?
No... no fancy dinner?
No big ring?
Just... didn't even
get down on one knee.
I love you to the moon and back.
But I kneel for no man.
Okay, okay.
I've heard your proposal.
I would like, uh,
maybe a week to think about it.
- Oh, stop it.
- It's a big decision.
So, are we talking, like,
big destination wedding
on Lake Como? 'Cause I could,
I could get behind that.
I'm thinking a ceremony
in the backyard.
We've both been married twice.
What about my bridesmaids?
I want it to be special.
It will be.
And it's that easy?
Medicare will pay for anything
if you got the right story.
Just last week, I told 'em
my cane wasn't cutting it.
I don't even have a cane.
And just like that,
they handed me
a shiny new motorized scooter.
Paid for 100%
by the taxpayers of America.
Remind me to count
the wheelchairs.
- Yeah.
- Hey, I'm no thief.
But I am an opportunist.
If I had a house,
I'd have one
of them poofy chairs that tilt
to help you stand up
and an automated bed, too.
All I need is a prescription
from a willing doc, cutie.
And I know where to find 'em.
Yeah, but you don't want
that kind of doc
to actually treat you.
So, what brought you in today?
Uh, had a bit of a rumble
a while back with this...
numbnut moving in on my block.
We got into it over
a hot chicken sandwich some...
do-gooder brought me.
I've been trying to treat it
on my own, but...
That ulcer looks
severely infected.
Well, if you want
to keep that arm,
we need to clear the infection.
Hey. Thought you could use
a pick-me-up.
Triple espresso with an absurd
amount of hazelnut creamer.
Thanks.
So, Cade showed up,
so I'm off this afternoon.
And your shift is over.
You want to grab lunch?
Uh, I can't.
I have another surgery.
You're starting another shift?
You sure that's a good idea?
You've been here all night.
It's an interesting case.
I'll manage.
Leela.
Um...
we need to talk.
What's there to talk about?
- We're fine.
- I thought so, too.
But you haven't been home
all week,
and we've barely spoken
since I floated the idea
of being Padma's sperm donor.
Okay.
Truth bomb...
I'm still trying
to process that.
Okay.
So it...
it is still an issue.
Leela.
Pre-op. Let's go.
Right behind you.
We'll talk tonight.
I think we better.
This is your second shift,
right?
Sure you don't need that coffee?
Positive. The adrenaline alone
is enough to keep me up.
Especially for a case like this.
Well, a full spinal
reconstruction is a great case.
But it's a marathon,
not a sprint.
Eight to ten hours.
A challenge of sheer endurance.
I can find someone else
- if you're tapped out.
- No.
I'm good.
I got this.
Is that our patient?
Yes. Ashley.
24-year-old female
with congenital dextroscoliosis
of the thoracic
and lumbar spine.
The pain has started limiting
her activity level, and...
she's not the type of person
to be limited.
Can one of you tell
my bossy wife
that stumbling around
like a troll to get my steps in
is irrelevant at this point?
Movement is medicine.
Music to my ears.
Naomi is also
Ashley's physical therapist.
I have to input some notes.
But Dr. Devi here
will talk you through pre-op.
Is that how you two met?
I thought I was getting
a lifetime of free massages.
But, instead, I get a lecture
every time
my butt touches a chair.
She is a couch potato.
It's because I can
barely get up off the couch.
That's true.
Well, we need a few more hours
to run all your pre-op tests.
The surgery will be
in the early afternoon.
Look at me, Dr. Sutton.
Don't I seem rarin' to go?
You're very brave.
I know this is scary.
- She's terrified.
- Well,
let me give you some hope
to hold on to.
It's just a mock-up,
but we should be able
to get pretty close.
As long as you make me taller
than Naomi,
I'm good.
Now get some rest.
You earned it.
Her type and screen
will be back in an hour, and...
it'll be another hour
until our OR is clean.
Find an empty bed
and get some rest until then.
I'll call you when we're ready.
That's an order.
I've seen a lot of gross stuff,
- but that has to take the cake.
- Seriously.
How do you get a fish hook
that size stuck in your cheek?
Really bad casting.
Hey, did I show you
this new game I got on my phone?
We need some help over here!
Please! Anybody!
- What's your name, hon?
- Scott.
- But it's not me. It's my coworker.
- What happened?
We were working
on some power lines nearby.
Uh, the plate wasn't secure.
It fell on top of him.
Looks like a blunt chest wall
injury on his left side.
The plate must have crushed
his chest.
Obvious chest wall deformity.
He may have broken every rib
on that side.
And whatever's left of the lung
underneath clearly isn't doing
too well.
You got to help him.
He's a good guy.
He taught me everything I know.
Sir, can you please back up,
please?
Thank you.
IV is in.
Uh, let's give the doctors
some space.
- Thank you so much.
- He's not gonna make it
to the OR like this.
Let's intubate.
Left lung is no bueno.
We need to do
a single lung ventilation.
You intubate, I'll position it
with the bronchoscope.
We got one good shot at this.
Pushing meds now.
Great view of the cords.
Inserting tube now.
Scope going in.
All right.
Advance.
Inflate the cuff.
He's stable.
But it won't matter
if we don't get him to an OR.
Okay, let's get transpo!
Hundley, let's call
for a portable chest X-ray
and page Austin.
Tell him
that I think our patient
needs to have his lung removed
using an emergent pneumonectomy.
Got it.
All right. Here you go.
- All right.
- Okay, hold on. This is a lot.
Yeah, but don't worry about it.
I will handle it all.
So far,
planning for our future child
has been a great distraction.
"Our" future child?
AJ, I need a sperm donor, okay?
Not-not all this.
Look, Padma,
I understand it's a lot.
But bear with me. All right?
I assure you, it will be worth
my top-shelf DNA.
Arrogant.
But accurate.
All right, let's hear it.
So, I took the liberty
of opening up
a 529 savings account
for the baby.
I will fund it annually
to make sure our child's
college tuition is paid in full.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
I don't want your money.
You're turning down
a college fund?
Ivy League schools
are expensive.
Okay, well,
what if they don't want to go
to an Ivy League?
Or college at all?
Good one.
All right,
moving on to my main point.
Now, I have bio siblings
and parents who I barely know.
We're not in touch and
I can't consider them family.
And I want a family.
Okay, see? This is...
this is what I was afraid of.
We're not creating a family.
I know. But we agreed
that I would be involved
- in the child's life.
- Yes.
Involved means visitations,
occasionally, on my schedule.
No. No, the child needs to know
that I am their father.
Okay, look, you can be there
on birthdays and holidays
and, look, some weekends, too.
What are you doing?
We-We're not done here.
Padma, I get
that you are a free spirit.
But a child has to have a roof
over their head,
- financial security.
- Okay, I have a roof.
You are not raising our child
in a van.
That's a deal-breaker.
You hear me?
Look, I'm needed in the OR.
I'll be back.
Okay, but we haven't
settled anything,
except for the fact
that you're gonna be controlling
and I won't be controlled.
I hear you. We're gonna
work it out, all right?
Just look over the papers.
I'll be back in a couple hours.
Mm.
Seriously?
Sorry to interrupt
your beauty rest, Devi,
but I'm on deck,
which of course means
you are, too.
No. I'm supposed to be
with Dr. Sutton today.
Yeah? Well,
you look pretty busy.
Now, if you'd like to opt out
of an emergent pneumonectomy,
then be my guest.
Pneumonectomy?
You're joking, right?
By now, you know me well enough
to know the things
I do not joke about.
But if you have better things
to do...
No.
Who needs sleep anyway?
My thoughts exactly.
Eh, free food and
a warm blanket, I'm all good.
- Not all good.
- What?
You still have a fever, and we
flooded you with antibiotics.
So, if this combination
doesn't work, we need a plan B.
I-I didn't know
there was antibiotics.
If antibiotics was gonna work,
I wouldn't be here.
Why is that?
I'm already on one.
I've been on one for weeks.
I had a bout of walking
pneumonia last month,
and I went to Atlanta General ER
that time.
I'm an equal opportunity
ER surfer.
They gave me, um, these.
You didn't mention these meds.
I need to know everything
you're taking.
That's the only one.
I owe my life
to fish oil and whiskey.
And lenvatinib.
- This one's for cancer.
- Seriously? Huh.
Well, they must have given me
the wrong bottle.
This drug costs, like,
$10,000 a month.
Huh, and it was prescribed
by a Dr. Conrad Hawkins.
Funny, think I'd remember that.
You know,
if I wanted a pat-down,
I would've gone through TSA.
I got to get out of here.
Relax. Just take a second.
Look...
I don't know anything.
I'm a nobody. I'm a little cog
in a very big machine.
I could end up at the bottom
of a lake
with my feet in concrete.
I hear you.
So, let's focus first
on how to treat you, okay?
I'll be right back.
Cancer drugs.
Parkinson's meds.
Viagra?
The prescribing doctors
are all from Chastain.
Dr. Bell, Dr. Pravesh...
And there's a lot more
where that came from.
Well, we have to call the FBI.
Let Agent Barker know
about this.
I know, and we will,
but Teri needs medical attention
immediately,
or she'll lose her arm.
I don't love the idea
of waiting to make that call.
I get the feeling
that she'd rather go to jail
than talk to the FBI anyway.
- So, what do you want to do?
- Treat her,
earn her trust,
and then find some way
to get her to open up
about the scam.
Okay. Let's work together.
How do we save her arm?
Well, I have a possible
solution, but it's unorthodox.
Padma has seemed to
have forgotten the condition
upon which I agreed to do this.
She wants my sperm,
but not my involvement.
And when you do have an opinion
and draw a clear boundary,
it's still not enough.
I should not have to explain why
I feel a certain type of way.
You are absolutely right.
Just like I shouldn't
have to explain
why I want a roof
over my child's head
that's not made of vinyl.
You're right.
See?
At least the two of us have
our heads screwed on straight.
It's his pulmonary artery.
Inflammatory mediators
are causing vasoconstriction.
He's going into acute heart
failure. Let's hang two liters
of saline and nitroglycerin.
Are my ears bleeding,
or did you just order fluid
and nitroglycerin
to save his heart?
My-my mistake.
I meant nitric oxide,
and hold on the bolus.
Well, maybe your head
isn't screwed on
so straight after all, Devi.
I'm sorry.
My brain's a little fogged.
Well, un-fog it, Devi.
There's no room for error here,
you hear me?
You are not putting
maggots on me.
I know it sounds medieval,
but these are
pharmaceutical-grade larva.
- They're grown in a lab.
- The maggots
will eat away
at the necrotic tissue.
It's your best chance
to avoid amputation.
You can close your eyes
if that makes it easier.
It won't stop me from feeling
like a decomposing corpse.
Hey, you seem tough.
You can handle a few bugs.
All right.
Get on with it.
I love bugs.
I haven't used sterile maggots
since I was in Afghanistan.
Field medicine at its finest.
I had some experience
with them in Haiti.
Works like a drug, but without
all the undesirable
side effects.
Well, why do I feel sicker
than when I walked in?
All right,
so, by the way,
I think I've found
the perfect solution
for our housing hiccup.
You're gonna love it because it
keeps you totally independent.
I don't remember asking
for your help.
Well, you didn't have to,
but I am prepared
to offer you my mother's house,
no strings attached, not one.
- You can't be serious.
- I know it's a generous offer,
but nothing's too good
for family.
It's a great neighborhood,
top-notch school district,
and, of course, I will pay
all the taxes and upkeep.
Just to clarify,
you want me to move into
your recently deceased
mother's old house?
Well, I can't imagine a better
place for our child to grow up
- than the house I was raised in.
- You are insane.
You didn't hear
a word I said earlier.
I just offered you a free house.
This is not the reaction
I was expecting.
Look, I understand
you're grieving,
so I'm gonna say this
as nicely as I can,
you have crossed a line.
- What're you talking about?
- We clearly have
very different ideas of what
parenthood looks like.
I'm not here to create
your Mini-Me.
I want my own baby.
This was a huge mistake.
I'm sorry.
I don't think
this is gonna work out.
Yeah, private ceremony,
you, me, and a judge.
That could be
just as meaningful.
On the other hand,
the world is so dark and dreary
right now, why would we miss
an opportunity to celebrate?
- Okay, now you're flip-flopping.
- No,
I'm not. I'm weighing all
options, looking at both sides.
Okay, here's what I have to say,
whatever you want,
my answer is, "Yes, dear."
That works both ways.
It can't just be what I want,
or what you want.
We have to find a middle ground,
- together.
- Yes, dear.
Hey.
I need to talk to someone,
and Leela's so busy.
Is everything okay?
No. Everything is terrible.
You're not having regrets
about the embryo implantation,
are you?
I am.
It seems I have chosen
the wrong father.
Okay. What do you mean?
AJ will make
a great dad one day,
just... not to my child.
I shouldn't have
rushed into this.
I should've weighed
all my options.
So Leela told you
about my offer?
Your offer?
I'm still happy to help.
But, look, between you and me,
Leela was not thrilled
when I threw out the idea
of being the sperm donor.
You did what now?
Wait... she didn't tell you?
I'm sorry. I...
I shouldn't have said anything.
Because this would
solve everything.
No. No, it wouldn't.
I promise you, this would
make things much worse,
- for the both of us.
- I mean, I get it's a little...
it's a little crazy, but...
you wouldn't be making
these demands AJ's making.
Padma, listen to me.
I love Leela,
and I don't want to do
anything to hurt her, so...
Please,
just forget that
I said anything.
This is what we live for.
We have to execute flawlessly.
If we do, our patient's life
will be changed
dramatically for the better.
Let's cross our T's
and dot our I's.
This is gonna take a while.
One slip,
and we can do great harm,
so let's focus.
You good?
Fresh as a daisy.
Well, if everyone's bladders
are empty,
let's get a move on.
Maggots are making
some real progress.
Never thought I'd say this,
but I'm glad bugs
are eating my flesh.
And I'm grateful to y'all.
Teri, will you tell us
what you know
about those prescription pills?
Now, see, you had to go
and ruin the moment.
Help us out, and we'll help
keep you safe.
What do you mean safe?
- Did you call the Feds?
- No,
because we understand
why you're afraid.
We know the men
behind this are dangerous.
A pharmacist,
the same one who filled
some of your prescriptions,
was murdered right here
in this hospital.
Her name was Phoebe Moffit.
No, Phoebe?
They killed Phoebe?
You knew her?
She wasn't like them.
She was no different than me.
She was just a good egg
who fell on hard times
and did whatever
she could to survive.
They took advantage of that.
And they're taking
advantage of you, too.
- Aren't they?
- We share a common enemy.
We will protect you.
You can help us
put an end to this,
so no one else has to die,
like Phoebe.
Here's the deal.
I'll tell you what I know,
for Phoebe,
but you got to swear
to keep my name out of it.
It'll be anonymous.
We swear.
Why don't we find somewhere
more private to talk.
Just start from the beginning.
How did the mob find you?
I had some hard times,
made some bad choices.
I got evicted from my home.
I was looking for a place
I could lay my head.
It was supposed to be temporary,
until I got back on my feet,
but it never works out that way,
so I had to figure out
how to make do.
That was when I first saw them.
This sketchy bus showed up.
All right. Y'all know the drill.
Let's see those
red, white, and blues.
I thought they were passing out
free meals or something,
the way everyone
- was carrying on.
- Hey, lady, you got
Medicare?
Maybe. What's it to you?
If you want to make some money,
let's see your card.
Hop on board.
It turns out
"red, white, and blue" is code
for Medicare ID cards
because of their
patriotic coloring.
Oh, I figured it
was some kind of scam,
but... if a hound's
hungry enough,
she'll do anything
for her next meal.
I had no clue where I was going,
but the moment
we made our first stop,
I knew I was in trouble.
Everybody get inside.
It looked more like
a massage parlor
than a medical clinic,
and I figured
any doctor who worked there
shouldn't be
prescribing aspirin,
much less real drugs.
But I quickly learned
that was the point.
Those guys didn't even bother
with an exam.
They just scribbled on a chart
and handed me scrips.
I didn't know what the drugs
were for, so I asked him.
He didn't like that.
After that, I learned
to keep my mouth shut.
Then they dropped us
at a pharmacy
on the other side of town.
That's where I met Phoebe.
All the other customers looked
at us like we were vermin.
But not Phoebe. She was kind.
Never asked any questions.
Her mom was sick.
She needed the money.
We all make mistakes.
I guess she paid for hers.
Oh, those bastards
are scarier than hell.
Taron especially.
If you want your fee,
have your bags and prescriptions
ready to be counted.
First time?
Welcome to the team.
Yeah.
Now, come back next week,
there's more
where that came from.
And if you say anything
to the cops, you'll regret it.
Understand?
I've been around the block,
and I knew the pills
in my hand were worth
a hell of a lot more
than 50 bucks.
So, I kept a little on the side.
For street resale,
you know what I mean?
Did anyone else keep pills
for themselves?
Yeah, we all skimmed.
Who were we cheating?
Bunch of crooks.
That explains why
we've seen patients O.D.
with those pills
in their pocket.
And why you had a cancer drug
with no cancer diagnosis.
Where did they take the pills?
I only saw the place once,
from the outside.
Eventually, my curiosity
got the best of me.
And-and, one day, I finally
saw them by some warehouse.
My guess is that's where
the mob does its dirty work.
Got to count the pills,
they repackage them,
and then they resell them
back to the pharmacies
for up to ten times
the original price.
This is it.
All the answers
we've been searching for.
Once the FBI knows this...
They'll shut that operation down
in a heartbeat.
But just remember our deal:
You can tell the FBI,
but keep my name out of it.
Almost done with the
high T-spine pedicle screws.
Let's shoot another
fluoro image.
How are those screws
coming along?
You're getting a little close.
We need to leave half an inch
more between those screws.
Dr. Devi...
Dr. Devi!
- What happened?
- You fell asleep.
There's a massive bleed
in Ashley's spine.
Cautery to me, now.
We need two units of reds
up and hanging.
- She's bleeding fast.
- No, no, no.
I asked you if you were ready
for this. You lied to me.
- I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. I'm so...
- Go home, Dr. Devi, now.
This is extraordinary.
With what you just told us,
we should have enough
to get warrants,
run surveillance, and with luck,
bring down the entire drug ring.
- Thank you both.
- Well, we're not the ones
you should thank.
Yeah, well, tell your source
that the Bureau
- is eternally grateful.
- We'll pass along the message.
Always a pleasure, Dr. Sullivan.
I hope for both our sake this is
the last time we work together.
If you ever want
to hang up that white coat,
there's a wide world
of Medicare fraud out there.
I prefer a stethoscope
over a handgun.
Wise choice.
Look at you.
Saving lives and bringing down
the mob at the same time.
- It was a team effort.
- Listen,
I know what you said about
not wanting to get comfortable,
but our job is done.
It's time to start
living your life.
- Same could be said of you.
- Oh.
Okay, that's fair,
but I have a life,
it's just centered
around my daughter.
No way.
What?
- Is that the guy who killed Phoebe?
- Yeah.
He saw us with the FBI.
He saw me.
Leela.
- I need to talk to you.
- Take a number.
I have a lot of sins
to account for today.
Devon told me everything,
about his offer.
I cannot believe
- he told you.
- Well, the question is,
why didn't you?
Can we not do this
right now, please?
No, we're actually
gonna do this now.
Okay.
I didn't tell you
because it's insane.
And I... I thought
of all people,
you would agree.
I don't, actually.
Look, this thing with AJ,
it's-it's really
not working out.
And Devon could be
a good option for us.
For us?
No,
it is not a good option for us.
It is a good option for you
- and only you.
- Look, I know it's
complicated, okay?
But Devon's offer solves
- a lot of problems.
- Oh, my God.
Padma, would you listen
to yourself.
I have given you everything,
even the freaking eggs
from my body,
but we cannot share this.
I will not
give you Devon.
Unexpected complications?
What does that mean?
One of the screws used
to reconstruct Ashley's spine
caused a significant amount
of bleeding.
- Will she be okay?
- Yes. With a little rest,
I have no doubt your wife
will make a full recovery.
That's a relief. Thank you.
Um, where's Dr. Sutton?
She got pulled into
an emergency surgery,
but she'll be by
as soon as she can.
And Dr. Devi?
You can spend the night
in Ashley's room, if you like.
The hospital will provide a cot.
Loved ones help
the healing process.
Call if you need anything.
So, I-I got your text.
Did you know Dr. Devi
was pulling double duty in
cardiothoracic and neurosurgery?
I think everybody was aware.
But Leela is
an excellent surgeon.
She's...
she's just trying to do more
and be better
than any human can be.
Today, her patient paid
the price for that arrogance.
What happened in the OR
could've been catastrophic.
I know, I agree,
and so does Billie.
We've had many conversations
about her stretching herself
too thin.
It's past time someone had
that conversation with Leela.
She has to make a decision,
or I will make it for her.
Hey.
You don't look so good.
I'm not.
I've lost everything today.
My future child
and my own sister.
May I join you?
Listen.
I grew up in foster care.
- I didn't know that.
- Moved from house to house,
never had a place to call home.
It made me resentful and angry
because all I wanted
was stability, right?
So, the very idea of you
raising our child
in a van...
Well, it was triggering.
I see.
And I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, too.
You know, I-I made this about
my past when it should've been
about your future.
But you did ask me
to be the father,
not some stranger.
So, you would have to
meet me halfway.
Padma, I can't help you
bring a child
into this world
and then abandon it.
This would be your baby
as much as it would be mine.
And you should tell your story.
But I cannot watch
my child grow up
from the sidelines.
I need a relationship,
a connection.
And if that's not what
you're looking for,
then I'm willing
to bow out gracefully.
But you are going to
have to find someone else.
You're a good man, Dr. Austin.
I think our child
should witness that firsthand.
Our child?
- You sure about that?
- You were right.
It was wrong of me to trivialize
your involvement.
It takes a village
to raise a child,
if you're still willing.
Absolutely, I am.
But just so you know,
the van is a deal-breaker.
Fine, but you need to ease up
on the Ivy League talk.
Let's let our child decide
what their future looks like.
Hey, you saying you don't want
a 529 account?
I never said that.
God knows how much college
is gonna cost in 18 years.
- What are your options?
- I leave tonight.
It may seem impulsive,
but I'm pretty sure that's how
- I've stayed alive so far.
- That's one option.
What else?
I quit running.
Try to build a life for myself.
Make friends
I can keep over time,
put down roots.
But I'd risk that, one day,
I'd find myself
bleeding on the pavement.
I don't want to go.
I've felt more at home here
than I did as a kid
in my own home, honestly.
What was your home like?
My parents divorced
when I was young.
Same here.
I was raised by my dad,
a man-child genius surgeon.
I was the gardener,
he was the flower.
Mm, the dots are connecting.
All this will be over soon.
Why are you still running?
We spoke to Agent Barker.
They have everything they need
to shut this down,
and your FBI protection
is right outside.
They're gonna put me
in a hotel for the night.
Try and find the man we saw
and arrest him.
And when they do...
...you could stay.
Create that life you want, here.
The people who want to kill me
have more than one soldier.
I hear that.
I'm so tired.
Tired of running.
Tired of... fear.
Why don't you just
give it the night?
I'll walk you out,
make sure the FBI tail's
got your back.
Yeah, just this once.
Hey.
You're up.
I thought you'd be
passed out by now.
I slept for a few hours.
I'm awake now.
- So, how'd your surgery go?
- I don't know.
I was asked to leave after
I nearly paralyzed my patient.
What happened?
It doesn't matter.
Kit gave me a week
to pick a specialty.
So, you were right.
I can't do it all.
You push yourself too hard.
It's as if you have
something to prove.
I do have something to prove.
I know you talked to Padma.
Why would you go behind
my back like that?
You knew exactly how I felt.
How would I?
You don't even talk
to me about it.
I should not have to explain
why I don't want my boyfriend
to have a baby
- with my sister.
- That's not true.
I was trying to help,
and I wish I never had.
But why can't you be honest
with me about it?
You do not want me
to be honest with you, Devon.
Well, what is that
supposed to mean?
I don't want kids.
Not now, not in a few years,
maybe never, okay?
So, you lied to me.
I think, deep down,
we both knew.
- I didn't know.
- Why else would you offer
to father
another woman's baby?
This isn't about Padma.
You led me on.
Made me think that
there was a chance.
A future for us.
And now there isn't?
A future for us?
I love you.
But not enough.
You want a baby
more than you want me.
I want you.
I want us.
But I also want
a family one day,
and I never hid that from you.
I'm not gonna apologize for it.
I'm not going to apologize
for wanting something different.
So, what are you saying then?
That this is it?
This is the end?
Yeah. I guess I am.
So, we haven't got a verdict
on the venue,
but we both agree it should...
- Be small.
- We'll invite a few friends
and figure the rest out
as we go.
Either way,
it's gonna be perfect.
Well, not quite.
Oh, don't be ridiculous.
I would hate
to disappoint you, darling.
That would be a terrible way
to start a marriage.
Randolph Bell,
will you marry me?
Thank God...
...because I can't return this.
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org