BEADIE's "Roll With
The Good Times" plays...
♪♪
♪ Baby, you know how I roll ♪
♪ Go and get
the gas tank full ♪
Meredith: Transplant surgeons
typically transport
donor organs by carefully
packing them on ice
and racing as fast as they can
- to the recipient.
- ♪ Shining in the sun, sun ♪
♪ Maybe we should ♪
♪ Go and make some fun, fun ♪
The organ can only survive
a certain amount of time
until it's placed
into its new body.
- Oh!
At best, the heart and lungs
only have four to six hours.
- Link!
- Jules?
- [ Sighs ]
- Hey, uh...
- Hey.
- Yeah.
I said I would call, and...
And I meant to,
- but...
- Oh, it's okay.
No, I'm not here for you.
Um, I actually just...
I work here now.
Don't suppose you could
point me to the scrubs?
Actually, never mind. I recognize
her from the interviews. Bye.
Hi. Hi.
I'm Jules Millin.
Mika Yasuda.
Think I might have, um,
accidentally slept
with an attending already.
You work fast.
- ♪ Got nowhere to be ♪
- But recently,
- ♪ Aall day ♪
- scientists have developed machines
that can improve
these odds.
Oh!
I really needed coffee.
♪ You look so fine ♪
♪ Coming my way ♪
Essentially, certain organs
can now travel in a box
that continuously
perfuses them with nutrients,
preserving their viability.
Hey.
I'm Lucas Adams.
Or Luke.
Just don't call me Skywalker.
- [ Chuckles ]
- ♪ Bum rum rum rum rum ♪
♪ Bum rum rum rum rum ♪
First day.
Who's nervous?
Wow, who is a ten
but he won't shut up?
What was that?
- Nothing.
- What'd she say?
[ Man chuckles ]
- What was so funny?
- Nothing.
Now, come on.
[ Sighs ]
Just... sizing up the competition
and liking my odds.
[ Chuckles ]
Because I said hello?
Don't worry, Skywalker.
Jules here already slept
with an attending.
♪♪
Wow.
You didn't say
it was a secret.
♪♪
This innovation has allowed us
to increase
the number of organs
available for transplantation.
♪ Boom-clap, tick-tack ♪
♪ Spin it all around
then jump back ♪
♪ One-two, nine-ten ♪
♪ If you wanna groove
just climb in ♪
♪ One-two, nine-ten ♪
♪ If you wanna groove
just climb in ♪
♪ Climb in ♪
♪♪
♪ Just roll with the good times,
yeah ♪
♪ Roll, roll
with the good times, yeah ♪
- Hey, Dr. Griffith.
- [ Shoes squeak ]
Slow down.
You're creating a safety hazard.
Sorry... Late... Tornado.
The tornado was yesterday.
Yes, sir.
Alright.
- ♪ Bum rum rum rum rum ♪
- Uh, the door.
♪ Bum rum rum rum rum ♪
And for over a hundred thousand
people in this country
who are currently waiting
for an organ...
♪ Bum rum rum rum rum ♪
...it's a chance at a new life.
♪♪
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 19  Episode 01
Episode Title:
"Everything has Changed"
Aired on:
October 06, 2022.
[ Clicks, electricity humming ]
Congratulations.
You all made it.
You're here.
♪♪
I know this OR looks like
a high-tech fever dream,
but it's all real and very
expensive, so don't touch...
That scanner cost
as much as my house.
I see and appreciate your awe,
but all of this high-tech
equipment is useless
without highly skilled
surgeons to operate it.
It's useless without you.
You will use it
to save lives.
You will use it to end them
because that's the game
we're in.
When we have a bad day,
we end a life.
You knew that and you went
to med school anyway,
and that makes you brave.
We didn't pick you
for your grades.
We picked you for your fight.
We're all getting
a second chance here today.
We're...
♪♪
Griffith.
Thanks for joining us.
I'm not sure interrupting
my opening speech
is a great way to start off.
Do you want
to explain yourself?
The tornado created
a family situation, Chief Grey.
I assure you,
won't happen again.
Let's allow for some extra time
in the morning, Griffith.
If you want to succeed here,
learn to expect the unexpected.
- That goes for all of you.
- Hmm.
- Now a bit about...
- Bailey! [ Gasps ]
- Are you back?!
- Man: Hey.
Do I look like I'm back?
No. No, I heard about
the new class, the new OR.
Couldn't resist coming
to see for myself.
Oh, looks like we all had
the same idea.
Okay,
I see baby surgeons.
I see
an attending surgeon.
Where are
the senior residents?
Well, we're still working
on recruiting senior residents.
Our prior class is all happy
in their new residencies.
- [ Screaming ]
- Push! Push! Push!
Ah. Okay. Okay, Dr. Schmitt,
don't forget to brace the head.
Oh.
Fix your face, Schmitt.
Okay. Okay, Rhadha,
one more big push.
And... let's go.
One.
[ Rhadha screaming ]
Okay, oh!
[ Sighs ]
- I...
- No.
- I'm sorry. I have to.
- You promised!
- I vouched for you!
- I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
[ Stammers ]
Schmitt!
You went gallivanting
around the world
while your wife
threw a mountain of money
at new surgical equipment.
Then you opened up
the residency program
six months
before you should have.
You made a residency class
from the bottom of the barrel...
The rejects.
Yeah, that smacks
of desperation.
I will not cosign.
Well, look, they are
an excellent group, Bailey.
They are a carefully
cultivated group.
We got hundreds
of applications,
and we combed through them
to find the gems.
This class... they may not have
gotten straight A's like you,
but they have stories
and they have heart.
They have empathy.
And when you're trying to build
a solid surgeon,
that counts for a lot.
And I would highly recommend
gallivanting around the world.
It changes your thinking.
It just... It opens up your...
Your mind.
You're telling me
I'm closed-minded?
I-I did no such thing.
Dr. Webber!
I promised Jo Wilson that if she
got me a spot in OB-GYN,
I would see
the residency through,
no matter when the surgery
program opened back up.
So, presently,
I'm risking not only my job,
but also my friendship.
That being said, I hate it.
I hate it so much.
You need
senior surgical residents.
I... I might so far as to say
you need a Chief Resident.
And if you make me him,
I will be mean.
I will be bossy.
And if I'm ever tempted
to go soft,
I will picture a return to OB,
and I will get stronger.
Stronger like a vagina,
which I've been forced to learn
can stretch to 200 times
its natural size
and lift a 30 pound weight
just by flexing.
I'll be the vagina...
of the program
if you'd let me.
Or, um, you might, um,
prefer the term backbone, sir.
I wish you all
the best of luck.
♪♪
You'll need to speak
to Chief Grey, Schmitt.
And, um,
I would suggest you...
modify the...
The speech there.
[ Clears throat ]
Yesterday's tornado
came out of nowhere
and blew a bus off a cliff.
The bus flipped over and landed
after a 20-foot drop,
and because
many of the passengers
were not wearing seat belts,
we have an inordinate number
of patients
who may have experienced
catastrophic brain injury.
How do we declare
brain death?
Dr. Kwan.
Numerous criteria
must be met
before determination
of brain death,
including at least
two clinical exams
and a confirmatory test
such as a brain scan.
Correct.
How many are there?
We raise our hands and we wait
to be called on, Dr. Adams.
It may seem infantilizing,
but it maintains
a necessary pecking order
that keeps people alive.
Dr. Adams.
How many are potentially
brain-dead?
- 14.
- Whoa.
Well, how many are donors?
Dr. Griffith.
How many of those 14
are potential organ donors?
- Nine.
- Whoa. Organpalooza. [ Chuckles ]
I can't overstate
how inappropriate that is.
I have a dark sense
of humor.
You don't get to talk
for the rest of the day.
- I was just...
- I mean it.
Every one of those organs
came from a person
who was living
their life yesterday.
A person with family and friends
who are devastated today
and praying
for a miracle.
- I'm so sorry. I...
- Don't be sorry.
Just don't talk.
[ Siren wailing in distance ]
We'll ask the families to move
to the waiting room
while we run
confirmatory tests.
We have already alerted
the OPO for potential donors.
We have transplant surgeons
on standby
from all over the country
to make sure
that not one precious,
life-giving organ goes to waste.
♪♪
[ Monitors beeping ]
This just got super real.
♪♪
♪ Ooh-ooh ♪
Amelia: No blood flow on
the transcranial Doppler.
Adams, his mother is
in the waiting area.
Uh, you want me to tell her
that her son is brain-dead?
You will take time and care.
You will be kind.
You will be gentle,
and you will be clear.
That goes for all of you.
♪ It's not what you know ♪
♪ No, no ♪
♪ So young ♪
♪ It's what you have ♪
No spontaneous respiratory
effort,
hypercarbia,
and no ocular reflexes.
She's gone.
Griffith, her husband
was also in the accident.
He is a post-op
surgical patient.
♪ The waiting weighs ♪
♪ Believe me ♪
♪ It wasn't mine,
and now it's yours ♪
No cough reflex.
Kwan...
On it.
♪ The age is new,
it grows with you, maybe ♪
♪ Growing always has
its pains, baby ♪
♪ No hidden meaning,
no trick to reveal ♪
♪ And that's the deal ♪
♪ And I say ♪
Amelia:
Her eyes are tracking.
She still has
some brain activity.
She's not brain-dead.
She is not dead.
Oh, thank God.
Mm-hmm.
♪ You're not alone ♪
[ Breathes sharply ]
♪♪
Hey, I rounded
on your post-ops,
and Mrs. Shaugnessy
says her incision hurts,
but there's no sign
of infection,
- so I just upped her morphine for today.
- Okay.
Oh, and Mr., uh, Mulligan
asked me
to thank you again for...
Why... Why are you pacing?
Oh, 'cause, um, I think
we have a match for Howard.
And I love Howard.
And, um, you know,
I'm just bursting to tell him,
but it's not official yet.
And I also don't want it
to seem like
I'm rooting
for somebody's death, so...
I'm not.
Uh, Dr. Pierce?
Yes.
I recognized you
from that article you wrote
about racial disparities in
outcomes after bypass surgery. Yes.
Well, wasn't a great picture.
[ Chuckles ]
Okay. I'm saying
that I recognized you
even though that photo
looks nothing like you
because I am a huge fan
of that paper.
I read it three times.
- You are... brilliant.
- Oh.
And, uh, I'm Dr. Jules Millin.
I'm a first year
surgical intern.
Winston: Dr. Millin,
are you just fangirling
or did you come here
to tell her something?
Oh, sorry.
Yes.
Um, I was told to tell you
that we got a call from UNOS...
You have a heart
for Howard?
Is Howard Mr. Jones?
Yes!
Yay! Yay, yay!
- Winston, will you...
- Yeah, I'll... I'll...
- I'll start the paperwork.
- Yeah.
- [ Sighs ] Oh, my gosh.
- Uh, Dr. Pierce, um,
can I please join you?
I just had to tell a family
the worst news of their life,
and I could really use
some of the opposite.
[ Telephone rings in distance ]
Ms. Milton, I'm Dr. Yasuda.
Your daughter Marina
is showing distinct signs
of brain activity.
Her eyes are fixating
on stationary objects.
But... But I saw everyone.
I saw all the other parents.
You're... You're saying
there's a chance she might live?
She might live through this?
We're continuing
to make adjustments
to her ventilator
and her medications
and hoping
the brain swelling comes down.
And, yes, there is a chance
that she might live.
[ Sighs ]
I'm...
too afraid to hope.
♪♪
Okay.
I get that.
How about if I hope for you?
I have seven sisters, and one
of them is around Marina's age.
So I will hope for Marina
the way I would hope
for my own sister.
♪♪
Um, I'll keep you posted.
[ Crying ]
Don't mind him.
He's a cry baby.
[ Crying ] I am.
It's okay.
I'm emotional, too.
[ Laughs ]
You've waited so long
for this, Howard.
I honestly didn't think
this day would come.
Dr. Millin,
why don't you check
Howard's blood pressure
while we're here?
What is it...
Bring your kid to work day?
Our surgical residency program
just opened back up today,
so we finally
have interns again.
You look 12.
Are you 12?
Uh, no, sir.
[ Chuckles ]
We're just old, babe.
We're so old that the young
adults look like children.
And now you'll get to grow
even older together.
[ Crying ]
Oh, no.
- He had just stopped.
- Sorry.
[ Crying continues ]
Yay! They're here!
The black scrubs
are here!
Who are the black scrubs
for?
Uh, for me, for OB.
The female body has become
a war zone in this country,
and pink
is a peacetime color.
Got it.
So it's a statement.
No, it's more a
state of mind. Yeah.
Need some help?
I'm good. You?
Actually, yeah, I do.
Um, do you remember that girl
from Saturday night?
Um, the blonde?
No, that was Thursday.
Oh, um...
Oh, oh, yeah!
The one that kind of looks
like the Snow White
- to your Prince Charming?
- Yeah.
And she had a Disney princessy
kind of name.
- Jules.
- Yes!
Yeah. Turns out
she works here now.
[ Elevator bell dings ]
Doing what?
Surgical intern.
[ Laughing ] Oh, my God!
[ Chuckles ]
I'm... I'm fired, right?
I should just go
pack my things?
You didn't know when you
brought her into our home
that she was
an incoming resident?
Well, there were drinks.
The bar was loud.
She might have said it,
and I might have nodded
like I heard it.
With your old man ears?
That hurts. Okay,
so what am I supposed to do?
Get ahead of it.
Talk to the chief.
Woman on P. A.:
Dr. Coen to PEDs ICU.
Dr. Coen, report to PEDs ICU,
please.
- Oh, hey, man.
- Nick: Hey.
- [ Chuckling ] Hey.
- How you doing?
Good.
Good, good, good.
Hell of a day, man.
Yeah, yeah.
It's been a while
since I've seen you.
Yeah.
What do we do now?
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Dr. Ndugu,
may I join you?
I would love to see
what's involved with procuring
an organ
for a transplant.
Yeah,
I guess that's fine.
- Yeah.
- What, me too?
- O-Okay.
- Yeah.
[ Sighs ]
Man, I've never seen
a line like this.
Yeah, it's pretty crazy.
I've never heard of eight donors
in one hospital in one day.
Freak storm, you know?
Terrible day.
- 40 lives.
- You said what?
It's the worst math.
It's transplant surgeon math.
We do it to comfort
ourselves.
8 deaths
saves up to 40 lives,
and that's not including
skin and corneas.
So, yes, it is a horrible day,
but it is also a beautiful day,
and it all coexists.
That is
a little comforting.
[ Telephone ringing
in distance ]
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ Chuckles ]
So how's everything been here,
uh, since the shut down?
[ Sighs ] Honestly, man,
it's been awful.
I mean, a teaching hospital
with no residents?
You know who ends up
with all the scut?
- The junior attending.
- Mm.
You know who ends up
holding the clamps?
The junior attending.
And you know when that starts
to feel like hell?
When the woman you love
is your boss.
[ Chuckles ]
So it's been rough.
I honestly just think I was
asking how Meredith's been.
Oh. Oh, yeah.
Okay. Um, good.
She's a...
She's a good chief.
So she made that job official,
did she?
Her title is interim chief,
but, you know, six months in,
feels pretty official.
- Got it.
- Yeah.
[ Respirator hissing ]
♪♪
Yeah.
I do, I understand.
It's just my patient has been
waiting longer,
and her cardiac and liver
function are deteriorating fast.
Also, the donor is
in this hospital.
Yes, I will hold.
- Um, I need you alone.
- Link was here first.
Oh, uh, yeah,
I... I just...
I slept with an intern.
But I didn't know
she was an intern.
It was... It was before.
It was not today.
It was...
Wow. This is awkward. Um...
I'm in no position
to judge you on this.
I do recommend you stay away
from elevators
for the foreseeable
future.
Go to HR. They have paperwork
for this kind of thing.
- Thank you.
- Mm.
Good luck.
Nick's here.
He's here.
Nick Marsh!
Don't try to be calm,
and don't try to be chiefly.
The man you love is here,
waiting for an organ
in the surgical corridor.
Of course he is.
Half the transplant surgeons
in the country are here.
Well, then go talk to him,
Meredith.
I'm on the phone
with UNOS.
There's a triple organ match
for Sarah Martinez.
They're saying someone's
in line ahead of her.
Meredith, you have been sad
for six months.
Even Zola has noticed.
Last week, she asked me
for Nick's phone number
so that she could call him
and explain to him
why you never
went to Minnesota
and that maybe he would
understand and come and visit.
And now he's here.
And you love him.
Don't be an idiot.
You never told me
that story.
- Yes, I'm here.
- Yes! Thank you so much.
- Thank you.
- Levi: Dr. Grey. [ Door closes ]
Um, sorry to interrupt.
Yes.
Uh, I have carefully considered,
and I feel...
[ Inhales deeply ]
- You hate OB.
- More than I hate war.
You'd make a good
chief resident.
Seriously?
[ Woman speaking indistinctly
over P. A. ]
[ Indistinct conversations ]
♪♪
- Hi.
- Hello.
♪♪
Dr. Adams.
Did you bring the patient
down... Liam Collins?
Yes, Chief.
They're prepping him now.
♪♪
- Dr. Marsh?
- Mm-hmm?
- I just got off the phone with UNOS.
- Uh-huh.
I have a triple organ transplant
match for my patient,
Sarah Martinez.
It's the first day
of the new residency program,
and I can't really disappear
into an OR for 25 hours.
So if you'd be willing
to take point on this,
then I can find someone
to transport your organ
back to Minnesota?
[ Exhales deeply, laughs ]
A triple organ transplant,
that's what we're talking about?
Those are super rare,
yeah?
♪♪
Uh, ok...
Um, do you feel comfortable
taking the liver
back to Minnesota?
It's for Chen. It's his patient.
He's doing the transplant.
- No problem.
- Okay.
I will scrub in.
Great.
This is... very helpful.
Good.
Shall we go and meet
Sarah Martinez and her family
and deliver the good news?
- Let's do it.
- Okay.
- Dr. Ndugu.
- Dr. Grey.
♪♪
That is not how I thought
that would go.
No.
Who has patient number 35467,
Liam Collins?
Oh, that's me.
Or, um...
I just sent him off
to pre-op.
- Why didn't you talk to his family?
- I did.
You didn't.
His mom is in the ICU,
screaming
at Dr. Shepherd.
What? No, I...
Okay, I know I definitely spoke
to somebody's mother.
Congratulations
on your first day...
I...
...and also your last.
Gotta be some sort of record,
right?
- Nope?
- Okay.
I really am so sorry.
I don't know how this happened,
- but I w... I will...
- [ Crying ] You will what?
What can you possibly do
to fix this?
Mrs. Collins,
I know that you have suffered
the worst loss
of your life today,
and my intern made
a terrible mistake
in speaking
to the wrong parent,
but I did do the final
round of tests on your son.
I did declare him
brain-dead.
How am I supposed
to trust you?
I wasn't given the chance to say
goodbye to my child.
How am I supposed
to trust your tests
when you and your staff
are capable
of making this kind
of mistake?!
[ Crying ]
Oh, my sweetheart.
Okay.
Oh, my sweet love.
[ Crying ]
Ma'am, I am so sorry.
Mrs. Collins, uh,
would you like me
to run
the last test again?
I would like you to run
all the tests again.
This is Dr. Grey's
triple organ match.
Then you had better
go talk to Dr. Grey.
♪♪
Go with him, please.
Make sure he doesn't
screw this up, too.
♪♪
[ Sighs ]
Davis: Group hug!
[ Laughter ]
Everyone joins.
Oh, everyone join.
[ Laughs ]
I don't know who you are,
but those
are the rules of group hug.
Davis, you're embarrassing
yourself.
I can live with that.
And it's all three organs?
She's getting
all three of them?
- Today?
- Meredith: Yes.
Well, if you don't crush
her surgeons first.
[ Laughter ]
Oh, jeez.
Oh.
♪♪
Say it again. I want
to make sure I understand.
I spoke with the wrong family,
and so Liam's mom
almost didn't get
a chance to say goodbye.
And so she's...
She's upset.
I'm sure "upset"
doesn't begin to cover
how that woman feels
right now.
Okay. Is she saying
goodbye to him now?
- No.
- No?
I need more, Adams.
Uh, I-I'm sorry.
I'm... I'm so sorry.
Dr. Adams, save your shame
for after your shift.
Your shame spiral is about you,
and right now,
we need it to be
all about our patients.
You understand?
Griffith?
The mom asked Dr. Shepherd
to run all of the tests again.
Is she doing that?
It felt like if she didn't,
the organs would not
be donated.
Okay,
what's the patient's status?
He's brain-dead.
I... Yes, I understand that,
but were his vitals stable?
Do you understand
why he's asking that?
He's asking you that because
if the patient codes...
If the patient's heart stops
before Dr. Shepherd's
finished running the tests,
then you get to be
the one who goes in
and tells that family that
their one-in-a-million match
just got wasted
because of your error.
Stop looking at me
like that.
Go help Dr. Shepherd!
♪♪
[ Vomits ]
[ Sighs, sniffles ]
Mrs. Collins
has her family doctor here now,
and she wants him
to sign off on the tests.
She does not trust us
as far as she can kick us,
and I cannot blame her.
[ Breathes sharply ]
Dr. Griffith.
I'll go get him.
Mm-hmm.
They had the same name.
And Mrs. Collins,
her first name is Jane,
and I said,
"Are you Jane?"
And the other lady,
she said yes,
and I guess
they had the same name.
You used the first name.
Well, I was trying to be
more personal
because I was about to tell her
her son was brain-dead.
Yeah, but you can see now
why we don't do that.
Yes.
Meanwhile,
who did you talk to?
Is there someone named Jane
walking around now who...
Who thinks that her child
is brain-dead...
- No, no.
- ...and he isn't?
No. I checked.
Her name is Jane Miller
and her son is brain-dead...
too.
Mrs. Collins?
Dr. Shepherd sent me.
This is our family doctor,
Dr. Shagrin.
Dr. Shagrin,
I'm Dr. Griffith.
We're hoping we could get
your opinion.
I know time
is of the essence.
Lead the way.
[ Telephone ringing
in distance ]
- ♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
- [ Elevator bell dings ]
Oh, sorry. Coming through.
Thank you so much.
Oh, yield, please!
On your right.
Excuse us. Just gonna...
Thanks so much.
And corner!
Coming in hot!
Old guy, sorry.
Don't got time.
♪ Got me walking on a thread ♪
Oh, gotta part the sea, y'all.
Thank you.
Oh, sorry. Excuse us
on the right, or the left.
Excuse... Dr. Shepherd!
♪ Like you mean it, mean it ♪
♪ Lasso ♪
♪ Drag me all over town ♪
♪ Yeah,
you really drag me down ♪
- ♪ And I feel it, feel it ♪
- [ Elevator bell dings ]
♪♪
Crap, wrong floor.
♪ I want it all ♪
Excuse me. Come on!
Come on.
♪ I want it, want it, want it ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪♪
[ Telephone ringing
in distance ]
Mrs. Collins...
I am so deeply sorry
for your loss,
but Dr. Shagrin
has confirmed...
[ Crying ]
[ Sobbing loudly ]
Mrs. Collins...
my name
is Dr. Benson Kwan,
and I lost my brother
in an accident...
[Voice breaking]
...when he was only 16.
[ Crying ]
It was devastating, and my life
was never the same.
And there is nothing
anyone can say
that can take
your pain away,
but the lives my brother saved
when he donated his organs?
[ Crying continues ]
I think about them.
I still think about the
little girl who got his heart,
the teenage boy
who got his kidney,
and the grandmother
who got his liver.
Because those people
give his death
some little bit
of meaning.
♪♪
And I cling to that.
I cling to it
after all these years.
♪♪
Tell Dr. Shepherd
I consent.
♪♪
Thank you.
Your brother just saved
a whole bunch more lives.
Never had a brother,
but you're welcome.
I want in on
the triple organ transplant.
What does your gut say?
My gut? Uh...
My gut says she's getting
her organs today.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
Well, I don't know.
Sometimes my gut is wrong.
I shouldn't have told you
to go back to Minnesota.
I called after you.
You didn't hear me.
Oh, I... I heard you.
♪♪
- You did?
- Yeah, I heard you.
Yeah, but...
♪♪
I was hurt. I was.
I wanted you to do more
than call my name.
I wanted you
to put in some effort.
It was a bad day.
[ Chuckles ]
It's been six months.
It's been a very difficult
six months.
Mm-hmm.
And you know how
I'm so stubborn and so proud.
Same.
- Uh, you got approval.
- I got approval.
- Okay.
- Excuse you?
- We both got approval.
- Yeah.
Meredith: Okay, well, you both
can be in the surgery.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
I thought I was lead surgeon.
- You are.
- Okay.
Yes. He...
You can both
be in the surgery.
- [ Breathes sharply ]
- Okay, let's go.
- Let's go.
- Yeah.
I read that they can turn
your body into a pod
and plant you as fertilizer
for a tree,
and that's what I want.
What?
Mom, don't be morose.
It's not morose.
It's what I want.
I want to be a tree
that you and the kids
and all the grand kids
can picnic under.
I want to make oxygen
and fight global warming.
I don't want to
become pollution,
and that's what a casket is,
and that's what cremation is.
It's land pollution,
and it's air pollution.
If I die today,
or when I die whenever,
just remember, sweetheart,
I want to be a tree.
I want to watch
over our family.
♪♪
Forever.
You ready?
[ Breathing heavily ]
I'm ready.
♪♪
[ Crying ]
[ Sighs ]
It's a no.
Uh, you said it's a no?
Dr. Millin, would you like
to close the chest?
What? The heart has
hematomas everywhere.
It is not usable
for transplant.
I can close,
Dr. Pierce.
Nonsense. She knows how to do
a running subcuticular stitch.
I'm sure she's practiced
on a thousand oranges.
Human flesh
is a little bit firmer.
You're gonna have to pull
a little bit harder.
Uh, what about Howard?
You'll explain to Howard
and his husband
that Howard will remain
on the transplant list,
but today was not his day.
B-But his husband
couldn't stop crying.
I know. It sucks.
But we take the good
with the bad here, Dr. Millin.
Schmitt, keep an eye.
[ Monitor beeping ]
O-Okay.
Um, 4-0 Monocryl, please.
You say please to Bokhee!
I did.
Right here. There.
They just keep
getting younger.
Right?
Adams, what are you doing?
I screwed up. I just want
to make sure she's okay.
You want to scrub in?
[ Scoffs ] For real?
'Cause I'm pretty sure
I'm getting fired later.
[ Chuckles ]
Well, if they haven't fired you
yet, you still got a shot.
Look, here's the deal.
We all have bad days.
We all make mistakes.
You just got to learn
from them.
You learn from them,
you're good.
Right?
What'd you learn today?
[ Scoffs ] Uh.
Raise my hand
before talking,
save the shame
for the end of the day,
and use full names
when speaking with next of kin.
Yes. Okay.
That's good.
Come on.
End your day better
than it started.
Okay? Let's go.
- Come on, let's go!
- [ Chuckles ]
[ Water running ]
[ Chuckles ]
♪♪
[ Pen clicking ]
Okay, so this is going to be
a long, arduous surgery.
Let's pace ourselves.
And say a prayer now
if you're the praying kind.
The donor is Liam Collins.
He loved rugby,
and he loved science.
The recipient is Sarah Martinez,
and she loves nature,
and she's about to be
a grandmother.
It's a beautiful day
to save lives.
♪♪
It's a beautiful day
to save lives.
♪♪
Derek was a God to him.
- I know.
- Man: Scalpel.
And Lucas was
Derek's favorite nephew,
and I do love him,
so I hate to keep saying this,
but I don't think
he has what it takes.
I know you don't.
He's a mess.
He doesn't follow
instructions.
He has to do everything
his own way.
Did you hire him because
he reminds you of Derek?
No. Not Derek.
He is a mess. He does need
to do things his own way.
Mm-hmm. But he also has
a stroke of the family genius.
- And he's a bit of a black sheep.
- [ Sighs ]
You don't see it, do you?
♪♪
Is that why
he drives me crazy?
[ Chuckles ]
He's me.
Yes, he's you.
He's got the spark.
He's got the drive.
He just needs a chance.
I had to be watched very closely
at that age.
Great.
Are you volunteering?
- Because I accept.
- [ Laughing ] No, I was not volunt...
Too late.
- I already accepted.
- [ Sighs ]
[ Humming ]
♪♪
♪ Call me a fool for thinking
maybe I could get over ♪
♪♪
♪ I could be stronger
than the fear in my mind ♪
♪♪
♪ And she said,
"Keep on getting stronger ♪
♪ Keep on getting wiser,
my dear" ♪
♪♪
♪ Don't give in to the voices ♪
♪ Or succumb to your fears ♪
♪ Oh, sing with me now ♪
♪ For the change I can become ♪
♪♪
♪ Oh, sing with me now ♪
♪ For the change
has just begun ♪
♪♪
[ Monitor beeping ]
[ Breathes sharply ]
We have a heartbeat.
- Yes!
- [ Laughs ]
- Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
- Whoo!
Alright!
♪♪
♪ Oh, sing with me now ♪
♪ For the change I can become ♪
♪♪
♪ Oh, sing with me now ♪
♪ For the change
has just begun ♪
♪♪
♪ Mm-hmm ♪
♪ But do you see me,
oh, Lord ♪
♪ When I look to you
for an answer? ♪
♪♪
♪ I need you to tell me
how to carry on ♪
♪♪
♪ And he said,
"Keep on getting stronger ♪
♪ Keep on getting wiser,
my dear" ♪
♪♪
♪ Don't give in to the voices ♪
♪ Or succumb to your fears ♪
♪ Oh, sing with me now ♪
♪ For the change I can become ♪
♪♪
Man: Weaning off ECMO.
♪ Oh, sing with me now ♪
♪ For the change
has just begun ♪
Woman: Vitals are stable.
[ Cheers and applause ]
- Whoo-hoo!
- Alright!
[ Cheering intensifies ]
Woman: Nice.
♪♪
- Whoo!
- Yes!
♪♪
[ Sighs ]
[ Door opens ]
Woman speaking indistinctly
over P. A...
Oh, hey.
Hey. Hey, how's
the first shift going?
It's endless.
I mean, it's exhilarating.
It's devastating.
I-I told a person
that his wife was dead today,
and then another man that his
husband wasn't getting a heart.
But I also sewed human flesh
on a living human being,
which was nothing like an orange
and different from a cadaver,
and I think I'm in love
with the whole thing.
That's great.
Hey, uh, listen,
this is a little awkward,
but, uh, would you mind
signing this?
What is it?
This is HR paperwork.
It's just so things
don't get muddy.
It just says that
our relationship
pre-exists
your employment here.
Uh, what...
What relationship?
Uh, well...
Oh, Link.
Link, you're a nice guy,
and... and we had fun,
but we don't have
a relationship.
I don't...
I-I don't want a relationship.
Okay, then why are you
waiting outside
the intern locker room
like a stalker?
I'm...
Okay, y-you're
a nice guy, Link,
so let's, um...
Let's be friends, hm?
[ Sighs ]
♪♪
Oh, my God.
- [ Gasps ] Ms. Milton!
- Mm-hmm?
Ms. Milton,
Marina is awake.
♪♪
[ Gasping ]
You did it!
You hoped.
[ Breathes sharply ]
I hoped.
Oh, baby.
[ Crying ]
Oh.
♪♪
It's okay.
How's that dark sense of humor
working out, Yasuda?
♪♪
Oh, my baby.
Okay, good.
Good, good, good.
Am I a tree?
- [ Monitor beeping ]
- [ Chuckles ]
I'm sorry,
are you a what, now?
Uh, not yet, Sarah.
[ Sighs ]
Can I see my kids?
Uh, no, Sarah, not yet.
Y-You need to rest
and recover,
and in a couple days,
we can talk about it.
Okay?
Davis Naish's "Ripples"
plays...
- I want to thank the donor...
- ♪ Slowly ♪
Mm-hmm.
...family.
Someone's child died.
♪ I'm becoming steadfast ♪
I want to tell them
I know what they lost.
Of course.
I understand, but, really...
you do need to rest.
And then we'll talk
about it more. Oh.
- Okay?
- Okay.
♪ Part of me
is far from ready ♪
♪ To come back ♪
♪♪
♪ I don't want to be
the last one chosen ♪
♪♪
Uh, you feel alright,
Dr. Griffith?
♪ I don't wanna be the source
of all your grief ♪
My mom died.
Um, I'm so sorry, um...
do you need a grief counselor,
a pastor, or...
- She died when I was born.
- Oh.
In this hospital, so I haven't
been here since then.
Since you were born?
I haven't been here
since the birth of me
killed my mother somewhere
in one of these rooms,
which is why I was late
my first day.
It had nothing to do
with the tornado.
I had a... panic attack,
and then I saw
the color of the walls.
I've been...
picturing this place
my whole life.
When I think of my mother
and the walls are beige,
and then I get here and
they're blue, and it's just...
♪♪
...disorienting,
disappointing.
♪♪
Got it wrong all this time.
♪ Soon there'll be
still waters ♪
Well, they only painted
the walls blue a few years ago.
You got it right.
♪ Soon there'll be
still waters ♪
♪♪
- ♪ Soon there'll be still waters ♪
- [ Sighs ]
Makes me feel so...
So much better.
[ Laughs ]
Thank you.
Thank you, Dr. Webber.
Of course.
And I'm sorry that I was late
on my first day
and I lied about why.
It's understandable,
Dr. Griffith.
It won't happen again.
[ Humming ]
♪♪
♪ Soon there'll be
still waters ♪
♪♪
[ Laughing ] You waited outside
the intern locker room?
Uh-huh. Mnh. Alright.
You... You set me up,
didn't you?
I mean, you did this
on purpose.
Don't hate me.
I needed a laugh.
So glad I could provide it.
- Hi.
- Keep walking, Schmitt,
we're not on speaking terms.
[ Sighs ]
♪♪
Harsh.
Yeah, well, I can be mean
when I want to be.
Oh, I know.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Okay.
[ Knock on door ]
Come in.
Hey. Uh...
- Hey.
- Thank you for that.
I-I've been at this
a long time,
and I've never done a triple,
so thank you.
How's Sarah?
Well, she's not a tree.
[ Chuckles ]
Sorry, yeah, she's good.
She's good.
S-She's awake,
and she's grateful.
- That's excellent news.
- It is.
[ Breathes deeply ]
Okay, I'm gonna go.
Or don't.
[ Chuckles ]
I need
a residency director.
Meredith: New beginnings
aren't always easy.
You're the best teacher
I know.
This class is a lot like
you were at their age.
They either didn't match
anywhere else
or got kicked out
of their programs.
So, they're... they're
diamonds in the rough...
Is that what you're saying?
Yes, and I think that
I would have never hired them
if I didn't know you
and I didn't know your story.
I think you inspired
this whole thing.
[ Breathes sharply ]
And I need
a residency director.
It's excellent pay, and you
wouldn't have to travel as much,
and I... would love it
if you would
just at least consider it.
When you get a new organ,
you spend your life
on medications
designed to suppress
your immune system
so that your body
won't reject it.
[ Rhythmic knock on door ]
- Hi.
- Hey.
You're here.
Yeah, you called and we came.
Hey.
Right, but, I mean, I...
I did call you three weeks ago.
Well, I couldn't work
three weeks ago, but now I can.
- Sort of.
- Not sort of. I can.
Well, he has
to be supervised.
You don't have to say it
like that.
Well, how do you want me
to say it, Owen?
- You're very Tan.
- Well, yeah,
- Thank you...
- because he's been surfing every day
with a 24-year-old
named Stella
while we've been paying out
our entire life savings
to a $1,700-an-hour
attorney.
Yeah. And she's been drinking
rosé angrily all day,
but you don't see me
criticizing her, so.
- Wow.
- Uh, I'm gonna go.
But you will
think about it?
Yeah,
I'll think about it.
♪♪
But at least you have
a life to spend...
- Let's sit down.
- Great.
- Yes, yes.
- ...and a body to medicate.
So, the attorney got all
criminal charges dropped.
For the low, low price
of a quarter million dollars.
Wow, okay.
So do you have
a medical license?
- W...
- A suspended medical license.
I just have to be supervised
for a little while.
How long is a little while?
Not that long.
Six months is that long,
Owen.
Fingers snapping
rhythmically...
Humming...
- [ Breathes sharply ]
- Yeah, six months.
[ Humming ]
Second chances can feel
like an insult
if you can't get over what you
lost the first time around.
[ Sighs ]
My eyes hurt.
- ♪ Go ♪
- Everything hurts.
I think
my fingernails hurt.
Not mine.
I feel high.
Saving lives is the most
epic high.
- That's Adrenaline.
- Plus Dopamine.
Eh, I prefer to think of it
as magic.
♪ Go, listen to the morning ♪
- ♪ Go be still among the trees ♪
- What do they call you, Griffith?
Simone.
[ Chuckling ]
What, no nickname?
Like, uh, Simmy
- or Simsim?
- ♪ Go, listen to the morning ♪
I am truly stunned
that you still work here.
Dude. One day
you're gonna screw up, too,
and I'm gonna [clicks tongue]
remember this.
- [ Clicks tongue ]
- Doubtful.
You want to know
what they call me, Skywalker?
Mm?
They call me Blue.
As in the color?
As in the ribbon
because I always win.
That's embarrassing.
I'm embarrassed for you.
You definitely
don't always win,
'cause this is a program
for rejects and losers.
Well, that's not
how I identify.
- Uh, me neither.
- Me neither.
Okay, fine, me neither.
Eh, it's kind of
how I identify,
but I intend
to prove myself wrong.
♪ Go listen, go, go listen ♪
I still can't believe you lied
to that mother.
Blue: I comforted that mother.
It was a win-win.
So, what'd you do
to get in here?
Oh, wouldn't you like
to know?
Or, it can feel like
a miracle...
Like a hard-fought victory...
♪ Riiiiiiise ♪
Subtitles: Synchronized by srjanapala
- [ Cellphones chiming ]
- [ Gasps ]
- ♪ Go ♪
- Sheesh. - [ Grunts ]
♪ Listen to the morning, go ♪
...a chance to live the life
you always wanted.
♪ Mother... ♪