Previously on ER:
Our goal is to enroll
200 donor-recipient pairs.
By mixing and matching, we find
kidneys for almost 50 percent of them.
Ask me again. Ask
me to marry you.
Grandma, I don't
know what happened...
but if it is what I think, it
scares the hell out of me.
She's yours, Tony.
Is it possible?
Oh, crap.
- What time is it?
- Six-fifteen. You let me fall asleep.
I didn't wanna stay over.
- It's okay.
- No, it's not okay.
We agreed it was too soon
for Sarah to deal with this.
Sleep in for another
hour. She won't even know.
Well, when are
you gonna tell her?
Tell her what?
Come on.
- I don't even know if it's true.
- You will be if you do the test.
What am supposed I to
do? "Can I have your DNA?
I wanna find out if I'm your
father"? What if I'm not?
- Don't wanna mess with the kid's head.
- Are you afraid?
No. Maybe.
I don't know. Maybe the actual
biology doesn't matter anyway, huh?
Of course it does.
- Want something to eat before you go?
- No, I'm fine.
- Some juice? SARAH:
We don't have any.
- I'm sorry. Did we wake you?
- No, I couldn't sleep.
- I'm just leaving.
- You don't have to sneak out.
She's not sneaking
out. She's going to work.
- And I'm late. I'll page you later?
- Okay.
- I made coffee.
- Since when do you drink coffee?
Since we ran out of juice.
Give me some.
Sorry, I meant to go
to the store. I just...
You know, if you want me to...
I can do all the cooking and
the shopping and cleaning.
If you do that, when would you do your
homework, talk on the phone and text?
It's called multitasking.
Since it is plainly ludicrous...
to page a surgeon at 6:15 for
something as silly as Tylenol...
the only conceivable explanation I have
for your call is you have a crush on me.
I'm flattered. Thank
you. Goodbye.
- Who was that?
- This new ICU nurse. She's useless.
Someone needs to
show her the ropes.
Did you say ropes?
Jane, come on. I
have to round soon.
FYI, this is my last
night in the call room.
- Prosthetics lab could be fun.
- We're through with hospital kink.
We're staying at
your place next time.
- Whoa, whoa. No, we can't. I've got a...
- I know, I know.
You have no bed.
You sleep on the couch.
Your sink is clogged.
This pathetic I-work-all-the-time-
so-my-place-is-a-rat-hole thing...
is not gonna fly anymore.
What?
Yeah, you're gonna clean up your
apartment and buy a proper bed.
Today.
- Jane, just because you wanna stay at...
- Hey, it's been three months, okay?
Upgrade the sleeping
arrangements, or you will be punished.
- Do you understand?
- Ooh. Yeah.
It's tradition. A symbol.
Yeah, a symbol of the
wedding industrial complex.
No, I'll wear a ring.
I wanna wear a ring.
- You just have to abide by my ring policy.
- Your ring policy?
Yeah, if one of us
loses our wedding ring...
we replace the ring and
give the new ring full status.
You're gonna lose it?
Well, I don't know. Something happens
to the ring and everybody freaks out...
like the marriage is doomed.
But a simple gold
band would be very nice.
Now we're getting somewhere.
So do you think we should
make an announcement...
or just tell people individually
and let it trickle out?
Is it all right if
we wait a while?
- Really? Why?
- You know, when you tell people...
you're getting married, they
start asking a million questions...
about a wedding, and
marriage is not about wedding.
Like it's not about ring.
Let's just enjoy this for a
while, the two of us, okay?
That's fine.
A secret engagement will be fun.
Jane, you take the boob rash...
and, Ray, you get the
bounty hunter with the gout.
Dr. Kovac returns.
Nice seeing you again.
- You too.
- Welcome back.
It was weird here without you.
- What's that?
- A rat died in the air vent.
There's a cleaning
crew up there.
Hey, did you really squash
your own hand in a vise?
I mean, because...
Wow, that's...
- Need a doc here.
- Jane, why don't we take this?
Thirty-five-year-old,
uncontrollable seizures.
You. Take the bus. Something
bad's gonna happen on the L today.
I upped my meds, but
the seizures won't stop.
- Well, you're not seizing now.
- No. Yes. Yes, I am. I...
Two milligrams
of Ativan should...
You're sitting up and talking.
You're not having a seizure.
- Can we not stop here?
- We're about to...
- Can you move me back?
- Just be patient.
- Okay, but move me now, please!
- All right, all right.
Lily's sick, Marquez is out on vacation,
and the rest are doing doubles...
to cover their shifts. This is
why nurses quit. They burn out.
The shortage just keeps
getting worse. What about Ben?
He was lured to a
hospital in Minneapolis.
New cars for nurses
willing to stay six months.
- You cool with that?
- What, I got left for a Camry?
No, it's a good gig.
I can't blame him.
Anna Hayes, 39, vomiting
and altered mental status.
- Tachy to 120, sats 92 on room air.
- This your mom?
- Yeah, I could barely wake her up.
- Ms. Hayes, I'm Dr. Gates.
- Can you open your eyes?
- Please, just take me home.
No, you need oxygen and fluids.
- Is she gonna be all right?
- I'm fine.
Ma'am, you're not fine. You're severely
dehydrated. We're gonna help you.
Access?
Twenty-gauge in the
right antecub, but it blew.
Sam?
Hey, Trauma 1's
open. I'll be right in.
Hey, Jeff. What's up?
I think we have something
that belongs to you.
Alex, what happened?
Mr. Brewer, let's
get you hooked up.
Yeah, okay. You're
not gonna need that.
- You're not gonna need that.
- No?
No, these are
temporal-lobe seizures, okay?
I never have any cardiac
or respiratory symptoms.
We'll hook you up to be safe.
If you haven't noticed, my,
uh, seizures are unusual.
I get hunches, premonitions,
that sort of thing.
- Nothing ever shows up on the monitor.
- I see.
Yeah.
Oh, here comes another one.
I'm sensing...
Bacon and eggs.
There you go.
Okay, so can you just give me the
Ativan, and I'll be out of your hair?
I'm sorry...
but I just think anybody could have
made that prediction, Mr. Brewer.
Look, I know that, uh, it looks
like I'm making this stuff up...
just so I can get drugs...
but that's not what's going on,
okay? Can you call my neurologist?
He'll back me up.
Did you get what you want, Alex?
Huh? For a couple of bags of
quarters? You could be in jail right now.
It's not anything like
they're saying, okay?
Officer Greenberg is gonna take you
home. I'm gonna call every half-hour.
You don't answer that
phone, we got a problem.
- Mom, it's not my fault.
- Of course it's not. It never is.
Mom, please, just listen to me.
I have to go back to
work. I'll talk to you tonight.
- Thank you very much, Jeff.
- Yeah.
Hey.
What's up with Alex?
He knocked off a
Laundromat near his school.
I'll get better faster
at home, really.
Mom, you're sick,
okay? We're not leaving.
- She hates hospitals.
- Well, but this is County. It's nice here.
You got organic food, in-room
massage. We have ice sculptures.
You're gonna love it here.
All right, she needs coags.
She's oozing around the needle.
Pulse up to 125.
When you were 4 years old,
our neighbor fell off that ladder...
and I brought him here.
Mr. Madsen?
Oh, he was such a grouch.
He was always yelling at you and
your brother for playing too loud.
But when you found out he
was sick, you wanted to visit him.
Systolic's only 84.
- She needs access, Gates.
- I'm trying, Sam.
She's clamping down. One
more try and I'll go central.
You stood up on your chair...
and you stuck your favorite
toy turtle in bed with him...
and you said anybody who
was sick needed a toy turtle.
- She's making this up.
- No.
No. I made a lot
of mistakes, son.
But you are the
one thing I got right.
All right, I'm in, Sam.
Let's get the fluids up.
You okay?
Yeah.
Good morning,
Neela. Ready to round?
Uh, sorry. Shoot. I need...
I need five more minutes.
I overslept. I never
oversleep. Is that a yoga mat?
There's an Ashtanga class in the
anesthesia conference room. Check it out.
Nurses' station, five
minutes. I'll see you there.
Hello, good morning. I'm Dr...
- Manish?
- Hi.
This is the doctor I
was telling you about.
I'm Emily. I've
heard a lot about you.
- What are you doing here?
- Uh...
- Well, I was...
- Saving my life.
Well, I was giving a talk about
the paired-exchange program...
at a dialysis center
in Evanston...
He was really impressive.
He gave us all hope.
And there were all
these people there...
and they were just waiting
and suffering, and it inspired me.
To donate your kidney? You
run screaming from a blood drive.
Well, I was moved
by their stories.
We worked together every day the
past month. How come you said nothing?
Because I thought
that I'd chicken out.
I've been on dialysis for six
years, on the UNOS list for five.
I'd just about given up when,
boom, Manish walks into my life.
I got tested. It turns
out I'm a good match.
Wow. EMILY: Amazing, right?
It's like right out of a
movie or something.
What's your differential?
Infectious hepatitis
is the top of my list.
- I sent viral titers.
- Good, what else?
Hepatorenal syndrome,
vascular disorder...
autoimmune and
alcoholic hepatitis.
- But my mom doesn't drink.
- We're running through possibilities.
Here, Luka, Jane's tibia fracture has
compartment syndrome. Ortho's MIA.
What about toxic ingestions?
Acetaminophen, poison mushrooms?
Tox screen's negative,
acetaminophen's zero.
Okay, get a CT and
notify Nephrology and GI.
Sam, come with me.
Is there anyone else
you want to be here?
My other son's at work.
- Don't bother him.
- I think he should be here. Is it close?
He's a repair guy over
at Begley's Appliances.
My mom works there too.
It's just the stomach flu.
- Don't bother Nick.
- It's more serious.
Why don't you go out to the front desk?
The clerk will help you call your brother.
It's all right, honey. Go.
- It's out there to the left.
- Thanks.
You're scaring him.
You're in acute liver failure,
ma'am. This is a little scary.
Did you hear what I said?
This is serious. You could die.
I heard you.
Do you have any questions?
No.
Manish nearly fainted
when I was drawing blood.
Now he's giving his kidney
to someone he barely just met.
Isn't that strange?
No, everyone goes through some
kind of a mini-life crisis in their 20s.
He's far from family, he's
unattached, he's unsure about career.
He's drifting. He's
looking for purpose.
Some people donate kidneys,
others end up at Jumbo Mart.
- Who are we to judge?
- Neela, what are you doing?
I came down to
the volvulus case.
You're supposed to be covering the
postop floor. Done with those changes?
- Well, not all.
- I'm gonna leave you to work this out.
I'll be in Curtain 3.
- You, upstairs. Shoo.
- Well...
What is this?
A consult note.
- I said black ink today. Only black.
- Oh.
- What color is this?
- Ah... Blue. Oops.
Hey, Mayday, how's it going?
Well, my Attending thinks
I'm a complete idiot...
and Crenshaw's back
to being a little bitch.
Most hepatic toxins take a few
days to destroy the liver, right?
Yeah.
Theoretically, you
could trash your liver...
by the time you become symptomatic,
the toxins couldn't be detected.
I suppose.
I'll page you later.
Ms. Hayes.
Anna.
What's a young woman
with no medical history...
doing with fulminant
liver failure?
Aren't you the doctor?
You've got a family, 40
good years ahead of you...
yet when I told you you
might die, you hardly reacted.
Oh, yeah, I guess we all have our
own way of dealing with bad news.
Huh.
You know, I used to be a paramedic
for 10 years before I became a doctor.
Young, healthy patients...
no matter how religious,
mellow, Zen, they were...
they don't wanna die.
Something kicks in. Instinct.
Well, maybe I've just
been too tired to cry.
You seem depressed.
Let's... Let's say someone
wanted to kill themselves...
without anyone
knowing it was suicide.
You know, there's a
whole class of chemicals...
that can damage the liver
just days after they're ingested.
Please.
I just wanna go to sleep now.
Fuels and solvents found in
refrigerators, dryers, cleaning products...
stuff you'd have access
to every day at your job.
Tell me what you took so I can help you.
Your sons deserve to have you around.
- They're all grown up now.
- I know I'm right about this.
Propane, kerosene, carbon
tetrachloride, what? Tell me.
I hear if you mix it with
juice, it's got quite a kick.
Everything okay?
Anna? Anna?
Anna?
Everything's back to
normal with you and Luka?
Uh... I don't know if I'd say
normal, but they're good.
- How's things with you and Katey?
- Uh...
She's great.
They're really great.
- But?
- Uh...
- But nothing. She's awesome.
- Our friend's hurt, help.
- Don't move so fast.
- Oh, come on, you're tough.
Don't make me walk.
- You can do it.
- Come on, guys. Give her a break.
- I got her.
- Get a gurney over here.
- Are you a doctor?
- We both are. RAY:
Okay, what happened?
- They were doing a formation.
- Most schools do three layers. We do five.
Tasha fell all the way from the top.
- Wow, a four-layer fall?
I need this kiddo back for
the Great Lakes Regionals.
Okay, Tasha, let's go.
Clear.
Still V-tach, no pulse.
- I have Poison Control on the line.
- All right. Put them on speakerphone.
What's this? SAM: She's on.
Possible carbon tetrachloride overdose,
fulminant liver and kidney failure.
- Why didn't you say anything about this?
- It's just a hunch.
- When did the exposure occur?
- Unclear.
Transaminases in the 2000 range.
It's too late. Nothing to offer
other than supportive measures.
- Nothing to offer?
- No.
If it's carbon tet, the
damage has been done.
That's right. The cell death
is irreversible at this point.
- All right, thanks.
- Epi's in, fourth dose.
Another hundred of
lido, and re-check the K.
- You were withholding patient history?
- I wasn't sure.
Charging to 360.
Where'd her son go?
At the front, trying to
get hold of his brother.
He better find him fast.
All right, clear.
I don't think I could do
something like this for a stranger.
So maybe it bothers
me that you can.
Look, Emily's parents are too old to be
donors. She's getting sicker every day.
- You would have done the same.
- I don't think so.
- You're a better person.
- I'm not a better person.
See, I'd be too worried about
time lost from work, complications.
I don't mean to be negative, but you
have to consider bleeding, infection...
I've considered it.
We've all considered it.
- It's covered.
- Covered?
- Manish.
- Look, it wasn't my intent.
It wasn't why I agreed, but they
offered. They insisted, actually.
- Manish, no.
- Just listen, okay?
First I refused, but I started thinking
what $50,000 could do for my family.
I don't wanna hear any more.
Look, when I was 14, my parents
sent me here to live with a distant cousin.
I went to school, learned
English, played baseball...
while my sisters sewed
shirts for $2 in Mumbai.
I understand you feel guilty.
Yeah, with $50,000, I could
hire an immigration lawyer...
and get my whole
family over here.
My parents could get proper health care,
my sisters could get a proper education.
I mean, Emily's family is wealthy, right?
It's no hardship for them, so why not?
Because people do not sell their
body parts in this country, period.
Not to mention that you could put
our transplant program in jeopardy.
- Nobody needs to know.
- But I know, Manish.
I don't understand. If you were looking
to clear your conscience, I can't help you.
- I would think you would understand.
- Well, I don't understand.
I don't and, you know, I kind of
resent the assumption that I should.
I can't do this,
Manish. I'm sorry.
No deformities, no step-offs.
We have this cheer. It's
cool. It's called Paper Dolls.
- Yeah, it's our signature formation.
- It's like a college-level routine.
Pulse is in the 120s and
the HemoCue is dropping.
Because she's bleeding into
her belly. We got fluid here.
We've got the All-Cheer Regionals
next week. I've been driving them hard.
The outer fliers have
their hand in this half Y.
- The other grabs hold of the middle flier.
- That's me.
- And the ending is really cute.
- Sounds great.
Liter of warm saline wide
open and call for O-neg.
Make sure Surgery
knows to get down here.
Oh, my God, surgery?
- If we don't have a flier, we are screwed.
- Watch it, girls.
Now, why don't we worry
more about your friend, okay?
I'll get the infuser.
Do you guys have any warm saline?
- There's LR in the oven.
K is 7.2. Amp of D50
and 10 units of insulin.
Nose is bleeding. KOVAC:
The coags are through the roof.
Oh, my God. She
wasn't like this when I left.
Her condition changed quickly.
Without a functioning liver, toxins
start to accumulate in the blood.
She's in an abnormal
heart rhythm...
and she isn't getting enough
blood to her brain and body.
We're doing CPR and
giving her medications...
but she's just not responding.
But can't you just do
something to fix her liver?
Once cells have died,
there's little we can do.
So is this it or what?
We're breathing and
compressing her heart...
but your mother's
body is shutting down.
Anything you guys wanna say?
No, Mom, okay?
This isn't happening.
This can't be happening.
- Please don't go.
- One more round for the kids?
Please don't let her die.
Sam?
- All right, clear.
- Whoa, wait a minute. She's got a pulse.
Sinus rhythm.
I don't understand.
Is she dying or not?
Her heart is beating, but her brain
was deprived of oxygen for a long time.
It's very likely that she
suffered serious brain injury.
Wow. She can't even die right.
Her pressure stabilized,
but her crit's still dropping.
- Did I mention I hate cheerleaders?
- I hate clowns.
- I heard Gates was afraid of folk singers.
- Really?
Two plus guarding with rebound on
the left. Could be a splenic rupture.
- Neela, you writing this down?
- Yes, Dr. Crenshaw, I am.
- How do you stand this?
- I don't know.
I'm like a child
coming back for more.
Let's bring her up to whatever O.R. is
open. Dr. Dubenko will meet you there.
Girls, Tasha's going to surgery now.
Everyone say goodbye and wish her luck.
I'm really sorry you need
surgery and everything, Tash.
But you should know that we will
have to replace you for All-Cheer.
- Where's my mom?
- Ha-ha-ha.
Hey, she sacrificed her spleen
for you guys. Show some respect.
It's gonna be okay. I'll
explain everything as we go.
- Am I gonna have a big scar?
- Not if we can help it.
Let me tell you something.
Don't talk like that.
She's not gonna die.
This is the best idea she's had.
You don't mean that.
This is your mother.
You don't know the first
thing about my mother.
I know she's barely
alive, and you guys
should be in there
instead of here fighting.
- Sorry, I just don't care.
- Why do you hate her?
Ever since Dad died, all she
does is try to make us happy.
Happy, right. By gambling
on the Internet all day?
- It helps her relax.
- Shut up.
She started with poker. By the
end of the year, she'd lost everything.
- Cars, savings from our dad.
- She has a problem.
When they stopped giving her credit,
she took out cards and racked up debt.
Eighty thousand dollars.
We gotta live with that.
- She was trying to get help.
- Stop making excuses for her.
The house is in foreclosure, Evan.
Next week, you're gonna be homeless.
All right, listen, she may be
screwed up, but she's your mother.
That's not good
enough. It's not.
- Can I get your advice on something?
- Yeah, of course.
Well, let's say I knew a really nice
person about to do a pretty bad thing...
but this bad thing had really good
consequences for a bunch of people.
- You don't need my advice.
- Yes, I do.
No, because you have, like, this ethical
alarm system hardwired into your brain.
It makes you a pain in the ass, but
it's one of the best things about you.
But if I tell what I know...
it's gonna mess things up
for a whole bunch of people.
They'll get over it.
- It'll be a major betrayal.
- Ah...
Do the right thing, Neela.
That's all I'm saying.
Is this where I'm
having my operation?
Yep, the O.R.s
are straight ahead.
I'm scared.
I know. We're gonna
take good care of you.
My stomach.
We'll get you more pain
medication when we get to preop.
- No, that's not it.
- Is it your mom?
We won't start
until she gets here.
I didn't fall from the
top of the formation.
You didn't?
The other girls, they did this.
They did this to me.
New cheerleaders are forced to submit
to 10 minutes in an equipment closet.
The newbie just takes it while her
teammates do whatever they want.
Tasha got kicked in the stomach
until she started coughing up blood.
I trust the authorities
have been notified?
Ray's on it.
Good.
There's something else I
need to talk to you about.
Sure, go ahead.
Can it wait?
- Not really.
- Well, it's gonna have to.
Our cases are completely
backed up. Let's go.
Oh, Dr. Kovac, you
really must see this.
This is Fred and Brenda.
Neurovascular symptoms
after a handfasting ceremony.
- A what?
- It's a Wiccan wedding.
- The guests bound our wrists with cords.
- It's where "tie the knot" comes from.
This is really strong.
Braided to be tough.
Like our marriage bond.
Regular scissors didn't work, and
the knots were too tight to undo.
- I can't feel my fingers.
- I can't move my thumb.
Is a Wiccan ceremony
recognized by the state?
We get married at the courthouse
so I can put Fred on my insurance.
They don't recognize us, because
we don't believe in mating for life.
You don't?
We're betrothed for
one year and a day.
To be re-evaluated at
the end of that period.
Yeah, well, it does seem like
"till death" is kind of extreme.
Yeah, just
Judeo-Christian bull crap.
I don't think so.
I don't... We're getting married
and all those things are on our minds.
Sorry, it just slipped out.
Uh... Okay.
Well, I guess, um...
All right, what...?
I'll be right back, okay?
What, the first people
we tell are strangers?
- Wiccans?
- I just felt like saying it.
Abby, have you seen
the cheerleading coach?
She's outside
practicing with the girls.
Oops.
When the tissues are deprived of oxygen
for a long time, they produce acid...
so we're giving her
medicine for that.
- How long can she live like this?
- Weeks, months. It's hard to tell.
But it's just a
matter of time, right?
I mean, if you wanna
help us, don't prolong this.
Well, she's not suffering.
Evan and I are gonna
have to be responsible.
We're the only family she
has. We're alone. It's too much.
I understand. A social
worker will call you.
We have programs,
there's a support group...
Sir, please, we've
been through enough.
She's been having
runs of V-tach.
Forget the lido drip.
What, you want amiodarone?
- No. Why prolong the inevitable?
- That's not your call to make.
Oh, come on, Sam. We
both know how this ends.
Why put her boys through it?
She's a full code. We
don't know her injuries.
We gave her CPR for 40
minutes. Her brain is fried.
Another run of 10.
Sam, your little raver is having
a dystonic reaction to Haldol.
It's cool, go.
Well, the lido's hanging
and the infuser's set.
If she has another
run, start the drip, okay?
Page Dr. Kovac and tell him
his patient in Trauma 1 is coding.
You heard what happened.
My girls are not staying in the
same motel as the football team.
- I need to talk to you.
- How is she?
Get off the phone.
I'll call you back.
Tasha's injuries were
not caused by a fall.
What do you mean? I
saw her hit the ground.
She was forced into a closet, and
then she was beaten by the other girls.
- What? My girls would never...
- Come on, don't do this.
She knows you know.
It's not what you think.
Tasha's sensitive,
never fit in with the others.
What she's referring to is just
a little team-building exercise.
They ripped open her
spleen. That's not little.
And I definitely wouldn't
consider that team-building.
My girls are regional champions.
They're under a lot of pressure.
Come on, yell, "Go, big blue!"
Go, big blue!
Just save the excuses
for these guys, all right?
Come on, yell, "Go,
big blue!" Go, big blue!
Mom, I don't care about the
money. Just please, don't go.
- Another mg of epi.
- Charged to 360, clear.
Okay, resume compressions.
- Why didn't you talk to me?
- Lido isn't gonna change the outcome.
- I thought you'd agree.
- Well, we work together here, Gates.
Clear.
- I'll be right back.
- You can't leave in the middle of a code.
- The other kid should be here.
- Gates.
Hey.
What do you want?
Look, I know you're angry,
and I know you got screwed.
You don't know anything.
I know your dad died and your
mom messed up. It ain't fair.
No, it isn't.
But your mom is dying.
And I know you care...
because if you didn't, you wouldn't
be out here sulking in the hall.
You go in there and you
forgive your mother right now.
I can't.
Nick, you have one shot
at being with your mother...
while she's dying.
Hold compressions.
That's enough.
- Save a cheerleader, save the world.
- I still need to talk to you.
- Make it quick. Manish is on the table.
- That's what it's about.
- Emily paid Manish for his kidney.
- Ridiculous. He knows better.
- It's true, he told me.
- He was screened.
- They would have picked this up.
- Well, they didn't.
Come on.
But it's wrong and could jeopardize
the whole transplant program.
All right. All right, Neela.
All right, well, look. Just as
an exercise, consider this.
There are over 65,000 people on
the UNOS list waiting for kidneys.
Can we really rely on voluntary
altruism to solve this problem?
- What are you saying?
- What am I saying?
Well, when somebody donates a kidney,
the recipient obviously benefits, right?
Hospitals make money.
Surgeons get paid.
The donor who gives up a kidney
gets flowers and a handshake.
Am I right?
Are you kidding?
So many sick
people, so few organs.
Why not let market forces
sort out the imbalance?
Because people
aren't commodities.
We don't live in a world where it's
right for rich people to buy body parts.
It's legal to rent out your uterus
or to harvest your eggs for money.
You can get paid to donate
sperm. How is this different?
All I know is that a dying girl is
gonna get a new kidney today.
And then what happens to the 65,000
others who can't afford to buy one?
Ancef will be ready to run soon.
Quick question.
Why are you doing this?
Excuse me?
Why are you giving
this girl your kidney?
I guess I've been inspired
by the work that we do here.
Mm-hm. And you would never
dream of jeopardizing everything...
by doing something stupid
and illegal, would you?
- What are you talking about?
- You know what he's talking about.
Okay.
Emily wanted to give me money, but I
turned her down after talking to Neela.
Money was never part of the
reason why I wanted to do any of this.
He's just saying
what you need to hear.
She's made up her mind about me.
- I don't know what else to say.
- All right, that's enough.
Neela, let's go scrub.
No.
I won't be a part of this.
Fine.
Shirley, have Crenshaw get me a
surgeon who actually wants to operate.
You can get out of
here, Neela. Now.
The tornado was hard to see against
the background, so I painted it black.
I was gonna put some lights in
the bottom, but I ran out of time.
Wow, that should look
really, really cool. Sam.
Yeah, and I fell down the
stairs at school, and it broke.
That's not the only
thing you broke.
I know, I broke my tibia and
my fibula. Can you fix it fast?
- I can fix you up in about an hour.
- An hour?
I'll never have time to finish my
tornado before the end of the science fair.
Hey, did you know that casts give
off heat when they're hardening?
No. SAM: Mm-hm.
It's called an exothermic reaction. It
could make a pretty cool science project.
Can you help me make it?
Ah, sure. I'll get the stuff.
Sam, can you dispose
of the rest of that Ativan?
- Sure.
- Hi.
- Hey.
- So I talked to your neurologist.
And I got quite an earful
about temporal-lobe epilepsy.
- Yeah.
- Interesting stuff.
- Well, I told you I was the real deal.
- Mm-hm.
Well, do you have any last
words of psychic wisdom...
before I medicate you and
sever your ties to the paranormal?
Oh, sure. Um...
Well, I see great things
for you in the year to come...
although you will struggle
to balance home and career.
- That's it?
- Yeah.
That's the most generic
fortune I've ever heard.
And you should really invite
your dad to the wedding.
I'm just saying.
Gates, can you
explain this, please?
Explain what?
Why did you write idiopathic
liver failure on her death certificate?
It should be carbon
tetrachloride ingestion.
Well, she never admitted it straight
out. We don't know what really happened.
You can't withhold information
whenever it suits you.
What she told you needs to
be part of the medical record.
If we document suicidality,
then life insurance won't pay.
We say it was natural.
What's the harm?
The harm is that it's unethical,
and it's insurance fraud.
Come on, insurance companies
screw people over any chance they get.
Why should those kids be punished
for life because of their mother?
- I'm worried about you.
- Don't worry about me.
No, I'm worried about
your ability to do this job...
and it's too bad because
you're good, but you...
You lie and you
think nothing of it.
It's not lying if we
don't know for sure.
Now, come on. Let their mother
do this one last thing for them.
I'm not gonna let you
lie for them, Gates.
- Hey, Gates, can you sign this discharge?
- Later.
Jane, have you seen Neela?
- Uh, Dubenko sent her home early.
- Oh.
I just had to wheel an appy up from
the ER, in case you're wondering.
- Wondering what?
- Why I'm here.
Good night, Jane.
King-sized, wrought-iron
frame. The rest is up to you.
Hey, you guys, have
you seen Tony around?
- Not in a while.
- Okay, have a good night.
Do you think I chased
away my father too fast?
No.
Maybe I should have
listened to what he had to say.
- Well, you can call him.
- I tried.
He checked out of his hotel and the
number he gave me is disconnected.
Um, Abby.
Sorry, I just need a minute
to check something, okay?
Hey, Malik, do we still have
the chart on Anna Hayes?
You think I memorize
the name of every patient?
The woman that
died of liver failure?
I forgot to do some paperwork
for the death certificate.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
Your first day
back, how'd it go?
Just like riding a bike.
Luka, I told Miranda
we'd be home by 8.
Coming.
- Good night.
- See you.
- Hey.
- Hey. How'd it go with your little secret?
Uh, terrible, actually.
Worse than expected...
but our cheerleader did well.
The police are interviewing the
whole squad as well as the coach.
- Good.
- Getting off soon?
- Uh, yeah, thank God.
- Yeah, me too.
Wanna grab a beer?
Sounds good, but, um, I've
got some dictations to do.
Okay, another time.
Dr. Gates.
You're still here.
Yeah, our uncle drove in from
Ann Arbor. He wanted to see her.
I'm sorry for your loss.
You know, I never got to
thank you for everything you did.
It's my job.
You really helped us.
Good night, Nick.
You know, she knew
it was the only way out.
It had to look natural so we
could get the insurance money.
I found some old
solvent at the store.
You helped her?
I left out a bottle.
At least she finally
got something right.
Good night, doc.
- Leave me alone.
- No, you can't break and steal things.
You're gonna end up
on the wrong track...
Mom, you're not
in my head, okay?
You don't know what happened.
Alex, come on.
Alex, open this door.
You hear me? Right now.
- Open the door.
- Go away.
I can't go away, I'm your mom.
Come on. Please,
Alex, don't do this to me.
Hey. You remember that time
that we made that science project...
for your school? That volcano?
And I couldn't get the mix of
baking soda and vinegar right...
and it erupted all
over the living room.
What were you? What, 5 or 6?
I know I didn't give you the
most stable childhood, okay?
I know you've seen a lot of
crazy stuff, that is mostly my fault.
The only thing I ever wanted
was for you to be happy, Alex.
Okay?
And I don't know
how to give that to you.
So please tell me what to do.
I know you're listening
in there, Alex, okay?
I love you.
You know that, right?
- Hi.
You look tired.
- Want a beer?
- Yeah, thanks.
I made chili, salad and
cornbread from scratch.
I know what your next question
is. My homework's already done.
All right.
No more fast food around here.
Wow, Sarah, this looks great.
Yeah.
Leaving so soon?
I guess not. Two.