Oh. Good morning.
Not so much.
Sorry. I hate when
repair guys are late.
He wasn't late.
He realized that my
"isolated termite presence"
is actually more of a complete
and total termite infestation.
I have to tent
my house. Oh, no.
So, you had to pack up
all your clothes and food?
Vikane gas doesn't
affect clothes,
but you should definitely
throw out all your food
when you go home.
Already did.
Where are you gonna stay?
Oh. You should stay
in our guest room.
I'll stay at a
hotel or something.
But you hate sleeping in hotels.
I hate intruding on my
friends, and I hate intruding
on my friends' pregnant
wives even more.
I-It's not an
intrusion. Stay with us.
I'm okay. Thank you, though.
We want to. Absolutely.
We insist.
Okay.
Thank you.
It's delicious.
It's disgusting.
And it helps me poop.
I did not need to know
that. Well, you're a doctor.
You obviously know what prune
juice does to a man's...
Shut up. I'm trying to eat.
Oh. Coffee and a Red Bull.
You prepping for
a post-breakfast
MMA match there, big guy?
I was up late, need a boost.
I was catching up
on some journals,
and I've already
been to a meeting.
Check my sign-off
sheet if you want.
I didn't say anything.
You don't need to.
Wolke and Perez,
you're with me today.
I thought we were
scheduled with Park.
I just had to fire one resident,
and you two are on probation.
Not exactly my vision
for the department.
Felt like it was time for me
to take a more
hands-on approach,
see how your surgical
educations are progressing.
We round in five.
Don't be late.
I want to do another
embryo transfer ASAP.
Three months is ASAP.
Not if we restart my
hormone injections,
add Methylprednisolone,
and do prophylactic
endometrial scratching.
A more aggressive uterine
prep means more side effects.
I can handle it.
Morgan, I understand
your impatience,
but one unsuccessful embryo
transfer is no reason...
I want to do whatever it
takes to get pregnant.
Now.
Not in three months.
Okay.
We'll start the hormones
and the
Methylprednisolone today.
I have a new idea.
The echo results were that bad?
Your heart muscle's
deteriorating way too fast.
We don't have time to
wait for a matching donor,
so we're gonna fix
the one you have.
We're going to remove
the scar tissue,
use a synthetic patch, along
with your healthy tissue
to reshape your
ventricle over a balloon.
It's kind of like papier-mâché.
If that's possible, why
didn't we do it sooner?
It's a challenging
surgical technique.
Which makes it right in
Dr. Lim's wheelhouse.
But I'm confident it's the
best option for your situation.
This surgery is amazing.
How did you even
come up with it?
I didn't. It's a modified
"Dor Procedure"...
Basically an endoventricular
patch plasty.
There's nothing basic about
it. I'm really excited.
Spare me. What?
Stroking my ego isn't gonna
get you off of probation.
I am not stroking your ego.
I am sincerely...
Start with a D.E. MRI
to map the scar versus
functional tissue,
while I finalize
the surgical plan.
Dr. Perez, what do I
need from this MRI?
Completely pristine images
of right ventricular scarring
without artifact or distortion.
No room for error on this.
- - Captions by VITAC...
There's a small mass.
Her pediatrician
said it was a cyst.
He doesn't think
she needs surgery
but suggested we get a consult.
She definitely needs surgery.
It's a minor
outpatient procedure.
She's only 13 with
no previous symptoms.
It's most likely benign.
We will need to do a needle
biopsy and a CT to confirm.
What's a needle biopsy?
It's kind of like a shot.
In my belly?
Honey, it's okay.
You'll be fine.
Mom, no.
Mnh.
Can you do it
while she's asleep?
General anesthesia would
add unnecessary risk
to a needle biopsy.
Please, I can't do this.
Kelli, we're gonna numb you
and you'll close your
eyes, hold your mom's hand,
and count to 10, and
then it'll all be over.
Do you promise?
Absolutely.
This is not good.
Looks good to me.
Any end systolic
volume less than 200
is within parameters.
I mean Lim's idea
for Bob's surgery.
You said it was amazing.
That was before I'd
done enough research
to actually understand it.
It's way too risky.
You're just mad
because she called you
out for brown-nosing.
I was sincerely psyched.
And now, after
reading one article...
I've read five.
And right-sided failure
has resulted in
negative outcomes
in every case I've reviewed.
Lim's been treating
this guy for years,
knows the case way better.
Yeah, she also knows
the patient better,
which could be impacting
her objectivity.
You want to question the
Chief Surgeon's objectivity?
No, I want to suggest she
reconsider her strategy.
I wouldn't.
Why?
'Cause you're scared of her?
Yes. And you should be, too.
My OD and you and
Powell going rogue,
I'd rather not add to...
Can you show Mr. Zegras
how to apply the eye drops?
Sure. No problem.
Good job.
Hey.
I just closed a deal
with one of the biggest
CROs on the West Coast.
They're going to consolidate
all their clinical trials
at St. Bonaventure.
That's awesome.
Unless you're telling
me because you plan
to close the clinic to
make room for the CRO.
I have the space,
but what I don't have
is a smart, aggressive,
ambitious physician
to manage the partnership
and serve as P.I.
You interested?
I-I'm flattered.
It'll be a ton of work
but a great opportunity
for St. Bon's and yourself.
I agree.
It's just a bit unexpected.
Can I think about it?
Of course.
Take some time.
But not too much.
I'll need an answer by Friday.
There's almost no
viable cardiac tissue.
And poor contractions
in what little there is.
There's still an
area of tissue left
that could be viable after CABG.
We can't start
surgery just hoping
there's enough tissue to
reshape the ventricle.
That's an inherent
risk to this approach.
If you have another idea?
A BiVAD with an
unmatched donor heart.
Considered it and ruled it out.
He'd reject an unmatched donor
heart in less than a year.
Beats dying on the table
in less than 24 hours.
I appreciate your opinion.
Not a huge fan of the tone.
Sorry.
If we put Bob on longer
term anti-rejection meds,
that would buy several more
months for the unmatched heart.
During which time, he'd
be completely vulnerable
to infection.
I know SVR is high risk,
but given Bob's condition,
I'm convinced it's the only
solution to keep him alive
long enough to find a
matching donor heart.
I plan to spend some time
rehearsing every surgical step.
I'd suggest you two do the same.
Why did you say yes?
It was one of those moments
when you say the thing
a polite person is
supposed to say.
Mm-hmm.
Even as you're realizing
you don't mean it at all.
Okay. It'll be fine.
You'll be at work all
day, and at night,
I'm sure Glassman will
just sit in a corner
and read the latest
presidential biography.
That's... oddly specific.
Old dudes love reading
about presidents.
They fantasize about how they
would've done it all better.
What's wrong?
It's not a cyst.
It's an invasive
hydatidiform mole.
Interesting.
That type of tumor
could only occur
from a mutated fertilized egg.
She has had sex.
She's only 13, which means
even if she consented,
it's statutory rape.
There's a new
problem. Actually two.
This type of tumor is caused by
a mutation in a fertilized egg,
which means the surgery
will be more difficult.
It also means your daughter
has had sexual intercourse.
Wait, but I'm on birth
control, and we use condoms.
How could I be pregnant?
You're not pregnant.
The implanted egg mutated into
a tumor instead of a fetus.
And no birth control
is 100% effective.
But you can still
remove it, right?
Yes.
Y-You don't seem
surprised to learn
your daughter's had sex.
I'm not learning it.
She's been going steady
with Ryan for over a year.
He's in her grade.
He's sweet.
A 13-year-old child
should not be having sex.
I'm not a child, and me
and Ryan love each other.
And if I want to have sex
with him, it's my decision.
You're okay with this?
Teenagers are gonna do it
no matter what
their parents say.
So instead of forcing
her to sneak around,
I chose to talk to her about
safe sex, birth control,
and help her have a
positive experience.
Your daughter...
Is scheduled for surgery
tomorrow morning.
And as I deflate the balloon...
I'll remove the final clamps.
That was... awesome.
Still not sure it's gonna work,
but it'll definitely
be exciting.
I'd keep the pessimism
to yourself this time.
Okay, I'm not a
pessimist... I'm a realist.
Who's on probation.
I know. Lim is a grown-up.
She wants her ideas
to be challenged.
It's part of our job to do it.
In recovery, we talk a lot
about the value of humility.
Hey, Lim is not a higher power.
And you're confusing being
humble with being a wuss.
Ah, it's Lim.
But feel free to ignore it.
Show her what a badass you are.
Hey. I haven't
seen you all day.
I took it off.
Lim's covering my residents,
and, uh, Kellan's in town.
Mm. We're gonna see
Young the Giant.
And left these in my desk.
That'll be fun.
Yeah, fun for me.
I think he'd rather
be with his friends.
Although, he does enjoy me
paying for the tickets and beer.
Oh, my God, Kellan
can drink now?
I'm sure he's been
drinking for a while,
but, yeah, legally
for a month now.
Time flies.
Faster than you'd ever imagine.
Have a good night.
Park?
Andrews just closed
a partnership deal
with a big CRO.
He wants me to manage
it and serve as P.I.
Congrats.
It is a great opportunity,
exactly what I have
been looking for,
but it's gonna mean a
lot more time at work,
and I'm hoping to
be a mother soon.
My favorite memories
are all school plays,
baseball games, camping trips.
And my biggest regret
is that I missed
way too many of those moments.
Sorry. I wouldn't have asked
if I didn't want to
hear your answer.
You have a great job.
You know, maybe not the
opportunity of a lifetime,
but you can have a set
schedule with reasonable hours.
You know, it seems to me,
you already have the
best of both worlds.
Thanks.
And tell Kellan I said hi.
Will do.
Kelli is prepped and ready
for tomorrow morning.
Good. We are going home.
A 13-year-old can't
consent to sex,
and we're obligated to
report it if she does.
You want to call the cops
because she had sex
with her boyfriend?
Not the police. Child
Protective Services.
Just because her
mom says it's okay
doesn't negate that
it's statutory rape.
But if two
13-year-olds have sex,
which one is the rapist, and
which one is the rape victim?
They're both victims.
But only if they're
both rapists,
which doesn't make sense.
The terminology is
not the issue, Shaun.
She's in seventh grade,
sleeps with a Teddy Bear.
At the very least, her
mother should be required
to talk to a counselor.
You really think that would help
or just create an
even bigger mess?
That's not our call.
We have a duty
to... No, we don't.
Our patient is post-pubescent,
Tanner stage four.
She has the right
to her own decisions
regarding sexual activity,
as long as the partner
is of similar age.
Just because her body has
matured doesn't mean she's...
I am the attending, and
that is my decision.
That's true, Shaun,
but maybe you two should
discuss it a bit more.
The law is clear.
There is nothing
more to discuss.
Mmm. That smells amazing.
I am going to change.
My mother's marinara.
Usually there's
roasted garlic in here,
but I was told you have
certain food sensitivities.
Did he say sensitivity
or did he...
Explosive diarrhea.
Mm. I'm gonna wring his neck.
As you should. Here, taste.
Oh, my God. Right?
That is fantastic.
It's better with
the roasted garlic,
but, you know, your
house, your rules.
Now I see
where he learned it.
Shaun
cooks just like you.
Pre-measures everything
and arranges the bowls
in the order they go in.
Surgeons. We know
how to get it done.
Not to mention your fondness
for extra clean utensils.
No such thing as extra clean.
No, but I cleaned it.
You rinsed it.
I'm gonna sauté some vegetables.
Should be ready in 11 minutes.
Okay. I'll get changed.
There... the septal
leaflet of the tricuspid.
Play it again.
He's got severe regurg.
Which means we need to add
a valve repair to the CABG
and ventricular reconstruction.
There's no way he's strong
enough for that much surgery.
We don't have a choice.
I just need to figure out
how to do it all
in one procedure.
We could still do the BiVAD
with unmatched donor. No.
It's... The same idea
I said no to before.
So, what do you want us to do?
Nothing.
I need to think this
through on my own.
We could help you research.
I just need to figure out
the best surgical plan.
Have you considered
implanting an Impella first
to decrease the afterload?
And significantly increase
his odds of stroking out?
Sorry. Go home, get rest.
This is my problem.
I'll figure it out.
Lim's under a lot of pressure.
I'm...
I'm... I'm... I'm fine.
I'm just tired.
See you tomorrow.
Your call has been forwarded
to an automatic
voice message system.
Hey, Quinn, it's Danny.
Um, if you have some time,
could you give me a call?
I'm not up for another meeting,
but, uh, I'm feeling like...
I really should talk to someone.
Thanks.
I was... about
to take a shower.
Unless you would
like to go first.
Thanks, but you can go ahead.
I'm gonna make some coffee.
Oh. Dr. Glassman
already made coffee.
He also bought croissants for
us before he left for work.
Wow.
With breakfast and
coffee already made,
we now have time to take
an extra long shower.
Together.
Yes.
We do have time for
that.
A new ventricle and a new valve?
Repaired ventricle
and replaced valve.
This is really
my... only option?
There are mechanical
heart devices.
That I've already considered.
With heart failure
as advanced as yours,
it's not a better option.
Okay.
Whatever you think is best.
We're gonna take
good care of you.
I know. Thank you.
Get the new valve prepped.
Good morning.
Oh. When you
start your morning
with shower sex and
croissants, it definitely is.
Lucky you.
Would you be okay if your son
was having shower
sex and croissants
in middle school?
I am still contemplating
nursery colors,
so not ready to
think about all that.
But... maybe her
mom has a point.
I spent all of my high
school sneaking around
my parents' backs.
That's not a relationship
I want with my kid.
We're talking about
kids... Early teens.
I was 18 when I
lost my virginity.
Leon Maxwell.
We'd been together for a year.
I was sure I was ready.
And... how was it?
Fine.
Fun, after we figured
some things out.
But starting from Leon,
all the way to
Dwayne in med school,
sex has always felt
like a distraction.
A distraction?
Okay, definitely
sounds like those guys
had no idea what
they were doing.
Once I was intimate
in a relationship,
I felt less like my true self
and less close to God.
That's why I stopped.
Stopped?
Like, stopped...
Having sex.
I don't intend to do it
again until I'm married.
How long has it been?
Years ago, before we met.
You never told me.
We joke about sex all the time.
I go along with the jokes
so I don't become the joke.
I would never make fun of
you for anything like that.
Lea, you told me my
Bible study group
was "Fantasy Faithball."
Mm.
I'm sorry.
But then what was
your plan with Perez?
The same as any guy I date.
It's not like I don't
kiss or some other things,
but...
if a man is not
willing to commit
to who I am as a person
or what I believe in,
he is not worth my time.
It just... seems
a bit extreme?
And a little sad.
I mean, it can be a
really fun part of life,
and you've just cut
yourself off from it.
You're not listening to me.
For me, it wasn't a value
add... It was the...
This is why I don't tell people.
It's impossible to know
exactly how to shape
and size this valve
without knowing the shape of
the heart it's going into.
Which we won't know
until Lim finishes
repairing the ventricle.
He'd be better off with
a transplant, right?
I agree.
The patient's just going along
'cause Lim steamrolled him.
A square peg won't
seal a round hole,
and at the stage of the surgery
we're going to find that out,
it will be too
late to turn back.
It is not a perfect solution,
but it's the best we have.
And you've explained to Bob
just how imperfect
this solution is?
He's aware of the risks
and that he has limited options.
Sometimes patients need help
making difficult decisions.
I don't think this is a decision
you should be making for him.
And I'm not the only one.
I trust you.
We're operating on Bob
first thing in the morning.
Her blood pressure skyrocketed.
She could have a stroke.
Start IV labetalol.
This is why children
shouldn't have...
Stop.
You need to focus
on the medicine.
She is going into
critical bradycardia.
We need to push atropine.
My patient's blood pressure
has remained stable.
We can operate tomorrow.
That's great.
Mmm. This smells amazing.
Mmm. Tastes even better.
The secret is thyme. You
got to have fresh thyme,
because if you let it dry,
it saps all the flavor.
That and a little
bit of lemon zest.
Truth bomb... uh, I might have
oversold my enthusiasm
for you staying here,
but if you keep cooking
like Gordon Ramsay,
I won't let you leave.
Well, as much as I love
sleeping in a twin bed
in a half-remodeled nursery,
I think I may have to decline.
Yeah, Ruben? Whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
That's... That's
double the quote.
Okay. Yeah.
Approved.
Unbelievable.
Now I have to replace
the roof rafters.
Yay. If you have to
replace the whole roof,
why not just get
a brand-new house?
Why would I do that?
I love the house.
It's ancient, too
big for one person,
and completely falling apart.
You do complain a lot about
all the repairs you have to do.
That is the house
where we brought Maddie
home as a newborn.
That is the house
where we celebrated
every single one
of her birthdays.
Every year, we'd turn that
house into a haunted house
with a cemetery in the
backyard and a fog machine.
We scared the living daylights
out of every kid in
the neighborhood.
I come home into that foyer...
and that staircase is
where Maddie would descend
in her prom dress.
You can never sell that house.
I can never sell that house.
Clinic's low on phlebotomy kits.
Any chance we could
steal some from surgical?
Sure.
Just make us whole when
your shipment gets in.
Andrews offered me...
I heard. Congrats.
You deserve it.
Thanks. I do.
But... you're smart,
aggressive, and ambitious.
I'm sensing there's
another "but."
You decided to never have kids.
Wouldn't really say I decided.
It just never happened.
I'm sorry. Don't be.
I can't be both the
mother I'd want to be
and the driven,
perfectionist surgeon
I know I am.
My advice... Decide
what brings you
the most fulfillment and
then commit fully to that.
You can't have it all.
But plenty of men...
No, they don't.
They're just less conflicted
about the choices they make.
You totally put me
on the spot with Lim.
I never said I was
gonna back you up.
You're right. My bad.
You and I know probation
means different things for us.
Yours is a slap on the wrist,
a correction for coloring
outside the lines.
I'm in a holding pattern,
while everybody watches to see
if I'm actually a
surgeon or a junkie.
Part of being a
surgeon is standing up
and fighting for your patients.
Why'd you leave your robe
hanging on the bathroom door?!
I didn't. I lent my extra
one to Dr. Glassman.
You both hang your robes
outside the bathroom?
I never noticed that before.
I'm glad
you find it so amusing.
What'd you expect?
You ran a sneak
attack on your husband
when you had a house guest.
Who else hangs their
robe outside the bathroom
so the steam doesn't
make it moist?
Mm. And that's not
the only thing.
Their cooking techniques,
cleaning styles,
the way they lay out
their toiletries.
You said he's like
Shaun's father.
Yeah. The apple
doesn't fall far.
Somehow, in this case, I think
Shaun's actually the tree.
Uhh.
One thing is clear...
Grandpa Glassman
needs a new robe,
one that doesn't
match your husband's.
Aww. Grandpa Glassy.
I love that.
Now if only I could
erase a certain image
of Grandpa Glassy.
Hey, I'm really sorry
about saying you
were... extreme and sad.
Thank you.
It's unfair of me to blame you
for being surprised at something
I've intentionally never shared.
Abstinence is important to me,
but I don't always
feel comfortable
being open about it.
Well, I'm really glad you did.
Do you have a vibrator?
Because in terms of getting
closer to God, I find...
No, we're not talking
about this right now.
Two croissants, please. Mm.
Cut this suture, Dr. Wolke.
The valve is seated... nicely.
I've removed a lot of scar
tissue from this ventricle,
but there's still more.
We need enough viable tissue
to close this ventricle.
I don't think we have it.
Hold this clamp. Tightly.
This area looked good
in the pre-op MIBI scan,
but it's dead now.
Must be delayed apoptosis.
What's the plan?
I need an idea.
Any idea.
We could do an
additional vessel bypass.
It might restore some
hibernating tissue.
Some, but we'd never find enough
to make up for this deficit.
Can we use a synthetic
patch to close the gap?
It needs muscle tissue
for the ventricle to pump.
You can't have a
functional heart
without a working
right ventricle.
Unless we do what we do
in babies with
Ebstein's Anomaly.
Bypass the defective
right ventricle,
divert deoxygenated blood
directly back to the lungs.
He'd only have one
ventricle pumping blood
to his entire body.
But in time, the left
ventricle would get stronger.
We keep those babies alive
until they're teenagers.
That could buy
you plenty of time
to find a matched
donor heart. Let's go.
Hey.
They already have
four clinical trials
with IRB approval.
Mm.
I am honored that
you thought of me.
It's just...
I'm trying to get pregnant...
IVF with a donor.
And I've decided...
I can't have it all.
At the risk of...
overstepping...
I think you're selling
yourself short.
My mother was the
Senior Director
for Human Rights First.
Total workaholic.
Growing up, sometimes
it seemed like
she was always on the
phone or a plane. Mm.
That must have
been hard for you.
It wasn't easy, but whenever
I really needed her,
she was always there for me.
She was my idol.
And to this day,
if I need advice on
a tough decision,
she's my first call.
There's more to
being a great mom
than parent-teacher conferences.
Is her
pressure climbing?
No. 120 over 81,
holding steady.
Curettage is complete.
The entire tumor's evacuated.
Massage the uterine fundus.
Pressure's dropping. Fast.
She is going into shock.
Could the tumor have caused
some sort of bleeding disorder?
There's no bleeding down here.
Push vasopressors and fluids.
What is this?
The tumor thinned
her uterine wall.
She's perforated. She's
bleeding internally.
Prep her for a STAT laparotomy.
Rapid infuse two units of O neg.
We need to isolate the vessel
and clamp it before she...
We just lost her pulse.
Retraction.
A uni-heart? That's new.
Well, once we removed
the scar tissue,
there was even
less viable muscle
than what we anticipated.
Dr. Wolke came through
with the audible.
Uh, sports reference.
She's saying it was your idea.
Aww.
Which Dr. Lim
executed brilliantly.
And I'd be saying that even
if she weren't in the room.
You'll still need a
donor heart eventually,
but this should
buy you five years,
maybe more before that.
Thank you.
The surgery was too
dangerous for Bob.
You were right about that.
And about advocating
for the patient,
even when you were
pissing me off.
Might've helped if I had
had the uni-heart idea
before the patient was
splayed open on the table.
Yeah, sometimes great
things come out of pressure.
Although, I try not
to depend on them.
Sounds like the perfect prelude
to letting me off probation.
Don't push it.
But... excellent work.
Keep it up.
You too, Dr. Perez.
Hi, honey.
Is it over?
Your surgery was a lot more
complicated than anticipated,
and it was successful.
We got all the tumor.
Everything kinda hurts.
I will increase your medication.
Ryan. Hey.
I thought this little guy
might, uh, make you feel better.
Aww. He's such a cutie.
Yeah, I got him
at the gift shop.
Hey, I brought your laptop, too.
The group chat's blowing up
over this new Apex update.
Um, is there Wi-Fi
in this place?
Kelli needs to rest tonight.
And when you go home,
sexual activity
will be very risky,
given the trauma
of your surgery.
For how long?
Six months, at least.
And maybe you should think
about waiting even longer.
We'll talk more
about this later.
Thank you...
both...
for saving my girl.
Hey. It's Danny.
Yeah. Having a bit
of a rough week.
Thanks, man.
Uh, you know where
St. Bon's hospital is?
There's a coffee
shop two blocks west.
I'll meet you out front in 20.
Okay.
This is awkward.
What's awkward? Nothing happened.
Wait. What do you mean nothing...
What do you mean, what do
I mean? Nothing happened.
Right. Nothing happened.
Exactly.
That is very impressive.
If I saw your mom totally naked
and I was also totally naked,
I would definitely
never forget...
That's not helping,
Shaun. Thank you, Shaun.
You know what? All
things considered,
I actually had a
really nice time.
I'll be craving that salmon.
I wrote down the recipe.
Actually, the salmon comes
out a lot more tender
out of my Viking oven.
I'm gonna have you both over
to dinner as a "thank you."
And my neighbor is calling.
The one who stole
your lawn mower?
No, the one who cut back
my trees without asking.
Yes, Brent?
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa. Slow down.
What?
Danny.
I was surprised to
hear from you, man.
Heard you went to rehab. Yeah.
All good. Been
four times myself.
I'm kinda in a hurry.
It's mostly black
tar around right now,
but... I got a
little bit of white.
♪ Home is where I want to be ♪
♪ Pick me up and
turn me 'round ♪
It ain't cheap, but
you're a doctor.
I'm sure you can afford it.
♪ The less we say
about it, the better ♪
♪ Make it up as we go along ♪
♪ Feet on the ground ♪
Yo...
♪ Head in the sky ♪
we doing this or not?
♪ It's okay, I know
nothing's wrong ♪
♪ Nothing ♪
♪ Hey, yo ♪
♪ I got plenty of time ♪
How'd your case go
with the probationers?
They both did good.
Great to hear.
Keep it up, Chief.
♪ You got light in your eyes ♪
♪ And you're standing
here beside me ♪
♪ I love the passing of time ♪
♪ Never for money ♪
♪ Always for love ♪
♪ Cover up and say good night ♪
♪ Say good night ♪
♪ Home is where I want to be ♪
♪ But I guess I'm
already there ♪
♪ I come home ♪
♪ She lifted up her wings ♪
♪ I guess that this
must be the place ♪
Danny?
Are you looking for me? No.
Um, no, I was
just... walking by
and... and heard the choir.
It's comforting.
We practice every
Thursday, and I'm late.
D-Don't mind me.
I'm just gonna sit
here if that's okay.
♪ Hey, yo ♪
♪ You got light in your eyes ♪
Are you okay?
♪ And you're standing
here beside me ♪ Yeah.
♪ I love the passing of time ♪
♪ Never for money ♪
♪ Always for love ♪
♪ Cover up and say good night ♪
♪ Say good night ♪
♪ Night ♪
♪ Home is where I want to be ♪
♪ But I guess I'm
already there ♪
♪ I come home ♪
♪ She lifted up her wings ♪
♪ I guess that this
must be the place ♪
♪ I can't tell
one from another ♪
♪ Did I find you? ♪
♪ Or did you find me? ♪
Are you the homeowner?
What happened?
Electrical fire in the kitchen.
Old house, old wiring.
Wouldn't have been so
bad, but the termite guys
apparently disconnected
all the smoke detectors.
♪ Where I'll be ♪
I'm sorry. ♪ Hey, yo ♪
♪ You got plenty of time ♪
♪ Hey, yo ♪