Previously, on
The Good Doctor...
Dr. Murphy,
you shouldn't be in contact
with patients, or their families.
Do you understand?
- Don't be stupid.
- What? There's no cameras in here.
Dr. Lim. Dr. Melendez.
I do not want to
be a pathologist.
Dr. Han, you need to make
me a surgical resident again.
Hey, what are you
doing up so early?
I'm not up early. I
never went to bed.
Oh, my God, didn't
you get my text?
I told you I was spending
the night with Jake.
I don't want to
be a pathologist.
Oh.
It's that still.
Shaun, no one's life goes
exactly like they dreamed as a kid.
You're still a doctor,
still saving lives,
just in a lab instead
of an operating room.
Where are you going?
I'm going to walk to work.
The hospital is four miles away.
Studies have shown that
walking boosts creative inspiration.
Shaun, I just think...
You don't understand.
Neither does Dr. Han.
I need to change his mind.
I don't know how.
- Mmm. We're gonna be late.
- So stop.
And don't be smiling at me
when you see me in the hall.
I smile at everyone.
I'm a friendly guy.
You'd be a horrible
poker player.
- What are you doing?
- Murphy's on the corner. Move it.
- That's not where his bus drops off.
- Do you think he saw us?
He's not looking over here.
Well, that doesn't
mean anything with him.
We gotta get out of
here before the light turns.
Let's go. Move it.
Through the generous support
of Saint Bonaventure Foundation,
we've been able to transport
Kenny and his mother
from their home in Mississippi.
And we'll be covering the cost
of surgery and post-op recovery.
And all I have to do
is buy one CD a month
for the next 100 years.
No repayment necessary.
We appreciate you allowing
us to share your case
as an educational
opportunity for our staff.
Well, you know what they
say. Those who can't, teach.
And as you can see, I
can't do much of anything.
Actually, y'all haven't
really seen anything yet.
How about we get
this party started?
The neurofibroma
started as a small bump
near the base of the spine.
In less than six months,
it encircled his abdomen
and grew to over 100 pounds.
The blood supply becoming
so intertwined with the patient's,
it was deemed inoperable.
But we've been able to come
up with an innovative surgical plan
that will allow us to slowly
peel the tumor off the
front and back of his torso
in one piece and give
Kenny his life back.
We didn't expect to see you.
This is just about logistics,
witness lists, scheduling.
The hospital's attorney could've
handled this on his own, Dr. Han.
I understand but I
wanted to be here.
Three reasons really.
If my doctors are gonna
be judged in this room,
I wanted to see the place, see
all of you, and see the mood.
Well, we try to
make it very casual.
Yeah, I know.
But have you ever been judged?
I have. It's scary.
Someone has gone to
the trouble of checking out
every aspect of your actions,
every decision you've made.
You don't know what they
know, what they're gonna ask,
what could be
misunderstood, misinterpreted.
Also, and this is
kind of embarrassing,
but our lawyer,
probably not the best.
I decided to save a few dollars on him,
so I could hire a private investigator,
check all of you out.
We're not the
ones on trial here.
You see?
You say you make it casual
and then you call it a trial.
Now, I'm sure she
won't find anything.
I mean, nothing
too crazy, right?
Maybe just something...
embarrassing.
Maybe a lapse of
judgment here or there.
I mean, like I was saying,
you parse every choice
anyone has made,
gonna be a few things they'd
rather not revisit. Am I right?
And the third reason?
Well, I thought maybe you'd
want to work out a compromise.
The surgery went well.
We were able to fully evacuate
the subdural hematoma
without any complications.
It's a good thing you didn't
hesitate to bring her in.
One advantage of being
an insecure, first-time mom
who panics every time
her child has a slight fever.
Did I just hear you admit
that you're insecure?
The girl who double-majored
in physics and chemistry
because the dean told her
they were the two toughest?
Mom guilt ruins
us all. You'll see.
Whenever you decide to give
up the motorcycle and settle down.
No way.
My kid's going to kindergarten
on the back of a Ducati.
I'm sorry. I need to go
check on another patient.
How long will she
need to stay here?
I'm still not sure what
caused the bleeding.
I didn't see any signs of an
aneurysm or AVM, so that's good.
I'll have a better idea
when I get the post-op test
results back from Pathology.
Thank you.
This is why I love pathology.
We don't just fix stuff. We figure
out how it got broken and why.
Good morning.
Just checking to make sure you got
my clot specimen and blood draws.
Just logged them in.
Great. And if there's any way
to expedite, I'd appreciate it.
The mom is a friend of
mine and stressed to the max.
- Pretty sure the bleed was caused...
- Stop.
Sorry. I meant, please, stop.
I'd rather not know what you
think. It causes confirmation bias.
Copy that.
Hey, um, did I see you on
Hanover Street this morning?
I don't know.
Were you on Hanover
Street this morning?
Yes. I walked to work.
Did you see anything
interesting on the walk?
Hmm...
Shaun?
We can't both expedite your results
and reminisce about our morning walks.
Sorry. Carry on.
You're totally freaking
out, aren't you?
No. I am not freaking out.
All my patients freak out
waiting for their final test results.
For 48 hours you don't
know if you've won the lottery
or if you're gonna be
dead in a few months.
Hell, I freak out, too. It's
the only time I feel helpless.
The treatment's over. There's
nothing left to do but wait.
I'm a little stressed.
That speech, not helpful.
My advice? Embrace it.
You're experiencing emotions
only a few people on
Earth will ever understand,
the kind Hemingway wrote about.
- I'm more of a Faulkner guy.
- You would be.
- You don't like Faulkner?
- No, I don't like Faulkner.
- Nobody really likes Faulkner.
- I like Faulkner.
Right.
Anyway, if there's
anything you need from me,
even if it's just to talk,
you have my direct number.
Do not hesitate to use it.
I appreciate that.
And I would like to
show my gratitude.
I know I haven't been the
easiest patient to deal with.
That's not necessary.
I mean, if you want, you can
make a donation to cancer research.
I already donate. I wanted to
thank you. Not society at large.
How about... Have you ever
tried Macallan's Sherry Oak 25?
I don't drink. And I just
said it's not necessary.
How about a weekend at Ojai?
- I hear the spa is amazing.
- No means no.
I'm not trying to molest
you. I just want to thank you.
And you have. And
you are very welcome.
Why do you have to
control every little thing?
I have pepper spray in my
purse. Don't make me use it.
Carly, I am gonna need 60 units
of type-B positive-packed
red blood cells held for OR.
Sixty? You operating on
a hemophiliac elephant?
Our patient has a
200-pound neurofibroma.
Cool.
There's more blood in
the tumor than the patient,
so we're gonna have to follow
massive transfusion protocol.
You...
You might need antifibrinolytic
agents to control the bleeding.
That's a good idea. Thanks.
I could do some research
on cell salvage techniques.
- Cancer is a risk, but if we...
- I'm sorry, Shaun.
Melendez has put
together a pretty big team,
so we have everything we need.
I talked to Murphy.
He definitely saw us.
What'd he say?
It's not what he said,
it's how he acted.
He was clearly
uncomfortable talking to me.
He's uncomfortable
talking to everyone.
We need to get
out in front of this.
Tell Andrews before
someone else does.
No. We need to figure out
exactly what Murphy saw.
How? We can't just ask him
if he saw us making... bread.
We're not gonna get
anywhere with indirect questions.
I'll talk to him.
You think you can read
him better than I can?
No, but if at first
you don't succeed...
Let the man try?
Dr. Han wants to see you two.
- Both of us?
- Yep.
Yep.
Have a seat.
Actually, we've been
meaning to talk you.
The issue is...
Dr. Han met with
the medical board.
We're not going to be
suspended or reprimanded.
The hospital will pay
fines on your behalf
and you'll need to complete a
few continuing education classes.
But overall, not bad.
- Thank you.
- Yeah, thanks.
Does this mean I'm back
on the surgical team?
No, it does not.
You convinced the
board that he's competent.
You're welcome.
We got a big problem
with our tiny patient.
I did a repeat assessment
of the pre-op CTs
and found a trace
subarachnoid bleed.
But there was no
bruise on her scalp.
I know.
The only way she could get this
injury is if someone shook her,
and they would have
to shake her hard.
Someone abused her.
No. I've known Laura
since high school.
She's the most composed,
even-tempered person I've ever met.
And she's totally
devoted to that baby.
- What about the father?
- She conceived via a donor.
A nanny, a relative, a boyfriend
who's been helping out?
She waited so long for this,
wanted to do everything herself.
Then it has to be her.
We need to call Child
Protective Services.
No. Not yet.
I'm gonna do an MRI to rule out
benign enlargement
of the extra-axial space.
- Before we ruin her life.
- Good idea.
Except for the part
about you doing the test.
She's your friend.
You think I'd try to help
someone cover up child abuse?
I don't know you well enough
to know what you would or
wouldn't do to protect a friend.
I could do the MRI. I'm
not the mother's friend.
But you are a pathologist.
Giving MRIs is not your job.
Page Farmer. Have him do it.
On it.
Murphy, we need to talk.
I don't have a girlfriend.
Okay...
Is that consistent with
what you've deduced
and seen regarding my life?
Yes.
Good.
Enjoy your apple.
It's not fair.
Shaun is being
punished for mistakes
that Han thinks he
might make in the future.
He's not punishing him.
He just saved his ass.
Okay, Kenny.
The MRA's gonna help us map
the blood supply to the tumor.
If you could just lie still.
No talking until we're done.
Sure, no problem.
We should take a stand.
Meaning what? Stage a walkout?
How much does one of
these bad boys cost anyway?
About three million, but it's
worthless unless you stop talking.
Sorry. My bad.
Us getting fired is not gonna
do anything to help Shaun.
And I'm not even sure
we should be helping him.
Did you ever stop to think that
maybe Han knows what he's doing?
Shaun has made mistakes but he
has three more years of residency.
That is plenty of
time to improve.
Yes, you can build a winning
team through supportive training,
but you can also do it
by recruiting the best
and pushing them, relentlessly.
No feelings, no
charity, no loyalty.
Those who thrive,
and get better than they ever
thought they could, you keep.
And those who don't, you cut.
That's not good.
It works for Jeff Bezos
and Bill Belichick.
I'm not talking about
your leadership lecture.
I'm talking about this.
We need to page Melendez.
What are you talking
about? You know me.
How could you possibly
believe I could hurt my baby?
I don't.
Which is why I ordered
the additional tests.
But did you never leave
her with anyone else?
Even for just a few minutes so
that you could take a nap or a bath?
Taking care of a
newborn, it's exhausting.
No, it isn't.
After waiting for so long,
every single moment,
no matter how hard...
It's not exhausting, it's joy.
Laura, I know you love her,
but you're still human.
You must get tired sometimes.
I don't, really.
You don't understand because...
Because you haven't experienced it.
But when you love
someone so much...
The tests, they
have to be wrong.
We expected the tumor to
grow since the last scans,
but not to this extent.
Blood vessels that I thought
we'd be able to quickly cauterize
are now thicker than my thumb.
It's impossible to remove the tumor
without causing you to bleed to death.
No.
I don't care how risky it is.
I'd rather die in surgery
than continue to live with this
huge damn tick
sucking the life out of me.
Kenny, as long as your
heart remains healthy,
you basically will be, too.
We can do a better
job treating the pain.
I don't want to be treated.
I want to be cured.
I want my life back.
I always thought all I had
to do was get enough money
or find the right doctors.
But if you're telling
me there's no hope...
I Appreciate
everything y'all done,
or at least tried to do.
The injuries from shaking a baby
are much different than
from blunt force trauma.
It's awful, but
also interesting.
It's like you're a detective
in a murder mystery.
Only thank God,
the baby's not dead.
That's exactly what Carly said.
She likes solving
medical mysteries.
She's very smart and aggressive.
Well, how does she
treat you? Is she nice?
Yes, she's very nice.
She wants me to
stay in her department.
She thinks we make a good team.
So, it sounds like you have
a case you're interested in
and a co-worker you
like who's nice to you.
Maybe pathology won't
be that bad after all.
I have work to do.
Since it seems we're gonna be
working together for a while longer,
maybe it is time we
came out of the closet.
Maybe? Are you
saying you want to?
Do you want to?
Maybe.
You're afraid it would
make things awkward?
People seeing us as a couple.
Yes, obviously.
But at the moment,
I'm more afraid that
we wouldn't be having
this conversation
if Murphy hadn't
almost busted us.
Which makes me think we're
not ready to have this conversation.
It's understandable
if we aren't.
We've both been in relationships
we thought were gonna last.
Understandable,
but why should we even
care what people at work think?
So, should we talk to Andrews?
Maybe. What do you think?
Maybe.
Uh, Sawchuck?
Sorry for the wait.
Excuse me. Duck curry and
rice? Forty minutes? Really?
Sorry. The kitchen
fell a bit behind.
- It shouldn't be much longer.
- You're not just behind.
People who've come in after
me, they've gotten their food.
Gone home, eaten, they're
in their PJs watching a movie.
I'm so sorry. I'll
check right now.
Duck curry.
Here you go, sir.
Duck curry, brown rice.
White rice.
Um. Excuse me. Duck
curry with brown rice?
- Yes.
- Connelly?
That's me. Thank you.
- What are you guys doing back there?
- I'm so sorry, sir.
You know what? I'm tired of
sorry. I just... I want my food!
You know, sir, it should
just be another minute.
I don't want to wait any longer!
I'm sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
I didn't... I didn't mean
to yell. I'm so sorry.
Carry on. Carry
on. Enjoy your...
She's always
trying to one-up us.
Morgan.
She's not staying late because
she wants to do research.
She's staying late so that
Han can see she's staying late.
It's just who she is.
Don't take it personal.
Mmm.
My dad's a taekwondo grand
master, coached me growing up.
He always used to say,
"Only you can beat you."
Well, my mom's a lounge
singer and she used to say,
"Upstage me and
I'll beat your ass."
You'd think if you're selling boba
you'd have straws wide enough
to get the balls
through the damn thing.
I can't believe
you drink that stuff.
It's like putting
gummy bears in a drink.
You give up? Want
a soda instead?
I see you.
Which is, I assume,
your primary objective.
I didn't even know
you were still here.
I've been reading the latest
journal articles on neurofibromas...
Go home.
There's nothing you
can do for Kenny Grimm.
And you're gonna have
other patients tomorrow.
I got an idea.
If we embolize the larger blood
vessels to the tumor before surgery,
we can use your body's
clotting factor to help clog them.
This should reduce
hemorrhaging during surgery
and allow us to excise the
tumor without you bleeding out.
We'll steer a catheter
through an artery in your thigh...
Yes.
Kenny, maybe you
should let them finish.
No, I shouldn't.
And yes, you should. Yes. Yes.
Yes. As soon as possible. Yes.
Thank you.
The tests came back. They
confirm the previous results.
Well, they're wrong.
There must be some other...
There has to be
another test. Please.
Ma'am, you're gonna
need to come with us.
- You need help.
- From you?
You're my friend and
you called the police?
Well, someone hurt your
baby. If it wasn't you...
No one hurt my baby. You're
wrong! How can you not believe me?
Just need to get a few more
branches off the aorta and we're done.
Well done, Dr. Browne.
- What's fluid status?
- CVP is 14 and rising.
Get diuretics on deck.
Forty milligrams, IV Lasix.
Careful. If his
pressure goes too low,
his kidneys won't perfuse.
I need you to keep his
CVP between eight and 12.
He can't tolerate much more of
this. We need to get him to an OR.
Embolizing his vessels
caused third spacing of
fluids to the body and lungs.
We saved the operation,
but now we only have
half the time to do it.
Hey. Any word?
No, not yet.
Isn't there someone from
radiology who can expedite?
Someone who owes you a favor?
Even if there was, I
would not waste it on you,
because you do not need it.
You're one of the most
willful patients I've ever had
and the finish line is in sight.
All you need to do is
just run through the tape.
Look, if it helps,
as soon as I'm done with this
patient, we can talk some more.
I can write you a script for
something to help with the anxiety.
But I don't think you
need it. You got this.
- More suction.
- Me, too. More sponges.
Retract.
That's it. What's his
estimated blood loss?
About eight and a half liters.
The entire human body
typically only has five
and a half liters of blood.
Yeah, I know.
Let's get 30 more
units on deck of PRBC.
Add cryo, fresh frozen
plasma and platelets to that.
We should have checked
for blood breakdown products.
If you don't mind, I'm
trying to pay attention to this.
I wasn't talking to you,
or about this patient.
We need to re-examine the
subdural blood clot specimens.
If there's hemosiderin
deposition
and chronic membranes,
including fibrous wall,
it could prove it was not abuse.
What else could it be? The tests
proved non-accidental trauma.
Yes, the tests were right.
Resected portion is secure.
IVs and central line?
- Secure.
Okay, everybody, get in
position. Let's flip this pancake.
On three. One, two, three.
Wait. His heart rate's
spiked. Lay him back down.
Softly. Softly.
We okay?
Yeah, just a blip.
Once more with feeling.
Ready? One, two, three.
- How we doing?
- Good. He's stable.
All right, swab the
posterior incision site.
Okay. Scalpel and
sponge on a stick.
- He's crashing.
- He's ventilating fine.
We've got no immediate
blood loss or hemorrhaging.
It looks like
distributive shock.
I need stat labs and
initiate shock resuscitation.
He's got a high white
count and what looks to be
a systemic pro-inflammatory
cytokine release.
Cutting off the blood
supply to the tumor
is causing
post-embolization syndrome.
I need intra-arterial lidocaine,
130 milligrams of methylprednisolone
and start antibiotics.
Should we be trying to
reverse the embolization?
Restore blood flow to the tumor?
Well, then we'd risk him
bleeding out even faster.
We need to abort.
Cut off what we've already
excised and leave the rest.
- No. We can't give up.
- We're not giving up.
We're stopping a futile
procedure to save the patient.
We need to get Murphy in
here. It's a blood flow problem.
Murphy has a special talent
for visualizing complex anatomy.
We don't have time. We
need to stop the PES now.
- Page Dr. Murphy.
- No, do not page Dr. Murphy.
I get it. You like him. But we
don't have time for an audition.
I'm trying to save my patient's life.
My patient, which means it's my call.
I am also trying to
save your patient's life.
So I'm urging you
to stop wasting time.
Now we've cut away almost
half. That's all we can do right now.
So let's remove it
and give him a chance to
live and fight another day.
The breakdown products show
the injury that caused the hematoma
happened at least
seven weeks ago.
When was she born?
A little over seven weeks ago.
The vacuum delivery must
have caused a subdural bleed
which re-bled two days ago.
The baby wasn't abused.
Shaun, we need you in the OR.
Any thoughts, Dr. Murphy?
You don't have enough time.
You can't fully map
the circulatory system
and remove the tumor
without killing the patient.
It's too complex.
Well, at least he was
brief and to the point.
Now, can we do what I...
But you don't have
to do it quickly.
We slow down, he bleeds out.
If you clamp the aorta, it could
lower the blood flow to the tumor
enough to slow the
release of the cytokines.
Clamping the aorta will kill
the intestines, kidneys and legs.
Not if we release the
clamp every 10 minutes.
Give it just enough blood
to stop the cytokines,
but not so much that
he bleeds to death.
Let's do it.
Thank you for the
consult, Dr. Murphy.
Reposition him to lateral.
Secure IV and central line.
Secure.
Ten-blade. Starting
mid-line laparotomy.
DeBakey.
Opening up the lesser
sac. Vessel loops.
Get a Rumel ready.
I need umbilical tape.
MRI exams show chronic
changes of surgery and radiation
but no sign of residual
tumor detected.
No signs. None.
Zero. Zippo. Zilch.
Wow.
We'll do another MRI in
six months just to be sure,
but you are in the clear.
This is exactly
what we hoped for.
Kinehora.
Knock on wood.
Thank you.
You son of a bitch. I told you.
You told me no.
It's too heavy for diamonds.
- Is it a magic eight-ball?
- Will you just open it?
I don't like baseball.
I do.
So you got me
something you like?
I caught that foul ball
down the third baseline
on my 13th birthday.
My dad was amazed
that I snagged it.
After the game, we
went outside the stadium.
And I was a shy kid,
but my father pushed me
to ask my favorite players
to sign it, and they all did.
Bert Campaneris, Rollie Fingers,
Reggie Jackson, Catfish Hunter.
Yeah, if it happened
today, it'd all be on video.
But all I have to remember
that awesome day
is that ball.
I wanted you to have
something that mattered to me.
Aaron, I can't.
Oh, yes, you can.
Bye.
Cancer changes people.
I've had patients tell
me it was a blessing.
That their lives
were better after.
They're idiots.
Maybe.
Would you have thought of such
a wonderful gift 11 months ago?
Care to do the honors?
Let's take it up.
I'm so sorry.
I should have trusted you.
Please talk to me, Laura.
Yell at me if you
want. I deserve it.
- It's not your fault.
- Yes, it is.
I should have done
more research,
looked harder for an
alternative diagnosis.
I mean, it's not your fault
you are the way you are.
You don't understand
the love a mother feels.
I understand that a lot of
mothers abuse their children.
You don't understand love.
Because you've never allowed
yourself to be vulnerable.
Even when you were married to
Kashal, you never really committed.
You always expect
the worst in people
because that's all
you see in yourself.
Okay.
I've never been in so much pain,
but felt so good.
We'll up your pain meds.
You're still gonna need some
skin and soft tissue grafts,
but the hard part's done.
Your prognosis is excellent.
Thank y'all so much.
What am I taking this thing
home in, a glass bottle?
Y'all got something that big?
He's just being a smart-ass.
Are you sure you
want to do this?
Shut up.
I saved the patient.
I deserve to be a surgeon.
Dr. Murphy...
Dr. Han, I want my old job back.
You're making a mistake.
- Am I, Shaun?
- Yes.
Because it seems like you're
doing really well in pathology.
You made a great
save on an earlier case
and a great save today.
You keep doing
well and over time,
we can build to you
having more responsibility.
No.
I'm a surgeon.
I am not leaving your
office until you reinstate me.
What are you doing, Shaun?
Do you think ordering me to do
something will change my mind?
Do you really think it's a
good idea to try and bully me?
I am a surgeon.
Do you realize that you
are proving my point?
That you're acting immature?
Showing that you don't
know how to communicate
and you can't control
your emotions?
I am a surgeon.
But you do have a
talent that I value.
So, I'm gonna give you one last
chance to maintain your dignity
and leave my office, now.
Because if I have
to call security,
you understand that I'm
also gonna have to fire you.
I am a surgeon!
I am... I am a surgeon!
I am a surgeon, Dr. Han!
I am a surgeon.
Holding back the flood
In this skyscraper town
You gave all that
sweat and blood
Now you think you're gonna drown
You can't tell
that you're bigger
Than the sea that
you're sinking in
And you don't know what you
got But you got it at your fingertips
Ooh, you got it in you
When the lights go out
And leave you
standing in the dark
No one ever told you
This would be so hard
I know you think
Your fire is burning out
But I still see you
shining through
You got it in you
When the lights go out
And leave you
standing in the dark
No one ever told you
This would be so hard
I know you think
Your fire is burning out
But I still see you
shining through
You got it in you