- Fine...
- I'm fine...
I'm too old.
Shaq on Jordan at the buzzer!
Oh, no! Yes!
Sweet move, yes!
Still got your sneaks on, Doc?
Hang on.
Point game.
You better be passing, baby,
you'd better be passing!
Good rebound!
All right, right,
time out, time out.
Time out?
Keep bonding, Mark, I got it.
Malik?
Time to save a life.
Oh, God... Hey, Doc,
you want some of this?
Dad, what are you doing?
Hey, Doc...
Hey, busy night?
Yeah, I thought the
sun would never rise.
One more for the road.
"Tearful and upset"?
That's her chief complaint?
Mr. Thomas here OD'd on
his son's jimsonweed tea.
We'll need to
send this to the lab.
Jimsonweed?
Got to keep up
with the times, Malik.
Is there anything
else in that tea?
No, but when my dad comes down,
he's really going to kill me.
Oh, nurse, it hurts
when I do this.
Dad!
Then don't do it, Mr. Thomas.
I always use my diaphragm.
I'm, like, a total
fanatic about it, but...
Did you have unprotected
sex in the last 72 hours?
The girls at the dorm say
you can take like a quadruple
dose of birth control pills
the morning after
and it will keep you
from getting pregnant.
Yes, it can work in
some circumstances,
but it's not the best
method of birth control.
It's just so weird.
My boyfriend will kill me.
Did he force you
or threaten you?
Maybe I'm just having a
breakdown or something.
Look, I can help you
if you tell me what happened.
I had a few beers
at this party last night.
I saw this guy Mike
and I was going to
give him a ride home.
And then I woke up in my car
in the dorm parking lot.
My tights weren't up all the way
and I don't know what happened.
You don't remember?
No.
Well, how well do you know Mike?
You're a hunky
chunky one, aren't you?
What's wrong with this guy?!
Psychosis and hypersexuality
are toxic effects of jimsonweed.
Can't you guys
give him something?
Let's cover you up, sir.
What kind of work
does your father do?
He's a malpractice attorney.
Medical malpractice?
Ooh.
Really?
Did you ever see
anything so pretty, Doc?
Oh, my God! Dad!
It's not that pretty,
Mr. Thomas.
Pretty as yours, Doc?
Hey! Come on!
Peter!
Here we go.
Hey, light on Hicks'
service today?
Yeah. Covering the ER.
I don't know
what these guys are
always whining about.
ER's a cakewalk
compared to surgery.
Oh, a cakewalk, okay, okay.
How about a little OR versus ER
and loser takes the next Gomer
who comes through the door?
Nah, squash is my game.
He's kidding, yeah?
Yeah, he's kidding.
All right, turkey, same stakes.
You think there's an ER patient
that I can't handle?
I think there's one
that can tie you
up your whole day.
Let's go.
All right, skyhook,
left-handed, top of the key.
Oh!
Your shot, Dr. Carter.
Just leave her hair
in the doll's mouth.
The doctors will figure it out.
Sounds like one for you.
Or maybe for our
young Jedi surgeon
so recently humiliated in hoops.
I think I have a better one.
Bring on your worst.
Hey, who made the tea?
Yoo-hoo.
Is there a butcher in the house?
Oh, no, Mrs. Chenevert,
you need to stay in your room.
That little room makes me jumpy.
I need to get this chili
fry cut out of my throat
before it burns me up.
Sorry. I still need
to finish her history.
That's what they
said at St. David's
before they kicked me out.
I took two buses to get here.
Pulse is 130.
Uh-huh. Are you
high on something?
Me? Uh-uh.
No crack or...?
Crack? Never!
Why don't you let her finish
and you can tell her
what you're high on
and then I think I have
the perfect surgeon for you.
Surgeon? What kind of surgeon?
Uh, a young one.
Hey, private hospital
turfed that woman.
Can you imagine?
Crackhead with abdominal pain.
What do you think?
Oh, yeah. Carter. Yeah.
Dr. Ross, you want some tea?
I'm cutting back on caffeine.
I think it's herbal.
Dr. Greene, you want some?
No! Don't drink that!
You don't want to
go there, big guy.
Hey, there, Sasquatch! Huh?!
Dad, no!
Your drug screen came
back positive for roofies.
Roofies?
Rohypnol.
It knocks you out
and causes amnesia.
You mean he put it in my drink?
Well, someone did, unless
you took tranquilizers.
Never.
Oh, my God.
How could I have been so stupid?
Hey, you weren't stupid.
You just trusted someone
you shouldn't have.
So, what's going to happen?
Well, we need to do
a medical evaluation...
and we have to call the police.
But what if I'm wrong?
I don't really know
what happened.
I mean, when I woke up
I didn't really know for sure
that I'd had sex.
He may have used a condom.
Well, then it's just
my word against his.
Let's finish your
medical evaluation.
We may be able to find
some evidence.
Need some help here.
Two GSWs... Hope
you're in the mood.
What happened?
Drug deal went bad.
A guy opened fire
in the Flyburger on Third.
Injuries?
Single GSW to the left flank.
Vitals stable, good
breath sounds.
I.V. saline, TKO.
Some guy shot me!
Yeah. Some guy.
It's always "some guy."
Doyle, get him into
trauma two. Malik?
17-year-old employee
hit in the lower left chest.
Check for weapons and needles.
Plus a through- and-through
to the right deltoid.
BP's falling, 90/55.
Sinus tach at 120.
Two large-bore IVs,
a liter of saline in.
O2 at 15 liters.
This one's more critical.
Grab the portable from two.
On my count. One, two, three.
H and H, type and
cross four units.
Two units of
O-negative just in case
and a portable chest.
Can we give him
something for pain?
Stand by with morphine.
I guess you need
to get hazard pay
for slinging burgers these days.
Belly's tender. Set up a lavage.
Pulse ox is 92 on 15 liters.
Ancef, one gram?
Yeah. He might have
a peritoneal violation.
Give him cefoxitin,
that same dose.
What do you got?
I got a cake for you to walk.
Exam two.
I need a surgical consult
on a lovely 50-ish crackhead
sent over courtesy
of the St. David's ER.
Oh, that sounds like a dump.
Yeah, well, you
lost fair and square.
What about this guy?
Uh, forget it, Carter.
It's Gomer tag, and you're it.
I can't believe he shot me.
Where's Malik?
Calling radiology.
I was just standing there, man.
Be quiet and hold still
so I can examine you.
You okay alone?
Yeah, he didn't have
a gun or any needles.
Gun? I don't own no gun.
Call me if you need me.
Can I help you?
Yeah. I'm looking
for my brother.
He's been shot.
Visitors can't go
in during a trauma.
Go to the desk and
tell them you're here.
Someone will come talk to you.
Kenny!
Kenny, you all right?
Chris, I got shot.
You have to wait outside.
That's my little brother.
Okay, but you still
need to wait outside.
Look, the cops wouldn't
let me catch the...
I couldn't get in the ambulance.
I'm staying right here.
Who capped you, Kenny?
I don't know.
Can't you give him something?
They think I'm a gangbanger.
Who?
I haven't finished
assessing him.
Please! Wait outside.
Stat-page Benton.
Why are y'all swarming
around this boy, huh,
when my brother's dying?
Nobody is dying anywhere.
Family members wait outside.
Are you in charge?
Haleh, could you...?
Don't send a sister
to shoo me away.
Get your ass in there
and fix him up now.
Look, we treat
the most critically
injured patients first.
Kenny's been shot.
You are tying up the staff
and delaying your
brother's treatment.
Why don't you wait outside?
We got work to do.
You think he's a gangster?
We treat everybody
the same. Same?
Seven for the white
boy, one for the brother?
Dr. Greene. I need you in here.
All right, Lydia, come with me.
He bradyed down.
His BP bottomed out.
Did you give him anything?
No.
All right. Give me a 14-gauge.
Pulse ox is only 85.
Lungs sounded okay to me.
He's got a tension pneumo.
Get that portable in here!
Neck veins are coming down.
What happened?
You've got to
constantly reassess
a penetrating trauma.
What's wrong with him?
BP's only 70 palp.
Doyle, I'm going to put
in the chest tube, okay?
You set me up with a 32 French.
I told that doctor my
brother needed help.
Your brother will be
fine. What's his name?
Kenny. Kenny Law.
The Southside basketball kid?
Yeah, man! You
gotta represent for him!
He was all-city point guard.
Yo! Black man.
You a doctor?
Yeah.
You need to get in here
and take care of Kenny.
Guy's stable. Go ahead.
You sure?
Yeah.
Hey, you, get off!
Hey, hey. Whoa!
Don't you touch him!
All right. I need a new tray.
Someone call security.
What's going on?
I got a tension pneumo,
trying to get a chest tube in.
All right, just let us
do our jobs, all right?
A mig of atropine and
hang a unit of O-neg.
All right, here we go.
Hook up the Thoraseal.
Looks arterial.
Somebody tell the
OR we're on our way up
and schedule the
guy in one to follow.
Let's move, people!
So, after you choked
on the chili fry?
Who said anything about choking?
You.
No, no. No.
The burning started right after.
All right, and the burning
has lasted on and off
for three weeks?
Babs?
What?
Where is your pain?
Yeah? That's more
like your chest.
You know, you're so much
nicer than that Dr. Smith.
Thank you.
I'm going to need
to examine you.
I'm going to put a
call over to St. David's,
see if I can find the doctor
who took care of you over there.
No, no. You can leave
your clothes on for now.
Take a deep breath.
And out.
Hey, Kerry.
Hey. I called you last
night for journal club.
I was out with Greg.
Hmm. How's that going?
Would you mind
writing me the scrip
for a new diaphragm?
So I guess it's going
pretty well, huh?
Well, we haven't done anything.
We've done some
stuff, but, uh...
I've got condoms, I'll
get a new diaphragm.
I'm just carefully planning
for a possible
spontaneous moment.
That's great, Jeanie.
You know, my viral load is down.
I'm just not sure
if I should risk exposing,
you know, Greg to HIV
unless he's the
love of my life...
not just because I'm lonely
and haven't had sex
in a year and a half.
I got one for you.
I'll take it.
29-year-old woman,
6½ months pregnant.
She was rear-ended
by a pickup truck.
Seat-belted, no
abdominal pain or cramping.
Vitals normal.
She refused an IV;
couple of minor lacs.
She's complaining
mostly of right ankle pain.
Hi. I'm Jeanie Boulet.
I'm Carla Reece.
Girlfriend, I've got to pee.
Dr. Greene, this is
Mr. and Mrs. Brodie.
Their son worked
at the Flyburger.
We heard he was shot.
Yes. He's stable now,
but he's going to need surgery.
Oh, my God. Is he
going to be okay?
I think so.
You can go on in and see him
before we take him up to the OR.
Oh, so that's what it is?
They get the red-carpet escort
while you call security on me?
The patient is
waiting for surgery.
He's not critical.
He was when you was
letting Kenny bleed to death.
They were being treated
based on what we saw
on initial exam.
What you saw?
Just another shot
nigger is what you saw.
He's had a gram of cefoxitin,
DT, and five of morphine.
BP's up to 110/70.
Good. In English, that
means he's doing well.
There's been some
internal bleeding
from the gunshot wound.
We'll need your consent
to take him to surgery.
Of course.
Was anyone else hurt?
There was another young man
we took up to surgery.
I know it's hard to
see your son like this.
He was in the wrong place
at the wrong time.
Billy is always in
the wrong place
at the wrong time.
Doesn't matter how
much we threaten
or worry.
Our son's a crack
dealer, doctor.
It was just a matter of time.
What?
I don't know, the
black kid isn't a banger
and he isn't a dealer
and we assumed he was.
I didn't assume anything.
One was stable,
the other wasn't.
There it is.
How can you tell?
Semen glows
in ultraviolet light.
I'm going to have
to take a swab.
Oh, my God, he raped me.
I'm afraid he did.
I'm also going to have
to comb for a few hairs.
Could I have VD?
Or AIDS?
We'll give you antibiotics
for any sexually
transmitted diseases,
and you should
be tested for AIDS.
Oh, my God.
I called Rita James.
She's a counselor
who specializes
in women in your situation.
Lori, if you don't tell
the police about this,
he's going to do it
to someone else.
The mixture of
alcohol and roofies
might kill his next victim.
Will you stay with me?
Of course I will.
Yeah. No, you saw her today.
Chili fry indigestion.
Yeah. I need her
records faxed over.
It shouldn't cost you much more
than the bus token you gave her.
No, I need them now!
Haven't you people ever
heard of the COBRA laws?
You know you can't
just dump somebody
because they don't
have insurance.
Go, Johnny, go.
Mark. Hello?
It's Dan Ferkich.
Uh, Kenny's basketball coach.
Mark took care of Kenny.
Yeah, I knew something was
wrong when he missed practice.
Someone from Woodlawn
Park must have got him!
They're scared to
face him on the court.
Settle down, fellas. I'm
trying to talk to the doctors.
Kenny's been taken up to the OR.
His brother went with him.
Chris is on it? Good.
Will he be all
right by Saturday?
Because we're playing
Woodlawn Park in the city finals.
He was shot, coach.
Damn, man!
We got to call the guys.
How can I check
on how he's doing?
You can go up to the
surgical waiting room
up on the sixth floor.
Someone up there can
tell you what's going on.
These guys are going to
have to wait down here.
Okay, just stay here.
Is that my baby's heartbeat?
Yep. Good and strong.
What a sweet sound.
Yeah, it is.
Everything appears to be fine.
Thank God.
How far along are you?
6½ months.
We'll have to monitor you for
contractions just to make sure.
We'll shield your baby
and take an X ray of that ankle
and put some
stitches in this arm.
Well, um... couldn't you
just tape it together
or something?
I could steri-strip it,
but you'd get a
much better result
with stitches.
The thing is, is I hate needles.
You're planning on
going through childbirth
without an epidural?
Honey, women were having babies
long before doctors and needles.
What do you mean,
they can't come up?
They're Kenny's friends.
Yup. We want to see him, too.
Only immediate
family are allowed
on the surgical floor.
Yeah? You let the coach come up.
Well, they shouldn't have.
I see what this is.
It's all right.
I'll hang with y'all here.
Man, how is Kenny doing?
Nobody knows.
That's because
they don't tell you
nothing around here.
Tricks.
What's going on?
Ah, natives are restless.
I heard that.
It's an expression, Connie.
Those guys live around here.
They're natives.
Yeah, well, that's
not what you meant.
Hold on. Jerry, let's knock off
those kind of remarks, okay?
Fine.
Those kids heard a
rumor that Kenny was shot
by some guy betting
on Woodlawn Park
for the championship game.
They think he was shot
over a basketball game?
Hey, kids get shot
over basketball shoes.
Maybe you ought
to set them straight.
The white kid was
a drug dealer, right?
Look, it's not our
job to spread rumors
or to stop them.
And it's a violation
of patient confidentiality.
Yeah, well, those kids
looked pretty riled up to me.
That's why the police
should handle it.
Daddy.
Hey, oh...
You're too big.
Oh, something wrong?
It's my mom.
She had a stroke this morning.
How is she?
She's in the ICU in Sarasota,
but, um, she's
paralyzed on her left side
and she can't talk.
All right, let's
go in the lounge.
Is there anything I can do?
Oh, no, thanks.
We're flying down
this afternoon.
Rachel just wanted to
see you before we left.
Is she going to be
home by the weekend?
I don't think so, Mark.
So, she's going to
miss school and soccer?
Maybe that's not
the best thing for...
I can't miss soccer...
I'm the goalie.
I'll talk to the coach, honey.
Why doesn't she stay with me?
How are you going
to do that and work?
You do it.
I can take her to school,
and then Ruth can pick her up
and keep her until I get home.
I want to stay here with Daddy.
I can handle it.
We're going to have to
transect at the sternum.
Lebshke.
I hear our patient's quite
the basketball player.
NBA material.
Have you been busy
in outpatient surgery?
Oh, I've been busy all right,
especially since I
don't have an intern.
Suction.
Yes, well, uh, Dr. Carter
asked to be
transferred to my team.
You don't think I'd poach
him from you, do you?
No, no, no. Of course not.
I mean, not unless
it was for his own good.
Richardson.
Suction.
I finally got someone
over at St. David's
to fax me your records.
What time you got?
I thought you said the
doctor's name was Smith.
No, that was my
doctor from before.
Was he a cardiologist?
Uh, heart doctor?
You know, I got
a party to get to.
Maybe I ought to head on home
and come back tomorrow.
Well, I'd love to let you go,
Babs, but this EKG is telling me
that you ought to stick
around for a little while.
She needs to be on a monitor.
O2 and a hep lock.
See if they've got enough blood
to do cardiac enzymes.
Didn't they run those
over at St. David's?
No.
And they didn't notice
the flipped T-waves
and nonspecific ST changes.
Is that bad?
It could be.
Or it could just be
the way your EKG always looks.
Dr. Smith ever tell you
that you had heart trouble?
You know, you're nice.
You sure you're a surgeon?
Sometimes I wonder.
Okay, here's your referral,
your antibiotic prescription
and your birth control pills.
I want you to take two
now and two in 12 hours.
If you don't get your
period in three weeks,
I want you to come
in for a pregnancy test.
Do you need any
help getting home?
My boyfriend's here.
Would you like me
to speak to him?
No. I'm fine.
Okay.
Hey, weren't you off hours ago?
Yeah.
You've been working a lot
since you got back.
You okay?
Yeah, Doug, I'm fine.
I'm going to go home
and sleep all day.
See you.
Okay.
Only a couple of
mild contractions.
Is that okay?
Less than six an hour is okay.
Is this your first pregnancy?
Yes.
You don't by any
chance happen to know
your blood type, do you?
Mm-hmm. It's A-negative.
And who's your OB?
Dr. Coburn.
Whoo. That stings.
Sorry.
So, when are you due?
June 15.
I'm going to be a
caboose by then.
You got any kids?
No, I don't.
You and your husband
must be very excited.
It's just me and the baby.
I'm fine with it.
The father, he
just be howling...
Trying to chew his leg
off like a trapped coyote.
I know the type.
Plenty of them around.
Wrapped up in themselves
like they're God's gift.
I definitely know the type.
Yep, there they are...
Two wedding rings.
He hates the idea of
Mommy getting married.
It's pretty normal at his age.
They should pass
in a day or two.
You mean we got to wait
till he poops them out?
Mm-hmm.
Dr. Weaver,
we need you out here.
We got a handicapped
guy jaywalking on Michigan.
Actually, he was jay-wheeling.
Handicapped, huh?
Oh, is that wrong now?
Back there's his wheelchair.
Car hit it.
Threw him 15 feet.
Obvious head, right
chest and shoulder trauma.
BP's 100/60.
Pulse is only 15, and GCS is 12.
So, what's the new way
of saying "handicapped"?
Try "person with a disability."
Okay.
Okay, everybody
got him? Let's go.
What's your name, sir?
Floor it, sister,
I'm breaking loose.
Pupils are sluggish.
Where are you injured, sir?
Everywhere. Just get off of me!
How much have you had to drink?
Oh, a couple of beers.
BP's only 90/50.
Pulse is 60 and thready.
He's high on something.
Cross table c-spine,
CBC, chem seven,
type and cross for four.
Also, get a blood
alcohol and a tox screen.
You want to pump his stomach
now or wait for the next dose?
No, we can roll him
on his side if he vomits.
Give me that Ewald.
Don't put that snake on me!
Get some soft restraints.
No snakes!
Okay, swallow when you feel this
at the back of your throat.
There you go.
What's that for?
I spoke with Dr. Coburn.
She agrees we should
do a Kleihauer-Betke test.
You mean stick
me with that needle?
You have A-negative blood,
which means you're RH-negative.
Do you know the
father's blood type?
No.
If he's RH-positive,
the baby can be, too.
That can cause a condition
called erythroblastosis fetalis.
Sounds bad.
If this test is positive,
we'll give you RhoGAM.
It'll protect the baby.
Wait, wait, wait, time out.
What if the father has
negative whatever?
Then you don't need the test.
I just don't think
I can bother him.
It's worth a phone call.
All you're asking
for is his blood type.
It's not like you're asking
for his love and support.
Yeah, well, he...
actually, he works
here in this hospital.
Which department?
He's a doctor.
We have a lot of doctors.
His name is Peter Benton.
Oh.
So, Dr. Smith has never seen
a patient named Chenevert?
Okay, thank you.
Still busy with that
chili fry woman?
You should be working
on your jump shot.
I'm trying to track down
a cardiologist named Smith
who saw her years ago.
Do you know how many Smiths
there are in Chicago?
Sounds like a big can of worms.
Hi, this is Dr. John Carter
from County General ER.
Malik, that group's getting
a little too big for chairs.
Could you ask them to
go to the waiting room?
Is there a problem?
No. Not a problem at all.
Dad... Where have you been?
When's Ruth coming?
I need you to wait in
the lounge, sweetheart.
Dad!
Come on.
Is everything okay?
I thought you were going
to draw me a picture.
Are you not taking
care of Grandma
because you and
Mom are divorced?
Of course not.
Rachel, the doctor
where Grandma lives
is taking care of her
just like I'd take care
of the doctor's family
if they were here.
Oh.
Excuse me, Mark.
Paramedics are
pulling in with a GSW.
What's a GSW?
I'll let you know
when Ruth is coming.
Kid they're bringing in
is from Woodlawn Park.
He's a center on
the basketball team.
He was shot coming
out of practice.
This could be payback
for Kenny Long.
We've got a drive-by shooting.
16-year-old, hit twice.
Left chest, right thigh.
BP's down to 60. Pulse 150.
Any witnesses?
Don't know. Cops
are right behind me.
O2 at 15 liters.
Two large-bore IVs,
a liter of saline's in.
Seven point five.
I'll call radiology
for a portable.
Start a central line.
First unit O-neg's in.
Need any help?
Check the thigh wound.
This guy's from Woodlawn Park?
Yep. He's the starting center.
The baby-sitter's on the line.
Should she call back?
No. Let me have the phone.
Where's he hit?
Hi. Can you pick up Rachel
at the hospital?
Left chest, right thigh.
How about tomorrow after school?
How many units do you
want cross-matched?
Okay, great. We'll
work it out later.
Six. I'm in.
BP's coming up, 90/50.
All right, we got a
handle on him now.
Doyle, how about
putting in a chest tube?
Sure. 32 French.
So, this was payback
for the kid from the other team?
I have no idea.
Your tox screen
came back positive
for opiates, cocaine, Benzos,
plus your alcohol level's
three times the legal limit.
You going to bust me on a WUI...
Wheeling under the influence?
I'm just saying
it's a lot of drugs.
I'm a cripple. I'm
in a lot of pain.
He's been asking for Demerol.
Looks like you've
got a T-4 deficit
from a gunshot wound?
About what, two years ago?
You the geek expert?
You stick with your rehab?
Are you getting
physical therapy?
I know it's a hard transition,
but nothing comes easy.
Oh, not that crap!
"You got to rise above"
and for what... so I can try out
for the Gimp Olympics?
Yeah, I wasn't
thinking that far ahead.
How about I just
get you into detox?
I'm not interested.
Once you're dried out,
you can get back in rehab.
Just get me
something for the pain!
All right?
There it is.
Bovie that one.
How many units has he had?
12. Two are fresh frozen plasma.
I doubt he'll ever
play basketball again.
Aah, he'll be lucky if he lives.
We'll have to resect this lung.
Dr. Benton, I
need to talk to you.
I'm in the middle of surgery.
I can see that. What is it?
I need to talk
to you in private.
Can't it wait?
I wouldn't have
changed into scrubs
and come in here
if it could wait.
Go ahead.
We'll be okay for a few minutes.
What is it?
Do you know your
blood type, Peter?
No. Why?
Carla Reece is in the ER.
Is she okay?
She had a minor TC, ankle sprain
and minor lacs.
She's Rh-negative
and Coburn's worried
about Rh incompatibility.
What about a KB?
She refuses.
Yeah. She's afraid of needles.
Yeah, so I need
your blood for typing.
I can get somebody
else to draw it.
No, no, no. That's fine.
You can do it.
Okay, how about the locker room?
Yeah.
Good breath sounds.
Got this one under control.
Drained about 300cc's,
but the bleeding's stopped.
Any word from the OR on
the other basketball casualty?
Kenny Law's still in surgery.
Think they'll cancel the
championship game?
Both teams lost their starter.
I hope they call it
before somebody else gets hurt.
Yeah, I'm waiting for the
next kid to be wheeled in.
All right, this guy's stable.
Haleh, call the OR
and get him transported.
Hey.
Family allowed to
use this machine?
The one in the
waiting room's broken.
Of course.
How's your brother
doing in surgery?
I don't know.
Would you like me to call up,
see what I can find out?
You could do that.
Listen, uh, I have
some information
about your brother's shooting
I didn't give you earlier.
Apparently, it was drug-related
and involved the other victim.
Your brother was an
innocent bystander.
Okay.
A Woodlawn Park student
was just shot in a drive-by.
So?
There's no need for retaliation.
Your brother was
not being targeted.
You accusing me of
having that white boy shot?!
No, no. I'm just
giving you information
in case you know anybody
who's thinking about revenge.
Who the hell you
think you're talking to?!
You don't know my 'hood,
and you don't know me!
Oh, yeah?
Well, I know about
the gunshot victims
who come in here every day
one after another.
And you think you know my life?!
It's my life, too!
I see these kids dying
in here every day!
And you think I can stop that?!
Man, what do you know?
That's not your brother in there
with his blood spilled.
It's not your brother
lying on that table!
You don't know a damn thing,
so why don't you back off
and stay out my face?
I found Dr. Smith...
Yancey Smith...
And I got him to dig
out one of your old EKGs
and it was normal.
Ducky.
Well, maybe not so ducky.
That means that there's
been a change in your EKG,
which could signal
a heart problem.
All from chili fries?
A lifetime of chili fries maybe.
But I feel better.
And this thing's
getting on my nerves.
You know, you feel better
because of the nitro patch.
So why don't you behave
yourself and let the tech do her job?
I'm going to come back
and check on you
after I've looked
at your enzymes.
Don't forget me.
How could I?
So, uh, did she say
she wanted me to
come by and see her?
She didn't say that.
Did she say she didn't want me
to come by and see her?
She didn't say that either.
Okay.
I've got to go scrub in again.
Uh, Peter.
Yeah?
Thanks.
Sure.
Dr. Ross?
Yeah?
Collision at second base.
Uh-oh. You must have
got hit pretty hard, huh?
It's the All-Star League.
Get punched in the eye?
Landed on me with his elbow.
All right, let's
get orbital films
on that eye and set
me up for suturing.
Still here.
Hey, you on hold?
I just called the
cardiology consult for Babs.
They're getting her old
records out of storage.
Babs?
Are you on with the OR?
Tell them we're still waiting
to transport that kid
from Woodlawn Park.
Okay, thanks, Shirley.
Yeah, we're still waiting
for the transfer GSW.
Mark, I got a question for you.
Just a sec.
Malik, can you
tell the Law family
that there's still no word,
that Kenny's still in surgery?
They're in the waiting room.
Yeah, I know where they are.
I'd like them to have an update.
Yeah, okay.
There's this guy I
want to get into detox,
but he's kind of a hard sell.
He's angry and defensive
so it's hard for
him to ask for help.
Plus he's uninsured.
So he doesn't
want to be admitted
and he can't pay if he is?
That would be the "glass
is half-empty" viewpoint.
Well, it's Simonson's program.
His thing is commitment.
So you just have to assure him
that he's not wasting a bed
on someone who's not motivated.
That is a hard sell.
Mark, kid in trauma's
bradying down.
Carter, time to play surgeon.
Jerry, if that
cardiologist comes down,
tell him I'm looking for him.
He's been stable waiting for OR.
Then blood started
pouring out of his chest tube.
Carter, help me crack him.
Rib spreader.
Suction's ready.
Blood's here.
Put two units
on the rapid infuser.
I'll incise the
pericardium. Metz.
Look at that.
That is a bullet
hole, right atrium.
I don't think we're going
to be able to clamp it.
No, too much
tissue's blown away.
I'll tie in a Foley.
We'll get tamponade
and a blood port.
Give it a try.
4-0 Prolene, and, uh...
spike a unit
of O-neg.
Carter's on fire.
He's better with his
scalpel than his lay-up.
Yes, Dr. Simonson,
I know beds are tight,
but the patient's
brush with death
has given us a
window of opportunity...
No, I assure you, Mr. Brown
is highly motivated to change.
Okay, great.
I'll send him right up.
Thank you.
Now if you can just
sell it to the patient.
I'm seeing an
idioventricular rhythm.
We need another mig of epi.
Faint pulse.
Heart rate's picking up.
Okay, let's get him
ready to move up.
You guys are keeping us
busy today... what have you got?
A candidate for
a pericardial patch
thanks to your
intern's good save.
How's the basketball
player doing?
First guy we sent up.
Died on the table
20 minutes ago.
Okay, let's move him.
Sorry to keep you in
the ER all day, Carter.
It's okay, I've actually
had a good day.
Want to scrub in?
No, thanks.
I've got a surgical consult
I should stick with.
Okay. Slick piece of work.
Hey.
I thought you forgot about us.
Sorry, I had an emergency
with another patient.
All right,
so how'd you guys get hurt?
Tommy broke up a double play.
The kid fell on top of him.
The pictures look okay.
That wasn't a slide,
Pelosi, it was a mugging.
That was a clean, hard slide.
All right, Mr. McDonald...
Three feet outside
the base path?
Your kid elbowed
mine on purpose.
Guys, can I talk to
you outside real quick?
If he can't take a hit,
he shouldn't be in the league!
Hey, he can take a hit.
Excuse us, fellas.
You got a couple of great kids
who want to play ball.
Why don't you let them
keep it on the field?
All right, guys.
Let me see this eye.
Drop that thing down.
Hey, Malik, can you join me?
What for?
Kenny Law died.
I have to go tell his family.
Well, if you're scared,
you should call security.
I'm a nurse.
Mr. Law...
word just came down from the OR.
I'm sorry to say
it's not good news.
What is it?
The surgeons weren't
able to repair the damage
in time.
They, uh...
Is he dead?
They were unable
to save your brother's life.
When did she start
having contractions?
Right before
Dr. Coburn got here.
It's way too early for this.
Father's blood type?
Yeah. He's Rh-negative.
Good, no Rh incompatibility.
I'm going to
ultrasound you in OB,
but first we have
to stop your labor.
How?
We'll start with an IV drip
of mag sulfate.
Oh, God, no IV.
It's okay, Carla.
It's okay, I'll do it.
It's all right.
If you're not going to
give me a pain shot,
then I got no more
business here!
Do you know how hard it is
to get somebody without
insurance into the detox program?
I don't give a rat's ass.
Look, your chair is messed up.
I'll have maintenance fix it
while you're in the hospital.
Give it 48 hours.
How 'bout I give it no hours?
I'm out of here.
Should I write up an AMA form?
No. Hold on.
I'll make you a deal.
Demerol 100...
Phenergan 50.
It's yours if you'll
check into detox.
Dr. Weaver?
Just give it a couple of days.
Give yourself a chance
to get your life together.
You trying to bribe me?
Do you want it?
Okay.
Okay. Let's do it your way, Doc.
Just give it a couple of days.
Okay, Mr. Brown...
It's a deal.
I won't sneak up on you.
I'll tell you
everything I'm doing.
Just close your
eyes and try to relax.
Relax.
Okay.
It's already a little numb
from the topical.
Now I'm going to use
some local anesthesia
with bicarb so it won't sting.
Take some nice, slow
breaths and think of a place
you'd really like
to be right now.
Good.
Just let yourself float.
You want to tell
me where you are?
I can't.
It's X-rated.
Never mind.
Just keep it to yourself, then.
Okay.
It's in.
It is?
Mm-hmm.
Really?
Oh, girl, you got the touch.
You sure you don't mind?
Because if she doesn't
eat by 6:00, she gets cranky.
I'll be over as soon as I can.
Hey, it's macaroni night
at Magoo's. I never miss it.
Is that okay with you?
Yeah.
Okay, good.
Remember: no dessert
unless you eat one
green vegetable.
I know.
Okay.
My baby.
He was my baby.
Why is that lady sad?
Well, she's sad
because her son died.
Why'd he die?
He was shot.
Did you take care of him
like Grandma's doctors
are taking care of her?
Sure he did.
Look, Grandma is going
to be just fine, okay?
Okay.
Get out of here. Go eat.
Hey, last one to
touch Magoo's door
has to eat two green veggies.
I need your John Hancock.
Haleh, when, uh,
Kenny Law came in here,
do you think I made
racist assumptions?
Black folks see
the world one way;
white folks see it another.
All white people?
When something happens,
you say it's got
nothing to do with race,
but for us, it's always
got to do with race.
Can I have my pen back?
Carter needs you in here.
His patient's crashing.
What patient?
You know, that chili fry lady.
Let's get her in Trendelenburg!
She's having multifocal PVCs.
What's going on?
Echo showed cardiomyopathy
with wall motion abnormality.
Enzymes confirmed acute MI.
She was having a heart attack?
Yeah. She was on her way
to the cath lab for angioplasty.
I don't hear a BP.
Lidocaine 100 IV
push, start a drip at two.
I lost her pulse.
Ah, damn! Bag her.
She's in fib.
Charge to 200.
Okay. Hands off.
Normal sinus rhythm.
Got a carotid pulse.
Check a BP.
15 liters O2 by mask.
Get a gas.
That was close.
BP's back... 100 systolic.
Fundal placenta, no abruption.
We're in good shape.
Is it a boy or a girl?
Well, I haven't
seen a penis yet,
but sometimes
boys are a little shy.
Are you still nauseated
from the mag sulfate?
Uh-uh.
Good, because your
contractions have stopped.
Biophysical profile?
Four parameters.
Breathing, tone, movement...
And amount of amniotic fluid.
Zero to two points each.
This one's a six,
so we're okay.
Oh, hello.
There it is.
Turtle sign.
It's a boy.
That little thing?
They grow.
Not as much as
they'd like to think.
Oh...
I'm having a little boy.
An acute MI and I thought
she was a drugged-out Gomer.
Aah, worked out okay in the end.
How you feeling, Babs?
What?
Not too great.
Well, you're going to be fine,
thanks to Dr. Carter.
Damn. I never should have
smoked that crack, huh?
We've got the
bleeding under control.
Pressure's holding at 90.
Six units are in.
I've dissected off
the femorals for you.
Not bad for a couple
of general surgeons.
Okay, we'll take it from here.
Arterial and venous cannula.
Let's get the hoses up.
Well, at least we saved
one of the basketball players.
It was a pleasure working
with you today, Peter.
Likewise.
I know you have your heart set
on a high-end specialty, Peter,
but I've got an
opening on my team
for a good general surgeon.
Not flashy, but we
still have a lot of fun.
It's not ambition, Peter.
It's about healing people.
Okay, just let me know
if you change your mind.
Dr. Hicks?
I'd be honored.
Good.
What?
Well, it means you'll be
working with Carter again.
He'll love it.
I thought you'd gone home.
Carter wants a rematch.
Not now.
Come on, now. The
honor of the ER is at stake.
Uh, Rachel's over
at Doc's with Doyle
and I thought I'd
go check in on them.
All right, look, you
got to help me out,
because I'm still
nursing a bad leg
and I don't think I can
take him by myself.
All right, ten minutes, no more.
Then you're on your own.
You know what?
I called up the OR
about Kenny Law.
Mm-hmm.
Whether my delay in diagnosing
would have made a difference.
And what'd they say?
There's no way of knowing.
Yeah.
But you're right.
I do make assumptions
about patients, about race.
I try not to act on them.
You know, I try to act
the way I'd like
the world to be...
Not the way it is or I am.
Mark, you're the least
cynical ER doc I know.
Hey, where do you
think you're going?
Going home, Doc.
No. You can't leave.
Sure I can. I've signed out.
They're expecting
you up in Detox.
We made a deal!
Yeah, well...
never trust a junkie.
He'll be back.
Yeah, looking for drugs.
And the nurses will
have to deal with him.
He's going to miss again.
And he scores.
It was a lay-up!
Here. Let's go.
Eyes are closed.
Malik!
Hey, come on.
You were right
to call me on that.
A little two-on-two?
Come on, Malik,
let's finish 'em off.
Come on, Malik!
Okay, just play ball, man.
Down low.
Let's go.
Aah!
I broke his heart.
Good hands... let's go.