Traffic and weather on the ones.
It's another steamer
today. Hot, muggy weather.
High in the 90s
with high humidity.
They say never
trust air you can't see,
and you will see it today,
with no end in sight to
the hot, humid weather.
WMAQ traffic. Maybe the only
thing hotter than the weather
are the tempers of folks
stuck in rush-hour traffic.
It's wall-to-wall,
you all out there.
Double the travel times
on the Edens, Kennedy,
Eisenhower, Stevenson,
Ryan, Borman expressways.
And the tollways... they're
not much better... maybe worse.
The Tri-State and 355 have...
Jeanie, hey, sorry.
I'm running over this morning.
I hope I'm not making
you late for work.
No. I'm not on
until this afternoon.
I did my residency at County.
Three years of
too many patients,
too little time
and no resources.
Sounds about right.
Yeah, hard to believe
we had no CTs, no MRIs
and glass IV bottles.
Glass?
Yeah.
Well, your lab work's back
and the results show
a viral load of 15,000,
which is good.
Coffee?
No. I've already had too much.
Yeah, so have I.
Listen, there's a
fairly new HIV cocktail
that I recommend
you start on now.
The three drugs?
Yeah, AZT, 3TC and
a protease inhibitor.
You know, there is
no long-term research
but the preliminary
findings are positive.
Not quite a cure.
No, but more hope than
we've had in a decade.
There may be
some side effects...
Nausea, vomiting, rash.
How much does it cost?
Oh, your insurance
will cover it.
Actually, I'm going
to stick with cash.
Well, that could cost
up to $16,000 a year.
I'm sure I can work that out.
Afraid of letting
the hospital know?
Well, I've heard of health
care workers getting fired
or reassigned for
being HIV positive.
Yeah, yeah. Me too.
I've got a couple
of them as patients
but not from County, though.
So I don't know
what their policy is.
It's hard to ask without someone
wanting to know
why you're asking.
Listen, I'm gonna
write the prescription,
but these'll get
you started, okay?
You're to take two of the 3TC
and six each of the AZT
and the protease inhibitor.
14 pills a day?
Yeah.
The 3TC twice a day
with plenty of water
the protease
inhibitor before meals,
always on an empty stomach,
and two each of the
AZT, three times a day.
Jeanie.
Just follow these
written instructions, okay?
Does your watch have an alarm?
Yeah.
Good. Get used to hearing it.
Miss a couple of doses
and this virus could
develop resistance.
How much do I need to worry
about transmitting
this to a patient?
If you use universal precautions
and are careful when
disposing of sharps
there shouldn't be a problem.
Shouldn't.
With the exception
of one dentist,
there has been no
case documentation
of any health care worker
transmitting HIV to a patient.
None.
So I'll see you in three weeks.
Three weeks.
Jeanie.
There are a lot of diseases
that can take your life.
But this one
can take over your life.
Don't let it.
Oh, are you the doctor?
I saw the name on
the... on the mailbox.
"John Truman Carter, M.D."
Well, I am
Betty from 318.
Are you a doctor doctor?
Because I'm feeling
a little short of breath.
Might want to lose the
cigarettes for starters.
You really think that might
make a difference at my age?
I don't know, Betty.
Just a wild guess.
Well, I tried one of
those humidifiers.
I stuck my head
in the darn thing.
Wait a minute! Wait a minute.
What time is it?
Well, uh, I just turned off
Regis and Kathie Lee.
Oh! Oh, God!
Oh, God! Benton's
going to kill me.
Betty, I can't help
you now; I'm sorry.
I'm late, and I am
going to die soon.
I'm sorry you're
not feeling well.
Maybe you should
try an albuterol inhaler
maybe an atrovent inhaler.
You know, that kind of thing.
You can't keep me here.
Settle down now.
Get off of me!
I want to get out of here.
What happened?
Can't take these
fat people on PCP.
Broke out of her restraints.
Where's security?
Where are the men?!
Get off of me, you bitches!
I want to get out of here!
Sorry, sir. Oh, geez.
Geez, Louise! God!
We've got to get her down.
You can't give it to me!
Keep her down. Sit on her.
You okay? What is this?
Psycho day?
Some lunatic in four
kept trying to lick me.
Maybe it's the heat.
Oh, God. Full moon?
I think the patients know
that County's going to close.
Getting their last
digs in while they can.
In here, right?
What the hell kept you?
Got the call five minutes
ago. We ran all the way.
Oh, man.
Hey, you don't think County's
really going to close, do you?
I mean, it can't, can it?
Have you been
reading the papers?
$150 million shortfall in
the Cook County budget.
Be real tough giving
this all up, won't it?
Where's Carter?
Do I look like his mother?
You can't do this
to me! Let me go!
Randi, you seen Carter?
He's a surgical intern now.
We don't really keep
track of him anymore.
Peter, sorry you were late.
We already saved him.
What are you talking
about? I'm not late.
You know Wayne
Lentloff, don't you?
Good to see you, Peter.
Hey, you missed a good one.
Nobody called me. Thanks, Wayne.
It was fun, Kerry.
We'll do it again.
Uh, listen, I
wanted to talk to you
about a fellowship
in cardiothoracic.
Uh, yeah, look, um, I haven't
made up my mind, but, uh...
Oh, I know.
I hear vascular wants
you, trauma, critical care.
Yeah, I talked to them, but...
I know, I know, but
you need to talk to us.
Cardiothoracic is
a great specialty.
Good man like you...
You could finish up the
fellowship in three years.
Listen, are you free Sunday?
I would like you to
come out for brunch.
Lake Forest, and you
are going to love it.
Hey.
Hey, you want a ride?
Oh, thanks. I think I
can make it from here.
So how'd it go last night?
How'd what go?
Your blind date.
Oh, God.
You know better
than to tell anything to Doug.
I only told him after he told me
about your blind
date last week...
The girl with the retainer.
I don't believe him.
Don't worry. Mine was worse.
Nothing could be worse.
This girl had an entire
vegetable garden
stuck in her teeth.
That's the baby pool
compared to Tad.
Tad?
Hey, Manny, can I get
a cup of coffee, black?
You got it.
I can't believe you'd go out
with a guy named Tad.
I did.
Here you go. I made
it fresh just for you.
Hey, Joey!
Yeah, fresh from
yesterday's grounds.
First of all, I order
a Manhattan straight
up, two cherries.
He orders a "fruity, yet
selfless" glass of Cabernet.
What does that even mean?
I have no idea.
Then he talks for 45 minutes
about his ex-girlfriend...
Whose name also
happens to be Susan...
How much he loved her
How much he wanted to marry her
how he wanted to father
her five or six children.
And by the way,
do I want children?
Do I want five or six children?
Okay, Tad could be worse.
I'm not even there yet, Mark.
I look over and he has
this drop of red wine
hanging from his nose.
What? You heard me.
This puny, little blob
just hanging there.
So, of course, I cannot
take my eyes off of it.
Is it going to fall?
Is it going to hang
there all night?
Is his skin going to absorb it?
How did it get there?
Mark!
No, really.
How do you get your nose
that far down into a wine glass?
What? Was he smelling it or...?
Mark, please.
Okay, what happened?
I went to the bathroom
and snuck out the window.
You're kidding.
Nope.
Wow.
Did he ask you to
the house for brunch?
How did you know?
Wayne Lentloff is
nothing if not predictable.
That's why I like him, actually.
He gets the residents out
to Lake Forest every year.
Shows them the
seven-bedroom colonial
the tiered garden,
the Olympic lap pool.
Very impressive.
All the benefits of
cardiothoracic surgery.
Of course, we're only in it
for the satisfaction of
helping our fellow man
aren't we, uh...
what's your name?
Gant, Dennis Gant.
Step in, Mr. Gant.
Take a look-see while I divide
this anterior rectus fascia.
Tonsil clamp.
A little bovie, please.
Ah-ah-ah-ah-ah. Not you, Gant.
Boys and girls in
vascular pull you aside?
Yeah, that's mostly
diabetics and smokers though.
Not for me.
What about a
pediatric fellowship?
Surgery above
and below the
diaphragm... Very high-tech.
Actually, no one's asked me.
Hard as it is to believe, Peter,
there are some of the
more elite fellowships
you might have
to go after yourself.
Hmm.
Carter, your colleague,
Dr. Gant here,
was kind enough
to cover the E.R.,
seeing as you were
nowhere to be found.
Perhaps you should
do the same for him.
Okay, let's yank
this little hyperemic sucker.
Pean clamp.
You got it?
Mm-hmm.
The key to landing a
good job is presentation.
I'm not going to
dress like you, E. Ray
if that's what
you're talking about.
Two summers, assistant
night manager, McDonald's.
Actually, that's a bit of a lie.
I just manned the
drive-through window.
Well, no, that's better.
That's managing the
communication and distribution system
of an international
Fortune 500 company.
Okay, okay.
I like that.
What you're saying
is make it a big lie.
Semantics can be
your friend, Jerry.
Ah, man, some guy's
puking over at chairs.
I'll get it.
Jerry, did you get the
liquor out of four yet. Jerry?
You can't bother him now.
He's rephrasing his resume.
Going for the
presidency of Chrysler.
You know, it's not necessarily
county that's going to close.
There are three other hospitals.
Yeah, but what if it does?
I don't know about you
but I've only got eight
hours' worth of savings.
You know what, you
guys ought to get E. Ray
to help you revise your resumes.
I'm a nurse, Jerry.
How many ways you
going to rephrase that?
Mark said something
about a couple of teenagers.
Does anyone have
a chart on them?
Oh, I haven't made one up yet.
Two 15-year-olds
won't call their parents.
Mark said he'd see them.
Who am I seeing?
The 15-year-olds over at chairs.
Right.
81-year-old ALOC
with abdominal pain,
coming in by private.
Anything surgical?
Nope. Nada. Nothing.
Carter, abdominal
pain at the back door.
Susan? Yeah.
Can you help me
with a chest tube?
Yes, I'm going
to see those kids.
Mark, did you get a
chance to read that synopsis
of Donald Anspaugh's
speech at Northwestern?
"Modern Architecture
for Emergency
Medicine Management"?
Anspaugh? Isn't he
the Chief at Southside?
Yeah. Doug did
his rotation there.
He said the guy's
a bit of a crackpot.
Well, you might want
to consider the source
in that evaluation.
I found his ideas intriguing.
Kerry, rearranging
the physical layout here
is not one of my priorities.
Well, could we at least
rearrange where security sits?
Three of our nurses
had to restrain
a PCP patient this morning
because it took the guys
more than four
minutes to get there.
Was anybody hurt?
Fortunately, no.
You know, Mark, just
because it's my suggestion
doesn't, by definition,
make it a bad idea.
She just has a way
of making you feel
really small, doesn't she?
Sorry, I had no idea
they'd send the bill to you.
Your insurance
company doesn't pay.
What, you think the
hospital's just going to eat it?
I don't know.
I mean, what do
they do, you know,
with immigrants and poor people?
They go after anyone
who's legally responsible.
That's me, Al.
We're still married, remember?
I screwed up when
I changed jobs.
This guy I'm working for...
He's independent,
doesn't give benefits.
CTA said I could
stay on their plan
but there was this
COBRA payment and...
I had no idea I missed it.
It was... it was real confusing.
They're going to
let me know if...
if I can get reinstated.
Can it maybe go
on your insurance?
You're not on my insurance, Al.
I joined my plan
after we separated.
$3,200 is what I'm
supposed to pay for you?
In about a week, I
get another bill for me.
Thomas, time to come in.
Where are you?
Franklin Heath,
81, sweet old guy
looking for someone
named Thomas.
His private-duty nurse,
Mr. Vincent travels
is over there bulking up.
Oh, he looks dedicated.
He's dumping him right?
It's not for me
to say, of course,
although I guess I can
mention he's done this
a number of times,
always on a Friday.
Thomas, getting dark.
Carol, what
happened to your car?
What do you mean?
Tow truck hauled it off.
What are you talking about?!
Go, go, go. I'll
take care of this.
Thomas, is that you?
Strong old guy, isn't he?
Thomas... where are you, Thomas?
Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait!
Wait, God, please!
Hey, no!
Um, that's my car.
Hey, yourself. Stop
beating on my truck.
Well, stop stealing my car.
You Carol Hathaway?
Yeah.
Repossessed.
N-n-no-no, that can't be right.
You missed three payments.
Oh, God, so I'm a little late.
I made the other seven on time.
No... come on! Wait!
Oh, man!
I know that you did,
which is why that I
thought tonight, we could...
No, I understand your parents
don't come into town that often.
Yes. Yes, I would
love to meet them
but I'm working tonight, so...
What time do they go to bed?
I'm kidding.
Okay, yeah.
Uh... okay, I'll
talk to you soon.
Okay, bye.
That's, uh, uh, old
friend from college.
Radiology called.
The films on that
Berman kid are back.
You want to
rephrase your resume,
you should talk
to him, not E. Ray.
Hey, I heard your car got towed.
It's definitely a mistake.
I know a couple of guys
who can track a repo
man down like that...
if you want.
Carter said I should tell you
he's in curtain three.
Nurse Hathaway?
You're still here?
We've been sitting
in those chairs
just like you told us to.
That doctor never showed.
Well, if you tell me
what the problem is
I probably could help you.
We need to see a doctor.
Jerry...
where's Ross?
Radiology.
Greene?
Trauma two.
Follow me.
B.P.'S 100/50, pulse 120.
Good bilateral breath sound.
Toes upgoing.
Trachea's midline.
E.T. tube 7½.
Mark, you said
you'd see these
kids an hour ago.
Carol, we were diverted.
Well, they need to see a doctor.
As much as I'd like to do
your entire job for you...
Thank you, Carol.
Perhaps they could wait
just a little bit longer?
Let's get a
non-contrast head CT.
You know where you
were waiting before?
Go back there and wait again.
Thomas.
B.P.'S 90/60, pulse 104.
He's been agitated
complaining of abdominal pain...
That is, when he's
not looking for Thomas.
Thomas!
Who's Thomas?
Who knows?
Malik, get a C.B.C., Chem
7, U.A. abdominal series,
and let's get an E.K.G.
So, if you don't
need me anymore...
Have a nice
weekend, Mr. Travels.
Thomas, come on in.
Dinner's ready.
Carter...
what are you doing?
81-year-old ALOC.
Complaining of abdominal pain.
No vomiting or diarrhea
and yesterday, he had
a normal bowel movement.
Mild tenderness, no
rebound or guarding.
I'd say you have
nothing here, Carter.
Did someone dump him?
I think that's a possibility.
Mm-hmm. Well, I
suggest you do the same.
You're in surgery
not Geriatrics, okay?
I'm really sorry about
my little blowup before.
It was completely out of line...
No excuses whatsoever.
Don't worry about it.
Thanks. Can I borrow
your motorcycle after lunch?
What?
Well, you see, I have to
be at my house at 3:00.
My car got towed
and I won't have
time to catch the el.
Mark, we're going
to grab a drink.
Walk with us.
Okay, Mark, I'll
check on those kids.
Do you know how
to ride a motorcycle?
It's just like a
big moped, right?
I guess.
Hi. I'm Dr. Lewis.
What seems to be the problem?
A woman doctor?
Best I could do.
We could call your
parents, if you'd prefer.
No. No.
Uh...
We...
lost our condom.
Okay, so you're
trying to tell us
the condom is...
Deeply...
deeply lost.
I thought the decision
wasn't being made
for another week.
That's what we all thought
until they called this meeting
for this afternoon.
So they gave no indication
as to what the
outcome is going to be?
Nada, niente, zip.
Could be us, could be Southside
could be Central, but
someone's closing down.
Here, I got this. Here you
go, Manny, three cans of pop.
Thanks.
I didn't think
they'd actually do it.
Neither did I.
Neither did Donald Anspaugh.
He called me about it.
Sounded like he was having
a psychosensory disturbance.
He's afraid he's losing his job.
You know him?
Did my last two
years of residency
at Hennepin with him.
Guy's completely lumpy.
I rather like him.
Heh-heh-heh. Give it time.
He eats med
students for breakfast,
residents for lunch,
and the attendings
are who he chews up for dinner.
There was this guy Michaelson...
He was a new E.R.
attending when I was there.
Anspaugh vetoed every
research topic he submitted.
What for?
He just didn't like him.
Wanted to make sure
he didn't get tenure.
So the meeting's at 5:00?
Yeah, and I want you two there.
But let's not mention it
to the staff.
They're nervous enough as it is.
Carol?
Yeah.
Could we be possibly
be out of Decadron?
No, it's on one
of the top shelves.
Yeah, oh.
Hey, so they repoed
your car, huh?
You knew that's what
they were doing, didn't you.
I didn't have the
heart to tell you.
You are such a coward.
You have a problem with that?
Look, it happened to me once.
I'm a little strapped right now.
I could help you out next month.
Thanks, but I'm way beyond
a little help from my friends.
I'm meeting a
realtor this afternoon.
I'm going to try
to sell my house.
That's news.
Well, it needs so much work.
I still haven't paid
for the new roof
and I don't even know
if I have a job next week.
But, hey, how's life with you?
How's Gretchen?
Uh... Gretchen...
The one who went to Smith.
Gretchen is fine.
And now, I am armed
with my trusty Decadron.
I'm going to go out
and cure the croup.
So, what did Morgenstern want?
Oh, I can't tell you.
There's a meeting today at 5:00
to announce if they're
going to shut us down or not.
Ah, that's the bad news, huh?
Don't worry about it yet.
Well, yeah, but it
affects my vacation.
Your vacation?
Oh, yeah... I'm going
to Hawaii, I decided.
What?!
Nothing. Just for
a moment there,
I thought you might be
worried about your residency.
Any news yet, Jerry?
Are we jobless?
No news, but you
can have your share
of rumors, if you'd
like to hear them.
No, thanks. This
day's been bad enough.
Hey, Carter, call me crazy,
but I think that woman's
trying to get your attention.
What is she doing here?
Ugh! Ugh!
Manny, Manny, what happened?
I think I ate something.
Yeah, uh... are you okay?
Yeah, it's just this
day's getting worse.
Great. Uh...
Ugh!
Um...
Anybody seen E. Ray?
Mrs. Bradley? Alex?
Yes. Hi. Hi.
Hi. Sorry to have
kept you waiting.
That's okay.
Alex, let's take a look here.
Well, it's not too bad.
Didn't even hurt.
No, I wouldn't think so.
How did you cut that?
Pulling the top off
a can of tennis balls.
He's taking lessons.
I hate them.
Oh, yeah? How much?
What do you mean, how much?
As much as doing your homework?
As much as going to the dentist?
Well, definitely as
much as both of them.
I hate it as much as
taking the trash out,
cleaning up after the dog...
You wanted a dog.
Yeah, but I didn't want Robert.
Now, you don't talk like that
about your brother. You
know better than that.
Alex, he loves you.
I know.
Who feeds the dog? Me.
No, you don't. I always do.
So, those shots you get
at the dentist... Novocain...
You're not allergic
to those, are you?
Mom?
No.
They stuck these
things in my nose
and gave me this oxygen
tank to take home with me.
Mm-hmm.
That inhaler thing,
it didn't work at all.
Now, Betty, you
can't smoke in here.
You can't smoke around
this oxygen tank, either, okay?
Even at home. It'll blow up.
I want you to know
that I asked for you specially.
Thank you.
Very flattered.
Carter, Malik
needs you in three...
Something about an
old guy, uh, Mr. Heath.
I'll be right back.
Call Carol and page
Dr. Lewis or Greene.
Oh... God.
He's Bradying down.
All right, get a mask on him.
What happened?
He arrested.
Monitor's flatlined.
Where's Dr. Lewis and Greene?
Up in MRI; I paged them.
Want to call that
private-duty nurse?
No. Mr. Travels
has gone traveling.
Let's give him, uh...
Carter, you're pumping
too hard. Thank you.
How about an amp of, uh...?
Epi! Epi...
And a mig of Atropine.
I think I just broke his rib.
I'm getting a faint pulse.
Whew!
Okay, ten mics per kig...
That's about... 500 mics.
Give him 500 mics of Dopamine.
Pretty damn good job, Carter.
I'll call for transfer.
Man, I can't believe...
I can't believe I broke his rib.
I mean, I knew
he was frail, but...
Well, that's better
than letting him die.
Yeah, huh?
Carter. Didn't I tell you
to transfer this
guy up to Medicine?
Come on, I've got
a hernia that needs
an H-and-P upstairs.
Now, move. Let's go.
Hello?
Mrs. Puro?
Oh, Carol. Hi there.
I-I'm sorry I'm late.
How did you get in?
Oh, your mother. She
makes a killer cup of coffee.
There you are, sweetheart.
I was just going
to call the hospital.
Mom, what are you doing here?
The material I told you
about for the kitchen curtains...
I thought I would drop it off.
And frankly, I am
just as glad to hear
you've changed your mind.
About what?
About selling.
I told Elizabeth.
Elizabeth?
First names only in my business.
I told her you must
have changed your mind.
Why else would
we put up curtains?
Not to sell it. Wouldn't help.
Mom, why don't you go
and see how those curtains
would look in the bedroom.
You want the same in the bedroom
as the kitchen?
Mom, we'll talk later.
Elizabeth, I haven't
changed my mind.
I really want to
sell this place.
You're kidding.
No.
Is there a problem?
How can I put this delicately?
I couldn't sell this house
if the rest of Chicago
burned down around it.
Well, I know it needs work.
The roof is...
The roof is new!
I was going to
say... The roof is fine
but I checked the basement.
The furnace
doesn't even turn on,
not to mention the asbestos.
There's no central air,
there isn't even a window unit.
Exposed two-by-fours
dry wall... the rug is lovely
but there are holes
in the carpet underneath it,
which unfortunately reveal
the subterranean termites.
The plumbing is not copper.
The electrical is a
fire waiting to happen
and as much as I
hate to mention it
you do live next
to the el tracks.
Frankly, I'm impressed
someone managed
to sell it to you.
Then a month after
the abscess was drained
she had to have a hysterectomy.
My God, was she in pain then.
Weeks. Weeks. Weeks!
And what's so unfair is
that, with all four of our kids,
cesareans, which
is a lot of slicing
right in the middle.
Couldn't stand up
straight till 1987.
So you can see why,
with this hernia thing... Ow!
Which is also
somewhat in the middle,
if you know what I mean,
I'm-I'm obviously
a little nervous.
Although being able to
talk to you is helping a lot.
I'm very grateful.
Of course, I'm not
going to be able to do this
while I'm out
cold, and Doctor...
What's his name again?
Benton.
Yeah, that's it. Benton.
When I'm under the
knife and he starts cutting.
Oh, my God. My God.
What if I don't come
out of this? Mr. Hartley...
I mean, I won't
know what happened.
Have you considered
having a local anesthetic
instead of a general?
I-I didn't know I had a choice.
Oh, yeah, and the
advantage to a local is that
while you feel no
pain whatsoever,
you're still completely awake,
and you can talk to the
surgeon all you want.
Can I ask questions?
Dr. Benton encourages it.
Right in the middle of surgery?
All the way through.
In fact, you can...
you could read up on
hernias in this book.
And anything that
you don't understand,
you can ask Dr. Benton.
That's great.
Yeah.
Jeanie! Ross was
looking for you.
Some kid needs suturing.
Going to be a while.
I have to go to radiology
and the cath lab.
Randi. Yeah.
Have you seen Mark?
I believe he's lounging.
Come on.
Wait, wait, wait.
This is a...
Hey, there you are.
I'm not talking to you.
You know, you made
poor Tad very sad.
What'd he say?
You don't even know him.
Got you.
That's a low one, Doug.
So I take it you don't want me
to tell anybody about
your date tonight.
You have another date tonight?
I hate this place.
Right there.
She hit it with her...
Carol, it really would be better
if we sewed them.
Everything in this entire house
could be better.
Fine.
But why are you mad at me?
I didn't put holes
in your floor,
break your furnace.
You're right. You're right.
I'm sorry.
I just... I really want
to sell this place.
I need to sell this place. Oy.
Is it because of Shep?
I mean, does it make
you think of him?
God, Mom, I never
even thought of that.
No.
No, I feel good being on my own.
I'm enjoying myself.
I just can't afford it.
The house, the car.
Somehow, I've accumulated
the debt of a 50-year-old.
We should call
your Uncle Mykola.
Uncle Myko? Why?
He made all that
money in real estate.
He could advise you.
Ma, it's not advice that I need.
Maybe not.
But spend some time there.
Keep him company.
You know, he has so much money.
He has no children of his own
and, sadly, he has not
been feeling well lately.
Are you suggesting
that I ingratiate myself
to Uncle Myko so that
he'll leave me his money?
Well, he's going to die.
I can't help that.
I mean, he has no children.
What's the poor man going to do?
God.
This feels like surgery.
It really does.
And I am floating,
floating, floating...
Except I always thought
you guys played music,
although I don't really miss it.
Is this going to
hurt, Dr. Benton?
I've already made the incision,
Mr. Hartley, and you didn't feel a thing.
No, no. I mean in
a couple of days.
Yeah. It's going to be tender.
No, I mean, like,
when I go back to work.
Look, go back to work when
you feel comfortable, okay?
Well, that's what I'm asking.
When will that be?
Are we talking Tuesday,
Wednesday, Thursday, Friday?
Another week?
What do you do, Mr. Hartley?
You know the
drawbridge on Michigan?
I send it up.
Send it down.
Send it up.
Up, down, up, down.
Rain, shine,
sleet, snow.
Some days, I count boats.
Some days, I don't.
By the way, what are the borders
of Hesselbach's triangle?
You might want to
shift a little to the left.
Manny threw up
right around there.
Manny from the roach coach?
Food poisoning?
I told you.
It wasn't the coffee, was it?
Are you ever
getting off that thing?
I'm on hold with the airlines.
At least, that's what
their reservations department
has told me 97 times.
Mark, you ready?
Or not, as the case may be.
We'll be waiting.
All right.
I told Susan Lewis
about the staff meeting.
I told Jeanie Boulet,
Malik and Carter.
I figure if you don't
tell Doug Ross
then you're okay.
Huh.
Thomas. Thomas.
How you doing there, Mr. Heath?
Thomas, where are you?
Your dinner's ready.
I bet those ribs hurt.
I'm sorry about that.
You hear me? Get inside now.
I'll get you something
for the pain.
Thomas, listen to me.
Listen to me!
I'm listening to you, Mr. Heath.
I'm listening to you.
There he is.
This is impossible.
Maybe you should yell "fire."
So crowded.
Every buzzard in the county
showed up for this one.
Present company excepted.
Alice Wakely.
She's run the county
health services since
the Paleolithic.
You know her?
Went to school together.
She was ahead of me, of course.
Okay! Okay, everybody!
I'll spare you and
make this quick.
While we obviously
regret the need
to close any county
medical facility...
She's lying already...
This isn't quick.
Our extremely strapped
budget has made it unavoidable.
As of two weeks from today,
Southside will close its doors.
Okay, there's the
good news for you.
Obviously, we're concerned
about the loss of jobs,
so we're going to consolidate
as much of the
staff as possible.
There's some people
here I want to introduce,
for those of you who
might not know them.
Harrison Holman is coming over
as new Chief of Obstetrics
Harrison!
Bonnie Brown
will share the CFO office
with James Malkovitch.
I've heard she's excellent.
Did a great job at Deaconess.
And with Mike Babcock
taking early retirement,
Donald Anspaugh
will become county's
new Chief of Staff.
Donald.
♪ ...Duke, Duke, Duke
of Earl, Duke, Duke ♪
♪ Duke of Earl, Duke, Duke ♪
♪ Duke of Earl, Duke, Duke... ♪
All right!
Hit it! Hit it!
♪ Nothing can stop
the Duke of Earl... ♪
Now, jazz it up.
Jerry!
Come on, dance with us.
No way.
Just a little.
You got it.
I was just thinking
how unusual it is
to see our whole ensemble,
you know, this happy.
Especially about keeping a job
where people puke on you.
Oh, is that the guy?
That's the guy.
Which guy?
He looks fairly normal.
So did Morgenstern.
So they finally came
down for Heath.
Took him to the CCU.
Oh, poor old guy.
Who do you think Thomas was?
His son maybe?
I know this sounds crazy,
but I think Thomas was his dog.
His dog?
Yeah. At one point, he seemed
to think that I was Thomas.
And he pulled me in really
close, ear to his mouth,
and he whispers, "Kibble,
Kibble, Kibble, Kibble."
It was oddly touching.
It was, Carol.
How are you?
Don Anspaugh.
Oh. Randi.
How are you?
Lydia Wright.
Pleased to meet you.
E. Ray. Please join us.
Excuse me. I got it. I got it.
Sorry, Lydia.
Help!
E.R.
Yes.
Uh, okay.
I'll let everybody know.
That was, uh, Dr. Weaver
calling from the lounge.
Dr. Morgenstern will be unable
to attend the party.
David, I'm sure
it's not going to be
as bad as you think.
I mean, look how bad everybody
thought it was going to be
when I came aboard.
True.
Funny how life
is so like surgery.
Sometimes you can
make that Rocky-Davis
in the right lower quadrant.
And then, there are those days
when your bowel ruptures
and spills into your peritoneum
and all you're left with is
intense pain and sepsis.
Oh, brother.
My kingdom for a ten
blade when that happens.
Lookit, so today's
not a total loss,
you want to grab some
dinner, maybe catch a movie?
The Music Box has some
really fine independents.
Sure.
Maybe a midnight
show at the Village.
Have you seen Caligula?
Uh-oh.
No, no, no...
don't do this to me.
Some of us have to date.
See ya.
Hi, there.
Don Anspaugh.
Mark Greene.
So, uh... what
do you like, Mark?
"Stars and Stripes Forever"
or "Dauntless Battalions"?
Actually, I got to get going.
Just kidding.
This is, this is torture.
I was off five minutes ago.
My plan was to
be in bed by 8:30.
No, no, no, no. I was saving
this guy for the two of you.
Oh, vomiting,
abdominal pain, nausea...
Thanks a lot, Malik.
What have you been doing,
training with Dr. Benton?
Trust me. You'll thank me.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Thank you, Malik.
Mr. Travels, right?
Yeah.
Mr. Heath's nurse?
I'm Dr. Carter.
This is Nurse Hathaway.
So, you're feeling bloated,
nauseous and flatulent.
Must have been something
I ate, don't you think?
It could be just so many things.
Toxic megacolon.
Intestinal parasitosis.
Scleroderma.
Ulcerative colitis.
Pyloric stenosis.
Oh, yeah.
Crohn's Disease.
Where would you
like to start, Doctor?
I don't want to waste any time.
Barium enema.
Oh...
Hi.
I hate it when you do that.
Come on, it's fun.
No, it's not fun.
It scared the
living daylights...
All right, I'm sorry.
It'll never happen again.
Hey, Heather, let's go
get a drink, you and I.
You couldn't get anything
going for tonight, huh?
Oh, now, come on. I'm here.
Thanks a lot.
Come on, let's get a drink.
It's never just a drink, Doug.
Is that all that
you want it to be?
Just once, it would be nice
if you could call
the day before.
Heather, you know my schedule.
It's hard enough for me to
plan two hours ahead of time
much less a day.
Some really sick little
kid would come in,
and then I would be
canceling on you all the time,
and then, you'd be
mad at me for doing that.
I am not mad at you.
Heather...
Hey.
You look as though
you've had a very
long, very hard day
and I would like to take you out
and see you
relax just a little bit.
I'll throw in a lottery ticket.
I've got to drop these
off at Neurology first.
So did you actually
give him an enema?
No. Compazine.
Carter went home to bed.
Benton's been beating up
on him pretty badly these days.
I'm shocked and horrified
to hear that, Carol.
Ding-dong. Avon calling.
Oh, please, allow me.
This is County
General on one alpha.
Unit 85.
We're en route with
a 32-year-old-male,
jumped or pushed in front of
an el train at Garfield station.
Massive head, face,
chest and extremity trauma.
Garfield's closer to Southside.
They're closed to trauma.
I came out of the
ambulance entrance
and my motorcycle had a flat.
I'd given myself plenty of time
to go home to the
apartment and change...
I don't care.
Really.
So, you live up
on the Gold Coast?
I'm renovating a three-flat.
Oh! Must be a lot easier
when you're an architect.
Yes, it probably is.
You know, you know the pitfalls,
how long things kind
of take, that sort of thing.
Uh-huh.
Oh... I see some friends.
Well, actually,
a friend... Susan!
Mark.
You didn't tell me
you were coming here.
Susan and I work
at County together.
Oh... Brent Smythe.
How do you do?
Hi.
This is Julie...
Mathers.
Julie's an architect.
Oh, really? Where?
Uh, Higgin, Bloom.
You're kidding. I
represent them.
You with Jackson,
Gearson, and Robe?
Going on 12 years.
They recruited me
right out of Stanford.
I don't believe this!
My brother went to Stanford Law.
He graduated in '85.
Jack Mathers. Of course!
He went to, uh, don't tell me,
Dudzik, Hiltzik, and
Strauss in New York.
You have a good
memory, don't you?
Multiple lacerations,
including a chunk of
his left rib cage missing.
B.P. 60 Palp.
1½ liters of
saline in the field.
He's got obvious open fractures
to the right femur
and left humerus.
Okay...
One, two, three.
Hey, congratulations
on staying open.
Thanks! I'll intubate... 8.0.
Get radial pulse.
Contact refill.
Jeanie, give me
an in-line traction.
All right.
BP's down, 40 palp. Pulse ox 80.
Set up a vent.
No response to pain.
Call Radiology.
Get a cross table C-spine.
Okay... I'm in.
Hang the O-neg.
Oh, man. Sucking chest wound.
How many units?
Type specific four,
type and cross ten.
What do we got?
Open chest wound
with severe
respiratory compromise.
He's intubated but
still not saturated.
Four units of O-neg are in.
B.P.'S still 40.
We got a pumper.
Elevate that flail segment.
I've got it. Okay, I've got it.
Kelly, okay, Jeanie,
you can go now.
Grab me some more Kerlix.
I've asked her to leave.
Jeanie, could you check
with the blood bank,
find out what's keeping
that type specific?
How long do you think it
takes to get a couple of drinks?
Hopefully, all night.
Mmm. I guess this is
how perfect couples meet.
Yeah, somebody
else's blind date.
Great story for
the grandchildren.
You know, you should call
Tad, and give him the tip.
Did you really think you
were going to impress her
in scrubs?
You don't think
she went for them?
I mean, I find it a turn-on,
but some women...
What, are they coming?
Follow me.
Oh, I know. I got some quarters.
I don't remember these
things being so small.
Well, you probably
haven't been in one
since you were 12.
Okay?
All right. Okay.
What do we do?
Look into the camera.
No fair. You're
hogging the frame.
All we're going
to see is my neck.
That was a great one.
Just sit there and look.
They don't give you
any warning at all.
Okay, it's coming up.
No, come on.
Okay, okay, I'm
ready. One good one.
There. See? That wasn't bad.
Nice.
Don't you ever treat
me like that again.
What the hell were
you trying to do?
Trying to save that man's life.
By giving him AIDS?
I was careful, Peter.
I used universal precautions.
You were working
on a chest wound.
What if you made a mistake,
cut yourself and bled into it?
I didn't.
Okay, what if I made
a mistake and cut you?
No person has ever got it
from a contact in an E.R.
So, does that mean no one can?
You pile up all the
data you want to,
but you better
damn well remember
what really happens
in this room, okay?
So, if you'd tested positive,
you would have quit?
In a minute.
Yeah, but you didn't
test positive, did you?