♪ I've got your number, lonely
♪ October 33
It's a natural progression
in any profession
for the student
to become the teacher,
the mentee
to become the mentor.
♪ Holds me down ♪
♪ Like you know how, darlin' ♪
♪ Hold me now
♪ Like you know my plight
♪ Got your number
It's not that much different
from parenting.
I'm your son.
We learn
from our ancestors
how to make
the perfect soup.
♪ I'm sending love
where you are at ♪
How to soothe an aching head
or heart.
Your call has been forwarded
to an automated
voice messaging system.
♪ October 33
♪ Your love's
my only good thing ♪
♪ Like, fair, fair, fair
♪ So, help me
hear the bird sing ♪
♪ I'll help you
capture your dream ♪
♪ Let's see it in the present
♪ And try to let it be
♪ I, I've got your number,
lonely ♪
♪ October 33
♪ Like, fair, fair, fair
We measure milestones
and percentiles
and first steps...
...to try and gain insight into
the person they'll grow into.
- Hello?
- ♪ October 33
Tate,
you're early.
I've just started
packing lunches.
♪ Crying in the back
As if knowing
a bunch of numbers on charts
is any true measure of what
we might make of ourselves.
Jackson.
♪ I do, to you
Hey, Dad.
♪ Hold on
♪ Fair, fair, fair
Alright.
I know it seems, like,
impulsive and out of nowhere,
but it's not...
It's just, uh...
uh, fast.
But it's not, like...
impulsive, impulsive.
It's...
I thought it through.
It's just I thought it through...
Oh!
*GERY'S ANATOMY*
Season 17  Episode 14
Episode Title: "Look Up Child"
Aired on: May 06, 2021
Captions by VITAC...
Sync corrections by srjanapala
Everybody alive?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
That's not...
Not why I'm here.
I thought
you were Tate.
He delivers meals
for me to people
in the community
that need them.
Okay.
Not Tate.
Well, come on in.
Take a load off.
I tested clean yesterday
and haven't seen anyone.
I haven't seen anyone,
either.
I just made
a fresh pot of coffee.
Want some?
I'm good.
How have you been?
I've been thinking a lot
about you lately,
what with everything going on
in the world.
I was gonna call,
but the way we left things
last time,
I figured you did not want
to talk to me.
And... I didn't want to be
one of those
added things
on top of the pandemic
to deal with.
How have you been?
How's your little girl?
She must be,
what...
She's 3 1/2 years old.
Her name is Harriet.
Right.
Look, I didn't travel
all this way
to just catch up,
so, um...
I need... answers.
Well, I've got about 150 lunches
to put together,
so if
we're gonna talk,
why don't you grab a pair
of gloves over here with me
and, uh...
help me out?
Oh, my God,
it's your night.
It's... Wait...
It's your night?
How can it be your night
with Harriet?
She's not packed,
she's not ready, she's sick,
- and I have a calendar.
- It's okay, no, no, it's not...
- It's not my night. Alright? April, hey.
- No?
- It's not?
- No, no, no, it's alright.
Okay.
Just take a breath.
What's going on?
What's wrong?
- She has a temp of 102, and...
- Okay.
And she's coughing...
- ...and she has no appetite.
- Come here.
But I-I took a rapid test...
It's not COVID.
Come here, munchkin.
Come here. That's good.
Hey. Why didn't you call
me? I don't know what it is.
Whooping cough
or RSV or rickets?
- It's not rickets.
- People get rickets, Jackson.
And... And Matthew
just went out East with Ruby
to see his sister,
and the power
keeps going on and off,
and I know,
I am a doctor,
I need to take a deep breath
and I should be cool,
- but I am...
- You're not being cool right now.
You're not even breathing,
okay? Go ahead. Oh, God.
She's been sick before,
obviously,
but, like,
COVID just makes everything
feel so...
big.
And I know I need to calm down,
but no one
in the history of calming down
has ever calmed down
- by being told to calm down,
- so I'm not gonna, okay?
I'm not
gonna tell you to calm down, alright?
I'm not telling you to calm
down, I promise. I just...
Why don't you let me
in the house,
- Yeah, yes, okay. Just... sorry.
- Maybe? Okay?
- Come in.
- Hey, sweetheart.
I can't tell you
how long it took me
to come up with
this nifty system.
First, we start
with a bunch of these,
what I've coined
the brawn bundle.
Here's how we do it...
Two pieces of smoked ham,
one slice of honey turkey,
and provolone.
Are you serious
with all this?
Roll it up, and once you have
your ingredients set,
you move down here
to the bread.
You won't believe
how much time that saves.
Try a piece.
Look, I'll make
the damn sandwiches with you
in order to...
It's fine.
Okay?
But I don't need
to taste anything
or have any food
or coffee.
Just... I don't need anything
from you, honestly.
I just need answers.
Okay.
Answers?
Mom said
something to me
that I cannot get
out of my head.
Yeah,
she has a talent for that.
She said,
for the first time ever,
that I sounded
like you.
Did you piss her off?
I said
I can't really see change
coming from inside
the foundation.
- There's too much bureaucracy.
- Well, to be honest,
I haven't thought about
the foundation in a long time.
Yeah, but what do you think
she meant by that?
Years ago, I learned
to never put words
in your mother's mouth.
If you had to guess.
I've never been one
for the establishment.
I always thought
the whole system is rigged.
So, how we doing
over there?
You know,
I don't think
ham-and-turkey sandwiches
get enough credit.
They're simple,
but they get the job done.
So I said that
the whole system's just broken,
needs to be thrown out
and rebuilt,
understanding that
that's damn near impossible
considering how many people
benefit from it
the way it is
right now.
That does sound
a little like me.
You look like you could use
some more turkey.
Ever use
a commercial meat slicer?
- When would I have done that?
- Summer job?
Anyway,
it reminds me of the O.R.,
without the pressure
of possibly killing someone.
Come on,
let me show you.
Yeah, I can figure it out,
thank you.
Okay.
You might want to...
You might want to
turn it on first.
Yeah, right.
Just,
what is it?
Here, let me show you.
Okay.
First of all,
you gotta lift this.
Here's your gauge
for how thick
you want to
make the slice of meat.
Okay. Got it.
Thank you.
The carriage goes
back and forth.Great.
I got it.
Kinda relaxing when you get
a rhythm going, huh?
So... you're saying
you wanted change,
but what?
You felt powerless
'cause you were an Avery or...?
As you know, the Avery name
carries a great deal of influence,
but it also carries...
a great deal
of baggage.
That amount of money
can...
become a burden
pretty quickly.
Everybody knows
you have it, so...
they expect you
to be responsible
to fix everything
with it.
And there's almost no one
in your shoes,
so almost no one
seems to get it.
At least
not when I said it.
Certainly not
when the name is synonymous
with just the worst
behavior imaginable.
Well,
not here it's not.
Here, nobody knows
who my father was
or that
I come from money.
Out here,
they just think
I'm...
Robert, who runs the diner.
God.
Uh, Matthew's been working
a lot.
I mean,
I've been working a lot.
Yeah, don't worry about it.
My place is, uh...
Please don't do that.
Don't be all weird-nice
with your voice an octave higher
like you do with people
at hotels or at the bank.
I have
a weird bank voice now?
It's making you nuts.
You... You can say it.
Just mess everywhere.
Pillows all over
the place.
I maintain
that throw pillows
are useless and stupid,
yeah.
How long has my munchkin
been sick?
Couple days.
She just
hasn't wanted to do anything,
just lie on me.
Also, she needs a bath.
She smells like feet.
Well, I hate to break it to you...
that's you.
- No, it's not.
- 100 percent you.
Oh, God.
That is me.
Yeah.
Go take a shower.
Jackson, I...
April,
go take a shower, please.
- Hey, Jackson.
- Mm-hmm?
I'm calming down.
See?
I am. I am.
- 10 minutes.
She ever taken
a 10-minute shower in her life?
I don't think so.
Some tunes?
Good idea.
Let's see
what she's got.
We got this, right?
We got this, baby.
We got this.
You're gonna feel better
in no time.
Harriet and Dad.
We got this.
Oh, come on!
Or maybe we don't.
John Moran's
"Thousand Watt Workout" plays...
♪ Looking like a fisherman ♪
♪ I'm dropping a line
in the sea ♪
I gotta give it to you...
That's some good turkey.
Best in the state.
Yeah,
I'll take your word for it.
♪ Hoping that
the graying skies ♪
So,
what'd your dad think
when you decided
to walk away from it all?
At first,
he thought it was just a phase.
But then when he realized
I was serious,
he stopped speaking
to me.
Completely?
He said I was selfish,
compulsive, lazy,
a stain
on the family name.
Which I now see
is such a complete joke.
No, he was never interested
in talking to me,
unless it was
about the hospital image
or profits
or expansion.
If I have to have
one more conversation
about cutting hospital costs,
I swear...
Someone's got to
do it.
I just knew
it wasn't gonna be me.
I was never gonna be
the son my father wanted
because I didn't want to be
the man the role required.
That's why
you're here.
Why's that?
Because...
you're ready
to leave it all behind.
Why does anyone have
an electric water heater?
A power outage is when
you need hot water the most.
Well, Harriet cried herself
to sleep.
I propped her head up
to help with the coughing.
Okay, thank you.
And I found a flashlight
and a few candles,
but I can't find any
damn matches in this place.
Oh, yeah, well, I'm married
to a first responder.
The matches are in a drawer
even I've never found.
Alright.
Well, then, stove it is.
Geez.
Can you get
some more candles?
What?
Oh, crap!
Sorry.
This is a nun.
I just grabbed the, uh... The first nun
you could find?
Saying I'm going to hell?
Since when
do you believe in hell? True.
But they're your candles,
so you're going to hell.
Okay.
Alright,
just give me this. Yeah, grab that.
Her fever's at 102,
so you might be right
about RSV.
Okay.
So we just
give her acetaminophen
and wait it out
unless she gets short of breath?
Versus driving in a blackout
to Grey-Sloan in a pandemic?
Yeah,
we're not going anywhere.
The risk
of exposure alone...
We don't need doctors, April.
We aredoctors.
And if
she gets worse...
Which she probably won't.
Exactly.
Yeah.
How's Meredith doing?
I've been
praying for her.
Oh, she's, uh...
She's awake. Yeah?
And she's getting better
every day, stronger.
Oh.
Yeah.
So, tonight wasn't
your night.
Yes. As usual,
your calendar is impeccable.
Well done.
No, I'm just saying,
uh, tonight...
Tonight wasn't your night,
so why are you...
How have I never been
to your place?
I feel like I guess
we must always do drop-offs
at mine or work.
It's... It's nice.
It looks really nice.
I like what you've
done. Jackson...
You guys are happy,
you and... you and Matthew?
We're busy,
like everyone else.
And Harriet and you
and him and Ruby,
the same house,
it's going...
Exposed brick is...
is cool.
- I know you've always liked...
- Do you really think
I can't tell when you're being cagey?
- I'm not being cagey.
- Am I happy?
Exposed brick?
Would you just talk like a person?
I went
to see my dad again.
Oh, God.
Is he sick?
No,
he's the same as always.
Obliviously medium happy about
his obliviously medium life.
I thought you never
wanted to see him again.
I didn't.
I needed to know if I was right
about what I... what I wanted.
And we're back
to being cagey.
I'm not trying to be cagey,
April.
He couldn't handle it.
Okay?
He couldn't step up
or step into his own,
and I can.
I want to take over
the foundation.
Is this the, uh,
coffee you showed me
last time
I was here?
We sold out
of our first batch.
The local paper
wrote us up,
so we decided to add
four more roasts.
I was gonna branch out
into other parts of the state,
and then,
ah, COVID.
Yeah, I remember.
You guys got hit pretty hard.
Hospital was
turning people away, right?
It was a lot.
I did
everything I could
to keep this place open
after COVID hit.
But then I ended up
just... bagging up food
for the regulars.
Word spread,
and every morning,
I come in here
and crank up
the Doobie Brothers,
start packing lunches.
It was
weirdly therapeutic.
Kept my mind occupied.
Well...
you got
quite the bubble out here.
Built a very different life
for yourself.
We're all raised
to think
that's some kind of
wild concept.
But what's wild
is going to work every day
doing something
you do not like,
thinking one day,
it'll just magically stop.
Yeah.
I just feel stuck.
Hmm.
Like there's two of me.
Like there's this...
This successful surgeon
that I worked so hard to become,
was trying
to push the foundation
to be
more progressive.
And also just the guy
that didn't ask
for any of this, you know?
I'm worried
that maybe it's too late...
The system's beyond repair.
Maybe I could be effective
from the outside.
Or maybe you could
let go of the idea
that it's your job
to save the world.
You know,
there's nothing wrong
with wanting
to keep things simpler.
Yeah,
I think about that a lot.
Actually,
I think, you know,
I could get a small place
in the woods,
maybe open
a private practice,
do things
I really care about.
Explore the great outdoors
with Harriet.
We all deserve to live our lives
however we want.
Sure, yeah.
You are an older white guy
who's always had money, so...
If nothing changes
in the world,
you're still gonna be fine,
but I... I hear you.
You given any thought
to what if?
What if
I didn't come back here?
you chose differently, yeah.
Well,
I'm more of a, hmm...
"never look back"
type.
Right, yeah.
Yeah, um...
When I was here last time,
I wanted to ask you why,
and I... I didn't...
I couldn't...
I guess I used to say
I was over it,
but I'm not.
I need to know
why you left.
'Cause, um...
...I realize that
it's really messed me up...
pretty badly.
And, um...
It just
made it hard to, like,
maintain relationships
and stuff.
Having this inclination
to run away all the time.
And I know,
I know...
Running away
doesn't actually solve anything.
I know that.
So...
And I've tried.
I've tried really hard
to rid myself of the shame
and the pain that comes with
all that, and, uh...
You know,
just kind of doubled-down
on being the best
at everything...
The best father
I could possibly be.
I probably stayed in my marriage
longer than I should have,
went along with
foundation business
longer than
I should have,
but no matter what,
when it gets rough,
I just end up...
right there,
running,
into the woods.
Try to fight
the you in me.
Can you not just sit there looking
at me? Can you say something?
Pretend that
I'm worth talking to?
I don't know how you can just
say nothing all the... Ow!
God! Aah!
Damn it!
God!
Oh, man.
You alright?
No, I'm not alright!
Give it... I got it!
Pressure,
pressure, pressure.
Okay.
Temp's down to 101.
It's just
a bad dream.
- Oh, yeah? How's her breathing?
- It's better.
- Oh, good, alright.
- Yeah.
- So we could be out of the woods.
So,
were you hoping
- Matthew wasn't gonna be here tonight?
- What?
No, I don't have a problem
with Matthew.
- Really?
- What?
Whenever you guys
are in the same room together,
you say
one of three things...
"Yup," "Sure,"
"Not a problem."
Well, okay, yeah.
We're not best friends,
but, I mean, it's civil.
He seems like
a fine guy.
- He seems, uh, kind.
- Kind?
I don't have a badword
to say about him.
That...
That's something.
So then why did you want to
come tell me this in person?
You're considering
running the foundation.
What's that
got to do with me?
That's the thing
I'm not...
just considering it.
I'm doing it.
Running the foundation means
I got to move to Boston.
W... Without Harriet?
No. God, no.
I'm moving to Boston,
and I really
need you all to come.
The foundation will employ
you and Matthew.
You'll be set.
You can do
whatever you want
in terms of an outreach program
or design or build.
Anything you want to do,
we'll fund it.
I would never
leave Harriet.
I could never,
ever leave Harriet,
which means I really
need you all to come with me.
Please.
Doesn't look like there are
any tendon injuries.
Yeah,
the cut's not that deep.
Okay.
Another wash,
then let's glue it.
I can handle it
from here.
Actually,
just hand me the glue.
Okay.
Ow.
Just give me
your hand.
Come on, man. Let
me do this. Okay.
I may not have practiced
in a while,
but... it is like
riding a bike.
Not exactly,
but okay.
Hold it together.
See?
Alright.
That is not bad.
Okay.
Does it hurt?
- Do you want any Tylenol or anything?
- Um.
No, no, no.
It's actually just...
It stings a little bit,
but that's fine.
Thank you.
Look at us.
We ought to open up
a family practice.
You know,
I'm gonna...
I'm just gonna
grab some air.
I get it, Jackson.
You're not the only person
in quarantine
who's drowning in big
"What the hell am I doing
with my life?"
Kind of questions.
But you don't just
up and move across the country
on a whim.
No, no, no, that's not what
this is. It's not on a whim.
Since the moment I met you
at Mercy West,
you have rejected
your family name, the legacy,
even the freaking plane.
You've... You've wanted
nothing to do with any of it.
- I resisted. That's not necess...
- No, no, no.
Sorry, you've been running,
kicking and screaming.
That is not
where this is coming from.
Okay? I can use this
as an opportunity
to make some profound changes
in the world.
You understand?
I respect that. I mean,
I-I admire that, Jackson.
As long as it's not an inconvenience
to your perfect little life here?
Uprooting my entire life
is not an inconvenience.
Okay,
you're right.
But I need this.
I know
that I need to do this.
I can feel it in my gut, and I
just want to trust that for once.
Okay.
How many times have you
"felt in your gut"...
- ...the need to just pack up a tent
- Don't...
and go
for a walkabout
and talk to yourself
amongst the trees?
So I'm the only one that's walked
away when I was having a hard time?
Just me, huh?
How many times
have you been
sitting in the front pew
at a church,
talking to God about the plans
for your life?
- It's not the same thing. I...
- Why not?
Why is it that you can find
solace and purpose in a church,
but I can't find it
in nature,
where I can actually have
some time that's quiet... -
...hear myself think,
think about what I want,
not what everybody else
expects of me?
So how long
did you spend
thinking about
going to see your father?
How much time did you spend
doing that?
- Don't reduce it to that!
- Or did you just, like, get in a car
- No, it's not on a whim, okay?
- And... and go...
- It was a realization.
- Okay, I...
I needed clarity,
and I went and talked to Robert,
and I got it.
You have never
wanted any of this.
And... And I'm just
supposed to roll with it
and see
what happens?
What... What happens
when you regret it?
What happens when you realize
that you actually hate it?
What you're asking
of me,
of... of our family,
of our daughter, it's...
What happens
if it doesn't work?
Matthew got on one knee
and proposed to you...
- Please don't. Jackson, I'm...
- No, no, no, it's true.
He got on one knee
and proposed to you
in front of me.
I stood there,
watched another man
become your husband
and stepfather
to my child
- ...our child...
- Mm-hmm.
...and at no point
did I come to you and say,
"Yeah, but what if
it doesn't work?"
I didn't do that.
I had your back that day
and every day since.
He bugs the hell out of you,
doesn't he?
I'm allowed
to be frustrated at the guy
who makes
sandwiches weird.
Who... I-It's... And he
calls her Hair-Hair.
I know. I know.
I'm working on that.
What I'm not allowed
to do, April,
what... what I've actually
never done,
is stand in the way
of the happiness
that you chose for yourself.
I had your back.
I know
this is a surprise,
but I'm just asking you...
Do the same for me.
I...
I... I want you to be happy,
Jackson.
You deserve it.
But running
the foundation?
I...
I'm sorry.
It's just...
You're not that guy.
I don't think
you ever will be.
So, that's it?
I'm either gonna fail or quit?
I'm sorry, Jackson. I didn't...
I didn't mean that...
Yeah, you did.
That's exactly what you meant.
Ok...
Fine. Yeah.
I did.
Jackson,
you are a brilliant surgeon.
You rebuild people's faces,
you rebuild their lives.
You find a way
to make them breathe
when...
When it seems impossible.
You gave a little boy back
his hands.
You prayed me
back into the world
when I was almost dead.
Y-You take out
impossible tumors,
and you make people
walk out into the world
with their heads
held high.
That's where
you've left your mark.
It's what
makes you exceptional.
Wh...
Why would you want
to give all of that up?
It's not about what I want.
It's what I need to do.
Well, you know what?
It's a little late to decide that.
Excuse me?
You don't get to choose
who I am in this world, April.
Nobody does.
Not my father,
not Mom... nobody.
And you don't get to choose
your career over mine.
That's...
I am happy.
I'm helping people.
I'm really helping them.
I am building
support systems
and resources for people
in rural communities,
and they need
so much,
and I can actually
do that for them.
And you can
keep doing that.
You can do it
on an even bigger scale.
across the country.
I'm... You're literally
just gaining resources.
April, I am not trying
to diminish your work.
We have
an opportunity
to do something really amazing
for all of us.
Matthew will go along
with it.
He'll follow you.
That's why
I like him so much.
Oh, God.
You know what?
You... You didn't always
have my back.
When I found
what I needed in Jordan,
you didn't go
with me.
You left me alone.
I went alone.
April, that's not fair.
You ran away from me.
And Samuel and the pain
and the grief,
which is understandable.
You know,
I was resentful at the time,
but I get it.
You were surviving.
You had to do
what you had to do to survive.
But this isn't that,
anyway.
I'm not
running fromsomething.
I'm trying
to run tosomething.
Trying to make
something my own.
It's not fair,
Jackson.
If you had
the opportunity
to finally
make it all make sense,
to become
what you were meant to be,
wouldn't you try really,
really hard to get there?
I would.
I did.
That's all
I'm asking for.
I got it.
99.3.
- Oh, good. Alright.
- Yeah.
So she's
a little more comfortable.
Yeah.
She's talking in her sleep.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Anything good?
Just gibberish.
She said,
"Amananome."
Ah.
That is the sea anemone.
Oh. She's been waking
me up the last few weeks
with a different
sea creature fact.
Are they really "facts,"
though?
In her head, they are.
It's the best alarm clock, ever,
I'll tell you.
Last week,
she told me
that she could hear "werewoofs"
throwing up in your basement.
Really?
I don't even have a basement.
Oh, I'm aware.
There's no
convincing her otherwise.
So stubborn.
Which I would say comes
from her mother... - Mm.
...but I think
we both know...
- 50/50 split...
- right down the middle.
Yeah.
I could never give that up
going to Boston.
Sea creature alarm clocks,
holding her when she's sick.
But I can't walk away
from this chance
to make real change
in the foundation.
I mean,
Mom was able to do both.
And I know in my gut,
that I can, too.
I mean, I owe it to Harriet
to try, at least.
- I know.
- And I know I can't do it all,
but, April,
I am telling you,
I can take this foundation
to a whole new chapter.
I mean, creating real
racial equity in medicine.
Are you kidding?
It's a revolutionary,
lasting change.
I could look my daughter
in the face
and know that I've done
everything I possibly can
to give her
a better world.
I know.
I could do all that
and... and be the father
that mine never was.
And all I need to do
is turn my life upside down.
Puts a lot into perspective,
huh?
Yeah, I come out here
every morning
just to
take it all in.
Feel like
I got a lot more thinking done
these last few days
out here
than... probably
all year.
Might find it
hard to believe,
but I've been thinking a lot
about our last visit.
Everything you said.
And the truth is,
I left because
that's what I do.
I chose this place
because it's safe.
Running the restaurant,
bagging lunches,
none of it
requires much of me.
I can walk away
and not look back any time.
And just forget about who
you're leaving behind, yeah?
I was convinced you were
better off without me.
Without a father?
How would you think
I'm better off without...
my father never being there
for any birthdays,
any graduations?
That time I got beat up
by Billy Paxton?
At my wedding?
The birth of my child,
your granddaughter.
My divorce... maybe that
would've been a good time
for you to step in
and share some wisdom.
A hug,
I don't know.
Help me
make some decisions?
It's not like
it was a few months, man.
Or a year
or 10 years.
It's my entire life.
- How could you think that's better?
- In my father's eyes,
I was the screw-up
in the family,
and I absorbed
that story.
Maybe I became it.
And I didn't want
to pass that down to you.
I did not want
to mess you up.
Congrats.
I get that now.
I hurt
a lot of people.
You,
your mother.
And to have found out
I have a granddaughter that I...
may never meet...
Yeah, well, it didn't have to
be that way, did it?
You're absolutely right.
So I buy her presents.
An art set, a basketball,
tricycle, board games.
What are you saying?
And you didn't send them?
I don't have
the right.
I don't deserve...
to take your time,
be in your space.
Not one day has passed
that I haven't regretted
leaving you.
It haunts me
in my sleep,
when I wake up
in the morning.
And I am truly,
truly sorry.
And yet I know an apology
will never make up for it.
And I have to live
with that.
I will never
get over it.
Oh, Jackson.
Crossroads like this,
you don't arrive at them often,
but I know
you will be okay,
no matter
what road you choose.
I'm still an Avery,
right?
I still find
some way to...
walk away
from it all.
Apple doesn't fall far
from the tree.
Isn't that
what they say?
Nice.
That's great. No, I'm sorry.
I just thought
that was funny.
I'm the tree,
you're the apple.
Do you really
think that?
I'm sitting here,
aren't I?
Jackson, let me assure you,
you are not me.
The fact that you're even
questioning your choices
is proof of that.
And if
that's not enough,
you are committed,
Jackson.
Committed to your work,
to your family,
to people in need.
And I know sometimes you want
to run away from it all,
but anybody with any sense
does that.
It's very different
from actually
following through with it.
I was scared.
I'm scared.
Yeah, but you're scared
of doing the wrongthing.
I was too scared
to do the rightthing.
You're not a runner.
If you were, you would have been
long gone by now.
Do you know how easy
it would have been
for you to walk away
from everything
after it all came out
about the foundation?
Did you even
consider it?
Not really, no.
Of course not.
'Cause you have it in your soul
to do the right thing,
to make things right.
And you didn't just
fix a disaster,
you made it better.
So if you don't want
to stay, don't.
But don't
blame it on me.
'Cause on
your worst day,
you are 10 times
the man I am.
- Jackson?
- Hey.
- Come in.
- I can't stay.
Honey,
it's pouring out here.
Here, Mom.
I mean, I can't stay
at Grey-Sloan in Seattle.
I can't keep doing
what we've always done.
You know how many
people of color
we've already lost
since the pandemic started?
The system keeps diminishing
and erasing us.
T-They're literally letting
people just die in the streets,
and we can do something
about it.
I got to show Harriet
that we can put our money
and our attention
where our mouths are.
And we can acknowledge
the connection between our work
and what's actually happening
in the streets
and give a sense of equity
in this world, okay?
It's not gonna change
after COVID.
We know that.
White supremacy is woven into
the fabric of this country,
and that
means medicine, too.
People that look like us
should not have to be
gaslit, shamed, and ignored
when they're
just going to the doctor,
constantly having to prove
that their lives have any value.
It's like this constant
cycle of stress
from poverty and trauma
and racism,
and it's definitely
impacting mental health...
It's definitely
killing us.
Where are people
supposed to turn?
They don't feel safe
going to the doctor.
They're scared
to call the cops.
This is like
a deep-seated neglect.
And if our deaths are not
affecting their profit margin,
then it's not
gonna change.
I want to take over
the foundation.
What?
I want to reallocate
every penny that we have
to equity
in medicine...
Women's health, trans health,
racial equity.
I want everyone who this country
abuses to be served, okay?
We need to challenge
all the ways that we teach,
everything that
we're doing.
If that means dismantling
the whole medical system
a-and... and designing something
that actually serves everyone,
then that's
what I want to do.
I-I see that now.
I'm ready.
Jackson,
where have you been?
It doesn't even
matter anymore, Mom.
It matters that I'm back
and I know where I belong.
Oh!
- I gotta go. I love you.
- Ah!
Where on God's earth are you going now?
I got to go
talk to April.
What?!
Jackson...
Here we go.
Yummy!
Are you gonna go with
crazy fork?
Pancakes
go in your belly.
Why do you always go
for the big ones?
Hey.
Take all the small pieces,
alright?
You want to cut your own little piece?
- A small one.
- What are you doing...
A small one this time,
that's soaked up in syrup?
Extra syrup?
Ooh.
There she is.
- There she is.
- Hi!
Mommy!
Hi!
Oh!
No fever.
Oh, good,
good, good.
I want orange juice.
Yeah, you can have
some orange juice.
You want me
to get it for you, baby?
No,
I get it myself.
- Okay.
Go ahead, baby.
Are you gonna unscrew the top
and pour it?
You are that guy,
Jackson.
I was an ass
for saying otherwise.
Yeah?
Pillows in every room.
They come in handy.
Hey,
are you sure about this?
I'm not sure
it's gonna work, but...
I'm sure
it's what I want, yeah.
Why is our timing always
so terrible?
I thought that was kind of
our thing... bad timing.
We just
never figured out
how to want the same thing
at the same time.
Even with Harriet.
Yeah, but, I mean,
it worked out pretty well.
Yeah,
but we were fighting,
and then we had sex
while our marriage
was falling apart.
That was actually
our thing...
Arguing until we were blue
in the face and then having sex.
Yeah, I guess
we were doomed, huh?
Look, if you're really
living your dream here,
I'll give it up,
because you're right.
I'm totally
springing it on you guys.
No. What?
You do not
get to do all the speeches
and the convincing
and that thing where your face
just lights up
just to
take it all back again.
Don't take it
all back.
You deserve this.
Wait.
What are you saying?
I am saying...
...we will
make Boston work.
I'm saying yes.
What?
You're saying yes?
To my question,
you're saying yes? Yes.
I'm saying... Yeah. I thought
that's what you wanted.
Yeah, but... Yes?
Like, I didn't think
it would be that easy.
I'm sorry.
You call this night easy?
No, not...
Not easy like that,
but, like, I thought
you'd have to pray
or consult with Matthew,
maybe get your pastor involved,
- some additional praying...
- Yeah. Yeah. Matthew will be fine.
Alright, well,
when does he get back?
I can help with the pitch.
I can talk to him.
- What do you want me to...?
- Uh, no. No. No.
No, that's a horrible
and weird idea...
- Yes.
- ...obviously.
Um, but tell him that
I can help him with work.
I'll make sure everything is
arranged for him and for Ruby.
We split up.
Oh.
We kept trying to tell ourselves
that our whole winding road
was God's plan
to bring us back together.
But he was still so angry
and so hurt.
I mean, I left him at the altar,
and then his wife died.
You know,
you don't just stop feeling hurt
'cause it's a better story
if God brought us together
in our pain.
He denied it
for so long.
You know, he tried so hard
not to hate me.
I think loving me,
making us a full circle
was the story
he was writing.
I mean, I guess it was the story
we were both writing.
I mean, I was trying
to get past my guilt.
He was... He was
trying to forgive God
for the loss of Karin.
But, y-you know,
ultimately, we learned that...
...life just
isn't always so tidy.
And God's plan isn't always
so easy to understand.
He's always been so good
with Harriet,
and I adore Ruby,
but we both started
working longer hours,
just avoiding coming
home.
And then, his sister got sick.
She lives in Philadelphia.
So he and Ruby went to
Philadelphia to be with her,
and... now she's better,
uh, but they're
still in Philadelphia.
And...
they are
not coming back.
I had no idea.
Yeah, I mean,
I was gonna tell you,
but, you know, hundreds of
thousands of people were dying.
I just didn't think my marriage
counted as a casualty.
And you were maybe
a little too proud to tell me?
Yeah, fine.
I was a little...
A little too proud.
You okay?
It's hard to say.
But...
it looks like
I'm moving to Boston.
So...
Fingers crossed
for new horizons.
♪ I know you're out there,
doin' the best you can ♪
No one said it was easy,
becoming the person
you're meant to be.
♪ But everybody needs
a helping hand ♪
It takes bravery a step into
the power you found
and earned and deserve.
♪ 'Cause we're all alone in this
together ♪
♪ But the storm
won't last forever ♪
He'll come back.
And you'll visit,
and he'll visit.
I know.
You know,
it's okay to be sad.
It's hard handing over something
you put your life into.
- ♪ So much light
- I'm not sad.
It's just, like,
I never in my life
felt pride
- ♪ We can hold each other up
- quite like this.
♪ We can hold each other up
♪ Yeah
♪ Hold each other up
The trick is, to take the
people who were there for you,
with you.
To remind you
you're not alone.
It's gonna
take a few days,
figure out what to tell
the chief.
Feels weird
to say Boston.
Feels like a...
I don't know.
It feels "I don't know"
to me, too.
♪ 'Cause I see hope
in togetherness ♪
Thank you.
Oh!
♪ So much light
Mommy, Daddy!
- ♪ And so much love
- I got her.
- ♪ There is strength ♪
- You go. Get ready to go.
♪ Strength in tenderness ♪
You...
have an entire legacy
behind you
as you create your own.
♪ We can hold each other up
Captions by VITAC...
Sync corrections by srjanapala