Ha.
Ah.
Ah. I love it when
those endorphins kick in.
You're not on today, are you?
I thought I'd drop by,
ease up your
workload a little bit...
After I take a shower.
It's his day off?
That's dedication for you.
Dedication? Man, that's sad.
Don't move, Mrs. Zarian.
It's a little bit of glass,
and it's almost free.
Susan, were your ears burning?
Huh?
David Morgenstern and I
were just talking about you.
He feels you're
the top contender
for Chief Resident next year.
Oh. Thanks.
This year's field
was pretty disappointing,
but we found your work
to be consistently solid.
Now, I know you're concerned
about the responsibilities
taking time away from the baby,
but that doesn't
have to be the case.
Keep the bevel facing out.
By applying
time-management techniques,
you can work more efficiently,
reduce on-the-job stress,
and get home at
a reasonable hour.
Mrs. Zarian...
I've got a book on the
subject if you're interested.
No pressure. I just want to let
you know how we're thinking.
Son of a bitch! What?
They cut me back
to three shifts a week.
They're cutting back on nurses?
Nurse managers, because
of our outrageous salaries.
Man, I still need $12,000
worth of work on my house.
Damn. They bumped
me up to six shifts a week.
So much for my weekend.
I know where you can
make some quick cash.
Talk to me.
I joined this guy
Alvin's investment club.
Yeah...
Put up a $2,000 membership fee,
and in a week to 10 days,
you collect $10,000 to $20,000.
From?
From the fees of the
new people who join.
It's called a pyramid
scam, and it's illegal.
What? That's not
what Alvin says.
Trust me. If you're not in
early, you lose your shirt.
When did you get in?
Hey.
Hey yourself.
All right, let's see
what we got here.
Where'd you learn
to do sub-q sutures?
From your med student.
Well, I obviously
taught him well, didn't I?
Benton.
I'll see you later.
Listen, I thought I
should warn you.
You might want to
invest in a new suit or two
or maybe some luggage.
See, you're going to Paris
to present our
clamp-and-run study
to the Institut
Français de Chirurgie.
Are you serious?
Oui. Simon did a chi-square
analysis of our results.
Our P-value is .06,
which means we're
one successful outcome
away from statistical
significance.
W-we can publish?
Soon. One more aneurysm will
burnish our numbers to a glow
that will blind the
most dubious skeptics.
And after that, MacGruder
and I head to D.C.
to play dog-and-pony
for the FDA.
Now, Simon doesn't
fly, so he stays here,
which makes you
the next natural choice
for Clamp-and Run
Ambassador to Europe.
Whoa, whoa. I don't
know what to say.
Look, okay, I-I'm honored...
Good. It's good practice
for the future. Don't worry.
Now, you've got to
find another patient soon
because some Norwegians
are doing a similar study,
and Peter,
we cannot let the Vikings
pillage our thunder.
Hey, Malik, you seen Carter?
Yeah. He called
and said he'd be late.
He should be coming any minute.
Oh! No, wait. Wait! Wait!
Oh! Oh! Yeah! Oh, God!
John, oh, God! Oh, God!
Oh! Ah! Ah!
Oh, baby.
Oh!
I think we broke my record.
Yeah?
Oh, John. What?
Your control is phenomenal.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Yeah. Thank you.
You know, uh, the
interesting thing?
You may find this
hard to believe,
but that wasn't
always the case. No?
It's hard to believe.
It's true, though.
But I find if I could
distract myself
and think about
the mundane things,
then I could delay
the inevitable.
Well, what kind of
things do you think about?
Um, let's see.
Sometimes, I, uh,
take a mental inventory
of the machines in the O.R...
Thoraseal, ventilators,
auto-infusers.
And then, as the degree
of difficulty increases,
I run the procedures...
Appendectomies, thyroidectomies,
bowel resections.
Yuck!
What?
While we're making love,
you're thinking about
bowel resections?
Well, given your
earlier testimonial,
I figured this is a classic case
of the ends justifying
the means. What?!
I'm kidding. I'm just
kidding. Ow! Get out!
So last night, I get a
letter from Jen's lawyer
politely informing me
that she's suing me
for full custody of Rachel.
Oh, no.
Yeah, it seems I've been a
"distant and absent father."
This, after commuting from
Milwaukee for half a year.
Well, it sounds like
a lot of lawyer BS.
I can't imagine she'd
actually go through with it.
I was climbing
the walls all night.
Oh, that's why you're here.
Tiny prick.
I beg your pardon?
I need a TB test too.
So I hear Morgenstern has
really turned up the pressure
on you becoming Chief Resident.
Yeah. It's a good opportunity,
but can I do it and
not work killer hours?
You know how well I managed
to balance work and family.
Guess that answers that.
You'll be able to work it out.
Take your paperwork home,
hours won't be that bad.
Ow.
You have to cut Kerry
Weaver some slack.
What do you mean?
You go out of your
way to avoid her,
and if she is going
to be training you,
you're going to have to
work together hand-in-hand.
Oh, there's an image.
What are you doing
here on your day off?
I went for a jog
and ended up here,
and I figured, "What the hell.
Might as well save some lives."
Another good
reason not to exercise.
32-year-old male, postductal.
Five-minute grand mal seizure.
All right. I'll take it.
Start a chart.
On his day off?
Those TPN orders
should have been called in
an hour ago. Sorry. I forgot.
I thought you wanted
a residency here. I do.
If you keep forgetting, you're
going to end up in North Dakota.
We've got six slots,
300 applications.
When do interviews start?
They already have. I'm on
my way upstairs. You stay.
Vucelich needs one more
aneurysm for his study.
Abdominal pains, chest
pains, traumas, call me.
How often do you get
dizzy spells, Mrs. Henry?
Oh, I get three or four a day,
usually when I'm
working in the shed.
You garden this time of year?
I'm a vermiculturist.
I raise earthworms.
Really? Mm-hmm.
Big ones from Belgium.
Finest castings in the world.
And by castings, you mean...?
Worm dung.
Black gold.
It's the best fertilizer
money can buy.
It fixes the
nitrogen in the soil.
And you sell the stuff?
Well, I sell the worms.
You're blood
pressure's a little high.
So it pays well?
Yeah. Six figures.
Huh.
Has he had a seizure before?
No. He's a health
nut. He runs every day.
We're going to have to
get a CAT scan of his head
to pinpoint the
cause of the seizure.
Alan.
Alan?
When's he going to come back?
It takes a little time to
recover from a seizure.
How long? Usually
about 30 minutes.
Multi-focal PVCs.
What?
His heart rhythm's a little off.
Probably oxygen
deprivation from the seizure.
Has he had a murmur before? No.
Ah, it's probably
nothing serious.
Let's get an echo of
his heart after the CT,
just to be safe.
Lidocaine bolus,
100 milligrams,
then start a drip.
No. Carter, John Carter.
I was calling just because
I thought maybe you were
trying to get in touch with me
to set up an interview
for the Residency.
No, huh?
Well, I am available any...
Uh-huh.
Okay. Right.
I hear Vucelich
doubled his finder's fee
for an aneurysm.
Could be.
A-ha. I made 1000 bucks.
Patient presented
with a history of ulcers,
but he says the pain's
different this time.
Rigid belly?
Hard to tell, he's so fat,
but you see the calcifications
on the descending aorta?
No. Where?
Here.
No, it's too lateral.
Probably just
schmutz on his lungs.
So I shouldn't call Vucelich?
Yeah, if you want
to get yelled at.
Harper?
I need you to
get this guy to CT.
Coming.
Do me a favor and return
this x-ray to his room?
Yeah. Which room? Six.
Are you done with that? Yes.
Wow. That's a mother
of an aneurysm.
How can you tell?
Calcification on the
descending aorta.
Yeah.
We're going to run a
CAT scan on his head
to rule out lesions
that could have
caused the seizure.
Uh-oh.
What's wrong?
He's in V-tach. Get
him to trauma. Haleh!
I'm here.
I got a pulse. What's
wrong with him?
His heart rhythm's gotten worse.
You sure he hasn't
taken any medication? No.
Non-prescription
drugs? No, never. He...
Okay, we're going to
get this under control.
Can someone take Mrs.
Wimbur to the waiting room?
But I just want to...
It's okay. Thank you.
Let's get another
50 of lidocaine,
IV push.
Heart's racing. 200.
Rhythm is all over the place.
Looks like Torsade de Pointes.
All right, Harper, get
lytes and a tox screen,
and check, see if we've
got any records on this guy,
anything that'll give us a
clue as to what's going on.
Lido's on board.
What's your gut say, Haleh?
Low potassium?
Lydia? Cocaine.
His wife says he's tox free.
We'll know soon enough.
Heart rate's up to 210.
All right, let's try
and cardiovert.
Paddles. Start him at 100.
Hands off. Clear.
Faint pulse.
There we go.
That's a nice rhythm.
He moved his head.
Rate's down to 160.
180. Whoops, here we go again.
All right, lidocaine's
not working.
Let's try bretylium,
500 IV push.
Prep transvenus
pacemaker. Charge to 200.
Hands off.
What makes you think
this is an aneurysm, Carter?
The calcium plaque
on the descending aorta.
Well, you just
saved this man's life
and made a group of Norwegian
surgeons very unhappy.
Good work. Thank you.
Where's the patient?
Uh... Room six.
To room six.
Hey, way to go, Carter.
Labs are back. Lytes are normal.
Tox screen's negative.
We were both wrong.
What the hell's
wrong with this guy?
Rate's up to 220. Faint pulse.
Pacer's in.
Let's overdrive him to 230.
Maximum gain. Got it.
See if I can grab
hold of this rhythm.
You're on. You've got capture.
Lovely. Let's take
it down slowly.
210...
200.
180.
It's jumping back up.
Lost capture.
V-fib! Lost the pulse.
Let's start CPR.
Add Pronestyl, 100 mgs, IV Push.
Paddles. Set them at 360.
What time is it? 0845.
Mark that time.
Hands off. Clear. Clear.
Wide complex tachycardia.
Still no pulse. Time?
9:05.
How long's he been down?
20 minutes. Tried the
pacer. He went into V-fib.
Shocked him 15, 20 times.
He keeps running
these chaotic rhythms.
Could he be hypocalcemic?
No, lytes are fine.
Cocaine? Tox screen's negative.
Acidotic? Good question.
Let's get another gas.
Time? 0922.
Another 100 of Pronestyl.
Got your blood gases
here. PH 7.24, PO-2's 110.
Still in fib.
He's going down.
You gone through all
the anti-arrhythmics?
Still got a few more.
Stand by with the amiodarone.
Back up. Clear.
Time? 0932.
Still no pulse. Try
magnesium sulfate.
Clear. Clear.
Time? 9:41.
High dose epi, five mgs. Clear.
Time? ROSS: 9:45.
Clear.
32 years old.
Time of death... 9:55.
Why?
There was an
electrical disturbance
in your husband's heart
that caused it to beat
in an irregular way.
I wish I could tell you
what caused it to happen,
but the truth is, I don't know.
Well, that's not good enough.
I mean... We came in here,
and his heart was... okay,
and you said it wasn't
anything serious,
so somebody must
have screwed up.
No. How did you let this happen?
Mrs. Wimbur... What
did you do to him?
Uh, hello, Alvin.
Oh. Well, do you, uh...
have his new number?
So, Kerry...
One...
Second.
Yes, Susan?
I've been thinking about
your invitation this morning,
and I would like
to throw my hat in
for Chief Resident.
I'm glad. I look forward
to showing you the ropes.
Me too.
Nobody signed up for
the gallbladder in 2 yet.
I've got it.
How long does a CAT scan take?
Hopefully, not
more than an hour,
but sometimes there's a wait.
I'm a little concerned
about my worms in the truck.
You brought your worms with you?
Just one bin.
I was making a delivery
when the dizziness hit.
You think someone
will steal them?
No. They're locked up.
You don't leave $5000
worth of worms unsecured.
But they could freeze.
Uh-huh.
Listen, if I gave you my keys,
could you bring them
in out of the cold?
Oh, we can't have
animals in the hospital.
Oh, there's no danger.
You know, worms are the only
disease-free organisms on earth.
It's a fact.
I really shouldn't.
Oh, please. They're my worms.
All right.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, and could you
feed them, please?
What do they eat?
Uh, table scraps, as
long it's vegetarian.
Nothing too greasy,
because fat doesn't
sit well with worms.
Mrs. D'Angelo, I see
you've been with us before.
Gallstones flaring up again?
They're killing me.
I can't sleep, I can't eat,
and every three weeks,
I end up back here.
Pain pills didn't help?
I took twice as much,
didn't do anything.
Yeah, you shouldn't do that.
Please, doctor,
get a surgeon to take
these damn stones out.
It's been going on like
this for six months now.
Aah! Aah!
Okay. Sorry.
Okay. I'll get an ultrasound
to see if there's any blockage.
Unless your condition
is life-threatening,
any surgery would be considered
elective, and unfortunately...
It's an 18-month waiting list.
Yeah, I'm afraid so.
My neighbor got
hers out the next day.
Does your neighbor
have private insurance?
Is it my fault I'm on Medicaid?
Okay, we'll start
with the ultrasound
and see what we have.
Thank you.
His name is Alan Wimbur.
You guys just picked him up.
I was hoping you could
do the autopsy today.
Hey, Jerry, where's
the ultrasound?
You got me.
Well, let me know,
because I'd like to observe.
Autopsy?
I want to find out what
happened to his heart.
You should go home.
His wife accused
me of killing him.
She's probably going to sue.
People get upset, feel they
need to blame someone.
I heard a murmur on exam.
Before getting an echo,
I wanted to get a CT.
Yeah, don't even think about it.
A guy comes in with a seizure,
first thing you want's a CT.
Thanks. I was just checking.
Dr. Greene, Dr. Morgenstern's
office just called.
He'd like to see you upstairs.
Oh, word travels fast.
You're making
excellent time, Peter.
Suction!
Let Carter suction!
It's his reward for
having a hound-like ability
to hunt down an aneurysm.
I just feel privileged to
be given the opportunity.
Well, now that's
what I call suction.
Thank you. Thank you.
MacGruder, is this patient warm?
Oh, shoot, shoot, shoot.
MacGruder!
Temp is 106.
He has malignant hypothermia.
Is he reacting to the
anesthesia? Yeah.
Give him dantrolene. Get
ice packs, cooling blankets.
Peter, get out.
If we don't get his temp down,
he's going to have
scrambled eggs for brains.
Who took this
patient's history? I did.
How could you miss
that he was intolerant
to fluorathane? I asked...
Damn it! I lay out a banquet,
and you crap all over my table!
He never had an
operation before!
Cooling blankets are here.
Well, lift him up,
get him under.
Peter, come on over
here. Come on, come on.
Evert the cortex.
Log-roll him over.
Suction, Peter.
Another 5.0 proline. More ice.
Tie that off, Peter.
So he never had an
operation before, huh? No.
Well, you're right. There
was no way of knowing.
My apologies.
Metz! Metz!
Are you free for lunch?
Susan... Yeah?
Medical Records
sent down the chart
on your gallstone lady.
Thanks.
I took a peek.
I know she's been
on cefoxitin. Yeah.
Cefotaxime has better
biliary penetration.
Okay.
I know it's hard memorizing
all the antibiotics out there.
But it's well worth
the time. Right.
Who's the ultrasound
for? Same lady.
Didn't she have one last month?
She's complaining of more pain.
I want to rule out
obstruction and cholangitis.
Remember Charcot's triad.
Cholangitis is indicated
by pain, fever and jaundice,
of which your
patient only has one.
I think you can rule her out
without the expense
of an ultrasound.
If you're going to be Chief,
you gotta watch the bottom line.
Mark.
I don't believe you've
met Kathy Snyder,
one of the hospital attorneys.
Hello. Hello.
So this is about
this cardiac arrest
who died this morning?
I haven't heard
anything. Have you?
Uh... No.
Kathy wanted to talk
about the O'Brien lawsuit.
Oh. Did we get a court date?
We've worked out a settlement
with Mr. O'Brien's attorney.
Hmm. I'm not sure
that I want to settle.
The hospital is sure.
It's a good thing, Mark.
Mr. O'Brien gets compensated
for the loss of his wife,
and you can put this behind you.
If I settle, this is gonna
follow me my entire career.
Every time I apply for a
staff job or insurance...
If it's a trial,
we could lose
two million easily.
You want to lug that
around your entire career?
I have been over
this 1000 times.
I didn't do anything wrong.
It was
a very complicated delivery.
I did as good a job as any
emergency physician could have.
Other emergency physicians
would, and have,
disagreed with you.
A pregnant woman
comes in with preeclampsia
and, for whatever reason,
you didn't pick up on it.
Her condition was masked
by a urinary infection.
Look, I don't want to argue
the details with you, Mark.
You make thousands
of diagnoses a year.
99% of them
are right on.
You made a
mistake, as we all do.
I don't accept
that. Mark, please...
No. This is my
reputation as a doctor.
I'm not going to settle.
Take my name off of it.
You can't separate
yourself from the suit.
Well, I'll hire my own
lawyer, and I'll fight it myself.
Ugh.
That's a lot of worms.
Hey, big fellow.
Woman says she makes
a fortune selling these.
To whom? Landscapers, farmers.
Could be a great sideline.
You're kidding, right?
No. These guys could
pay for the hole in my roof.
I cleaned the spoiled
food out of the fridge.
Veggie? That's
what you asked for.
They don't like grease.
How do they feel about yogurt?
I don't hear any complaining.
Eat up, little worms.
John.
Hi.
Told you it was an aneurysm.
You were right.
Did Vucelich know who I was?
Didn't you tell him about
me? That I found it?
I meant to. I mean,
I should have.
The whole thing
happened really fast.
I was going to say something,
and they just assumed that...
What are you doing in here?
The hospital decided
to settle the O'Brien suit.
Uh, isn't that good news?
Morgenstern thinks I'm at fault
for not picking up
the preeclampsia.
That's not fair. He
wasn't even there.
You were there.
It was as complicated
a case as I've ever seen.
You did everything you could.
You think I should have
caught the preeclampsia?
It was a difficult diagnosis.
Any one of us
could have missed it.
But if you were called
up on the witness stand
and asked, "Did Mark
Greene screw up,"
what would you say?
I'm sorry, Mark.
Come on, dude, be bold.
We start our own
investment club.
We collect right off the bat.
No, thanks, man.
Oh, what's to lose?
What did you lose? 2 grand?
Hey, Alvin's going
to come through.
Jerry, can you find out
why that worm lady
isn't back from CT?
Uh, she had palpitations,
so they're doing
a cardiac work-up.
Okay. Call me when
she comes down.
Jerry, did Medical Records
copy a chart for me?
Yeah. O'Brien, right?
Yep. Thanks.
Hey, what happened to
those worms in Radiology?
They're doing a consult.
No, no, no, those earthworms.
I put a bucket of
earthworms in there
and they're gone.
Well, I didn't take them.
Hey, Ray. I'm Dr. Ross.
I understand you've
been having headaches
and missing some school?
Yeah. They hurt pretty
bad. Mm-hmm. Okay.
Where in your head does it hurt?
Here.
How long you been having
these? About a month.
How often?
Um, all the time, I guess.
Do you feel dizzy? Uh, yeah.
Okay. Pull like that. Mm-hmm.
You play sports?
J.V. football, middle
linebacker. All right.
When I was a running back,
we used to hate you guys.
Squeeze my hand.
Mm-hmm. Okay, you ever
get headaches playing sports?
No.
No. Okay, well, we're
going to get you a CAT scan.
You know what that is? Um...
No? It's when we take
a picture of your brain.
We want to make
sure it's still in there.
All right. I'll be
back in a minute.
Tradition holds
they serve olive and
walnuts with the drink.
Dr. Vucelich, Dr. Benton,
I'm sorry to interrupt you.
I misled you both earlier.
The finder's fee for the
aneurysm this morning
should go to Harper Tracy.
She's a third-year medical
student. She caught it.
Well, taking credit
for a colleague's work
is a very dangerous
precedent, Mr. Carter.
I can assure you that it
will never happen again.
Well, your reassurance
rings hollow just now.
One has to wonder
if this is a momentary
lapse of integrity on your part
or a sign of a fundamental
flaw in your character.
Well, time will tell.
In any event, the patient's
secondary condition
means he's not an appropriate
candidate for the study,
so there will be
no finder's fee.
Is there anything else?
No.
Strange boy.
The patient is being excluded?
What's that? Oh, yes.
It seems that he
has a history of,
excuse me,
neurological problems,
which exceed the
parameters of the protocol, so...
What were we
talking about, Peter?
Oh, I remember. George Cinq.
Walnuts, olives.
Actually, I was an habitué
of this bistro called
"L'Amie Louis,"
and there was a...
Mrs. D'Angelo,
feeling any better?
No. Are you going
to do that test?
I consulted with another doctor,
and we feel that the
ultrasound is unnecessary.
You don't have any new symptoms.
You're not even going to check?
Given that you
don't have a fever
or any other symptoms,
there's no way I can
justify the expense.
The expense. I see.
I can take it from here.
I know the routine.
Ow. The nurse gives me
a few pills that don't work,
and I'm pushed out the door.
I checked the elective
surgery waiting list,
and they can get you
in by the end of the year.
It's February 1st.
Help!
What happened?
They were out by the trash.
Must have been there an hour.
Wendy, I want you to get
some warming blankets.
Heat up some saline.
We'll do a warm water lavage.
We could get a few of
those warming lamps
they use on newborns.
Great. Great idea. Go up to
OB, see if they'll lend us some.
All right... Oh, damn it!
The lid's frozen.
Oh, God. All right.
Rib spreader, rib spreader.
W-what are you doing?
I'm gonna knock
it loose, like a jar.
What do you got?
Hypothermia, earthworms.
5 grand worth.
Earthworms? Yeah.
They're Belgian.
They don't take kindly to cold.
Got it, got it!
Oh, no! Oh, it's frozen solid.
Oh! Well, maybe they're
still alive underneath.
Surgical mallet.
Reflex hammer.
Thanks.
All right, all right.
Oh, no. What am I
going to tell Mrs. Henry?
Good news, buddy.
Your brain's right
where it should be.
All right. Let's
talk about school.
Why?
Well, because school
can cause stress,
and stress can cause headaches.
Are you having any trouble
with your classes or students
or teachers or anything like that?
No.
No? All right. What about
your girlfriend? Any problems?
Which one?
There's a problem right there.
How many girlfriends
do you have?
A few. I don't know.
Mm-hmm. All right.
You're not doing drugs,
are you? Smoking pot?
No.
No? No... No.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine. Mm-hmm.
What's the matter?
I can't. I can't...
What?
There's something
wrong with me. Mm-hmm?
Okay.
All guys who are your age,
they think that there's
something wrong with them.
No.
I'm different.
How are you different?
The girls at school...
I...
I don't feel anything
when I'm around them.
I think I'm gay.
I know I am.
I mean, what am I
supposed to tell my dad?
My brothers?
I am just sick of... of
being this fake person.
Haleh, will you call psych?
See if we can get
a Resident down
to take a look at the kid in 1,
preferably somebody
from Adolescent Medicine.
What's the problem?
Kid thinks he's gay.
He needs somebody to talk to.
I'm going to lunch.
I'll check the charts.
Try and make yourself
useful, huh? Okay.
Good catch this
morning on the aneurysm.
Harper, Carter, give me a hand.
What happened?
She collapsed in the lobby.
Acute shortness of
breath, chest pain.
Pulse is high.
Carter, start her
on an oxygen mask.
Harper, what do we order?
Oh, EKG, chest film,
blood gas, Chem-7,
CBC, cardiac enzymes.
And...?
Myoglobin. Myoglobin.
Do it!
She has neck-vein distension.
Temp's 101.
Susan!
Chief complaint?
Shortness of
breath, chest pains.
She has a history
of renal failure.
What's the differential? Susan?
Harper.
Acute MI, pulmonary embolism,
pneumonia, pericarditis,
congestive heart failure...
Pleural effusion. Pleural
effusion. Stop that!
Do I hear prompting
from the peanut gallery?
Let's get a gas cooking
and get an EKG.
See how her heart's doing.
After you.
Whoo! Hell of a way
to spend your day off.
Yeah. I wish I never
would have come in,
believe me.
Jody O'Brien?
It's the first time
I've looked at that
since the big day.
She had two high
BPs, proteinuria.
I missed the preeclampsia.
If I hadn't, she'd be alive.
It could have happened
to any of us at any day.
Not supposed to happen to
me. Well, you are arrogant.
Arrogant?
It's like there's
you and the Pope.
You guys are infallible.
Then, of course,
there's the rest of us.
Yeah? Well, after today,
the Pope's on his own.
Good.
I think I might
have killed that guy
this morning.
Mark... Hey, Mark.
When I first checked his heart,
I heard a murmur.
He must have had
a congenital defect.
That guy crashed 10
minutes after he got in there.
There's nothing you
could have done about that.
Yes, there is.
I could have gotten an echo,
and then I could have
gotten him straight to the O.R.
You're holding yourself to
a ridiculous standard, Mark.
I've got to get to an autopsy.
It's your day off. Go home.
Low-voltage EKG.
BP's falling.
She's decompensating.
Where's that blood gas?
I'll check. You got it?
These numbers don't make sense.
Uh-oh. What?
Looks like you hit a
vein instead of an artery.
Is that the blood gas?
No. Yeah, but I screwed up.
I tapped a vein
instead of an artery.
No, I screwed up
and tapped a vein.
Well, whoever screwed
up, do it again and do it right.
Carter, you do it.
Non-specific ST changes.
Where are we? Susan.
I don't know where
you are, Kerry,
but I'm at pericardial effusion.
Or pump failure or an embolism.
Let's get an echo!
Positive Ewart's sign.
Pressure's down, 50/30.
Pericardiocentesis tray!
Don't you think you should
confirm your diagnosis
before sticking a
needle in her heart?
I've made my diagnosis.
Alligator clamp
is on the needle.
The diagnostic gold standard
is an echocardiogram.
Fine. You wait while
the tech comes down.
I'll see if there's any fluid
around her heart. Okay.
I'm in.
Anything yet?
Nope. Not yet.
Here it comes.
What do you know?
Looks a little cloudy.
I wonder if it's transudate
or exudate fluid.
Anyone know the gold
standard to differentiate the two?
Kerry?
Measure LDH to protein.
What's the LDH ratio
to identify exudate fluid?
I'd have to look it up.
It's .5 to one.
Greene?
Yeah.
You guys should come
down here more often,
brush up on your gross anatomy.
You guys find
anything conclusive?
Why? What are you looking for?
Something wrong with the heart.
Think you missed something?
Possibly.
Well, you came at
just the right time.
Size and shape, normal.
380 grams.
Okay, who wants to section this?
Bill, I think it's your turn.
Martin, will you
hand him a knife?
Doug, it's been an hour,
and psych still hasn't
come down for that boy.
All right, I'll call them.
Why don't you
talk to him yourself?
Because there's nothing
physically wrong with him,
and I have four other patients.
Is it because the kid's gay?
What?
You heard me.
If you mean, is it because
that boy's particular problems
fall out of my
frame of reference
or my area of expertise,
then the answer is yes.
If you mean, is it
because I'm homophobic,
then the answer is no.
Okay?
No congenital or
valvular anomalies.
Endocardium, normal.
Myocardium, of normal
thickness and color.
Blood vessels at base, normal.
Coronary ostia are in the
usual anatomical position.
Arteries show no sign
of plaque. He's normal.
No sign of anything congenital?
Were you here just a second
ago? What was the cause of death?
Typical ER thinking...
Got to be cause
and effect, right?
Down here, we operate
on a slightly different gestalt.
Sometimes, there are answers,
but many times... mystery.
That's not very satisfying.
Mm. You think
you're a scientist?
You want explanations,
hard answers,
algorithms of care?
That's dog crap.
Medicine's an art,
and art is ambiguous.
All right.
Preliminary results:
Idiopathic dysrhythmia.
No known cause of death.
Nurse?
Hi. How are you feeling?
Oh, tired.
They gave me a
million-dollar work-up
and couldn't find
anything wrong.
I just want to take my
worms and go home.
I have some bad news for you.
Your worms were
mistaken for trash
and put outside in
the snow. Oh, no.
By the time I found out,
they were already frozen solid.
We brought them in,
we tried to warm them with
blankets and warm water.
We used all our capabilities,
but we couldn't get them back.
I'm very sorry.
Can I see them?
What's that?
Vucelich's study protocol.
"Parameters for
exclusionary status."
Are you excluding someone?
Vucelich did.
Anyone I know?
Guy we worked on
today. He went bad.
He ever drop people who do well?
Why are you reading this now?
Has he dropped
someone before this?
Mrs. Rubadoux.
He's... he's not, I mean...
Vucelich wouldn't
drop bad outcomes
just to pretty up his
numbers, would he?
I don't know.
I don't need you trying
to hide my mistakes.
If I screw up, let
me deal with it.
You're right.
Don't lie on my behalf. I won't.
It's insulting. I got it, okay?
I gave you the credit.
What do you want?
What is with you today?
It's this residency thing.
My chances of getting in here
are about one in 50-something.
I don't even have an
interview set up yet.
I'm gonna end up
in North Dakota.
Damn it! What?
I forgot Dr. Benton's
night TPN orders.
None of his post-ops are
getting their IV supplements.
I got to run.
Susan...
One... second.
Yes, Kerry?
According to the
Washington manual,
the determinative
LDH ratio isn't .5 to one.
It's .6.
Oh, you got me again.
If you're going to be Chief,
get your facts straight.
You know what? If
being Chief means
having you breathing
down my back all day long,
to hell with it.
Life's too short.
I don't want you as my
mentor. Just stay out of my way.
That's the first time
I've ever seen you
act like a Chief Resident.
Maybe Morgenstern was right.
Hey, Ray, where are you going?
I was just coming to talk to you.
I was just telling my dad
how good I've been feeling.
It was taking a long time,
and the nurse said the
CAT scan, it was okay?
Yeah, it's normal.
No tumors or, uh...
I hate to tell you
what's been going
through my head.
No, he's fine. Thank God.
Uh... could be migraines?
Uh, yes. It could
also be stress-related,
which is something
that I wanted to talk
to Ray about, if I could just...
I know what it is.
It's that damn trig.
Every time I have
one of those quizzes,
I get these headaches.
You're kidding.
No, I do. Could
that be what this is?
Uh, it could.
Because if that's it, I
know the prescription:
Applying the seat of your
pants to the seat of the chair.
Yeah.
Button your coat.
I'm sorry about this.
I spent the whole damn
day in the waiting room.
It's okay.
Listen, Ray, if you
want to talk about this
or anything else at all,
you just call me here, okay?
Sure.
I thought that she
was still at Beth Israel
doing protein kinase, or
whatever it is she does.
Oh, right, right...
He's on the phone.
Be off in a minute.
No, no. I don't need him anyway.
Look, I just want
to get the records
on one of our patients.
Which one?
Rubadoux, Sylvie.
I believe she was dropped.
Claire, could you come
in here for a second?
I can't find my pocket schedule.
Help yourself.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
My life is unraveling
as we speak.
What jacket did you
wear at the lecture?
Dear Claire, let's be serious.
How could I possibly know
what jacket I was wearing?
Why don't you just
find my schedule
like I asked you to?
Who's that? Who's been
asking? No, no, tell me.
Kemper's been asking?
Well, you can tell Kemper
that I am centimeters away.
With any luck, I'll be in
the New England Journal
next month.
Yes, I'm afraid I'm
going to miss the forum,
so please pass on my regrets.
Tell them I've
checked into McClean
to ride out a fugue state.
21, 22, 23, 24, 25...
Damn, man. Where
did you get all that?
Alvin came through.
No guts, no glory.
You've got to be kidding me.
Life ain't fair.
Are you going to
report that to the IRS?
I assume that's a
rhetorical question.
Well, I'm going to
make my fortune
the old-fashioned, legal way.
Delivering Chinese food?
No. Raising earthworms.
I got a dozen in there.
I thought those
worms froze to death.
Nope, most of them moved
into the middle of the bin
for warmth and survived.
Is that brilliant?
You took that lady's worms.
I did not. She gave me
enough to start my own colony.
It's my ticket out of this dump.
Come on, guys, let's
go home. Good night.
Good night. Bye.
Aah.
Sorry. Didn't mean to scare you.
No, you didn't.
I just finished your
discharge summaries,
I called in your TPN orders,
and I rounded the
patients upstairs.
Can I go home now?
Goodbye, Carter.
I'm sorry about what
happened earlier. Mm-hmm.
Good night.
Carter. Yeah?
Were those TPN
orders called in on time?
Yeah.
No. I screwed up again.
They were 45 minutes late.
I know. I called the pharmacy.
So are we sworn enemies forever?
No.
Denial is a funny thing.
It keeps you from asking
the scary questions.
Which ones?
The ones I've been
asking myself all day today.
Am I dangerous?
Should I be practicing medicine?
We all ask those questions,
and the answers
are "no" and "yes"
in that order.
I hope so.
I lost my family for this job.
You're wallowing.
Yes, I am wallowing.
First good wallow I've had
in a while, so don't ruin it.
Well, I'm going to drive home.
You want a ride?
Nope. I jogged in.
I'm going to jog out.
Hey, you want to
hear something funny?
Definitely.
You know that guy
who died this morning?
It wasn't my fault.
I did everything right,
and he died anyway.
So, what's the lesson in that?
You can't win.
Oh, man. You are wallowing.
Good night.
Susan?
Yeah?
Did anybody think it was
odd my coming in today?
No.
Oh. I was just checking.
Good night.