Doug...
Doug!
He's not here.
I need you to take
a look at little Susie.
I'm not on yet, am I?
You're a pediatrician.
You're always on.
Yes, but I'm not
your pediatrician.
What time is it?
Uh, 6 a.m.
She was up half
the night coughing.
All right.
Hey there, little one.
What's going on?
Let's see.
Seems pretty agreeable.
Well, yeah, that's
because I kept her company
for the last five hours.
Ah...
What's the matter?
I got elbowed
in the Mommy and
Me class yesterday.
Hmm. Sounds vicious.
Oh, yeah, it was.
I had the blue end
of the parachute,
and little Susie was underneath,
and this yuppie mother came by
and yanked it and shoved me.
I'm telling you,
this mother thing is not easy.
Well, you wouldn't
know it by her.
No temperature.
Lungs are clear.
No sore throat.
This is the healthiest,
happiest baby
that I have ever seen.
Oh, God,
I am never going to
make Gymboree tonight.
Doug?
Doug, paramedics
are at the back door
with an infant, unresponsive.
Okay. You need a hand?
Always.
Okay. Oh, bye-bye. Can
you hold her for a sec?
Sure. Thanks.
Hey, little Susie.
Hey...
What do you got?
Two-month-old male
found unconscious
and cyanotic in his crib.
What is it? What's wrong?
He was fine last night.
Unresponsive at scene.
Gave him two rounds of epi
and atropine in the field.
Got nothing.
He just had a
little bit of a cold.
I just took him to our
pediatrician yesterday.
Let's tube him.
Number four uncuffed.
Hook up a compression, will you?
Got it.
Number one,
straight laryngoscope.
I need tape on the tube.
Here you go.
Temperature?
It's 93.
It wasn't a bad cold,
not even a fever.
Deep tendon reflexes absent.
He's unresponsive to pain.
Let's try a high dose epi.
What's he weigh,
about 10 pounds?
12.
Asystole. Okay. 0.5.
Did our doctor miss something?
What's your name?
Mr. and Mrs. what?
Kenway.
Okay, Mr. and Mrs. Kenway,
we need you to wait outside.
What's wrong with him?
Haleh...
I'm Haleh Adams. We need
to let the doctors do their work.
I want to stay with my
baby. Come on, sweetie.
It's okay. I'll be with you.
Anterior fontanel is flat.
Anything on the monitor yet?
No petechiae or ecchymosis.
Another dose of epi?
What's his down
time? 45 minutes.
Any pulse? No.
Pupils fixed and
dilated. Defibrillator?
No rhythm. I'm gonna shock him.
Charging.
Susan...
Susan, it's over.
It's over.
I'll mark the chart.
SIDS?
Lydia, take him off the monitor.
I'll get his parents
back in here.
Will you stay with him?
You got to look at that face.
She was fast
asleep... weren't you?
Thank you, Conni.
You're welcome. Here you go.
Ooh, yeah.
Mm, yeah.
What?
Oh, yeah.
You're my little girl.
Oh, my little girl.
Yeah.
I love you.
Yeah. I love you.
Yeah, I love you.
Yeah.
Hi.
You look awful.
Uh, post-op, two hours sleep.
How's tonight look?
Good, if Benton
ever lets me out.
It's been, like, two days.
It's been, like, over two days.
Well, I have a couple
of hours tonight
between 6 and 8.
Your place?
Mm-hmm... Dr. Wolverton.
Hey...
Come with me.
Where we going?
This way.
Hold the elevator!
Where are the films
on that Spencer kid?
Radiology's backed up.
Oh, damn. Four West again.
Gabriel's calcium back yet?
Normal. It's on his chart.
Neuro's consulting on Weingast.
The films are...?
Yeah, in the reading room.
Next time, leave it bedside.
Uh... This way.
Oh!
I'm sorry.
Hey. Hey!
Hey, I could use some help here.
Now?
No, next Labor Day.
We'll send somebody.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
We'll clean it up.
Later.
When we get back from, uh...
Radiology. Yeah.
Conni?
Oh, hi. Dropped
the lateral decubitus.
Could you hand me those charts?
We came in looking
for the films on...
Smith, John.
They don't appear
to be here, so...
We'll be back. Later.
Close call.
Hey, could you
guys give me a hand?
Uh, sure.
No problem.
Uh, right here okay? Great.
Do you want a bite?
I don't think so, Lydia.
Oh, God, I do. I
missed breakfast.
What's in the boxes?
Something for me?
Mm-mm.
It's for the children's
Christmas drive.
Oh, yeah, there's going to
be one lucky four-year-old
who gets this.
I haven't sorted through it yet.
Is it Secret Santa time already?
Almost, and I arranged
for you to get me,
so make it good.
So my mom sold the house.
Helen's moving?
Yeah, to the burbs.
She's been storing this
stuff in her basement for me
for years.
Now Carol's pawning it off
on some unsuspecting
four-year-old.
No, I'm going
to toss half of it.
You'd never throw
away this stuff.
My mom's the saver, not me.
KC and the Sunshine Band.
Yeah, you can toss that.
Whoa, this...
Aw, come on.
Now, you've never
twirled a baton.
No, I did. I did.
I did.
Something like this.
Okay.
Scalp lac in 3.
Anyone seen Carter?
Nope.
What is it?
You're not a Catholic, are you?
Said goodbye to
the old homestead?
Yup.
Must be hard.
No, not really.
You know, when my
folks sold their place,
I went back there,
and I carved my
name into every closet.
It's just a house.
It's a home, Hathaway.
It's got little height
measurements
on the kitchen door.
It's got a banister
where I fell off,
and I broke my collarbone.
It's got this cool crawl space
where my brothers and I
used to hide our Playboys.
Playboys?
Yeah, when we were kids.
Uh-huh.
So, um, no ID on this patient?
Nope. Nothing.
We found him at the Goodman.
He's been sitting
there for a while.
Yo, Shepherd.
You gotta move your rig.
I need someone to cover a shift.
Not tonight. I'm sorry.
Bet she'd take a rain check.
Sorry, buddy,
this is something I can't move.
Hit-and-run's here!
Need a hand with this one?
Yeah.
What's open?
Trauma 1.
Doris...
35-year-old male,
auto versus pedestrian.
BP 110/65. Pulse tachy at
120, possible mandible fracture.
500 cc bolus, normal
saline, O-2, 10 liters,
and hare traction
on the left leg.
On my count.
One, two, three.
Back to the slopes. See you.
What's his name?
Ethan Brown.
Mr. Brown, you're in the ER.
You were hit by a car.
Let's get a cross-table C-spine.
Chest. Pelvis, left
femur, mandible.
CBC, type and cross
four units, Chem 7.
My wife!
Try not to talk, Mr. Brown.
Your jaw might be broken.
We'll contact your wife.
I'll get a Foley in.
Pressure's good. 125/80.
Midshaft fractured femur.
Good distal pulses.
Abdomen's benign.
Droperidol, 2.5, slow IV push,
and let's watch his pressure.
What happened? Someone
ran him down. Hit-and-run.
Interviewing witnesses now.
No! No!
TMs are clear.
No Battles Sign.
All right. Clear CT.
No, no, no, Mr. Brown...
You've gotta leave the mask on.
Okay, calm down. Calm down.
Hi. I'm Carol.
What's your name?
Why do you ask that?
Just curious.
Mr. Sullivan.
Can't smoke in
here, Mr. Sullivan.
Suture kit.
Thanks. Can you hang out?
I'm not sure he's
gonna need any.
Can you hand me that saline?
May I borrow a pencil, please?
Why is your arm
bleeding, Mr. Sullivan?
I work for the, uh...
I work for the committee.
I'm a... I'm an architect.
This is a... this is,
uh... This is a pen.
Here you go. How's this?
Is there someone we
can call to take you home?
Why do you... Why do you ask?
I mean, I know where it is.
Okay. No, he's not
going to need any stitches,
but let's call psych
and social services.
Get Matthews to supervise...
Matthews has got the interview
for Vucelich's
research project...
Then get Jones to do it...
Jones, Lieberman, Sheets,
they all got interviews.
They're wasting their time.
Vucelich is never going
to pick a third-year...
You ought to apply.
It'd be great for your
career, your resume.
Yeah, not to mention yours.
You have a hematoma
on your neck.
What do we have?
Hit-and-run, moderate velocity.
Left femur fracture,
head trauma.
What is he on?
Droperidol for agitation.
We couldn't control him.
Got Mr. Brown's films.
There's a shadow
in the right base.
Carter, hemothorax!
Pulse up, 120.
I'll set up a Thora-Seal.
O-2 sats falling.
Number 32 French.
Hey, I know.
I know.
Curved Kelly.
I'm in.
Anyone call CT?
Yeah. They're ready for him.
Suction.
It's draining.
His real name is Joshua Shem.
He's a diagnosed
paranoid schizophrenic.
Ran away from his
residential home.
They faxed us this.
Prolixin, Thorazine,
Trilafon, even Clozaril...
Won't stay on any of them.
This is the third
time he's run away?
Yeah. They said they
won't take him back again.
Three strikes, and
you're out, huh?
Any family? His mother.
I'm still trying to
track her down.
Okay. Thanks, Jeanie.
Hey, Randi, could
you find me the number
to Campanelli's, please?
You don't wanna
go there, Dr. Ross.
Excuse me?
Drafty, stuffy,
and the pasta's kind of iffy.
Anyone we know?
What's this?
You told Mark you
couldn't work tonight.
Personal obligation.
We got failure to fly in 3.
A kid fell off his bunk bed.
You care to join me?
Okay.
Ethan! My God!
Ma'am...
Is he hurt?
Is he going to die?
No, he's not going to
die, but you really can't...
You can't go with him. Ma'am!
I'm his wife!
Mrs. Brown,
your husband has been
in a serious accident.
We're taking him
up for a head CT,
but his injuries do not appear
to be life-threatening.
Then he's not gonna die?
No, I think he's
going to be fine.
Come with me, I'll show you.
Oh, my God!
My sister, she's unconscious!
What happened?
She had a skating accident.
They took care of
her at St. Anne's,
sent her home,
but in the car,
she started shaking all over.
Sounds like a seizure.
What's her name?
Reba.
I couldn't wake her up.
Reba?
Reba, can you hear me?
She's postictal.
Let's start a line.
15 liters O-2 by mask.
Does she have a
history of seizures?
No. We were at the
skating rink, practicing,
and a boy ran into her.
Her legs were
cut up pretty badly.
Pupils equal, round, reactive.
Did she hit her head?
I think so. She had a headache.
Were any X-rays taken?
I don't know. They...
They stitched up her legs.
Responsive to pain.
BP 120/70. Pulse 56.
We need a head CT.
What's going on?
Your sister had a seizure,
which can happen
after a head injury.
We're going to take
an X-ray of her brain,
make sure there's
no bleeding, okay?
Okay.
A small, gold
pendant would be nice.
Earrings, Ford Explorer.
Thank you, Lydia.
I'll keep those in mind.
How serious?
Seizure following head trauma.
They saw her at St. Anne's.
Barkley's the chief over there.
You want me to call
him... Don't bother.
They didn't even do a CT.
Hey, doctor. We wrapped up
that hit-and-run. That quick?
Witness ID'd the plates,
and get this, it was his wife.
Come on.
Lydia? Lydia,
where's Brown? Who?
Ethan Brown, the guy
who got hit by a car.
Oh, Exam 4.
Call Security.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Die! You bastard!
I hate you! I'm gonna kill you!
Get her out of here!
Cyanotic. Pulse ox's down to 70.
Hyperventilate him. Blood gas?
What was that about?
Marital bliss.
After dinner, power
Christmas shopping.
Everything for everyone
in under three hours.
Actually, you could come.
Shop for Jennifer and Rachel.
Nah, Rachel's getting a bike.
Jennifer already
has her present.
I agreed to spend four...
Count them... four wintery days
with her folks in Sheboygan.
Four days with the Reverend?
Yeah.
Go with God.
How's she doing?
She's coming around.
Hi, Reba. I'm Dr. Lewis.
Do you know where you are?
Mm...
Hospital?
Do you remember what happened?
No.
It's normal to be
confused after a seizure.
We want to keep her
in the hospital for...
Uh-oh.
Valium, five.
What's happening?
Pulse ox 85.
Put her back on the mask.
Oh, my God. Help her, please!
Doctor... Dr. Vucelich.
Uh, Carter, John Carter.
Ah, Carter, yes.
I'm going to see your
Dr. Matthews at 5, right?
Well, no. Actually,
I'm Dr. Benton's student.
Well, in that case,
I guess look forward
to seeing him later, then.
Well, no, actually, uh,
he's not signed up.
I know he wanted to be,
but I believe
your list was full.
Carter, you don't
have to cover for him.
I mean, if the man
isn't interested...
No, no, no, no. He's interested.
He's definitely
interested, um...
Well, to be honest,
I forgot to sign him up.
Aha.
And he was pretty
upset about it.
I see. Well, I guess I'm going
to have to cover for you, then.
Why don't you send him in at 6?
I think it's a hickey
you have on your neck, Carter.
Yeah. Yeah.
That makes 20 of Valium.
How long has she been seizing?
10 minutes.
Let's load her with Dilantin.
900 milligrams at 50 a minute.
She's probably
tearing her sutures out.
Is she on any drugs?
No.
Diabetic?
Is she allergic to lidocaine?
Lidocaine?
Yeah, it's like Novocain.
They would have given it
to her before the sutures.
I don't know.
They were injecting
her with a lot of stuff.
Hold the Dilantin!
800 phenobarb.
Could be lidocaine
toxicity. Get a level.
100 in.
Conni, I want you to get a hold
of a Dr. Barkley at St. Anne's
and have him fax
her chart over ASAP.
I know I gave you
nights off this week...
Yes, thank you.
Yes, well...
Not that it did any good.
Hudson pleaded with
me to cover for him.
So I guess you couldn't
cover for Bowers, then?
I'm good, Mark,
but not that good.
Reba Siburry's seizures.
St. Anne's gave her a
toxic dose of lidocaine?
Her level was nine.
Missed all the fun.
This would make a
terrific case report.
You know, Morgenstern's dying
to have somebody present a paper
at the SAEM conference.
I could use the credit.
The hospital pays for the trip.
Trip?
It's in Miami.
Sounds like a
terrific opportunity.
I can't write and
present a paper.
Sure you can. And
take care of Susie?
I thought your dad was
going to help pick up the slack.
Yeah, but I still
barely have time
to get dressed in the morning.
Well, I can help you
with your schedule here.
Yeah, thanks, that's great,
but I can't spend my days off
in the med library
doing research.
And a trip?
Okay.
Are you disappointed?
Of course not.
Do you think I should do it?
Susan, it's your decision.
Do your voices tell
you to harm yourself?
Harm anyone else?
Voices, voices, voices...
I don't... I don't...
I don't hear, uh,
you know, voices.
Do you want to
stay in the hospital?
I'm not, uh... crazy,
or, you know, whatever...
What you think.
No, no, but you might
want to try new medicines
with fewer side-effects...
Thank you, no.
I have... I have...
I have work to...
May I?
Here, Josh.
How are you going to eat, Josh?
The Colonel makes me chicken.
And sleep?
I'm, um... I'm
building a... a house.
It's cold outside.
Look, I... I know! I
have a... I have a jacket.
I know, um,
how... how to
take care of myself.
I am... I am a...
I am a man to...
Okay.
Josh, it was nice
meeting you. Okay?
Come on, let's go.
Can you hold him? Nope.
Not even for a day?
I've got calls in to
some halfway houses.
I'm sure I can place him.
He's in no imminent danger,
to himself or anyone else.
There's nothing I can do.
You think he can take
care of himself on the street?
He claims he can.
And you're gonna
take his word for it.
I didn't write the law.
He's an adult. If he
wants to go, he goes.
Guess Joshua
is off his checklist
for the day.
No, he's a good guy.
He must get 30
cases like this a month.
He does what he can.
So what do we do?
Well, we try and stall him.
Hope that a home comes
through, wait for the mother to show.
I got Benton that
interview at 6.
It's, what, like 15 minutes
to your house, right?
So that gives us an hour
and 20 minutes, tops,
before study group,
which is nothing.
Look what you did to my neck.
You are an incurable romantic.
Only one problem, though.
Carter!
Oh, man.
I haven't told him yet.
See you later.
Hey...
Got a patient for you.
Great.
Hey, I was wondering, do
you have plans this evening?
Reason I'm asking is because
I bumped into
Dr. Vucelich earlier...
And?
And... What? Nothing.
You sign me up? No, not really.
You better not have.
Well, see, the thing
is, he requested you.
He thinks you're gonna
be great for this study,
and he wants to
talk to you about it
in his office at
6 tonight, today.
Do a 2 percent block,
irrigate, pull the nail,
no stitches.
Okay.
Hi, Josh.
I... I have... I have to go.
But we're not finished yet.
What?
Hey, Josh... This
is really good.
I just draw what they tell me.
I have to go, uh... home.
I have to... I have to...
Where is your home?
Oh, I just bought one.
Oh. Where?
Wicker Park, on Hoyne Street.
Yeah, Jugendstil. Proto-Modern.
I guess. Maybe.
It's nice. Very solid.
Turn of the century.
Living room, fireplace.
Copper inlay. Tile.
No fireplace.
Just plaster walls.
No. Go behind.
It's... It's there.
You'll see that it's there.
Thanks. I didn't know
I bought a Jugen...
Joogen... thing.
Stop it, stop it,
stop it, stop it.
Hey, Josh, are you hungry?
I...
You should eat something.
I'll let you keep the pencil.
Okay?
Okay.
Your psych patient's still here.
Uh-huh.
Consult been down?
Yup.
Not admitted?
Nope.
Why hasn't he been discharged?
I'd like to put a
sterile dressing
on his abrasion,
and maybe put some
antibiotic ointment.
As long as we have a bed,
let's get him fed, cleaned up.
Good idea.
Okay, 7:00?
You look beautiful
whatever you wear.
I love you too. Bye.
Your personal obligation?
ER.
Hang on.
Dr. Greene?
It's for you.
Hillsborough Community Hospital.
Where's that?
Uh... Milwaukee.
Hello.
What happened?
Oh, God.
Is she all right?
Ra... Rachel, my daughter?
Yeah. Of course.
I'll be there as soon as I can.
Mark?
Jen and Rachel.
They're at a hospital.
I gotta catch a train.
What happened?
Car accident.
Is Rachel okay?
It's only Jen.
No, take my car.
Thanks.
Yeah.
Greene. Jennifer Greene.
Any news?
No, they won't tell me anything.
Yeah.
Okay. Thank you.
Are we this bad
when people call?
No, I give them a bucketful
of complete and
accurate information.
Anybody know anyone over there?
I used to date one
of their O.R. techs.
Oh...
I haven't talked
to him in six years.
Dial.
Hey, that's cool.
It is, isn't it?
A patient gave it to me.
What's a patient doing
drawing you a Sullivan Arch?
Sullivan? Joshua
calls himself Sullivan.
Yeah. Louis, Lewis.
Something like that.
It's over at the Art Institute.
He says it's his home.
Unfortunately, it's
about to be true.
Oh, Shep, no, give me that back.
Oh, no. Come on.
No, Shep, please.
Is that you?
Oh, come on.
Oh, come on, you
were cute! Shep!
No, stop, stop, stop.
Come on, give it back!
"To the coolest
girl in the class."
Okay, very funny.
"I'll never forget
"what you did for me
last summer at the lake.
Love, P.J."
Oh, yeah?
What did you do that
made him so grateful?
It's a "her," not a "him."
I was calming her down
because she broke
up with her boy...
You know, I don't need
to be telling you any of this.
This is great. This is trash.
No, this is going home.
You're gonna thank me one day.
This is good stuff.
Food poisoning in 4.
Oh, and Morgenstern
wants to see you.
Uh-oh.
No, it's good news.
About presenting
the lidocaine toxicity.
Mark told Morgenstern
about that case?
No, I did. He was very excited.
This is a great opportunity.
Finally got rid of
that migraine in 5.
Oh, good.
Food poisoning in 4.
Psst!
I think I can make that
window of opportunity.
My place at 6?
You got it.
Carter, Harper...
I need to pull the
drains on some post-ops.
Well, you've got
your interview at 6:00.
Which is why you're gonna do it.
Harper, scalp lac
in the Suture Room.
I have food poisoning in 4.
Well, after the
food poisoning in 4.
That's great.
Shem, Joshua. He's 28.
Diagnosed schizophrenic.
You've gotta be
kidding. Six months?
No, I checked there too.
They don't have any beds.
Okay.
Yeah, I'll try Carnegie House.
Okay, thanks. Bye.
Doctor...
I see you found all my patients,
and they're all grateful
to still be with us.
Endarterectomies?
Thanks, Claire.
Why don't you tell my wife
I'll meet her at the restaurant.
Mm-hmm.
You wouldn't believe
the Christmas presents.
Yeah, must be hundreds.
At least.
Why don't you come
with me, Benton?
I think you're going
to find this interesting.
What about the interview?
This is it.
Excuse me.
I'm Madeline Shem,
Joshua's mother.
Oh, hi. I'm Carol Hathaway.
I'm glad you came.
Was he hurt?
No, just a small
abrasion on his arm.
We spoke to the
residential home.
But they won't take him back. I
know. He's run away so much.
We've had no luck
getting him into another.
Took us nine months
to get him into that one.
Well, could you take him home?
Oh, I wish.
Joshua's let go of everything,
his past, his family, our home.
None of it means
anything to him anymore.
He'd never stay.
Hard to believe
he was gonna be an architect.
Had a breakdown in college.
Hi, Josh.
I brought you pencils,
sharpened just the way you like.
Thanks. Thanks very much.
We've been waiting
for these to arrive.
I, uh...
I give him money, which
makes me feel better,
and his pencils, which
makes him feel better.
That's really the only thing
he still cares about.
Still...
I love you, Josh.
Radial and ulnar
pulses are strong.
He's gonna need a tetanus.
Yeah, and let's give him
five of morphine, slow IV push.
Give me the bullet.
Impaled foreign body.
Fell off a ladder onto a
Christmas reindeer display.
They're gonna fire me.
Through and
through left deltoid.
Distal neuro and
vascular intact.
I crushed Rudolph.
Darned expensive,
those displays.
Your last meal?
Breakfast.
No, no...
I don't know.
Can you feel this?
Yeah, yeah.
BP's 140/85. Pulse 110.
O.R. been notified? This?
It's killing me.
O.R.'s ready.
Gram of Ancef.
Spectacular case earlier, Susan.
It's a shoo-in for presentation
at the SAEM conference.
Might even make
it into the annals.
Uh-huh.
Doctors forget that a
seemingly benign anesthetic
has the potential
for cardiac
and neurological toxicity.
Okay, let's get this
puppy up to the O.R.
I presented at the conference
when I was a resident.
Terrific case,
terrific opportunity.
I left the visual
aids on the plane.
Well, I have to decline
your offer, Dr. Morgenstern.
Personal reasons.
You do realize, don't you,
you're a candidate for
Chief Resident next year?
I know that I need to start
presenting and publishing,
but it's just that now's
not a very good time.
There's never a good time.
I'd just hate to
see the personal
overwhelm the job.
I'm not overwhelmed,
Dr. Morgenstern,
and I'm doing my job.
Yes, but to build a career,
you've got to take
on more responsibility.
I've taken on plenty
of responsibility,
so you'll have to forgive me
if I don't stay after
school these days
to work for extra credit.
Where's Emergency?
My wife and daughter
were in an accident.
Where's Emergency?
Oh, over there.
Where's the ER?
This is the ER.
Jennifer and Rachel Greene?
Sorry?
I'm Mark Greene. I'm
an Emergency physician.
My wife and daughter
have been in an accident.
Just sent up to the O.R.
What floor?
Second. Take the
stairs. It's faster.
Jen, Jen!
Jen, I'm here.
I'm okay, Mark.
Rachel's okay.
Where is Rachel?
Where's my daughter?
Probably in the waiting area.
She's okay.
I wanna stay with my wife.
You can't right now.
I'm a doctor.
I'm Dr. Shreiger.
What are you, a Resident? Yes.
I'll be working
under Dr. Musgrave.
You can't be in
here, Dr. Greene.
I'd like to talk
to the Attending.
Your wife suffered
multiple injuries
when she was broadsided.
She's stable,
but she's got a compound
right tib-fib fracture.
The films?
Abdominal CT showed a
small amount of free blood,
so we're gonna do an
exploratory laparotomy,
and we'll have an orthopod in
to fix the fracture.
You should have a
seat in the waiting room.
Dr. Musgrave will find
you when we're through.
Susan, this came for you.
I had to sign for it.
Ooh, secret admirer?
Uh... No.
Is it from Chloe?
The one and only.
Might as well open it.
These are $100 bills.
There's, like, 20 of them.
30 of them, she says.
$3000?
Are they marked and sequential?
What did she write?
You read it.
"Ho, ho, ho, little Susie.
Aren't you surprised
your mommy is so rich?
Give this green
stuff to Aunt Susie
for helping out
and doing so much for you.
Do you remember me?
Loves and kisses,
your crazy mom."
I think she's trying
to pay her debt.
She must have been stoned.
Ah, it's a holiday
thing, you know.
Brings out the ghost
of many a deadbeat relative.
I come from a long line of them.
I don't want her money.
My advice?
You take what you can get
and do not expect more.
Hey. Hi.
Daddy! Daddy!
Hi. How are you, baby?
You all right? Hmm?
This is Craig, Daddy.
Uh, Craig Simon.
This is my daughter, Amanda.
We were all in the
accident together.
Oh, hello.
Hi. We've spoken
on the phone before.
Oh, right. The appeals court.
Right.
The kids are fine.
Jennifer's got a
bad break to her leg.
It's a...
Compound fracture,
yeah. Talked to the doctor.
Right.
Uh, we were going to
a staff Christmas party.
A guy came out of nowhere.
Yeah, she's a terrible driver.
But I was driving.
Our car was squished, Daddy.
Mm...
Your head's all right?
Yeah. It's nothing.
I want to make sure that
Jennifer's going to be okay.
If it's all right with you,
I think we'll stick
around for a while.
Sure.
Randi...
Randi!
It's going to be pretty hard
for people to see through that.
They can walk around.
Okay, I'm getting out of here.
If you hear anything about
Mark, will you call my machine?
Sure.
Bad news for Joshua.
St. Joe's, Lacey Street,
Carnegie House...
All the residential
homes have a wait list
of about 600 years.
Yeah, well, it's
too late, anyway.
He left an hour ago.
He's too sick to be out there.
He's not sick enough
to stay in here.
Maybe I'm not cut out for this.
In rehab, I work with a patient,
I feel like I'm giving
them something.
We give them something.
We give them a Band-Aid
and send them back to the front.
Treat 'em and street 'em.
We do the best we can.
And when that's not good enough?
Most days, it has to be.
So you're familiar
with endarterectomy
for the prevention of stroke.
I've done some reading.
And you also know
that symptomatic patients
with stenotic lesions
do better with surgery
than with medical care alone.
Not all studies agree.
True.
When do doctors ever agree?
I assume you're familiar
with the CASANOVA trials.
Carotid artery stenosis
with asymptomatic narrowing,
operation versus aspirin.
Right.
And what did they find?
No benefit from endarterectomy.
Well, I'm about to
prove them wrong.
I really wasn't planning
on hiring third
years for my studies.
They don't have the skills.
I've got the skills.
Really?
Mm...
You're arrogant as hell.
I like that.
Let's see those skills, doctor.
Scrub in.
Jennifer Greene?
Hi. I'm her husband,
Dr. Mark Greene.
Doctor...
I'm Dr. Musgrave.
Everything went well.
Thank God.
I took a look at the spleen.
No rupture, no lacerations.
Ortho did an open reduction
and internal fixation
of the midshaft
comminuted fracture
of the right tib-fib.
No complications.
You can see her soon.
How long do the
screws gonna stay in?
About six months.
You can hold onto it.
It's a copy.
Thank you.
Do you wanna translate for me?
Hey...
Oh!
How are you?
Let me look at you.
Still ugly as sin.
Let's get a drink.
So what about this fancy dinner?
Something wrong?
Can't I just take you
to a nice restaurant?
I would have been happy
to throw something
together at home.
Mom, just let me do this, okay?
Well, suit yourself.
Thank you.
Um, what do you want?
Champagne cocktail.
Moet, please.
I'll have a Manhattan,
straight up. Thanks.
So how's my famous son doing?
Well, I'm still fixing
kids for a living.
How's Howard?
I never see him.
Year-end tax deadline.
I'm a CPA widow.
What can I say?
Have you heard from anyone?
Besides the Tribune
calling about you?
Anyone else?
What's up, Douglas?
Nothing is up.
Now, don't even start.
I know you.
Dad called.
What does he want?
He saw me on TV,
and he just wanted
to touch base.
So what did you say?
I told him to... get lost.
He wants money.
He's not going to
get any money, so...
Does he think
he can just waltz
right into our lives
any damn time he wants to?
I didn't tell you
this to upset you.
He's up to something, Doug.
Just forget about him.
Hey... He can't touch us...
ever again.
Hi, Josh.
How are you doing?
Why do you ask that?
It's beautiful.
Mm...
They destroyed this
in 1970... something.
We're going to go
and rebuild and...
Josh, look. You forgot these.
Thank you very much.
We've been, uh...
we've been expecting these.
Is there anything else you need?
We can... We can
always use, uh...
If you have pencils...
Here, Josh.
Try and stay warm, okay?
What did she say?
She said, "Okay,
hon. Let's go home."
Ah, the beauty of codependency.
Hey...
Jeanie and I are just
drowning our bad day.
Over root beer.
Ah...
How was surgery?
Slow. I held a clamp.
Sorry about tonight.
Did you guys have a date?
A date?
During med school?
What, are you kidding?
How many more years?
Counting the Air Force?
Air Force?
She felt like she needed
a little more direction
in her life.
Did a lot of drugs as a kid.
Didn't do well in high school.
15th in a class of 2,000.
Could have done better.
Um, in college, I
knew I wanted more.
To be a fighter pilot.
And a doctor, so one semester...
This really good-looking
recruiter comes by...
And I signed up.
You have been listening.
Yeah, I've been listening.
They're paying for med school,
and after residency, I give
them four years of service
Wow. My husband thought
I was an overachiever.
Mm. She hasn't even
gotten to the astronaut part.
Sorry! Ride's over.
I forgot my soap.
Oh, hi, Mrs. Bassett.
Oh, your baby's getting so big.
Oh. Well, actually, she's...
Oh, and beautiful,
just like your mama.
Thank you.
She's really cute.
Yes, you are.
Good night.
Hmm.
I used to love this.
Last night as I got home...
Well, there better not be
anybody behind this wall!
Ah!
Watch out, watch out.
A fireplace?
It's beautiful.
How did you know about this?
I met an architect today.
He knew about my house.
An architect?
Dance with me.
To this?
Oh, you don't know how.
Oh...
Okay.
Now you've gone too far.
...And it's times
like this I feel
You've always
Been close to me
Was I wrong to work nights
To try to build a good life?
All work and no play
Has just cost me my wife
So take a letter, Maria
Address it to my wife...
Hi, baby.
Mm.
Mark.
I spoke with the doctor.
Everything went really well.
Rachel?
She's fine.
In the waiting room.
Is Craig still here?
Yeah. He is.
Oh, Mark.
Oh, I know.
We don't have to talk now.
When you come home.
I didn't want to tell
you before Christmas.
I know.
I know, Jen.
You fell in love with him?
I didn't mean to.