- Are you following me now?
- You wouldn't call me.
- I didn't know you were here.
- For now.
- Working for Charlotte.
And sleeping with my best friend.
You should knock before you walk
into a doctor's office. It was funny.
Twice I come to town,
twice you walk in on me.
- I have a patient.
- I know.
Jane Williams,
30 years old, 33 weeks pregnant.
Ambulance brought her in,
she had a stroke.
- How...?
- Good, you're both here.
You met my new neurologist. Your patient
has neurological problems. I called him.
Okay, Tim,
can you tell me what happened?
She was eating breakfast,
and we were arguing.
Suddenly, her orange juice drops,
it falls out of her hand,
and there's orange juice everywhere,
and Jane can't speak.
- Baby's heartbeat is normal.
- Jane, I'm Dr. Montgomery.
Can you understand what I'm saying?
Are you in any pain?
[SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
Jane. It's okay. If you understand
what he's saying, nod your head.
Okay, just try to relax.
We're here to help you.
When did this happen,
the orange juice and the not talking?
An hour ago? Maybe longer?
I need you to be as exact as possible.
It's important.
- An hour and 20 minutes ago.
- Good. Good, then we still have time.
She didn't have a stroke,
she's having one right now.
And if I can stop it
in the next hour and 40 minutes,
there's a good chance I can prevent
- any permanent brain damage.
- And what about the baby?
If you treat Jane,
what happens to the baby?
Okay.
Did the fight cause this?
Strokes can just happen,
often without warning.
There are no predictors.
- You two...?
- The divorce has been ugly.
She hates that this baby
keeps me in her life.
That was the last thing she said
right before she...
She wished that she wasn't pregnant.
So she'd never have to see me again.
Good news.
There's no evidence of a bleed,
which means I can perform
an endovascular clot evacuation.
Excuse me just a minute.
I don't want you fishing around
inside her brain.
- You should use TPA to bust the clots.
- It's contraindicated in pregnancy.
No, it's not. Not in the studies I've read.
And I'm the ob-gyn.
Oh, I know. Double-board certified.
- Stop. Archie.
- Archie? I guess you are mad.
TPA is rolling the dice.
The procedure is something I can control.
And if Jane's life were at risk,
it might make sense.
But this stroke isn't gonna kill her
or the baby. What you're proposing could.
- What about her quality of life?
- The baby is 33 weeks.
Its lungs aren't fully developed.
It needs more time, TPA offers that.
I'm a good neurologist, Addy. Some might
say I'm a great one. You used to say it.
We have a little over an hour
to stop this stroke.
And I am telling you
that we can save both of them.
VIOLET: You got it?
- Yeah, one sticky bun
from Damn Those Doughnuts,
one bagel with onions from Canters,
a fruit bowl, and a maraschino frappe
from the Juice Collective.
VIOLET: Where's my coffee?
- You can't have coffee, Violet.
VIOLET:
I'm not giving up coffee.
- Maraschino?
- They were out of pomegranate.
- Oh, my God. Did you get two?
- No.
No, no, no. That's for Charlotte.
Oh, an apple fritter makes up
for you refusing her marriage proposal?
I didn't turn it down.
I delayed on your advice.
And speaking of advice,
pregnancy cravings
are not a license to eat poorly.
It's not a pregnancy craving.
I'm just hungry.
Page 156.
Read all about cravings,
which is what you are having.
Page 336.
People who are not pregnant should
butt out, which by the way, means you.
I couldn't find the page
I was looking for,
the one that says it's important for you
to tell the father that you are pregnant.
I don't know
if either of them wants kids.
- I don't know if I want kids.
- You think it's time you found out?
- You have to tell someone, Violet.
- I did. I told you.
SAM: Everything okay?
NAOMl: Uh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah. No.
- No, no, no.
- What's wrong?
- I don't think I can talk about this.
- What?
- Nai, you can talk to me about anything.
- It involves another man.
Mm. Uh...
Shoot.
Okay. Um...
Addison caught me and Archer
having sex in his new office,
which is on the 4th floor
of Pacific Wellcare.
Sam, are you...?
Okay.
- Okay.
- Okay, so you need to...
- You need to give me advice.
- Right, right. Okay.
So, uh, are you worried
about Addison finding out
that you are sleeping with her brother,
or are you worried
about everybody finding out
that you kept
Archer getting a job downstairs a secret?
Oh, both.
But, um, really, I'm worried
that she's gonna guilt him
into not having sex with me again.
Because the sex is really good.
Sam, you...
- Are you okay?
- Yeah. No. I have a girlfriend. I'm good.
- Yeah, how's it going with Sonya?
- Wow. Really, really...
It's incredibly, sh...
- She's making me wait.
- Oh.
- We're waiting. Until she's ready.
- But she's ready now, so...
- Oh.
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Take your inhaler.
Nai, I'm not a virgin anymore.
- All right. All right.
- Okay.
I never thought we'd get here.
We're friends.
Yeah, we got here.
Friends.
Yeah.
[ELEVATOR DINGS]
Uh, hi, can I help you?
Yeah. Is Dr. Wilder in?
I have an appointment.
No, he's actually running a little bit late.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Wow, I must look pretty crappy, huh?
No, I just had a rough morning,
you know? One of those mornings.
But is Pete gonna be here soon?
Why don't I show you to his office?
He'd be here any second.
- Oh, great.
DELL: Okay.
When I got the call
about Terri's accident,
I was so stunned.
She was so...
So excited when she found out
she was pregnant.
She and Mark didn't think
it was ever gonna happen,
- but you made them believe.
- I'm so, so sorry about what's happened.
You know, it's just one stupid guy
who drinks and drives,
and my whole family's gone.
I came here today because Terri and Mark
died without a will.
The extra embryos they had left over,
um, the ones you have frozen?
- Yeah.
- They've been left to me.
Oh, were you interested
in donating them?
No, no. I, um...
I'd like them.
For myself.
I want to have a baby.
My daughter's baby.
Hi, Keith. Dell said that...
Dell! Get me a two mgs of narcan
and call an ambulance.
Keith. Can you hear me?
Keith. Hey. Hey! Keith!
Hey. They're calling 911.
Here. Here, is there anything I can do?
Damn it! Keith.
SAM: How long's he been using?
- He came to me for help with stress.
He's a real estate agent.
He lives and dies by the market.
Last year, the market crashed,
addiction took over.
The guy's a total mess.
He lost his job, his wife. He's got Hep C.
- Trifecta.
PETE: I've been treating him for free,
but I think the real reason he comes
is because I give him clean needles.
You started
a needle exchange program?
Sam, I know this guy.
He should not die in the streets.
Right now,
this is the only way I can help.
[COUGHING]
What the...? How did l...?
- I found you on the floor. You OD'd.
- Oh, I feel like crap.
You feel bad, but we got you breathing.
We've got an ambulance coming.
KEITH: Oh, my head. It hurts.
- Easy, just relax.
- Why don't you lay back down?
KEITH: No.
What, are you trying to kill me?
Nobody's trying to hurt you.
We're just trying to help. Keith...
KEITH:
Get off!
You all right?
They seem like a nice couple.
They're divorced.
And they barely speak.
Well, I guess they spoke
long enough to conceive.
Speaking of not speaking, are we gonna
have a fight about Naomi again?
- You think I'm mad about Naomi?
- Good, you're not mad.
This is you, not mad.
Like the time I loaned your sweater
to Crystal McCullough.
She puked on it. She puked up
strawberry daiquiri all over my sweater.
But you weren't mad.
I wasn't mad that you loaned it,
I was mad that you lied.
And I'm not mad about Naomi.
I'm mad that you took a job
with a practice that is trying to bury me.
You knew,
and you didn't have the guts to tell me.
Wyatt left chasing some
ridiculous amount of pharmaceutical cash.
So Charlotte needed a big name,
who better but me?
Why are you here, Archer?
There were some things
I wanted to get away from.
Like? Stalker ex-girlfriend?
Publisher who knew where you lived?
There's always something.
After the way we left things,
I wanted to try again, make it better.
Like, let's do this case.
See how much you enjoy working with me.
- So long as we do it your way?
- Well, that would help.
It's the right way, Addy.
NAOMl:
I'm just concerned.
Look, I know I'm a 52-year-old litigator
and not a 19-year-old cheerleader,
but, um, my gynecologist started me
on hormone therapy
- and he thinks I'm ready for implantation.
- Yeah, but it's not just age.
The stress of losing your daughter?
That takes its physical toll
and doesn't exactly make you
an ideal candidate for IVF.
Terri wanted to bring a baby
into this world more than anything.
And I can do that.
I can bring her baby into the world.
Well, your gynecologist was right.
You are certainly ready.
But having your own grandchild?
You're still grieving, Sharon.
This isn't about grief.
This is about honoring my daughter.
I've never seen Keith that bad.
You have to call the police
and let them handle it.
- I know how you feel about addicts, Dell...
DELL: I'm not being punitive.
I'm not mad. The guy needs help.
You tried, and it's not working.
And at least in jail,
he'll have to go cold turkey.
- Jail isn't the answer for him.
- I don't know. I think Dell's right.
- Thank you.
- Keith needs to be in a program.
I've talked to him before. I know he has it
in him to get clean with the right help.
You think
you can get through to this guy?
I think I should try.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
ADDISON: Jane, I know that you wanna
talk to us, and I know that you're scared,
but all these people, all this equipment,
is to help you get better.
ARCHER: I'm gonna give you
some sedative to keep you comfortable,
But I need for you to be awake
so that we can test things as we go, okay?
I need you to trust me.
My sister trusts me. So can you.
ADDISON: Your baby is doing great.
ARCHER: Stay with me, Jane. Okay?
We're gonna get you through this.
I brought you a peace offering.
Your favorite: Fritters, warm apple.
Deep fried
for your southern taste buds.
We have breakfast here, Cooper.
Well, maybe you can skip breakfast here,
and we can...
Look, I understand you're angry.
But you can't not talk to me.
I'm sorry I said no about the marriage,
but I did tell you I wanted
to spend the rest of my life with you.
Can you tell me what I did wrong
that's so unforgivable?
If you really don't get it, I can't help you.
- Well, we have to talk about this.
- No. We don't. And we won't.
Save the rest of your earnest little "I can
make it all better" act and leave, okay?
It's good, isn't it?
See, this is fortuitous, finding you here.
We need to talk,
and you've been avoiding.
Avoidance isn't good for anyone, Violet.
I'm not avoiding you, Sheldon.
I've been very busy,
and I have a patient waiting.
- Hey, Cooper, you going back up?
- Oh, good, you guys are talking.
- At least someone's talking.
- In fact we're not talking.
VIOLET: We're talking, Sheldon.
I love talking to you.
- I love spending time with you. I'm just...
- Busy. I know.
COOPER:
Cute kids.
Over there, Sheldon.
- Ah. Don't you think?
- I guess. In small doses.
I'm not really a kid person.
They don't seem to like me.
- So you don't have kids of your own?
- No. God, no. Thankfully.
You must see them in your practice?
I bet you're great with them.
You know what I find?
I'm okay with kids.
In short bursts. Beyond that...
Well, it's not a problem, is it?
- You miserable or starving?
- Both.
- Anything you wanna talk about?
- This is doing the trick.
- Terri Hughes' mother came in today.
- Why?
We have Terri and Mark's embryos in our
freezer. And she wants them implanted.
In her.
- I don't know what to do.
- I do. Say no.
Well, I know there are issues
with her carrying her own grandchild,
- and her age, but Sharon seems to...
- I'm not interested in Sharon's reasons.
Terri was my patient.
I'm interested in what she'd think.
- And she would never, ever want this.
- How can you be so sure?
Terri hated her mother.
Giving that woman another child,
Terri's child,
would have been her worst nightmare.
ARCHER: Okay, I'm twisting the coil,
capturing the clot.
A few more minutes,
I'll be able to pull it out of there,
returning the blood flow in your brain
back to normal.
[JANE GROANS]
- Keep her still.
ADDISON: She's having contractions.
ARCHER: You have to stop that.
ADDISON: I will. Draw up terbutaline.
ARCHER: Quickly.
ADDISON: Focus, don't nick a vessel.
Jane, I know you're in pain,
but I need you to stay still as possible.
ARCHER: We're running out of time.
ADDISON: Give it a minute.
NURSE: Heart rate's up, 120, 140.
ARCHER: Addison.
ADDISON: It's a side effect of the
terbutaline. Just a few more seconds.
ARCHER: Stay with us, Jane, okay?
ADDISON: Contractions are slowing.
ARCHER:
Okay, captured the clot.
Removing the coil,
I'm injecting the dye.
Well, isn't that a pretty sight?
No, no. Okay, all right.
Do you think it's ever appropriate
for a mother to be implanted
with the embryos of her daughter?
I was dreading the choice between power
berry and dragon fruit vitamin water.
Okay, mothers act as surrogates
for their daughters all the time.
If Sharon wants a baby so badly,
let her adopt.
Sharon doesn't want any child,
she wants their child.
She doesn't deserve it.
I don't like it any more than you do,
but if I don't do it...
Well, she just goes to another doctor
for implantation, right?
I mean, they're her property.
- By law, I'm not saying they should be.
VIOLET: She's 52.
There are very few doctors
who could successfully impregnate
a woman her age.
If Naomi says no,
then the problem ends here.
But isn't getting older women pregnant
part of the beauty of IVF?
They get to have time, have careers,
and still be moms.
And what does that mean for their kids?
I mean, can you imagine volunteering
to be team mom in soccer in your 50s?
Or going prom dress shopping
in your 60s?
I don't know, maybe the fact that Terri
hated her mother
makes the decision for me.
- I don't have to worry about age or grief.
- Yes, yes. She should not be a mother.
People become parents at different times
in their lives for different reasons.
It's not always ideal. If this woman
is willing to make a good-faith effort
to be the kind of parent
she knows she should have been before,
why would we be against that?
Isn't that what this baby,
any baby, deserves?
Pretty good team, you and me.
No. We are not a good team.
I made a life here, Archer.
Away from Bizzy, away from Derek.
I'm trying to figure out me.
And I can't do that with you
- judging everything that I do.
- I will be supremely supportive.
You don't know
how to stay out of my life.
You never have.
And when I needed someone
to make Phil Davidson pay for
leaving me out at the lake, that was great.
But now,
when I'm struggling
to find my footing in this place that's mine.
- I miss you.
- I miss you. But this isn't a visit.
You're in my city. You're in my building.
You're sleeping with my best friend.
- I mean, you're in my patient's brain.
- I'm not moving in with you, Addy.
I just wanted to be closer.
You have to go.
I love you, but you have...
You know, this is crazy, Charlotte.
- What, riding the elevator?
- Stop.
Okay? The masking and the sarcasm.
It's like we take one step forward
and two steps back.
I want you to talk to me.
Do you not see that we're a perfect match,
and you're screwing it up?
[ELEVATOR RUMBLES]
I got embarrassed and humiliated.
So don't tell me
about screwing things up.
You think it's easy for me
to look you in the face
after I sobbed in your lap like
a 12-year-old girl, asked you to marry me
and got turned down?
[ELEVATOR WHIRS]
- You shouldn't feel humiliated.
- Well, it happened and I do.
And there is nothing
you can do about it.
- He's dead, isn't he?
- No, Ellen, it's not that.
I'm sorry to startle you.
- I'm looking for Keith.
- Come in.
He stopped by my office this morning.
He OD'd.
I helped him and then he ran off.
I haven't seen him in months.
I'm surprised he even came to you.
- He can't afford it.
- We have a deal.
He stops by so I can keep an eye on him.
I give him clean needles
- so he doesn't spread...
- You're helping him get high.
- I'm helping him stay safe.
- It's enabling.
And I should know
because I was queen of enabling,
but it doesn't work, Pete.
I had to cut him off.
For his good and for mine.
He's an addict.
I know, it's a horrible disease.
Well, call it a disease if you want.
It's politically correct, I get it.
But he chooses to shoot up.
And I choose not to have anything
to do with him.
This man?
This is my husband.
- The man I loved.
- I'm trying to help you get him back.
It's not up to you, Pete.
It's up to him.
And he's beyond hope.
- How's she doing?
- Tim, hey. Um...
Archer was able to stop the stroke.
He woke her up, but there is swelling,
so she's still paralyzed on the side.
She hasn't been able to talk yet.
But he's very hopeful.
- And the baby?
- Everything's looking good, Tim.
Uh...
Did you want to go in there
and see her?
She doesn't want me here.
I'll let her family know that she's okay.
What do you think about
me staying over, tonight?
Oh, no, no. No.
I don't want Maya to wake up
and see you here in the morning.
- I could sneak out early. I'll sneak out.
- No. No, I am sorry, but I can't.
But I will make it up to you.
Tomorrow night?
- Yeah, actually, I can't. I have a date.
- You have a date?
- With another woman?
- Well, I don't date men.
I support the choice, but...
- All right, funny. You're a funny guy.
- You're upset.
No, I'm not upset. I'm not. I'm just, um...
I'm just surprised.
- I thought that we were...
- We are.
And it's great. It's amazing.
But I'm not your boyfriend.
I didn't say you were my boyfriend.
Look.
I'm the good-time guy.
I'm your good-time guy.
And you should enjoy the good-time guy
because the good-time guy is good.
Do you wanna go again?
I'll do things that you've never heard of.
Okay, but you have to leave. Right after.
Good-time guy will go. Right after this.
[LAUGHING]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Uh, just a minute.
- Hello, Violet.
- Hey, Sheldon.
This is unexpected.
I know.
I could have called.
Maybe I should have called, but l...
I didn't want you to say no.
- To what?
- Violet.
We should be able to talk
about our situation.
I'm sorry, situation?
You know what I like most about you?
How easily we can talk about things.
How in sync we are.
How we get each other.
I get that there's a problem.
I just have no idea what it is.
Oh, hey, Cooper.
Oh, hey, Sheldon.
You're here, talking to Violet.
- And you're here.
- I got some gyros,
and I needed some advice,
but you guys are here talking,
which is great. So I should go.
- No, don't go.
- Thanks.
Gyros for three it is.
[PHONE RINGING]
- I can wait.
- I'm sorry.
- Yeah?
- Hey, I need you to decode.
Um, Sonya's here. Ahem.
Tell her to call 911 if necessary, Sam,
all right?
You're a father,
you can't afford to die for sex.
I got this. I got this.
What do you need decoded?
Okay, it's Archer.
- What's a good-time guy?
- A guy who you have a good time with?
Speaking of which.
So do you... Do you think I'm the type
that would be okay dating a guy like that?
Well, you were okay sleeping
with a guy like that. Twice already, so...
I am a divorced woman with standards,
and I have no practice at dating.
I mean, is this what people do?
Is this what you're doing?
- Are you being a good-time guy?
- Uh, no. No.
Just that
Sonya is not a good-time-guy girl.
That's why she made me wait.
- So I'm trashy.
- No, you're not trashy. You're a queen.
- You are an African queen.
- Who you calling an African queen?
You are an African earth mother...
[MOUTHING]
She's crazy.
- Who just happens to be
with a good-time guy.
- It's okay. It's different.
- Is it?
I mean, is it different?
Because it, uh... It feels trashy.
Look, okay. I gotta run.
So just go with the flow.
NAOMl: She naked?
- Uh, she... Almost.
- You nervous?
- Yes, I am. Very.
Sam, Sonya really likes you.
Okay? You've already won her over.
Just...
- Go for it.
- Okay.
Okay. Go for it.
I've made you wait long enough.
[GROANS]
They found you down at the beach.
I hope I remembered my sunscreen.
This isn't funny, Keith.
You're gonna have to stay here for a while.
You know I hate hospitals.
You have bacterial endocarditis.
It's an infection,
the kind caused by using dirty needles.
I gave you new needles
whenever you asked. You have Hep C.
This was to prevent the spread.
- What did you do with the needles?
- I traded them.
- I didn't share the dirty needles, Pete.
- You traded my needles for more drugs.
God, I don't wanna be like this anymore.
Okay, I'm trying. I am.
And I haven't done well, but I can.
I can, I know I can.
- As soon as I get out of here.
- Hey, hey, hey.
The bacteria is eating away
at your heart, Keith.
Do you understand that?
The hepatitis is destroying your liver.
If you leave now, you will die.
- You mad at me?
- You are a grown woman.
Having sex with my brother,
but still, you are a grown woman.
Um, do you think
that a responsible grown woman like me
can also be the type of woman
that goes out with the good-time guy?
- Is that what he's calling himself?
- Yeah. And l... I don't know. Can I?
Here's my advice.
Be careful listening to my brother.
Things don't tend to end well
for the women in his life.
And you are my friend.
- What, are you mad at him?
- You know, he comes here and...
Oh, it changes me.
He pushes me
and I start acting like a teenager.
I mean, I am a competent woman.
And when he's here, I feel like...
The little sister.
You know what? I'm not blaming him.
But part of the reason
I asked Kevin to move in
is because Archer kept badgering me
about our relationship not working.
And how I was dating
out of my element.
- Because Kevin's a cop.
- SWAT.
So I made a choice to prove him wrong.
And he was right.
And I hate that.
Why don't you
have a different relationship?
Look at me and Sam.
Married, divorced and awkward.
Now, we're actually talking to each other
about our love lives with other people.
- You are?
- Yeah.
And if Sam and I can get past all that,
surely you and Archer can.
[CELL PHONE BEEPS]
Oh, I gotta go.
NAOMl:
Hey.
- She called 911.
- Oh, sweetie, I'm sorry.
Yeah.
SHARON:
My daughter hated me. I know that.
I have no idea
what she told you about me, but l...
- I imagine it wasn't flattering.
- Well, I could say that that is privileged.
But I don't think that'd help either one of us
to understand what's going on here.
So yes.
Terri had negative feelings.
That's why I'm not sure
what you're asking for is a good idea.
I do corporate litigation.
I'm good at my work. I love it.
And when I got pregnant,
everyone told me:
"Don't worry, it'll be amazing,
it'll change your life."
And it did, but it wasn't amazing.
It was hard and exhausting and...
It didn't make me feel anything
like work ever did.
So Terri's sense that you resented her,
it had some basis in fact?
I loved my daughter. Very much.
But she changed my life
from being in control and fulfilled
to feeling constantly overwhelmed
and inadequate.
But Sharon... Sharon.
Listen to yourself.
If motherhood for you
was more burden than blessing,
why would you wanna subject yourself
to that again?
Because I want it
to be different this time.
- But what makes you assume it could be?
- The pain.
I've lived with it every single day
while she was alive.
Not being what she needed.
I kept thinking that at some point,
I would be able to
make the relationship right.
I can't bring Terri back,
but I can have the child that she wanted.
And give it love and attention
and the support that she would've...
That she deserved.
That every child deserves.
I am capable of that.
[GROANS]
Jane, you're in labor.
I need to deliver the baby now.
It's early, but I think it'll be okay.
JANE: I need...
- It's okay. I'm gonna take care of the baby.
Okay?
- I'm surprised you called.
- Hey, um...
The baby is in distress,
and Jane's not dilated, but I can't wait.
I gotta do a C-section, but she's still
on blood thinners from your procedure.
I need to reverse them or she'll bleed out.
- That'll put her at risk for another stroke.
- The baby can't survive without surgery.
Uh...
What if I do a C-section with a spinal?
Can you do an intraoperative EEG,
monitor the neurostatus?
That sounds like a good plan.
Okay, we're gonna
get you up to the OR.
- Tim.
- I already called him.
Go ahead.
- I want you to hear me out.
- I told you once, Cooper,
no more talking and expressing.
It's done.
You know what? It could be done
and over. It wouldn't be that much mess.
You're not pregnant, we don't
live together, no vacations planned,
I don't have a thing at your house,
you wouldn't leave a shirt at mine.
But emotionally,
I'm not ready to let go.
We are so not the cute couple,
in and out of each others pockets,
finishing each others sentences.
But we're still a couple. We're us.
And I love us,
and I am nowhere near ready to give up.
- Even if you are. I'm not giving up.
- Well, won't that be lonely.
VIOLET: Hey, Pete.
- Hi.
- L...
- Hey, will you sign a 5150?
For Keith Embry. He's a drug addict.
You can't lock up an addict
and force him into treatment, Pete.
It's more than that.
He's living on the streets, got no job.
- Not eating, got no clothes.
- Grave disability.
- You've done your homework.
- Think it's a bad idea?
I think... I think it's better
when people want treatment.
Forced treatment is problematic.
And with addicts,
I mean, he'll just lie to you, Pete.
If he stays on the streets,
he's gonna die.
But 72 hours in a psych facility
isn't gonna change that.
Seventy-two hours to evaluate,
choose to do a 14-day hold, then 30 days.
Does he have a support system?
A wife or kids?
He has a wife, but no kids.
Thank God. That'd be a disaster.
Well, kids can inspire things in people
that adults can't.
I mean, if he'd had kids...
I mean, wouldn't it make a difference
if you'd had kids?
I'm passed that window.
The sad truth is it's probably better
that Anna and I didn't have kids.
I'm too selfish. And I get angry.
So will you sign the 5150?
You know, when you force something
on someone that they don't want,
they'll never fully commit.
So if he doesn't want this for himself,
he'll just walk out the door.
The baby?
ADDISON:
Almost there, Jane. Hang in.
ARCHER:
Any bleeding?
ADDISON:
Persistent oozing around the edges.
- Any changes in her EEG?
ARCHER: No, she's fine.
ADDISON: Bovie.
NURSE: There you go.
ADDISON: Okay, Jane,
I'm gonna take the baby out now.
Lap pad
and have an intubation tray standing by.
- What's wrong?
ADDISON: He's not breathing.
Yet. Laryngoscope
and a suction catheter, now.
It's aspirated meconium.
How much time do I have?
ARCHER: You've got about 30 seconds.
- Please.
ADDISON:
Okay, come on. Come on.
Stand by with a 3-0 endotracheal tube
and a ventilator.
ARCHER: Twenty seconds, Addison.
ADDISON: Come on, breathe, breathe.
Come on, breathe.
[CRYING]
He's okay. He's gonna be okay, Jane.
Yeah.
I think I was wrong.
About Sharon using Terri's embryos.
- What about Terri?
- I was thinking about Terri growing up.
About how she must have felt,
and how kids intuitively know
if their parents resent them.
But I was also thinking
that children only see one side.
And that if a parent
understands their feelings,
and really wants to change...
I actually think Sharon
will be a different mom this time around.
And she's not just trying
to replace her daughter? It's not guilt?
Maybe the fact that she's committed
to being a good mom.
Maybe that's reason enough
to give her a second chance.
KEITH:
Hey.
- Keith, what the hell are you doing?
- Oh, I gotta get out of here.
I'm just... I'm going crazy.
I'm sorry, Pete, but I just...
- I got to, man.
- No, you need to stay.
I need you to get better.
Ellen needs you to get better.
She still wants her husband back.
- I can't be that guy anymore.
- You can.
I'm not gonna sit back
and let you hurt yourself, Keith.
You have a real chance to get clean.
I can't.
Whoa, whoa. No, no. Wait, wait, wait.
No. Hey, Pete.
You're gonna be committed
to the psychiatric ward
- at St. Ambrose.
- No.
They have doctors who treat addiction.
They can help you.
Oh, you son of a bitch.
You son of a bitch.
All right, relax. Relax.
If it's gonna work, he has to want it.
He can get there.
He's not beyond hope.
He's not.
NAOMl:
Okay.
Here we go.
- Wait, wait, wait. Please. Please wait.
- Sharon?
What if I'm making a mistake?
What if...
What if I can't do any better this time?
What if...?
What if... What if I'm just destined
to be a bad mother?
NAOMl:
Sharon.
Sharon?
You're not destined to be anything.
You have a chance
to be whatever you want.
And if the person you were before
wasn't working,
you can change it.
And you can be the kind of mother
that you think that that baby,
that Terri's baby deserves.
And if you commit to that,
and you decide that it's what you want,
it'll be amazing. For both of you.
This is the chance you wanted, right?
Then take it.
Okay.
Hey. He's beautiful.
Breathing on his own.
You did good, Jane.
Yes, you did.
Want me to hand you the baby?
[CRYING]
I'm glad you're here.
Anxiety-induced asthma.
What do you have?
- For Sam?
- Yeah.
- I don't need anything.
- Yes, he does. Sonya is a problem.
- We haven't...
- Sealed the deal.
SAM:
St... Well...
We've tried, but I just...
I get nervous, and then I start to wheeze.
Butterbur and dried ivy.
Steep it in hot water for five minutes.
One big glass should help reduce
bronchoconstrictions for a few hours.
Good luck.
- What?
- It's just...
After everything you two have
been through, you're still... You're friends.
- Is that weird?
- No, no, no.
- It's great.
- I think so.
Yeah.
She still not talking to you?
I opened my soul, and nothing.
Pete doesn't want kids.
Sheldon doesn't want kids.
I don't want kids.
You know?
I mean, what business do I have
having a kid?
Me.
Raising a kid by myself that I don't want.
- Wouldn't know what to do with.
- You're not alone.
Every night,
I wake up in a cold sweat, Cooper.
I lay there panicked.
That I'm gonna wait too long.
I'm gonna wait too long.
And then it'll be too late to have
an abortion, and I will just be stuck.
And I'll never be free ever again.
- Violet.
- I don't know what to do.
All I know is that unless
you're bringing me sticky buns
and gyros and burgers then...
Heh, heh, I'm lost, Cooper.
I mean, I see you and I feel better,
but most of the time, I walk around lost
and alone and scared.
Well, then I will be here.
Whenever you need me, I will be here,
and we'll sit, and we'll eat.
We'll figure this out.
We'll work through everything
and make it okay. Together.
- You'd do that for me?
- I'd do anything for you.
I am not glad
that you are working for the enemy.
And you're gonna have to learn
to stay out of my personal life.
But if you wanna be here, then...
This is gonna be fun.
[CHUCKLES]
- Thought you had a date.
- I canceled.
- So no good-time guy?
- I don't know.
All I know is
that I was getting ready for a date,
and I realized
that I would rather be with you.
So I'm more than a good-time girl.
Now, I never said you were a
good-time girl. Good-time guy, that's me.
No, you...
You're a keeper.
Are you gonna let me in?
- Where's your child?
- Oh, um, she is at a sleepover.
Well, then let's get you naked.
Peace offering.
Corn bread chicken casserole.
Momma used to bring it
to the neighbors to make peace
after Landry and Duke let their pigs out.
It's the only thing I know how to make.
I screwed up, Coop.
And I wanna make it right.
So I was thinking,
you wanted me to move in
a few months ago.
Maybe now, that's the right thing to do.
A good first step.
What's the matter?
- Going somewhere?
- I'm moving in with Violet.