- Previously
on "New Amsterdam."
- Looking for someone
who lived here years ago.
Horace Reynolds.
- Nobody by that name has lived
here since I've been around.
- Courtney, I found Dad.
- You were right.
I've been feverishly
trying to make up for all
of my shortcomings,
been wounding myself
so that you can save me.
I am not the problem.
You are.
- Leyla, this is a bad idea.
- So?
- Let's get married tomorrow.
In New York.
Okay, what do you
need for a wedding?
You need two people in love.
You need a couple of people,
a couple
of friends to witness it.
Is that a yes?
- Yes!
Yes!
- I didn't have to sit on my
suitcase to do up the zip,
which makes me think
I've wildly under packed.
- Well,
who says you need clothes?
- I love it when you're cheeky.
I'll be at Heathrow in an hour.
This is really
happening, isn't it?
- This is really happening.
I just spoke
to the fine folks at
the botanical garden,
and they are ready
for an intimate ceremony
with our closest friends.
And they even threw in some
exotic flowers for free.
- And Luna?
- I'm heading to Connecticut
to pick her up now,
and what I'm being told
is her big girl princess dress,
I'm assuming, Gwen went
for maximum cuteness here.
- Of course she did.
- Hey, what's
your flight number?
- It's 476.
Why?
Are you tracking me?
- You know I am.
Are you kidding me?
I can't wait to see you.
♪
- I love you.
- I love you more.
- High chance
these two systems
will miss each other
by about 12 hours.
Alba will be ocean bound
by this afternoon.
We will keep you updated,
so please stay tuned.
- Well, Samira is
nestled at her sleepover,
and she promises not
to call for us at 11:00.
- Hmm, that's sweet.
It's a total lie,
but it's sweet.
- Um, so...
Are we ever gonna
talk about the other night?
- You mean about me
being the problem
in our relationship?
I don't quite know what to say,
to be honest.
- Oh, Martin, I...
You know,
the night that we met,
that was the most
breathtaking night of my life.
I mean, there I was, doing my
usual gay bar routine of just
standing there awkwardly,
not talking to anybody,
eyes down, and, uh,
this gorgeous man comes over
and says, "hello", to me.
But why me?
- Because you were cute.
- There were lots
of cuter guys there.
- Not to me, they weren't.
I saw something in you.
- Martin, you didn't...
You didn't look across the bar
and see into my soul.
You didn't.
You came over because
part of you was drawn
to broken birds
that need to be saved.
And I'm not... I'm not
a broken bird anymore.
I love you,
but sometimes it just...
it feels like you have
this need to be the strong one,
and in order for you
to be the strong one,
I need to be weak.
- Okay, I hear you.
- Okay, thank you.
- And I can't believe
you have the gall to say
that our problem
is that I am too supportive
because there is nobody,
Iggy, and I mean nobody,
who wishes you weren't broken
more than me.
It has been
your go-to move for years,
and as far as I can see,
you have no interest
in changing that.
♪
- Somebody need a half caf,
with two shakes
of cinnamon and extra foam?
- You didn't have to do that.
- Why not?
It's not your drink anymore?
- It... it is.
It is.
Um, it's perfect.
Just didn't think
you remembered.
♪
- What meme are we all
obsessing over now?
Come on.
- Not a meme.
A storm.
- With the sudden
trajectory shift,
Hurricane Alba is now slated
to hit New York City
and the surrounding areas.
Citizens in Lower Manhattan
are advised to evacuate
and seek shelter above
sea level for the duration
of what is now considered
a category 4 storm.
- It is
heading straight for us.
We can't
have a repeat of Sandy.
As the new medical director,
what's your plan
to save this hospital
and everyone in it?
- I'm open to ideas.
- What do you mean
Dr. Langford can't lead
the emergency response?
- I mean, he's not equipped.
He literally asked me
where the bathrooms were.
- What about Max?
- Oh, you mean the guy
getting married tomorrow,
who no longer works here?
Why can't you come in?
- Well, if the hurricane's
changed directions once,
it'll probably
change direction again.
- Yeah, and if it doesn't?
- Look, I'm finally getting
some answers
to some personal stuff
I've been putting off
my whole life,
and I can't turn back now.
- Geez,
if you don't want to lead
the response team, just say no.
- No?
- No!
- I lack the institutional
knowledge to guide
the hospital
through something this big.
One day I hope to,
but that's not today so...
- No... no.
- My department
is literally bursting
with patients
I have to evacuate,
and yours is not.
I just mean the needs
of your department
are non-critical.
- It just arrived.
They're prepping
Mr. Clingman in OR-2.
- Excuse me,
I've got to go put this
non-critical heart
in Mr. Clingman's chest.
- I barely survived
Hurricane Fuentes,
and now you want to put me in
the path of a real hurricane?
♪
- What's wrong with you?
Your weather app broken?
You usually live
for this kind of thing.
- Yeah... yeah, I'm just not...
I'm not feeling it today.
- Yeah, you and me both.
You know,
I asked every department head
in this hospital
to lead us through the storm,
and every single one of them
said no.
- You didn't ask me.
- You really think
taking control
and leading a response team
is in your wheelhouse?
- In my wheelhouse?
You don't think I can do it?
- I didn't say that.
- Give me that binder.
Let me see this.
- Iggy.
- No, no, no, not another...
no, not another word.
I am in charge now.
Thank you.
- Took you long enough!
Come in!
- Uh.
- Watch your head.
Mr. Horace is in the back.
How he thought he could get
all this storm prep done
by himself
with that hurricane
around the corner is beyond me.
That's why I insisted that he
call to get some real help.
Just didn't think that help
would be so well dressed.
Mr. Horus, your friend is here.
- Hello, Mr. Horace.
♪
- Don't just stand there.
Grab those sandbags.
Let's get to it.
- Coming through.
Oh, God.
Uh, hi... hi, everyone.
Can I have
your attention, please?
Everybody, your attention?
- Hey, listen up!
- Thank you.
Uh, yeah, so as some of you
may recall
from Hurricane Sandy,
the ED will be
the first place to flood,
so everything
and everyone not nailed
to the floor down here
needs to be moved up or out.
Capeesh?
Okay, thank you.
As you were.
- Very professional.
- You patronizing me?
- No, never.
You seem like you know
exactly what you were doing.
- It's all in the binder,
I have no idea what I'm doing.
- Hey, hey, we need
some help over here!
- Sir, sir, we're not
set up for her right now.
- Please, she can barely walk.
- Dr. Bloom, I got you.
- Okay.
- Ow!
- Hey, what's your name?
- Her name's April.
- Okay,
is the pain in your stomach?
Okay, I'm just gonna
lightly press.
- When was your
last menstrual cycle?
♪
- Do you think she's pregnant?
- I'm just gonna check
your lymph nodes.
Okay, well,
your symptoms are consistent
with that
of an ectopic pregnancy.
That's when the embryo
grows outside of the womb.
Left untreated,
it can be life threatening.
- Oh, my God.
♪
- Huxley, uh, Bay 26.
Excuse me.
Dr. Shinwari?
- Want me to take
the boyfriend up to charting?
- That's not her boyfriend.
That tattoo behind her ear,
I've seen it before.
That woman's
being sex trafficked.
♪
- No, no, no, no, no!
Help!
♪
- Okay, okay.
Relocate patients
to higher floor, check.
Transport all vital materials
to corresponding floors, check.
Uh...
- So now what?
We just wait?
- I, uh... I don't know.
Let me check on that.
Let's see.
Oh.
Oh!
- Uh.
Uh, that's fine.
That's fine.
Nobody panic.
Our main grid has gone down
and, um, our backup generators
should kick back on
in about 5 seconds, okay?
Five Mississippi,
four Mississippi,
three Mississippi,
two Mississippi,
and one Mississippi.
One Miss-iss-ipp-i!
There it is.
Okay,
apparently we just needed
a slightly longer state name.
Okay, everyone,
make yourselves at home,
and like my friends in
the meteorology community say,
we will weather
this weather together.
All right?
Whoa!
♪
- Iggy!
It's not safe here.
We have to move somewhere else.
- Okay... okay, yeah.
I think everyone is headed
to the EV overflow, right?
Okay, just,
uh, give me a second.
I have the right chapter
here, somewhere.
- Iggy,
the binder's a lost cause.
- No, no, no.
No, don't...
don't... don't say that.
So the only pages
that aren't wet
say that we should
start putting boards
on the window
24 hours in advance.
All right,
if every... if everywhere
with a window is dangerous,
that means we need to find
somewhere without
a window, right?
But this hospital is basically
made out of windows, so...
- Hey, hey.
Panic's not an option.
Neither is hiding.
You asked to lead, so lead.
♪
- Okay.
Yeah, thank you.
Okay.
You said the magic word.
- Please?
- Hide.
Hey, everybody,
listen up, okay?
We're gonna head
to this hospital's
innermost stairwells.
It is the farthest we can get
from this weather,
and it happens to be
the one spot in this building
that has no windows, all right?
Dr. Wilder,
I need you to take the rear.
Make sure
everybody makes it out.
Let's go.
Everybody, come with me.
All right, guys, come on.
Quickly and safely.
- We have to get April
away from him.
- We don't even know if she
wants to get away from him.
- She's been
branded like property.
I mean,
he barely lets her speak.
- Okay, say you're right,
and she wants out.
If he thinks you're onto him,
he'll take her and leave,
and she'll
pay the price for that.
- Well,
we have to do something.
- I need some help!
- Okay, keep an eye on them.
I'm gonna be right back.
- I got a traumatic hip injury.
- Max, we're not set up
for triage.
We're trying to evac...
- I need to stabilize his hip,
all right?
There could be internal damage.
I'll be quick, but there's
no moving him until I do.
- Dr. Bloom, the patient's
O2 stat is dropping.
- Go, I got this.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
- What's going on?
♪
- You just
gonna leave it like that?
- Like what?
- You gotta pack those bags
tight against that wall.
Shoot, you better
just let me do this.
- No, I... I got it.
- Never thought
a man in those brogues
would know how to do that.
- I had to teach myself.
This wall ever leak before?
- Yeah, like a sieve.
Owner call it
"self-remodeling the building".
Got these... got these
pipes going nowhere.
Beams holding up nothing.
Threw up some paneling
and some paint,
and suddenly the empty basement
with the flooding problem
was an apartment.
Miss Kate better than me,
putting up with this.
- Well, it's a good thing
I came back, huh?
- Oh, is it now?
'Cause I don't need no favors.
I'm getting
by just fine by myself.
- At least you had
a choice in the matter.
- Looks like you two
have things under control.
Oh, my photo albums.
It's always something.
Look out!
Ah!
♪
- You still with me, Fareed?
- Yeah.
- This is gonna make
you feel a little better, okay?
Just a little pinch, okay?
- My wife is gonna
kill me, Dr. Goodwin.
You know how long we saved
to buy that cart?
- The cart can be replaced,
but your life cannot,
and, Fareed, call me Max.
- Okay, Max.
- I think it's working.
- Good.
The sooner that pain goes down,
the sooner
we can examine your hip.
Now let's just give that
a minute to work...
and try to relax,
all right?
♪
- Max?
- Yeah?
- I... think I soiled myself.
- It happens.
We'll get you cleaned up,
and... and... and, um...
Fareed, have you ever had
kidney problems in the past?
- I donated one to my daughter,
but the other
has been working fine, why?
- I think your kidney
is failing, and I think
we need to get you upstairs
to a dialysis machine
right now, or...
we need to go now.
- Watch your step, please.
Okay.
Come on everybody,
we should be safe in here.
All right?
Okay, go on.
Yeah, go on.
Okay.
Okay, great, great.
Thank you, everybody.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Uh...
- You should say something.
- Yeah.
- They seem really scared.
- Yeah, yeah, okay.
Okay, so I know that that was
very unnerving for a lot
of you, but I promise you,
we are... we are protected here.
We are very safe
from the storm.
And the good news is
we only have to huddle
in here for
the next four or five hours.
- Four or five hours?
- Yeah, yes,
it's for all of our safety.
- I can't breathe in here.
- Being enclosed
in a tight space
can trigger physical reactions.
That's perfectly normal,
okay, everybody?
But I promise you,
you truly have nothing to fear.
- I can't breathe either.
- Okay, guys,
simple breathing exercise,
okay?
Maybe everyone can
just close their eyes
and listen to the sound
of my voice, okay?
And take
a couple of deep breaths...
Getting more relaxed
with each breath.
Oh, oh!
- Gladys, you all right?
- I'm sorry.
Oh, oh!
- What's happening to us?
- I, uh... I... I don't know.
♪
I can't breathe either.
- I can't breathe.
I can't breathe!
- Okay, all right,
I gotcha, I gotcha.
Let's just...
Hey, I think... I think
her airway... airway's blocked.
- No, no.
- No?
Um...
Cardiac arrest?
- No.
- No?
What?
What is it?
Okay, breathe, breathe.
What have you got?
Carbon monoxide.
Carbon monoxide!
Okay, carbon... okay.
Okay, hey, we gotta move.
We gotta move, everyone.
Come on.
Nice and slow, take it easy.
Nice and slow, everybody.
- I don't...
I don't want to die.
- We got you, Mrs. K.
- Put your back into it!
We're getting it.
- All right, okay.
- The beam.
The beam.
Here.
- Help me.
Come on.
- She can't breathe.
She's got two minutes tops.
Wait!
I'm not leaving you, okay?
I'm here with you.
I got you, all right?
- I'm gonna lever that pipe up,
then you can pull her out.
- All right.
Come on, come on.
Come on!
Come on...
We've got it clear.
Get her out!
- Okay, help me get her
to the table.
Nice and easy, nice and easy.
Okay, yep, take her back
just like that, all right.
- I thought moving that pipe
was gonna fix her.
- Is that her bone?
- Gonna need some rags,
your needle nose pliers,
and some plastic wrap.
- What are you
gonna do with that?
- I'm gonna save her life.
- Yeah,
just down the hall, guys.
Okay, all right.
Nice and slow.
- Oh, hey, Iggy.
- Oh, my God.
Oh, Max, like mana from heaven,
oh, my God.
Are you here to take over?
- What?
No, I heard you're in charge.
- I got people shredded
by flying glass in the ICU,
poisoned by gas
in the stairwell,
and now my EPM is destroyed,
and I have no idea
what I'm gonna do next, Max.
These people
are gonna see through me.
- There's a gas leak
in the stairwell?
- That's your takeaway?
- I have a patient
who needs dialysis.
The elevator's down.
Now you're telling me
the stairs are, too?
- Iggy.
- Yeah?
- Go, go, go.
You're doing everything right.
it's just a few bad breaks.
- Okay.
- So how do we get up
to the sixth floor?
Max, can't we wait
for the storm to pass?
- You won't make it if we do.
It's okay.
Slow and steady, all right?
- Oh.
- Okay, April,
let's get you set up.
- Where...
where are you taking her?
- We just need a urine sample.
It'll just take a minute.
- There's just
so many people around.
I don't
want us to get separated.
- Understood.
He can wait outside
the door for you, April.
♪
Okay.
Okay, if you just give it back
to me when you're done, okay?
Okay.
♪
- How much longer is
this going to take?
- We're gonna get right on it.
♪
- Okay, everybody follow me.
Keep following me.
We're almost there.
- Wait, dead end?
- No, listen, listen,
it's not a problem.
We just have to...
we've got to move
some of this debris
out of the way.
Hey, everybody,
can you hear my voice?
There's more than enough room
for everyone to park
in here while we get this done.
Okay?
Piece of cake.
- Do we have any blankets?
It's freezing.
- No, no, guys,
we're not staying here, okay?
We just need to get through
this ward, and once we do,
we're right next
to the ED overflow,
and there Dr. Bloom
and her entire team
is gonna be able
to treat everyone.
All right, that's good news,
so just come on.
I need you to stay with me
and help me push through.
That's not happening.
Uh, okay, um...
All right, new plan,
new plan everybody.
My bad, follow me.
Come on, it's okay.
Whoa!
♪
- Yeah, yeah sheets.
- All right,
we need to mop this up now.
- Lay them flat so we
can mop up as much as possible.
Come on, everybody,
lay 'em down.
- Yeah,
but it's pouring out there.
We don't have enough
sheets to stop it.
- Can we call somebody?
- No, no, no.
Internet, Wi-Fi, phones,
they're all down.
No one even knows
that we're in here.
Yeah, spread them out.
- What do we do?
- Uh, we, uh... we, uh...
We... we shut off
the backup generators.
- And kill any patients
on ventilators too?
- No, they'll all be
on portable generators by now.
Everybody will.
This is it.
This is the plan.
- I'm pretty sure the binder
wouldn't approve of turning off
the backup generators.
- There's no binder.
There's no binder.
It's just us.
♪
- Iggy, if you even graze
that wire, you'll die.
♪
- You in some good hands
right now.
The best, some might say.
Yeah, that young man over there
who's working on you,
he a big time heart surgeon,
Yale educated,
top of his class,
you know that?
- What are you
giving me those for?
- Look, you're gonna take
the exposed end
of that bone
and push it back in.
Now, look,
the ribcage is curved,
so it should
just glide back in.
Here you go.
- No, I'm not a doctor.
- Well, look, I can't do this
with my hands alone.
All right?
Look, you're working
on a car engine.
- Okay.
- All right.
Okay, all right.
- Just push it on down.
Yeah,
just a little bit further.
Careful, hold on, hold on.
There you go.
Okay, hold it right there.
Don't move, don't move.
Just... okay, just relax.
Now that that's in place,
she should...
- What's happening?
- There's tension
in her thorax.
I just need a pen.
I need a pen.
Get me that pen, that pen.
Hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry,
hurry, hurry, hurry, okay.
♪
- There we go.
- You're okay.
- April, we got your labs back,
and they are positive.
You are definitely pregnant.
- Oh, okay.
- Hey, hey,
it's all good, babe.
- Since this is ectopic,
the best way to resolve
is surgery.
- Okay.
- What kind of surgery?
- A laparotomy is the best...
- Why are you lying to us?
- I'm not.
- A nurse just told me
this could all be
fixed with some pills.
- Pills can be used
with some ectopic pregnancies.
- But why not this one?
- Based on the gestational age
of the embryo and where...
- Yeah, we'll take our chances
with the pills.
It's our choice, right?
- Well, it's April's choice.
Look, look,
I know you want to get out
of here, but this is
a super safe procedure...
- Yeah, we're out of here.
♪
I don't feel so good.
- Just hang on, okay?
Here we are.
Okay.
We're gonna get
your kidney functioning
in no time, all right?
Just let this machine work.
- Max, what's happening?
- We just lost power.
- He did it.
Iggy did it.
- Quickly, everyone, let's go!
- Hey!
Excuse me!
Wait!
Take these.
They'll terminate
the ectopic pregnancy.
You'll need to watch her
closely for the next 24 hours.
She could
still suffer from a rupture.
If she starts running
a high fever or menstruating
more than normal, just...
just bring her straight back.
- I'll watch her.
See, baby?
Everything's fine.
April?
April!
♪
- Okay,
first thing I'm gonna do
is get you a social worker.
We're gonna get you
somewhere safe.
Hey, hey, you're okay.
Hey, you're okay.
Oh, honey, you're okay.
- I can try a manual flush.
Without the supplies...
- There's nothing left to do,
is there?
♪
- Maybe call your wife.
- There's no signal.
♪
Maybe you can tell her that
when my life was
at its darkest..
She was my...
Light.
- It's working.
- I've got a signal.
I should call my wife.
- I should call my wife too.
♪
- I'll come in
and check on you as soon
as I can, Mrs. Carnegie.
- Thank you, Doctor Reynolds.
- Well, there's a story, huh?
Hey, yo!
Hey!
- What you want?
- I...
I need answers.
- I don't have any.
Hey!
Think I jacked up
my shoulder moving that beam.
You know any
good shoulder doctors?
- Yeah, I know a few.
- Will you call me
with that number?
- Yeah, I'll give you a call.
♪
- The social worker's
the name is Shondra.
She's helped dozens of women
in the same position as you.
She's gotten them help,
and she's gotten them safe.
- I have a friend.
I think she'll want
to come too.
- You can't contact her.
No one can know where you are.
- But I'm not the only one.
- Okay, you can talk
to the police,
but you cannot have contact
with anyone
you knew before
for any reason.
This won't work otherwise.
Do you understand?
Picking up that red pen
was the bravest thing
you could have done.
You took back your future...
But freedom comes at a cost.
♪
- I never thought I'd get out.
I never let myself think it
until you gave me the chance.
Jackson hurt me,
made me do things that...
But at least
I knew what was coming.
Now, not knowing
what's next seems even scarier.
But I know I've got to do it.
You're not alone.
♪
- Okay, so the ICU
is still a disaster.
Gladys, maybe you can
coordinate with maintenance,
see if you
can get it back online,
and I'll do an inventory
of all key usable equipment.
Yeah.
- Where will I be?
- Building a temp ICU
with whatever I can secure.
Pick a location.
I don't care where.
Just make it happen,
and we'll keep the patients
in Pan de Villa
'til it's up.
- Okay.
Who needs a binder?
- Oh, thank God.
- Hey, I'm okay.
- Oh, how are you?
How are the kids?
- They're good.
We're all good.
- Good.
Did you stay in your office?
Uh, no, I did
quite the opposite actually.
- Didn't you get my message
to hunker down, to stay put?
- Martin, I... I led the entire
hospital response team.
I was in charge
of New Amsterdam.
- Why...
why were you in charge?
- Because I asked to be.
- Why would you risk it?
Why would you do that?
Because I had
something to prove.
You know, the only reason
I didn't think I could do it,
the only thing holding me back,
was this voice in my head.
And, Martin, the voice is you.
♪
- Well,
if that's really true, then...
What are we doing?
♪
- I don't know.
I don't know.
I do know that...
I can't be who I am,
I can't be who I want to be
with you.
♪
- Okay, um...
Then you should move out.
♪
- So how's April?
- She's with
a social worker now.
- We make a good team,
Doctor Bloom.
- I concur, Doctor Shinwari.
- So...
let's go
do something about it.
- Earlier,
when I brought you a coffee,
I saw a look on your face.
Flash of worry.
- No, I was appreciating it.
- You were wondering
whether you had to pay me back.
We started
with this money thing,
and it keeps coming back.
It's in everything we do,
and it's not going away.
- Lauren, let's just go home,
get some sleep.
- You need money,
and you need my apartment,
and you need your immigration
to go through...
And you need all those things
more than you need me.
- No, don't say that.
- What happens when we fight?
You can't win
because I have all the power.
What if you want
to break up with me?
You can't leave.
The money, it just...
just taints everything.
Even me getting you
a cup of coffee.
So you're gonna
take my apartment.
- What?
No, no!
- Yes, just until
you get your visa.
And I am not gonna be there
with you.
I can't be there with you.
- Where will you go?
- Someplace safe.
♪
- Yes, well,
can you please just
check the name Helen Sharpe?
No, no,
I understand confidentiality,
but she's my fiancée,
and she's...
No, no, I don't want
to go on a brief hold.
Can you just tell me
what happened to her flight?
I...
- Oh, there you are.
- ♪ When I wake up
♪ Well, I know I'm gonna be
♪ I'm gonna be the man
who wakes up next to you ♪
♪ And when I go out
♪ Yeah, I know I'm gonna be
♪ I'm gonna be the man
who goes along with you ♪
♪ And when I come home
- Hey, so...
I know it's last minute,
but I was wondering if I
could change from
the fish option
to the meat option.
- Yeah, right.
Just as soon as I figure out
where we can even
have a ceremony.
- Oh, I'm assuming
the Botanical Gardens is out.
- Unless you have scuba gear.
It's fine, we'll regroup.
We'll figure something out.
- Hey, hold on.
Actually, no need to stop
the love train over a venue.
- Well, except for the fact
that we don't have one.
- Actually, you do.
It's a perfect place.
- ♪ And I would walk
500 more ♪
♪ Just to be the man
♪ Who walked
a thousand miles ♪
♪ To fall down
at your door ♪
♪ When I'm working
- Leave a message
after the chime.
- Okay, so I hope
that your dress
isn't too wrinkled,
because I think
we're getting married right now
on the roof at New Amsterdam.
Our friends have turned
this place
into magic, which is fitting
because this place
has always been magic for us.
It's where we work,
and it's where you and I
became friends, and it's
where we fell in love,
and it just makes sense
that this would be
the place
that we finally start...
Forever.
- ♪ I'm gonna be the man
who's growing old with you ♪
♪ But I would walk 500 miles
♪ And I would walk 500 more
- ♪ Just to be the man
who walked ♪
- Helen?
- ♪ A thousand miles
to fall down at your door ♪
♪ But I would walk 500 miles
♪ And I would walk 500 more
- Max, I can't.
I just can't.
I'm so sorry, Max.
- ♪ A thousand miles
- I'm so sorry.
- ♪ To fall down
at your door ♪
♪
- ♪ When I wake up
- What happened?
- ♪ Well,
I hope I'm gonna be ♪
♪ I'm gonna be the man
- She's not coming.
- ♪ Who's wakin' up to you
♪ And when I'm dreaming,
well, I know I'm gonna dream ♪
♪ I'm gonna dream about
the time I had with you ♪