Previously on "ER.."
No one's ever gotten me
a real diamond before, Mark.
How dare you accuse me
of trying to manipulate you?
I deserve better
than that.
Here's the deal.
Let me shadow you.
Throw in a couple
of procedures
a couple of stitches
here and there
and I'll make
your little lawsuit vanish.
‐ It's Carol.
‐ What?
Carol Hathaway.
Now, you are sworn to secrecy.
I didn't mean to mislead you
about my family.
It's really not that big a deal.
You told me we had to cut PAs.
Jeanie, why don't you
give Kerry and me
another day or two
to recheck our figures?
I love you, Carol.
Hey, I didn't hear you get up.
Um, I didn't wanna wake you.
Where you going?
I gotta go
sign some papers.
Your last day was yesterday,
wasn't it?
That's for unemployment.
Did you take a look
at the, uh, want ads?
‐ What's the point?
‐ We've been back for four days.
Al, all you've done
is look at the sports page.
Don't start, okay?
This, uh..
This Atlanta high‐rise job
is gonna come through.
I can feel it.
I left some chicken
in the fridge for lunch.
Don't know how long I'll be.
‐ Morning, Kerry.
‐ Hey, Don.
What is all this?
It's computer equipment
Dr. West is setting up
thank you, for the Synergix
Attending coverage.
Ah, well, your trial period's
a good idea.
Letting them show their stuff.
Listen, uh, any further
rumblings from Jeanie Boulet?
Well, yesterday was her last day
and she left without a word.
I think her threats just came
out of the heat of the moment.
Mm‐hmm, well, we certainly
don't need a PA alleging
that she was fired
because she was HIV positive.
Jeanie knows she was fired
for financial reasons.
If anyone questions at all
all they have to do
is look at the budget.
Mm‐hmm, hold that elevator.
You handled a difficult
situation very well, Kerry.
Thank you, Don.
Hey, sweetie.
Boy, were you ever snoring
when I left this morning?
Shh!
Oh, poor baby.
You have a hangover?
I don't think I should have
had that fourth margarita.
You know, I went to go
put your present on
and when I came back,
you were out like a light.
‐ Oh, I missed the grand finale?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
You know, I think I need a B12
shot to keep up with you.
Well, you know what?
I got just what
the doctor ordered. Get up.
‐ Turn around.
‐ Easy, I could hurl.
Just keep your eyes closed.
‐ 'Why?'
‐ Just do as I say.
Don't be a pooper.
Stand there. Hold on.
'What's going on?'
Just don't turn around
and keep your eyes closed.
Okay.
Take two of these
and call me in the morning.
The interns have seen meningitis
in every kid with a runny nose.
I thought Doug
was coming back today.
Oh, he called.
His car broke down.
I mean, here.
He called here.
Mark and Cynthia are in there.
So?
Hey, what's going on in there?
Nothing.
Hi.
Jeanie, hey.
Uh, this is Harold Percy,
and this is Barbara Leeman.
‐ Hi. I'm Jeanie Boulet.
‐ Hi.
I filled them in
as best I could.
‐ Thanks.
‐ I gotta get to work.
Good luck.
Would you like
a cup of coffee?
‐ Decaf?
‐ Always.
Dr. Doyle said you were fired
from your PA job
because you are HIV positive.
Is that true?
Yes, I believe it's true.
I was reprimanded
for doing a life‐saving
procedure in a body cavity.
A few weeks later,
I was fired..
...and the hospital claims
it's budgetary reasons.
'Oh, they always give
other reasons.'
Were you ever
disciplined before?
No, never. Actually, I was
October's employee of the month.
'Oh, good, did you keep a log
of what was said?'
No.
‐ Is it too late to do anything?
‐ 'Not necessarily.'
We're going to outline
a protocol for you to follow.
I warn you,
it might get ugly.
I want my job back.
Hey, can I, can I
borrow a buck?
No.
See ya.
Here.
They, uh, say JFK never
carried any cash either.
‐ Oh, yeah.
‐ Keep the change.
‐ Thanks.
‐ 'Hey, Scooter.'
‐ Chase. Hey!
‐ Hey!
What are you doing here?
Uh, I came to see,
you know, the good doctor.
Anna, this is my cousin, Chase.
‐ Hi.
‐ This is Anna Del Amico.
We, uh,
we're interns together.
Oh, now I see why
you got into medicine.
Come on, gang.
We're behind on sutures.
‐ Anna, could you, um..
‐ Sure.
I'll get started on these,
Scooter.
Hmm. Nice.
So, what's up?
I, uh, I escaped to the vineyard
for Thanksgiving.
I was..
...hauling, um, firewood
when a spider got me.
Oh, man!
Dr. Greene, hello.
‐ Ellis West.
‐ Hi.
I'm an SPG doctor.
Uh, Synergix Physicians Group.
Good for you.
Listen, doc,
whatever your misgivings
when the SPG attendings start
backing you up next week
it will make your job
a lot easier.
You are preaching
to the choir, okay?
Less work is fine with me.
Good, then I'll just set up
and stay out of your way.
Kerry, uh, this is Dr. West.
Oh, hi.
We know each other.
‐ How are you?
‐ Good.
What's all this?
This is the Wertz
dictation system.
You dictate on the fly.
It gives you verbal prompts.
Here, this you put
on your belt.
Puts everything
on a floppy.
And this is the, uh, earpiece?
It's the earpiece
and the microphone.
Well..
Okay.
I don't know how my mom ever
kept these things straight.
Cynthia, this is awkward
for me
but, um,
it's my job to tell you.
Some people find certain things
in the work place inappropriate.
Like sex in the lounge so..
We didn't have sex
in the lounge.
I was just trying to cheer up
three of the seven dwarves.
‐ What?
‐ Grumpy, Sleepy and Doc.
Mark's all three.
Just, um, a little
more discretion, okay?
'What's the matter
with you?'
You should be happy
that he's happy.
Jeanie, I thought
your last day was yesterday.
Nope, I'm gonna
keep working here.
Didn't Weaver lay you off?
I'm not accepting it.
You go ahead, girl.
Hello! That smarts.
Sorry.
Hey, we missed you
at Thanksgiving dinner.
At least until
that third round of martinis.
‐ Was gramps after you?
‐ About what?
He's back trolling the gene pool
for another successor.
We've been through this, Chase.
You're done. You're gonna
need IV antibiotics.
You're still his first choice.
Eliot's in Thailand,
A. C.'s too lazy.
‐ Barbara's..
‐ Barbara.
Barbara.
What about you? You're already
an exec with the company.
He knows your work.
That's why he wants you.
Now, why can't anybody
just accept the fact
that I'm a doctor?
It's like my photography, or..
...A.C.'s summer stock.
Gramps just..
...sees them as phases.
All the little chickens
will come home to roost.
Not me.
Hi. I'm Dr. Weaver.
What's the problem?
I'm having a sickle cell crisis
and somebody stole my Percodans
at the bus station.
Where's your pain?
It's like having a migraine
all over.
'Mr. Jackson says the pain
is ten out of ten.'
Pulse and temp are normal.
My pulse and temperature
don't usually go up.
I need 250 of Demerol
as soon as possible.
That's a big dose.
I know me.
I need to break the cycle now.
BP's normal, 130/80.
Let's run in two liters
of saline.
O2, six liters.
Draw a CBC
with a retic count
and give him 60 of Toradol.
I'm allergic to it.
‐ Two of Stadol, then.
‐ That too.
I'm telling you
Demerol's all I can take, okay?
Who's your doctor?
I go to the Pontiac Clinic.
Okay, give him 50 of Demerol IV.
Repeat once in 15 minutes, PRN.
50 won't touch me, miss.
Give the medication
a chance to work, Mr. Jackson.
I need 250.
Let's call the clinic and see.
Rollover TC.
Daughter was seat‐belted.
Mom wasn't. Mother's shocky.
Chest and abdominal trauma.
BP's 80 palp, pulse 140.
Daughter's BP is 90/50.
Pulse 120.
Left leg's badly mangled
and pulseless.
‐ Massive blood loss on scene.
‐ Okay.
Anna, you're with me
in trauma two.
I'll take this one.
‐ Need a hand?
‐ Thanks.
Why don't you check her leg?
Everybody, this is Dr. West.
‐ My mom's calling me.
‐ I'm sorry.
‐ What?
‐ Where's my mom?
She's next door with Dr. Greene.
BP's down. 90/50, pulse 120.
Open saline wide.
CBC, type and cross for four.
Chest, C‐spine,
pelvis and left femur.
‐ Don't touch my leg.
‐ Get some pressure on it.
ABD pads.
We wear trauma gear
in the trenches these days.
Too late now.
Leg's pulseless.
Massive bone
and tissue loss.
Probably gonna
have to be amputated.
Is my mom okay?
That sounds
like a larynx fracture.
‐ Does your neck hurt?
‐ Mmm.
‐ I think you're right, Ellis.
‐ Alright, what have we got?
I'll make room
for the cavalry.
Thanks for your help.
Rollover TC.
She's hypotensive
'with an open femur'
'and a possible
larynx fracture.'
‐ Her mom's in two.
‐ Okay.
Are you having
trouble breathing?
‐ Am I gonna die?
‐ Alright now.
Listen, we're not gonna
let that happen, alright?
‐ 'Set up intubation.'
‐ Mind if I take her?
Sure, you take this.
I'm gonna go check next door.
‐ 'Ally, oh, please.'
‐ Hook her to the Thora‐Seal.
‐ How's she doing?
‐ Please, God, Allison.
DPL's grossly positive too.
I'm losing a pulse.
‐ She's arresting.
‐ Here's more O‐neg.
‐ Pump in four more.
‐ Start CPR. I'll intubate.
She's flatline.
I'll cross‐clamp the aorta.
Thoracotomy tray. Let's go.
'Hang two more and bag her.'
Let's get an abdominal CT
and finish the X‐rays upstairs.
If we hurry, maybe
we can save her leg.
‐ Do they need me in two?
‐ No.
There are three docs in there.
Stat page Dr. Romano
to the OR.
‐ Dr. Weaver.
‐ 'Hmm.'
I'm glad you reconsidered
the PA cutbacks.
‐ What are you talking about?
‐ Jeanie, she just clocked in.
Kerry, that sickle cell
guy's had 100
of Demerol, says
it hasn't touched him.
Yeah, did you call
the Pontiac Clinic?
I tried.
Number's not in service.
Why am I not surprised?
Crit and retic count okay.
White count's normal.
What's the problem
with you people?
I need more Demerol.
Run in the rest of the saline.
Give him four tabs of codeine
to go and street him.
This should be interesting.
‐ What?
‐ Look.
‐ May I speak with you?
‐ Sure.
Just keep taking deep breaths.
‐ What are you doing?
‐ I'm working.
No, you're not, you've been
terminated, you're off payroll
and you're not covered
by malpractice insurance.
Alright, alright, I won't see
any more patients
but I'm staying.
Jeanie, don't humiliate
yourself by being
forcibly removed
from the premises.
You do what you need to do,
Kerry.
I'll do what I need to do.
Time of death, 12:07.
We have to tell her daughter.
She went right from CT To OR.
I'll take care of it.
She was so worried
about her daughter.
Hey, Mark, how you doing?
Ah, today's the day
we save some lives.
I'm very excited.
Where's my scrubs?
Listen, we gotta kinda
be low key about this.
If anybody asks‐‐
I'm just,
I'm your attorney, okay?
I'm here to research
your work
so I can prepare
a proper defense.
‐ Sounds good.
‐ Look, calm down, okay?
I'm not expecting anything big,
maybe, you know
a couple of sutures
here and there.
Look, I cannot let you
practice medicine.
What are you talking about?
We had a deal.
I defend you in the civil
rights suit against you.
In exchange,
I play doctor for a day.
We'll see.
‐ How's my case going anyway?
‐ Where's my scrubs?
Look, I'll get you
your scrubs, okay?
Just try and do it
low profile.
Yeah, right. Listen,
don't worry about your case.
Right, it's gonna vanish
into thin air.
You made quite a deal
for yourself.
Have Dr. Anspaugh call me
as soon as he's free.
It's very important.
Hey, guys, how did it go?
Well, Marquis de Sade's
got nothing on Scooter.
Don't call me
that at work, okay?
‐ Marquis de Sade or Scooter?
‐ That's funny.
‐ Oh!
‐ Wanna go to lunch at Shaw's?
I can't. I'm on duty.
Blow it off.
It's my job.
I can't just blow it off.
Okay, Dr. Schweitzer.
Just asking.
You see, my family think that
I'm just dabbling in medicine
till I come to my senses
and quit.
'Sounds like fun.'
Eddie, you bastard.
You're trying to kill me.
‐ Shut up, Darlene.
‐ See.
They're ganging up on me.
I can see the appeal. You should
come by the house sometime.
‐ We'll all party. Ciao.
‐ Like that's gonna happen.
I've got a couple of winners
for you, wife says hubby tried
to beat her up,
complains of pain all over.
Vitals and mental status normal,
never mind being plastered.
'You're going to jail, Darlene.'
Let me up.
I gotta pee.
ETOH, bump on the head,
contusions and abrasions.
'No complains of pain,
he says that the woman tried'
'to run him over, and no LOC,
vitals normal.'
‐ Oriented times three, GCS 15.
‐ You'll be alright, Eddie.
Okay, I'll take him,
you take her.
Okay.
Why the cuffs?
She's under arrest
for assault
with a deadly weapon,
pickup truck.
I was just trying to get away
and this son of a bitch
was chasing me.
He's on Eddie's side
'cause he works
with the police motor pool.
You wanna uncuff her
so I can examine her?
While she's here,
she's my patient.
No matter where she is,
she's my perp.
You wanna go on record
as interfering with the care
of a woman
with critical injuries?
For God's sake.
Were you trying
to kill yourself?
No, I‐I was just mad at Eddie,
that's all.
‐ Take any drugs?
‐ Me? Never.
I want a blood alcohol
and a drug screen.
‐ Will you excuse us?
‐ I want the tests.
I need to evaluate her first.
Maybe you could wait outside
while I examine her.
With the lung extrication,
there's been over two hours
of pulseless, warm ischemia.
She's got massive crush
injury to the leg.
Her abdominal CT is normal
and her vitals are stable.
Yeah, but with contamination,
bony loss and protracted shock
an above‐the‐knee amputation
is indicated.
I say we attempt
to save Allison's leg
with a vascularized
free fibular transfer.
That would be four hours
of anesthesia
on a limb
that's too far gone.
Look, face it,
at this point
a long surgery is too risky.
Do you know how to do
a fibular transfer?
‐ No, I don't.
‐ Okay, on three..
Is that why you think
I shouldn't do it?
‐ Have you ever done one?
‐ No.
But she's a good candidate
for an aggressive approach.
Oh, no, you mean,
she's a good guinea pig
for you to practice on.
Oh, don't be so dramatic, Peter.
She's a young woman.
She deserves a chance
to keep her leg.
Got a hot one, eh, Lizzie?
Couldn't ask
for a better candidate
for a free fib transfer.
Wait till you see her
in action, Peter.
So, you worked something out
with Jeanie?
No, she's fired,
but she's protesting
and I'm trying to get legal
to deal with it
but Anspaugh's been
in a closed‐door meeting.
Man, glad I don't have your job.
No.
We'll go to trial.
Irv, my client's willing
to lose 100 Gs
rather than settle, okay?
No, no, no.
It's your move, Irv.
Oh, baby.
‐ What's this about 100 grand?
‐ It's not about you.
Uh, could you maybe
give me some specifics
on how you're planning
to defend me?
‐ Wh‐where do we change from?
‐ This way.
How about telling me
a little bit about my defense?
What's there to tell?
We're going to kill 'em.
We'll go for assault
with a deadly weapon
but, hey, no caving this time,
right, buddy?
Go for it, Billy.
‐ Kill the bitch.
‐ Right.
Sounds like you boys
have it all worked out.
Stick to the medicine.
I'll handle the law enforcement.
Your X‐rays are normal, sir.
You'll be back to battering
in no time.
What? Battering?
We scuffled is all.
Did your wife
lose consciousness
at any time
after she was assaulted?
Hey, she tried to kill me.
No, I don't wanna.
‐ Get off of me.
‐ Come on, nurse.
‐ Just draw the blood.
‐ Hey, what are you doing?
Nobody's drawing this woman's
blood without her permission.
This is constitutionally
permissible search.
Delay will result
in loss of evidence.
She's bradying down.
‐ 'Pulse 39.'
‐ 'Darlene.'
She might have taken drugs
and been afraid to tell us.
‐ She wouldn't lie.
‐ Let's give her .5 of atropine.
Let's pump her stomach.
Ewald tube.
‐ I want those tests.
‐ Get a warrant.
You've got one coming, okay?
We better get Greene
to back us up on this.
I don't need any backup.
I know my rights and hers.
Alright, Darlene, I want you
to try and swallow this tube.
Afternoon.
Hey, hello, doctor.
‐ Herb Spivak.
‐ Uh, Maggie Doyle.
Are you a Synergix attending?
What do we have here?
Oh, partial extensor
tendon laceration.
You best treat that with
irrigation and, uh, debridement
and give it a couple
of loose sutures
and a, a splint
and you'll be fine.
Herb, why don't you come
with me?
‐ 'Thanks.'
‐ How did you know that?
I hired a doctor for a couple
of weeks from an emergency room
for 100 bucks an hour,
he told me everything.
Blood gases, chest tubes,
peritoneal gavage‐‐
Uh, lavage,
peritoneal lavage.
Uh, oui, oui, lavage.
‐ Why don't you sit down?
‐ Uh, what's that?
Uh, I'd like you to practice
your suturing on this.
‐ Pig's foot?
‐ Yeah.
Okay. Which ones?
Um, running, uh, vertical,
interrupted, deep thermal?
‐ Why don't you try all of 'em?
‐ Okay.
Uh, this won't be
but a moment, okay?
‐ Alright.
‐ Hey, Mark.
Hey, welcome back.
How did it go?
Well, it's a long drive from
Flagstaff in an old Cadillac.
It's nice to spend
some time alone.
‐ Where's Carol?
‐ I don't know.
‐ Doug.
‐ Oh, are we glad to see you.
Otitis, rhinitis
and gastroenteritis.
Ah, it's nice to be loved.
Hey, Doug, how..
‐ Hey.
‐ Hello. How are you?
Um, good, I'm gonna get
right to work on these
I guess. It's good to see
all of you.
Hi. You all done?
Yeah, the system is up.
I usually don't get so hands‐on
with patients anymore.
Well, I'd prefer blood
on my shirt
to a staff mutiny any day.
Well, it sounds like you could
use a little R&R.
How's a week
in St. Bart's sound?
St. Bart's?
In the Caribbean?
Yeah, Synergix conference
is there next week.
You could give a paper on..
...inner‐city ER Management.
We'd take care
of your airfare and expenses.
Why?
Well, a doctor
with leadership qualities
is a very valuable asset.
It's a real offer.
You think about it.
I will. Thanks.
I'll be at the Ritz‐Carlton.
Okay.
‐ Hey, Doug.
‐ Hey.
So, how was it,
meeting your father's in‐laws?
I'm glad I did it,
but it was hard.
Sherry's death
hit them really bad.
‐ That was her name. Sherry.
‐ Listen.
I'd‐I'd like you to see
a depressed, anhedonic girl
complaining of loss
of appetite and insomnia.
She's in exam room three.
Psych take a look at her?
I'd like you
to evaluate it first.
‐ Hey, good to see you, doc.
‐ Yeah, feel like I never left.
Hey.
What?
Mark Greene.
Mmm, come here, you.
So now you've had a loss
of appetite and insomnia
because of me?
I'm surprised I lived.
Well, sounds serious.
Mmm, shut up and kiss me.
‐ Okay.
‐ Mmm.
Carol, do I collate
these clinic charts..
Oops!
‐ Excuse me.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Doc, what do you think?
Hey, not bad.
I love that running stitch.
‐ Yeah, that's good.
‐ Hey, Dr. Greene.
If the, uh, police need
evidence, like a blood test
and the patient refuses
to give it, what do I do?
Medical personnel can decline
to collect physical evidence
where the subject is unconscious
or indicates his or her refusal
to consent to the procedure.
The People versus O'Neal, 1993.
‐ Herb Spivak.
‐ John Carter.
‐ Thank you, Dr. Spivak.
‐ You need a consult?
No, he doesn't.
Uh, hey, listen, Herb.
That was not very low profile.
Well, I was being a lawyer.
What's the big deal?
Offering a consult?
‐ Listen, why don't you start‐‐
‐ I'm ready.
Jeanie.
If Yosh needs a doctor,
he can ask for one.
I'll be right in.
‐ I cannot allow this.
‐ Okay.
What are you doing?
I am just logging the fact
that at 2:30
I was prohibited
from treating an ankle injury.
‐ Chuny, call security.
‐ It's Anspaugh.
‐ Finally.
‐ No, it's not for you.
'He wants to talk to Jeanie.'
Yes?
Alright, I'll be right up.
I'm gonna take
this tube out now.
Blood alcohol's pretty high.
270.
Is she coming around?
Yeah, she's perking up..
...since she puked.
Let's see.
No pill fragments though.
‐ Here comes that cop.
‐ Here's your warrant, smartass.
‐ Now draw the damn blood.
‐ Let me read it first.
Is that her stomach contents?
I want that too.
Does that warrant specify
stomach contents?
It doesn't matter.
Give it here.
Oh, no, you don't.
That's destroying evidence, pal.
‐ You're under arrest.
‐ You can't arrest me.
‐ What? You can't arrest him.
‐ Watch me.
You have the right
to remain silent.
‐ Where you taking him?
‐ Jail.
You've the right to the presence
of an attorney.
Carter's getting arrested.
‐ Anything you say..
‐ For what?
For protecting
the doctor‐patient privilege.
Look, officer, uh, Dr. Carter
is an inexperienced intern.
If he did anything rashly,
uh, we can work this..
Carter, what did you do?
I stood up for my patient's
civil liberties.
Don't worry, this will be
taken care of in no time.
So what's the charge?
Obstruction of justice.
Her HIV status
defines Miss Boulet
as a person
in a protected class
and her firing constitutes
an adverse action
by the hospital.
Her layoff was budgetary.
We would argue
that was pretext.
'And ignoring your progressive
disciplinary policy'
'and firing an exemplary
employee after one incident'
proves discriminatory intent.
Why don't you take a seat,
Kerry?
I don't wanna take a seat.
If you're reinstated,
you'll let the matter drop?
Yes.
Well..
We'll have an answer
for you today.
We appreciate your time.
We can't cave in to this.
It's blackmail.
Our only option..
...is to hire her back.
The media would swarm all over
a federal case like this.
You know what,
you pushed me to make
the cutback.
What about the budget?
Her PA salary is nothing
compared to the risk
of the countless pain
and emotional suffering
lawsuits from the patients
she treated.
Do you know what
this will do to my authority?
Well, you're strong, Kerry.
You'll survive.
This femoral defect measures
at least 13 centimeters.
We're pushing the envelope
on fibular transfer.
She's throwing PVCs.
I'll push fluids
and start lidocaine.
Remove the distal clamp
from the femoral artery slowly.
It's back‐filled.
The anastomosis looks dry.
Excellent.
Does she know about her mother?
No, she was put under
before her mom died.
'Poor girl.
Release proximally.'
Alright, arterial flow's
restored.
Toes are pinking up.
Pressure's heading south.
‐ 'Map's down to 70.'
‐ Maybe we should bail.
I'm almost there.
Let's finish.
Alright, give her two more units
of packed cells.
‐ Let's pick it up, Lizzie.
‐ Pickup.
Metz.
Here's the, uh,
police district phone number.
Great, thanks, oh,
Cynthia, my daughter
is getting dropped off
for a dental appointment.
Can you come find me
when she gets here?
Rachel? I can't wait
to meet her.
Alright, well,
call me back then.
‐ Was that legal?
‐ Yeah.
‐ So, what did they say to do?
‐ Well, they're finding out.
It's not everyday
that interns are arrested.
Cop's leaving.
She's all ours.
What happened?
'Oh, baby, please forgive me.'
It's never gonna happen again.
'You almost killed me, Dee Dee.'
‐ Carter went to jail for this?
‐ 'My mind just snapped.'
'My‐my foot hit the gas.'
'You know how crazy
I get when we fight.'
Is this really necessary?
Let's say
it's a tradition.
You know, Superintendent
Rodriguez is a..
He's a family friend,
if you just give him a call
I'm sure we could clear up
this whole misunderstanding.
Over here.
Don't I get a, uh,
a phone call?
‐ I get a phone call.
‐ Nah.
Just a blindfold
and a cigarette.
‐ What?
‐ You'll get everything.
Don't worry.
Look here.
'No smiling.'
‐ Hey, Doug.
‐ What's going on?
This sickle cell guy
Weaver turfed, he's back
and I can't tell if he's a
junkie or he's in a real crisis.
‐ Okay, alright.
‐ 'Get a doctor in here.'
'I'm in pain.
Hurry up.'
I'm Dr. Ross. Just get
his vitals and start an IV.
Sit back, will you, please?
You're gonna give me
some Demerol.
Is that what works for you?
Yeah, yeah,
but nobody believes me.
What do you think
caused this crisis?
No, I'm stressed,
I'm trying to get home to..
...um, my, to KC
for my sister's wedding, right?
And‐and somebody stole
my pain pills.
They take everything?
Yeah, they took everything, man.
Will you give me, will you
give me some Demerol, please?
I'll tell you what I' gonna do.
I'll make you better
but we'll do it my way, okay?
‐ Alright.
‐ Vitals are normal.
Start an IV.
Five of Dilaudid.
Then three every ten minutes
till he doesn't feel
any more pain,
while she's medicating you
we're gonna try something,
alright?
I want you to close your eyes,
I want you
to think of a place
that makes you feel calm.
‐ Oh, c‐come on, man.
‐ Hey!
I'm trusting you.
You gotta trust me, okay?
‐ Close your eyes.
‐ Alright.
‐ Think of a place.
‐ Alright, um..
A place, uh..
My‐my granny's kitchen.
Okay, good.
‐ Close them. Close them.
‐ I can't do this.
‐ Yes, you can.
‐ No.
‐ Breathe slow.
‐ It hurts.
Hmm.
‐ Hey, any word on Carter?
‐ Nope.
Dr. Greene said
the hospital lawyers
can't even find out
where he is.
Uh‐oh.
You have your PA position back
retroactive to your clock‐in
time this morning.
Then I'll get back to work.
There's a hand lac
in the suture room for you.
Thank you.
Hey, uh, Jeanie, let me know
if you need anything.
I will.
You know, and I know this was
not about your HIV status.
Do I?
'The last pin is seated.'
Can we get out now?
‐ What's going on?
‐ 'I don't know.'
She's desatting. Pulse ox
is down to 92 on 100 percent.
Ex‐fix is on.
Bring her up.
‐ Cut the anesthetic.
‐ Run of eight.
Damn! 50 of lidocaine.
‐ T waves have flipped.
‐ Bottom's falling out.
Pulse ox 88.
She's crumping.
She's in fib. Crash cart.
‐ Alright.
‐ Charge her to 200.
Let's move! Come on.
Off!
Three hundred. Off.
'We gotta crack her chest
and get to that embolus.'
Three sixty. Off.
'Forget it, Peter.
Lizzie, start CPR.'
Get on it, Corday.
'Sternal saw.
Sternal saw.'
'She's out.'
Uh, l‐let me provide
the counter‐traction, Mark.
I want a nurse to do it.
L‐let me just hold her arm
while you reduce it.
Hey, Mark, hey, come on, man,
I'm not getting anything.
We had a deal.
You're not giving me anything.
Alright, grab her arm.
Now, just hold the arm tight
while I pull. You ready?
‐ Yeah.
‐ And go.
Whoa!
It popped right back in.
What did you do?
Did you pronate
and externally rotate?
Uh‐uh. In‐line traction.
‐ Mark, Rachel's at the desk.
‐ Oh, right.
Can you order post‐reduction
films on Mrs. Miller?
Got it.
Hey, what happened to Jeanie?
Dr. Anspaugh gave her
her job back.
Oh, how does Kerry
feel about that?
She's pissed.
Hi, sweetheart.
‐ So, you two have met?
‐ Oh, we're old friends by now.
Now, how could she be
wearing the jodhpurs
'with that bubble butt?'
'Maybe she has a bell'
'that dings
whenever she backs up?'
'You mean, like this?'
Ding! Ding! Ding!
Well, I think she looks hip.
Oh, yeah, dad. Sure.
Real hip.
Cynthia, uh, when do you
get off work?
Uh, about, uh, ten minutes.
Yeah, is there, is there
any way you could run
Rachel to the dentist for me?
I‐I gotta follow‐up
on this Carter thing.
‐ Sure.
‐ Is that alright, Rach?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
‐ Thank you.
Okay. Maybe we'll go
window shopping.
Hey, hey, Herb, uh, where
you going with that chart?
Look, look, I got
the perfect patient for me.
A three and a half inch scalp
lac on a sleeping transient.
Isn't that where
you guys all start?
Um, I'll tell you what,
I'll suture him
and you can cut my knots.
Let me sew a little bit.
You're not a doctor, Herb.
Whoa, whoa.
Mr. Deindorfer?
We got a code blue in exam four.
‐ Looks like a V‐fib.
‐ Grab that red card for me.
'Defibrillator coming up.'
Two hundred. Clear.
Whoa! Whoa!
Herb!
‐ Ah!
‐ Wow!
Wow. What happened?
You're gonna be okay, Mr. D.
Unbelievable.
‐ Jeanie. Jeanie!
‐ Hey.
What's going on? I've been
calling everywhere for you.
They told me in the ER
that you were working today.
I've been rehired, Al.
We're gonna get caught up.
I got the call from Atlanta.
Six months on the high‐rise,
job starting Tuesday.
Yeah, but I got my job back.
Yeah, but tell them to shove it
'cause we're moving to Atlanta.
We need to talk about this.
We'll have plenty of time
to talk.
I fought hard for this job.
It means a lot to me.
The truth is, you don't
believe my job is real.
You got no faith in me.
Al, it's not about that.
Yes, it is,
it's about you
not being able
to depend on me.
You're not gonna tell anyone
in Atlanta
about our HIV status,
are you?
It's nobody's business.
I'm not running away.
You have a life here
and I don't.
Don't you see what making
this fresh start means to me?
Don't you see what getting
my job back means to me?
I gotta go pack.
I'll see you at home later.
'Mr. Carter.'
Um..
...Dr. Carter?
‐ Excuse the hell out of me.
‐ No, no, no.
You know, just‐just
for accuracy's sake.
So I get my one phone call now?
Seeing as you're in
on a misdemeanor offense
we're waiving the fingerprint
check. You can bond right out.
Oh, thank God.
What do I have to do?
Hundred bucks,
and you're out of here.
Great, my credit cards are in my
wallet which they took from me
and they put into that box
right over there.
We don't take credit cards.
It's cash and carry, doctor.
That's all I got.
That was unbelievable,
feeling the power
of life and death
in my hands, it was‐‐
Were you trying to get me fired?
Well, forget the deal.
Okay? It's over.
You're out of here.
‐ It worked.
‐ Cool it, huh, Herb?
Mark, Randi's getting Anspaugh
on the phone.
Could you talk to him about
getting Carter out of jail?
‐ Sure.
‐ Somebody's in jail?
‐ Are you a doctor?
‐ Nope.
‐ Herb Spivak. I'm a lawyer.
‐ Oh!
One of our interns was arrested
for destroying evidence.
That's no problem there.
Get a bail bondsman.
He'll be out in the morning.
By the way, Mark,
your lawsuit's gone.
Uh, what?
That's right.
Sayonara. Kaputo.
I just got off the phone
with Mickey Everett
the attorney for the law family.
He convinced them
to drop charges.
‐ Really?
‐ Yeah.
He'll have papers
drawn up in a week.
How do you pull that off?
Well, it just so happens
that Mickey Everett and I
are part of a billion‐dollar
class action
against big tobacco.
We're looking at maybe
a $10 million legal fee.
Nobody's pushing away
from that golden goose
until it's plucked clean.
Uh, Mark, let me ask you.
Can I have this as a memento?
‐ Yeah, sure, you can‐‐
‐ Oh!
That's the doctor
who saved my life.
‐ Thank you, doctor.
‐ You're welcome.
‐ 'May God bless.'
‐ Yeah, yeah, good.
Yeah, take care.
You look great.
Unbelievable.
Medicine, that's a calling.
Listen, Mark, Morton's some
night for a steak. On me.
Thanks for a thrilling day.
‐ Mark.
‐ Jen.
‐ Did Rachel have any cavities?
‐ Uh, Cynthia's not back yet.
She, uh, took her,
but y‐you know what?
They're, uh, we can wait
for them in the lounge.
‐ Cynthia?
‐ Yeah, the new desk clerk.
She really likes kids,
and Rachel gets along
great with her,
so she took her.
The appointment
was a while ago.
I'm sure they'll be back
any minute.
Oh, my God.
Me and Cyn went to makeovers
'across the street
from the dentist.'
I got my nails done
and my toes too
and she wanted her eyebrow
pierced, but I said no way.
This is Cynthia,
and this is Jennifer.
‐ 'Rachel's mom.'
‐ Hi.
It's just temporary, all
the teenagers are doing it so..
She's eight.
Oh! Well, it will wash out.
Come on, Rachel.
‐ Come on.
‐ Bye, sweetheart.
I was sick of that
little‐girl hair.
Oh, Mark, I'm..
I'm so sorry. I‐I,
we were just having so much fun
and‐and you said
that you liked it
when I showed it to you
in the magazine.
Uh, it's okay, really.
You're not mad at me?
No.
So we're still on for, um
a lingerie show
and margaritas tonight?
Ah, you know, I‐I kinda
need to give my liver
just one night to regenerate.
Uh, so I'll take a rain check.
‐ Hey, Mark.
‐ Yeah.
What are we doing about Carter?
I called a bail bondsman
and they're gonna
release him in the morning.
Wait, so he has to stay
in jail all night?
‐ You wanna call the family?
‐ And say what?
John Carter III's in jail?
Um, here's the police
district phone number.
‐ Great. I'll deal with it.
‐ Okay.
Uh, here's enough oral Dilaudid
to get you
to your sister's wedding.
Oh, great.
Thanks a lot.
Yeah, alright, you're welcome.
Hey, what is he doing
back in here?
It's not your concern, Kerry.
He's my patient.
You don't help an addict
by giving him drugs‐‐
That is a sickle cell patient
in pain.
No, that is a drug seeker
who has learned to manipulate‐‐
He cannot function
without painkillers, Kerry.
People live in pain.
They suck it up
and get past it.
What's up with her?
I think the crown
is weighing
heavily on the queen's head.
Mark.
Hi.
I'm so sorry.
I just, um,
I really wanted to make it
special for Rachel
and I, uh..
...made a mess of it.
‐ It's okay.
‐ Your ex‐wife hates me.
No, she was just..
She was shocked.
‐ So were you.
‐ Yeah.
I guess I was.
Rachel's really happy
and really sure of herself.
You must be a really great dad.
‐ I don't know about that.
‐ No, you are.
I was really excited
about tonight.
I wore your present
and everything.
My feet are killing me.
‐ So you're a doctor?
‐ Hmm?
Um, yes.
Yes, I am.
So..
...what are you in for, Shrike?
Is that‐that your name?
Shrike?
Obstruction of justice.
Yeah?
Me too.
How about that, huh?
I was expecting something
a little bit..
No, no, no, I'm not
making snap judgments.
‐ Got something for you.
‐ You do? Uh..
What's this red bump?
Uh..
...that's a, that's a nasty
carbuncle.
Um, may I?
‐ 'Yeah.'
‐ 'Pants up, ladies.'
Come on, Carter.
Your other girlfriend
bailed you out.
I got a girlfriend.
Uh, I guess I gotta go.
Just, um, soak that
in warm, soapy water
about four times a day.
Should clear right up.
Girlfriend?
Anna?
‐ Oh, oh!
‐ Hi, knucklehead.
Thank God.
Sorry, I was, uh..
I was wondering what
I should get you for Christmas
and then, it finally
came to me. Bail.
I thought I was gonna
be spending
the weekend in there
with Shrike.
Yeah.
So what happened
with Darlene?
Did you get her
into the, into the home?
Oh! Oh, yeah,
she, uh..
She, actually,
she did try to kill him
but, uh, they kissed
and made up
and went home
and lived happily ever after.
I should have had lunch
with my cousin.
I know what you mean.
You know, I'm noticing
it's kind of expensive
to have a rich guy
for a friend.
Hey.
Hello.
English breakfast,
uh, you know
I figured
since you were English.
It's perfect.
Why aren't you at home
putting your son to sleep?
Uh, I get him on the weekends.
So, how's Allison?
Well, her parameters
are stable
but she's still comatose.
She hasn't so much
as twitched.
Hmm.
Maybe you made the right
decision for a young lady
who has a lifetime
ahead of her.
I keep asking myself
whether I made the decision
based on my lust
for challenging surgery.
Yeah.
I ask myself that same question
all the time.
You know, where does
wanting to help end
and ambition begin?
There's the rub.
'Jeanie.'
I...just went to gas up
the car.
I thought you'd gone.
No.
Hey.
Say the word and I'll..
...pack your stuff too.
I can't, Al.
My life is here.
My job is here, I..
I've worked too hard.
I can't just walk away.
Come on. I mean, all the abuse
they put you through?
I know,
but i‐it's made me realize
who I am and what I want.
I can't tell lies anymore.
We've been through a lot.
Can't just..
...throw that away.
You've always been
able to make me laugh.
Make my head spin
like when we were teenagers.
Yeah, well, uh..
...give it some time.
See what it feels like.
Well, I'll, uh..
I'll call..
...when I get there.
You do that.
Take care.