Come on. Is the system down?
Worked fine for me.
I don't have time for this.
- How you doing?
- The computer's not working.
That's not what
I'm talking about.
I know. I'm fine.
A patient died because
of something you did.
I think it's safe to say the
one thing you are not is fine.
I'm dealing.
How exactly are you dealing?
I'm getting back to work.
I have a diabetic toe to debride,
and I'm putting it behind me.
How do you do that?
Put it behind you?
By moving forward.
- I appreciate the concern.
- You're welcome.
I'm gonna make an appointment
for you for grief counseling.
Dr. Mohan. She's an expert
in dealing with hospital staff
who've experienced
stressful events.
That's not necessary.
You agree you've
had a stressful event?
And while I am comforted by
your commitment to move forward
by not looking back,
I still want you
to see Dr. Mohan.
If she says that you are fine,
then and only then can
you go back to surgery.
It's working now. You
just have to be patient.
Heart rate, 36.
Push another five milligrams of
morphine and prep a nitro drip.
We need atropine on board, stat.
- What do you got for me?
- An MI with severe bradycardia.
He's had aspirin, nitro,
and now we're trying to give
him a real rate with atropine.
- Cardiology see him?
- He's got a broken pacemaker...
And probably needs his
coronary arteries cleared.
Feels like a triple bypass,
but you're the expert.
His BNP is sky-high.
What do you see?
His ventricles are
barely pumping.
He's had two massive prior MIs.
End-stage heart failure.
His heart is way beyond repair.
- What are our options?
- He's 73 years old.
His age is an absolute
contraindication for transplant.
- He's dying.
- Well, he's not dead yet. What else?
How about cardiac
resynchronization?
That will get what's left of
both ventricles working together.
A biventricular pacer?
Should make him feel a little
better in the few months he's got left.
His rate drops any
lower, he'll arrest.
Claire, prep his jugular to
float in a temporary pacemaker.
Shaun, call up to the cath lab,
and have them get an estimate
on how long it'll take to
get the bi-pacer in house.
Something wrong?
Um, not at all. Just a little bit
too much coffee this morning.
Okay, let's go. Do it now.
Restraints, please.
I don't wanna get
stuck with a needle.
You're scaring him.
Haldol five milligrams.
- Thank you.
You're scaring him.
- Who are you?
- Dr. Shaun Murphy.
This patient is
psychotic, Dr. Murphy.
He's not psychotic.
You don't like
people touching you.
He's not psychotic,
he's autistic.
You're being an
excellent patient.
Okay. We're finished.
You're same as me.
Can we release his hands?
Dr. Murphy, his hands?
Now I'm here, son.
Mom and Dad are here.
You can let go of his
hands, he won't hurt you.
Wrong stop. Wrong stop.
Can someone tell
me what happened?
Liam has a 5.4 centimeter
laceration on his forehead,
probably from a fall.
The wound was infiltrated
with five milliliters
of 1% Lidocaine.
Seven...
Seven single-interrupted
5-0 Prolene sutures.
He will have a small scar,
but no other long-term
effects from this injury.
You're my son's doctor?
I am. Dr. Shaun Murphy.
- Shaun with a "U."
- Got lost.
- Got lost. Got lost. Got lost...
- Yes, yes, yes.
- But you're okay.
- Got lost...
You won't be taking
that bus again.
This light is too bright.
These rooms make him
anxious. Can we take him home?
No.
Your son is jaundiced,
clenching his right abdominal
muscles when touched, and febrile.
He should not go home.
Why am I here?
Your pacemaker malfunctioned.
You had a heart attack.
I think I get that part.
Your neighbor's gardener saw
you on the ground inside your house.
Called 911, saved your life.
Well, I must
remember to thank him.
How old are you?
Me?
I know how old I am.
I'm 28.
We have a biventricular
pacer on its way,
and it's gonna make
you feel a lot better.
Is it?
I will be back to
prep you for surgery.
Liam has elevated
bilirubin and liver enzymes,
a white cell count of 23.
Abdominal ultrasound shows
dilatation of the bile ducts.
Sounds like
ascending cholangitis.
It can lead to sepsis
if the bacteria gain
access to his blood.
- Is he stable now?
- Yes, his vital signs are stable.
The cause could be anything
from cancer to diet, so...
Liam's parents have him
on a special ketogenic diet.
High-fat diets can cause
obstructive gallstones,
which could have
set the whole thing off.
Do an ERCP to clear them.
After that, a few weeks of
broad-spectrum antibiotics
should take care of things.
I want your help.
With what?
Endoscopic Retrograde
Cholangiopancreatography.
ERCP? Why?
You've done those before, Shaun.
You're good with
people who have autism.
Okay, Glen, let's
get this started.
Glen, you almost finished?
It's Dr. Kalu.
Glen?
Yeah, we have a code green.
Patient is a Caucasian
male, 185 pounds.
Shaun, can you talk
to him or something?
I can't push the midazolam.
Four lights. Four doors.
Yes. Lots of things.
Thirty-two, eight.
Thirty-two is the number
of cabinet windows.
And eight is the
number of handles.
His end-tidal CO2 is rising.
He needs oxygen, he
has respiratory depression.
It's a common
reaction to midazolam.
CO2 is coming down.
You can proceed, Claire.
Thank you.
Have you been around a
lot of other autistic people?
I've never met
someone with autism.
Ah!
So it must be nice to spend
some time around Liam, then?
Why? Why would that be nice?
Okay.
There are no stones.
Where are the stones?
There is scarring.
This has nothing to
do with gallstones.
The entire biliary tree
is so thick with scarring,
we can't even get
the camera through.
The differential diagnosis for
biliary tree scarring includes
primary sclerosing cholangitis,
liver failure,
secondary to primary
biliary cirrhosis.
Yeah, Shaun, we can add a
few cancers to that list as well.
It's a long and ugly one.
Find another way to
figure out what it is.
We could do an MRI.
No, we couldn't.
It's not possible.
That's the first time I've
ever heard you say that.
- Liam is stimming.
- Stimming?
The tics and spasms are a
neurological response to stress.
If he's doing an
MRI, there is stress,
if there is stress,
he won't keep still,
if he won't keep still,
we can't do an MRI.
Therefore it is impossible.
Maybe if you just keep talking
to him like that, he'll doze off
and it'll all be simple.
Give him a mild sedative.
He didn't respond well to midazolam
during ERCP. Depresses his breathing.
His respiratory saturation can't
be properly monitored inside...
I get it. He could die in the
MRI and we wouldn't know.
You're just gonna have to
find a different way to calm him.
Okay, we'll do it.
Guess he has an idea.
We have a code green.
Patient is a Caucasian
male, 73 years of age.
Shaun, what are you doing?
Counting.
- Counting what?
- Distance.
Why?
I want $1,643.
You can get that by counting?
That's why you're alone
and pacing in this room?
- What do you want the money for?
- I want to buy a television.
- $1,600 for a television?
- And 43.
I'm a surgeon, I get paychecks.
You're not a surgeon yet,
you're a surgical resident.
There's a big difference
in the paycheck there, pal.
I am not a child, "pal."
How about $1,000
for a television?
No. The one I want
is $1,643, okay?
- Well, I know, but you have a budget.
- A budget?
You have rent,
food, bills to pay.
I should do my own
budget. I have an MRI to do.
These are live feeds.
Entrances, ER, receiving dock.
If your patient had
left, we would've seen it.
Then where'd he go?
A freight elevator.
But we don't have
cams in the freights
and he doesn't pop back up.
So we're dealing with
an alien abduction here?
Sorry.
We don't have cams
on the freight elevators
on levels one, four and
five, and the basement.
And you've got people
looking on those floors?
We've covered four and five,
and we're moving on to one.
Hey.
What's in the basement?
Pediatric patient
lost a blanket,
just gonna check lost and found.
That's nice of you.
While you're there,
you might wanna
check if they found
your code green.
Hello, this is Doctor...
This is Shaun.
I can hear you when you speak.
I was thinking about something.
There are 24 steps from
the ambulance to the ER.
Please turn down the lights.
That helps calm him.
There are 24 steps from
the ambulance to the ER.
There are 22 steps
from the ambulance to the ER.
He has very long strides.
Yes.
There are 22 steps from
the ambulance to the ER.
There are 37 steps
from the elevator to Room 405.
In Room 405,
there are six steps to the sink.
Six steps to the sink.
We're getting good images.
It's amazing how accomplished
you are for someone with ASD.
Three steps to the window.
Three steps to...
Three...
It's seven steps.
It's seven steps to the door.
Liam, there are seven
steps to the door.
- You need to get him out.
- Just a little more time.
- He's scared.
- It's okay to be scared.
We need to finish this.
- Seven...
- You're doing wonderfully, honey.
Just breathe.
No, it's seven
steps to the door.
Glen.
Glen?
It's Dr. Kalu.
Let's get you upstairs.
Go away.
We've got to get
your new pacer in.
Don't you get it?
I broke my pacer on purpose.
I want to die.
With the new pacemaker,
you'll feel better.
So, I'll be cured?
Good as new?
Well, it'll reduce your
pain and then hopefully...
You think this is the
first time I've heard that?
It's always the next best thing.
The truth is,
I'll just keep getting
worse. I know it, you know it.
Do you have any
family you can talk to?
Brother's dead,
and I don't have a wife,
so no, there's no-one around to
nag me into doing what you want.
We have great
counseling services here.
I'm in pain, Twenty-Eight.
All the time.
Talk therapy gonna
talk that away?
Let's get you upstairs.
Your color's not good, and
your lungs are crackling,
which means there's
fluid building in...
I know my...
I know my rights.
I don't have to get
treatment if I don't want it.
The minute I catch my breath,
I'm gonna walk out of here,
so you can just leave.
I'm not leaving.
We can't treat it until we
find the underlying cause.
- How do you do that?
- Surgically.
It's called exploratory
laparoscopy.
We use a camera to
navigate Liam's mid-section.
Now, there are
significant risks.
Perforation of an
organ. Accidental spread.
Seeding a malignancy.
And you have to do this because
he can't stay still during an MRI?
You obviously know
your son better than I do.
Do you think we
should try again?
So, Shaun told me
he's getting a TV.
Seventy inches, all the works.
Is he now?
It's just a TV.
It's not about a TV.
Why are you so
worried about him?
He's showed up late for
work half a dozen times,
he calls me at 2:00 in the morning
because he can't find a screwdriver,
and his superintendent wants
to kick him out of his building.
- Did you show up?
- What?
At 2:00 in the morning,
when he called you
about a lost screwdriver,
did you show up?
He was frantic. I didn't
know what he was gonna do.
There are 47 residents here.
All of them show
up late sometimes,
all of them make mistakes,
and hopefully, all of them learn.
You wanna worry
about Shaun, fine.
But you fought to hire him
because you know he can learn.
The question is, are
you willing to let him?
Shaun?
I can see the pixelation.
- That's great, listen...
- It's not great.
It's not good.
On a high-quality display,
the human eye at 20-20
cannot detect the pixels.
You disappeared
after the failed MRI.
I failed.
Yeah, see, I don't
think it's about that.
You were hesitant with
this kid even before that.
You asked me to do the ERCP.
Doctors don't have to
like their patients, Claire.
- You don't like him?
- I don't know him.
Shaun, there's something
else going on here.
- I know you know that.
- No.
No. Uh-uh.
He has the same
condition you have.
You have never
met anyone with...
Do you like all
people with psoriasis?
- I don't have...
- Yes, you do.
And you can never get rid of it.
Okay.
It's too bad you don't like him,
because I think he likes you.
Not only that, I think
he looks up to you.
So, you know how he thinks?
Well, not as much
as you probably do.
What are you waiting for?
For you to pass out.
And judging by the
size of your ankles,
that shouldn't be
too long from now.
Then hopefully I can get
you upstairs before you die.
Why do you give such a damn
about what I do with my life?
I don't know, Glen.
Why do you wanna die so bad?
I've lived.
I've had decent jobs. I've
had jobs that went nowhere.
Had a good roof over my head,
and had that good roof taken from me.
I loved a girl and
we got married.
Twenty happiest
years of my life.
Then she died.
And now I'm alone
and in pain.
Feels like the end of the story.
- I understand.
- Yeah?
You've had some tough
times too, Twenty-Eight?
Nobody understands what it's like to
be so good-looking and successful?
I was raised by nannies
and housekeepers.
Oh, my God, you're an ass.
Your point is you didn't suffer
because you were
good-looking and smart,
you suffered because
you were rich?
Only time I ever saw my
parents was Christmas.
Seriously, the story continues?
They had this big
party every year
and wherever they were traveling,
they'd always fly home for it.
And I'd have to come home, too,
from whatever school
they'd sent me off to.
When I was 18, I
decided I was fed up.
I was a man.
Done being their son.
And I was gonna
tell them publicly,
tell all their friends what
horrible people they were.
So I came home from school,
and I knocked on the door and...
someone answered.
But it wasn't my
parents, it was a stranger.
Turns out they'd sold
the house months ago.
They were gone.
I guess they were
done with me, too.
To prep Liam for
the laparoscopy,
we'll need to make four
small incisions in his stomach.
I don't need to do it.
- Liam, you do need to...
- I don't need to!
If you could just hold
still for a second, Liam?
The, the bus driver
lets me off, I get lost.
- You're safe now.
- I get lost.
I'm hungry. I can't make food.
Can't do bath.
Don't need to do it.
Can't do food.
Can't put on clothes.
Can't do bus.
I took the bus.
I got off at the wrong stop.
I got scared, but
then I found my way.
I did an MRI and a man got hurt.
I made a mistake.
I make a lot of mistakes.
You tried to walk.
You made a mistake.
But mistakes are good.
You should make more.
You're like me.
You have red eyes, uveitis.
Liam takes vitamins.
Does Liam also take
herbal supplements?
Kava root. Why?
He doesn't need the
laparoscopic surgery.
I know what's wrong with him.
The red eyes.
They're caused by
an immune flare-up,
which can create the scarring
that we're seeing in
his digestive system.
The solution
requires us to go in
and remove damaged segments
of the bowel, piece by piece.
"Us"?
Yes, myself and my team.
Is Dr. Murphy on your team?
Of course.
Thank you for
diagnosing our son.
Dr. Melendez, you have our
permission to do the surgery.
But in no way will
Dr. Murphy be in it.
The parents, they won't budge.
They don't believe that
anyone who has autism
is capable of doing surgery.
Well, clearly they're irrational, I
don't know, shallow-minded people.
Who cares? What's the difference?
You agree with them, right?
- Do you agree with them?
- It's my team.
I don't want anybody telling me
who's supposed to be on my team.
- Including the Board.
- You're not answering my question.
- Your question's moot.
- Moot?
No, it's not.
If you agree with them,
then the only issue is
somebody stepping
on your poor little toes.
Get over it and go save the kid.
If you don't agree,
if you think Shaun
can handle surgery,
then tell them that. Tell
them to go screw themselves.
Either they agree that Dr. Murphy
belongs in that room with you,
or you can go find them
someplace else to do the surgery.
I was an 18-year-old
with no-one and no money.
So I worked three
jobs and took out loans.
Still alive.
That's not a bad
story, Twenty-Eight.
What happened with the parents?
I talk to them now, but...
they're not the people
who got me here.
It was the people
I didn't expect.
The ex-Marine at the shelter
who got me my first job.
And this crazy artist girl
who convinced me to go
after what I really wanted.
When you think
you're alone, Glen,
you're not.
All right.
All right?
Ready? One, two, three.
No disturbing dreams?
After a 36-hour shift?
From the moment
my head hits the pillow
to the moment I wake up,
all I see is black.
How's your level
of concentration?
Have you had any
difficulty focusing?
I mean, I can do the New York
Times crossword puzzle in one sitting.
Sure, sometimes I
wish I was more focused.
But that's pretty normal, right?
Shaun's different.
He also has savant syndrome.
He has a remarkable memory.
He has autism.
Same as our son.
Same limitations.
You saw what happened
to our son in the MRI.
He knew he needed to
lie still, but he couldn't.
Now, what happens if
Dr. Murphy breaks down like that
while he's standing over
my son at an operating table?
You know your son,
I know surgeons.
And after working with
Dr. Murphy, after challenging him,
in surgery and everywhere else,
probably more than he deserved,
I can tell you, he has
my complete confidence.
I'm sorry,
he doesn't have ours.
So, what do we do now?
I've contacted my
colleague at St Joseph's,
updated her on Liam's
condition. They have good people.
We can arrange for
transportation as soon as possible.
Where's my phone?
Have you seen my phone?
Where's his second bag?
The one with his medications.
I want...
What, honey?
He said I could do it.
I want Dr. Shaun.
Your pacemaker's here.
The techs are
programming it as we speak.
The moment they're
ready, we're gonna put it in.
I told you my wife died.
The truth is
she left me.
But I gave her
good reason for that,
so I got what I deserved.
We all make...
But you didn't get
what you deserved.
Good parents who loved you.
They were lucky
to have you, Jared.
- You appear remarkably well-adjusted.
- Thank you.
That's not a compliment.
That's my concern.
Well, I assume everyone
responds differently.
The thing is, everyone responds.
Strictly speaking, you
don't meet the criteria
to be required to go into treatment,
or take a leave of absence.
So I'm not gonna ground you.
You're a strong woman, Claire,
and that strength has
undoubtedly played a major role
in getting you where you are.
But if you have suppressed
feelings about this incident,
you need to find someone
to share them with.
Because if not,
they will eat you up,
no matter how strong you are.
All right, Glen. Second time...
Oh, come on.
Thank you.
It should be a very
interesting surgery,
I'm glad I'm participating.
His pressure is bottoming out.
- What's happening?
- His bowel must have perforated.
He's going into septic shock.
His perforation
could be anywhere.
What's the best way to access the
entire bowel as quickly as possible?
Full-length midline incision.
Good. Mark it.
And what do we do
once we get in there?
Eviscerate the entire bowel
so we can check every inch
for necrotic segments.
Okay. Let's make the cut.
Are you gonna take it or not?
This is the Number Three L.
It's made of high-carbon
steel. It doesn't break.
That's correct, Dr. Murphy.
Time of incision, 2:05 p.m.
We have a code green.
Patient is a Caucasian
male, 73 years of age.
Where'd he go?
Yeah. On my way.
I have a five-centimeter
segment of proximal jejunum.
It's necrotic, but
not perforated.
Mark it and move on.
Shaun, why are you
just standing there?
We have 25 feet of bowel to run.
Shaun, we need to get moving.
Unless you've found something.
I have. The perforation.
Clamp it off, I'll get in there
with the enterotomy scissors
and remove the damaged segment.
I can't.
You can't? Why not?
It's a phlegmon.
You found a walled-off abscess?
- It's large.
Don't touch it. - I already am.
If you move and
that thing ruptures,
the pus will spread to his entire
abdominal cavity. This boy dies.
I know, that's why
I'm not moving.
Claire, I need you
to open it up gently.
I'm gonna evacuate
the septic contents,
flush the cavity
with antibiotics,
and then I'm gonna have
you remove the capsule.
- I didn't do anything.
- That's the pressure tanking.
You need to finish what
you're doing right now.
Let's go, Claire. Come on.
Clamp.
You guys check left.
Hey. Hey, come on.
Stop.
Come on, Glen, we can do this.
I don't want to. I
just don't want to.
Please, leave me alone.
Once I get my strength
back, I'll climb up and jump.
I can't let you do that.
When this temporary
pacer fails, which it will,
your heart may stop and
you may die suddenly.
But more likely, Glen, you
slip back into that slow rhythm,
your chest is racked
with excruciating pain,
and your lungs
start to fill with fluid
and slowly you suffocate.
Yeah, give it a
rest, Twenty-Eight.
Just get me a DNR and a cab.
You can't help me.
Yes, I can.
It was a difficult procedure.
- We removed a total of two feet of...
- Is he okay?
He will be okay.
Thank you.
I... I'm sorry.
We're... We just...
He's our son.
You shouldn't feel bad.
You did what you
thought was best for Liam.
You love Liam.
I didn't have that
from my parents.
It also means I didn't
have to take Kava root
so I didn't get
hypereosinophilic gastroenteritis.
Are you gonna get
in trouble for this?
You're worried about me now?
You signed the DNR.
All I'm doing is
sitting with you.
When they say your father's name
They're talkin' about a boat
They're not talkin' about him
'Cause they don't
trust you as far
Are you feeling any anxiety?
No.
Pain?
Some.
Would you like a dose of
morphine to help with that?
But back then, the
ship seemed sunk
I couldn't sleep
when I wasn't drunk
But now a bad idea
Has cut you in two
Darlin', I just don't know
Thank you.
Some things you just let go
Oh...
Find your guy?
I did.
You put in the biventricular?
How long did it take to get
access to the coronary sinus?
I didn't do the surgery.
I didn't put in a
pacer in. He, um...
He didn't want it.
He was a good guy.
I lost a patient, too.
Want to talk about it?
I do.
Your surgery went well.
You should be able to get up
and move around in two weeks
once we're sure the antibiotics
have cleared your infection.
Hear that?
It won't be too long
until we can go home.
You did great, honey.
The lights.
Are the lights okay?
Do you want them dimmed?
They're okay.
You'll love the software.
It makes it very easy to budget.
And the best part, it links
directly to the bank and...
Get rid of the ball!
He was the first
quarterback picked in 2013,
but his stats outside the pocket
are only 27% completed passes.
Their back-up QB is
65% under pressure.
Absolutely.
- He's wasted potential on the bench.
- Yes.
Anyway, the link to the bank
will help make automatic... Oh!
Did you see that?
He pinned it against his
helmet, even with the Pl.
I want to go to the Super Bowl.
Okay, see? That's exactly the
kind of thing you have to think about
before you buy. Tickets
are very expensive.
No, you know
what? You should go.
- I should go. We should go.
- Okay.
Excuse me.
It's almost closing time, so...
I'd like to buy this TV.
Stay as long as you like.