[RAINDROPS PATTERING
AND THUNDER RUMBLING]
[VIOLET BREATHING HEAVILY]
No, no. In and out.
You gotta breathe in too,
not just out.
In. In.
No, no. You're not...
Not like a vacuum cleaner.
Like a normal person.
- Relax.
- That's easy for you to say.
You're not gonna have 8 pounds
of flesh and bones coming out of your...
Ah. Okay, I don't... No visual.
CHARLOTTE:
This is visual enough for me.
The point of me staying over
wasn't to wake up next to a pillow.
- You can always leave.
- I know.
But I agree to adult sleepovers
in this carnival
because I get my itches scratched
when the sun comes up.
- Usually.
- Charlotte, I'll be right there.
I'm going back to the room.
If you're not there by the time I'm naked...
Come on. She's bluffing.
Yeah.
Keep breathing.
JANINE:
Thank you.
- Hey. No Phillip today?
MALCOLM: Hey.
He couldn't get off work.
On the upside, he promises me
a bigger budget for the baby's room.
But I don't mind. It's not his thing.
Malcolm's better at it.
One of the perks of being a nurse.
I get to fill in for my brother.
- Hey, sorry I'm late.
- Again.
We'll talk about this later.
- Hey, Malcolm.
- Fellow nurse man.
She fires you,
we'll take our business elsewhere.
- How long have you been like this?
JANINE: A week maybe.
I walk up a flight of stairs
and I feel like I need to take a nap.
Since Phillip has diabetes,
you think this is related?
- Gestational diabetes or something?
- No, there's no association.
Your blood sugar's fine.
Let me just have you sit up.
Well, maybe it's the baby weight.
Look at me. I'm as wide as a highway.
Hey, you're beautiful.
I'm gonna listen to your lungs.
Deep breath.
Good. Again?
What? What is it?
- Dell, get an ambulance for me.
- Dr. Montgomery?
I don't want you to panic,
but I hear a little bit of fluid in your lungs,
which could indicate a problem
with your heart.
- Phillip. Is he here yet?
- I called him. He's on his way.
NOAH:
Addison.
Oh, perfect.
There are 40 heart surgeons
in this hospital.
I didn't know this was your case.
I just responded to the page.
So did you get a chance to look
at my patient's echo?
Yes, yes.
Diffuse myocardial dysfunction.
See, that wall's barely moving.
Oh, my God.
Both mom and baby could die.
I'll do everything I can to save them.
Doctors think HMOs
are about denying healthcare.
About how little help
you can give people who are sick.
While HMOs make a mint.
You're right. Most doctors do think that.
- I think that.
- Thank you.
You know how few people
would say that to my face?
You know, you're very charming,
but I'm just...
Thank you.
I'm having a hard time figuring out
what you think I can do for you.
My practice is never gonna be
a part of an HMO. Not ever.
Good. Neither would I.
I got out. Took the money and ran.
Oh, are you proud of that?
No. Most of my life, I've been a rich ass.
Then over the past year,
I watched my best friend die.
ALS. He suffered.
A lot.
Medicine failed him.
I failed him.
And it changed me.
I wanna start
a state-of-the-art medical practice.
Change the way medicine works.
Change the way doctors work.
I'm not at liberty to discuss details,
but I want you to run it.
[CHUCKLES]
Mr. White, I'm...
I'm very flattered, but l...
It's William. And just hear me out.
I've done my homework, Naomi.
You are the preeminent
fertility specialist in the area.
You helped fund one of the first
whole wellness practices.
And in the past year,
you've had to deal with finances
and internal power struggles.
It's not even your practice anymore.
It's still my practice.
Maybe. But is it what you want?
What if you had access
to cutting-edge technology?
To the best scientists and researchers
at your fingertips?
Top doctors in every specialty
under one roof?
- I have the best doctors now.
- Think bigger, Naomi.
I'm talking about, say, the guy
who created the first embryonic stem cell.
I'm talking about giving full wellness care
to people who can't afford it.
You set the agenda, then hire
whoever you want to make it work.
So you can focus on what you do.
Being a doctor. Making life.
You know, my ex-husband and I
built our practice from the ground up.
And leaving it is something
I would never entertain.
Well, entertain it now.
I'm offering you the chance to do
what you've always wanted to do
with no money worries.
What's the downside?
Hey, Nai, you free for lunch today?
Maya hit me up this morning about
taking her someplace cool for summer.
Thinking we could figure out
our summer schedules.
No, I can't. But tomorrow.
You having lunch with Duncan again?
No, no. I just... I'm busy.
Is everything okay?
Yeah, everything's great.
Oh, thank you.
Okay.
I know testing urine is a crappy job,
but jeez, Sam, lighten up.
What is it? Another UTI?
Well, yeah,
you do have a urinary tract infection,
but you also tested positive
for chlamydia.
Now, the good news
is that it's treatable.
So I'm gonna give you a prescription
for sulfa for the UTI
and doxycycline for the chlamydia.
Now, do you have any idea
how you might have contracted this?
Um...
Bill.
He's been cheating for a while.
I'm sorry.
How did I let my marriage come to this?
Well, this is not your fault.
Now, if you need help in dealing with this...
Oh, no, no, no. I'll figure it out.
That's what I do, I figure things out.
I always tell my students, "Stay focused
on the problem, the answer will be clear."
I need to get away.
From Bill.
Sounds so easy to say, doesn't it?
No, it's tough to know
when you're ready for it to be over.
Well, I'd better pull myself together
and get back to school.
Donna, if...
Give me the prescription.
I'm gonna be okay.
Okay.
Big Ben has a big appetite.
I'm an eating machine.
Six slices. Up here.
Thank you so much. That was yummy.
- Aah! Sorry, ma'am.
- Excuse him.
Somebody calls me "ma'am,"
I just wanna choke them.
Oh, that's okay. I've been called worse.
Oh, Lisa, this is Violet. Violet, Lisa.
- Hi.
Nice to meet you.
How many weeks are you?
- Uh, 35-ish?
LISA: Well, you've got the glow.
Being a parent, nothing compares.
So I've heard.
I'm really looking forward to it.
See you later? Okay.
Bye.
Nice. She's, uh...
I like her.
You need help with that box?
Her heart's just not working anymore?
It's called cardiomyopathy.
The heart muscle becomes inflamed.
In this case, the added pressure
on Janine's heart from the baby
caused it to progress rapidly.
From all the tests,
it looks like it's been going on for a while.
I'm afraid that the damage
is irreversible.
- You didn't see this? You've been there.
- Honey.
You're my brother
and you're blaming me?
JANINE:
Stop. It's nobody's fault.
ADDISON: Janine's right.
I think we need to focus on the solution.
So, what do we do?
She is going to need a new heart.
Oh, my God. I'm going to die?
No, that's what you're telling me,
I'm pregnant and I'm going to die.
How fast can we get a heart?
We need to notify UNOS.
Get her on a list. It could take time.
How long can her heart hold out?
It's impossible to tell, but not for long.
The pregnancy is making
your heart work harder.
Which is why, Janine, I think
that you need to consider a termination.
No. No.
ADDISON: Janine, at 20 weeks,
the baby can't survive.
We need to relieve the pressure
on your heart till we find a new one.
She kicks. She kicks me.
She's alive in there. Please.
We can't take that kind of risk.
Janine, I want this baby as much as you,
but we need to buy you more time.
You're not listening, Phil.
She doesn't wanna lose the baby.
JANINE:
No, I can't lose the baby.
You have to save us both.
I'm begging you.
COOPER:
Hey, Bobby. Bobby, it's Dr. Cooper.
- My body's on fire.
- You're having an allergic reaction.
We need to figure out
what you've been exposed to.
- So, what you've been eating.
- I don't know.
Try to do better than that.
If you took something
you weren't supposed to,
you're not gonna get into any trouble,
but you need to tell me.
BOBBY: L...
- Look, you need to check him for pills.
Check his pockets.
Check everything he came in here with.
Draw up 125 of Solu-Medrol
and 50 of diphenhydramine.
NURSE: Okay.
DONNA: Is he gonna be okay?
I'm Bobby's teacher. I found him.
Did you see anything?
Has he been taking anything?
Mrs. Keating, thank you.
- Is Bobby okay?
- He's having a severe allergic reaction.
We're trying to figure out what.
And he's in here, you should go in.
Donna.
DONNA: Sam.
- Sam?
What's going on?
My student, he's in there.
The sulfa you gave me
and the doxycycline?
I gave him both and he's reacting.
You have to tell the doctor what he took.
- Oh, no, Donna.
- You can't tell them.
You can't tell them Bobby and I are...
That I'm sleeping
with one of my students.
She's not a vulture.
She's not a predator.
- She was confused.
- I have no sympathy, except for the boy.
How's Bobby?
COOPER:
He's... You know, he's stabilized.
He's alert. Rash is not progressing.
- Stevens-Johnson's Syndrome?
- He reacted to the sulfa.
He's lucky. People can't just
give other people their prescriptions.
She was trying to help.
What did he tell his parents?
He said that a friend gave him some pills
so he could stay awake, study.
Now they're happy he's doing better.
Bobby is a minor. This is statutory rape.
She should not have slept
with her student, all right? Absolutely not.
But he's gonna be 18, in what,
like a month?
You spoke to him, it was consensual.
I mean,
he said he made the first move, but...
That does not absolve her,
and it doesn't absolve you
of your legal duty to report this.
- To protect him.
- But in a few weeks, it won't be a crime.
What good is it gonna do
either of them if I report this?
She's gonna lose her job, her credentials.
He's gonna end up humiliated.
DELL:
Oh, he'll be a rock star.
Mary Kay Letourneau, hot.
That boy was 13 years old.
So by comparison,
Sam's patient's done nothing wrong.
What 17-year-old hasn't wanted to sleep
with one of his teachers?
Donna was in a position of power,
and she abused that.
Why assume
a 17-year-old isn't mature enough?
Because he's being forced
to grow up too quickly.
To make decisions about his life
that he's just not ready to make.
Think about yourself at 17.
I was mature, all right? Heather wasn't.
But thank you, Naomi, for the free therapy.
All right, if this were Maya
and a 35-year-old male gym teacher...
Well, I would kill him.
But that's not the...
I know that there's a double standard here,
but it's different when it's a girl.
- It is.
- It shouldn't be.
SAM:
Look, I hate abuse.
But I don't think
that's what we're dealing with here.
Donna is not a criminal.
Now, as long
as she doesn't see him again,
that's all we want, isn't it?
Even if she gets the new heart,
he won't look after her.
- He's not gonna take care of her.
- Phillip?
He sends me in his place.
Who does that?
Even now,
he's in the lobby on his BlackBerry.
This is his baby. His wife.
He should be here for her, you know?
There still isn't a heart,
but Janine is at the top of the list.
I've also got a call in
to the head of UNOS.
Janine's blood type O, so am I.
It's the most common.
It shouldn't be so hard.
That works in her favor,
but organ donation is a difficult process.
- Supply can't meet the demand.
- I wanna do something.
If I could give her my heart...
We're gonna find you one.
How long do Janine and the baby have
to find a heart before they die?
Forty-eight hours.
Isn't that someone else's job?
I can't stop. Nesting.
I see mess or clutter
or things out of place and...
So she seems nice.
Lisa. And her kid is cute.
Yeah, I like them.
What? What's wrong?
I just hate it that you're maybe
carrying my baby and I didn't tell her.
- You think you should?
- You think I shouldn't?
It's just... You're happy.
And I'm all for full disclosure,
but do you think you should tell her
something before there's anything to tell?
SHELDON:
Violet.
Oh, sorry, Pete.
Were you two in the middle of a?
Just finishing.
- Are those for me?
- No, for me.
From a patient. She's in love with me.
Her name is Anita.
I started treating her a few months ago.
She was painfully shy.
She wanted me to help her
be more assertive
with a co-worker
she had fallen in love with.
She didn't know how to talk to him.
And as she realized
how easy it was to talk to you,
she channeled her love to you.
- It's classic transference.
- Clearly.
- You don't have to say it like that.
- Like what?
Like a woman couldn't fall in love with me
unless it was a therapeutic mistake.
- I didn't say that.
- I can be very charming, you know.
- I know.
- Well...
I was just saying that it happens,
that it's part of the process.
Are you having your own feelings?
This is not about counter-transference.
I mean, granted my love life
is at best complicated right now,
but I just wanted to talk to a colleague.
I guess, go on record if nothing else.
But also to see if you had any secrets.
[SIGHS]
I hate to fail.
I think you won't fail.
She's lucky to have you, Sheldon.
And can you really blame her?
[CHUCKLES]
Dell, I'm going out, so if my 2:00 gets here
before I do, put her in a room for me.
Yeah, what else would I do?
Dell, later we're gonna have a talk.
And I mean a come-to-Jesus talk.
You're not my mother, Naomi.
You're not even my boss.
Everybody's patience
is wearing thin, Dell.
- What?
- Hey, Naomi won't push this, I will.
Leave. Take the day.
Get it together, Dell.
I'd just found out about Bill's affair.
From his e-mail.
There were lots of e-mails
from different women.
Pictures.
They were all so young.
And I was feeling old and insecure.
- And Bobby?
- He just got transferred into my class.
The way he looked at me, it just...
It just made me feel better.
He'd find reasons to stay after
and I'd help him with his homework.
When we wanted a break,
we'd just start talking.
For hours.
I tried to get him to focus
on girls his own age.
He kept coming back to me.
I know, but you're the adult.
You should have stopped him.
I love him.
Oh, look, I know it's wrong.
But when I thought something
was gonna happen to him in the...
This is a crime,
and we should be reporting it.
SAM: Yeah, bottom line,
you can't see him anymore.
- If you do...
- Yeah, don't.
Okay.
[NOAH SIGHS]
I hate heart transplants.
You're basically waiting
for someone to die
to save the person who you wanna live.
It's horrible
to have to sit and wait and sit.
And not be in control.
Well, you can only do so much.
And if you've got a baby?
A baby who could die,
you're content to just chalk it all up to fate?
No. Then it's on me.
Exactly.
We are the ultimate narcissists.
Life and death is all up to us.
No wonder so many doctors
are insufferable.
Am I?
I think you're one of the good ones.
[PAGERS BEEPING AND VIBRATING]
When they brought him in,
I recognized him and I paged you.
It's Phillip, Janine's husband.
He's comatose. No corneal reflexes.
- Type two diabetic. Tox screen negative.
- What happened?
Glucose was initially less than ten.
Looks like an insulin overdose.
EEG shows no evidence
of any brain activity.
He's brain-dead.
Oh, my God, do you think...?
[ADDISON SIGHS]
- What?
- He's an organ donor.
- Can I help you?
- I'm fine, thank you.
I like the atmosphere.
Open, friendly, comfortable.
Uh, what are you doing here?
I told you I was not interested.
Well, I figured I'd check out exactly
what you're holding onto.
Well, that's not a very good idea, so...
Because of the other Dr. Bennett?
I read his book. Don't worry.
As far as he knows, I'm a patient.
I doubt he thinks
that I'm trying to get you pregnant.
And you should go.
Lunch tomorrow.
You are pushing.
I'm a man who knows what he wants.
Aren't you popular these days.
What?
- The guy you were just talking to.
- Oh, no.
He's just... He's a patient, so...
Good night, Sam.
Good night.
I can't. I can't breathe.
I can't think.
What am I gonna do without Phillip?
Janine, I know this is unthinkably hard.
And none of us could possibly imagine.
It's awful.
But I need you to focus right now.
Focus on the baby that you're carrying,
the baby that you and Phillip created.
Because if you don't do this,
you both could die.
My husband is dead and you want me
to take his heart to save myself?
- To save both of you.
- I can't.
How could I?
Janine, listen to me.
It's hard for anyone to fathom.
But the heart is a machine.
A heart is tissue that provides
a hugely important function.
It is not your husband.
You are not taking from him.
He is providing for you.
It's what he'd want, you know it is.
Phillip's death is tragic,
but it's giving you a chance.
Now you need to get over your fear
and do this.
If not for you, for the baby.
And for you.
He's my brother.
And I haven't even digested that
because I know that there's
something more important right now.
We can't save him.
We can save you.
Once the heart's out,
we've got four to six hours to get it in.
Montgomery, Barnes, hold it.
Don't you dare touch him.
You're not removing his heart.
How is she? Donna?
Um, I don't know.
You know, we need to focus on you.
We're gonna get you better.
I keep texting her. She won't answer.
I get it, Bobby.
People fall for their teachers.
It wasn't like that.
I didn't have a crush on her.
We started talking, and it was real.
Have you ever talked to a teenage girl,
Dr. Freedman?
It's like deciphering code.
This was a real conversation.
Even so, given the age difference...
Why are people so hung up on age?
Donna.
- You're not supposed to be here.
- I know, I just...
- Donna.
- Hey, could you give us a minute?
Um, no, I really can't.
- Please?
- We had a deal.
BOBBY:
I want you to go.
Mrs. Keating?
I just wanted to make sure
Bobby was feeling better.
- Dr. Freedman, is there a problem?
- No, there's no problem.
She's here to see me.
I think you need to go, Donna, now.
I never meant to hurt him.
I don't understand.
- I love her.
- You're sleeping with our son?
Leave, now.
- I'm sorry.
- Now.
[CHUCKLING]
[PETE SIGHS]
What?
You know the woman
you met this morning?
Violet, the pregnant woman.
Yeah?
We're not together.
But there's a chance that it's my baby.
Look, I like you,
and I wanna start things off being open.
She doesn't know who the father is?
You know... Um...
It's a long story.
What are you thinking?
Do you know how hard it is
for a single mom to find a man
who's smart and funny and likes kids?
Someone who likes me and my son,
who doesn't just think he's in the way?
I like you, Pete.
This feels good and right.
So it's not the end of the world.
But I have Ben,
and I have to protect him.
So I guess what I really need to know is,
what are you thinking?
Where's your head at, Montgomery?
Woman needs a heart, can't find one.
Suddenly her husband drops dead,
bam, you got one.
- Awfully convenient.
- Yes, it's very coincidental, Charlotte.
And perhaps we could ponder
just how coincidental it is if we had time.
- But we don't.
- His wife is deteriorating.
She needs that heart now.
If we wait, she'll die.
Insulin overdose is a well-known cause
of death in diabetics.
Accidental overdose or on purpose?
Because this hospital will not condone
suicide to provide organs.
Or be party to destroying evidence
if it wasn't an accident.
I want someone from the ME's office
to collect trace evidence from the body
and find me a cause of death.
Before you touch him.
If he was murdered,
we destroy evidence...
- We don't have time, Charlotte.
CHARLOTTE: We'll make time.
I'm not letting a murder get away
just so you can have your heart.
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
Dr. Gordon, please call the OR.
Donna.
You've got to go home.
I know, but I can't.
He needs me. I need him.
No, this has got to end.
Now, his parents are...
What were you thinking?
I screwed up, Sam. You ever do that?
You see the train wreck
and you just keep going
because it makes you
forget everything?
We all do, but you've gotta turn back.
You gotta turn back now.
COP: Donna Keating?
DONNA: Yes.
COP:
You're under arrest for statutory rape.
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will be
used against you in the court of law.
ADDISON: He's been in there
for over an hour, Charlotte.
NOAH:
You gotta get him out of here.
CHARLOTTE:
You need to wait. He's doing his job.
NOAH:
Her pressure's dropping.
ADDISON:
Baby's showing signs of distress.
NOAH:
We have to do this now.
[CHARLOTTE SIGHS]
CHARLOTTE:
Do you have everything you need?
PATHOLOGIST:
I'll be done shortly.
ADDISON: You've taken his blood,
photos, scoured his entire body.
NOAH: Can't you get the rest of what
you need after we take the heart?
- I'll take that as a yes.
ADDISON: Charlotte?
Charlotte.
CHARLOTTE: Do it.
ADDISON: Let's go.
NOAH:
I'm gonna scrub in.
Have him ready for incision
in three minutes.
- Hey.
Love is a bitch.
For you or for Lolita's brother?
I know this is crazy,
but I think Donna really loves him.
- You're turning into a romantic.
- I've always been a romantic.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Ah... You... Oh, now that really hurts.
- That really hurts me.
- Okay.
- You can take it.
- No, I'm talking to you.
What? It's polite.
- What?
- Sure, okay.
[ELEVATOR DOOR CLOSES]
Who was that guy
by the elevator last night?
What are you talking about?
Woman, look, I was married to you
for 12 years, all right?
I know when you're hiding
something from me.
I mean, if you want to blow off Duncan,
I'm all for it.
Just don't hide it from me.
Duncan and I are fine.
I thought we were good.
- Telling each other everything.
- We're good, Sam.
- All right.
- We are.
- We're good.
- Yeah. Okay.
His airways are clear
and there's no indication
of any residual damage
from the asthma attacks.
Awesome. I can go to soccer today?
Oh, rest the engines, bud.
Next week, okay?
I didn't mean
to put pressure on you last night.
I just... I think you're a good guy.
And you told me the truth.
I really appreciate that.
I just want this to work.
Okay.
Oh, Violet, hi.
Hey. I just came to check up on you.
But, wow, she really loves you.
She has dreams about me.
- Sex dreams?
- Yes.
I thought I was making progress.
We went over it yesterday.
But then Anita says
that we've been so close for so long,
she can't stand not expressing
what she feels anymore.
And that it may seem crazy to me,
but she wants me bad.
So damn bad.
- I'm quoting her.
- That's excellent, Sheldon.
- Now you're mocking me.
- No.
No, she's saying to you
what she can't say to her co-worker.
You have to get her to talk to him.
If she has feelings
and she doesn't tell the other person,
it's a missed opportunity.
You know what, Violet? You're good.
Clearly, so are you.
I'm scared.
ADDISON: Dr. Barnes says
the heart's taking. You can do this, Janine.
You and the baby are gonna be fine.
It's not that. It's Malcolm.
He's been there for me.
Everything I've ever needed,
every time I've needed anything.
He would do anything for me.
Well, why does that scare you?
I think...
I know he loves me.
But he's in love with me.
He's never done anything
or said anything, it's...
Phillip is gone.
And I needed a heart.
Then Phillip died.
Look, I don't wanna think it,
I don't even wanna believe it,
but do you think Malcolm killed him?
For me?
Hey. What are you doing here?
Uh, I didn't feel like being at the office.
And, you know, I heard about Phillip.
I wanted to see how Malcolm was,
and Janine.
Something happened?
Janine thinks that Phillip's death, that...
She thinks that Malcolm
may have killed him.
She says
that Malcolm's in love with her.
I mean, well, yeah.
I mean, I could have told you that part.
- What, you didn't see it?
- I don't know.
I mean, he's good to her, but...
Well, he's also a nurse,
so he'd know how much insulin to use.
He'd know what they'd look for,
what would look normal.
We're talking about Phillip's brother.
No, we're talking about
watching someone slip away.
Someone that you love.
William, I am flattered.
I really am, but you're asking me
to orphan my baby, and I can't.
Oceanside is not just a job.
These people are my family, so...
I saw that yesterday.
And while I admire it,
I have to think of my own family.
I love them, which is why I live
3,000 miles away from them.
So they don't interfere with my life.
Well, Sam's not like that.
We're, um...
I can tell him anything.
Does he know you're here?
There's no one else on my list,
Dr. Bennett.
I'll be back in two weeks
to make an official offer.
L...
SAM:
Donna.
Is everything all right?
My husband posted bail.
His parting gift.
He's done with me.
I'm sorry. Come to my office.
[CELL PHONE CHIMES]
What?
It's Bobby.
He says he wants us to go off together.
And he doesn't care
about his parents, school, anything.
All he cares about is us, me.
The thought of it right now,
to escape everything?
- I wish I could.
- Well, you know that you can't.
I love him, Sam. He's all I have.
- What's wrong with me?
- Nothing's wrong...
You can't help love, I get that.
But if you love Bobby,
you gotta let this go.
How do I do that?
Dr. Montgomery, how's the baby?
I just checked their chart,
and they're both doing fine.
It's hard watching her
go through all this pain.
Losing Phillip, maybe the baby.
That baby means everything to her.
Well, at least she has you.
- Is there something bothering you?
- No. Yes.
The timing of this, of Phillip dying
in a way that kept his heart pumping.
You think he killed himself for her?
You think I killed him.
I think there's a fine line
between miracle and convenience,
and I think about this pregnancy
and how I got to know Janine and you.
- And not Phillip.
- He pushed me to be there.
And you let him.
Here was this wonderful, sweet woman
feeling alone in her marriage.
And there was Phillip,
not deserving what he had.
Not appreciating what he had.
But he had it. He had her.
So I wanted something I couldn't have.
Don't tell me you've never felt that way.
I loved my brother.
But he wasn't good enough for her.
But if he's dead, at least she's alive.
Hey, you all right?
You know, Malcolm might have killed
his brother for someone that he loved.
And me? I can't even find her, Pete.
Betsey.
All I know is St. Louis.
You know, Heather is working
for a company in St. Louis,
but I don't know who Betsey's with
or where she's living
or what she thinks about me, and...
I mean, as far as she knows,
her father's gone.
That's horrible, Dell.
But Heather was in a good place
when she left, and she loves Betsey.
But she's my child.
You'll know.
When Violet's baby is born, you'll know.
And you...
I bet you'd do anything.
I mean, what kind of man am I
that I just sit here and watch?
Just because you haven't found her yet,
doesn't mean you won't.
- Hi.
What's going on?
I wanna believe
that it won't be a problem.
That I can be there for you
and Ben and the baby.
Yeah, the baby has to come first.
I get that.
I can make that work.
I need to be there for both of them.
For the baby and for Violet.
[SIGHS]
Okay, well,
I guess it's better you know now
before anyone gets hurt.
I'd like to keep treating Ben.
I don't want this to affect him.
Uh...
I don't know, Pete.
- Hey, you are testing Phillip's blood?
- Mm-hm.
Why? I mean, the ME's doing that.
I think he did it. Malcolm.
I think he murdered his brother
and I need evidence.
I need proof.
Addison, we just pulled off
the unthinkable.
I mean, two lives were almost gone,
and then a heart dropped in our laps.
Now they're gonna live. It's a miracle.
You and I did it.
Can't we just focus on that?
I can't.
Phillip's dead
and Malcolm might get to be with Janine.
Why's he gotta be a bad guy?
Maybe he's just a guy
who didn't get along with his brother.
You told me he was a good guy.
Good people don't murder their brothers
and then get to sleep with their wives.
Can't they just be two people in love?
I mean, why try and tear them apart?
Okay, Noah, there are lines and rules
and things that you can't do.
I mean, they shouldn't be together.
It's wrong.
Autopsy results came back.
ME ruled it
an accidental insulin overdose.
Guess it all worked out.
- I still think he did it.
- There isn't any proof.
You kissed me back.
You're angry at me.
You say that I'm at fault.
But it isn't just that I kissed you.
It's that you kissed me back.
That's why you're angry.
Thank you for letting me talk to him.
BOBBY:
What's going on?
Bobby, honey, listen to me.
- As soon as they leave.
DONNA: They can't, Bobby.
Don't let them tell you that.
Don't let them make you feel this is wrong.
I'm twice your age.
Age doesn't matter, Donna. I love you.
You're 17, and I was in a really bad place
and I needed you, but I don't love you.
You're lying.
They're making you say this.
Bobby, you have your whole life
ahead of you.
No one's saying that this isn't real,
what you feel.
What we both feel. You know it.
No, I'm sorry.
Bobby, I know that you love her.
But sometimes the best thing to do
when you love someone and it's not right
is to just let go and move on.
- Charlotte.
- William.
- I had no idea you were in town.
- Just a bit of business.
I wanted to check in and see
how my practice was doing.
There were some bumps,
but I'm feeling good
about where things are heading.
Patient bookings are strong.
Good, good. I'm glad to hear it.
That's all you wanted?
I'll be back in a couple weeks. You can
bring me up to speed on everything then.
You were right.
I wasn't being honest.
And I think maybe I should be.
You know what I think?
I think that what we're doing is too hard.
We're divorced,
but I still care about you.
And hearing about everybody you're dating
and what you're doing, it's just...
It's not good, for either of us.
You said you could handle it.
I mean, I thought we were friends.
I know I did, and we are. But I...
When your dating pool
is everybody that I know,
Archer, Bryce, Duncan,
there's a limit, Nai.
And maybe I said I could handle it,
but I can't and I shouldn't have to.
- So, what are you saying?
- We can't be friends anymore.
I need some distance.
To let go. To move on.
- You want distance.
- I need it.
Don't you?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Pete.
Oh, Sheldon, what happened?
Anita thought
I was gonna confess my love.
When I insisted her feelings were
misplaced, she beat me with the roses.
- It was great.
- It was great?
I forced her.
I pushed her to a breakthrough, Violet.
And when she saw what she did to me,
she broke down.
She realized she'd spent so much money
on gifts for the wrong person.
She called her co-worker from the office,
and they're having dinner.
Wow. You should feel so proud,
Sheldon.
You know,
you gotta put something on that.
But that's not the best part. The best part
is I had a breakthrough of my own.
When someone has feelings
and doesn't let the other person know,
that's a missed opportunity.
But isn't that what I said before?
Yes. And I convinced Anita,
but then I realized that it applied to me.
I'm in love with you, Violet.
From the first time we rode
on that elevator.
I don't care whose child you're carrying.
I can talk to you about anything.
I wanna talk to you about everything.
And when I'm not with you, I'm empty.
Will you marry me?