Previously on "ER"
No!
Give him back to me!
Give him to me! Coco.
Group therapy
in your first week?
God, all I did
was observe the
first two weeks of
my psych rotation.
I'm going to have a baby.
I heard there might
be a surgical trauma
fellowship run
out of the ER.
It was my idea.
I brought it to
Greene and Weaver.
I‐I need time for Reese.
Don't use him as an excuse
to screw me over.
I'll find something else.
No, no, I don't want you
to forfeit it to me.
If you want it,
by all means, you go for it.
I'll still get it.
‐ Morning, Carol.
‐ Morning.
Did you see that
beautiful blue sky?
Oh, not yet. I came in
when it was still dark.
‐ Cracker?
‐ No, thanks.
What are you doing?
I woke up with
an urge to clean.
Do you realize this
peritoneal lavage kit
expired in 1996?
Listen, if your
symptoms persist
maybe you could work
your magic on the admit area.
Yeah, I think I've, uh,
been cured, thanks.
Well, it's worth a shot.
‐ Morning, doc.
‐ Morning.
‐ Whoa.
‐ I'm sorry. Excuse me.
Uh, no, it's my fault. I wasn't
looking where I was going.
You're looking bright.
Oh, well, uh, yeah
I'm presenting on a
panel this afternoon
at the Chicago Society
Of Trauma Physicians.
Well, I'll stop griping
about having to attend.
What's your topic?
Ultrasound versus CT
in blunt abdominal trauma.
Got some promising
findings, actually.
I look forward to it.
Ow!
Hey, man, you want to try
getting it to me next time?
Proper way
to throw a Frisbee
is off the middle finger,
side‐arm.
For me, it's the, uh
flick of the wrist
that gives it that rotation.
Great catch.
For me, the key to Frisbee
is a light touch.
So you're on
your way to work.
Yes, my shift begins
in 15 minutes
and today's my last day.
Oh, I thought everything
was going well with the INS.
Oh, it is. I got amnesty.
‐ Congratulations.
‐ Thank you.
I'm going to school to get my
civil engineering license.
You and Kubby are gonna
stay here in Chicago?
‐ Yes.
‐ Great.
Carol, do you know anything
about this woman, Coco Robbins?
Oh, yeah. Her and her baby
are coming into the
clinic today, right?
She's schizophrenic
and social services
is having us monitor
her baby care?
Well, I had to make sure
she's taking her meds.
Well, it's a pretty risky
proposition, isn't it?
She deserves a chance.
So this was your idea?
Don't worry about it, Lynette.
I am in touch
with the halfway house
where her
and her baby are living.
And I'll volunteer to be there
for all her appointments.
You asked me to be responsible
for the clinic, remember?
And I didn't know
anything about this.
You're right.
I'm sorry.
I should have told you about
the arrangements I'd made.
No, Carol.
You should have asked.
She's due in a few minutes.
Hey, what are you guys doing?
Drafting teams for
rotisserie baseball.
Do you want in?
Oh, can I, uh,
draft Ken Griffey?
‐ He's mine.
‐ I already got Sammy Sosa.
'Cause he's got
the cutest buns in baseball.
Carter! How would you like
to perform a righteous act
and make me
a happy man all at once?
Alright.
Dean signed us on
for a mentoring project
at the Math‐Science
Magnet School.
It's PR, you know,
they put some of their
top high school students
into area hospitals
like a, uh, an independent
study program.
So we're getting one
whether we like it or not.
What I need you
to do is hold his hand
and give him
a few errands to run.
‐ Ah, okay.
‐ Good.
Uh, it is a public school,
but I'm assured
that the kid is not
a convicted felon.
When's this all
supposed to take place?
Any time now.
Kid's name is Antoine.
‐ Oh, today?
‐ Yeah.
And don't
leave him unattended
around the drug lockup.
‐ Thank you.
‐ What's wrong?
Uh, nothing.
Are you back with us?
No, I'm still in psych.
You'll be back
doing real medicine soon
so don't get too used
to the cush life.
Yeah, I won't.
Sally McKenna?
Did they get the glass
out of his eye?
The doctor's still
with your husband.
My name is Lucy Knight.
I'm a student doctor
in psychiatry.
Can I ask you
a few questions?
Listen, Michael's
been very stressed out.
I mean, he's in law school
um, but he's never done
anything like this before.
The doctor said
he attacked a car?
He was working on a paper
for the last few days
so I‐I left him alone,
and today I woke up
and‐and he was in the street
smashing our car
with an aluminum bat.
And does Michael
have any history
of psychiatric problems?
No, not at all.
Michael ever
use any drugs?
No. Never.
I mean, he'll drink a few beers,
but I mean, a few beers
doesn't make a person freak out
like that, you know.
I mean, I‐I think it's just,
it's just a build up of stress.
Well, I will go talk
to your husband
as soon as the ER docs
are done with him.
'Hey, Jeanie.'
‐ Still doing triage?
‐ Uh‐huh.
‐ So, how you feeling?
‐ Not bad.
Any, uh, side effects
from the ribavirin?
No.
Nausea? Fatigue?
Peter, please. I'm fine.
Well, you look a little tired.
Listen, why don't you
let me check your LFT's
if the hep meds aren't working
then, the sooner
we know, the better.
I've got a lab appointment
this afternoon.
Listen, if, um, you
know, if you need me..
Thanks. Excuse me, I've got
patients I need to triage.
Carol, your appointment
hasn't shown up.
What?
Coco Robbins and her baby
they're late.
‐ Did she call?
‐ No, but I tried calling her.
No one at the halfway house
has seen her all morning.
Maybe I should go over there.
Maybe you should
call children
and family services
or the police.
God, I didn't think
she'd do this.
If she doesn't stay on meds,
there's nothing we can do.
'Hey, Carol.'
There's someone here
to see you, a Coco Robbins.
Coco.
Are you all right?
Where have you been?
On my way here.
I know I'm early
but I wasn't sure
I should bother you.
‐ Early?
‐ 12:00 noon?
Yeah, they wrote
it down for me.
Oh. I must have written
it down wrong in the book.
Is it still okay?
Yeah, it's fine.
Nurse Hathaway will take
you into the clinic.
‐ Come on, Coco. How's he doing?
‐ Really good.
‐ He's so beautiful, isn't he?
‐ He is beautiful.
‐ Morning, Peter.
‐ Hey.
I understand the trauma
fellowship's going to happen.
And Anspaugh's made
a formal announcement.
Look, I'm‐I'm sorry
I came down so hard on you
about your interest.
It was really
silly of me to be
so proprietary about it.
Well, apparently
they're expecting
at least 15 applicants.
Really?
So, um, have you given up
the cardiothoracic?
'Hmm?'
Haven't made up my mind yet.
Well, by all means
feel free to apply
for the trauma fellowship.
I appreciate that.
If you do,
we have the inside track.
You know, home team advantage.
Yeah.
So, um,
are you planning on going
to the trauma conference
this afternoon?
No, I couldn't get away.
Romano has me doing
a keyhole cardiac bypass.
Oh, very fancy.
Well, I don't think
you'll be missing much.
I understand it's
a rather dull affair.
Yeah, yeah, probably.
Okay. Well, if you'll excuse me
I have a partial gastrectomy
to get to.
Lucy, tell me
about Michael McKenna
that patient who
smashed up his car.
I was just
going in to see him.
You haven't worked
him up yet?
The ER just
got done with him.
Okay, Lucy, what I need
you for is to pull
all the information
and present the patient
so I can come down
and quickly decide
if they need to be
admitted or medicated.
How long do you expect it will
take you to get to Mr. McKenna?
‐ 15 minutes.
‐ I'll see you in ten.
Enjoying your psych rotation?
I guess you heard that.
A little advice,
as a med student
your job is to get
to know patients
not be hand servant
to your resident
and work up all
his patients for him.
But the med students
who help their residents
get better grades.
Now is the time to learn about
talking and listening
to patients.
Don't let that
get lost in the shuffle.
‐ Right. Thanks.
‐ You're welcome.
Her chest sounds
a little tight.
She'll need to stay for
an albuterol treatment.
‐ 'Will she be okay?'
‐ She'll be fine.
Hey, Nita. It's
Reverend Lynn.
Would you cancel
all my morning appointments?
Yeah, looks like
I'll be here for a while.
Yeah, right. Bye.
Sorry this is
taking so long.
You're obviously busy.
I can wait.
How'd you do that
to your thumb?
Hammering the gutter
on my church.
It hurts like hell.
‐ I'm Matthew Lynn.
‐ Hi. Jeanie Boulet.
‐ You're a minister?
‐ South street AME.
Do you know it?
I'm not much
of a church goer.
I had my fill as a child
being told what I couldn't do.
I hear you.
You have
a subungual hematoma
a collection of blood
under your nail.
It's a simple procedure
to drain it
so I will call a doctor
and give you something
for the pain.
Looks like you also have
some swollen joints.
Rheumatoid arthritis.
I've had it for years.
I take a bunch of pills
for the inflammation
then I take another bunch
to keep the first bunch
from giving me an ulcer.
That's not much fun.
Oh, I'm pretty lucky.
I've seen worse.
Well, I would lay off
the hammering for a while.
I don't want you having
another accident.
I don't believe in accidents.
If I hadn't hit my thumb,
we would never have met.
So this is
a divine intervention.
Something like that.
‐ You Antoine Bell?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Ah, I'm Dr. Carter.
‐ How you doing?
‐ Alright.
You'll be spending
some time with us
this next couple
of weeks, huh?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
‐ Come on, I'll show you around.
Well, it's slow right now
but that can always change.
Sorry, I can't make
the trauma conference.
I have a conflict
with the executive committee.
I'll cauterize that bleeder
in the abdominal wall.
Mm‐hmm.
If you like, I can leave a copy
of my talk in your office.
You know, I found the positive
predictive value of ultrasound
is actually higher
than previously reported.
Excellent.
And by the way
what did you think
of, uh, Peter's study?
Oh, he told me
he wasn't presenting today.
No, no, no, I'm talking
about the sternal saw paper
he and Kerry Weaver
had accepted
by the Annals
Of Emergency Medicine.
‐ Quite provocative.
‐ Really?
Yes, it could attract
the grant money we'll be needing
to keep the trauma
fellowship running.
Hmm.
I look forward to reading it.
'Michael? Hi.'
I'm Lucy Knight.
‐ How are you feeling?
‐ Pretty embarrassed.
I'm from psychiatry and I just
wanna talk to you briefly.
So, law school's been pretty
rough going, your wife said?
It has, but I got out of my
system what I needed to get out
and I'm fine now.
I've felt like
smashing things before.
What got you to the point
where you actually did it?
Uh, you know,
pressure, uh, things.
And how have the
last few days been?
Just, formulating my thoughts.
And how do you cope
with your stress, usually?
Not much can be done.
Do you ever
have a drink?
Maybe a few beers?
I‐I do.
And have you been
drinking more recently
to cope with
the stress?
How much have you had to drink
in the last few days?
Drinking...helps.
Oh, god.
It‐it helps you relax?
Uh, It helps 'em be..
...more quiet.
Who does it make more quiet?
My demons.
You don't believe me, but..
...I hear them.
Are you hearing them now?
Michael?
I'll call Dr. Myers.
I would never hurt my wife.
I'm stronger than they are.
They..
I wouldn't do what they said.
I hit the car instead.
They wanted me
to do it to her, but..
...I hit the car.
He took three ounces
of Enfamil 20 with iron
at 4:25 this morning
and he burped at 4:47.
He peed at 5:05...
you're writing this all down?
‐ Is that okay?
‐ Of course.
I just want to make sure people
see that I'm getting
it all right.
‐ Look.
‐ Could you listen to his heart?
It beats so fast.
Babies' hearts
beat faster than adults.
It's perfectly normal.
'Oh, good, I just,
I thought maybe something'
was wrong, which is why
I came a little early.
No, he's fine.
Aren't you?
Sometimes he spits up
a little after he eats.
Mm‐hmm, which is
perfectly normal
for a happy, healthy baby.
You can relax, Coco,
he's doing great.
And you're doing great.
I think he's
a very lucky little boy.
I have to do right with this.
Better than..
Better than right.
I know, and you are.
If something goes wrong,
I know I'll lose him.
You taking your meds?
Yeah, yeah. It's right here.
Look at my journal.
Everything's going good
at the halfway house?
Great. There's another woman
there with a two‐month‐old girl.
Everyone's so nice.
They just love having
these little babies around.
What's not to love?
Any questions?
You'll be back in two days?
Two days, 10:00 a.m.
I'll be here.
You'll have to do better
controlling your temper
Mr. Pipitone, no more
putting your foot
through picture frames.
Yeah, my passion got
the better of me.
What can I tell you?
She's lucky that's all
I put my foot through.
‐ You married?
‐ Divorced.
‐ Dating anybody steady?
‐ Not right now.
There you go, fast and loose.
Don't let them get
their hooks into you.
From the age they grow boobs
till the day they die
they can make you crazy.
‐ Do I tell the truth?
‐ Yep.
Alright, it looks like
you're going to have
to stay off this foot
for a couple of weeks.
A couple of weeks?
No, doc, I can't do that.
I got to get back out
on the dance floor.
I go ballroom dancing
a couple, three times a week.
'Really?'
‐ You dance?
‐ No.
What you got
against dancing?
It'll turn you
into a chick magnet.
I'd like to dance.
I just never learned how.
Except for my wedding.
I learned to tango.
Ah, the tango.
You know what I mean.
Alright, Mr. Pipitone.
I'll check in
with you later.
Two weeks, huh?
‐ Uh, with the foot?
‐ Two weeks.
Hey, Carter. Where's your
scared straight kid?
I wanna give him the obligatory
tour of the morgue.
He's not a scared straight kid.
He's from the Math‐Science
Magnet School.
Really?
Who said he was
a scared straight kid?
No one. My mistake.
If you see him, tell him
I'm looking for him.
Hey, Antoine, we got
a trauma coming in.
Paramedics are bringing in
a stabbing victim.
We're going to take him into
that trauma room right there
and I want you to follow
along, alright?
‐ Just hang back.
‐ Alright.
Seth Willows?
Here we are.
Mrs. Willows?
No. My name is
Leila Morgan.
This is my
foster son, Seth.
Hi, Seth.
I'm nurse Hathaway.
'What happened here?'
He put his hand
through a window.
‐ Can I take a look?
‐ No.
‐ It won't hurt.
‐ No!
Seth, stop.
Stop this!
‐ Carol, you okay?
‐ Yep.
Okay, Seth
why don't you take a seat?
Sit down right
there now, please.
I'm so sorry.
We're having such trouble
with him.
I'm gonna get him into an exam
room take a look at the hand.
I'm also going to call
for a psych consult.
We got a 55 year old man
stabbed in the neck
during a robbery,
BP's 135/82, pulse 110.
Airway seems okay.
Alright, we got
a zone two neck injury.
Good carotid pulse.
Can you see?
What else about the third man?
Was he big, small?
‐ Skinny, not big.
‐ 'Excuse me, sir.'
Are you usually
hoarse like this?
No.
Alright, could be
a nerve injury.
Yeah, or an expanding hematoma.
Call X‐ray.
I need a neck film.
Pulse ox 96.
'You wanna explore
him in the OR?'
'No, he's pretty stable.'
Skinny and what
else, Mr. Cho?
What was he wearing?
I don't know. Dark clothes.
Alright, on my count.
One, two, three.
He needs a tetanus booster.
Gram of ancef?
No, let's give him
three of unasyn.
‐ Why wasn't I paged?
‐ Didn't need you.
Okay, here's the plan.
Chest is clear.
We need an angiography,
esophagoscopy, laryngoscopy.
Well, I think we should
protect his airway first.
Hold on, hold on, I'm covering
the ER, alright?
Fine. I'm finished here.
'Chuny, draw up four of versed
and ten of Norcuron.'
Sir, we're giving
you some medicine.
'It's gonna make you sleep,
when you wake up'
there's gonna be a tube
in your mouth.
And you won't be able to speak.
No, no, I got to finish
with the descriptions.
No, he needs
to be sedated and intubated.
His wife is DOA at the scene
the killers are at large.
Just give me a minute
to get all the
description that he can give us.
Please.
Alright.
Mr. Cho, the teenager
was he dark‐skinned?
Light‐skinned?
'Medium.'
Going my way?
If you're going
up to the OR, I am.
Why so glum
on this bright spring day?
I've got a lot on my mind.
Would that be
the trauma fellowship
I hear you've applied for?
Might be.
Oh, I'll have
to invite myself
to sit on the selection
committee.
Anspaugh says you've got
a fighting chance.
Well, I did have
before Peter decided to apply.
Peter's applied
for the trauma fellowship?
Yeah. Haven't you heard?
No. I must be out of the loop.
Well, I'm sure he was
planning on telling you.
Yes, I'm sure it was
just an oversight.
'Oh.'
I am so sorry for the wait.
Someone will be in soon.
The sun is shining,
the birds are singing
and after that Vicodin,
I'm feeling no pain.
Wait.
Why don't you do my,
what did you call it?
Uh, subungual hematoma.
I see you're
a physician assistant.
Well, I'm working triage today.
You said it's
a very simple procedure.
To tell you the truth, I'm not
doing procedures anymore.
Anymore?
I have Hepatitis C,
Reverend Lynn
and I don't want to
risk infecting you.
How could you infect me?
Well, if I cut myself‐‐
Cut yourself?
On what?
I thought
you just needed to drain
the blood blister.
That's true.
So, if you're careful,
it shouldn't be any problem.
Right.
You remember,
I don't believe in accidents.
Hmm?
What happened
to your kid, Carter?
You think the blood
freaked him out?
Maybe the cop freaked him out.
What was he
locked up for, anyway?
Listen, Antoine is not
a juvenile offender.
He attends the Southside
Math‐Science High School
and he's here for
an independent study project.
‐ Oh.
‐ Hmm.
Hi, I'm Lucy Knight
and this must be Seth.
Hey, Seth, how
you doing in there?
I've only had
him a few weeks.
He got kicked out
of a group home.
I thought I'd
take him on.
I've handled
some tough ones.
‐ 'And why was he kicked out?'
‐ 'He's too much of a handful.'
He's been shuttled from foster
home to foster home
for the past three years.
How are you feeling, Seth?
I'm sorry about him
kicking that nurse.
I gave him some Inderal.
He shouldn't try to attack you.
'Oh, he's on Inderal?'
'Yeah, they just put him on
it. That's the latest.'
And what other medications
is he on?
Well, this is what they gave
me at the group home.
Tegretol to control
his impulsiveness
uh, Ritalin and clonidine
'for attention deficit.'
'And Mellaril at bedtime
to calm him down.'
Sounds like he's being
overmedicated.
Hey, Seth,
do you want a cookie?
So, how are things going?
Okay.
Do you ever get dizzy sometimes?
Sometimes I do get
a buzzy feeling in my head.
‐ Do you find that he's clumsy?
‐ He can be.
That's what happened here.
He fell against a window
and put his hand
'through trying to break
the fall.'
'This wasn't
from an outburst.'
I've been looking for you.
You took off right in the middle
of all the action.
Was it the recurrent
laryngeal nerve?
That Korean,
you said he had a nerve injury
that made him hoarse.
Was it the recurrent
laryngeal nerve
that got injured?
Yeah, probably.
Supplies the vocal cord muscles.
That's right.
I like this book.
Frank Putnam, puncture
wound below the nipple.
Tripped and fell on a sprinkler
head while jogging.
BP is 95/65,
pulse 120.
Decreased breath sounds
on the left.
Hurts to take a breath.
Prep for a chest tube,
32 french.
‐ Where's my wife?
‐ She's on her way.
Okay, everybody,
on my count.
‐ One, two, three. You okay?
‐ Yeah.
‐ I just pinched my finger.
‐ It's all her fault.
Betadine, number ten blade,
and one of versed.
‐ It's all who's fault?
‐ My wife.
Forcing me to exercise.
'I should have stayed
on the couch.'
Carol, chest tube tray.
'It's a beautiful day,
she says.'
'You should be
out of the house.'
'That's the last time
I listen to her.'
'Okay, Mr. Putnam,
now just relax.'
‐ You should finish your rounds.
‐ Oh, come on.
I'll be admitting
this patient anyway.
What have we got?
Uh, chest impalement,
sixth intercostal space.
There could be injuries
below the diaphragm.
Set up the ultrasound.
Abdomen's soft
and non‐tender.
I think it's just
a chest injury.
Well, we can't be
too sure, Peter.
Okay, tube's in.
Hook up the thoraseal, Carol.
Where's carol?
Pressure's 110, there's
no way he got the spleen.
Better safe than sorry.
200cc's out
of the chest tube.
Alright, no free fluid
in the abdomen
What did I tell you?
Fine. Still could have
nicked the diaphragm.
Didn't I say there
was no possibility of that?
Excuse me, are we taking
this guy up to the OR?
Yeah, I wanna
give him a laparotomy.
‐ 'Check his diaphragm‐‐'
‐ I'd prefer laparoscopy.
It's less invasive.
Yeah, but you might miss
a hollow viscus injury.
Okay, look, why don't
you guys take a moment
and figure out
what you want to do?
Mark, I need your help.
You okay?
I was cramping
and now I'm spotting.
Is it time
for your period?
No, Mark,
I'm pregnant.
Do you see a heartbeat?
Can't tell. It's hard
to get a good view.
Come on, Mark.
No.
'I don't see a heartbeat.'
'Oh, man.'
Carol, it's not necessarily
a blighted ovum.
It's probably just too early
to see with this.
I'll call radiology
and I'll set up an appointment
for a vaginal ultrasound,
alright?
So you, uh, planning on
going through the pregnancy?
I was hoping to, yeah.
What does Doug think?
Uh...I figured I'd
wait on that one.
You know, get through
the first trimester.
I mean, if I miscarry,
there's not much to tell.
He'd probably want
to know either way.
Yeah, and I will, I'll
tell him at some point.
Just trying to get used
to this myself right now
and...things are
complicated enough.
Okay.
I'll call
for that appointment.
Thanks, Mark.
'And you say he's
been irritable?'
Off and on, kind of grouchy
from all the spitting up
and his stomach
hurting, probably.
Has he lost any weight?
I think so,
now that you say that.
His pants used to be snug.
‐ And now they're looser.
‐ Where do you live?
'Some apartments
on cottage grove.'
'Pretty old building?'
Yeah, I'd say so.
Roaches be having
family reunions.
Peeling paint?
Peeling everything.
I bet Lonnie likes
to put things in his mouth.
Yeah, he do.
Has he been screened for lead?
Lead? No.
What's wrong with him, doctor?
Well, We're gonna
run some more tests.
Try and get a better sense
of what's wrong.
So let's get a CBC.
And a lead level.
Right.
I wanna try and find out
if Lonnie's symptoms
are a result of lead poisoning.
'Maybe from eating flakes
of paint, which kids do.'
But the, uh,
lead level results
won't be back for a couple
of days but there are things
we can learn from
the blood work.
Okay, whatever.
Just, make him better.
Mm‐hmm.
Ease up. Down.
'Dissect and mobilize
the internal mammary.'
‐ Got it.
‐ 'Excellent, Peter.'
'You definitely have
the dexterity'
'for cardiothoracic,
no doubt about it.'
This is amazing.
It's like operating
a marionette.
'The cutting edge
of cardiac bypass surgery.'
‐ 'Didn't I tell you?'
‐ 'You told me.'
Alright, let's keep flooding
the field with CO2.
We'll spoon up
the coronary artery
and lift it off
the anterior wall
and then we'll anastomose
the internal mammary
to the anterior descending
branch of the left coronary
make an end run
around the diseased artery.
You're familiar with
the concept of an "end run"
aren't you, Dr. Benton?
Of course I am.
Yes, I know that you are.
High levels
of lead can cause
basophilic stippling
in the blood cells.
And there it is.
‐ See this?
‐ Yep.
And the red cells
are hypochromic
or less red
than normal red cells
which is a sign
of anemia.
Anemia, low iron
in the hemoglobin.
That's right.
Red blood cells need iron
so they can deliver oxygen
to the tissues.
Right.
Kids who are
anemic lack iron
which makes it very easy
for the lead
to bind to the red
blood cells.
So you can see how this
puts kids like Lonnie
in a doubly bad position.
How?
Well, poor children are
more likely to be anemic
'because of inadequate diet'
'and poor kids are more likely'
'to be exposed to lead paint..'
Because of living
in older buildings
instead of newer ones.
Yes.
So this kid's
got lead poisoning?
Mm‐hmm.
Looks like
a pretty severe case.
Dr. Romano, are you upset
about something?
Why would I be upset?
I've been talking you up for
the cardiothoracic fellowship
to anybody who'll
listen to me.
and today I find out
you've thrown your hat
in the ring
for the ER trauma fellowship.
It's a bit confusing.
Well, I wasn't taking
the cardiothoracic fellowship
for granted.
Hmm. So the trauma fellowship
is just a fallback. I see.
And if you were selected
for both, you would choose?
Cardiothoracic.
Any indecision you're feeling
about your future, Dr. Benton
'I can help, just say
the word and I will take'
the cardiothoracic fellowship
off the table.
No. It's my first choice.
Just be clear, Peter.
'For your own sake..'
...and mine.
Carol,
radiology called.
They can see you at 5 'O Clock
for the ultrasound.
Great. Thanks.
Listen, why don't we
get out of here
take a walk,
grab a movie?
I thought you had to go
to a trauma conference.
Uh, who wants to
hang out in a room
with a bunch of doctors?
Go to the conference.
I'm fine.
I know. I just thought‐‐
Actually, I could use this time
by myself right now.
Alright.
But I'm around
if you need to talk.
I know.
Oh, I told Kerry that
you weren't feeling well
so if you have
to take off early.
Thanks, Mark.
Nurse Hathaway?
Coco, what are you doing
back here? Are you alright?
If I didn't do
something right with the baby
would you have to tell on me?
How you doing, Seth?
Got any more cookies?
Sure, I do.
I was talking to
your foster mom.
She seems like a
pretty nice lady.
What do you think?
She's new.
She said your natural mom
died a few years ago.
I never knew my dad.
It's hard to grow up
without a parent.
She died in a car crash.
It was my dad's fault.
That's an awful thing to happen.
Do you think about it a lot?
No.
Does it make you mad sometimes?
Got any more cookies?
That was my last one.
If you don't wanna talk about
your mom and dad
we don't have to.
Why do you want to?
I like talking to you.
I wanna know
what's on your mind.
My dad gets drunk a lot.
That's why you have stay with
foster parents sometimes, huh?
He's an alcoholic.
A lot of people
have that problem.
Makes it kind of tough
on you, though.
I only wish that my dad would
come and see me sometime.
'Taxi.'
Taxi!
‐ Come on!
‐ 'Taxi!'
Hey...taxi.
Tax..
Hey, hey! Thank you...
very much!
'Elizabeth?'
You alright?
I cannot get a cab
in this bloody city.
Listen, uh...
you could take the el.
It goes right near the hotel.
‐ You sure?
‐ Yeah, yeah.
I just, I wasn't sure
about the bath.
Nobody showed me.
I didn't know what to do.
Yes, you did. You knew to come
back and ask for help.
I was afraid to look stupid.
Well, you did the right thing.
Hi.
Just support him with
your hand, like that..
...and then just gently
wash him with a mild..
...soap. Yes.
You're good at this.
You must do it a lot.
No, not really.
You'll get good at it, too.
Here. Why don't
you give it a try?
Yes.
Oh, Hey, Dr. Carter.
Did you need me?
Yeah. Come on in.
Crackin' the whip on you, 'twan.
‐ Alright.
‐ Then we out.
Those friends of
yours from school?
Friends from the neighborhood.
You know, you don't have
to worry about the tie.
It's not necessary.
Oh, my mom said to wear it.
Have you ever had a
job before, Antoine?
No.
I realize that this isn't a job
but there's some things I feel
like I ought to tell you not..
...not to give you
a hard time, but..
...you're a bright person
these are things
you're going to have to learn
anyway. It might as well be now.
‐ Alright.
With any job that you
have in the future..
things are gonna
be expected of you
and that means you can't go
hangin' out with your buddies.
Oh, but I had a reason
for doing that, doc.
I don't wanna hear any reasons.
I'm not givin' you a hard time.
Just lettin' you know
what I expect of you, alright?
‐ Yes, sir.
‐ Alright.
‐ 'What's next?'
‐ Specificity.
No, uh, I got sensitivity.
It's a little crumpled.
I'll take it.
Methodologies?
No.
False negative rates?
Bingo.
Okay...outcomes?
Uh, it's got a footprint on it.
Looks kind of interesting.
Uh, it's, not very sexy.
It's just matter analysis.
Thought it might help me
bag the trauma fellowship.
Yeah, can't hurt.
It'd be better
if I had it published.
Look, I'm really sorry
about that chest wound today.
Why are you sorry?
You did a great job.
Yeah. The trauma room shouldn't
be a battleground for surgeons.
‐ Oh, you mean Peter.
‐ 'Yep.'
Well, that must be tough.
‐ 'What?'
‐ Competing with your boyfriend.
Not boyfriend. Just competing.
‐ I thought you two were..
‐ History.
I gotta get better sources.
This is us.
You think they'll
still let me speak?
Ten minutes, that's nothin'.
Yeah, I'm supposed
to go first.
Yeah, well, you were busy
saving someone in the ER.
Four hours ago?
Work with me here.
So why aren't we stopping?
I guess it doesn't
stop here on weekends.
Don't worry, we can get off
at the next stop.
‐ Does that feel better?
‐ Much.
You should be
taking care of people.
Not working up front checking
pulses and doing paperwork.
Hey, Jeanie, I'm sorry
it took so long.
I got held up in the OR.
Hey, Reverend Lynn,
how're you doing?
I can't complain.
Miss Boulet has been
taking good care of me.
You two know each other?
Since Peter was a little boy
with straight A's.
I haven't seen you
around lately.
Yeah, well, you know,
I've been pretty busy here
and taking care of Reese.
My mother used to attend
Reverend Lynn's church.
Are you the Jeanie
that worked with Mrs. Benton?
‐ I am.
‐ She spoke of you.
Just before she passed,
she told me you were her angel.
That you brought her comfort.
Yeah.
I'll never forget
how much you meant to my mother.
You see?
I told you we didn't meet
by accident.
So Dr. Benton and I
are both in your debt.
I'd like to offer
some healing prayers.
I need all the help I can get.
You mean right now?
While the spirit is moving.
Amen.
That wasn't so bad.
No.
Uh...conference room C.
‐ Which way?
‐ I don't know.
But you've been here before?
Yeah, but I don't know
the rooms.
Uh, conference rooms, right.
'...but I'm serious.'
'I'm gonna marry this girl.'
‐ Sorry.
‐ Let's get out of here.
Excuse me, could you tell us
where the trauma
physicians conference is?
‐ Did you check the directory?
‐ Uh, yeah, conference room C.
But there's
a wedding in there.
That's ballroom C. Conference
room C is on the lower level.
‐ Of course.
‐ Where's the elevator?
Through the bar.
‐ Makes sense.
‐ Thank you.
‐ Want a drink?
‐ Sure. We got time.
Oh, look, a giant pig
ice sculpture.
Oh! Sorry.
She's had a little
too much to drink.
So, are you here
for the conference?
This is taking too long.
‐ Yeah, let's take the stairs.
‐ Oh, good idea.
'You're terrible.'
Me? You're the one who
ran into them. Hurry up.
I'm in heels.
Yeah, well, take
them off, woman.
‐ Woman? Did you call me woman?
‐ Who, me?
Yeah, I'll let it slide seeing
as you rushed to my rescue.
Yeah, well,
I haven't saved you yet.
Well, at least we can
make an appearance.
It's a dead end.
Uh‐oh.
Ha ha ha, very funny.
No, really, it's locked.
You've got to be kidding me.
I think somebody didn't want us
to make this conference.
‐ 'Dr. Carter?'
‐ Mm‐hmm?
Um, could I see you over
here for a minute, please?
This is Sharice Haines
and this is her son Andre.
I think he might have
lead poisoning.
‐ Could you take a look?
‐ Sure.
‐ How you doing?
‐ Hi.
He's been feelin' sick.
I don't know why.
I sent some of my friends to go
bring Andre and his mother in.
Yeah, I can examine
him right now.
And do those blood tests, right?
Well, if that's
what's called for.
First thing is to take a history
and do a physical exam.
May I see your son?
Let me ask you a few questions.
Dr. Carter..
...I know it's past 4 o'clock..
...but can I hang around
and see how this goes?
Absolutely.
Thank you.
Does it hurt when
I do that, Andre?
'When I press in here?'
Seth is being
drastically overmedicated.
He's been sent from foster home
to foster home.
Each time, he gets
put on a new med
without regard to the old ones.
Looks like you found out
just in time.
Well, the credit really
goes to my student.
Lucy talked to the boy
and the foster mom.
Found the problem right away.
Good for you, Miss Knight.
So now we can put Seth
on the proper medication.
Actually, Dr. Deraad,
I think he could benefit
from psychotherapy as well.
All Seth really needs is
for someone to listen
to him and to care.
I'm glad to hear you say that.
Most students think it's
just about pushin' meds.
They don't wanna take
the time to do therapy.
A lot of residents
are like that, too.
Isn't that right, Dr. Myers?
'I suppose so.'
You might just learn somethin'
from your student on this point.
'I was wonderin' if I could
continue counseling this kid.'
Well, your psych rotation's
almost over.
And then I start
my second ER rotation
but I'd still like to
see Seth if I could.
I'll supervise you myself.
I think this would be a
great case for you, Miss Knight.
Well?
I don't understand.
You know, we can
look into transplants.
Talk to some experts.
‐ They're fine.
‐ What?
My liver function tests
are almost normal.
I guess the medication
must be working.
Yeah, I'll say.
Maybe I stressed myself out.
Made myself sick.
Yeah. Uh
I guess you can't underestimate
the power of prayer, huh?
Okay, we need you to take
everything off, put on the gown
and the radiologist will be in,
in just a minute, okay?
We have a struggling
national health service.
You have to wait ages
for non‐emergencies
but I believe in it.
No, I meant for the surgeons.
I mean, you seem
so desperate to stay.
Am I that transparent?
Well, not desperate.
Well, I like it here.
It suits me.
You don't get homesick?
Well, a little.
I do get lonely sometimes.
I complain about work, but it's
my most loyal companion, really.
It's hard to get used to it,
you know, being alone.
But, uh..I, uh..
...after a while, you expect it.
And then you start
to appreciate it.
‐ You really believe that?
‐ I'm full of crap.
You two locked in?
‐ Yes. Oh.
‐ Yes!
Still want that drink.
You got it.
Well, I see you haven't
learned your lesson.
It's a character flaw.
I'm a stubborn old mule.
I hear you.
So, you're here.
It's a start.
Is there a heartbeat?
You said you've had
some cramping?
A little, and earlier today,
some spotting.
There we go.
Right there.
Strong steady heartbeat.
‐ Are you sure?
‐ No doubt about it.
Thank god.
Not a 100 percent guarantee
'that everything'll be okay
but it's a good sign.'
'The bubonic plague?'
'I was nine years old.'
The counselor told us
not to feed the squirrels
'cause we might catch
bubonic plague.
Could you?
I don't know,
but Timmy fed the squirrels.
So Jimmy had to be
locked in the cabin.
Timmy, not Jimmy.
I said, Timmy.
Sounded like, Jimmy.
Oh, listen.
‐ What?
‐ It's weird.
‐ What's weird?
‐ They're playing a tango.
‐ You know the tango?
‐ Wanna crash a wedding?
You do know how to do this?
It's a traditional
American wedding dance.
‐ 'Cause I'm not sure.
‐ Just follow my lead.