Previously on Grey's Anatomy...
Dr. Grey, you were on a
plane. You were in a plane crash.
Where's Lexie?
My sister is dead.
They're taking us home
tomorrow on a plane.
That's why I told Bailey
to just sedate all of us.
Cristina, please. Say
something, please.
I'm worried that you're
just running away.
Yeah, I am. I'm fleeing.
And so should you, 'cause
horrible things happen here.
No, something horrible happened,
and we should stick together.
How is Yang, by the way?
Does she like Minnesota?
Who says I have to like him?
He's my sex friend.
How'd it go with Dr. Thomas?
I respect you. You're
a historical landmark.
It's been a while
since I've had anyone
who cared enough
to give me grief.
He is my bestie. He's
my you here in Minnesota.
They call you Medusa...
The serpent-haired monster
who turns folks to stone.
I don't think that
you're a demon.
Focus on what you're doing.
Are you firing him?
We can't fire him.
We can force him
to retire, though.
It's okay if you're
not ready to fly.
I said I'd come. I'll be there.
She's not gonna get
on that plane, is she?
Probably not.
You are my person. You
will always be my person.
Sometimes things are
simply out of your control.
You can't change them.
You can't bend
them to your will.
It doesn't matter if you're
already 45 minutes late,
if your hair isn't brushed,
and you haven't fixed breakfast,
and you're hemorrhaging
brain cells by the second
while you sit here...
Dying...
Dying inside.
Pee.
Pee. Just relax and pee.
Did you do it?
Did you do a pee-pee
in the big-girl potty?
Potty.
Pee-pee in the potty.
Please don't make
me strangle you.
I can't move.
I need to move,
but I can't.
I think I may be
frozen to this spot.
Literally frozen.
I could stay.
Keep you warm.
Do you like being the big
spoon or the little spoon?
I am not a spoon.
I'm a knife, and I'm gonna
stab you in the eyeball.
You know, I think I'm gonna
try and get some sleep.
Oh... You sure?
I can't look at you.
I'm sure.
I can't look at you either.
Okay, please tell me
you're as miserable as I am?
We are potty training,
and I am wearing an apron.
No, I'm happy as can be.
My coat doubles
as a sleeping bag.
Here you go, Zo.
Hi, Zozo.
Now don't forget to tell
mommy if you have to go pee.
Okay?
It's all about the layers, Mer.
Good morning. How are you?
Morning!
We sure got a nice
fresh snowfall last night.
Sure did! Have a good one.
You too!
Who is that?
Just me being neighborly.
I'm neighborly now.
Oh, no. I think she just...
Did you just pee on me?
I think she just peed on me.
See, you have a fake voice, too.
Well, I'm using it on a
child. You're supposed to.
You know what? Tell her
she's got to get her act together
or she'll never be on
the Supreme Court.
She's gotta buck up.
Excuse me?
Buck up. All right.
It's a Minnesota thing.
We don't wallow
in our self-pity.
We're... We're tough.
We're friendly.
We're...
My car is buried under
a mountain of snow.
Buck up.
I hate you.
Okay, I'm almost ready.
Hi. Hey. Hi.
So she needs a change... Uh-huh.
And I am late.
Okay. Well, Daddy's
gonna take a train today
to give a boring paper to
a bunch of boring people.
Zola, your daddy's my hero.
I love you. Bye.
I'll see you in a
couple days. Oop.
All right.
I forgot the fish sticks.
What for?
Oh, it's, uh, Multicultural
Day at preschool.
We're Brazil. I
burned the first batch.
All right. I'll see you later.
Okay, bye.
Say "Goodbye, Mama."
Bye-bye, Mama. I know. I know.
Well, you're in a mood.
My car is buried under
a mountain of snow.
Don't get crumbs
on the upholstery.
Oh, you brought me a Danish.
Don't get
emotional. Just eat it.
You're going to need
your strength. Here.
Oh! A complete vascular ring.
And a huge aneurysm.
Biggest aneurysm
I have ever seen.
Considering how old you
are, that is saying something.
Now if you're gonna
start talking like that,
I'm going to get someone
else to scrub in with me.
This is ours?
Still in a mood?
Oh, thank you, God. Thank
you. Thank you. Thank you.
Hey, hey, hey, I'm
trying to drive here.
Sorry, Dad.
That ginormous
thing is in my body?
Yes.
It formed because of a
congenital heart defect,
so it's been there a long time.
We'll need to
perform two surgeries.
The first one will
repair the aneurysm.
And the second will
deal with the defect
to prevent another
aneurysm from forming.
Wow.
And we thought we
were ready for everything.
All right, this is nothing.
We're prepared for
a nuclear holocaust.
This is just a few
days in the hospital.
Are we expecting a
nuclear holocaust?
No, we're trained for disasters.
Are you EMTs?
No, we're... Will.
What? These are my doctors,
and I don't want them
to think we're crazy.
Hey, we're not crazy.
We're doomsday preppers,
ready for the apocalypse.
Ah.
You think we're crazy.
No. No, no.
Look, we're not, like,
Mayan calendar nut jobs.
We're preparing
for the real stuff.
Ozone depletion, global warming,
melting ice caps.
We met at a workshop
on making bug-out bags.
Dare I ask?
They're survival backpacks.
You should really have
one or several, actually.
One in the home
and one in the car.
So your surgery
will be this afternoon.
We just need to run some
scans, and then we'll be all set.
Okay. That's okay, babe.
Small doses of radiation prepare
your body for ozone depletion.
I guess it's my lucky day.
It's huge. I e-mailed it to you.
Look at my giant aneurysm
and marvel at the
gift Thomas gave me.
I can't. I'm driving.
Besides, I'm jealous. You
have a new best friend.
I really do.
I might love him more than you.
I'm happy for the both of you.
And I get two
surgeries out of it,
'cause she has a
complete vascular ring.
Imagine your good luck.
Oh, are you still being
a bitter working mother?
I am. I have pee on my shoe.
You're a doctor.
Can't you call it urine?
Because "urine on my
shoe" is more appealing?
I need help!
Oh, there's an accident.
Is it bad? It
doesn't look like it.
I gotta go.
I'm fine. There was a
woman on a bicycle.
I think I hit her. I
heard my tire blow.
Hurry! Someone call 9-1-1.
I'll do it. I'll call.
She's being crushed under there.
Does anybody know CPR?
Can you hear me?
I'm a doctor. What's your name?
Melissa.
I can't breathe.
Okay, Melissa, we're gonna
get you outta here. Okay?
I'm a doctor. She can't breathe.
We gotta get
this car off of her.
I'm on with 9-1-1 and
they say don't move her.
The paramedics are on the way.
She can't breathe! She
will die before they get here.
Look, I don't wanna be
responsible if she's paralyzed.
Don't you see she's
dying under there?
Do you wanna be
responsible for that?
I need someone to
help me move this car.
Is anybody gonna help me?
Come on, guys. We got this.
Ready, guys. Okay,
everyone on three.
We got this, okay? Here we go.
One, two, three.
Come on!
Just a little higher.
Okay, let me help you.
Okay, easy, easy. Okay!
She's out.
Oh, she's blue.
Come on, damn it. Breathe.
Come on. Breathe.
Breathe.
Breathe, damn it.
Oh, she's alive.
She's alive.
Dr. Yang.
I hope you got some shut-eye.
A gastropericardial
fistula came into the ER,
and I'd like you to join me.
Uh, with a pneumopericardium?
A huge one.
Did you do a pericardial
decompression?
Just about to.
I can't. I'm scrubbing
in with Thomas.
Cristina...
I'm offering you a
gastropericardial fistula.
Chocolate? Pretzels?
No. Chocolate.
Dr. Yang.
Sorry. Not available.
Wilson, I've got
cyclist versus auto.
Multiple crush injuries.
I need you to call upstairs.
Tell them we need a trauma
OR. Open, and get Ross.
He's on my service.
You, I need you
to go get my car.
It's at the intersection
of Fourth and Pike.
In the backseat, there's
a box of frozen fish sticks.
Grab 'em, nuke 'em,
bring 'em up to daycare
for Brazil day.
Grey, you know you
just stole my intern?
Sorry.
It's interesting how
crazy you can be
and still comb your hair.
I find her delightful.
Yeah?
You got a bug-out bag
in that big ol' car of yours?
I have no desire to
survive Armageddon.
When the big one
hits, I want to go quickly.
Huh.
You didn't mention your surgery
was an aneurysm the
size of a honeycrisp.
It's an apple, the state fruit.
I don't recall mentioning
this surgery to you at all.
Dr. Yang, could I talk to you?
That aneurysm
is a disaster area.
We have a solid surgical plan.
Let me assign the
surgery to somebody else.
No.
Look, I don't know
what's going on.
Maybe you pity Thomas.
Maybe you actually
like him. Hell, I like him.
He's a great old guy.
But there's nothing to
gain by working with him.
Nothing.
There is, actually.
Suction.
There's a lot of blood.
Suction keeps clogging up.
Adjust the angle.
Lower your hand.
Ross, let's run the small bowel.
How do I do that again?
Just take them in your
hands, look for injuries,
nice and slow.
Hey, I just dropped
Sofia off at daycare.
Did you remember it
was Multicultural Day?
Yeah. I made fish sticks.
Ugh, I signed up for
plantains and I totally forgot.
I'm sure no one will notice.
Yeah, well, Mark always
kept track of that stuff.
Okay, the break is
near the femoral artery.
Ooh, she's losing
a lot of blood?
Um, yeah.
Suction.
I'm trying.
Okay, Wilson, just get in there
and scoop it out
with your hands.
Just scoop it out.
Just get right in there.
This would go faster
if I used scissors.
Well, when the tissue
is this thin and friable,
I find the fingers are easier
to isolate the anatomy.
Oh, there you go.
Okay, I've located
the insertion point
in the carotid.
Ah, Dr. Parker.
Two visits in one
day. What a treat.
Well, it's my job to
ensure my department
is working to the
highest standard.
Oh, nonsense.
You want the front-row
seat to my inevitable demise.
I hope you'll forgive
me if I disappoint.
Dr. Yang, are we ready to
bypass to the subclavian?
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Did the aneurysm
blow? Hold pressure.
I'm trying to. I'm trying to.
The hole's getting bigger.
Damn it. Damn it. Damn it.
Watch your language, Dr. Yang.
I run a respectable OR. Clamp.
Dr. Yang, I suggest
you get one, too.
Put her on bypass.
You need time to...
Listen to me.
Dr. Yang will tell you
that I have been doing this
since the Jurassic Period.
We'll have this done in a jiffy.
That's it. I'm scrubbing in.
Clamp on.
Let's go, Dr. Yang.
Time's a-wasting.
Okay. The liver's
exsanguinating.
Ross, suction. Wilson,
grab a clamp for this.
Right away. Which
one should I ask for?
Debakey.
Uh, good news. We tracked down
the young woman's
parents in Toronto.
They're getting
the first flight.
Suction, and let's
hang more blood.
That one makes 57.
Grey, we've replaced her
entire volume of blood four times.
I got this. More laps.
It might be time to
pack her and let her rest.
Looks like you're at a point
of diminishing returns, Grey.
There's a limit to how
much this patient can take.
She was crushed by
two tons of twisted metal.
That's a lot of
trauma for the body.
I know.
I know exactly how much
trauma that is for a body.
I'm not doing
damage control here.
I'm not gonna pack her
up and hope for the best.
I need you to stop.
She needs an intact liver.
Meredith, just take a second.
I am trying to save her life.
Hands off the patient. Now.
Grey.
Let's pack her up.
That was a train wreck in there.
We saved her life.
That aneurysm could have blown
no matter what we
did. You know that.
You should've listened to me
when I suggested
that you put her on...
You walk into my OR
in the middle of a surgery
and try to backseat drive?
I'm trying to help you, Craig.
I'm not Craig. I'm Dr. Thomas.
And I don't need
or want your help.
Dr. Thomas, you're a
danger to our patients.
I need to see a patient.
Surrender your license.
Go out gracefully. It's time.
I will not step down.
Okay. You want to go that
way, we can go that way.
Starting today, I sign off
on every patient you see,
every scan, every Band-Aid.
Talk to him.
Please.
So her liver has been packed.
The next 24 hours are crucial.
Monitor her closely.
Um...
Meredith, do you have a moment?
Do you want me to
take point on this?
On my patient? No.
Meredith, I'm concerned that...
This may be hitting a
little too close to home.
I mean, after what you've
been through, what...
What happened
with your sister...
Same injuries, same age.
What's your point?
Emotions might be
clouding your judgment.
They're not.
Excuse me. I have to
go check on my patient.
What happens now?
The next few hours are critical.
When she wakes up,
if she can speak and
move her arms and legs,
then we'll know she
got good blood flow
and that the grafts held.
I'm sorry... Uh...
Flowers aren't
allowed in the CCU.
We have a seed bank
in case, you know,
it all goes to hell.
We have every grain
and every fruit and
vegetable you need.
Katy was like, "What
about the flowers, Will?
"If the world is ending, I'm
gonna want something beautiful."
You know, I'll put
them just outside.
She can see them
from there. Okay?
This is my fault.
The aneurysm would've blown
no matter whose
hands were on it.
Her vessels are cotton candy.
I know, but Parker
wouldn't have given
that surgery a second thought
if I wasn't in there with you.
Oh, don't flatter yourself.
That man has been after
my hide for a long time.
Probation is one step
away from being fired.
You know, I find
it a little unseemly
to worry about my
employment prospects
when there's a woman's
life hanging in the balance.
Come on. I'm gonna
give you a ride home.
We have another
surgery tomorrow.
You need your sleep.
It's going to be fine.
Thomas made me leave my patient.
Now she's gonna
die, and he'll be fired.
Well, I'm leaving
my patient, too.
I have to pick Zola
up from daycare,
and Derek's out of
town so it has to be fine.
It's not gonna be fine.
She's surrounded by interns.
That's one of the signs,
Meredith, like locusts
or the four horsemen
of the apocalypse.
Well, except there's
only three of them
and it's one night.
You need a bug-out bag.
What's that?
Like a diaper bag for adults.
I'm making mine right now.
Well, what do you have so far?
Tequila.
Well, that's a good
start. What else?
Well, the sign of a
well-packed diaper bag
is backups in case you run out.
- So more tequila?
- I am out
trying to have one night,
and my intern decides to
close my patient's wound,
an infected wound,
which I left open to heal.
Dumbass, over-eager,
barely-out-of-med-school child!
I'm staying.
I'm going back.
Hi. Hi.
Hey, cutie pie.
I gotta run. My interns
are with my patient.
There's extra
clothes in the bag.
Okay. Okay.
Hey.
No, no, no. No.
No, don't do that to yourself.
It's good for her
to see you work.
It is good for her
to see you achieve.
Yes. That's how she'll
become CEO one day.
Yeah? 'Cause mommy
works. That's good.
Okay. I owe you one.
My first surgery's at 10:00.
I'll just drop her off
at daycare with Sofia.
Okay. Bye.
Well, can't you just give
your sex friend more sex
in exchange for not
firing your old man friend?
Ew, I'm not a prostitute.
Besides, I thought of that.
It's just way too much sex.
She is barely hanging on.
Should I take her
back into surgery?
What does Webber think?
He thinks I'm too
emotional to handle this.
Vitals check.
Okay.
Are you still there?
Yeah. Why are you whispering?
Granola guy's asleep.
He brought his own hemp pillow.
Stable over here. You?
Stable-ish.
Maybe we should
try to get some sleep.
I'm not gonna be able to sleep.
Yeah. Me neither.
You know what we need?
What?
A 30-second dance party.
Okay.
I'm too tired.
Yeah, me, too.
You do it. Uh-uh.
Dr. Yang!
MEREDITH AND
CRISTINA: Please be alive.
Please be alive.
Good news.
Ms. Doomsday is doing great.
While you were getting
your beauty sleep,
a lot has happened.
Katy, why don't
you fill in Dr. Yang?
Although she hasn't
had her coffee yet,
so maybe just give
her the broad strokes.
You guys are gonna go
ahead with my second surgery
this afternoon.
Dr. Yang will
start to prep you...
As soon as she
brushes her teeth.
She needs another surgery
to take out the packing
and check for more bleeding,
but right now she
would never survive it.
So what do we do?
There's a perfect window.
We have to correct her acidosis
and her hypothermia
and make sure her
coags are stable.
And until then?
Until then, we have to
try and keep her alive.
I am so sorry. I'm so sorry.
I have surgery in ten minutes.
I tried leaving her in daycare,
but she's running
a little fever.
No big deal. I'm sure
she's just teething.
But they won't take her
if she hasn't been
fever-free for 24 hours.
Did I mention I have surgery?
In ten minutes. I'm sorry.
Dr. Grey, the patient's BP
just plummeted to 70 over 50.
Crap. Edwards.
No, I... No.
I did your fish stick
drop. I valeted your car.
I am here to practice medicine.
Great. Monitor her temp.
If it gets above 101, give her
a teaspoon of acetaminophen
and push fluids.
Her sippy cup is
in the bag. Bye, Zo.
Bye-bye.
This is a bad idea.
Parker will never
sign off on this surgery.
I can't tell you
how strenuously I object to
your extracurricular gymnastics
with that man.
He's making you
conventional and skittish.
You know, condoms
don't protect against that.
How did...
You were the first
one to point out,
I've been around a long time.
Now Katy is awake,
she's speaking,
she's moving her extremities.
Yes, but...
The repair worked, so
why put her in danger
of another
life-threatening aneurysm?
Well, what about Parker?
I spend very little
time thinking about him.
Can I assume that's
your child I hear
wailing outside those doors?
Well, she has a fever,
and Derek is out of town,
and I have this patient...
Dr. Grey, you know why men
think they can run the world
and women can't?
Because of crying babies.
I was hoping no
one would hear it.
Uh, we can all hear it.
I can hear it.
Dr. Ross out there can hear it.
Only difference is, the
crying doesn't affect him.
But you and I are
genetically predisposed
to respond to crying babies.
It's pulling your focus.
It's gonna be fine.
I'm almost done.
Okay, this is about
world domination.
If we're going to take over,
we need to have our babies
crying somewhere
other than the ICU.
Dr. Yang, could you go
over the risks of the surgery
one last time?
Will, Dr. Thomas went
over all of it already.
I could die or
turn into a potato
or start leaking unicorn
poop out of my ears.
I signed the scary paper
already. I'm doing it.
He also said that you
could live with this condition
for years without
another aneurysm.
Right?
Yes.
Last night, I didn't know
if you'd even wake up.
And now I know what the
end of the world feels like,
and I don't want
to feel that again.
You want me to live
with a sword hanging
over my head every day,
afraid to hiccup because I
might blow an aneurysm?
That's not living,
and you know it.
We take action, Will.
We look disaster in the eye
and we do not shrink with fear.
Tell him, Dr. Yang.
Tell him it's
gonna be all right.
Scissors. Get the tube ready.
Got it.
Hey. I'm here.
Lung collapsed. I have
to do this chest tube.
I can keep her
till 3:00, but then
I've got a hernia repair.
Hey, Brooks, see if
Zola's temp is down
and if you can sweet talk
daycare into taking her back.
Okay. Got it. Tube
is in. Zero silk.
I'll just go get her.
Okay, don't forget
her diaper bag.
She's got extra
clothes in there, diapers.
The sippy cup is
in the side pocket,
and if she goes
pee-pee in the potty...
Meredith, I'm not gonna
potty train your kid.
Right. Okay. Sorry. Forget it.
Already did.
He's doing it, Mer.
He's doing the surgery.
And if he does
it, he'll get fired.
Yeah.
I need to figure out
the exact right time
to reopen my patient.
A month ago, this would've
been someone else's decision.
I was just a resident
along for the ride.
Now if I misjudge...
Yeah.
Doomsday.
You know what we need?
Dance party?
Nope.
We need to buck up.
Yep.
Dr. Parker.
Ah, Dr. Yang.
You're a day late
and a dollar short.
I just had to reopen my
gastropericardial fistula...
You need to take
Dr. Thomas off probation.
I take it you weren't
able to convince him
to go gracefully?
Why would I?
He's a liability.
Because he's old?
No, because he habitually
undermines my authority.
Look, you were in
that OR yesterday.
Yeah, he saved
our patient's life.
He was insubordinate
and reckless.
He cut out her aneurysm
and interposed a graft
in under 30 minutes.
Now I can't do that. Can you?
There's no good reason...
Cristina, there is no
point in belaboring this.
It's done.
Then undo it.
Let him ride out his tenure.
Firing him would be
bad for the hospital
and bad for you.
Please, just let this slide.
Look, I know you're
in an awkward position,
and it's partly my fault
for sticking you with him.
You came in a little strong,
and I felt like I needed to
temper your overconfidence.
But he's holding you back.
And once he's
gone, you'll see that.
Okay, her temp is 96.
What were her last coags?
Her INR was 1.3,
and I tested her pH levels
two hours ago, and it was 7.29.
Okay, let's run 'em again.
Why the hell are you
sitting out in the cold?
Sun's out. Gotta take advantage.
Let me do the surgery
with someone else.
Dr. Yang...
Or go kiss his
ass. Play politics.
I don't think you understand
how serious he is.
There is a path that a
doctor walks in this hospital.
They begin by thinking
that I'm some sort of God.
Then they start to
worry that I'm insane.
And then they take
some comfort in the notion
that it's just senility.
I mean, we've gone from
"A" to "Z" in no time at all.
Yeah, well, if this goes south,
it could be the end for you.
So be it.
Maybe I'm ready.
Well, I'm not. You can't
leave me alone here.
Oh, we're talking
about you now, hmm?
You should've raised the flag.
I couldn't work
here without you.
You're afraid to fly.
You're not going anywhere.
Hey, it's not funny.
No, it isn't.
You love me more
than anybody has
in a very long time.
Look, if I'm going,
I want to go down fighting
for something that I believe in,
for this young woman's future,
and these women who
have so much to live for.
Come on.
You know I'm right.
You know that she
deserves this surgery.
And we're the
best team to do it.
So...
You decided to go back in.
This is my window. Her
pH and coags are good.
She'll never make it
through another day
if I don't stop this bleeding.
What?
Oh, nothing. I just, um...
Don't. Don't say it.
Say what?
This is nothing like what
happened in the woods.
We are in a hospital
with medical resources
that we could only
dream of having out there.
And I'm gonna use them
and try like hell to
save this girl's life
so when her family comes
I can tell them she's alive.
So don't say this is
Lexie. It's not Lexie.
Good luck.
That's all I was
gonna say. Good luck.
Oh.
Thank you.
And it's the right call,
bringing her back in.
I was gonna say that, too.
So we'll take the
packs out slowly
so that we can
look for the bleed.
Wait. It's 4:30.
I thought you were with Zola.
No, yeah, 4:00 to 5:00,
that's Dr. Kepner's shift.
Yeah, that was before
my surgery went long.
23-year-old with more
gallstones than I've ever seen.
It's weird, right,
23-year-old with gallstones?
April, who has my daughter?
Um... 4:30... Jackson, I think.
April.
When I realized my
surgery was going long,
I sent my intern to make sure
that Alex could
take her for longer,
but he couldn't push
his surgery again,
so he left her with Ted,
so I was just about to
go relieve him right now.
Unless Jackson got there
first. His shift was after mine so...
Who's Ted?
Nurse Ted from the ER.
And I can tell by
the look on your face
that you don't know who Ted is.
Um, don't worry about it.
I'm going there right now.
Zola will be fine. Okay?
Ross, follow her.
Do not leave her side
until my daughter is
physically in her arms.
On it.
Ready, Dr. Yang?
Ready, sir.
Scissors. WOMAN: Here you go.
Wire cutters. Wire cutters.
Balfour retractor.
Here you go, Doctor.
Sternal retractor.
Retractor. Here you go.
These vessels are so fragile.
Let's go gently.
You're gonna have to suction
like your life depends on it.
If your hands move even a
centimeter without my say,
she's gonna bleed out.
Where's my suction?
I'm trying, but there's a
lot of bleeding over here.
Okay, keep trying,
Wilson. Wilson, hold still.
I thought I was.
Ross, are you
sure my kid's okay?
It's like Camp Zola in
the attendings lounge.
She was smashing gummy
worms into her face when I left.
Who's letting her
have gummy worms?
You're right. It doesn't matter.
Get in here and help
retract. I need more visibility.
If this continues
to go this well,
I'm prepared to
put your name first.
When we publish?
That's big of you.
It is.
You know what? You
need it more than I do.
This could be your
last journal article.
Is that your version
of "thank you"?
No, it's my version
of, "This is the end.
"Get while the getting's good."
Thank God I never had
children. They'd be just like you.
I'd have drowned them
like puppies in the river.
Oh, come on. I'm
your dream come true.
That is the truth.
You're gonna make me gag.
BP's dropping.
This is really a lot of blood.
Who moved?
Somebody moved. Say it now.
I did.
Just a little. I'm sorry.
It's okay. It actually helps.
It means the bleeder's
in the retroperitoneum.
Okay, now literally this time,
nobody move.
Don't be crass.
Women of your generation
think they have to be crass
or no one will
believe their strength.
You're fighting a battle
that women of my generation
have already fought for you
so you could have the
grace to appreciate their work
and move on to something else.
Yeah, I'm still gagging.
You know what? These
sutures aren't holding.
Can I have another
4-0 Prolene, please?
BP is really down.
I'm well aware of that.
Stop looking at the monitors
and just help me
find this bleed.
Watch your dissection
and don't hold your breath.
Now you're gonna tell
me when to breathe?
Renal vessels are clear.
Damn it. Keep retracting.
You hold your breath
when you stitch.
When you stop breathing,
you stop thinking.
It's a mistake.
Now what?
Hang on.
I'm breathing.
Slowly.
Not like an anxious hyena.
Freeze. Keep your
hands where they are.
We have to find the
source or she's dead.
Okay, do not panic. Don't panic.
My name will be first.
Saw that coming a mile away.
You will be the surgeon
of your generation.
I knew it as soon as I met you.
People will try to diminish
you as they did me,
and they will fail.
I would like it to be known
in the medical community
that I helped train you.
Hmm?
Okay. Your name first.
Found it. Clamp.
Tiny tear in the external iliac.
Whew.
Okay, does anybody
know what we do now?
Ligate the artery. Nope.
Replace the clamp with a patch.
Nope.
Then what?
30-second dance party.
Dance or you're fired.
That clamp's coming
up. Can you adjust it?
Can you reach it, Pops?
Dr. Thomas?
Thomas! Dr. Thomas.
I need another clamp.
Move! Move! Move!
Someone get to him.
What's going on? I
don't have a pulse.
Get a crash cart. Right away.
Grab his clamp. Damn
it. I need a better angle.
Switching sides. WOMAN
2: Let's get an IV set up.
Get gowned and gloved.
What's happening?
Are the paddles on?
- He's in v-fib.
Charging. Shock
him. Charge to 200.
We're on it. Clear.
Nothing. What the...
He collapsed in the
middle of surgery.
We already shocked him once.
- Charge to 300.
- Charging.
Why is this surgery
even happening?
Don't worry about
that right now.
Clear!
Nothing. Go again.
Charging. Is there a pulse?
Clear!
Parker, is there a pulse?
Someone tell me what's going on.
Starting CPR.
Deal with your
patient, Cristina.
Don't hold your breath.
You stop thinking
when you stop breathing.
Breathe. Please, God.
Breathe.
Oh, God.
Please don't tell
me that she's...
She's okay.
Katy has a strong heart.
She should have a
long life ahead of her,
a long, long life.
Thank you.
She's okay.
Breathe, Dr. Yang.
Don't be crass.
You're skulking.
Women of your
generation are graceless.
It's an affront to nature.
Mediocre surgeons will see you
and feel themselves
wilting in your shadow.
Do not shrink to console them.
Do not look for friends here.
You won't find them.
None of these people have
the capacity to understand you.
They never will.
If you're lucky,
one day when you're
old and shriveled like me,
you will find a young doctor
with little regard for
anything but their craft.
And you'll train them
like I trained you.
Until then, read a good book.
You have greatness in you, Yang.
Don't disappoint.
Oh, my God. Where is she?
Who has Zola?
Ah!
There she is. There's your mama.
Kepner had to scrub
in on a colectomy
so I took her, right?
Hi.
You look like you're
feeling much better.
Mmm-hmm. Well, we
read Goodnight Moon
a couple times, didn't we?
And then you tried to show
me how to play patty-cake, right?
And it turns out, Uncle
Owen is pretty terrible at that.
Oh, and her fever broke
a couple hours ago.
Uh, 99.2 last time I checked.
Dr. Grey! Dr. Grey!
Is she crashing?
Melissa's asking for you.
Go, go. I don't need
to be anywhere.
Okay. Bye, Zozo.
Say bye. Say bye.
Hey, you, what we gonna do?
We're gonna do
high fives. Patty-cake.
Patty-cake,
patty-cake, patty-cake.
Melissa.
Meet Dr. Grey.
Hi.
I...
don't know how
much you remember.
I was trapped...
Under something.
And you were there.
You were there, right?
I was. I...
Thank you. WOMAN:
Thank you, Doctor.
What's this?
My list of Tucker-tested
babysitters.
You need a deeper
bench, Dr. Grey.
You're an attending now,
you never know when
a crisis is gonna happen,
and this is gold.
I don't give it out
to just anyone.
Thank you.
Don't wake up.
Please don't wake up.
Good girl.
Oh, God. No!
Not tonight.
Not one more thing.
Oh...
I downed the tequila
bottle from my diaper bag.
I can barely...
I don't even know
what my name is.
Lexie's dead.
Yeah.
Everyone's dead.