♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
Ow. Damn it.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
What are you doing?
I'm making Lucas
a Halloween costume.
I'm trying to make Lucas
Ow.
Uh, you know, I think
they sell costumes.
My mother made these really
great Halloween costumes.
My fourth-grade sunflower
won first prize.
No, and then one year
I was raggedy Ann and she made
these authentic pantaloons
with a wig made
out of red yarn and--
well, she actually sewed
me into the pantaloons
and then told me that
I couldn't get out of them,
so, um, I peed my pants
trick-or-treating
and was humiliated
because she's a sadistic
narcissist
with serious intimacy issues,
but she made
really great costumes.
Did you--?
Did you dress up?
You ever go out
trick-or-treating
with your brother?
Adam and I used
to egg trick or treaters.
Oh.
Was that fun?
I'm late for the er.
Hey, big man.
All:
Uh-oh.
Bye. Mwah.
You smell good.
Mm.
I taste even better. Ha, ha.
What are you doing?
It's called foreplay.
Stop looking at my stomach
like that.
Like what?
Like you're trying to picture
a baby in there.
Oh, I'm doing no such thing.
Oh-- Charlotte.
Don't be that way.
Sam:
He's been coming every day
for how long?
Grant:
Two years ago, weekend ski trip,
Georgie hit a tree,
never regained consciousness.
None of the neuro guys
gave him much hope,
but you're always good
with referrals
and so I just thought, maybe--
we could help him
come to terms with this.
Grant:
He hasn't let go. At all.
Amelia will be honest with him.
Oh. Uh, bright lights
don't do much for Georgie,
but she likes
being talked to.
See? You can say
it's just a reflex,
all the other doctors did,
but I know
it's more than that.
The trauma to your wife's head
damaged her reticular
activating system,
which controls
her level of consciousness.
Like waking up. I know.
Then you also know
that it is hard to determine
how extensive the damage is?
Which means I could be right,
she hears me
and responds to me.
Amelia:
It's possible, but
Georgie is only manifesting
very primitive reactions.
I mean, a twitch, a blink.
After all this time,
that doesn't bode well.
Look, I can run
a bunch of tests, but--
uh, then run them.
I don't want you to get
your hopes up, Mr. Schwartz.
My hopes are already up.
They have to be.
Run the tests.
Pete:
What have we got?
Mva. Car versus pole. Two males.
Jacob Deever, 43 years old,
wearing seatbelt.
Minor facial lacerations
and a bruised arm.
Twenty-two-year-old Evan Arnold,
unrestrained.
Closed head trauma
and possible fractured tibia.
Hey, look, really I'm fine.
I don't need to be here.
Mr. Deever, I'm Dr. Wilder.
We're gonna help you out,
but I need you
to relax for just a minute
while I examine
the other driver.
We were in the same car.
He, uh-- Evan.
He hit his head
on the windshield.
Okay, let's get
a c-spine, chest,
a pelvic trauma panel
and a head ct.
Either of you have
anything to drink?
What? No.
No, I-I just happened
to take my eyes
off the road for a second.
What about drugs,
prescription or otherwise?
No, no. God, no. You know what?
I have an appointment
that I need to get to, so--
okay, let me just get someone
to clean up that scrape
on your head and--
no. No, it's good. I'm actually
fine. I just need to go.
You have the right
to refuse treatment,
but you're gonna have to talk to
the police about the accident.
Why don't you wait for me
at the nurses' station?
I'll get your statement,
then you can go.
He seems pretty antsy.
Should we hold him
for a tox screen?
That's not why he's nervous.
I know this guy that he's with.
Arrested him a couple times
in the past few months.
He's a prostitute.
Hey. You wanna see
something funky?
Thirty-three-year-old woman,
Georgie Schwartz,
persistent vegetative state
for over 24 months.
Looks like the case study
from my neuroanatomy final.
I hated neuroanatomy.
Just skip down to the labs.
Her tsh is low, but her thyroid
levels look fine.
I don't get it.
Hmm. Iron-deficient anemia. Hmm.
You're focusing
on the wrong organ.
Your patient's pregnant.
All I did was put my hand
on her stomach.
Which is usually the prelude
to a little something-something.
She's got me boxed in.
I know the feeling.
You and Pete aren't having sex?
Uh, no. We have a lot of sex.
Sorry. No, I just meant
the boxed-in part.
Okay, I'm gonna, um--
I'm gonna tell you something,
but you can't ever,
never ever, tell anyone.
Never ever.
Okay.
Pete's mother...
She's in prison.
What?
What, like "prison" prison?
What'd she do?
She like a bunny boiler?
Or like Bonnie and Clyde?
I don't know.
He won't talk about her.
He's got a brother,
he won't talk about him.
Which is obviously wrong.
He should tell me this stuff.
I should know about it, right?
I mean, I'm his wife.
What'd you do?
Nothing.
Violet Maryann Turner.
Okay, I googled.
There are 33 Adam Wilders.
Mm-hm.
So you think
we can start trying?
Oh, you're healed
from your bladder reconstruction
and your kidney function's
back to normal.
I think you'd be crazy not to.
Laying in that hospital bed,
this always felt so far away.
Sometimes I thought
it would never happen.
But now, I'm ready--
we're ready. --For a baby.
If you want my advice,
forget about ovulation days
and thermometers
and just have fun.
I can't wait to tell my husband.
Hon?
Dr. King,
this is my husband, Jacob.
Nice to meet you.
So nice to meet you.
You okay?
Yeah.
Good.
Charlotte:
Enjoy.
Thanks again.
Hey, Charlotte.
Do you know that guy?
He's the husband
of one of my patients.
Is something wrong?
He was in the er
a couple of hours ago
with a male prostitute.
Are you sure?
They were in a car accident.
Same car.
Angela just spent a year in hell
having her bladder reconstructed
so she could have
a baby with that man.
If he's out there
rubbing on some guy,
she needs to know.
Right. Before we destroy
both their lives,
don't you think
we should figure out
exactly what's going on?
A married man gets into a car
wreck on his lunch hour
with some hustler
in the other seat.
Yeah, let's give him
the benefit of the doubt.
So I narrowed it down
to three Adam Wilders.
Oh, no, this is so him.
Do you think so?
Yeah.
Is that Pete in college?
See?
What?
We're looking
for Pete's brother--
Cooper.
Did you remember "never ever"?
Never ever.
Sorry.
Never ever will I mention this.
Thank you.
Is he missing?
He's-- he's estranged.
Maybe not for long.
Pete doesn't know
that you're doing this?
Well, there's no harm
in looking.
What would Pete's response be?
Well, if I told him
it was for his own good--
then I'd say,
why are you the one doing this?
And once you find him,
what's the plan?
Is that--?
The baby's heartbeat.
I'm sorry.
Oh, my god.
Grant:
Can I talk to you for a minute?
Yeah.
I don't know how this happened.
It's pretty clear
how it happened.
We've never had a problem
like this here.
We screen every staff member.
We do background checks.
I've helped take care of their
patients.
It's not that kind of place.
You still need to call
the police.
If you can just give me
a chance to figure this out.
Someone here had sex
with a comatose woman.
That's a crime.
Sam:
Georgie's not
the only victim here.
What does that mean?
Look at her husband.
The man's destroyed.
Our primary interest
here should be
in doing what's best
for the couple.
They've already been
through one trauma.
Instead of putting
them through another,
which Bob would have
to handle on his own,
we need to protect them,
Addison.
Don't even think about it.
Do not shut that door.
Do not close those blinds.
Cooper, do not take
your pants off.
We're in the middle of a fight.
I'm calling a truce.
Good luck with that.
Cooper:
You don't--
What?
You know what.
I do?
We should have called
the police.
Ahh. You're still talking
about the case?
I was right and you were wrong.
Okay.
Okay, I was right?
Okay, you have your opinion,
I have mine.
That was at work,
we're at home now,
so let's not talk
about it anymore
until we're at work again.
What? What is that?
Does that actually work for you?
Leave work at work?
Well, yeah.
That's what me and Naomi--
I am not Naomi.
I know. I know that.
All right, I am mad, Sam.
I know.
My mad doesn't go away
just because I'm at home.
I take my work home with me.
Addison, come on.
I was right and you were wrong.
You know what?
Go home. To your own bed.
No sex for you.
Wait, wait, wait.
So you're punishing
me for having
an opposing
professional opinion
by withholding
sexual favors? Really?
No sex for you.
Good night, Addison.
Ha, ha.
Look, uh...
You know, I really appreciate
you not calling Angela.
You know, i--
if she knew about...
It was just a lapse of judgment.
But I was at the gas station,
he asked for a ride
and he seemed harmless, so--
Mr. Deever, don't talk
to me like I'm an idiot.
Well, what exactly
do you think happened?
Evan's a prostitute.
I think you paid him for sex.
You think?
Look, I've been married
to my wife for almost 20 years.
I love her.
I would never cheat on her.
And with a man?
That's disgusting.
Are you kidding me
right now?
I'm not here to judge you.
I just want you to understand
that Dr. King
is ready
to talk to your wife.
You leave Angela out of this.
She is none of your business.
And, Dr. Wilder,
nothing happened
between me and that man.
You hear me? Nothing.
This... it doesn't seem real.
You must feel...
Actually, I don't know
how you must feel,
but I want you to know
that I will do everything
I can for your wife.
I'd like to do a full
examination as soon as possible,
and then
I don't see any reason
why we can't terminate
the pregnancy immediately.
Wait. Why?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I-I didn't even ask
about your religious beliefs.
I-i--
I just assumed that,
given how this happened
to Georgie--
no, no.
Why are you talking
about this like
it's a terrible thing?
Mr. Schwartz, do you understand
that Georgie is pregnant
because someone went into her
room and impregnated her?
Not someone, Dr. Montgomery,
it was me.
The woman is in a coma, Sam.
She can't move or speak.
Which means she cannot consent.
They're husband and wife.
You think that being married
means
you don't have
the right to say no?
No, I'm not saying that.
The man climbed on top
of a comatose woman--
all right,
I am not defending what Bob did,
but the man is broken.
I mean, you look at him,
you see how
he interacts with her.
He needs counseling,
a way to accept
that she's not coming back.
Bob Schwartz is a sick,
twisted, pervert, right?
Please, tell him.
The husband could be using sex
as an outlet for his grief.
Or if he
truly believes his wife
can feel
and she can respond--
I've seen it before with the
families of comatose patients.
They suffer a loss
that they cannot accept
and they try to ignore it.
These situations are
complicated.
It's not complicated.
We call the police
and they arrest this guy.
Sam:
Oh, come on, Addison.
He is god knows how far
into an emotional breakdown.
He's not out to harm her.
He's deluded.
He bathes her, he feeds her--
he violates her, and now he's
expecting her to have this baby.
I have seen a lot of things
since I became a doctor,
but this is unimaginable.
Have the baby? What, is that
possible with her in a coma?
Probably not.
It's happened.
Rarely, and Georgie's already
at risk of throwing an embolus.
Pregnancy would increase
that tenfold.
I'm not saying I think that
Georgie should have the baby--
well, unfortunately, Georgie
doesn't have a say in this,
and after I'm done,
neither will Bob.
What are you gonna do?
Take him to court?
Try and strip him
of medical power of attorney?
If I have to, yes.
Addison.
You really disagree with me
on this, Sam? Really?
Sheldon:
Let me to talk to him.
Maybe I can help him understand
why he's doing what he's doing.
I'll chaperone.
We're all pushing in the same
direction, Addison.
All right.
I'll give you a day. One day.
And we're not all pushing
in the same direction, Sam.
I am right. You're wrong.
How'd your meeting
go with Jacob?
He claims he didn't know
Evan was a prostitute.
Do you believe him?
Should I?
I tested Jacob's blood for HIV.
Charlotte, you can't test
someone's blood
without their permission.
He came into my hospital.
I'm the chief of staff.
It doesn't give you
the right to--
he's positive.
And in case you're curious,
I checked
Angela's blood too.
She's negative.
We have to tell her.
They're actively trying
to have a child.
It can't come from us.
They made a damn law
that allows us to do it, Pete.
Allows, doesn't require.
Why are you still trying
to protect this guy?
I'm not,
but yanking Jacob
out of the closet
isn't gonna help either of them.
You and I both know
how devastating that would be.
Give me time with Jacob.
Let me get him to see
that he has to be
the one to tell her.
That he owes it to her,
to himself, to tell the truth.
How's the investigation?
Adam Wilder, lawyer in valencia.
Mm-hm.
He looks okay, doesn't he?
Seems normal.
Pete's been so elusive.
I was expecting
america's most wanted.
Okay.
Read that.
"My name is Violet Turner
and I am married to your
brother, Pete."
Yeah. No. You cannot
send this e-mail.
Pete wants this.
He just-- he just doesn't know
that he wants it.
Oh, come on,
it'll be one of those things.
I'll do it, he'll get pissed
and then he'll thank me
for it later on.
This is Pete.
You remember Pete? The man still
hates his dead wife.
Not a forgiver.
He's in pain, Cooper.
No, you should have seen him.
He's in pain.
And I wanna help him.
I have to help him.
Is this helping?
You press send, that is contact.
You can't undo it.
So am I sleeping here tonight
or next door?
Whatever.
So, what, we're ignoring
each other now?
I am trying not to say things
I can't take back.
Addison, Bob Schwartz--
I am trying not to say things
I can't take back.
Bob Schwartz has nothing to do
with you and me, here and now.
How can you act like
nothing's wrong?
Like today didn't even happen?
We disagreed about something.
A huge something.
Look, Addison,
if working with you means
we can only be together
when we agree--
sex. You wanna have sex.
Is that all you think about?
Yeah, Addison. That's all I ever
think about. All day long.
How I can't wait to get home
and have sex with you.
Then let's do it.
Come on, let's have sex.
I'll lie here, dead and still,
and you can have all the sex
you want with my body.
Go ahead, knock yourself out.
Have a ball.
We'll be like
Bob and Georgie Schwartz.
Or is that something
that you and Nai used to do too?
I told you I was trying not
to say things I can't take back.
You should have tried harder.
You know what I love
about this place?
None of this toting
around thermoses,
just good old environmentally
unsound, non-biodegradable,
here-for-a-thousand-years
plastic bottles.
Where are you off to
all cheerful this morning?
Sheldon and I are gonna go talk
to your buddy Bob Schwartz.
Is Sam going with you?
Shouldn't you know that?
We're fighting over that case.
Seriously?
He is wrong.
And he compared me to Naomi.
Well, he didn't really,
but he kind of did
and then i-- whatever.
We're arguing about
the case and he's wrong.
You know he has a right
to his own medical opinion?
If I could come home
to a guy like that,
I would not be wasting my time
arguing about work.
Why can't you just
stay out of my life? Hmm?
Please.
Pete:
You didn't return my call.
Okay, you are
not listening to me.
You're HIV positive.
What?
What are you talking about?
We took blood from you
when you were in the er.
Well, that just can't be.
So, what?
God, what am I supposed
to do now?
There's someone I'd like you
to talk to.
Amelia:
Bob? What happened?
She started bleeding. At first,
just a little and then--
I'm having trouble
keeping her pressure up.
Start a second line.
I'm calling Addison.
Are you sure she's the best one?
If you love your wife,
Mr. Schwartz, she's the one.
I was just curious.
It only happened
one time. That's it.
Pete:
You couldn't already
be HIV positive
from whatever happened with you
and that guy in the car.
There's nothing wrong
with having sex with men.
Violet:
But there is something wrong
with you living a lie like this.
I'm not lying.
So you know, withholding
the fact you're HIV positive
from your sexual partners could
land you in prison.
Oh, please.
Look, no--
Jacob. Jacob.
Do you enjoy being intimate
with your wife?
I enjoy making my wife happy.
That's not really
the same thing.
I-I just don't wanna
hurt her, okay?
That's it. I want everything
that everyone else wants.
You know, I wanna be happy.
Be normal.
You can.
You can be happy
and normal, and gay.
But as long
as you're hiding this,
how can you really be happy?
And until you're
honest with Angela--
Jacob:
No, no, no.
Everything that we have,
our marriage, maybe even a baby,
I just-- I can't take
that away from her.
But she's never really gonna
have that anyway.
And if you are honest with her--
how?
God, how can I tell her?
Shouldn't be much longer now.
Georgie hates
hospitals.
She's not gonna like it here.
Bob, you talk about Georgie
like she's present.
She is present. For me.
Physically, yes.
But emotionally--
I'm sure it's very difficult
for you.
The hardest part
is her not being able to talk.
Whenever
anything bad happens,
she always knows
what to say.
You know, what
the silver lining is and...
I always wonder
what she'd say about this.
She'd be appreciative, I'm sure,
of everything you're doing.
But you understand
that even after the tests
that Dr. Shepherd ran,
it's very unlikely
that Georgie will ever be
anything like the woman
you married.
Are you trying to get me
to walk away from her?
I'm trying to get you to think
realistically about your future.
She's my best friend.
I've never ever...
She was my first
and she's supposed
to be my last,
till death do us part.
I can't just...
She's my best friend.
I-I can't abandon her.
W-We're supposed to die
in each other's arms.
If she loved you
half as much as you say,
she wouldn't want this for you.
She'd want you
to be loved by someone
who can love you back.
She'd want you happy.
I'm not saying
give up on her, Bob.
I'm just saying...
Don't give up on yourself.
Hi.
Nice job with Jacob today.
Thanks.
Look what I bought.
Ha, ha.
It's a pumpkin,
and it's not plastic or cheap.
It's a handmade pumpkin costume.
So that Lucas can have
all the happy childhood memories
and you can keep your thumbs.
I found Adam.
What?
Your brother.
I know who Adam is.
He lives in--
stop talking.
Why are you so obsessed
with this?
It's my job to care.
You're shrinking me?
No, as-- as your wife.
It's my job
to care as your wife.
Look, I know this is difficult,
but he's your family.
We're strangers, Violet.
We were split up as teenagers,
we went to different houses,
I haven't talked to him since.
So maybe this is a good time
to reach out.
Okay, for a second,
I will be a shrink. All right?
This emotional disconnect
from your past,
from who you were,
it's damaging, it's unhealthy.
And it can affect your
relationships down the line.
With a child, with a spouse.
I have to go back to work.
Your wife is okay, Mr. Schwartz.
Her cervix dilated
and the placenta
detached, but she's alive.
And the baby?
We lost him.
I'm sorry.
You think Jacob's ever gonna
come back here and tell him?
I think he's a little
more concerned
about telling his wife.
Then allow me.
Mr. Arnold.
Do you practice safe sex
with all your tricks?
Always.
Charlotte: That's good.
Because the man you got into
the accident with, Jacob Deever,
tested positive for HIV.
We'd be happy to test you,
if you'd like,
but if you're telling the truth
about using condoms,
it's not likely to be a problem.
You don't understand.
I said I practice safe sex
with my tricks,
not with the man I love.
Addison:
Hey. How's Georgie?
She's stable. Bob's with her.
Great.
Unfortunately, he's less stable.
How much less stable can he be?
Well, losing Georgie,
for the most part anyway,
and now the baby.
I mean,
these are profound losses.
He's confused and hurting.
But I talked to him
about coming in
to start working on his
recovery, so...
Good luck.
Right.
Amelia:
Come on, Addie.
They give child molesters
their kids back
if they get enough counseling.
Really? You're starting
to sound like Sam.
Sam is not all wrong.
I have to go check
up on Georgie.
Bob:
...Because you and I,
we never give up.
We stick it out.
We never let anything
get in the way of us.
Sweetie,
I'm sorry to tell you,
we lost our baby.
There was nothing they could do.
But you know what?
Don't worry,
because we'll keep trying.
We're gonna have
a family one day, Georgie.
Cooper:
Charlotte just hung up on me.
She literally hung up the phone
while I was mid-sentence.
I mean, I'm horny.
And she's mad, and horny.
What am I supposed to do?
Well, when you're boxed in,
you need to get out of the box.
How do I do that?
Do something you've
never done before.
Like what?
I don't know, Coop.
I got stuff on my mind.
Can you just figure
it out for yourself?
Finish the e-mail
to Pete's brother?
Yeah. I don't know what to do.
Do I send it? Do I erase it?
I think you need to figure
that out for yourself.
I just think, with Adam,
we could have a family.
You know? A real family.
Pete could have a brother,
I could learn
more about who Pete is and...
Okay, that was about me,
and I know this isn't about me--
well, it's a bit about me.
Violet, uh--
I mean, he might get mad.
Okay, he will get really mad.
And what if he and Adam
don't like each other as adults?
Or what if Adam doesn't like
kids and he's not nice to Lucas?
What if he's mean to Lucas?
I'm staying silent.
But a real family, that's worth
fighting for. Right?
And I think Pete's--
I think he wants to fix this.
It's the right thing to do.
I know it is.
Mm-- mm-mm. Mm.
What did you do?
Pressed send.
Done. Ship sailed.
You're mad?
Do you know what this is gonna
do to my marriage?
To Pete? Did--?
Have you lost your mind?
I didn't send it.
Ow. I was just trying to help
you make up your mind.
I know. I'm just--
I'm frustrated.
Why won't Pete talk to me?
Angela:
So is everything okay?
Please tell me it's not
my bladder again.
No.
I didn't call you in to talk
about getting pregnant.
Jacob:
Angela, I do love you.
I've always loved you.
I love what we have together.
But what Evan
and I share is, um...
It's-- it's different.
I don't expect you
to understand that--
Jacob, I know.
I've always known.
Not about Evan,
but about who you really are.
You don't spend 20 years
with someone and not know.
Okay, you have to know
I didn't mean to hurt you.
I know I should be enraged.
I know I should be screaming,
but all I can think about
is how hard this must
have been for you.
All the pretending.
Living two lives.
Not being yourself.
Ha, ha. God, I'm so healthy.
I was gonna say.
Listen, I wasn't completely
pretending, okay?
My feelings for you are real.
I just didn't know.
When we first met,
I didn't know who I was, okay?
Or maybe I did
and I just didn't wanna know.
I just didn't wanna know.
But now you know,
and that's good.
That's a good thing.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
We will always be friends.
It's okay. I'll be okay.
Take care of him.
I will. Thank you.
I'm going to, um...
I'm going to go.
There's something else
you need to tell her, Jacob.
Evan and I...
We are both HIV positive.
Wh--?
Pete:
You're negative, Angela.
We'll test you again
in six months.
Angela, please.
Hey.
What are you doing
at your house?
Well, I wasn't having
much luck at your house.
You wanna try again?
Do you?
I called the police on Bob.
I turned him
in for molesting his wife.
All right. Give me a sec.
I'll be right over.
Wait, you're not mad?
You think I'm right.
No.
I'm furious. You were wrong.
That man needed counseling.
He needed...
I was right and you were wrong.
But that was at work.
We're at home now.
I'm gonna practice
what I preach, and, uh...
I'll yell at you tomorrow.
So tomorrow we'll fight?
But tonight--
sex for me.
Sex for you.
Okay. I only got a half an hour
because I'm supposed
to meet Cooper for drinks.
Then we'd
better make it count.
Hold that pose.
I'll be right over.
Sex for me.
Man:
I just need to see a doctor.
You need to take it easy.
Man:
Are you a real doctor?
I told you to pipe down.
Now sit down and wait your turn.
Someone will be
with you in a minute.
Man:
Pipe down.
Lively in here tonight, huh?
Halloween brings
out the crazies.
Mm.
What's that?
Oh, this?
Uh, this is a miniature
Alabama Lane cake
that was made just for you.
Is that how we make up now?
With sweets?
No, no. This is a bribe.
This is how we make up:
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
I'm so, so, so sorry.
There will be no more
baby talk. No pressure.
I mean, I don't even
wanna see a baby.
Ew. Babies. Mm.
I just
want to see you happy.
You're very cute
when you're lying.
And maybe we can practice
not making a baby.
I plan on that.
Okay.
Pete:
One, two, three. Whoo!
Violet:
Isn't this fun?
Actually, it is.
I can see the merits
of your family tradition.
I thought Halloween
wasn't your thing.
But it's your thing,
so now it's our thing.
Hey, okay, Lucas.
Go ahead.
Go ahead, Lucas.
Go with Anna. Go with Anna.
There you go.
Okay, um...
I'm going crazy.
I'm not enjoying this.
I know I should be,
but I'm not.
I, um...
I almost sent an e-mail today
to your brother.
Violet--
you have to give me
something.
I mean, I need to feel
like I know you.
I need to feel
like you want me to know you.
Please. I mean, obviously
your mom did something
to land herself in prison,
but your brother--
what is it about your family
that makes you so angry?
I'm gonna tell the story once
and I'm never gonna
tell it again. Okay?
My mother...
She liked to have a good time.
She was a party all by herself.
And my brother--
Adam made excuses for her
because he thought she--
I was the one that cleaned
the vomit off the floor.
I was the one that woke
her up twice a night
to make sure
she was still breathing.
She was a drunk.
And she was...
Beautiful,
so there were men.
Lots of men.
And I don't even know
who my father is.
Anyway, finally,
there was Henry.
I have no idea what
he saw in her,
but he was the first man I ever
met who didn't ignore me.
I was 13 and he was the first
good man I ever knew.
Which, now I think--
h-he took us to ball games,
helped me with my homework,
told me I could be a doctor.
And things were steady,
things were good.
But even though Henry
was living with us,
even though he wanted
to marry her,
there were a lot of men again.
One morning she came
in the kitchen,
she'd been out all night,
and he was there
packing to leave,
because I guess he'd had it,
and she starts screaming.
I didn't know what was
happening.
And then they're in the kitchen,
she's screaming
and then she's hitting him,
he's defending himself,
and then she gets
a knife and then...
And then he was dead, and...
He was a good guy.
Then I called the cops on her.
And Adam, he lied for her.
He testified for her.
That's why she only got
manslaughter.
You think there's good
in everyone, Violet.
It's not true.
There's no good there.
My family is garbage
and I won't go back.
Okay?
Okay.
Anna: There we go.
Violet: Hi, bud.
Hi.
Pete:
Are we done?
Because I have a shift in the er
and I wanna go start work early.
Yeah, we're done.
Pete: Okay.
Yeah.