According to
Elisabeth Kubler-Ross,
when we are dying or have
suffered a catastrophic loss,
we all move through
five distinct stages of grief.
We go into denial.
Push another amp...
Because the loss
is so unthinkable
we can't imagine it's true.
Clear!
We become angry with everyone,
angry with survivors, angry
with ourselves, then we bargain.
Damn, O'Malley,
come on. Live, just live.
His ICP's 30.
Push 70 of Mannitol,
start bagging.
His brainstem.
We beg, we plead. We
offer everything we have.
We offer up our souls, in
exchange for just one more day.
Stevens! Can you hear me?
Look at me, Stevens.
Damn it.
When the bargaining has failed,
and the anger is
too hard to maintain,
we fall into
depression, despair,
until finally we have to accept that
we have done everything we can.
We let go.
We let go and move
into acceptance.
Anybody know if he's a donor?
Oh, God!
Whoa, whoa. She wants
it out. Can we take it out?
- She's breathing over the vent.
- Let's pull out the tube.
Dr. Bailey.
Slow down. It's OK, slow down.
His ICP went through the
roof. We did everything.
Everything.
Chief, his organs are viable
for now, but it won't be long
until he's acidotic
and hypothermic.
Is he a donor?
Um... I don't know.
I called his mother.
She's on her way.
Let's close him up and get him to
the ICU in case she wants to see him.
- Who's George?
- What?
John Doe, the guy who threw me
out of the way of the bus, saved my life.
Everyone's crying and saying,
"John Doe is George." Who's George?
- You can't tell her.
- Alex.
She coded in my arms.
Out of nowhere, she died.
Just... I'll tell her.
I'll tell her when
she gets stronger.
Alex.
You OK?
I had... a dream.
- He was in his uniform.
- What?
George is gonna die in the
Army if we don't stop him.
Hand me my phone.
I need my phone.
Who said that was George?
Why do we think that's George?
Meredith said...
I don't know.
That's not George.
Look at his feet,
look how tall he is.
That's not George.
He wrote in my hand.
- What do you mean he wrote?
- What did he do?
He grabbed my hand and squeezed
it and he wrote with his finger.
- Wrote with his finger?
- In my hand, he wrote
"Double O Seven."
Well, give...
- OK, what'd I write?
- "Joe."
- No! No, I did not write "Joe"!
- Are you serious?
- You mean this
may not be O'Malley?
- This is funny.
Did anyone try and call O'Malley?
Can we get him on the phone?
I'm telling you, he
squeezed my hand.
Shut it. You don't
get to talk anymore,
you don't get to
talk ever again.
I could've sworn it was George.
- I got voicemail.
- He's not answering.
He has a freckle
in his right hand,
it's shaped like Texas.
I used to tease him about it.
I'll check.
You people, answer your pages.
George O'Malley jumped
in front of a bus today.
He knew what he was
doing and he did it anyway,
and he did it to save a life.
So I'm not gonna allow
you doctors to stand here.
There are lives on the line,
there are lives we can save.
So if George O'Malley
can jump in front of a bus...
we can answer our damn pages.
So let's go.
Damn it. Damn it, O'Malley.
How long ago did the pain start?
I don't know. A few weeks.
Growing pains.
I took him to see our
doctor. He's a bad doctor.
He stands there texting
while I'm talking to him.
He diagnosed Andy
with growing pains.
You know, I grew
up, and growing pains
did not cause me to fall
down on the soccer field.
Mom, you're being
a little dramatic.
Your pain is
dramatic to me, Andy.
Your mom's right. It's a
good thing that you came.
OK. Thanks,
because it does hurt.
Everything hurts, all the time.
OK. I'm gonna give
you a quick exam.
Let me know if the
pain gets worse.
This doesn't feel real.
- Does this feel real to you?
- No. I don't know.
Oh, crap.
I don't want... I can't.
Uh-uh. Don't look away, now.
Come on, you can walk over to her.
- Mrs. O'Malley, I'm so sorry.
- You were his wife.
In God's eyes
you're still his wife.
You should decide about
his organs. You decide.
- But... Uh, um...
- I can't do it, Callie.
I can't do it. You understand?
Ronnie and Jerry are off on
some fishing expedition in Alaska,
and they're gonna come home
and I have to tell them that Georgie...
That's all I can
do. It's all I can...
I can't.
I... I can't even see
him like this, I can't.
You need to do this for
me. Can you do this for me?
Speedboat accident,
19-year-old female.
Lost vitals twice, but
BP's holding in the low 80s.
Both arms amputated
at the scene,
right leg's hanging
on by a thread.
You recover either of the arms?
Probably at the
bottom of Puget Sound.
She was thrown from the boat
and got pulled into the propellers.
She needs more
access, bleeding out.
Get a central line
in her. Let's go!
Type and cross her and get
as much O-neg as possible.
Wait! I found them!
I found them! Her arms!
They were on the boat with her.
I found them in the water.
You have to take them.
They were just
floating in the water.
You can sew them back on, right?
We'll do everything we can.
Oh, my God, Jojo.
That was so gross.
Jasmine, you
just saved her life.
You think?
I'm so sorry. I just heard.
I don't know what to say.
Go home. You need to go home.
You need to cry
and scream and...
When my brother
died I ate donuts.
I ate a lot of donuts and
that helped some, but...
God, I don't know what to say.
His mom wants me to
decide about his organs.
He lost his wallet
in the accident.
They don't know if he's a donor.
His mom wants me to decide.
I can't. I can't tell her
no, but I can't decide.
I mean, we were only
married for a few months...
OK, but during those months,
you were the most important
person in George's life.
No.
No, I wasn't.
I'm sorry. OK, so let's
take a look at the X-rays.
Do I need to take my
son to another hospital?
What?
That doctor's hands are shaking
as he tries to stick
my son with a needle,
and those nurses are crying.
You and your friend... What
the hell is going on here?
There was an accident,
and one of our people died.
Andy is my person.
He's my only person,
and something is wrong with him.
So what I'm asking you is, do I
need to take him somewhere else?
No. No.
I'll make Andy my person, OK?
I'll make Andy my person too.
- I didn't tell her, OK?
- Karev.
Look, we just ignored her DNR.
Her kidneys quit and she
coded. She was freakin' intubated!
She's not strong enough.
- What's her BUN?
- Fifteen.
- And her creatinine?
- One-point-five.
She's strong enough.
You have to tell her.
- Why? It can wait.
- No, it can't!
It can't wait because George's
organs won't be viable for long.
If they want to use them, they
have to do it soon. I have to decide,
and I need Izzie to help me because
she's the one who should decide.
She's who should decide.
So that's one reason, and
the other reason is, Karev,
if you let them unplug George without
giving her a chance to say goodbye...
I mean it, she will
never forgive you.
You have to tell her.
Her pressure keeps dropping.
Throw in an IO, get the
blood in a rapid infuser.
These are pretty clean amputations.
We can reattach these arms.
Yay! I found them, you know.
I'm looking at omentum.
Let's get her to an OR now!
Does your friend
have any allergies,
medical condition,
on any medication?
- She's not our friend.
- Jasmine!
We barely know her. We met
her on the plane from Sydney.
We're backpacking,
seeing the States.
We're just traveling mates.
- She's really nice, though.
- Let's move!
Her name, can you give me that?
- Clara.
- Mm-hm. Clara Ferguson,
I think.
- Clara Ferguson.
- Clara, hang in there. Stay with me.
She lives with her mum in London.
I have her backpack in my car.
- OK, get it.
- Should we stay?
Yes. In the waiting room.
I'll update you when I can.
Dr. Shepherd.
Mr. Jennings. It's
good to see you.
- Derek, right? May I call you Derek?
- Of course.
I understand you lost a
resident. It's sad. I'm sorry.
But the hospital
board is meeting soon.
I need to know if you'd like to be the
next chief of surgery at Seattle Grace.
George... it's me.
You know, I pretty much
died not too long ago.
So I need you to call me back.
Please.
I know. I played the cancer
card, I'm gross. Whatever.
I need to tell you something
and I need you to not panic.
I need you to keep breathing.
I need you to
stay alive 'cause...
I swear to God, I need
you to stay alive, all right?
OK.
O'Malley...
he got in an accident.
He's brain dead.
I'm sorry, what?
What about his heart?
OK.
His eyes. I know.
Don't want to imagine
him without his eyes.
George would give everything.
His skin, his eyes, he
would give everything.
I have a kid in there.
Fifteen years old,
previously healthy.
Has back pain bad
enough to cause vomiting.
Can you talk it through with me
because I can't
figure out what it is
and I think best out loud.
Did you not hear
about George O'Malley?
I did. It's incredibly sad.
I cannot talk to you right
now. I cannot work right now.
Dr. Bailey, I hear that.
And I don't mean
to be insensitive,
but this kid, this
kid's still alive.
And I don't know what's
wrong with him, not a clue.
So, I need you to work.
I need you to talk through this
living patient with me, Bailey.
Please.
How's his neural exam?
Normal.
Could it be a
compression fracture?
Plain films and CT are negative.
- Any congenital problems?
- None reported.
Hey.
- Need to go home?
- No.
- Did you eat?
Can you eat?
No.
- Did you cry?
- No.
- Maybe if you cried...
- You just...
Just you being here is...
Don't say anything.
Just be here, that helps.
How are you?
- Meredith, we need you.
- OK. Excuse me.
Amanda, you have to
go. We need the room.
- I'm so sorry.
- I know.
I'm sorry. I'm...
I'm so sorry.
You too, huh? Growing pains?
You're saying this
is growing pains.
No, not just growing pains.
He has a mild case of scoliosis,
which, combined
with the growth spurt,
could account for the pain and
the clumsiness on the soccer field.
We'll see if it settles in
a couple of weeks. If not,
come back for more tests.
Why don't you just run them now?
Because the next set of tests
involve things like sticking
large needles into Andy's spine.
All right, then. Heading home.
- You're sure about this?
- No.
But I'm gonna write a
prescription for muscle relaxants.
You know I'm here
if you need me,
which I really
hope that you won't.
Did Torres decide about
O'Malley, about his organs?
- I don't know.
- I'm gonna see where they are.
Chief, look, I... I know this
is the worst possible moment,
but... we need to talk.
The board is planning a coup.
They're saying that
you dropped the ball,
that our ranking
isn't coming up.
They wanna oust you.
They're asking me to support it.
They're asking me to
step up to take the job.
Take my job?
I told them I'd think about it.
I bought you some
time, but you need a plan.
Torres has made a decision.
Are you here to give an
update on the boating victim?
- Yeah. Where are...?
- They left.
Her friends left. They said
they had a plane to catch,
something about a concert in Vegas
they didn't want to miss. Left her pack.
She's got dozens of surgeries
ahead of her, if she survives.
When she needs
a support system...
OK, until we find her
family, you're it. Keep that.
I'm sorry, you want... You're
ordering me to be her friend?
She's gonna wake up in a lot
of pain, missing one of her legs,
and unable to use
either of her arms.
So, yes, I'm ordering
you to be her friend
'cause I'm sure as
hell not gonna do it.
I'm heading back to surgery.
Patient is George O'Malley, 29.
Procedure is organ
recovery for donation.
I will call on the
receiving surgeons.
Kidneys.
St. Luke's Children's. Boise.
- Who's it for?
- Sorry?
- Who are his kidneys for?
- I gave all that to the nurse.
I would like you to tell me.
Molly Kemper, eight years old.
Hypoplastic kidneys.
Thank you.
Lungs.
Lungs and heart are going
to Portland Medical Center.
Terry Class, age
22. Cystic fibrosis.
Liver.
Whoa.
You are evil. You are the devil.
- I am, I admit it.
- Cristina, you know the rules.
The rules are stupid.
Are you saying
my shrink is stupid?
I'm saying she's a prude.
- She's prudey and misguided.
- Mm-hmm.
She wants us to get
to know each other.
She wants me to keep
getting to know myself.
She does not want me
burying myself in you.
And if we start to have sex...
I'll bury myself in you.
- Oh, now who's evil?
- It's not gonna be
too much longer.
You want me to
quit therapy? Hmm?
- No. Crap.
- Mm-hm.
All right. We have to go to
O'Malley's funeral anyway.
No. I hate funerals.
Let's skip it.
We can push up Ceviche's
débridement. That's a good excuse.
- Ceviche?
- Chopped-up fish.
- Propeller accident. Ceviche. Funny.
- Right. It's sick.
- That's what makes it funny.
- We're going to the funeral. Come on.
"Then all these unicycle boys
with wings carried us on a platform
like we were Cleopatra
or something. Hilarious."
I can't believe they went
to Burning Man. Hags.
They never even
heard of Burning Man.
I hate them.
I hate them!
Clara... forget them.
OK? They're morons.
They're... Just think about today.
OK, the fact that
today you're gonna get
what we believe is
your final débridement.
After that we'll get the physical
therapist here to get your arm moving.
I'm gonna save this
piece for you to do.
- Thanks.
- Now I'm gonna ask you
one more time.
- No.
- Don't you want to
call your mom...
- No.
- Before your next surgery?
No. Not yet.
But we could write
her another e-mail.
Will it make you
late for your funeral?
No. No.
Hi, Mum. I hope you're well.
Aside from the heat and the
smell, Burning Man was amazing.
There is an appointed
time for everything...
and a time for every
affair under the heavens.
A time to be born,
and a time to die.
A time to plant, and a
time to uproot the plant.
A time to kill and
a time to heal.
A time to tear down
and a time to build.
- A time to weep...
- Are you OK? You want the wheelchair?
And a time to laugh.
A time to mourn
and a time to dance.
A time to cast away stones,
and a time to gather
stones together.
A time to embrace,
and a time to refrain
from embracing.
I'm sorry.
- You're laughing?
- She's laughing.
George... George is dead.
He's dead. They're about
to put him in the ground
and the priest is doing
classic rock lyrics,
and that girl, that redhead,
is crying harder
than his mother.
And she never even met him.
You are far more twisted
than I ever realized.
And you got
married on a Post-It.
I got married on
a Post-It. I did.
- And you guys got married for real.
- - I know!
And I got cancer! What?!
O'Malley got hit by a bus.
She never stops crying.
Not now, please. Not now.
It's been a week.
You've been avoiding me.
- Not now.
- I am buying you time.
I am buying you time.
You have no idea
what I've given.
what I have sacrificed.
For every miscalculation
you think you see,
there have been a hundred
things that I have gotten right,
and no one knows.
Look, I'm on your side, OK?
I'm not the board.
I'm not Jennings.
Then back off, then.
Just back off and
give me time to think.
Let me have a minute to...
O'Malley was my intern.
And I'm trying to
just take a minute.
So, Derek, please...
back off.
You want a ride home?
I was gonna clean
out his locker.
Give his stuff to
his mom, but...
I was a bad friend. To George.
I was about as good a friend
to him as Clara's friends,
who keep sending
postcards from the trip
that she'll never get to take.
I just... I...
I abandoned him completely.
I just moved out and
stopped talking to him and...
Why? Because he
didn't think I was as hot
as I thought he was?
Because he didn't love me back?
This may be bad
timing, but I gotta ask.
What did that guy have?
I mean, he wasn't
much to look at,
but... you and
Stevens and Torres?
Tell the truth. Was
he, you know...
hung?
- That's...
- I know, I said bad timing.
But seriously, he was
kind of a dorky little dude.
- Stop! Stop talking!
- Sorry, sorry.
He... He died. I...
George died.
Yeah.
OK. Any pain here?
All right, take a deep breath.
Any dizziness when you
stood up? Take a deep breath.
- No.
- OK.
You are going home.
You are gonna come back in
12 days for another round of IL-2
and then you have your
PET scan two weeks after that,
but there's no need for
you to keep living in this bed.
You should take it easy.
You're still a cancer patient,
but you're no longer
a surgical patient.
Thank you, Dr. Bailey.
I don't know how to...
Thank you.
Don't forget to sign the
discharge papers before you leave.
Andy?
He's got serious pain
in his inguinal area,
down his legs and lower back.
He's got a temp of 101.
His mom says he's
been throwing up all night.
Please don't tell me this is
growing pains, Dr. Robbins.
- I can't do it.
- It's OK.
I can't move it at all.
It's only been three days
since your last surgery.
The swelling will come
down. We'll keep trying.
You're doing great.
Right. Great.
So, where did we leave off?
- The Grand Canyon?
- Yeah.
Big, gorgeous
hole in the ground.
OK. Miss you, Mum.
- Uh, wish you could see it.
- Clara... Sorry.
You are doing great, but
you got a long road here.
Believe me, your mom,
she's gonna want to know.
And she's gonna want to help.
She made me from scratch.
That's what she always says.
Like, when I wanted to
go skydiving, you know?
"Don't jump out of a plane, Clara.
I made that body from scratch."
Or when I sprained my ankle.
"Be more careful, darling. I
made that ankle from scratch."
Miss you, Mum.
I'm doing great.
Love you, Clara.
Come in.
Hello, Dr. Torres.
Chief, I was just...
I was just wondering.
I haven't heard anything about
my application
for attending, so...
Dr. Torres, Dr. Chang's
401k took a hit.
He's putting off retirement
another year or two.
So... So, what, you're
not giving me the job?
There is no job. Not this year.
I'm sorry. I assumed you heard.
OK. Dr. Chang is
basically a figurehead.
You're clear on that, right?
When people want
the best, they page me.
I have basically been running
Dr. Chang's department...
Dr. Chang has an
impeccable record!
- He is a dinosaur!
- And so am I!
You're...
This is...
- You're gonna regret this.
- Dr. Torres...
No! No, no. I am just...
No, I am excellent!
I am excellent, and
any other hospital
would be thrilled to have me.
I'm flattered for
the offer, Larry,
and I'm seriously
considering it.
But it's complicated and
I need a little more time.
I can't give you
more time, Derek.
I can give you more
money, better benefits,
and a whole lot of press.
That's what I can give you.
- But I can't give you much more time.
- - Yes, I am.
I'm a superstar, a
superstar with a scalpel!
- Torres!
- No! Don't say my name.
I am too big a star for
you to say my name.
I build arms out of nothing
and legs like God.
And when I win the Harper Avery
and every other prize there is,
you will rue this
day, Chief Webber.
That's right. I said "rue."
Tight ship you're
running here, Webber.
Real tight ship.
- Amanda. Hi.
- Hi.
What are you doing here?
I... can't sleep.
I can't fall asleep, 'cause
I see his face all the time.
I see him at bus stops.
He was sweet,
smiling, and then...
And then I see the
way that he ended up,
so that even his best
friends can't recognize him
and I can't sleep.
Can you... Can you sleep?
I...
am gonna write
you a prescription...
for an anti-anxiety medication.
And I want you to take it
because the sleep deprivation thing
can be quite harmful.
- Dr. Robbins.
- Chief.
Did you order an emergent
3-D MRI for this patient?
OK, you're mad, I see that.
But with the patient's
mother's insurance
it could take weeks to get an
MRI and a specialty pain referral...
So you expect the hospital
to pay with whose money?
- Sir, I only thought...
- I don't want to hear it,
Dr. Robbins.
Now discharge the patient,
refer him back to his physician,
and do it now!
Dr. Karev, change of plans.
Open up!
Open the door, Torres.
Open the door, or
I'll keep knocking
and potentially damage
my multi-million dollar hands.
My ex-husband died.
He died. He actually
got hit by a bus.
George got hit by a bus, and
now I have to get a new job
and I'm never gonna
see my friends anymore
and Arizona keeps
bringing me donuts!
This place for sale? It's nice.
- What?
- Oh, nothing, nothing.
Oh, my God!
- Hey, Derek!
- Oh, hey, hi!
- Dude, get a room.
- On the stairs? Doesn't that hurt?
Leave us alone, we're newlyweds.
A Post-It wedding does
not make you newlyweds.
You know what?
You're newlyweds, too.
- You need your own space.
- What are these?
Keys to my trailer.
Your new home.
Enjoy.
- Dr. Hunt.
- Yes?
I'm Louise O'Malley,
George's mother.
Of course, I'm sorry.
I didn't... I'm sorry.
It's all right.
Well, I hope you don't mind
me coming here to see you.
I know you surgeons
are very busy people.
- My Georgie was always...
- That's no problem. It's fine.
I'm...
having trouble. I'm...
having trouble...
I...
I think it's because I'm
having trouble understanding.
There's a piece of
the puzzle missing.
I do better when I understand
things, how things happen.
And George, my George...
The boy I knew,
the boy I raised,
my boy, would never
have joined the Army.
So I'm trying to understand.
I'm trying to understand
that piece of it.
I'm trying to understand why
Georgie wasn't at work that day,
why he was on his
way to my house
to tell me he joined
the Army in wartime.
I don't understand.
And Dr. Webber said
I should talk to you.
Mrs. O'Malley, I didn't
know him like you knew him,
didn't know him long,
but he had tremendous
potential as a trauma surgeon.
He was very fast on his feet.
He could think and act
simultaneously under intense pressure.
He had tremendous potential.
And...
He was impatient. He
wanted to become better faster.
He wanted to save more lives.
He was good.
And he was thoughtful
and generous.
Now, I think in
the end, I think...
I think he was heroic and noble,
and I liked him very much.
And I think he gave you a good
reason to be very, very proud.
Hey, I'm headed out.
- Just wanted to say good night.
- Good night.
Clara, you just moved... You
moved your fingers, like you waved.
You waved goodbye. This is huge!
That's huge? That I waved?
That I waved a finger?
That's my life from now on,
that's the best I
have to hope for?
Clara...
Do you see that woman
out there talking to Dr. Hunt?
We buried her son this week.
He had an accident, like you.
He wasn't even as bad off as
you were, and he didn't make it.
Clara, I know that
it doesn't feel like it,
but it is a miracle
that you lived.
It is a miracle. So you
should call your mom.
She would want
to know the truth.
You stupid little bitch.
You really don't get it, do you?
You should have let me die.
You had no business.
I've got one working hand,
I may never walk again.
Do you think you're God?
You had no business.
Your friend is better
off. His mum is better off.
Do you think this is a miracle?
Who wants to live like this?
Just let me die! Just
let me die, please!
- Just let me die!
- Hey, Clara...
Just let me die! Get off me!
I need some help in here!
- Clara, stop! You have to stop!
- Get off me!
In medical school, we
have a hundred classes
that teach us how
to fight off death...
and not one lesson
in how to go on living.