To a critically ill patient,
an organ transplant
means a new start,
a second chance.
But the body is designed to
fight off any outside invader,
even one that's
trying to save it.
Jackson Avery
really has a bigger say
than any of us in
running this hospital?
That can't be true. Can it?
Well, he's a voting member
of the management team
and he also represents the
Harper Avery Foundation.
And their 175 million bucks.
As opposed to our $15 million apiece.
- Huh.
According to Stan, not only
does he have the deciding vote,
he can veto ours.
Because a transplant doesn't
guarantee that it's an easier life.
That is ridiculous.
He's a fellow.
So are you.
But he's a plastics
fellow. And I'm me.
Well, let's not overreact.
I mean, it's Jackson. He's
not some corporate stranger.
He's one of us.
No, you're right.
He's a smart kid.
He's gonna follow our lead.
No. No. We made this plan.
We pulled it together.
Look, I'm grateful to Harper
Avery for an infusion of cash,
but I'm not gonna
let some, some...
Plastics fellow?
Plastics fellow tell me
how to run my service
'cause his mommy said he could.
Preach.
There's a threat that the body
will reject the organ outright.
It was your idea.
It was pillow talk. And
suddenly, it's a business plan.
You were all for it at the time.
You investing in
the hospital, sure.
Anointing your son boy king?
What on earth makes you
think that young man's prepared
to take on this kind
of responsibility?
He's my son. I know
what he's capable of.
And he's my student. I do, too.
You know, actually,
I should revise that.
Now he's my boss, and my
girlfriend is my boss' boss.
What could possibly go wrong?
You are forgetting who
you're dating, Richard.
I'm the chairman of the
board of a large foundation.
I have made an extremely
savvy investment.
And I will manage my
investment as I see prudent.
I've placed at the
top of the organization
an individual that is energetic,
motivated, and responsive.
There's only one room in which
I take orders from my boyfriend.
This is not it.
Good morning,
ladies and gentlemen.
Good morning.
Shall we?
Okay, so we're agreed
that the peds and adult ERs
will be combined to save on personnel?
- Yeah.
I'm sorry, guys.
I was running on time,
and then my last rounds'
patient turned into a crier.
Pow.
We were discussing
the reopening of the ER.
And the trauma department.
Oh, yes.
I'm not ready for that just yet.
If you need more time with
the material, we can go ahead...
No, no, I've... I've
read it. It's just that
the foundation feels like the
ER is not a forgone conclusion.
They need a site visit, a
chance to look over the numbers.
It could be a month
before a decision.
Okay. The foundation
knows we plan on getting
our Level I trauma
designation back, right?
They know that's the idea, yeah.
It's the fact.
I think we should table this
until we can bring in Owen.
He'll have a lot of
thoughts on this, too.
Yeah...
That's the other thing.
What thing?
Okay.
Since we are starting fresh,
the thought is that new leadership
would be good for morale.
What, like, chief of surgery?
Oh, no way. Firing Owen?
Okay, we're not firing Owen.
Thinks that... Your mother.
The Harper Avery Foundation...
Your mother, Avery. Just say it.
It's a recommendation.
It's an inappropriate one.
Tell your mom
that. This is bull...
And this is going
nowhere. I have surgery.
Yeah. Me, too. We
should come back to this.
You know, I don't care who's
giving you your marching orders,
this thing with Owen
is not happening.
Well, say what you want,
but without the Harper Avery
Foundation, none of us are here.
And we appreciate that.
But no one expected them to
come in and start dictating policy.
Yeah, well, no one asked you
to sue the hospital
into bankruptcy either.
For the plane crash
that killed Lexie?
If we put Kepner's
donor to OR One,
that moves Bailey's
hernia to OR Five.
Robbins is in Five. Okay, Six.
We don't have enough
nurses to staff Six.
I thought you said you
were getting them back.
I'm trying. Some of them
are bitchier than I am.
Chief.
Yeah. UNOS just called.
They got a kidney that's a
match for Jaelynn Donovan.
Yeah, we have no
room today, Karev.
No OR staff. Half
the nurses have quit,
including the
transplant coordinator.
You may need to
decline this one.
This girl's 16. She's been
on dialysis for three years.
Okay. All right.
Well, we'll figure it out, okay?
Okay, so...
Owen. Just a second.
Owen, they're talking
about replacing you.
Ruth, excuse us, please.
What? Why? Who is?
Avery.
But we're not gonna
let that happen.
I just didn't want you to hear
a rumor and think I didn't tell...
Dr. Yang, it's UNOS. They
have a heart and lungs.
I'm gonna talk to
Catherine Avery.
You're not gonna do
anything. I am. Take your call.
Dr. Yang here.
Bradley Parker, 31
years old, end-stage ALS.
Trach-dependent. Had a
lap-chole three weeks ago.
Now presents with a chief
complaint of hematochezia.
He actually used the
word "hematochezia."
Yeah, he was an
internal medicine resident
at Mercy West while I was there.
He did a residency with ALS?
He was diagnosed second year
and worked till he couldn't anymore.
He's an amazing guy.
Is that coming from...
Hey, could you turn that down?
Hey, guys. What the
hell is going on here?
This is a hospital. There
are very sick people here.
That includes you, too, Brad.
Okay, everyone out.
Let's go. Out. Come on.
It's all right.
I invited them.
Uh-huh.
Well, Dr. Edwards and I need
to discuss your next steps.
So maybe if
everyone could leave...
I already know my next step.
I'm donating my organs.
We do organ donation
after a patient's brain dead.
You're nowhere
close to brain dead.
I'm doing...
Mom.
He's doing DCD.
Donation after cardiac death.
He can give if his heart stops.
I'm being kept alive
by this vent.
Once we disconnect it...
Booyah.
Chief Hunt signed off.
Welcome to my funeral.
Avery... Am I in or out?
What? That's...
Word is I might be out of a job,
so I'd like to hear it from you.
Yeah, there was a thought that
a change in leadership
could be good for staff morale.
For morale?
I've been killing myself
to keep morale up
for the past three weeks,
to keep this place open.
And no one is saying
that you haven't...
Nobody's saying anything.
I've been shut out of every
decision that you people make.
And now I hear this?
All right. Calm down.
Don't tell me to calm down!
Guys, guys, guys. Let's
take this somewhere else.
This is coming from you, too? You're
all just talking about a new chief?
No. No.
It was brought up,
and we tabled it.
Oh, you tabled it?
You shouldn't even
be talking about it.
Listen, this is a
decision that we have...
Avery, enough. I'm
just trying to explain...
Avery, go!
You know as well as I
do there are politics here.
We're trying to find
our way. Just sit tight.
I am through sitting tight.
I am through looking like
an idiot while you all lie to me.
No, we're not lying to you.
When you said that
we were in this together,
I thanked you, and then
one hour later, you quit.
You're a liar. You lied to
the staff. No, no, no, no.
We are doing the best we can.
And then I'm this poor
sucker running around
trying to fix this mess
that you all made!
You don't!
You do not want to get into
whose responsibility this is.
You don't want to get into
who's responsible for all of this.
You don't!
Well, I can make this
decision easier for you.
I quit.
Whoa.
Right there.
Owen, what happened?
Did you get the
heart and the lungs?
Yes.
That's great.
Talk to me.
Nothing happened, I'm just...
I'm done.
I should've been
done a long time ago.
Okay, what are
you talking about?
Shepherd is right.
This is all on me.
No one blames you.
Well, somebody does.
And as long as that's true, I...
I don't see how I
can be effective here.
Depending on when
the organs come in,
you might need to
adjust the OR board,
move things off until tomorrow.
Sweetheart. Owen...
Not the same.
Surgeons save lives.
You just catch it when
it falls out of someone.
OBs do surgery.
If a baby is not coming
out, I go in, and I get it.
It's not the same.
Plus every patient that I
have is two patients in one.
So beat that.
You wear pink scrubs.
Yeah.
Yeah, you win.
I have no response for that.
You really pull it off, though.
Thank you.
Mmm-hmm.
Alex, do you know Jason?
Yeah, Chest
Peckwell. Jason Myers.
Have you seen where
Jaelynn Donovan's parents are?
Isn't Jaelynn up in dialysis?
I know where she is. I
asked about her parents.
Excuse me. Are you
getting on or what?
I'll take the stairs.
I'm going up there, too.
Are you?
Turn to page six,
everyone, the...
Dr. Avery, could you...
Come on in, sweetheart.
We're just going over
the purchase agreement
you'll be signing tonight.
I'm sure you've
read through them.
Can I speak with you
outside for just a moment?
Of course. Excuse me.
Of course.
Yeah, it's right here.
No, I did not read through them,
as I couldn't possibly read through
them as they are not in English.
I understand.
I am not a lawyer and
I am not an accountant.
Stop. Breathe.
Nobody understands
those documents.
That's why these smart people
are here to explain them to us.
All you have to do is
hear what they have to say.
Ask a couple of questions,
and trust your gut.
Now put on your game face and
go in there and listen to the suits.
Try not to nod off when they start
talking about debt-to-equity ratios.
It's like a sedative. Go on.
Okay, one more thing.
When we are in there,
I am not "Sweetheart."
Okay, baby.
Okay...
What the...
Who is this?
God. It's Thelonious, Dad.
We've only been getting dialysis
for, like, an entire
year together.
I'd be more comfortable if
you were in your own chair.
It's bad enough to
be in kidney failure.
Now you're gonna
suck all the fun out of it?
I'm just asking...
Honey, let's not fight. Not now.
It's too big a day.
Oh, no. What?
We found a kidney, Jaelynn.
No more dialysis.
Oh, my God, Theo.
I'm getting a kidney.
Sweet.
Yeah.
Did anyone call
Jackson for this?
Who cares? I mean,
this is, this is his fault.
Why do we need an
emergency meeting?
Hunt quit. What?
You can't keep throwing
that plane crash in his face.
Don't make this my fault.
He walked out. You
shouldn't have told him.
Wait. Wait. You told him?
That he might be getting
fired? Of course I did.
Nothing was
decided, and besides,
we weren't gonna let
Avery get rid of Hunt.
Avery has his own agenda.
No, warning Owen
is the least we can do.
We went behind his
back long enough.
Cristina, we should probably
keep what's said in here private.
Well, then count me out.
I have a heart-lung
transplant coming in.
Oh, well, Karev's kid just
got a kidney from UNOS.
Two transplants in one day?
Three with Kepner's DCD.
Three? That doesn't happen.
Well, it did, okay? And
the ORs are fully booked.
We have half the nursing staff
and no transplant coordinator.
Who was handling all that? Hunt.
Oh.
Nurses' station.
Avery. Hey, what are you all
doing about the Pegasus protocols?
The what now?
Pegasus put all these
protocols in place,
one of which is telling me
that I have to do hernia repairs
using their stupid
Varner technique.
Now I have a
hernia repair today.
I would like to do it the way
I've been successfully doing it
since you were
sucking your thumb.
We'll look at that.
Well, when?
There's all sorts
of idiotic rules here,
like the OR layout and organ
transports, bariatric centers.
Isn't that why
you're the boss now,
so the place won't
be run by idiots?
Thank you, Bailey.
You're welcome, boss.
Hey, have you guys
seen Chief Hunt?
I would like to
know why he signed
a death warrant on
one of my patients.
Well, good luck.
He's gone. He quit.
He... What? Hunt?
Ask boss man over here.
There was a
disagreement about policy.
Yeah, well, then
change the stupid policy.
Not before he changes
my stupid policy first.
My hernia's this afternoon.
They're going to get the donor
heart and lung as we speak.
We should have you in the
OR sometime this afternoon.
Not a minute too soon.
You should've seen what
I coughed up this morning.
I swear to God,
the thing had hands.
Dr. Yang. I was
hoping I'd catch you.
Hey, you get your fat
head out of my door.
Bad enough I gotta watch
you go by my window
eighty times a day while
you walk your stupid laps.
I just want to know
if Dr. Yang knows
about the pepperoni pizza
you've been smuggling in here.
Snitch all you want. I'm not
gonna be here much longer.
No kidding? You're dying.
Hey, there is a God, and
he's heard my prayers.
Mr. Schultz is getting
a heart-lung transplant.
A heart? Well, he
doesn't need a heart.
He's got junky lungs.
I've been on this
machine for three months,
and you're giving
that bastard my heart?
You're not looking
too good, Herman.
Somebody might be dying today.
Shut up.
Mr. Crump, please calm down.
Mr. Schultz's heart
is compromised
because of the stress caused
by his pulmonary hypertension.
So a heart-lung
transplant is the...
You're gonna have
pulmonary hypertension
unless you get a
supervisor down here.
That doesn't make any sense.
A supervisor, now!
Absolutely. Right away.
Yeah.
So why do they hate
each other so much?
They were neighbors.
Crump's wife left him for
Schultz, like, 30 years ago.
No. Yes.
She ended up leaving him, too, for
some other guy in the neighborhood.
No. No. Yes.
Can your mind be
blown on your own time?
Right now I have to
talk with my supervisor.
Um... Well, you
own the hospital now.
So doesn't that make
you the supervisor?
It does.
So I will have that
conversation with myself.
Well, should I, like,
stick around for that or...
Oh.
You're pushing all
of our surgeries?
There's no place to do them.
Mer, I need you to do a
kidney procurement in Missoula.
I gotta stay here and do the
transplant, and Robbins is in surgery.
I can't. Hunt is gone,
and I have to sort out where
all these patients are going.
Come on. I'm not gonna
risk some Missoula hack
screwing up the dissection and
giving me some unusable kidney.
Jaelynn got a kidney?
Can I do anything?
I said I need a surgeon.
You're not a surgeon yet.
And I forgot. Neither are you.
Upper management's too
busy to get a kid a kidney.
Dr. Immerman to peds ICU.
Call Dr. Shepherd and
ask him to fix this board,
and book me a plane to Missoula.
The patient's this
really sweet kid...
Whatever. You can come, too.
I've heard your plan, but
you still haven't heard mine.
I can see not wanting
a colonoscopy,
but that's not the only option.
We could do radionuclide
scans, angiography.
I mean, there's a bunch of
endoscopic procedures that we could try.
This is why I didn't tell you.
I knew you'd disagree.
And I didn't want
to have to spend
valuable minutes of
my life convincing you.
You're depressed,
but we can treat that.
I'm not.
I'm...
ALS...
Is 100% fatal.
If I donate my organs, my
death can mean something.
If I keep fighting,
I get an infection
and can't donate.
I've decided
to stop fighting it.
So...
We're extra careful
and we just make sure that
you don't get an infection.
Come on. Please let me help you.
There are people who love you,
who need you.
Come on. You are
still alive and so...
So you.
April.
Yes.
You're fired.
This is where you should check
your meds off every day. Okay?
You'll start your
mornings with prednisolone
and mycophenolate at 8:00 am.
Then follow that with
fk-506 at 10:00 am.
And 10:00 pm those
are for every day.
Then you'll also be on
trimethoprim-sulfa three times a week.
Now you're just making up words.
Look, you have to take
them no matter what, all right?
Or you'll lose the kidney.
You can't miss a dose.
She won't.
Fine. I'll do whatever
you just said.
Okay, the meds, they can cause
pretty dramatic mood swings,
hair thinning, weight
gain, diarrhea, acne.
I mean, they don't
always happen,
but if they do,
don't be alarmed.
If you were dying, would
you donate your organs?
Of course.
Even if you still had time?
This the DCD guy?
I have a plan. He just
won't even listen to it.
You know, he's a
doctor. He knows the deal.
He's not gonna get
any better. Yeah, but...
He's gonna save a crapload
of people. I think it's awesome.
He's got perfectly good
organs. Might as well use them.
Oh, my God.
He has good organs.
That is genius. I am a genius.
So you'll have to pick up Zola.
Did you sort out the OR board?
I started, but I have a surgery.
I have Torres looking at it right
now. Why are you on a plane?
Because Alex
wants his kid's kidney
mobilized before perfusion, and
he's being a giant baby about it.
All right. Well, call
me when you get back.
Okay.
He doesn't mean
to be a giant baby.
Karev, I think he just hates feeling
like you guys left him in the dark.
You don't have to teach me
how to speak Alex. I'm fluent.
I'm just learning.
I shouldn't take it personally that
he's acting like he hates me, right?
I mean, he's just
feeling abandoned
by everyone in
his life right now,
and the fact that
I'm dating a guy
and not available to go to
Joe's Bar every night is just...
He's feeling hurt and lonely.
Or he hates you.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
What's wrong?
She locked herself in there.
Jaelynn, sweetie. It's
okay. Come on out.
Jaelynn, it's Dr. Karev.
Look, Jaelynn, come
on. I know it's scary.
Just come out and we'll talk. You
can ask me whatever you want.
It's the silent treatment.
She won't crack.
Once we took her phone from her.
She didn't speak
to us for seven days.
Oh, she's talking to somebody.
She texting you?
Maybe.
Tell her to come
out of the bathroom.
I don't tell her what to do.
Just do it. Make me.
Are you for real?
"Dr. DF"?
Dr. Douche Face.
Who's that supposed to be?
Who do you think?
Now give it back.
Make me.
It's called a domino transplant.
Because you guys are
the same blood type,
we will put the new heart
and lungs into Mr. Schultz,
and then take
Mr. Schultz's original heart
and give it to Mr. Crump.
So his heart in my
body? Nothing doing.
It's the best
solution in this case.
The best solution
is a 62-year-old
getting a 70-year-old's
hand-me-downs?
Technically, all donor
hearts are hand-me-downs.
Mr. Schultz's heart is 80%
functional. Yours is only 10%.
Yeah, you hear that? 80%.
You'd be lucky to get
a ticker like this one.
I'd be lucky if you dropped dead
right now and I
got the fresh heart.
Mr. Crump, you should
really consider this op...
Look, I would rather croak
than have this bastard's
old lump of meat in my chest.
Hey.
This day just keeps
getting better and better.
Yeah, right. It's great.
Okay, sir. You need to sit down.
No, I need to get
out of this room.
Sir, calm down. Just...
Please. Get out of my...
So he's rejecting
the heart out of spite?
Yeah.
I can't figure out how
to talk him into taking it.
Have you talked to Owen?
No. But I know him.
He just needs time.
What is your
husband's deal anyway?
Oh, Cristina.
You know, it's like
everyone has gone crazy.
Owen and Derek are
at each other's throats.
Avery's on some
kind of power trip.
You know, I am supposed to be
prepping for a major transplant,
and Callie's left me with an OR
board that's like a Rubik's cube.
Wow. In charge
one day, and already
the hospital's
spinning out of control?
Okay, I gotta go. We're here.
You need to stop listening
to my conversations.
Is the place really
spinning out of control?
What? No, of
course not. Shut up.
Everything's perfectly fine.
Where is everybody?
They've gone. We're
pretty much done here.
What do you mean
done? Where's our kidney?
Why do you look confused?
Where is our kidney?
Hands off my kidney!
I'm telling you, this
isn't your kidney.
And I'm telling you, show me
the paperwork to prove that,
or I'm gonna reach down your
throat and take one of yours.
I found our kidney.
Great. Now call
off your attack dog.
Wilson, stand down.
Where is it? It hopped
a flight to Seattle.
All by itself? How'd it do that?
I don't know. We gotta get
home. Come on. Let's go.
You sent her an emoticon
of a bee and an ice cube?
It means "be chill"
And come out of the bathroom.
I know it's you.
Theo would never text emoticons.
Just... Give me five minutes,
and then I will never
bother you about it again.
Okay. Five minutes, but in here.
I know you're scared,
but you need this kidney.
At least with dialysis, I won't go
bald, get fat, and poop my pants.
That's not the solution,
and you know it.
Can't I, like, take
the next one?
I'm, like, not ready for this.
Yes, you are.
Look, Jaelynn,
there's this girl, and I didn't
tell her that I was into her,
and now she's with
some dude with big arms.
Um... Are you,
like, hitting on me?
'Cause you're, like, old.
God. No. No.
No, my point is, is that
this kidney is a good thing,
and that you need to
take the good things
when they're in front of you,
because if you don't, someone else will.
So you're saying,
take this kidney
so some dude with
big arms doesn't get it?
Yeah.
Let's get her prepped.
Don't leave her side.
Got it.
Hey. How's it looking?
You sent me all the way
out here to get a kidney
that's already flying coach to
Seattle as an unaccompanied minor?
What? I don't even know
who's coming to pick it up.
Find out. Alex, I...
Look, just deal with it, okay?
Are you okay there? You
look a little overwhelmed.
Anything I can help you with?
Can you read everything in
my arms and own this hospital?
You actually gonna
look at those protocols
or just keep
carrying 'em around?
Right. Your hernia. I'm gonna get
you an answer just as soon as I...
Too late. I already
did it, my way.
That's not... Bailey,
you shouldn't...
Well, you couldn't make a
decision, so I made it myself.
You gonna get rid of me
now like you did Hunt?
I didn't get rid of
Hunt. Why... Sign this.
What is this?
Authorization for a
domino transplant.
Yes, why am I...
Because when you
anoint yourself king,
it comes with certain
responsibilities. You have to sign this.
I need to know
what this is first.
Well, I could take the
time to explain to you
how a heart-lung
domino transplant works,
but by then, both my
patients will be dead.
I know how a damn domino works.
Hey, April. Here, take these.
What are they?
Hunt left before he could
coordinate the recovery teams
for your DCD patient.
So it's just a list of which
organs are going where.
Yeah, well, he's not my patient
anymore, per his request...
Just sign this.
Just handle it, please.
Hey, make sure you sign
your own name, not your mom's.
Really?
Avery. What?
I want to know who the hell sent
my kidney flying
coach to Seattle
when I sent two
surgeons to pick it up.
Wait. What are
you talking about?
He's talking about
the protocols.
Look...
Pegasus policy states, look,
"Donated kidneys coming
from outside a certain radius
"will be flown unaccompanied,
saving personnel hours."
So when the other
hospital called,
the nurse just told
'em to put it on a plane.
Told you they were stupid rules.
You should read 'em sometime.
Oh, great.
Does anybody know
what's going on?
Tough day, boss?
He is drowning,
and he is taking my
hospital down with him.
Where is all this
drama coming from?
He will handle this.
Just give him time.
He's paralyzed.
Decisions are like
building blocks.
He'll make one, then
another will follow.
You do not do
this job one calmly
thought-out decision at a time.
You're spinning
plates, 10 at a time,
and you're doing it at a sprint.
He will get there.
You act like I don't have any
idea what I'm talking about.
When I was Chief, I worked
hand in hand with the board.
So I know what it takes to...
You are not doing
it now, Richard.
I am not thinking
of myself, Catherine.
I'm thinking of your son.
Look, if he fails at this, it
will follow him his whole life.
It'll define his entire career,
this failure, and he
didn't even choose it.
His mother chose it for him.
Ca...
You find me a real heart yet?
I've got a real heart for you.
You just have to get
over yourself. Move on.
Whatever it is that happened
between the two of you
is so far in the past...
It's like it was yesterday.
Okay, fine.
You can't forgive him. So don't.
Beat him.
Take his perfectly good
heart and outlive him with it.
There's, uh...
Really enough juice left in that
heart to get me to his funeral?
There's enough juice to
get you dancing on his grave.
Then my heart will stop.
The monitor will flatline.
And you guys will
have to get out of there.
Because the docs...
Will only have five
minutes to open me up
or my organs will be no good.
Are you sure?
Don't do this now, Mom.
I know it's selfish,
but I want more minutes.
The closer it gets...
I will support you either way.
But if you want to stop...
We can end this right
now and go home.
Mom.
She just wants to make sure
that if you have any doubts...
Your son is still a doctor.
And...
He wants to save a
17-year-old girl in Idaho
who is gonna get
one of his kidneys.
The other one is going to
a 44-year-old
councilman in Nevada.
His kidney could be
president one day.
You get it now.
I do.
Keep going.
Okay.
Um...
Half of your liver is going to
a 50-year-old artist right
here at Seattle Grace.
And a 10-year-old in
Oregon will get to play
on his little league team
'cause of the other half.
Did you get the OR
straightened out?
The place doesn't run without
Owen, Derek. You know it.
I didn't force him to leave.
But once he started talking
about who's to blame...
Because he feels the blame,
every day since it's happened.
And you remind
him again and again.
You say you forgive
him, but you don't
or you won't.
So what is it?
What is this about?
'Cause it's not about him.
Where are you going?
Surgery. Remember that?
No, I'm in Two.
No, you're not. I am.
Move. I've got a
domino transplant.
And I'm getting
a kid off dialysis.
I can totally wait.
No, you can't.
Well, I can't. Let's get
this show on the road.
This kid's a flight risk.
Find someplace else.
This OR's the only
one that's staffed.
Could you guys please shut up?
My patient is
trying to die in here,
and he'd like to
do it in silence.
Oh, God. He's dying in there?
Maybe you should go first.
How long is he gonna be?
Because Yang needs the OR.
I've got an OR.
Shut up! Hey,
all of you shut up.
All right, here's what
you're gonna do...
Okay, just give me one second.
Kepner, go back to your patient.
He can take as long as
he needs. We will wait.
Yang, you're in OR Two.
What? No. Heart and
lungs trump kidneys.
Take the patient
back to holding, and
the next OR that's
available is yours.
You can't... That is it.
Well, you heard the man.
He's the boss. Now move.
It's about time.
You mean "Thank you, Meredith
"for carrying a kidney
across state lines for me."
Whatever. Hand it over.
Can I scrub in? I'd love to...
I got Murphy.
You want me to apologize, Alex?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry
we bought the hospital.
I'm sorry you have to think
of us as your bosses now.
But we didn't do it for just us.
We did it for everyone,
for you, for Wilson,
who, by the way, fought
so hard for you today,
I thought she might cut
someone to get you that kidney.
So drop the attitude
before nobody
wants to work with you anymore.
There's nothing to talk
about, Shepherd. Move on.
Come on. This is costing me gas.
You can afford it.
Nobody blames you
for hiring the plane.
Not me, not anybody else,
and you shouldn't either.
You never would've
signed that paper
if you knew what
was gonna happen.
Let it go. You blame me.
You said it, Shepherd. You
said it again this morning.
I was pissed.
I've been pissed,
but not at you.
The world.
Yeah.
Yeah...
I'm pissed at Mark.
You gotta let that go.
It's almost time.
When the monitor
goes, when he's gone.
They'll have to
start operating, so...
We should probably
pay our respects now.
Time of death, 1846.
Start the clock.
No. No.
Hazel, we only have five minutes
or this will all have
been for nothing.
Come on.
Okay. I'm sorry.
No!
Honey, we've been
preparing for this. Let's go. No.
Come on. No!
Come on, dear. No.
Okay, I am... I am sorry, Hazel.
I'm so, so sorry.
Come on. Come on.
No. Sweetie.
Come on.
No.
Was he there? No.
Move over.
Um, hi.
Yeah. I heard you
almost killed somebody
trying to get
Jaelynn her kidney,
and I was kind of a
douche face, and...
Anyway, I'm, I'm
sorry. And thanks.
Okay.
Can I buy you a
beer or something?
Um, I'm all set.
Yeah, we both
are. We're all set.
Yeah.
Well, that was, uh...
What were we talking about?
I'm sorry. What?
Okay, thanks. Thank you, Doctor.
He stepped up, didn't
he, my reluctant son?
If I were the kind of
woman to say "I told you so,"
this might be the time.
He got through the day.
Oh, come on.
Can't you just say
that I was right once?
No, not when the
stakes are this high.
You want him to step up,
but the steps are too high,
and the consequences
for his career are too grave.
It's not fair to him.
Don't you tell me
what's not fair for my son.
You want to give
professional advice? Fine.
But you're wandering
into parenting advice,
and that is not your place.
Yeah, you're right. I'm
sorry. I overstepped.
Yes, sir, you did.
You ever...
You ever say something
and then a minute later,
realize you sound like
a complete imbecile?
Um... That's never
happened to me.
I've been a single
mom for 28 years,
ever since Jackson's dad
ran off to God knows where
because he couldn't stand
the pressure of being an Avery.
And I've been looking for a
man who cared about Jackson
the way a parent would,
and the moment I find
him, I bite his head off.
You're always gonna know
what's best for Jackson.
Yeah?
Okay, thank you, Doctor.
Yeah, right there.
Okay, thank you.
Well...
That's it, then.
We're officially the
new board of directors.
For better or worse. Thank you.
Congratulations, everyone.
Actually, I'd like
to share a list
of a few things I think
are our top priority.
You mean that the
foundation thinks...
No, I don't, actually...
Mean the foundation or my
mom or these stupid protocols.
I mean me.
Okay, well... Let's just listen.
Okay, I'll listen.
All right.
Number one, I move that
we reinstate Owen Hunt
as chief of surgery,
effective immediately.
Dr. Hunt has agreed to this.
There were some conditions.
Which brings me
to my second point.
We are reopening the ER.
We will be a Level I
trauma center again.
That will be top priority
once Owen Hunt is
here to share his input.
From now on, the
foundation will follow our lead.
We will tell them our
decisions as we make them.
Well, hear, hear.
Yeah. No, that sounds good.
I've got one more thing.
Maybe you shouldn't push it.
The transplant
process is very scary.
We are building a new hospital.
And that was your
vision, not mine.
My priority is to make
sure your vision comes true.
And while it is important
that we become
a leading center for
research and innovation,
we have to remember something,
we are now officially a
hospital run by doctors.
That should mean something.
It is our responsibility
to be the best doctors
we can possibly be
so that those who come after
us can strive to be their best.
So...
With that in mind,
I move to rename the hospital.
Again?
Why would we do that?
To, to what?
Let me guess. The
Harper Avery hospital?
No.
I propose that we give
this hospital a name
that can honor the very
reason we've come together
and been able to do this,
a name that exemplifies
the spirit of this hospital,
but also the depth
of our dedication.
A patient goes from worrying
about getting an organ
to worrying if the
organ will be rejected.
All in favor?
Aye.
Mmm-hmm.
The anxiety continues
until they can finally open
their eyes after surgery
and see that their gift
has been accepted.