Previously on ER..
Someone's down!
We have to wait for the area
to be secured.
We should not be out here!
I thought you were supposed
to smooth things out
between the ER
and paramedics.
You're my new intern.
I just gave you an order.
Peter, I wasn't aware that
Reese had a hearing problem.
What I do with my son
is my business.
And I'm not interested
in continuing as intern chief.
My beard is stuck.
I wouldn't have asked
so many questions
if you had told me
what you were doing.
Well, I'm sorry
that you thought
it was your business to ask me.
Carter?
'What are you doing here?'
♪ The taste of love is sweet ♪
♪ And hearts like ours meet ♪
♪ I fell for you
just like a child ♪
♪ And oh but the fire
went wild ♪
Hey!
Morning, Carter!
‐ It's Grace Jones.
‐ Ah.
Hey, I didn't wake you up,
did I?
I mean, you're on at 7?
Uh...yeah
but no‐no problem.
'Good. You settling in
down there?'
Yes, I like it.
You have a very interesting
CD collection.
What?
I said you have a very eclectic
CD collect..
Thanks.
You know, anything you want to
listen to
just ask me, don't ever touch it
on your own, though.
I mean, I‐I've rented
to a lot of students
so I had to make that a rule.
Carter, let me make you
one of these, man.
Oh..
It will sling‐shot
you into your day.
Yeah.
You're in a really good mood.
I am just...so glad
to be 100% focused on medicine.
‐ Hey, can I ask you something?
‐ Sure.
Do you find it easy to evaluate
other people's work?
Hmm, time to grade
your student, huh?
'Hm‐hm.'
I worry about being too harsh.
Does she deserve
to be judged harshly?
I want to be fair.
Lucy hasn't gotten
off to a great start
this year, clearly.
But she's smart,
and she's willing to work hard.
So I think maybe
I should just go easy
and give her a chance
to turn things around.
Go on. Keep talking.
‐ 'One of the strippers?'
‐ 'Yeah, I'm saying, "Damn!"'
'Can't you cover that up?"'
She was destroying the magic.
I thought I'd come
for a ride‐along this morning.
Tell the truth, It's more fun
than the hospital, isn't it?
He likes it out there
on the front lines.
I mean, either that,
or we need closer supervision.
Somebody's got to keep
an eye on you, Morales.
Hey, doc, right here.
Oh, by the way,
can I crash here tonight?
My building's being fumigated.
You have to ask the captain.
It shouldn't be
a problem though.
You can sleep on one of the
Barcaloungers, I've done that.
Who paged me?
Huh, I got an 87‐year‐old man
with ascending cholangitis
for you.
Yeah, well, I stopped
taking admits at 6:30.
Why didn't you page
today's on‐call team?
Ah, the guy came in while
you were still on call
and Dr. Romano
specifically asked for you.
How sick is he?
He's septic, intubated, ah..
‐ Hypotensive and in renal‐‐
‐ No, no, no!
This can't be happening.
Look, I haven't had
so much as a nap
in the last 24 hours.
Rounds are about to start.
I have to take a shower,
I smell bad
and you're giving me a patient
who's sick as a dog.
Look, what does that say?
What does that say? 6:38.
I'm not on call!
Eh, he's in curtain three.
Hey, we've all been there.
Shut up.
‐ Tony Broadway?
‐ Yeah.
Is that
a great porn star name or what?
Hey, Carol, want to know
your porno star name?
What?
Take your middle name
and the name of the
street you live on.
Like mine would be
Anthony Broadway
Tony Broadway.
You got that mixed up, Jer.
That would be your
romance novelist name.
Excuse me.
Your porno star name
would be your pet name
with your mother's maiden name.
Like my porno star name
would be Nibbles McGee.
Nibbles, that's a great
porno name.
So, then mine
would be Fluffy Florez.
What if you don't have a pet?
Just use one that you
had when you were a kid.
Nibbles. That is a great name.
I don't think
that's right, Jeanie.
So, Carol, what would yours be?
Oh, mine wouldn't work.
Hey, Jerry, have we
gotten a package
from Lakeside medical supply?
‐ This early?
‐ Yeah.
It's supposed to arrive
first overnight.
Tell me as soon as it gets here.
Kerry, have you got a minute?
We need to prepare these
attending schedules
and I'm not familiar with the
computer program down here.
EPSKED? It's a snap.
Jerry can take you through it.
You can't give me a hand?
Well, I got a lot of patients.
Dr. Anspaugh, got a woman
on five‐three
who's complaining
about her bill.
Says she was charged for
procedures that weren't done.
Why are you telling me?
Because those calls go to
the chief of emergency services.
Or the interim chief.
Tell her you'll pull her chart
review the bill and call her
within two days.
"...and I don't know how
I'm supposed to learn
"in this kind
of hostile environment.
"Our relationship has turned
completely adversarial
"and it's not good
for the patients."
Dr. Carter, we need to talk.
Hey, Lucy, is everything
alright?
‐ Hmm?
‐ You were talking to yourself.
I mean not that that's a bad
thing, but‐‐
Actually...do you think
I should sit down
and talk to Dr. Carter?
Well, it depends on how
direct you want to be.
You don't want to be
confrontational from the get go.
You don't want him
to be defensive.
‐ Right.
‐ I would do it over a meal.
Oh, like a chat.
I like that, that makes sense.
'Oh, damn.'
'Um..'
‐ 'Hey, Lucy?'
‐ Hmm?
'Could you get me a tampon
from the thingy, please?'
Oh, I got one here.
'Damn it.'
‐ There you go.
‐ 'Thanks a lot.'
Peter, I'm sorry I'm late.
I was in the ER
with an admission
you need to see right away.
What's the problem?
87‐year‐old‐male
septic with
ascending cholangitis.
He's on mezlo and flagyl.
I got his pressure up
with high dose dopamine.
Well, he's too sick
for open surgery.
We'll do a percutaneous
decompression.
I booked the OR already.
So, busy night, last night, huh?
Oh, God, horrible.
12 admissions, plus this one.
I got an abdominal
aortic aneurysm
stab wound to the chest
fall from a second‐story
balcony.
They just kept coming.
I used to work 36‐hour shifts
as an intern back in England
but this is making me realize
how long ago that was.
Alright, so I'll take him down
and we'll round at 8, okay?
Lovely.
Gives me enough
time for pre‐rounds
and, uh...a shower.
Oh, you know, um, I bumped into
David Kotlowitz an hour ago.
He's a terrific ENT.
He's done a lot of work
with cochlear implants.
Did you tell him about Reese?
No, no. I just told him
I had a friend
in need of straight talk
on the subject.
Hey, Elizabeth, don't feel
the need to solicit
medical advice
on my behalf, alright?
I've worked with Kotlowitz
before.
That's the only reason
I brought it up.
If you'd rather I hadn't‐‐
Yeah, I'd rather you hadn't.
Fine. Forget about it.
What is that, a sternal saw?
Oh, yes, it is.
What is it doing down here?
My midline thoracotomy proposal
sailed through
the human subjects committee.
‐ Nobody told me.
‐ Yeah.
Well, I'm certified to use it.
So, we're up and running.
I thought we're gonna sit,
and talk this thing through
before it got underway.
Surgeons use it on odd days
ER docs get it on evens.
Your turn's tomorrow!
‐ Hey
‐ Hey, bad news.
I was...hmm?
We're still not pregnant.
Umm, I guess we're going to have
to redouble our efforts.
Yeah, but they say if you do it
more than three times a week
we get diminishing returns.
You know, like re‐using
the same tea bag.
That's a romantic idea.
It wasn't very romantic, was it?
‐ Come here.
‐ Uh, Doug.
‐ Mm‐hm.
‐ Excuse me.
I've got a lethargic
four month old
hasn't been eating,
you better come see him.
Okay.
‐ You okay?
‐ Yeah, yeah.
Okay.
The baby's name is "Sun."
Is he Korean?
Actually, it's Sun.
His mom's a little different.
Mm‐hm.
Alright, Mrs. Everly,
I'm Dr. Ross.
Can I take a look at Sun, here?
Please, I don't know
what went wrong.
He doesn't want to nurse.
Okay, we will figure it out.
Hey, you his big sister?
‐ What's your name?
‐ Sky.
‐ Hello, doctor.
‐ Well, hello, Sky.
Sun and Sky, huh?
She said he was fine until
a couple of days ago.
And then I noticed
she wasn't nursing so well.
Mm‐hm. Given him any solid foods
or formula?
Oh, no, only my milk.
My breasts are, like engorged
with him not eating.
When was the last time
he pooped?
Oh, man.
‐ When?
‐ Yesterday morning.
Mm‐hm, you sure?
Yes, I haven't changed
him since then.
'Okay, we're gonna hydrate him.'
'We'll give him 50ccs'
of D5 quarter normal saline.
'We're gonna have to do
some blood tests'
and I need your consent
to do a spinal tap.
You'd to stick
a needle into his spine?
‐ Won't that hurt?
‐ Not now.
We're gonna sedate him,
he is not gonna feel pain.
Ma, it's going to be okay.
Do you really think so, honey?
We'll be right back, okay?
Let's get a CBC, chem 20
and blood cultures.
Will you be able to
assist with the LP?
Yeah, sure but how are you
going to sedate him?
Propofol, I'm going to go
through pedes ICU and get it.
General anesthesia?
We've done that
before in the ER?
Um, there's a first
time for everything.
I'll take
the proper precautions.
'How could you?'
'You're not helping
with all of the yelling.'
'Oh, I don't care.'
'There's an ambulance
out front.'
‐ 'Don't open that door.'
‐ 'Get away from me!'
‐ 'Don't touch me.'
‐ Open up!
'Get away from me! Don't touch
me! Don't touch me! Don't‐‐'
‐ Yes, hello.
‐ We got a 911 call..
‐ Male with bleeding‐‐
‐ Yes, I called‐‐
This is a mistake,
she shouldn't have called.
Get in here, for God's sake!
‐ Where's the injured man?
‐ Here, he's in here.
This is not a medical emergency.
‐ Everything's fine.
‐ Where's he? Where'd he go?
I don't need to go
to the hospital.
‐ What is your name, sir?
‐ Richard Weingarten.
He let this lunatic drill
a hole in his head.
I'm an emergency physician,
why don't you let me
take a look at that?
I'm alright.
Okay, just sit down here,
sit down.
What are you ashamed of? Oh!
‐ What happened here?
‐ Well, it's called trepanation.
It's a centuries‐old practice.
'It's a legitimate means'
'of increasing
brain‐blood volume.'
I had mine done
in Amsterdam, 1968.
Oh my God.
'It was like God lifted'
'a weight from my shoulders.'
This is a surgical drill.
We're going to the hospital.
You can't take me
against my will.
I've studied this for years.
I didn't embark on it lightly.
Let us at least
put a bandage on
and get a blood pressure.
Okay, sir, just sign this.
It says you refused treatment.
I want you go to the rig
and get some saline.
Come on, Rich, we did it.
‐ You did it‐‐
‐ The internet!
That's what started
this whole thing!
For God's sake, Laura.
Get her outside!
Are you out of your mind?
What are you doing?
‐ Outside, Now!
‐ Don't touch me!
Why don't you just calm down?
'I want to go back inside,
I want to go back inside.'
I can see that
you're an intelligent person.
'I don't wanna take you
anywhere against your will.'
I had to do something.
Alright, okay.
It doesn't look like
you penetrated the dura.
All I want to do is put
a sterile dressing on
to clean the wound, okay?
I'm going to leave you
some saline
and a supply of gauze
so that you
or your friend
can keep it clean.
I forgot to bring any gauze.
Hmm.
Yeah, I've held enough
screaming babies to know.
They have to be sedated.
Doug...what are you doing?
You can't administer propofol
to an infant.
Well, you've been doing it
upstairs for ten years.
You're not an anesthesiologist.
I didn't think you'd have
a problem with it, Alex.
Well...well, I do.
I have him on a cardiac monitor,
a pulse ox, dynamap
and I have a crash cart
standing by.
You can not just make up
policy as you go along.
I'm here trying to prevent pain.
Do what's best
for this little boy.
If you want to discuss policy
then leave,
and we'll do it later.
We will.
Dr. Carter, you want to grab
some lunch later?
Let's see how the day goes.
Can you tell me
about this patient
with dysuria in curtain three?
30 year old male with pain
on urination for three days.
The UA is negative
for white cells‐‐
Chlamydia.
‐ Did you do a sexual history?
‐ Yeah.
He's only had two partners
in the last year
and he used condoms.
So he claims.
Send off a DNA probe
and treat empirically.
What's the treatment
for chlamydia?
Doxycycline BID or
a one time dose of zithromax.
Very good.
But I really think you should
look at his chart.
‐ Hi, I'm Dr. Carter.
‐ Hey.
I need to ask you,
do you always use condoms?
Uh, pretty much, yeah.
There's times recently
where you haven't?
Well, once or twice,
maybe, yeah.
That's all it takes.
We're going to give you
some antibiotics.
'cause I believe that you have
a very common infection
called chlamydia.
What, VD?
A sexually transmitted disease,
yes.
Wh‐whoa, she doesn't think so.
He also had conjunctivitis
and polyarticular arthralgias
of the knee and ankle.
Mr. Bussey, would you
excuse us for a moment?
He was in Mexico three weeks ago
and had diarrhea
and the timing and symptoms are
classic for Reiter's syndrome.
You could've included that
in your presentation.
I tried to, but you cut me off.
All you had to say was,
"I think it's Reiter's."
You wouldn't let me get a word
in, you're always doing‐‐
I'm always doing what, Lucy?
Like right now,
you're getting defensive.
You don't even hear me.
So, what's the treatment
for Reiter's syndrome?
Indomethacin.
But, we can still send
off a chlamydia probe.
No, you're right, it's Reiter's.
Good pick up, Lucy.
Propofol is ideal
ideal for use in the ER.
This is about how
policy is made.
And it wears off
within four...
Don't you think a doctor
should be trained..
We've got a gunshot wound
to the chest coming in.
The saw is sterilized
in trauma one.
We need to be ready to go
in case this guy qualifies.
You'll be documenting
ten critical times.
The clock starts when?
Soon as the patient
enters the trauma room.
Don't they need to have a
cardiac arrest
to be in the study?
This guy sounded okay.
These patients
can deteriorate en route.
46‐year‐old man shot in the
right chest with a BB gun.
‐ Hemodynamically stable.
‐ The BB gun?
The punk who shot me
needs to be put under the jail
ten years old, or
no ten years old.
Let me up off of this.
I can walk.
Doctor, let him go.
Doesn't look like
he needs a thoracotomy.
Nope, he just needs a tetanus
shot and a Band‐Aid.
You can follow me, sir.
You want to turn right around
or can we hang for a little bit?
Nah, take ten minutes.
Hey, Carol, what's going on?
Um, just doing
a quick blood draw.
Uh, so, how's the clinic
going today?
Oh, I just love prenatal days.
Takes me back to my OB Roots.
Why don't you let
one of the nurses do that?
'Cause I was trying
to be discreet.
Then let me do it. It's kind of
hard to stick yourself.
Thanks.
What kind of labs you need?
Just a, uh, a CBC.
Check if I'm anemic.
Oh. I only ask
because if you'd like
I can run the results
through the clinic.
Be more private.
That's a great idea.
Um..
...listen, what I'd really like
is to check my hormone levels.
Oh, okay.
Infertility work‐up?
I don't want to discuss
it in detail. No offense.
No, I wasn't trying
to get in your business.
It would be really great
if you could run it
through the clinic.
‐ Okay.
‐ Thanks.
Mark, I'm glad I caught you.
I've had to move things around
on my surgical schedule.
The interview with Dr. Lee
has been pushed to 1:30.
‐ Is that going to be a problem?
‐ No, it's fine.
‐ Have you looked at her CV?
‐ Yeah, it's pretty impressive.
If she's half
as impressive in the room
she just might be our
next chief.
And not a moment too soon.
Dr. Greene, I‐I didn't think
you were going to be around
till this afternoon.
I was on a, you know,
paramedic ride‐along.
We brought in a patient,
so, uh..
So, you, uh, finish your
student evaluation yet?
I thought I had till
the end of my shift.
Uh, no big deal.
This afternoon's fine.
I mean, I wrote one.
I wrote an evaluation for Lucy
but I tore it up
'cause I want to be fair.
When you're putting
something on paper
that's gonna impact
the rest of her life, you know.
Just evaluate her work.
Jerry, what are
you talking about?
I'm talking about
your porn star name.
You take your pet's name
and you put it together
with your mother's maiden name.
Try it.
Like, mine is Rex Voytek.
Oh, I know that game.
But it's your drag name,
not your porn name.
Drag name?
Yeah, it's the name of your pet
and the street you were born on.
Oh, I don't think so, dude.
Ru Paul had it on her show.
Yo, man, leave some crumbs
for the rest of us.
Who are you,
the cookie police?
You're welcome to have some,
but I brought those in
for the docs and the nurses.
So, then you're
the cookie fairy?
'Oh, now, wait a minute.'
It's bad enough you come
in here raidin' the icebox
all the time, Now you want
to call names.
Connie, you begrudge us
a few bottles of juice?
It's not like you guys
ever bring anything in.
Hey, buddy, you should thank me
for every cookie I keep
from going down
your fat snack hole.
You just keep talking, Morales.
Hey, what's going on?
That one's got a problem.
You antagonizing my colleagues?
He called Yosh a fairy.
I called him the cookie fairy.
‐ 'It was a dumb joke.'
‐ A real dumb joke.
‐ Ready to head back?
‐ 'Yeah, let's go.'
I got no problem
him being a bone‐smoker.
I was just joking with him
like I would with anybody.
Don't worry about it.
Write the discharge orders
on Gardner and Wootton
as soon as possible.
Bed control likes to have them
by 12:00 noon.
Yes, doctor,
I am aware of that.
Hey, don't go there,
I told you I was going
to have a hard time seeing you
as my intern, right?
Huh, well, it's complicated
for a lot of reasons, isn't it?
Dr. Corday, Mr. Frybush's
creatine is much higher.
Thank you, Kass.
Should we call a renal consult?
Yeah, this guy needs dialysis.
So, did you ever
get that shower?
Uh, no.
Can you tell?
Well, go ahead. I'll cover SICU.
Peter, I don't want
special treatment.
You turning down a shower?
Look, I've got
a lot of work to do.
Okay, have it your way.
I've got to go find Weaver.
She's just itching to cut
somebody with that saw.
Going out to the roach coach
on my break.
‐ You want something?
‐ Yes, yes.
A triple espresso.
Thank you, Kit.
Elizabeth, how would
you like to scrub in
on a bilateral adrenalectomy?
Oh. I appreciate the offer,
but I'm post‐call.
I've got to finish my work,
and quite frankly
I have to catch up
on an hour's sleep.
A case like this comes along
once in a blue moon.
I'm up to my neck in ER
Administrative garbage
but I'm not passing this up.
Well, it's been a while
since my last adrenalectomy.
It'll be fun. I'll do the right,
you do the left.
I can get Dr. Kennedy to cover
your service.
Jeanie, the Everly baby's
spinal tap
came back negative
for meningitis.
What do you think's going on?
Could be a lot of things.
We got to talk to the mom again.
Yeah. Maybe I could take
Sky out of the room.
She doesn't really need
to hear all of this.
Good idea.
Her mom leans on her a lot,
don't you think?
‐ Pretty smart kid, though.
‐ Yeah.
Okay. Hey.
What did you find out?
Well, the spinal tap
was negative
so I have to ask you
some more questions.
Maybe Jeanie and Sky
could take a little walk.
I don't want to be worried
about her wandering all over.
I'd rather stay here with mom.
Okay. Can she help me
put some toys away
while you and Dr. Ross talk?
'Good idea.'
‐ You mind helping me?
‐ I don't mind.
I'll be right back, mom.
See what toys we can find, huh?
Okay, we need to see
if we can figure out
what the cause
of Sun's deterioration is.
Now, has he had a polio vaccine?
Oh, God, polio!
But he was vaccinated.
Is that 100% effective?
Do you have a doll at home, sky?
‐ No.
‐ No, really?
I had one. Those are for babies.
I'm a big girl.
'I talked to
a pediatric neurologist.'
‐ And how old are you?
‐ Six.
Six.
After the adrenal vein
we'll work our way
around the medial
and inferior edges of the gland.
And, cut, please.
And another tie.
Elizabeth, cut.
Elizabeth?
Sorry. Yes.
You really do need a rest.
Why don't you step out?
No. I'm fine. I'm fine.
Go take a nap.
I'm sorry I dragged you along.
‐ Dr. Goodman?
‐ Mm‐hm.
Hey, Dr. Weaver,
can I run something by you?
Yeah, make it quick.
20‐year‐old man with aphasia
and right arm weakness.
CT scan was normal.
Spinal fluid is clear.
I'm thinking vasculitis or MS?
Interesting, send
off a sed rate
and a complement level
on the CSF.
Also, look at the differential.
There may be some zebras
you haven't considered.
Okay. Hey, Yosh,
is that Lucy's palmtop?
I love this little thing.
She let me borrow it.
Can I use it? When you're done.
I'm done.
Here you go.
‐ You know how to work it?
‐ Yeah, Lucy showed me once.
'I'd hoped to avoid this,
but things haven't improved.'
'And I don't know how
I'm supposed to learn'
'in this kind of
hostile environment.'
'Our relationship has turned
completely adversarial.'
Ouch.
'And it's not good
for the patients.'
'We need to talk.'
By the time we leave
the house, this crazy bastard
lets Dr. Greene
look inside the hole
in his head with a penlight.
Unbelievable.
I thought, I'd seen it all.
So, the doc writes him out
a scrip for antibiotics.
The guy thanks us for coming.
Yeah. I've got a way
with ranting lunatics.
I ain't kidding, man, you do.
Hey, what's up, guys? What's up?
‐ We're all here.
‐ You're not on today.
Truth is, they're here because
we got you a little something.
You like it?
That's great.
You're one of the gang now.
‐ Yeah...almost.
‐ Almost?
Well, there's something
every paramedic goes through
and we think it's only
appropriate that you do too.
How many patients
have you brought in
strapped to a backboard with
a c‐spine collar...thousands?
Now, what do you
have in mind, guys?
Well, come over to the pool
table. We'll show you.
See, as a part of our training
we all get on the board
ourselves. You know,
to see how it feels.
So, you want me to
lie down on the board.
Hey, don't worry about it.
We all did it.
Yeah, it comes with the coat.
This is good now.
Oh, and you gotta
drop your pants.
‐ No, no, no.
‐ No, he doesn't!
Forget about that part, guys,
right. Just forget about it.
You know, I do have to, uh,
get back to the hospital.
Then don't fight.
All you got to do is lie down.
Relax, guys. Back off,
back off, man.
Let him do it on his own.
You want me to lie
down on the table?
‐ Yes.
‐ Thank you.
‐ Yeah.
‐ There you go.
‐ You okay?
‐ Perfect. Fine.
Get him!
‐ Hey, don't fight.
‐ Cut it out, guys.
‐ Get the shower!
‐ Come on, the shower's on!
'Stop it!'
‐ Stop it!
‐ Come on, take it easy, doc.
Hey, guys, guys, guys, come on.
Let him up.
‐ 'No.'
‐ Let him up.
We weren't going to hurt you.
'Much.'
It's all over for now.
Hey, Jerry, know what
your name would be
if you was a porn star?
Oh, that game is tired, man.
I got the best ever,
"Satan Monroe."
Your mother's
maiden name is Satan?
‐ Carol, I need you.
‐ What's wrong?
A 23‐year‐old woman complains
of severe right
lower quadrant pain.
Pregnancy test is positive.
‐ A possible ectopic.
‐ What's her name?
Maria jones. Five pregnancies.
Two live births, two abortions.
'Hi, Maria.'
We're gonna take
care of you, okay?
‐ It hurts, it hurts.
‐ Alright.
Oh, oh!
Let's get a CBC,
beta HCG, chem 20.
Oh!
Type and cross, two units
and start a line of saline.
Oh, oh.
Did you do a pelvic?
Couldn't do a good one.
She's in too much pain.
She said, I'm pregnant.
Is my baby okay?
Okay.
Oh, oh!
Let's do an ultrasound
while we're at it.
Oh!
It just hurts so bad.
Okay, you're gonna be fine.
You're gonna be fine.
Sorry I'm late.
We were just about
to start without you.
'Dr. Lee, Mark Greene.'
I'm sorry, if I held things up.
I'll try not to
take it personally.
'You've been very flexible'
with your time today
and we appreciate it.
I'm happy to be here.
Let's get right to it.
Three years as associate chief.
'Excellence in
clinical teaching award'
'two years in a row.'
How do you think you can
improve our department?
Well, right away you could
benefit from an eight‐bed
observation unit
for 23‐hours stays.
Paid for how? We're
a cash‐poor county hospital.
That's exactly why you need it.
'Tell us more.'
Well, I set up a unit
like that in Atlanta
and it saved the hospital
$2 million a year
'in unnecessary admissions.'
'What kind of patients
are we talking about?'
‐ Lucy, take this.
‐ What is it?
Your evaluation.
‐ It's blank.
‐ You fill it out
Since you think
I'm so adversarial.
Oh, and keep better
track of this
before someone
walks away with it.
Did you listen to
my private notes?
You're so sure
I was going to give
you a bad evaluation
you're already planning
me a countermove.
What's with that
"Hostile workplace"?
I didn't even know
it was time for my evaluation.
Oh, please.
Why'd you want to have
lunch with me today?
To get things out in the open.
Well, they're out in the open.
Now, why don't you fill that out
and let's see how fair‐minded
and objective you can be.
How long will my brother
and mom be upstairs?
Not much longer.
So what was the name
of the doll you used to have?
Baby.
Was Baby a boy or a girl?
She wasn't a boy or a girl
because she didn't have
a penis or a vagina.
What are you doing?
Letting him lick the spoon.
Do you ever let your
little brother lick the spoon?
Sometimes, with
things that he likes.
Like what, yogurt?
'Sun doesn't like yogurt.'
What does he like?
Lots of things.
Does he like honey?
Your little brother
licks honey off
of your spoon sometimes?
He likes it.
Okay.
Hey, Sky, let's go find your mom
and Dr. Ross, okay?
Okay.
'I really like
the observation unit idea.'
Good.
‐ A very good presentation.
‐ Thank you.
I'd be happy to give you an
official walking tour of the ER.
No, thanks, I don't
need to be hand‐held.
But I do wanna walk around
and get the lay of the place.
Feel free. I'll catch up
with you before you leave.
‐ It's a pleasure.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Mark, do you like her?
‐ She's good.
‐ You didn't say much.
I didn't think you
were very impressed.
I'd like to continue
this meeting
in a less formal setting.
I'm gonna see if Dr. Lee
is available for dinner.
‐ Would you be able to‐‐
‐ I can't tonight.
I'm‐I'm sorry.
Excuse me, Dr. Anspaugh.
‐ Are you feeling better?
‐ A little bit.
Going to the bathroom
helped, huh?
Maybe it was just gas pains.
Well, you haven't had any
bleeding, which is good.
Hm‐mm, you're further along
than we thought.
Looks like 15 weeks.
I wasn't even totally sure
I was pregnant.
Look.
Can‐can you tell?
Is it a boy or a girl?
I can't say for sure.
It looks like a girl.
After having two boys,
that'd be pretty nice, huh?
Mm‐hmm.
Well, I don't see a penis
'but you can't always
tell on an ultrasound.'
You'll have to come back
to the clinic for a follow‐up.
Make sure she stays healthy.
Mm‐hmm. I'll do that.
Come on, Corday.
Pull yourself together.
It's just a few
more hours to go.
Okay.
Hey, Elizabeth.
Listen, can you do me a favor?
Can you watch the service?
I've got to have a sit‐down
with Dr. Kotlowitz.
‐ Really?
‐ Yeah. I ran into him.
I, uh...actually,
I, uh, went looking for him.
Peter, that's terrific.
Yes, go, go.
I can cover service.
'Thanks.'
'Dr. Corday, I need
orders on a new admission.'
I'm not in the mood
for any jokes.
No. Mr. Ramos is back.
Ramos? Fem‐pop bypass?
Well, I discharged
him yesterday.
Oh, he's back with
a wound infection
and a pretty bad asthma attack.
You know the bounce‐back rules.
Yep, I know. He's mine.
He's on continuous albuterol.
Hello, Mr. Ramos.
Let's take a look
at your legs, shall we?
I was hoping you
would be here today.
Well, where else
would I possibly go?
I asked the mother if she'd
given the baby any food.
I guess I was talking
to the wrong person.
The baby's the lucky one,
we can treat botulism.
‐ But what do we do to help Sky?
‐ She's gonna be fine.
Her mom's draining all
the childhood out of her.
Now, look, as much neglect
and abuse as I see
trust me, Sky is okay.
Yeah, a little girl needs
to be a little girl, though.
Yeah, that's true.
Hey, guys.
Okay, now, um..
'You can't give
honey to your brother'
'or to any baby because it
can hurt them. Is that okay?'
'Honey can have
botulism spores.'
'Their intestines are immature'
'and they can't
kill off the spores.'
'He's maxed out with
a pressure of 65.'
Systemic resistance is 3,500.
Let's start levophed.
Dr. Corday,
I need you over here.
Mr. Ramos is pretty tight.
Okay.
‐ Oh!
‐ You okay?
Yep, yep. I'm fine.
How much albuterol?
20 an hour.
He's had solumedrol?
‐ 125 in the ER.
‐ Okay.
‐ I'll push some magnesium.
‐ Magnesium?
Yep, it relaxes
the smooth muscles
of the bronchioles,
second line agent.
Dr. Corday, can you
come look at Mr. Frybush?
Give me five minutes, okay?
Hey, Carter, can you
explain this evaluation to me.
If things were going this bad,
you should have come to me.
Do you have something
personal against this girl?
‐ Wait a sec‐‐
‐ I want to see you and Lucy.
And we're gonna figure this out.
Find her and then find me.
‐ Can I hang onto that?
‐ No.
Sounds like you're
in a good mood.
Oh, hey, can you do me a favor?
I need a place to crash tonight.
My building's being fumigated.
‐ Do you think Carol would mind?
‐ Are you kiddin'? Come on over.
‐ Save me a few bucks.
‐ Sure thing.
‐ Glad to have you.
‐ Thanks.
He's set up for another
four hours of continuous.
Okay.
Magnesium's on board.
How are you feeling, Mr. Ramos?
‐ Dizzy.
‐ Whoa, whoa.
‐ What's happening?
‐ Maybe he's hypoxic.
How much mag did you give him?
Two grams slow IV Push, 40cc's.
40cc's of 50% mag sulfate?
Not 50%, five percent.
No. Dr. Corday,
you gave him 50%.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, you're right.
I've given him a lethal dose.
He's not breathing.
Number eight ETT Tube!
He's bradying down,
heart rate's 30.
Okay, two grams
of calcium gluconate.
Push an amp of atropine.
Bag him. Prep for an IJ.
I'll float a pacemaker.
Lost the pulse. We're in PEA.
I'll start chest compressions.
Seven and half gloves
and an eight French
cordis introducer.
The cochlear implant is
nothing short of a miracle
and the technology
keeps improving.
Yeah. Now, I'm impressed
by what I've read.
Oh, well, no,
don't read‐don't read.
Talk to people who have it.
Talk to parents of the children.
As a matter of fact,
I can get you in touch
with a number of
people who've faced
exactly what you're facing now.
Great. I mean, I've already
heard an earful
from the opponents, so..
Oh, the fanatics, hm‐mm.
Yeah, well, they've
got their agendas.
Alright, the level of passion
with which these people
will attack you, it's, uh,
it's bizarre...it's bizarre.
Somebody actually used
the word "genocidal."
Said I was trying to
eradicate deaf culture.
Wow.
Deafness is not some
alternative lifestyle
and the people who
claim it is, I mean
they're...they're
beyond reasoning with.
Yeah, look, the thing I'm tryin'
to figure out is
why make an argument against
hearing and speaking, you know?
Honestly, you wanna
know what I think?
I think it comes
down to laziness.
I think a deaf person can
function in the hearing world
but some of these
people, they just
don't want to do
all the exercises
and do all the drills
that it takes.
Yeah, look, I mean,
uh...it's years of hard work.
Yeah, but they have the
energy to attack me
and other doctors.
So I say, the hell with them.
You do not...do not
stand in my way
when I'm trying to help
a person to function.
Hmm. Wow.
Why don't you tell me
how you really feel?
Anyway, anyway, anyway
you bring in your‐your son
and we'll see if
he's a candidate.
So, uh..
You work closely
with Dr. Corday?
‐ Actually, she's my intern.
‐ A‐ah, ha.
She told me about the fallout
she had with Rocket Romano.
Oh, yeah.
Do‐do you know
if she's seeing anybody?
I'm just wondering.
Actually, uh, I'm pretty sure
she's involved with somebody.
Oh, well, I'm not surprised.
‐ Yeah.
‐ Oh, well.
‐ Thanks.
‐ Alright, you bet, anytime.
Give me a call.
Uh, check, please.
Systolic, 60 palp.
Come on, come on, come on.
We've got capture.
Turning the rate, down to 80.
Did you page Dr. Benton?
‐ Done.
‐ Pulse is stronger.
‐ Good.
‐ Pupils are fixed and dilated.
Oh, that could be the atropine.
That, or he stroked out.
What happened?
I inadvertently gave him
enough magnesium
to cause a cardiac
arrest...20 grams.
Oh, no.
I looked at the label.
I thought it said..
...five percent, but it was 50%.
But I looked at the label.
Hey, I got your blood work back.
Oh, thanks, Lynette.
Progesterone level's normal.
That's good news, right?
Means you ovulated.
Yeah, except I've been trying
to get pregnant and I haven't.
Well, how long have
you been at it?
Couple of months.
Oh, Carol, come on.
Give yourself at
least six months
before you start
worrying about it.
Yeah, you're right. I'm crazy.
Maybe you guys need to
increase your sexual activity.
How often do you,
you know, do the "do"?
‐ What?
‐ Oh, sorry.
Am I being indiscreet?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Carol, what's the deal?
I went in to see
your rule‐out ectopic
and she's dressed
and ready to leave.
‐ Maria Jones?
‐ Yeah.
She pulled her IV?
Hey, Maria, where are you going?
I'm feeling better, nurse.
I'm going home.
Wait a minute, you came
in here in so much pain
I couldn't even examine you.
But I'm better now.
Wait, wait, uh, we
need to make sure
that everything is okay
with you and the baby.
Just let the doctor look you
over and what's the hurry?
Look, I just wanted to know
if it was a boy or a girl.
And nothing wrong, so
why worry about it?
Wait, wait, wait!
You‐you were faking
those abdominal pains?
Girl, are you crazy?
But you said you weren't even
sure you were pregnant.
I mean, why would you lie
and‐and cause all that drama
just to find out
if it's a boy or..
Oh, no. Are you gonna
abort this baby?
‐ What? Get of me!
‐ Carol!
She's had two boys
and two abortions.
Are you gonna get rid of this
child because you think it's a‐‐
It's my baby and I'll do
what I wanna do with it‐‐
I told you, that
ultrasound is inconclusive.
‐ It could be a boy.
‐ Lady, take your hands off me.
Unless you really
wanna fight me.
Step away, Carol. Let her go.
Girls ain't nothin'
but trouble anyhow.
What's the matter with you?
'How could you inject a patient'
'with 20 grams of magnesium?'
I make no excuses.
It was a grievous error.
Where were you during
this misadventure, Dr. Benton?
I was out of the hospital
on a personal matter.
I came as soon as I was paged.
It wouldn't have mattered even
if he had been in the hospital.
You left your
intern unsupervised
and now this patient may have
suffered hypoxic brain injury.
I stopped by the unit.
Mr. Ramos' eyes are open
and he's responding to commands.
You are not to leave
the hospital while on duty
'and you are not to leave
your intern unsupervised.'
I know it's hard for us all
to view Elizabeth as an intern
but as a consequence
we've opened up
this hospital
to enormous liability.
I'll speak to risk management
and the hospital attorneys.
They'll determine
what information
to release to the families.
Don't either of you
discuss this with anyone.
Could we get together tonight
and not talk about this?
I have to pick up my son
from, uh, my sister's house.
Alright.
You just need to get
a good night's sleep.
I didn't fill out this
evaluation, Dr. Greene.
‐ 'Who did?
‐ She did.'
‐ Why did she?
‐ Because he told me to.
I didn't tell you
to give it to him.
‐ I told you to give it to me.
‐ No, you didn't.
Okay, wait.
Don't talk to each other.
Talk to me.
Mark..
...I just wanted to know how
she thought she was doing
before I made
my final assessment.
So, I tried to put myself in
his shoes and be very critical.
He handed me this form
and said, "Fill it out."
and I assumed that
meant turn it in.
How could she assume that?
That makes no sense.
See, that's part of his problem,
he gives incomplete directions.
Oh, "He gives," I give
incomplete directions.
‐ 'Name a time.'
‐ 'Just one?'
Tell her to name a time when I
medically gave her incomplete‐‐
‐ Defensive.
‐ Okay.
Talk to each other.
Don't talk to me.
Whatever this is,
I can't fix it.
Work it out...both of you.
Kerry, I need to talk to you
about the variant X‐Ray
interpretation report. Please
don't blow me off this time.
I'm sorry, Don.
There's a trauma coming in.
Possible candidate
for the thoracotomy study.
I didn't realize that
was up and running.
Stab wound to the left chest.
Had a pulse in
the field initially.
Gave him epi,
1500cc's of saline
and shocked him
twice for V‐tach.
Perfect candidate.
Lily, got the stopwatch?
Right here.
Do you mind if I tag along?
Now. Start the timer.
Here we go.
On my count...
one, two, three.
Hang two units of O‐neg
on the rapid infuser.
Get type specific
as soon as you can.
Ten blade. Let's go.
Good breath sounds bilaterally.
Seven‐and‐a‐half gloves.
Okay.
Skin incision is complete.
Mark that time. Saw, please.
Sternal retractor.
Good job.
I need a purple top.
Pulse ox 85.
Mark the time.
Suction, please.
Pickups and metz.
Looks like blood
in the pericardium.
First hemoglobin is 9.2.
Okay. Pericardium is open.
Mark the time.
And I've identified a stab
wound to the left ventricle.
‐ What are we at, Lily?
‐ 42 seconds.
Take over internal compressions.
Tamponade the wound. Two‐o silk.
Looks like one horizontal
mattress should do it.
‐ Two units are in.
‐ Hang another two.
How's the heart feel, Don?
Starting to fill.
Get the paddles ready.
Okay.
Cardiac injury is repaired.
‐ Mark the time.
‐ V‐fib.
Charging to 20, and clear.
‐ Sinus rhythm.
‐ Cardiac activity is restored.
'Record the time.'
‐ I've got a pulse.
‐ Excellent job, Kerry.
‐ Dr. Greene.
‐ Dr. Lee.
Finding your way around alright?
Yes. Thanks.
I wanted to ask you..
...I didn't feel
I was connecting with you
during my interview.
Is that a correct assessment?
How do you mean?
Well, I'd look over
at you and wonder
"Am I making my best case here?"
Well, It was a good interview‐‐
Because I like this department
and I want this job
and I don't mind saying
I'm one of the baddest
ER bitches out there.
If I didn't make my best
case during the interview
I'd like to try again right now.
Can I grab a soda
and sit down with you?
Yeah, sure.
Call me when he's in recovery.
'Thank you.'
Don, I...I have
something to confess.
Oh?
Oh, for a while,
I‐I felt resentment
when it became clear
I wasn't your choice
to run the emergency
department full time.
Well, it's not that you
weren't qualified, Kerry‐‐
Oh, hold on.
Now, I am so grateful
to be putting all of
myself into medicine
and I want you to
know there are no
lingering hard
feelings on my part.
Well, I must say, I could
sense the bad feelings
and I did wish there was
something I could do about it
because...I value
your friendship.
Well, how's the
job search going?
We interviewed a wonderful woman
Amanda Lee, out of Atlanta.
Hm‐mm, I don't know her.
Why don't you join
us for dinner?
I'd love to hear
what you think of her.
Don, I'm trying
but I'm not all
the way there yet.
Thanks.
Isn't it a little weird living
with one of your bosses?
No. We get along okay,
plus it's a bargain.
All I have to do
is a little yard work here.
Clean out the gutters.
Do the stuff that
she can't handle.
U‐huh?
Roxanne, if you make
me forget this day
I will owe you
the biggest favor.
Lousy day, huh?
My med student
is driving me crazy.
Lucy.
There's so much that
I want to teach her.
‐ And it's just not happening.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
‐ I think I'm not a bad teacher.
‐ No.
And I don't even think
she's a bad student.
No. You know what?
I can say one good
thing about Lucy.
She's not here.
Oh, you make a good point.
I didn't mean to
put you to work.
Oh, no, Mark. Don't be silly.
This is gonna be nice.
‐ Oh, man.
‐ You want some more?
No, no. It was good, though.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Who's making all that noise?
What's up, man, huh?
Come on. Let's get
ready to go, huh?
Come on.
Say goodbye to Aunt Jackie.
Jackie, who gave him this phone?
Oh, it's a toy, Peter.
It's a cute shape
and he likes it.
Yeah, well, he probably
saw you on it all day.
Hey, hey.
I'm sorry.
You know, we went
to a surgeon today.
I'm just trying to do what's
best for Reese and I feel like
I'm in the middle of
a battlefield, you know.
The more information I get,
the less I know what to do.
I don't really have anybody
to talk it over with, you know.
Well, what about Carla?
Yeah, she..
She's looking for me to
take the lead on this thing.
I can't be going back and forth
with it over with her, you know.
'Your girlfriend's a doctor.'
Why can't you talk
with Elizabeth about it?
Hey, hey.
Peter?
'Hey, come on.'
Come on. Hey, man.