Good workout?
Bring on the day.
Me too.
Come on,
what are you eating?
Peanut butter-banana-bacon
sandwich.
Delicious.
Elvis was
on to something.
I get it,
you crave calories.
But I told you,
healthy ones are
best for the baby.
I know. That's why
I doubled up on the bananas.
Anyway, just came in
to say, I give up.
You've been nagging me
to meet Bernie.
He's been all over me
to meet you,
so let's just
get it over with.
I can meet tonight
after work.
Molly's?
Or before work?
Maybe in, like, an hour?
Hospital cafe?
Bernie's got
a tight schedule.
You know what? I want to meet
Bernie more than I want
to argue with you.
So fine. I'll be there.
Thank you.
He's a really good guy, Ethan.
I love him.
You will, too.
Linda Harper, 28-year-old
female, GCS 12,
diaphoretic,
and very confused.
BP 100 over 76.
Heart rate 120.
Normal sinus rhythm EKG.
Dad said Mom's been fighting
a cold the last few weeks.
Today she was holding
the baby and passed out.
Landed on him.
Okay.
It's okay, little man. Dad's
right here. Everything's gonna
be all right.
Evan Harper,
18-month-old male,
gross deformity of the right
arm, splinted in the field,
no other apparent injuries,
.10 morphine en route.
Okay, his arm needs to
be reduced and casted.
Let's do it
in special procedures.
Wait, you're taking
him away?
We need to set his fracture.
He's only a toddler.
It's safer to do it upstairs.
But my wife's staying here.
Go be with your son.
We'll take really good
care of your wife.
James, where are you?
Linda, I'm right here.
I'm right here.
I've gotta go be with Evan.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
Will you call her
brother Manny?
I don't want her to be alone.
Yeah.
I'll get the number,
get him down here.
Thank you.
All right, let's get
a CBC, CMP, COAGS,
cardiac labs, and let's start
a 12 Lead EKG.
Whoa. Dr. Manning.
Oh, my God.
Your patient's brother
is here,
Manny Calderon.
Thank you, Leah.
Mr. Calderon?
Hi, I'm Dr. Manning. I've been
treating your sister, Linda.
Is she okay?
The nurse said she fell.
She passed out. We're trying
to figure out why.
What about the baby, Evan?
He has a broken arm,
but he's going to be okay.
James is with him,
and until he comes back,
Linda said I can share
with you what I've learned
so far.
Come on, I'll take you
back to her.
So, Linda's upper body
is covered in bruises.
There's also petechiae,
the small capillaries
of her skin are inflamed
and bleeding.
I think it's all a result
of something happening
inside her body.
She has more
than a cold then.
Until I know more,
I don't want to speculate.
Here, she's in here.
Manny.
Okay?
Great. Emily asked you to be
the buffer for the Bernie
introduction, didn't she?
She's nervous.
She wants you to like him.
Or at least not scare him.
Right, because
I'm the problem in this.
Just try to have
an open mind.
Hey, Emily.
Ethan, this is my boyfriend
Bernard Kim.
Call me Bernie.
Nice to meet you.
Honey, this is April.
Oh, April, it's lovely
to meet you.
Oh, okay, we're hugging.
Emily and I are just...
We're just so touched
by how supportive
you've been
and... Thank you.
It's my pleasure.
So, why don't we
grab a table?
Keep things moving? Babe?
Yeah.
Oh, you're not coming?
Greetings are done.
Nobody ran.
You don't need
me anymore.
Heh.
Look, I am not bragging
when I say that
this hybrid O.R.
could revolutionize
trauma surgery's interaction
with emergency medicine.
It's set up for interventional
and open procedures.
We've got surgical lights,
we've got a C-arm, case carts.
There is a scrub room
right outside.
Okay, maybe I'm bragging
just a little bit.
Doctor, can I get a shot
of you in front
of the operating table?
Yeah, sure.
All right,
thank you, everybody.
The hospital's PR department
will forward you complete
press kits.
Thank you.
So, I'm going to bring
the Trib through in five
and then the local
NBC affiliate after that.
I'll be ready.
I really appreciate
your putting on the charm.
Ms. Goodwin,
you built me Xanadu.
I would sing and dance
for you if you wanted.
Oh, I'm gonna
hold you to that.
Oh, my God,
it's Dr. Connor Rhodes.
Can I have
your autograph?
You're gonna have
to get in line.
I'm kind of a big deal
around here.
I've gotta admit,
this is an
impressive space.
Yeah. Feels right.
Look... Now that
I am officially
open for business,
it's pretty easy to see
how jumping the gun last week
was a mistake. I'm sorry.
Are we good?
We're good.
It's Latham.
I've gotta go.
Congratulations, Connor.
Thank you.
Hey, you could have told me
Bernie's old enough
to be my dad.
First, that's
an exaggeration.
Second, I didn't know.
It's just a number, right?
Does it really matter?
No, not if Emily
acted like an adult,
instead of a 12-year-old.
You mean like how
you're acting right now?
April, every boyfriend
my sister's had has
been a train wreck.
You really think Bernie,
who she met in AA,
who's 20 years older,
is gonna be different?
Well, I mean, she does,
so you have to give him
a chance.
I wanted to, but then
I walked into the cafeteria
and I saw the same red flags.
April, I know
how this ends.
He splits, she folds,
and I'm left to pick up
the pieces.
Let's just hope
this time you're wrong, okay?
Look, I've gotta get
on transport right now.
Let's pick this up later.
The OTCs did nothing.
Urgent care prescribed
Zofran and Imodium.
Been taking them
for over a week, but...
Oh, it's so embarrassing.
It's okay, I get it.
Both ends?
I haven't eaten in days.
Where is it all coming from?
Likely viral gastroenteritis.
Urgent care
said the same thing,
but I've been like this
almost a month, and it's
not even flu season.
Unfortunately,
there's often an
exception to the rule,
and this time
it's you. Tests?
CBC, CMP, quantitative HCG.
Oh, that hurts.
CT abdomen and pelvis, got it.
Techs will be by soon
to take you for your scan.
The sooner the better.
I really feel like crap.
No pun intended, right?
Ms. Blake, I'm Dr. Choi.
Oh, thank God.
Finally, a real doctor.
44-year-old female,
complaints of lumbago.
Pain, ten out of ten.
HPI symptoms...
The important info...
I was getting
dressed for work,
bent down to put on my shoes,
and my back locked up.
Well, why don't we
take a look?
Is it okay if student doctor
McNeal examines you?
Have you done
this before?
Oh, wonderful.
I'll be gentle.
Guess you can't make
the pain any worse.
Laid on the floor for an hour
hoping the pain would ease up.
Nothing.
I see a surgical scar.
Discectomy?
L4.
Two years ago.
Felt pretty good
right after,
but these days it feels like a
bad sneeze could paralyze me.
Unfortunately, as common
as back pain is,
there's not a perfect fix.
Slow, slow.
Press against my hand
like a gas pedal.
It hurts.
Stabbing pain.
We have to do
the other leg?
It's gonna hurt, too.
So will flexion, extension,
the femoral stretch,
FABER test.
Been down this road
a few times?
Today's the worst
it's ever been, though.
What would you suggest?
CT?
Five of Valium
for the spasm?
Oh, bless you.
She got on you a bit.
Patients are going
to do that.
Don't take it personally.
It's all good.
When I was playing ball,
I had an OC could rip me
a new one like no other.
Compared to him,
Nora's a peach.
Hey, Doc.
Hey.
Got a sec?
Yeah, what's up?
Not here.
Here's the deal.
Your voice on Ray Burke's
wire is a problem.
Yeah, Jay told me.
I'm sorry. I didn't know
PD had something
going on with him.
Well, it's not just PD.
Feds are in on this too.
It's a joint
task force. Listen.
I just came to give you
the heads-up.
They're looking
your way now.
Me?
Mmm-hmm.
What for?
Taking kickbacks.
What the hell
are you talking about?
You ran Ray's blood for free
and off the books,
then accepted
a sweetheart deal
on his wedding venue.
It's a bad move.
I was treating a patient
from the neighborhood.
E.D. docs, they make
house calls all the time.
They've never been
an issue with the hospital.
Well, they are with the Feds.
Unbelievable.
Yeah, I... Look.
You can still get
ahead of this, okay?
You can make it go away.
'Cause from now on,
whatever happens
between you and Ray,
pass it on.
Become a CI
for the task force.
An informant.
That's crazy. No way.
Doc, this is a big case.
High priority, understand?
You don't have
a lot of options.
Maybe, but I'm, uh...
I'm still not doing it.
Will, listen to me.
You get jammed up
with the Feds,
it could cost you
your medical license.
I said no.
It's the wrong answer.
I'll be in touch.
Doctor.
BP's dropping,
down to 90 over 70.
Heart rate's jumped, 130.
Spleen's abnormal.
Ultrasound.
Spleen is
grossly enlarged.
Also, free fluid
in the abdomen.
Wasn't there on intake.
Grab two units
and then let's move.
I need some help!
What's going on?
She's bleeding internally.
We need to get her
up to surgery now
to control it.
She'll be
okay though, right?
Doctor Manning.
Hi.
Linda, your labs
came back.
The cold you can't shake,
the bruising and petechiae,
and now your spleen...
They're from
primary myelofibrosis.
It's a type of leukemia.
Oh, my God.
Leukemia.
That's cancer.
It is. There are
some medications
that treat the disease,
but the side effects
can be extreme
and the results are unproven.
There is one treatment
that can offer a cure.
It's a stem cell transplant.
Transplant?
There's a list, right?
I'll be at the bottom.
No, no.
There are lists for organs
like hearts and lungs.
Because they come
from deceased donors,
there's a limited supply.
But stem cells come
from living donors.
So anyone able
to give blood
can likely also
give stem cells.
There are a lot of options.
See, baby,
we're gonna beat this.
Thank you, Dr. Manning.
Of course.
I'll call hematology
to get things started, okay?
Gracias.
BP's still low,
temp's ticked up, 102.
And three trips
to the bathroom.
I couldn't even
keep down ice chips.
I'm sorry. I wish
I had an answer.
All your blood work
was within normal limits.
And the CT did show
a cyst in your ovaries,
but that's not uncommon.
Yeah, my sister
has the same thing.
Oh...
Your neck hurt?
It's stiff.
Headache?
Off and on.
Set up for
a lumbar puncture?
Isn't that a spinal tap?
For the flu?
It's possible that
it's evolved into
encephalitis or meningitis.
I will never skip another
flu shot, I swear.
Is there someone
we can call for you?
No, my girlfriends,
they'll bring drama
I don't need right now.
Mmm-hmm.
Uh, what about your sister?
She and my parents
live out of state.
Mmm.
It's okay,
I've got my podcasts,
and they can actually
go with me into
the bathroom, so...
They might make
better company, then.
I see the Valium's helping.
I'm trying to move around
a little, loosen things up.
Those my CT results?
Yes, scans show spinal
degeneration and scar tissue
at L3 through L5.
We suspect it's chronic and
not the cause of today's pain.
That's likely
structural, so...
You want an MRI.
Compare it to the scan
taken when I had surgery
two years ago to see
if anything's different.
Forgot. You know the drill.
Yeah, so I know an MRI
won't show anything
more than the CT.
You'll give me some
low grade muscle relaxer,
recommend physical therapy,
but those meds won't do
anything more than
a baby aspirin.
And I'm a lawyer, a partner
at Astor, Caldwell and Davis.
I don't have time
to lie on the floor
doing pelvic bridges
with some
glorified trainer.
So how about you just
write me a script
for what will work?
Norco 10/325s,
then we can all
get on with our lives.
I'll talk to the pharmacy.
I take it back.
I think Nora's got the edge
over my old coach.
What are you doing?
Running Nora's name
through the Illinois
prescription database.
See if she's flagged
as a frequent flyer.
You think she's just
trying to score pills?
Faking her pain?
Maybe. Dodging an MRI
and then immediately
pressing for meds
reeks of a con job.
She's not on file.
Still doesn't mean
we're getting the whole story.
So what do we do?
Nora had her back surgery
at East Mercy.
Call over there. See if
she's only coming to us
because they cut her off.
Cesar.
Ricky Glendon, 19.
Hit by a bus.
GCS 5, intubated on scene.
Hypotensive, but no obvious
long bone deformities.
Belly's hard
as a rock. Maggie?
I got you.
Baghdad's ready.
All right,
let's get him in.
All right. On my count.
One, two, three.
Give me the ultrasound.
Here you go.
Fast scan's positive.
There's free fluid
in the belly.
I need to get in there.
We'll do it in the hybrid O.R.
Maggie, decision time.
You on my team or no?
I'm in.
Good.
Page anesthesia,
assemble the others,
and prep the hybrid
O.R. for surgery.
Copy that. April.
Take over the AD?
As long as you need.
All right.
Jay, where are you?
Call me back.
Better yet, just stop
by the hospital.
Everything okay?
Yeah, just...
You know, Jay and I,
still arguing
over Dad's stuff.
Really? I thought
Pat didn't hold on
to anything.
Yeah, he didn't.
These are old baseball cards.
Oh.
So what was all that
with Voight this morning?
So secretive.
Nothing. He wanted
a curbside diagnosis
because he doesn't
trust his own doctor.
He's a pain in the ass.
He should get
a second opinion for that.
Get it?
Pain in the ass.
Oh, yeah. That's funny.
No, it wasn't.
But that's why I love you.
Oh, it's Goodwin.
I gotta go.
I'll see you.
We get a stem cell donor
for Linda?
Come in and close the door.
There's a problem.
Linda Harper isn't
a U.S. citizen.
That complicates
her ability to access
the transplant network.
Why? Patients can't be denied
based on immigration status.
No, but they can if they're
unable to prove they have
stable insurance
to cover the procedure
and the follow-up cost.
But she has insurance.
James, her husband,
is a citizen
and covered by Medicaid.
Doesn't that include Linda?
The marriage allows
Linda to apply
for a green card,
but until she has
official legal status,
James' Medicaid
does not extend to her.
This is ridiculous.
So despite the abundance of
stem cell donors out there,
Linda can't get to
any of them
because of red tape?
Ms. Goodwin, a transplant
is the only treatment
that can save her life.
I know.
That's why I think the family
should bypass the network
altogether with
a direct donation
from her brother, Manny.
And pay out of pocket?
It's expensive, I know.
But there's not
a better option.
I'll speak with James.
All right.
Thank you.
Mmm-hmm.
When this is tied,
the mesentery
will be hemostatic.
Marty, talk to me.
Massive ST elevations.
Kid's 19 and he's having
a heart attack?
Apparently.
We need an angiogram.
Let's get the C-arm
in place. Maggie?
Introducer kit,
wire and lead.
Read my mind. Let's go.
So, your LP revealed
a high presence
of white cells
in your cerebral
spinal fluid.
So it is encephalitis
or meningitis.
Yes and no.
The search for the
infecting bacteria or virus
was inconclusive.
So, you have the symptoms,
but not the cause.
That's strange, isn't it?
Tara, you're slurring.
My face feels weird. Tingly.
Ptosis of the left eyelid.
It's really droopy.
Left corner of the mouth
is lagging.
Seventh cranial
nerve issue?
Mmm-hmm.
Does your mouth feel dry?
Tastes like metal.
These new signs, whatever is
going on, it is definitely
affecting her brain.
Let's get an MRI and push her
to the front of the list.
Squeeze my fingers.
What's wrong with me?
We're gonna find out.
Order a transvaginal
ultrasound as well.
For the ovarian cysts?
Why? We already saw them
on the CT.
Yeah, well, I want
a better look.
Okay.
I understand
it's an enormous
amount of money.
I don't care.
We'll take out loans,
sell the car.
It's Linda's life.
And in all honesty,
this is the hardest part.
The medicine itself
is straightforward.
Manny, as Linda's brother,
you are the ideal candidate
to donate your stem cells.
It's a series of infusions
to boost your
bone marrow production.
When can he start?
Today.
By the end of next week,
it's likely you'll be
able to donate to Linda.
Manny, you all right?
I don't know.
Mr. Calderon,
it's a simple procedure.
I don't think I can.
Can what?
Donate.
Manny, what the hell
are you talking about?
I'm sorry, James. I just...
I can't.
Manny, you have to.
Mr. Calderon, I don't
know if you understand.
If we don't do this
transplant, your sister...
I know. But I can't.
What the hell's
wrong with you?
You're her brother.
Then leave.
Mr. Harper...
If you're not gonna help,
just get the hell out of here.
I said out!
Manny, are you okay?
Why?
I'm sorry, James.
Without you, she'll die.
Your sister
needs you, Mr. Calderon.
Please, help us
understand
your decision.
Donating stem cells means
my name goes into your system.
They monitor them.
That's how they get you.
Ah.
You're undocumented
as well, aren't you?
Yes.
And so is my wife.
She's pregnant.
I love my sister.
I risked our lives to get us
here from El Salvador, but...
If I get deported...
The hospital is prohibited
from sharing personal data
to law enforcement.
That includes
immigration officials.
No one will know you're here.
Government will find out.
They'll come for me
and then for my wife.
Mr. Calderon, I realize that
these are uncertain times
for immigrants
but you'd be donating
stem cells to your sister.
You'd be saving her life.
They won't care.
You don't understand.
How could you?
But it's real.
They take people
from work, from home.
They separate families.
I might
never see my wife again.
Meet our child.
I'm sorry.
No.
Damn it,
the tear is too close
to the takeoff of the LAD.
I can't deploy the stent
without occluding
the left main.
We're gonna have to crack him
open and revascularize.
I'll call upstairs
and get us a bypass machine
and perfusionist.
And Dr. Bardovi, too.
I'm going to need
an extra set of hands
to assist.
Okay, let's prep and drape.
On it.
Tara's MRI results.
Clean. No tumors,
lesions, or clots.
And the transvaginal
ultrasound.
Scan only shows
simple ovarian cysts.
Nothing abnormal.
Are you going to fill me in
on why you doubled back
to look at the cysts?
I thought one might
have been a teratoma.
A clump of cells
that shouldn't be there.
Well, it would explain
the sharpness she feels
in her abdomen,
and if the teratoma contains
primitive brain cells,
it could have tricked
her immune system
into attacking her
actual brain cells.
Causing the
neurologic symptoms.
Okay, yeah, I see
the connections,
but the kind of teratoma
that you're describing
is super rare.
Yes.
But a teratoma is the only
thing that connects
all her symptoms.
Then why didn't it show up
on the ultrasound?
I don't know.
But just because a
radiologist couldn't see it
does not mean it's not there.
Dr. Halstead,
there are cysts
in each ovary.
Even if there is
a teratoma hiding,
you don't know
which one it's in.
Yeah.
Our only move would be
to push for surgery.
Take them both out.
An oophorectomy.
You want me to call gyne?
She's only 30.
I do this, she won't
be able to have kids.
So, do I call gyne?
No. Start over.
Take a new history.
Draw all new labs
and test for zebras.
Start with an ANA,
SSA, SSB,
and antithyroglobulin
antibodies.
Okay.
Connor.
Oh, wow.
I asked for the CT fellow
and I get the Attending.
My new title
really carries some weight.
Easy there, tiger.
You only got me
because the elective CABG
I was starting
is now on hold
because your trauma
needs a bypass machine.
Mmm, also maybe because
you miss operating with me.
Scrub in.
Bypass machine should be
down here any minute.
Actually, I put a hold
on that order.
Machine's already prepped
and ready for use up
in the O.R.
Simpler to bring your patient
up than the equipment down.
You're right.
Let's do it.
Guess I do miss
operating with you.
Love hearing
you say I'm right.
Dr. Choi?
Just heard back
from East Mercy.
Nora's not on file
as a frequent flyer.
Never been a patient there.
Well, she definitely
had a surgery.
Scar on her back
is clear proof.
Well, I'll start calling
other hospitals,
see if she's on file
somewhere else.
If Nora is playing us,
it stands to reason
she'd also lie about
where she had her operation.
Maybe it's simpler
than that.
If I were trying
to game the system,
I certainly wouldn't
use my real name.
So, if she's not
Nora Blake, who is she?
Good question.
Dr. Charles, can I ask
you something?
I've got a strong feeling
my patient gave a fake name
to get a prescription.
Huh.
You think we're dealing
with addiction?
Likely, but I can't
help her with it
if I can't separate
fact from fiction.
You know,
often when people lie,
they tend to describe
things in generalities.
But when they
use specifics,
it's more likely
they're telling
the truth.
Your patient give you
any details?
The type of meds
she wanted.
Oh, and her job.
That she's a partner
at a law firm.
Astor, Caldwell,
and Davis.
Huh. Start there.
Thanks.
There.
Nora Blake is actually
Brenna McDouglas.
Gotcha.
Am I a match?
No, I'm sorry.
You don't have enough HLA
markers in common with Linda.
What about Evan?
He's the only
other blood relation.
It's possible, but
the injections needed
to boost stem cells
increase the chance
that the donors themselves
develop leukemia
in the future.
Evan's family history
and his young age...
His risk would be
significantly higher.
Is there any other way?
Stem cells can also
be extracted directly
from Evan's bone marrow,
but it's an invasive process,
and given Evan's weight,
it would take
multiple procedures
to harvest the amount
of cells needed.
It would be painful for him,
and I can't guarantee it
would be successful for you.
So the only way
to save my wife
is to give my son
the disease
that's killing her
or put him through hell
and hope for the best?
I'll donate
my stem cells.
I came to the United States
for a better life.
Linda has one
with James and Evan.
I can't take that from her.
Fine, you got me.
My name's Brenna McDouglas,
not Nora Blake.
Can I have
my prescription now?
It may feel
like you need them,
but more pills
aren't the answer.
I'm in pain.
Don't you even care?
Yes, we care.
And we want to help.
Let us set you up with
an addiction therapist
who can devise a pain
management strategy
that doesn't
involve opioids.
Here's some referrals
that I think you should
take a look at.
No! I don't need
a therapist
or a new plan.
I need my refill.
What is the big deal?
My God.
I'm a lawyer
with great insurance,
not some junkie
off the street.
Or worse, some hombre
that probably
can't even speak
the language.
That guy in the next room...
Mexican or whatever...
He attacked a man.
He fought him right
in the emergency room.
But nobody gave him
a hard time
or prevented his care. No.
The doctor,
the administrator...
They're bending over
backwards for him.
There is no way
he comes before me.
So give me
my prescription
or, so help me,
I will sue you
and this entire
emergency room.
No.
Then get out,
and send me your boss.
Dr. Lanik, my patient
would like a word.
You ready?
Routine
LIMA procedure
should do it.
Mammary artery's
a perfect size match.
But, if for any reason
it feels off,
we'll use the saphenous
vein instead.
What, you disagree?
No, approach is spot on,
just wondering why you're
in the lead surgeon position.
Because this is my patient.
He was when
he was downstairs,
but now he's upstairs.
I've been with Ricky
since he entered the E.D.
I'm gonna see him
through to the end.
And I have no problem
with that,
as long as it's as
my number two.
Scalpel please, Beth.
Stop.
Beth, scalpel.
Hand him that instrument,
and you're off my team.
This is my O.R., Dr. Rhodes.
You can assist
or you can leave.
What will it be?
I already told you,
the CT cases on the CT floor
belong to the CT Attending.
This shouldn't have
even been an issue.
No, because I wouldn't
even be up here if I had
a bypass machine downstairs.
Well, you don't. Scalpel.
It's about time.
I've been trying
to reach you for hours.
Voight says the Feds
want to come after me.
Yeah, I know.
Well, what the hell?
You couldn't let me know I was
about to get sucker punched?
The Feds kept it from me.
They know you're my brother.
That I'd run interference.
And did you?
Deaf ears.
PD, the Feds, they've been
looking for a way
into Ray Burke's circle
for years.
Now they got one,
they're not letting go.
I'm calling Ray,
I'm giving the venue back.
This is not worth it
to save a few bucks.
Will, you can't do that.
Judges are
expediting warrants
and your clearance
in the CI program.
This is happening.
Whose side are you on?
Look, I'm not happy
about making you a CI.
But Ray Burke is a bad guy.
Haven't I told you about
all the felonies?
Will, they want him
for murder.
He's gotta go away.
So if I was running
the task force, yeah,
I'd wanna use you too.
Ray's that dangerous
a criminal
and your best plan
to nab him is me.
He hardly ever lets
anyone but family
past the front door.
You're perfect.
You're a squeaky clean kid
from the neighborhood
who's an attending
at a big-time hospital.
For Christ's sakes,
he invited you in.
This is insane.
Sometimes you've gotta do
things you don't want to do.
That's life.
No.
Screw the task force,
screw Voight,
and screw you.
She's seizing.
Five of Ativan.
SATs have plummeted. 70.
Face and lips
are turning blue,
she's cyanotic.
Can't protect
her airway either.
I'm intubating.
Sux and etomidate?
Don't need meds.
She's out.
I'm in. Bag her.
Cancel the new labs,
transfer to gyne
for the oophorectomy.
Both ovaries have to come out.
But, Dr. Halstead...
I don't have a choice anymore.
If I don't act now,
she'll be dead.
Prep her to move.
It'll take five infusions
to boost your stem cells
to donation level.
So come back tomorrow
and I'll meet you
at the outpatient clinic
for number two.
I know helping Linda
is the right thing to do,
but...
I'm scared.
Manny...
What's going on right now in
this country... I'm sorry.
I hope it's not
always like this.
See you tomorrow.
Stop!
Hey!
Stop right there.
Immigration and Customs
Enforcement.
You're under arrest.
Hey, what are
you doing?
No, no, no,
you need to stop.
This man is donating
stem cells.
Ma'am, please step back.
I need you to stop.
He is saving a life.
Get your hands off of me!
Ma'am.
Due diligence?
That's your position?
A patient made a complaint
against Mr. Calderon
regarding an altercation
with Mr. Harper.
I looked into it
and discovered
the immigration issue.
Unsure what
hospital policy was,
I brought the matter
to Ms. Garrett.
I reached out to legal
for clarification.
They reached out to
immigration officials
for further explanation
of federal protocols.
You're passing around
Manny's information
like it's a game
of Telephone.
Agents took him
down at the hospital!
The hospital is protected
as a sensitive location.
ICE had no right
to make an arrest here.
I was informed that
there was
an active Immigration and
Customs Enforcement warrant
on file for Mr. Calderon.
So when authorities
asked for permission
to come on the property,
I gave it.
Did you even read this?
They took Manny
for a misdemeanor
theft charge
from 2010.
Stolen items
valued at $8.62.
You gave permission
for this.
Manny's wife is
also undocumented
and she's pregnant.
We just put
a target on her back.
I am not happy
with the way this turned out.
But my duty is
to protect this hospital,
not to pick fights
with the Feds.
I am sorry.
Tough day, huh?
You all right?
She used an alias,
lied to score drugs.
She should be
the one in cuffs,
not that poor guy
just trying to help
his sister.
I'm with you.
But, look, I mean,
she's an addict, right?
And putting her behind bars
wouldn't work anyway.
I'm gonna have a lot of cases
that break the wrong way,
aren't I?
Mmm-hmm.
But you know what?
You're also gonna have
a whole lot that won't.
Pathology report.
One of the ovarian cysts
was a teratoma.
Oh, thank God.
What if I'd been wrong?
Are you supposed to say stuff
like that to a third year
medical student?
Probably not, but that
was the toughest call
I've ever had to make.
Yeah, but you said
you didn't have a choice,
so how tough
could it have been?
I'm sorry.
I am so sorry.
Did the hospital
change their position?
Are they gonna help?
What is this?
I compiled a list
of immigration attorneys.
Perhaps they can get
Manny released quickly
or expedite
Linda's citizenship
so she has easier access
to the transplant network.
That family came to us
for medical help,
and the best we could do is
give them a list of lawyers?
There are millions of people
out there like Manny.
What happens
if they get sick?
This is telling them,
"Be afraid to go
to the doctor."
Hey.
About earlier...
Sorry I had
to get rough.
Don't be.
You were just
protecting your territory.
So am I.
What are you looking for?
Uh, about three-and-a-half
square feet.
Ah.
Space for a bypass machine.
Of course.
Big ticket item.
Good luck.
Good night.
Ethan.
Hey, you got a minute?
Bernie, it's been a long day.
I just want to go home
and not think about anything.
Please.
Hey.
I'm really sorry
I put you in this position.
Look, I'm a...
I'm a middle-aged guy,
and I meet
your sister in AA.
We start dating,
we shouldn't,
and I get her pregnant.
And I'd be furious,
too, if I were you.
But I'm committed
to my sobriety.
And...
Look, all I can say is
I love Emily.
And I'm gonna
take care of her.
And our baby.
Okay, Bernie.
Okay.
Look, man, it's been
a pretty long day
so I don't want to
get into it with you, okay?
I'm really your only option?
Yeah.
Okay then.