[Jon Batiste's "What A Wonderful World"]
♪
[exhales]
♪ I see trees of green
♪
♪ And red roses too
♪ I see them bloom
♪ For me and you
[machine beeping]
♪ And I think to myself
♪
♪ What a wonderful world
[water running]
♪
I love you.
♪ I see skies of blue
♪ And clouds of white
[labored breathing]
♪ The bright blessed day
[phone vibrating]
♪ In the dark sacred night
♪ And I think to myself
♪
♪ What a wonderful world
You okay?
♪
- ♪ The colors
of the rainbow ♪
♪ So pretty in the sky
- [exhales]
- ♪ And also on the faces
♪ Of all the people going by
♪ I see friends
shaking hands ♪
♪ Saying "How do you do?"
♪ They're really saying
♪ "I love you"
♪
[no audible dialogue]
♪ I hear babies cry
[keys clacking]
♪ I watch them grow
♪ They'll know much more
♪ Than I'll ever know
♪ And I think to myself
♪ What a wonderful world
[machinery beeping]
[phone buzzing]
♪ What a wonderful world
♪
[machinery beeping]
[air hissing]
[frenetic percussive music]
- Lauren!
Hi.
Good morning.
Check this out.
It's a play on
an egg-white Croque Madame
with farm fresh ingredients
and twenty seed
ancient grain bread...
- So it's a sandwich?
- No.
No, ma'am.
Because this has
"Granny Smith agave compote"
spread all over it.
- Applesauce.
- Okay, yeah.
Fine. You got me.
It's an applesauce sandwich,
all right?
Maybe I spiraled during the
sourdough-banana-bread phase
of the pandemic.
- Are you gonna eat that
in the meeting?
- [stammering] In what meeting?
- Hospital-wide.
Max just called it.
- He did? Yes.
- Mm-hmm.
- Today just keeps
getting better, doesn't it?
- You're incredibly upbeat
for someone who's
living on seeds.
- Oh, come on.
Everyone loves
a Goodwin townhall.
Max gets all hopped up
and fires an entire department?
Boom!
Max threatens doctors
with jail time?
Boom!
Let's get a good seat.
- What the hell
is wrong with you?
- Plantain truffle scone?
- No.
♪
- Of all the gin joints
in New York.
- Uh, I owe you call or 12.
- No worries.
I got the hint.
- My silence wasn't a hint.
- True.
After a few months,
it definitely became
more of a statement.
- My silence was me
hunkering down,
battening the hatches,
focusing on my patients.
- Okay.
And now?
- [scoffs]
I've got no idea.
I haven't even thought
about now.
- Well, once you lift
your stay-at-home order,
just, um, let me know.
♪
- How about tonight?
[laughs]
- Wow.
It wasn't even planned.
Good morning, everyone.
- Max, what are the chances
you can just give me
the highlights
and skip the razzle-dazzle
and get back to work?
- Yeah, it'll be quick.
Promise.
- See ya, Dermatology.
- No.
No one is getting sacked today.
- Aww.
- Yeah, so... no, Iggy.
I just wanted to tell everyone
how proud I am
of this whole hospital,
of everything that
we survived together.
We've been through hell.
We're tired.
We're hurting.
But our sacrifices are
starting to turn the tide.
- This doesn't sound quick.
- So today, things are
finally turning around.
Today, Dr. Kapoor gets off
his ventilator.
- [gasps]
- Yes.
- Yeah.
It's great news.
And listen...
I want everyone to know.
I am committed to fixing
the cracks around here, okay?
The system abandoned us
when we needed it most.
[rumbling from above]
And I... I vow... uh...
[rumbling continues]
I vow to fix the system
that left us overburdened
and unprotected that, uh...
[clears throat]
The system that left
our most vulnerable patients
behind, and then hopefully,
New Amsterdam can finally
get back to nor...
[rumbling intensifies]
[dramatic music]
[whooshing]
- Prep the ED for triage.
- On it.
- We're gonna be overrun.
Warn the blood bank.
- Copy.
- We're gonna need to call in...
- The rest of the trauma team.
- Yeah.
[metal rattling]
[tense music]
- [gasps]
- 28-year-old flight attendant,
unrestrained,
thrown against the wall.
- Any fatalities yet?
- Ah, my chest!
- Not yet.
- Let's keep it that way.
- Ma'am, we're gonna take
good care of you, okay?
Let's get her to Trauma One.
Hey, I need an EKG,
a portable chest,
and full blood panel
including coags.
- Oh, my chest!
- It's on me.
Ready?
One, two, three.
[dramatic music]
- Okay, deep breaths for me,
Shenaz, okay?
- Let's go.
Monitor cardiac input.
- It hurts.
- 90 over palp.
- Neck veins distended
with muffled heart sounds.
- Tamponade from
blunt force trauma.
Okay, Shenaz,
there is fluid building up
in the sack around your heart.
It's squeezing your heart,
making it hard to pump blood.
We're going to do our best
to fix it.
Walsh, start a morphine drip.
Reyes, I need
a Pericardiocentesis.
And grab me if you see blood.
♪
[indistinct chatter]
[patient groaning]
What you got?
- Nothing.
- A 747 goes down,
and you got nothing?
What about this one?
- Well, seeing as
I'm a trauma surgeon
and he doesn't need surgery...
- I encourage you to harken
back to just a few months ago
when we all chipped in
to save lives
no matter our job title.
- I'd prefer not to harken back
to a time
when thousands of people
died every day,
but maybe that's just me.
- Walsh?
- Mariel Rabkin,
a 34-year-old
hit by a flying iPhone.
- Okay, let's get her over to...
- Page me if she needs surgery.
- Copilot with deep abdominal
blood lac and blood loss.
Heart rate up to 118.
BP down to 108/40.
- See, good things come
to those who wait.
- Hawaii.
- Ma'am, you're in New York
at New Amsterdam Hospital.
- Hawaii.
[labored breathing]
- Oh.
- Got a stat request
from the ambulance.
The copilot needs O-neg blood.
- Okay, then you're with me.
Let's get her into Trauma One.
- Occupied.
- Trauma Two.
- All right, we're going
straight into the OR.
Grab a side.
♪
- Excuse me, Dr. Goodwin?
Nelson Peña.
I'm the lead investigator
with the NTSB.
- Welcome to our little bubble.
I assume everybody
tested negative?
- My Go Team is fully intact
and ready to begin
the investigation.
- Uh, well, that's good to hear,
but isn't the plane still
floating in the East River?
- Well, this Go Team deals
with the human element
of these incidents.
- Sounds like
we're on the same side.
- No doubt.
We'll do our best
to stay out of your way.
We just need to interview every
crew member and passenger
who may have
pertinent information.
- Well, roger that.
Or... sorry.
As long as it doesn't interfere
with patient care,
I will help in any way I can.
- Understood.
We wanna start with the pilots.
Captain Starks?
- I'll find him for you.
Hey, have you seen the pilot?
- Uh, yes, actually.
Right here.
- What am I looking at?
- Captain Dane Starks.
He has been catatonic
since he arrived.
- There's no masses.
There's no bleeds.
Ventricles look normal.
This looks fine.
- No, no, no.
That's the problem.
It's not that he can't talk.
It's that he won't.
[tense music]
♪
.
[frenetic music]
- Dr. Mandle.
- Morning, Dr. Goodwin.
- Yeah, it was supposed to be.
Why is Dr. Kapoor
still on a vent
when you told me
he was getting off today?
- I told you I was hoping
to take him off today,
but we ran out of propofol
and had to switch to fentanyl.
- Sorry.
- Which takes longer
to wean the patient off.
- I understand that,
but it sounds like you said
we're out of propofol.
How is that possible?
- Because we've had patients
on vents
for the last 12 months straight,
as has every hospital
in the country.
Look, the stockpiles are empty,
and the factories
can't meet demand.
- If I get you propofol,
can you get Kapoor
and the other patients
off the vents?
- Yes, but...
- That is all I needed to hear.
♪
[elevator dings]
- Dr. Goodwin.
- You guys always
walk together like that?
- We have rehearsals at noon.
You're welcome to join.
- [chuckles]
- Any update on the pilot?
- Right, the pilot.
Sorry.
- Some of the passengers
reported seeing him
acting strangely
before the flight.
If Captain Starks knew
he was impaired before duty,
then this becomes
a criminal case.
- Right, well, Captain Starks
is currently with his physician,
but once we're done,
I'll let you know.
- We'd like to test
his blood alcohol level...
- Unfortunately,
you can't interrupt
a patient's evaluation...
- Evaluation?
So then the pilot's
not actually injured?
- Look, Agent...
- Investigator.
- See, that makes sense because
it's your job to investigate,
and it's our job to heal.
So once we're done...
- Dr. Goodwin.
To clarify,
you're blocking access
to a key witness.
- I'm helping a patient.
[indistinct PA announcements]
[tense music]
[sirens wail distantly]
[clock ticking]
- [clears throat]
You know, sometimes
when people are having
a hard time talking,
it's not because
they are scared.
It's because they're distracted.
You know, their brain
keeps wandering off
into the most random
pockets of life.
They try to focus,
but they can't.
You ever feel like that?
Yeah.
We all do.
But that's...
That's only part of it.
The other part is that
right when your brain
gets into a groove...
Bam!
It... it's right back there.
It's in Indiana.
It's in the crash.
All over again.
But then those
memories disappear.
And you...
You try to go back to them,
but your brain
wanders off again,
and you can't focus,
and round and round you go.
And you start to wonder
if this is what it's like
to go insane.
But it's not.
It's trauma.
And trauma is a beast.
It's invisible.
It's not gonna show up
on your CT, but it's real.
It's as real as cancer.
And just like cancer,
if it goes untreated,
it'll get worse.
That is a fact.
[soft dramatic music]
But you know, Dane,
all of these things
that you're feeling,
I can help them go away,
but you have to start
talking to me.
That's where we start.
♪
- I don't...
I don't remember any of it.
- Yeah, okay.
Yeah.
That's perfectly normal,
actually.
- No, I was...
I was having a manic episode.
♪
Nobody knows.
I'm bipolar.
-BP's down to 90 systolic.
- We've got to get
this bleeding under control.
Lap pad.
- Push an amp
of calcium gluconate.
[machinery beeping]
Let me see.
[indistinct chatter]
- Do you smell that?
Is someone chewing gum?
Mints, candy, anything?
- It's the copilot.
It smells like ethylene glycol.
- Antifreeze.
- When the plane crashed,
maybe a hose snapped.
Her open abdominal wound...
- Absorbed it.
Which is why we can't get
the blood...
both: To clot.
- So push Fomepizole.
It should act as an antidote.
- HB level 8 pH 7.6.
- It's clotting.
Good save.
- Not so fast.
Emergent lab is back.
- Liver enzymes are elevated.
- How high?
- 3 1/2 times normal.
- That's not the antifreeze.
- We're missing something.
[alarm blares]
- Now what?
- BP falling.
- Temp's dropping.
- She's septic.
Start her on amp,
gent, and Flagyl.
Hang a bag of dopamine
at 2 mcg a minute.
- Coding 15 mils.
[dramatic music]
- Brad Winton.
- Sent up to neuro
for observation.
- Because we couldn't
do that here?
Brenda Nelson.
- Admitted to OB for spotting.
- And?
- OB took over.
- Eva Schafer.
- Copilot's in surgery.
- Prognosis.
- Cassian doesn't exactly
give updates.
- Yeah, well then,
go force one out of him.
You know what?
How does no one know
what happened to our patients?
- 'Cause once we pass them on,
they're no longer our patients.
- Wrong.
This is an emergency room,
not a waiting room.
You know what?
I want a full report
by end of shift of everyone
who came through here today.
Go.
What?
It's a perfectly
reasonable request.
[machinery beeping]
- We've got a problem
with Shenaz.
- Dissecting aortic aneurysm.
Couldn't see it
till I drained out the fluid.
- Yeah, but look.
See here?
The tear's causing
the blood to pool
in between the layers
of the arterial wall.
And what does that mean,
Dr. Walsh?
- The aorta could rupture.
- Page cardio.
[dramatic music]
- What are you doing?
- We're not sending
another patient
off into the great unknown
when I can help them
right here, right now.
- We just paged cardio.
She's not your patient anymore.
- They're all my patients.
Iodine.
- Bill, Max Goodwin here.
How's everything at University?
- Well, we're losing over
$40 million a month,
and I'm laying off my janitors
just so I can find
enough cash to pay
for the staff and supplies to
restart the elective procedures
that will allow us
to generate enough cash
to hire back those janitors.
What do you want?
- Propofol.
- Are you serious?
- Do I sound like I'm kidding?
We're completely out,
and we need it.
- Everyone's out and needs it.
So even if we did have it,
there's no way
I'd give any of it to you.
- But you'd be helping patients.
- Ugh, it wouldn't be helping
my patients.
Look, we're in the middle
of a massive drug shortage
of our own.
Metronidazole,
Avonex, Revlimid...
My 15-year-old son has more
access to drugs than I do.
Welcome to the new normal.
- I don't know
what authority you have.
I am not telling you where
any of our patients are.
- Ma'am, we are authorized
to speak to any individual
who may have information.
- Hey... whoa.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, enough.
You don't have the right
to come into this hospital
and rip a patient away
from their doctor,
violating HIPAA rules and...
- As a matter of fact, we do.
[tense music]
- What is this?
- A federal order.
Issued by the United States
Department of Justice,
which supersedes HIPAA
by 120 years.
So I'll ask one more time.
Where's the pilot?
♪
.
- So it's my understanding that
pilots with bipolar
can still fly
as long as they're
on the proper medication.
- They can.
They can also end up with
nothing but 3:00 a.m. flights,
no raises,
and a nudge out the door.
- Regulations exist to protect
you against retaliation.
- You have kids?
- Um...
[clears throat]
Do I have kids?
Yeah.
I do.
Like, a lot.
- All right, so your oldest
is taking her first solo flight.
You find out
the pilot is bipolar.
How good are you feeling?
- I'd feel great about it.
- Excuse me?
- Well, you asked me
how I'd feel if I found out
the pilot on my kid's
first flight was bipolar.
I'd feel great about it.
Because I know that
you're no more likely
to have an episode
than the next pilot is
to have a heart attack.
So I'd feel great about it.
What's your current
treatment plan?
- I see someone once a month.
I take lithium.
300 milligrams daily.
25 milligrams of antidepressant
antipsychotic every other day.
- What about your flight record?
Any safety incidents?
- No.
- Okay, so I'm gonna
mirror that back for you.
Um, you're in treatment.
It's working.
You know your dosage
to the milligram
which indicates that you are
a highly responsible individual.
And I don't know about you,
but that is something
I tend to like in my pilot.
What about this morning?
Did you take your medication?
- Yeah.
- All right,
so what are we talking about?
- Four years ago,
this cop buddy of mine...
We were having a beer
down at the airfield.
Talking shop, laughing.
I...
I realized that
I was controlling the planes
with my mind.
[tense music]
Landings.
Takeoffs.
And in fact,
I was controlling
the whole world with my mind.
He took me to the hospital,
and that's how I was diagnosed.
- Right.
Well, I'm sorry.
That sounds awful.
- No, but that's not the point.
[sighs]
He didn't take me
to the hospital
because I was having a delusion.
It was because my response
to the delusion
was to grab his gun.
And to point it at my head.
What if... [sighs]
What if that's what
I was doing again?
♪
Today?
- You think
that this plane crash
was you trying to kill yourself?
♪
[indistinct chatter]
- Be right back.
- Hey.
- Hi, I need to...
I need some more time.
- Uh, I need you to listen.
- It never fails to amaze me
how stigmatized mental health
is in this country.
- Yeah, couldn't agree more...
- It's unbelievable.
You know, at New Amsterdam,
we have dozens of doctors
with a variety
of mental health care issues.
And because
this hospital's policy
is one of understanding
and respect,
they manage their condition
without it
ever affecting their work.
- Which is exactly why...
- Right? Seems simple.
But no, everywhere else
in the world, it's some flaw.
It's some deficiency.
It's a detriment.
It's their fault somehow.
No wonder these people are
hiding it from their employers.
You know...
Which compounds their shame,
increases the public's mistrust,
and contributes to inadequate
medical intervention.
It's so simple.
I'm tired of it, Max.
I want to bring mental health
care out into the open.
No more shame.
No hiding.
[exhales]
I'm sorry.
What do you need?
- We need to hide your patient.
♪
[machinery beeping]
- Enzymes are six times normal.
Liver's not gonna last
much longer.
- I need to expose
the entire organ.
- You'd need to extend
the surgical field
across the whole abdomen.
[suction whirring]
- Scalpel.
- Do you wanna call in Gastro?
- No, there's no time.
You mind getting
your hands dirty?
- Of course not.
- Great.
- But it's been a few years.
- You have a steady hand?
- Well, yes.
- Clear field of vision?
- Yes.
- Still like that
Thai food place on 17th?
- Yes.
- Then what are you waiting for?
[tense music]
♪
- Endo linear stapler coming in.
- One centimeter to the left.
[machinery beeping]
- BP's dropping.
♪
- Retractors.
- Assessing surgical margins.
- There.
Bile duct is scarred shut.
- The antifreeze must have
caused a chemical burn.
- Now bile's backing up
into the liver
causing it to shut down.
Okay.
Listen up.
We're gonna resect
a large portion of this liver
and reconstruct the bile duct.
Otherwise, we're gonna lose
Ms. Schafer.
I need a hemostat and lap pads.
Will you stick around?
- Yeah.
I'll stick around.
♪
[machinery beeping]
- Advancing catheter.
Okay.
I'm at the aorta.
And...
[alarm blaring]
- BP's dropping.
Dissection's extending.
- Drainage greater than 200.
- What the hell were you doing?
- I was trying to stop
the dissection.
- Well, you didn't.
You made it worse.
- I'm trying to fix it.
- Not fast enough.
Thanks to you going rogue,
I've gotta crack her chest here.
- Going rogue?
In case you haven't noticed,
I'm also wearing a white coat.
- Your job is
to stabilize patients
and then get out of the way.
Out.
[alarm blaring]
- Thoracotomy kit coming in.
- When we were knee deep
in the pandemic,
you were thanking me
for taking your patients.
Well, thank God
we're not there anymore.
I need a rib spreader,
Richardson retractor,
and some gauze.
- On it.
- Bloom, out.
Get me some O-negative blood
on a rapid infuser!
- Abduct and extend arms.
- Hey.
Sorry about the new digs.
I just thought maybe
a change of scenery would...
- NTSB is looking for me,
aren't they?
- Um, yeah.
They are.
- [stammering] Yeah... okay, look.
So you should just hand me over.
I mean, I put hundreds,
I mean, if not
thousands of people at risk.
And I don't deserve
special treatment or...
- No, no, Dane.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Slow down, Dane.
I just... I need you
to help me with something.
Why do jets dump fuel?
- What?
- Well, the ED just admitted
about a dozen or so patients
that were all doused
in jet fuel.
- [breathes frantically]
So more people hurt?
- Dane.
Stay with me.
Why... why do planes dump fuel?
- [exhales]
It... it's how you achieve
ideal landing weight.
You can't land
if you're too heavy.
- Okay... okay, so if you were
gonna land early... let's say...
Or unexpectedly,
you would dump the fuel?
You would, am I right?
- Yeah, yeah.
- So why would you
dump that fuel
if you weren't trying
to save the plane?
Not crash it.
You weren't trying
to crash the plane.
You were trying
to save the plane.
- Or I was just out of my mind
and hitting random buttons
like a lunatic.
I mean, I... look,
it doesn't mean anything!
All we know is that
my plane crashed!
[breathing heavily]
[tense music]
♪
- No.
No.
That's not true actually.
We know one other thing, Dane.
We know where you crashed.
Right?
I bet that river
looks pretty striking
when you're flying
over Manhattan.
That little streak of blue
right down the middle.
♪
- Yeah.
Sure.
- Right?
Kinda like
a landing strip maybe?
Dane, you didn't...
You didn't hit a building.
You didn't hit a street.
You went right into the middle
of the river,
the one place, by the way,
with the lowest risk of injury
for civilians for miles.
Miles.
And you're gonna tell me that
that's an accident?
[impactful piano music]
♪
-Leland, it is so nice
to hear a friendly voice.
And yeah... I need a favor.
- Yep, sounds like
you reached out to Bill first.
- Yeah, well,
VJ is still on a vent
along with
a dozen other patients,
and they are in desperate need
of propofol.
- I'm sorry, Max.
We ran out of propofol
over a month ago.
Wish we had some to share.
- People thought toilet paper
was hard to find.
- Don't get me started
on my theory about that.
- Not sure I wanna know
your theory about that.
- Is there a chance you guys
need Acyclovir?
That's one of the few things
we're good on, thanks.
- Well, let me know
when you're not
because we have a crap-ton.
I understand why HCC sends us
all the same resources,
but we serve a predominately
geriatric population.
What the hell
are we supposed to do
with this much
herpes medication?
- Welcome to the new normal,
my friend.
- Dr. Goodwin.
- Uh, so sorry, Leland.
Gotta call you back.
Think I'm about to be arrested.
- Arrested?
- Hi.
Before we do the cuffs thing,
can I just say...
- We're not arresting you.
- Okay.
- We think you'll hand over
Captain Starks
willingly and without incident.
- Why would I do that?
- We've recovered the black box.
[dramatic music]
.
- Miriam,
thanks for taking the call.
I know how crazy things are
at Baptist,
and I know that the answer
is probably no.
But is there any chance
that your hospital
has a surplus of propofol?
- Of course.
How much do you need?
- That's amazing.
Thank you.
The only thing that is gonna
help my friend is propofol.
You know Dr. Kapoor...
- Oh.
Max, I'm so sorry.
I thought you said prostodin.
We haven't had propofol
for months.
I'd be surprised
if anybody in the city has.
Uh, while I have you,
is there any chance you have
any extra ventilator tubing?
We've been buying ours
from Home Depot,
and they just ran out.
- We've been buying ours
from Home Depot too.
[dramatic piano music]
How are we gonna fix this?
- I don't know.
- Hey.
I gotta call you back.
Ready?
- Yeah, I guess.
No. Is it bad?
- I don't know.
I don't think they'd
be playing it for us
if it was good.
[sighs]
- How is she?
- She's stable.
[sighs]
What's going on with you today?
- I miss it.
- Miss what?
- I miss the pandemic.
I mean, the worst of it.
You know,
I feel like a sociopath
even saying this.
But when we were hit
the hardest?
When the ED was above capacity?
I felt like
I'd spent my whole life
training for a moment
that finally came.
I helped people.
I saved them.
And even when
I couldn't save them,
I was doing exactly
what I was meant to do.
[soft piano music]
♪
I held patients hands
as they died.
I sang songs to them.
And now what?
I'm just supposed
to pass them off
as if they don't matter to me?
[locker clanks]
They matter.
- Um...
I never told anyone this,
but when my deployment ended,
I missed it, you know?
I missed knowing what I had
to do and doing it.
I missed the fight.
We were at war, Lauren.
♪
It's okay to miss the fight.
[padlock clanking]
Oh, and by the way,
you haven't stopped
saving people.
The doctors, nurses...
Me.
You saved us too.
You're still saving us.
♪
[door thuds]
- [sighs]
- The way you sliced
through that abdomen,
I'm gonna start calling you
Zorro from now on.
- [laughs]
Well, you're the one who made
the call about the bile duct.
That pilot is in recovery
because of you.
Very clutch.
[soft dramatic music]
♪
- Helen, I think they're clean.
- Sorry.
Sorry, I just, um...
Sorry.
I can't do this.
[door closes]
- Dane, what the hell
are you doing?
- 660.
- You're gonna kill us all!
Let go!
- 660.
- What is that?
660?
- Starks is incoherent.
- 660!
Air speed!
- There's nothing wrong with...
It's...
- The copilot is struggling
with Captain Starks
for the throttle,
but it's too late.
Starks has them in a nosedive.
[plane droning]
- 660!
- Stop! Let go!
For God sake!
[plane crashes,
recording cuts off]
[dramatic music]
[switch clicks]
- The copilot desperately
tried to save the plane,
and she almost did.
- I... I don't understand.
What about the fuel dump?
Why would Starks have done that
if he wasn't...
- It wasn't Starks.
- You think it was
the copilot as well?
- Flight data recorder tells us
there was a last-ditch effort
to pull the nose up
before they hit.
Schaefer's a hero.
She subverted what would've
been a wholesale massacre,
while Starks was clearly
out of his mind.
♪
There's no fixing this.
- [sighs]
.
[approaching footsteps]
[tense music]
♪
- I'm gonna walk him out.
- Passengers who were admitted
are either stable or discharged.
Copilot's 02 sats
are finally good.
Heart rate holding steady.
Still some post-op delirium
from the anesthesia.
- What kind of delirium?
- Hawaii.
Six...
660.
- We keep telling her
she's in New York but...
- 660.
- What's 660?
- Hawaii.
660.
Hawaii.
[frenetic music]
660.
♪
- Captain Starks!
- Oh, boy.
- What is Hawaii 660?
- It's a flight number.
A plane that went down
in the Pacific last year.
- Why did it go down?
- There was
an equipment problem.
- Faulty air speed indicator.
It told the pilot...
- What does this have
to do with...
- Dane, help me understand.
- The indicator told the pilot
they were flying faster
than they actually were.
So when they ran
into some weather
and they slowed the plane down,
they actually slowed it
to an unsafe speed.
And so the engine stalled,
and it went into the sea.
- Okay, okay.
All right.
So, on takeoff,
if a pilot discovers
that his air speed indicator
is giving him
an inaccurate reading,
and he is flying too slow,
what would that pilot do?
♪
Would there ever be any reason
to deliberately take your plane
into a dive?
- That would depend
on a number of variables.
- Yeah.
- The plane is as heavy
as it's gonna be at takeoff,
so the first thing you'd do is...
- You'd dump your fuel.
- Yeah.
And then you'd...
push the throttle forward.
You'd... [scoffs]
You'd get the nose down.
You'd go into the dive
in order to gain speed.
And then you'd...
You'd lift up at the very end.
- Which is exactly what you did.
Right?
Which is what your copilot,
I think,
was trying to say.
♪
- Copilot's conscious?
- Yeah.
And anxious to talk.
- You think that
Captain Starks jeopardized
the lives of 150 people.
We think he saved the lives
of 150 people.
♪
[phone vibrates]
- Sorry.
I'd love to relish
in this moment, but I...
Florence, thank you
for getting back to me.
- Of course.
Except I had no idea you called.
I'm desperately looking
for acyclovir.
Is there any chance you guys
have some to spare?
- No, we're in the middle
of a serious drug shortage
ourselves.
- Yeah, that checks out.
Well, thanks.
- Yeah.
Hey!
Um, hang on a second.
[phone rings]
- Max?
- Hey, Leland.
You're on with Dr. Brighton
from Brookhaven.
She's asking for acyclovir.
Do you still have extra?
- Sure.
I can send it over now.
- Seriously?
- You're doing us a favor
taking it off our hands.
Also, do either of you
need metronidazole?
We're pretty stocked up
on that too.
- No.
We're good on antibiotics.
- Uh, Leland.
Hang on a second.
[phone tapping]
[phone ringing]
- What do you need now, Max?
- Bill, you're on
with Brookhaven and Memorial.
You were talking
about metronidazole earlier...
Do you still need it?
- Yeah, I need everything.
Why?
- Memorial has extra.
We'll send it over right now.
♪
- [scoffs]
Oh, my God.
If we can help with anything...
I mean, non-drug related...
Please let me know.
- You don't still have
extra vent tubing, do you?
- Tons.
Yeah, I had my guys
buy out Home Depot.
- Yeah, great.
One second.
[phone tapping]
- Hello?
Miriam, you're on
with Brookhaven,
Memorial, and University.
Do you still need
that vent tubing?
- Desperately.
- University will send over
a bunch right now.
- I don't know what to say.
Can I give you some
pulse oximeters?
- Memorial could
really use those.
- I'm sending you a shipment.
- Well, this worked out great
for everyone.
Well, except for you, Max.
- Didn't wanna kill the vibe,
but glad I could help.
- Propofol's a tough one.
- Max, you need propofol?
- Yeah.
Apparently everyone does.
- Not us.
We just found a ton of it
in storage.
You'll have it by end of day.
♪
- Why weren't we all
doing this before?
♪
[ambient music]
[approaching footsteps]
- You're in my spot.
♪
- Safest place in New York.
- How's our Miss Luna?
- I wouldn't know.
She's still frolicking
in suburban splendor
with Georgia's parents.
- How often do you get
to see her?
- Not enough.
I miss her...
[chuckles]
Like crazy.
- I know.
- It's just not safe enough
to bring her home.
- Nothing's safe
anymore though, is it?
Everything that was normal...
Friends,
restaurants,
intimacy...
They all seem so strange now.
- [chuckles]
- They feel...
They feel wrong.
[soft piano music]
I used to be scared
of the virus,
but now I am scared of normal.
- [chuckling]
Normal.
I kept thinking,
once everything
gets back to normal,
then I would finally
fix this hospital,
that I could fix it.
But I don't want to fix
this hospital anymore...
I mean, even if we could
go back to normal.
I don't want to fix this system.
[scoffs]
I want to tear it down.
You know,
I wanna tear it all down
and build something better...
Something better
for my daughter,
something better for you,
better for all of us.
- ♪ I see trees of green
- I mean, otherwise,
what the hell was this for?
[Cover of
"What a Wonderful World"]
- ♪ Red roses too
- Sorry.
Am I boring you?
- ♪ I see them bloom
- No.
Not at all.
In fact, I think there are
a lot of people rooting for you.
[cheers and applause]
It's 7:00.
- ♪ And I think to myself
[people cheering and applause]
♪ What a wonderful world
[car horns honking]
♪
♪ I see skies of blue
♪ And clouds of white
[phones beeping, buzzing]
♪ The bright blessed days
♪ The dark sacred nights
♪ And I think to myself
- Hi, is he...
He's awake.
- ♪ What a wonderful world
- Oh, thank God.
- ♪ The colors
of the rainbow ♪
- Hey, buddy.
[laughter]
- ♪ So pretty in the sky
♪ Are also on the faces
♪ Of people going by
♪ I see friends
holding hands ♪
♪ Saying "How do you do?"
-The damage to his heart
was extensive.
He's going to need
a new mitral valve.
The virus also ravaged
the surrounding heart muscle.
- ♪ I hear babies cry
- How bad?
- No way to sugarcoat it.
Even if you found
the best heart surgeon
in the world,
I'm not sure it'd be enough.
- ♪ And I think to myself
[phone buzzing]
♪ What a wonderful world
♪ Yes, I think to myself
- How can I help?
♪ What a wonderful world ♪
[gentle music]
♪