Previously on ER:
Because I'm no
longer chief of staff.
- I need my job back.
- Kovac is gonna offer you the job.
- We're colleagues, we're contemporaries.
- Hey, no touch.
I keep thinking
they'll arrest me.
Oh, stop worrying about it.
- Just focus on Alex.
- He knows his dad is gone.
No, no, no, Gates.
You cannot put in an EJ.
ER said okay on EJ.
- I told you not to do that.
- You're dead.
Take it easy. All
right, okay, okay.
But you're in my ER now,
so put on the damn coat.
Your new intern?
Resident in-service
exam is Friday.
Practice questions and
instructions are in the packet.
Shouldn't we learn something
before you start testing us?
It's to get a baseline. We'll
re-test you at the end of the year.
Um, is there a makeup
date? Friday's my day off.
I volunteer at Big
Sister/Little Sister.
Yeah, well, I'm post-call, which
means I volunteer to sleep all day.
Well, too bad.
Conference room, 8 a.m.
- Come on, guys.
- Who else is on?
Weaver is on at 12. Until
then, you're in charge.
- What about Morris?
- He just called.
He's running late, he
said start without him.
For his first shift as an
Attending? Did he say why?
I couldn't understand him. It
was windy and the music was loud.
- Ma'am.
- Windy?
Believe or not,
I'm walking on air
I never thought I
could feel so free
Flying away on a
wing and a prayer
Rat-bite kid is in Bed C.
Waiting on a shot of
penicillin and a piece of pizza.
- Oh, the surgeon is in.
- I think I left my badge here.
- Are you nervous?
- No, I'm okay.
- Happy rounding.
- First day, don't let them haze you.
The sidewalk was crooked.
I wanna talk to Johnnie.
You're gonna have
to call them back later.
Look, J.Lo, I got 10
minutes left on my card...
and I ain't signing until
I talk to my attorney.
Don't tell me Johnnie
Cochran's dead.
- Give me a break.
- Let me help.
- It's not heavy.
- They found some bad wiring.
The whole place
is like a tinderbox.
Really? Got a light?
James Anderson, shortness
of breath, history of heart failure.
Gave nitro spray
and 40 of Lasix.
The guy's a chronic CHF'er. Forty
won't do the trick, he needs 80.
Protocol says 40. Not that I'd
expect you to know or give a damn.
Picked him up in the hall of his
apartment. Place had some wild stuff.
- Feather boas, stiletto heels.
- One, two, three.
Sounds like your locker.
What meds is he on?
It's on the paramedic
sheet, which is also part of...
Protocol, right.
I smell a theme.
- Eighty of Lasix.
- Unh.
- Sats suck. GATES:
Must have a bad lead.
He does. Look at this,
it's on his chest hair.
Is that part of the...? What
do you call it, protocol?
Isordil, Bumex, glyburide.
Benzoin for the chest lead.
- Here you go.
All right.
Protonix, Diovan and carvedilol.
Let me help you.
- All right, sats are up.
- Lasix in.
Hey, can you look at me?
- It's good.
- Saved your ass again, Zades.
Hey, where's that famous
sense of humor of yours?
You know, it was
bad enough before.
Now I gotta roll in,
have you play me...
because somebody
gave you a white coat?
- What are you so pissed off about?
- I'm on probation for a month.
Limited shifts, no extra runs,
and one wrong move, I'm finished.
What? Those two drunk guys
outside of Ike's press charges?
No, the bar manager filed a complaint,
so chief's gotta make sure I feel it.
- I didn't hear anything about it.
- Well, of course not, you're Mr. Teflon.
- Only now it's Dr. Teflon.
- It's no big deal.
- What's probation, a month...?
- It's my job, man.
My job.
You know, the one good
thing about you working here:
You may just have to listen to
somebody besides yourself once in a while.
And I can't wait to
see those sparks fly.
I'll catch you later, killer.
Well, he didn't mean
"killer" killer. He meant...
You know... All right,
back to work, everyone.
Barack. Barack Obama.
Don't waste my time, put him on.
Benny, your
neighbor's on the phone.
Something about Jim.
Excuse me.
Triage desk.
Uh, no, I'm here for
someone, James Anderson.
They brought him in
an hour ago, I think.
Triage desk.
Thank you.
- Hello, I...
- Fill out this form, sir.
I'm here to see a patient.
Oh, okay.
Then try this one.
Easy, now. We got
enough patients already.
Charity, I got one for you.
I'm Hope, my name is Hope.
Right, 8-year-old
girl fell off her bike.
Oh, poor little angel.
Hey, think fast.
- Whoa. What's this?
- It's your lucky day.
Residents get to wear
the new transport beeper.
If this thing goes off, I can sign
out my patients and go, right?
Well, if your Attending, i.e. me,
agrees that the patient is critical...
and needs a physician transport,
then, yes, Ray, you may go.
Sweet, I'm gonna go
check the transpo locker.
- Is Dr. Kovac around?
- Hey, how you doing?
I think Dr. K ran upstairs...
but I'm pretty sure I can help
you with anything you need.
You represent this hospital...
and that's how you approach
people asking for help?
Angela? I was
waiting for you upstairs.
I'm sorry, my train was late.
But I had the lovely
opportunity to meet "Dr. Pratt."
Impressive.
- Got a minute?
- Yeah, sure.
What?
Haleh, what the
hell just happened?
I think you got served.
- Greg Pratt, Timmy Rawlins.
- Hey.
He's gonna be filling in for Jerry.
- Really?
In fact, he was Jerry
before Jerry was Jerry.
Wow.
Yeah, back in the mid-'90s.
Got stuck in a rut.
I had to get out.
- Out of the hospital?
- No, out of Chicago.
I lived in the Kalahari for a while,
selling biltong outside of Kakamas.
Then I spent a couple years
mining uranium in the Siberian tundra.
Ran into a misunderstanding in Thailand,
that landed me in the Bangkwang prison.
But most of the '90s is still a blur.
- Wow, sounds rugged.
Hell, I'd take Bangkwang
over ER this time of year.
As you know, them new interns will
mess you up worse than Chinese hash.
Ain't that the truth?
It's about the Curtis Ames case.
Risk Management wants
to meet tomorrow at 9 a.m.
Curtis Ames?
Left-sided paralysis
following an embolic stroke.
You placed a central
line for pneumonia...
and he boarded down
here for three days.
February of '04?
Oh, oh, oh. But I thought
the case had no merit.
Ha. Guy wants his day in court.
But the lawyer said...
It's been a year since my deposition.
- Excuse me.
- Angela from Staff Affairs?
- Ms. Gilliam.
Ms. Gilliam, Dr. Tremons on the
phone, he says his privileges have been...
Tell him the Anesthesia chair
has to keep his ACLS current...
just like every other
physician in this hospital.
Okay. I got you, baby.
Look, malpractice suits are a
waste of time and resources...
but it happens to almost
every doctor at some point.
It doesn't reflect on your
abilities as a physician.
See you tomorrow.
Ultrasound confirmed cholecystitis. Hang
a bag of ertapenem, send her to surgery.
I'll give the nursing report.
Scaphoid fracture,
thumb spica in Bed A.
- Discharge with clinic referral.
- No problem.
This one over here?
Curling iron, upper inner thigh.
Dressing and tetanus, and,
uh, send her on her way.
- How do you even know that?
- Don't ask, don't tell.
Pratt, sign Gates
up for some more.
- The man knows how to clear a bed.
- Really?
Why do I have patients with blank charts
and I haven't heard about your CHF guy?
- He's stable. We're waiting on labs.
- His sats are 91. He's hypoxic.
- That was before oxygen and Lasix.
- What's the EKG show?
Nothing to worry about.
This gentleman's here
for James Anderson.
- You family?
- We're business partners.
My name's Cray. Bennett Cray.
All right. Dr. Gates
can take you in.
- But keep me apprised.
- All right.
We're waiting on
some test results...
but, uh, we could use
information on his medical status.
Yes, I can help with
that. I brought in his meds.
Your, uh, mascara's running.
Oh. It was a long night.
You round twice a day,
5:30 a.m. and 7:30 p.m.
In between, you'll cover
floor patients and consults.
And hopefully scrub
in on a few cases?
Sure.
Neela, this is Jill Connelly and
Ken Maser, your fellow interns.
And this is Dr. Crenshaw.
Sweet urine of a
hairless eunuch.
- Dustin?
- No, I don't think so.
What I asked for was
a freaking ginger ale.
Dustin? Dustin?
Dr. Crenshaw is our
new Chief Resident.
Neela Rasgotra.
Put in two years in the ER, then
defected to become a real doctor.
Wow, it took you that long to figure
out you were wasting your time?
- Oh, I don't think of it that way.
- Really?
And why is that?
I developed clinical
and procedural skills.
I became proficient at ultrasounds,
central lines, chest tubes, cutdowns.
Wow, you know what worries me?
Maybe all of this is gonna
seem too easy. You think?
Think there's a
chance you might be...
Oh, I don't know.
What's the word, um...
bored by what we do up here?
- I don't think so.
- Good.
Good. Then I think I'll
leave you all to it. Bye.
Someone want to explain to
our international prodigy here...
how we do wound rounds?
Mr. Cray.
Doctor.
His oxygen level is up.
He should be waking soon.
Is there any family
he'd like here?
Uh, just me. That's all.
Just the two of us.
We each come from a long
line of homophobes and bigots.
The closet reflex dies hard.
- How long have you two been together?
- It's been over 15 years now.
We found each other late.
He thought no one'd ever love
him, and I'd already resigned myself...
to being a lonely
old drag queen.
In the right light, he looks like
Barbara Stanwyck in The Lady Eve.
Ha. To you, maybe.
Now I look more
like Mrs. Doubtfire.
I'll let you two talk, and, uh, I'll be
back as soon as I know anything, okay?
Hey, Luka, can you sign a wrist
x-ray order for the Obama lady?
Sure.
I hear the baby's doing well.
- He's starting to hold his head up.
- Oh, that's great.
We never got to talk about
everything that happened.
It's not your fault, Sam.
If it wasn't for me...
If it wasn't for
you, I'd be dead.
How is everything?
It's good. You
know, pretty good.
I, uh...
Alex is seeing this shrink
lady, but he's not really into it.
- He likes to keep everything bottled up.
- I meant with you.
I'm fine. Really.
You want me to
try talking to Alex?
No, you've got enough
on your plate, uh...
- but thank you.
- Sam, hey.
Just don't beat yourself up.
You did what you had
to do. It was self-defense.
Born in a poor village
in central Guatemala...
Soledad Guttierrez is an immigrant
who works cleaning houses.
She's had a hard time
adjusting to life in the U.S.
Wow, you really bonded with her.
Felicity, hurry up and
get to the point, will you?
Soledad is worried every day and
prays all the time for her husband...
and 4-year-old son back
in their hometown of...
"Chichicastenango."
Oh, sure, I got down to Chichi for
el Día de los Muertos back in '96.
She's thorough,
there's no denying that.
But she's getting older and might not...
- Look, look, look.
I don't need her
whole life story.
Why is she in the ER today?
Well, she had a great uncle
who died of a heart attack.
His wife and children
were left without anyone...
so they had to move
in with her parents...
All right, stop, stop, stop.
What brought her to the ER?
Her heart. It's her heart.
Good, so do you
think it's an MI?
Pericarditis? Dysrhythmia?
Well, she's been unable
to find a suitable church...
so I believe that she feels
so alone in this world...
that her heart is aching for
her family and her homeland.
Okay, okay, well, diagnostically,
what you just said is nothing.
- Need a hand here.
- Group home resident, 22 years old.
Release me, you
merchants of destruction!
- You need to stay in bed.
- Morris.
Good to see you.
Glad you could make it.
Oh, the pleasure's all mine.
The home thinks he might
have ingested something.
All right, 10 of
Haldol, 2 of Ativan I.M.
Oh, this is Rodney
King all over again.
- Hey, no pictures in here.
- You ain't fooling nobody.
- Harriet, get back to your bed.
- Obama gonna see this.
How you feeling, Mr. Anderson?
Oh, better.
Tell him he can go.
He's got a show tonight.
We're having a fundraiser for
the Chicago HIV/AIDS Coalition.
And I don't want you
missing it on account of me.
He never misses a show.
Fine. Listen, we
have some test results.
Good news is you did
not have a heart attack.
- Oh, thank God.
- But you're not making urine...
which means your kidneys aren't
working, so you'll have to go on dialysis.
- I don't think so.
- Jim.
- It's pretty urgent.
- I've been to enough doctors already.
Had enough tubes and
machines and treatments.
No, I'm not gonna do it, don't ask me.
- It's okay, Jim.
It's okay.
So, what else can we try?
What are his other options?
His options?
Well, dying. Very soon.
No, it's enough already.
Jim, there's no choice.
Dialysis can substantially
prolong your life.
I already got the bad
heart. I'm sick of being sick.
I'm not gonna be some
broken-down cripple.
You're tired, I know that.
- But remember what we always said?
- It's enough.
- Choose more life.
- Whatever's gonna happen.
- No matter what, remember? More life.
- I don't wanna do this to you.
You promised.
Okay.
But you gotta do
something for me.
Call Lorraine and tell
her what's going on.
- Jim.
- Call her.
Just tell her to bring the boy.
I wanna see him.
It's not a good idea.
Don't get into it all.
Don't try to explain it.
Just tell her I wanna see them.
It's been too long.
Please, Benny.
You got to do it.
All right.
His sister and her son.
I've never met them.
So dialysis?
Yeah, let's get him
up as soon as we can.
I'll make the call.
Hmm. He was already 50
by the time he figured it out.
He wanted to tell his family,
but they shut him down.
So he just left.
Disappeared one day.
Found me.
No openings now, but I told
them we could start him down here.
His serum K level is still high.
All right, amp of bicarb, 25 grams
of D50, 10 units of regular insulin.
- May I use that phone?
- Sure.
There's one down the
hall if you want privacy.
Thank you.
Oh, excuse me.
Gates, Rheumatology came
down on the polymyositis patient.
- No H and P on the chart.
- Didn't get to it yet.
No, that's not good
enough. Sam, you got this?
You come with me. - All right.
Give me an ETA on the dialysis.
I got enough problems without
you pissing off other departments...
by not keeping
current on your charts.
- Trying to use my time well.
- Not enough. Get that up-to-date.
- Thank God, someone who understands.
- Rough morning, Greg?
I'm glad to have you.
Will you come check
my vertical mattress?
I think I everted
the edges too much.
- Not until he listens to my bronchiolytic.
- Did you try a neb?
Don't worry, I'll show you.
I'm with Dr. Pratt today.
Okay.
I need to present my
barbell-on-the-toe guy.
I can help you with that.
Hey, guys, this is the esteemed
Dr. Weaver in the house, okay?
So take advantage.
Present to her.
Soak up all her
decades of experience.
Decades? What am I, a fossil?
All right, go run and hide.
We'll be there in a minute.
You know what? I'm fine.
I'll push charts, help
clear some beds.
- I hope this isn't awkward.
- What?
- That you and I are equals now?
- I guess.
Hector Rodriguez, 38.
Found on the sidewalk.
Hey, there's Tony. Tony, man.
- Cue Ball, what are you doing here?
- Some misunderstanding.
- History of ETOH.
- We know.
- Did you vomit any blood?
- Not this time.
I was just sleeping and
some skank called 911.
Where do you want him?
- Did you fall?
- Oh, no, no. That's old.
- A junkie rolled me weeks ago.
- Yeah, occupational hazard.
Hope, get this dude to Exam 3.
- I got him. I know him.
- Look for signs of occult trauma.
- Yes, sir, Dr. Pratt.
- I can get him.
You finish that.
Is that the bleeding
heart of Jesus?
Sure is.
Isn't God great?
You ain't so bad
yourself, honey.
There were no open spots upstairs,
so we're starting him on dialysis here.
Is that Uncle Jimmy in there?
Hello, uh, Lorraine?
You're the man I
talked to on the phone?
Bennett Cray.
My brother, Harold,
and my son, Brian.
James asked you to call us?
He wanted to see his family.
Now?
Like this?
It's par for the
course, I guess.
He's having ectopy. Runs of six.
Damn it. Get Gates and Pratt
in here. His K's going up again.
Ejection fraction is 10 percent.
What does that mean?
It means his heart's not
pumping well enough.
- He have an advanced directive?
- You mean like a DNR?
No, I talked to the
other doctor about this.
Well, why are you
asking about a DNR?
We need to know how
far he'd want us to go.
- Whatever you can.
- We knew he was sick...
I talked to him, he said he was
having problems with his diabetes...
and some trouble with
his congestive something.
He called you?
Yeah, in June, when I graduated.
What are his chances?
Well, it's possible if we put him on
dialysis, avert a cardiac incident...
Can he take all that?
He's very resilient.
- He's been through a lot.
- He's been sick for years.
He's not the type to wanna
be kept alive on machines.
Well, your brother and I
have discussed these matters.
We need a few
minutes to figure this out.
- Sure.
- Maybe I can be of some help.
Jim and I are good friends. We've
been together for quite a while now.
Thank you, this
is a family matter.
We appreciate all you've done.
We'd like some privacy now.
Oh, yes, all right,
I'll just step outside.
QRS complex is widening.
Ready to start the run.
- Wait a minute. Hold on.
Sam?
Where's Gates, and
why is this chart blank?
He goes fast. He probably
fills out the paperwork later.
- You got this guy's meds in your notes?
- Yeah.
Okay.
Amp of calcium chloride.
- We doing this?
- Yeah, in a minute.
Let me give him calcium
to stabilize his heart.
Once we do, we'll
figure out what's next.
Okay.
Hey, Haleh?
Pass me a head sheet and Vicodin?
Get him started on something for the pain.
Sorry, we got rid of head
sheets about a year ago...
and we're not allowed to dispense
meds from the ER anymore.
What's a patient supposed to
do if they can't get to a pharmacy?
You are preaching to the choir, sister.
I liked it better when you ran the joint.
Charged. Clear.
Still V-fib. Resuming
compressions.
- What happened?
- Amp of epi.
Why isn't he dialyzed?
QRS widened. Gave him
calcium, and now he's crashing.
Is my uncle dying?
What's that alarm?
It's his meds. He gets afternoon
doses of glyburide, Lasix and didge.
What?
- Did you say didge?
- Digoxin, 0.25 milligrams.
It's right here.
Can everybody step back for a
minute while we work on him, please?
Charge to 360 again.
You help my brother
with his medication?
Sometimes, yes.
No one said didge.
You showed me Diovan.
- That's what I was told.
- By who, the paramedic?
What does Zadro's sheet say?
Digoxin.
- You didn't look at his med bottles?
- We didn't have them yet.
He has high levels of intracellular
calcium from the didge...
and I pushed more,
enough to stop his heart.
Why? Because you couldn't slow
down enough to read the med sheet right.
Can you tell me what's going on?
The drugs we gave him to treat
his QRS has irritated his heart.
Clear. Clear.
No change.
Uh, so, what now?
What else can we do?
Hey, what about Digibind?
Depends on his DNR status.
Have you all come to a decision?
We've decided it's enough now.
It's time to let him go.
- What? No.
- Our brother's an old man.
- He's been sick for a long time.
- No.
- He wants to fight.
- He's got no one.
He has friends.
A support system.
And who's gonna
take care of him?
- You?
- I always have.
We're his blood.
We don't think he'd wanna
suffer through all this.
You don't know that.
You don't know him.
- But I do.
- And that was his choice, not ours.
I love him.
I asked you once politely to go.
You have no part in this.
We can treat your brother with
Digibind. It'll give him a fighting chance.
He's been in arrest for seven
minutes. His heart isn't salvageable.
I'm sorry, Mr. Cray, but if
this is what his family wants...
Please, wait.
We'll continue CPR as long as there's
hope for a meaningful recovery, but...
You can all come closer
if you'd like to be with him.
Call it in five minutes.
Excuse me.
I'll be right back, okay?
Hey, we caused this to happen.
No, you caused this to happen.
- So give me a shot at fixing it.
- You're never gonna save him.
The family are not the
caretakers. That man is.
No living will, no durable
power. Go with blood relatives.
We have a chance. This
is a teaching hospital.
- Teach me.
- Oh, you wanna learn.
Okay, well, here you
go. That man's gonna die.
That's what needs to happen right
now, so forget about the Digibind.
Lidocaine, one more round of epi,
and then you can pronounce him.
Understood?
You need a break?
Sure.
All right, a hundred
of lidocaine.
Get ready for some more epi.
And, uh...
- Ten vials of Digibind.
- Wait. I thought the other doctor said...
Your brother expressed a clear
desire for resuscitation earlier.
This is a fixable condition.
We're gonna give it a go.
- Did you discuss this with Pratt?
- Yes, we discussed it.
Am I going blind?
Oh, bless your heart.
First, check the intraocular
pressure with a Tono-Pen.
Um, I'm not sure
how to use that.
All right, I'll be right back.
This is interesting.
So how's the new intern doing?
She's very, uh, devoted.
Diligent, inquisitive, likes
to discover new things.
All attributes I like
in a newbie. Unh.
God, you're disgusting.
- Who left this here?
- Ray.
Whoa. If I get a page, I got less
than five minutes to get on the roof.
- Where's the Tono-Pen?
- Oh, had two stolen, wound up on eBay.
JAY-CO makes us
lock everything up now.
Syringes, eye drops,
even guaiac developer.
Only Attendings get a key.
I am an Attending.
Make sure you
check under the hood.
Ow!
Hey, look, is there any rule
about desk clerks dating doctors?
Shut up, not-Jerry. I got dibs.
Oh, sweet. There's a
pile-up in Northbrook.
I am so out of here.
Let's see what we got.
- Sinus tach at 110.
- Got a pulse with that?
- Strong carotid.
- Excellent.
Cycle the dynamap.
We got him back for now.
Jimmy.
I'm right here, Jimmy.
BP's 105/62.
That's good enough for dialysis.
Get the tech back down here.
Mr. Cray? There are
two friends of yours here.
Oh, would you tell them
I'll be out in a minute?
Uh, they work with us.
Our brother was a lot more
screwed up than we realized.
I'm sorry he never told you.
Oh, we knew he was
an oddball, antisocial.
We thought he just fell into some sad,
lonely life. We never realized he was a...
Degenerate. LORRAINE: Harold.
He's not a degenerate.
His life hasn't been a waste. I know
it'd be easier for you to believe that.
He lied to us for years.
Well, he didn't want to.
He didn't see any other way.
You need to go now.
I'm not going anywhere.
You wanna take
care of him? Fine.
It doesn't have to be like this.
We need another doc.
This guy is crashing.
All right, call for a vent, 100
percent, AC 14, tidal volume, 600.
Yo, Cue Ball, what's up?
- Oh, that didn't sound good.
- Pressure dropped to 80.
All right, normal saline,
wide open, 5-liter O2.
What is she doing?
I think it's the 23rd Psalm.
He doesn't have a line. - Why?
Will you stop that, please?
His vitals were stable, crit's 32.
His only complaint was shoulder pain.
- The x-ray was negative...
- Did you say shoulder pain?
- Yeah.
- Type and cross four units.
What happened?
Alcoholic with distant trauma history
presents shoulder pain and hypotension.
Prep belly for ultrasound.
Hey there. ABBY: Hey.
I thought you said
you were coming alone.
Oh, come on, it's
me, Uncle Archie.
Oh, he's so cute.
He looks more like Kovac.
They usually look more like
the father in the beginning.
It's nature's way of
making sure Daddy...
doesn't get insecure
and club us to death.
Can I hold him? Sure,
he wants me to hold him.
Whoop, a little spit-up there.
No problem. Oh, a little bit more.
I missed this part with my kids.
Oh, I'm so happy to see you.
I was going crazy so I
thought I'd take a walk.
I tried paging you.
How's surgery?
Oh, I thought it would be
nice to get back to work...
and distract
myself from stuff...
but my new chief is such a
rectal tissue. It's all misery.
Okay, you better take
him. It's starting to get gross.
- Thanks a lot, Morris.
- Here.
Here you go.
So are you loving motherhood?
Yeah, uh, it's bizarre.
- Sore nipples?
- Shut up.
- Oh, I think he's hungry.
- Yeah, maybe.
- Oh, damn it, I've gotta get back.
- Well, thank you for coming.
Well, it's very nice
to see you. Oh.
And nice to see you.
And, uh, call me if
you need anything.
- Okay, I'll be back to work next month.
- Bye.
Okay, I think I
need to feed him.
Yeah, I'm down with that.
Breast-feeding is a natural
thing. Nothing to be ashamed of.
- You're not sneaking a peek at my tits.
- Okay.
- Come on, Mr. Rodriguez, wake up.
- Got a 14-gauge in the right wrist.
You got a 14-gauge in? You're
gonna have to teach me that one.
This the ruptured spleen?
Foley's in.
Who's touching my dick?
Not me. That was only
one time, and I was lonely.
It's a catheter, Mr. Rodriguez.
Abdomen is flat.
Pressure's up to 100 systolic.
Hey, angel face.
What's going on?
Yeah, what is going on? I
thought we were going upstairs...
Dr. Gates discovered that
there was internal bleeding.
- Based on Kerr's sign.
- You caught that?
That's my boy.
Everybody knows you be tripping
off some phat laced powder...
Tony's the one you
want pushing that Narcan.
High praise indeed.
Check him out now
with his fancy M.D.
Chest sounds clear.
- What are you doing?
- Examining him.
It's a little crowded. Step
back, write up the H and P.
- Well, I can't do that un...
- I will dictate to you.
Chest clear.
Cardiac S1, S2 without
murmur, rub or gallop.
Am I going too fast for you?
Hey, I heard Faith's
guy was crashing.
Her name is Hope.
I think it's okay.
Good, well, we're done in
there. You guys called it?
Uh, no, actually,
the Digibind worked.
- Neela, check a quick rectal.
- I have to do the rectal exam?
Gates, what part of "no
Digibind" did you not get?
It worked. PRATT: So what?
You got his heart back,
but his brain is shot.
Now he'll be comatose for
three weeks until his organs fail.
- You don't know that for sure.
- What did you just say to me?
I'm an intern, not an
idiot. Been patching up...
Then maybe next time, you'll know the
difference between Diovan and didge.
If what I'm told doesn't make
sense to me, you got that?
I've been in this ER for five years
working my way up as an Attending...
so if you think that you're gonna
spout some crap like that to me...
then we got a lot
more to talk about.
Now get the hell out.
Okay, I was out of line. Can
I check the rapid infuser...?
- Get out of here.
- I'm working.
Not anymore.
- Shift's over.
- Oh, yeah?
- Pressure's stable.
- O.R. is ready.
Sats 92 on 4 liters.
Stool is brown, guaiac negative.
- Good.
Let's squeeze in two units,
portable monitor, let's move him up.
Thank you, Jesus.
I thought you were gone.
Working on my charts.
Listen, I know I made a mistake, but that
guy would have needed calcium anyway.
If I had known about the didge,
I'd have used a lower dose.
- Pushed it very slowly.
- I said I was wrong.
What do you want from me?
How about, "I won't ever
again flat-out disregard...
something you tell
me to do or not do"?
He would have
wanted the Digibind.
- So what?
- So what? That's gotta matter.
It was a judgment call
that wasn't yours to make.
If you can't give weight to my judgment
on a patient that I've been treating...
- What?
- No.
No, no, no, go ahead.
Finish the sentence.
Nope.
Yeah.
From now on, you
chart as you go.
No more of this saving the
paperwork for the end of the day.
And next time you don't
do what I tell you to do...
or any other
Attending tells you...
you're gonna find yourself getting
bum rushed right out of this program.
- I was wrong from your point of view...
- From my point of view?
Because of the Digibind,
that guy has a chance.
You really think that you saved
him? Is that what you think?
Oh, then he's gotta
have a corneal reflex.
- No.
- Cold calorics?
Absent.
And negative doll's eyes, right?
That means no
sign of brain activity.
No chance for recovery.
So as your, uh, favorite new mentor,
let me just say, great save, Dr. Gates.
Hey.
How's your first day going?
Guy comes in with a few scrapes,
ends up with a splenectomy.
Well, sounds like a good case.
Yeah, it does sound like one.
I wouldn't know, because
Dr. Crenshaw won't let me scrub in.
Sent me to do dressing changes.
Yeah, he's a stern
taskmaster, that Dusty.
I'm an intern, Lucien.
Nurses do wound changes.
You know what? That's his call.
You assured me this
would be a step up.
Two months ago, I was harvesting
saphenous veins for a CABG procedure.
- Now I can't hold a retractor?
- It's only the first day.
Why recruit me if you won't
allow me to do anything?
He's tough, I know that,
but his methods work.
He needs to break you down to
un-learn you of your bad habits.
What am I, a pony?
I don't need to be broken.
I'm not gonna learn or un-learn
anything by standing out in the hall.
Neela, you're in a
different culture now.
This is how we shake the ER out of
you and build you up again as a surgeon.
Well, does it have
to be so humiliating?
No, it's just much
more effective that way.
Oh.
- I was wondering where you went.
- Yeah, I was taken off the case.
Yes, I thought I
detected some tension.
- Where are the Andersons?
- Oh, they won't stay as long as I'm here.
Even Brian.
Well, it's nice
your friends came.
They want me to go to the club.
Do the show.
Well, they're gonna move him to ICU.
We won't know anything for 24 hours.
Maybe you should go.
He's not coming
back from this, is he?
- There's something I should tell you...
- No.
You made a mistake, got
something wrong about the didge.
It contributed to
his heart problems.
I've been around hospitals
long enough to get that much.
- I'm so sorry.
- No.
You treated him well.
Both of us.
We appreciate it.
Maybe they were right.
Maybe he was ready.
This has been
coming for a long time.
But here's the thing.
As bad as it all may sound,
I belong to a rare tribe...
constitutionally incapable
of giving up on fantasy.
If I can get up like a lady and
sell a torch song to a crowd...
then I sure as hell can
hold onto the hope...
that maybe, somehow...
Jimmy's gonna be okay.
You make me wish
I were a drag queen.
No.
We are all liars,
just like they said.
The makeup, the
wig, the padded dress.
All a beautiful lie
we tell ourselves.
But it makes us feel better.
Nothing wrong with that.
No, nothing at all.
Thank you, doctor.
Hope, impacted cerumen
needs a washout in 1...
and migraine lady
needs an H and P...
The abridged version, please.
- -in Curtain 4.
Oh, and hey, uh, you know,
once we're done here...
maybe we could go over
some procedures and stuff.
Help orient you.
Maybe over dinner?
You're asking me out?
No, no, I mean, not exactly.
I mean, you know, yeah.
Have you accepted
Jesus in your life?
Jesus in Accounting or...?
Oh, yeah, well, sure, yeah.
I mean, I've thought about it.
- You haven't, have you?
- Yes, yes, I have.
Jesus is totally cool.
I mean, to me, anyway.
You should come to my Bible group
sometime. I think you'd really like it.
Bible group?
- Okay.
- Great.
The next one's Wednesday night.
Bible group.
That's hot, right?
Trust me, carrot boy, you ain't
anywhere near tapping that.
You know, if there's
anything you need...
I mean, if I can help make
your adjustment smoother.
- In any way.
- I'll let you know.
Um, things are a bit
complicated right now.
Yeah, for me too.
- But maybe we can get some...?
- Coffee?
- Coffee or something?
- Yeah.
- Sometime?
- Coffee would be good.
Okay, then.
- Well...
- Good night.
- Hey, kiddo.
- Hey, Mom.
I, uh, talked to
Dr. Alice today.
She said you were quiet.
Do you not like her?
Scoot.
Now, you've been through a
lot, you know. We both have.
I just wanted you
to have her to talk to.
- I can't.
- Yeah, you can.
- That's what she's there for.
- No, Mom, I can't.
I saw.
You know, Dad on the
ground, just sleeping.
I saw what you did.
Did you remember the wine?
I knew there was a
reason I let you live here.
So were you the best one there?
How many people did you save?
Did you rock?
You're nobody till
somebody loves you
somebody cares
You may be king You may
possess the world and it's gold
But gold won't bring you
happiness When you're growing old
The world still is the
same You'll never change it
As long as the stars shine above
You're nobody till
somebody loves you
So find yourself somebody
Get yourself somebody
Find yourself somebody to love