Hi, kids.
Mommy, look what I made.
Oh, wow.
It's a farmer and a
cow and some horses.
It's beautiful.
It's for Ted's office.
Oh, he's gonna love it. And
it'd be nice if you called him Dad.
Give me a big hug.
Secret is the Haas avocados. I
can e-mail you the recipe if you want.
It's the third time they've
changed plans since Friday.
These idiots think you can just add a
14th floor and the mayor won't notice.
And I thought turning the garage
into a nursery was complicated.
Any luck on your end yet?
Not for lack of trying.
Ted.
Come on. Come on, Margo!
I have to go tell a
client he's an idiot.
Go kick some ass.
I have to take Stella to karate by
3:00 and a birthday party at Julia's after.
You okay?
Yeah. I'll be back. Just
make sure she's dressed.
Honey! Honey!
He's actually on time.
He's six minutes early.
Something's happened. I'm on it.
Good morning, Jimmy.
Anybody die while I was gone?
Did you iron your shirt?
I thought about shaving.
Couldn't find a razor.
What the hell
happened in Baltimore?
Sorry, chief.
Never kiss and tell.
I think you just did.
There's no such
thing as "just a kiss."
Did you iron your shirt?
Everybody's flash today.
Has she left Mark?
Is she going to?
I think I can hear
cancer kids calling.
Are you planning on
asking her to leave Mark?
Not sure. Cameron
keeps my calendar.
Hey. This is a big
deal. This is an affair.
Have you even talked to Stacy
about what the hell this means?
Didn't have a lot of time for
talking, if you know what I mean.
Great. Breaking up a marriage.
Fertile ground for high comedy.
We need to talk about this.
Gosh, wish I could. How did
the HIV test go? You study up?
I rescheduled for this
afternoon. We have a new patient.
Thirty-four-year-old
female, movement disorder.
Movement disorder? Fascinating.
This isn't just gonna go away.
No. But maybe you will.
Probably suffered head
trauma in the car accident.
Trauma leads to the dyskinesia.
According to her husband,
the flailing started before
she got anywhere near that car.
What does the
flailing look like?
Her arms spasm uncontrollably
and there's a mild facial twitch.
Demonstration?
You wanna know what it
looks like, go see the patient.
Oh, snarky. Was he like this
the whole time I was gone?
The patient's been on a fertility
regimen for the last 13 months.
Excess estrogen in the
system could explain...
Who finished the
animal crackers?
Sudden movement disorder
could be a symptom of Huntington's.
If you finish something, don't just
put back the empty box, throw it out.
Huntington's takes
a day to confirm.
We should put her on tamoxifen
in case it is the fertility meds,
counteract the estrogen.
That's a great idea if
you wanna kill her baby.
Movement disorder can
present in the first trimester.
She's not pregnant.
Peeing on a stick is only 99%
accurate. Get a real pregnancy test.
You know, the one with the blood
and the hormones and the rabbit.
Oh, I'm sorry,
it's still your limo.
What do you say, Miss Daisy?
Whatever you want.
Lame duck's done quacking.
You quack, people shoot at you.
Cuddy just put me here
to make you miserable.
Another two days, you can go
back to making yourself miserable.
Okay, get an MRI. See if it's
in her head or in her uterus.
You're gonna want
to paralyze her.
You run tests on a flailer,
somebody's gonna lose an eye.
Sorry. You think I'm pregnant?
We need to find out for sure.
Would all this go away
once she delivered?
It could also be neurological.
We need to get an MRI.
Can she do that
if she's pregnant?
The risk to the fetus
is extremely low.
But there is a risk.
I don't think we should
do it until we're sure.
Ted, I think you should
take Stella home.
I wanna stay here.
We should be with you.
You should take
her out of the room.
We're gonna temporarily
stop Margo's spasms.
You can do that? Vecuronium.
It's a paralytic. Essentially cuts
off the brain from the muscles.
Don't worry. Your
mom will be just fine.
It'll make running
the tests easier,
and it won't be dangerous for
the baby if you are pregnant.
Let's go, Stella.
I want to go with Mommy.
We'll be just outside, okay? We
gotta let the doctors get her better.
All right? It's okay, sweetie.
Love you. Love you.
Your vitals will be
watched closely.
I'm gonna close your lids
so your eyes don't dry out.
Just try to relax.
What the hell did you do?
Were you just cold and lonely?
Of course he told you.
He's an eight-year-old boy.
Hey, you're the
one who kissed him.
Why are you so
worked up over this?
Because you're married.
Not to you.
This is none of your business.
The last time you left, I was the
one stuck picking up the pieces.
Oh, right. He cried himself to sleep
every night. That so sounds like him.
He's been pining for five years.
You're being dramatic.
No. Actually, I'm underplaying.
This is me being restrained.
It was one kiss. Are you
being intentionally thick?
This was not just
a one-night stand.
You can't toy with him.
I'm not.
He's probably toying with
me. I don't know what I'm doing.
Oh, boy.
Welcome back to the world.
You're off the vecuronium.
Could you wiggle
your toes for me?
The MRI was clear. Whatever
this is, isn't in your brain.
MRI. So I'm not pregnant?
I'm sorry.
So what do we do next?
Well, it could be a variety of things,
some treatable, others more serious.
Open up.
I'm gonna run a genetic
test for Huntington's.
That one of the more
serious ones? Yeah.
It's also possible that this is just a
symptom of the fertility treatments.
And now that we know you're not pregnant,
we're gonna start you on tamoxifen
to counteract the estrogen.
Will that undo all the
fertility treatments?
For the time being,
yeah. But it could cure you.
You can start trying again
once we get you healthy.
Damn it!
The spasms are gonna get worse
now that the vecuronium is wearing off.
What are you so scared of?
I'm still your mother.
I'm just a little sick.
Why did you even bring her here?
I told you to leave her at home.
Hypervigilance,
sudden irritability.
Symptomatic of lunch with Cuddy?
The patient now
defines Huntington's.
Then what do you need me for?
Start her on Huntington's meds.
Before we get her
test results back?
We start her on valproic
acid, it could destroy her liver.
Could stroke. If we wait,
she could progress
to full-blown psychosis,
and then her kid will never
get the chance to say goodbye.
Wanna tell the
class how that feels?
Huntington's patients don't
progress to psychosis in a day.
She went from zero to
60 in world record time.
Indicating it might be something
other than Huntington's.
We got a problem.
Stay away from me!
Where's my daughter?
What's happening? She's
having a psychotic break.
No! She is not yours!
What do you want with her?
Calm down! TED: Honey.
Margo, you're
gonna hurt someone.
No.
Push two milligrams of Ativan.
I want my daughter!
She's not yours! I want my
daughter! No more experiments!
No!
How can her Huntington's
test be negative?
All the signs are there.
Movement disorder, psychosis.
It should be Huntington's.
Yeah. It would certainly
make your job easier.
Well, good news for Margo, it's
not Huntington's. Bad news for us,
her psychotic break
eliminates fertility meds.
Which means we have no
idea what's wrong with her.
We give you so much,
and you give us so little.
You know, the patient is prime age to
develop spontaneous schizophrenia.
Almost impossible. No
family history of mental illness.
How about toxins?
None of her family members are sick.
Nobody at her office, her volunteer group,
kid's classes, and
PTA members, all fine.
So she raises a daughter, runs a
business, she does charity work,
she volunteers at
school, attends PTA.
What makes Mommy run?
You're thinking drugs? Cocaine.
Explains the psychosis
and the flailing.
And the uncanny ability to bring
home the bacon, fry it up in a pan,
and never ever let Teddy
forget that he's a man.
I'll go look for her stash.
Take Foreman.
There's gotta be a
reason for the stereotype.
I know you're in there.
I can hear you caring.
The door was locked.
It means I didn't
wanna see anyone.
High school reunion?
It's for a patient.
She can't roll.
Hey, I locked that door, too.
Paranoia. Must
be the good stuff.
Times like these, I
wish I had cancer.
So what did she say?
It depends. What did you do,
and who are we talking about?
We both know that as soon
as we talked, you ran to Stacy
so you could gossip and giggle.
I need to know what she said.
I have a crazy idea. Why
don't you go talk to her?
Because my bestest buddy
says that could lead to trouble.
She sounds confused,
but I don't think she is.
I think she's waiting for you to do
something, show her you're serious.
Wow.
It's a big jump from "infidelity
is morally wrong" to "do her."
I didn't say "do her."
I said do something.
What exactly did she say?
She didn't say it was a mistake.
She's not gonna leave Mark
in the middle of his rehab.
Too much guilt.
She left you.
Harsh toke, dude.
House.
Killjoy.
I could've covered this. You
need to get that test today.
I wish you guys would remember
my birthday instead of my HIV test.
Forgive us for being
concerned. I got a bet with House.
He says you're too scared to
get it. I say you're too anal not to.
I'll cut you in.
That was a colossal waste.
Who would've known?
Searching a high-end
family home for illicit
narcotics was such
an obvious choice.
Working moms
practically live in their cars.
Little bump on the run.
You were a car thief, right?
Mama's little helper.
House, Ritalin.
Cocaine with a PG rating.
Prescribed to her daughter.
Mommy does everything for her family
these days, even swallows their pills.
It's possible the kid's
meds are the kid's meds.
Pop enough Ritalin, it
can explain everything.
Well, Ritalin maybe explains
some tics, some involuntary...
No, case reports
have referred to chorea.
She's been cut off from her
stash, so the flailing's tapered off,
the psychosis hasn't
returned. It's perfect.
Tox screen will confirm that.
Half-life's 12 hours. Drugs
will be out of her system.
We're done. Get rid
of her. We're not done.
We have to confirm the diagnosis before
we send her home to die of something else.
Oh, yes. The power tastes
so sweet. You just can't resist.
You're like a diabetic
at the ice cream counter.
You wanna say no, but you
need that chocolaty goodness.
Yeah, well, I'm still
signing the charts.
So until tomorrow, you're
not allowed to kill anyone.
Wuss.
We've asked her three
times if she's on any meds.
So we don't ask her.
Candy striper.
So, you like dogs?
That's not a dog.
Smart kid.
Are you always
such a good little girl,
or does Mommy sometimes say you're
the reason she needs a double martini?
Who are you? Over here,
kiddo. I'm talking to you. Focus.
Must be because
you're off your meds.
Who are you?
Doctor and candy striper.
She's not on any medication.
Well, that's strange.
'Cause this bottle has her name on it.
And I think these are medical pills inside.
What's he talking about?
The doctor prescribed Stella...
A few months ago.
I never told you about it,
because I never gave her any.
That's funny, 'cause
the bottle's almost empty.
You missed a couple
of days. Take five.
Stop. Why? Unless
they're not hers.
You need some water, sweetie?
I'm not taking Ritalin.
Come on. All the
cool moms are doing it.
And tox screen
says you're cool, too.
You were on drugs
while taking care of Stella?
I'm sorry, Ted.
It's a cafeteria menu.
It should take a couple
hours to process her.
Then you can take her
home and divorce her.
Working late?
Or are you just avoiding Mark?
It was one kiss, Greg.
So far. I'm planning
on keeping a chart.
I'm moving back to
Short Hills. I think it's time.
You're leaving?
It was never meant to be permanent,
and now that Mark's getting better...
Yeah, much better.
Except for the
whole walking thing.
He needs to get back to work.
Right.
Saving the next generation from
making bad choices about acne cream.
You're running away because
the kiss meant something.
I'm not running
away. I'm going home.
With Mark.
I love Mark.
You love me more.
I don't want you to leave.
Are we okay?
I'm sorry.
Let's just get you home.
That's a good idea.
Mommy! Hey!
Call a code! What's
wrong, Mommy?
What's going on?
This better be important.
You've gotta come
back in. No, I don't.
Margo's stable,
but... Oh, my God.
Well, I'll be right there.
She had a stroke.
Perfect.
Gotta go back to work.
Right now?
Well...
Patient's stable. Could
maybe wait a half-hour.
He should have been
here 20 minutes ago.
Doubt if he makes it at all.
I saw him leave with Stacy.
He was probably just
walking her to her car.
Oh, yeah. That
sounds like House.
He's not an idiot. He's not gonna
hook up with a married woman.
I hope he is getting some.
Maybe he'll mellow out.
What took you so
long? It's midnight.
Traffic. Cinco de Mayo.
You owe me $100.
You didn't take the test?
Fear trumps anal every time.
It's not a big deal. I had the
viral load and antibody test.
It's 99.9% that I
don't have HIV.
And if you have the test, and it's
negative, you gain a tenth of a point.
But if it's positive you
lose nearly 100, right?
No arrhythmia, so Ritalin
isn't the big problem.
Something else is going on.
Fine, let's play doctors.
I removed the clot
which caused the stroke.
Problem is, we don't
know where it came from.
Did ultrasounds of her
heart, arms and legs. All clear.
Could be a protein C deficiency.
Wouldn't explain the
movement disorder.
Nothing explains everything.
What if it's a crime syndicate?
Let's say Ritalin and the
fertility meds plotted a caper.
Ritalin takes care of
the psychosis, the flailing.
I still don't think Ritalin...
Fertility meds are
competitive by nature.
They had to do something bigger,
something really unexpected.
Fertility treatments have been
known to cause endometrial cancer.
Which could cause clots, which
could have caused her to stroke.
So ultrasound her
uterus this time.
See if there's something growing in there
that doesn't look adorable in a onesie.
Cameron. I love you.
You'll get your test
results tomorrow.
The prescription for
my heart condition.
A bit on the cheesy side.
I was trying for romantic.
Still fits.
Did you tell Mark?
I told him I had to work late.
You gonna tell him?
How am I gonna tell him?
Still working on that
phrasing. How about,
"You know all the stuff you were worried
about when we first came here, honey?
"You were right."
Pithy.
Everything's easy when you
don't care if you hurt anyone.
You already did
the hurting part.
He just doesn't know it yet. If
I never tell him, it'll never hurt.
I want not to love
Mark. I wanna hate you.
I want all of this to
be simple, but it's not.
You can either
have a life with me,
or you can have a life with him.
It can't be both.
It's not easy, but it is simple.
No endometrial
thickening. No masses.
No cancer.
She's on fertility treatments.
She had a blood clot. It's there.
Millions of women are on fertility
treatments and they don't get cancer.
Right. They get babies.
She had a blood
clot and a stroke.
She'll get another one and probably
die, if we don't find that tumor.
Do an endometrial biopsy.
Biopsy's painful and unnecessary.
We just did an ultrasound.
What?
If you have a personal
issue that's interfering with...
What are we waiting for?
Your four weeks just expired.
Your reign of terror is over.
Mine has just begun.
Now go stick a needle up her
hoo-hoo and find that cancer.
"Hoo-hoo"?
He went to Hopkins.
Pergasaurus has got 1,500 horsepower
blown and injected with alcohol.
Yeah, that baby really moves.
Oh, yeah, and the transmission,
two-speed Powerglide.
Suspension...
What are you watching?
TV.
What are you doing here?
Ted's with my mom. He
asked the nurse to watch me.
What nurse?
She's not really watching me.
I got that.
Do you still have the balloons?
No.
Do you wanna play something?
Nope.
When can Mommy come home?
Don't know.
What's wrong with your foot?
War wound.
Does it hurt?
Every day.
Is that why you're so sad?
Oh, aren't you adorable?
I'm not sad, I'm
complicated. Chicks dig that.
One day you'll understand.
That's what my parents say when
they don't want me to know something.
They say that a lot?
Only when they're talking
about making babies and stuff.
When you catch them fighting?
They don't fight.
Not ever?
People who love
each other don't fight.
Right. Forgot that.
What floor was that nurse
on who was watching you?
Two.
Good talk.
At your age, the type of uterine cancer
that develops is not likely to metastasize.
It's very treatable.
Okay, hold still, Margo.
I'm feeling a little bit dizzy.
Oh, my God.
BP's dropping.
What's going on?
Get him out of here.
Heart rate's 98 and rising.
We've gotta find that bleed.
What'd you do, hit an artery?
With what? I hadn't even
started the procedure.
I need some advice.
Whatever it is, can it wait?
Yeah.
What was Greg like after I left?
An egomaniacal
narcissistic pain in the ass.
Same as before you left.
Do you think he's capable
of having a real relationship?
What happened in
Baltimore? Nothing.
Right. Maybe something.
Right.
Technically, most of the
something happened after Baltimore.
Oh, God, Stacy.
I don't know what to do.
Are you seriously thinking
about leaving Mark?
No. I don't know.
I can't.
And you want me
to tell you it's okay?
It wasn't all bad with Greg.
I was with him for a reason.
You left him for a reason.
I could swear I
remember him being fun.
Sorry for the scare.
Just tell me she's okay.
Ultrasound showed the bleed
was coming from her liver.
It's rare, but the blood
got into her fallopian tubes.
In a way, it was lucky. Let us know
we were looking in the wrong place.
The tumor's in her liver.
Is it cancer?
We're running some more tests.
There it is.
It's a liver tumor.
Well, if it's malignant,
at least she's
only gonna leave one
child without a mother.
Do a biopsy.
We can't. It's vascular.
House.
What? I'm here about Stacy.
What about her?
I think I'm losing her.
Your wife, your problem.
She won't talk to me.
So what? You gonna talk to
me instead? Talk to your shrink.
She keeps saying
everything's fine.
Find a bar. Talk to a stranger.
You're the only one
who's been through this.
I'm shutting her out.
I'm saying things and then
hating myself for saying them.
How did you get past that?
Didn't.
Can you please be a human
being for one minute and talk to me?
Sorry. Gotta go. People dying.
You're not gonna outrun me.
House!
You're not ready for this.
I've seen the way you and
Stacy talk to each other.
You're an idiot.
You probably just set your
rehab back three months.
Let go. Get off of me!
Liver tumor doesn't make sense.
You saying the CT was wrong?
I'm saying the symptoms don't add
up. A plus B does not equal liver tumor.
We gotta solve for X.
We gotta look
at this differently.
What do we know about her?
The side effects of
the Ritalin caused the...
No. We've examined the file up
and down. Come on, give me that.
Why do you people always
overlook the human element?
What do we know
about her? Margo...
Dalton. The woman.
She's a people-pleaser. She
doesn't like to let people down.
Never fights with her husband.
She turned to drugs instead of
asking for help to manage her life.
So if she can't manage now,
why does she want another kid?
Foreman, I need your help here.
You wanna pull a bank
job, would you go it alone?
If you gonna rob a home, sure,
that's a one or two man crew.
But a bank, you need a
lookout, a getaway driver.
I'm not saying anything until
the metaphor plays itself out.
So here's the caper.
Fertility meds
create a distraction.
Mommy had three refills on
Ritalin in the last three weeks.
That team goes
straight for the top floor.
No trouble taking out communications, but
they need the specialist, a safecracker.
All he does is stroke,
blood clot, liver tumor.
Foreman was right. This
badass even does flailing.
Come on.
There's only one guy I know
who does that kind of work.
Birth control pills?
While the surgeons are
cutting out a chunk of your liver,
should I have them
do a hysterectomy, too?
A hysterectomy?
I'm trying to get pregnant.
You don't have to lie to
me. We're not married.
You're Supermom.
You can do anything.
You work seven days a week,
you volunteer, you raise a kid.
Yet you still somehow find the
time to lie to hubby number two
that you really, really wanna give him a
child with his chin and pretty brown eyes.
What makes you
think that I would...
Because it fits.
Birth control pills caused
a hepatocellular adenoma.
Explains all your symptoms that
aren't explained by your other lies.
That's it?
Also...
I'll have the tuna on rye.
Would you like to
leave my room now?
Your tumor is benign.
Stop taking the pill, and
it will go away on its own.
I'm canceling the surgery.
What are you gonna
tell my husband?
That I'm canceling the surgery.
You can do the explaining.
It's tricky, huh?
It's one thing to say
you can't have a baby.
It's another to say
you don't want one.
Personally, I'd make
up some other lie.
Could...
Could I die on the table?
Could you die if
you tell him the truth?
I need this surgery.
I'm not on the pill.
You can't cancel the surgery.
If she goes off the pill, the
tumor goes away on its own.
You have no proof the
birth control pills caused this.
You have no proof
she's even taking them.
If we do the surgery maybe
we'll kill her on the table.
Then I can prove I'm
right at the autopsy.
Or we can forget the surgery,
let the tumor grow, and kill her.
Why don't you take it up with Stacy,
see which option minimizes your risk?
Here's what I think she's
gonna say, "Oh, I love Greg.
"But if you go against the patient's
wishes, you're calling her a liar.
"And if something goes
wrong, I end up in court
"having to defend the big mean
doctor, albeit with dreamy eyes,
"who wouldn't believe
the nice suburban mom.
"And even though his cane makes
me melt, do the damn surgery."
Shocking.
It's benign.
People do crazy things for love.
No, crazy is hanging out in the
park all day talking to pigeons.
Margo knows what she's doing.
She gave up half her
liver to save her marriage.
No, she surgically removed her
fingerprints to cover her pathetic lie.
It's twisted and manipulative.
I get that. But it's also
romantic.
I'm barely willing to put
the seat down after I pee.
Do we need to talk?
Nope. I'm fine.
So the surgeon got the
whole tumor, and it was benign.
That's good, right?
Yeah, benign is good.
How could a benign tumor
have caused all the symptoms?
We believe all your wife's
symptoms will go away now.
Oh, thank God.
Look, I'm gonna pick up Stella.
I'll call you after I
get the babysitter.
Dr. Foreman,
you can help me.
You could tell my husband that
because of all this,
I can't take any more
fertility treatments.
Confidentiality rules stop me
from telling your husband the truth.
But my obligation
to lie ends there.
Are there...
Is there a birth control method,
something that won't make me sick?
Margo, you're gonna
have risks with everything,
especially if you're not
telling your fertility doctor.
If you keep doing this, it's gonna
kill your marriage and kill you.
You don't know.
In a few years,
we'll give up.
Stop trying to get pregnant.
We'll hug, cry.
Eventually Ted will stop thinking about
it, and he'll appreciate Stella even more.
And we'll live happily
together for the next 50 years.
Something you need to see.
Knowing is always
better than not knowing.
It's a referral request.
Right.
The HIV thing came in earlier.
You're fine.
You won't read your
mail, but you'll open mine?
It said "confidential,"
and I wanted to know.
The most important letter of
my life, and you're still an ass.
Comforting, isn't it?
Hey.
Hi.
I'm gonna talk to Mark tonight,
and I'm gonna stay here with you.
Don't do it.
This isn't funny, Greg.
I know.
You
spent all these
months chasing me.
Now I'm here and you start
running? What the hell changed?
Nothing.
Nothing changes.
I'm not gonna change.
Who asked you to?
Mark is willing to
do whatever it takes.
I'm not.
Never was.
Now you're introspective?
Weren't so analytical the other night.
You were happy with
Mark. You'll be happy again.
Shut up about Mark. What
the hell is wrong with you?
I can't make you happy!
What?
How do you think
this is gonna end?
We'll be happy, for what? A
few weeks? A few months?
And then I'll...
I'll say something
insensitive or I'll
start ignoring you.
And at first it'll be okay.
It's just House being
House. And then,
at some point, you will
need something more.
You'll need someone who
can give you something I can't.
You know I'm right.
I've been there before.
Oh.
It doesn't have to be.
It does.
I don't wanna go there again.
I'm sorry, Stacy.
$50 says they're
divorced in a year.
Six months, tops.
I'll take that bet. It's
the perfect marriage.
There's nothing to fight over if
you never talk about anything.
What did you tell her?
I told her she's
better off without me.
That's probably true.
You're an idiot.
You don't think she'd
be better off without you.
Right. I sent her off on a whim.
You have no idea
why you sent her off!
Don't do this. This
was no great sacrifice!
You sent her away because
you've got to be miserable!
This kind of psycho-crap help get
your patients through the long nights?
Or is it just for you?
Tough love make you feel good?
Helping people feel their pain?
You don't like yourself.
But you do admire yourself.
It's all you've got,
so you cling to it.
You're so afraid if you change,
you'll lose what makes you special.
Being miserable doesn't make
you better than anybody else, House.
It just makes you miserable.