My offer's withdrawn.
You can walk to work.
Got it. You're morally outraged.
Now, can we get
through this part?
'Cause the next part's awesome.
How do you rationalize
something like this?
You broke into Stacy's
therapist's office.
Borrowed a key. And
stole her treatment notes.
Nope. I made copies.
"Mark is," and I quote...
"withdrawn, passive
aggressive, won't communicate,
"like he resents me
because I can walk."
I don't wanna hear this.
"Dishes in the sink, toilet seat up."
Meanwhile, she can't
stop thinking about...
I can't read that, is she
obsessed with a gray horse or me?
It says she thinks
you're an annoying jerk.
It's a pet name.
Here's the kicker.
They're not having sex?
Doctor cleared
him, but no lift-off.
She's frustrated, so
she's doc-blocking me.
Paperwork, seminars,
meddling with my patients.
But now you've got
the proof you need,
just take those personal
psych records to Cuddy,
and that'll show her
Stacy's out of control.
You ignoring me?
While looking for my newspaper.
Efficient, huh?
Over here.
Dr. Wilson, I want
you to meet my stalker.
Your waiting room sucks.
I am not treating you.
Because you're a closet case?
We're not together.
He is so self-loathing.
But we gotta go now. So,
maybe see you after work.
No, no, no, no.
Nobody can figure out
what's wrong with me.
Well, your shirt is gaping at the
collar. That means you've lost weight.
You're flushed, that's fever,
and you're short of breath.
And finally, there's the KS lesion on
your face. It means you're HIV positive,
and you've progressed
to full-blown AIDS.
So you're sick because your immune
system is shot and someone sneezed on you.
May I be excused now? Brilliant,
but my immune system is fine.
Your concentration-camp
physique begs to differ.
Get your T-cell
count re-checked.
I've already done that.
They test for T-cell lymphoma?
It was negative.
All of this will be fascinating
to an HIV specialist.
Now let go of my cane before
it becomes your new boyfriend.
Honey, I will marry it if
you will look at my file.
Congress says you can't, so...
I didn't touch him.
He's going into
anaphylactic shock.
Go see Stacy. We
gave him epi. He's fine.
You need a lawyer. Go
see Stacy. You hit a patient.
Four words, two mistakes.
He's not a patient,
and I didn't hit him.
Of course you
didn't. Go see Stacy.
I didn't cause the anaphylaxis.
It's probably one
of his HIV meds.
Abacavir. I'll pass that along,
make sure the ER takes
him off it. Go see Stacy.
You have to treat him. Medically,
this case is a snooze-fest.
AIDS plus infection.
You don't treat him, he
charges you with assault.
Just 'cause he says I hit
him, doesn't make it true.
Watch, I am surrounded
by naked cheerleaders.
See?
Although, I like my chances
of some action this morning.
I forgot Wednesday was hooker
day. This could have waited.
You make me meet
you at your house.
Your husband is
conveniently absent.
Mark's at physio. I'm stuck
waiting for the exterminator.
I saw a rat last night.
Well, I'm surprised your
feet are touching the floor.
I barely slept.
What was Mark up to?
If memory serves, a quick
climb up Mount Gregory,
and you'd doze
through a seal hunt.
Clubbing, shrieking.
What're you doing?
Sorry, it was just
driving me nuts.
You hate washing dishes.
People change.
I could make sure you'd
sleep like a baby tonight.
Rather take care of it myself.
I was referring to the rat.
Trenton Pest is sending a guy.
What's going on?
It's not what you think.
I know it looks like we're cleaning
dishes, but actually we're having sex.
We're working.
Wow, wish I had become a doctor.
Place would be spotless.
Take 10 minutes, cure
the guy, and stop whining.
I give you Kalvin Ryan,
so flamboyant in person,
so boring on paper.
Obviously got an
opportunistic infection,
probably TB or PCP.
Have you read his file?
I started, but I found the
characters two-dimensional.
He went to an HIV
clinic last week.
Tested negative for TB,
PCP, MAC, CMV, HSV.
It's not an
infection. HIV clinic.
So few patients, so much money.
Redo the tests. The
results make sense.
Kalvin's T-cells are at 200.
That's strong enough
to fight infection.
Fine, parasite.
Nope. The stool
sample was negative.
Two months ago, he
was down to 30 T-cells.
Then he changed his meds,
his immune system rebounds,
his viral load drops, everything's
getting better, but he's getting sicker.
Face it. This might
be an interesting case.
What if his immune
system is too strong?
An auto-immune disease?
With HIV, that's impossible.
His new HIV meds kicked his
system out of a sound sleep.
It wakes up hungry,
cranky, spoiling for a fight.
And when it doesn't
find an active infection,
it starts attacking the harmless
remnants of old infections.
Immune reconstitution syndrome.
His meds made him so much
better, he made himself sick?
Sounds pretty... Boring!
This is so not interesting.
Chest x-ray to find the old
infection and start him on steroids.
If you're wrong, the steroids will tank
his immune system. He'll get worse.
Now that would be interesting.
Where's the Coumadin?
If your patient's
got a blood problem,
then blood thinners
aren't exactly...
It's for Stacy's rat.
Death by anticoagulation.
Trying to win Stacy
back by killing an animal.
Very caveman.
I don't want her back.
I just want her to admit
her feelings for me.
I go to Cuddy,
Cuddy fires her or reassigns
her. Either way, I'm happy.
If you want her back,
either tell her or, better yet,
shut up and cry yourself
to sleep like everybody else.
Hi, this is, Mark Warner,
1724 Spring Street.
Listen, you don't need to send
that guy down. We caught him.
No, you should send the bill to
Princeton-Plainsboro Hospital,
attention Dr. James Wilson.
Yeah.
Your lymph nodes
aren't swollen, that's good.
Maybe Dr. Chase should check.
Sorry, mate, hands full.
He's too pretty to be straight.
You ever done any modeling?
Does anyone actually
fall for that line?
Every day.
Why do you think I
became a photographer?
I'm guessing you guys didn't
think about dating on career day.
I love my job. Really?
You seem more the "find it
exceptionally satisfying" type.
I'm not sure
there's a difference.
Your mom died of diabetes.
How's your dad's health?
Last I heard, he had cirrhosis.
Love is love.
Satisfying is "social
validation, fun can wait."
I have fun.
Yeah, she's got some
scheduled for February.
Last you heard, your father?
He threw me out when I was 16.
It's just as well.
I got tired of getting BB guns for my
birthday when I'd asked for a Barbie.
Dads can be real sweethearts.
Sensitive and cute.
He's cute.
He ran into that
heating vent, right there.
Hopefully, Mark's anger
will go away eventually.
He's not angry, he
just doesn't like you.
Nothing unique there.
Didn't seem real
wild about you, either.
He's fine with me.
He's angry. Said so in group.
Of course he's angry. He's
looking at months of painful physio.
He's mad at you.
There's no way he said that.
No.
But it's true.
He resents you for
being able to walk.
Been there.
I resented you for
a hell of a long time.
Past tense?
Might be the hospital.
What?
Bad time? Where are you?
At your girlfriend's place.
Ignore the moaning
and squeaking.
His lungs are too scarred to
tell which infection triggered
the immune reconstitution.
He a smoker?
Yes, and possibly
more than cigarettes.
His tox screen came back
positive for recreational drugs.
Not surprising, not
medically relevant.
His heart looks
a little enlarged.
That's a typical
side effect of AZT.
What are Kalvin's
most recent infections?
Toxo, CMV,
and PCP.
Well, let's assume
it's one of those.
Give him ganciclovir
for the CMV.
We can hardly hear
you. Where are you?
In a closet.
Your girlfriend's other
boyfriend showed up.
Ganciclovir for the CMV.
Sulfadiazine for the
toxo, Bactrim for PCP.
Gotta go. It's killing time.
Your tox screen came
back positive for...
Crystal meth and ecstasy.
Recreational drugs are dangerous to
begin with, but for someone with HIV...
I didn't mistake
them for vitamins.
I'm a PNP boy.
Party and Play.
Drugs and sex.
You don't approve?
Does the sex include condoms?
If he's negative,
sure. If he's positive...
Why put on a raincoat
if you're already wet?
You could get hepatitis,
or another strain of HIV.
Or I could get hit by a bus.
AIDS isn't a death
sentence anymore.
I don't wanna have any regrets.
How long have you been coughing?
About an hour or so.
Try to take a deep breath.
What is it?
I think it's blood.
I recommend
post-exposure prophylaxis.
Your chances of
conversion are slim,
but I'd like to put you on
three anti-viral medications.
Nelfinavir, zidovudine,
and lamivudine.
There are side effects,
headache, nausea, vivid dreaming.
You'll be tested for
HIV at six weeks,
three months, six months.
Very interesting.
He coughs infected blood in Cameron's
eyes and mouth, that's interesting?
The "coughing" part,
not the "in Cameron" part.
New symptom, blood
vessel ruptured in his lung.
I closed the tear.
Well, it takes immune
reconstitution off the table.
What's it put on the table?
It's okay, she's not here,
you can skip the nice-guy acts.
You know, some human beings are
actually capable of human feelings.
My giving a damn or not is not
gonna change what happened.
Could be Goodpasture's syndrome.
No edema, no bloody urine.
Well, KS on his face could mean KS in
his lungs, with bleeding from the lesions.
I would have seen them when
I repaired the tear in his lung.
Wegener's granulomatosis?
Wegener's would have
responded to steroids.
Maybe you should go
home, take the rest of the day.
I'm fine.
Well, this is good.
He's pretending to care,
you're pretending not to.
I think we should reconsider
drugs. Kalvin uses crystal meth.
Concerned enough about
his health to stalk me,
while indulging in
deadly street drugs.
A study in contradictions.
Interesting, but still
not medically relevant.
It could be, if his
drugs were tainted.
They cook meth with
battery acid, lye, lantern fuel...
Find Kalvin's
pills, test for toxins.
Foreman, you're with me.
I need a consult
on another case.
We have another case?
It's a hip-pocket deal.
Patient presents
with a distinct neck tilt.
Wry neck. Is he an athlete?
He's a regular runner.
Any pain associated
with movement?
None that he's complained of.
Best-case scenario, an
infection in the ear or lungs.
Worst case, brain-stem tumor.
You should do an MRI,
CAT Scan, full work up.
I don't think so. No insurance.
No drugs in here.
I'll take the bathroom.
How about a drink after work?
Take your mind off what happened.
Cameron?
I might have HIV, a drink's
not gonna wash it away.
There's like zero chance
of you contracting the virus.
Big difference between
"like zero" and "zero."
What did the infection
control guy tell you?
He was very reassuring.
Kept reminding me that the
hospital covers all my medical costs.
Apparently forgot to mention
that if I do test positive,
that they'll pass it on to legal, and
legal will dig up any dirt they can,
trying to prove that
I'm a drug user or tramp,
and that's why I have HIV.
It's not like they're
gonna find anything, right?
Right.
Check this out.
Kalvin's a photographer.
The broken bulbs were props.
The glass is from
1930s fluorescents.
Some of the bulbs
are date-stamped.
Pre-World War Il,
fluorescent bulbs
contained large
amounts of beryllium.
Beryllium dust inflames
the lungs, they get rigid,
patient can't breathe.
My father co-authored a
paper on acute berylliosis.
Phew!
For a moment there, I
thought you were smart.
Cameron, get a biopsy of Kalvin's
lung tissue, run a spectrographic analysis.
I can handle it.
No reason to risk exposing the
entire team. Then who would I torment?
I'm sorry.
About what happened.
It's best not to talk.
You're gonna feel a sharp pinch.
This actually is gonna
grab a piece of your lung.
What were you guys
looking for at my hotel?
Your drugs.
We thought maybe
you'd used toxic meth.
We'll know if you were exposed
to beryllium in a few hours.
Well, if you're still curious,
it's in my bag over
there on the chair.
You brought drugs
into the hospital?
Glad I wasted my
time at your hotel.
I told you I used, you
didn't ask me for a sample.
You're not pissed about this,
you're mad because I
coughed blood on you.
That was an accident.
Would you stop being nice?
It's useless, and
worse, it's boring.
Get angry!
I had one stupid
night, I end up with HIV.
Do you have any idea
how pissed off I was?
This wasn't your fault.
You broke into my house?
Well, I had to, Mark isn't here.
He has physio. Oh, really?
How's he doing? What
happened with all the cheese?
Well, I had to get rid of it before
Steve McQueen ate any Coumadin.
I named your rat.
Steve's tilting his head.
Any neurologist will tell you
that suggests an infection
or a brain-stem tumor.
Death cures both those things.
We can't kill him.
If it's an infection, it could be
caused by something in your house.
Something that
could affect you guys.
Smell this.
Does it smell like urine?
You missing any asparagus?
Okay, stuff these.
If he doesn't get
better, then it's a tumor.
Then what, chemo?
Steve McQueen without hair?
It's a blessing he died young.
Hello.
Hi, honey.
I'm sorry I missed you,
yeah. I came home.
All right, I'll see
you in a few minutes.
Okay.
Bye, hon.
Chest hurts.
Heart rate's a 100 and climbing,
could be an allergic reaction.
Neck veins are up. Must
be pericardial effusion.
There's no wheezing. The tear
in his lungs must have reopened.
Kalvin? You're bleeding into
the area around your heart.
I can't breathe. The
blood's crushing your heart.
Once we remove
it, you'll be fine.
If I die, please tell my dad...
You're not going to die.
Tell him sorry.
Where's the blood?
It's clear.
Only one other thing
could cause this.
A tumor in his heart.
CT confirmed a
mass in Kalvin's heart,
and several smaller
ones in his lungs.
That's why his heart's
enlarged, not the AZT.
You okay?
She's fine, probably getting
bored with the question.
Masses in the heart and lungs,
what kind of cancer are we looking at?
They may not be cancerous.
This is classic
Non-Hodgkin's lymphoma.
HIV-positive patient with
a primary heart mass?
It could be sarcoidosis.
His lung tissue was negative.
Lymphoma's a death
sentence, sarcoidosis is treatable.
So is an ear infection, but since
he didn't test positive for that either...
I want to do the
Kveim-Siltzbach test.
Do you have any idea how much
paperwork Cuddy's gonna need signed?
Do it.
So...
How's the patient's father?
"Tell my dad I'm sorry"?
Might as well have
waved a red flag at a bull.
He's not coming.
Well, it's not a tragedy.
Dad doesn't wanna see him,
he doesn't wanna see the dad.
You're the only one
who wants them together.
He asked. He
thought he was dying.
Dying people lie, too.
Wish they'd worked
less, they'd been nicer,
they'd opened
orphanages for kittens.
If you really wanna
do something, you do it,
you don't save it
for a sound bite.
What did you say when
you thought you were dying?
On the other hand...
His dad tossed him out.
So what's our guy
wanna apologize for?
Everybody has regrets.
If the growths in your
lungs and heart are sarcoid,
your body will
recognize this material,
and we'll see a
reaction on your arm.
Did you really
wanna see your dad?
You called him?
Thanks.
He would've come,
tried to straighten me out.
How are you holding up?
I'm fine. Convincing.
What did you do with my drugs?
The lab disposes of
them after analysis.
Too bad.
They could've done
you some good.
Not really my thing.
You know, I hope
you don't have it, but...
Getting HIV might have been the
best thing that ever happened to me.
I used to be a good boy.
Never wanted to
piss anybody off.
Playing by the rules makes
everybody else happy.
Now I'm happy.
So you just show up
every time he's at physio?
Of course not.
Also when he's at group therapy
or out for dinner with friends.
And when she happens to mention
to Mark that you dropped by...
You tell your wife everything?
It's a process.
But Stacy doesn't have any
reason to hide this from Mark.
As far as she knows, Mark's
okay with you being there.
My bet is she mentions me
to Mark as little as possible.
Because she
thinks that he thinks
that she still has
feelings for me.
You know why she thinks that?
Because she still
has feelings for you?
If you're right,
she did tell him
and I don't get through
the door tonight.
If I'm right...
So how long do we stay here?
Until something happens.
He's not gonna come
out with us right here.
We are downwind, and he
seems to have hearing loss.
He's not blind.
Steve McQueen does
not run from danger.
Antibiotics, on
the other hand...
He ate around the pill?
Smart.
Admit it, you like him.
He's all right. For a rat.
You wanna know how cool he is?
His urine showed traces of
hydrogen cyanide, formaldehyde, lead.
He's a smoker.
Your husband's been lighting up,
which is particularly stupid,
given that it could cause his AIP...
Okay, I blow my smoke into
the vent so Mark doesn't know.
I always knew.
Bluffing.
You started two
weeks after my surgery.
Menthols, then
lights after a month.
Why didn't you say anything?
'Cause it helped me
monitor your misery level.
One trip outside was a good day,
and upwards of
six, you were in hell.
You could have
asked me how I was.
I already knew.
I'm sorry you were miserable.
Sorry I caused you so much pain.
Glad you changed your
mind about that drink.
Come on in.
You should get changed, there's
this new place on campus that looks...
Are you high? Uh-huh.
I thought the lab
disposed of the drugs.
Not all of it.
Slow down.
Your pupils are
dilated. You're not...
Come on, Chase, don't turn
into a good guy on me now.
You're late.
And hung over.
Or maybe not.
Why do you have a rat?
Jealous?
Get out of my room!
Don't you dare put this on me!
I'm not gonna grovel, Dad!
That's not what I'm
asking for! Like hell it isn't!
You said you didn't call.
Well...
Don't mind me, just
here for the show.
Yeah, well, there's
not gonna be any.
What happened
to the big apology?
Yesterday he was all,
"Daddy, I'm so sowwy."
This is none of your business.
Well, you should've thought
of that before you stalked me.
Now I'm interested. So
what's he got to apologize for?
You're the one
who tossed him out.
Now why would I do that?
I don't know, because it's tough
to brag to your hunting buddies
that your son knows
all the words to The Wiz.
That's a lie. 42nd Street?
No. Much easier just to
get drunk and beat him.
Explains his hating you,
and also your cirrhosis.
Also, why the more I
talk, the more you sweat.
What it doesn't explain, is
why he's got to apologize to you.
Residual guilt for sharing
your special toy with other boys?
Just leave it alone.
You just wanna leave the bigot with
some peace of mind after you're gone?
Look, this has got nothing, and I
mean nothing, to do with him being gay.
Now Kal brought this on himself
with what he did to his mother.
He steal her signature look?
No.
No, he killed her.
Kalvin lied!
Yeah. That
certainly is shocking.
Mom's kidneys were failing, she
needed a transplant, they tested Kalvin,
he was a match, he
was also positive for HIV.
Mom never found a
qualified donor, she dies.
Tragic tale.
Undercut slightly by the rapid-fire
delivery and constant movement.
Too much coffee this morning?
He didn't kill her. Our bodies
aren't donor farms for our parents.
It's not 1980. We know
how HIV is transmitted.
If Kalvin got HIV through unprotected
sex, dad has every right to be pissed.
So you always use a condom?
Yeah.
Brothers on the down-low got to.
I'm not ready for any
Foreman Juniors yet.
You? Working
girls are sticklers.
You're not gonna poll Chase?
I'm not an idiot.
Obviously not.
Who doesn't sleep with a drugged-out
colleague when they have a chance?
Where's Wilson?
We got the result
of the Kveim test.
But so...
I have cancer?
In all likelihood, yeah.
Non-Hodgkin's lymphoma.
And I am
dying?
We need to biopsy the tumor.
It's near your aorta,
so getting that sample
carries serious risks.
Is my dad still here?
He hasn't been in?
We'll inject a dye around your heart
to make the tumor visible on the CT.
Then a surgeon inserts a guide
wire, runs it up into your heart,
where he takes a small piece of that tumor
so we can look at it under the microscope.
Ativan.
It'll help settle you down.
Why are you so calm?
Not coming off meth helps.
Last night probably
shouldn't happen again.
Do you think I want it to?
When two people have
had sex, unless it sucks,
if they can do it again,
they're gonna do it again.
And that's when
things get complicated.
And it didn't suck.
So now you've gotta drum up another
excuse to be around the love of your life.
Could hit another patient.
Yeah, don't like
to repeat myself.
People will say I'm formulaic.
Well, that rules out letting the
rat go so you can catch him again.
I can't do that.
Steve needs two weeks' antibiotics
and a smoke-free environment.
Cigarettes aggravated
his infection.
The rat is actually sick? That
thing could infect the entire hospital.
Steve's infection is not
contagious to humans.
I'm an idiot. How do I
miss mycoplasmosis?
Was that the kid's father?
Yeah. Remember the Black
Death? It started with rats.
Well, what's he
doing in the hallway?
Is the kid getting
his biopsy already?
He just won't go in the room.
Who knows what else he has,
parasites, bacterial infection?
The kid doesn't have
parasites. Not the kid, the rat.
Was he still sweating?
Rats only sweat
through their tails.
Not the rat, the dad!
Where are they from?
Montana. What's going on?
You were right, it's a parasite.
Cancel the
biopsy, it'll kill him.
Hey, Daddy, come with me.
Yeah, I'm not going in there.
Your son asked to talk to you.
Why is he here?
He wanted to talk to you.
Did you two used
to hunt together?
Foxes? Did you kill foxes?
It's Montana.
Those masses in your
chest are not tumors.
They're parasitic cysts from
a bug called echinococcus.
Touch a dead fox,
they jump aboard,
they can hunker
down for decades.
Growing, spawning,
shopping, putting on plays.
I've been tested for parasites.
Okay, it's cancer. You happy?
The cysts isolate the parasites,
keeping them from showing up in stool
samples. Even in blood tests, cardiac...
All right, you don't
need me for this.
But you've got the
same things in your liver.
I have cirrhosis.
Liver cysts have identical
symptoms, with one addition, fever.
And liver cysts we can test for.
Your diagnosis
could confirm Kalvin's.
So, option A, we
draw some blood...
No, no, no. Look,
you're not touching me.
Well, you see, this is
why I need you here.
I want you to tell your son that you
won't take a simple, painless blood test
to save his life.
You
never expressed
a shred of regret
for what happened
to your mother.
Jeez, Dad.
If you'd have worn a damn
rubber, you'd have been fine.
You could have saved her life.
You wouldn't be lying here.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I get it!
You're really mad at
him for killing himself,
and for destroying
everything you love.
I don't have time for this.
Are you gonna apologize?
I'm living my life
the way I want.
Are you gonna give
me some blood?
Look, if he doesn't give
a damn, then neither do I.
Okay, option B.
Why did your wife kill
herself? Did she hate you?
She was a diabetic!
You know, you don't know
a thing about my Susan.
Either Susan wanted to die,
or she was both fat and stupid.
Used a Twinkie instead of a gun.
And girls with big appetites, well,
they just can't get enough of anything.
Shut up!
Probably nibbled on every
Devil Dog in the county!
Shut up! Just in case I'm
not making myself clear,
I don't mean the
delicious snack.
You son of a bitch!
Yeah? Come on!
Thank you. Means I can do this.
We're gonna need
some epi in here, stat!
Are you out of your mind?
You said you didn't care.
Notice how you can't breathe?
Now, either that's the cane
or, I just ruptured one of those
liver cysts we were chatting about,
and you've gone into
anaphylactic shock.
Exactly the same
way your son did
when he accidentally
tripped against my friend's car.
I'm just so excited
to find out which.
I'm gonna schedule the surgery.
Clamp.
Pressure's holding.
Give me the syringe.
Clamps...
Two successful surgeries, two
lives saved. I'm over my quota.
Can I have next week off?
Two family members assaulted.
It was self-defense.
You baited him.
You're right, I
was asking for it.
The low-cut blouse,
the do-me pumps.
You flooded his gut with
a parasite. He could sue.
Go see Stacy.
Okay.
That's it, "okay"?
No name-calling? No squawking,
no rending of garments?
I like this t-shirt.
You lied to me.
If this is about my mom, I...
This is about your
lonely, miserable life.
I'm not miserable.
And as long as there's a gay
bar around, I'm never lonely.
You haven't had a single
visitor except for your dad.
Drugs are great, HIV freed you,
your dad hates
you, you're so happy.
Everything's a lie.
You blame yourself
for your mom's death.
You're not trying to have fun,
you're trying to self-destruct.
You wanna kill yourself,
fine, but stop recruiting!
Heard you hit another patient.
Yeah, sure, why not?
He hit me first.
Cuddy didn't mention
that. Let me see.
I'm the doctor.
My concern is purely legal.
Looks okay. Does it hurt?
A little.
You need some ice.
There's no way that
Mark doesn't know.
About the smoking.
He would have said something.
Then he hasn't been
near you in months.
We're fine.
Can't be easy.
Stop squirming.
Why would you lie about this?
I'm not lying.
I don't care if you're sleeping
with him or not, but you're not, so...
I am.
You're lying.
You know when I have sex?
You can smell that on me, too?
The only people who know about
what's going on with me and Mark,
are me and Mark.
Well, I just know you.
And I know you.
You're confident, arrogant,
but you're never certain
unless there's a
reason to be certain.
One other person knew.
I told you I was
seeing Dr. Harper,
you can easily
get into her office.
You read my file.
The dishes, the concern,
the acting like a human being.
You have...
This whole time, you've
been manipulating me.
You knew that I had
an angle the moment
I poured soap
onto a scrub brush.
You could have thrown
me out or ignored me
or found another exterminator. You didn't
even tell Mark that I kept coming by.
You let this happen because
you wanna be with me.
I don't anymore.
Get out.
I'm sorry.