♪ Sometimes we rock and roll ♪
♪ Sometimes we stay at
home and it's just fine ♪
♪ This heart's on fire
This heart's on fire ♪
♪ I am my mother's hen ♪
Please walk around
the other way.
Be careful...
What happened?
Nothing. They're just getting
the lobby ready for the big party.
It's an annual fundraiser.
Like a carnival?
No, it's a swanky
black-tie ball.
You think a hospital
lobby is swanky?
Not yet. Add some
lights, a few decorations,
and, most importantly, alcohol.
It becomes a streamer and
balloon-infested hospital lobby
with a cash bar.
It's for charity. Better to
spend the money for the cause.
Actually, it's worse. You need
to spend money to make money.
I don't like parties.
It doesn't matter.
All residents will be expected
to attend and make a donation.
This is Dr. Alex Park, he's
the last of Coyle's residents
to be reassigned to our team.
Meet doctors Jared Kalu,
Claire Browne and Shaun Murphy.
Hi.
Nice to meet you.
Welcome back.
How was Costa Rica?
Beaches were awesome.
Monkeys were horrible.
Little bastards stole my
new camera and a pair of...
How old are you?
Forty-five.
That's even older
than Dr. Melendez.
Dr. Murphy is a talented
doctor who has autism,
which sometimes causes him
to ask inappropriate questions.
No worries. Inappropriate
questions can be very revealing.
I'm a late bloomer.
Park's being modest,
which is very unlike him.
He was a cop for 15 years
before he went to med school.
Now that we all know each other,
Reznick and Browne have
dibs on cases this week.
You make your picks?
- Yes.
- Definitely.
Is there karaoke?
And now, our all-star line-up,
playing center out of
Moose Jaw, Saskatchewan.
Whoo!
Spirit, stop it. They don't
have time to fool around.
I'm not fooling around. I need to
document the momentous event.
Then at least get it right.
I'm from Taipei, Taiwan.
Correction, from Taipei, Taiwan,
which I believe is a
suburb of Moose Jaw,
Dr. Audrey Lim...
And assisting Dr. Lim are
two docs I've never met.
Hello, I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy
from Casper, Wyoming.
And...
Dr. Morgan Reznick. Mill
Valley, California. Represent.
- Whoo!
Okay, Spirit, that's enough.
All right, put your phone
away, or it becomes my phone.
Well, folks, looks like the
suits are shutting me down.
Thanks for all your
support. Love you. Bye.
Sorry, but my friends
insist I keep them up to date.
It's all right. It's a big day.
Spirit was born with
ectopia cordis. She's been...
Why didn't they repair it
when she was an infant?
They couldn't. Her
rib cage was too small.
But after 14 years of
slow and steady growth...
It's time to put this
baby where it belongs.
This is an interesting view.
I can see the aortic arch.
- Murphy.
- Oh, it's all right.
I'm used to people
being curious.
I'm sure you're looking forward
to when there's nothing
to be curious about.
Mmm, what I'm really
looking forward to is crowds.
You like crowds?
I don't know. I've
never been in one.
I can't go to a normal school,
and my parents barely
ever let me leave our house.
Well, when a small bump could
stop your heart, it makes sense.
But you still have
a lot of friends?
Yeah, of course. I mean, I just
can't do anything fun with them.
If you can't do anything fun,
then how did you get
them to be your friend?
Well, in case you haven't
noticed, I like to talk.
- And, uh...
- Yes.
We all do everything
online now anyway.
The first thing I'm gonna
do when I get out of here
is take all my
friends to a concert.
Like, general
admission, on the floor.
I don't even care who the band is,
just as long as the place is packed.
Oh, and I'm gonna hug everyone.
You've never hugged
anyone? Not even your parents?
Kissed by my parents,
high-fived by my friends,
but, nope, no hugs.
It's just too risky.
Hugs make me feel trapped.
Sorry. Almost done.
Pain in the upper
right quadrant.
It's jaundice.
Bilirubin's off the chart.
That doesn't make sense.
He's been doing so
well since the transplant.
Every check-up this
year's been perfect.
Well, it could just be
a temporary flare-up.
We'll increase his anti-rejection
meds and do a full liver exam.
We'll know more then.
You two, do the work-up,
and you find a new liver.
Shouldn't we wait
for the biopsy result?
Not when I already
know what it's gonna say.
He needs a new liver ASAP.
I mean, that's gonna be
hard. He's blood type O.
It's gonna be impossible.
He's lucky they were
able to find the first one.
Well, he better get lucky again
'cause it's our only
way to keep him alive.
We're screwed.
Barbara Boxer got ear
barotrauma scuba diving in Cozumel
and cannot fly for two weeks,
which means we don't have
a keynote speaker for our gala.
You think this is funny?
I've just never
seen you anxious.
And I seriously doubt
Barbara Boxer scuba dives.
It's just an excuse.
She sent me a picture
from the hospital.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
Anyone can fake a photograph.
- What are you doing?
- I'm doing a search
to see if our esteemed senator
from the great state of California
ever once, once talked about
scuba diving in an interview.
It doesn't matter if it's true.
What matters is that
we find a replacement.
I need you to get me a
meeting with Aidan Coulter.
- Oh, Aidan Coulter?
- Yes.
Uh... What? I sat next to
him once at an A's game.
And the story I remember
is that you two were talking
smack that entire game.
And after he spilled
his beer on you
and insisted on buying you a
new jacket, you refused him.
So he owes you.
Just get me a meeting. I will
handle everything from there.
Okay. I'll see what I can do.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Huh.
You'll be fine. You've
had liver biopsies before.
And they've always hurt a lot.
Please, is there another way?
Well, the other way, Eric,
would be going through your neck,
and I don't think you'd
like that any more.
Eric, you know why NBA players
all wear headphones before games?
Now, don't look at him. Look
at me. I need you to answer me.
Why do NBA players wear
headphones before games?
I don't know. I
guess they like music.
No, they need music.
Music helps them forget
about everything else
and focus on what's important.
The game.
Who's your favorite player?
Curry.
Okay. This is the song he
listens to before every game.
How do you know?
Because he's my
favorite player, too.
I want you to close your
eyes and focus on this.
Just this.
- It's cold.
- Yeah, now it is.
But if you stay focused,
pretty soon it'll stop feeling cold
and start to feel warm.
When that happens, I
want you to nod your head,
and you'll feel some
pressure and a small pinch.
- But what if it doesn't?
- Now close your eyes
and focus.
You ready?
Two minutes,
he'll be good to go.
How'd you know he
was a basketball fan?
His shoes.
He's not wearing any shoes.
Yeah, they're in a
backpack in his room.
You searched his backpack?
Well, it's less
invasive than a rectal
and, most of the
time, more useful.
Okay, Spirit, just
keep still and...
"And during a few parts of the exam,
we may ask you to hold your breath,
"but it'll only be
a few seconds."
You got it.
You gonna buy a tux or rent one?
The fundraiser is black-tie.
I have a suit. It's new.
I bought it for my
resident interviews.
It doesn't matter how
new it is. It's not a tux.
Wearing a uniform at
work reassures patients.
Wearing a uniform at a party
does nothing but make
you hot and uncomfortable.
This party is work.
Get a tux. And not a crappy
one from some outlet store.
Get fitted by a pro and
spend a minimum of two grand.
You're gonna meet rich
people who can help your career.
And they're not gonna wanna
help some slob in a suit...
I'm not a slob.
No, I am very clean and make
sure my clothes are never wrinkled.
And it's too big.
Her heart, it's enlarged
53% since her last exam.
Her last exam was
only six months ago.
It won't fit.
Too big.
The biopsy confirmed
acute cellular rejection.
We maximized his
immunosuppressives, but...
I found one.
A type-O liver.
Are you sure?
Park and I checked the
registry, and there weren't any.
I found it online.
He, uh, already tried to make a
direct donation a few months ago,
but the patient died
before the surgery.
I contacted him,
which wasn't easy,
but he still wants
to be a donor.
That's amazing. Great job.
What's the catch?
He wants to be a donor,
but he's not on the registry.
I mean, there's
got to be a catch.
He, uh... Well, he
can't be on the registry
because he is in prison.
For murder.
Actually, um, seven murders.
Boris Tirayan was a Russian mafia
enforcer convicted of seven murders.
Who now wants to make amends.
He tried to be a donor
a few months ago,
but the patient died before the
red tape could be worked out.
But now it has.
Are there any laws against
an inmate becoming a donor?
No. But there is a ton of liability.
What if he attacks someone here?
He'll be guarded by state
prison guards on a separate level,
away from patients and
all non-essential staff.
Everyone deserves a
chance to turn their life around.
Guy wants to do something
decent, we should let him.
I don't think we owe
a murderer anything.
But maybe he owes us
something. He has a debt to society.
Which he would repay by
donating his inner organs?
Isn't it a slippery slope between
a guy who wants to make amends
and turning our prison system
into a superstore for body parts?
A slippery slope that
saves a child's life.
It'll never happen.
He's just trying to get to a hospital
where it'll be easier to escape.
You have no idea
what his motivation is.
I know he's a lying sociopath
who doesn't care about
anyone but himself.
He's been a model
inmate for nine years,
tutors other prisoners
in the library...
Yeah, because he's trying
to get someone to trust him,
to give him an inch,
and as soon as they do...
We got approval.
He's gonna stall, make excuses,
and when he sees his chance,
someone's gonna get hurt.
I think it's worth
taking that chance.
Anybody who doesn't agree,
feel free to sit this one out.
When you started menstruating,
the increased estrogen
caused pulmonary hypertension,
which isn't a
surgical issue in itself,
but along with your
atypical vascular system...
Your heart's grown too big.
We will control
your blood pressure
so that you will keep growing,
but your heart won't, and
then by the time you're 18,
- we'll be able to...
- No. I'm not waiting any longer.
- Spirit, honey, it will be okay.
- No, it won't.
I'm sick of being
stuck inside all the time.
I'm sick of this!
I don't ever wanna text,
call, or video chat again.
Mom, I wanna be touched.
I wanna be shoved.
I wanna be punched. I don't
even care. Just... Please.
Please.
I want the surgery now.
I need it.
I'm sorry. We can't.
We need to get rid of all
the furniture and artwork.
I get removing the
paintings, but the furniture?
Don't want the prison
guards sitting down on the job.
He's gonna be in full
restraints, cuffed to the bed.
Well, that's our plan.
But we also need to
be prepared for his plan.
Okay, we need to get rid of
the window blinds, curtain rods,
jacket hooks, and make
sure there's no metal rivets
or eyelets on the mattress.
Uh, what's he gonna
do with a metal eyelet?
Tear it off the mattress and
file it down to cut your jugular
or bend it into a handcuff key
or shove it into an electric socket
to create a spark
and start a fire.
I've seen knives made out
of toilet paper, soap, and salt
that could amputate
a fat guy's femur.
I'm not quite sure he needed
the part about the guy being fat.
So I've been thinking.
You wanna go to the
fundraiser together?
It's not a prom. We
don't have to bring a date.
Yeah, we don't have to,
but we can, if we want.
Everyone basically knows
we're seeing each other, but still,
you know, I think it might
be a nice opportunity to
take our relationship
out into the open.
Unless you don't want to.
No, it's a good idea.
Are you sure? 'Cause,
you know, we don't have to.
Yeah. Let's do it.
Let's go.
What's wrong?
It's fine. He'll be all right.
No, I won't. I don't want
a murderer's liver. It's evil.
Eric, there's no such
thing as a good or bad liver.
It's just, uh, just an organ.
Eric, this is your only choice.
If we don't do the
transplant, you will die.
Look, I don't want
him to be a part of me,
inside me forever, all right?
I don't care what you or
anybody else says, okay?
It's my body,
and I don't want it.
That's ridiculous.
Personality traits aren't
transferred in an organ transplant.
It's also irrelevant.
Children don't consent to
surgeries. Their parents do.
But if he doesn't cooperate
with the anti-rejection regimen,
we could be wasting a liver that
could save someone else's life.
No one's getting
saved by Tirayan.
I found a type-A donor. It's
not a perfect match, but...
His body's already
rejected a perfect match.
There's no way it can tolerate
an incompatible blood type.
No, the only way to save Eric
is to do the transplant with
Tirayan's liver. That is it.
We have no other option.
Let the OR know we're
gonna need more restraints.
Dr. Clinton Ford out of Alberta
developed an experimental
resorbable material.
It would allow us to
expand her rib cage
and create room to
fit her heart inside.
An artificial sternum.
That would actually grow
along with the patient.
The surgery isn't reversible.
If it doesn't work,
we can't just move her
heart back to where it was.
It would allow
her to have a life.
She has a life.
And she'll be healthy as long
as she stays out of crowds,
doesn't hug anyone, or do
anything where she might fall...
I get you're autistic,
but I know even you realize
when a patient cries and
throws her phone against the wall,
they're not happy with
their current health.
There's no reason
to make this personal.
There is if his medical
judgment is biased.
I saw she was upset.
You saw it, but you
didn't understand it.
You're very competitive.
Are you trying to make
Dr. Lim think I'm biased,
or are you trying to
undermine my confidence?
I'm actually trying to
help you and the patient.
She wants to be
able to rub elbows,
and you need to learn
how to trade elbows.
The resorbable plate is
experimental and risky.
But my medical judgment
is that it's worth it.
Make sure she agrees,
and then get her prepped.
Why me?
I'm not famous. I don't know
anything about medicine.
And giving the keynote
speech at your fundraiser
is a steep price to pay
for a beer-stained jacket.
You grew up in San Jose.
You went to San Jose State
despite being accepted
by both Princeton and MIT.
And you headquartered
your company here,
despite huge tax breaks offered
by Chicago and Minneapolis.
And it was his favorite jacket.
And when I offered
to have it cleaned,
he said not to bother because
he didn't even like the jacket.
He was being polite.
"Polite"?
I take it you've never
been to a game with him.
You did some
homework, but not enough.
I love this city, but I
hate giving speeches.
So don't give a speech.
Tell us a story.
Like the one you
told at the wrap party
at the Youth Dance
Company's fall musical,
the one where you got
lost at the Paris catacombs.
I stand corrected.
Your success is
inspiring, Aidan,
as well as your
loyalty to this city.
And the fact that you're
young, apparently very funny...
I'm in.
Actually, I was in as
soon as Aaron told me
what you wanted to meet about,
but I was curious what your
attack strategy would be.
So how was it?
It was very effective.
Now, don't worry. He's been
a model inmate for nine years
and tutors the other
prisoners in the library.
Coke nail come in
handy up at Pelican Bay?
I make jewelry. Helps
me pick up the beads.
Is there a history of cancer
or liver disease in your family?
I went through this a couple of
months ago. You have my file.
We need to do our own exam.
And there's nothing about
your family in previous records.
Are they still alive?
They're dead to me.
Quit stalling, or we'll
send you back right now.
I haven't spoken to anyone in
my family since I was 15 years old.
Last I know, uh, both of my
parents were healthy enough
to kick the crap out
of me on a daily basis.
Any other questions?
Why do you want to do this?
Maybe I just like cute nurses
and bad Jell-O. What do you care?
We don't. As long as
you do what you're told.
Don't worry. I'm very
good at following orders.
Councilman Burns must be
very happy with his facelift.
He just bought another
table for the fundraiser.
I aim to please,
but you already knew that,
and I need to get into surgery,
so stop being so coy. What's up?
You and Isabel always
seem very happy,
able to manage both your
professional and personal lives.
I'm flattered you think
so. But still a bit coy.
When I met with Aidan
Coulter about being our keynote,
I thought there was a spark.
Okay, so now we're
getting somewhere.
Surgery can wait a few minutes.
Is it unprofessional
of me to explore it?
He's not a hospital employee
but potentially a significant donor
and younger.
Quite a bit.
Mmm-hmm.
I don't know. Maybe
I'm just imagining
something that
doesn't even exist.
Oh, I doubt that.
You're an attractive,
smart, interesting woman.
I'm sure there was a spark.
But you can't date
a donor like Coulter.
Sorry.
There's no actual
policy against it.
I'm not talking policy.
I'm talking optics.
The last thing you want is
someone thinking you'd use sex
to get a big donation.
It's a double standard, I know,
but it's the world we live in.
I said no! I don't want it!
I thought you gave him
something to calm him.
We did, but he's too agitated.
I'm going to start him
on IV midazolam now.
Eric? Eric, remember what
Dr. Park said earlier about focusing?
I know you can do that.
How about we get you
those earbuds you had earlier?
- No. Leave me alone!
- Eric, stop it!
Look at me!
Do not move.
You wear very stylish clothes.
Um, thank you. I assume you
mean when I'm not in surgery.
Yes. Do you think people believe
you're a better doctor
because of that?
Some people.
Others probably just
think I'm a show-off
or arrogant, gay. I don't care.
I do it for myself.
You look good, you feel good.
Does it help you make friends?
Feeling good about
yourself helps with everything.
Do you know where I
can buy a stylish tuxedo?
I can pay $2,000.
Okay.
Dr. Reznick says if I want people
who matter to help my career,
I need to wear a tuxedo that
costs $2,000 to the fundraiser.
Have you talked to
Glassman about this?
No. I make my own decisions now.
Murphy, people who
matter will help your career
because they're impressed with
your talent and potential as a surgeon.
And I could send
you to my tailor,
where you'll definitely
spend two grand,
but my advice would
be, just rent one.
Make sure you get
fitted by the manager,
and for a couple of
hundred bucks, you'll be fine.
I'm gonna need you to
count backwards from 10.
Ten, nine, eight...
Eight...
Looks like you were wrong.
I said he'll do anything
to convince us to trust him,
to let our guard down.
His eyes, they're swelling up.
So's his tongue. He's
having an allergic reaction.
Stop the anesthesia.
Give me 0.5 migs
epinephrine IM now.
I'm on it.
Epi's in.
He's hypoxic. We
need to intubate.
Getting a 5.0 tube.
Now!
You had a severe allergic
reaction to the anesthesia.
We had to intubate you
and give you steroids.
Wait...
You didn't do it?
We can't operate on you if you
can't breathe under anesthesia.
You did everything you could.
The patient's parents
wanted you to know
they're extremely grateful
for everything you did
or tried to do.
You can try again.
I'm sorry. We can't.
No, you try again.
Try again.
You try again.
Try again. Try again!
- Calm down.
- Try again! Try again!
I said calm down now.
Same old, same old, yeah?
That's the way it's
always been for me.
Nothing I ever...
He's still on top
of the UNOS list.
We're gonna be calling and
rechecking every registry and database
all night.
How long do we have?
Without a new
liver, maybe a day.
So what'd you get?
Hugo Boss? Armani?
Dr. Andrews said I
should just rent one.
And you're gonna listen to him?
He's the chief of surgery,
and he knows about clothes.
If Andrews had a son, you think
he'd let him go to an important
event in a cheap rental tux?
He said people who matter
judge people based on their talent.
Yeah, that's what he
tells someone else's kid.
To his own, or someone he
actually respects, he tells the truth.
Cut here.
Do you respect me?
You're smart, able to
memorize a ton of information,
but, no, not really.
Suction the mediastinum.
You've certainly
put a lot of thought
into what someone you claim
not to respect wears to a party.
Just because I don't respect
him doesn't mean I don't like him.
Everyone's uncomfortable
in fancy clothes
and hates kissing up to
bigwigs at a fundraiser.
They do it. They don't
cower at home alone.
You use your autism as a crutch.
Okay, I think if you liked him
any more, he'd have a black eye.
Make sure we're clear on that
side and the aorta isn't kinked.
The aorta isn't kinked.
Good. Now for the
moment of truth.
Position the plate.
Perfect fit.
What the hell? What did you do?
I don't feel nothing.
No, don't touch him.
If he can't control
his bladder...
He can control
himself just fine.
Nice try, but the
vacation's over. Stand up.
Re-check his cuffs first.
You're getting changed,
and we're going.
Just take him like he is.
I'm not gonna get
stuck in the van
for the next three
hours with him like that.
Watch his hands!
Put the gun down! Now!
You shoot me, he dies.
Now, no one is shooting
anyone. Everyone, stay calm.
Give him space.
You did something good,
Boris. Don't ruin it now.
I did nothing, yeah?
I accomplished nothing!
Whatever happens next is
completely in your control.
You have power,
but it's not unlimited.
You're not gonna escape.
You're not just walking out of here.
But there are
things, concessions,
that can make your life better.
So let's just take
our time and talk.
There's no rush.
What do you want, Boris?
What do you really want?
I don't want anyone to help me.
Whatever you call it, these
life-saving measures, I...
No. No.
Do not do it.
No, don't listen to her. It's your
choice. You do what you want.
Yeah.
Boris, no!
Let's go. Let's go. Move! Move!
Melendez is en route.
All right, ready? Let's
go. Three, two, one.
Page urology and
cardio-thoracic, stat.
He's dead, and he
has a donor card.
We're gonna take
everything he can donate.
♪ Our love was hard to
maintain so we broke it ♪
♪ But your smile reminds
me that I cannot lose ♪
♪ More of you ♪
♪ So can we can we
laugh about being crazy ♪
Thank you so much.
Your speech was
perfect and hilarious.
Oh, you're very welcome.
And I appreciate the
opportunity to help change my rep.
You have a rep?
All work and no play.
It's something I'm
working on changing.
Your rep or your lifestyle?
I need less stress and more fun.
Would you like to
play golf sometime?
On a real course
with actual grass?
Absolutely.
Would you like to dance?
I'd love to.
All right, let's go.
♪ Like it's true ♪
♪ So can we laugh
about being crazy ♪
We need to get Eric
prepped right away.
What's happening? Did
you find a new liver donor?
Actually, it's the same one.
Circumstances have changed.
What?
This is incredible.
No, I don't want it.
Eric, when the donor found out
that he couldn't do
the surgery to help you,
he became incredibly sad
because he wanted you to live
more than he wanted to live.
He ended his life
so that you could
have his liver.
He...
He knew he'd done
some bad things,
and I think that this
was the only way
he knew how to make amends.
I think we should
try and help him.
Do you think you can do that,
help someone do something good?
Yeah.
Everything looks good.
Remember to take deep breaths so
you don't develop any lung complications,
and obviously,
avoid lifting anything too
heavy for the next few weeks.
What, honey?
I want a hug.
♪ Over the horizon ♪
♪ She's smooth sailin' ♪
♪ These concrete seas ♪
Wow. You look
like a million bucks.
No, it cost $2,368.
Well, it was worth every penny.
Good investment.
I'm glad to see you're treating
yourself. You deserve it.
How much did your dress cost?
I don't remember.
- Okay.
- And just so you know,
that's not the best question
for an event like this.
Why not?
I don't know. It just isn't.
Okay.
Can I buy you a drink?
I don't like tequila
anymore. It makes me vomit.
Well, okay, they
have other choices.
Glass of wine or a soda?
No, thank you.
Uh, that's a partner at a firm
that did some pro bono
work for us last month, so
I have to go thank him.
Okay. Bye.
♪ I won't wear you down ♪
♪ No, honey, I won't ♪
♪ Wear you down ♪
Hello.
♪ She's smooth ♪
♪ Smooth, darling ♪
There you are. And nicely done.
You got the look. Now
you've got to put it to use.
There's work to do. Mingle.
Okay.
I see you, Dr. Chen.
She runs the Rivington
Fellowship at the Mayo Clinic.
I wonder who brought her here.
I don't know.
Mingle.
You still think
people can't change?
He didn't.
He's an assassin who
murdered people for money.
Today was just one
more cold-blooded killing.
You helped him sacrifice his life
so that he could save someone else.
I am not a fan of what you did.
Look, even if it did prove...
He didn't sacrifice anything.
He died a long time ago.
His crew was probably gone.
In prison, he was a nobody.
And now he lives on as a hero
to Eric's family, to
the press, to you.
Jaundice is improving.
Edema is resolving, too.
His vitals look good.
It's been a great night.
Three other lives
were saved as well.
Do his parents know what he did?
I wanna send them a card.
I know they're gonna be sad, but
I wanna tell them I'll take
good care of their son's liver.
I think that's a great idea.
Wow, this is impressive.
It's kind of like prom
but without the acne.
And with the DJ that played
the MGM Grand last week.
Would you do me the honor?
♪ I bet you think
you look cool ♪
Classy.
I brought my A-game.
♪ They don't play
no more slow cuts ♪
♪ Everything is turned up ♪
♪ I bet you think
you look cool ♪
♪ I'm not the one
to rain on parades ♪
♪ But you in the
club in some shades ♪
♪ What is goin' on now a day ♪
Oh, you better.
What are you doing at the bar?
Oh, you look pretty.
♪ Put on my Sunday best
and show out Show out ♪
♪ I just wanna
have a good time ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ I just wanna have a good time
I just wanna have a good time ♪
Mmm...
The first little
while is the hardest.
And then you move on.
You never did.
Well, that's true.
It doesn't mean
you don't have to.
Maybe.
Thank you. Well,
what are you gonna do?
Are you gonna sit
around and mope?
At least try.
How do I do that?
I don't know. If I knew,
I would have done it.
Let's dance.
Okay. That'll be lovely.
♪ Is this why I
stay in the house? ♪
Don't be shy. You can't hurt
me. I have a bionic sternum.
Ooh, you smell good, Jenny.
What is that, strawberry?
Strawberry mango. It
comes with the lip gloss.
I got it at the mall.
We can go together!
It's a plan. Let's all go.
You know what?
Let's take a selfie.
- Yes.
Yes, that's a great idea.
Okay, bring it in.
Bring it in, guys. Closer.
Peace signs. - Cheese.
Okay, this is so
cool. This is so funny.
Okay.
You remember this?
Should I?
You really don't remember?
No.
What's wrong?
It's the song I played during
our first overnight at the hospital.
♪ I wanna touch
you but I'm too late ♪
We had our first
kiss to this song.
♪ I wanna touch you
but there's history ♪
I'm sorry. It's been a long day.
Yeah.
Jared, it doesn't mean anything.
Yeah, it does.
♪ There's a love
between us still but... ♪
I love you, Claire.
But you never loved me.
And I thought that maybe
someday that would change,
but it won't.
♪ But I know I'm
out of my mind ♪
Goodbye, Claire.
What...
♪ But something's changed
and I don't know why ♪
♪ And all I wanna do
is go home with you ♪
♪ The lights go down ♪
♪ I want you around me ♪
♪ Don't overthink it ♪
♪ Just finish up your
drink and surround me ♪
Not one of them has a
clue how to write the...
Hello, I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
I'm a resident here.
Dr. Jake Levy,
surgical oncology.
Toby Yang, pathology.
May Curtis, ortho.
♪ Surround me ♪
Okay.
Apparently, I was wrong.
I told Dr. Murphy he'd
be fine renting a tuxedo.
Clearly, he chose not to listen.
I'm sorry.
Don't be. You look
fantastic. What is it? Armani?
Yes, it cost...
No, no. Whatever you
paid for it, it was worth it.
How's the golf game, Jake?
Oh, same as always.
I know how that is.
You play golf, Murphy?
I have. But I don't like it.
None of us do.
You know what they say,
"Golf is a good walk spoiled."
Yes, yes.
♪ So don't let me go
No, don't let me go ♪
♪ Surround me, surround me ♪