Previously on The Resident...
You told maintenance about us?
I'm gonna tell everyone!
You are my son and I know you.
And I also know that one
day you will want to meet
your biological mother.
That woman is a stranger
who threw me away.
- I do not want to meet her.
- When you're ready,
- you go see her.
- I want you to meet Cain
and get to know him.
I would just like
you to have this man
- as an ally.
- Page me if there's
- any surprises.
- You're not leaving
this man's nerve
function to a third-year.
Get back there and do your job.
You cross lines that
I would never cross.
We are very different people,
and neither of us are
ever gonna change.
Five other dialysis
patients died.
Whatever killed your
sister, it killed them, too.
One click is all it takes to get
immediate access to the
records of any patient on the drug.
You could be fired for
accessing medical records
for patients that aren't yours.
If we can't get the
answers any other way...
Okay, you got this.
You got it, you got it.
- Hand. Two hand.
- Huh?
- Carpal tunnel? Oh,
'cause there's a celebrity
- called "Carpal Tunnel."
- Don't hate.
Think he's giving you something.
He's-he's giving you something.
Uh, me-me. Ceiling?
- Oh...
- Oh, my God.
- Ten seconds!
- Do something different, do
something different! Yeah, okay...
Give me a ceiling.
Give-give me a microphone.
- Give-give me a house!
- Time!
- Give me a break!
- Rick Astley!
- Obviously.
- I'm lost.
"Never gonna give you up."
- Wow.
- I mean, come on.
I'm gonna raise.
Call your 200...
raise you five.
Out.
Can't take the heat, huh?
Call.
Two pair.
Two pair, aces and kings.
Yeah. All right.
You're the man, Dr. B.
Let's play some
real poker, boys.
$1,000 ante.
♪ ♪
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
Those two seem okay,
after their man-breakup.
- No. Breakup's a bit harsh.
- Conscious uncoupling?
They're just not working
directly together anymore.
Speaking of work, I can't
be in the clinic tomorrow.
Um, do you have a better offer?
I wish. No, I'm
working on neuro.
We lost another nurse.
And Red Rock's policies
are not helping at all.
Keep cutting days
off, adding shifts,
all these overlapping
surgeries...
Yeah, that'll mean
more double shifts.
Or triples, if
triples were a thing.
What's going on?
E-mail update from
the review board.
They are still "working on" my
request for hemopleatin data.
- It's taking too long.
- I know.
The more time, the
more patients could die.
Like Jessie.
I need 20 new celebrity
names from everyone.
Let's go.
Exactly how often will we be
throwing these game nights?
Once a month.
♪ ♪
Up to you, gentlemen.
All right. I'll-I'll go all in.
Come on. You
know I'm out of cash.
What else you got?
Horace Dudley.
- Ortho, 70 years old.
- Keep talking.
In and out every couple of
months for persistent back pain.
X-rays, CTs, MRIs,
nerve conduction
studies, steroid injections.
I've performed multiple
microdiscectomies,
and still he wants more.
You're betting a patient?
Insurance?
Silver hair. Platinum insurance.
I say the pot's right.
What do you got?
Flush to the ace.
It's a good hand.
Not good enough.
Full house, queens over eights.
Sorry about that.
Horace Dudley is now my patient.
♪ ♪
Hemopleatin is
Chastain's standard of care
for chronic anemia patients.
Can't change that
because of a hunch.
It's more than a hunch, but yes.
That's why we
need more evidence.
How long has it been standard?
Since the last administration.
Here. This is every Chastain
patient who's on hemopleatin.
They're all confidential.
Their names are listed,
but you can't get access
to their charts
without getting flagged.
You see that's
not normal, right?
Conrad, your
father's on this list.
He's had blood transfusions
for Crohn's flare-ups.
He must have chronic anemia,
so his GP put him on
hemopleatin to help.
I got a patient.
And if you two get caught
digging into files you
have no access to,
keep my name out of it.
You got to get him off that.
He just got back
in town last night.
I'll have him come in.
I'll call some friends
at Atlanta General.
Someone should
be able to tell me
if they're using it, too.
If they really appreciated us,
they'd get more
nurses, not cookies.
Mm. Mm.
Or at least better cookies. Ugh.
You don't know this about me,
but I make a mean
oatmeal raisin.
- Hmm.
- Maybe for next game night.
Yeah, that sounds good.
In fact, maybe we could host.
You know? Maybe we could, um...
move in together and then host.
Honey, I...
I'm just not into living
with a boy before marriage.
I've done that more than once.
- Oh.
- This artist in Paris
and a teacher in Conyers, so...
The one in Paris was way better.
So, I don't know, it's just
not my thing anymore.
Okay?
- Morning, Horace, I'm Dr...
- Dr. Cain.
Yes. Dr. McGill told us
that you'd be taking
over Horace's care.
He spoke very highly of you.
Your mug's on the
side of the building,
- so you must be the best.
- I can't deny that.
And I'm Nic,
the nurse practitioner
on your case.
How are you feeling
today, Horace?
Better than before
my last surgery,
but worse since
my last injection.
His lumbar spinal
fusion, the last epidural.
Those are beautiful.
She keeps busy when we're here.
- We're here a lot. So
I looked at your scans,
and good news:
all the problems you've had
for decades, I can fix them.
Permanently.
- Where is he?
- Wha... Uh,
Dr. Bell? He is 15 out,
and then he's
going straight to PT.
- Thank you, Grayson.
- No problemo.
Do you know anything
about an ortho patient
named Horace Dudley?
Yeah. Yeah! Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Cain got him with a baller hand.
Trip-queens over eights.
Dr. Cain won my
patient in a poker game?
This man in need of a miracle.
Is this the patient
you won in poker?
Yeah, that's correct.
Now, look at the degeneration
of the discs. No wonder
- he's been in and out
of here for years.
- Yeah, so what's your plan?
Cervical spinal fusions?
If I wanted to go the
ordinary route, yeah, sure.
But I'm not ordinary.
Artificial disc surgery.
But not just one.
I'm gonna replace all
four of the affected discs.
What, a four-level
disc replacement?
- Has that ever been done?
- Not in the United States.
So when I'm done, Horace
Dudley will have a bionic spine.
There are no U.S. studies
on long-term outcomes
for multiple artificial discs.
Every study needs
a first patient.
Horace Dudley
will be that patient.
Well, great. I'll just need
to see the overseas data
before I can sign
off on the surgery.
Sure. I'll send them right now.
♪ ♪
Oh. Mm.
Dr. Broome.
Uh... Bonnie.
Please call me that.
I-I know you have
a mom, Dr. Austin.
They call him A.J.
So, lunch?
A poker game?
Are you kidding me?
- Good morning to you, too.
- No. You can't gloss this over.
This is wrong on
every level imaginable.
You gambled a person.
Look, now, hold
it. That wasn't me.
A bunch of men drinking,
betting, gambling with a life.
- You're complicit.
- So, what are you
actually mad about?
The drinking? The
gambling? Men in general?
Patients are human beings
with needs, not poker chips.
Horace Dudley
is my ortho patient
who sometimes makes
the uninformed choice
of finding surgeons
to do operations
I've warned him against.
I've been encouraging
him to go to PT,
and now, after one
night of Texas hold 'em...
What does it matter
how Cain got him?
This is a patient who is
going to go to a neurosurgeon.
He's proved that over and over.
And Cain's as good as
McGill. He's better even.
This is a radical surgery
that might paralyze or kill him.
It's a proven technique; it just
hasn't made its way here yet.
Oh, and because it's Cain,
and he brings in millions,
we have no problem
being the first.
Well, somebody
has to, you know that.
Forget it. I'm
going to the board.
I'll tell them he trades
patients over cards,
publicize his surgical notes,
file a complaint with the AMA.
- No, don't. Don't.
- Why the hell not?
Be-Because this is why
I'm keeping him close.
The board will side
with Cain, and he...
he'll destroy you.
I don't want to see that happen.
Thanks for the
vote of confidence.
Oh, Kit, come on.
What... Wh-What
are you gonna do?
Turn your head all the
way to the left for me.
Stop when you hit pain.
- Uh, uh, r-right there.
- Okay.
- That-that hurts.
- Okay, now go all the way
back to the right.
This stops now.
How can I help you, Dr. Voss?
How about you start by
telling your patient the truth?
Horace has already been
fully briefed on his
upcoming surgery.
Dr. Cain won you
in a poker game.
Excuse me?
Your original neurosurgeon,
Dr. Vince McGill,
ran out of chips, so he
put your name in the pot.
Like betting a car.
Only he bet you, and lost.
Lab extension 2419...
What'd you have?
Full house, queens over eights.
I won 20 grand in Vegas
once, queens over eights.
He thought he
had me with a flush.
Of course, he didn't.
I remember one time,
about three months ago, right,
I drew sixes on a big
blind. Flop, nothing.
The river was sweet.
- You know what it was, yeah.
- Yeah.
Thanks for getting here so fast.
Well, when my son summons
me for an ASAP checkup,
I do as I'm told.
How's the device company?
It's never easy to
challenge the status quo,
- but you know that.
- Yeah.
- So, what's going on?
- Hopefully nothing.
I'm just a little concerned
about one of the meds you're on,
so I wanted to check you out.
I feel fine. Couple of
Crohn's flares now and then,
but, uh, the steroids help.
All right, we're
just right here.
Leg swelling? Chest pain?
No, none of that.
Breathing okay?
Well, a little shortness
of breath here and there,
but I figure that's age,
plus a little too much
room service on the road.
Okay, I'll do a quick
exam down here,
and then we'll run up to CT,
so I can rule out a blood clot.
I missed you.
I missed you, too.
Did I tell you Nic
and I got chickens?
Hi, good morning.
Hi, I'm Dr. Okafor.
Rosie. This is Lacy.
And...
- I'm sorry, I just...
- You're fine.
Thank you.
I've had to be strong
for her, you know.
What are Lacy's symptoms?
She used to be so smart.
All this energy,
all these friends.
And now her teachers
say that she's not playing
with anyone at recess, and
she can't keep up in class.
They might hold her back.
A mental disorder wouldn't
cause this kind of lethargy.
I will run some tests,
and then we can see
what we're dealing with.
Um... will it take a long time?
We don't have clinics in Dawson,
and the hospital
is so expensive.
I already had to take
off a shift at the diner
to drive here.
I was only supposed
to take three hours,
and you know traffic
coming into Atlanta.
I will do everything I
can to help you both.
Thanks.
I got to take this. I'll
meet you guys inside.
Yo.
So I have an out
if you need one.
Oh, well, that's
tempting. What is the out?
A child with an undiagnosed
condition and heart murmur.
You and Mother of Raptors
could come in for a consult.
Hard pass.
You're just trying to get
a look at my bio mom.
I'm trying to save this family
the expense of an ER visit.
I'll think about it.
I'll be back to you.
Jessica doesn't want to move
in with me unless we're married.
You know she lived
with an artist? In Paris.
I've never even been to Paris.
I'm not sure what
you're looking for here.
Jessica's done
all this stuff, right?
She's had real
relationships before me.
I haven't. Not really.
You know the one time I
downloaded a dating app,
I was too freaked
out to even open it.
Now all I do is
pay student loans
and hang out with you.
I'm boring.
I've never even had car sex.
Does an RV count?
Look, Jessica took her
path, you took yours.
They brought you to each other.
Don't let insecurity
ruin a good thing.
Okay, Dr. Wisdom.
Okay, no, I know
that I'm not exactly the guy
to give out relationship advice.
The woman I left at
the altar is now dating
some hotshot sportscaster
in San Francisco
while I spend my days with you.
So do as I say, not as I do.
Hi, Mr. Jones.
No, Jonesy, if
you would. Please.
Hurt your arm, Jonesy?
Fat Charlie got his revenge.
Was it because you
called him Fat Charlie?
No, no. Fat Charlie is my horse.
I know what you're thinking.
I'm too old to still be
a professional jockey.
My wife tells me every day.
Of course, she's
a horse trainer,
so she can work forever.
Is she here yet?
She hasn't checked in.
Preemptive apology if she's
a little much. She worries.
- It's understandable.
- Maybe it's time to quit.
Never.
If I'm not on the
back of a horse,
I'm not alive.
You got to fix me up.
Jonesy, you have a
fracture of your distal radius.
See that?
Now, yours is easily treatable
and won't need surgery,
but we're also seeing
signs of low bone density.
We need to run some
tests. Okay? We'll be back.
That's another
thing I've never done.
- What, break your arm?
- No, ride a horse. Have you?
Yeah.
See?
Let me guess, third cup?
- Fourth. You?
- Second.
- I need to catch up.
- Mm.
You're not the only one.
- Hey, Cindy.
- Mm?
Wake up.
- What time is it?
- I was gonna say
time to prep Cain's OR,
but I don't think you should
be doing that right now.
- It's okay. I'm fine.
- You're exhausted.
Who isn't? We're
overstaffed, underlapped.
Flipped around, upside down.
Sorry, coffee just kicked in.
With all these
overlapping surgeries,
they don't think about us.
Nurses and techs... we're
here early to set up the ORs.
And we stay after and make
sure everything is cleaned up.
First in, last out, from
one OR to the next.
All so Red Rock can
schedule more operations
and make more money.
No comment.
But I'm pulling rank.
Go home, get some rest.
I'll look around, there's
got to be someone
- who can swap with you.
- Me. I got you covered.
Jessica, you just finished
back-to-back surgeries, too.
Well, then I'll be in
back-to-back-to-back surgeries.
I may as well ride
this second wind.
Okay.
Scalpel.
Retractor.
Curette.
You've hardly spilled
a drop of blood.
Anything is possible in my OR.
Disc.
- You okay in there?
- Great.
Like a free nap.
- How's he doing?
- So far so good.
Nice to see you, Marshall.
Okay, I just have a second.
Jessica's covering
for Cindy in the OR,
so I'm trying to find someone
to cover for Jessica on the floor.
Anyway, I heard back
from my friend at General.
Hemopleatin patients
have died there, too.
A dialysis patient. Had
a PE just like Jessie.
He had two kids.
We need those records.
And someone in Oncology
who has more access.
I'm gonna try something else.
Do you have any nurses
who can help out in Neuro?
Cain scheduled way
more than we can manage.
Sorry, we're short, too.
Happy freakin' Nurses' Day.
- Hey.
Can I steal you for 30 seconds?
I got 20. What's up?
You did that
rotation in Oncology.
Were there any doctors that...
might be willing to
think outside the box?
I'm not sure what you mean.
Conrad and I think there's
a problem with this drug,
hemopleatin.
We're trying to find a doctor
who will share patient outcomes,
- but if we can't...
- You mean open patient
records that aren't yours.
That's an invasion of
privacy, plus it's illegal.
You could be fired.
My sister might have died
because of this drug.
So, honestly, I
don't give a damn.
Rules exist for a reason, Nic.
You can't just go break
them because in the moment
you think it's right.
You and Conrad, I love you guys,
but I thought I
made myself clear:
I am not going to
be that kind of doctor.
But we'd only been
dating a month.
It was more like three weeks.
I can't even say for
sure we were in love.
You were in love, I was in lust.
Let her talk.
Medical school was like a dream.
Full ride, good grades.
I understand.
You had priorities.
No. No, not priorities.
That's... No, that's...
Harsh. We were kids.
She could have
ended the pregnancy.
Credit us that.
We saw it through.
I managed to stay in med school.
I hid the pregnancy
from everyone.
And then...
- we...
- Then you gave me away.
There's no judgment
here. Really, there isn't.
But we should at
least be honest, right?
I mean, he didn't want
me because he didn't think
I was his.
And then, by the time I
was born, you decided
you were going to be
together, so next thing you know,
you got married and
you had three more kids.
The marriage was
fast, the kids were not.
They came ten
years later. It's...
At 22, it wasn't just
Lamar who wasn't ready.
I didn't think I would
be a good mother.
I still don't know
if I ever was.
But I knew I would
be a good doctor.
A really good one.
And it was a time when
there were almost no doctors
who looked like me.
That mattered.
I had a goal, a mission,
something to prove,
and I proved it.
You know what? Since
you're such a good doctor,
can you do me a favor?
Come with me to a peds consult.
Right now?
Yeah.
Stay.
Eat.
Well, that expression
doesn't look like,
"Hey, Dad, you're dying."
Lungs are clear. No blood clots.
Good. Now why don't you tell me
the part you wouldn't
tell me before?
The drug you're
on, hemopleatin...
I think it may have
caused Jessie's death.
- Nic knows?
- Yeah.
Not easy.
Right now we only have
anecdotal evidence that it happened.
I need access to a
large sample of patients,
and I can't even get the
data from this hospital.
And I work here.
Conrad, let me in.
Maybe I can help.
- Henrietta.
- Yes, dear?
- What's wrong?
- I can't breathe.
Oh... Somebody help!
Help!
Call a Code Blue, get
me an intubation kit.
What's happening?
His throat is closing.
It's a complication
of Cain's surgery.
We need to intubate him.
Hang in there, Horace.
Throat's swollen shut.
- I can't get it in.
- Sat's 70%.
- Did somebody call Cain?
- It went to voice mail.
He's suffocating. We're out
of time. We need an airway.
That's it. We can't wait.
Get me a cric kit now.
Code team's on their way.
Wait, you're gonna cric him?
- Sats?
- 60%.
Then, yeah, I'm cricing him.
Come on, come on, come on.
Trach tube.
We're in.
02 sats are rising.
What in God's name
happened here?
This is Cain's patient.
Have you paged him?
Cain signed out. He's
not answering pages, texts,
- carrier pigeons.
- Well, then, wait
until you do hear from him.
- If the patient
isn't emergent...
- The patient needed to be criced
because of Cain's operation.
- I can fix him now,
I'm not waiting.
- Let's just give Cain
a couple of hours.
Because you're worried
about what he'll say
- if I do this.
- No, Kit.
Because I'm worried
about what he will do to you.
It'll be bad for you if you
take one of Cain's patients
to surgery without
consulting him.
Horace is my patient now, and I
didn't win him with a card game.
I got him because Cain's
unjustifiable experiment
nearly killed the man.
His life is still in jeopardy,
so I must try and save him.
And I hope to God I can.
It looks like Jonesy has
early-onset osteoporosis.
His chart says he's got celiac.
Low bone density is
a common problem.
Not if he's stays gluten-free,
which he says he is.
Mm. He can't keep riding.
Another fall and his bones
could shatter like glass.
Poor guy. We have
to break it to him.
Well, at least he got
to have the experience
in the first place.
Wendy Jones?
Right here.
Hi.
- Hi.
- Hey.
- You almost done here?
- Yep, shift's over.
- You want to grab a bite to eat?
- Not quite.
You have a suit?
Uh, I'm not a three-year-old.
- Yeah, I have a suit.
- Great.
Get it, put it on, let's meet
back here in one hour.
I'll text you the details.
Whoa, whoa, wait.
Where are we going?
- D.C.
- D.C.?
Yeah. My jet's fueled
up and on the runway.
I think I can get you all of
the data you could ever need.
He said
his stomach hurt and
then he started throwing up.
Dying, hurts like dying.
- Need me?
- Heart rate is 176.
He's in AFib with RVR.
All right, let's get
20 of diltiazem.
Let's get a liter
of normal saline
and give four of ondansetron.
Deep breaths.
- That's better.
- Okay, let's get him to CT,
- see what's going on.
- I don't know what happened,
We were sitting
here the whole time.
Except for when I went to the...
Open your mouth.
You ate a death cookie.
Jonesy knows he's
allergic to gluten.
Yeah, he also
knows that eating it
helps him stay on
his stupid horse.
Uh, the truth is,
I had a cookie.
Hmm.
Three cookies.
So you eat gluten,
flares up your celiac,
and the aftereffects
keep the weight off.
- Hmm.
- Well, look, it's harder to keep
the weight off at my age.
If I get too heavy for
Fat Charlie, then...
You won't be able
to ride anymore.
Not professionally.
Except when celiac is
flared, it stops your body
from absorbing
nutrients like it should.
That is why your
arm broke so easily.
We met at the track.
You fell in love with a jockey.
If I'm not riding
anymore, who are we?
Honey.
Sure,
the riding crop and
the cute little pants
and the helmet were
what did it for me at first.
But then, when I fell in
love, I fell in love with you.
Dude.
You've got someone
who loves you.
Don't ruin that for something
that doesn't make sense anymore.
It's time to hang up
the saddle, Jonesy.
You don't have to
retire the whip, though.
Mama has needs.
I'm out.
Meredith, glasses. Jessica.
Dr. Bell. How's your back doing?
I'm all right, thanks.
We have to figure out what
happened to Cain's poker prize.
Aren't you worried about
angering the great Dr. Cain?
I'm the CEO, so, frankly, no.
I'm here to help.
You figure out what happened?
Retropharyngeal hematoma.
Compressed his airway.
Well.
What have we got here?
One of the manufacturer's
discs was defective. It happens.
Certainly. But it's more likely
with each disc that's inserted.
Taking these out,
gonna put 'em back.
Okay, let's-let's
start with this one.
She seems nice from here.
Is this normal for Lacy?
No. She's been doing
harder puzzles for years.
Here, let me have it.
It's okay.
- Have you ever seen a cow?
- I saw a baby deer.
- Where?
- I think she means at camp.
Our church took
the kids in July.
To North Carolina,
in the mountains.
Lacy brought books.
Picture books. She was...
She was good then.
She was reading.
She came back like this?
No, she was fine
when she got back.
She had a flu. It was rough.
A flu. How long
after her return?
Couple of weeks. Had to
miss the first day of school.
The mountains of North
Carolina in July, that is tick season.
Lyme disease.
But she doesn't have a rash.
Sometimes it doesn't show up.
Sometimes it's
hidden under the hair.
Lacy, have your
bones been hurting?
Lyme is known as
"The Great Imitator."
It can mimic
virtually any disease.
Untreated, it can also
cause neurological symptoms.
That could be the source of the
cognitive decline you're seeing.
But don't worry, it is treatable
if diagnosed this early.
We'll run a test to confirm,
but if this is Lyme,
I am quite certain
we can get Lacy back
to herself in no time.
You hear that, baby?
It's gonna be okay.
There you are.
Whoa. Is this a
surprise date night?
Going to a shareholder meeting.
This is a Marshall thing.
He knows the CEO of this
kidney dialysis company in D.C.
They handle 50% of the
renal patients in the U.S.
We're hoping they're gonna let
us take a look at their database
for hemopleatin patients.
You are a rock star.
Who kind of looks like a spy.
Good luck. Let me
know how it goes.
Maybe think about wearing
that suit to our next date night.
Can't keep a
fireman from the fire.
I was gonna call you.
Dr. Okafor and I agree
that you saved that
little girl from a lifetime
of preventable disabilities.
I'm glad I could help.
You are a good doctor.
You don't think I
loved you enough
or wanted you enough,
but how could I? I...
I didn't know what your
adoptive family had named you.
The records were
sealed back then.
So...
every time a little boy
came into my office,
if he was the right age...
and had the right color of skin,
I looked for you in his eyes.
I...
I never stopped looking.
Well, now you can.
Would it be moving too fast
if I invited you
to Thanksgiving?
Um...
I spend Thanksgiving
with my family.
The one that raised me.
I understand that.
But maybe there's
something we can work out.
No promises, but...
Understood.
Even if this doesn't
work, what you are doing
is above and beyond, so...
thank you.
Well, it's the annual
meeting of one of the top two
dialysis companies
in the country, so...
it'll be a blast, right?
Not exactly, but,
hey, if they'll give us the data
on hemopleatin,
it'll be well worth it.
How many of these things
have you been to in your life?
Hundreds.
Okay. What's the plan?
Try to stay awake
through the financials.
You'll see. It's so boring,
half the people fall asleep.
When the speeches are over,
we'll find the CEO, Jim DeLoach,
and we'll go from there.
Shareholders of DiaCure,
I present to you our CEO
and the man behind the
miracle, Jim DeLoach!
♪ Here we go! ♪
♪ No ♪
♪ No way ♪
♪ No one ♪
♪ Gonna ♪
♪ Stop now, go! ♪
♪ Save the complaints ♪
♪ For a party ♪
♪ Conversation ♪
♪ The world is loaded... ♪
Well, this is new.
♪ It's lit to pop and
nobody ain't gonna stop ♪
♪ No ♪
♪ One. ♪
All right. All right, all right!
- The moment you've
all been waiting for is now.
- Yeah!
The DiaCure financial release!
Goliath.
Hey!
♪ ♪
And this year,
DiaCure's pretax
operating profit was...
$1.2 billion!
Yeah!
So, this is our big data guy.
Welcome to
corporate health care.
♪ Love teachers ♪
♪ It's lit to pop and
nobody ain't gonna stop. ♪
Success.
You saved Horace Dudley's
life and his ability to walk.
Not that we should have
had to do that surgery.
That man had four hockey
pucks shoved in his spine.
Is that what you'll
tell the board?
Cain is not one
of the good guys.
But if I go to war
with him and lose,
I won't be here
to fix his mistakes.
I agree completely.
You won't be able to save the
Horace Dudleys of the world.
So I'm not giving up.
I promise you I'm not.
I'm just gonna have to
fight in a different way.
Dr. Cain.
I owe you an explanation.
I assume it's about
how you took my patient
into the OR without
my permission.
You were wrong to
perform that operation.
I've heard enough. I'm filing
a complaint with the board.
No, wait, please.
Uh, what I mean is,
I believe you were wrong.
That doesn't make it so.
We both have different
approaches to patient care.
We just do.
I can't fault you for leaning
into Red Rock's mandate.
You also can't fault
me for doing things
the way I've always done them.
So maybe there's a
way we can keep an eye
on each other's
surgical practices...
while making an extraordinary
amount of money along the way.
What'd you have in mind?
A joint venture.
An ortho-spine surgery center
for comprehensive spine care.
To include neuro
and ortho surgery
and physical therapy.
Both quality and
quantity of patients.
Agreed.
- Thanks, Jules.
- Mr. DeLoach,
this man says that he knows you.
"Winnie the Winner" Winthrop.
- How you been?
- Fantastic.
You the son? Look
just like your old man.
Conrad Hawkins.
Dr. Conrad Hawkins,
Chastain Park in Atlanta.
No kidding. That's amazing.
So what are you doing here?
Been way too long
since the Old Green.
Was a private
gentlemen's club in D.C.
It's a hell of a thing
you've got here.
A falcon?
Yeah. Always loved the birds.
So, you kids want a drink?
Actually, we need
help with something.
Anything for the old Winnie.
Your database. We're doing
a little research on a drug.
Bigger the sample size,
more accurate the data will be.
No problem. It's all yours.
That's-that's great.
That's a big help.
Just need a little
something from you fellas.
Little QPQ.
I've had my eye on
Chastain for a while.
Big market, lot of promise.
An exclusive with DiaCure renal
services would help us all out.
Think you can make that happen?
Okay.
So, five seconds of action,
and then I'm on the road.
Usually, it's at
least ten seconds.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
- Okay.
- That's it?
Five seconds are up.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
Next time, don't waste it, or
else I'll have to punish you.
- Ooh, a consequence?
- Mm-hmm.
Bring it.
Think he'll be back to the ER?
My guess is, he's
done with horses.
Yeah, the next time we see
him, it'll be for a sex injury.
He gets it.
So do I.
Stupid to question
the love of your life
for something
that's just... stupid.
So Jessica is the
love of your life.
Nicely done, man.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH