Since the early 1900s,
morbidity and mortality
conferences, or "M&M"s,
have helped surgeons learn
from cases
where there was
a serious complication.
Or a fatal outcome.
No.
♪ I'm going for show
♪ Just give me
a beat and melody ♪
During M&Ms, we assess both
systematic and personal errors.
We review every step,
every decision.
We get to the bottom of what
happened and how it happened.
Yeah?
♪ I got this stage
Room service.
Hi.
Thank you.
You, uh,
get your kids to school?
I did.
Good.
They were five minutes early.
Mm-hmm.
They're never
five minutes early.
What's your day look like?
Tedious.
I have a follow-up with
Hamilton, and then I have
to watch someone I really like
get interrogated in an M&M.
Anything good?
No, he avulsed the IMA
right off the aorta
during an ileostomy takedown.
Patient bled to death.
And there was no attending
in the room.
Oof.
Yeah.
What time's your flight?
I have to leave for the airport
in about 20 minutes.
I wish you were staying.
I have 20 minutes.
♪ You know,
I'll seal your fate ♪
We consider what we could have
done better or differently...
Wow.
♪ Uh-huh
I know.
♪ Face present and I feel
something coming for ya ♪
♪ Na-na-na-na-na
Oh, you were right.
This is fun.
♪ Can't escape, but it's okay
...and hope we never make
the same mistake ever again.
♪ A hook and a verse
♪ A couple of words
♪ Watch me do this
♪ Got it in your head
Hey.
How was Mr. Yeyni's CABG?
Oh, smooth. Yeah.
Were you able to
talk to Richard?
No.
All he said when I asked him
about it was,
"Save it for the M&M."
Well, I mean,
he's not wrong.
We are
a teaching hospital.
I know M&M's are essential,
but I hate them.
Both things are true.
Dr. Manner to the E.R.
Grey!
Here, take this.
A ventral hernia repair.
Patient's name is Franks.
1443.
Wait.
Right now?
Yeah.
What about the M&M?
A-Aren't I supposed to weigh in?
No one else is available,
and I need to run the M&M,
so unless you're
needed on a plane,
I really need you
in O.R. 3.
Okay.
I'm on it.
But, you know,
go easy on Schmitt.
I'm sure he's suffering enough,
and he's come a long way.
He's still not here yet.
Where is he?
I don't know.
Doesn't he live with you?
I don't put GPS locators
on my roommates, do you?
No need to be rude.
Do you think you'll have
to go up there? Since
you were in the room?
Hey,
where's Schmitt?
I don't know!
Okay.
Okay, we all have
surgeries and clinic,
so I'm gonna go ahead
and get started.
Um, ask questions as they arise.
Keep them constructive.
We are a teaching hospital.
This is how we learn.
Dr. Schmitt
will be presenting...
Uh...
Okay, so, our first case is
colorectal surgery service.
26 year-old male...
♪♪
Dr. Schmitt.
The case is a 26-year-old male
with history
of ulcerative colitis.
...at which point,
we were about ready to proceed
with stapling the anastomosis,
but I felt that I needed better
exposure of the small bowel,
so I reached into the cavity.
Questions are not encouraged --
They're required.
Dr. Wright,
ask a question.
Um...
Uh, had you observed
any bleeding at that point?
No.
Did you have good visualization
on what you were
putting traction on?
I believed I did.
Okay.
At that point,
everything was dry
and ready for anastomosis.
As stated, the patient...
It's been so long since
I've seen a waterfall in person.
Dr. Schmitt?
Continue.
Um,
everything was dry and, um...
the field was clean,
so I asked for the GIA stapler.
But there was --
Um...
There, uh --
There was no indication
of any abnormal anatomy or
friable structures, right?
That you could see,
I mean.
What?
Meaning you
couldn't have predicted
that the aorta was
gonna rupture...
This is just the best.
Yeah. I'm gonna stay here
awhile, you guys.
It was an unanticipated
complication.
Is there a question in there
somewhere, Helm?
I didn't think so.
Schmitt, go.
Uh, that -- that was the...
the f-- the field, it filled
with blood, and, um...
I'm -- I'm sorry.
You're Devon Gomez.
Never knew I had a groupie.
It's nice to meet you,
Dr. Schmitt.
Schmitt, call it.
I killed Devon.
I, uh...
I just -- I killed him.
He's dead.
Dr. Schmitt,
look, we are here --
Dr. Schmitt, no, no.
We are here to determine
what ha-- and how to --
Hey, no, no, no!
The M&M isn't finished.
Um, un-until
Dr. Schmitt returns,
Dr. Webber
will take the questions.
If Dr. Schmitt was
the primary surgeon
and you're the attending,
who's in charge?
The Webber Method dictates
that a resident cannot go on
to the next step
in the procedure
without an attending
being present.
Yeah, I-I understand
what the method is, sir.
I'm just not sure I understand
the chain of command.
I beg your pardon?
Well, I mean, the --
the Webber Method
seems to rotate authority
during surgery
depending on
which step you're on,
which, with all due respect,
sir, seems...confusing.
Perhaps a little more time
in our program
would help clear up
any confusion.
Alright, let's get back
to the next question, please.
In a Webber Method surgery,
can you just remind us
what exactly happens
if a complication arises,
even if it's not at
the predetermined step
when an attending
would need to be called?
Well, an attending
should be called anyway.
Right, but for all
intents and purposes,
your method sets up
these senior residents
as the attendings,
right?
Didn't you specifically
use the word "attendings"
when you first
introduced the method?
"Today you will be
the attendings."
...you will be the attendings.
Welcome to the Webber Method.
Dr. Webber, was there ever
a meeting of department heads
to discuss whether
we should adopt
this particular
teaching style?
Does that
make a difference?
Well, yes, I mean,
we have meetings to discuss
what brand of sutures
we're going to buy.
Why not meet about this?
Are other hospitals using this,
Catherine?
Other
foundation hospitals?
Dr. Webber is your
chief medical officer, Dr. Fox.
The method's
named after him.
You never considered
that there would be
negative consequences
or a P.R. nightmare?
Dr. Lin, you recently
promoted the Webber Method
while recruiting
new residents.
This is a teaching tool,
my dear,
not some risky
cure for cancer.
It's a teaching tool that
cost a patient their life.
Dr. Bailey,
you initially
expressed reservations
about the method.
What changed for you?
Is the M&M on the patient
or the Webber Method?
Because the method
didn't hold the scalpel.
Thank you.
Well, there are clearly
residents who are not ready.
What about
the American Board of Surgery?
Have they sanctioned it?
Everybody, just please.
Dr. Webber is just prioritizing
our education.
- We're here to learn.
- Okay, everyone.
Why would they weigh in on a
method for general procedure?
We need to get back
to asking questions.
- What they need to approve...
- This hospital...
Here we go.
How's the pain?
It's okay.
It's not terrible.
Good.
Listen, Owen,
I-I know that
you have gone through
something horrible,
and I've given it two days,
but now I'm gonna
sit here until you tell me
what the hell
is going on.
Noah's wife
has called the house
several times
looking for you.
Why?
Teddy --
Owen, after everything
that we've been through,
after 20 years,
I deserve the truth.
What does Heather want?
Why did Hayes quit?
I know that something
happened in the car.
Can you just tell me,
please?
You're right.
Something happened in the car.
But, Teddy, I'm asking you
to trust me.
I can't tell you.
What about me?
Don't I deserve the same?
Doesn't trust
go both ways?
Of course, but --Owen, it's me.
You can sit there as long
as you want, okay?
But I'm not
gonna tell you.
I love you.
But I can't.
You can.
But you won't.
Okay, I won't.
♪♪
Legal hasn't heard anything
from the Gomez family.
We may avoid a lawsuit
altogether.
Hmm.
But you still have some
decisions to make.
I have some
decisions to make?
He's my husband, Dr. Bailey,
but this is your hospital.
The method was successful
as long as the residents
stuck to it.
But surgical residents are
not known for their humility,
so whether or not
the method continues on
after this suspension,
it's up to you.
Dr. O'Dell to the ICU.
Dr. O'Dell...
Hey, ventral hernia's
repaired.
How was the M&M?
I want to check in on Richard
before my VIP's scans.
The M&M was awful.
Richard needs space.
But I put you down for
a Roux-en-Y hepaticojejunostomy
in O.R. 4.
Oh, well, I've already
over-scheduled my own day.
I want to help you,
but I can't --
Look at my face.
This is a desperate face.
This is
a-a begging face.
I'm desperate
and I'm begging,
and I'm asking for
your help, Grey.
Look, I'm down a trauma surgeon,
a cardio surgeon,
a peds surgeon,
and now a resident
'cause Schmitt walked out.
And t-the rest of them
are so traumatized
that they'll probably
need a safe space
and a week off
to feel their feelings.
Okay.
I can take the hepatico-J.
And I know someone
who can do the hernia repair.
Ideally, a surgeon.
Uh-huh.
Hi.
Hey. You okay?
You kinda went after
Richard in the M&M.
I went after the method.
Right, but the Webber Method
is Richard.
Do you still stand by it?
The Webber Method? After
everything that we just heard?
We don't use it in
our department,
so I'm not really
sure that I can --
I know that you respect Richard.
We all do.
It's why I wanted to speak
to him before the M&M.
Maggie, the method works.
You just haven't
been around to see it.
Exactly.
I haven't been around,
and I come back
and Richard's new
teaching method
has gotten someone killed,
and no one is being honest
with him about it.
So, you respect him,
but I love him,
so I'm gonna keep
telling him the truth.
Okay?
Okay.
I gotta take this.
Alright.
Thank you, Carla.
Hey, um, have you
seen Levi anywhere?
No one has seen him
since the M&M.
No, I've been swamped
all morning.
Oh, uh, I might have
a double arthroplasty later.
You want in?
Films show major scar tissue,
so it should be fun.
Things better with
you and Shepherd?
Uh, no.
But...I feel great.
Dr. Burkes to oncology.
Hello.
I'm Dr. Lincoln.
What seems to be going on?
Uh, Ms. Hanley.
Second grade science teacher.
Wish she had been mine.
Please, call me Lila.
Not even my students
call me Ms. Hanley.
Anyway, uh,
my leg's numbed up again.
I've got shooting pains
right below the knee.
But this time
when it happened,
I barely made it down
the staircase at the IMAX.
Northwest Science Center.
We go every year
during winter camp.
X-rays show
some minimal changes
indicative
of osteoarthritis.
Okay.
Uh, you said "this time."
This has happened before?
It's happened
a couple times.
Cortisone shot
usually does the trick,
but now my leg's
a little off.
And no allergic reaction
to the cortisone?
No.
Okay.
Perez here will do
a work-up on your knee,
and we'll see if we can
get you that shot.
Uh...
Morning, Francesca.
I would say it's
good to see you,
but I really wish
I wasn't back here.
We're gonna figure out why.
Tseng?
Francesca Lyons, 26.
Complains of continued pain
in the lower back.
Treated for pain from
mildly herniated discs
with an epidural injection
three weeks ago
and another
six weeks ago.
Do you mind if
I take a look?
Has the pain been consistent
since your last injection?
I felt great during
the first week.
I hiked in Discovery Park,
I biked around the waterfront,
and I got back on Bumble.
Sounds very busy.
I started having sex again,
but the pain just came back,
same as the time before.
And now I am on my period, so
I have horrible cramps and this.
Tseng, would you call
for a GYN consult?
Perfect. Lady problems.
That won't be embarrassing to
bring up with my new boyfriend.
Hiker or biker?
Neither.
He's got a boat,
which normally I hate
because sharks
are close to boats.
But I'd be willing to suck it up
because he is so, so hot.
He is shark-risk hot.
He wants to cruise around
Puget Sound next week,
and I want to
have sex on a boat.
We will see what
we can do.
Hayes! Hey.
I've been
looking for you.
Do you have a second?
Sure.
So, I heard you quit.
I have some cases
to hand off.
But, uh...yeah.
Bailey can't
lose you right now.
I know.
Well, I've been
trying to call you.
It's been pretty hectic
getting the boys packed up.
So, what?
Your whole life flashed
before your eyes
and you realized you're unhappy
here and need to quit?
Something like that.
And your plan was to leave
without saying goodbye?
Yeah.
Why?
Because if I said goodbye
to you, Grey,
I might not
actually leave.
♪♪
In all the years
since Abigail died,
you're the first person
who got it.
You made me
feel less alone.
You helped me believe
there might even be life
after Abigail.
Thank you for that.
♪♪
Take care.
You too.
♪♪
Hi, Francesca.
I'm Dr. DeLuca,
and this is Dr. Wilson.
Hi, there.
Hi.
You're gonna stay with me,
right?
Of course. Yeah, we're gonna
figure this out together.
So, I treated Francesca
for back pain
and minor degenerative
disc disease,
but her pain coincides
with her period,
she's on oral contraceptives,
and she has pain with sex.
Okay, yeah, okay.
Um, thank you, Dr. Shepherd.
Francesca, would you mind
if Dr. Wilson examines you?
Go for it.
Thank you.
Okay, um...so how long
have you been having severe pain
with your periods?
Since I was the girl
sitting on the bleachers
for half the month
during P.E.
Nothing like 30 eighth graders
knowing your menstrual cycle.
Okay, you're gonna feel
a little pressure, okay?
Ahh! Ooh.
Has you ever been evaluated
for endometriosis?
Mnh-mnh.
It's when the cells that line
the inside of the uterus
grow outside the uterus,
and in some cases,
the tissue can accumulate
in one space.
Now, that would also
explain the back pain,
if that's where
the tissue built up.
A little pressure.
Okay,
the good thing is,
if it is that,
then it is treatable.
When do we start,
and how long is recovery?
We'll schedule
a diagnostic surgery,
and if endometriosis is present,
we'll do what we can
to try and remove it
when you're ready.
The sooner the better.
I've got things to do.
And by "things,"
I mean my new boyfriend.
Never underestimate
the value of pain-free sex.
Let's see if we can
get it done today.
Yeah.
♪♪
Okay.
Privileges received.
Pays to have an in,
I guess.
Thank for coming back.
Sure.
You're saving our sanity.
Yes.
And a man's life,
of course.
Of course.
Okay. What do we got?
45-year-old man
with a right-sided
direct inguinal hernia.
Okay.
Five months of pain.
Booked for
an open repair.
Okay, got it.
And what do you have?
Hepatico-J.
Sorta feels like
you took the fun one.
I would never do that.
Never?
Have fun.
You're going to O.R. 3.
Okay. O.R. 3.
You're gonna need
scrubs first.
Oh. Thank God.
Nurse Hazard to the O.R.
Construction accident.
Something with a circular saw.
I believe she just
needs sutures,
but there could be
debris inside.
Okay,
have we gotten an X-ray,
cleaned out
and examined the wound?
No.
I'm waiting for the twist in the
story as for why you haven't.
I-I thought you'd want to
examine her first.
Just in case, you know?
Or you could observe
while I do the exam.
I-I wanted to make sure
that I was doing it right.
Well, you haven't done anything,
so how could it be wrong?
X-ray, irrigation,
lap tray now!
Okay, yeah.
Wha...
Nurse Cline, extension 2219.
Perez, what's Lila
still doing here?
She wanted
a cortisone injection.
Uh, that's why
I paged you.
I think she also
needs an MRI.
I was thinking
it might be --
Um, Lila?
Will you show me exactly
where it hurts?
It's along there.
The cortisone shot
should help,
but if you're looking for
a more permanent solution,
you might try
losing a little weight.
I might try
losing a little weight?
Maybe start with some
good walks with a friend
and build up to more.
I've been on
a diet since 1992,
and I get a serious workout
every day chasing 8-year-olds.
How am I supposed to take
"good walks with friends"
when I have shooting pains
coming from my knee when I walk?
All I'm saying is,
you might be surprised
what even 10 to 15 pounds can do
to exacerbate joint pain.
Got it.
So if I just figure out
how not to be fat,
all my problems
will magically go away.
Thank you.
Zero stars.
Lila...
Oh, I'm sorry, Lila.
Wait, uh...
It looks like you might
have foot drop,
based on the way
you're walking.
Have what?
Uh, a foot drop
is something that
losing a solid 10 to 15 pounds
will not fix.
Would you like me to
order the MRI now, sir?
Walking there might help me
build up to more.
♪♪
Thank you.
Hayes, please.
Altman, I can't.
We almost died together, and
y-you can't return a phone call?
What happened?
Please, can you just --
can you just tell me?
Talk to your husband.
I am talking to my husband,
but he's not talking to me!
There was something wrong
with Owen even before
he got in that car.
I felt it.
I feel it.
And if you've loved Owen
as long as I have loved him,
you feel when
he's lying to you.
You -- You -- You feel
your stomach turn to ice.
And now he's hurt, and
I know he's in so much pain,
but I have this horrible feeling
in my whole body,
so can you please tell me
what happened in that car?
He told me
to get out first.
He told me to
think about my kids.
And for that,
I'll always be in his debt.
It's a miracle he survived.
I might not have.
Thanks to your husband,
I got to get home to my kids.
I -- I get to
bring them back
to my family in Ireland.
They get the chance to --
to build a new life.
But why? Why are you
building a new life?
Hayes, I see you at work.
It's not like you
just to quit without notice.
So whatever he did or whatever
he said to you must be so big
that you're willing to
uproot your whole life.
And for that,
I am -- I am so sorry.
My kids and I have been
uprooted long before
I got in that car
with you and Owen.
Your husband's alive.
Try to hold on to that.
Goodbye, Altman.
♪♪
I'd like to be alone.
I know you would.
Richard, I know you know
how traumatizing it is
for a surgeon to lose a patient
due to an honest mistake.
Yeah, I do.
So do you.
Do you remember what
happened to my niece?
Sabie?
Yeah, you're right.
You're right.
Um...it's because of Sabie that
I know how agonizing it is
for a family to lose a loved one
due to a surgical error,
especially one that
could have been prevented.
You publicly humiliated me
in the hospital
where I've worked
for over 30 years --
Richard, that was
not my intention.
I was just trying
to do my job.
I took an oath --
I took the same damn oath!
Now, Schmitt
didn't make a mistake.
Schmitt made a decision,
okay?
He chose to subvert
my teaching method.
He chose to proceed
without waiting,
and then, somehow,
you went after me?!
I believe in systems,
okay?
I believe in scientific data,
of running scenarios
multiple times
to ensure they work
before we implement
new procedures,
and I-I don't believe that
we have done that here.
We?
W-W-W-Who is "we," Maggie?
You haven't been here.
Neither has Meredith, so
neither of you get an opinion.
So please leave me alone
before I say something
that I'll regret!
♪♪
What do the classic lesions
of endometriosis look like?
Most commonly, they have
a blue-black appearance...
like right there.
Nice catch, Dr. Wilson.
We'll get a biopsy
to confirm.
Hey.
How's she doing?
Hey. I thought
you had a consult.
I-I finished.
Wilson, can you
pull the scope back?
Yeah, sorry.
Are those all lesions?
Yes.
Here and here by
the uterosacral ligament,
which explains
the back pain
and also why
your epidurals didn't work.
We'll get a biopsy
and send it to Path.
Menstruation, pregnancy,
ovarian cysts,
menopause,
endometriosis...
I want to know
what men get.
All the research.
Sounds like we make
a good team.
Raaah!
♪♪
I'm worried
about Richard.
Because of the method?
You thought it was
a good idea, right?
It was.
For lap choles.
We had a two-month-long waiting
list for patients in need.
Then he extended it to more
complicated procedures.
I wasn't here,
but he must have thought
the residents
could handle it.
Yeah,
that's what he said.
He just screamed at me
that you and I
don't get to have a say
because we weren't here.
How did I get
dragged into this?
Because I wasn't at
the M&M?
I did sign off on it, and then
I wasn't there to defend it,
so, yes, I'm sure he
feels like I abandoned him.
He thinks we all did.
Hey.
Want some coffee?
Thank you.
Did Owen run you out of
the room already?
He is the worst patient.
I remember this one time
when he was 18 with the flu,
I swear, the whining that was
coming out of his mouth,
it was guttural.
How's Farouk?
He's so good.
They weaned him off a few lines
already, and so far,
he's tolerating
the anti-rejection meds.
T-Teddy?
What?
Did did Owen
say anything to you?
Or -- Or -- Or Hayes
about what happened
in that car after I got out?
Hayes came by to check on
Farouk, and he said goodbye.
I think that near-death
experience,
it made him want to --
Owen's keeping something from me,
and it is big.
For all I know, he's got a
secret wife in another country.
I'm serious.
I mean...
Owen confessed something,
Megan, to Hayes.
It wasn't a near-death
experience that made Hayes quit.
It's whatever Owen said to him
when he thought he was dying.
Owen did something,
and if it's so big
that he can't even
tell me...
He probably
did do something.
Come on. It's Owen.
He's rash and stupid and
almost always...selfless.
All of you almost died
to save Farouk.
But, Owen, he --
he literally put himself last
in order for that heart
to get here.
He -- He chose to
end his life
and went careening down a cliff
for us -- Farouk, me, you --
and he would
do it again, Teddy.
He always believes that he's
making the right decision,
so whatever he did, whatever
he's doing...it's Owen.
He must believe that
it's his only option.
♪♪
Rongeur?
Chief.
Always a pleasure.
Hey, um, as soon as Perez
is done in here,
I need him with Garrison
on an ex-lap in O.R. 5.
I'm short
on residents today.
Not a problem.
Almost done.
Okay.
Perez made a nice catch
on this patient.
Caught a foot drop
that I missed.
Spinal disc
herniation.
Well, nice job, Perez.
You seem to be the only one
who hasn't turned into
a hapless intern
after the M&M.
I caught it because
I examined her thoroughly.
Excessive weight can cause
damage on the joints.
True,
but you looked at Lila
and decided she was
just a fat person.
Fat people know they're fat.
You do not need to tell them.
Of course not.
But if the weight might be
making things worse --
Might. Might be.
Obesity is a disease.
It's not as easy for some of us
to lose weight as it is for you.
Sir.
Sorry. I made a snap judgment
based on her history and BMI.
Well, stop looking at the BMI.
Excuse me?
It's stupid.
The Body Mass Index is
a fancy title and formula
that was developed like 200
years ago by a mathematician.
It doesn't account
for differences
in the density of bones
or muscle tones or fat.
It looks at numbers,
not distribution.
So stop looking at it
and examine the patient.
So why is it even
on the chart still?
So insurance companies
can rob us blind.
Hey, they charge higher premiums
for higher BMIs.
Told you it was stupid.
Now, let's hurry up.
I need Perez.
Do you want to finish
the discectomy?
Um, yes.
Hey!
So, I, um --
I just updated Francesca.
We are going to
start her on
a new low-dose, continuous
birth control, and, um, then --
I know Link is
really angry with me.
And I can hear
in your voice,
which goes up an octave
every time I enter a room,
that you are who
he's talking to about it.
He's actually not.
It's okay.
You're his best friend.
I am grateful that he has
someone to talk to.
But if it means that we can't
work together effectively,
I need for you
to tell me that,
because this was
awkward today,
and our first responsibility
is to our patients.
Okay?
Thank you for
your help today.
So, my wife
works 24-hour shifts.
If you want,
we can get coffee and talk.
You are my boss.
Mm-hmm.
But you're also
a very nice person
who happened to
study the female orgasm.
Casual sex is good,
right?
Oh, I'm very
pro casual sex.
With friends?
Yeah, casual sex
with friends
can be the best kind of
casual sex.
A friend wants to take care of
your body, make you feel safe,
and please you
all at the same time, so...
Oh, but it's not
casual for you, is it?
Okay. Wilson, if you love him,
you have to tell him,
or you have to stop
having sex with him.
Those are the only
two choices you have
to give this friendship
a chance of surviving, okay?
But before you do,
check Wendy Costello's
incision in 1202.
Helm?
You know, I was so busy
worried about
what Schmitt did in that O.R.,
but you were in there, too.
You're not okay, either,
and...I missed that.
I'm sorry.
I used to never
raise my hand in class,
even though I always
had the right answer.
All through elementary school,
I was so scared
that people would hate me
or call me a know-it-all,
so I just...
didn't raise my hand.
I thought
I outgrew it.
I should have said something
to Levi.
I could have stopped him
in that O.R.
He would have listened to me.
I'm his best friend.
It can be very hard
to speak up
to people who are
so sure of themselves.
But in that O.R.,
Schmitt was the lead surgeon.
So he wasn't just your best
friend, he was your boss.
Hmm?
Yeah, I was kind of a
know-it-all, too, you know?
I know.
Hard to believe.
♪ I've seen the light
Okay.
♪ I've felt the darkness grow
I preach responsibility.
I encourage people to take
the full consequences.
I try and live my life
with personal accountability.
Even if my intent was good,
it killed a man.
Your intent was good,
Richard.
♪♪
Lines can blur,
and sometimes good intentions
can cloud good judgment.
I'm sorry
I wasn't here.
I was gone
with good intentions.
You three are the --
the closest I have to, um...
Well, you know.
The thought of disappointing you
is -- is unbearable.
I wasn't disappointed,
Richard.
I was mad.
I was enraged.
Not at you
or the Webber Method.
I mean,
a little bit at you.
Mostly, I was
enraged at myself.
Because, suddenly,
I was right back there again,
right there
where Schmitt was.
And I have spent years
struggling with
the appropriate amount of
accountability to take
for Sabie's death
on my table.
And, yes, the surgeon
holding the scalpel is the one
who is
ultimately responsible,
but if you discount all of
the other factors at play,
then how does that
surgeon recover?
How does that surgeon move
forward and heal other people?
How does
that surgeon heal?
What happened to Levi
is devastating.
And to me.
And it deserves to
be scrutinized
from every single angle.
The world's changed.
Medicine's evolved.
These students are -- are unlike
any I've ever taught.
And I just wanted to give them
something to...
feel excited about
practicing medicine.
But you are what's exciting
about them practicing medicine.
They don't need a method.
They just need you.
♪♪
Dr. Eisenburg, 4673.
Hey.
So, you're welcome.
Perfect technique,
barely left a mark.
Might be
my best work yet.
Maybe it's Seattle.
Maybe, or it's having
my favorite resident back.
I'm not sure.
You want to grab some dinner?
Celebrate my stellar work?
Hi.
Hello.
Sorry.
For what?
Um, Amelia Shepherd
and Maggie Pierce,
this is Nick.
These are my sisters.
Oh.
Wow. Hi.
Nice to meet you.
Mm-hmm.
Uh-huh.
Um, I'm from Minnesota.
Oh, are you on
the secret project?
I would've noticed.
He has a post-op.
I do have a post-op.
Yeah.
Very complicated
hernia repair.
Okay.
Nice to meet you.
♪♪
I have a thing...to go do.
Hmm.
I like Minnesota.
It is...
full of surprises.
I have a thing, too.
Hey.
We're home,
and we brought falafel.
Oh, no.
I stopped by Nicoletti's.
Oh, we got enough food
to feed a --
You?
Maybe.
I guess we should talk next time
before we do anything.
So, I misread something
at work today.
I've been
thinking about --
Oh.
You first.
You go ahead.
Link...
What is it?
Link, I...
We shouldn't have sex.
Oh.
♪♪
Okay.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Okay.
I will be right back.
Do not eat
all the garlic bread.
♪♪
Can we talk?
Yeah. Come in.
I let you down.
When you introduced the
Webber Method, I had concerns.
But I decided to
trust in it,
because it was you.
And I know I --
I should have been
more vocal about it
from the beginning.
I should have said
something m-more.
I-I should have
said m-more.
It's okay, Bailey.
You can say it.
Despite
the physician shortage
and the backlog
of surgeries,
I feel, strongly,
that the Webber Method
should not just be
suspended temporarily,
but permanently.
Understood.
Oh, and --
and for the record...
you did say something.
And I had my wife
overrule you.
It wasn't right,
and it wasn't fair,
and I'm sorry I did it.
♪ So, what do I do now?
It's been said that
a house divided against itself
cannot stand.
Good night.
♪ Sunrise
But conflict on the road
to progress is inevitable.
Thanks, Mrs. Schmitt.
Levi.
My mom shouldn't
have called you.
Please go away.
Hey, look, we've --
we've all lost patients.
I know it's hard,
but it's part of the job.
But you got to
come back to work.
I'm not going back there.
What do you mean?
If -- If --
If you don't come back,
you're gonna lose
your residency spot and --
Please go away.
Levi --
Please go away
and don't come back.
We're done.
♪ Before another day ends
♪ Today I'll survive
♪ Tomorrow,
I'll make sense of my life ♪
And at least some division
is always a certainty.
Because we all want what we
think is best for everyone.
Owen, I just...
♪♪
Thank you, Dr. Hunt.
♪ Our stories
will keep us alive ♪
Teddy --
No.
Teddy,
just leave it, okay?
I can't.
Teddy. Teddy!
♪ Midday, I've grown
a little restless ♪
And when we can trust at
least that much to be true...
♪ But the strength of the sea
is tamed by the shore ♪
Hi.
Bad timing, bad hallway,
bad sisters.
No, no, no, it was fun.
Was it?
Yeah, it was.
It was fun.
Do you have
to leave tonight?
I don't want to
leave you ever.
♪ Our sacred ground
will cast out any doubt ♪
I'm sorry.
Was that weird?
That's --
You know what?
Screw it.
We're adults.
I don't care.
I-I don't like leaving you.
I want to be with you.
You know?
Why don't you just come
with me on the red-eye
and spend a few days
with me in Minnesota,
and I'll come back
with you.
As exhausting as that sounds,
I have the kids.
And you know I used to
know everything
that went on in there.
And right now, I'm feeling
pretty disconnected
from some people
that I'm very close to.
Hamilton is recovering,
so I think I'm going to
take advantage of that
and just stay put
for a while.
But for the record,
I don't ever want to leave you,
either.
And my children
are asleep.
If you don't have to
leave tonight...
I don't.
Then why are we
still standing here?
I don't know.
It's simply not realistic
for any house
to avoid some division.
♪ Sunset
But how much division
can any house withstand...
♪ Maybe it's all necessary
♪ The holding on
♪ The letting go
Dr. Altman.
Tell me what you just got out
of my husband's car,
or I'm gonna have to
call the police.
♪ And I'll take a deep breath
...before it finally falls?
♪ Let's get some rest
♪♪