Previously on ER:
Your East Coast squeeze is here.
She's kind of a looker in
an interstate off-ramp way.
I'm here now, baby.
- Bobby hit me.
- What?
- Broke a rib.
- I'm sorry.
I didn't know. You didn't say anything.
Why didn't you go to the police?
He is the police.
- A compass?
- Seems we always find each other.
- Can we talk?
- What?
I'm pregnant.
What are you doing?
Well, Christmas was two weeks
ago. I figured it's time to put it away.
Leave it. I like it.
You wanna be one of those people
dragging some dead brown tree...
out into the street
in the middle of April?
I like those people.
They don't give up easy.
I made this for Maggie
when I was, I think, 6.
We were living in a
motel in Minnetonka.
Don't you have a search-committee
meeting this morning?
I could skip it. We
can talk some more.
No, you should go. I
have to be in soon, so...
We haven't figured anything out yet.
- Yeah, I really...
don't wanna get into it again.
You've made a decision?
We don't know what
we are to each other.
- No one ever knows that.
- Oh, come on.
We've been friends for a
long time. Good friends.
- Yeah?
- Been through a lot together.
That doesn't mean we
could take care of a child.
It has to be your choice.
I know that.
Fall in the ambulance bay.
No head trauma, no LOC.
Okay, it's all right. I'm fine.
- Complains of hip pain, can't bear weight.
- Stop it.
- I'm trying to be professional.
- It's annoying.
Whose job is it to
deice the entrance?
Get back to work.
Only a bruise, I'm fine.
- I'm gonna go find you a bed.
- No. I don't need all that.
Hey. Acetaminophen OD.
Should I give Mucomyst?
Could you look over
the positive-cultures list?
- CT's down, we're closing...
- Hold it! I'm not even on today.
Guys, guys. Easy. Easy.
Look, she had a nasty little slip on the
ice, so let's give her some space, okay?
Thank you.
- All right. What?
- What "what"?
- What do you want?
- I need a few weeks off.
- Why?
- My band got a recording deal.
We're going to L.A.
Back away from the gurney or
I will impale you with my crutch.
- Kerry.
- Back off, Elvis.
Damn salt's ruined my shoes.
Newark's been snow-free all
year. Why don't you go back there?
These are Jimmy Choos. - Who?
Why are you wearing his shoes?
Choos. And they cost
me about 400 bucks.
A, number one, you shouldn't be wearing
shoes that cost more than people's rent.
And B, number two, it's January
in Chicago. Get some damn boots.
Let me tell you something:
You're not a morning person.
No, I am not. Hey, excuse me. Excuse
me, can I get some more coffee, please?
And some Splenda, about a fistful.
- No problem.
- What?
- Shut up.
All I'm saying is that you're not
really prepared for winter, are you?
- So?
- So...
So?
So, so, so why don't you
stay at my place today?
I wanna see Michigan Avenue.
All right, fine. Whatever.
Just don't buy it, will you?
- I can shop if I want to, Vic.
- On whose credit card?
You're still worried about Bobby. I
told you I severed all ties with him.
Just because you severed
all ties with Bobby...
doesn't mean that he
severed all ties with you.
- He has no idea where I went.
- Of course not. He has no idea.
He would never think
of you being with me.
- He doesn't know where you are.
- No. No. He's a freaking cop.
How hard do you think that
is, huh? What are you, stupid?
I mean, how stupid
do you have to be?
- What?
- Give me some money.
- What for?
- For a cab. Give me some money.
Oh, come on. Don't do this. Don't
be ridiculous, okay? Just don't...
Give me the money.
Yeah. I need another 20.
Come on, don't do this.
And you know what you should
think about? You... Don't touch me.
You should think about
getting into meditation classes...
or maybe Pilates or something,
because you, Vic, are getting very ugly.
And I mean that in the most
metaphorical sense, okay?
Come on, don't walk away mad.
- Don't.
What? Now I gotta go get
myself some boots, you jerk-off.
Oh, come on. Come
back here. Jodie.
I'm sorry, I'm having
trouble clearing a bed.
You know, this really isn't necessary.
I'm sure I can get to my office...
Oh, you should let
me examine you.
All right. Just treat me
like any other patient.
- You sure?
- Yeah. Get me out of the hall.
Neela, let's run the board.
- I have to take my broken-hip lady...
- Hey.
- Not broken. MORALES:
Ted Cunningham, 23.
Lost his Shiley at
the nursing home.
They found him cyanotic,
put a 7.0 in the neck.
- Okay, Pratt, go with them.
- He had a lot of mucous.
We tried to suction him. His
trach tube came out, he turned blue.
- You from the home?
- No, I'm his mother.
Ted, can you open your eyes?
He can't follow commands.
Okay. Excuse us.
- NG tube and Number 6 Shiley.
- Ninety-four and 15 liters.
- He needs an NG?
- Use it as a guide to change the airway.
- How long has he been like this?
- Two years.
Ever since the
night he turned 21.
His friends took him to a bar
and made him drink 21 shots.
And on the way home...
he stepped into traffic and
got clipped by a pickup truck.
You spend your whole
life raising a kid right...
and then one stupid
night turns him into this.
Where are you? It's
time to open the presents.
Just making sure.
Oh, I think you can stop now.
We could find a
way to make it work.
- If that's what you want.
- I don't know what I want.
I mean, I'm 37 years
old. If not now, when?
You know how I feel about it.
Everything happens for a reason.
It scares me, Luka.
Having it or choosing not to?
Yeah.
All right, pull the
NG and bag him.
Abby, bag him.
Is he all right?
He should be much better
now that he has a new tube.
Thank you.
Sats up to 99.
What's Coburn doing here?
Kovac's got her down on
this lady with ovarian torsion.
Dr. Rasgotra, someone
seems to have left this.
So how's married life?
It's very nice, thank you. We're
looking for a place of our own.
It sounds exciting.
The Army want Michael to finish
his Residency at a military hospital.
- Then, where's the closest program?
- Fort Hood, Texas.
I'm hoping he can end up
somewhere not too far away.
Tenderness over the
greater trochanter?
Probably just a contusion
from where I hit the ground.
I'm going to check
your range of motion.
Ow! Oh, God.
Pain with internal rotation.
That's happened before.
I just need an ice pack
for 10 minutes and it'll stop.
Something for the pain
perhaps? Percocet? Vicodin?
No, no. I have too
much work to do.
Eight hundred of ibuprofen
and call for a hip series.
Well, I'll have to run it
past my Attending first...
I'm sorry.
Hey, pull the curtain, please.
- How's she doing?
- Bit cranky at the moment.
You'll soften her
up for me, right?
- What?
- For my TO request.
What do you need time off for?
Neela, do you know
who Barry Ginzberg is?
- Gynecologist on the fourth floor?
- No.
No, he's a record producer,
a mogul, an idol maker.
He took a listen to a couple
tracks my boys laid down and:
We are going to L.A. and
we have a gig at the Key Club.
If all goes well, we get to record
a demo at his studio in Venice.
- Italy?
- California, on the beach.
Congratulations, Ray,
that's really awesome. Here.
Super-infected foot fungus in 4.
Only thing is, is I'm
gonna need a little time off.
- How much is a little?
- Just a month.
- That's not little.
- Can you check out this patient for me?
Amanda Ramsey, 15,
presented with vague pain.
Sorry. I have to get some ibuprofen
and a hip series for Dr. Weaver.
Please, I'll trade you.
- Haven't told her yet.
- Thanks a lot.
Amanda, I'm Dr. Rasgotra.
How much longer do you think it'll be?
Because I didn't mean to make a big deal.
- I probably just need Motrin or something.
- We ran a test on your urine.
Do I have a bladder infection?
You're pregnant.
Did you know that?
You didn't tell my
parents, did you?
They've been told that
you were here, but that's all.
Who's the father?
Some guy from school.
Boyfriend?
No.
I can get our Adolescent Clinic
to come down and talk to you.
- My parents won't like that.
- There are a number of options.
Yeah, I can keep it or
put it up for adoption.
Or you could
choose not to have it.
I could never do that.
It'd be against God.
They stabbed me in the heart!
P. P. Perkins, mugging
victim. Wounds to chest, arms...
- Name's P.P.? PERKINS:
Got blood coming out.
- He's only satting 82.
- You guys need a hand?
No, we're on it. Chest
tube, in here. Let's move it.
Okay, we're gonna need
to remove an ovary, Sara...
but that's why God
gave you a spare.
It's gonna be fine. Prep her in
2. I should be up in 15 minutes.
- How's it going?
- Well, good.
She's young and the
other ovary looks good.
Oh, no. I meant...
- Oh, "How's it going?" Well, fine. You?
- Good.
I just got paged
for an ultrasound.
- Do you know anything about that?
- No.
No, but I remember hearing
that you surg your own practice?
Yeah, yeah. It's going
very well, you know.
The only problem's
the boss. What a bitch.
- I'm the boss, Abby.
- Right.
- Now you're patronizing me.
- No, I...
I just... I just might want to
come and see you. I need an OB.
Congratulations.
Wow, I had no idea.
I'll shut up.
Yeah, it wasn't
something I expected.
Is it something you want?
I'm not sure I'm at the
right place in my life for this.
So...
So you don't wanna keep it.
- I'm sorry. COBURN:
I'm always prepared. Here.
Thanks.
I've got office hours every
afternoon. Just come by any time.
I can help you. Whether it's
prenatal care or termination.
Whatever you decide.
Thank you.
And whatever you do, Abby,
it's gonna be the right thing.
Thanks.
- Systolic's only 86.
- Almost there. Get the Thora-Seal.
Okay. A little pressure now.
All right. So who really
jacked you, huh, P.P.?
- Some guys I know.
- Sats coming up.
Drinking by fire in this alley.
Right. Must be real good
friends to stab you in the heart.
- Did somebody call the cops?
- On their way.
I'm sure they're rushing over.
- No.
- BP's better, 110/75.
- No cops? They could have killed you.
I got problems. I got problems.
- Cops only gonna make it worse.
- I feel you, bro. Trust me.
Then do me a solid, man.
Anything for you, P.P. Anything.
More lube.
- It's cold.
- Oh, sorry about that.
- Dr. Coburn.
- I called OB.
Couldn't there be a
mistake with that test?
I don't think so.
Here. You see this?
That's the heart beating.
It's about seven
weeks old, I'd say.
They won't understand.
- Your parents?
- They'll say I've sinned.
I can help you talk
to them if you want.
Can I have a minute?
You were in with a patient,
so I thought it was best to just...
It would be better if
you presented to me first.
Well, either way, I had to call
an OB. She's 15 and scared.
- Family on the way in?
- They're very religious people.
Call me when they get here.
How'd you do this?
Tried to hop a bus.
What, did you slip on the ice?
I was skitching,
fell off the fender.
Might be easier
just to pay the fare.
Do I look like I got
surplus income to blow?
Can I get another 3-0 Ethilon?
- Mm-hm.
Were you on your way home?
I haven't been home in
a while. Since, like, May.
Your folks must be
worried about you.
Yeah, they worry a lot.
Always wanting to know
what I'm doing, what I'm up to.
Gets to be a real
drag, you know.
Doesn't sound so bad.
I'm an independent spirit, you
know. I wanna be on my own.
Do they even know where you are?
No.
Just left one day.
What if I don't know
how to love it right?
Abby.
Maybe I'm not strong enough.
Being a parent
makes you stronger.
And it breaks your
heart. You told me that.
That's not what I meant.
- I'm sorry, I didn't mean...
- No, don't... Don't use that as a reason.
I'm sorry.
What if I go shopping and
leave it in the supermarket?
Don't worry, I'll do
all the shopping.
I'm afraid I'd mess it up, Luka.
We won't.
Okay.
Keep the wound clean and dry.
Come back in a week to
have the stitches removed.
That's it? ABBY: Yeah.
Unless you wanna talk to
somebody from Social Work.
Your daughter's right in here.
- Mandy? Are you okay?
- I'm fine, Mom.
I'll leave you all to talk.
Could you stay?
Sure.
Mom.
Daddy.
Something happened
and I'm real sorry.
What happened, sweetie?
We ran a test and
did an ultrasound.
Amanda's pregnant.
We're waiting for
some blood results.
- As soon as they arrive...
- That's fine.
There are a number of places
we can refer you to for counseling.
We'd like to be alone
with our daughter now.
Thank you.
No free fluid on ultrasound.
Waiting on surgery to evaluate.
Not anymore, Red.
What do you got?
Morning, sunshine.
- Who are you?
- Clemente. Who are you?
- I'm Surgery, see the badge?
- Oh, yeah.
You must be the bedside-manner
coach I heard so much about.
Multiple stab wounds.
Stable after the chest tube.
- Anything enter the peritoneum?
- Not sure. Ultrasound's negative.
Doesn't answer my question.
- Hey, I got the cops out here.
- Relax. Relax. I got your back.
If you can get a smile out of
Surgery, I'll pay for the date.
You're right on the cusp
of sexual harassment.
The cusp. That would
be a new position for me.
Hey, guys. I'm the Attending
Physician on this case.
- Clemente?
- Yeah.
This dude is very sick.
He's out of it completely.
He won't be able to give
a statement. I'm sorry.
- Hold on a sec. You're Victor Clemente?
- Yeah. Were you listening to me?
He won't be able to give a statement.
- Easy.
We're not here on your
patient. We're here for you.
Dubenko's feisty
gopher's at it again.
- What?
- The chief Resident from the Death Star.
- She's down on a consult.
- Albright?
He's hemodynamically
stable with no peritoneal signs.
- So why'd you call me?
- Look, missy, it's protocol, all right?
You didn't really just
call me "missy," did you?
Okay, look. The case
meets trauma criteria.
Next time, call me when you
know what you got on your hands.
Are you Dr. Albright?
He was stabbed. I need to
know if he needs surgical repair.
Neela Rasgotra. I wanted to catch
you about doing a surgery elective.
Right. Work up your patient.
Image the belly, explore the
wounds, figure out how deep they are.
If they enter the
peritoneal cavity, call me.
I'll be more than
happy to get involved.
One-third of stab wounds
enter the peritoneal cavity...
and damage the viscera.
One-third go in and
don't hit anything.
And one-third...
are shallow and tangential.
The trajectory was suggested by the hilt
mark of the knife. He won't need surgery.
You should pay more
attention to your interns, Red.
I'm an R2, actually.
Okay, R2. Call me about that elective.
We might be able to work something out.
Parking violations? You
gotta be kidding me, right?
Okay. But you had some
other problems back East.
What problems you talking about?
You left Newark General
under some serious allegations.
I never.
I never, never, never
compromised a patient's care.
- Do you understand me? I never.
- Okay, okay.
Let's get back to Mrs.
Kenyon. She had issues...
What issues? She had
no issues. She was a nurse.
I'd ask her for 6-0 Vicryl and
she'd bring it to me. No issues.
- Can I go now? Thank you.
- Not yet.
All right. You do realize
that son of a bitch hits her?
- So you have seen her?
- You realize that. No, I haven't seen her.
But I can see what's going
on here and it's pretty low.
To sic you on me because he can't keep
his wife happy, that's pretty pathetic.
All we know is Mrs. Kenyon's a
missing person who might be in trouble.
- Be in more trouble if you find her.
- Meaning?
Meaning sometimes people go
missing because they feel safer that way.
- My advice: Stop looking for her.
- Don't you go missing.
- I'm gonna wanna talk to you.
- Why would I go missing? Why?
Confusing me for
one of your scumbags?
Settle down before
it gets embarrassing.
Hope this conversation
doesn't throw me off my game.
After all the cops'
lives I've saved.
I'd hate to be less than 100 percent
when your brother comes in with a bullet.
I think we're done for now.
Take it easy.
Hey, we got any
loperamide in stock?
Yeah, I'm sure we have some.
- I got you the good stuff. Today was...
- Hey.
Sorry. It's turkey
day in the cafeteria.
No.
- No what?
- Is the answer to your question.
Can I at least
state my case first?
Okay.
This is big. This is a big
opportunity for my band.
And for me.
And you never know when you're
gonna get another shot like this.
My recollection is you were warned last
year about your commitment to this job.
Yes, I was.
To your credit, you've done an excellent
job showing us that you wanna be here.
- I do.
- You're a good doctor.
- Thank you.
- We don't need to discuss this further.
You're valuable, you're
valued. Conversation over.
Have you tried the stuffing?
It's great stuffing.
And, you know, I got
you an extra piece...
- Dr. Barnett!
- Look, Kerry...
Dr. Weaver.
Have you ever dreamed
about something...
without ever believing it
would actually happen?
Because that's what this is.
I've...
This is so huge to me,
that if I couldn't do this...
I would seriously
consider quitting.
Far be it from me to stand in
the way of the next Springsteen...
or KC & The Sunshine Band.
Resignation accepted.
What?
- Why do you wanna do surgery?
- I'm curious about it.
The hours suck, Attendings
are slave drivers...
Residents stab each
other in the back.
Not like down here where
we're one big, happy family.
What's wrong? Ashlee Simpson
get caught lip-synching again?
- I think I just quit.
- Quit?
To go to California
with my band.
Oh, great. Yeah. No, bold move. I
like it. Keeping that music dream alive.
No, you'll love California.
Everybody, Ray Barnett, rock god.
Morris, I've already sent
my paperwork up to Surgery.
Well, get it back. I can't spare you,
especially now with Ray on his way out.
If we're not fully staffed,
you're not going anywhere.
I don't care what
Dr. Cruella says.
Three forty-five, that'll
work. Yeah. Thank you.
Ray's out? MORRIS: Yeah.
Up and quit, not gonna
let the man keep him down.
- I don't think he meant to.
- Hey, guys. Guys, come here.
- Know the girl I've been hanging with?
- Jodie? Yeah, we love Jodie.
Taught me to tie a knot in a
cherry stem using only my tongue.
- Really?
- Come on, guys.
- Anybody ask for her?
- No.
You never saw her, okay? And if
anybody asks, the same goes for me.
- What?
- Pretend you never heard of me.
Pratt's bringing in a
patient. Get with him, okay?
Okay.
He gets weirder every day.
Look, you heard
what Dr. Albright said.
So? She's the chief Resident upstairs,
I'm the chief here. You work for me.
- Oh, come on. That's not fair.
- Fair? What's fair?
Excuse me, doctor.
Mr. Ramsey.
I can sign whatever I need
to, and we'll get out of your way.
Like me to call anyone
for further treatment?
Thank you. I think we'll
arrange our own prenatal care.
Amanda decided to keep it?
The baby.
It's just that she's young
and it was an accident.
No, no.
I don't believe in accidents.
Now, I know you may
not understand this...
but it is God's will for
her to have this child.
I only mean you may want to
consider the long-term effects.
You might wanna consider the spiritual
effects of what you're suggesting.
It's my job to make sure the patient
understands all the options available.
A human life has
just been created.
And I'm sorry, but anything
that interferes with that...
is morally indefensible.
Finished chemo two days ago.
Couldn't get an IV, too dry.
O.R. needs an Attending to sign
off on your pancreatic pseudocyst.
- Where's Clemente?
- On the roof.
- A chopper patient?
- No.
He just says that his cell phone
gets better reception up there.
Place a subclavian and
bolus him. I'll be back.
Okay, triple lumen
tray and 1 percent lido.
- He's tachy at 132.
- A little bit cold here.
I was never the
sickly type, you know.
- No?
- Always very healthy.
Used to do triathlons.
Believe that?
- Me too.
- Really?
Smoking, drinking
and watching TV.
- You should stop that.
- I have.
Six years ago, I find out I inherited
the Philadelphia chromosome.
Ran on my mother's
side of the family.
I never knew.
Screwed by genetics.
First time, I was panicked
the baby would be bipolar.
I'm not so sure I've
changed that much.
The chances are
slim, you know that.
Crossing the street is a risk.
If you let it get to you,
you'd never have children.
Nobody would.
Well, maybe some
people aren't supposed to.
Well, I don't think
you're one of them.
Yeah, well, you don't
know what it was like...
with Maggie and Eric.
Come on. You're
looking for reasons again.
And what are you looking for?
Someone to have a baby with?
That what you think?
Because if it is, then what
the hell are we doing here?
Happy New Year.
A whole cascade of things
have to happen to cause CML.
Philadelphia chromosome
doesn't mean cancer.
No, just that you're born
with a big strike against you.
Soon as you get this, call me.
I wanna talk to you
immediately. Right away.
Maybe you're trying me right now,
so I'm just gonna hang up and...
And you gotta call me.
You gonna jump?
- It's not a trick question.
- Yeah, sure it's not.
Here. I need you
to sign off on this.
- What are you doing here? It's freezing.
- Yeah, well, I got a very high core temp.
It's a Latin thing.
- You wanna talk or something?
- No. Why would I?
I don't know. You
seem a little ragged.
Yeah, I just got some
chick trouble, that's all.
- Then I'm your men.
- Except I don't like to share.
You know, I heard you
never stick anyplace.
Maybe people don't go to the mat for
you because they have no idea who you are.
All right.
All right, so there was this
crazy nurse at my last hospital.
- In Newark?
- Yeah.
She's a piece of work,
and it just ended bad.
It usually does.
You know, I came here just to focus,
to stay on the straight and narrow.
- Sounds like a good idea.
- Yeah, one would think.
Except it's easier said than
done, because this girl...
she's got my number, if
you know what I mean.
And a very pissed-off husband.
See? I'm starting to
like you more already.
Damn, so many patients.
- Don't you feel better now?
- Not really, no. Can't say that I do.
Type and Rh are back on Amanda.
Then we're done.
- You off already?
- Yeah.
- I have a doctor's appointment.
- Oh.
I'm going to see Coburn.
- Coburn?
- At her practice.
Uh...
- I'll get Clemente to cover.
- It's okay. You're working.
No, I should come with you.
- It probably would
be easier if you didn't.
Hey. Hey.
When I say I want us to keep it,
you don't like the way it sounds.
But anything else is a lie.
Luka. Neela's waiting for you
to sign off on the Ramsey girl.
Get Clemente to do it.
- He's MIA.
I don't know what else to say.
Don't say anything.
Take one of these every day. It'll
help keep you and the baby healthy.
- Okay.
- Where are your parents?
My mom's making some calls
and my dad had to go to a meeting.
If it makes you nauseous, try taking
it at night before you go to bed, okay?
This is some more
information that might be useful.
And we got this for
you from the ultrasound.
I wish this didn't happen.
I wish I could make it go away.
Well, everything
happens for a reason.
There was this party at
my friend Ginny's house.
And I drank some beer...
and I did some other stuff
with a couple of guys, and...
And I must have passed
out in the bedroom...
because when I woke up...
my jeans were on the floor and
there was blood all over the sheets.
I tried to change the covers...
Amanda...
were you raped?
Always thought the first time
would be with someone I loved.
Why didn't you say something?
I don't want this. Please.
You need to explain to
your parents what happened.
They'll understand.
You have to tell them.
I did tell them.
Mrs. Ramsey?
I'll call you back.
- Amanda told you what happened to her?
- Yes.
And you still want
her to do this?
That baby can't be punished
for how it was conceived.
It's not up to us to determine
who gets to be born.
We're talking about
a 15-year-old girl.
- Your daughter, who was raped.
- Neela.
You'd force her to carry
this to term, change her life?
I wouldn't force
her to do anything.
She believes the same
things that we believe.
This is an inappropriate conversation.
- Inappropriate?
- She's terrified, doesn't wanna keep it.
- Let's take a walk.
Think for one minute about what's
in your daughter's best interest.
You think it's in her best
interest to kill the baby?
Because I can assure you...
that in the eyes of God,
it most certainly is not.
Excuse me.
Leave these people alone
now. They've made a decision.
Parents have no legal rights.
Pregnancy emancipates her.
There's nothing else you can do.
That girl's head is so far twisted, she
doesn't understand she has a choice.
She doesn't want an abortion.
She doesn't wanna have the
baby either. Anyone can see that.
What about misoprostol?
It's used as an abortifacient.
She won't consent to
that. Just let it go, Neela.
You're the wrong person
to talk to about this.
Excuse me?
I would like your permission
to consult another Attending.
Someone who's not Catholic.
Listen to me very seriously.
I'm a doctor first, above
and beyond anything else...
and I don't let my personal beliefs get
in the way of a patient's best interests.
Ever.
Now, give me that chart
and move on to the next one.
I'm sorry. I...
- There's gotta be something that we...
- You're done here.
Do you wanna have this baby?
I have to.
Is it what you want?
No. No, it isn't.
This is called a laminaria.
It goes into the cervix...
where it absorbs water and
swells, creating a larger opening.
After that happens...
it's possible that the
fetus might fall out.
- Possible?
- You might have a miscarriage.
- Does it hurt?
- A little.
There might be some cramping.
Is it a sin?
It's just a medical
way we have...
of giving God a
chance to reconsider.
Abigail Lockhart?
Oh, my God. Nobody was out
today. I had the pick of the litter.
Hey, come on. You gotta leave.
Hey, what the hell's
wrong with you?
Cops are on me,
getting on my ass.
Why? Your dick of a husband, Bobby,
has put out a missing-persons report.
- That's why.
- He did?
Yeah. How long we got
till he traces you to me?
How long before I'm walking around
with my testicles in a jar? Tell me.
Vicky. Vic, Vic.
I love you.
Sometimes you can
be such a little faggot.
Oh, yeah?
I'm gonna get a big boyfriend who'll
kick your maniac of a husband's ass.
How do you like that,
huh? How do you like that?
Hey, you're ripping the leather.
Quiet, will you?
- That's great. That's great.
- You gotta pay your tickets.
That's great. Damn it.
Vic, what's going on?
Hey, X-Ray, how's it going?
So this must be Jodie, huh?
Who, her? That's not Jodie.
Hi. RAY: Hey.
It's weird. I've parked here a lot
of times and never had a problem.
Yeah, it's weird.
We're gonna take the el.
Right.
Nice meeting you. - Likewise.
Yo, Ray.
Bret. Hey, how was practice?
- Thanks for meeting me, man.
- Yeah.
Grab some coffee?
Yeah. So I took care of
everything. Schedule's all cleared up.
I thought we were gonna
talk before you did anything.
Did something happen? Don't
tell me Ginzberg isn't interested.
No, it's still on.
Here's the thing. You've been pretty
busy with this whole doctor thing lately.
- Kind of distracted, you know?
- True. True.
But I'm a hundred percent onboard
now, okay? Hundred and ten, actually.
Well, we all got together
and talked about it.
Who did?
The guys. This morning.
Kind of decided the band's
gotta make some changes.
Changes?
What do you mean, changes?
You'll need to come back to
have the laminaria removed.
Probably feel a little pain.
Nothing to worry about.
You can take ibuprofen.
That should help.
Before I formed thee
in the belly I knew thee.
And before thou camest forth
out of the womb I sanctified thee...
and ordained thee a
prophet unto the nations.
Jeremiah 1:5.
Man was born of dust.
It was only when God
breathed life into Adam...
that he became a living soul.
Genesis.
You're a Christian.
What do I tell my mom?
She'll think you're
having a miscarriage.
And you will be.
All done. You can
take her home now.
Okay. Thank you, doctor.
Weaver's MRI results are back.
- What happened?
- Sorry?
What were you doing in there?
Taking care of the patient.
Hey, Abby. It's me.
I guess I missed you.
Um...
Nothing. I'll see you soon.
Okay.
Advanced degeneration
with a cartilaginous flap.
At least that explains the pain.
I've seen that kind of thing heal with
enough bed rest and physical therapy.
I've been putting this off for years.
Maybe it's time to face the music.
- I'll need a total hip replacement.
- Not necessarily.
Just when Henry's starting
to run around like a crazy man.
- How is he?
- He's great.
You should see him.
He looks just like Sandy.
Went by your place...
but I figured you might
come home this way.
I don't want everything we have
to come down to this one decision.
We can get past it.
You did what you had to do.
Doesn't mean we
can't be together.
I didn't do it.
I couldn't.
I wanna keep it.
I want us to have this baby.