Previously on ER:
If you can handle a relationship with
no strings, sex with no commitments.
- I'm all good.
- These are really beautiful.
They're kind of embarrassing.
Well, I had a good time with
you, I just wanted to let you know.
- I'm Simon Brenner.
- Seems like a nice bloke.
- Is that what you call it?
- I quit.
Well, I need something else.
I'm talking about my marriage.
I just, I don't know if I can fix it.
Hi, Sheryl, I'm Dr. Rasgotra.
Four kids, 23 years
later, here I am.
You shouldn't have to
go through this alone.
It was my choice to end our
relationship. I'm letting you off the hook.
Joe's still asleep.
- He had a rough night.
- Yeah.
How many times was he up? Three?
Four.
- You have your interview today, huh?
- Yep.
Are you looking at apartments?
What am I supposed to do?
I told you the truth,
that was not easy for me.
And you know how badly
I feel and how sorry I am.
We're not doing this now.
What? What do you want?
I swear, I don't care
what it is. I'll do it...
Did you think coming to Croatia
and apologizing was all it would take?
No, I didn't.
Well, you tell me you
were weak, you screwed up.
You broke my trust. You
put our son in jeopardy.
- What the hell do you expect?
- I don't know.
It... I have to get ready for this
thing. You... We'll talk about it later.
Will we? That's all I'm asking.
Well, we're not
doing it now, okay?
Hey.
- Hey.
- Long time no see.
I know, the shift gods have
been conspiring against us.
Well, I have the
perfect solution.
How about a little romantic
getaway in Quebec?
- Quebec?
- The Little France of the Americas.
I booked us into a B & B this
weekend and I thought maybe...
Shoot. I made plans to do a wreck
dive in Lake Michigan with the guys.
- A wreck dive?
- Yeah.
Did I mention it's
called Little France?
I'll try to get out of it.
- Let's talk later, okay?
- Okay.
- Hey, Morris, doughnut?
- Yes.
- What's the occasion?
- Yeah, Gates.
No reports of
hell freezing over.
That hurts, Frank. If you don't
want any doughnuts, big guy.
Sorry I cast aspersions
on your generosity.
- Hey, Sam.
- Dr. Gates.
Frank? Labs back on
my deodorant eater?
- Negatory.
- Doughnut?
- What are you doing?
- I'm sorry, you want a jelly?
I thought we agreed
to keep it under wraps.
- Be cool about us.
- What?
It's a doughnut, not a dozen
roses. I bought for everyone.
Sometimes a doughnut is
not just a doughnut, okay?
So cut it out.
Ah, there she is, Ms. Croatia.
- So how was it?
- It was good, thanks.
- And you did actually go this time, right?
- Yes, I actually went.
Abby, hey. ABBY: Hey.
- Have a nice vacation?
- Yeah.
Great. PRATT: Damn.
Oh, you guys all right?
- Wow, what is that, gasoline?
- Underground tanker erupted in a geyser.
- Soaked head to toe.
- Tried to cap it off.
We hosed him off, but
the fumes were bad.
- He needs to be soaked.
- Call HAZMAT.
Clean him. You
need to be looked at.
We're fine.
Oh, somebody get a gurney.
- Hey, put those out.
- Reidy, you okay?
- Is he breathing?
- Wait, don't get up.
There's nothing wrong
with Internet dating but...
So, what's the problem?
Working in a hospital, the hours,
the intensity, it can be alienating.
There's just no way to date a
normal person in the real world.
You don't think that
there are doctors online?
Or, God forbid, other hard-working
professionals who might relate...
even though they've never
heard of gentinomium?
Gentamicin.
I'm just saying,
happiness takes up space.
Everyone has to make room
in their life for it, not just doctors.
Well, speaking of gentamicin...
the cultures are still
negative, which is good.
The fevers could
be atelectasis...
so three laps around
the ward today, okay?
Oh, hold on.
I'm posting a
profile of you online.
- No, you're not.
- Yes, I am.
- I'm pretending to be you.
- All right, then.
I want a tall, dark, symphony conductor
who is fluent in Italian with abs of steel.
I'm on it.
- Hey, how's Mrs. Hawkins?
- Still running a low-grade temp.
The graft is infected.
Are you sure?
- Well, couldn't that be a hematoma?
- No.
Not with the stranding
and irregular density.
Switch her to linazolid. Take
her up to O.R. in the morning.
Go ahead, answer
that. I'll talk to Sheryl.
It should come from me.
It'd be weird if it came
from someone else.
It's the ICU again. Look,
let me take care of this.
- I'll come back and tell her.
- Okay.
Meet me in the ER when you're
finished. We got consults piling up.
- Hey, we need a line.
- I got it.
- Do I still have eyebrows?
- They'll grow back.
- Burn yourself?
- Yeah, a little bit.
Make sure you get that checked out.
- I got this.
No, she's fine. Sam, you
don't need coddling, right?
Human fireball in the
ambulance bay, I love this place.
Sats are good.
Some singed nasal hairs,
but the lungs are clear.
Partial thickness
burns to both the hands.
- Nothing circumferential.
- Burns are minimal.
Maybe 5 percent
BSA. You got lucky.
We need a doctor on the board.
- Brenner's not busy.
- He's about to be.
- Who's Brenner?
- New attending.
He thinks he's
God's gift to medicine.
And women. ABBY: Great.
- We can always use one of those.
- Abby, you're with me.
Admit Mr. Sucar to the burn
unit. Keep an eye on his airway.
All right.
I gotta say, I was
shocked when Luka quit.
- I always thought he'd be a lifer here.
- Yeah.
Well, change is probably
a good thing, right?
Is that why you
cancelled your interview?
I didn't cancel it.
I just postponed it. I'm gonna see
what's happening with Luka first.
You got 14 candidates
going for one attending slot.
Be gone before you get
a chance to reschedule.
In three months you're
gonna find yourself out of a job.
- Pratt, we need a doctor here.
- I'm on with Nephrology.
Got it. LAVERNE: Kwan Lee, 19.
He got jumped on the
El platform on Addison.
Hi, Kwan, I'm Dr. Lockhart.
What happened?
I was waiting for the train. These
guys pulled me off the bench.
Vitals stable, 18
gauge in the antecube.
All right, on my count.
Ready, one, two, three.
- I tried to run away.
- Pulse 122, sat 98.
Lungs sound good.
You have any family
you want us to call, Kwan?
- They're in Seoul.
- What's your plan?
CBC, trauma panel,
chest x-ray, see if...
A radioulnar series.
- Oh, my God.
- It's okay.
What's his sat?
Ninety-eight. I
think I said that.
Just a bit of blood. It's
probably from your nose.
I want to go back to Korea.
Chicago isn't working out.
Come on, more
about your new hottie.
- Hottie is too reductive a word.
- You're killing me.
If dialysis won't unlock your
A-V shunt, we'll revise it in the OR.
- Thanks, Lucien.
- Yeah, she's hot.
But she's also... She's
complex, innovative, she's...
She's kind of earthy. It's
completely unprecedented.
- You know what I'm talking about.
- Oh, shut up.
- Who is she?
- No comment.
Where did you meet?
- All I'll say is, I love this new job.
- I knew it, she works here.
Lucien, shampoo man's gonna follow
up with you as an outpatient, okay?
If he must. Lunch later?
- That could work.
- My office, 2:00?
I'll try to make it.
- Hey.
She's so hot.
Missy Voltaire, restrained driver,
minivan T-boned by an SUV.
Haleh, page OB and
let's get the ultrasound.
- When are you due, Missy?
- Next month.
My husband's gonna freak. He's
been superstitious about the pregnancy.
- Is this your first baby?
- No, it's our 13th.
You did break your arm.
There's a fracture right there.
No, no, no.
I've got a critique in a week and
I've got all those zDUBS to do.
What are you talking about?
I'm a freshman at the art
institute. I study animation.
- Can we take his collar off?
- Sure.
Laverne, come here and I'll
show you how to clear a C-spine.
I'm gonna work my way
down your vertebrae, okay?
- That sounds fun.
- Let me know if anything hurts.
All right, you're looking for tenderness,
step-offs, any other irregularities.
- How long have you had this?
- I'm not sure.
Yeah, it's a bit fluctuant.
- Is it infected?
- It could be a node or a cyst.
Abby, Morris could use
some extra hands in here.
- Okay.
- I'm coming.
- I'll talk to Surgery.
- Okay.
- Surgery?
- To get a second opinion.
I'll be back to
explain it to you.
I got this.
I just came over to meet
the famous Abby Lockhart.
I'm Simon Brenner. Your
reputation precedes you.
Right back at you.
- They all have D names?
- How can we help?
This is Missy, 35
weeks, G13, P12.
- Abby, will you do an ultrasound, please?
- Sure.
So are you Catholic? - No.
Mormon? MISSY: No.
Just really, really fertile.
- Yeah.
- Baby's very active.
- God, you should see after I eat.
- It's like Riverdance. MORRIS:
Chest and pelvis are stable.
After number eight, my
husband got a vasectomy.
Three months later,
poof, I'm pregnant again.
- His boys refuse to be held back?
- Yeah, took it as a sign to keep going.
- OB's here, what have you got?
- Thirty-five weeker, G13, P12.
Thirteen kids? Are you
out of your frigging mind?
Haleh, CBC, CHEM-7,
LFTs, type and cross for four.
Do you wanna add a
Kleihauer-Betke test?
ER docs never
remember to order that.
That's not true.
Fetal heart rate 156,
amniotic index, perfect.
Let's monitor the fetus for a
couple of hours just to be sure.
Continuous FHT. I'll be
back to check the strip.
- You got a minute?
- Mm-hm.
I'm very curious.
Why a physician with your experience
would wanna work in palliative care?
Why would you
wanna give up the...?
Emily, good morning.
- -the adrenaline rush of the ER?
I've reached a point where I feel I
need to make a change, you know?
I'm looking to
refocus my energies.
- Oh, I see.
- And my father died a short time ago.
Oh, I'm very sorry to hear that.
I cared for him during his illness,
and I was with him when he died.
You calling me a liar?
- Made me appreciate...
- Excuse me for a moment.
- Sure, take your time.
- Please feel free to look around.
Hi, nice to see you.
Bull hockey!
Cheese and crackers.
Hey. Hey, do you play cards?
- Uh, sure.
- Good, I'm dying for some real action.
Actually, I'm dying
of cancer. Sit.
We'll play five-card draw.
Nothing wild but the dealer.
Sit!
- Luka Kovac.
- Walter Perkins.
You visiting family?
No, I'm actually here
for a job interview.
- Oh, what line of work are you in?
- I'm a doctor.
I used to work in the
ER at Country General.
- Can I have three?
- Used to?
What? Did you get fired?
No.
Well, why in Sam Hill
would you wanna work here?
Every morning I wake up,
there's another empty bed.
Let's just say I'm trying to make
some changes in my life, okay?
You want some advice, run
from this place and don't look back.
Take me with you when you go.
Straight flush.
You wanna play for money?
He's distant and angry.
It's like not one thing
I do or say isn't wrong.
It makes sense that there
would be a period of time like this.
After I got over there and I told
him, I kept waiting for it to get easier.
I kept thinking, okay, the
bad part's gonna be over now.
It's not easy to be patient.
I don't know, he's planning things.
You know, without including me.
He's applying for jobs
without discussing it with me.
He was looking at the real estate
section today. What does that mean?
This is what you signed up for.
He gets to make the
next move. You get to wait.
You always use
propofol for reductions?
Mm-hm. It's a great drug.
Short half-life, easy
to titrate. It's very safe.
Shoulder doesn't
seem to wanna go back.
Do you want some
countertraction, old boy?
- No, I'm good, thanks.
- Ortho prefer a scapula manipulation.
We should let Skye
here take a shot.
You look fit enough to pop
that thing back into place.
- I'm more about finesse than force.
- I'll remember that.
Fine, Dr. Wexler, take a shot.
Okay, Simon.
- We can take it from here.
- Then take it.
We're good here, thanks.
- The shoulder's in.
- Wow.
- Did you stop the propofol?
- That was fast.
- I'm good.
- Yeah.
Even the new attending
recognizes that.
- Brenner?
- He's the kind of guy you wanna hate.
But somehow can't.
- I totally know what you mean.
- Yeah, totally.
Hey, you gonna
fix my arm or what?
- It's all done.
- What?
The sedative we gave you...
can cause you to lose the minutes
before we gave you the medicine.
Milk of amnesia strikes again.
Okay, all done.
Can you run that
to the lab for me?
This is what I thought America
would look like before I came here.
I wanted to come here
ever since I was 10.
Sounds like you were
a very ambitious kid.
That's not what my parents thought.
They said art was a hobby, not a career.
Well, my family were the
same. Science or nothing.
Hi, I'm Dr. Rasgotra. I've come
to check out this neck thing.
I could not afford the tuition,
but I sent my portfolio anyway.
- And you got a scholarship?
- Partial.
My parents had to give
up a lot to send me here.
- I'm sure they're very proud, Kwan.
- I don't know.
I didn't expect
people to be so...
- I don't know. ABBY:
What do you think?
It's probably an infected cyst,
I can do an I and D if you want.
- What's an I and D?
- Incision and drainage.
I'll open up the
area and clean it out.
Open it up? I don't understand.
It's a simple procedure.
It's to make sure the
fluid doesn't reaccumulate.
- Can this wait until I'm home?
- It's hard to be far away.
But you're here now,
so let us take care of this.
Dr. Brenner, labs are back
on your guy with the ear worm.
One step ahead of you, Frank.
Wired to receive lab reports,
I get them anywhere, anytime.
- Really?
- Yeah, sure, take a look.
Doesn't that raise
confidentiality issues?
Loosen up, Greg. Oh, excuse me.
If I'm the uptight one,
then this is bizarro ER.
I was thinking about you.
Get a sputum sample
from the homeless guy.
Nursing man needs a new diaper.
And swab the dripping
ulcer on the diabetic.
I was gonna have Dawn help
you, but you could handle it yourself.
- Anyone seen Dr. Brenner?
- He's around here somewhere.
Yeah, he still has a
few more asses to pinch.
What was that, doctor?
Where did you find this
guy? He's a piece of work.
Is he? PRATT: Yeah.
I don't wanna be the
boy who cries wolf...
- He's a wolf.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
Did residency in the
finest hospital in Melbourne.
Maybe so, but he ended
up without a clue on how to...
Uncle Donny. To what
do we owe this pleasure?
- Uncle Donny?
- You're his uncle?
My sister had a brief disastrous
tryst with an Aussie back in the '70s.
I've been trying to lure Simon to
the Northern Hemisphere for years.
Squeeze in a lunch at the Faculty
Club? I'd like to introduce you around.
You can survive without Simon
for a few hours, right, Greg?
- Definitely.
- Excuse me.
Is my wife here? Car
crash, very pregnant?
Missy and the baby
are doing great.
And you, young lady,
you must be Daisy.
Aye? Your mum
told me all about you.
- I'll take you to her.
- Thank you.
Sam, can we get some videos
for these kids in the family room?
Meet me out front in five? I
am so glad this is all working out.
I heard the attending interviews
were today. What time is yours?
- I postponed it.
- Really, why?
I'm still trying to get used
to the time change, I mean.
- Well, it's good to have you back.
- Thanks.
It's a child-life
emergency, please.
I have the Swiss Family
Robinson here. I'm not kidding.
A DVD player, a Nintendo,
a coloring book, I...
Steal from the PICU.
Yeah, I don't care.
- Do you think we could talk later?
- I'm a little busy now.
That's why I said later.
If it's one of those amends
conversations, I'd rather not.
It's five minutes.
It's all I'm asking.
Look, Abby, this... It's not
a good day for me, okay?
When they told me it had spread,
there was no one for me to tell.
So I figured, that's it.
I'll go back to Cayeux.
Where?
Cayeux-sur-Mer. It's a little
town on the coast of France.
I spent some time there in
the service, right after D-day.
I met a girl.
I promised her when I left
I'd see her again someday.
- Did you?
- No.
But when they told me I
was dying, I wanted to go...
and then the doctor
said I couldn't.
There wasn't time.
Now look at me.
Stuck in this place.
Could've been to Europe
and back five times by now.
I just made my first trip back
home to Croatia in almost 10 years.
And why did you stay
away so long? Two.
When I left, it
was a difficult time.
I was determined
to forget everything.
Forget what?
It's much better now,
it's an amazing place...
but back then, you
know, things were bad.
There was a lot of
chaos and destruction.
Oh, you mean the war?
When I left, I thought
I'd never go back.
It's called healing via
secondary intention.
The hole gets smaller as the
wound heals from the bottom up.
Did you like it there
when you first got there?
It was lonely, but it
gets better, give it time.
- Trauma 2. BRENNER:
Hey, it's Simon, is that Sam?
You got me.
I just got a lab report back on my
new phone, wanted to let you know.
Sparkling's fine, and
the grilled radicchio.
Cut.
Anyway, cytology came back
on the Korean kid, Kwan Lee.
- Dr. Brenner, you're on speakerphone.
- High-grade large-cell lymphoma.
- Dr. Brenner.
- Kid's got cancer.
Node's full of blasts,
looks very aggressive.
Tough break for the...
- It's an infection.
- Kwan.
That's what you said, you
said there was an infection.
- No big deal, that's what you said.
- It's probably early.
- It's good that we caught this...
- Shut up.
I don't have cancer.
I'm 19 years old.
I was mugged, I don't have cancer.
- Settle down, okay?
Get me out of here.
- Kwan.
- I don't have cancer.
I want to go home.
Get me out of here.
- What's going on?
- I want to go home.
What did you give him?
- Propofol.
This never happened.
After all he's been through...
he did not need to learn he had
cancer over the speakerphone.
Okay, so your plan
was to erase his memory.
He could be allergic,
he could stop breathing.
- I know the risks of propofol.
- He's waking up, come here.
- He's a terrified kid, all alone.
- We could've helped him deal with that.
This was gonna haunt
him for the rest of his life.
However long that
is. Why not take it?
- Start over, do it better.
- That's not how it works.
I know how it works.
It's our job to deal with
the consequences...
you can't pretend
it never happened.
Oh, well, thank
you for the lesson.
Look, I'll review the
slides at oncology...
and confirm the
diagnosis before I tell him.
He's my patient, how
about I deal with it?
- Hi.
- Hey.
So how long do I have to
stay here? I'm kind of starving.
Well, Sam could get you a tray.
No reason he has
to be NPO, right?
Listen, Kwan, is there anybody here
in Chicago that could pick you up?
Oh, I'm fine on the el.
I know, but just...
After the procedure and everything
I would feel more comfortable...
if there was someone
to drive you home.
Is there anybody from
school? A roommate, maybe?
My RA might come.
She's kind of weird, but
she's always been nice to me.
Okay, well, let's call her.
Thank you.
Sure.
So, what brought you to Chicago?
County General.
I thought I'd dive into work
and leave everything behind...
but it's not so easy, you know?
On a good day, you maybe
delay death for a while...
but you never really beat it.
You should try standup comedy.
- You're a gloomy bastard.
- Sorry.
So, what made you decide
to go back home then?
My father got sick.
And I thought I can
maybe fix things, you know?
Bring him back to Chicago,
find him the best oncologist.
He wouldn't leave.
You know? He wanted to...
He wanted to stay in his country,
surrounded by the people he loved.
He decided he wants
to die there, like that.
Good for him.
At first, I felt angry.
You know? Betrayed.
Why? Because he
didn't wanna fight?
But, eventually, I let
go of it, you know?
I just tried to
be there for him.
So, what? You learned
you can't fix things?
That made you feel this
might be a good place for you?
Kind of.
Two pair. Two
kings and two fours.
Aces over eights.
I believe they call that
the dead man's hand.
Hey, listen. If I'm canceling
the hotel, I should let them know.
It's the wreck of the Northerner.
Schooner from the 1800s.
It's been there for over 200 years, it
should still be there after this weekend.
Uh...
Okay, Little France
will have to wait.
I'm sorry you went
through all that trouble.
I feel bad bailing at the last minute,
and I really wanna do the dive.
Okay.
Hey. What if I came with you?
- Do you even dive?
- I have once, in Belize.
Kind of hated it, but I
could hang out on the boat...
mix martinis, wait
for you to come up.
It'll be cold and boring.
Really? I'll see
if there's room.
- I've had it with Brenner.
- Anspaugh's Australian love child?
Yeah, I'm pretty sure that
nephew story's just a cover-up.
Brenner's not so bad. You know,
I think he has a refreshing energy.
And I think you've
got a man-crush.
Don't be ridiculous. Wha...?
I see the way you look at him.
Just because I can see
the appeal of another man...
Forget it.
Having an extra attending might make
it so you can spend time with Bettina.
- When's the surgery?
- I have no idea.
- We broke up.
- Oh, no. Oh, no.
Please tell me you didn't
bail on your sick girlfriend?
No, I didn't bail. She did.
- I have to respect what she wants.
- She wants flowers, cupcakes.
Women love cupcakes.
- Are you listening to what I'm saying?
- Yes, I am.
Bettina is pushing you away
because she's afraid to depend on you.
If you don't see
that, you're an idiot.
Oh, wow. Wow.
Thanks, Morris.
But you know what?
I don't need romantic
advice from a guy...
whose only lasting relationship
was with an inflatable doll.
Cupcakes. With sprinkles.
Damn it.
What, can't you help?
- Me?
- Yeah, I can't reach the Zofran.
I don't know, Sam, what if someone
sees us? They might get the wrong idea.
Do you have to be a dick?
This porridge is too
hot, this is too cold.
Porridge?
I don't know how
to act around you.
I gave you a doughnut, Sam.
A doughnut. Nobody cared.
And you're acting like I got down
on my knee and offered you up a ring.
Here. Stop being so nutty.
Sam, we need you in here, now.
Oh, God, it hurts.
- No bleeding.
- What happened?
I don't know. She was
fine five minutes ago.
Baby just had a
decel into the 70s.
- You're gonna be okay.
- Shut up.
No, it's not. I'm not okay.
What's going on? She
never did this the other times.
- She's having contractions.
- I can see that.
- You think she's abrupting?
- I don't know, seems to fit.
- Missy?
- She's hemorrhaging in her uterus.
- Pulse ox, 66. ABBY:
Okay, Sam, grab some O-neg.
- Get the airway box, we're going up.
- Up, where?
She needs an O.R. now. I'll
explain it to you on the way.
Honey, something's really wrong.
- Squeeze in the blood.
- I wanna see the kids.
- I know, I know, you're gonna be okay.
- What's going on?
- Oh, God, I need to push.
No, no, no, wait.
You have to wait.
I can't. I need to push.
Hang on.
- Damn it.
- Everybody out now, go, go, go!
We're going back.
We'll deliver here.
- That's an arm, Abby.
- It's way out of our league.
There's an increased risk of
cord prolapse shoulder dystocia.
- We're not set up to do that.
- She's gonna bleed out.
- By the...
- Treatment for abruption is delivery.
We can do it now or wait until both
mom and baby are hypoxic or dead.
- Go, go, go.
- Okay, people.
Move out of the
way. Coming through.
It's rotated at a weird angle.
Where's OB? Kid's gonna
have a brachial plexus injury.
- Systolic's 71.
- This is taking too long.
- Head's the biggest part, takes time.
- Heart rate's in the hundreds.
- Forceps?
- No.
Vacuum? ABBY: No, not
yet. I mean, I don't know.
Put her in McRoberts.
- What?
- Put her legs up.
- What's the matter, is the baby stuck?
- I just need to turn it.
- Have you done this before?
- Call OB, we're screwed.
You're not helping.
Is that meconium?
- Does anyone know what they're doing?
- Shut up, everybody shut up.
Morris, suprapubic pressure.
Sam, get her legs back now.
Brenner, get ready
to bag. And Missy.
- Missy, next contraction, you go.
- What?
Okay? Okay. MISSY: Okay.
Down and through.
Head's out. That's a girl.
- All right, bulb suction?
- Baby had a presenting arm.
And you delivered in the ER?
Mom was bleeding out,
baby was bradycardic.
You did it, you did good.
I told you 13th time's
the charm, right?
- Well, then, nice job.
- Why, thank you.
Did you hear what
we just did in there?
Well, what Abby did, rather.
Gotta give credit where credit's due.
- What is wrong with you?
- Excuse me?
Are you a sociopath?
A sadist, stoned?
I don't understand how anyone
can give a cancer diagnosis...
with such a lack of sensitivity.
I was talking to his
nurse, not the patient.
You were on speakerphone.
And I swear, it was like you
were smiling when you said it.
I didn't realize
that, and I'm sorry.
- But what's done is done.
- No, it's not, it's not done.
We have to live with what
happened today and it makes me sick.
You know, I heard that you were
tightly wound, but I had no idea.
Get the hell away, before I
throw that thing against the wall.
What's the deal with the chopper run?
We've been suited up for 15 minutes.
Dispatch called,
there's a wind advisory.
They closed our helipad,
so they sent it to the CALP.
Were you planning on
telling us, or leave us hanging?
Maybe he likes us in yellow.
Well, your secret's
safe with me.
It better be.
- Okay, I gotta work now.
- Okay.
Saved the last one for you.
Frank, you are an
officer and a gentleman.
Thank you.
- Lucien.
- Skye.
I don't think you should
join me on the dive.
I shouldn't?
You don't wanna be on
the boat all day by yourself.
It won't be any fun.
You mean, it wouldn't
be any fun for you.
- What?
- I might get in the way.
Spoil your playtime
with the boys.
Is that it?
- Lucien.
- What?
How come I've never
met any of these boys?
- You're not really doing this, are you?
- Doing what?
Look.
I've tried to be cool with your
fluidity and your independence.
I've scolded myself for being
envious of your dive buddies...
your climbing club,
your bike team.
You don't need to be
jealous. They're all friends.
- I happen to have a lot of guy friends.
- Yeah, you do.
You do. In fact, you have a
pathologic need to solicit male affection.
Excuse me?
You think I don't see the game
you're playing with Brenner?
Forgive me for being slow.
- I'm finally getting it now.
- Get what?
The whole
love-the-one-your-with thing...
is nothing but a bogus justification to
screw anything that catches your eye.
Well...
Good. Good, you
finally figured me out.
And you're absolutely
right. I've done everybody.
Pratt, Morris, Gates.
Security guards, Mel,
the Roach Coach guy.
And I'm having a damn
good time with Simon Brenner.
We've worn the
varnish right off my desk.
You know, it's
too bad. It really is.
I was starting to let my
guard down with you.
Bought this to keep
you company on my dive.
- Skye.
- Gotta run.
- Scheduled a quickie with Frank.
- Wait.
- I thought you left.
- I'm just working on a project.
- I really wanted to tell you...
- Yeah, you know what?
I am really not in the mood for your
righteous disapproval right now, okay?
- Abby...
- I know I'm supposed to take it.
But not tonight. And tomorrow,
I promise, I will bend over.
Abby, stop.
Good job today. That's
all I wanted to say.
All right, look, I know
I've been judgmental.
I just... That I grew up surrounded
by people with problems, big problems.
I watched them dig
themselves into a hole...
and not really
try to get out of it.
And maybe that's
not you. I hope it isn't.
I'm working really hard
for that not to be me.
I know.
Sometimes it's hard for me
to be real rah-rah about it.
I hate rah-rah.
- All right, well, night.
- Night.
Oh, Dr. Anspaugh.
- Hi, Abby.
- Hi.
Um...
I know I postponed my interview
today, but that was a mistake.
I don't know why I thought I
should wait, because I shouldn't.
I wanna be an attending here.
And I think I would be a good one.
So I was wondering if, maybe,
you could squeeze me in tomorrow.
- Or the next day...
- I have a few minutes right now.
Come on in.
Honey, listen, a B in history...
does not ruin your chances of
being appointed to the Supreme Court.
Yeah, listen, my doctor's
here. I gotta go, okay, honey?
Okay, I'll call you
later. I love you.
My son, Tommy, is
so hard on himself.
I mean, it's sad.
When I was 15, my greatest
ambition was to date a boy with a car.
Sheryl...
Uh-oh. What?
I don't know how to tell
you this, so I'll just, uh...
You've developed a
postoperative infection.
Well, I knew that. That's
why I'm on the antibiotics now.
Right, but now the
aortic graft is involved.
And tomorrow we're gonna
have to do a surgery to clean it out.
Hopefully, that
will be it, but...
You know, Dr. Dubenko
was gonna tell you hours ago.
But I felt I should do it.
And then I couldn't.
All day long, I've avoided
this room and I'm sorry.
Don't worry.
It's not like I had big
plans for the morning.
Sheryl, I've given hundreds
of patients bad news.
I don't know why
I'm being so crazy.
- Don't know why I couldn't tell you.
- Because we've become friends.
It's sweet.
Damn it, I don't know
why you got infected.
Just...
Just bad luck, you know.
Something that statistically...
It's okay, Neela.
Don't cry. Don't.
- Yeah, but you've been doing so well.
- So?
You go back in tomorrow,
you do what you have to do.
I survived a
ruptured aorta, right?
I mean, not such a
big thing after that.
I'm gonna have the
same surgeon, right?
- Definitely.
- Then I'm gonna be fine.
I'm gonna be just fine.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- How did it go?
- Good, good, I took the job.
You did?
You don't know how badly
I wanna tell you I'm fine.
That we can work everything
through and find a way to fix it.
- Luka, you know you don't need to...
- Or that I could forget and go on.
But too much has happened.
I have to move out.