.
- Welcome back.
- Thanks for holding
things down for me
while I was out of commission.
- I'm more than happy
to stand in as chief
till you settle back in.
Brothers in arms.
Got your back.
- It couldn't have been easy,
coming back here
given our relationship.
- My coming back here is not
about you or us, it's about me.
- What is this?
Flash money and an undercover
investigation,
what does that look like?
- Small bills.
- Not 40-50K?
- Hell no.
- I don't
want to endanger myself.
I don't want to endanger
you because you can't
handle being in the dark.
- I care about you, Milena.
I can handle it.
♪
- Hey, what are you doing up?
- Oh, nothing.
- Dylan...
You're staring
out the window at something.
- There's this blue Impala
parked behind my building.
Been idling there
for like 15 minutes.
- It's probably an Uber
or someone who pulled
off the road to make a call.
- Yeah, you're probably right.
- Okay.
What is going on with you?
Talk to me.
- I'm just worried somebody
might've followed you.
- No one's more
careful than me.
♪
Gonna go shower.
- Morning.
- Hey, um,
while I got you here...
I've been holding onto this
for you since you left.
Your old coffeemaker...
- Yeah.
- Uh, thing, I guess.
Yeah, you-you just never
reached out to me,
let me know where you were,
so here you are.
I remember how you craved
your--craved your coffee.
- You know, I'm not so addicted
to caffeine anymore,
but you keep it.
Yeah, thanks though.
- Okay.
- Excuse me,
do you need any assistance?
- Oh, no, thank you,
I'm--I'm okay.
Ugh, God...
- Are you sure?
- Hey, here,
let us help, we're doctors.
- Okay.
Why are hospital parking lots
always so far away
from the front door?
- I'll find you a wheelchair,
help get you inside.
- All right--mm, okay.
- Watch your step.
- Thank you.
- I woke up this morning,
and something just felt off.
It was like everything
just got super swollen.
- Mm-hmm.
- How many weeks are you?
- Almost 33.
- Okay, your belly
is a bit distended,
so let's take a look.
- Uh, it's a boy.
- Oh, that's great.
- That's great.
Can we contact your OB for you?
- I don't--I don't actually
have one right now.
I'm--I'm sorry,
I'm kind of in a bit
of a transition
with things right now.
- That's okay.
- All right, Ingrid,
so I'm seeing some extra
amniotic fluid and your baby's
abdomen looks a little swollen.
- That--that
doesn't sound good.
What's causing this?
- Well, sometimes it
could be caused
by an infection,
sometimes the baby has anemia.
- Is the baby going to be okay?
- I'd like
to do some further testing,
but it's
not necessarily serious.
- Yeah, the good thing is,
you're already far enough
to deliver a healthy boy,
even if we have to induce
labor, all right?
- Thank you.
- Hey, Doris, got your page.
What do we got?
- 22-year-old male
in Treatment 3.
Name's Luis Pena, passed out
in front of the mayor's house.
- The mayor's house?
- Mm-hmm, during a protest.
He's in bad shape, you'll see.
- Okay.
- Are you the doctor
in charge of Luis Pena?
- I am, and you are?
- Mindy Zheng,
I'm a journalist.
Perhaps you've read my
Substack about the protest.
- I haven't, excuse me.
Hey, Mr. Pena, so--
- Luis is on day 36
of a hunger strike,
and he doesn't want
his progress thwarted
in any way whatsoever.
Got it?
- Doris, would you page
Dr. Charles, please?
- Yeah.
- Ma'am, would you please--
would you step outside?
- No, she stays.
Mindy's telling my story.
♪
.
- Look, Luis, your labs
are concerning.
Your liver enzymes are up,
your kidneys are starting
to fail, I mean,
you're likely to go
into multi-system organ failure
if you don't allow us
to give you nutrition.
- Nutrition?
- Yeah, through a feeding tube.
- So food.
- Yeah.
- Five weeks, Luis, that's,
um...
that's real commitment.
- I made a promise to myself.
- Tell me about that,
a promise about what?
- You know Greyland Recycling?
- Yeah, I'm familiar with it.
- They have a huge contract
with the city.
Greyland handles
most of Chicago's
indus--industrial--Mindy.
- Greyland recently closed
a metal shredding facility
in a white affluent
neighborhood,
and the mayor just approved
the final permit
to relocate that facility
to South Chicago,
into a lower income
neighborhood.
- Where I grew up.
- Somehow guessing
that metal shredding,
not the best thing
for the environment.
- Definitely not--
of course, Greyland claims
that pollution controls
will help keep residents safe.
- If that was true, why did
the rich people want it gone?
- It's environmental racism.
- Look, your cause,
your devotion to it,
I find genuinely admirable,
but have you asked yourself
how effective you can be
from a hospital bed?
- That's why Mindy's here,
so people know how I'm doing.
- Oh, hey,
you can't smoke in here, bud.
- Of course, yeah, it just
helps with the hunger pangs.
- Yeah, I understand.
- So what is our end game
strategy here, Luis?
- I won't eat until
Greyland calls off their move.
- And if they don't?
- Sometimes change
requires sacrifice.
- Well, um, we're gonna
let you rest up a bit
and check back
in a while, okay?
♪
- So what's his status?
- Well, he'll drink water
but nothing else,
won't even allow
an IV for fluids.
I mean, pretty soon his body's
going to shut down.
- So is there anything else
we can do?
- He knows what he wants,
he has very clear logic
to support his goals, you know,
he understands the stakes.
- PUBS is short for
Percutaneous Umbilical
Blood Sampling.
It'll tell us a lot more
about how your baby
is doing in there.
- Okay.
- Okay, now,
this first needle is
going to temporarily
paralyze your baby.
- Don't worry,
it's not as scary as it sounds.
Just to keep him from
moving around too much.
- He does like to kick--okay.
- Okay, little pinch.
Great, that wasn't too painful.
All right, now,
with this second needle,
we're going to draw blood
right from where
your umbilical cord
connects with your baby.
- Like an amniocentesis?
- Did you have one done before?
- No, but around the end
of my first trimester,
I did this blood test,
a panel, and it said
that there was a chance
that the baby might
be born with spinal
muscular atrophy.
- SMA, that's
a serious condition.
I'm surprised you didn't
mention this earlier.
- I guess I was trying
not to think about it too much.
Could that be the cause
of the swelling?
- Perhaps,
but it's hard to tell.
Let's see what the lab has
to say about the blood test.
- Okay.
- You're gonna have
one more pinch.
Here we go...
- Hey, buddy.
Got a patient
asking for you by name,
a Gerald Simmons, a navy vet.
Ring a bell?
- Can't say it does.
What's he in for?
- Severe headaches,
chest palpitations.
BP's jumping out of the gym.
I'm setting him up
for an EKG as we speak.
CPO Simmons,
allow me to present
Lieutenant Commander
Ethan Choi.
- At your service, chief.
I'll take over, Trish.
I apologize,
but it's getting so I
can't remember all
the patients I've seen.
Have we met before?
- No, but I got
a recommendation
from the VA that
you were a good doctor.
- They didn't say anything
about me?
My feelings are hurt.
- Gerald,
I see your BP's 170/110.
It's good you came in.
- Yeah, start him
on a nicardipine drip for that.
- On it.
- You got some
serious-looking scars here.
Can I ask
where you got this one?
- I had a valve replaced
almost ten years ago now.
- And this other one?
- Appendectomy when
I was a kid.
- You know, when you're
done taking inventory,
you should check out his ink.
It's pretty cool.
- I'm sorry,
I don't know why I did that.
- That's okay.
- Oh...
- What is it?
- It feels like something's
sitting on my chest...
- It's his heart,
start bagging him.
I'll start compressions.
- Yeah, no pulse,
all right, he's in V-fib.
♪
Charge to 200.
Clear.
- Got a pulse.
- All right,
sinus tach, hold CPR.
- Keep bagging,
let's get him intubated.
- Hello, I'm Dr. Scott.
This is our charge nurse,
Maggie Lockwood.
- I'm Caitlin.
This is my husband, Theo.
- Okay, and you must be Zoe.
So what's going on?
- We were leaving a restaurant
just outside the city.
- We're on a road trip,
we're visiting my sister
in Cleveland.
- And Zoe couldn't walk from
the restaurant back to the car.
- Some idiot janitor
mopped the bathroom floor
but didn't put a sign up.
- So you fell
on the slippery floor?
- Well, we didn't
see that happen.
- You don't believe me?
- We don't believe you, no.
- I'm sorry,
am I missing something?
- Zoe's had a history
of alcohol issues.
We think
that's why she can't walk--
- Are you serious right now?
I fell and hurt myself, but you
think I've been drinking?
- We can smell it on you, Zoe.
How dumb do you think we are?
- Pretty dumb, actually,
because I haven't had
one sip of alcohol in months.
- Calm down.
- How embarrassing this is.
- You all right, Zoe?
- Here.
- Okay, CBC, CMP,
blood and urine tox,
and blood alcohol.
Plus a chest X-ray and CT
abdomen and pelvis
to see about that fall.
All right, that should give us
a clear idea of what's
going on here, yeah?
- Well, that was strange, huh?
- Yeah, weird timing on the MI,
for sure.
- I'm talking about
him touching you that way.
You think he mistook you
for someone else?
- No, I think he
was more confused
than anything else,
given his condition.
Except, you know that
tattoo he had on his arm?
- Nautical star?
- Yeah, my father had one just
like it, in the same location.
- Well, perhaps
they served together.
I'm guessing they're
probably the same age.
Hey, Trish,
please start a normal
cardiac work up, would ya?
Chest X-ray and a blood gas,
trops, CBC, CMP, and an EKG.
- Well, this is
a nice surprise.
- Hey, Felicia, uh,
you're not at work, are you?
- Uh, no, not today.
I'm actually heading
to your Dad's to pack up
the last of his stuff.
- Perfect, um,
you think I could ask you
to do me a big favor?
- Do we have a lunch date
I forgot about?
- No, Daniel,
I'm here for a patient.
- Oh.
- I've been following
the news on Luis.
I read that he was brought
over here this morning.
- Luis Pena's your patient?
- Yes, for many years,
but we haven't had
a session for a long time, so.
- Oh.
- Oh, God, Luis.
- Yeah.
- Have you
gotten him to eat yet?
- No, he's very serious
about this.
You should definitely
have a chat with him.
- I will. Want to come in?
- Yeah.
- Labs are back on that
PUBS test you requested.
- Oh, great, thanks, Trini.
- Yeah.
- Looks like the baby's anemic.
We need to transfuse him,
try to buy him a little
more time in utero.
- That's weird,
it says the baby's
blood type is O-positive.
- Yeah, so?
- Yeah, that's what I thought--
Ingrid's is AB-negative.
- That's not
medically possible.
- Ingrid can't be
this baby's mother.
♪
.
- I mean, technically, I'm not
the baby's biological mother.
I'm a surrogate.
I mean, I was a surrogate.
- Was?
- You remember that
genetic panel I told you about?
The one
that said the baby had SMA?
When the couple found out,
they decided
to terminate the pregnancy.
- But you didn't.
- I just--I just couldn't.
- Were the parents
made aware of that?
- What does that matter?
They--they didn't
want the baby anyway.
- Okay, you know what,
this is something that
we can discuss later.
What's important now
is the health of the baby.
So we're gonna start
by transfusing him
with some blood, see if that
helps cure the anemia.
- Okay, thank you.
- Dr. Asher?
So we have to confirm this
with the biological parents.
- I'm not sure that
that's our responsibility,
especially if the parents
gave up the baby.
- Well, we don't know
if that's true.
Look how long it took her
to tell us about
the genetic defects.
- Why would she be lying?
- Bottom line, she can't
ghost the parents like that.
They have every right
to know what's going on.
We have to notify legal
so they can contact them.
- You're right, okay.
- What I'm seeing here
worries me--worries us.
You are risking your life now.
- I'm doing
what needs to be done.
- But haven't
you made your point?
- Last I checked,
nothing's changed.
They're still relocating
the metal shredder.
- Then I don't think
I have made my point.
- Mindy, I'd like to have
a moment alone with Luis.
- No, he wants me here.
- Okay, I have to tell you,
she doesn't have
your best interests at heart.
Her priority is her story.
- I called Mindy.
I initiated the contact.
- Considering what you and I
have dealt with in the past,
I think you
can understand my concern.
- You see the old me.
You don't see that
this is important.
- Um, Dr. Richardson,
quick word, please?
♪
I just feel like
I'm missing something.
Can I get
a little more history?
- Luis tried to take
his life three years ago.
He's been struggling
with depression his whole life.
- Okay.
- I mean, what if this is
just another suicide attempt?
We should
have him on a psych hold.
- But even if you're right,
you know, a psych hold's not
gonna solve the problem
of getting him to eat.
We can't force feed him,
he has capacity.
- I am terrified that he's
going to take his own life.
- I get that,
but unfortunately,
we just--we don't have
the legal grounds to stop him.
- So your
CT scans are negative.
I'm not seeing any injury
from a fall.
But your blood-alcohol content
is very high
at .240 grams per deciliter.
- You're drunk, we knew it.
I'm not! It's a mistake.
- We've got to get you
into some kind of program.
Can you help us with that?
- Of course.
- I didn't drink anything.
- All right, stop lying, Zoe,
okay, that's enough.
- I'm not lying.
- Just stop, it's insulting.
You're slurring your words.
- It's insulting,
you're slurring your words.
- Uh, get a line,
hang a liter of saline.
- You got it.
- We're going to
hydrate Zoe, okay?
She should
sober up pretty soon.
- How's our squid?
- Not sure,
tachycardia's still persistent.
Doesn't appear to have
damaged any heart muscle,
but cardiology wants
to cath him to make sure.
- And his BP?
- Still elevated.
- Even after the nicardipine?
- Yeah.
- That's odd.
All right, let's add
an esmolol drip on top.
See if we can't get
that back under control.
- Hey, Ethan!
- Hey.
Hope this was what
you were looking for.
- Thank you, I know
it's a huge inconvenience.
- Ah, it's not that big a deal.
I like coming into Chicago.
Actually, wondering if
maybe you
want to grab a bite after work?
- Yeah, I'd like that.
- Great.
So what are you hoping to find?
- I think my patient
knew my father.
Uh, you wanna take a look?
- Yeah.
- Here they are,
doctors Asher and Halstead.
This is
Meg and Jonathan Harris,
they just got in from Indiana.
- Ingrid was our surrogate.
- I can't believe
this is happening.
- I'm sorry.
- How is she?
We heard the baby's
having some swelling?
- That's because
of the Type 1 SMA.
- Actually, we're not sure
those things are related.
- How could they not be?
Weak muscles, inability
to swallow, collapsed lungs.
Median survival rate
of less than a year.
That's what this baby
has to look forward to.
- We didn't want this,
for him to suffer.
When we made
the decision to terminate,
Ingrid and I
sat together and cried.
- I understand.
- What do we do now?
- Well, from this hospital's
perspective, Mr. Harris,
right now, our top priority
is the health of the mother
and the baby.
- Ingrid is not the mother.
My wife is the mother.
Ingrid had a contract with us,
and what she's doing is wrong.
- I don't understand.
Why--why she did this?
Our poor baby.
- Dr. Asher, it's Ingrid.
The baby's heart rate.
- Great, thank you--excuse me.
- Ingrid's here
in the emergency room?
- Mr. and Mrs. Harris, please!
- What--what's going on?
- Fetal heart rate decels.
- The baby didn't
tolerate the procedure.
- What have you done, Ingrid?
- What are they doing here?
- How could you do this to us,
to our baby?
- Mr. and Mrs. Harris,
you have to leave, please.
- Let's open the Hybrid O.R.
for an emergency C-section.
This baby
needs to be delivered now.
.
- Wow.
I haven't looked
through this in years.
- Patrick looked so handsome
in his uniform.
Bet it runs in the family.
So what exactly
are you looking for?
- This guy says we've never
met before, but I don't know,
there something about him
that seemed familiar.
There, that's it.
That's the picture
I was thinking of.
- Could that be your patient?
- Gerald, yeah.
Certainly looks like him.
And, see, they both
have the same tattoo.
- So I guess they
did serve together.
That's pretty remarkable.
Wow, your father's
so young in this photo.
It's funny.
He got older, but he didn't
really change much.
- Yeah, change--
the scar, that's it,
that would explain it.
- Explain what?
- Excuse me.
♪
- Your dad and Gerald?
- Yeah.
- So what am I supposed
to be looking at here?
- His appendectomy scar.
Look at the coloring,
then look at this.
- Well, when was this taken,
50 years ago?
I mean, come on,
photos age, right?
- It's not the photo
that's changed, it's the scar.
See how the pigmentation
has changed?
- Yeah, I don't know, maybe.
- I think he has
a pheochromocytoma.
- An adrenal gland tumor?
- Yeah, it would explain why
his hypertension's
not responding to medication,
and the tachycardia,
and the change
in pigmentation of the scar.
- I think you're reaching.
- I'm going to need
your approval to get this scan.
- All right,
let's CAT scan him,
get plasma-free metanephrines,
and, uh,
at worst,
we'll definitively rule it out.
♪
- Hey--hey,
Pops, what's going on?
- We need to talk.
- Okay, you wanna grab a beer
at Molly's after my shift?
- No, we don't have the time.
Come on.
- I need you to tell me
about this drug dealer,
Milena Jovanovic.
- Uh, I don't know
what you're talking about.
- Well, the word is,
on the street, is that you two
are seeing each other.
- Who'd you hear that from?
- I've got intel
all over the city, son.
- Well, you got
some bad intel.
Milena was
a former patient of mine.
- Okay, then why was she
coming out of your apartment
at 5:00 a.m. this morning?
You know
you can't lie to me, boy.
- I wouldn't date
a drug dealer.
You know that.
Look, you don't have
to worry about me.
- I'm always gonna
worry about you, son.
Whatever you're doing,
I get the distinct feeling
that you know it's wrong.
I love you.
- Dr. Scott, they need you!
- Can somebody help us?
- Help!
- We've got an alarm,
get me Dr. Scott!
Excuse me, sir.
- What's happening?
- She's having a seizure.
- Push 5 of Ativan.
- Meds are in.
Thank you.
Come on, sweetie, breathe.
Breathe.
- What happened?
- Oh, thank God.
- She's gotten worse
since we've been here.
Is this related to the alcohol?
What's going on?
- We are going to get
to the bottom of this.
♪
- Hi.
The C-section went off
without a hitch.
Both Ingrid and the baby boy
are healthy
and in good condition.
- The baby's healthy?
- Yes.
- How can that be?
What about the SMA?
- Actually,
there's no sign of any defect.
He's breathing well,
and his muscle tone is good.
The neonatologist is performing
a more thorough exam
as we speak,
but all signs look optimistic.
- Oh, my God.
- I don't understand.
What about the panel
we took the first trimester?
- That's happening more
and more these days.
A lot of false positives.
- We were told
it was 99% accurate.
- Big tech, unfortunately,
got a look at the profit
potential and has,
quite frankly,
joined the market
in an irresponsible way.
They're providing
promises of accuracy
that just
aren't achievable yet.
- And your doctor
should've advised you
to schedule a follow-up amnio.
- I don't know what to say.
We didn't think
he would survive birth.
- Well, you made what
you thought was
the right decision at the time,
but unfortunately,
you were given
false information.
- Honey--honey, listen.
It's like--it's like
it's a miracle.
After all these years,
we have a baby.
- We have a healthy baby.
- Thank you.
♪
- Okay, I'll be right back.
All right, protein is down,
albumin is down.
He's near the end.
- Dr. Marcel.
- Yeah?
- A Cook County judge
has issued a court order
to place
a feeding tube into Luis.
- What?
- You petitioned a judge?
- I had to.
- On--on what grounds?
- Dr. Marcel?
- This isn't right.
- Lonnie...
- All right.
We have to place
a feeding tube.
- You can't do this.
- Yeah, well,
I'm not allowed to let him die.
- But it's his choice.
- The judge disagrees.
- No...
- I'm sorry, Luis.
Soft restraints.
- Please, don't do this.
- Dr. Marcel...
- Soft restraints, let's go.
- Hey.
Hey.
No.
Don't do this.
No!
Don't do this!
♪
.
- Okay, tube's in.
Just started nutrition.
Should see some improvements.
- Thank you, Dr. Marcel,
that's good to hear.
- You know, I, uh,
I kinda wish you'd
read me in before you
petitioned the court.
- Why, so you could
talk me out of it?
- What exactly did
you say to the judge?
- That Luis is experiencing
temporary mental deterioration
due to the severity
of his poor physical condition.
- Oh, come on, that's a bit
of a stretch, isn't it?
I mean,
from where I'm standing,
he clearly
has decisional capacity.
- How would you know?
You just met him this morning.
- Well, maybe
that gives me a little
objectivity in this case.
- When it comes
to this patient,
in these circumstances,
I have considerably
more insight
into his state of mind.
♪
- Hey, Dean, look.
- Gerald's CAT scan.
- The pheochromocytoma,
it's there.
- I'm not seeing it.
- Look closer,
on top of his left kidney.
It's small,
but there's definitely
an indiscriminate mass.
- Well, "definitely" is
a bit strong, but, yeah,
if you squint, I grant you,
there might be something there.
What about the metanephrines?
- Positive as well.
- All right, well,
let's get him up to surgery.
- Ingrid's contract
stipulated that she's allowed
to spend 30 minutes
with the baby postpartum.
- I feel so guilty.
Maybe we should give her
another hour or so.
- Honey, that will just
make things harder.
- Dr. Asher,
why don't you inform Ingrid
that we'll be transporting
the baby in a few minutes
so the Harrises can begin
bonding with their child.
- Sure.
- I got Zoe's labs back.
- Her blood-alcohol content
is now up to .310.
- Wouldn't alcohol poisoning
explain her seizure?
- For sure,
but her numbers are still
climbing while she sits there
on a saline drip.
I mean,
how's that even possible?
- She must be drinking.
- We checked
all her stuff for booze.
Her parents are watching
over her like a hawk.
She couldn't have possibly
snuck a drink at--
She swore up and down that
she didn't drink anything.
What if she wasn't lying?
- But how?
- Take another look
at her CT scans,
the one from this morning.
- I got your labs back, Zoe.
Seems your blood-alcohol
content keeps rising.
- That doesn't make any sense.
- Yeah, it's tripping me up,
too, because Zoe
said she hadn't had
anything to drink.
- Nope, not a drop.
- Still, though, I gotta try
to make sense of these numbers.
You know, I do keep
thinking back on this fad
from a couple years ago.
A bunch of kids used
to take tampons
and soak them in alcohol
before using them
and then absorb the alcohol
through the bloodstream.
You wouldn't know anything
about that, would you?
Reason I ask is, you were
on this road trip today,
stuck in a car
with your parents.
Conditions were there,
if you were desperate
to get your buzz on.
- No way.
- Yeah, you are
wearing a tampon.
It showed up in your CT scans.
Whatever you're doing, Zoe,
I get the distinct feeling
that you know it's wrong.
♪
- Zoe.
- Honey,
you're making yourself sick.
- Zoe, why don't you come
with me to the bathroom, okay?
- Okay. Look what we have here.
- That, I believe, is a pheo.
- Looks like you were right,
good sleuthing.
Please send this to path
for frozen section.
Make sure it's benign
and the margins look good.
Big win for the U.S. Navy
today, guys and gals.
- I've been asked to bring
the baby to the NICU now.
- No, no.
- Give us a minute.
- Ingrid, it's time.
- I can't believe they're going
to take my baby away from me.
- Look, I understand
how you feel,
okay, but he is their baby.
- They didn't want him.
- Ingrid...
- Meg, you're not
supposed to be here.
- We owe everything
to you, Ingrid.
I don't know how we can ever
repay you for what you've done.
And I'm so, so sorry
for what I did,
for what I wanted to do.
If I had known...
Ingrid, I shouldn't
have listened--
I should've been like you.
I will never forgive myself.
- No, Meg, don't.
- And you were so strong.
You're so brave.
- No, stop.
That--it wasn't like that.
I wasn't brave,
I wasn't strong.
I--I knew.
- You knew?
You knew what?
- I had this friend,
they said the same thing
to her,
but her baby was okay.
And I just had this feeling
that this baby would too.
- Why didn't you tell us?
- Because I--
because, I wanted him.
- Oh, Ingrid...
- I'm sorry--I--I am so sorry.
- No--no...
Look at him.
Look at what you did.
He's beautiful.
- He is.
♪
And, um...
and you...
You're going to be a great mom.
- Thank you, Ingrid.
- Yeah.
♪
- Oh, my God! Fire! Fire!
- Oh, my God, fire! Fire!
- Back up--back up!
Clear the way!
♪
- I need help in here!
Luis--backboard, let's go!
On my count, okay, we roll him.
One, two, three.
Easy, easy, easy.
One, two, three, let's go.
Luis--get him to the room.
Come on.
♪
.
- Okay, tube's in.
Let's get him on a vent--
let's go, come on.
- Leads are on.
- Looks like
90% of his body is burned.
Okay, I need two liters of IV.
Let's go through the burns
if we have to.
Let's roll him.
- Got it.
- Nice and easy.
Let me see him.
Okay, put him down.
- Can he survive this?
- How in the world
did this happen?
- I know he had a lighter
and some cigarettes
when he came in this week.
Oh, look, there, that was full,
that thing.
- But how did he get to it?
He was in restraints.
- He said his wrists hurt.
- You loosened his restraints?
- Well, he was in so much pain.
- I can't get blood pressure
or a pulse.
- Okay, he's in PEA.
Okay, let's
get a milligram of epi.
Let's go, come on.
- Got it.
- With these burns
and malnutrition,
his survival's unlikely.
Hey, Luis!
- Epi's in.
- No.
- Luis, buddy, come on.
Come on, buddy.
♪
- Asystole.
- Okay.
Time of death, 19:47.
♪
- Well, at least
she got her story.
- Um, not the one she was
hoping for, is my guess.
- Just put in your discharge
paperwork, you're good to go.
- Thank you, Dr. Scott.
- Zoe's feeling much better.
I think we all are,
and as much as we wish
this hadn't happened...
- We can now get Zoe
the help she needs.
Those substance abuse programs,
can we still get
that information from you?
- Absolutely.
- Good on Zoe
for coming around.
- Yeah,
pretty late in the game.
- It's never too late
to do the right thing.
- Why'd you change your mind?
- You did a nice thing for me,
saving this.
I was rude to dismiss it,
so I would like to apologize.
- Not necessary.
- Come on, Will,
you can be honest.
There must've been a bit
of you that was upset with me.
- Well, okay, yeah.
I didn't hear from you
for almost two years.
- I ghosted you.
- Yeah.
I wanted to believe what we had
was more meaningful than that.
- Will, come on.
Of course it was.
Will...
Me cutting you off
wasn't because
I didn't care about you.
Okay, I needed to work
on myself, on my sobriety,
clear everything away
so I could start again.
You know, now that
we're working together again...
Maybe we could agree
to turn the page?
Be friends?
- Sure.
♪
- So Mindy Zheng already
published her story online.
And almost immediately,
the mayor put Greyland's
relocation permit on hold.
So at least it looks like,
you know,
Luis might be
getting what he wanted.
- I know, but did he
have to lose his life for it?
And did I do the right thing
getting that court order?
I don't think so.
Oh, I'm sorry, I have trouble
with that kind of thing.
- Hi.
- Hey.
- You were all
that I thought about today.
♪
What's up?
- We can't do this anymore.
It's not safe for you.
- I'm not worried.
- Cops saw you leaving
my place this morning.
- Um...
- It's okay.
I didn't
blow your cover, but...
- Yeah.
So I guess this is it?
- It's not
what I want to do, but...
We gotta.
For your sake.
♪
- Yeah.
- You know, I--
- Oh, there's the
man of the hour.
I was just telling Gerald
about your stick save today.
He made the right call
coming in to see you.
- How are you feeling?
- Dean said I had
a pretty close call today.
- He's a tough old salt.
Let's not make it
a regular thing, all right?
- Thank you.
- So Gerald, you didn't tell me
you served with my father.
♪
- I remember
when this was taken.
- Um...
I'm not sure if you've heard,
but Patrick passed away
about three months ago.
- I know.
He didn't want me
to see him when he was sick.
- Yeah, he kind of
cut himself off.
I didn't find out how sick
he was till it was too late.
- Patrick was always
a very private person,
but he told me a lot about you.
That's why I came in today--
I wanted to meet his son.
- So you two were close?
- Yes.
Look, I shouldn't have come in.
- Wait, I--I don't understand.
- Your father
never wanted you to know.
- Know what?
- We were in love.
♪