We're a lot alike,
you know.
You'd do anything to
get what you want.
What did she tell you?
I can't wait to hear.
Your father,
he's telling people
I slept with him.
I should never
have made you come.
Your father died
from an overdose of insulin.
Someone in the hospital
gave it to him.
Now there's nothing
keeping us apart.
You and I are way past that.
Look, we're not...
We'll just...
We'll put
everything behind...
Ava, stop!
You ungrateful prick.
When was the last time
you had a mammogram?
You are saying that
I have breast cancer?
I have something
to tell you.
My lymphoma is back.
I want to marry you again.
Anyone else would have
bailed on this whole mess
a long time ago.
But you're still here.
Because
it's you, Ethan.
I'm late.
Late?
My period.
Tim Burke's
out of prison.
You were responsible
for his father and his
brother being incarcerated.
You've known Natalie
for a while.
What do you think,
will she like it?
Agent Lee told me
what was going on.
Will loves you.
You would be a fool
not to take him back.
I am so sorry.
Whoa.
Natalie! No!
Natalie!
Dr. Halstead?
I got her. Get to
the Doctors' Lot.
Yes, Doctor.
What am I looking at?
Dr. Manning was thrown
from the vehicle.
Blunt head trauma,
loss of consciousness.
Elsa?
Yeah?
Put a collar on her.
Start an IV and
get her on the monitors.
Yes, Doctor.
And a nasal airway.
I got it.
And a chest X-ray.
Yes, Doctor.
Take our boy here
to Trauma 2.
Elsa will give you a look-see.
Nah, I'm staying with Natalie.
You're a mess, Will. Come on.
I'm staying.
Halstead, you're
her boyfriend or whatnot,
impairs judgment. Go.
I just...
Please, Dr. Halstead.
Whoa! Hey,
hey, hey, hey!
It's all right, man.
I got her.
Go on. Dr. Manning.
Come on. Come on,
come on, come on.
She's gonna be okay.
Natalie.
Talk to me.
She's not protecting
her airway.
She's clamping down.
20 etomidate and 100 sux.
Right away.
And that's ready.
I'm in.
You should be in a gown.
Okay, please let me
examine you properly.
Elsa, I'm fine.
I just need to
catch my breath...
No. You're covered
in blood.
Did you lose
consciousness
at any point?
No. I'm good.
Okay.
You need stitches.
I need to call
the plastics resident.
No. You just do it.
No, I'm only a student.
The resident will do
a much better job.
I don't care.
I just wanna get
back to Natalie.
Okay. Um...
Suture kit, please.
Okay.
Sorry.
Excuse me? Excuse me.
I... I heard Dr. Manning
was in an accident.
Dr. Marcel from Trauma
is taking care of her.
Natalie!
Sir!
Natalie...
I'm sorry,
Dr. Marcel.
Who are you?
I'm her fiancé.
Her fiancé?
Yeah! As in
we're engaged.
I guess the night shift
didn't get the memo.
Is she okay?
Chest X-ray and
FAST exam are negative.
Vitals are stable.
But we don't know yet
how bad her head injury is.
Tell CT we're
bringing her up
for a STAT pan scan.
Right.
Excuse me. Can I...
Can I go up with her?
Just don't
get in the way.
Sorry.
Let's roll.
Why didn't you
call me right away?
Well, it... It was
your wedding night.
Ms. Goodwin, we just heard.
Sharon, how are they?
Well, Dr. Halstead
has some displaced
rib fractures.
He's being held
for observation.
Dr. Manning suffered
a head trauma.
She's stable,
her vitals are good,
but she's unresponsive
and intubated.
We're getting
CTs now.
I'm gonna
look in on Will.
Ethan, April,
I need you now.
Elderly slip-and-fall
in three. I'll take that.
Thanks.
Got it.
Status on Tim Burke?
Stable.
You could take
him to County.
On our way.
Hey. He dies en route,
wouldn't break my heart.
Let's go.
Heads up, everybody.
Patient's landing.
Possible drug-induced
psychosis.
Doris, I need you.
Sharon?
I'm short-staffed.
Yeah.
Dr. Marcel.
Ma'am?
I need you to stay.
Say no more.
Happy to oblige.
Courtney?
Maggie?
Eighteen-year-old male.
Cameron Geddes.
Stop it.
Delusional. Found
wandering naked.
Too agitated
to get vitals
in the field.
This is his grandmother,
Nancy Geddes.
There's nobody there!
Stop it! What are we doing?
What are we doing?
Okay, here, Dr. Marcel,
go to Treatment 5.
Need a psych consult.
Yeah.
Cameron!
I'll get a psych.
Then maybe you
and I can talk?
Yeah.
Okay.
So, I guess
we'll be going.
I'm going.
You're staying.
What?
You heard me.
CeCe, we just got married.
We're on our honeymoon.
Danny, I know you.
You wanna be
there for Will. Stay.
I could really
use your help
for a couple of hours.
So am I calling upstairs?
No.
I'll be back at the hotel
by lunch. I promise.
I'm getting a massage
and a facial.
Take your time.
Bye, Sharon.
Thank you, CeCe.
Your mammogram?
They found a mass.
I need a biopsy.
Don't feed the sharks.
It's not good for them.
Lock him in.
How could you
take drugs?
How could you do that?
Calm down, calm down!
Ma'am, can we give
the doctors some room.
Let them do their job?
I'm sorry,
who are you?
Dr. Charles,
head of psychiatry.
Other than abrasions,
I'm not seeing any injuries.
Five of Haldol IM.
What is that? What...
What are you doing?
Is that drugs?
Are you giving
him more drugs?
Well, in order to help
your grandson, we do need
to calm him down a bit.
Let me get a CBC, BMP, EKG,
and tox screen.
Make it an extended tox
screen, cover all the bases.
So, Elsa says that you
refused the gown and
the CT head and chest.
Typical doctor,
terrible patient.
You know, I could
plate your ribs.
It won't hurt as much.
Why am I not surprised?
Connor...
Natalie was coming to tell me
something last night.
She got in the car,
said, "I'm sorry,"
and then we were hit.
She... She didn't
get to finish.
Will, you okay?
Yeah.
Connor, Officer Atwater
is here.
Says he wants to talk to you.
Okay.
What's he want?
It's gotta be
about my father. Um...
His death was labeled
"suspicious."
I'll be back
to check on you.
Thank you.
Okay.
Appreciate you, Doc.
Yeah, man.
First thing I want to
tell you is that
I'm sorry for your loss.
Appreciate that.
Take a seat,
won't be too long.
No problem.
Um...
Your father
was given insulin.
He was not a diabetic,
none of the doctors
ordered it in,
and there's no record of it
on his chart, so...
Yeah, you're saying that
it was intentional.
'Cause normally,
you wouldn't test for
insulin in a heart patient
going through
cardiac arrest.
Right.
Luckily, the pathologist
went the extra mile.
Even so,
can't trace insulin.
So, I would suggest
that they knew exactly
what they were doing.
Is there anybody
around here, Doc,
that you think would
wanna hurt your father?
The fact is my dad
was the type of guy
who could make enemies.
It's common knowledge
you two didn't get
along so well. Right?
Yeah. The relationship
was complicated,
but it was improving.
You blamed him
for your mother's suicide.
Accused him of sleeping
with your girlfriend.
You punched him out
at a party.
Can you tell me where
you were before your father
went into cardiac arrest?
I was at his house.
Kevin, what is this?
Do I need to get a lawyer?
That's up to you.
You want me to stop?
You gotta be kidding me.
I was looking
for old photographs.
Anybody vouch for that?
Our housekeeper, Carlotta.
Now, we done here?
For now.
Connor...
I respect you.
You save a lot
of lives around here.
I just gotta make sure
you didn't take one.
What did
Dr. Manning's scan show?
Well,
you can see here
a grade two liver laceration.
Small amount of blood
in the abdomen.
You need to operate?
Well, we surgeons
love to cut,
but it's a solid
organ injury.
No blush on the CT.
Not operative.
It's still wait and see.
You all go back to work.
I'll let you know
if anything changes.
Okay.
We need to
go to the pharmacy.
Yeah. Right.
You told the police
about my father and me.
He asked.
I told him
the truth.
Last night you said
that I was ungrateful.
Ungrateful for what, Ava?
Oh, my God, I got
you your hybrid room.
I defended you in front
of the Oversight Committee...
You said, "He's gone.
You're free. We can
be together now."
Well, that was my mistake,
wasn't it?
Thinking you could
get past yourself.
And we could start over.
So you did it
so we can be together.
What?
But I wasn't interested.
And so, now you're...
You're getting even?
You're not
making any sense.
I think
you killed my father.
You're as delusional
as your mother was.
Tell us, Connor,
with your father dead,
how much do you inherit?
Twenty million?
A hundred?
Good morning,
Dr. Latham.
It's negative.
I'm not pregnant.
Oh. Okay.
It's weird.
I'm never late.
But it's good
though, right?
Yeah.
We could still go
to Cabo for Christmas.
I can have Margaritas.
We should get back.
Okay.
So after this,
we'll get some
ice cream, all right?
All right.
What kind are you getting?
Vanilla.
Mr. and Mrs. Donovan.
Hi, I'm Dr. Choi.
This is April Sexton.
Hey.
Hello.
Hey, Thomas,
I understand you're
not feeling well.
My head hurts.
And he's been
really tired lately.
And if you're
standing to his side,
he can't see you.
Has Thomas suffered
any injuries lately?
A fall? Concussion?
No.
Can you follow my finger?
He has some loss
of peripheral vision.
Let's get a CBC,
CMP, blood and
urine cultures to start.
Right.
We're gonna find out
what's going on, okay?
Excuse us.
What did he take?
He didn't.
His tox screen
was negative.
Well, then what's making
him act like this?
We don't know yet, which is
why we'd like to have him
admitted to the psych ward.
Psych ward.
What are you
talking about?
Well, the psych
ward is where
Cameron can get
the thorough evaluation
that he needs.
No, no. My grandson
is an A student.
He's going to college.
He's not crazy.
I'm not saying
that he is.
This could be the result
of something entirely
physical, Mrs. Geddes.
Of course
it's something physical!
You're not gonna take him
to the psych ward.
Ms. Geddes, it's in your
grandson's best interest...
No. You're not
taking him.
I'm not gonna
let you take him.
Okay, okay.
Well, how about this...
How about I have
him admitted to one
of our medical floors
with a sitter
and we'll have him
evaluated there.
How about that?
Okay.
Okay. I'll write
the order.
Every kid needs
a grandma like you.
Had one myself.
Isn't he age-appropriate
for schizophrenia?
Yeah, he is.
And I got a strong hunch
that that's what
we're dealing with here.
Then why the charade,
sending him up
to a medical floor?
Well, because
I'm treating
two people here.
I mean, a diagnosis
of schizophrenia?
It's gonna be
devastating to her.
The more we can ease her
into the reality
of that possibility,
the less overwhelmed
she'll be.
Dr. Rhodes.
I have to inform you
that Dr. Bekker has filed
a complaint against
you with HR.
You put your hands on her,
and I witnessed it.
Mmm-hmm.
I also heard you
accuse her of murder.
I don't understand.
Dr. Bekker is a first-rate
surgeon, one of the best.
Why would you
say something like that?
Dr. Latham, you can be
a fine surgeon and still...
Have issues?
No, look, Dr. Latham,
I didn't mean to make
any comparisons.
I find it inconceivable
that Dr. Bekker could
have done such a thing,
but if you feel so strongly
about it, why haven't you
gone to the police?
Because I don't
know for sure,
and I can't prove it
one way or the other.
This is untenable.
Mr. and Mrs. Donovan,
we got Thomas's
labs back.
They were all normal.
Well, that's
good news,
isn't it?
Well, whatever's
going on is not
infectious.
But we still don't know
what's causing his symptoms.
And given his
headaches and lack
of peripheral vision,
we'd like him
to have a CT
scan of his head.
His head?
Yeah.
Uh, Thomas, honey,
give Daddy and me a minute
to talk to the doctor.
We'll be
just outside, okay?
Mommy?
You can see us,
and we'll be back.
Hey, why don't
I stay with you,
keep you company,
is that cool?
Thank you.
Okay.
Hey.
You think this is
something really serious.
Making a diagnosis
is about ruling
out possibilities.
This scan will allow us
to do that.
He's a healthy kid,
hardly ever
catches a cold.
Mmm.
Whatever's bothering
Thomas, this will
help us find out.
I'm so sorry, Natalie.
What are you doing here?
Haven't you
done enough, huh?
Look at her,
for God's sake.
I... I didn't know
she was gonna
get in my car. So...
How do you even
sleep at night, huh?
You realize
you've done nothing
but ruin her life.
Get out of my face.
I don't want you
coming around here again.
I don't care
what you want.
She's not
your responsibility,
man. She's mine.
How? How do you
figure that?
Hey!
Everything okay
with you boys?
Yeah. Natalie and I
are engaged.
What?
See for yourself.
We're getting married.
You on the square,
Fiancé?
I'm sorry. What is
that supposed to mean?
Well, I didn't see
that ring on her finger
when she came in.
'Cause we certainly
would have removed it.
Is this really
any of your business?
As her doctor,
yeah, it is.
Hey.
How's Natalie?
She's still out.
I now know what
she was gonna tell me.
She got engaged.
To Phillip?
You knew?
No.
He... He showed me
the ring,
said he was gonna ask her,
and to be honest,
it was weird.
Weird how?
It was right when
his daughter was being
prepped for surgery.
You'd think
he would've been
focused on that.
Yeah, I never liked
the guy, but, you know,
I'm not exactly unbiased.
Will, you're splinting.
No, I'm just a little
short of breath.
No, you're more than
just a little short of breath.
Let's get you back
down to the ED.
Gonna get you a chest X-ray.
It could be a pneumothorax.
I'm not going...
Will, Will, Will, now.
Yeah.
You may feel
a little pressure,
but nothing more
after that.
You okay?
He says he can hardly
see at all now.
Here,
I'll take a look.
This is Dr. Abrams,
our chief of neurosurgery.
Neurosurgery?
Thomas, do me a favor.
Uh, look
straight ahead.
Raise your hand
when you see my finger.
Thomas, don't you see
the doctor's finger?
That's it,
just keep looking
straight ahead.
Don't move your head.
Could we step outside?
So your son's CT
scan and MRI
indicate a mass around
the pituitary, most likely
a craniopharyngioma.
A what?
A tumor.
A benign tumor.
Oh, benign.
But unfortunately,
he needs surgery.
Right, the deterioration
in his vision
indicate that the tumor's
pressing against
his optic chiasm,
so we need to operate
as soon as possible.
I believe
we'll have
a good outcome.
I know this is hard.
I am so sorry.
He's so little.
My baby.
Thomas was a surprise.
The doctor said
Livie'd never be
able to get pregnant.
And then...
Then when
she told me the news,
God, I wasn't sure
I even wanted a kid.
Now I can't imagine
life without him.
He's our whole world.
I just hate
the thought...
This little kid
having brain surgery?
Yeah, me too.
I'll catch up with you
in a little bit.
Clear.
Yeah,
a pneumothorax.
If Dr. Halstead
had let me
give him a proper
examination,
this never would...
It's not your fault.
Will, I need to
admit you and put
in a chest tube.
No.
You're at risk for
a tension pneumothorax.
You could die.
She's right.
Aspirate and put in
a one-way valve tube.
That is not protocol.
Elsa, please...
It'll temporize me,
and I won't need
to be admitted.
Come on, Connor,
I don't want... I don't
wanna be here anymore.
I hear you.
Ms. Curry, get me
a small chest tube
with a Heimlich valve.
Okay.
What's going on?
Charge nurse refused
our patient.
What?
Darya, come on.
No, no, Dan, we can't
turf him here.
He just needs a workup.
In the psych ward.
My nurses aren't equipped.
Dr. Charles,
where are we going?
To the psych ward.
No, we talked about this.
He's not crazy.
Ms. Geddes, I'm sorry,
I have nowhere else
to put him.
I'm not gonna let you.
Ma'am, please.
No, no, I'm gonna
take him home.
I just can't let you do that.
Well, you can't stop me.
Yes, ma'am, he can.
He's my grandson!
Cameron is 18.
He's an adult who, right now,
is a danger to himself
and potentially to others.
No, no, we...
We need to go home.
I'm gonna
take him home.
Believe me...
He'll be better at home.
This is what your grandson
needs right now.
No, he needs to go home.
Mrs. Geddes.
Please, let me...
Please don't make
me call security.
Please.
Security?
Mrs. Geddes,
please.
Honey, we're gonna have
to wait in here.
No.
You're going to be fine.
You're gonna take a nap,
and when you wake up,
we'll be with you.
Just like at home.
Everything's gonna be
all right, sweetheart.
The doctors are gonna
make you feel all better.
We love you.
April?
Have you seen Dr. Abrams?
He should be
headed up any minute. Why?
I've been going over
Thomas's history.
I'm just not sure
we're doing
the right thing.
Sam? Sam, I think
we're rushing this,
and I know
what you're gonna say.
Whoa, whoa. Don't assume
you know what I'm
gonna say. What is it?
When Thomas came in,
his pulse was a little slow.
His reaction time too.
Mom said he'd been
tired lately.
All consistent with
craniopharyngioma.
But the kid's really small
for his age, right?
What, you're suggesting
this is an endocrine problem?
Possible, isn't it?
Unlikely.
Very unlikely.
All right,
do the blood work.
Hey, just so you know,
if we delay surgery
and you're wrong,
this kid could go blind
or he could
wind up comatose.
Dr. Bekker, thank you.
I have information which
I think will be of
welcome news to you both.
I pressed the lab to
analyze the insulin
which killed Mr. Rhodes...
What's the point?
It's untraceable.
Normally, yes,
but I thought
no stone should be
left unturned.
Well, it appears that
this particular batch
was ever so slightly
contaminated with chromium,
which is
indeed traceable,
and we will find,
in no time,
who had access to it.
That's great news.
Yes.
The police seem confident
that they should
wrap this up quickly,
which means that
you two can stop
accusing one another
and my department
can get back to normal.
Ava?
Ava.
Give me an hour
to get to O'Hare.
One hour. You'll never
see me again.
No.
I did it for you.
Ava, come on.
We could have been so happy.
You ruined it all.
You really are
an ungrateful prick.
No! No, no, no, no!
No, no, no, no!
Help! I need help
in here! Come!
Help!
Dr. Latham!
She slashed her carotid.
Do we have a prepped OR?
I'll bump my case.
Right.
Pressure on the artery.
One, two, three, go!
Let's go!
Come on.
I got fingers
on the carotid,
but I'm losing her pulse.
She's arresting.
We're gonna open
up the chest. Knife?
Marty, she needs
blood, epi.
I'm working
as fast as I can.
Rib spreader.
Dr. Rhodes?
She tried
to kill herself.
Dr. Manning,
can you hear me?
Lighten her sedation.
All right, she's breathing
on her own.
Dr. Manning, I'm gonna
pull your tube.
Sorry for any discomfort.
Do you know
where you are?
Uh...
Hospital?
Do you recognize me?
Sam.
All right,
squeeze my hand.
Good.
All right,
follow the light
with your eyes.
Good.
Do you know why
you're in the hospital?
You don't remember
what happened?
Mmm-mmm.
No.
Nothing.
You were hit by a car.
No fractures,
but you do have a TBI.
Memory loss
is consistent.
It'll likely resolve.
Your initial neuro exam
is heartening.
You... You try to rest.
I'll be back tomorrow,
and we can discuss
your treatment going forward.
I'm...
I'm happy that,
all things considered,
you're doing well.
I'll tell your fiancé
he can come in and see you.
Fiancé?
Yeah, keep it brief.
Carotid
clamps are on.
Marty, how much blood
has she got?
Ten units
and ten of plasma.
All right,
it's now or never.
Intracardiac epi?
Fibrillating,
another round of epi.
Paddles. Charge to 20.
Charging.
Clear.
Come on. Come on.
Dr. Rhodes.
Come on.
Dr. Rhodes,
she's gone.
Time of death,
16:22.
Until we sort
through this,
it does not become
public knowledge.
Hey, man. Internist
is on her way.
Okay, good.
Kid's getting
a slew of tests.
I heard you got married
last night.
Congratulations.
Yeah, thanks.
You know,
I really should not
still be here.
You know, I was doing
my surgical oncology
rotation last month,
met your wife.
Not an easy road.
No.
Just a sec.
My grandson
doesn't belong here.
Maybe not.
But what I do want
to tell you is that
Cameron is at an age
when schizophrenia
tends to present itself,
especially
in young men.
Now, if that's what
we're dealing with,
could be a...
A onetime episode,
or it could be
the start of
a longer illness.
No.
No, no.
Ms. Geddes.
It... It's an illness
that can be managed,
you know?
People can live long,
very full lives.
I've taken care of Cameron
since he was a baby.
I've tried to protect him
against his mama,
who was a drug addict,
and against gangs,
from getting arrested...
Cameron survived.
Cameron made it out.
He has
a full scholarship.
This...
This can't be
happening to him.
Listen, I mean,
all kinds of things
happen to us
that we can't anticipate,
we can't imagine,
and what I've learned,
from my own
experience, anyway,
is that until we learn
to accept the...
The unacceptable,
we're... We're just
of no use to anyone.
Not to our loved ones,
not to ourselves.
You know,
Cameron needs you,
and the person
he is right now
needs you more
than ever.
You two have
faced a lot together,
and there's just...
There's just no
doubt in my mind
that you can
face this too.
Mmm.
Well, I can
go home early.
Wow.
That's it?
He feels bad.
That's his way
of showing it.
Mr. and Mrs. Donovan?
Good news.
Thomas doesn't
need surgery.
Really?
His latest tests
show that he is
severely hypothyroid.
That would account for
his headaches, fatigue,
even his vision problems.
But... But the scans
showed a tumor
on the pituitary.
What they showed
was a mass
called hyperplasia,
an enlargement
of the organ due
to his hypothyroidism,
but it's not a tumor,
and it will shrink
with medication.
Thomas, honey,
you're going
to be just fine.
So I don't have to take a nap?
No, you don't need to.
Hey, they, um...
They had this
in the lost and found.
Don't know
how clean it is.
You really
should be admitted.
That's what you'd
tell any patient in
your condition.
Elsa, stop.
I'm leaving.
Okay, but you're
not gonna "leave"
leave, are you?
Why would you ask that?
You... You've been
through a lot.
No, I'll be back.
Good.
Did you get your results?
Metastatic
adenocarcinoma.
Yeah, I'll need to get
a PET scan to determine
where it's spread,
and then either lumpectomy
followed by radiation
and chemo
or a mastectomy.
Sharon, I don't want
anyone to know.
Mag, you're looking at
a long course of treatment,
likely debilitating.
I don't care,
I'll manage.
If you're having
the treatment here,
people are bound
to find out.
No, I'll go
to East Mercy.
Mag...
I don't wanna be
the sick person.
I don't wanna
be pitied.
I intend to keep
on working.
Okay.
Okay?
I was just so worried
because you were
unconscious, and...
And no one was
actually sure if you
would wake up, but...
But, hey, you did.
You made it.
You're gonna be okay.
I can't remember
what happened.
I know, I know, and...
And that's okay.
The doctors said that
the memory loss,
that's...
That's normal.
Oh, Phillip...
Yeah?
I don't...
I don't remember you
asking me to marry you.
That's okay.
You will, I promise.
Okay.
Eyesight's better.
He's already responding
to the levothyroxine.
Good.
What?
April, would it really
have been so bad
if you'd been pregnant?
You can ask me
about having a kid
after what we saw
those parents
go through today?
That's why I'm asking.
I... It's a lot of pain,
I know...
But it's a lot
of love too.
Yeah.
Makes me think
maybe we're missing
out on something.
Maybe we are.
Someday.
Yeah. Someday.
Rough day, huh?
You have no idea.
Why are you still here?
I'm just leaving.
Whatever you said,
Grandma's on board.
Huh.
So how do you want me
to manage
the kid tonight?
Ativan, 2 milligram,
IVPRN.
One Haldol if he needs
something stronger.
Copy that.
Danny.
There you are.
I was just coming
to you. I'm so sorry.
I made a reservation
for us at Gibson's.
I think you know
Dr. Marcel.
Hey,
I think I met you the day
I got some really
challenging news, right?
Good evening, ma'am.
How are you?
You know,
I've never
been better.
Glad to hear.
Thank you.
Good night.
"Never better," huh?
Never better, huh?
Not gonna let
a little thing like
cancer get in your way?
We gonna press on.
It's just like
you taught me.
You know what? I think
I might have passed
that along today.
Yeah?
Tried to, anyway.
You're good looking.
Dr. Latham, I just want
to say thank you.
I couldn't imagine
having had
a better teacher.
You're welcome,
but I don't understand.
I'm leaving Med.
Leaving?
But we did everything
we could to save her.
And your father's death,
you've been exonerated.
It doesn't matter.
I'm never gonna
be able to get past
what happened here
and nobody's ever gonna
be able to forget.
I need a fresh start.
And I just I need
to go somewhere
where all I will be
is just another doctor.
Oh.
I don't want you to go.
That's very kind of you,
but you will find
another surgeon.
No, that's not
what I mean.
I'm not talking about
a surgeon.
I don't want
my friend to go.
I got a call
from Dr. Latham.
Please don't try to
talk me out of it.
You know, I've been known
to be very persuasive...
But I won't.
You've been
really good to me,
Ms. Goodwin.
I hope I'm not
disappointing you.
No, you have not.
You will be missed,
Connor Rhodes.
Would you mind
saying good-bye
to everybody for me?
I just think
it might be
a little hard.
Of course.
Good luck, my friend.
Thank you.