We're trained to be vigilant.
To chase down the problem.
What...
Hi.
Hey.
To ask all the right questions.
To find the root cause.
Until we know
exactly what it is.
Dr. Hunt, please.
No, he did not go home for the
night. This is Dr. Yang. Page him.
No, I will hold.
And we can confront it.
You are.
What? What is it?
You didn't come home.
Yeah, there was a bus crash.
What time is it? What
are you doing here?
I just...
I figured you had a rough night,
so...
I brought you some coffee.
Great. Thanks.
It takes an extreme
amount of caution.
Where is it?
I forgot it.
But, um...
You go back to sleep.
Okay.
Or we can overstep ourselves.
We can create problems
where none exist.
Come back to me.
I'm not coming back.
You miss it.
What's to miss about neuro?
Me.
We decided it was a bad idea.
Well, that was before, when
we were trying to get Zola back.
I miss you. Just
come back for one day.
Remember the
mystery... The magic...
Gliomas...
Meningiomas...
Astrocytomas!
Dr. Webber?
Dr. Webber.
Rise and shine, Richard.
Dr. Avery is here for
our bladder surgery.
Oh, right. Right.
Hey, hey. Hi, Catherine.
Oh, take your time, honey. I
want to see this bladder you baked.
Look at that. Dr. Keaton.
Homegrown from the patient's
own bladder and stem cells.
Beautiful.
All those late-night
calls paid off, didn't they?
Yeah, we couldn't have done
it without your consultation.
Flatterer.
All right. Well, before we
stick this thing someplace
where the sun don't shine,
I'm gonna go and find my son.
And you should go
and find a pot of coffee.
Yeah.
I'll see you before surgery.
Dr. Keaton.
All right.
Late night, sir?
I'm fine. I sit with Adele
till she falls asleep,
then I like to be
there in the morning.
But when do you have
time to get some sleep?
I'm fine, Bailey.
I'm fine.
Yes, sir.
Get your scrambled
egg off my blanket.
I said I'd bring you one.
You said you weren't hungry.
You are gonna have
heart failure at 35.
No, give me another card.
Don't you feel bad, using a
distraught mother to help tutor you?
No. I feel bad that I had
to sit with you all night
so you wouldn't cry yourself
to sleep over your sad preemie.
He has a brain bleed.
No, he barely has a brain bleed.
Look, we expected
it. I'm watching it.
Oh, that's supposed
to make me feel good?
You are this close
to failing your boards.
Don't even say that.
I know exactly what they'll
ask that's gonna take you down.
Is it Robbins? I gotta go.
It's Robbins. I'm coming, too.
Hey. Have you seen
Derek? Have you seen Owen?
He put me on his
service. I told him not to,
and he gives me
an arachnoid cyst.
I have to pull the plug
on a brain-dead trauma.
I need Owen to approve it.
There he is.
Hey.
Don't take too much.
That's my lunch.
Fine. All right.
Thanks. Okay, bye.
So he's just sharing his
nasty trail mix with someone.
I mean, people do that.
It doesn't mean anything.
Cristina. What?
I gotta go find Derek.
Okay.
Okay, let's go over
the game plan again.
If we see my mother...
We're buried with work today.
And you're sorry, but
Jackson has no time
to spend with her, okay?
There you are.
Dr. Avery.
Dr. Sloan. How nice
to see you again.
Now move out of my
way so I can see my boy.
You look skinny.
Tell me you did
not forget your tux.
Tux?
Jackson is my date,
for the frontiers of
medicine benefit tonight.
Oh! This is Dr. Mara Keaton.
Mara is my star urology fellow.
Mara, my son Jackson.
Hey.
Dr. Mark Sloan.
It's a pleasure
to meet you both.
Pleasure to meet you.
Mara's considering Seattle
Grace as an option for next year,
and I thought, well,
who better to show her
around than my son?
Dr. Sloan, can you spare
him for just a couple of hours?
Absolutely.
Show her around. Take your time.
I can't possibly. We
are buried with work.
Kepner can cover for you.
Perfect. Perfect.
Perfect.
So, this is it?
We do it now?
Unless...
Do you need a minute
to say something...
I've said it.
He's been listening
to me talk for 22 years.
I'm sure he's grateful for
a little peace and quiet.
What now?
We'll turn off the ventilator.
His respirations will stop.
I'll disconnect his monitors
and his feeding tube...
And then... He said this once...
We were watching
some dumb movie on TV
and this guy pulls the
plug on another guy...
He said, "Don't you
dare do that to me."
He was joking. "Don't
you do that to me.
"You leave that plug in the
wall, you put my organs in a jar.
"Don't you give up on me."
Stop. Stop this.
Stop it. Stop it.
Stop. I can't do this.
I can't do this.
Turn this back on.
Turn it back on.
The husband withdrew
consent, Owen.
I had already turned off
the vent when he said no.
He has medical POA.
He said stop. I stopped.
So what are you gonna do?
I'm going to get in on
Teddy's preemie surgery.
No, you're not.
You're gonna stay with him
until he gives his consent again.
You want me to try
and talk him into it?
No, I want you to
help him through it.
I want you to help
him understand
that this is the only
option left for his husband.
I want you to do your job and
find some damn compassion.
Do you need something?
I just wonder if I could help.
No.
I've been with these guys
since Michael first came in.
And we've talked. They know me.
Aren't you on nights now?
Well, I can hang
around if it'll help.
Well, I don't... Cristina,
she can help, let her help.
Thank you.
Thanks.
So I'm a week out of
law school... Uh-huh.
First big interview, huge firm.
I've never had a
better interview.
So I stand up to shake
hands, and I pass out...
Right over the coffee table.
Draped over the coffee table
with my butt in the
air. And your skirt...
My skirt rides up to my waist.
Not even good
panties. Granny panties.
Ooh! Wow.
Did you get the job? No.
Well, your next interview
will end much better
once we remove the cyst.
We're gonna perform what we call
a marsupialization of the cyst.
We open up the wall of the
cyst so that it can drain freely
and then the
fluid won't collect.
So your dizzy spells will stop.
But you said you found a tumor.
Mmm-hmm. We did. It's a small
one. It's called a meningioma.
It's benign, so we're
gonna leave it alone.
If it ever does cause a problem,
it's easy enough to remove.
Dr. Grey could do it.
Oh. Go, girl.
But the cyst is in
the temporal lobe.
That's what's causing the
seizures and the dizziness.
We're gonna go after that.
- So this is it?
- This is it.
We will see you
when it is all over.
Thank you.
Dr. Grey. So glad
you could join us.
I've been kidnapped.
She misses me.
She's not even on neuro anymore.
Well, she's thinking
about coming back.
I'm not.
She is. She's
remembering the magic.
Can he even take heart surgery?
He has to. He has
a pericardial tumor
compressing on his heart.
He's decompensating.
He has a brain bleed.
Shouldn't heart surgery
wait till after it's cleared up?
I wish we could, but it
has to happen today.
Hey.
So Tommy's hip dysplasia
can be treated with a harness.
And I brought you a scone
since you skipped breakfast.
Oh, thank you. Pumpkin.
Eww.
I'll take it.
Eat that.
Right. Like I can eat.
You didn't eat all night.
You're gonna pass out.
Just eat it.
When are you going
to do the surgery?
As soon as he's prepped.
Karev will let you know
when we get started.
Yeah, I'm gonna scrub in, right?
You just want him
to have surgery
'cause it'll look
good for your boards.
I do not.
And also I do, but it's
gonna be great for my boards.
Look, he's gonna
be fine, all right?
He's not scrubbing
in. He was up all night.
Oh, shut up.
Should Karev really
be hooking up with
the heart-patient
intern mom? I mean...
What? No, he's not.
He spent the night.
He gave her a scone.
You gave me a scone.
Yeah, I spend the night with you,
too, because I'm married to you.
No. No. She's his intern.
I mean, he's just trying
to be nice, to care.
I mean, Alex Karev is
trying to be more human,
and I think that we
can thank me for that.
They're doing it.
They built you a
beautiful bladder.
Can I see it?
Oh, honey, no. You don't
want to see that thing.
It's nasty.
No, no, picture a bread
bowl like your soup comes in...
Uh-huh.
Only this one is
made out of meat.
Please don't make me
laugh. I'm gonna pee.
Oh, God. There I go.
Oh, sweetheart. I'm so sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
It's all right. That
should end today.
You won't have to be scared
that your bladder will let go
every time you laugh.
Or sneeze or cough or have sex.
You're gonna
have a very full life
when Dr. Avery's done with you.
I like to think that
everybody lives a very full life
once I'm done with them.
And there...
We...
Are! Great.
That's a perfect
craniotomy. Right, Dr. Grey?
You dragged me back into neuro to
watch Lexie do a boring procedure?
Hey, it is not boring.
It's her first solo cyst.
Be a big sister. Cheer her on.
Shepherd, I've got
a motorcycle cop
open on the table
with a C7 fracture.
I need your eyes on
the cord. Can you...
All right. I'll be
right there. Okay.
When you marsupialize
that, make sure that you...
Tack the edges. Yes, I know.
Okay.
She knows what she's doing.
Just observe. I'll be right back.
If you need anything...
We won't. Go.
And this is OR two, which
looks exactly like OR one.
You still have to cover
the ER in the fifth year,
and study for your boards?
Yeah, it's a pretty
rigorous program.
Speaking of which, I need to
be getting back to work, so...
Do you mind if we
watch for a second?
Of course.
God. I thought I had
no time for a social life.
Are you still dating anyone?
Am I still dating?
I mean, are you dating anyone?
Tell me about you.
Where'd you go to school?
Well, my dad's the director
of surgical science at Oxford,
so I did my
preclinical years there.
Oxford. Wow.
Then residency at Mass Gen,
then I transferred to the Brigham
to study under your mother,
and here I am.
That's quite a
pedigree, isn't it?
Well, you know, a little hard
work and a lot of good timing.
No, I get it.
I totally get it.
Is that Derek Shepherd?
So there's cord damage.
Do you mind if we
stay and watch this for...
Just a few more sutures.
God, I have seen some
tiny little hearts, but...
This is the tiniest.
Whoa.
His pressure's dropped.
What happened?
Doctor, his fontanel is bulging
and the pupils are dilated.
His IVH. Brain bleed.
Give me the
ultrasound. Here you go.
Okay. Right there.
It's progressed to stage 3.
He's gonna need a
ventriculostomy fast,
or we're looking
at hydrocephalus.
And brain damage. Page Marcus.
No, Shepherd should take
this. No, he's in surgery.
Just page Marcus.
He can handle it.
No, the kid's getting
Shepherd. Just wait for me.
The cyst is
draining really well.
Really well.
Great job.
Whoa. Where is that
blood coming from?
It's all right. It's
just a little bleeding.
We just have to find the source.
Let's extend the
craniotomy a little.
Open her up more?
Yeah. It's okay. Just a little.
Okay. Here you go, Doctor.
But I hear stories of people
waking up all the time.
Not this. Not brain death.
But he's still breathing.
The machine is breathing
for him. When we shut it off...
He dies. He's already...
Your husband has died.
Oh, good.
Okay, this is an EEG.
It's a brain scan of another
patient in a coma, also ventilated.
These lines
indicate brain activity.
You can see these
spikes going all the way.
If you take a look at your
husband's, it's completely flat.
We've seen no brain
activity for the past 72 hours...
Just stop.
Well, I'm just
trying to explain...
Explain to me how you
can tell me that he's dead
and then tell me to turn
off life-sustaining treatment.
Explain that.
Sam, you can take your time.
This is a difficult decision.
You should just be with
Michael and take your time.
Take all the time you need.
Thank you.
It's okay.
It's okay. I know
how hard this is.
Like that?
Uh-huh. There it is. Little
bleeder. Just cauterize.
Okay. Bipolar.
Here you go.
There. Okay.
Look at that. That's her tumor.
What?
Oh, my God. There it is.
Do we take it out?
We should...
Let's call OR two and find out
how long Dr. Shepherd's gonna be.
I mean, he said it would
be easy. That I could do it.
I know, and it's right there.
They said he's just finishing.
He'll be here any minute.
Okay. All right. Well, let's
just wait and see what he says.
Okay.
Cord's clear.
Spine is stabilized.
What do you think?
Well, I think his
motorcycle days are over.
Hopefully, he'll be
able to walk again.
Dr. Shepherd, we
need you in OR four.
It's Tommy. He's
got a grade-3 bleed.
He needs a ventric
placed. Karev, slow down.
Who is Tommy?
Morgan's baby.
The intern Morgan.
All right. Well, just give
me a second to finish...
Can you come now? Please.
Go. I'll finish. Okay.
Where's your hot tourist?
Yeah, she's not here for
a tour. I'm being set up.
My mom's trying to
expand the Avery dynasty.
You were supposed
to tell her we were busy.
You and Dr. Hotness should be
getting busy, if you get my point.
Actually, she should
be getting your point.
What are you, 12?
Why are you so obsessed
with me getting laid?
'Cause it works for me. It's
called passing on wisdom.
Also pimping.
She's here for one night.
No.
I am not going to give
my mother the satisfaction.
It's not your mother you
should be trying to satisfy.
Child!
Sam.
Is there...
Do you have any
questions I can answer?
No, thank you.
If you could stop circling
like a vulture, I'd appreciate it.
Do you want me to talk to him?
No.
He just needs time to grieve,
you know, to work through it.
He needs to think clearly.
He needs to understand
what has happened.
He's losing his husband.
They were going
to a grocery store,
just living their
nice, boring life,
going to the same store
they've gone to for 22 years,
and a car hits them.
Sam never saw this coming.
Like I said, I
just... I've taken
some time to get to know them...
Are you married? Have
you ever been married?
No.
Then stay out of it.
You have no idea what
you're talking about.
You don't know Sam.
You don't know the first
thing about what he needs.
There you are.
What are you doing here?
We're finished. The cyst
is draining. She did great.
And get this. Lexie
resected the meningioma,
perfect margins.
She was perfect.
You did what?
Took the tumor out.
Why the hell would you do that?
The plan was to remove the cyst.
She did not consent
to that surgery.
The tumor was right there.
Are we supposed
to close her up and
put her through
another brain surgery?
You should've paged me.
I did, twice.
Derek, Lori is fine.
Lexie took her to recovery.
Her vitals are great...
We won't know how
she is until she wakes up.
I should've known better.
You should've known better.
Give me the scans.
I want to know
everything that
you did in there.
Poor woman. 50 years old,
and she has to wear adult
diapers to go on a date.
Kind of takes the magic out of,
"Let me change into something
a little more comfortable."
You're terrible.
She probably saved
herself some trouble.
By her age, all the good
ones are already snapped up.
Tragedy, isn't it?
Mmm.
I'm ready with this new
bladder if anybody's interested.
Uh, yeah. Bring it
over here, Dr. Bailey.
Dr. Avery.
I seem to have lost track
of the other Dr. Avery.
May I scrub in with you?
No, you may not
scrub in with me.
I gave you a job
to do, Dr. Keaton.
But surely...
Do you want to go to
the benefit tonight or not?
Yes, ma'am. Of course.
Good. You lost
him. You go find him.
Benefit, hmm? Sounds like fun.
Fun? It's exhausting.
Once upon a time, I
was Catherine Fox.
Ever since I've become an Avery,
every fundraiser,
gala-charity brouhaha
that comes along, I gotta
squeeze into some pantyhose,
get zipped into a couture
gown and represent.
And every time
you go into an OR,
they expect you to do Harper
Avery award-winning work,
even though I can
never win a Harper Avery.
The name comes with
way too much pressure.
You can crumble
under it, burn out.
Happened to Jackson's father.
I do not want it to
happen to Jackson.
Yeah, it's a lot to hold up.
Ugh!
Don't you wish you could
just go back sometimes?
I would love to just be
Catherine Fox all over again.
I was so much
more fun back then.
Ah, you're still fun now.
I am, huh?
Glad you noticed.
You try the cafeteria, too?
Oh, jambalaya? Disgusting.
Why do they even try?
April's got yogurt.
Ooh!
And leftover something.
So Lexie removed a
tumor from a woman today,
and now Derek's all
worried that we gorked her.
Did you?
No.
Well, I've spent the entire
morning with Owen's stupid nurse.
Owen's nurse.
The stupid ICU nurse.
Well, that's not what you said.
And you know what?
This is really good.
Kepner can cook.
Freaking jambalaya day.
It's like a hearty
bowl of salmonella.
Hey, how long have you been
screwing the intern with the preemie?
What? Morgan?
I am not.
Uh, well, you both were in
the on-call room this morning...
Before dawn.
Yeah, studying.
You're feeding her.
Alex. No. Bad dog.
Shut up. I mean, she's my
intern and she's a patient.
This is gonna turn
out like Rebecca.
Oh, yeah. Smashed-up
face? That was bad.
Yeah, she's gonna fall for you,
and then she's gonna go crazy
and then she's gonna
pee on my couch.
Oh, gross.
Go to hell, the both of you.
Okay, just keep her
off my couch, please.
Are things with Owen any better?
Is that my turkey casserole?
Oh, yeah.
How do you keep the crunchy
onion things so crunchy?
I put them in last. Come on. I
looked forward to this all day.
Delicious.
Stop facebooking
my mom, all right?
Uh, I'm not.
Really? Then how does she
know I broke up with Lexie?
Why is she here trying to hook
me up with some junior urologist?
Hey. Hey, those are mine.
They have electrolytes.
I showed her around
half the damn hospital
before I realized I
was on a blind date.
You told me to
unfriend her. I did.
Hi. I'm looking for Dr. Avery.
Oh, yes. He's right there. Oh.
There you are. Yeah.
Shall we continue?
Let's do that.
That's great.
Cristina?
Drop it. We were talking.
No, you were
talking. I said drop it.
I'm fine.
Everything is fine, really.
I thought we could
check out your cafeteria,
get a bite to eat, talk.
Listen, Dr. Keaton...
Mara.
Yeah, you're very nice, okay?
But I am not really interested.
I'm not sure what you mean.
Obviously, my mom thought there
might be some kind of connection
or something
here, but I'm sorry.
I'm just not looking
for... A hookup?
Or whatever. I see.
You think I'm being served
to you like a concubine?
No, I didn't...
I'm not here to
service you, Dr. Avery.
I'm here to serve your
mother for a grade.
And she has tasked me with
digging up as much as I can
about your boards, your
standing, your love life,
and when you're gonna stop
screwing around in plastics.
You're not a
setup. You're a spy.
I rank this task slightly above
wiping vomit from bedpans,
but your mother is a
very demanding woman,
and if you know
anything about her,
you know I can't go
back empty-handed.
So if you're really sorry and
not just a presumptuous pig,
you would do a girl a solid,
and you will tell me whatever
it is you want me to tell her.
And you can do it in the cafeteria,
because I'm bloody starving!
Not a chance.
It's jambalaya day.
Come with me.
Where is Lexie?
I told her to go wait for the
labs. It's going to be fine.
Oh, God, honey.
We're Lori's parents.
We were in Rome.
We just got here.
I'm Dr. Shepherd.
This is Dr. Grey.
How is she?
Lori's surgery went very
well. Her vitals are excellent.
We won't know more until she
comes out of the anesthesia.
She's starting to come around.
Hey, Lori. How are you doing?
Let me look at you, okay?
Well, responses are
good. Follow this for me. Up.
Down.
How you feeling?
Honey, we're right here.
Hi.
That's a good sign.
Hi, sweetheart.
It's called aphasia.
The part of the brain that helps
control how she forms words
was damaged in the surgery.
There is a chance, with therapy,
that she will regain
some of her function.
Some?
What the hell did you do to her?
Mr. Bosson... I am sorry. I...
I had the best intentions.
It was an outcome
that I did not foresee.
I'm sorry. I made a mistake.
We're suing you.
She's 27 years old.
You ruined her life.
We are going to sue
you. Honey, honey...
Honey, stop. Lori can hear you.
It was my mistake. You
weren't even in the room.
My mistake was leaving
you two in there alone.
I can't believe
you would do this.
I thought, if you
had seen the tumor...
You didn't think at all.
Okay, it's my fault.
Let's just let it be my fault.
This will kill Lexie. It'll
destroy her confidence.
Does she even have to
know? Of course she does.
She's not strong enough.
Then she shouldn't be a surgeon.
Hey, did she wake up yet?
I am telling you,
Dr. Webber was amazing.
He cradled your bladder
in those big old hands
like it was his own little baby.
Oh, my God. Stop it.
And I said to him, I said,
"You got a fat, ugly baby."
Stop. I'm gonna pee.
Wait.
I'm not gonna pee?
No, baby. You are
not going to pee.
I'm not gonna pee!
Okay.
Wait, wait, wait.
Here we go. Okay.
Satisfied customer.
Ah. We are quite
a team, aren't we?
Hey.
You know what would
make this thing fun tonight?
If you came with me.
I've got Jackson coming, but
I'd much prefer a grown-up along.
I wish I could.
I mean, I really do, but...
You know what?
I'd be honored to join you.
Yes. Okay.
Can you get a tux?
Sure.
This is gonna be so much fun.
You have to stop thinking of
this as giving up on Michael
and try to see it
as helping him.
Emily.
It's a hard step.
But it is his next step, and
he really needs you right now.
How can I do this when
he said not to do it?
How?
It would've been better
if he died in the crash.
He'd be just as dead,
but you wouldn't
be feeling like this.
This way,
he's died in slow motion.
On Monday, his heart
ruptured, and I repaired it.
But on Tuesday,
his lungs collapsed.
By Thursday, his kidneys failed,
and the sepsis and infection took
three more days to kill his brain.
Sam...
If he had died in the crash
by the side of the road,
if you had seen him zipped
up in a bag and driven off,
he would be every bit as
gone as he is right now,
but you would know it.
And you could take
some comfort in that.
I didn't know him. You did.
But I would imagine
he would have
wanted you to have that comfort.
Bring me the papers.
You're an Oxford-educated
surgeon. Come on.
Yeah, I know! It's insulting.
You think I like snooping
around after her slacker son?
Watch it.
The woman has no
sense of boundaries.
Yeah, she does.
She just hates boundaries
so she ignores them.
You gotta set boundaries
with her. You gotta tell her no.
No. Have you met her?
She'll fire me.
No, actually,
she'll respect you.
You gotta tell her no,
and then when she gives
you those big, sad eyes...
No, she doesn't make
those eyes at me.
When she glares at you with
disgust and disappointment...
Bingo. That's when
you stick to your guns.
I don't have guns.
I'm unarmed.
You are not unarmed.
You have guns. I can tell.
When we took out the tumor,
we damaged Broca's area.
So she can understand speech
and she knows what she wants to say,
but she can't say it.
Okay, well, just tell
me that he can fix it.
He can't. It's irreparable.
What do you mean? I mean...
She's not gonna be able to talk?
She's 27. She...
He has to fix it. I mean,
there has to be something.
There isn't.
I mean, this is my fault, too.
I shouldn't have let you do it.
Oh, God.
Oh, my God. She...
It was right there.
And I mean, I never
would've done it if...
You saw it. I mean...
I know. I know. You're
not gonna cry right now.
You're gonna go
and talk to Derek.
And he is gonna be
pissed and disappointed
and he's gonna scream at you
and he won't look at you for days.
Just take it.
And you'll move on
and you'll learn from this
and you will never
make this mistake again.
Yeah, his heart's good.
Ventric's draining well.
And you got 2-for-1 surgeries.
Your son's a gold mine.
We're lucky to have
you as his doctor.
Since you're about to fail
your boards and work at a bar.
Stop saying that.
I'm gonna go see my boy.
You and Morgan a thing?
No. No. Her dumbass
boyfriend bailed.
She just needs someone
to keep an eye on her.
She's my intern. Right.
You ever see one
of those gorillas
that likes to cuddle
the little kitten
and raises it as its own?
It's called imprinting.
The scared little kitten
lets the big gorilla cuddle it
because there's
no mama cat around
or, you know, the dumbass
cat boyfriend left town.
That... This isn't that.
Watch out, 'cause she's smitten.
She is not.
You know what? Go watch
your animal channel or whatever.
Big dumb gorilla.
Getting all ready for your date?
It's not a date. It's a
function with a colleague.
Mmm-hmm.
Does she know that?
What do you mean?
I mean, the way
you two have been
flirting with each
other all day.
I am not flirting.
Well, why do I feel
like I need a shower?
Are you suggest...
Look, I am a married man
with a wife in a nursing home.
I know that.
I am not... Oh, God.
I love my wife, Bailey.
Oh, Dr. Webber, I
know you love your wife.
You're killing yourself
because you love your wife.
You're not getting any sleep,
you're trying so hard to make
sure she knows she's loved.
Give me that.
You can give yourself a break.
Okay? Everybody in this
hospital flirts with everybody else.
It's fine.
You're a good man.
I know it. We all know it.
But I don't know if
Dr. Winky Pants knows it.
Well, I'm just saying,
there's flirting for fun and
then there's flirting for profit.
I know which one you're doing.
That's everything?
Uh, yes. It's just a
matter of time now.
Okay.
Uh,
thanks.
Damn you.
This is why it took me three
years to tell you that I loved you
and another three years
before I moved in with you.
You thought I was
scared to commit?
I was scared of this,
scared of how much I loved you,
scared of the
feeling that I'd never
be able to find
happiness without you.
That's what I was scared
of. I was scared of this.
This right here.
Ho ho.
Damn you.
Dr. Yang, can I do anything?
Can you stop
screwing my husband?
Oh, my God.
I have no idea why I
am even bringing any...
Okay, you gotta listen.
You gotta listen, please.
Don't touch me.
I'm not... We're...
Dr. Hunt and I are not...
I flirt with him.
I do. I'm a flirt. It's just how
I get through a long shift.
But I flirt with
everyone, and I swear
it does not mean anything,
and we have never done...
You switched to nights.
Well, I switched to nights
because my boyfriend...
I have a boyfriend. Here.
Here. Call him. He'll tell you.
And do you want to look through
my text messages? You can...
Stop. Just stop.
Dr. Yang, I am so
sorry. He's just...
He's the chief. I would never...
I swear.
I'm sorry.
You stick to your surgical plan.
You find a tumor,
you find anything...
You close up, and you
make a plan for that.
I know. I know that.
Do you?
Do you? Because if you
had taken the time to look,
you would have opted to
approach the tumor from this angle...
And Lori would be
speaking right now!
It's just stupid, a
stupid, arrogant mistake.
You stick to your surgical plan.
You make an
incidental finding...
Don't you look fine?
Ah!
Mom, Mara has something to say.
I... I don't really.
Sure you do.
Dr. Avery and I have decided
we won't be joining you tonight.
Oh?
Unless, of course, you
really want me to, and...
Guns.
Since you brought
me across the country
to run a personal errand for you
when I could've been gaining
valuable surgical experience...
There you go.
I've decided to
take the night off.
I'm going to do
what I want to do
with my time and you can just...
You want to stop right there.
Yeah, you're done.
So you captured my spy.
She will be very well
treated. Now you have fun.
Okay? Fly safe. I love you.
Doctor. Doctor.
Doctor.
I was gonna uninvite
you all anyway.
I have a date.
Rough day, big guy...
Pericardial tumor
and a grade-3 bleed.
But you're still kicking.
Hey, you about ready to go?
Uh, almost.
Uh, hey. Can you take
another picture of us?
You know, just for
me to have tonight.
Of course.
Alex. Get in here.
No, that's cool. It's...
Get... Get over here.
Okay. One. Two. Three.
All right.
Hey.
Ah.
She's a smitten kitten.
You look lovely.
I thought you were
gonna stand me up.
Well, I'm afraid I am.
I'm sorry,
Catherine. I can't go.
Is this because I've been
flirting with you all day?
No. No.
Come on, Richard. You
know I'm just having fun.
Your wife has
nothing to worry about.
My wife has Alzheimer's.
How bad?
It's bad.
She's in a care facility.
I go see her every night.
She usually doesn't
know who I am.
She knows I'm a friend, but...
She's not there.
And I miss her. I miss
laughing and talking.
I miss feeling like a man,
not just a friend.
Anyway, today, I wasn't lonely.
Today I felt like a man.
And it felt good.
So...
I don't trust myself going
to dinner with you tonight.
And my wife needs me.
And I need to see my wife.
Richard,
you are
a good man.
You know that?
I'm trying.
Thank you
for a lovely day.
You sure you want to change?
We could go somewhere nice,
somewhere where you
could look that amazing.
Actually,
I'm really not that hungry.
No?
Could you help
me with my zipper?
Can you help me
a little bit more?
Our intentions are always pure.
We always want
to do what's right.
But we also have the
drive to push boundaries.
So we're in danger
of taking things too far.
We're told to "Do no harm"
while we're trained to
cut you open with a knife.
Are you okay?
No.
Are you thinking about Lori?
This is why I can't
come back to neuro.
You can't even look at me.
It's no good for us.
I know.
You want to talk about it?
No.
Do you want to
take your mind off it?
No.
Do you want me
to leave you alone?
No.
So, we do things
when we should have
left well enough alone.
Because it's hard to admit
when there's no problem to treat.
Hey. You're awake.
You didn't come home.
Yeah, there was a...
A bus crash or a train
crash or a patient crashed?
Yeah. Right.
To let it alone.
Why are you staring at me?
Well, I'm weighing
how upset you are
and if I want to get into this.
You do. You want
to get into this...
I'm tired and
it's late. With me.
You know what? That's the point.
It's always late,
and it shouldn't be.
And you should want to get
into it with me but you don't.
I mean, where are you?
I am here. For God sake. I'm
right freaking here. I'm home.
No, you're not.
Before we make it so much worse.
Before we cause
such terrible damage.
You have to be honest with me
because I am going crazy here.
Do you love me anymore?
It's not about if I...
Owen, please
answer the question.
I love you so
much that it hurts.
Okay.
Well, okay, then.
Then we can work
on this. We can talk.
You know, we have to talk,
because I cannot
be like this anymore.
And I mean it when I say
that I'm going crazy, 'cause...
'Cause that nurse Emily...
I mean, I accused her
of sleeping with you.
You what?
I'm sorry. I just... I
mean, I feel like...
My whole body feels like...
Like you were cheating on me.
And then you come home and
you tell me that you love me,
and I'm relieved.
I mean, I'm so
relieved because...
Stop. Stop.
I said I love you so
much that it hurts.
Okay.
I said
it hurts
to love you.
Just say it.
I'm not cheating
on you with Emily.
Okay.
But I did cheat on you.