.
- Okay,
let's bring it up a bit.
- I love it.
My dad is gonna hit the roof
when he gets the bill.
- What's he gonna do,
fire you?
- I wish he would.
- You liar.
All right, it needs
to go 6 inches lower.
The street level sight line.
- Look out!
- Russel!
You're okay.
Oh my God,
you're okay.
No, don't.
Don't touch him.
Go call 911.
You're okay,
you're okay.
No, no, no, look at me.
Look at me, honey.
Could someone
please help over here?
- [gasping]
- Trauma 4.
- Incoming.
- 45-year-old male,
multiple penetrating
injuries to the chest.
GCS 12, BP's 90 over palp.
- Did you give him
anything for pain?
- We've given him
4 morphine and 500 saline.
- What happened?
- Chandelier fell from about
20 feet and landed right on him.
- How long ago was this?
- Maybe 30 minutes.
- Did he lose consciousness?
- No.
- All right.
Let's get ready to move 'em.
Very gently on my count.
One, two, three.
- Ah!
- All right,
can you tell me your name?
- [shaky voice]
Russel Rollins.
- Russel?
- Connor, oh, thank God.
Help me.
- All right,
we're going to, bud.
airway's in tact.
Get me a set of vitals.
Someone draw a gas
and get a chest X ray.
You know him?
- Since I was a kid.
Russel, can you move
your fingers and toes?
- I think.
- Where did this happen?
- At the store.
- Claire?
- Sat's 90.
Heart rate's 124.
- All right,
everybody, quiet.
Russel, take a deep breath
for me, huh?
- [screams]
- I don't hear much
on the left side.
We're gonna need
a chest X ray.
It's not optimal,
but we're gonna do it from here.
- Am I going to die?
- Hey, Russel, listen to me.
No, you are not.
- No, you are gonna
be fine, Russel.
You're gonna be fine.
- You have to wait over here.
- All right, I'm gonna hold
the plate from here.
You just shoot as
head on as possible, okay?
- You got it?
- Here, Russ.
Listen to me.
You're doing great, buddy.
I just need you to keep
as still as possible, please.
- X-ray.
Everyone clear?
both: Clear.
[whirrs]
[monitors beeping]
- Big hemopneumothorax
with some shift.
He needs a chest tube.
- I got it.
- Who's the trauma
attending on call?
- Dr. Zanetti.
- Page her. Tell her we need her
down here right now.
- Got it.
- I'm sorry, are you family?
- I'm--I'm his employer.
Claire Rhodes
from Dolan Rhodes.
- The department store?
- Yeah.
- Dr. Rhodes, is he--
- He's my brother.
[monitors beeping]
- What are we looking at?
- 45-year-old male.
Impaled glass
in his left chest.
Arrived hypotensive, but
responded to blood and fluids.
Left tension pneumo.
- That's a cluster.
- Oh, God.
- Ma'am, let me show you
where you can wait.
- Got a chest tube
in on the left side.
Pressure's improved.
Base deficit was 8.
- We need to get this thing off
to see what we're dealing with.
What did you sedate him with?
- Got two of versed
with the chest tube.
- Which one of you is in charge?
- That's me.
- I need to remove it
without allowing this piece
to vibrate in the slightest,
so I'm thinking
cuts here, here, and here.
- Yes, ma'am.
[elevator bell dings]
- Nat.
Guess who Connor is.
- I'm not talking to you.
- Oh, come on.
- What was it you said?
"Try thinking like a doctor,
not a pregnant woman?"
- I was crazed, all right?
I didn't mean it.
- You meant it.
- Look, I need to ask you
about a patient.
You wrote that article
review on vertigo, right?
- Yes, that and other pediatric
vestibular disorders, why?
- Well, I got a 24-year-old
in four who lost her balance
and took a header.
I'd like a second opinion.
Get that package yet?
- What package?
- I sent you
an olive branch.
Not a real olive branch
obviously,
although now that I'm
thinking about that,
maybe that was the way to go.
I'm trying to apologize.
- What's the patient's name?
- Dylan.
Her name is Dylan.
- Captain Trevor Jackson.
Ma'am.
Army?
- Ranger. First Battalion.
75th Regiment.
- Cool.
Follow my pen line.
- You served?
- Navy.
Reservist now.
You're a long way from Georgia.
What brings you in today?
- Fender bender.
It was my fault.
I got light-headed.
Thought I was gonna pass out.
- Well, you been
drinking, soldier?
- No, sir.
- Blood work.
You two in town
for business, pleasure?
- Visiting my family.
Lincoln Park.
- I got to get back to duty.
Mother-in-law's cooking
packing on the pounds.
- Kids?
- Not yet.
- One day, baby, one day.
I don't want her to
have to raise kids alone
while I'm still being deployed.
- Captain Jackson,
are you diabetic?
- No.
- I'm afraid these numbers
indicate differently.
Your blood sugar's at 350.
- What? No.
There's no way
I have diabetes.
- Baby, listen
to the doctor.
- If I have diabetes,
they won't deploy me,
and that's it.
I'm done, and I can't be
a soldier anymore.
You understand.
- Well, it's true you don't have
the classic risk factors--
obesity, family history--
and your white blood
count is elevated,
so it's possible there's
some underlying infection
driving your blood glucose up.
- Okay.
- We'll run some more tests,
see if that's the case.
- Please.
- All right,
we'll be right back.
- It's gonna be okay, honey.
- Can you smile
for me, Dylan?
All right, now I'd like you
to tilt your head
to your left for me,
all right?
- I tried an Epley already.
It didn't seem to help.
[tuning fork chimes]
- Can you hear this?
- Yes.
- How about now?
- Not as well as the other.
- You a musician?
- Mm-hmm.
Getting my master's at CCPA.
- The Conservatory?
Impressive.
Follow my finger for me,
all right?
I don't mean to scare you,
but becoming a doctor was
actually my fallback plan.
I wanted to be a musician;
a violinist, in fact.
- I don't have
a fallback plan.
Music's all I ever
wanted to do.
- You see, that's what
I was missing.
Here, can you
squeeze my hands?
Plus, Paganini's C minor
Caprice broke my will.
- You and just about
everyone else.
It's a bear.
- Yeah.
[both humming]
- I played snare
in marching band freshman year.
- What do you call the guy
who hangs out with the band
but isn't a musician?
The drummer.
- Thanks.
- I've got my recital
next month,
all Bach program.
Maybe you can come.
- Sure, I'd love to.
Dr. Halstead.
- She's got a slight
nystagmus in her...
- In her right eye,
I know.
And the hearing loss
in the left.
I'm thinking
it could be syndromic.
- Well, apparently
you didn't need a consult.
- Come on,
I value your opinion.
How come you never told me
you wanted to be a musician?
- You want an opinion?
Call a neurosurgeon
and send her for a stat head CT.
- I want a CTA
of his chest ASAP.
Figure out exactly
what's bleeding.
- Got to get him on his back
before we get him upstairs.
- Oh, you're gonna use--
- Yes, he is.
Can you hold the patient
steady please? Thank you.
- All right,
hang in there, Russ.
[saw buzzing]
- All right, we're gonna
flip him over onto his back
gently on my count.
One, two, three.
- Okay.
- All right, let's start
to package him up.
Newbie, start a femoral line.
[monitor beeping]
I got this.
- Reese, get over here
and help me
splint the glass
to keep it still.
One wrong move on the way,
and he could have
a massive hemorrhage.
- Maggie?
- Yep.
- Call the blood bank.
Tell them I want
five more blood, five plasma,
and six platelets
typed and crossed.
- Yes, ma'am.
- All right,
are we ready?
- Look, I wish I had
more to tell you.
Russel's on his way
to CAT scan right now,
so we can figure out
what's injured.
We think that it has
something to do
with the subclavian artery.
- English?
- The one that supplies
blood to the arm.
He's gonna need an operation.
We have to remove
the glass and--
- You haven't removed
the glass?
- It's actually keeping him
from bleeding to death.
We are trying to get good
imaging so that when we operate,
we're not going in blind.
- So get it.
- Is this how it's gonna be?
- What did you expect?
- I had to leave, okay?
The way things were with Dad,
there was no--
- Right, you left him,
Connor,
but you left me too.
Just go take care of Russel.
- Did you hear?
He's that Rhodes.
- Oh, a prince in disguise.
- Your friend with
the glass shards?
- Uh-huh.
- These are them.
Unusual case.
Couldn't help myself.
- Yeah, I get it.
- Looks like this thing goes
through the left subclavian.
- There's just so much scatter
with the leaded glass.
It's impossible
to make out the details.
I think we're gonna have to
go to interventional
for an angiogram.
- Want my opinion?
- Yeah, sure.
- Try Surgical Theater's SNAP.
- What's that?
- S-N-A-P?
Surgical Navigation
Advanced Platform?
You ought to crack a journal
once in a while.
- Yeah, well...
- SNAP three-dimensionalizes
CT images.
Because it's 3-D,
you see your surgical point
from every angle.
- Okay, well, where
do I find this SNAP?
- There is one
in the main OR neuro room.
- Great, thank you.
- Dolan Rhodes.
I bought some
socks there once,
the only thing I could afford.
- If this works out,
I'll get you a tie.
- Dr. Travis, you have a
visitor in the main lobby.
- Captain Jackson,
Mrs. Jackson,
I'm Dr. Manning,
Natalie Manning.
- Ma'am?
- I understand
you're a Ranger.
First Battalion?
- Yes, ma'am.
- My husband was
in the First Battalion.
Captain Jeffrey Manning.
- Was?
- He was killed in action
six months ago,
Kandahar Province.
- I'm very sorry, ma'am.
I didn't know your husband.
- Jeff always got
so uncomfortable
when people would say,
"Thank you for your service."
But I guess that's what
I want to say.
- Appreciate it.
- And thank you
for your sacrifice.
- Nat?
- I thought I would
pay my respects,
but it was really about Jeff-
me looking for Jeff.
[indistinct chatter]
- Dad.
- Doctor.
How's our patient doing?
- Russel's stabilized for now.
I have found something
that could help us
with the surgery.
It's an imaging system
called Surgical Theatre SNAP.
- Okay.
- It's FDA approved,
so insurance is gonna cover it,
but Russel is going to be
looking at a lengthy
hospital stay afterwards,
and I just want
to make sure that--
- That somebody
covers the co-pay?
- We will.
- Hang on there, Bernie Sanders.
Now, I love Russel
as much as you do,
but we have to be
responsible to the company.
Are you prepared to do this
for every one of our employees?
- We are talking
about Russel here.
God, he's worked for us
since he was 14 years old.
He's family.
- Us?
When did it become "us"?
- That's your dad?
- Yep.
- Fathers like that
keep me in business, baby.
- Dr. Charles,
do you have a minute?
- Sit down.
Don't mind if I eat.
I missed breakfast.
- Please.
It's my patient,
Captain Jackson.
He's a physically fit
active service army ranger,
but his blood sugars
indicate he has diabetes.
- You run labs?
Do a CT?
- His pancreas is healthy.
There are no signs of tumors.
His labs came back clear
for infection
and autoimmune disease.
I can't find a reason
for his diabetes,
but I did find this.
He fractured two
thoracic vertebrae.
- Ouch.
- Exactly.
So why hasn't he
said anything?
- Why do you think
he hasn't said anything?
- Overseas,
I saw a number of soldiers
who were away
from home a lot.
They were depressed.
- Depressed patients
tend to mask or hide pain.
- Right.
The thing is,
diabetes is a red flag
for the military.
You test positive,
you don't go back to combat.
- So if you were depressed
about overseas deployment...
- You'd think he'd be
happy to have diabetes.
He's home for good.
Well, that's not the case.
Jackson's extremely upset
at the possibility
of not going back
to active service.
Something's going on
with him.
- Let's go say hello
to Captain Jackson.
- Thank you, sir.
Captain,
this is Dr. Charles.
He's a senior attending
physician here.
I've asked him to consult,
just to make sure
we're covering all our bases.
- Yes, sir.
- Please, as you were.
You're Mrs. Jackson?
- Yes.
- It's nice to meet you.
I just wanted to make sure that
I have your history straight.
So you've seen combat before?
- Yes, sir.
- And this was your first tour?
- Seventh.
And...
- What was in
the test results?
- You have a couple
fractured vertebrae
that will heal on their own,
but all your other tests
failed to give us an answer.
We can't find a clinical reason
for your high sugars.
- Clinical?
What does that mean?
- A physical cause.
- I'm sorry, what kind
of doctor are you?
- He's a psychiatrist.
- A shrink?
I don't need a shrink;
I'm not crazy.
- Nobody's saying that you are.
- Honey, they're just
trying to help you.
- How is a shrink gonna help me?
- As I said, we're covering
all our bases.
- You think I'm faking this?
- No.
You can't fake blood sugar.
- So what are
you saying, huh?
You think I did
something to myself?
You think I'm a coward?
- Not for a second
is anybody saying you're--
- Trevor.
- Whoa, whoa, Mr. Jackson.
- Captain.
- I'm out of here.
- Mr. Jackson...
- Whoa, whoa, Captain.
- Whoa, whoa.
[metal clattering]
- Jackson!
- Captain! Captain!
Nurse, please, a little help!
- Come on, baby.
- Watch your back.
Left.
Straight to surgery.
Thank you.
- Hey, Maggie?
Can you help me out?
- With what?
- With, you know, an IV.
The patient's veins
are really small.
- How many goes
have you had?
- Three.
- Oh, man.
Okay, I got a kid
with a broken arm in two.
No needles.
Think you can manage that?
- Yes, ma'am.
- I'm not sure you're aware,
but Connor knows
Russel Rollins,
and it just didn't
seem appropriate to me
that my son be
the one treating him.
- Well, the degree
of familiarity
doesn't warrant taking
Dr. Rhodes off the case,
and Mr. Rollins,
when he was lucid,
did not request
another physician.
- Let me put it another way.
I would like Russel to receive
the very best medical care,
and I do not think
my son can provide that.
- Your son
is a first-rate surgeon,
otherwise I would not
have hired him.
- I want him off the case.
- It's not your
decision to make, sir.
- Excuse me, but I'm the one
writing checks here.
- And while we appreciate that,
this is my shop,
and I will not be pulling
Dr. Rhodes from the case.
- I want you to remember
this conversation,
because if anything
happens to Russel,
you will be repeating it
in a courtroom.
- I will remember.
And you, sir, have a nice day.
- This may not be
your shop for long.
- Dr. Halstead.
- Yeah?
- Your violinist.
Radiology just sent the report.
- Has anyone from
neurosurgery seen these yet?
- They're talking
about scheduling surgery
as soon as possible.
- Acoustic neuroma?
- Tumors, essentially,
caused by a genetic condition
called neurofibromatosis.
It disturbs nervous system
cell growth.
So these neuromas are pressing
against your inner ear,
and that's why you've been
experiencing the hearing loss
and the dizziness.
We need to remove them
and stop the internal bleeding.
- When?
- As soon as possible.
- What are the side effects?
- There's a good chance
you'll lose your hearing.
- My hearing?
- Yes.
[metal clattering]
Dylan, I know it seems like
your world is coming
apart right now,
but we got lucky here today.
Okay, that fall you took
might've just saved your life.
- I'm a musician.
- This could've killed you,
and you don't always get
a warning sign.
I want to transfer you upstairs
and admit you into
the hospital proper.
Is that okay with you?
- No, I want to talk
to the woman
who was in here earlier--
the violinist.
- Dr. Manning?
- I'm not going anywhere
until I talk to her.
- Okay, I'll tell her.
- How's he doing?
- Okay.
- Don't think it'd be
a very good idea
for me to go back in there.
- No.
- Wow, seven tours.
That must be tough.
- Well, I knew
what I was signing up for.
I'm proud of my husband.
- Of course.
I just--I know you must
miss him and worry about him.
- Like every soldier's wife.
- And I know
the illness is a blow,
but at least, you know,
you have him home,
and he's close, right?
- Thank you.
The chairman is here
to see you--
of the hospital.
- That's never good.
- Mm-hmm.
He's waiting in your office.
- Okay.
Barry.
- Sharon.
- Nice surprise.
- Well, I was on my way
to the Art Institute
for a preview.
I thought I'd drop by.
- A little out of your way.
- I got a call
from Cornelius Rhodes.
He's friends with some members
of the board--golf buddies.
Said he spoke with you today.
- He did.
- Unfortunately, he feels
his concerns were not addressed.
- Oh, no,
they were addressed.
- He feels he was dismissed.
- Good.
I'm glad he got the message.
- Sharon, I would never tell you
how to run this hospital.
- And I appreciate
your faith in me, Barry.
- But the Rhodes are
wealthy people.
- Mm-hmm, and how much
has Mr. Rhodes
given to this hospital?
- His mother's
donated quite a bit.
- No, no, how much
has he donated?
- Mr. Rhodes was talking
about making a $200,000 gift.
- Right. Talking.
- I don't think we can ignore
the fact that the Rhodes--
- Barry, listen.
I can understand the need
to cultivate donors.
Mr. Rhodes can make
a $200 million gift,
but I still will not
let him dictate
who performs surgery
in this hospital,
and I think going to war
for that conniving S.O.B.
is not a good idea.
- Incredible.
- Wait till you
get the headset on.
It's like I'm moving around
inside of his body.
- Okay, so tell me
how this thing works.
- It combines images
from the CT angiogram
and creates a three-dimensional
model of the patient's anatomy.
With the HTC Vibe,
you get virtual reality.
It allows us to better
tailor our operation.
Are you having some concerns?
- No, no, no,
just--just curious.
Oh, by the way, Dr. Rhodes,
I met your father today.
- Yeah?
Did he charm you?
- Not exactly.
- Hey, Dr. Zanetti.
Take a look at the middle-left
subclavian artery.
- The glass is going
straight through.
It's like a finger in a dike.
- I can't believe there's
still flow past the injury.
- Rotate a little to the left.
There.
Looks like our dike
sprung a leak.
- He's bleeding.
- Yeah.
- I think we can get away
with a collarbone incision.
Come on, let's go.
- Claire, Dad,
this is Dr. Zanetti.
Russel is being prepped
for surgery right now,
and she and I will
perform the operation.
- Okay.
- You must have a lot
of faith in him.
- I do.
- Hmm, I never thought
I'd see the day;
my son saving lives.
- Your father, is he as big
a tube steak as he seems?
- That he is.
- You leave him
out there, Rhodes.
Don't bring him in here.
[saw buzzes]
[monitors beeping]
Okay.
All right.
Ready to pull this out?
- Ready.
- Okay, take a deep breath,
and whatever you do,
do not break the glass.
- Damn it.
- You lacerated
the subclavian vein.
I need suction.
- We have 20 seconds
before he bleeds out.
- More suction.
- Systolic's 90.
What's going on?
Are you guys in trouble?
- Shut up, Marty,
just give him blood.
4-0 Proline.
Suction there.
Right there.
- No, that's not it.
- Damn it,
I can't see anything.
- He's 34 degrees.
- I can't see a thing.
More suction.
- Dr. Zanetti, let me.
I got this.
Let me.
- You better not
screw this up.
Gentle.
- Okay, I got it.
- That wasn't about
your father, was it?
I really hope you weren't
trying to prove something.
- The Captain has been
gaining weight,
seems to bruise easily.
- That's totally consistent.
- I just can't believe it.
- Let me do this.
Mrs. Jackson?
- I'm sorry, I don't want
these to get cold.
- I--I won't keep you long.
In reviewing your
husband's symptoms,
I'm pretty sure I know
what's causing his diabetes.
- Hmm.
- And, um--
and I think you do too.
- What?
What are you talking about?
- You don't lie
a whole lot, don't you?
I mean, you're certainly
not very good at it,
to your great credit.
To lie well,
you have to loosen up.
You know, make eye contact,
stuff like that.
- I don't understand
what you're saying.
I mean, lie?
Lie about what?
- Somebody's got
to go in there
and tell your
husband the truth.
I could do it.
Let me hold those for you.
- Maggie, any word
from Dr. Rhodes on the surgery?
- Nope, he's still in the OR.
- I'm afraid I've got
some bad news.
- Oh, please,
I am having a terrible day.
- It's about to get
a little bit worse.
We have a case of domestic
abuse on our hands.
- You couldn't!
Are you out of your mind?
- That woman has been poisoning
her husband with prednisone.
- Why would you do
something like that?
Oh, my God.
- I read on the Internet that
if I gave him some prednisone,
it would look like diabetes.
I just wanted him home safe.
It's been ten years
of worry,
of nightmares.
You can understand
why I did it, can't you?
- Well, whether I understand
or not, it doesn't matter.
- There's a doctor here.
Her husband was a ranger,
and she lost him.
He's dead.
Isn't it better
to be sick than dead?
- Why did you
let it go so far?
Why didn't you
talk to someone?
- What good
would talking do?
I wanted him home.
Talking wouldn't
bring him home.
- Mrs. Jackson, I'm sorry.
What you did is a crime,
and I have to report it.
- Am I going to go to jail?
- I don't know.
- She's not gonna
do the surgery,
at least not until
she's given the recital.
- You told her those tumors
might kill her first?
- Hearing and being heard
it's how Dylan interacts
with the world.
She can't imagine her life
without that ability.
She needs more time
to process all of this.
- She doesn't have more time.
- I don't know what to tell you.
It's not our decision to make.
- I don't believe this.
I miss something
with one patient,
and it's too late to fix it,
then I catch something
like this early on,
and I still can't fix it.
Nat, the medicine is clear.
The patient should not be
making this decision. I should.
- So you became a doctor
to tell people what to do?
- I became a doctor
to save people's lives.
It's all I've ever wanted to do.
I don't have a fallback plan
or some hidden passion.
This is it for me.
It's just...
no one ever told me there'd be
this much loss involved.
- I pulled this out of
the deep depths of my closet.
I reached out to
Anne-Sophie Mutter's people,
but it seems she's
on tour in China, so...
I'm guessing you know
Bach's "Concerto in D minor"
for two violins?
In my day, we all learned it.
- Sure.
- Get out your violin,
Dylan.
We're gonna have that recital.
Come on.
- The tumor's that bad?
- Yes, but we're
gonna get it out.
- And my hearing?
- Let me explain something.
The memory is not
just in the head.
We also have what's called
kinesthetic memory,
the body's memory.
It remembers movement,
resistance,
and the position of its parts.
So hearing or not,
your body can still
remember how to play.
Don't focus on the sound.
Concentrate on the feel,
the vibrations.
Just close your eyes
and remember.
[plays Bach's
"Concerto in D minor"]
- We'll taper off
the prednisone,
and your system will purge it
over the next few days.
The side effects
will dissipate,
and your blood sugars
will return to normal.
- Where are they taking her?
- She's turning herself
in to the police.
- Lauren!
- Captain, easy.
- We'll get through this...
together.
- Dr. Rhodes,
how's your patient?
- The surgery was successful,
and he should be okay.
- Oh, thank God.
- Isn't that great news,
Mr. Rhodes?
- Yes, I had every
faith in my son.
- That's exactly what I told
the Chairman of the Board
when he dropped
by to see me today.
- Thank you.
- Of course.
- Well, looks like we can go.
Thank you very much.
- Dolan Rhodes.
That's a big name
in Chicago.
Growing up with that can give
a person a skewed perspective,
like whatever he wants,
he ought to get.
- My dad give you a hard time?
- [laughs]
Nothing I couldn't handle.
- My grandfather was the one
who started the business.
- Oh?
- Yeah.
Salt of the earth
kind of guy.
He used to say to me,
"You're gonna have to
work harder than everybody
else," you know?
"Be better than everybody else
so that you don't turn out
like everybody
expects you to."
- Hmm.
- "So that you don't turn out
like your father."
Took me a while
to get that message.
- Well, congratulations,
Dr. Rhodes.
- Dr. Halstead, messenger
just left this for you.
Charvet.
Ooh, someone likes you.
Mm-hmm.
- Yep.
- Reese.
Treatment 1.
- Where's the patient?
- You play golf?
- No.
- Me neither.
Who's got the time?
There's something that
golfers get.
The "yips."
Some kind of mental block.
They can't make
the simplest putt.
Even really the golfers.
- I'm not following
this conversation.
- You got the yips
with needles,
and I'm gonna
help you get over it.
Let's get started.
- You want me on--
- Yep. Jab me.
Let's go.
I don't have all night.
Mm-hmm.
- Dr. Rhodes.
Back in the OR?
Pretty ballsy move,
pushing an attending aside.
Someone with a fragile ego
would've chopped your head off.
- Sorry.
- Don't apologize.
Never apologize.
- How'd it go?
- They got everything.
She's gonna be fine.
- And her hearing?
- I'm sorry.
- So what was in that
package you sent me?
- Three bars of chocolate:
dark, milk, semisweet.
Wasn't sure which you'd prefer--
and a jar of olives.
- Olives?
- Well, I know you've been
craving brine these days, so...
- An olive branch.
I've got a patient
I got to check on in peds.
You're forgiven.
[wolf howls]