That's it, Fran. One more push.
As babies, we were easy.
One cry meant you were hungry...
It's a boy.
How is he? Is he okay?
Another, you were tired.
He's perfect.
It's only as adults that
we become difficult.
Hey, wake up, pretty lady.
Mmm.
Morning.
It's gonna be a great morning.
We made you eggs benedict.
Where's Sofia?
Napping. Ooh! Try the eggs.
The bacon is jalapeno-infused.
Tomorrow we're making
short ribs infused with cabernet.
I just want coffee
infused with cream.
No, yeah, but just
try the hollandaise.
I have to get ready. I
have a big surgery...
Hold on. So I...
Mmm. I'm so sorry.
We start to hide our feelings,
put up walls.
It gets to the point where
we never really know
how anyone thinks or feels.
What?
My key's not working.
Yes, because I
changed the locks.
Oh, come on!
Yes, this isn't my trial,
but that doesn't mean you can
lock me out of my own mouse lab.
My mouse lab.
Bailey, don't...
Without meaning to, we
become masters of disguise.
Q's hyperglycemic, too.
Which means that about
20% of the mice with implants
have diabetes again.
Look, we should
really tell Dr. Webber.
No, we are not telling him.
Well, okay, but...
Kepner, it is precisely
because of challenges like this
that I handpicked
you for this trial.
You handpicked me because
Cristina, Alex, and
Jackson all said no.
And because you
go above and beyond.
Look, you solve problems
like no one else can.
Say it with me.
I solve problems...
Like no one else can.
Exactly. Now let's get to work.
Fifth year is the hardest
year of your residency.
Every surgery you do
will go on your record,
the wins and the losses.
In just a few
months, you will...
What did I miss?
You're OB now?
Oh, how the mighty
have fallen, huh?
She misses Zola.
Her uterus hurts.
Oh, leave her alone, dirtbag.
Of the more complicated
surgeries you've scrubbed in.
You are embarrassing me.
I'm getting to deliver babies.
I'm making life, you know?
Yeah, you know what?
You're making me gag.
Okay, slumming it in OB for a
few weeks is okay. Whatever.
But wearing the vagina
squad scrubs in public? Ugh!
We have standards, Meredith.
It is extremely important
that you rack up
as many good outcomes
as possible for your boards.
I am implementing a system.
I will receive an e-mail
if any of you exceed
more than 10 bad
outcomes in your OR.
Ten. Any more is unacceptable.
Welcome, Dr. Kepner.
Sorry. I got stuck in
the lab with Bailey.
I don't care where you were.
I care that you
already have, let's see,
two bad outcomes in your OR.
Ooh!
Loser.
Of course that's nothing
compared to Karev's
impressive five bad outcomes.
Oh!
I keep getting dud patients.
Tell it to your board examiners.
The point, people, is to keep
your bad outcomes to a minimum,
or you will be hard-pressed
to find a fellowship next year.
Who are you texting?
Who do you think?
Uh, Dr. Yang, are you sure
that you're getting all this down?
Mmm-hmm.
Bad outcomes are bad,
which is why I have zero so far,
a perfect record
I plan to continue
during my ortho
rotation this week.
No one dies during
a hip replacement.
Let's hope.
I'm sorry. I will make
sure that the scrub nurse
separates your
macrodissectors from your micros.
I told her that yesterday,
but she must have forgotten,
which I know sounds
like an excuse,
and I am sorry for that, too...
Lexie. Yes.
Leave. Now.
Okay.
Hey. Can you go have sex
with him and make him be nicer?
I told you, he's going
to be hard on you
until you learn
all of his quirks.
They're not quirks.
They're these scary, nitpicky
rules just to drive me crazy.
Like what is the deal with him
needing 16 towels in the OR.
At all times?
Well, if I give you
all the answers,
you'll never learn on your own.
You're just as mean as he is.
Hi. How's your day going?
Bad. My OR is a mess, my
caseload is an exercise in boring.
Which you can't tell me
because we can't talk about neuro.
Right.
I know something
else we can do instead.
No kissing in the hospital.
Why not?
We don't work together
anymore. You're just my wife.
Ooh!
9-1-1.
Wait.
Okay. Now you can go.
I should be grateful that
they're getting along, right?
But I'm not, though. I'm bitter.
All they do is cook together and
talk about food and watch shows
where other people
talk about food and...
Don't read that.
"I'll bend you over the
conference room table and..." Oh!
Okay, why did you
let me read that?
My husband can't
get enough of me.
Jealous?
Yes, actually.
Arizona and I haven't had
much "alone time" lately,
and so instead, we eat.
Oh, that's depressing.
Yeah, let's just
talk about the case.
Okay. What is it? Okay.
Hip replacement,
shoulder dislocation? Ha!
This is your first time
copiloting with me.
You think I'm gonna
bore you with routine crap?
My feet hurt!
Mr. and Mrs. Moser? Hi.
Hi. Sorry.
My lazy sack husband
thinks that this is his bed.
It's not?
No, this is our
patient's parents. Yeah.
This is Dr. Yang. She's
my co-surgeon on the case.
Oh, so nice to meet you.
Get up!
Come on. Pretend you
have manners for a second.
What, the kind of
manners that allow you
to insult your husband
in front of strangers?
Stop it. TYLER: Stop fighting.
You're scaring the doctors.
Hi. Tyler.
I'm... I'm not staring
at your boobs.
I mean, I am,
but I can't help it.
Tyler suffers from a
degenerative bone disease
called cervical spondylosis.
He was in a car
accident two years ago,
which further injured his neck,
and so we are gonna
build him a new one
in a three-day,
three-part surgery.
Do not point that camera at me!
You look beautiful, sweetie.
Oh, are you the
OB? Drugs, please.
Where's the attending?
She's stuck in an emergency C.
They were driving home to
Olympia when her water broke.
She's two weeks early.
Hi, Mary. I'm Dr. Grey.
I don't care who you
are, just give me drugs.
Okay, let's see if
we have time for that.
Over here, honey.
Wow. You're crowning.
Wow? Did you just say "wow"?
This is it. It's all happening.
Clay, I swear to God,
if you don't point that
camera someplace else!
Oh, God!
Are you pushing? She
shouldn't push, right?
Just give me a second.
Look over here.
I'll distract you.
Brain tumor! Brain tumor.
I call brain tumor
on the video camera!
You can't call brain
tumor right now.
It's my tumor. I make the rules.
Brain tumor?
Nobody said anything.
She has a grade IV astrocytoma.
You could have led with that.
It's been a little hectic.
Oh!
Head.
Hi, Emma.
Sweet little girl.
It's called a butterfly tumor
because it extends into
both sides of the brain.
She has about six months.
She's dying, so they
decided to have a baby?
Well, that's not the point.
So I had St. Catherine's
send over all her scans,
and I want you to
take them to Derek
and get him to do a consult.
Derek hates me. You are
better off taking them yourself.
The only thing holding
our marriage together
is that we can't
talk about neuro,
so he can't know that I
had anything to do with this.
So you're using me?
I'm your tumor mule?
Do you want him to
stop yelling at you?
He needs to be inspired.
Hey, Karev, trade with me.
Ortho for cardio.
I mean, you need a good outcome,
and I'm just doing a stupid
neck surgery with Callie.
There's no such thing
as a stupid neck surgery.
You're just afraid of
tanking your winning streak,
so now you want
back on the easy train.
Not happening.
What easy train?
That's what Dr. Karev
calls your service.
'Cause your patients never die.
It's a compliment.
Oh, it has nothing
to do with the fact
that you're piling
up bad outcomes?
They were dud patients.
I'm sure. Shall we?
Who do I have to pay to get
the tennis match on in here?
We'll have a nurse look into it.
Yeah, well, make
sure she's cute.
Chuck Cain, 71.
Came into the ER last night
after a syncopal episode.
The scan showed a
narrowed aortic valve
that we will replace during
open-heart procedure.
Open-heart?
It's a safe surgery.
Don't worry.
I don't care about safe.
I care about the scar.
How big?
Ten inches at most.
Ten? Nope.
Not doing it.
Trust me.
A scar is a small price to pay
for how much better
you're going to feel.
How old do you think I am?
You're 71.
Because you read the chart.
But if you didn't,
you'd say 60, right?
Look, I'm in incredible shape,
and the ladies agree.
But look, the minute you
open up my chest, I'm done.
There's no more
meeting women at the pool
with a scar like that.
I mean, all they'll see is a
future of doctor's appointments,
hospital visits, and bad sex.
So, no. No open-heart surgery.
Look, Mr. Cain.
We'll investigate alternatives.
And get me a decent
pillow while you're at it.
My ass has got more
cushion than this thing.
Is it July yet?
'Cause I need a whole
new crop of residents.
Huh. Little Grey
still struggling?
Oh, she's drowning.
I didn't know how lucky I had it
until Meredith
was off my service.
Do you know how to
read these budget reports?
No. Why do you think
I gave up that job?
You're a huge help.
Homemade maple-ginger scones.
Try.
Oh, no, no, no, really.
I just had a big lunch.
The scone's a very
tough pastry to make.
You have to be exact
with the ingredients,
the baking temperature...
Hey, how is the house coming?
We're working on the
drywall now. Really?
Mmm-hmm.
All right. I get it. I'm a bore.
But Avery's doing
all my surgeries,
and I'm taking up cooking
to keep my mind sharp
for when the next
big case rolls in.
Yeah, you keep
telling yourself that.
Dr. Shepherd. Yes.
Dr. Grey is looking for
you. She says it's important.
My wife? Nope.
Lexie.
Try a scone.
You know you want to.
Uh...
Attaboy. Mmm.
Today we're taking
out the old hardware.
Tomorrow Sloan will
remove the scar tissue.
And then we'll implant the cage.
Yeah! All right.
So... Your turn.
Just get in there and,
you know, have fun with it.
Why wouldn't you just
do a fusion in this case?
Isn't that standard procedure?
He's had four fusions already,
so we're really going
for a long-term solution.
Really get in
there with the drill.
Right, right, right. Come on.
But the risk of paralysis is
quite high with your approach.
Our approach, and only
lame surgeons do fusions.
We're not lame.
We're fun. And badass.
Here, like this.
There you go.
Oh, oh, oh.
Yeah.
There you go. Felt good, right?
Yep. Yeah.
Dr. Yang, that's your phone.
Really? During surgery?
It could be anyone.
Mmm-hmm.
Melanie, could you please
read Dr. Yang's message aloud?
Melanie, don't do
that. Yes, Melanie, do.
It could be Chief Hunt.
He might need Dr. Yang
on an urgent matter.
Yep. Definitely sounds urgent.
Melanie, don't touch that phone!
Just, um...
Turn it off.
No more texting me in the OR.
Well, did anyone...
No. Good.
'Cause the only thing getting
me through these budget reports
is that, and I get to do this.
Mmm.
I have to check on my patient.
I don't want Callie to
give me a bad outcome.
I'll be quick. Come on.
Okay. Okay, okay.
Hunt, I found
last year's budget.
I was just won...
Whoa. Whoa. Um...
Excuse me.
No, it's okay. I
was just leaving.
Keep your phone on.
Okay.
In the conference
room? Richard...
Hunt, you're a chief now.
Act like it.
In the conference room?
So tell me you found the article
I asked you for two days ago.
No, but I'm really close.
This is the chart of a
patient with a butterfly tumor.
Butterfly tumors are inoperable.
No, I know, but this patient,
she's a new mom, and it's
a really sad story, actually,
but I was wondering if you
could do a quick consult...
This is why you needed
to find me so urgently,
to tell a woman her
tumor's inoperable,
to remind her how
sad her story is?
No, I just...
Just find the article.
Hey, April, I can't
cover the ER tonight.
I have to do research
for Shepherd.
No, what?
Take it up with Shepherd.
I... Come on...
Where are my mouse labs?
Oh, uh, sorry. I was
stuck in the OR all day,
trying not to fall
behind in my surgeries.
Oh, so you'd rather just fall
behind in my opinion of you?
I will take care
of it right away.
It's hard to be a team when
only one player cares, Kepner.
We removed all the old hardware,
and we're all set to
implant the cage tomorrow.
So just try to get
some rest, okay?
Oh, well, I'm
gonna stay the night
and make sure he's
got some company.
I'll stay. I don't
need the rest.
And I do?
I don't know. You're
always talking about
how big the bags
under your eyes are, so...
What? Aren't
visiting hours over?
Yes. They are.
Sorry.
Uh... Um...
All right. Well, call
if you need anything.
All right? Okay.
Okay.
Whew! Well, surgery brings
out the worst in people.
Marriage brings out
the worst in them.
I'm grateful they dropped
everything to help take care of me,
but seriously, the second
I'm better, I'm moving out.
I need some peace and quiet.
Well, let me help you
get some now, okay?
Mmm!
What the hell?
I want to check your
reflexes every half-hour
to make sure there's no
nerve damage from the surgery.
You're home already?
Yeah, it's the advantage
of a boring caseload.
Well, did your
day get any better?
Yes, if you count the
fried chicken sandwich
I got in the cafeteria.
Any interesting cases tomorrow?
Meredith.
No work talk.
I'll be right back.
Meredith.
Why didn't you tell
Derek about Mary's tumor?
I did. He said it
was inoperable.
Did you show him the scans?
Did you tell him it
was in the frontal lobe?
I didn't get a chance.
Um, I am naked and
wet in the shower, so...
Derek's a tumor junkie.
He needs to see the scans
and meet the patient
to spark the case,
the same way he needs
a 16th towel in the OR
to position his arm
on the microscope.
Are you gonna remembe r all
this or do I need to write it down?
Naked and wet in the shower.
I need to write it down.
Chuck Cain.
I gave you his blood
work five hours ago.
Alex, I need you to
cover the ER tonight.
No.
Look, before midnight
would be nice.
I'm still looking. It's the ER.
People will die
if we're not there.
Which will be
your fault, not mine.
Got it. Here you go.
Finally.
Alex, please, can't you just
be a person for a second?
See?
This is why you
don't deserve this job.
You're bad at it.
You get all stressed
out and frantic
and nobody wants
to listen to you.
You have no authority, and your
voice, it gets all high and nasally
like this when you're nervous.
It's annoying.
You're annoying, so, no,
I can't be a person
for a second.
Deal with your own crap!
Still not paralyzed.
Good.
Do you know you snore?
Yes, and I've been
told it's adorable.
It's not. MR. MOSER: Morning.
Oh, sorry we're late, baby.
Of course, your
smarty-pants father
refused to check the traffic
report. Are you hungry?
Uh, he can't eat before surgery.
See? I told you,
no food allowed.
Oh, please. One
little donut won't hurt.
Actually, it will, just
like it will it hurt all of you
by promoting high
cholesterol and plaque buildup.
I confirmed your consults,
and I know you're gonna
ask me about that article, but...
You haven't found it yet? Look!
Butterfly tumor.
Wait. I mean, all the
doctors we've seen
said the tumor's inoperable.
Surgery could put her
in a coma or kill her.
It's just another set of scans.
Exactly, and it'll
be good for you
to have some alone
time with Emma.
You know, that way I
can die knowing that
you're not gonna
drop her on her head.
Fine.
Run the scans.
Okay.
I really don't
have time for this.
Two more moms just came in.
Well, yeah, but as long as no
one's crowning, they'll be fine.
What are you doing?
Researching a new
surgery for my neck guy.
What are you feeding my mouse?
Q is diabetic. A
donut could kill him.
Then why is he in your office?
So Meredith can
run tests on him.
Are you really gonna
do her grunt work?
Bailey blames me for
Richard losing his trial.
The last thing she wants
is for me to work on it.
Which is why you're
doing it in secret.
Okay, that is the worst
idea I've ever heard.
Seriously.
I am your chief
resident, Dr. Grey.
Which means if you cross me,
I will make your
life a living hell.
I will put you on
call every night,
I will assign you dumb interns,
and I will make sure
that you get every exploding
bowel and rotting limb
that comes into this hospital.
Okay.
Relax. I'll do it.
It's 'cause I made my
voice different, right?
That's why you...
Go away before you
embarrass yourself more.
Oh, that's Owen. Duty calls.
Are you two talking
yet, or is it just sex?
Not just sex.
Hot, dirty,
stand-on-my-head sex.
I'll take that as a no.
You know what?
Who cares if we talk?
Besides, if you want
to talk about something,
how about the fact that
you're wasting your fifth year
playing around with
vaginas and mice, huh?
Want to talk about that?
Do you really
stand on your head?
I'm very talented.
This procedure is
minimally invasive.
And the great news is,
the scar will look like
this. It's much smaller.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
but I want this instead.
What the hell is that?
That's my friend Tony's groin.
I had him e-mail me
a picture last night.
He had the same problem
with his valve last year,
and his doctor replaced it with
a catheter through the groin.
See? Barely any scar.
It's called a T-A-V-I.
Yeah, a TAVI is an
experimental procedure.
There are tons of risks,
bleeding, stroke...
Look, I'm the one having
this and paying for it, right?
So if I say I want a
TAVI, give me a TAVI.
Look, there is a much safer
solution to your problem.
It's called a rash guard.
You wear it at the pool.
No one will see your scar.
Clearly you've never
been to Palm Beach.
Only fatties wear rash guards.
I can't get through to this guy.
He wants a TAVI.
Look into it and decide
if he's a good candidate.
I'll look into a TAVI.
See? Now that's the
answer I was looking for.
I knew you had it in you, kid.
Hey, Grey.
No, keep walking.
Eyes ahead. Act normal.
I saw Kepner take a
mouse into that room.
What's going on?
I don't know anything.
You blinked. Okay.
Okay, now, you know something.
Is something wrong
with the device?
I really shouldn't
talk about it.
Grey.
Bailey's not gonna
find out about it?
Bailey locked me out
of my own mouse lab.
I'm not telling her crap.
Some of the mice
are hyperglycemic.
We're running some
tests to find out why.
All right, this is what you do,
get a healthy mouse,
run some labs,
and compare the
stats. Can you do that?
Well, April's
being a little bit...
You can handle Kepner, Grey.
Now, I'm on call, so page
me when you get the results.
Okay.
All right.
Uh... Hi there.
Beautiful day, isn't it?
Oh, damn it.
You need a hand?
No, just, the cage won't fit.
His bone's so destroyed,
the screws won't hold.
We should do the fusion instead.
No. Well, I researched it.
We can re-fuse him if we take
down enough of his scar tissue...
I said no.
Hey.
My surgery got pushed.
And I can't pick
up the short ribs.
The butcher closes
at 6:00, right?
Why are you so
gung ho to do this?
Why are you so not?
We could roast a chicken. Yes.
Could we please
shut up about dinner?
Please.
Sorry.
Forget it. We're closing him up.
What? No.
Yes. We need more time
to figure out a new game
plan that's not a fusion.
So I'm gonna secure the
cage temporarily and close.
Which means I'm free
to go to the butcher.
Problem solved.
Most astrocytomas spread
out through the corpus callosum.
It fans out like smoke.
But if you look at
your tumor, Mary,
I've never seen
anything like it.
Look at the edges,
they're smooth, defined.
They're easier to cut around.
Yes, if I can keep
my entire dissection
inside and never
let it drift outside...
I'm sorry.
Are you, um, saying
what I think you're saying?
Mary, I think I can
remove your tumor.
I love this guy.
We don't know this guy.
He's amazing, right?
Tell my husband.
He's pretty amazing.
This isn't a decision
you make on a whim.
You're right. You need
time to make this decision.
We don't need time.
We've decided. Sign me up.
Emma.
Yeah.
If you get to call brain tumor,
I get to call Emma.
It's not just the
two of us anymore.
We have a daughter.
She needs these
six months with you.
I mean, you're her mom.
Please, Mary.
Don't do this.
You're ditching
OB to be a vet now?
April dumped
Bailey's trial on me.
I would be annoyed, but it
turns out I'm good with mice.
And I found her
secret snack drawer.
Sweet.
Hey. Hey, that is not
your food. Not your food.
What have you done to my office?
Get over it. I'm helping you.
And go get me a healthy mouse.
Bailey hasn't left the lab in 48
hours. I can't steal another mouse.
I can't steal another mouse.
Fine.
Fine. Just keep
going, and good job.
Tell me what it feels
like to get a bad outcome.
Neck guy's paralyzed?
Not yet.
What would happen if I
took my name off the case?
Do it. You can take my old guy.
Altman's trying to make
me do a TAVI on him.
Oh, no way. You're just
asking for a bad outcome.
Peanut? No.
Derek ran an MRA.
And found out he can reach
under the pericallosal vessels
and reach the
tumor on both sides.
So he's operating? No.
Mary's afraid of the risks.
Well, Clay, really,
but she listened to him.
Okay, but did you tell
them how good he is?
Yeah.
Kind of.
Do I have to do
everything myself?
Hot.
Right?
Come on. Come on, G.
Come on, little guy. Come on.
Your voice doesn't
whisper, Kepner.
Sorry. Sorry. I didn't
want to distract you.
I need to run an A1C on G.
G is healthy. We don't
need to run an A1C on him.
Yes, but I think I'm on
to something, though.
On to what?
I'll tell you when
I figure it out.
I read the research, I talked
to some other surgeons.
But I'm not doing a TAVI on you.
And that's your final answer?
That's my final answer.
I'll give you some time
to make a decision.
And here I took you for a
guy who had a pair on him.
It's a stupid scar, Chuck.
You really want to
die because of it?
Hey. Sorry I'm late.
I got stuck planning
tomorrow's surgery.
Well, did you figure it out?
You know it. Sofia?
Mmm. She is asleep.
She was so talkative...
Whoa!
I miss that.
I bet I know what else you miss.
Oh! Who's hungry? I
got braised short ribs,
roasted potatoes, and
a nice pinot from Napa.
It looks amazing.
It's not me.
Me neither.
It's me.
Oh!
The car seat's not clicking in
and it's supposed to be clicking.
Let me try.
You just have to
line up the arrows.
I heard Dr. Shepherd came by.
Look...
I'm sure he's a great surgeon,
but we've seen a
lot of great surgeons.
And I know I'm the
bad guy here, but...
I just had a baby.
I want to be happy, you know?
At least today.
Maybe a couple more months.
But a couple more
months isn't enough.
She wants more.
We made this
decision a long time ago
because we knew that
once Emma was born,
we'd be too emotional.
She's not thinking...
But now she's seen
and held her baby.
And she can't
imagine not being here.
And she wants more time.
I want more time.
I'm not ready for her to die.
And she's not, either.
And that's why
she wants to fight.
Diane Schiffman would
make a great wife, you know?
And she's great with
the kids at the block party.
Yeah, 'cause she's always drunk.
What about Wendy McDowell?
Too uptight. She'll turn
Emma into a nervous wreck.
Erin Miller?
She's way too hot for you.
Mary.
I know.
It's time.
Come here.
Thank you, honey,
for giving me this.
And I'm gonna see you soon.
Oh!
You, too, my precious,
little perfect girl.
Okay.
Okay, let's go.
Here we go.
Are you kidding me? How
the hell is this not working?
Dr. Torres... Just give
me a second, okay?
As co-surgeon on this case, I
say we abandon the reconstruction,
and do a standard fusion.
We're not quitting. How many
times do I have to say that?
I'm simply recommending
an alternative solution.
Yeah? Well, your solution sucks.
He's lost motor
evoked responses.
Okay, that's it.
You know, I'm out.
I'm taking my name off the case.
Wait. There's an electrode out.
Unbelievable.
All right. How's that?
Great. He's fine.
Done. Your name's off the case.
5.5-millimeter cobalt chrome rod
and alternating
cross connectors.
I'm gonna link the
three rods together.
What? You can use
the cobalt rods for this?
What do you care?
You're off the case.
Go!
All right. Let's
get the next one.
I compared healthy
and hyperglycemic mice.
It looks like the islet
cells are being rejected.
So it's not the device.
Well, that's good.
It could be a recurrence
of autoimmunity.
Or a problem with
the engraftment.
Maybe it's not the
cells being rejected.
Maybe they're just not surviving
because of other causes.
So we should check
for signs of rejection?
Exactly. Okay. Bump me.
We're looking in
the wrong place.
The device is working, but
something is harming the islet cells.
How did you figure that
out? It doesn't matter.
So tell Bailey to look
for signs of rejection.
And who do you think you are?
What? God? Is that who you are?
Dr. Bailey, she was just
doing what I asked her to do.
Because either you're God,
or you are the most
reckless, arrogant resident
I have come across
in my entire career.
I mean, to put your hands
on another clinical trial
after you already ruined
one is a level of stupidity
so staggering... I delegated.
This has nothing to do...
You are fired from
my trial, Kepner.
And you...
Just give me back my mouse.
Not until you read my research.
Dr. Bailey! Read my research.
Hey, that kinda works.
Okay, I've cleared out the tumor
on the right side of
the brain, but look.
See all those vessels
blocking the way now?
It's like a line of defense.
That's why the tumor's so smart.
It grows on both
sides of the brain
so we'll be too
scared to cross over.
But she has six months.
That's something.
You know, and you tried. There's
no shame in stopping now...
Lexie. Yeah.
We're not stopping.
But you just said
the tumor is smart.
We're smarter. Bipolars.
Hey, it's my fifth year.
I have to defend every decision
made in my OR at the boards.
Do you know why I picked
you to be my co-surgeon?
Because you...
You take crazy risks in the OR.
But the surgeon I've worked
with the past three days?
Safe, boring, a B-minus
version of herself.
I get it. Fifth year
is competitive.
Your whole career depends on it,
but if you're not careful,
you're gonna wake up one day
and realize that you're
no longer the badass,
hard-core, spontaneous,
take-charge,
crazy, fun person
you thought you were,
but instead, some sad, sorry
wife who stays in every night
and talks about food like it's
an orgasm when it's clearly not.
An orgasm is an orgasm.
I'm sorry. What?
Don't let fifth year get to you.
Hi.
You mind if I sit?
Please.
She's herniating. What
the hell happened?
A vessel leaked. The
tumor's starting to swell.
Okay, we're gonna
have to drain the ventricle.
Get me a blunt-tip needle. Now.
You're going in blind?
We have no choice.
Just tell me.
We got it.
We got the whole tumor.
Thank you.
You have a mommy, Emma.
You have a mommy.
Once they have prepped you,
I will meet you in the
cath lab and do the TAVI.
Hey, Chuck, what the hell?
Crap.
Look, the lady had a
bigger pair than you.
No hard feelings,
okay? Let's go.
Hey, doll, how old
do you think I am?
I want my patient back.
I was being cautious. You
can't punish me for that.
Actually, I can.
You've had some bad outcomes.
We all get bad outcomes.
Your problem is that
you let it get to you,
and now you're scared.
The only thing worse than a
bad surgeon is a scared one.
Pretty soon,
you'll be able to do
everything you
couldn't do before,
feed yourself,
look girls in the eye.
How about sports?
Don't be an idiot, idiot.
You know that he
cannot do sports.
Will you just get a divorce?
And what did I tell you
about this name calling?
Get a divorce.
Well, okay, then I got a
new one for you, bitch face.
Oh, how original.
I said get a divorce!
I get it.
You had to stay together
until I was outta high school.
Then it was college,
and then this neck thing
happened, but that's over now.
My neck's fine, so you two
are free to leave each other.
Listen, kiddo. No, baby, it
has nothing to do with you.
You hate each other!
You hate each other.
It's obvious. So go.
Go to the court.
Just get a divorce!
Okay, why don't we
give Tyler some space?
How'd that feel?
Awesome.
Yeah.
Uh, you paged?
Eight of the mice
are hyperglycemic.
What?
I've been locked in
this lab all day and night,
hiding it from you,
trying to understand why,
and Meredith
Grey figured it out.
Now I've got just
weeks' worth of
tests to run and
mice to monitor,
real patients to check on.
Well, so you get help.
From who? I fired Kepner.
There's no way in hell I'm
putting Meredith on this trial.
Help will show up.
Trust me. It always does.
So, you're gonna go home,
get some rest.
The work will be here in
the morning. Go. Right now.
Don't worry, Q. I got your back.
He just went in blind
and he hit the ventricle.
It was the most incredible
thing I have ever seen.
All Sloan taught me today
was how to brine a chicken.
Altman called me a chicken.
What you said to me the other
day was horrible, mean, and...
All right. You're
doing it again.
You're like a friggin' mosquito.
Yeah, well, that's all changing.
Lexie, you're leading
pre-rounds tomorrow.
Jackson, you're
touring med students,
and, Alex, you've got nights
in the ER for the next week.
Any of you argue with me,
and I'll take you off the
OR board indefinitely.
I, on the other hand, just
got fired from Bailey's trial.
So I'm gonna spend the night
drinking and flirting with boys.
Ah!
Whoa, whoa.
No. We can't do this anymore.
No more sex in the hospital.
You know, I'm Chief
now. I have to act like it.
Fine. Whatever.
Do you want to go get dinner?
Uh, sure.
It's not always easy
to speak your mind.
Or we could just go
home and have sex there.
Let's do that. Yeah.
Okay? Let's do that. Okay.
Sometimes you need
to be forced to do it.
Hey. You brought pizza?
No. Pizza? I made a coq au vin.
What are you... Wait.
No, no, no. What...
What are you doing?
Not my coq au vin!
Mark, I love you.
I love how great you
are with our daughter.
I love that you and Arizona
are friends. But you...
You need to leave, 'cause
tonight I'm gonna eat pizza
and drink beer in
bed with my wife
and tell her all about
the neck I just built,
and then we're gonna
have lots and lots of sex.
Okay? We're great parents,
but we're more than just
mommies and daddies.
We are hot and we are sexy,
and your new hobby, the
hollandaise and the short ribs
and the coq au vin, is getting
in the way of our sex lives.
So, please, start
having sex again.
Okay? But not tonight. 'Cause
tonight, you're babysitting.
Can I at least have some pizza?
That was incredibly hot.
Sometimes it's better to just
keep things to yourself, though.
Play dumb...
I had a good day.
So good, in fact, I wanna break
our rule and tell you about it.
Even when your whole
body's aching to come clean.
Don't.
Are you sure?
Come here.
So you shut your mouth...
Keep the secret...
And find other ways
to make yourself happy.