[Door opening]
Why is there a letter
of resignation on my desk ?
I told you. I got a job offer.
I don't want to hear this again.
Working at a private medical co-op.
Moving to L.A. This is not my Addison.
My Addison is a world-class neonatal
surgeon. My Addison lives to cut.
Your Addison would have been promoted
to chief of surgery,
so stop Addisoning me.
I want a change, I need a change,
this is how I'm going to do it,
- at that practice, with those people.
- You don't know those people !
I know plenty ! My best friend,
Naomi, from med school.
She's a fertility specialist there,
she's an amazing woman.
- [Knock on door]
- Mother just needs a moment to herself !
[Addison] Her ex-husband, Sam,
is an internist.
- You wish you had his people skills.
- We can't keep doing this.
I love you, I do,
we're in this together.
- But we got to make a change.
- [Barks]
Violet is a psychiatrist
and she's incredible. Grounded, strong.
[Man] Hello ?
Hello ?
Violet, you have to stop calling here.
I'm married now.
Cooper. A pediatrician.
One of the best in his field. A pro.
Lisa.
Oh, God. I'm sorry. Lily, right ?
Your name's Lily, right ?
Sorry. I'm getting
a little uncomfortable.
- If you could...
- [door opens]
Lori ! Lori !
Pete does alternative medicine.
As a surgeon I don't believe in that
kind of thing, but the man is a healer !
So I know exactly
what I'm getting myself into.
You're going to go there
and do what ? Wear jeans ?
Walk on the beach ?
Dance in your underwear ?
- Maybe I'll dance naked.
- You belong in the OR.
You'll be back begging for your job.
No. I won't. I am changing my life.
Now I can walk away angry
or I can walk away with your blessing.
Either way, Richard, I'm going.
I'll keep your job open
as long as I can.
Come here.
[ ? Scissor Sisters :
I Don't Feel Like Dancin']
[Inaudible] Sam !
[Inaudible] Addison !
Sam ?
Addison ?
[Inaudible] What the...
How did you end up getting a house
right next door to me ?
- Naomi said you had the best realtor.
- Naomi said.
Addison, what are you doing here ?
It's... not like I look bad naked.
A lot of men have enjoyed
seeing me naked.
A lot of men. Well, not a lot.
I mean, eight.
- Well, 11.
- No. Here in Los Angeles.
Here.
I...
Didn't Naomi tell you ?
Tell me what ?
[Man] Oceanside Wellness Group.
- Hi. Dell, right ? Where's Naomi ?
- Yes.
- I need to know where Naomi...
- [Naomi] Mr. Wilson ?
You guys can come on back now, OK ?
- Hi ! You moved in. Everything good ?
- Yeah. Whatever.
Naomi. I need to talk to you.
- So...
- Hey, Dr. Bennett.
- Hi.
- Putting my boys in a cup.
- We're going to get Leslie pregnant.
- I'm ovulating.
Congratulations. That's great.
- Never done it into a cup before.
- Yeah.
- Yeah...
- That can be kind of... Naomi ?
Dell, take Ken and Leslie
back to exam room number one.
I'm going to be right with
you guys, OK ? Thanks.
- Just in the conference room, please.
- Fine.
[Sighs]
Addison ! Hi.
- Hi. Hello. Oh, oh.
- Nice to see you. Hey.
[Both laugh]
So... What happened to
the amicable divorce ?
Progressive decompensation
of repressed rage
secondary to feelings of abandonment.
It's shrink talk.
For Naomi finally getting pissed off
that Sam left her.
What are they mad about now ?
[Addison] Naomi didn't tell Sam
that she hired me.
To work here ?
Here he is. All good. Oh.
Next time you want to hide your
vegetables, feed them to the dog.
You can't shove them up your nose. Your
nose is off limit as a hiding place, OK ?
[Grunts]
Ooh !
Mommy and Daddy are fighting again.
- Addison ! Cooper. Remember me ? Yeah.
- Cooper, yeah.
- Handsome.
- Hi, Cooper.
Pete. Hello.
- You're back in town.
- Yes. She works here.
- Naomi hired her.
- You're working here ?
- Yeah.
- Welcome aboard.
- Oh.
- So Naomi didn't tell any of you
that I was coming ?
It's a power play. Naomi's trying
to show that she has the power.
Why did Addison take the job ?
Wasn't she some hotshot in Seattle ?
Did Naomi just run over us
with a steamroller ?
- Is she crazy ?
- Naomi's insane.
I mean, Addison. Is she some
crazy person who gets kissed once
and decides to change her whole life ?
You kissed Addison ?
- Really ?
- Focus.
I know she has the largest chunk
of this practice,
but we agreed to equal votes. We are
supposed to vote. Sam, do something.
- Yeah. Me ?
- This divorce is killing us.
- You need to apologize.
- [Pete] Say you were wrong for walking
- out, we can get back to being family.
- I never... I...
I didn't...
I am not apologizing to her.
She's the one.
Naomi hires Addison and
moves her in right next door to me.
- I saw her naked this morning.
- You saw her naked ?
- Did she look good naked ?
- [Both] Focus.
- So just get it in the cup ?
- Yeah. Just get it in the cup.
I want a kid. I've always wanted a kid,
but this is just...
A lot of clients are nervous.
Remember, once you have the baby,
how it got here won't matter.
- Eyes on the prize.
- Yeah. Eyes on the prize.
Oh, OK, the five-cent tour.
Exam rooms. Two is for peds.
Three has the gynie exam table in it.
- You and I will share it.
- You didn't tell them you hired me.
They'll get over it. It's fine.
Scrub sinks are over there.
We contract with the lab downstairs.
No, Nai, I don't think
it's fine to them.
To them, I'm the interloper.
I don't lope.
I own 55 percent of the practice.
I made a decision.
They have to live with that.
I have to...
They will get over it.
OK, here's your birthing suite.
[Addison] But I deliver babies
in a hospital.
[Naomi] You used to deliver
Now, unless it's a C-section,
you deliver here.
- It's very popular with the patients.
- OK.
Uh, so I guess I should meet my staff.
I don't have a staff. [laughs]
OK. Let me see if I understand this.
I left a hospital
with a state of the art ob-gyn wing
- and a staff of 60...
- You'll have Dell.
- He's studying to be a midwife.
- Boy who answers phones.
Plus, you have Pete.
Laboring moms love Pete.
The alternative medicine guru ? Do you
know how many babies I deliver a day ?
- Here you'll be lucky to deliver one.
- One patient, the entire day ?
[Naomi] I told you.
We do things differently.
This may be a big city, but this co-op
is about practicing small-town medicine.
Every patient is special
and gets our full attention.
It's not about surgeries.
It's about connecting. I told you this.
I know. I just... I didn't think it
would be one patient, the entire day ?
You wanted change. This is it.
Yep. This is it.
Hey, Naomi. We need to talk to you.
- Sam needs to talk to you.
- I don't need...
- I'm just going to go some...
- No. Stay. She is staying.
You can't bring in somebody
without a vote.
- Yeah. This is not...
- [Ken moaning]
- This is not a...
- [Ken moans]
- What is that ?
- Somebody's getting happy.
Mr. Wilson giving a sperm deposit.
Get away.
- That's a loud deposit.
- Go, Mr. Wilson.
- You guys are so immature.
- This is definitely different.
- [Indistinct chattering]
- Help ! Please come quick !
I was helping him get in the mood.
Now he's not moving !
- What's wrong with him ?
- Pupil's blown. He's having a stroke.
All right. He's had three rounds of epi
and a 200 lido bolus.
- Defibbed times five on scene.
- Get out of my way. Hold CPR.
- How long has he been down ?
- Uh... At least 20 minutes.
- I'm going to call it.
- What ?
- What about the shockie things ?
- No point turning this into a show.
No ! No ! Use the shockie things !
- I'm sorry, he's gone.
- Time of death, 9 :42am.
[Gasping] No.
We were going to have a baby.
He was going to be a dad.
[Sobbing]
I want... I want his sperm.
Uh... He didn't get a chance to make
his donation before he died.
- You can take it from him now.
- [Both] What ?
I want his sperm.
I want Ken's sperm now !
[Violet] I get Naomi's mad.
Hell hath no fury and all that.
I know the practice needs an ob-gyn,
but since when do we not vote ?
I had sex with this woman last night.
We started this practice
to be in charge of our own destiny.
Very real, you know, Internet sex.
But she wanted me to call her "Mama."
But she promised
all this really freaky stuff.
And I'm talking, like, stuff.
OK. Ew ! That's it. I'm done.
Come on. What ? Why ?
Because you're a sex addict
or an Internet addict
- or some freaky addict.
- You're a stalker.
- Stalking your married ex-boyfriend.
- I am not.
I'm... calling him occasionally.
- Stalker.
- OK, that's it.
I'm cutting you off.
You get no help from me.
- You're getting no more help.
- I don't ask for your help.
- Oh, come on, stalker.
- I'm not a stalker !
[Pager beeps]
Hey. I just want to say
that I am really sorry.
- About Naomi and the job. I...
- I got a 911 page.
[Sighs]
Don't mind her. She's not mad at you.
She's mad at me.
OK.
Do you think there's something wrong
with having sex with a woman
who wants you to call her "Mama ?"
Oh, God, it just sounds so much worse
when I say it out loud.
- There's a patient for you.
- Thank God.
No, not him. You.
I have a patient ?
[Dell] This is Bill Henderson and his
daughter, Lucy. This is Dr. Montgomery.
- She'll deliver your baby.
- [Groans]
It hurts, doesn't it ? That's what
you get for getting pregnant !
She hid it for months.
Suddenly it's "Daddy, I'm in labor."
How about we get you
into the birthing suite ? Dell.
- See if we have a chart.
- Can I get in on this ?
Don't have field experience
for training.
- How about you just find the chart ?
- [Shudders]
Ken's sperm.
You want us to take
Ken's sperm right out of...
Are you sure ?
I'm sure. Ken would want it too.
I know he would.
I mean, you can do it, right ?
Look here. You're distressed,
I understand.
Unless you have written consent, I won't
let you molest your husband's corpse.
Well, let's not use words
like "molest" or "corpse"
about her loved one.
It's her boyfriend, not husband.
Oh, well, fine.
She wants sperm of a man
she has no legal rights to.
- That makes it all better. No.
- What ?
OK. Hey. Let's...
Can we stop, Charlotte, right ?
You know my name, Sam.
Don't act like you don't.
I'm chief of staff, and you know it.
You and I,
we're on the same side here.
I don't think this is a good idea.
My patient died while visiting
a fertility specialist.
- They were trying to have a baby.
- For the patient to enjoy while alive.
- Unless the girlfriend's a mantis.
- Did she call me an insect ?
- No. She didn't.
- I'm sorry. That was rude of me.
I get my back up any time
you people in that practice of yours
- try to bend rules in my hospital.
- We don't bend the rules.
We just do things differently.
You and I,
we can work on this together.
We can figure this out.
Because I'm a good person,
[stammers] you're a good person.
I mean, we can... right ?
We can... Together...
- I did read your book, by the way.
- Oh. Great.
I took issue with most of it.
Now, I'm on her side. We want Ken's
sperm or you got a fight on your hands.
That man's swimmers
are staying where they are.
You got a way to fight,
I'd like to see you try.
I'm calling Naomi on you.
Lucy Henderson,
my patient until she got pregnant.
No previous medical problems.
It looks good.
The dad is mad as hell.
I could use your help in there.
Oh, yeah, no.
That, down there, is not my area.
So when the baby comes out, I'd be happy
to examine it. Until then, Godspeed.
- [Scoffs]
- Give me two secs to grab my kit.
- I'll join you.
- For ?
Read further in the chart,
she has a holistic birth plan.
- Oh, my God. Are you kidding me ?
- Laboring moms love Pete.
Hey, listen, um...
...your moving here, it didn't have
anything to do with me kissing you ?
- What ?
- It's OK. It's just that... well,
- you should know, it was just a kiss.
- Wait. You think
- I moved here because you kissed me ?
- It was a good kiss.
- It was an excellent kiss. But...
- Stop talking ! All right ? [chuckles]
I did not move here
because you kissed me.
- OK.
- You are actually deranged enough
to think that I would pick up my entire
life and move because of a kiss ?
- Let me clear that up. I wouldn't.
- OK.
Shut up. Just go in there and do
your little Eastern voodoo thing you do,
and let's help that girl
have her baby in peace.
What do you expect me to do ?
He was your patient.
My patient's dead. This is about your
patient who wants a dead man's sperm.
- Besides, I got mad.
- You got mad ?
- I got mad.
Neither of us makes
good decisions when we're mad.
Another doctor who can bill
is a very good decision.
We agreed when we split
we would not let it affect work.
My work is fine. In fact,
watch me take care of my patient.
Hey. Listen. We still have time, OK ?
Get a good sample for at least 24 hours.
I can't believe it.
He was so happy.
I know, I know.
I want his baby. I want to have
something of him, of us together.
- Please.
- All right.
- Where are you going ?
- Hospital won't touch the body, I will.
Lay a hand on him,
I'll have you arrested.
I'm not a person who plays games, Naomi.
You know that. Now, please, step back.
- OK, now I'm mad.
- I told you.
[Sighs]
- Hey.
- Hey. Where's Naomi ?
- Had to get to the hospital.
- She gets to work at a hospital,
but I don't.
- [Addison sighs]
- [Clears throat]
You know, I could help.
You know, with Lucy.
Thanks. That's nice, but I'm good.
- You don't take me seriously.
- What ?
You think I'm some
dumb surfer boy, eye candy.
You have no respect
for me or my midwifery skills.
I have total respect for you
and your... midwifery skills ?
- Is that even a word ? Midwifery ?
- It's a word.
It's definitely a word.
[Chuckles]
[Woman counting quietly]
Jenny ?
She's been counting the tiles for over
an hour. Do you know this lady ?
Yes, I do.
What the hell happened to her ?
- She had your card in her wallet.
- Well, thank you.
Thank you for calling me.
My sister, she's got mental problems.
She's a good person,
but she's got mental problems.
- It's why I called you before the cops.
- We don't need the police.
- I can handle it.
- Can you do it quick ?
She can't stay. She's obstructing
customer flow...
If you give me some time,
I will take her out of your hair.
Can you do that for me, Paul ?
Can you do that ?
- I guess.
- Thank you.
You're getting charged by the hour,
so you might as well hear me.
- Inhale.
- [Sobs, breathes deeply]
- Exhale. Focus on me. Exhale.
- [Exhales]
Deep breaths. In. Out.
- Good. Good. Much better.
[Sighing] My dad. He's just mad.
I want this baby.
I just... I screwed up.
I'm such a screw-up.
Hey. Lucy ? Listen.
Everyone screws up once in a while.
And, in this room,
you get a free pass. OK ?
OK.
These are Ken and Leslie's medical
records, including Ken's signature
on a contract, with my office,
regarding his donation.
Now, I think that is more than implied.
Live consent is different.
- You're considering this ?
- It could be persuasive in court.
You patient will sign something
indemnifying us from legal action ?
She just wants her baby.
Fine. You do the procedure,
you take possession of the sperm.
Thank you for your help.
- Well done. Very badass.
- I know, right ?
- Get away from me. It's good.
- [Laughs]
- Are you Dr. Naomi Bennett ?
- I am.
Get that tramp's claws
off my husband's sperm,
or I'll sue so fast your head will spin.
- Who are you ?
- I'm Ken Wilson's wife.
Jenny ? You look very angry to me.
Did something happen to make
you feel out of control in the store ?
OK. Well, we've been working on rage
directed toward your husband
for leaving you. Are you angry ?
That's OK. Feel the feelings.
Get angry. Let's talk about
getting angry.
- She's not answering.
- Yeah, I got that, Paul.
What's the deal ? She gets upset so
she goes crazy with the counting ?
Well, for many people, counting
establishes a sense of order.
Oh, my God. When did my knees turn 80 ?
- We got kneepads on aisle eight.
- I'm not gonna be here much longer.
Jenny and I are about
to have a breakthrough.
Right, Jenny ?
Can you look up at me ?
Can you look into my eyes ?
Come on, Jenny.
I know you can do this.
- [Screams]
- [Paul] Whoa !
- You OK ?
- Yes. I'm fine.
- You sure ?
- Yes.
[Sobbing, counting]
- [monitors beeping]
- [Door opens]
Just checking to see if you need
anything. Any help.
- We're all good.
- [Scoffs]
- OK, Lucy. You ready to push ?
- Please.
Mr. Henderson, your daughter's
going to start pushing now.
Would you like to come
and sit by her side ?
- For what ?
- [Sighs]
Why don't you squeeze my hand, OK ?
If you need to.
OK.
- OK.
- [Exhales]
- Lucy, you ready ?
- [Lucy] Yeah.
- OK, go ahead and push.
- [Grunting]
Good. Push.
Good. Good. Push.
- [Breathing heavily]
- [monitors beeping]
- [Addison] That's good. Push.
- [Straining]
- [Pants]
- Stop. Stop.
- She's short of breath with JVD.
- Isn't Eastern medicine your thing ?
I have a lot of things.
She's short of breath.
Do you want to double check
or trust me ?
The baby's in distress. OK, Lucy,
don't push for right now, all right ?
Just give me a minute, OK ?
Dr. Montgomery, something's wrong.
Lucy ? Lucy ? Lucy, wake up !
Lucy, wake up ! Lucy ?
Get her on high-flow oxygen.
- Get an ambulance.
- Just held her hand.
She's going into congestive
heart failure ! Ambulance !
Lucy ? Honey ?
Her mom died. In childbirth.
She died having Lucy.
I'm applying pressure,
but the cord is compressed.
She's going to be OK ?
And Lucy's blood is flooding her lungs,
and the umbilical cord is cutting off
the baby's blood supply.
- I called the ambulance.
- How long does it take ?
Ten to 20 minutes in traffic.
- We don't have 20 minutes.
- I know.
- We're going to lose her and the baby.
Thought you might be hungry.
You'll have to pay for it.
That and the ice pack.
- And the flip flops. But...
- Thanks.
- You OK ?
- Yeah.
It's just... Look, I know her.
She's been coming to see me
for months, and I know her.
She's not the type to...
She's gentle.
[Indistinct radio chatter]
- Paul !
- Look, I'm sorry. But I don't think...
I don't think you know
how to handle this.
I do know how to handle this.
There's something I'm not seeing.
Something she's not telling me.
If she's not telling her shrink,
you must not be good at your job.
Patient's hold things in.
They hold things in for years.
- What's going on ?
- Do not touch her !
- Violet, we have to...
- Think of your sister. Please.
- I'm working here, Cooper.
- Really ? It looks like you're shopping.
It's a joke. Dell told me you were here.
I came to see if you need help.
- You look like you could use some.
- No, I don't need any help.
You know what ? This ?
You drove all the way down here
to see if I was still mad at you.
Who is the stalker now ?
- Let's settle down.
- Sorry, I got to let them take her.
- If she gets violent with you...
- She got violent with you ?
- Come... Look at the pupils.
- Not now, Cooper.
This is a psychiatric emergency.
I can stabilize her.
Just give me a minute
and give me backup if I need it.
I just feel...
...if I knew how it started or
where she was when it happened.
So how do you figure out
how it started ?
You have security cameras, don't you ?
He wanted to "find himself."
Turns out he wanted to find me,
only 15 years younger and half as
smart. Any idea what that's like ?
- I think I can imagine.
- Like I don't feel my age, feel scared ?
I feel it alone while
he's yanking it in a cup
for a chick he met hiking in Sedona.
I know this is unfair.
I understand. Believe me.
- You know, I was with him 17 years.
- Maria,
Ken really wanted Leslie
to have his baby.
And Leslie wants Leslie
to have Ken's money.
- I don't think that she would do that.
- I didn't think my husband'd dump me.
So there you go.
If you want protection,
legal protection,
I think Leslie would agree
to whatever you ask.
I don't want protection.
I want Ken's sperm.
- What ?
- For myself.
Now we'll see who ends up alone, right ?
Where the hell is the ambulance ?
- You have to make a choice.
- Make a choice ?
If I wait any longer for the ambulance,
I could lose them both.
Or I get the baby out
and maybe save them.
- Save them ! Of course.
- Maybe. Maybe save them.
Dell, glove up.
I need you to decompress the cord.
Come here.
- Like this ?
- Yes, that's good. Steady pressure.
OK.
[Exhales]
I need to be in a hospital. There's
no way I can perform a C-section here.
It's not sterile,
I don't have any equipment...
- Addison.
...no extra blood,
an epidural would take too long.
She's a healthy 17-year-old.
No one could have foreseen this.
Know what happens when a scalpel
slices into a person without anesthesia ?
- Addison...
- Shut up !
I am trying to talk myself into this.
I can't when you keep Addisoning me.
So just... [exhales] hold on.
OK. Pete, take over for Dell.
Dell, go find a surgical tray
from somewhere.
She will feel every slice,
but we have to try.
- Addison.
- I am going to scrub in,
find sterile drapes,
a local anesthetic to help the pain.
- [Pete] Addison.
- Stop Addisoning me !
I can treat her
so she won't feel any pain.
The cameras show her on this aisle.
She stopped, next thing,
she's looking at the floor.
[Cooper] Maybe a camping accident ?
Something traumatic.
Or maybe, you know,
this guy, he works here,
he told me that marshmallow gets so hot
it sticks like napalm.
- That's not that bad, I guess.
- [Cooper] Not bad enough for counting.
They had a house at the lake.
[Pete] I stimulated the needles.
Lidocaine's in, pain receptors blocked.
- She's ready.
- She's not going to feel anything ?
- I'm sure.
- If she wakes up screaming in pain...
- I'm sure. I'm very good at what I do.
- Are you really, really sure ?
Trust me.
OK. Here we go.
I'm going to cut on three.
One...
...two...
Three.
OK. OK. Yay. OK.
- Did I or did I not say trust me ?
- You did.
- And I do. Now.
- That was good. It was good ?
There's no time to celebrate.
We have to move fast.
Both mom and baby are still in danger.
She can't just swoop in and take it.
She was divorcing Ken's sperm.
She was with Ken for 17 years,
that should count for something.
I know, but he was with Leslie.
He loved her.
Please, he barely knew her.
He met her on a hiking trip in Sedona.
I thought we were on Leslie's side.
- You would.
- She is your patient.
A marriage should count for something.
He just moved on.
Come on. Could we please
not make this about us ?
I'm talking about Ken.
He bailed, she got nothing.
He died ! All things considered,
I'd rather be her.
The one people feel sorry for ?
The one who got left ?
I didn't...
Don't think for one moment
I have been taking this lightly.
- Oh, no. You walked out.
- I did not walk out.
I said I was unhappy.
That I was questioning.
Instead of working on it,
you shut the door.
You weren't in love anymore.
How are we to work on that ?
I never said that !
I'm not an idiot.
I knew exactly what you were saying.
So then you fight.
You have some passion about the thing.
I wanted to see you fight,
just once, for us.
Naomi, I'm sorry,
profoundly, for hurting you.
But you're fooling yourself if you think
you're the only one who got left.
- What are we looking for ?
- Stop talking so I can think.
Something in the ad.
That's what triggered her.
- Did you have a boy ?
- [Softly counting]
Did you have a son
that we haven't talked about ?
Did something happen to him ? Jenny ?
Did he... Did you lose your son ?
- Did he pass away ?
- You'll make me lose my place !
25,136. 25,137. 25...
- He died.
- One, two, three...
One, two, three, four.
One, two, three...
If you really want Ken's sperm,
you can fight it out.
You probably have
more rights than Leslie.
But, with all the legal wrangling,
24 hours will pass, Ken won't be viable.
- Nobody gets anything.
- OK. Let's do that.
[Inhaling deeply]
You honestly never thought about it,
in all those years ? Leaving him ?
Nothing's perfect. But I made my peace.
Yeah, I did too.
At least I thought I did.
[Sighs] I yelled at him so much.
Last time I saw him... God.
Maria. At some point,
you have to let him go.
[ ? Brandi Carlile : California]
OK. [laughs] It's a girl.
Come on, baby. [laughs]
You want to come hold
your granddaughter ?
Yes. Welcome, little girl.
- Oh. [laughs]
- She looks just like Lucy.
- [monitor beeps]
- Addison.
She's in V-tach !
- [Pete] I'm on it.
- [Addison] Got to close.
- If she has a chance, I have to close.
- Charging to 200.
Clear !
- Again, 300.
- The paramedics are here.
- No !
- [Pete] Clear !
Got an open body cavity
and a barely sterile environment.
Do not let them cross the threshold
until I say so. Understand ?
- Got it.
- How you doing there, Pete ?
Kicking ass and taking names. You ?
Ass-kicking and name-taking
are on my résumé.
Charging to 360. Clear.
Start her on a lidocaine drip.
Two migs per minute. O2 at ten liters.
- Hey there.
- [Slurs] Did I have the baby ?
- Yes, you did.
- Is my dad ? Is he mad ?
- No, your dad is not mad at you.
- [Elevator dings]
Thank you. For...
Thank you.
[Chuckles] Well, that was pretty cool.
Dell. Good work in there.
I didn't come down here
because you kissed me.
- OK.
- I didn't.
- I need you to say it.
You did not move down here
because I kissed you.
You so moved down here
I heard that.
Maria's going to let Leslie have it.
We can do the extraction on Ken.
- What did you say ?
- Just that it was time...
...to let him go.
Good. That's... that's good.
OK.
Oh, and my book... was brilliant.
[Counting softly]
[Clears throat] His name was Will.
Hey, Paul. Do you think you could clear
out this area for a little while ?
- For Jenny ?
- Yeah.
I can do that for Jenny.
Hey, Jenny.
This is Dr. Freedman.
He's a pediatrician.
- And he's my friend.
- Hi.
I have Will's file here.
It says he was suffering from double
vision when you brought him in.
He was ten.
Diagnosed with a Brainstem Glioma.
[Violet] That something
they could've caught earlier ?
No, they got it early.
But, because of the location of the
tumor in the brain, it was inoperable.
So Will started chemo and radiation
and they put him on a steroid
to reduce the pressure in the brain
from the tumor.
And the tumor responded, at first,
and then Will developed kidney failure.
- Well, that happens with chemo. A lot.
- [Cooper] It does.
At that point, you and your husband
decided to stop treatment.
- Is that right ? Jenny ?
- [Counting softly]
Making that choice... A lot of people
aren't strong enough to do that.
[Cooper] These tumors... don't quit.
Treatment makes kids so sick,
they can't do anything.
Then you didn't come back
to the hospital for a few months.
Did you go away ? To the lake ?
[ ? Chris Garneau : Sad News]
[Jenny gasping]
We all went together.
That's what I would have done. Exactly.
When you came back to the hospital,
Will was having trouble speaking,
but his spirits were high, good.
- Sounds like he was a great kid.
- [Cooper] Yes, it does.
And then ?
- He went into a coma.
- [Counting]
[Cooper] Then you made him comfortable.
Made sure everyone
had a chance to say goodbye.
And on the 16th, at 5 :13am,
you took him off the machines.
And...
...it says you held him and...
...he breathed on his own
for over four hours.
[Counting softly]
That was hard.
Holding him like that.
For all that time.
[Mouthing silently]
Will...
He had the most aggressive kind
of brain cancer that a kid can have.
You didn't make it happen.
And there's no cure. Only the choice
on how you're going to ride it out.
You did everything
a great mom could do.
So no matter how
you second-guess yourself
or what your head tells you,
you didn't let your son down.
You did not let your son down.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. My baby.
[Moaning]
Goodbye, honey.
[Gasping, sobbing]
[Sniffs] Thank you.
- She's all right ?
- Yeah. She's going to be all right.
- My assistant.
- Yeah. I was.
- Don't forget to...
- Yeah. I'll pay for the stuff, Paul.
[Exhales]
Thanks. For coming down.
- I'm here for you.
- Don't say that.
- Now I just feel guilty.
- I'm a better person than you are.
The thing is, Cooper, OK,
the thing is that...
...I am kind of a stalker.
- I know.
[Imitates casting a line]
Why didn't you tell them I was coming ?
Truth.
All right. Fine.
I need you here.
OK ? I need you here because I'm tired,
and I'm lonely,
and my best friend divorced me
and I have no one.
I need you here to be my someone.
All right, I shared. You satisfied ?
- I'm gonna need a lot of cheesecake.
- [Elevator dings]
OK.
We want to see you in the conference
room, if that's OK. I mean now.
- [Violet] We're a team. We're partners.
- [Sam] Can't just bring somebody in.
- [Pete] Without asking.
- We're a democracy. We vote.
- We vote, or it doesn't happen.
- You're right.
We should have voted.
I was wrong.
Good. OK. Let's vote.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa !
Hold on a minute.
Ah... I have been working here
less than 24 hours,
and in that time, I discovered
that I am not welcome here,
I learned that I am
a one man gynie show,
and I performed crazy MacGyver surgery
and Sam saw my booty ! [chuckles]
So this has not been a great day
for me. This day kind of sucked.
But you know what ? I had one patient.
One patient. The entire day.
And I loved it.
So you want me gone ? Too bad. I'm in.
I'm putting my foot down.
My foot's down. It's down.
I'm not going anywhere. So...
...yeah.
I thought I had a big finish, but...
...I don't, so... I'm done.
No. No !
I do have a big finish.
If I hadn't been here today,
if you'd had someone else,
that girl would have died
delivering her baby.
I saved her life.
I saved your asses.
I'm a world-class neonatal surgeon.
And I'm here to stay.
Welcome to the new Oceanside Wellness.
[ ? Swingfly :
Something's Got Me Started]
That's why I didn't tell you
she was coming.