Did you ever think maybe
that I had misdiagnosed you?
No.
There was something wrong with me.
I'm grateful for what you did.
You know, I really appreciate
your saying that.
We knew this was coming.
And, honestly, the fact
that I got any time at all,
you gave me that.
They said he had a blood clot,
and it happened so fast,
they couldn't save him.
- That song.
- I love that song!
Oh. Sorry.
- Thank you.
- Oh.
Hey, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
You got to partake.
The Chicago Handshake
was Sully's favorite.
It's a shot of Malort
with an Old Style chaser.
Ooh, yeah. I'm... I'm good.
Oh, no, no, come on. Just one round.
Just one round, please.
Hey, how about that toast, yeah?
- I don't drink.
- Why? You religious?
Uh, recovering addict.
Well, I'm a drunk, but you
don't see that stopping me.
Jake, Jake, quit harassing my girlfriend
and make your damn toast already, yeah?
All right, all right, all right.
- I wanted... whoa.
- Whoa! You OK?
Yeah. Thank you, sweetheart.
- He's harmless, I promise.
- No, it's fine. It's fine.
I once saw my man
put back a dozen of these
and still walk out of here upright.
Now, none of you wusses could ever.
But you damn well better try
in his honor.
- To Sully!
I wasn't done. But to Sully.
Miss you, buddy.
Oh, man.
You, uh... you ready to bail?
Uh, yeah.
Early morning tomorrow.
I appreciate you coming out.
I know these guys can be a lot.
No.
No, it's been fun.
It's nice finally meeting
more of your past.
Yeah.
I'll call you an Uber.
Wait, are you not...
you're not coming?
I thought you were working tomorrow too.
Yeah, yeah, I'm just...
I'm just gonna finish this round.
All right.
I'll be right behind you, I promise.
Just, um, maybe leave
the key under the mat.
Sure.
You know what time it is, right?
Yeah, I think so. And... shots on Rip!
Shots on Rip!
Shots on Rip! Shots on Rip!
- Shots on Rip!
- Another round.
Hey!
- Dr. Charles, good morning.
- Good morning.
This is my daughter, Penny.
- Hello, Penny.
- Yo.
Yo.
Can you solve the area
of this green triangle.
The area of the green triangle?
Oh, yeah, that's easy.
You just take that number right there,
and then you do it with that number,
and then something else.
- Really helpful, thanks.
- You're welcome.
Penny, don't. Don't be rude.
- What?
- He thought it was funny.
He was being polite.
- Were you being polite?
- It was really funny.
Or did you really think it was funny?
It was really funny.
- Hey, Dad.
- Hey, Carl.
Uh, this is my colleague.
Dan Charles. Nice to meet you.
- The famous Dr. Charles.
- Uh-oh.
Uh, Jackie, can we talk for a minute?
Sure.
I'll see you later,
and it was nice to meet you both.
Penny, honey, get your stuff together.
No.
I've been trying to admit a patient
into the Med Surg Unit
for the past two hours.
No, do not put me on hold.
Man.
Place is jumping
for a Wednesday morning.
Jackson-Monroe closure,
the gift that keeps on giving.
Pharmacy dropped off our restock.
I noticed.
When are they sending a tech
to scan into the Pyxis?
Well, they're understaffed,
so they can't send someone
till this afternoon.
We're not gonna last that long.
I'm already running low
on Zofran and Tylenol.
My concern exactly,
which is why I was hoping...
No. No.
RNs are not responsible
for stocking the Pyxis.
- That's the pharmacy's job.
- Yes.
And believe me,
I already gave them an earful.
But despite said earful,
they can't send someone
till this afternoon.
I'll get to it as soon as possible.
Or make someone else do it.
You're the boss.
Delegate.
Everything OK?
No.
Carl filed a petition to relocate
- and to take Penny with him.
- What? Where?
Wyoming. It's where his folks live.
I was just getting my brain
around the fact
that we're divorcing, and now he wants
to take my kid 1,000 miles away.
You want to go grab a cup of coffee?
I can't. My shift is starting.
- I'll take the heat.
- I mean...
- I can't lose it.
- OK, OK.
- OK, we'll talk later.
- I'm around.
OK.
- Hey.
Sorry. I didn't mean to wake you.
- No, no.
- It's time.
So what happened?
You never made it back
to my place last night.
Yeah, yeah.
Um,
I guess I stayed at the bar
a little later than I expected.
Figured I should head straight in here
and try and get a few hours
of sleep before my shift,
- you know?
- Yeah, sure.
But a text would have been cool.
Right, yeah.
Uh, I... I think...
I think I left my phone at the bar.
I'll, uh... I'll go back
at lunch and pick it up.
Maybe take a personal day.
Why? I'm already here.
You've got to be exhausted.
As somebody who has worked hungover,
I don't recommend it.
I'm fine. I'm fine, I just...
I just need a shot
of espresso to wake up.
OK?
I'm gonna... I'm gonna
take a run to the coffee truck.
- You want anything?
- Uh, no, I'm good.
But...
you might want this.
Thanks.
Mm-hmm.
Dr. Asher, we have a pregnant
Jane Doe coming in from a fall.
Any idea how old she is
or how far along?
No identification, no purse.
CPD's investigating it
as a suspected robbery.
Wait, so someone pushed a pregnant woman
off of a pedestrian bridge
just to steal her purse?
- How far was the drop?
- About 10 feet.
Thank goodness she landed
on her side and not her belly.
OK, everybody, nice and gentle.
Let's maintain the C-spine
and secure the ET tube.
Come on.
All right, on my count.
One, two, three. Nice and gentle.
Let's get a fetal Doppler.
Prep the ultrasound.
OK.
Clear breath sounds bilaterally.
She's wearing a wedding ring.
Let's hope her spouse
is looking for her.
Baby's heart rate's dropping.
Baby's measuring about 23 weeks,
but that could be off by as much
as two weeks either direction.
If the baby's less than 21 weeks...
- It won't be viable.
- Heart rate's down to 85.
OK, I have to do a crash C-section.
Call the OR. Come on.
Let's go.
We have 20 minutes, tops,
to get this baby out.
- Synced and corrected by synk -
- www.addic7ed.com -
Left, right. Good.
Now, follow this all the way
over here and here.
Well, your extraocular
movements are intact,
your pupils are equal,
round, and reactive,
and I reviewed your post-op head CT,
and there's absolutely no evidence
of any traumatic injury,
and you haven't had a fall since then.
- Correct?
- No.
Right, well, that's all good news,
but still doesn't explain your concern.
So I'd like to refer you to a colleague
for further evaluation.
An ophthalmologist?
A neuropsychiatrist, one
of the best in the business.
- Dr. Eleanor Hess.
- A psychiatrist?
Yeah, hey, look, Dr. Hess
isn't some quack shrink
like your pal Dr. Charles.
She's a real doctor.
Right.
Well, I appreciate
your concern, Dr. Abrams,
but, you know, honestly,
I think I just need more sleep.
Thanks again for seeing me
on such short notice.
For you, Ms. Goodwin, of course.
It's OK, honey. It's OK.
Doctor's almost done.
- You're almost done, right?
- All done.
Sorry about that, Abby,
but the good news is
I don't think it's appendicitis.
Abby's pain isn't confined
to the lower right quadrant.
We read that pain from appendicitis
can be generalized in infants and kids.
True, but Abby doesn't have a fever.
Yet. She doesn't have a fever yet.
Look, I know we're being
those obnoxious parents, but...
It's fine. It's fine.
Doris, let's do
a full appendicitis workup...
CBC, BMP, urinalysis,
and ultrasound of the appendix.
And, uh, let's give IV fluids,
two of morphine and two of Zofran.
- Thank you, Dr. Ripley.
- Yeah, sure thing.
Don't you want to order CRP
to test for inflammation?
Yeah, yeah. Of course.
Just making sure you're
paying attention, Doris.
Right.
Hey.
I hate to ask, but I'm gonna need you
to restock the Pyxis.
No, that's the pharmacy's job.
Yes, I know, but they can't
send anyone until this afternoon.
I'm juggling four patients,
including one critical.
That's still four to one.
Critical patient counts as two.
I almost never pull rank, Doris.
You know that.
But I am not asking you
to restock the Pyxis.
Don't forget this.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
- OK?
- Thank you so much.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- Mm-hmm.
Hey, what's... what's
Dr. Collins doing here?
Uh, my patient, Rosie,
lives in a sober living
residence for teens.
Dr. Collins is the
clinical director there.
That's right.
She was considering taking that job.
So what's going on with the kid?
Is it a relapse?
Uh, no. Drugs aren't involved.
Rolled her ankle
coming down from a layup.
Oh.
Uh, so we're just getting some X-rays.
Well, sounds like a plan.
- OK, well...
- So did she ask for me at all?
Did she ask if I was working today?
- She didn't, no.
- Oh.
- Bad breakup?
- Bad?
No, no, no, no.
It wasn't bad.
I didn't think it was bad.
- What happened?
We had a fight and, uh,
you know, it was my fault, admittedly.
Shocking.
I texted her to apologize,
see if she wanted
to have a drink, and she just said that
she needed some time to think.
- That's understandable.
- Yeah.
So... well, you know, that was that.
Wait, you... you just didn't respond?
The writing was on the wall.
What writing?
You...
I mean, she asked for a minute,
and then you just disappeared.
- No.
- Yes.
I'm sorry to break it to you,
but, um, you ghosted her.
Ghosted her.
Dr. Asher, this is William Tompkins.
You just delivered his wife, Vivian.
Hi.
Please tell me Vivian
and the baby are OK.
She wasn't due for another four months.
Both mom and baby pulled through.
Oh, thank God.
Thank you, thank you, thank you so much.
Now your baby girl is
intubated to help her breathe,
but she's already trying
to fight the tube
- and breathe on her own.
- OK.
And Viv, how's Viv?
Vivian will be OK.
She did start to hemorrhage
after delivery.
Ultimately, I needed
to perform a hysterectomy.
No.
We needed to do it to save her life.
I'm gonna kill the son of a bitch
who did this to her. I swear to God.
Mr. Tompkins,
I understand your rage, I do.
But when your wife wakes up,
she may remember what happened,
and she may not.
I need you to be calm when you see her.
Can you do that?
Yeah, yeah. Of course.
Of course.
This way.
Viv, honey?
- Will?
- Hey.
Hi.
The baby, where... where is she?
The baby is here. OK, Cora is here.
Dr. Asher delivered her, and...
Is she...
She's small, but she's a fighter.
I can tell already.
I'm sorry.
Why are you apologizing?
It happened so fast.
This was not your fault, Viv.
I was looking over the railing.
Someone attacked you, honey.
And the cops are gonna find
whoever did this, and...
No one attacked me.
I don't understand.
I heard this voice telling me...
T-telling you what?
I'm so sorry, honey.
I just... I couldn't take it anymore.
Vivian, did you jump?
I'm so sorry.
She's tachycardic.
Vivian, I need you to stop talking
and take a few deep breaths, OK?
She needs to rest now. I need you...
Viv, you almost
killed our baby and yourself?
- You need... you need to leave.
- Viv?
- Please.
- No, wait.
Come on. Come on. You need to leave.
Look at me. Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Take a deep breath.
And breathe out.
Breathe in. Breathe out.
It's OK.
Good job. It's OK.
Oh, Dr. Ripley.
Abby Campbell's labs
and imaging just posted.
- What's the headline?
- What do you think?
Everything was normal. It's...
Norovirus.
Her parents are probably gonna
want a stool sample to confirm.
Yeah, well, they can go to
their primary care for that.
Prepare a discharge, and I'll...
I'll sign off when I'm back in an hour.
I'm taking my lunch.
An hour for lunch, must be nice.
Sharon, good morning.
Good morning.
It is so good to see you
looking so well.
- I appreciate that, Debbie.
- Good. Well, shall we?
Actually, Peter, I was gonna
suggest that we relocate
the meeting to your office.
Yeah, sure. I'll get...
I'm afraid I have a time crunch.
Got a plane to catch.
Meeting won't take long, right, Peter?
- Uh, it shouldn't.
- Of course not.
Please.
Would you like something
to drink, Debbie?
- Water would be great.
- I'll get it.
Where are you flying off to?
We're visiting our oldest
and the grandbabies.
- Here you go, Sharon.
- Thank you.
So, how old are those grandkids now?
Izzy's four and Penny's seven.
- No, no.
- Please.
Please, please, please!
Oh, my. Oh, oh.
- Careful there, Sharon.
- Just leave it.
- I'll call housekeeping.
- Let me get you a tissue.
- Oh.
- OK.
Uh, you know, forget that.
I'm calling a doctor.
No, no, no, it... I don't need a doctor.
I need a Band-Aid.
Look, I'm fine.
Really, really. I'm... I'm fine.
Hey.
Dr. Archer, got a minute?
It's about my patient
from Dr. Collins' facility.
OK, what's up?
I was reviewing Rosie's chart,
and I saw she had stitches
about a month ago for
a 3-centimeter laceration
- over her right eyebrow.
- OK.
But when I was wrapping Rosie's ankle,
I couldn't help but notice
there's no scar.
- What?
- It's like it never happened.
There's nothing there.
Well, then, it's not possible.
It wouldn't heal that fast.
And when I asked Rosie
about it, she got very cagey.
She said she had a minor fall,
and Dr. Collins stitched her up.
Yeah, that doesn't make sense.
Margo doesn't do sutures.
She's an addiction specialist.
Yeah, you understand my confusion.
Maybe you want to talk
to Dr. Collins about it?
So, Dr. Asher told me that
you reported hearing a voice
right before you jumped.
Can you remember what it said?
That...
everyone would be better off if...
I wasn't here.
Had you heard the voice before?
Not a voice.
No, more of a...
a feeling, like a sinking feeling
in the pit of my stomach.
And when did that start?
A few months into the pregnancy.
This...
feeling that...
that she's doomed with me as her mom.
Did you share these concerns
with anyone?
Will.
He was really supportive
and patient.
And, of course, you know,
the feelings didn't go away.
No, they got worse.
I tried talking to my OB,
but she just said
it was the baby blues.
I'm sorry, Vivian.
Your feelings never should
have been discounted like that.
I wasn't trying to hurt my baby.
I-I swear.
I...
I thought
I was sparing her somehow.
I believe you.
I do.
Can I see her?
Can I see Cora, please?
I... I really need to make sure
that she's here.
You know what?
We, um... we will...
we will arrange a visit
as soon as we possibly can.
We tried to wake her up to
tell her it was time to go.
- She can hardly open her eyes.
- Stethoscope.
She just keeps falling back asleep.
And she's barely responding
when we call her name.
- Abby.
- Abby!
Abby.
Breathing's shallow. Abby.
Abby, wake up for me.
- Where am I?
- Abby, honey.
- Oh, Abby.
- Please open your eyes.
Doris, let's get a head CT stat
- and put her on a monitor.
- OK.
Head? You think there's
something wrong with her brain?
I thought you said
this was a stomach bug.
That was my belief, but now
she's had a change in mental status.
Why are you so behind
the eight ball here?
You were ready to discharge her,
and now she can't open her eyes.
Mr. Campbell,
I understand your frustration.
No, no, I don't think you do.
I want you off my daughter's case.
I want a different doctor.
Who do I speak to about that?
I'll, um...
I'll get Dr. Lenox.
OK?
You're done.
I don't get it.
She came in with stomach cramps
and vomiting.
Her ultrasound was normal.
Labs are normal.
And now it looks like
she might have stroked.
She's too young for that.
Did she appear jaundiced on intake?
Jaundiced? No.
And you checked her eyes too?
I would have noticed
if she was jaundiced, Hannah.
OK, I'm just trying to think
if there's any visual clues
you might have missed, you know?
You think I screwed up
because of last night?
Mitch.
I wouldn't be working
if I was in any way impaired.
- That's not what I'm saying.
- Look, I...
- It's not.
- I didn't miss anything.
All the puzzle pieces are there.
I just... they don't make sense.
OK.
Excuse me.
Dr. Lenox, hey.
Uh, did Abby's head CT come back yet?
I think it's best,
given the family's wishes,
if you step away from this.
Please.
Her head CT...
Completely normal.
What if it's meningitis?
It's my next thought as well.
I just talked to the family about an LP.
I'll keep you posted.
Thank you.
- Hey.
Figured I might run into you.
- Receipt in the bag?
- Yes, thank you.
So Dr. Tanaka-Reed asked me to consult
- on Rosie Peters' case.
- Why?
I thought it was just a sprain.
It is, but it has nothing
to do with her injury today.
- OK.
- Yeah.
So he noticed that Rosie
had recently had stitches.
Right. That's right.
She sustained a minor, just very minor,
fall at the residence,
and, uh, it was late.
Urgent care was closed,
so I just stitched her up.
You sutured her?
Yes, Dean.
I am board certified
in internal medicine.
I can suture.
Extraordinarily well, apparently.
There's no scar.
Look, I... I don't know
why you're involving
yourself in this.
You're lucky that I'm involved, Margo,
because if you had gone
to any other attending,
then you wouldn't have this
opportunity to explain
what the hell is going on here.
She had a slip up
a few weeks ago, all right?
It was during a particularly
stressful moment.
She took two Percocet,
and she was distraught.
She is subjected
regularly to drug testing,
and she was gonna lose her scholarship
- when she tested positive.
- Right.
So you falsified
the procedure to justify
the drugs in her system.
You have no idea
what losing that scholarship
would have done to Rosie.
It would have sent her into a spiral,
truly jeopardizing her sobriety.
It's funny because I distinctly
remember making a similar argument
to you when you fired my son.
So it's all about you, then?
Uh, that's not what I'm saying.
Oh, really?
Because it seems like the only reason
you're upset is because
I didn't break the rules
when you wanted me to.
Now you're twisting my words.
Look, Sean isn't a kid.
I gave him plenty of chances
to change his behavior,
more than I should have, frankly,
and that is because of you.
- Oh, is that right?
- Yep.
And you know what?
You want to report me to the
medical board, go right ahead.
All I ask is that you just
leave Rosie out of it.
I appreciate you seeing me
on such short notice
and making the trip to Med.
Well, I am mostly retired.
I haven't found a hobby yet,
so my time is predominantly free.
And Dr. Abrams mentioned that you were
at Stanford previously.
What brings you to Chicago?
I wanted to be closer to family.
Sam's my nephew.
He didn't mention it?
Uh, he did not, no.
Well, it's only by marriage.
So don't think less of me.
Well, enough chit chat.
So, what's going on?
Why did you seek out Sam's opinion?
Lately, my peripheral vision seems off.
Like, um,
I'm not seeing accurately.
A blind spot?
No, not exactly.
A distortion?
I guess.
Are you seeing something
that's not there?
Yes.
Um...
Are you familiar with what
happened to me recently?
I am, yes.
I'm seeing her.
Her?
My attacker.
Her name is Cassidy.
I'm seeing visions of her
whenever I'm in my office.
Does she say anything to you?
No, she hasn't.
She just watches me.
That is deeply unsettling.
I'm so sorry.
- Hey.
I was just visiting Vivian Tompkins,
and she said that she's been
asking to see her baby.
Yeah, she did.
Was there an issue when you called NICU?
Didn't call the NICU
because, unfortunately,
her husband has just filed an
order of emergency protection
- on behalf of the kid.
- That seems extreme.
I think, from his perspective,
what Vivian did was extreme.
Do you think she's a threat
to her baby still?
Because she's expressed nothing
but remorse and regret.
We can't really do
anything until a judge
makes a ruling, right?
Well, what if the court
rules in her husband's favor?
Then what? She just
never gets to see her child?
I really don't think
that that's gonna happen.
I hope not.
I just attempted to put a splint
on the displaced fracture in 5,
and the patient was in so much pain
that I had to stop.
I administered morphine
prior to you getting there.
2 milligrams.
I found this on the Mayo stand.
You gave a grown man a child's dose.
No wonder he was in pain.
No, that's impossible.
I know that I drew up
8 milligrams for Mr. Billings.
What?
- Oh, my God.
- Um... oh, my God.
I was supposed to give
2 milligrams of morphine
to Abby Campbell.
- You mixed up their orders?
- Um, I'm sorry.
I-I don't know what happened.
Well, that explains Abby's symptoms.
She's got morphine toxicity.
Tracy, prepare 0.25 milligrams Narcan
- and meet me in Treatment 3.
- Wait, no, no, no.
I'll do it. I can do it.
No, you won't. Take a walk.
- You're off the floor.
- Doris?
What happened?
Doris accidentally gave Abby Campbell
- 8 milligrams of morphine.
- Wait, what?
Dr. Lenox, that was obviously a mistake.
It was a never event,
as in it can never happen.
- Doris has to go.
- Wait. Wait a second.
No.
Either you fire her, or I'm
taking this up the chain.
I believe you're suffering from PTSI.
It's post-traumatic stress injury.
It's an anxiety response
that can develop after a trauma,
and I'd like to refer you to a colleague
for cognitive behavioral therapy.
Another referral?
Well, I don't do long-term therapy.
Well, I was hoping this wouldn't be
a long-term problem.
You've been through a terrible trauma,
and it's gonna take
some time to work through it
on the cognitive level.
But there must be something
that can help my brain along,
like medication.
Well, we can certainly discuss SSRIs,
but I'd like to temper
your expectations.
These visual intrusions,
they don't just disappear,
even with medication.
Thank you for your time.
Oh, but our time's not up yet.
I'm afraid I have a meeting
I have to get to.
I hope you understand.
Uh,
do with this what you will,
but in my experience, when you try
to run away from your demons,
they chase you.
It was lovely meeting you, Dr. Hess.
- Eleanor.
Margo, can I speak
with you for a minute?
Uh, yeah.
Hey, why don't you guys
wait for me in the lobby,
and I'll bring the car around, OK?
OK, so, uh...
I'm not gonna report you, obviously.
Oh, thank you.
Bringing Sean up
was not only unnecessary,
but it was irrelevant.
But if I make our whole breakup
about what you did, then I...
Oh, you didn't make
our breakup about anything.
I only realized that after the fact.
I'm sorry if I ghosted you.
You absolutely ghosted me.
Well, that was not my intention.
Well, then what was your intention?
To...
To pull away from you
before you pulled away from me.
That's... that's very
self-aware of you, Dean.
Yeah.
And that's not meant
to be an excuse, by the way.
Well, what is it meant to be?
An apology.
Well, I...
I appreciate that. I do.
All right.
So what are you doing later?
You want to maybe
take a walk by the river
and talk some more?
I mean, just as friends.
Oh, well, I think
I have enough friends.
Oh, I get it. Oh, I get it.
No, I got a handful friends,
and it's already way too much.
Well, um... yeah, I should get going.
- I don't want...
- Yeah, I get it.
- To keep Rosie waiting.
- All right.
- Bye, Dean.
- Bye, Margo.
Hannah and I just got off the phone
with Judge Minkowski,
who is the judge, you know,
assigned to Vivian's case.
We both advocated that she
should have supervised visits
with her daughter,
and given the time sensitivity,
she's gonna issue a ruling
by the end of the day,
or that's what she says.
You know, Vivian made
a terrible mistake.
She did, but I don't think
she should have to spend
the rest of her life paying for it.
Of course not. And neither should you.
Oh. I'm afraid I might.
Hey, look, just because Carl
is going for full custody
does not mean he's gonna get it.
He's gonna use my psych hold against me.
I know it.
He's already set up
a custody hearing for tomorrow.
And my lawyer...
I'm not confident in my lawyer.
You know what?
I want to set you up
with this guy, Larry Dale.
He's probably the best
family attorney in Chicago.
I can't afford the best anything.
Let me worry about that, OK?
Larry is a very soft touch with
friends and family discount,
not to mention I basically
put a wing on his house
with my troubles. So you know what?
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
That would be, um...
that would be amazing.
Look, man, I have, uh...
I've been where you are,
you know, like, a bunch.
It's just... it's really important
to just feel like you have
somebody in your corner.
You know?
You in here?
Hey.
We need to talk.
I know.
I could have seriously
hurt someone today.
You didn't.
That little girl's guzzling apple juice
and watching cartoons as we speak.
All of my years of nursing,
I have never made a mistake like that.
I know, Doris.
I know.
I just... I don't know what happened.
I do.
You're juggling too many patients.
And when you advised me
that you couldn't handle
any additional tasks, I...
I didn't listen.
Maggie, this is not on you.
It is. It is.
Listen,
I know you have to let me go.
I don't have to do anything.
What about Lenox?
Leave Lenox to me. OK?
So maintenance said it's not as big
- as your current office, but...
- No, it isn't.
You can't beat the location.
Of course, they'll clear all this out,
bring in your furniture,
hang your artwork.
Yeah, yeah.
And how long will it take?
They said it could be
move-in ready by Friday.
- Friday?
- Friday.
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
Sharon?
You OK?
I don't think this office will work.
Judge denied the husband's petition.
Yeah.
Vivian Corrigan will be allowed
supervised visits
while they're still in the hospital.
I'm so glad to hear that.
You know, maybe I'm being unfair,
but I just...
I just don't buy that no one
noticed she was in such a bad spot,
you know?
Not her friends, not her
husband, not her doctor?
I don't know.
I mean, human beings are
just endlessly inventive
in coming up with ways to not look
- at difficult stuff, right?
- Mm.
Yeah.
Dr. Lenox.
How'd it go with Doris?
If Doris goes, I go.
Excuse me?
Dolores Perez has been
a nurse at Gaffney
for over 15 years,
and she's been nominated
for the Daisy Award
for Excellence in Nursing
three times in a row.
I understand. Today was
a particularly stressful day.
It's not just today, Dr. Lenox.
My nurses are regularly missing breaks,
balancing unsafe
patient-to-nurse ratios,
and being asked to perform duties
that are outside of our job description.
Like restocking the Pyxis.
Like that.
Well, I certainly can't afford to lose
two senior members of
the nursing staff right now.
I didn't think so.
And beyond that,
the situation you're describing
is unsafe and untenable.
I'm giving my State of the ED
address to the board next week.
I'll make it a top action item.
What's an action item?
It's code for I will
hound you until it gets done.
So either agree to it now or...
Face the wrath of Lenox.
You'll be shocked to hear this,
but it's not a pleasant wrath.
Oh.
Come in.
- Hey.
Just wanted to let you know,
maintenance will have another office
for us to look at tomorrow.
You know, I think I'm gonna stay put.
I'm sorry you went to all that trouble.
There's no trouble.
And I hope you're not regretting
coming back to work for me.
Never, Sharon.
After everything that's happened,
it's just a real comfort
having you back with me.
Stop, stop, stop.
You're gonna make me emotional.
OK, well, I'm really glad
you're not moving,
'cause I always loved this office.
- Yeah.
- Me too.
All right.
- Well, I will see you tomorrow.
- OK.
- Have a good night.
- You too.
Hey.
So what's going on
with your patient's parents?
They gonna sue?
Surprisingly, no.
It turns out what they preach
in those legal meetings
is true.
You know, owning a mistake right away
and apologizing immediately,
it, uh, goes a long way.
Good.
On that note...
I'm sorry I made you worry last night.
And, um, that's the first thing
I should have said this morning.
Sorry if I got in your head today.
I didn't mean to do that,
make you second guess yourself.
How about a cozy night on the couch?
Take-out and reality television.
Tell you what, how about
you get things started?
I'm gonna grab a drink with the guys.
I won't be long.
What?
That's what you said last night.
Scout's honor.
And the night before that
and the night before that.
Didn't realize you were keeping count.
Trust me, I don't want to be, but...
But what?
I'm worried... maybe we should wait
until we get to my place to have this...
What are you worried
about, Hannah? Just say it.
I'm worried you're trying
to numb your grief.
With alcohol?
Look, I don't want you to go down...
I think you got us confused, Hannah.
That's your issue, not mine.
- Wow.
- I... I just mean that...
No, I know what you mean.
Do whatever you want tonight.
Yes?
- Hey.
- Hello.
I just wanted to grab the number of that
child custody attorney from you.
Already called him.
Yeah, he should be reaching out
by the end of the night.
Of course, you did that.
Hey, for the record,
I'm really glad to have you
- in my corner, Daniel.
- Oh, come on.
No, it means more than you know.
It's all gonna work out.
You're gonna really like this guy.
You're gonna love him,
as a matter of fact.
I bet.
Yeah.
OK.
Anyway, um, good night.
Good night.
- Hey!
- Hey.
You're up. Rip!
You're up.
Take my spot.
I'll join next game.
Come on. Where you going?
For a walk.
Watch where you're going.
Hey! Hey, you... you hear me?
- Hey.
- Yeah, I heard you.
And you got something to say?
- Leave it alone, man.
- No, no.
You ran into me.
Get out of my face.
Make me.
- Synced and corrected by synk -
- www.addic7ed.com -