Previously, on
The Good Doctor...
How hard can it be to just
act like a normal human being?
No!
Stop petting that stupid rabbit!
We're never going home again.
We have each other,
and that's all we need.
My brother went to
heaven in front of my eyes.
Never forget, you're the smart
one. And I'm proud of you, Shaun.
I can throw in the hanger as
well, but I wanna get you ordering.
I only have 560 of these.
- Dad?
- This is $10 off...
Hey! Penny. Hey.
I missed you, too.
No, Penny, come. Stay.
Hey, Dad.
Sorry it's so
early, I just landed.
Actually you're a bit late.
Five weeks.
I know. I know.
I'm sorry. It's... It's...
It's a long story, okay?
But how was it?
It was your mother's funeral.
Dad, I...
Okay. Well, you
have my cell number...
It only works if you answer it.
Dad?
Dad! Hey, hey.
Hey, are you okay? Are you okay?
You can't breathe? No? No. Okay.
I'm gonna call for help.
Hello, 911?
My dad collapsed. He
can't breathe. Please hurry.
Just hold on, Dad.
Good morning, everyone.
Right on time. What, did you sleep
here, or use a teleportation device?
I used a teleportation device.
Nonsensical questions
usually imply sarcasm,
which I've found people
often answer sarcastically.
Good one.
Trauma wants a consult
on a 66-year-old male
who collapsed from
severe anaphylaxis,
complicated by
respiratory arrest.
Now, his son just got
back from Thailand,
and almost immediately, the
father had his allergic reaction.
The patient has a few
allergies, pollen, mold, shellfish,
but no corresponding
allergens were in evidence.
Why are we doing a
surgical consult on an allergy?
No, we're not.
We're doing a consult
on the excruciating
abdominal pain he now has.
As you may have heard.
Mr. Wilks? Hi, I'm
Dr. Neil Melendez.
Heard you have
some abdominal pain.
The guy was in some serious pain,
10 milligrams of morphine worth.
Test results show elevated lipase,
amylase, pancreatic enzymes.
Pancreas is enlarged. Could be
pancreatitis, maybe alcohol-induced?
The son said he smelled alcohol
on his father at 6:00 in the morning.
And anaphylaxis has been known
to precipitate attacks of pancreatitis.
Guess that's it, then.
Meaning you totally disagree.
Not everyone who starts their day
off with a mimosa fries their pancreas.
Your eyesight must be a whole lot
better than mine, because I can't see
the entire pancreas due
to the overlying bowel gas.
We'll order an abdominal
CT and take a better look.
There you go.
Where the hell's Murphy?
It's a severe fracture, but I
don't think you'll need pins.
Young bones tend
to heal very well.
"Young Bones." Isn't that a
Star Trek: Origins graphic novel?
Hmm.
I'm not sure.
No, that was a joke.
Where are your parents?
They're coming. They
both work in the city,
so it's a long drive for them.
I was on a school field trip
when I tripped over my own feet.
Of course, it was right
in front of Shelby Lomar.
At least it was pretty gross, so I
got some sympathy points for that.
I would expect this to have been
caused by a more serious accident.
Nope, just a trip.
I do that a lot.
What can I say, I'm clumsy.
Yes, now follow my finger.
You have some nystagmus,
an involuntary eye movement.
So, what's that mean?
When you fell, did
you hit your head?
No. What, you think I
have brain damage?
Nystagmus can be a sign
of a neurological issue.
Oh. Well, that would explain
the "C" I got in social studies.
That was another
joke, wasn't it?
I'm going to order
a head CT for you.
Go for it.
Shaun, are you
getting any sleep?
Yes.
Really? I mean,
really getting sleep?
I got here on time.
Well, that's good.
I used a teleportation device.
Radiology form, please.
Shaun, that boy,
he looks like...
Steve. He does.
Is he related?
His name is Evan
Gallico, so I don't think so.
Wow. That is uncanny.
- Just coincidental.
- He looks exactly like your brother.
No, he doesn't.
His hair is shorter.
It freaks me out. It
doesn't freak you out?
- No.
- It's okay if it does.
No, he's not
Steve. Steve's dead.
"I used a teleportation
device" was a joke.
Yeah, that's... That's good.
So, I couldn't come to Mom's
funeral because I fell in love.
She was another teacher
at the school. A Thai woman.
And she was kind, and
beautiful, and loving,
and very, very sick.
She had a congenital
heart defect.
Look, if you don't wanna
tell me where you've been
for the last six months,
then don't, it's your business.
But don't insult
my intelligence.
Well, I couldn't just leave her.
You couldn't leave her for five
minutes to make a phone call?
This a bad time?
No, come in.
According to the CT, you
have a lesion on your pancreas.
Well, what do you think
this lesion could be?
We're not sure. That's
why we need to biopsy it.
It could just be a benign cyst.
Or?
Or
It could be cancer, right?
We'll know soon enough.
This won't take long.
I know, I've had two of these.
One more and I
get my Scout badge.
That was funny.
Tough to tell without looking at you,
but I'm guessing that was sarcasm.
No. I have autism, which makes
it hard for me to read social cues.
Jokes are difficult.
I used to know a kid
with autism. Peter.
He was kinda
weird, but super-nice.
Used to know?
You don't know him anymore?
He died. Hit by a car. You
know anyone who died?
My brother.
That sucks.
Why did you have
the other CT scans?
My parents have...
What's the word for
fear of getting sick?
Hypochondriasis.
No, worse than that.
They have nosophobia.
I love that word.
What do you think
of Ms. Gannett?
She's nice.
I think she's callipygian.
She's what?
Callipygian? It means "having
shapely buttocks," Shaun.
Duh.
You read the dictionary?
Where it lacks in plot,
it makes up for in vocab.
So, you married?
Girlfriend?
Boyfriend?
Tropical fish?
- I like Lea.
- Hmm.
And who's Lea?
Lea is a friend.
A friend you date?
A friend with benefits?
I lend her batteries sometimes.
I like where this is going.
So, you know, keep going
'cause if you don't, I will.
It's kinda my thing, you know?
Just constant talking.
It annoys everyone.
Murphy.
- Well, I guess not everyone.
- Hey.
- My family's pretty used to me...
My friends are pretty
talkative, as well, so...
You're giving the
fractured arm a head CT?
Yes.
Get back to the pancreas.
He's not clumsy. He has a
brain tumor behind the inner ear.
Forget the pancreas.
Mr. and Mrs. Gallico?
- Hi.
I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
I'm treating your son.
Well, how is he?
We were told it was a bad break,
but it should heal no problem.
I know why Evan tripped.
He has a tumor in the
temporal bone behind his left ear,
which is affecting his balance.
I've arranged for a consult
with Dr. Najid in
oncology, and she's going...
No, that won't be necessary.
We already have an oncologist.
Evan's been diagnosed
with stage-four osteosarcoma.
He was complaining
of a sore shin.
And the last thing that we
expected was bone cancer.
The doctors at SFM, they
gave him a year to live.
That was seven months ago.
Osteosarcoma explains
the severity of his fracture.
He will need pins
in his arm after all.
Can we see him?
Yes. He's in Room 414.
Dr. Murphy?
He doesn't know
about his diagnosis.
We would really like
to keep it that way.
He's the patient. Doesn't he
have the right to know the truth?
Well, no.
He's also a minor,
so, no, he doesn't.
Evan's very intelligent,
he'd be able to handle it.
Well, Shaun, maybe
it's not just about Evan,
maybe it's about
his parents as well.
Maybe it's just too difficult
for them to tell Evan
right now. I don't know.
Then they're the ones
who shouldn't be told.
Well, let me ask you this, Shaun.
What's so wrong about Evan
being allowed to enjoy as
much of his life as possible?
Evan wants to know the truth.
How do you know that?
If this were Steve, if
this were your brother,
would he wanna know the
truth? Is that what this is?
Dad's such a tool.
I found my birthday
present in their closet,
right where they always hide
it. I was just about to open it
when Dad caught me
snooping and freaked out.
I hate all that
phony surprise stuff.
It's an Aqua Blast Water Cannon.
I was with Mom
when she bought it.
Thank you, Shaun.
Your honesty's refreshing.
Yes, he would want
to know the truth.
Well, there's nothing
we can do about it.
It's not your decision,
it's theirs. He's their son.
Claire, I need you.
Sure, what's up?
I need someone to lie for me.
Okay.
I'm flattered?
Hey, Doc.
There's something I
need to tell my dad.
We haven't moved him.
He's still in room 326.
Do you have a medical
question for me?
Is he dying?
We don't know yet. The
biopsy will tell us more.
Okay.
My dad is a good guy.
We've just never been on
the same page, you know?
My mother was the
one that I could talk to.
Same for him.
So, without her,
we're both pretty useless.
Room 326.
Right.
Dr. Murphy called me
in for a second opinion.
You need some pins in your arm.
Why? What's changed?
Well, after studying
the radiology report,
given how bad the break is,
we just think it would be
a prudent step to ensure
an efficient and thorough
mending to the break.
Will I be able to
play baseball again?
Well, I don't see why not.
Once it's completely healed,
and after some physiotherapy.
How long before I can pitch?
It's hard to say.
He wanted someone
to lie for him.
And he picked you.
Merrill's son asked
for personal advice.
- And he picked you.
- I know, right?
He's lying to his
dad about something.
Yeah? What?
I don't know.
You didn't ask?
It didn't seem
relevant. Medically.
You know, it's not that
difficult to be a human being.
Just tell him to come clean.
Honesty's the best policy.
A lie is a stone in your heart.
Who said the last one?
- Me. I made it up.
- Huh.
And I got it.
He's anaphylactic.
Would you get me an epi?
- I'm coming out.
- His throat's constricting.
Pull the tube.
So, what's up with Dr. Browne?
She's Lea, isn't she?
Claire is my colleague.
Oh, come on, I saw the
way you were looking at her.
How?
I don't think I
looked like that.
Okay, so then why'd you
call her in for a consult?
Mmm...
Okay.
Yes, she's better at
talking to people than I am.
Wow, I counted,
like, 50 tells there.
- You really suck at lying.
- I know.
Too bad, it's an
important social skill.
So, how do you know when to lie?
When people need to know
things, they need to know.
If they don't, lie through your
teeth and feel good about it.
What if they need to know
the truth, but it'll hurt them?
Some can handle it, some can't.
So how do you know
who can and who can't?
You tell the truth.
If they like you after,
then you'll know.
If they don't, then it
doesn't really matter anyway.
You have cancer.
Yeah, I know.
My parents took
me in for a sore leg.
After a whole bunch of tests,
they talked to the doctor and
came out, told me I was fine.
That's it. Just "fine."
The next day, they
bought me a PS4.
So, I googled my symptoms
and I narrowed it down to
osteosarcoma or growing pains.
Kids don't get gaming
systems for growing pains.
Hey.
It's okay.
I'm not afraid to die.
You're not?
Well, I mean, the dying
part will suck if it hurts,
but I'm not afraid about
the actual death part.
Because you believe
you're going to heaven?
Because I don't.
If I believe in heaven,
then I gotta believe in God.
Then I gotta believe
God made me sick.
How messed up is that?
It's just easier to think
that it's all random,
and when it's over, it's just...
Over.
So, what about Lea?
Where'd you guys meet?
In the hallway.
- That's a beautiful story.
- Yes.
She's my neighbor.
Convenient.
He had another
allergic reaction.
The pancreas?
Merrill Wilks, yeah.
And the second attack was
even more severe than the first.
It coincided with biopsying
the pancreatic lesion,
which now appears was a cyst.
Well, now we know he's
allergic to whatever's in that cyst.
We also know that the next cyst
that pops will probably kill him.
Well, if there is a next.
Let's run a couple of tests,
see if there's any evidence of
parasites and MRI his entire body.
If we're lucky, he only had the
two cysts and he can go home.
Are you looking for loopholes?
Hoping to save Evan?
Everyone makes mistakes.
Which means you should
double-check every file in the hospital.
The oncologist flagged his
neutrophil count of 634 as low.
- That is low.
- Below normal.
I can still hear the
word "low" in there.
He's just a kid. I know how
hard it is to think of him dying.
He's okay with that.
I find that hard to believe.
We all die. If we accepted
that, we'd be happier.
Maybe, but we're not
good with contentment.
Fighting death is
what keeps us alive.
Okay.
We got a hit. Echinococcus.
Echinococcus? The cysts
are filled with tapeworms?
"Cysts?" There are more?
- Three more?
- Four more.
You missed the one in his brain.
- Dr. Glassman?
- Yeah.
You used to be a
neurosurgeon, right?
So they say.
Take this, will you?
I need one. Who'd you recommend?
What you got?
Wow, that's cool.
How the hell did I get
tapeworms in my head?
No idea, but you do.
You can pick up the eggs
from coyotes or wolves.
Have you been hanging
around coyotes or wolves?
I live in the suburbs, we
don't even have a petting zoo.
You might have had these
cysts for quite some time.
When one of them burst,
that's what caused
the first allergic reaction.
Well, why did it burst?
Why did it burst?
Any sudden movements,
twists, turn, squeeze.
- A hug?
- Could be.
But you weren't there
for the second one.
I punctured the cyst on your
pancreas during the biopsy.
As you've seen, allergic reactions
get worse each time they happen.
So, a third one,
that would be bad,
that would be... That
would be very bad.
So we're gonna have to surgically
remove all of the cysts intact.
Dr. Glassman's one of the most
highly-acclaimed neurosurgeons
in the state. You are
very lucky to have him.
And Dr. Kalu is fast becoming
a very accomplished flatterer.
The cranial cyst,
that is a big deal.
We're gonna have to take
off the top of your skull.
You'll be digging into my brain?
Well, yeah, pretty
much. With saline.
We use it to gently displace
the cyst, and then, puff.
It magically pops out. Kind
of like delivering a baby.
You know, if childbirth
were painless.
And then we move
on to the other cysts.
Hey, we're gonna
take good care of you.
Evan doesn't have cancer.
It might not be cancer.
Look at you on
time. Two for two.
It might not be cancer!
- The fractured arm?
- Yes.
You said he'd been diagnosed
with stage-four osteosarcoma.
Evan was diagnosed with
the flu eight months ago,
but his symptoms were actually
a better fit with Epstein-Barr virus,
which is linked to
Langerhans cell histiocytosis,
which causes osteolytic lesions in
the long bones of the upper limbs.
And those lesions could be
misdiagnosed as signs of osteosarcoma.
- Yes.
- What about his brain tumor?
Langerhans can also
manifest in the skull.
Instead of a death sentence,
he could have something
that could easily be
treated with prednisone?
Next, we need to do a
bone-marrow aspiration to confirm.
I assume you looked at his file?
For a very long time.
Well, there must've been a biopsy.
What did the pathology report say?
Yes, there were two biopsies,
both were positive for osteosarcoma.
Murphy.
They could be false-positives.
Do you have any idea how unlikely
it is to have two false-positives?
0.3%.
Which we can comfortably
round off to "not likely."
It is possible...
Yes, but it means telling the parents
of a dying child that there's hope,
when really, there isn't.
Grab a shower and
get ready for rounds.
Wow.
- Imaginative and creative.
- Yes.
What are the
chances you're right?
0.3%.
Well, 330-to-1.
333-to-1.
You really think that it's worth
putting Evan's parents through all this?
Of course. If we
did this 333 times,
we'd be giving false
hope to 332 people
for approximately four hours,
and we'd save one
life. Isn't that worth it?
Anyway, Dr. Melendez won't
let me ask for a consent to test.
What if I don't tell
them what I'm doing?
A blatant ethics violation,
that's your solution?
Yes. How do I do that?
Well, you do it, and then
you don't tell anyone. No one.
If anyone asks, your attending
noticed a low RBC count
and needed to find the
cause. That's it, no biggie.
Hmm.
You know Wilks' Grocery?
Santa Clara and 17th?
It's been an institution
for nearly 60 years.
My grandparents
started it in 1958,
and my wife and I
took it over in '82.
But when my wife got sick,
and I started talking to Kevin
about taking it
over, he just took off.
To him, it was just a place
to sell lettuce and toilet paper.
My father chairs a real-estate
development company in the UK.
Thought I'd be the perfect
person to set up the US office.
You wanted to be in
the helping profession?
I wanted to be in my profession.
It's not about how small
or how big the venture is,
it's about doing
something that's yours.
I guess.
When he was little,
we were inseparable.
He used to love to
come to the store.
To work.
I even had a little
apron made for him,
had his name on it, too.
Still, you know,
kids... Grow up.
I'm just grateful that he
stayed close to his mother.
He could talk to
her, tell her anything.
So could I.
And when she went,
I lost them both.
Looks like he's back now.
All I know is he ditched
me when I needed him.
Well, you know, as a
wise person once said,
"Holding a grudge is
a stone in your heart."
What's that for?
Local anesthetic for a
bone-marrow aspiration.
Why do I need a
bone-marrow aspiration?
My attending saw a low RBC
count and wants to find the cause.
No biggie.
"No biggie?"
You're lying.
What's going on?
You already told me I
have terminal cancer,
what's worse than that?
You might not.
Might not be osteosarcoma,
might be Langerhans cell
histiocytosis, which is treatable.
"Treatable?" As
in I might not die?
That's why I need to
aspirate, to find out for sure.
Do my parents know?
I was told not to
get their hopes up.
Then let's do it
before they get back.
Roll onto your side.
Is there a Scout
badge for aspirations?
I think someone
just made a joke.
- Hello.
- What are you doing?
Painkiller. My arm hurts.
That wouldn't explain why I'd
be injecting your lumbar region.
Okay.
Yes, hello. I think Evan may have
been misdiagnosed with cancer.
I think he has something
that creates bone lesions
that look like osteosarcoma.
It's a small chance,
0.3%, but I...
You... You told Evan
that he has cancer?
And now you are telling
him, and us, that he doesn't?
I'm telling you he might not.
That's why I need to
perform this aspiration.
He says whatever I
have might be treatable.
- Are you insane?
- No, I am not insane.
I thought you'd be happy!
There is a significant link between
Langerhans cell histiocytosis and...
Get out. Go. Get out.
Let me get you some water.
- Oh, my God.
- Dad's right here. Right here.
Respiratory, stat!
He has a massive embolus,
probably thrown from his fracture.
It's located at the bifurcation
of the pulmonary arteries.
He's close to
hemodynamic collapse.
Yeah, no kidding.
I'd like to assist.
Not a chance.
Okay. I'd like to assist.
You're obviously
too close to the case.
I think I'm just the
right amount of close.
Murphy, you lied to the parents
just so you could try to
prove your ridiculous theory.
You're too damn close.
Saddle embolism. Scrub in.
We have to get rid of the
embolus before he arrests.
His heart is barely
pumping blood.
I can feel the pulmonary artery,
I just need to find
the obstruction. There.
I got it. Knife.
EKG's showing right heart strain.
He can't take this much longer.
I know, but if I
move any quicker,
I could nick the left main
artery and kill the boy.
The phrase "no
biggie" gave me away.
You really gotta learn
how to lie, Shaun.
Am I in trouble?
Yes.
Unless you're right.
If I'm wrong, they
shouldn't be upset.
They know it's highly unlikely.
False hope, Shaun,
it's just plain cruel.
Hey. Did he talk to you?
Did you talk to him?
I don't know what to tell him.
You love your father, don't you?
Yeah, of course.
Right, well, he's about
to go into brain surgery.
There's huge risks
involved. Whatever this lie is,
can you live the rest of your
life knowing you kept it from him?
My... My girlfriend wasn't sick.
Okay? She dumped me.
She's married, with two kids,
had no intention of leaving them.
I... I was an idiot.
You got your heart broken.
That's the problem here?
No. No, Dad.
The problem is,
I didn't run away to Thailand because I
thought Wilks' Grocery was beneath me.
I was afraid that I would
never be able to fill your shoes.
And then I proved myself right.
Left pulmonary artery's
open. Ring forceps.
Ring forceps.
Come on.
Got it.
EKG is normalizing.
He's okay. Nice job.
All right, flush the left
pulmonary artery, close him up.
Okay.
Um, Dr. Melendez,
take a look at this.
Recycling, Shaun,
very responsible.
It's a book.
I appreciate that.
Thanks, Shaun.
Hey.
We got the embolism.
He's in recovery
and he's doing fine.
But, while we were in there,
we did find something else.
Lesions on his ribs.
Irrefutable proof
of osteosarcoma.
It's metastasized
to his chest cavity.
I'm sorry.
I'm very sorry.
Give that a nice,
warm, saline bath.
Forceps and Taylor
scissors, please.
- Forceps and scissors.
- Thank you.
Look at that.
That's what built the pyramids,
painted the Mona Lisa...
Invented the Internet.
And there is our interloper.
Squeezeball, please, Dietra.
"Squeezeball"?
His name for it, not ours.
The saline gently
displaces the cyst,
and will coax it out
of its little hiding place.
Hopefully in one piece,
so we don't have to call 911.
Come on now.
Tray, please.
There we go.
And you got it.
Got it.
He has his father's eyes.
That was incredible.
One down, three to go.
Hey, there he is.
Hi, sweetie.
What's the matter?
Nothing, we're just
happy. You did so great.
You had what's
called an embolism.
It clogged an
artery in your lungs,
but the good news is they got it
and you're gonna be just fine.
Hmm.
Still, too bad about
the cancer, huh?
No. No, no, no. The doctor did not
know what he was talking about...
Dad, I know all about it.
I have for a long time.
I am so sorry.
It's okay.
Because I'm not gonna be alone.
Grandma's gonna be there, too.
Auntie Arlene.
Uncle Jim, if he figured
out how to stop swearing.
I'll get you some water, buddy.
So, I took Penny for a
walk, just around the block.
And I picked her up some of
those rawhide treats, you know,
the ones that Mom
used to like to give to her.
I miss her, Dad.
Coast is clear?
Yes.
Thank you.
I was wrong.
You tried.
Your parents hate me.
I know.
I gave you false hope.
Yeah. But for a minute
there, it was pretty awesome.
I'm going to ask
you for a favor.
Well, I'm not giving
away my Make-A-Wish.
Would you mind if I
read you something?
It's not long.
That, I can do.
"Atticus was right.
"One time, he said you
never really know a man
"until you stand in his shoes
and walk around in them.
"Just standing on the
Radley porch was enough.
"The street lights were fuzzy
from the fine rain that was falling.
"As I made my way home..."
I can't protect you
from the course of a life
But you know me and
you know I was born to try
It's just the symptom of
the middle age of time...
"'... why he hadn't
done any of those things.
"'Atticus, he was real nice.'
"His hands were under my chin
"pulling up the cover,
tucking it around me.
"" Most people are, Scout,
when you finally see them.'
"He turned out the light
and went into Jem's room.
"He would be there all night,
"and he would be there when
Jem waked up in the morning."
Sounds like a good book.
I could've used a
spoiler alert, though.
No more fears, no more trials...
Thank you.
Confusing you from what you need
Every hand that you hold It
comes back though you know
That's all.
Every word, every lie
It comes back every time
Every time