Your kids, your keys,
your family photo album.
Little more suction.
Perfect. There it is.
Clipping the cystic duct.
It's the list you
repeat in your head
before you fall asleep.
I just went to prep Lizzie
Hagans for her biopsy,
and it was already
done. By you. At 5:00 a.m.
You're welcome.
I thought you were going to D.C.
I was, until Mr. Cordell got
septic from his gallstones.
Derek can wait.
Mr. Cordell can't.
Why is your
girlfriend stalking me?
It's the short list of things
you'd grab in case of disaster.
So apparently, Grey
starts morning pre-rounds
in the middle of the night now.
I've been here for hours.
The list makes
you feel in control.
What are we looking at?
I don't know. I'll
know when I see it.
Okay, now what am I looking at?
All of Grey's surgeries
since November.
At first, I thought
it was just a fluke.
My God. Is this right?
Your kids.
She hasn't lost
a single patient,
not one bad outcome
since November?
How is that possible?
She's on a streak.
Your keys.
It's time for rounds. Let's go.
Dude, Grey is
pitching a no-hitter.
She hasn't lost a single
patient since November.
What?
Your family photo album.
Whoa.
When the fire starts,
when the tsunami hits,
when the earth literally quakes,
do you remember your list?
Whoa! Watch the cabinet!
Somebody...
I got it! I got it!
Or do you just duck and cover?
You okay? We're okay.
Everybody okay?
We're not moving.
Yeah, safety feature.
It did this to me after
the last earthquake.
The last earthquake?
I did a lot of research about
Seattle before I moved out here.
Earthquakes were
never mentioned.
They don't happen too often.
Only when you ride in
elevators, apparently.
Apparently.
Remind me not to ride in
an elevator with you again.
Sure, Dr. Pierce, or I guess I
could just start taking the stairs.
It is Dr. Pierce, right?
Yeah, uh... Um...
Ethan.
Sorry. Ethan. Yeah.
Oncology, right?
Radiology.
Sorry.
No problem.
Ah. There we are. Oh. Yeah.
Anyway, see you around.
Yep.
My God!
You had to dive on top of me?
I was being your human
shield. I was protecting you.
Do I strike you as a woman
who needs protecting?
You're right. All right.
Next time, I'm gonna use
you as my human shield.
Oh, I should call
and check on Tuck.
Oh, you know who probably
felt it where she lives?
Hmm? Your sister.
Yeah, you should call
and see if she's okay.
I will call when I am ready.
I've asked you, Miranda.
Please, just let this rest.
Well, what about the
trans-family support group tonight,
the one I told you about?
You planning to go, or...
No. Why not?
Why is this any
of your business?
Why, indeed?
Miranda. Miranda!
Warren. There he is.
Hey, you feel that quake?
Yes. Yes, I did.
Exciting stuff, exciting stuff.
Almost as exciting as what I
have planned for you today.
Breast enhancements
and nose jobs.
You need to fix that attitude.
Today is all about instilling
self-confidence and changing lives.
So, you play your cards right,
you just might get an invite
from me to join the Plastics Posse.
You think that sounds cool?
I did not, at first,
but it grows on you.
Come on.
Two more on the way,
one adult male, blunt
abdominal trauma,
one minor with a
leg fracture post-fall.
Page Grey and Karev.
Right away.
Kepner, you're here.
I'm glad to see you back.
Yep, back and busy.
Here, you take bed eight.
I'm gonna head
over to five and six.
Grey Sloan Emergency.
I got a page? Bed seven.
Okay. Got it.
Did you need something else?
No, no. Bed eight.
I'm on my way.
Okay. Yes.
Yeah. MAN: You've
got more incoming?
I was paged about a hip? Yes.
Jean Dominy, 75, angioplasty
patient, discharged last week,
brought in today with
shortness of breath after a fall.
Well, I fell out of bed,
dear, onto my hip.
I'm pretty sure I
busted the damn thing.
You know, I had it
replaced 15 years ago.
Oh, wow. Okay, so the
earthquake threw you off balance?
Yes. Well, that and Herbert.
He lives down the hall.
I invited him over so I
could spit-shine his nine-iron.
His club, dears.
Oh, of course.
I mean, his penis, ooh...
Anyway, well, we
were having sex.
You know, vigorously,
legs up in the air. I mean...
Well, you know how
it goes. Mmm-hmm.
And then... Okay.
So, I'll just check off the
box for "sexually active."
Yeah. Oh, uh, yeah.
See, I have this book
with all the positions listed.
It is like a menu for
love-making. Really?
And, anyway, we
were trying number 28,
you know the... Uh-huh. Oh.
And then the earth
started shaking.
And I thought,
"Whoa, there is no
way that Herbert..."
Ow! Ooh. Hmm.
See, now, that's no good.
I'll never get to 29 if
I'm hurting like that.
You can fix it, right?
I'll tell you what. We're
gonna get you some films.
And then we'll go
from there, okay?
Okay. Okay.
14-year-old male, sustained
a non-displaced tib-fib fracture
secondary to a 14-foot
fall from a chair lift.
44-year-old male with
blunt abdominal trauma.
BP is 135 over 85, pulse 95.
So, you all were skiing
when the earthquake hit?
If only. Didn't even get a chance
to ski, thanks to the dweeb.
Danielle, be nice.
Edwards, set up
for a trauma panel
and an abdominal ultrasound.
On it. We were on the lift.
I was with Danielle.
Brian was with Micah.
Everything started
shaking, and they fell.
You mean, the dweeb
fell. Dad tried to stop him.
And he took my dad
down with him. Danielle!
You know, he shouldn't
have been up there.
He doesn't ski. He
didn't even want to go.
Okay, why don't you and your mom
go wait in the
waiting room, please?
She's not my mom. Yet.
We're engaged.
Brian thought we should
take a family ski trip.
Of course, we always
do what Brian wants to do.
Shut your face. Shut your face!
Why don't we all shut our faces
and let us figure out what's
wrong with you guys, okay?
Hey, we need to re-stock the
supply cart in trauma two right away.
Right away.
Hey, that kid in bed two's
ready to be discharged.
Ditto bed one, who
has hypochondria
and not a giant tumor
growing in her head.
Heard anything from
Herman? How's she doing?
Ooh, um...
"Enjoying blind institute. Learning
how to not bump into things.
"Not typing this, obvi.
Don't kill any babies."
Okay, well, she
sounds all right.
Is Somebody gonna
answer that call?
Not it. Yeah, no, all yours.
I'll page someone for you.
Thank you.
Grey Sloan Emergency.
Is this the hospital?
I need help.
Well, you need to
hang up and call 911.
I tried. It was busy.
My mom fell off a chair.
She's not moving. I don't
know what to do. What do I do?
Your what? Your
mom? How old are you?
I'm 11.
Where are you? Our
cabin. I don't know.
The power's out. Please help.
All right, it's all
right. Just hang on.
Somebody, Kepner,
get on with 911
and get them to trace the
call on line three right now.
It's a kid with her injured mom
in the mountains somewhere.
Go. Okay.
Are you still there?
I'm here. I'm right here.
What's your name?
Ruby.
Ruby, I'm Owen.
Are you a doctor? Can you help?
I can. I'm right here,
and I'm going to help you.
We were making S'mores.
She was getting hot
chocolate from the cabinet.
Watch your back.
Yes, it's a line coming
into Grey Sloan Memorial.
She was standing on the chair,
and then everything was shaking.
Then she fell. Now she's on the
floor. I can barely see anything.
She's on the floor. Is she
awake? No. What do I do?
Two hours! I waited two hours!
And now I still
can't leave because
somebody
double-parked behind me!
Quiet, please.
Don't you have
security here or a valet?
Listen, I'll find someone...
You better waive my co-pay!
He said, "Quiet!"
I'll get it. I'll help you.
Ruby, I am gonna
move to another phone
so I can hear you better.
Don't hang up. No, no, no.
I'm just moving to another
phone. I'll be right there, okay?
Okay?
Okay.
I always screw this up.
What?
No, no, no. No. Nothing.
Don't worry. I'll be
right back. Just hang on.
Where's that chest X-ray?
Move, move.
- Ruby, you still there?
- I'm here.
What's going on?
Okay.
Uh, is your mom breathing?
Yes, yes.
It sounds like she's snoring.
And what position is she in?
Is she on her side? Is she...
She's on her back.
She's just laying
there. 11-year-old kid,
her mom fell at a
vacation cabin somewhere.
Kepner's trying
to trace the call.
Ruby, I need you to hold the
phone to your mom's mouth, okay?
I need to listen. Okay.
An obstructed airway.
We need a trauma room.
This one's free, right?
No. No.
Occupied, apparently.
She needs to call
911 from a land line.
It's the only way the
EMS can trace her directly.
Ruby, listen to me.
What kind of phone
are you calling on?
If it is the phone in the cabin,
you need to hang
up and call 911.
No, that one's dead.
I'm on a cell, my mom's.
Cell won't work.
Crap. Okay, okay.
Her lips are blue. Why
are her lips turning blue?
Because your mom's
not getting enough air.
So, no go on the
open trauma room.
It's fine. These injuries
look pretty superficial.
You know, we would be
on the Wolf Run right now
if it was just you and me on the
trip, like it was supposed to be.
Dani, honey, this
is not Micah's fault.
It's not his fault he can't sit in
a chair? Because I think it is.
The kids don't get along.
Oh, you're kidding.
Karen and I got
engaged over the summer
after three years of dating.
I would have proposed
after the third date,
but the kids...
I thought, "Let's take a trip.
"Let's do something together
as a family, see if it might help."
I think I made it worse.
Do you think I made it worse?
Sometimes, adversity
can make a family stronger.
Or tear it apart.
I'm just saying, swap me out. I
want to be close to the good stuff.
Not that you're not the good
stuff, but she's got a streak going.
Stop saying that, and
definitely don't say it to Meredith,
unless you want it
to end. You'll jinx her.
Ow. That hurts?
I'm concerned about this
abdominal tenderness.
Schedule a CT and rush his labs.
So what, so you're not
gonna swap me out?
Never mind.
Could you go back one?
One more?
This one.
How soon can we do it?
Well... You know what?
We're not gonna schedule
the surgery quite yet.
But I want to do
it before summer.
Six weeks. Then
we'll all meet again.
We'll talk through our
options. Thanks for coming in.
Yeah, I don't get it.
Are we no longer
granting wishes today, or...
Did you see how she
looked to the boyfriend?
He's not here for support.
He's here for approval.
Six weeks.
That's how long it's
gonna take her to realize
that it's not her wish
that we'd be granting.
So, you're saying she
was being too hasty.
I'm saying I'm not giving
that girl a set of new breasts
that were never her
idea in the first place.
That's just a
bra full of regret.
All right, time to power up.
The Posse's got a big afternoon.
Ruby, open your mom's
mouth and take two fingers
and sweep the back
of your mom's throat,
like a scooping motion.
She might have something
blocking her airway.
Let's see if you can get it.
Okay, okay.
There's nothing. What now?
Try a Heimlich. Give a
hard push on your mom's...
Belly? I've seen it on
TV. How hard do I...
As hard as you can.
Nothing happened. Nothing...
Nothing came out. Her
breathing's getting worse.
Okay...
Okay, we're gonna try
opening her airway another way.
I need you to put your
hand under your mom's chin
and very gently lift it up.
No, wait, stop.
You'll paralyze her.
Hello? What should I do?
Hello?
So, the good news is,
your EKG and chest
films came back clear.
So, my ticker's good.
How about my kicker?
Well, you have what is called a
below-the-stem femur fracture.
Oopsy.
Now, you have two cracks in
the bone, one here and here.
So, how do we get me back
in the saddle? So to speak.
Well, I would like to
completely replace the hardware.
Now, it's a very big surgery,
and it does carry risks,
but you would come
out of it with full flexibility,
which I think is what...
So, I'd be good
to go on my back?
You should be.
Or on my side.
Or that thing, you know,
where you bend over
the couch and then he...
Like I said, full flexibility.
Yeah, okay, but considering
your cardiac history,
I'm not sure a big
surgery is a great idea.
Tell me, dear, have
you ever been married?
Are you seeing
anyone or getting laid?
Well, that's not... I mean...
You see, I was married to
my husband for 44 years.
That's 44 years
with the same man.
We had three children,
seven grandchildren,
and a lifetime of memories.
He was the first
man that I ever loved.
And he's the only
man that I ever will love.
But I'll be hot-damned
if he's going to be the only
man to ever razz my berries.
I mean, I have time left,
and there's still things
that I want to do, you know?
There's things
that I haven't done,
and there's a
whole lot of things
that, I mean, I didn't
even know you could do.
You know, like that thing
where you go... You know?
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Right, right, we got it.
Yeah.
I mean, what's
the point of living
if you can't try something new?
Hmm?
I want that surgery.
Sounds good.
That is a five-hour
surgery on a 75-year-old
who has a stent and
is on blood thinners.
I can't believe
you would suggest
a surgery like that to a patient
without running it by me first.
I'm sorry. You called
me for my opinion.
Look, I do hip
replacements all the time
on far older patients
with far weaker hearts.
She is clearly still active. I think
her heart's in pretty good shape.
That's not your call.
Okay, we are talking about a
healthy, vibrant woman here.
She deserves the best quality
of life that we can give her.
If she wants a new
hip, that's her call.
So she can get
laid? Really? Really?
You think that's
important enough
to risk her dying on the table?
If her hip is so damaged
that she winds up immobilized
and bed-ridden for the rest of
her life, then, yeah, I sure do,
because either way, she's dying.
Fine.
I will reevaluate the images
and take a closer look.
Maybe there's
another option. Okay?
Thank you.
Kepner told me
about the little girl.
What can I do?
Tell me, can I help?
We are trying to get an airway.
By risking paralysis.
I'd rather have her
paralyzed and alive
than dead with
respiratory arrest.
Do you have a better idea?
Hello? Are you still there?
Ruby. Go ahead.
Lift her chin and
pull it forward, gently.
Okay.
Okay, now put the phone
on your mom's chest, okay?
And let me listen.
The stridor's gone. She
opened the airway, but...
She still could be in distress.
It's something else.
Ruby, put your head
on your mom's chest
on the left side and listen.
I don't hear anything.
What am I listening for?
Breathing. Do you
hear her breathing?
No.
Owen. Owen.
Okay, okay, okay, Ruby,
now put your ear on
the right side and listen.
Anything?
Ruby?
She's breathing! I hear it!
Okay, could be a tension pneumo.
Ruby, now just push the
phone into your mom's chest,
right where you
were just listening.
Just push the
phone in and move it.
That's sub-Q air.
Do you hear that?
Mmm-hmm. She's gonna need...
She's gonna need to
release the trapped air
with a chest tube
or something. Okay.
It's the only way, or her
mom's gonna suffocate.
You mean... You're
gonna ask her to...
Okay. Ruby,
I'm gonna ask you to try
something. It's gonna be fine,
and I'm gonna walk you
through it, step by step, okay?
Okay, but can you tell me
fast? The phone keeps beeping.
I think it's running
out of battery.
What are you doing here?
I am hiding out.
We're waiting on the dad's labs,
but I couldn't sit there
and listen to those two
bite each other's
heads off anymore.
Me, neither.
Brian's labs came back
clear. How's Micah?
Looks like a grade four
splenic lac, possible rupture.
We need to prep him for ex-lap.
What? He's crashing.
Crap. Oh, crap!
His pressure's bottoming out.
Hurry up!
He's in v-fib. We
got to bag him.
One, two, three.
Easy.
Where is that crash
cart? I need those paddles.
Almost here.
There's no time.
Got a rhythm.
Edwards, you and Wilson
go and prep that OR, please.
Magical. Told you.
What?
Nothing.
Get going. Move.
Ruby, do you guys have
straws in the kitchen?
No. A pen, maybe?
A ballpoint pen?
Anything?
Not yet. Lines are down
because of the earthquake.
They're trying to triangulate
from the cell towers.
How's the mom?
Okay. Wait! Wait.
We got milkshakes on
the way here. Got a straw!
Great. Now, we're
gonna need you to get a...
What? What?
I don't want to
ask her to do this.
Ruby, we're gonna...
We're gonna need you to get a
knife. Not a big one, but a sharp...
You were making s'mores?
Are the skewers there?
Yes. Got one. Oh, God.
You want me to stick
this into her, don't you?
Ruby, you can do this. You can.
It's gonna help your mom, okay?
We just need you to find the...
Second intercostal. I don't
know how to explain that to her.
Wait, wait, wait.
Um, Ruby.
Okay, touch your
mom's left collarbone,
the one that looks like a
wing, coming out from her neck.
Now walk your
fingers down from it.
Two steps. You got it?
Okay. One. Two.
Stop. Stop.
Now slide your finger
right underneath that rib.
And with your other hand,
right above that finger,
push the skewer
in about an inch.
I can't do that.
Ruby, yes, you can.
What if we're
wrong? I'm not wrong.
Okay. Ruby, you can do this.
She could puncture
her heart. She won't.
Ruby, right now.
Oh, God.
Ruby, push. Hard.
Push hard. Push hard. Right now.
Oh, my God! There's blood!
She's bleeding!
It's okay. It's okay.
Now take the straw
and put it over the skewer
into the hole that you
just made and push hard.
She's breathing
a lot! You did it.
Thank God.
Wait, wait. She stopped.
Her lips are going blue again.
Ruby, put your fingers on
the right side of her neck,
right by her throat.
Do you feel a pulse?
No.
Okay.
Ruby, I need you to
get on top of your mom
and put your hands on her
chest and push hard right now.
Okay, I'm gonna teach
you how to do CPR.
All right, let's take a look.
Yikes. That hip took
a hell of a pounding.
Oh, Ethan, you have no idea.
Could you, please, zoom in
on the right femoral prosthesis?
Sure thing.
Twice in one day, Dr. Pierce.
Yeah. Careful, or
you'll get sick of me.
Unlikely.
Yeah, see that? There.
Her femur lateral to
the stem is cracked.
Her hip isn't gonna
resolve on its own.
She needs surgery.
Although, I guess the
femur fracture isn't displaced.
Maybe I could put in a
plate to bridge the fracture,
go in from the side. It
would be a little less invasive.
And less time in the OR?
A lot less, actually.
Good, so she could stay
on her blood thinners,
substantially lowering
the risk to her heart.
And she can get back
to getting her freak on.
I'll let her know.
I've been taking the
stairs, by the way.
Since this morning,
you know, just in case.
Oh, I wasn't serious
before. I was just...
Yeah, I know.
I'm not actually
taking the stairs.
Oh!
Okay.
I would like to take you
out, though, sometime.
Maybe for coffee,
or a drink, or...
The point is, I'm flexible.
This is coming out all wrong.
I'm gonna start
over. No, no, it's...
I'm gonna stop you, actually.
I'm sorry, Ethan.
You seem really...
Tall... Nice.
But, I'm just...
I'm not... I don't...
Sure. That's okay. I understand.
Okay.
This is basically my office,
so, if you're waiting for me to make
this less awkward by leaving, I...
Oh, right. Of course. Okay.
I'm gonna get out of here.
Take this with me. Bye.
Is Karen around?
She went to get
snacks. How's Micah?
Actually, we need
to talk to Karen.
Sorry. Legally, we can
only talk to the legal parent.
Are you serious?
Who cares?
Dani! What?
They didn't have turkey,
so I got a ham and Swiss.
Ugh, nast.
Lovely.
Really?
They have news on Micah.
Micah's stable,
but I'm afraid his injury
is worse than we thought.
His spleen is ruptured,
and he's lost a lot of blood.
He had a cardiac episode in
CT, and his heart stopped beating.
Oh, God.
But we're taking
him to surgery now.
We do have to remove his spleen.
My God.
What were we doing up there?
Why did I let you talk
us into that stupid ski trip?
Karen, come on.
It was an accident.
But he didn't want to go.
There was an earthquake.
Karen, come on. For
god's sake, this is...
I didn't plan on any...
Okay, so we will
give you an update
as soon as Micah
is out of surgery.
He's 14. He's 14!
This couple might be the
biggest casualty of the earthquake.
Oh, my God!
Ruby, you're doing great.
My battery's at five
percent. I'm getting tired.
You can do this.
Just keep pushing.
Push, push, push, over and
over, like the beat of a song.
Ruby, do you know
the song Stayin' Alive?
Is it new?
We'll sing it for you, okay?
And you just... You push
to the beat, just like this...
Okay, Ruby, you sing
now. You sing with us.
They found the region.
Ruby, did you hear that?
Help is on their way.
They're gonna find you.
Some of the roads are blocked.
They're sending a helicopter in,
but they don't know
how long it will take.
Okay, Ruby, you just keep
going until they find you, okay?
You keep singing,
and you keep pushing.
And when they find you, use
their phone and you call me back.
Okay.
Ruby?
She's gone.
They'll find her. She'll
call. They'll find her.
Yeah, she could be
on her way in right now.
Unless she's alone in a
cabin with her dead mother.
She'll call.
Anything?
Did you hear the
mom going at that guy?
That couple is
doomed, all that fighting.
I do not miss that.
Look at us, we're both in
adult, stable relationships.
For once, we're on the
healthy side of things.
Sure.
I had to cancel
D.C., but it's okay.
Sometimes he cancels,
and I say it's okay.
We're happy. We're in a groove.
Kind of sounds like a rut.
We are not in a rut.
Whatever.
I resent you saying it.
Okay.
And you're hardly an expert
at long-term relationships.
Really? And
that's not even true.
What? Izzie?
That was a cancer marriage
that lasted five minutes.
And then there was Ava,
who peed on my couch.
All right, would
you quit it? No,
there's one more I'm forgetting.
Hello? I'm right here.
Oh, I know. The
nurse who had syph.
As in syphilis?
It was a long time
ago, Wilson. Relax.
Bovie.
It's not a rut.
I have an entire world to
manage, all on my own.
My world does not and should
not revolve around Derek Shepherd.
I wanted to go to
D.C. this weekend,
but I'm a busy surgeon
with two kids at home,
and he's at the NIH.
So right now, we're just
going to have to accept
that this is the
way our lives work.
But that doesn't
mean we're not happy.
All right, fine. You
have a happy marriage.
With no husband in it.
All right, plate's in position.
I'll be placing the screws next.
Her pressure's good.
Rhythm's stable.
So, you and Ethan.
Is that a thing?
No. I'm not... No,
he's not my type.
Sure. Right.
You're not so into
cute, smart, or funny?
No, he is. I mean, he's great.
He's a radiologist.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Did you
just go all upstairs-downstairs?
No. No!
No, I didn't mean it like that.
No, I just... I
don't date at work.
Or you don't date down
at work. No, no, it's cool.
Don't worry. I'm sure you
have many other fine qualities.
It's okay if you're
kind of a snob.
I am not a... God, you
make me sound awful.
"Dating down?"
What is that even?
I just don't date
people who are...
Beneath you?
No, that is not what
I was going to say.
Underlings?
No, stop it. I
wasn't gonna say...
Just a lowly maker
of X-rays, madam.
I didn't mean to...
Will you stop it?
And we'll use the rasp
to smooth out the bridge.
You know, Mrs.
Thurman could come out
looking like a completely
different person.
So that she can be happy
with what she sees in the mirror.
But what if it's not her nose
that makes her unhappy?
I mean, maybe it's
some other part of her life,
like that patient with
her boyfriend's boobs.
How can you be sure that
she's making the right choice?
You do realize I
can't talk to you
about your sister's case, right?
I'm not asking about
my sister's case.
I'm asking about
this lady right here.
All right, well, I know she's
making the right choice
because I talked to her
at length, and I listened.
And I've gotten very
good at knowing.
44-year-old
female, vitals stable,
tension pneumo relieved
by a needle thoracostomy.
Is she okay? Is she...
Trauma from the fall.
Her pupils are fully
responsive. GCS of eight.
Yeah, I got this.
Ruby?
Hey.
My phone died,
but I kept singing till they
came, just like you said.
I know. I know.
You did great. You were perfect.
You're okay.
How is she?
Subdural hematoma with a shift.
What can I tell Ruby?
Nothing. Not yet.
Heart rate's dropping. Damn it.
Drill, now.
I need to evacuate this clot.
What can I do? Let me help.
Let me work.
Mrs. Thurman's awake.
Good.
She looks like she's
been in a bar fight,
and she says she can't wait
to see what she looks like
when the swelling goes down.
What else?
Nothing.
It's a big change.
She's had that nose
for plenty of years.
I just... I hope she
doesn't regret it.
It was not a new thing,
this change that she wanted.
It wasn't a whim.
It was how she had
always seen herself.
Her best version of her.
The one that was the most true.
Now, with a
patient like this one,
a patient who's dreamt
about these changes
since they were six years old,
those patients do
not change their mind.
For them, change isn't elective.
It's not a choice.
It's a chance.
It is her chance.
And you can't know
that without talking.
And listening.
It's not because
he's a radiologist.
Okay, and it's not just because
I don't date people from work.
I just... I kind of don't date.
Hey, listen. I was just
giving you a hard time.
No, no, no. I didn't...
There's a gap between
me and most people.
There just always has been.
I used to think it was because
I was younger in school,
but even after school...
The gap, it just got bigger
and more impossible.
I wasn't too young.
I was just too...
Different.
So, I know what it looks
like when I say yes to Ethan.
It's fun, and we're happy
for a while until it's not.
Things always get
awkward and weird.
So, I overcorrect,
or he misinterprets.
And then we're not on
the same page anymore
because we never
were on the same page.
We were always miles and miles
apart with this gap between us,
pretending it wasn't there.
I don't want to pretend.
I came here to work and
just stay focused on that,
and I'm fine on
my side of the gap.
I'm a little lonely, but fine.
There's just no point
to me saying yes.
Yeah.
Okay, that's a load of crap.
When you were younger,
fine. Kids are weird. But now?
You're a grown-up
doing your grown-up
job with other grown-ups.
There's no gap. And
there's nothing to lose.
There's just you being scared.
And for no reason.
So choose not to be.
Life's too short to be
scared. Screw the gap.
Let Ethan, I don't
know, razz your berries.
Ew!
Okay, goose your gander. Okay.
Tickle your tail feathers.
Cup your coconuts. Nope.
Rock your rump.
Poke your hontas.
Wallop your wonderland!
There's still bleeding from
the short gastric arteries.
I see it.
Close to the pancreas. I see it!
Well, I can't get
to it from here.
How many units did
he use? Four units.
If everyone would just shut up
and give me two freaking seconds,
I can get this suture to hold.
There. Edwards?
No leaks. Looks good.
The streak's alive.
What was that, Wilson?
No.
Wait, nothing. I
didn't say anything.
You said, "The streak is alive."
No! No, I said, "Freak." I
said, "The freak is alive."
No, you didn't. No, she didn't.
I didn't hear anything. I...
You're pitching a no-hitter.
You haven't lost a single
patient since November 14th.
Eighty-nine surgeries in
a row with good outcomes.
Did you say November 14th?
Yeah, and 22 were traumas.
I mean, who does that?
You, because you're magic.
Edwards, you can
close. Wilson can assist.
What did I tell you?
Look, I told her
not to tell you.
This kind of thing
messes with your head.
I'm on a streak.
There's no such thing.
It's just dumb luck.
Look, you're not that great,
anyway, so just forget about it.
No, no, no, it's not that.
It's the date that it started.
What about it?
That's the day that Derek left.
And I've been perfect ever
since, have not lost one patient,
not one, since the day he left.
What does that tell
you? That you're right?
That I'm better off without him?
Brian, your repeat
labs look really good.
I should be able to
discharge you very soon.
How's Micah?
Not my kid. I know.
Karen won't even
speak to me right now,
and, you know, I had
all the best intentions.
I was trying to bring
the family together.
I thought I was helping us.
It all backfired.
Maybe, now, we're too far gone.
Maybe I can't get Karen back.
Maybe Danielle is right.
Maybe Karen and Micah
are better off without me.
All I wanted was for us
to be happy, be a family.
Can you just nod or blink twice
or something if Micah's okay?
Thank you, Dr. Grey. Thank you.
You know, you should try and
close your eyes, get some sleep.
It could still be a while.
Do you think I hurt her?
No. No. Ruby, you
did everything right.
You don't know that.
How is she?
She's fine. Ruby, your
mom is gonna be fine.
Really?
Absolutely.
So, I called my
sister and checked in.
A bookcase fell. But
other than that, she's fine.
Good. Okay.
I owe you an apology
for what I said earlier.
Yes, you do.
And I will consider accepting
your apology, Ben Warren,
if you make it up
to me. At home.
You can start by
making me dinner.
And then some other things
that I haven't even thought of yet.
Well, you know
I'm still on call.
I can wait.
Six weeks, right?
Eight, just to be
sure. Ease back in.
Herbert isn't gonna
know what hit him.
Or Edward. Or Irving.
Or maybe that guy
upstairs with the bad toupee.
They're lucky guys. Mmm-hmm.
I'm telling you, girls.
You have healthy hips.
Put them to good use.
Hold that! Wait, please!
Hi. I will have
that drink with you.
If you want to, if
you still want to.
Great. Let's do it.
Wait. Now?
Do you mean now? No.
Yes? I don't know.
End of the week?
Yes.
Thank you. For today.
You're welcome.
Mmm.
So my streak lives on?
Sure. If you
believe in that stuff.
You're right. I
don't need Derek.
I don't need him in my house.
I obviously don't need him
to prove I can have 89
good outcomes in a row.
I'm doing great.
My kids are happy.
My career is soaring.
Derek going to D.C. did exactly
what it was supposed to do,
which is remind me of who
I am outside of my marriage,
which, by the way,
I'm kind of amazing.
Okay.
But that doesn't mean that I
don't want to share it with him.
I want to tell him that I'm...
We're on a streak.
I can handle Micah's
post-op if you want to take off.
That list of things
you'd grab in a disaster.
Hello?
Hi. Is he in the lab?
What?
I know this is Derek
Shepherd's phone.
Who is this?
Your kids, your keys,
your family photo album.
Who is this?
That list goes out the window.
Hello?
When the disaster
starts with you wondering
if this must be the woman who's
been screwing your husband.
That's a whole other earthquake.