Dr. Kovac.
We couldn't find the left arm.
BP's 100/60. WOMAN: Pulse 120.
Okay. Sir!
Sir, you're gonna
have to settle down!
Settle down!
Fluids in the field?
Bolused a liter of saline
and gave him 10 of morphine.
Okay, now...
get another IV going.
Pre-op labs, serial crits,
type and cross times four.
Who's on for Trauma?
Benton's on at 7.
Okay, see if he is here yet.
I don't have a hand!
Where's my hand?!
Titrate another 10 of morphine.
Sir, you've gotta calm down!
Oh, man, that's gotta hurt.
I... I don't have a hand!
Not gonna be
playing the flute again.
That bastard shot me!
With what? A howitzer?
Shotgun, point-blank range.
Page Ortho. Get an O.R.
I need my hand! I need my hand!
Found it, but I don't know
what you're gonna sew it to.
Sir, settle down. BENTON:
Get some restraints.
Out on the corner, 6:30
in the morning, selling rock.
You've got a regular
pharmacy, don't you?
My... My hand!
And a gun.
Selling drugs is dangerous.
Malucci, get over here.
Do you have this now?
Yeah, go.
All right. Deflate the BP cuff.
I had a tough week with my kid.
He's 14, and he's
been getting high.
It's tough for me
to lecture him.
He knows I'm sober now,
but it was only two years
ago I was high all the time.
Now when I try to talk to
him, he just walks away
or he screams at me.
Tells me I have no right
to talk to him about it.
I think he's probably
right, you know,
after all I put them through.
Hey, I got the perfect
plan for killing off Romano.
We wrap the hand around
the gun, pull the trigger,
it's got this guy's
prints on it. Huh?
Put down the hand, Malucci.
When do we get another
opportunity like this?
Put down the damn hand.
Listen, when there's
a patient on the table,
I want respect, all right?
Respect for the patient
and respect for me.
Respect for a
drug-dealing banger?
The only thing I wanna
hear from you is the medicine.
You say so, Pete.
When you're addressing me,
it's "Yes, Dr. Benton.
No, Dr. Benton."
Are we clear?
Hey, Brian. Sign my card?
Yeah.
There you go. Thanks.
You were doing a crossword.
I was listening.
You know, this isn't
my first meeting.
I had months of this in rehab.
When's the last time you shared?
I'll get up tomorrow.
There are other meetings.
No, you're right.
I'll share tomorrow.
I used to go to one
at Saint Michael's.
It seemed like it
had more addicts.
I like this one.
It's convenient.
I thought you might feel more
comfortable around NA people.
I go to meetings,
I take my meds,
I pee in cups when
they ask me to.
If you want me to get up
and share, I'll do that too.
I'll do it tomorrow.
Hey. Hi.
Busy night? Mmm. Not bad.
Any messy leftovers?
Well, there's a hypersexual
dementia guy in Curtain 3.
He's fast.
Thanks for the warning.
Hey, uh, you and
Kovac still going out?
Not many secrets down here, huh?
No.
Is he doing okay?
It's just he seems a little off.
I'm sure he's fine.
Good. See you later.
Bye.
I always hate
mornings like this.
Good and slow. Just
the way I like 'em.
Calm before the storm?
Always means it'll get crazy
before the end of your shift.
Hey, Frank. Call Security.
Mike passed out in
the linen room again.
Mad Mike? He's back?
Back and unbelievably stinky.
No need for Security.
I threw him out of
there twice yesterday.
And tell Housekeeping to
keep that damn door locked.
Frank, what do you got?
Ah, a little homeless helper.
Just speeds things along.
Give me that.
I'm not gonna hit him.
Give me it.
Kerry, remember
I'm off today at 6.
How could I forget? You
mentioned it three times.
Well, uh, actually
just two, counting now.
Cutting school early
today, Dr. Greene?
It's on the schedule.
Going to a professional
conference, I hope.
No, a personal one.
Oh, you and Lizzie going off
somewhere romantic again?
I put in the request weeks ago.
No doubt.
Frank, those films
back on my elbow lac?
Wha...? Where's Frank?
Out harassing the homeless.
What?
Old cop habits
are hard to break.
Good morning.
Hi.
You wanna get some lunch?
Kerry, paramedics
have a 13-year-old.
Fell on her way to
school. Two minutes out.
Okay. Luka, you take
it. Chuny, go with him.
Sure.
Lunch?
Yeah, sure.
If there's time.
Abby, page Corday.
She might have a
herniated disk in 3.
Kerry? Yeah, I know. Six.
I should have grabbed a coat.
It's gonna be snowing
again before you know it.
Excuse me. Hi.
Is this the way to the
ER? I'm just a little lost.
This is the ambulance entrance.
Walk-ins are in front. Oh.
Thirteen-year-old
girl, ground-level fall,
oriented times three, no LOC.
- I'm okay.
School wouldn't let her back
until she got checked out.
I'm fine, Dad. Really.
What's her name?
Teresa.
Did you pass out when you fell?
No. Around the front, ma'am.
No, no. It's all right.
Authorized personnel only.
My daughter works here.
Excuse me. Hi. Hi.
I'm Maggie. You are?
Uh, Chuny. Your
daughter works in the ER?
Yes, she's a doctor.
Frank, can you
help this lady? Yeah.
Chuny, come back
later. I've got bagels.
Okay.
I've got lots of 'em.
Catch you sleeping there again,
I'll chain cinder
blocks to your legs
and toss your worthless
carcass off Navy Pier!
Do you have any pain?
No, please, I just
wanna go back to school.
Let the doctor check
you out. She loves school.
What grade are you in?
Seventh. I'm missing a test.
Yeah. CBC, Chem-7 and UA.
Is there something
wrong with her neck?
Just a precaution.
She has some pain,
but it's probably nothing.
Okay. This is gonna
take a few minutes.
Mr. Ruiz, why don't
you get a cup of coffee?
I wanna stay with my daughter.
You can come right back.
Deborah, will you show Mr. Ruiz
where the coffee machines are?
This way, sir.
Honey, I'll be back in a minute.
Sir.
Any chance you're pregnant
before I get an x-ray?
No.
Do you have anyone
you'd like to designate
as the adoptive parents?
I need to find someone
to adopt my child?
No, but a lot of women
already have someone in mind.
Uh, a family member,
an acquaintance.
No. No one.
Can I be candid?
In my experience,
it's very unusual
for a woman of Asian descent
to offer a child
up for adoption.
We've found that
most Asian women
end up changing their minds.
Oftentimes at the last minute.
Did you bring me out
here just to make sure
I wouldn't change my mind?
Lots of women never
make it past this bench.
I can't keep this child.
Have you discussed
adoption with your family?
No. You really should.
And what about the father?
Is he prepared to sign
away his parental rights?
Does he know you're pregnant?
Well, he may want
to keep the baby.
What if I don't want him to?
He's the father. He has rights.
Hi. Hi.
Can I, uh, help you?
I'm making a fresh
pot. Be ready in a sec.
It's Kenyan,
fresh-ground. Smell that.
Excuse me. Excuse
me, who are you?
Lord!
Maggie Wyczenski.
You want a bagel?
I've got lots of bagels.
Let's see, what kind would
you like here? Any kind.
No, no, it's not
ready yet. In a minute.
This area's for ER staff.
Bagel? Yeah.
Sesame? The area is for staff.
No. Raisin. You got raisin?
Malik, go. Get out of here.
Excuse me, you are not
supposed to be in here.
Now, it's fine. Really.
My daughter's a doctor
here. Abby Wyczenski...
Uh, no. Lockhart, actually.
Abby Lockhart.
I just heard this loud pop.
How would you describe
the pain, Mr. Patterson?
Al, please.
Is the pain sharp or dull, Al?
Well, it's a bit of
a bastard, really.
It's like a burning
down my right leg.
Mm-hm. Any numbness?
Yeah, a bit.
What were you doing
when you heard the pop?
Surfing.
I know I'm a bit old for it,
but I've been
surfing all my life.
Is this tender?
Oh, yes. Very.
Oh, it's hard to give it up.
Have you ever
paddled out yourself?
Can't say I have.
You were surfing Lake Michigan?
No. Kauai. That's,
uh, where I live.
I'm in town for the, uh,
sportswear convention.
Plane trip nearly
killed me with this back.
Will you get me a
safety pin, Abby?
That's London, is it?
Just trying to pick...
Pick the accent.
Sussex. I went to London
for university. Yours?
Zambia. Born and raised.
My father was a doctor.
You're gonna feel a
couple of pinpricks.
Tell me if they feel the same.
Abby. Yeah?
Your mother's here.
Duller on the right
than on the left.
Your mother. She's out front.
Pull on my hand
with your right foot.
No, she's not.
Nice lady. Kind of a looker.
My mother's in
Florida. Maybe she was.
Right now she's serving
breakfast out of Admit.
Doesn't seem to know
you're back to nursing.
You two don't stay in
touch much, I guess.
You know, he's
flying in the air...
That's not my mother.
Ooh, yeah.
Like, 65 miles
an hour. And the...
I have no idea
who that woman is.
So I'm walking down
the aisle like this...
Looks clear. Okay, Teresa.
Now this terrible
thing can come off.
So she's okay. Can we go?
Her neck is fine,
but I need to do a
complete neurological exam.
Well, how long is
that gonna take?
I gotta get back to work.
It may take a few hours.
I'm sorry, Daddy.
Forget about it.
I gotta call them. Is
there a phone around?
Pay phone in the waiting area.
I need to examine your face.
Any pain here?
No.
Here? It doesn't hurt anymore.
You worried about your father?
I'm sure he wants us to be
certain that you're all right.
Will you stand up, please?
Okay, now lift your arms
up, keeping your eyes shut.
Higher?
No, that's fine.
Keep your eyes
closed for a little longer.
All right, final calls.
Everybody finished
with these bagels here?
Wait, wait. There's still some
fresh-squeezed orange juice.
Fresh-squeezed?
Yes, fresh-squeezed.
Think I'd use that
concentrate? There you go.
Try that. Thank you.
Frank?
How much longer do you
think my daughter will be?
I don't know. I...
I think she's still
with a patient.
All right.
She'll be out as
soon as she can.
I'll be over here.
May I? Yes. Eat up.
Thank you.
Who's that?
Some nut job, claims
she's Abby's mom.
Weaver called Psych.
No kidding? Nice legs, huh?
Mmm. Mother-daughter
fantasies come instantly to mind.
Dr. Malucci, I think we have
patients needing your attention.
Actually, chief, we don't.
Rescue 54 is two minutes
out. GSW to the chest.
There. Now you're busy.
Gunshot wound. Yes!
Not on your own.
I can handle it.
Where's Benton?
Surgery. Corday's around...
Okay, find her. Go.
I'm ordering a CT on a
girl while I call the police.
Head trauma?
No. I'm just stalling for time.
I think her father's
abusing her,
and he wants to take her home.
Okay, send her up.
When the cops show,
cancel the procedure.
Okay. Still no Psych?
I could page 'em again.
Abby has no idea who she is?
Said she'd never
seen her before.
Hi. Hi.
Well, I think the
bagels were a hit.
Everybody loved them.
I put everything in bags.
I put it in the refrigerator.
Great. Go in there whenever.
Can you stop for one minute?
There was a lot of
leftovers in there.
I took them all out
and threw them away.
You can't leave that...
Can I talk to you
for just a minute?
Oh, my God.
Look how pretty you are.
You have a beautiful face.
Just pick your
hair back a little bit.
Maggie, I need you to
stay in our waiting area.
Could I work on you?
That's what I do...
I can't have you
back here by yourself.
I'm an artist. I do
collages and things.
But I do makeovers
to make money.
I could make you over.
I cannot have you
back here by yourself.
I'm waiting for Abby.
Okay. It's just right
across the hall.
There are sick people
there. Maggie, the thing is,
Abby says that you
are not her mother.
Of course I'm her mother.
You know, why don't we
gather up your things...
No, wait. Wait. Wait. Wait.
So she...
She... She said she's
not my daughter?
Please, let's go.
No!
Where is she? Abby!
Damn it! Damn it! Maggie?
Abby! Abby, where are you?!
Maggie, take it easy.
Abby, it's your mother!
Maggie, it's all right.
Abby!
Maggie, you cannot
go back there!
Abby! Frank, call Security!
Get Psych down here now!
Abby!
God, please pick
up. Please pick up.
This is Eric. Leave a
message after the beep.
Eric, if you're there, could
you pick up the phone, please?
It's Abby. Eric? Hello? Hello?
Okay. Eric, Mom is in Chicago.
What the hell is she
doing in Chicago?
Because I can't... I
can't take her now.
Okay? She can't be here. I...
Well, Al, I'm afraid
you've herniated a disk.
That doesn't sound too good.
With the weakness in your foot
you'll need surgery to eliminate
the pressure on your nerve.
Can it wait till I get home?
I wouldn't suggest it.
I don't want back surgery.
Then I'd recommend
an outpatient procedure.
Endoscopic surgery.
And how long will that take?
An hour.
I'd insert a small endoscope
into your spinal column
and remove fragments
of the herniated disk.
Couple of stitches
and a Band-Aid.
Dr. Corday, got a
GSW to the chest.
Benton's still upstairs.
Okay.
Will I be able to surf again?
I don't see why not.
If you'll excuse me...
Call the O.R.
Book a room for an
endoscopic discectomy.
Abby! Abby! Abby Lockhart! Abby!
Maggie! Maggie.
Maggie, calm down.
What the hell is all that about?
Abby! Abby!
You need to calm down.
Abby!
Calm down, ma'am. Abby!
Somebody... No, there's...
Hey, I think
someone's calling you.
Abby! Abby!
Is there someone we can call...?
Maggie! Maggie! You
need to calm down.
Have a seat, ma'am.
Calm down.
Have a seat.
All right. All right.
Take a breath.
Okay. All right.
All right. I'm fine.
Abby!
Abby.
There she is.
That's my daughter.
Hi, Mom.
Abdomen's soft. No rebound.
Please! I don't wanna die!
Hey, hey, partner, pipe down.
I can barely hear anything.
Decreased breath
sounds on the left.
Trachea midline.
Trauma panel,
O-neg, cross times 10.
He needs a chest tube.
Mother, may I? Huh? Chest tube?
Step in.
Look at you. Look at you.
You're still so pretty.
What are you doing here, Maggie?
Came to see you.
How'd you get here? On the bus.
I came on the bus.
Does Eric know where you are?
Oh, you know how busy
your brother always is.
So you just left?
And... And you didn't call.
Why...? Why didn't you call
me and tell me you were coming?
I was worried about you.
I heard about you
and Richard separating.
A year ago. I...
Yeah. I'm divorced.
Oh, my God.
What about your job?
The department store.
My daughter is more
important than any stupid job.
Oh, you know what? I left
all my stuff in the coffee room.
I'm gonna go get it. And
you and I are gonna talk.
I'm working.
I know. I know. I know. I know.
But I'm gonna wait for you.
And we're gonna
talk. I'll be back.
Frank said that you
said you didn't know her.
How long has she been bipolar?
Since I was a kid.
And she's off her meds?
Apparently.
I called the inn. They
said the weather's great.
Getting away for the weekend?
Pending any
last-minute complications.
He means me. And there won't be.
Hemoglobin's 11.
How much you get out?
Only 700 cc's.
He's losing blood somewhere.
Pressure's dropping, 60 palp.
No breath sounds on the right.
Bullet must have tumbled
to the right side. Malucci...
Intubate and put in
a second chest tube.
Right you are.
Okay, we need a chest tube tray.
Tension hemopneumo?
Yeah. Let's find out.
So where you guys going?
Wisconsin. Lake Hatteras.
Heard you had a kid.
GSW. It's surgical.
So you've got it?
Three docs, no waiting.
Oh, oh.
He's bleeding
into his right chest.
Lost his pressure.
God, I love this guy.
He's an entire medical education
in one convenient
package, you know.
Jackie?
Oh, God. Cleo, do you
know where Peter is?
I think he's up in the O.R.
Why are you down here?
I've been trying to reach
him. I told the man at the desk.
What happened?
What's the matter?
Well, they called me at
work and I came right away.
It's Jesse.
They said that he
was brought here.
Jesse? Your son?
Man over there said that he
was brought in a few minutes ago.
That he was shot.
Somebody shot my boy.
Where's Dr. Benton?
Um, 2, with Spencer on a hernia.
What the hell are you doing?
Found a hole in
the right ventricle.
Let's cross-clamp the aorta.
Thank God for bangers, huh?
Better than a good shooting
war. Come on. Get out of my way.
Hey. Hey, that's my patient.
Peter, we've got it.
All right, I'll oversew it.
2-0 silk. Move!
Peter, Dr. Malucci's assisting.
The guy's not
even gonna make it.
It's his nephew. What?
- It's Jackie's son, Jesse.
- Oh, my God.
Where the hell's the 2-0 silk?
Hey, Frank. Half day?
Twelve to 12. Much going on?
Pretty slow.
My mother's here.
Y-you weren't expecting her?
No. Um, do you
have a few minutes?
Sure.
Pregnancy test
on that Ruiz girl.
Damn it. Where the
hell are the police?
I'm a few minutes early. You
want to grab some coffee?
Yeah. That'd be great. Okay.
Still not filling.
There has to be another hole.
Left ventricle is macerated
on the posterior surface.
More 2-0 silk. Come on!
Blood's pouring
out of the right chest.
Crack open his other side.
Hold on. Peter!
I can get it. Somebody
cut off that damn alarm.
There's no time, Peter.
Another thoracotomy tray?
Lizzie, you ordered a
percutaneous discectomy
on a 50-year-old?
Robert, I'm busy.
It looks like Doctors Greene
and Benton have this covered.
Why don't you step out, please.
That's Peter's
nephew in there. Whoa.
And you've opened up
both sides of his chest, huh?
Well, anyway...
Patterson is a candidate
for open lumbar disk surgery.
Endoscopic surgery's
the best treatment.
And it's faster too.
Yes, it is. No dramatic muscle
dissection, no bone removal.
And you can still
ditch out of here in time
for your romantic weekend.
What the hell are
you insinuating?
That I'd choose an
inappropriate course of surgery
to accommodate my weekend plans?
You said it, not me.
I've got to get back.
Gloves.
The bullet tore up the
hilum. Foley catheter.
I'll throw in a purse
string. No. I'll do it.
What was going on out there?
- Nothing.
Heart's not filling.
All right. Uh... We're
going to bypass.
I'll take the aorta. You
take the femoral vein.
We need ice!
Malucci, get four
basins full. What for?
We'll pack the head to
preserve brain function.
That'll work? Just get it!
She sold cosmetics.
But she used to
get fired all the time.
What about your dad?
He split when I was
7. Couldn't take it.
She's an artist.
And when I was little
and she was manic,
it was fun, actually.
'Cause we would
do stuff like, uh,
camp out in the living room.
Actually really camp
out with tents and stuff.
We painted the walls
of the living room once.
This whole landscape. It was...
And then suddenly
everything would change.
She would start
screaming, crying, and...
Eric took the brunt of that.
He was much more
of a rebel than I was.
Eric is your brother? Yeah.
She was living
near him in Florida.
He's in the Air Force.
He's an air traffic controller.
Really? Yes.
And then she would get depressed
and just go to bed for weeks.
So by the age of 10 I had
figured out how to scam meals
off the neighbors so
Eric and I could eat.
Could get her some
help, you know.
Could get her on
lithium or Depakote.
No. She won't take the drugs.
She likes it when she's manic.
But I-I can't do this again.
I'm not strong enough.
Jackie? Jackie.
Did you find Peter?
Yes, he's in with the trauma
team working on Jesse now.
Oh, thank God. How is he?
He was shot in the chest.
We found some
bleeding around his heart
and Peter's trying
to repair it now.
His heart?
His condition is very grave.
They're working to stabilize him
so they can move him to the O.R.
Oh, Lord. I...
Can I get you anything? No.
No. I should try Walt again.
He's out on a parts run,
and I don't know
what's keeping him.
Mrs. Robbins?
Is Jesse okay?
Get out.
Is he all right?
You don't get to
be here. Please...
Get out. Get out!
I don't want you here.
You get away from him.
You stay away from my son!
All right. The aortic
clamp is released.
Stop the bypass. Sponge
stick. Still has oozing.
I can't see.
I'll suction. All right.
Move the light.
He's bleeding out everywhere.
All right, uh, let's get a...
Uh... Give him a...
Give him a...
Give him two liters
of FFP and a...
A-a 10-pack of platelets.
He's not clotting.
We can reverse it.
Uh, more suction!
Pump's running dry.
We're not keeping
up with blood loss.
Well, squeeze it in faster!
Finally! Where you been?
Been waiting here for hours.
You said you were
gonna run a few tests,
and then you disappear.
My eye is just a little
sore. Otherwise, I feel okay.
I'm gonna lose my job,
and we've been
sitting here for hours.
Mr. Ruiz.
Mr. Ruiz, would you
step out in the hall?
Who the hell is this?
Please, sir. Out in the hall.
Teresa, you wait here.
I'm Detective
Tancredi, Chicago P.D.
Dr. Kovac here is concerned
about the extensive bruising
he discovered on your daughter's
body when he examined her.
What?
She has bruises all over
her back and stomach.
Yeah, from her fall.
They're at least a week old.
You think I beat my little girl?
Oh, my God.
I love my daughter.
I would never...
No. Mm-mm.
You're wrong.
You are very wrong.
More lap pads. I can't see.
If I can put one more suture in,
I can stop the
ventricular bleeding.
Cut.
Chest cavity's
filling with blood.
He's oozing everywhere.
Come on, Jesse. Come on, man.
Don't give up on me.
Jesse...
Come on, man.
Don't give up, please.
Come on, Jesse.
Peter...
Peter.
No!
Oh, Peter. Shhh.
If I work Christmas
Day, I get Christmas Eve
and New Year's Eve off.
New Year's Day too.
Yeah, right. You buy that?
Hi.
Uh, hey.
D., can you...? Can you
guys give us a minute?
Yeah. You bet.
Um...
So...?
Uh, yeah.
I'm sorry. I...
Guess I shoulda told you sooner.
Well, I'm not sure what
I'm supposed to say.
I wanna give him
up for adoption,
but I need your
permission to do it.
Him?
Will you sign the paperwork?
Please?
Where's Peter?
Still talking to his sister.
God, what a tragedy.
You didn't recognize him?
I only met him
once. You all right?
Headache.
Oh. Your neck's still
sore from hockey.
Next time I'm gonna
go early and warm up.
My O.R.'s free.
You still wanna go?
I have an outpatient procedure.
Should take less than an hour.
Okay. You know, it's
Friday. If we leave before 6...
One hour, I promise.
Dr. Greene? Yep?
What should we do with the body?
It's a mess. I don't
know where Benton went.
Police been here?
Not that I've seen.
You can't do anything
until they sign off on it.
It's a real freak show, though.
Well, why don't you
pull a sheet over it?
You think he heard me? Who?
Benton. You know, all that stuff
I was saying about his nephew
before I knew.
I don't know.
Excuse me. Yeah?
Is Teresa Ruiz
here? Who are you?
A friend. They brought
her here from school.
She never went
back. I got worried.
Up in Radiology.
You can't miss it.
Just look for a long
line of pissed-off people.
Could you tell her
Vinnie stopped by?
Yeah, Vinnie. Right.
So where's the best surfing
spot for a beginner like me?
Waikiki.
But you've got to
get out there early.
Damn. It's bleeding. Cautery.
It's 10 to 6. I know.
Pressure's dropping, 100/80.
Okay. Let's run
in another liter.
I can see the disk.
Can't get a good hold of it.
There we go. Got it.
Oh, we got some leaking fluid.
It's just irrigation solution.
It's looking good.
Let's get ready with 4-0 Vicryl.
We're almost
there, Mr. Patterson.
You'll be hanging 10
again before you know it.
Hanging 10.
So you do know
something about surfing.
Only what I've picked up
watching Frankie Avalon movies.
What are you doing?
Waiting for you.
Can I see?
They're beautiful. Yeah.
May I see?
This is Dr. Legaspi.
Psychiatrist?
Yes.
I don't need you.
Abby tells me you
have bipolar disorder.
How long have you
been off your meds?
Am I off my meds?
Why'd you stop?
I don't like lithium, all right?
It makes me tired. It makes
me sick to my stomach.
I can't do these on
drugs. I can't do anything.
What medication are
you on now? Prozac.
Uh, I was depressed.
A-a doctor at my HMO,
he gave them to me.
Stay away from antidepressants.
They trigger manic episodes.
She knows.
Okay, I'll write you a
prescription for Depakote
if you promise me that you'll
stay away from the Prozac.
Sure.
Great.
I will go get you the scrip.
You okay?
Thank you.
So are you gonna take it?
You bet.
What's this?
I called. That's enough for
a bus ticket back to Tampa.
Oh, don't. Really,
don't. Don't start.
Mom, I can't have you here.
I told you that last time.
I can't do it anymore.
Honey, I... I came
here to be with you
after what happened
with Richard.
I'm fine. Just please go home.
Why do you wanna hurt
me? Why do you wanna...?
I didn't ask you to come here.
You just showed up.
Off your medication again,
wearing a dress that
would look ridiculous
on a woman half your age,
running around the hospital
screaming, humiliating me.
Why, why, why?
Oh, now the crying
and... And the depression.
And you know what comes next?
Weeks of me worrying
that I'm gonna come home
and find you dead in my bathtub.
Or maybe with your
head stuck in my oven.
All right!
All right.
Fine.
I'm out.
Dr. Benton?
Listen, I'm... I'm sorry. I...
I didn't know he
was your nephew.
Get away from me.
Look, I-I just thought
he was some banger.
Six o'clock on the dot.
You're ready to go?
I'm waiting for you.
What is that?
Hey, stop it!
Stop it! Peter! Hey!
Kerry, you okay? You all right?
Peter!
Whoa. Hey! Hey, easy!
What the hell's going on?!
Malucci! Stop.
I was just trying to apologize.
Says her father
never touched her.
Says she falls down a lot.
And you believe her?
Doesn't matter what I believe.
Court's not gonna remove her
from the home when he denies it
and she says it's not him.
Can I talk to her?
Sure.
What happened this morning?
I fell down.
What about the other bruises?
My father wouldn't hurt me.
Sometimes people who love us
hurt us anyway.
Sometimes they can't
control their anger.
No, they don't mean
to, but they do hurt us.
It's a sickness.
And something
they need help with.
Do you know you're pregnant?
We ran a test.
I told him this would happen.
He wouldn't listen to me.
Listen to you about what?
He won't wear a condom.
He won't.
That's what we fight
about all the time.
That's when he hits me.
But he doesn't mean to.
Your father?
No.
Not my dad.
Then who?
Vinnie. Vinnie?
My boyfriend.
We're in homeroom together.
He... He's in the seventh grade?
He'd never hurt me on purpose.
He just gets upset.
He loves me.
What is it?
I was halfway to my car.
Patient's complaining
of backache.
What patient? Patterson,
lumbar discectomy.
Dr. Corday's case? Yes.
Perfect. She signed
him out to me. Great.
Mr., uh, Patterson, I understand
you're having a
bit of a headache.
You want a couple of Tylenol?
Ugh. My back,
it's... It's killing me.
Okay. Roll over on your side.
I... I can't move my legs.
Can you feel this? No.
You, help me roll him.
Okay, you're
leaking spinal fluid.
It's probably a cord
compression. Get him to O.R.
And find me Elizabeth Corday.
Mark, it's lovely.
Nice big bed.
Let's see the bathroom.
Hey, the tub. It's huge.
We can both fit in it.
Hello?
Yeah. Elizabeth.
Who is it? I don't know.
Hello. This is Elizabeth Corday.
Elizabeth?
Where's your coat?
You look like you're
freezing to death.
I'm sorry.
All right? I'm sorry.
I've ruined everything. I know.
I've ruined everything.
And I've hurt you and
your brother so much.
I'm sorry. You have
every right to hate me.
Of course you hate me.
I don't hate you. I'm sorry.
I don't hate you,
Mom. I'm so sorry.
It's okay. I love you.
I love you so much.
You're my angel. My angel.
I never meant to hurt you.
Please forgive me.
Oh, please forgive me.
I forgive you, Mom.
When you were born,
you were this little baby.
It was like you were the
answer to all my prayers.
You were the answer
to all my prayers.
And I thought to
myself, I'll be okay now.
I'll be okay 'cause you're here.
I'll be okay. And I
held your little hands.
I loved you. God,
how I loved you.
I... I know. I'm so sorry.
I know. I'm so sorry.
Shhh.