I like to call it
exactly what it is.
Low ovarian reserve.
I'm the reason we haven't
gotten pregnant.
Look, I just
wanna make sure
I'm not the problem.
I don't even know
if I want
a baby anymore.
Look, I don't know
what's going
on between us,
but maybe
it's a good thing
I'm going away.
You told me to get
out of your life.
We can figure...
We aren't good
for one another.
I'm sorry, Natalie.
Hey.
I'm alive.
Yes, sweetheart.
I want you to remarry.
She wants you
to remember her
the way she is tonight.
But, Dad, I'm never
gonna see her again.
Do you want
me to come with you?
Nah, it's just
a blood draw.
So, big day, huh?
First day of radiation.
Yeah.
3:00, in the basement.
So, I'll stick
around, then.
You don't have to.
Why?
Uh-huh.
You don't have to.
Mmm-hmm.
Hey.
You going to Lainey's
thing tonight?
I haven't decided yet.
I mean, you were always
closer to her than I was.
You don't have to
tiptoe around me.
I mean, if you want
to go to the party,
you should go
to the party.
Sure, of course.
Look, I'll see
you there.
Okay.
Actually, Will?
I'd like us
to be friends again,
if that's something
you want, too, of course.
Yeah.
Yeah, I would.
I really hate
to break this up,
but I got a peds burn
in Treatment Four.
Got it.
You, too, Will.
Mom's a little agitated.
Trini thinks
she's on something.
I don't seem to have
my insurance card
with me here right now.
I know I'm in the system,
though. You can look it up.
That's okay.
We can deal
with it later.
Hi, Ms. Driscoll?
I'm Dr. Manning,
and this is Dr...
Dr. Halstead, yes.
I told you
I was here before.
He's the one
that saw me.
Of course, I remember.
Yeah.
So, I understand
Jesse here
had an accident.
Yeah, um,
he was nuking some
water in the microwave
to make some oatmeal,
and I told him that
he shouldn't do that
if I wasn't
there with him.
Sorry.
I'm sorry, Mommy.
You know, I just turned
around for a second.
I swear.
It's okay.
You are very
brave, Jesse.
I can't believe
you're only six.
How about we give
Dr. Manning some...
I'm sorry. Just give
her a little space
to examine...
No, I need to be
here with him.
I'm so sorry,
I'll get...
That's okay. No problem.
Thanks.
Your finger's injured.
How'd that happen?
I must have done it
when I was trying
to get in my car.
How about we go next door?
I'll take a look at it.
I... I want to be
here with him.
We'll be right in there.
You can keep
your eye on him
through the window.
How's that sound?
Uh...
Okay.
Baby, I'm gonna
be right here.
All right, you're doing
so well, Jesse.
There you go.
Yeah.
All right, you can have
a seat on the bed there.
Let's take a look
at that finger.
I know.
Yeah,
it's dislocated.
I had to get us
to the hospital.
My keys were
locked in the car
and I thought
I'd smash the window.
I finally realized
I have a spare in
the kitchen drawer.
Tell me, Lynne,
you under the influence
of drugs right now?
What? No.
No.
There are a number
of treatment programs
I can recommend
if you're struggling
with addiction.
"Addiction"?
You didn't really
recognize me
in there, did you?
Five milligrams of Oxy,
eight times a day.
You said,
"Should be fine.
No problem."
That was four years ago.
You want to point
the finger at someone?
Try looking in the mirror.
3% to 4% superficial
partial thickness
on the shin,
ankle, and foot.
All right, let's prep
to wash and debride.
Is it bad?
It is not as bad
as it looks, all right?
And if we take really
good care of it,
it'll be better in no time.
So, when the accident
happened with the microwave,
where was your mommy?
Was she sleeping?
My mom works really hard.
It makes her tired.
I didn't want
to wake her up.
It's all right, Jesse.
Well, you're right.
I saw you a little
over four years ago.
You were complaining of
post-surgical complications
with your left knee,
and you stated
then your pain
level was a nine
on a one-to-10 scale.
I wasn't lying.
No, I'm not
saying you were.
If you didn't believe me,
you shouldn't have
written a prescription.
You all were handing
these things
out like candy,
and now that
you've decided
there's a problem,
I'm left to fend
for myself.
You think I like
having to score drugs
out on the street?
It shouldn't
have happened.
Maybe I should have
been more careful.
But I want to help you now,
and I'm sorry I didn't
recognize you.
I got high this morning
instead of getting
my boy ready for school.
How can anything be more
important to me than him?
I'm...
I'm just so ashamed.
It's all right.
We need to talk.
Shoot, Sexton.
I'm all ears.
Crockett.
Yeah?
What's with
the cloak and dagger?
Ethan is coming home
from deployment tomorrow.
Uh-huh. I take it
you two haven't spoken.
Yeah, well, he's been
incommunicado.
It's Navy protocol.
Look, I have been
agonizing over this
for six weeks.
I don't know
what I'm gonna say.
How about, "Ethan,
so glad to see you"?
I mean, you and I agreed
what happened
was a mistake, right?
Crockett, I kissed you.
Yeah, for like
three seconds.
Because you stopped me.
I don't even know what
would have happened if...
Don't make yourself
crazy over this.
Okay, I have
to tell Ethan.
Dr. Marcel.
Yeah?
Incoming. You're going
to Baghdad.
Copy. Duty calls.
Come on.
You good, Dr. Sexton?
Yeah, yeah, I'm good.
Okay, with me.
33-year-old male.
Side impact, high-speed
motor vehicle collision.
GCS 15.
Can you
tell me your name?
Alex.
Okay, Alex,
I'm Dr. Marcel.
This is Dr. Sexton
and Nurse April.
We're gonna get you
patched up, okay?
Nice and easy, folks.
We go on my count.
One, two, three.
Nice and easy.
Go.
All right, got a deformity
of the left arm.
Good pulses. X-ray!
BP 104 over 62.
Heart rate 100.
Hurts to breathe.
Poor breath sounds
on the left side.
Probable pneumothorax.
Chest, Mike.
April, April,
help.
Hey, Alex, you gotta
lay down for us, okay?
Good call, Dr. Sexton.
It's your show.
Chest tube tray.
Wait, what are you doing?
One of your lungs
has collapsed.
I need to insert
a tube to reinflate it.
Oh, my God,
you're gonna put me under?
Just numb you up.
Give you something
for the pain.
100 of fentanyl,
10 CCs lidocaine.
Ultrasound to me.
I'm in.
Okay, I'm seeing
some free fluid.
Hang a unit of blood
and plasma and draw
trauma labs.
Call upstairs
for a pan scan.
What's happening?
We're sending you
upstairs to get a clearer
picture of what's going on.
Once we get that sorted,
we're gonna have Ortho set
that arm of yours, all right?
Alex, you're in
good hands here.
Just sit tight, bud, okay?
Excuse me, Lynne?
I just wanted
to give you an update
on your son.
The debriding went well,
and Jesse's wounds
don't appear to be infected.
Will there be scarring?
Well, every
patient's different,
but with proper care
and follow-through,
it should be
greatly minimized.
Mmm-hmm.
How are you feeling?
I'm fine.
Uh...
So, what about scarring?
You just asked me that.
So, uh, tell me
what I need to do.
I want to write it all down.
Sure. Um...
You know, I'm gonna
go compare notes with
Dr. Halstead real quick,
and then
I'll be right back.
Mmm.
Will.
Yeah?
In about an hour,
my patient will be
ready to be discharged,
but I have to say,
I have some
serious concerns
about his after-care.
Mmm-hmm.
Jesse's wounds
will need constant
maintenance.
He might even
need pain meds,
and I just really
don't feel comfortable
releasing him...
Into an addict's care.
Yeah.
I'm gonna go call
Child Protective
Services and...
Hold on. Instead
of discharging Jesse,
how about we admit
him to the PICU?
The hospital can
act as his guardian,
and I can help Lynne
get ready to take
care of him.
But he doesn't need
intensive care.
That's against protocol.
If you recommend
in-patient care,
no one's gonna
second-guess
your judgment.
I'm sorry, Will, but no.
I can't do that.
That kid is all
she has, Natalie.
I gotta do whatever
I can to keep her
from losing him.
Please.
Forty-eight hours.
That is the longest I can
justify keeping him here.
Thank you.
But you're just kicking
the can, Will.
There is no way
she's gonna be
completely clean by then.
Dr. Charles?
I'm sorry, you weren't
answering my pages,
and I've got a patient
who needs a consult.
Isn't Dr. Kwon on call?
Yeah, but he's busy
on the floor.
I brought the chart.
Maybe you could
review it here.
Um, her EKG
and her blood work
came back normal.
No indications
of cardiac syncope.
She's been diagnosed
with panic disorder?
Mmm-hmm. She was
prescribed fluoxetine.
Been on it
for about two weeks.
So she had another
panic attack.
But how do we know if
her regimen is effective?
I guess I thought
that maybe you could
speak with her.
Ms. Curry, antidepressants
often take several weeks
to kick in, right?
So I would tell Ms. Patel
that you understand
her frustration,
to be patient,
and stick with
the prescription.
Is there anything else?
Yes. Panic attacks
have triggers, right?
Negative words
or thoughts.
Yep.
Well, there's this theory
that by repeatedly vocalizing
those triggers,
you can decouple them
from their power.
Like cognitive defusion.
There's an app.
Basically, you record
your anxieties,
and the app then
turns them into songs.
I think it's admirable
that you want to do
everything you can
to help your patients,
but offering up gimmicks
in an emergency setting,
I really don't
see the benefit.
You know, the best care
for Ms. Patel is with her
regular psychiatrist.
So I suggest that
you discharge her,
and that she follow up
with whoever that might be.
Okay? Okay.
How's he doing?
Yeah, well,
no solid organ injury,
but I'm not liking
this free fluid
in his abdomen.
Well, his blood
pressure's steady.
Doesn't seem like
he's actively bleeding.
Could be nothing,
or it could be a bleed
we can't see on CAT scan.
Let's get Mr. Minguez
in for a diagnostic
laparoscopy.
See if we can find
out what's bleeding
and how badly.
Well, couldn't
we just watch and wait?
And risk
an open procedure
if he goes downhill?
I don't think so.
Surgery's the only play.
Wait, so you're not gonna
lay out his options?
He might not need surgery.
Well, you saw
how he acted earlier.
He's afraid of going under.
We give him an out
and he'll take it.
No, he needs this.
We don't know
what he needs.
It's a surgery to see
if he needs surgery.
As much as I value your
input, Nurse Sexton,
I am the surgeon
and this is the plan.
All right,
if you'll excuse me.
Wait, you want to keep
my kid here?
No, no, no.
She said that I could
take him home.
So that's what I'm gonna do.
I'm doing that.
Whoa, whoa.
Here's the story. Uh...
If you insist on
discharging your son,
we're gonna be left
with no other option
than to call Child
Protective Services.
Child Services? Why?
You're not currently
capable of taking
care of your child.
I told you, this was
the only time that this
has ever happened.
Lynne, you know I'm right.
Is there anyone else
we can call?
Jesse's father?
An aunt or uncle?
No!
Okay.
It's just us.
Well...
Oh, my God.
My baby's gonna be
taken away from me.
Not if we get you
in a better place.
You said you've attempted
to get clean before.
What treatments
have you tried?
Methadone and NA,
and cold turkey.
Nothing works.
Ever tried
a detox protocol?
That's a month
in a facility.
Who's gonna take
care of my kid?
What if we sped
things up?
It's called
rapid detox.
Yeah, now, I normally
wouldn't suggest it,
but we don't have much time.
We push you
through withdrawal
under sedation
to manage the symptoms,
and in 24 to 48 hours,
you'll be down the road
to treating your addiction.
Withdrawal.
The last time
I went through that,
it almost killed me.
It is not without risk,
but I don't know
what I can do
to keep you together.
Can I say goodbye
to my son?
Of course.
Hold up.
Hey.
Looks like we're
gonna stay here
for a couple days.
What? No!
It'll be fun.
Remember, like,
when we had that leak
in the bathroom?
We had to go stay
in that hotel.
What was that secret
handshake we made up?
That's it. Okay.
Well, you be good
for the doctors, okay?
Okay?
So they're really gonna
stick a camera inside me?
It's a lot less dramatic
than it sounds.
That's what
they told my dad
when he needed
a new heart valve.
He had a stroke
under anesthesia.
Never woke up.
Alex, I am so sorry.
You know,
this procedure
is minimally invasive,
very safe,
and Dr. Marcel
is a great surgeon.
I'm sure he is,
but it's just hard
not to think about.
If you have any questions,
I can track him down.
I just... Is this really
my only option?
How's she doing?
Okay for now.
Got the dexmedetomidine
flowing.
Ativan at the ready.
She still rousable?
Hi, Lynne. I need you
to swallow this pill.
What is it?
Naltrexone, to prevent
you from relapsing.
Will, what are you doing?
Starting her on
a rapid detox protocol.
Has this been authorized?
You said we were
all kosher here.
Asha, don't worry.
We are.
Really, Will?
Rapid detox?
Plenty of clinics
are doing this, Nat.
We're not off
the reservation here.
Does she understand
the risks?
She does.
Even if she gets
through this,
even if the procedure's
a success,
addiction is not something
that can be cured rapidly.
There are a host of triggers
that Lynne's gonna have
to overcome.
Of course,
and this will
be a head start.
Get her past
the cravings,
the withdrawals...
I don't know.
I can't be the reason
she loses her kid.
I gotta make this right.
The hell'd you do?
My patient just backed out
of his laparoscopy.
Alex was concerned
about the procedure.
I just answered
his questions.
But he already consented.
Because you made
him believe he didn't
have a choice.
And you may be okay
keeping people in the dark,
but you can't just
assume that I am.
"In the dark"?
What are we talking
about here?
Our patient or Ethan?
Ethan? What?
I just want to make sure
Alex knows his options.
He has no options, April.
This procedure gets riskier
every minute we wait.
When we're rushing this man
to the OR in shock,
it's on you.
So...
You wanna tell me
what's going on with
you and Dr. Marcel?
There's nothing going on.
Hey, I can't have
my sister and my mentor
slugging it out every day.
Noah...
Spill it. Give it up.
Dr. Sexton?
Hmm?
If you're looking
for something to do,
Dr. Lanik has
a forearm laceration
that needs stitching.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Maybe something
you wanna talk about
with a girlfriend?
I kissed Crockett.
Okay.
It was a mistake.
I had just found out
some really bad news.
I was feeling
worthless. I...
What news?
Ethan and I have been
trying for a baby,
and I found out
that I may not be able
to have any.
Oh...
April.
Come here.
I'm sorry,
Ms. Patel.
So that's it?
You're sending me home?
Medically speaking,
there is no reason
to keep you
in the hospital.
You're telling me
there's nothing
you can do?
Um...
No, no, there is
one thing we can try.
It's not a proven therapy,
but it's been working for me.
All right, whatever
gives you anxiety,
you speak it
into this app,
and it turns those
words into a song.
The theory is that
when you sing it back,
you uncouple the words
from the influence
that they had over you.
Disrupt the cycle
of negative thinking.
What do I say?
Oh, I don't know, anything.
Anything that
stresses you out.
Am I good at my job?
I think I am,
but it's hard to know.
Good, okay.
Great, now
sing it back.
Um...
Am I good at my job?
I think I am
No, I can't do this.
I feel stupid.
No, that was good.
Just try it.
No, I don't want to.
Okay.
Oh, God.
All right, yeah, no.
We can try that later.
You know what,
if taking my antidepressants
is all I really need to do,
then I'm just gonna do that.
No, no, I wouldn't take
your meds off-schedule.
Okay.
God, I just want
to get out of here.
Okay.
Look at you.
Come on, give it to me.
Give it to me, huh?
Working that gown.
They let you wear
whatever you want
during chemo.
Well, the good news,
radiation goes
by a lot quicker.
The bad, they don't got
those plush La-Z-Boys.
And...
We can't go in together.
Heard you were
down here.
Hey, Dr. Singh.
I didn't know you sat in
during these things.
I'm here
to see Ben, actually.
I wanted to do this
in person.
Is it okay that
Maggie's here?
Uh-huh.
I reviewed your blood work,
and it seems
that whatever jumpstarted
your immune system
to fight off the measles
had the added benefit
of putting your
cancer in remission.
What?
You're kidding, right?
No, I'm not.
Congratulations, Ben.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, Ben.
I'm so happy
for you, Ben.
Yes! Thank you!
Yes! Come on!
Let's go!
This is
the best day ever.
Thank you, Dr. Singh.
Okay, I'm really sorry
that I couldn't
do more for you.
I'll manage.
Hey, Priya,
are you okay?
My throat...
What?
I can't...
I need the response
team out here!
Hey, Priya,
can you hear me?
Dr. Lanik's on his way.
Okay, I need epi.
It's okay.
You're gonna be okay.
What the hell happened?
I... I don't know.
Dr. Halstead!
Lynne's seizing.
She's going
through withdrawal.
Push another
five of Ativan.
I already did.
Seizure's not breaking.
BP's spiking, 180 over 100.
She needs a propofol
bolus, Will.
We gotta snow her.
All right, do it.
Gotta protect her airway.
Mommy?
Jesse, what are you
doing here?
Why is she shaking like that?
Put him on a mask.
Belly's distended
and tender.
Mmm-hmm.
Heart rate's up to 120.
BP's 91 over 76.
What happened?
He's in hemorrhagic shock.
Two units on
the rapid transfuser.
Can we still
scope him?
No, too unstable.
We have to open him up.
Open up the Hybrid Room!
Let's move.
How's your patient?
Oh. Uh...
She had another
panic attack,
but she's stable.
Dr. Lanik just
ordered repeat labs.
She had another one?
Any ideas on the trigger?
Dr. Charles,
I'm really sorry.
I couldn't send her
home with nothing.
So, I had her
try the singing.
And you think that
that's why she had
another episode?
Yeah, well, she got really
anxious, and then she took
another anti-depressant,
and I don't know.
I think this is my fault.
Wait, wait, wait.
She took a second dose
on top of her
regular prescription?
Yes.
When exactly
did she do that?
Maybe 20 minutes
before she collapsed.
But panic attacks
are typically
an immediate response
to a stressor,
not time-delayed.
And an extra antidepressant
wouldn't provoke
a toxic response anyway.
Look, why don't we add
an FBC and tryptase
to her blood work?
More tests?
What are you thinking?
I don't know yet,
but I'm not positive
we're looking
at panic attacks here.
Okay.
Your mom told me
that you kept some of your
favorite books in here.
Why don't you pick
one out for us to read?
Why was that doctor
sticking something down
my mommy's throat?
To help her breathe.
It's 'cause of that
stuff she takes, isn't it?
Have you ever heard
of a bad habit?
So, I used to bite
my nails all the time,
and that's a bad habit.
And sometimes it's really
hard to stop when you're
so used to doing it.
My mom has a bad habit,
doesn't she?
And it's making
her sick.
Is that why I have
to stay here tonight?
Well, it's a little
more complicated
than that, Jesse.
'Cause I can take
care of her.
I know what to do. Look.
You have Narcan
in your backpack?
My mommy gave it to me.
And you know
how to use it?
If I find my mom
and I can't wake her up,
I tilt her head back
and squirt one of these
in her nose.
I've done it before.
You have?
A couple times.
You don't need to worry
about my mom,
'cause I can take
care of her.
Please don't take her
away from me.
Lot of blood.
What's that
grey patch?
Ischemic bowel.
Can we
salvage that?
If we got in here
three hours ago.
All right,
let's get control
of this bleeding.
April, hemostat
times two.
Dr. Sexton,
clamp under me.
Marty,
how we looking?
A little tachycardic,
but pressure's holding.
It feels oozy.
Hang another unit
of blood and plasma.
Got it.
Mesentery's
clamped off.
You ever resect
a bowel before?
No.
Lucky you.
GIA 80 to Dr. Sexton.
Let's get to work.
How do you feel?
Like a rotisserie chicken.
Listen, Maggie...
I wanna apologize
for earlier.
When I got the news
about my cancer,
I just...
I went a little wild.
For good reason.
But still,
it was selfish,
given where you are
in your fight.
I don't want to
go out and celebrate.
Not until we both
can declare victory.
How lucky am I
to have found you?
You give me hope, Ben.
How do you feel?
My throat is sore.
But overall...
I'm sorry, I'm so hoarse.
Could I have some
water, please?
Of course.
Thank you.
Whoa.
You see that?
Hand's pretty darn steady.
Is there a chance
this detox might work?
Excuse me, Ms. Driscoll.
I'm Sharon Goodwin,
Executive Director
of Patient
Services here,
and this is
Madeline Gastern
from Child
Protective Services.
What's going on?
I regret
to inform you, Lynne,
that the department
will be taking medical
custody of your child
until we can determine
your fitness as a parent.
No.
I don't
understand.
You promised not to do this
if I went through the detox.
Lynne, I didn't do this.
You lied to me.
Why did you lie to me?
Hey.
You called in
Protective Services.
We had a deal.
The terms changed.
When did that happen?
When Jesse told me that
his neglect was not just
a one-time occurrence.
That kid's
living situation
is far more dire
than your patient
led you to believe.
Dr. Halstead.
What?
Charge nurse asked me
to tell you
your patient,
Lynne Driscoll,
just left AMA.
So how is he?
We'll keep him
under observation
for about a week,
but he should be fine.
Good.
Oh, yeah, so I am gonna go
check on some paperwork
down in the ED.
Yeah. Excuse me.
Look, Crockett,
about today, I am sorry.
Come on.
I shouldn't have
pushed so hard.
You were just trying
to do the best thing
for your patient.
I've been thinking
about it, and, um...
I think maybe
you were right.
Sometimes people
don't need
to know everything.
I don't think
I should tell him.
Okay.
Systemic what?
Mastocytosis.
It's a genetic condition.
Completely manageable.
Okay, but what about
my panic attacks?
Shortness of breath,
elevated heart rate,
loss of consciousness,
all symptoms
of panic attacks
and mastocytosis.
Except mastocytosis
can actually be made worse
by taking antidepressants.
So the fluoxetine was not
only not treating anything,
but that extra
dose you took?
Probably what made you
pass out in our waiting room.
But my stress is real.
Probably just
good old-fashioned
job-related stress.
Look, we're going to check
in with your psychiatrist,
but in the meantime,
what we want to do
is swap out
your antidepressants
for antihistamines.
Okay?
Okay.
Thank you.
Really.
You bet.
What are you doing?
Deleting this app.
It doesn't work.
Mastocytosis should have
been on my differential
from the start,
but I got so focused
on this app that I...
I totally missed it.
Don't be so hard
on yourself.
Look, you came up
with a creative idea
to solve a tricky problem.
It didn't happen
to work, but... I mean,
look at it this way.
If you hadn't of tried it,
Priya would have gone home
thinking she still
had a panic disorder.
Because she rejected
my bad idea.
Like you said,
it's just a gimmick.
You can't sing away
your problems.
Ethan.
Hi!
I thought you were
coming home tomorrow!
I shipped out early.
I wanted
to surprise you.
What?
Mission accomplished.
Baby, I...
Look, I didn't like
how we left things.
I've been thinking
about it a lot over
the last six weeks.
Me, too.
Sit. Um...
You and I, we've been
working so hard
and trying to start a family,
and I think I got
caught up in planning
that I forgot
what the objective
of the mission really was.
I'm sorry, I didn't
want to make it
sound like a briefing.
It's okay.
But you...
But you need to know
that I...
I love you,
and I love your passion
and your loyalty.
And I don't want to go
another six weeks
without you in my life.
So...
April Sexton...
Will you marry me?
This a good silence?
Before I answer that, um...
I need to tell you something.
It might change
your mind.
Okay.
I...
I got tested,
and I don't think
I can have kids.
I'm sorry.
Baby, no.
No, I'm sorry.
But, hey, that's okay.
Look, I love you
no matter what, okay?
We'll figure this
out together.
I love you so much.
So much.
So is that a yes?
Yes.
Yes!
Whoo!
I'm glad you came
out tonight.
You know, I figured
CeCe probably would
have approved.
Oh, yeah.
Sure she would've.
All right,
thank you all
for coming tonight.
I'm gonna miss you
all so much.
We'll miss you
too, Lainey!
All right, all right.
Up next, Dr. C!
Let's make some noise!
Seriously?
Seriously,
you're gonna sing?
He's gonna sing?
A friend of mine told me
that you can't sing
away your troubles.
Well, I guess
we're about to find out.
There you go and, baby
Here am I
Well, you left me here
So I could
Sit and cry
Golly gee
What have you done to me?
Well, I guess it doesn't
matter anymore
Do you remember, baby
Last September, how you
Held me tight
Each and every night
And, oh, baby, how you
Drove me crazy
Well, I guess it doesn't
matter anymore
A little help?
Baghdad.
Dr. Halstead?
35-year-old female.
Found down, unresponsive.
Looks like an OD.
No response to Narcan.
She's been shocked
and epi'd once already.
On my count.
One, two, three.
Will.
Continue CPR.
Crash cart!
She's in v-fib,
no pulse.
Charge to 200.
Lift up. All right,
let's go.
We are not
losing her. Clear.
Pulse.
No pulse.
Continue CPR.
Another round
of epi. Charge.
Let's go.
Clear.
Come on, Lynne.
Pulse?
It's been 11 minutes now
without one.
Eleven minutes?
Halstead,
pronounce her.
Time of death, 20:43.
I'm sorry.