Okay, this is the moment
of truth, Dr. Marcel.
If there's a chance
she could lose function
in her hands,
she'd be against it.
Knowing your mother,
I'd agree.
Let's get her off the table.
Come on.
How could you
do this to me?
Your life was on the line.
I know that we have history,
but it is history.
We could try starting fresh.
New neighbors.
Your father
never wanted you to know.
We were in love.
You're the one
who should have this.
Vanessa's biological father,
I loved him at the time.
What happens if those old
feelings are still there?
I'm so happy to see you.
Will, the Vas-COM trial,
please tell me you're
not going to testify.
I have to.
Then what about me?
You're going to ruin my life.
They're going
to throw me in jail.
Let go of me.
I used to be a cop.
Inside, I'll always
bleed blue.
It wasn't my idea
to drag you in.
I can't wait
for this case to be over.
The building's on fire.
You need to get out.
You lying bitch.
Take the back stairs!
Let's get him out of here.
Let's get back in the room.
One, two, three.
Hey, up here! Up here!
Hermann!
Hey, Will!
We need the basket.
On it.
Hey, grab me the skid.
Will, need a hand
over here, man.
I don't think he's going
to last much longer.
Any other way
out of here?
Just both stairwells,
but CFD's coming up.
Let's get him
by the window.
Slide the curve
to his feet.
You guys okay?
Yeah, yeah.
Clip the straps.
Yeah.
Grab him by the feet.
We're going to
pull them through.
Okay. Yeah.
One, two, three.
Good job. Clip him up.
We're going to
swing him around
counterclockwise, all right?
And one, two, three, go.
Hey, Roy!
Skid's coming down.
You got it?
On the way!
One, two, three.
All right. Let's go.
Slide him down.
Stay low.
Let's go. Skedaddle.
Let's go! Go!
Whoa!
Hey, Will, Dylan.
Hey, you guys
should be on oxygen.
Yeah. Yeah.
Hannah?
I'm okay.
I thought you got out.
No, I...
I went back in
to find you.
Your lungs are clear.
Anybody seen Milena?
As far as CFD can tell,
no one else is
in the building.
I got to find her.
What we got?
Male, mid-30s.
GSW to the abdomen.
GCS 3t.
Extracted from structure fire
with an inhalation injury.
Dr. Asher's in the next
ambo with Dr. Halstead.
All right.
Dr. Taylor and I
will take this guy.
You take Hannah.
Okay.
All right, let's go.
Come on. On my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
All right.
Bilateral breath sounds.
Get me an X-ray, chest,
and belly, please.
BP 98/68.
Heart rate 130.
All right. Single hole,
left upper quadrant.
This guy's in trouble.
Let's roll him.
Second hole,
right back.
Through and through.
Let's hope.
Laparotomy?
Yeah. Let's see
how bad the damage is.
Any time.
X-ray.
Okay, no retained
missiles.
Two units whole blood
and prep the hybrid OR.
On it.
Jo!
Jo?
Dylan?
Oh, man. You've been hit.
We got... We got to get
you to the hospital.
Dylan.
Yeah.
It's not your fault.
Come on, Jo.
Stay with me.
You're gonna be okay,
all right?
You're going
to be okay. Hello?
This is Dr. Scott.
I need an ambulance stat.
So you had
a mild inhalation injury,
but you responded well
to the supplemental O2.
How high was
her CO level?
Uh, peaked at 12, but now
it's back to normal.
How are you feeling?
Good.
Can I get dressed now?
Uh, yeah, I guess so.
Well, if you want
to take a couple hours...
Will, thanks,
but I'm fine.
Oh, what about Dylan?
Did he find Milena?
Yeah, but it's not
looking great.
Oh, God.
Hey, you all right?
Yeah.
You could use
some cleaning up.
I've got to testify
at the Vas-COM
trial today.
All my clothes,
everything, it's gone.
I'll see if I can
scrounge up a clean shirt.
It's Milena.
Tracy, let's go.
Follow me.
Lost pulse and went
systolic on the monitors.
Yeah, she's bleeding
from everywhere.
Let me take over. All right.
Maggie, hit her
with a milligram of epi,
one of calcium,
an amp of bicarb,
and keep transfusing.
Come on.
Does her pulse check?
No pulse. She's asystole.
Give her another round.
Open her chest.
It's no use.
She's coagulopathic.
Then another round.
Come back, Jo.
Come on. Come back, Jo.
We lost her, Dylan.
We lost her.
Jo.
Time of death, 8:04.
She's gone.
I'm so sorry.
It was my fault.
It was not your fault.
I shot the gun.
Dylan, you were being
attacked, all right?
There was an assailant.
How could you know the bullet
was going to go through him
and hit Milena?
How could you know that?
Her name was Jo.
And you were trying
to protect her.
I did a hell
of a job, man.
Buddy, you did
the best you could.
I killed her.
I killed the woman
I love, man.
Oh, God.
I wouldn't go in there
if I were you.
She's still upset?
Livid is the word
I'd use.
What's her prognosis?
Since she hasn't yet
rescinded power of attorney,
I suppose I can share.
She's going to Brooks
Emmerich in Boston.
In my opinion,
it's the best neuro
rehab center in the country.
In all likelihood,
she'll come back
from this.
Good. Thank you.
Hey, Sam.
You understand
why I opted to sack
the vessel?
I understand,
but your decision was...
Well, uninspired
is the kindest thing
I can say.
And personally,
I've struggled
not to take offense.
Offense?
Yeah.
Clearly, you doubted
I could make the repair.
Oh, believe me, that
had nothing to do with it.
You say so.
Oh, and not that
this had anything
to do with your decision,
but it is ironic
the way you managed
to sideline
the chief of transplant,
some might say
making room for
the next rising star.
Hey.
He's waiting to hear
about Goran.
I can't imagine what
Dylan's going through.
I know.
Ms. Goodwin,
can I have a word?
Yeah? Oh. Sure.
Look, I know this is
probably the last thing
you need today,
but I I'd like
to be taken off
the transplant service.
Taken off?
Yes.
After all
the time and money
that has gone into
your training?
After having,
in effect, a fellowship
with our premier
transplant surgeon?
I have my reasons.
Well, I'm sure you do.
And I'm guessing
it's personal
and not related
to your competence
in the OR.
That's right.
Well, the answer is no.
Whoa, Ms. Goodwin.
Hold on.
Look, look, no, no, no.
Dr. Marcel, I know all
about Dr. Blake's surgery,
and I suspect
you feel a need to atone
for the decision you made.
But do you have any idea
what it would cost
to replace you,
to recruit a top-notch
transplant surgeon?
No, you don't.
And we are not about to
start turning away patients.
No, no, no, no.
Uh-uh.
You are on
the transplant service.
Wait, deliberate?
You're sure?
No question.
We found traces of accelerant
at the base of both stairways.
Excuse me.
The fire, it was arson?
Goran's the
most likely suspect.
Could have wanted to flush
Milena out, got trapped.
We won't know
for certain
until we check
security cameras
in the area.
Thanks.
I'm sorry, Will.
And I brought
all this on you.
Please, you don't need
to apologize.
Yeah, but had I not
asked you to
let her stay...
Dylan, come on.
My loss was nothing
compared to yours.
I'm fine.
I just feel for you.
Dr. Marcel and I
are in complete agreement.
The patient's hilum
is not reconstructable.
His liver's shot. Sorry.
No pun intended.
He's going to need
a transplant.
I'll put him
on the list, okay?
Hold on.
He might die
before that happens.
Yeah. What a loss.
I'll donate.
What?
I said I'll donate.
Oh, come on.
Hey, Dylan.
Look, I get it.
But you're in no condition
to make a decision like this.
I can't let him die.
What's your blood type?
A positive.
Well then, that's that.
He's B negative.
Well, then we have to
find a donor.
You do not
give up, do you?
Dr. Marcel,
your case.
We'll do our best, okay?
Looks like that breakfast
burrito is getting cold.
You know,
I forgot all about it.
I tried to talk to Dylan?
Did you know
he was in love with her?
Like, grief on top
of grief,
you know?
Yeah.
What can you say?
Well, what could anybody say?
Brutal though, right?
So who are you
talking to these days?
What do you mean?
Well, you know, after
all that Lonnie business,
I thought you'd look
for another therapist.
You know what?
I haven't... I haven't
really been looking.
No?
Uh-uh.
Hey, doesn't the, uh,
Vas-COM trial start today?
Subject changer.
Yes, it starts
this afternoon.
Good luck with that.
Maggie.
Look who's here.
Grant.
Hello, Maggie.
He wanted to see
where I worked.
Oh. Sorry.
It's kind of
a sad day for us here.
Yeah, Vanessa told me.
Are you getting coffee?
You should join us.
You know, I didn't
realize how late it was.
I have to get back
to the ED.
Another time, then.
Yeah. Yeah.
Thanks for coming, Dad.
Oh, hey.
Hey, I'm sorry about Jo.
I know you were close.
Yeah.
Look, Dad,
I need a favor.
Can you call the head
of narcotics, get me
the yellow file on Goran?
I need to see if he's
got any relatives nearby.
Relatives?
Yeah.
He needs a liver transplant,
and I've got to find a match.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
hold on, Dylan.
Don't you think you're going
through an awful lot
for this guy?
He's my patient,
and I've got to do
at least one thing right.
Okay.
Dr. Archer,
17-year-old boy,
David Sullivan,
was brought in last night.
Smoked marijuana
laced with fentanyl.
Narcan'd in the field.
Resident put him
on saline to flush
his system.
Okay.
Treatment 6.
Here's his
latest drug panel.
All right. Thank you.
Yeah.
Can you sit up?
Try to sit up.
What's going on?
Where am I?
David, I'm Dr. Archer.
I'll be treating
your son today.
Thank you.
Where am I?
Stop saying that.
Look, you know perfectly
well where you are.
This... This isn't
like him, all right?
David's not some pothead.
His labs are good.
Drugs have pretty much
cleared his system.
Who are you?
Hey, he's your doctor.
They said the marijuana
had fentanyl in it.
Your son might not even
have known.
We're seeing
a lot of cannabis
sprayed with fentanyl.
You could have
died, David.
Are they coming?
Are who coming?
He's still high.
His THC levels
are negligible,
but we'll keep him on an IV,
make sure we flush his system.
I'm not listening to you!
Hey, hey, David. Hey.
What is going on
with you?
I'll check back
in a little while.
Okay. Thank you.
Hey.
Can you page
Dr. Charles, please?
Yeah.
Hannah?
I can't catch
my breath.
All right.
We'll get you
in a room.
Ethan!
Let me help.
Hey.
She's dyspnic
and wheezy.
Okay. Will, I got this.
No, I'm staying.
100 milligrams
of SOLU-MEDROL
and a breathing treatment.
Yeah.
Why wheezing? Why now?
Inhalation injury was minimal,
and the CO wasn't that high.
I don't know.
Until we can figure this out,
I think we should intubate.
Just saying... Yeah.
No, please.
She's setting at 92
with the cannula.
Maybe we don't need to.
Please.
She doesn't want it.
This isn't what
I'd recommend.
All right.
We'll see if
you can pull through
without intubation,
but I want a chest CT.
Mags, order a blood gas
and let Radiology
know we're coming up.
Will do.
Sit tight, okay?
You're too close to her.
You can't be objective.
You need to back off.
We're not together.
It doesn't matter.
You were, and feelings
just don't disappear.
Mr. and Mrs. Sullivan?
You again.
You know, David,
I don't think we met.
Um, I'm Dr. Charles,
and this is Dr. Cuevas.
You're psychiatrists?
Yes.
Stay away from me.
Okay.
Oh, God.
He doesn't need
a psychiatrist.
He doesn't need a...
No, he smoked
some pot. That's it.
And it was stupid.
I admit that.
You know, especially
for someone who's earned
early admission to Stanford.
Oh, well,
that's pretty impressive.
Hey, David,
I see you haven't
eaten yet.
Honey, the doctor's
talking to you.
It's poison.
David, it's...
It's not poison.
I want to go home.
Well, if you hadn't done what
you did in the first place,
we wouldn't even be here.
Eric, that's not helping
right now. Stop.
David, I want you
to know that we
completely understand
that this can be a really
uncomfortable place,
and we want you
to know that we're
going to try and get you
out of here as soon
as possible, okay?
Okay.
Nice to meet you.
Yeah.
Dr. Cuevas,
this is Dean Archer.
He is the head of the ED.
Nellie is starting
a psych rotation today.
Ah, another lamb
to the slaughter.
Hardly a lamb,
Dr. Archer.
Sorry.
So what's going on
with the kid?
What are you thinking?
He's paranoid, exhibiting
persecutory delusions.
It isn't just what he said
but his body language,
refusal to make
eye contact.
Yeah. The question is,
is it chemically induced,
or is there
something else
going on here?
Well, if it is
chemically induced,
it should resolve.
Yeah. In the meantime,
we got to get
a better history
from the parents.
Yeah.
I'm seeing
ground glass opacities.
And an enlarged
pulmonary artery.
She's definitely got
interstitial disease.
But what is causing it?
We need to get
a bronchoscopy,
clean out her lungs.
They can take a biopsy,
see if we can find out.
Hannah! Hannah!
She's only sating at 83.
Get respiratory in here.
We got you, Hannah.
We got you. Okay?
Just relax.
There you go.
I'm in.
We should have
intubated her downstairs.
Look, I was upset earlier,
but I don't want you
to get the wrong impression
about David.
I mean, he is a great kid,
and we're very proud of him.
You know,
this whole business
with the marijuana,
that's way out
of character.
He was such a sweet,
happy child.
You know,
everyone would always
compliment us
on how good his manners are.
And up until now,
I mean, he's been
a straight-A student.
So his grades
have fallen off?
Just recently.
Any other changes
in his behavior that
you can think of?
Anything at all
come to mind?
Well, I guess
he's quieter lately.
Quieter?
Sometimes, he seems
off in his own world.
I mean, he spends
a lot more time alone
in his room.
Well, you don't notice it
so much because
you're at work.
Okay, so he's been spending
more time alone.
What about...
What about friends?
Does he have
a group of buddies
he normally hangs out with?
I don't know. I mean,
he doesn't bring
anyone home.
You know,
I guess he's just
more of a loner these days.
Yeah, but I mean,
that's true for
a lot of kids, though.
You know,
since COVID,
and the online classes
and the socializing.
Sure.
I mean, the pandemic
has been really rough
on young people, for sure.
But you haven't noticed
anything different?
I don't know.
Some...
Okay, I'll get up
at night sometimes,
and I'll see that the light
in his room's still on.
Well, yeah. I guess that's
why David sleeps so much
on the weekends.
He's just not getting
enough rest.
So sleeping habits
have changed?
Oh, I mean, this is all
normal teenage stuff,
right?
Very possibly.
But honestly,
we would really
appreciate it if you would
give us permission to have
another quick conversation
with David
just to help us
figure out, you know,
what's going on
and maybe what isn't.
We certainly
don't want this
to happen again.
No. We don't.
I guess if you think
that it will help.
Great.
Thank you.
All right.
Dr. Scott.
Dr. Marcel.
Bogdan Costavich,
Goran's brother.
He's B negative.
A match.
He's agreed to donate
a lobe of his liver.
Well, Mr. Costavich,
this is very generous.
I just want to make sure
you understand what it is
you're agreeing to.
This is... Well, it's
not a simple procedure.
Yes. Dr. Scott
explained to me.
Yeah. There's risk involved,
and it might be as long
as two months
before you're able
to go back to work,
so just keep that in mind.
Goran and I,
we went different ways.
I know he's done bad things,
but he's my brother.
I understand.
Please, Crockett.
Yeah. All right.
Dr. Scott here is going
to get you prepped, okay?
I'll see you in there.
Hey.
Here's her biopsy.
Talc crystals embedded
in periarterial granulomas.
Look,
on the street,
heroin is often cut
with talcum powder.
When she used,
the talc formed emboli,
which went into her lungs.
So she's had these
granulomas for years.
Obviously, she's been
able to get by.
But the smoke
last night triggered
the interstitial disease
and caused
the inflammation.
Yeah.
Hey, she's on steroids
right now.
Let's see how she responds.
Okay.
All right.
Grant.
I got your text message.
Maggie, I was hoping
I could catch you.
Okay.
You seemed
uncomfortable
this morning.
Was it because of me?
No, no, no, no, no.
Look, I was very happy
to bring you
and Vanessa together.
And it meant
a lot to me, too,
to see you again.
I felt the same way.
Tell me, Maggie,
you ever wonder
what it would have been like
if we'd just run off together?
I mean, if our parents
hadn't found out and...
Grant.
I mean,
if they hadn't made us put
the baby up for adoption.
Of course I do.
But that's not
what happened.
I'm married, Grant.
And I'm very happy,
and I love my husband.
And you have
a relationship
with Vanessa now,
and that's fine.
That's good.
But I can't be
a part of that.
I'm sorry.
Dr. Marcel.
Yeah. Get him prepped.
I'll be right there.
Going into this transplant,
I hope there's
no residual resentment.
I'm a surgeon.
The patient needs me.
On top of that,
I'm doing this for Dylan,
so, no, Ms. Goodwin.
No resentment.
Glad to hear it.
As you know,
the hospital is obligated
to have a senior
surgeon supervising,
and since Dr. Jones
will be resecting
the donor liver,
he can take that role.
Yeah, that's fine.
I also came to tell you
that we're experiencing
another shortage
of packed red blood cells.
I can only
allow this patient
seven units.
Ms. Goodwin,
a surgery like this is usually
allotted 10 to 20 units.
Yes, I'm aware,
but we can't have
any one patient
depleting our supplies.
We have other surgeries,
other patients.
So call another hospital.
I need that blood.
I've tried.
We're all in the same boat.
So you keep me
in transplant
but tie my hands?
I'm sorry, Dr. Marcel.
Seven units.
So, David,
do you know why
you're here?
Can you remember
what happened at all?
Why should I
talk to you?
Well, you don't
have to, actually.
But we're really just
trying to help you.
Dad said the pot was bad.
When you smoked it,
were you
alone or with some friends?
What difference
does it make?
Maybe none at all.
But I mean,
just out of curiosity,
were you hanging
with your crew, or...
People are stupid.
Certainly can be.
Let me ask you,
have you noticed
anything different
about yourself, about...
I don't know,
the way you...
The way you think,
about the way
you feel about things?
Anything at all?
I think maybe...
I know. I know.
I know.
David?
You're trying
to read my mind.
Is there someone in here
who's telling you that?
What?
No. I'm not crazy.
You know what?
Sometimes I have this...
This little voice
in my head that's
trying to tell me stuff,
and I actually get confused.
I lose track of whether
is that me talking
to myself,
or is it someone else?
Does that ever
happen to you?
Okay.
And... And does that voice
ever tell you to do things?
Yes.
Not to trust you.
Okay.
There's something wrong
with me, isn't there?
You know, pal,
we're going
to figure it out.
Okay?
You can trust me on that.
Okay, so we know
what we're looking at.
His affect,
disordered thinking,
the voices.
Now we can move forward.
We can start a course
of treatment.
I think we need to take
a little breath here, Doctor.
The patient is a minor,
which means that
it's his parents
who are going to be
determining how we proceed,
so I hope that you
were observing them
as closely as you were David.
Dr. Marcel,
how's it going?
Good.
Just the
hepatic anastomosis
has taken some work.
Both the native artery
and the donors'
are a little short.
You're using
a parachute technique
to bring them together.
Yeah.
Okay, good.
Holler if you need me.
Okay.
Almost got
the arteries together.
How are his vitals?
BP's starting to tank.
Where we at on pressers?
Maxed out.
Fluid resuscitation?
Same.
Let's hang another unit
of packed cells.
Can't. That was our seventh.
We're out.
He's getting acidotic.
Crockett?
Yeah, almost there.
One more.
Okay, hepatic artery
anastomosis complete.
BP 87/56.
Should I transfuse
more platelets?
Yeah.
And 90 mgs per kg
of Factor VII.
Why?
Got to get him clotting.
Get me some Evarrest.
We're gonna go ahead
and pack and get out.
Pack? No.
You have to complete
the bile duct anastomosis.
No. He's lost
too much blood.
Gotta get him
clotting now,
or we'll lose him.
Maybe you should
call Dr. Jones.
I know what I'm doing.
We pack him,
recycle what blood
he's lost,
and wait to complete
the transplant.
You can't stop the surgery.
I have to.
Believe me,
it's the only option.
All right, lap pads.
Let's go. Come on.
There it is. Keep going.
Hey, Dan.
The new psych fellow's
looking for you.
Oh.
Yeah, thanks.
We were able
to diagnose that kid.
It's funny. I think
that Dr. Cuevas is taking
a certain satisfaction
in being able to put
a name on it.
I mean, I get that.
I was like that
when I was starting out.
But you know,
there's a little
more to it.
Yeah. So what is
the diagnosis?
Schizophrenia.
I mean, we have to
follow up and confirm
and all that,
but I'm...
I'm pretty sure it's
what we're looking at.
Yeah. Have you told
the parents?
Not yet.
I tried to call
my son yesterday.
Didn't know
you had a son.
Yeah.
15 years ago,
lost him to drugs.
He's alive. I don't...
I just don't know
where he is.
Sorry to hear that, Dean.
Yeah.
I'm telling you this
because I know
what it's going to be like
for those parents.
Boy.
Oh, they're going
to remember
that laughing kid
running through
the sprinklers,
how proud he was
when he learned
how to ride a bike.
And they are not
going to understand
how it's possible
that some outside force
has stolen that boy away.
Oh... You know that.
Yeah.
Well, I gotta go tell them.
Gotta go tell the parents.
Well, like you always say,
at least now
he'll get the help he needs.
Let's hope so.
All right,
let's unpack him.
You got it?
Great.
Thank you.
Okay, no active bleeding.
Marty?
Vitals are steady.
Looks like it worked.
Hell of a call, Crockett.
All right.
Good job, everyone.
Let's wrap this up.
So, Dr. Cuevas and I
have a strong hunch
about what could be causing
David's difficulties.
Is it really
such a mystery?
I mean,
it seems like just
normal adolescent stuff.
I know you've
noticed his...
His odd comments,
his jumbled thoughts.
His fearfulness.
You... You think that there's
something wrong with David?
We think David is
suffering from an illness.
We'd like him to see one of
our outpatient psychiatrists.
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
Another psychiatrist?
It's just part of
the evaluation process.
I don't understand.
This isn't
making any sense.
What is going on?
We know that you love
your son very much,
and this might not be
easy to hear,
but we believe
that David is developing
a schizoaffective disorder.
What?
Mentally ill?
No.
Psychotic?
No!
No, we're taking
David home right now.
How can you
say that about him?
This is
a treatable condition.
How?
We have a much better
understanding
of the mechanism...
My boy isn't crazy.
You're the ones
that are crazy.
I think if we can just...
Can we please
talk about this?
No. No.
Look, we don't want
anything to do with you.
Stay away from us.
We should sue you.
Oh, my God.
I mean, I've had patients
with schizophrenia before,
but I've never had to break
the news to the parents.
Sadly, their reaction
is not uncommon.
Well, how is that boy
supposed to get any help?
Exactly.
Come in.
Ms. Goodwin.
Dr. Scott.
I wanted to let you know,
Goran's transplant
is going well.
Dr. Marcel thinks
he'll pull through.
Well, good.
I know how much
that means to you.
I'm sorry,
I have to run out.
I have
the Vas-COM trial.
I also wanted to tell you
I'm leaving Med.
What?
You once reminded me
that I wear a white coat,
not a blue one.
But the thing is,
here in Chicago,
I don't think I'll ever
be able to escape my past.
I don't think
I'll ever be able to
take that blue coat off.
But Chicago's your home.
You grew up here.
Yeah, that's the problem.
Those old ties
keep pulling me back in.
I have to go someplace
where I can just be
a doctor. So...
Well, you will be
sorely missed.
Is there any way I can
talk you out of it?
This is where I met Jo,
and where I lost her.
So every time
I go past that room,
I think of her, and...
Understood.
It has truly been
my pleasure, Dr. Scott.
Wow. Extubated.
RSBI was normal.
Passed her breathing trial
with flying colors.
Talc granulomas.
Heroin addiction.
A gift that keeps giving.
The pulmonologist will
get your lungs cleaned up.
You'll be fine.
Yeah, till the next thing.
I just can't seem to
shake the past.
Hey, you're not
in this alone,
Hannah, okay?
Excuse me.
Dr. Halstead,
you and I have
a date in court.
Where did you get
that outfit?
Maggie dug it out
of the lost and found.
Yeah? Well, she didn't
do you any favors.
Jessa Rinaldi,
we're placing you
under arrest.
What?
Don't say anything.
You're charged with
aggravated arson
and one count
of attempted murder
against Dr. Will Halstead.
Oh, come on.
What the hell is this?
This is absolutely
ridiculous.
We have credit card
evidence of your client
buying accelerant
plus surveillance
camera footage
of her entering
and leaving the building
immediately before the fire.
Let's go.
I thought Sam told you
I didn't want to see you.
He did.
But I have something
I need to say.
Look, if you came
to apologize...
I didn't.
I came to thank you.
I had a win
in the OR today,
largely because of you,
what you taught me.
It made me realize, I...
I have an obligation
to continue this work,
that I can't throw away
the knowledge you've
given me.
Very nice speech, Crockett.
Meanwhile, I'm sidelined
with this injury.
I know.
When I come back,
which I will,
if you think you're going to
be on my team, think again.
All right.
You know, if it had
been me on the table,
and it was you
who had to make the call,
I'm pretty sure you would've
done the same thing.
Good night, Pamela.
So I don't know
if he mentioned it,
but I actually
did my residency
with your partner
way back when.
A little before your time.
But, uh, anyway,
so, um, you know
I had to part company
with my therapist
about, ah,
two months ago.
And I don't know,
lately I've just been really
missing the interaction.
And, uh...
And then today,
I just had this
brutal day, and...
I'm sorry. I just
have to ask you
a few questions. Uh...
Do you smoke?
No.
Take any
recreational drugs?
No.
Do you have
a gun in the house?
No, I do not.
Okay.
So you were saying
that today was
particularly difficult?
In what way
was it difficult? Hmm?
April?
Ethan. Hi.
I, um...
I saw your dad's obituary.
I... I would have come
to the service, but I...
I wasn't sure.
I mean, I didn't want
it to be awkward, so, um...
Um, are you back
in Chicago?
Yeah. Yeah.
I finished my NP program.
I'm working with
a medical group here, so...
What about you?
Are you all better?
Yeah, uh, pretty much.
Guess my NFL career
is over, but...
How's the family?
Emily, the baby?
Well, he's probably
huge by now.
Not a baby anymore, no.
Um...
But good.
They're really good.
You didn't get married
or anything, did you?
No.
Did you?
Um...
Well, I will see you around.
Yeah.
Hello.
You have a call from...
Sean Archer.
An inmate
at Cook County Jail.
Will you accept?
Yes.
Absolutely.
Dad?
Dylan.
Hey, Dylan.
Wait up.
It wasn't Goran.
It was Jessa.
What?
The fire. Goran had
nothing to do with it.
Jessa from Vasik, she was
the one who started it.
Yeah, Ms. Goodwin
told me you were leaving.
I know you've
been through a lot,
but if your decision
had anything to do
with the fire...
It didn't.
You know what?
I appreciate it.
Yeah.
Yeah. Maybe give it
a couple of days.
Think about it.
You're a good guy, Will.
Take care, man.
You too.