Previously on "ER".
‐ Are you firing me?
‐ Jeanie, I'm sorry.
Oh, geez!
Your clinic proposal.
That's tonight, isn't it?
Yeah, Oak Park, 7 o'clock.
I thought that's what we said.
Your husband lied
to you about his condition.
He's going to die.
Peter Benton, Rocket Romano.
Dr. Benton.
Hey.
Lizzie's talked about you.
I don't usually do
this kind of thing.
Sure, that's what
they all say.
My family has a few bucks,
and everything changes.
A few bucks.
Is that what this is to you?
Carol!
Oh, man, look at you.
I hardly sleep a wink
on the redeye
and you're jogging
and smiling.
There's nothing like
a visit with the folks
to make you appreciate
home sweet home.
Well, the staff
will be thrilled.
You haven't been too high
on the popularity list lately.
Yeah, I've been
kind of a jerk.
‐ Worse.
‐ Pain in the ass?
Keep going.
‐ Total schmuck.
‐ Bingo.
I mean, we all understood.
It's just we‐we're glad
you're getting over it.
As you know,
that meant a lot to Doug
you, uh, showing up
like that.
Meant a lot to me, too.
Oh, I almost forgot.
I found this
when I unpacked.
‐ "CH"?
‐ Yeah. Carol Hathaway.
‐ It's from D. R.
‐ Did you read it?
‐ No, but I was tempted.
‐ Uh‐huh.
Anna, can you come in here
and give me a hand?
Uh, what have you got?
I've got a shoulder reduction
on a boxer.
‐ Coach made him take ballet.
‐ Mm. I'll do the traction.
Then I will give you
counter‐traction.
Okay.
Oh, thanks, Lily.
‐ So how have you been?
‐ Fine.
On my count.
One, two, three.
Seen any, uh, interesting cases?
Uh, no, not really.
Done any interesting
procedures?
Nope.
Hey, you want to grab
some breakfast?
I'm not hungry, thanks.
Are you still angry?
‐ I'm over it.
‐ You sure?
Can we just focus
on the patient, please?
‐ Hey, cute little bugger.
‐ Oh, thanks.
I bet he keeps you
pretty busy, huh?
Actually,
he lives with his mother
so I see him
when I can.
‐ Huh.
‐ What about you?
‐ You got any kids?
‐ Huh.
None they've been able
to pin on me.
You know, Peter..
...you've been
on my mind lately.
You made the shortlist
for my team.
You still interested?
Sure.
I just have a couple
of reservations.
‐ Reservations?
‐ Yeah.
I need a team player
someone who is compatible
with Lizzie Corday.
Now, word has it
you and she have had
a couple of run‐ins.
We've had our differences,
but we've worked them out.
Differences can be healthy.
You think you can
keep up with her?
Absolutely.
Do you have the time?
Sure.
Great.
We'll do a trial run,
see if we're all compatible.
Then I'll make
my final decision.
‐ Whoa! What's going on?
‐ Mark, when did you get back?
Uh, hi, late last night.
What are all these people
doing here?
Oh, these are patients
for your new clinic.
Oh, no, the clinic doesn't open
till next week.
No, you said to put
the announcement in for today.
No, I said next week.
‐ Oh, man!
‐ Oh, I'm really sorry.
I...is there anything
that I can do?
Start giving out numbers.
Okay, everybody listen up
I need volunteers
to come back next week.
You'll get on the front
of the line.
No? Then everyone's gonna have
to be really patient.
Tell that to my boss.
‐ Hey, Brian, Davy, cut it out.
‐ Oh, miss.
I can't keep standing like this.
I've got the gout.
Here, take a chair.
Anyone else need a chair?
You need to stop
jumping up and down
and you need to go
wait over in chairs.
‐ Take a number.
‐ Aw, 27!
I might as well be waiting
six hours in the ER.
Go ahead, that would
help me out a lot.
Carol.
Oh, Kerry, hi.
Uh, did Mark tell you
about the scheduling snafu?
Yeah, it's very unfortunate.
I need to have a word with you.
Yeah, I'm lil' busy right now.
Weren't you scheduled
to work in the ER today?
Yeah, but I had to take the day
off, so I could run the clinic.
I don't suppose you could spare
anyone to help me out?
When I signed off
on the clinic, you promised
that you would find
your own personnel
and it wouldn't impinge
on your regular duties.
Well, uh, I could always turf
the runny noses, BP checks
over to the ER and have one of
the nurse personnel handle them.
Okay, I'll give
you Yosh Takata.
‐ Who?
‐ Nursing administration.
Excuse me.
Transfer from upstairs.
Why don't you, at least,
talk to a friend of mine
at the Gay and Lesbian
Defense Fund?
'They represent people
with HIV and AIDS'
'who've been fired
from their jobs.'
Maggie, thanks
for your concern, really
but that's not
what happened.
Sure.
You're the best PA we have.
I just hate to see you give up.
I'm not giving up.
I'm moving on.
Al's already in Atlanta
checking out leads
on a couple
of construction jobs.
But it is illegal
for them to fire you
for being HIV positive.
You think that's why
they fired me?
You don't?
No, I...no.
They could've done that
last year.
It's because of the budget.
Hi.
‐ I missed you.
‐ Me, too.
You did?
'Cause you didn't call.
Oh, we were on the road
the whole time
so I wasn't able
to wrap it.
What's this?
Oh, it's beautiful.
‐ Thank you. I love it.
‐ Mm.
Oh, my...will you
latch it for me?
‐ Sure.
‐ Oh.
The guy at the shop said that
it is a genuine diamond.
A real diamond.
No one's ever gotten me
a real diamond before, Mark.
I love it.
‐ Pardon us.
‐ Welcome back.
Ah, there's no place like home.
Ugh, this coffee's terrible.
Oh, um, I'm really awful
in the kitchen.
‐ Sorry.
‐ I think it tastes really good.
‐ What do we got?
‐ Approximately 12‐year‐old boy.
Hit and run
on his way to school.
GCS seven,
got routine blood work.
Chest and abdominal films,
C‐spine.
BP's funky, 80/palp.
Gave two units O‐neg.
The name on this notebook
says Rodney Price.
There's a mass
in the upper left quadrant.
The abdomen is tense
and distended.
‐ Crit's falling, 26.
‐ He's bleeding internally.
I'll hang another unit
on the rapid infuser.
Looks like he ruptured
his spleen.
I don't know. That's the
biggest spleen I've ever felt.
‐ Got the wet reads.
‐ Ah, great.
Yeah, see, here's the shadow.
That's the hematoma
pressing down
on the splenic flexure.
‐ Looks like a rupture.
‐ Uh‐uh, no, no, no.
Oh, wait‐wait a minute,
wait a minute.
Film's mislabeled.
See, the gastric bubble is
under the right diaphragm
instead of the left.
Yeah, but with
a splenic rupture
the gastric bubble
can be displaced.
No, no, no,
not that much, it ca..
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Wait a minute.
That's not the kid's spleen,
that's his liver.
The liver's in the wrong place.
‐ Backwards?
‐ Yeah.
His abdominal organs
are reversed.
‐ That's remarkable.
‐ Alright.
Let's get him up
to surgery, move!
You ever do a case
like this before?
No, I've never even seen
a case like this.
This is one in a million.
Alright, everybody.
Page Romano.
Do you have previous
clinic experience, Yosh?
A little.
Where would that
have been?
‐ Uh, chart review.
‐ Oh.
You don't see many patients
in chart review.
No, but I sure know
a lot about them.
Alright, we're gonna have to
double up on patients in here.
And I will be
with you in a minute.
You said that
an hour ago.
Alright, I want you
to sign in patients
start a chart
and check their vitals.
‐ 'Where?'
‐ Out here.
If anyone seems
the least bit emergent
I want you to take them
over to ER Triage.
Can you handle that?
If I have any questions,
I'll give a holler.
Great. Mark.
Oh, bring the kid
out here, please.
‐ Do you have a sec?
‐ I gotta get to Radiology.
Alright, but I got
a triple failure otitis media
that needs a script
for Augmentin.
Alright.
How's it going, Carol?
You know, I would've been
organized by next week.
I don't suppose you, uh,
could help me at all today, huh?
Yeah, well, it's a little busy
not having Doug here.
‐ Yeah.
‐ But I'll see what I can do.
Alright, I appreciate it.
Thank you.
Oh.
I think Carol's mad at me.
Nah, she's just got
a lot on her mind.
Listen, that hospital lawyer
dropped off these papers
for you to sign,
he says they're urgent
about the civil rights case.
Right, just file 'em in my box.
‐ Along with the others?
‐ Yeah.
'Cause I'm not gonna let
these bastards get to me.
Oh, the man of the hour's
arrived.
‐ This is situs inversus?
‐ Sure is.
Fantastic case, Peter.
I've never seen one
in the flesh before.
It's probably worth
considering a case report.
Well, I'm actually thinking
of running a literature review.
Actually, I took the liberty,
there's absolutely nothing
on abdominal situs inversus
in trauma.
Oh, really? Well, I can be
the first to write about it.
Just heard the good news.
You've got quite a nose
for sniffing out zebras.
I wish I could take
the credit, but Peter landed
and it's, as they say,
finders keepers.
Nonsense. Peter won't
mind you scrubbing in.
Give us all a chance
to work together.
Well, I think he might.
‐ No, no, of course not.
‐ Great. You both can run it.
I'll just hang out
on the sidelines in case
I have to take
one of you out of the game.
Shall we scrub?
So, uh..
...don't you think
it's time we called a truce?
I am not at war.
You know I feel really terrible
about what happened.
I didn't mean to mislead you
about my family.
It's really not that
big a deal, okay?
‐ No hard feelings?
‐ No.
Oh, excuse me, John.
‐ I hope I'm not interrupting.
‐ Hey, Henry.
Hey, Henry, what are you
doing back here?
I just wanna thank you
for giving me time
during my ER rotation
to finish my brain blots.
Henry, grab the end
of that, please.
The end? Oh, alright.
The results are
so promising.
I got a Howard Hughes
Research Fellowship.
‐ Ah. Glad I could help.
‐ Well, you did.
And I was wondering,
if it's not too much trouble
if you might just
do me one more favor here.
‐ Favor, huh?
‐ Uh, yes.
See, I'm not, I'm not able to..
Excuse me.
I'm not able to start
a new rotation
until you remove these UEs
from my evaluation here.
So if you could just..
"Unable to evaluate
physical examination.
"Unable to evaluate technical
and procedural skills.
Unable to evaluate interactions
with the healthcare team."
‐ Yeah. You can't just pass me?
‐ Uh...no.
You barely showed up.
Well, then the registrar
says that I need to repeat
this clerkship until I pass.
Anna, you don't have
a student, do you?
Uh, don't need one.
Well, then, I guess
it's just, uh...you and me.
Jeanie, I've been
looking for you.
Well, you found me.
Good news.
Atlanta Memorial called.
They're very interested in you.
I faxed them
an excellent recommendation.
You should be a shoo‐in
for a PA position there.
Thank you.
Jeanie, if there were any way
I could change things
believe me, I would.
‐ I'm‐I'm gonna miss you.
‐ I know.
There's absolutely no way we can
take all these people today.
You bring them back next week,
they'll get first priority.
You're refusing to give
physicals to homeless families?
I am not refusing,
we simply don't have
any more appointments for today.
But I called two hours ago,
and a lady over the phone said
that this was
a walk‐in clinic day.
Cynthia, did you give
this man permission
'to bring in all these people?'
Well, the clinic's open.
I figured that it would be okay.
Are you a complete idiot?
Can't you see
we're swamped already?
‐ I'm really sorry, I‐‐
‐ What's going on?
Oh, she invited
the entire Hazleton Shelter
for free physicals.
Carol, can I talk to you?
So there was miscommunication.
If you have a problem with
Cynthia or any other employee
in the future, have the courtesy
to speak to them privately.
Don't dress them down
in front of the entire ER.
‐ Anything else?
‐ No.
Liver's lacerated, let's excise
the left lateral aspect.
Which, anatomically,
is the right lobe.
‐ Correct.
‐ I don't know about you, Peter.
But I'm getting dizzy now.
Maybe we should put
a mirror on the ceiling.
We could operate
from my bedroom.
Alright, Janet, do me a favor,
get a photo from the other side.
Peter, expose the gall bladder.
Found any family
on this kid yet?
‐ Not last I heard.
‐ Well, let's get on it.
I wanna get releases
for these photos.
Liver's still bleeding.
You ever used
an argon beam coagulator?
No, I wanna do
the Pringle maneuver
while you practice
your ABC's.
Go for it.
I've got a colleague
who would love to get his hands
on some blood samples
from this kid and his family.
Suction, please.
Here we go.
Alright, heads up.
Have pathology pickle this.
'Bet no one's ever seen
a backwards liver.'
We can use it to play
stump the med student.
Not to mention publishing.
Dr. Corday and I
we're discussing it.
‐ You both up for it?
‐ I'm game.
‐ So am I.
‐ Excellent.
We'll fight over whose name
goes first on the papers later.
I'd say that's a wrist.
That's definitely
a fracture of the wrist.
Yeah, but there are eight bones
in the wrist. Which one?
What do you think the odds of
catching TB in this place?
Henry, which bone is broken?
Ah, it's th‐the lunate.
No, that's over here.
Here, remember this,
would you?
It's a mnemonic.
Never Lower Tillie's Pants
Mother May Come Home.
Maybe you boys should
talk privately.
No, I'm just..
...teaching Henry
the bones in the wrists.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
‐ Here, the, uh..
M for mother is the
greater multangular.
Wait, wait, wait, you call that
the multangular?
I was taught
it was the trapezium.
‐ Really?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
And I call that the scaphoid,
what do you call it?
‐ Navicular.
‐ Hmm.
So my little mnemonic
wouldn't work for you.
It's okay.
I have one of my own.
Really, well, let's hear it.
Okay.
Uh..
...Scared Lovers
Try Positions
That They Can't Handle.
‐ Go with Anna's.
‐ He's already learned yours.
Yeah, I like yours better.
I‐I don't think that
I need either.
I'll just, uh..
...memorize the names.
Excuse me.
If Dr. Anspaugh calls,
tell him I'll have this budget
in his hands
by this afternoon.
Do you know
who left this note?
‐ Uh, no.
‐ "CH". That's me.
‐ Dr. Weaver.
‐ Yeah.
You drive a Plymouth?
You left your lights on.
Oh, that's hard to believe.
Thank you.
Herb Spivak. Snakebite
to the upper left torso.
‐ From a bivittatus.
‐ Non‐venomous?
No, but it's got teeth
like a piranha
with a head
the size of a papaya.
Mark, can you take this
non‐venomous snakebite
to the left thorax.
I left my lights on in the car.
‐ Sure. Curtain area three.
‐ Yeah.
Can you sign off
on this quarterly budget?
‐ Anspaugh is expecting it.
‐ Where?
Just below my signature.
I'll be right back.
So how did this happen?
I was feeding his python.
It bit me.
What do you except?
You spilled the chicken soup.
‐ Who are you?
‐ Gary Lomax.
Owner of
Jungle Gary's Reptarium.
He spilled chicken soup
on himself.
‐ What?
‐ Pythons love chicken.
So I dipped the rat
in my chicken soup.
It spilled on my jacket,
and bingo, the guy got me.
Python must have thought he was
the world's biggest chicken.
‐ Ellis.
‐ Hey, fancy meeting you here.
Uh, security said
my lights were on.
Ah, a little ruse to get you
out here so I can
thank you for getting us
the contract.
‐ Anspaugh approved it?
‐ Ink's still wet.
Synergix is now supplying
extra attending coverage
to County General,
it's all because of you.
Why didn't you just come
inside the hospital?
I wanted to avoid any suggestion
of preferential treatment.
Well, it's not
preferential treatment.
‐ It's just good business.
‐ We have that in common.
It's good business
for me to say thanks.
‐ Thanks, Kerry.
‐ Phalaenopsis.
Oh, Ellis,
you shouldn't have.
‐ Alright. You know phals?
‐ I love them.
Something else
we have in common.
Great job, Peter.
You really drained
the hell out of that liver.
Once I got my bearings,
it really wasn't that difficult.
I'm just glad
the case came along.
Me, too, but a compass
would've been helpful.
'Check the serial crits
and coags.'
'Make sure the Jackson Pratts
don't clot off.'
'Lizzie, catalog the photos,
and dig up every article'
'you can find on
situs inversus viscerum.'
'Okay, I'll keep an eye
on the core temp.'
'If it drops below 35, I'll
place him in a warming blanket.'
'I'll alert
the Genetics Department'
to see
if they want to consult.
Dr. Romano, this is Mr. Price,
Rodney's father.
School called.
Told me there was an accident,
told me to come right over.
How's my boy doing?
We had to remove part of his
liver to control the bleeding.
He's in serious condition, but
he did come out of surgery well.
Aren't you..
...Peter Benton
from Collins High?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Isaac...Price.
You two were classmates?
Yeah, class of '83.
Peter was on
that college track.
‐ Nose to the grindstone.
‐ It paid off.
Your son had
an excellent surgeon.
Isaac, is your son
on any medication
or allergic
to any drugs?
I don't know.
He lives with his mother.
Listen, is Rodney
gonna be alright?
You know,
we're doin' our best, man.
Damn it. Damn it.
‐ Can I help you find something?
‐ Oh, no.
‐ You've done plenty. Thanks.
‐ 'Carol.'
I think you better move your
patients out of the admit area.
We could get cited
for blocking fire exits.
Dr. Doyle, did you want
your December meal tickets.
‐ Uh, who has time to eat?
‐ I'll take 'em.
Well, they're
for the residents.
You heard her,
"Who has time to eat?"
You're gonna need
a tetanus booster, antibiotics
and I'll have to extract
those python teeth.
Malik, could you get me
some Betadine?
'I brought Flora along'
in case you wanted
to swab her.
Flora?
She's actually quite gentle.
‐ When she's not hungry.
‐ How do you know?
She's harmless except
for mouth rot.
And you‐you think
we should get a culture?
I love her dearly,
but her mouth's a cesspool.
Malik, you want to,
uh, give him a hand?
I don't think so.
Just grab her middle.
Don't let go.
Now, this next case
of situs inversus
apparently shows
no cardiac involvement.
Ah, Dr. Benton.
This is a great, great
teaching case.
I was just discussing it with
the residents and the students.
Dr. Benton and Dr. Corday
performed the surgery.
I understand that
photographs were taken.
I'm sure everybody
would love to see them.
Uh, actually you know what
we need to change
the patient's dressings.
No, no problem.
We'll come back later.
This is great work, Peter.
Don't forget those photos.
Anspaugh's impressed.
‐ Yeah. Here.
‐ How's the kid doing?
'Uh, he's stable.'
Lucky break,
the father knowing you.
Should make it easier to consent
him for blood tests.
Genetic breakthroughs
are hovering in the wings.
You'll talk to the family?
‐ Yeah.
‐ Yeah, great.
‐ Peter, is something wrong?
‐ No.
I'll be happy to talk
to the father if you'd prefer.
Why?
I just thought
you might be more comfortable
since you know Mr. Price.
I don't know him.
What difference would it make?
It's tough if you've a personal
connection to a patient.
I don't have
a personal connection. I j..
I don't want him to think
we're using his kid.
We've treated him
as best we can.
‐ 'Haven't we?'
‐ Yeah.
Then you've got nothing
to worry about.
‐ Excuse me.
‐ It's my fault.
I'm not used
to the floor plan yet.
I don't think we've met.
I'm Jeanie Boulet.
Yosh Takata, new RN.
The new RN?
How'd you get past
the hiring freeze?
I didn't know there was one. I
put in for a transfer to the ER.
‐ How long you've been here?
‐ Two years.
‐ Oh. Do you like it?
‐ Yeah, I do, yeah.
Okay, well,
it's good to meet you.
‐ I gotta run.
‐ Okay.
How did you get these
other scars?
That was defending
a cave diver.
We got caught
in a kelp forest.
‐ Do you dive?
‐ No.
Oh, spectacular.
So when did you start
handling snakes?
He's defending me
in a wrongful death suit.
‐ Ah, you're an attorney.
‐ Yeah.
Flora ate his neighbor's
Jack Russell Terrier.
'Obviously, they have no case
whatsoever.'
'The breed's
not even recognized'
'by the American
Kennel Association.'
Gary offered to help me work
with snakes
in exchange for legal counsel.
How could I refuse
such an offer?
Oh.
Sure, Al, I know.
I know.
Okay, I love you, too. Bye.
You okay?
Yeah, just Al..
...foreman job
in Atlanta fell through.
Oh, I'm sorry. Does he
have other possibilities?
Al's always got
other possibilities.
‐ Let me give you a hand.
‐ Thanks.
‐ How's it going for you?
‐ Oh, lousy.
I don't know why I ever thought
I could run a clinic?
I've no supplies. I can't even
write a script for an earache.
‐ PA's can write scripts.
‐ Yeah.
But Kerry Weaver won't let me
use any of the ER staff.
What's she gonna do?
Fire me?
Mark.
You are so romantic.
I am?
Hiding that note
under the charts.
I mean, my heart skipped
a beat when I saw my initials.
What?
On the envelope, C. H.
What you wrote was really sexy.
‐ Did you mean it?
‐ Yeah, sure.
Then, my answer is yes.
I will.
Hey.
Everything okay?
Well, we just got
some labs back
and, uh...Rodney's crit
is okay.
But his platelets
are falling.
We're concerned that his blood
might not clot properly.
What does that mean?
Is he gonna pull through?
Well, he, uh...he may need
to have a transfusion
but don't worry about it. I'm
gonna keep an eye on him, okay?
You know,
thanks, Peter.
I know you're doing
everything you can, man.
It's like all the doctors
who've been in to see him
making sure he's alright.
Isaac, are you aware that
Rodney has a rare
genetic syndrome
that caused his abdominal
organs to be reversed?
Is that why he's so sick?
No, but when he was hit
by the car
his liver was
severely injured.
See, if it had been
in the proper position
the prognosis
might be better.
Um..
Listen, I, uh..
I know it's not easy, alright?
Times like this,
you know, to ask, but..
...w‐we'd like
permission to, um..
...draw some of Rodney's blood
along with yours
and your ex‐wife's
to do a genetic study.
Yeah, okay. Okay.
I'll do anything
if it'll help Rodney get better.
Um, here.
You need to sign
the consent.
On a scale
of one to ten
how would you rate
your pain?
Oh, I don't know.
Ooh! When you
push like that
it's a nine
or‐or an eight.
But it could be
a six or a seven.
I'm not sure.
Ask him to describe
the quality of the pain.
Mr. Kottmeier
please describe
the quality of your pain.
‐ Quality?
‐ Yeah.
Is it dull?
Is it sharp?
Is it crampy?
Is it constant?
It's crampy, alright.
Sometimes it's sharp, too..
...when it's not dull.
I'm not sure.
I'm a double Libra.
You know how that is.
Not that I believe
in horoscopes.
That appears sharp to me.
I think we're dealing
with diverticulitis, Henry.
What do you want to do?
Oh, um, well, that‐that
could be surgical or not.
Um, order
an abdominal ultrasound
or maybe get a CT.
I'm not sure.
Well, why don't
we just start
with a history
and a physical?
Would you write me a script
for Erythromycin ointment?
I got a kid
with conjunctivitis.
Having you here today
has been a saving grace to me.
Thanks.
You worked really hard
to get this clinic going.
I wish I had your guts.
Gotta fight for
what you believe in.
What if you don't have
the ammunition?
Look for it.
‐ That won't hurt him, will it?
‐ 'No, no.'
Give me five units
of platelets and FFP.
'And 500 units of heparin now!
Move!'
‐ Hey, what's wrong?
‐ 'His blood's not clotting.'
‐ 'What's going on?'
‐ 'Oh, my God!'
He went into DIC.
I'm bolusing 500 of Heparin.
He's bradycardic.
Lungs are wet.
Put him on 100% oxygen.
‐ Damn. His stats are falling.
‐ Pulmonary hemorrhage.
Let's get him
on his stomach.
Here we go, people.
On my count.
‐ One, two, three.
‐ What's happening here?
His lungs are
filling with blood.
We're trying
to help him breathe.
Jesus, please.
‐ Isaac, you got to stand back.
‐ But..
Isaac, you got
to stand back, man.
'He's in asystole.
Amp of Epi. Come on, baby.'
We gotta get him
to turn back over.
Here we go,
on my count.
One, two, three.
Move.
Got to start CPR.
‐ Connie, have you seen Cynthia?
‐ She's on a break.
Do you know if she
left her purse?
I don't know.
She really likes you.
Oh, yeah.
We're just having fun.
You gave her a diamond.
That's serious fun.
Mark, what are you doing?
Uh, nothing I just lost my pen.
Here, did you sign off
on the budget?
Uh, actually,
I found an error.
‐ 'Really?'
‐ 'Yeah.'
'Here it has your salary $500
more a week than mine.'
Yeah, that's remuneration
for my taking over
administrative duties
until Morgenstern returns,
God willing.
$25,000 a year?
'Mark, you signed off on this
three months ago.'
'If you had a problem, why
didn't you say something then?'
I guess I just wasn't
paying attention.
Hey, uh, Jeanie, have you
seen a chart for Kottmeier?
No, no. Uh‐uh.
Guess I'll start a new one.
Um, and have you, um,
traveled anywhere recently?
Uh, just Louisville
to visit the in‐laws
a‐and then to, uh..
Okay, time to
wrap things up.
History and physical
just took 90 minutes.
Shave an hour off that
and you should be
within passing range for this
clerkship. Come on, let's go.
There's a rectal abscess in two
with your name on it.
Mr. Kottmeier, someone will be
in to see you shortly.
It would've gone a lot faster if
my allergies hadn't flared up.
Take an antihistamine.
Hi, Mr. Kottmeier.
I'm Dr. Del Amico.
I'm gonna examine you.
Boy, when they say shortly
they mean shortly.
This new clinic's a godsend.
I work part time.
No benefits, so thank you.
No. Thank you
for saying that.
There you go, Hector.
That shot will keep you
from getting sick.
If it's not too much trouble
could you
take a look
at Hector's chin?
He keeps crabbing about it
but I don't see
anything wrong.
Sure.
Okay. Hector, does it hurt
when I do this?
I can't feel it.
You don't feel me
pressing on it?
‐ No.
‐ No?
Okay, I'm gonna go see
if I can find a doctor.
Okay.
High‐dose Epi 7 CCs,
one to a thousand.
Another mg of Atropine.
Move!
We got a blip.
‐ Was it a pulse?
‐ No pulse.
'Maybe he's got fluid
around the heart.'
‐ Pericardiocentesis needle.
‐ Flatline.
An Epi can cause
a few transient heartbeats.
Damn, no blood.
Alright, Epi drip wide open
and more platelets.
Let's go.
Peter, it's been 20 minutes.
Peter!
Peter.
Time of death 4:52.
Ah!
Get him up to CT,
keep the C‐collar
on until Radiology
clears the C‐spine.
‐ You want films?
‐ No.
The neurosurgeon
will take them.
Kerry, I'd like
a minute with you?
Sure, Jeanie, what is it?
I want to take
a look at the budget.
‐ The ER budget?
‐ That's right, yeah.
Jeanie, I told you I..
It's nothing personal.
I tried everything I could
to try and keep you here.
The numbers just
don't support it.
If I'm being fired on the basis
of the budget, I just wanna see
the numbers, not hear
your interpretation of them.
Believe me, I've gone over them
with a fine‐tooth comb.
'It's‐it's not fair,
but that's the way it is.'
How do you justify
the hiring of a new nurse?
Yosh Takata was hired to replace
two nurses who've left.
Mm‐hmm. And what about
giving yourself a raise?
Salaries are confidential.
I sure as hell know why.
‐ Jeanie, I'm sorry I can't‐‐
‐ I'll find someone who can.
Hey, Carter, have you ever
had a patient complain
about his chin
falling asleep?
Heads up, Henry.
No, but I'm sure if it's
contagious, Henry will catch it.
Where are you going
with my patient?
Your patient?
Mr. Kottmeier's my patient.
Then why did I do a history
and physical on him?
Actually, I'm quite
fond of all of you.
Henry, you did
remember to sign
Mr. Kottmeier out
on the board, didn't you?
Was I supposed to?
‐ Where are you taking him?
‐ To the surgical ward.
Mr. Kottmeier has
an inflamed diverticulum
that perfed
into his mesentery.
‐ He needs a colectomy.
‐ Hold on, hold on.
Have you considered
medical management?
Treat the abscess first
with a course of Flagyl
and Cipro before jumping
into surgery?
‐ I'm willing to give it a shot.
‐ No, no, no, wait.
Are you just agreeing
with me because
you think that's what
I wanna hear
or is it because
you really believe that?
What?
I‐I don't want you
agreeing with me
because, uh, just to please me.
Believe me, I'm not,
in fact, I've already
considered several alternatives
to surgery.
‐ You have?
‐ Shut up, Henry.
Mark, if you have a problem
with my salary, come to me.
Don't bring it up
to the staff.
Do you have any idea
how many additional hours
I'm working
every week?
What are you talking about?
You disclosed our salaries
to Jeanie Boulet.
No, I didn't.
‐ You didn't?
‐ No.
Hey, Carol, what happened to all
the patients in your clinic?
I gave them meal tickets, and
stashed them in the cafeteria.
Pretty stressful day
for you, huh?
Tell me about it.
So anything interesting
in Doug's note?
Oh, I wish I knew. I lost it
before I got to read it.
Too bad.
Hey, how are you
on Medline searches?
Why?
I just did one
on submandibular paralysis
and I came up with zilch.
I'm not surprised.
I've never heard of it.
Well, I've got this kid
in the clinic who is complaining
of a numb chin,
what should I do?
Why don't you try numb chin?
Numb chin.
It sounds a little too,
uh, you know, easy.
Hey.
‐ Wow.
‐ There you go.
I'm sorry, Isaac.
Um, can we have a word
with you out in the hall?
I don't wanna leave my boy.
We'd like your permission
to perform an autopsy.
Why?
Well, because
it could be useful.
Did something go wrong?
He started bleeding when you
stuck him with the needle.
No, that's because
his blood wouldn't clot
because of the injury
to his liver.
Then why do you need
to do an autopsy?
Uh, for research, it‐it..
...it could be helpful.
And that's why
you're so interested.
‐ And not because he was hurt.
‐ No, no, no.
Isaac, we were trying
to save his life.
When you took his blood
and mine
were you trying
to save his life?
No, but we would..
We'd like to study
his condition.
I don't want
my boy studied.
Well, we understand
how you feel‐‐
Look at him!
Don't you think
you cut him up enough?
‐ Isaac, I'm so sorry‐‐
‐ 'No!'
I don't want you
cutting up my son!
You're right.
I'm sorry.
I‐I'll leave you alone.
Focus, Henry.
‐ What do you hear?
‐ Uh.
‐ Uh, I'm not, I'm not‐‐
‐ What do you hear?
‐ I'm not sure.
‐ This man has pneumothorax.
Come over here, I'll show you
how to put in a chest tube.
‐ I'll grab a tray.
‐ It hurts.
Yeah, I bet it hurts.
Hang on there, buddy,
and everything
will feel better
in just a minute.
Okay, Henry, first thing
that you wanna do
is feel for the ribs
along the mid‐axillary line
locating the fifth interspace..
Can I get some Betadine?
...where you make the incision.
‐ I‐I‐I'm not feeling so good.
‐ What?
‐ Not feeling so good.
‐ Sit down.
Put your head
between your knees.
Lily, give me the Kelly.
How you doing, Henry?
Lydia, do me a favor,
slide Henry out of the way.
Carter,
he's a little cyanotic.
What?
Can't get a pulse
on the banger.
Lydia, call an attending!
Change the dressing
twice a day
and think twice before
defending any sky divers.
Thank you, doc.
Hey, Mark, we need you
in trauma one.
Anna, Malik,
we may need your help.
‐ What happened?
‐ Banger had a tension pneumo.
Henry passed out.
Alright, I'll finish
the chest tube.
Get your student
into trauma two.
Okay. Henry, you're gonna be
just fine.
Alright, everybody grab hold.
On my count.
One, two, three.
‐ What happened?
‐ I don't know.
I was showing him
how to put in a chest tube
and he just fainted.
‐ Get on the other side.
‐ Wheezes bilaterally.
‐ Pulse ox is 86.
‐ I need to intubate.
Chuny, give me a laryngoscope.
Come on, let's go!
Did he complain
of feeling sick?
He's always complaining.
He's a hypochondriac.
‐ Is he on any meds?
‐ Not that I know of.
Okay, let's get a CBC,
chem 20 and a tox screen.
Alright, I'm in.
‐ Bag him.
‐ Pulse ox is worse.
‐ Down to 82.
‐ What?
‐ Get a blood gas.
‐ Pressure's crashing!
What the hell's going on?
His wrist is red, his left hand
is red and edematous.
Right hand's also swollen.
Oh! Oh, my God.
He's allergic to latex.
Okay.
He's in asystole!
Amp of Epi IV push!
ET tube cuff has latex.
We've got to extubate.
Lily, get me an ET tube
from the latex‐free cart.
'Wash your hands first.'
'Chuny, do me a favor,
get me a basin of water.'
Found a non‐latex ET tube.
Give me a mg of Atropine
and 50 of Benadryl!
Laryngeal edema. I'm having
a hard time getting in.
How long has he been down?
‐ 'Thirty seconds.'
‐ Damn it.
‐ Watch his teeth.
‐ I know.
‐ Can you see the cords?
‐ Barely.
Alright, Malik,
high‐dose Epi 7 CCs!
You're doing great, just keep
sliding it in, very gently.
‐ I'm in!
‐ Great, good job, good job.
'Got a pulse.'
‐ Whoa!
‐ Everything okay here?
Everything's under control.
Peter, I'd like
to speak to you.
Oh, yeah, I'd like
to speak to you as well.
Um.
Uh, I've been reconsidering
the possibility
of joining your team.
Hmm.
I understand Mr. Price
refused an autopsy on his son.
Did you try everything
to convince him?
He doesn't want us
carving his boy.
You explain to him how our
research might benefit others?
He doesn't want it.
Give him some time.
He's emotional.
I don't feel comfortable
doing that.
How do you think we made
advances in heart surgery?
In transplantation?
'By refining our procedures
on patients'
and then studying
the results.
That kid was a freak of nature
and we have a responsibility
to do research.
That freak was a little boy
named Rodney Price
whose father doesn't understand
why he lost his kid
and all you want to do is cut
him despite his father's wishes.
We're scientists, Peter.
'We're not allowed
sentimentality.'
Now, you go back
and get consent
because I want it.
No, you get somebody else
to do it.
I just got a lab report back
on one of my clinic patients,
a seven year old.
Turns out he's got
acute lymphocytic leukemia.
I thought maybe a doctor
should speak to the mother.
How did it present?
Kid's only complaint
was a numb chin.
I checked it in the computer
and ran some tests.
Well, the mom knows you,
why don't you talk to her.
Call me if she has
any questions.
And then I plea bargained her
down to a misdemeanor
not two weeks
after she shot a guy!
No.
Oh, Mark! Listen,
you could have saved yourself
a whole bunch of
urgent phone messages
if you'd have told me
Herb was on board.
'I didn't know
you two knew each other.'
Oh, yeah, I served on
the Trial Lawyers'
Banquet Committee last year.
Herb was our keynote speaker.
You know, I've been filling him
in on that law family suit.
Aah, you got yourself
quite a little mess, doc.
Yeah, I've decided
to ignore the whole thing.
Oh, wrong impulse.
You'll get slaughtered.
Listen, you better
file this right away
to avoid
a summary judgment.
Now, Mark, the hospital's board
of directors
is gonna be
very relieved to hear
that you have
such excellent representation.
You know, you came
about this close
to losing your job.
Listen, Herb, if you have
any questions at all,
please, just give me a call.
I shall, I shall.
Take care of yourself, Alan.
You too. Mark.
Why did you let Alan believe
that you're representing me?
Honestly, doc,
he's a lousy lawyer.
He jumps to conclusions.
Nevertheless,
I could represent you.
I think your fee would be
a little too steep for me.
Four hundred an hour
with a $10,000 retainer fee.
Yeah, I figured.
But honestly
I don't need the money.
I'm bored.
I'm looking for new challenges.
Here's a deal.
Let me shadow you.
You throw in a couple
of procedures, nothing big
you know, maybe a couple
of stitches here and there.
And I'll make
your little lawsuit vanish
just like that, gratis.
I got an autopsy consent
on the Price boy.
The father just
needed more time.
Why didn't Rocket send you?
I refused.
That's a ballsy move, Peter.
It wasn't a move.
I told him what I felt.
Well, it worked.
Take a look at tomorrow's
surgery schedule.
You're scrubbing in
on a lap splenectomy at 7 a. m.
Rocket's team.
He's partial to residents
with backbone.
J‐John?
Yes, Henry.
What happened?
You went into anaphylactic shock
from latex.
I‐I was near death.
Yes.
And you were there.
Yes, Henry, I was there.
And‐and so was Anna.
It‐it was like a dream.
Anna!
Hey, Henry.
It was the most amazing thing.
I remember being drawn
toward this bright light
'and then suddenly I was'
floating up above you..
...over there..
...in the corner..
...watching..
...as the two of you..
...enveloped..
...in a blue glow.
Worked together..
...united..
...to save my life.
Thank you, John.
Thank you, Anna.
You were my angels.
You brought me back
to the living!
Goodnight.
Can't be a chart
you're writing.
‐ No.
‐ And from your expression.
And the way
you're covering it up
I'd say
it's something personal.
Yeah, it's, um..
‐ It's a love letter.
‐ Oh!
The sentimental kind
or the I'd like to rip
your pants off kind?
Definitely the latter.
I'd like to be writing
one of those.
Pity I broke up with Jeremy.
Could've been more fun
long distance.
‐ Someone from back home?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
A self‐possessed dermatologist.
I'm afraid
I broke his heart.
Well, it's 9 o'clock
and since you're writing
rather than living out
your prose
I'd venture to say
you're alone.
Yeah.
Fancy grabbing a drink?
I would love to.
It is an unenviable job
running the ER
and making difficult
cost‐cutting decisions.
I got your message.
Jeanie came in quite upset
about the budget
and I was just
explaining that
it appears that
you've treated her
honestly and fairly.
She gave herself
a $25,000 raise.
That comes from
the administrative budget.
I understand that's your story,
but I don't buy it.
I think something else
is going on.
And what would that be?
My HIV status.
Jeanie!
I believe that's why
I'm being fired.
I see.
Well, um..
Let's not do anything rash.
I am, uh, late
for a dinner at the moment
but tomorrow
I can give the budget
another more
thorough review.
We have been over these figures
a dozen times.
You told me
we had to cut PAs.
Jeanie, why don't you give
Kerry and me
another day or two
to recheck our figures.
Thank you, Dr. Anspaugh.
I will.
Jeanie, you're really gonna use
your HIV status like this?
I call it as I see it.
I tried everything to keep
you here and then I bent over
backwards to help you
get a job in Atlanta.
It just isn't fair,
is it, Kerry?
You know, I have never
discriminated against you
because of your HIV status.
I was the one who fought
to keep you here.
Kerry, like you said before,
it's nothing personal.
‐ To your health.
‐ Thank you.
‐ Here.
‐ Oh! What have we here?
What have we here?
Another present?
Oh, it's beautiful.
Should I try it on?
‐ You can try it on later.
‐ Okay.
I dream of the taste
of your neck
and the smell
of your hair on my pillow.
You do?
No, silly, you do.
Did you really mean everything
you wrote in the letter?
Yeah, yeah, I did, it was, uh..
I was homesick.
Do you remember this afternoon
when I said that I will?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
‐ I changed my mind, I won't.
‐ You won't?
‐ Mm‐mm.
Oh.
Not unless you go first.
Lie back.