Work keeps our minds active.
It keeps us out of trouble.
Thirteen seconds to
run a low-exposure,
high-resolution,
full-body x-ray.
When this ER reopens tomorrow,
this thing is gonna save
us time, money, and lives.
Say that first part again.
What, 13 seconds
for a full-body x-ray?
We're gonna be able to
do a complete evaluation
of GSWs, stabbings,
crush injuries,
without ever having
to leave this ER.
Do you like your new toy?
Yeah.
Then shut up and
thank me for it.
When we're not working,
our hands are idle,
and the devil will find
work for idle hands to do.
Need any help?
Nope.
It's on. You ready?
Mmm-hmm.
Obviously I won't be wearing it
with a t-shirt and underwear.
Oh, no, no, no.
You should only wear it
with a t-shirt and underwear.
Or nothing would be even better.
Okay, I have to practice
walking on it for a while,
if I want to wear it to work.
Ooh!
Yeah, totally.
And when you have an idle mind,
well, that's the devil's
playground, too.
It was wet and
cold. I got the flu.
And I couldn't wait to go again.
That was the first
time I went fly-fishing.
Has he stopped kicking?
For the moment.
Her eyesight is
developing this week.
Unless it's not.
Unless she's blind.
She's not blind. Or he's not.
Or if he or she is
blind, that's fine.
Blind is fine.
What do we call it, "it"?
One of us can
say "he," one of us
can say "she,"
and we're covered.
Well, no, because
then it's gonna be
born thinking one of
us is always wrong.
Well, maybe it
can't hear anyway.
Maybe it's deaf. Deaf is fine.
Helen Keller went
to Harvard, Meredith.
Okay, well, what
if it's not fine?
What if it's absorbed
a twin body?
Two heads, extra arms...
Stop.
I'm just saying,
if anyone's gonna
have a baby with
two heads and three
arms and 11 toes,
it's gonna be me.
Would you just go
to sleep? Please.
Sleep.
And we own a hospital.
Yeah, we have for
several weeks now.
Yeah, but today it has an ER.
And coffee sleeves with
the new logo on them.
We needed the coffee sleeves,
right? They're a good expense?
Oh, yeah, for branding. We
had a 17-hour meeting about it.
I love the new logo. It
really catches the eye.
And these coffee sleeves,
excellent thermal retention.
What's up with the sheet?
I thought you guys put it
there for some kind of unveiling.
No.
Well, somebody should
say a few words, right?
I mean, it's unlucky not to.
Hey, why are you
guys staring at the wall?
Oh, we're waiting
for the big unveiling.
Mmm. Well, you should
be staring at my wife.
New haircut?
No. It's her leg. She's
wearing high heels.
Because she has a sexy high-heel
leg that makes her ass go pow.
Ooh, wow!
Hey.
Whoa. Okay.
Baby got back.
Mmm-hmm. Come on, guys.
You can comment, too.
You have permission.
It's the one time in
your life you can say it...
No. And not be gross.
Well, I think it's
a fine gluteal...
No. Yeah. Let's
just do the unveiling.
No. Yeah.
Guys, I think the painters
actually just left that there.
Oh.
Let's get back to work.
Okay. End of speech.
Awesome. We are awesome.
Did you see our picture in this?
I'm at 28 weeks and I am
worried about DiGeorge syndrome.
DiGeorge? There's, like,
what, a one in 100,000?
It's too rare.
More likely it'll have a
cleft palate or a heart defect.
Wait, if your baby has
a heart defect, I will fix it.
What about phenylketonuria?
No, we screen for that at
birth and treat it with diet.
What about a giant hemangioma?
Like a huge,
out-of-control bloodsucker?
Now that's a possibility.
Or maybe a congenital cystic
adenomatoid malformation.
Again, I will operate
and do a lung transplant.
We own a hospital...
"A cutting-edge,
research-oriented hospital
"with an advanced
Level I trauma center."
Whatever's wrong with
your baby, we will fix it.
But you agree, there's
definitely something wrong?
Oh, my God. Marcus Cho?
Who's Marcus Cho?
He's like a
high-functioning moron
who was a year
behind me at Stanford.
And he just got published
with his attending for...
No. No. For what?
Robot-assisted surgery
for mitral valve regurgitation!
He looks kinda smart.
He's a moron.
I heard there was an OB using
forceps during a breech delivery.
Pulled a little too hard and...
Pop.
Now that's what
I'm talking about.
We'll let these fluids
go in for a few hours
and then set you up
for chemo this afternoon.
Who's gonna set me
up, you or Dr. Wilson?
Dr. Wilson.
She's been begging
for more time with you.
Did you cry?
I have that effect
on the ladies.
I'll bet you do.
Hey. Hey, sorry. You got a sec?
Yeah. Pablo, this is Dr. Myers.
Hey, what's up, Pablo?
I just want to say, I
have that C-section in 20
if you wanted to watch,
unless you're busy.
Watch you actually
do a real surgery?
Yeah, you can criticize my scalpel
technique, which is awesome.
Dr. Karev?
Uh...
We're slow. I don't care.
Whoa!
Oh! Oh! Whoa.
Uh... This popped
out. Is that bad? Sorry.
Hey, don't sweat it, little man.
I'm not little. I'm 12.
My growth was stunted
by a lifetime of cancer.
I'll check in later. Okay?
Did you do that on purpose?
Is she going out
with that nozzle?
I hate him.
Well, the guy's a
doctor. You can't do that.
You know what else we should do?
What?
And get to know the
new electronic board.
It automatically updates
the location of your patients
and any labs that
have been ordered.
And we now have
workstations at every bed,
which are fully integrated
with the new charting system.
And the beds are now numbered
differently, so just pay attention.
And now what you have
all been waiting for...
The Lodox, low-dose
radiation x-ray statscanner.
It provides full-body
anterior and lateral views.
The low radiation
makes imaging safer
for children and pregnant women.
It is our most cutting-edge
tool in diagnostic technology.
Murphy. When can we use it?
Oh! I'll volunteer.
When I was six, I stuck a marble
up my nose, and
it never came out.
We checked my
stool for over a year.
Listen, this is not a toy.
I know we all want to
see this thing in action.
But be patient. The
last thing we need
is some line forming when
some real trauma comes in.
Chief Hunt, we've got an
ATV accident two minutes out.
And here we go.
Oh! Dr. Avery.
Hey, I know you've
been thinking about
raising the profile
of the hospital.
Not today, Dr. Bailey.
Today I am going to the ER
to find something to operate on.
Well, I have a proposal for a Grey
Sloan human genome mapping program
that'll cost less than
Chicago's program.
No money. We spent
it on the new ER.
Okay, if you and the
other board members
would just read over the...
I am a doctor today, Bailey.
Okay. Okay.
What have we got?
16-year-old female.
ATV collision. GCS is six.
Open depressed skull
fracture with active bleeding.
Let's take her to Lodox.
Get a statscan before
we take her to trauma.
They're using the
Lodox. The Lodox?
Oh, someone say "Lodox"?
Got here just in time.
Sweet. This is gonna be great.
All right, everyone. Let's
get ready for this transfer.
All right, on my count.
Hold on.
She's bleeding
through these bandages.
Ross, ABP pads.
Got it.
Uh... It looks like it's
a branch of the MCA.
Pressure's not
gonna tamponade it.
We need to get her
straight to the OR.
Page Shepherd.
Ross, you're on this.
She's right here.
What about the Lodox?
She needs an intraoperative CT.
It'll only take 13 seconds.
We don't have 13
seconds to spare.
She could stroke out at
any second. Let's move!
Let's go!
You guys want to
look for my marble?
Mr. Kramer.
Our best neurosurgeon,
Dr. Shepherd,
just started operating
on your daughter.
You're gonna fix her, right?
Well, she sustained a
lot of damage to the brain.
Since she wasn't
wearing a helmet...
She was wearing a helmet.
We have been riding every
weekend since she was 13 years old.
I would never let her
near a bike without one.
We stopped to take a picture.
She took her helmet off for a minute,
and that idiot comes
flying out of nowhere.
I swear to God,
I am gonna hunt that
son of a bitch down
and I am gonna
crack his skull open.
We're gonna do
everything we can...
So what are you
standing here for?
Get in there!
Dr. Yang, you got a sec?
I don't. I'm looking
for Dr. Russell.
Well, I'm looking for funding.
You're pitching me now?
Yeah. You're on the board.
And I have been
postponing research
to write policy to
become, like, a lawyer,
while people like Marcus
Cho are out there doing it.
We should be doing it.
Don't you want
this hospital to be on
the cutting edge of
medical research?
Exactly. We're on the same page.
Okay. Then you'll fund
my genome project.
What? No.
I need to find some badass,
earth-shattering cardio research
I can get in on. Okay...
I can't tell you how
happy I am to hear that.
Dr. Russell, I need
to be put to work.
I need to know what research
projects you have pending...
Great. What are you
doing this afternoon?
Oh.
I think I have just
the procedure for you.
I got a page.
I'm sorry. Do you know
who needed a GYN consult?
No, I don't know.
Dr. Grey.
Do you need a GYN? Nope.
Then who paged me?
Can I help you?
Well, I noticed your patient
has acute abdominal pain.
Any chest pains?
Because if you wanted to put her
through the Lodox
for a full body scan,
you could.
If you wanted, you
know, to use the Lodox.
Do I need a full body scan?
It only takes 13 seconds.
No, you don't.
No Lodox. Thank you.
Oh...
So recently,
the pain has been getting worse?
I thought I had the stomach flu.
Mmm-hmm.
I drown myself in
that sanitizer stuff,
but when you're teaching
kids, they're just little germ bags.
I've been out for a week.
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's been great for me. I haven't
taken a day off in 28 years.
You know how many
cooking shows they have now?
I don't.
It turns out, I love
watching people cook things.
And then this morning,
the pain was so bad,
I couldn't move, so I
called the ambulance.
Okay, Madeline, so from what I'm
seeing here, it looks like gallstones.
Oh, God. Does that mean surgery?
It does.
But the good news is, we
can do it laparoscopically,
which means no big incisions
and very little recovery time.
And I'll take them out,
and you'll be on your way.
Well, I get to watch some
more people cook stuff.
Okay, so I'm gonna get
them started on admitting you.
You just sit tight.
Great. Thank you.
Did you just update
your patient file?
Mmm-hmm. Watch this.
So cool!
You do get excited about things.
Yes, I do. Hey, how's that baby?
It probably has
three arms and a tail.
How's your paramedic boyfriend?
Terrible.
I mean, great.
Perfect. Just not... I probably
have to break up with him.
Why?
Okay, are you really asking?
Because I really
need to talk about this.
Well, now I'm not
sure I'm asking.
Okay.
Matthew's never
been to the carnival.
And he thinks
that I haven't either
because that's what I told him,
but I have. I'm sorry.
And you want to go to
the carnival together?
Because I've been
already and I rode the rides.
Oh. You went to the
carnival with Jackson.
I have ridden the
rides and they are good.
The tilt-a-whirl
and then that one
that spins around
when your back is
up against the wall
and then the floor falls out
from underneath your feet.
And I want Matthew to go
with me, but he wants to wait,
which is why he's perfect,
because that's what I want.
I always wanted to
wait, but I didn't wait.
And now I just, every night,
push him closer and closer.
And I feel like
I'm just gonna slip
and buy him a ticket and
shove him on the tilt-a-whirl,
and then he's gonna love it,
and I will have corrupted him.
And I'm not a corrupter.
Well, I don't know why
you're talking to me about this.
I am a big fan of the carnival
and I go every chance I get.
Yes, I know, but...
Okay, so your whole thing
is, God has a plan, right?
Yeah.
Well, there must be a reason why
God let you go to
the carnival already.
Maybe you're supposed
to take Matthew.
You're right, I should not
be talking to you about this.
Fancy new ER, and all
I've done is splint a pinkie?
This is why we
bought a hospital?
Hey. If we get off at a decent
time, and we put
Sofia down early,
and I could make
dinner, and we could...
Really?
Really.
So, you think tonight?
Is definitely the night.
For sex, right? We're
talking about sex?
The sexy night. Okay.
Ladies, hey, just the two
people I was looking for.
Walk away, Bailey.
No, no, I need to speak
to board members,
and I remember you all
giving me some kind of crap
about how the door's
always open, so...
But right now it's closed.
One minute. It's
the wrong minute.
Are you kidding me?
Okay, what happened
to the new hospital,
run by doctors,
all about doctors?
Okay, well, it...
What happened is, my wife's
new leg is making her feel sexy.
And we haven't had
sex in a long time.
I mean, we've done stuff,
don't get me wrong.
But we haven't done other stuff,
and other stuff is
happening tonight.
So that's what we were talking
about when you interrupted us...
Walking away.
- You warned her.
- I did.
Mmm-hmm.
Meredith Grey, I want to talk to
you about human genome mapping.
Right now? Yes, right now.
I'm operating.
Exactly. I have you
cornered. You can't walk away
or start talking about
the sexual antics
you're going to
engage in tonight.
But you can listen.
Bailey. Now!
Genetic mapping can lead us to
developing targeted
therapies for diseases.
Oh, no. Oh, yes,
precision medicine, where we
treat illness at its molecular source
instead of just dealing
with the consequences.
What's this?
What it is is the future of
medicine. It's a way that we...
No, Bailey. Shut up.
Please. You're removing a gallstone.
You can do that in your sleep.
No, it's not gallstones.
Oh. It's calcified.
Okay, well, you'll need to do a
biopsy and maybe open her up.
But don't think the worst.
This is a hard mass.
This is cancer.
Crap. It's spread to the liver.
If she was teaching until
last week, it can't be that bad.
All right, if we resect part of
the liver maybe we can get it all.
It's worth a try.
Mmm. Oh.
Look at that.
It's encasing the hepatic
artery and the bile duct.
We could continue, but
we can't take the artery.
It's unresectable.
Well, let's finish up and close.
You have to take that much off?
I need the exposure.
There's more damage
than we could see on the CT.
It's been a few hours.
I'd really like to get
an update to the father.
Okay, but just so you know,
he's kind of a big, angry maniac.
You can handle it.
Of course. I'll just make
sure security's close by.
Look, Ross, this is an arena
in which I know you excel.
Just start with the
positive news, be confident,
and don't make any
promises you can't keep.
You're my voice out there.
I'll channel you.
It'll be fine. Yes.
I'm Derek Shepherd.
It's a beautiful
day to save lives.
I'll channel you
in my own voice.
Thank you.
This is the lotus valve.
We're doing a lotus valve.
50% of people with
aortic valve defects
don't survive a
year after diagnosis.
But the lotus valve
is noninvasive.
It minimizes aortic regurge,
doesn't need balloon inflation
or rapid pacing of the heart,
so less stress on the
body, less blood loss, less...
Well, you're
obviously up to speed.
I've been dying
to get in on this
ever since you started testing.
Outstanding.
The results of phase
two have been amazing.
Phase three should be a hoot.
God, you can retract and
resheath before you deploy.
Exactly. That's the
best thing about it.
You have total control
over the entire procedure.
It's incredibly flexible if you
don't get it right the first time.
But I imagine you will.
Me?
I wondered if you might like to
try your hand at
placing the valve.
Oh, my God. Yes.
Thank you, sir.
Dr. Jason Myers to the ER.
Nobody's tried it yet?
No, not yet.
That is sad. This is
a beautiful machine.
It is sad.
It's like a carnival ride
with all the lights turned off,
just sitting there
going to waste.
It would be so fun...
And it cost us a lot of
money just to be pretty.
Why would God present
us with this gorgeous thing,
just put it right
in front of us,
and then want us not to use it?
I don't think God was involved.
The board paid for it, so...
And we definitely
want it to get used.
Okay, one of you
two paged me, right?
No, I didn't. Nope.
He went to the ER.
Then ortho, then back to the ER,
and then he went
to the cafeteria.
The cafeteria? What a tool.
Yeah.
Dr. Jason Myers to proctology.
Wait. Listen.
All right. Well, that was fun, but
I have actual doctor work to do.
Damn.
I got a great idea
for the next one.
Come on.
But if you want to deny
my dying cancer wish...
So I'm gonna die from this?
Is that what you're saying?
There is no cure for nonresectable
late-stage gallbladder cancer.
Chemo may give
you more time, but
it has not been shown
to provide a cure.
I'm sorry.
Ms. Skurski?
You guys, what
are you doing here?
Mr. Arnold said you
were in the hospital.
Dr. Grey, these are
some of my students,
who are supposed to be at their
after-school study session now
with their substitute.
What are you doing
here? Mr. Arnold sucks.
Lucas, we don't say "sucks."
Sorry. He's just a jerk.
He sends, like, five people
a day to the principal's office.
And we never get free time,
even after we finish our homework.
And his breath
smells really bad.
You're coming back soon, right?
Of course.
Don't worry.
I'm...
I'll be good as new really soon.
Isn't that right, Dr. Grey?
Yes.
Yes, that's right.
The good news is her
vitals have been stable.
But her injuries are extensive.
We'll be operating
for several more hours.
Wait. What does
that mean, extensive?
It's hard to say.
Susie's suffered damage
to the parts of her brain that
control speech, motor functions...
She's paralyzed? My
little girl is paralyzed?
No, no, I mean,
paralysis is a possibility,
but we can't tell what kind of
deficits she'll have until she wakes...
What kind of things are
you expecting? How bad?
There might not be any.
Which one is it, are
there or aren't there?
At this time, it's too early...
You said she might
not be able to speak.
We don't know...
What the hell do you know?
I know this must
be scary for you...
Damn right, because
you don't know anything.
Don't talk to me till you
know what's going on,
or get me someone who does!
I know I shouldn't have
lied right in my kids' faces.
I kinda pride myself
on not doing that.
I just couldn't tell
them. I just couldn't.
Maybe there's a way
to help prepare them.
Maybe it would
make you feel better.
I teach them science and math.
I teach them things that make
sense, and this doesn't make sense.
I...
Yesterday, I was watching TV.
I was happy to have a little
break from school,
and today, I...
I'm probably not even
gonna make it to finals.
Their parents will
have to tell them. I...
I... Or Mr. Arnold. I just
don't know what I would say.
This sucks!
We don't say
"sucks," but this sucks.
I only have a dog bite and
two patients with the flu.
I have a sprained ankle.
Yeah, let's do that.
Get him in the machine.
He doesn't need
a full body scan.
It's a really bad sprain.
I have a stomachache.
Stomachache could be
a tumor, kidney stones.
No, I have a stomachache.
We spent hundreds of
thousands of dollars on that thing,
and it's just sitting there.
Okay, how bad is the sprain?
What?
Ow.
That ass does not quit.
These heels are killing
me. What was I thinking?
I mean, heels were a pain
even before I had a plastic leg.
Why'd I think it'd
be better now?
Can I take a look? Nope.
Oh. Well, I just
might be able to help.
You're not my
doctor. You're my wife.
Here we go.
What?
We're not gonna
have sex tonight.
I... Who said...
Who said that we're not
gonna have sex tonight?
That's what you're saying.
You just told me your leg hurts
so that tonight when I put on my
drop-dead gorgeous underwear,
you're gonna tell me to
change into my sweats.
And then when I
look disappointed,
you're gonna say, "Please
don't make that face, Callie.
"You know that my leg's
been bothering me today,"
and...
What kind of manipulative
bitch do you think I am?
You're not manipulative
and you're not a bitch.
Okay? I'm a bitch. Yeah.
You are uncomfortable like you
have been for a very long time now,
and if I were a
really good person,
I would continue to be patient,
but apparently, I'm not.
A GYN patient just came in.
This time I have a name. Talia.
If you can find her,
you can treat her.
I'm looking for a Ms. Talia.
A Jenny Talia.
I'm here to see Jenny Talia.
Oh, you have got
to be kidding me.
Yeah.
Karev.
A moment.
Uh-oh.
What the hell are you doing?
Dr. Webber, I was...
Out of all the childish, sophomoric
things to do to someone,
this may be the most pathetic.
Come on. Look at the kid.
He lives in this hospital. He
never gets to have any fun.
What's the big deal?
The big deal is, I thought
you were better than this.
Jenny Talia?
You need to up your game.
You're cutting right
into her frontal lobe.
Calm down, Ross.
Her whole personality
could be affected.
Her memory could be gone, and
that man out there is gonna kill me.
Did I ever tell you about the
first time I went fly-fishing?
No.
Yeah, I went out to the Hoh
River to fish winter steelhead.
For hours, I tried to
cast like I'd practiced.
But if you over try,
it'll never happen.
And then just once,
the rod loaded perfectly.
The line formed a tight loop,
and the fly just danced out
over the river about 70 feet.
It had a life of its own.
See, the key was to relax,
feel the rhythm, and
let the rod do the work.
Just one perfect cast.
Why'd you tell me that?
Did it calm you down?
Yeah. Mmm-hmm.
Right now I am about to remove
a hematoma from broca's area.
And if I am not careful,
she'll never speak again.
There is a lot to be afraid of.
Patients will be afraid.
Parents will be afraid.
And the only way to get
through it is for you to stay calm.
The brain is swelling.
What are we gonna do about that?
We're gonna...
We're gonna give
her more Mannitol.
Good.
That was amazing.
The valve started operating
before I fully released it.
Incredible, right?
And almost no
paravalvular leakage?
Revolutionary technology,
and the rate of success with
phase two has been astounding.
Well, when do we
start phase three?
Well, that's up to you, really.
Up to me?
You're giving phase three to me?
No. No. It's my trial.
I don't need another surgeon.
What I need from you is $12
million so I can keep it going,
for patient recruitment,
research staff, lab space.
I want to make Grey Sloan the
premier destination for this procedure.
I thought you were
bringing me on to this.
You're pitching me.
It's nice to finally
have someone
on the board who
gets what I'm doing.
This is exactly
what I was afraid of.
The administrative crap
is taking over my career.
Russell called me
"someone on the board."
I mean, he doesn't even
see me as a surgeon.
I'm just someone
who cuts budgets.
Stop kicking in there.
I mean, what are you, choking
on your cord or something?
Cristina, please talk to it.
He or she. Who?
The baby. No.
The sound of my voice
only makes it kick harder.
For some reason,
Derek can calm it down.
Maybe you can, too.
You know, I'll talk
to it when I see it.
When she gets her first
period. I'll take that off your plate.
Or if it has a penis, I'll
tell him not to think with it.
Ow! Cristina,
please just talk to it.
Hello.
This is Cristina.
Yang.
I don't know. What do
you want me to say?
Anything. Just talk.
Get up.
Hey, this is Miranda Bailey.
I am an excellent surgeon
and a forward thinker.
Your mother's a surgeon.
Your father is a surgeon.
You'll very likely
want to be one, too.
But I'm hoping by
the time it's your turn,
there will be very
little surgery left
because human genome mapping
will have given people information
so that they can fight their
diseases before they happen.
Keep talking. It's working.
Armed with information, people will
be able to live longer, healthier lives.
Now I know this is a very
expensive undertaking,
but maybe if you
hadn't spent so much
money on coffee
sleeves and new logos,
there'd be money in the budget
to fund a forward thinker like me.
I think she's talking to us now.
Look, here is my proposal,
which I've made to you
because you're in charge.
Which is messed up,
but I'm not gonna go there
because I want your money.
We are in charge.
I am in charge.
I am gonna crush Marcus
Cho because I am in charge.
Wait. Don't leave. I...
Hey, Cristina,
please talk to it.
Ow.
Okay, right.
Okay.
That was the
ambulance from earlier.
They thought they left one
of their backboards here.
They found it.
All right. Brooks.
What are you doing? Hop in.
Really? Mmm-hmm.
Let's find that marble, and the
rest of you, line up and watch.
At the very least,
we're going to
figure out how to
run this damn thing.
Chief, we got a motorcycle
accident coming in.
Extensive crush
injuries. Hop out.
But it only takes 13
seconds. Out now.
And the rest of you,
let's prep for incoming.
Dr. Marsha Lowe to the ER.
Is that a specimen cup?
Yeah.
Did you place a warm
cup of pee next to me?
It's my urine sample. What,
should I go put it on your desk?
If you want to die.
But the memo says
that you're in charge
of the random drug test policy.
Okay, whatever drugs
you are doing, stop!
Mmm-hmm.
Ew.
What was that about?
That's what happens
when the hospital's slow.
The doctors start
punking each other.
Oh. Well, I just
wanted to let you know
that we found funding
for your project.
Oh, I get it.
You popular kids are punking me,
like this is some high
school volleyball team.
Well, I do not want to play
varsity that bad, Kimberly.
Bailey, you get your
genome lab, for real.
Yeah, right.
Yeah, Cristina just assembled
a quick board meeting.
Now we haven't dotted all
the I's or crossed all the T's yet,
but it looks like you're
gonna get your funding.
But Avery said there
wasn't any more money.
Yeah, well, one of the other
departments cut their budget.
You're cutting my budget?
Just by a couple million.
I asked you for
more money, not less.
I'll have to lose a resident,
a research assistant...
Probably two
of each. Sorry.
Wait. Wait.
What does that leave me with?
It leaves you with me.
To do the work of four people?
I am the best four people you
will ever have working for you.
I will treat your patients,
take your surgeries,
and assist in research, including
projects I find on my own.
Feel free to pile it on.
But I can't possibly...
The board believes you can.
Dr. Sanchez to Oncology.
Well...
I told Bailey she's
getting her genome lab.
She was so happy.
She looked great.
That's fantastic.
Hey, are you okay?
Yeah. I'm just... I'm
really happy for Bailey.
No, you're in pain. You've
been standing all day.
Here. Sit down.
You know, I really... I don't...
I don't want to keep
saying yes and then
not following
through with it, okay?
I really don't.
No,
I'm a jerk for putting
pressure on you.
You know what? I think
that I can try. I can try.
It's just... I need
to adjust this thing.
Let me help.
Callie, don't.
I am an orthopedic surgeon.
Let me try.
Give me your hands.
Now. Can you remove
your pants, please?
Yeah.
Okay, I got you.
Okay.
Whoa! That's not fixing
it. That's taking it off!
Look at me.
I'm gonna put my
hand on your leg.
No, Callie. Don't.
The prosthetic is not the
problem. Your leg's your problem.
I deal with residual
limbs every single day.
It's... They get sore.
Yeah.
Is that okay?
It feels better.
You know I could... I could
give you a massage, too.
With your girlie
hands? Forget it.
Thank you, Callie.
Hey. Right now I'm Dr. Torres.
This came for you.
But I don't know if you
want to see it. It's not my call.
They're here, aren't they?
A lot of them.
They're in the lobby.
But I can also say that
you can't have visitors.
Three, two, one.
All right. He's all set.
Avery, would you do the honors?
Six, seven,
eight, nine,
ten, 11, 12...
Thirteen.
Look at that.
It's worth every penny.
You can see the
fractures of both legs
and of the proximal aspect
of the right radius and ulna
all in the same x-ray.
It would've taken,
like, 15 scans
to get that much
information before.
It's freakin' magical.
It was definitely
worth waiting for.
Yeah.
Okay. Let's get
him out of there.
Are you ready?
Good news first, stay calm.
Can I hear the fishing
story one more time?
Come on.
What took you so long?
Mr. Kramer, the good news
is, your daughter's alive.
Until she wakes up...
No, no, no. No, don't,
don't, don't, don't you do that!
Hey! Whoa! Look, sir, please!
You're not gonna tell
me that. You do not...
No! Listen!
Your daughter is
alive, you hear me?
Listen to me. Your
daughter is alive.
She's alive.
And we hope she's gonna wake up,
but we don't know
what's gonna happen.
Okay? Her vitals are stable.
But it doesn't do
you or her any good
to be afraid of
what we don't know.
Let's get cleaned up, and
you can go see her, okay?
She always wears a helmet.
She...
I make sure...
I know.
I always...
Mr. Arnold always yells.
Well, he's probably frustrated.
I know you don't like
him because he's not me,
but you didn't like
me at first, did you?
But at least you gave us free
time if we finished our homework.
Maybe you should
tell him that that's
how I did it and
that it motivated you.
Right?
If...
Mr. Arnold were going to be
your teacher for the rest of the year,
what else could
you do to help him?
Someone could offer him a mint.
That's a great idea.
But not in a mean way.
Just casually, right?
What else?
Don't skip after-school
study sessions?
You got it.
But he's not gonna be our
teacher for the rest of the year.
Is he?
You're not gonna come back...
Are you?
What...
What would happen if I didn't?
It'd suck.
Sorry.
No, you're right.
It'd suck.
Now...
What else can we
do to help Mr. Arnold?
Come on. Help me think.
What happened to cool and calm?
Yeah, well, that never would've
worked with a guy like this.
Sometimes you gotta
shake the hell out of 'em.
Hey. You ready?
Yeah.
Page me with updates.
Rough one? Very.
Me, too.
How's the baby, still kicking?
Quiet now. Probably dead.
Oh, Meredith, stop.
Well, I'm just kidding.
Mostly.
Really, I need you to stop.
Bad things happen,
and it just makes me feel better
to be prepared when they do.
But you don't know how
things are gonna turn out.
Right. Exactly what I'm saying.
We own a hospital
full of machines.
Let's go find out
everything we can.
He actually gave
Dr. Bailey his pee.
Anybody find out about this,
I'm throwing you under the bus.
You're not scared of this guy.
No, I'm scared of Dr. Bailey.
Hey, Karev.
Think he's onto us?
That was pretty funny today.
The pranks, the
drug test, the pages...
You guys, you really got me.
Yeah, well, the kid's got
a little crush on Wilson.
We were just
having a little fun.
The kid does. Right.
Well, you two kids have
fun laughing about it later
while I'm nailing Jo in
the bathroom at the bar.
Hey.
At first, idleness can seem
like a welcome distraction...
The troublemaking and the fun.
She is asleep.
Holy mother of...
Could you massage my leg again?
Uh-huh. Yeah.
A little higher.
There?
Nope. Higher.
Everyone needs some idle time to
focus on something other than work...
even if it means focusing on
something that's a little bit scary.
Are you nervous?
No. Just take a look,
and then we'll know.
Ugh. Is there a huge teratoma
growing out of its head?
See for yourself.
Aw, hey.
Look at you.
"Avery's too young," I said.
"He's too inexperienced," I said.
"He has no business
running this hospital."
Where you going
with this, Bailey?
I was wrong is where I'm going.
You all made a
smart decision today.
I'm not gonna disappoint
you. Thank you.
Stepping back from work is
the only way to get perspective.
Hey.
What's all that?
Russell put me on
the lotus valve trials.
I have to get through
most of this tonight.
Is he piling it
on a little heavy?
Yes, he is.
Are you gonna stay late
and play with your new toys?
They're not toys.
One, two,
three, four...
But they are pretty fun.
Five, six...
Oh! I see the marble.
Seven, eight...
Nine, 10.
See? 10 fingers.
And it's only after we have
everything in perspective...
Eleven.
That's not a finger.
It's a boy.
That we remember where
our hands truly belong.