Previously on Grey's Anatomy...
I love you.
I love everything about you.
I get to change lives!
That's the dream!
Fine, I don't want
to go to Africa.
I found out that I'm
pregnant with Mark's baby.
Are you in or are you
out? ARIZONA: I'm in.
Oh, my God!
Callie! Callie!
I choose you to be the one
with whom I spend my life.
Uh, I can't keep doing
this alone, Arizona.
I thought we were
past the hard stuff.
We have a child! I know!
How could you do this? I
don't want to fix us anymore.
This is Penny.
Callie's moving to New York.
And she's trying to
take Sofia with her.
You hired a lawyer.
You started this.
There's this Bible story.
Two women, both claim to be
the mother of the same child.
My client is prepared to
offer scheduled visitation
every other weekend.
King Solomon had to choose.
That is ridiculous,
and she knows it.
Sofia cannot take a six-hour
flight by herself twice a month.
That would be a
hard no. Hold, please.
Two mothers. Only
one gets the kid.
We knew they'd shoot that down.
They are shooting
everything down
because they're
being unreasonable.
They have the luxury of
being unreasonable right now.
We have less than
12 hours to try to settle.
Their witness lineup is
better, and they know it.
We have Richard Webber.
Maybe we should
put April on the stand.
Kepner? No!
We're not calling a witness
you just fired as a patient.
But she's seen me with
Sofia more than anyone,
and she's a good
person. She'll tell the truth.
No, she's a wild
card. It's too risky.
Webber's good. He better be.
What is your client prepared
to offer as an alternative?
Solomon came up with a
plan. He proposed a 50/50 split.
Visitation rights for Dr. Robbins
on school breaks and summers.
That puts us right
back where we started.
Literally. He offered
to chop the kid in half.
It's a reasonable compromise.
Yeah, well, you can take your
compromise and shove it up your...
Oh, no. You know
what? You can...
Arizona, look at me. We
are at an impasse here.
If we don't settle,
if we go to trial,
you risk losing it all.
Only one of you is walking out
of that court with sole custody.
I am painfully aware of that.
Then I urge you to
consider their offer.
Their offer is insulting.
And last time I checked,
you work for me.
That would be a hard no. Hold.
It all ends if one mom
relinquishes her custody.
Gamble.
We're here.
Or else they both
stand their ground.
We'll see you in court.
And the kid gets torn apart.
Hi, Sofia!
Mer will be down in a second.
I'm so sorry about this.
Please. It's the best
way to spend a day off.
Hey, I'm thinking
pancakes for breakfast.
With chocolate chips?
Crazytown!
Let's do it.
Does, um, Sofia
know anything about
what her mommies
are doing today? Nope.
We're gonna talk to her after we
know exactly what's happening.
Hey. You ready?
Hey. Come here.
Come here. Oh, I'm
gonna miss you so much.
You know what?
Mama loves you so, so much.
I will see you again
before you know it.
I know.
You're hugging me too tight.
You're hugging me too long.
Callie, we have to go.
We don't want to be late.
Come on. Come on.
Come on. Come on. Okay.
Hey. Let's go find Zola!
Hey.
She's gonna be fine.
She's with Maggie.
Okay, come on.
Come on.
It's gonna be okay.
This one is deeper
than I would like.
I'll stitch it up.
You have to go.
Is the baby okay?
Let's take a look.
Jenny?
Hi, Tara.
I heard you fell.
On some dishes.
I was washing them and, uh,
got soapy water all over the floor.
Then I slipped. I told
her I would do them later.
- She's nesting, I think.
- Mom, cut it out.
There is the baby's
heartbeat, nice and steady,
and the baby's active, which
is exactly what you want.
I fell really hard.
Are you sure?
Well, the baby looks great,
but I see some free
fluid in your abdomen.
It might be bleeding.
Or amniotic fluid.
Jenny, I'm gonna have to
take you up and have a look.
Surgery? No. No surgery.
I don't want to go
through that again.
It's nothing. I'm gonna
make a small incision,
put a scope in there, make
sure everything's all right.
You'll be there,
right? I'm sorry.
Actually, I wish I
could. Today I can't.
Dr. Russo will monitor the baby.
He's the OB on
call, and he's great.
I will be there, though. I'm happy
to. Don't you need to get going?
Yeah. Um, I will check in later.
Um, Russo's good, but he can be
a little old-school, just so you know.
All right. Go. Okay.
I can't believe you
dumped Kyle with a note.
Brutal. Yeah, not
my finest moment.
That's like dumping
someone by text, only in 1980.
Remind me why you
broke up with him at all?
You know why. I know.
It's just that he's so hot
and he's into you
and he plays guitar,
and he's sick, so you
always know where he is.
Wow. I know.
You had to choose
between doctor and girlfriend.
You made the right
choice. Thank you.
However, there are countless
other brains to cut into
but a limited number
of butts like his.
Keep your eyes on your own butt.
Hey.
Well, I, uh, ground
the beans myself.
Thanks. Let's go.
Wait, wait.
We have a few minutes.
How you feeling?
Robbins.
It'll be tough, but right now,
you have to look past the pain
to what you'll have
when they're done.
"At the end, you'll
have a baby."
That's what I tell all
the laboring moms.
You're not drinking. Oh, okay.
We're here today
to determine a custody
modification of a minor
between two divorced parents,
Arizona Robbins
and Calliope Torres.
The trial's witness
pool is unusual
in that it'll be shared
by both parents.
The parties have stipulated
to call each witness once,
at which time, each
side will have a chance
to examine that witness.
If you're testifying, remember,
this is not a popularity contest.
You are not choosing sides.
We're all on the same side,
the side of a 6-year-old child.
Dr. Torres, Dr. Robbins,
custody hearings
are, without exception,
very difficult on
all parties involved,
your daughter included.
Things said here will
undoubtedly be harsh
and cannot be unsaid.
I ask this of parents before
I begin any custody hearing.
Are you both sure
you want to proceed?
Yes, Your Honor. I'm sure.
Dr. Torres.
I'm sure, Your Honor.
Then this court
is now in session
to determine sole
physical custody
of Sofia Robbin Sloan Torres.
Dr. Torres and I worked
together on a pro bono project
building prosthetics
for injured vets.
And that's a very
meaningful project for you
because you're a vet
yourself. Is that correct?
Yes, I served as a
surgeon in the Army.
Charity work and the vet card.
That's smart.
Yeah, it's not good for Robbins.
What was the
connection for Dr. Torres?
Well, she just cares.
While she didn't serve,
she's always been
willing to pitch in, to help.
She's a very empathetic person.
Big-hearted.
Has Dr. Torres discussed her
move to New York with you?
She has. Did you feel
it was a sudden move?
Um, well, not for her.
I mean, it was sudden
because Dr. Blake's
schedule determined the move,
but for Callie, no.
This is who she is.
She gets thrown a
situation, it doesn't daunt her.
It inspires her.
I've seen it time and
time again in the OR.
She just jumps in.
And this is no different.
She's found a great
school for Sofia,
and she's making the best
of a tough situation with grace.
It's something I
admire about her.
No further
questions at this time.
You live with
Dr. Robbins, don't you?
I rent a room in her house.
I bet you never expected
to be living with a 6-year-old.
Yeah, sure. I wasn't, uh,
thrilled to be living with a kid
uh, till I started
living with one.
I had never been
around a lot of kids before,
but Sofia's a blast.
She's so smart and hilarious.
I mean, she and her mom
are just laughing all the time.
The place is so happy.
Sofia makes the place happy.
We see so much dark
stuff every day at work.
It's really nice to come
home to a happy kid.
Mmm.
So, would you
say you love Sofia?
I... I have come to.
Yes. Oh, that's nice.
And how long have
you known Sofia now?
Well, we met a few months ago.
Oh, and how well would you
say you've gotten to know Sofia
in the few months that you've
spent together, Dr. Blake?
Very well.
Oh! Very well. That's good.
That's, uh, very good.
What's her favorite color?
Blue. Her favorite toy?
Objection. Irrelevant.
This isn't a quiz show.
I'm trying to establish the nature of
Dr. Blake's relationship with Sofia.
I'll allow it.
Her favorite toy is
Astronaut Barbie.
Her favorite cereal
is Whole Grain O's.
Her favorite
animal is a unicorn.
Her favorite sea
creature is a mermaid.
And her bedtime is 8:30.
And her favorite thing
to do in the morning
is pick out her outfit.
You can ask me
anything you want.
5 millimeter scope.
Why aren't you there? In court?
Why aren't you there?
I've seen enough
people fighting over kids.
I've had enough of
fighting over my own,
and mine's not even born yet.
Well, there's the free fluid.
Suction irrigator, please.
How are we looking
here, Dr. Karev?
Uh, well, that's not blood.
Oh, no. RUSSO:
Looks like amniotic fluid.
Show me the uterine
fundus, please.
Damn it. Uterus is perforated.
Let me have a look
there. Thank you.
Getting fluid in her abdomen.
This pregnancy has
just become non-viable.
This baby's barely
viable outside that womb.
It's only 24 weeks.
You can repair it, can't you?
- I can try.
Throw in a plasma
patch, hope for the best.
- "Hope for the best"?
- It's experimental.
But if we want to
prolong this pregnancy...
Of course we do. RUSSO:
Then a patch is the way to go.
Five seconds ago,
you wanted to deliver.
Now you're confident
in a plasma patch?
Dr. Karev, I am
the OB on call here.
You are a peds surgeon.
If I say that a patch
is best, a patch is best.
Kepner?
If it keeps the baby
in, I vote for the patch.
Stay in your lane, Dr. Karev.
Prep albumin polymers, please.
I'll update the mom.
How'd it go? How's Jenny?
Well, she's still in
surgery but doing great.
We located the
source of the leak,
and Dr. Russo's
repairing it right now.
And the baby?
The baby is healthy
and still in utero,
which is what we want.
It's too little to
be born, right?
It wouldn't be ideal.
I need you to sign one more
form for Dr. Russo's repair.
It seems like I was just here
signing these for
Jenny's last surgery.
I just had a feeling.
I said goodbye. I left for work.
I was two blocks away
and I had an awful,
just sick feeling.
I turned around, I drove
home, and there she was.
On the floor, blood everywhere.
I just had a terrible feeling
that something was really wrong.
It's a good thing you did.
And your work schedule will
be pretty grueling, I'd imagine.
Actually, it's a
research fellowship,
so it will be far
more predictable
than a surgery
resident's schedule.
Oh, I see.
What was Sofia
wearing this morning?
What? What was
she wearing today?
I...
I don't know. You didn't
see her this morning?
No, I did. I just...
I can't, uh, recall
exactly what it...
Objection. Relevance.
Moving on.
What grade is Sofia in?
Second.
No, first.
She's in first grade.
I have to go, and this
is getting hard to watch.
Are you sure? PENNY: Yes.
Because you didn't sound sure,
and you keep saying this
is a child that you know,
a child that you're
gonna soon co-parent.
I can see how you
might not remember
what color tutu she
wore to school today,
but to not even know
what grade she's in...
So many objections.
Badgering, irrelevant...
Sustained. I'm sorry.
I don't mean to belabor the
point, but you said it yourself.
You've only known
Sofia a few months, so...
No, that is not what I meant.
But that is what you said.
All right, Counselor.
I know what grade she's in.
I do. I do.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
Maybe it wasn't that bad.
That was really, really bad.
Oh, God.
But it doesn't kill us. Not yet.
I can't believe Arizona
let them pull that slimy bull.
It was a smart
move, and it worked.
But we've got smarter moves.
I'm gonna put Dr. Grey
on the stand tomorrow,
and she's gonna close strong.
Look confident.
You're the Chief of Surgery.
Doctors Torres and
Robbins report to you.
That is correct.
And for those of us
who aren't surgeons,
Dr. Torres operates on bones
while Dr. Robbins
operates on babies.
Is that correct?
Well, fetuses and babies.
Yes.
How does the schedule
of an orthopedic surgeon
compare to that
of a fetal surgeon?
Well, it varies day to day.
I see, but in your opinion,
which specialty has more
unscheduled surgeries?
Ortho or fetal? There's
really no comparison.
But Dr. Robbins'
schedule is dictated
by the unpredictable
nature of childbirth, is it not?
Objection. Speculation.
She can't do that.
You can't do that.
I asked if Dr. Robbins' schedule
is dictated by the
unpredictable nature of childbirth.
Objection. Speculation.
Your Honor, I'm asking an
expert witness her opinion.
It's only speculation if
counsel is calling into question
the expertise of
this witness as Chief.
Overruled. Counselor, proceed.
Dr. Robbins' schedule is
unpredictable, wouldn't you say?
It can be, yes. Any surgeon's...
Sure, but how many unscheduled
emergency procedures
did Dr. Robbins log
over the past six months?
I have no idea.
I would like to introduce
into evidence Document 2C.
Take a look. This might
refresh your memory.
What is that report, Doctor?
This is a list of emergency
procedures performed
by Dr. Robbins and Dr. Torres
for the past six months.
And according to that document,
how many emergency
procedures did Dr. Torres log
in the past six months?
Twenty-seven. Twenty-seven.
And how many did
Dr. Robbins log?
Ninety-two.
Now, even for a surgeon,
wouldn't you call that
kind of schedule grueling?
You can say that. I wouldn't.
I would say it's
wildly successful,
but then, I would never
put a woman's success
in the con column.
What about her daughter, though?
Ninety-two.
Ninety-two times she
dropped everything,
Sofia included, to go to a job.
Would you ask that
if she were a man?
Ninety-two times she
chose work over her child.
Your Honor...
Ninety-two times
Dr. Robbins was saving babies,
saving parents from
losing their own children!
No further questions.
Don't get discouraged.
They're trying to turn your
strength into weakness.
This court is adjourned
until tomorrow.
No, over here. Right
up against the bed.
God, Mom. Just go home to sleep.
This is so embarrassing.
I'm sorry. She's a nightmare.
That's right. I'm
everybody's nightmare.
Can I have another blanket, please?
- Sure.
Hey! How's everyone feeling?
I hear you're
sleeping over tonight.
Thank God you're back. She's
nicer to me when you're around.
Surgery went well?
Yeah. Russo did a plasma patch.
Yeah, that's a good call.
This baby needs more time.
Okay, listen. I'm sorry that I
wasn't here for the surgery,
but I'll be checking
in later, okay?
I told you. Kepner and
I have Jenny handled.
She's doing fine. The baby's
good. Everyone's stable.
Um, where's Russo?
I need to look at a
post-op ultrasound
to make sure the leak is sealed.
Should you be here?
Shouldn't you be at home getting
ready for court or something?
No. I shouldn't be here.
I should be at home
fixing my daughter ice cream
and reading her Charlotte's Web.
So could you please page Russo
so I can look at the ultrasounds
and get the hell out of here?
Okay.
Thank you.
It's an impossible situation.
A break-up is tough
enough as it is,
but with a kid in the mix...
I can't even imagine.
I mean, just because you're not
the parent who gave birth to the kid
doesn't make the
kid any less yours.
Biology or not,
no parent ever fought
to stick around for me.
It was a horrible mistake.
The custody battle? Me
breaking up with Kyle.
I told you that. Who's Kyle?
He was a
once-in-a-lifetime butt.
I said that, too.
I'm calling him. Ooh.
Mmm, the drunk-dial.
It's a bad idea. I'm not drunk.
Hey! Steph, look at me.
You have 10 more
seconds to talk about him,
and then no more Kyle talk.
I said that to you. I know.
Ten, nine...
Shut up. I'm calling him.
And it is not
drunk-dialing, sir.
It is me undoing my mistake.
Okay. I...
Give it back. No.
You are a good friend.
I know.
So, what were you thinking?
Okay, um...
When the baby's born...
Starting Day 1, huh?
I would like to be in
the room for the birth.
So if that makes you
uncomfortable... No, not at all.
Really? Yeah.
Yeah, I want you there.
Okay, um...
Well, when the baby's
on a feeding schedule,
whenever that happens,
then I'm thinking weekends?
You don't want
to split the week?
I do. Yes.
But when the baby's older,
we may need to switch
to every other week.
I've read that that is
just... Easier on the child.
Yeah, I read that, too.
But I want Easter.
It's important to me.
I go to church, and you...
Worship the Easter bunny.
Right.
Now, are we talking
Easter egg hunts
or just church?
Yeah, of course there
will be an Easter egg hunt.
All right, then
Easter's all yours.
Uh, and you can have the
Super Bowl and Halloween.
Mmm, sure.
Okay, now, what
about, uh, Christmas?
We switch off.
We switch off. We,
uh, make a plan.
We respect the plan.
We don't fight.
Yeah, we don't fight.
Okay, sweetie.
Yeah, no, it's
past your bedtime.
Okay. Hey.
I love you.
Okay. No, no, no.
No, I don't want to
talk to Mommy, okay?
Okay, bye...
I feel gross.
I feel gross. Court covered
me in a layer of gross
no amount of wine can wash away.
Tequila? Mmm-mmm.
You know, you
don't have to stay.
I'll be fine alone till
Penny gets home. Mmm.
That won't be for hours.
I buried her in
scut and post-ops.
I'll call you a cab. Go
home and see your kids.
My kids are asleep.
They're with Maggie and Amelia.
What if last night
was our last night?
Stop. Don't do that.
I am doing this all wrong.
Mark used to say that.
You know...
When the kids were babies,
he used to call me all the time,
when Sofia would cry
or she got soap in her eye
and he didn't know what to do.
He called you? He had two moms!
Yeah, but the two of
you were so on top of it,
he didn't want you to know.
So he swore me to secrecy.
He would hate this.
So much.
He would find it unacceptable.
I lie awake every night
thinking maybe I started
something I shouldn't have.
I shouldn't have to choose
between the person that I love
and the person I love.
I hope you don't have to.
I tried not to love Penny, Mer.
I tried.
So hard.
I know. This all sucks.
Come on, Sofia, honey.
You had a really good time
with her yesterday, okay?
Uh-uh. Yes! You did.
You built forts and
it was really fun.
Morning! Come on
in! Hi! Here we go!
I don't want to.
I'm sorry. It's been a
really rough morning.
She woke up really early and then
she didn't have breakfast, so, uh...
That's okay. We will
make waffles, or...
I'm going with you.
I can't. Oh, I can't.
Mommy can't today.
I'm running late, and
you're here to play with Zola,
but I will be back
just as soon as I can.
No.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I love you.
I hate you.
Okay, let's go find Zola.
She'll be fine.
Hey. How's Jenny doing?
She did okay overnight,
but her mean pressure
is trending down.
I don't like it. What
does Russo say?
Russo says to watch and wait,
but I'm thinking
about texting Arizona.
Arizona doesn't
have all the answers.
She has more answers than Russo.
And you're just pissy because
she fired you as a patient.
Shut up. She's got
enough on her plate today.
Okay, look. If Russo
says watch and wait,
I say we watch and wait.
Any evidence of fetal
distress on the monitor,
just let me know, okay?
And Dr. Torres and Sofia
couldn't possibly be any closer.
So, you've seen them together
frequently over the years.
All the time. They went
to the same daycare
and now they're
at the same school.
Sofia's actually at
my house right now.
And what about Dr. Blake?
In your estimation, how
does she get along with Sofia?
Great. Sofia loves Penny.
She's a great kid like that.
She's very open to new people
as long as they're good people,
and Penny is a very good person.
Thank you, Dr. Grey.
It's your witness, Ms. Gamble.
You mentioned that Sofia is
at your house today, Dr. Grey.
She is. It must be nice
for you and Dr. Torres
to have daughters
around the same age.
And they get along,
right? It is very nice.
They love playing together.
So, who's watching your daughters
right now while you're here?
Their Aunt Amelia.
You recently lost your
husband. Is that correct?
I did.
My sincerest condolences.
Thank you.
So, you're a single parent.
I am. And Callie's
a single parent.
Is that a question, or...
So you two must help
each other out a lot.
Two single parents.
Callie drops Sofia off
at your place sometimes
when she has to work
or when she has plans
or when she needs
a night off. Correct?
A "night off"?
Being a mom isn't a job.
We don't punch in and punch out.
There are no nights off.
We are both single parents.
That's not a dirty word.
But we do need help getting
our kids to where they need to be
with all of their limbs intact.
So we lean on each other.
That's not a sign of
weakness or bad parenting,
if that's where
you're going with this.
It takes a village,
and we have a village.
Here in Seattle. What?
The village you
just mentioned...
The seamless support
system these mothers built,
this essential network.
It's all here in Seattle.
Sofia's friends and her
school, her teachers...
Her home is here in Seattle.
That's what Sofia
would be leaving.
Is that what you're saying?
No. I was saying...
No further questions,
Your Honor.
Dr. Robbins was already
a brilliant pediatric surgeon,
but since she's
completed her fellowship,
I've watched her turn into
one of the most renowned
fetal surgeons in the country.
A child would be lucky to
have her as a role model parent.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
Dr. Webber, you work with
Dr. Robbins, is that correct?
Uh, yes, that's
correct. Mmm-hmm.
Would you say there's overlap
between your specialties?
Yes, there is.
So, you two have gotten
close over the years.
Professionally. We have. Yes.
Are you a trivia buff?
Yes.
So, you and Dr. Robbins have
enjoyed trivia nights together.
That's correct, yes.
You go and play, drink,
and flirt with women.
Is that correct? No, it isn't.
I'm married and I don't drink.
So Dr. Robbins did all
the drinking and flirting.
You just went for the trivia?
That's an over-simplified... It's a
yes or no question, Dr. Webber.
Yes. You're good at trivia?
Sure. Don't be modest.
How many times do you think
you and Dr. Robbins have won
over the past, oh,
let's say, six months?
I wasn't counting. The bar was.
They kept a running tally.
Does this piece of
evidence, Document 3C,
refresh your recollection?
You've won 25 times
in the past six months.
That's 25 nights Dr. Robbins
was out drinking with you,
not including the
times you lost.
Where was Sofia
during those evenings?
I don't know.
I'm sorry. I didn't... I
didn't quite catch that.
I said I wasn't privy to
her childcare schedule.
I would like to introduce
into evidence Document 4C.
It is a transcript
of text messages
from Dr. Robbins to Dr. Torres
asking her to take
Sofia unexpectedly.
Callie and I swap all the time.
We have very flexible
schedules. Shh.
Could you please tell the court
the tally at the bottom?
Dr. Webber?
Thirty-four. Thirty-four.
She asked Dr. Torres to
switch with her 34 times.
We know she was out
with you at least 25 times.
And that's in addition to
the previously mentioned
ninety-two times
Dr. Robbins was unavailable
to parent her own child due
to her professional demands.
Now, let's just pause and
think about this for a minute.
There are only 180
days in six months' time,
and so far, we've counted
approximately 150 times
in which Dr. Robbins
shirked her duties.
150 out of 180.
Objection. Badgering
the witness.
Calls for speculation.
Sustained.
Your Honor, we'd like
to request a short recess.
So, Callie's okay
slut-shaming me now?
Don't let them rattle you.
They're making it sound like
a working mom is a bad mom.
I mean, we just
lost in there, right?
'Cause they made me sound like
I was a selfish,
irresponsible, sex-crazed...
Arizona. Stop. I don't...
You have your chance right now.
They tried to rewrite the story.
Now's your chance
to set it straight.
You need to get up
there, tell them the truth.
Judge Kane is smart.
She'll know the truth
when she hears it.
You tell the truth,
and you will win this.
When Sofia was born, how
did that day start for you?
I was in a car accident.
Can you tell us what you
remember about the accident?
I don't remember
much, but I remember...
I remember waking up
on the hood of the car
and I was covered in glass.
I was, um, barely...
I'm so sorry.
Take all the time you need.
I was barely conscious, um,
and the only thing that I
could feel was just pain all over.
I could have died on
the hood of that car.
And I wanted to give up.
But...
I couldn't because I
was pregnant with Sofia.
And if I died, she died.
So...
I had to fight
to stay alive, for
my daughter's sake.
Being a mother is the
reason I'm still alive today.
Jenny, your BP's borderline low,
but otherwise, your
cardiac evaluation is good.
So, she's cleared for surgery.
Surgery. What surgery?
What happened?
Dr. Russo says
we have to deliver.
Jenny's still leaking
amniotic fluid,
which means we're out of time.
We need to do a
C-section, deliver this baby.
Right now? It's
too early, right?
It's not ideal, but
there may be no choice.
Please don't. Not yet.
I don't want my baby to die.
Honey, everything
is gonna be fine.
Can I see you outside?
If that baby comes out now...
It has to.
The fetal heart rate's already
showing decreased variability.
Well, what can we do?
I can deliver, then you do
what you can for the baby.
Look, it's hard to keep those
babies alive. The odds suck.
Compromised lungs,
high risk of brain bleeds.
It's the only option left.
It's what we're doing.
So, I just lied to my daughter,
and I will go back in there
and keep telling her that
she'll be okay no matter what,
but to do that, I need to
know that you have done
everything in your
power to make this okay.
Can you tell me that?
Tell me that you have
done everything you can
to keep my baby
and grandchild alive.
Robbins wouldn't deliver.
Do you have another option?
Then I'll see you in surgery.
Is Robbins an option?
No.
Dr. Robbins, you
were with Dr. Torres
before she was pregnant. Yes.
Were you together
when she got pregnant? No.
So her pregnancy
was not an agreement
you entered into
together, correct?
No.
It was an agreement she entered
into with Dr. Mark Sloan, correct?
They agreed after the fact,
but, yes, Mark
was Sofia's father.
Callie and I were together.
We were a couple
before the pregnancy
and then after
Sofia was conceived.
So, you became part of the
parenting plan later, correct?
Just to be clear,
Dr. Sloan and Dr. Torres
were Sofia's parents
and then you came around.
No, I didn't "come around."
I'm Sofia's mother. I
legally adopted her.
Mmm, she doesn't want
to go there. No, she doesn't.
Her last names are
Sloan and Torres.
I'm gonna have to stop
you before you continue
for your own sake.
You're not going to imply
that I'm any less Sofia's mother
because we don't
share the same DNA.
Dr. Robbins, excuse me.
Because that would be offensive.
It would be offensive
to anyone in the room
who has an adopted child
or is an adopted child,
and for you to say that...
Dr. Robbins... I chose
to be Sofia's mother!
It did not fall into my lap.
There was a choice, and
I could stay or I could run,
and I chose motherhood.
And it was the best
choice that I ever made.
I'm so sorry.
I'm a doctor, and I have
to answer my phone,
so I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Thank you.
Somewhere more important to be?
Actually, yes. Excuse me?
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I love my child,
and I want her with me,
but I know that, no
matter how this ends,
she'll survive.
She'll be healthy and safe
and well-taken
care of and loved.
Because...
We are her mothers.
But there's a child at the
hospital who will not survive
unless I am there,
so I have to...
I have to... I have to go.
I am through the uterine wall.
More suction, please.
Vitals are holding.
Why isn't he stopping?
Did you ask him to stop?
Yes. But he's insisting
on taking the baby out.
Is he into the uterus? - Yes.
Well, did he cut the
cord? No, but he's close.
Tell him not to. Damn it!
I did.
Okay, everyone. Change of plans.
Dr. Russo, please
stop what you're doing.
- Excuse me?
- Hi, Tara. Hi, Jenny.
You're doing great,
okay? Hey, Karev.
- Cord's intact.
- Beautiful.
Dr. Russo. I said
stop. Now, please.
Robbins, I've almost
completed the C-section.
But you won't be finishing it.
Someone tell me
what's going on right now.
Um, Tara and Jenny, I am
going to put that baby back in there
so it can cook
a little bit more.
- How's that sound to you?
- You can do that?
- It's not too late?
- It is too late.
She's already lost most
of the amniotic fluid.
There's not enough left.
I'm going to fill the depleted
uterus with Lactated Ringer's,
and the baby's gonna be fine.
- Warren, how's she doing?
- Pressure's holding steady,
but we should hurry.
Okay. Mom, I need your consent.
Dr. Robbins can give
the baby more time.
Every additional week
this baby stays inside,
the better the
chances of its survival.
Mom?
We trust Dr. Robbins.
Okay. Uh, Dr. Russo,
thank you for your help.
Please scrub out.
Unbelievable.
Okay, Jenny.
We're gonna put you
out for now, all right?
Tara, you want to say
hi to your grandbaby?
What is it?
It's a girl. You
have a daughter.
Is she pretty? She's beautiful.
She looks just like you did.
Okay. We need to say
goodbye to her now.
Goodbye for now.
Goodbye, little girl.
No matter what
the judge decides,
I know that you're
a good mom, too.
And I just want you to know
this doesn't change that.
The things that you
let them say about me...
I would never have
done that to you.
Never.
I'm sorry. The judge
is ready for you.
All rise and come to order.
Honorable Judge
Madeline Kane presiding.
Please be seated.
I've taken all testimony
and evidence in this
matter under submission.
And after careful consideration,
my ruling is as follows.
I hereby grant sole
physical custody
of Sofia Robbin
Sloan Torres to...
Oh, have you heard
anything? No, not yet.
Robbins said she'd text as
soon as the judge decided.
Torres, too. This sucks.
What the hell?
Give him a stat
CT with contrast.
What happened?
Why wasn't I paged?
Why would you care?
He passed out.
Possible meningitis.
She's not my doctor.
I don't want her here.
Get her out of here.
Wilson.
No, don't. I'm...
I'm going.
If you're wondering how
the Solomon story ends...
Did you get all your
things from upstairs, Sofia?
Your books and everything?
Spoiler alert...
The true mom would
rather give her baby up
than have it ripped in two.
Hi, sweetie.
But what happens when
there are two true mothers?
How the hell did this happen?
How?
That's a no-win situation.
Mommy.
Can we go home now?
Yeah. We sure can.
Let's go home.
That is an entirely
different story.