Come on!
Yeah!
Hatchet! Hatchet!
Come on, Toros!
Let's make some noise!
Nice to meet the
pride of Trois-Rivières.
I still got your
Wings rookie card.
So what's that worth?
Well, it's a collector's item.
They don't make
them like you anymore.
So you want to go?
Square up. Good luck.
He didn't get a hand on you?
You're gonna be
a force in the show.
Hatchet! Hatchet! Hatchet!
Come on, Toros!
Get a trainer over here!
Capacity crowd is on its
feet, five seconds on the clock.
Ah!
How is it possible for one man
to be blessed with so much skill?
I had one just like this, except
it was Bruins and the Habs.
Where'd you get it?
Birthday present for
someone in pediatric oncology.
Twenty-two-year-old
enforcer with hemoptysis.
He's a hockey player?
No, he's a superhero.
He's coughing up blood
because he probably broke a rib
and punctured a lung while
breaking someone else's rib
and puncturing their
lung in the name of sport.
Nice conclusion, to which the
ER already jumped 18 hours ago.
Short man equals bullied child.
I was average height as
a kid. And never bullied.
Until now.
X-ray ruled out traumatic
sequelae, overt TB and lung cancer.
Sarcoidosis. Nodules could be
too small to show up on an X-ray.
But fighting's the
best part of hockey.
Without it, you've
got the Ice Capades.
Fighting has nothing
to do with hockey.
It's like the cheerleaders
at a basketball game.
Cheerleading's the
best part of basketball.
Without it, you've
got basketball.
He's a duck hunter.
He could have contracted
psittacosis from exposure to fowl.
He had three teeth
knocked out two weeks ago.
Infection could have
led to oral bleeding.
Not without
continuing dental pain.
Then he took an
elbow to the gut,
which caused an esophageal tear.
Chase, CT the patient,
check for sarcoid.
Adams, sputum cultures
and serologies for psittacosis.
Taub, I'd tell you
why I think your theory
is not just wrong
but ill-conceived,
but it's more fun to prove it by
having you check the stool for blood.
Now while we wait for the
stool fairy, I'm a man down.
So if you want to drop
your pants and hit the ice.
The faster you guys
can do this, the better.
The NHL's been sniffing around,
and being in the hospital's not
really helping my marketability, so...
You have to be pretty
good to get called up.
Yeah, leading the
league in penalty minutes.
And visits to the ER, not
counting the ones you've caused.
Not a hockey fan, I gather?
I am, that's the point. Fighting
cheapens a great sport.
Oh, come on. That's like
saying passing cheapens football.
It's part of the game.
I don't cause injuries.
They're self-inflicted?
No, I prevent them.
I take the hits, so the
smaller guys don't have to.
I thought you'd appreciate that.
Neighbor's baby again?
I could hear it
through earplugs,
two pillows, and
three sleeping pills.
Hmm.
What is wrong with you?
I just said, "Hmm."
You're trying to figure out
some deeper significance
to my having a
couple of crappy nights.
Which one of us is analyzing
the word "hmm" here?
Fine. I'm sorry.
Apology accepted.
However, it's not the crying
that's keeping you awake.
The sound of a needy child
is stirring your paternal juices.
The sound of a needy
child at 112 decibels
has stirred my inner
murderer. Don't mess with me.
Explain the stains on
your shirt. You're lactating.
The fact that
you're the only fruit
on your family tree
is getting to you.
It's not a big deal. So I'll
probably never be a dad.
It sucks. I'll lose
a little sleep, but...
You're not supposed to feel
bad when you dodge a bullet.
It's like you've
got survivor's guilt.
There are actually
things in this world
that give life even more meaning
than soap operas
and monster trucks.
And we happen to be missing
out on at least one of them.
You remember the falconer?
Beth?
You dated two falconers?
Yes, Beth.
The night the
two of you split up,
you came around to my place,
wallowing in
self-pity and tequila.
You passed out.
She called that night. Asked
me to give you a message.
She said she was pregnant.
Which, God and Planned
Parenthood willing,
means you are the
father of an 11-year-old.
I told you the next
morning. Hypothetically.
I asked you how you'd feel
if Beth had gotten pregnant,
and you said, and I quote, "It
would be the worst mistake of my life."
And scene.
Two performances
Sunday, dark Mondays?
Just as well.
I want to kill my mother.
My Popo's on her own
and my mother always
needs me to take care of her.
Well, you could
kill Popo instead.
I have to take her shopping,
to her friends, to Atlantic City.
I love her, but every
night, every weekend...
And only if there
was some solution,
some place where you could live.
That's not there.
My mom would freak. It would
be the ultimate sign of disrespect.
Okay. Then stay.
And maybe you'd consider
not bitching about it?
Not everyone's lucky enough
to have your independence.
Don't worry. When you lose
your family, you'll have it, too.
He doesn't have sarcoid.
Look at that. That's his spleen.
I know, but he's
gotten it supersized.
Deep vein thrombosis, caused by
any one of his many injuries or surgeries.
Leukemia's a better fit.
We have a guy who is punishing
his body on a daily basis.
Don't you think that's a
more likely cause than cancer?
No, because she
doesn't have an agenda.
Well, that was
incredibly unprofessional.
Although, it's
really Taub's fault.
If you're not prepared to
slam her into the board,
she's got no reason
not to go after you.
Might I suggest pulling her
jersey over her head first?
We should get an ultrasound
for DVT and WBC for leukemia.
You think I could have cancer?
More likely it's just a DVT.
This is my agent.
I gotta take this.
Yeah.
Give me some good news, Kenny.
I thought you said "any day".
Okay. All right.
I gotta go.
I called Beth.
I have an 11-year-old son.
Liver failure could
alter hormone levels,
cause abnormal
breast development.
Alcoholism. We should search
his home and locker room.
Note that the person who
wants to search the home
didn't sleep in one last night.
You have the imprint of a
seatbelt buckle on your cheek.
I got in a fight with my mother.
She hit you with a seatbelt?
It could be hemochromatosis.
Explains the liver
and the spleen,
but hemoptysis is a stretch.
What about leptospirosis?
That's a good fit.
If you ignore the fact
that he's a pro athlete
who looks like
the Incredible Hulk,
which means he's got to be
on steroids, which is a better fit.
All we really know
for sure is that
it was his evil job that
caused the problems.
Yes, I don't like him. Doesn't
mean my judgment's affected.
Maybe. Let's take a
look at the instant replay.
This is the hit that
precipitated Booby Orr's fight.
Dirty or clean?
- The hit was clean.
- Really?
The guy released the puck at
least a second before the hit.
We have a difference
of opinion. That's all.
Absolutely.
Maybe she's as biased as you.
Or maybe the entire league is.
After review, the league
disciplinary commissioner ruled the hit
illegal and dangerous, and
suspended the player for three games.
Adams and Taub, run
antibody titers for lepto.
Chase and Park, check out the
home, the locker room for booze,
steroids and Taub's objectivity.
At least you're free.
You gonna get your own place?
If I can find a place
I can afford, so no.
If you want, you can crash at
my place. Got a spare bedroom.
That might be kind of weird.
I live in an apartment,
not a dungeon.
It's just two single
people, opposite sex.
Your bedroom door
has a lock on the inside.
Hey, if you prefer
your car, be my guest.
Scrip for ganciclovir.
If his neighbor has mono,
it could mean he has mono.
If he has mono, explains
his spleen and hemoptysis.
And it's caused by the Epstein-Barr
virus, which explains his liver.
And my moonroof leaks.
Thank you.
Why don't we just assume
that you're not the dad?
Well, either you're the dad
or she cheated on
you with your dad.
Oh!
Sand art. I used to love this.
He's bitter, not
mentally handicapped.
Who knows what Beth
told him about you?
At worst, you're a rapist.
At best, you're a rapist.
Maybe she said I
was a dead war hero.
Raised by a lunatic mother
and abandoned by his father.
Oh, I know, squirrel handcuffs.
You think he's got any of those?
If you really wanted me to do
nothing with this information,
then why did you give it to me?
Because you
were pining for a kid
and you deserved to know
that you already had one.
But your paternal cravings are
more theoretical than applied.
You want vicarious immortality
more than you want
a lifelong burden.
You're assuming he's
gonna be a nightmare.
What if he's a good kid?
He's a kid. Best you can
hope for is he's a nightmare.
House, I'm not naive. I realize
that this thing could go very badly,
but the point is my son wants to
meet me, and I want to meet him.
Popo, I presume.
Hey. I let myself in.
This is... We've met.
I thought the whole point of
this was to get away from Popo.
My dad's getting a cyst removed
and my mother had
to take him to the clinic.
Don't worry, she'll
be gone in an hour.
I'm not worried
because it's not my issue.
She seems awfully quiet.
You haven't seen her drunk.
Bobby?
I found him crying
in the fetal position.
It's not a new symptom.
He's crying because
his liver failure
threw his hormones out of whack.
Aside from the crying, he's
actually recovering nicely.
Aside from the guy
in the book depository,
the Kennedys had
a lovely trip to Dallas.
Repetitive blows to the head
can cause chronic
traumatic encephalopathy,
the symptoms of which are
aggressive behavior and depression.
So your theory is that
his aggressive behavior
caused his aggressive behavior?
He's not depressed,
he's just bummed,
because he knows
he's a talentless moron
who's only one lost fight
away from being a barista.
I understand that can
get to a guy after a while.
If he quits being an
enforcer, it could save his life.
You don't want to save his life.
You want to kill his career.
I moved into Chase's apartment.
He knows. He was staring
at our matching cups.
I told you we
should have split up.
We're not having
sex. With each other.
Yet. Yes.
Yes?
I just mean no one knows the future
right now, so we don't really know...
The only conclusive test
for CTE is post-mortem.
But an MRI of his brain could
reveal white matter disintegrity,
which is the effect of CTE.
Why? Are you trying
to sleep with her?
'Cause a simpler
technique is just to ask.
I was doing something nice. No.
That doesn't fit.
He's only had three
concussions since he was 10.
It's not enough to cause CTE.
Three reported concussions.
These guys are taught in high
school how to dupe the tests.
Guilt? This is really insulting.
It's not guilt.
Park is a friend.
So it's guilt.
Chase convinced you to leave
Mommy and now he feels responsible.
No MRI.
Do a psych eval, if he doesn't
start weeping again, send him home.
Dr. Wilson?
Duncan?
James.
Nice to meet you.
It's nice to meet you.
Um...
How are you doing?
Good.
I got you this.
Oh.
Thank you.
Go ahead. Okay.
It's got three games built-in,
but you can download
more from the website.
I know.
You already have one.
I can always use a backup.
Hi. Can I start you
with something to drink?
Just water, please.
You got a GameDeck?
Way to go, Dad.
According to your psych eval,
the only thing happier
than you is Disneyland.
I'm sorry you had to
see me like that last night.
I'm just upset about being in the
hospital, I'm on some weird meds.
But they must be working,
because I'm feeling a lot better now.
Depression could be the
symptom of a serious illness, CTE.
Yeah. My aunt sends me
every article she can find on it.
Then you know it could kill you.
In the long run,
like a lot of things.
You might be right.
And an MRI could confirm that.
I have enough evidence of head
trauma in my file already, so...
My mom said you had trouble maintaining
relationships with normal people.
She also said you
were a nice guy.
I always figured she was lying
'cause she didn't want me
to hate my deadbeat dad.
I didn't know.
I know, now.
You're a bright kid.
Thanks to you. Thanks to my mom,
I'm also a big,
soft-hearted wuss.
I think you may have
gotten that from both of us.
I got to go, but it was
really nice meeting you.
It was nice meeting you, Duncan.
You want to hang out again?
Absolutely. Tonight?
Tonight?
Well, I... There's...
That would be great.
Okay. I'll text you.
Thank you. How'd
you talk him into it?
He agreed once I
promised him anonymity.
Mr. and Mrs. Doe liked
the name John, apparently.
Unfortunately, we just wasted
his time and proved House right.
Nothing?
What about that?
That's an artifact.
That's a density.
I know you think I'm
convincing myself,
but this brain has been
hammered for years,
meaning evidence may
be subtle, but it's there.
Meaning you see
what you want to see.
Unless, of course, Chase is an
idiot and I do have brain damage.
Patient's stroking out.
Chase. Can you get me out of...
Oh...
Hello?
The good news is it's
isolated ophthalmoplegia,
which means he
didn't have a stroke.
Bad news is Taub was
right. You're still sick.
I said "right", not "competent".
Bursts your CTE bubble. You're
gonna need a whole new theory
to keep Uncle Jesse and
his Olsen Twins on the bench.
Can we discuss my
incompetence somewhere else?
Dr. House. Could I
talk to you for a minute?
Could be neurosyphilis.
He's only 22.
And he's been on the
road since he was 14.
So he was trash even
before he was trash?
Are you curious
about what he wanted?
I assume he wanted
me off the case,
and you told him I was
hit in the head as a child,
and your mother made you
promise to take care of me.
He was doing what
he always does.
Sticking up for the little guy.
He told me to apologize to you,
or he would excrete
down my throat.
I'm paraphrasing.
So if he should ask,
I was a gentleman,
or I will excrete
down your throat.
Microscopic polyangiitis fits.
We should start
plasmapheresis immediately.
We need to run an ANCA
panel to confirm first.
Putting him on plasmapheresis
could make him bleed out.
MPA can progress quickly.
We may not have time
before it reaches his lungs.
I think you're right, thus
confirming my objectivity.
Start the treatment.
Miserable yet?
He's polite, well-adjusted,
and a straight-A student.
Which means he doesn't need you.
So why don't you get out
while the butterfly effect
is still in the cocoon stage.
I'm making him dinner.
You don't make an
11-year-old dinner.
You give him a
jar of peanut butter.
It'll be fine.
I could give this
kid a quinoa salad
and he would eat
it just to be nice.
'Cause he's a gutless
placater, just like his dad.
He's nice.
This is a terrible idea.
Because we like each other?
Yes. Because of the
statement, "We like each other."
You've known him 25 minutes.
All you know about him is that
he'd lie about a quinoa salad,
whatever the hell that is.
You're jealous of an 11-year-old
because you are an 11-year-old.
So tell me about yourself.
I mean you're smart,
you're nice, but what else?
I don't know. I'm a kid.
Right.
What are you looking for?
Nothing.
You want peanut butter?
Do you have prosciutto?
You like prosciutto? I'm weird.
No! No, I like it, too.
I've got some in the fridge.
How about goat cheese?
I love goat cheese.
I think that was the
best pizza I ever had.
It was the hint of Dijon.
Do you have any aunts
or uncles or grandparents?
My mom got into some
stupid fight with my grandfather.
They all kind of cut us off.
Hmm.
Are you talking to your parents?
Yes, and they're going to be very
surprised and excited to meet you.
That's awesome.
You have arrived
at your destination.
Well... Thanks for the pizza.
Sure. Sure. I mean, it was
great to spend time with you.
I love you, Dad.
It can't be easy
doing what you do.
I mean, do you love it?
Is it fun?
I had my own plastic surgery
practice, making lots of money.
But I wasn't happy. It wasn't
what I went to med school for.
Every winter, my dad would
flood the backyard and make a rink.
I was Lemieux, my
little brother was Gretzky.
I was good. I won the NDHA
scoring title three years in a row.
I kept getting bigger
and stronger and better.
Until I didn't.
My Juniors coach told me that
if I wanted to stay on the team,
that I'd have to use my size.
Every game, I got
less and less ice time,
until it was all
fighting and no hockey.
There's something
going on with my arms.
I can't feel them! Doctor,
I can't feel my arms.
Patient's arms
are now paralyzed.
ANCA panel was
negative. It's not MPA.
Lyme disease could
cause paralysis,
if he was hunting, he'd
be exposed to ticks.
No target rash or
cardiac involvement.
Roomies with benefits
keeping you up?
Cribbage. I played
with Park's Popo.
Is that two separate events?
Her grandmother. ALS
could explain the symptoms.
Sensory involvement
rules out ALS.
Okay, now this is interesting.
We'll get back to the
patient in a second.
Your issue is the
same as Wilson's.
Except you're haunted by
the pitter-patter of tiny skanks.
You don't feel guilty about
getting Park thrown out of her home.
You feel guilty about all the
women that you've screwed over.
My mother needs 1,000
bucks for snow tires.
Park's a friend, Popo's fun.
Paralysis has gone
from his face to his arms,
meaning it's descending,
which is the hallmark of botulism.
So it was something
he ate. How innocuous.
You've overcome
your bias by reversing it.
The only problem is that
being in love with the patient
is just as judgmental
as being in hate.
We didn't find any
contaminated...
No contaminated
food, I'm not an idiot.
But what if it's not from
ingesting, but from injecting?
He was treated for intractable
muscle spasms by the team's trainers.
Sometimes they use Botox.
We need to start the antitoxin.
The antitoxin could
cause anaphylaxis.
We need to test
first to confirm.
As if to prove my point.
Last time you said there
wasn't enough time to test
prior to a more
dangerous treatment.
It's a different situation, a different
symptom, a different diagnosis.
Different emotion.
Give him the antitoxin.
Anything?
No adverse effects.
Chase let me move in with him
to get away from my grandmother,
then he practically let my
grandmother move in with the both of us.
He's being way more than nice.
Then which answer is it?
Chase feels guilty for
pushing you to move out?
He didn't push me.
Guilt about skanks?
He loves skanks.
It's not the other option.
There are people that like me,
people who even
want to sleep with me.
Some of them are
even good looking.
That good looking?
Did you see that?
You're feeling something?
Yeah.
I could give you crap for
making me wait 11 years,
but instead I'm gonna thank you
for not making me
wait another 11.
Every little girl wants a pony
until they have
to clean up after it.
You think I'm gonna quit
on this? On an 11-year-old?
The only relationship you
haven't quit on has been with me.
Hmm. A needy,
truculent narcissist.
I think it's been the perfect
training for parenthood.
That's not even close.
This is the rest of your life.
If you screw this up,
you don't get to run away.
You get to ruin both your lives.
This is a bigger responsibility
than any you've ever
taken on, and screwed up.
I know.
That's why I'm
so excited about it.
You're really happier doing
this than looking at boobs all day?
Luckily, I get patients like
you every now and again
who let me
re-experience the joy.
You know the best part of my day
is when I'm sitting
in that penalty box
after I beat someone up.
It's the only time
I know I'm safe.
Think Lemieux
ever felt that way?
I'm not going back.
To hockey?
To enforcing.
Whatever that costs.
Good for you.
Oh!
First goal for the
Pocket Rocket.
Bobby?
We need a team in here!
He's completely paralyzed and
he tested negative for botulism.
I am now accepting long shots.
Polio?
Some kids were never vaccinated.
Unless they played sports all their
lives and had two physicals a year.
How about MLD?
That's a bad fit.
I say that not because
there's no treatment for MLD,
but because it's a bad fit.
His cognitive abilities
are unaffected.
Prion disease could explain the
waxing and waning symptoms.
The test for prions
is a brain biopsy.
And given his history,
there's got to be brain swelling.
We can't risk
drilling into his skull.
Pretty sure we can.
We also could keep talking until we
can find an answer we all can agree on.
What, all of us? Those of us
who love him, those who hate him?
Those who don't give a
crap about him or you?
Or I could just discuss it
on my own with Foreman.
He's not your friend.
I get it, he's a patient.
I'm not... He never
had your back.
He didn't insist that
I apologize to you.
He asked me to
take you off the case.
Biopsy his brain.
Hey, Dad.
Hey.
Sorry I'm late. Got in a fight
with my mom. She is such a tool.
I'm sure she means well.
She wants to open a reserve in
Costa Rica for rescued birds of prey.
But how serious is she?
From my recollection, she
used to talk about doing a lot.
Yeah, but she bought
plane tickets for Monday.
Well, Costa Rica is beautiful.
And the schools are
supposed to be great.
Oh! I'm not going. It's
her stupid dream, not mine.
Then what will you do?
Uh...
I thought maybe I
could stay with you?
Your place is only three
miles away from my school.
I can bus it every day.
And I do my own laundry.
I keep my room tidy.
Duncan, this...
This is very sudden.
I know. I'm sorry.
Please don't send
me to the jungle.
If it's okay with your
mother, it's okay with me.
Take me off the case.
I've obviously completely
lost my objectivity.
I'm not helping.
I'm not even neutral.
Agreed.
So why shouldn't I take
you off all my cases?
Because you were
right. I hate bullies.
You work for me.
You're not a bully.
Pretty sure I am, dickwad.
I've known a lot of bullies, people
who didn't like me because I'm short,
people who didn't like
me because I'm Jewish.
Yeah, I get it, there's a long
list of reasons not to like you.
You relentlessly mock, but
it's not for self-aggrandizement,
it's because ideas are
bigger than feelings.
At least that's what
I choose to believe.
I also thought you had the
side effect of desensitizing me.
You little hebe.
Here are some ideas for you.
You screwed up. You kept on
screwing up. Everything you said is true.
Except it doesn't
mean you walk away.
You just learn to trust nothing.
Everything you think you feel,
everything you think you know,
you question every call,
play through every whistle.
I just had a light bulb.
Maybe.
You can trust light bulbs.
Stop. It's not prions.
Epstein-Barr gave him mono, it
also gave him Miller Fisher syndrome.
The plasmapheresis
played through the whistle.
We gave it to him for MPA, but
when he got worse, we took him off.
When he got better, we
thought it was the antitoxin,
but it was actually the
plasmapheresis still working.
We had the right treatment,
just the wrong diagnosis.
It was my metaphor
that solved the case.
Put him back on
plasmapheresis. He'll be fine.
Nice save.
Didn't quite make up for being
a sieve the rest of the game.
Ex-girlfriend's baby again?
His mother is
moving to Costa Rica,
he asked if he could
move in with me...
and I said yes.
Well, it's only six
or seven years.
Unless he can't
get into college,
in which case it's more a
matter of your life expectancy.
I said yes, knowing I'm
not remotely ready for that,
knowing he's not ready to
be separated from his mother.
This isn't the act of a
mature, rational adult.
I can't do this, House.
You were right.
I have an idea that can make
this entire problem go away.
Yes, I really want to hear your
clever late-term abortion joke.
You were right about
everything. This is life.
It's real. It doesn't
just go away.
None of that is true.
Hey.
Duncan.
Actually, it's Wendel, one "L".
If you're gonna get pissy,
remember, it was House's idea.
You're an actor?
Five commercials, and a
recurring on Days of our Lives.
You were regretting not
having kids, so I gave you one.
Thereby rendering you
regret-free. It's a priceless gift.
Get out. Well,
it's not priceless.
He charges SAG minimum...
Get out!
Chillax, Dad.
Can you do an Australian accent?
I just got the call.
Three-year deal, 2.1 million.
What about the flooded backyard
and pretending to be Lemieux?
That's why I took it.
After all I did to get here,
half a dream is
better than nothing.
Maybe my new coach will see
what my Juniors coach didn't.
That'd be nice.
I'm not sleeping with you.
That's a shame.
This is about Popo.
She's not sleeping
with me either, right?
You were jealous
of me, my family.
Maybe you've got too
much and I've got too little.
I might sleep
with you after all.
The woman that I called,
that was really Beth?
Found her on Facebook.
How much did she charge?
Nothing. She's
still pissed at you.
Can you pass the bacon?
I thought you liked prosciutto.
Nobody likes prosciutto.