This is the main entrance,
though it's not really private.
- So this is where he's...
- You can take a look.
- Hi.
- Oh, my God.
Is that really you?
Aww.
And look at you,
like you were never
even pregnant.
How are your boobs feeling?
Besieged.
- That'll happen.
- Mm-hmm.
Cover this side.
What's with all the suits?
Some mucky-muck
flying into town
for heart surgery.
This is what they call
an advance team.
And here I thought
you were rolling out
the red carpet for me.
Sorry.
But I'm glad to see you.
I'm surprised you didn't ask
for a couple more weeks.
Well, it's been a month.
I was just joking.
You mean you don't think
I'm a bad mom?
Juvie.
Respiratory distress.
All right.
Welcome back,
Dr. Manning.
Thank you.
Trauma 2.
- I'll get your stuff.
- Thanks.
All tenens to the ED.
13-year-old female,
Michelle.
Worsened on the ride.
This is her father.
Michelle, I'm Dr. Manning.
I'm gonna take care of you.
- When did this start?
- 20 minutes ago.
- Is she asthmatic?
- No.
Bee sting?
Something she ate?
Definitely not
something she ate.
How can you be sure?
Because she never eats anything
I don't prepare for her.
All right, we're gonna
move her on my count.
One, two, three.
Call respiratory
for a vent, stat,
and get a crash cart in here.
- Yes, Dr. Manning.
- She's in bronchospasm.
Breathe, breathe.
Draw up .3 milligrams of EPI,
1/1000, and give it IM.
- Got it.
- I'm not sure that's safe.
- She's on other medications.
- What medications?
Metoprolol, and Tegretol
for her seizures,
- Methadone for her pain...
- Methadone?
She has Mitochondrial Disease.
It affects her body's ability
to produce...
- I'm familiar with Mito.
- Stats are dropping.
All right, we can't wait
for respiratory.
We need to intubate.
Get me 20 of Etomidate,
80 of Sux.
She's spasmed down.
Where are the drugs?
I lost the IV.
I'm trying again on this side.
We don't have time.
We need to crich her.
Get me a 10cc syringe
and a 16-gauge needle, now.
- What is happening?
- Sir, I need you to step out.
Don't tell me what to do.
My daughter is dying
and you're letting her.
- Now!
- Sir, step back.
No, look...
It's all right, kiddo.
- Needle, now.
- Here, doctor.
Go ahead and hang another liter.
Stand by.
I'm okay.
I'm okay!
Hold off.
I'm okay.
Sats are improving.
- Let's get a face mask on her.
- Yes, doctor.
Oh, thank God
you pulled out of it.
Sorry I scared you, Dad.
Are you okay?
Am I okay?
Listen to you.
Oh, you silly girl.
Deep breaths, deep breaths.
I've never seen someone
improve like that so quick.
You?
No.
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -
You had a G-tube implanted?
Helps with her nutrition.
She's not the greatest eater.
We IV her supplements
and vitamins.
My smoothie.
And the, uh...
Central line catheter?
It's for all her meds.
Mm.
She's good to go.
You are a very brave girl.
Got that from her mother.
My wife died four years ago.
Breast cancer.
I'm sorry.
Not long after that's
when kiddo here
started getting sick.
Migraines, fatigue, IBS.
For a while, I figured
it was just part
of the mourning process,
but it kept happening.
I got that.
I took her to...
I don't know how many doctors,
but nobody knew what was wrong,
so I went online
and found out about Mito.
You went online for that?
For the first time,
what Michelle was going through
finally made sense.
Good news, we know what it is.
Bad news, there's no cure.
So we manage.
Okay.
Well, I'd like to do
a full workup
before discharging her.
See if we can find
what caused those spasms.
Could take a couple of hours.
You guys okay with that?
Do what you do.
We're old pros.
Never leave home unprepared,
just in case
we end up in the hospital.
This way.
Well, it looks like
royalty's arrived.
You're referring to him...
or him?
Princes come and go,
but there's only one
King Downey.
Ah, yes, Your Highness.
Welcome.
Guy's a surgical rock star.
This prince flies halfway
around the world
to have him replace his valve.
This is the place we want to be.
Come on, your room's ready.
Downey, number one
with a bullet.
Although, I suppose
if that were true,
you'd be yanking it out of him,
wouldn't you?
Doctor Rhodes,
they're ready for you in OR 2.
Thank you, Maggie.
This woman stabbed her husband
in the right flank
with a pair of scissors.
Sounds like they could use
a marriage counselor.
Mr. Mason,
I'm Dr. Halstead.
So, tell me,
when did this pain start?
Who let this man
in the hospital?
become a doctor?
Whoa, gentlemen.
I take it you two kids
know each other?
I had the pleasure
of serving time on a carrier
with this man,
Chief Petty Officer Mason.
Choi.
Great to see you, Chief.
What are you doing in Chicago?
I retired two years ago,
and, uh...
Let's catch up after we let
the doc here do his thing.
Nothing doing.
You come to Chicago Med,
you get me.
Chart, please.
You're in good hands.
Honor to meet you.
So...
what brings you in here?
I feel like
I swallowed a fishhook.
Well, let's take a look.
There you are.
- Heard you were back.
- Hey.
Hey.
How's Owen?
He liking that mobile thing
I hung up?
Mesmerized.
He can't stop staring at it.
Success.
Wasn't the same without you.
I'm glad to be back.
I just hope my son forgives me.
Of course he will.
Absence makes the heart
grow fonder.
I'm not that absent.
Oh, no, I didn't...
I didn't mean any...
I'm sorry;
I'm exhausted.
I... it's just...
It's our first day apart.
Absolutely.
First day.
What's all this?
My 13-year-old's
medical history.
Dad keeps a copy of everything
in the car just in case.
This is all for a 13-year-old?
Girl presents with bronchospasm.
I get this close
to criching her.
The moment her father
leaves her side...
She catches her breath.
Like magic.
The kid's
a budding Harry Potter.
She has mitochondrial disease.
Mito?
We really are
talking fiction here.
You don't think it exists?
Always felt like
a wastebasket diagnosis to me.
Doctor can't figure out
what's really going wrong,
says it's Mito, calls it a day.
Hmm.
What did the muscle biopsy say?
That I don't know,
because I haven't found it yet.
Want a second set of eyes?
Yes, thank you.
You're welcome.
- Okay, here you go.
- Okay. Yeah.
Yeah.
See you.
Okay, bye.
Oh, my God.
You guys are so cute.
We're just friends.
Uh-huh.
Another dating app?
Why? You go to any bar,
and there's a line
around the block
to buy you a drink.
Oh, well, at least
these guys know how to type,
for the most part.
Look at this one.
Profile name,
"Windy City Winner."
Nope.
Another idiot without a shirt.
Oh.
That's...
Joey.
"Cold Tech, Warm Heart."
It says his favorite thing is
watching the Chicago skyline
at night
from Promontory Point.
Please, he hardly ever
leaves his computer.
Hate to drag you two ladies
away from electronic romance...
Oh, my gosh!
But Treatment Five awaits.
Have fun.
Okay.
I need everything
to stop spinning.
Okay.
You brought her in?
Sloane's my girl.
Ride or die since junior high,
and we're college roommates.
She appears inebriated.
I only had two glasses of wine.
She told me
she was staying in to study
for her environmental studie.
Bacteria.
Yes, look... going over things
from her field trips.
I'm so sorry, Ames.
- Don't deserve you.
- It's okay, Sloaney.
Her knee appears swollen.
Well, she did fall
in the shower this morning.
Well, often, in college,
people find out
their actual limits,
and she exceeded hers.
You got wasted like this a lot?
No, not me.
Never once.
Maybe once.
All right, let's draw some labs,
start an IV,
get her on a liter
of normal saline,
see if we can't sober her up.
Yep.
99.3.
A little hot, that's all.
That's it?
That, my friend, is it.
You don't want to
run a CAT scan or something?
CAT scan?
It's pretty standard, isn't it?
Not with what I'm seeing,
unless there's something
you haven't told me.
When I go to the bathroom,
there's blood in my stool.
Blood.
Bright red?
Dark?
Dark.
How long has that been going on?
About three months.
And you're just
seeing a doctor now?
Can you roll over on your side?
You know what's coming.
But it'll just be
for a few seconds.
We call this the Chicago Med
handshake.
Okay, done.
Chief,
we are gonna do
that CAT scan after all.
Not a scratch on the liver,
but a hole in the diaphragm.
She got him good.
Uh, Doctor Downey.
- Good morning.
- What's he doing here?
The patient, Marty.
Hmm.
Do you know this patient?
No.
Ah.
Are there any concerns,
Dr. Downey?
No.
And we are... done.
What did he want?
I have no idea.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
It's a fricking
Rose Bowl parade in here.
Well, the prince
has a lot of well-wishers.
Is he gifting David
a polo pony this time?
I thought I saw
a saddle back there.
Do I sense a tinge of jealousy,
or are you just upset
because I let him use
your parking spot?
Look, Hawaiian shirts aside,
I think David is a lovely man.
It's, frankly, our priorities
that I tend to question.
Look at this ED, Daniel.
You don't get this without that.
Downey helps make Chicago Med
a destination hospital.
Yeah, like Disneyland.
Right?
Hi, Michelle.
How are you feeling?
- Well...
- Not great, to be honest.
I'm wondering if we should
adjust her IV fluids?
Okay.
Well, we'll look into that.
This is Dr. Halstead;
I've asked him to join us.
Thank you,
by the way, for keeping
such a detailed account
of Michelle's history.
Yeah, well, sometimes
it feels like a full-time job.
I bet.
Well, we were looking over
her records
and didn't come across
any results for a muscle biopsy.
Do you know if one
was ever performed?
No, we haven't done a biopsy.
Uh-huh.
I highly recommend one.
It's really the only way
to confirm a diagnosis of Mito.
Well, no,
the doctor was concerned
how Michelle would react
to the anesthesia.
What's he talking about, Daddy?
Nothing, kiddo.
You know, she should rest.
I'll be right outside.
Can we chat outside?
What are you doing?
- Just trying to confirm...
- Michelle has Mito.
If I wanted her retested,
I'd ask.
I came here because she was
having trouble breathing
and this was
the closest hospital.
I didn't come here
to debate her diagnosis.
We're just trying to find a way
to help your daughter start
feeling better.
No, Dr. Halstead thinks
he knows better than her father.
- I was not questioning...
- Oh, the hell you weren't.
Daddy?
My stomach...
Michelle?
Are you okay?
- Pulse is strong.
- Pupils are equal.
IV?
- It's good.
- April, ammonia ampule.
- Got it.
- Anything you need?
Thanks, we got it.
We need to take a look
at that hand.
Do something.
Dr. Halstead.
Thank you.
Michelle?
Okay, Michelle?
It's okay, kiddo.
It's okay.
I'm here.
Daddy's right here.
Daddy!
Yeah.
You still want to
convince yourselves
there's nothing wrong with her?
I'm guessing,
by your expression,
it doesn't look good.
It doesn't.
You have a large mass
partially obstructing
your right colon,
which explains the symptoms
you've been experiencing.
I can't be sure, but...
in all likelihood, I...
Colon cancer, right?
My doctor at the VA,
she thought this might
be what it was.
Wait, you have a doctor
at the VA
who knew your symptoms
and hasn't had you scanned yet?
Dr. Glass, but it...
It wasn't her fault, okay?
She's been beating the drum
for me.
It's that VA.
They got their own special pace.
Slow.
Hey,
you think I'll make it
another week?
What happens in a week?
Reunion.
You know, all the chiefs
from the Vinson
who were deployed to Haiti,
helping out after the quake.
I remember.
You'll be at that reunion,
Chief.
How's that feel?
Is that okay, Michelle?
How's your stomach feeling now?
A little better.
It never feels great, though.
That's why I'm so lucky
to have my dad.
He's always there
to take care of me.
Now, where else
would I be, kiddo?
Hey.
How's that, uh...
young lady doing?
I wish there was
a simple answer to that.
How about the un-simple one?
So something's clearly
wrong with her,
but Mito?
I'm not buying it.
Could it just be
all the medication?
The girl's a walking pharmacy.
Who knows how she's reacting
to all those drugs?
Ideally, I'd wean Michelle
off everything
and establish a new baseline.
You think the dad
would go for that?
Not a chance.
The guy is dead set it's Mito.
I... I got a weird feeling
here, doc.
It... it's like...
they've built their lives
around this disease.
Huh.
I don't know, Will.
It feels like something
worth investigating to me.
Yeah, I think it'd be great
if you went and talked to them.
What, I walk in there?
A shrink?
No, it'd change
the whole dynamic.
You'd never get a clean read.
I need to watch them
without them knowing
I'm watching them.
Dr. Rhodes, your presence
has been requested
on the fifth floor.
Dr. Downey wants
to speak with you.
Yeah, yeah, I'll come up.
He'll be right up.
Well, let me know what he wants.
Yeah.
Hey...
How's our patient in five?
Still sleeping it off.
Um... about that profile?
I'm wondering if it's something
Joey just had up
and forgot to take down.
Does it say the last time
he was on?
Mm...
He was last active...
today.
- Today?
- Mm-hmm.
Excuse me.
I had a question
I wanted to ask you.
What's it like being a doctor?
Oh, not a doctor.
Fourth-year med student.
Oh, I'm premed.
Does the work load
ever calm down?
No, just gets worse.
Miles, my boyfriend,
is about ready to dump my ass.
Last night, he begs me
to go see some band at Metro,
Well, in my experience,
med school and guys don't mix.
Most of them
are liars and cheats anyway.
You say, "Let's take it slow,"
and for them, that means
a license to sleep around.
Seizure in Five!
Get one milligram of Ativan,
and grab the attending.
Thank you.
I've got her airway.
Oh, my God.
Have you ever seen her
have a seizure before?
No.
Where's that Ativan?
How often does she
drink like this?
Is it possible she's detoxing?
No way Sloane's a closet alkie.
We don't keep secrets
from each other.
All of this
from one night of drinking
doesn't make sense.
Dr. Rhodes.
Nice work down there.
Thank you.
So my angels tell me
you spent time in Riyadh?
Your angels are correct.
I was there last year
helping injured oil workers.
How's your Arabic?
Sounds good to me.
Come on, I want you
to meet somebody.
So here it is.
Hyponatremia?
Yeah, her sodium levels
are pretty low.
119.
Her...
Glucose is 74,
so she's not diabetic.
Her blood alcohol is negative.
- What caused her...
- Hey.
Her seizure?
Is everything okay?
You know, with us?
You on that app too?
What?
No.
What are you doing on it?
I mean...
you said you like
to take it slow
and get to know a person.
Yeah, get to know one person,
not get to know me
while you date half of Chicago.
No, I'm not dating half of...
And the Chicago skyline?
When's the last time
you were even outside at night?
There'll be a pulmonary
thromboendarterectomy,
full bypass, hemodilution.
Now, I like it
because it gives us
a clear field, so we can
completely remove the blockage.
Would you like me
to translate this into Arabic?
Why would you need to do that?
I see that I don't.
So surgery's set for 3:00.
Make yourself comfortable
while my team preps.
Stop worrying.
You're making me nervous.
You certainly don't want that
while I'm operating.
We'll see you in a bit.
I'm not a CT surgeon,
but bypass
for pulmonary thrombus
isn't common, is it?
Who wants common?
I know my patient doesn't.
You okay with common?
Dr. Downey, what exactly
am I doing here?
You're helping me
prep for surgery.
I guess so.
Did he eat?
Oh, okay, good.
Good.
And you're sure
you have enough milk?
Okay, because you know,
I'm really close;
I could always come...
Okay.
All right, well,
call me if you need anything.
You know, I'm, um...
just ten minutes away.
I'll call you
in a little bit, okay?
Give Owen a kiss for me.
Okay, bye.
There's something
you need to see.
That feel okay?
Do you need anything?
No, water's fine.
Notice how normal she is
with April,
and then... and then
her dad walks in.
Hey.
How you doing, kiddo?
Hanging in the
And her smile disappears.
Hey, Dad.
I can't hold that cup.
Can you bring it
Of course, sweetheart.
See, so before,
she's drinking on her own,
and now, all of a sudden,
she needs her dad's help.
It's like she's instantly
self-infantilizing.
Why would you do this?
Because I asked him to.
Without consulting me?
This is my patient.
You know, I ought to
haul your ass up
in front of the ethics
committee.
This is an absolute violation
of patient rights,
and you know that.
I do, Sharon,
but we could be
looking at a case
of medical child abuse here.
Child abuse?
Mr. Joffe is overbearing,
but he's clearly not intending
to hurt Michelle.
Of course not.
He's trying to save her,
but that's precisely why
we would refer to this
as a conversion disorder.
My gut is telling me
this entire relationship
is driven by her being sick
and him taking care of her.
Hold on.
Even if it's not Mito,
her symptoms could still
be explained by something else.
A Chiari malformation, maybe?
Before I call this guy
an abuser,
I want to
rule everything else out.
As soon as Michelle can stand,
he's gonna take her home,
and then we're out of options.
Okay.
You erase that footage
immediately.
Dr. Manning,
I understand how you feel,
and I want you to run whatever
tests you deem necessary
to narrow your differential
diagnosis;
however, if there is even
a 1% chance of abuse
taking place,
we have an obligation here.
So what do you need
to make a clear call?
I need to talk with Michelle
without her father present.
All right.
This is how
we're gonna make that happen.
All right, Michelle.
Here's the MRI machine
we're gonna be using.
It's still warming up,
but we have Dr. Charles here
to keep us company
until it's ready.
Are you okay with that?
Hi, Michelle.
Hi.
What kind of doctor are you?
I am the kind of doctor
whose job it is to make sure
you don't get nervous
about getting in that machine.
I'm not scared.
I'm used to this kind of stuff.
Me and my dad are in hospitals
all the time.
Hmm.
Well, we're hoping to
make it so that
you don't have to be
in them so much.
How does that sound?
Okay.
Good.
Six teaspoons
of gunpowder green tea.
Boiling water.
Gently.
Arabic tea.
This helps you prep for surgery?
Swirl.
Pour.
Make sure the tea
stays in the pot.
Sugar.
Mint.
Stir.
Slowly.
Don't want to change
the viscosity.
Viscosity?
Wait; that's why
you use hemodilution
to allow bypass
without reperfusion injury?
Should be done.
Tea with mint.
That's Moroccan, not Saudi.
It's not for the prince.
Thank you, Dr. Rhodes.
You can go.
That's it?
You did a nice job.
I remember Dad got tickets
to a play that day, "Wicked."
Oh, my daughter wanted me
to take her to that.
Was it good?
I don't know;
I never saw it.
I went into my dad's room
to see if he was ready,
but he was looking
at pictures of my mom
and being sad, so...
I went back to my room.
Then what happened?
I have got to confess,
I am so jealous of those socks.
Those hedgehogs are fantastic.
Okay, so you went back
to your room,
and...
Oh, I just waited
for a long time,
and then my stomach
started to hurt,
and I got dizzy,
and I yelled out for my dad,
and then...
And he came?
Yeah, he came.
He picked me up
and took me to the hospital.
Since then,
it's been like this a lot.
And how's your dad been doing?
Does, uh...
Does he still get sad?
Not so much.
I guess I keep him pretty busy.
Makes sense.
So.
We, uh... we good?
We should be all set.
Thank you, Mr. Joffe.
Now, if you can sign
just three more forms,
I promise you'll be done.
Dr. Manning's
been down in radiology
with my daughter
for over an hour.
Would you like me to page her?
No.
I'll just go down there.
Oh, I'm sorry,
you can't be in the room
while your daughter's
having an MRI.
Yeah, that's what she said,
but I'm not waiting around
anymore.
Mr. Joffe?
I'm Dr. Charles.
Could I talk to you
for a second?
Yeah, why?
Well, it's about your daughter.
There's a consultation room
right over here
if you have a couple minutes.
No, you know what?
If you have something to say,
can you just say it?
There is a strong possibility
that your daughter's
medical issues
have a psychological
component to them.
What the hell
are you talking about?
It's very important
that you understand that
I wouldn't be telling you this
unless I perceived
significant risk
to both you and your daughter,
but I want you
to consider the possibility
that when your wife died,
your daughter
might have misunderstood
your attempts to protect her
from your grief.
- Her isolation...
- Wait, what?
So I've been making her sick?
That's what you're
accusing me of?
It's much more complicated
than that.
No, but it's my fault.
I'm to blame.
That's actually
not what I'm saying.
If you'd hear me out...
I cannot believe you people.
I am not going to stand here
and listen to this.
I'm going to get my daughter
and get here out of here.
Michelle!
Excuse me,
my daughter's having an MRI.
- Where is that?
- Right over there, sir.
Where's my daughter?
She's still in the MRI machine.
Well, turn it off.
I'm taking her home now.
I'm sorry, sir,
but we can't do that.
No, please...
Mr. Joffe!
- Please, Mr. Joffe.
- Open this door.
- Open this door!
Mr. Joffe?
Madeline Gastern.
We are from the Department
of Child and Family Services.
What the hell is going on here?
A charge of medical child abuse
has been brought against you
by this hospital.
Child abuse?
That is a legal term only,
Mr. Joffe...
Michelle will be taken
into custody by the state
while the charge
is investigated.
What are you talking about?
I'm sorry;
I know this must be confusing,
but we need to sit down
with you and explain
why this has happened.
You.
You set this up, didn't you?
- No...
- Shame on you.
- Mr. Joffe...
- You...
Stay away from me.
Let me tell you something.
You people have
picked the wrong battle.
Dr. Ethan Choi
from Chicago Med.
I've left a few messages
for Dr. Glass.
We have a patient of hers here
who needs...
Please don't put me
on hold again.
I'm aware of that, but...
Unbelievable.
Maggie, I'm taking an hour
of personal time.
I wouldn't do it
if it wasn't important.
Why are you still here?
Hey, heard one of your
old shipmates was here.
- How's he doing?
- Not good.
I'm headed to the VA
to crack some heads.
You want me to come with?
Power in numbers?
I'll be okay.
Thanks.
You look a little lost.
I'm not sure what's going on
with my patient.
Her labs are inconsistent
with how she presents.
Whenever I get confused,
I always go back
to the history and the physical.
It's the best place
to find answers.
I need to know everything
you ate and drank last night.
I already told you.
Two glasses of white wine.
That's it.
And a ton of water
'cause I didn't want a hangover.
What's a "ton"?
Like, six or seven
of those bottled waters.
I would have had more
if it wasn't so expensive.
Expensive?
You said you were at home.
- I was.
- What is this?
"Metro"?
Were you there last night?
No.
You went to Metro?
Oh, my God.
You were there with Miles,
weren't you?
Did you hook up with him?
Oh, my God.
I can't believe it.
I'm so stupid.
Amy...
You're a liar
and a bitch.
Amy...
I hope you get an STD
and it kills you.
Let's get a urine tox.
If she took ecstasy,
that would explain her thirst.
Right.
By the way...
wow.
Excuse me.
I'm looking for Dr. Vicky Glass.
Over there.
Dr. Glass?
Yes.
Lieutenant Commander Choi,
Naval Reserve.
I'm a resident at Chicago Med.
Chief Mason came into our ED
complaining of stomach pains.
We did a CT and found this.
This cancer could kill him,
something that
could have been prevented
if you'd run a scan
three months ago
when he first told you
about his symptoms.
Well, I couldn't get him in
for the scan.
Believe me, I wanted to.
I did everything I could
to make it happen,
but as you can see,
there's a huge backlog here...
And you're underfunded
and understaffed.
I don't care.
These guys deserve better.
You can't get a scan approved;
go through back channels.
Oh, you mean screw protocol?
Yes, screw protocol.
Hey, that's an idea.
After all, the VA pays
for ER care
if a patient can't get
to a VA hospital.
Well, I could just tell him
what to say to get a CAT scan
and send him to you.
That what you mean?
- Yeah.
- Good.
We done chatting here?
'Cause I've got to get Mason in
to see a surgeon.
It might be too late.
I just got the results.
Wanted to bring them
as soon as I got them.
You didn't have to do that.
Wow.
Her UTox is negative.
No drugs.
I am out of ideas.
I need to talk to an attending.
I'm taking down
my online profile.
Whatever.
Don't do it on my account.
Go have fun.
"Fun"?
I... I've been on one awful date.
She asked me to go on a hike,
and I got bit by a spider.
It still hasn't healed.
Did you hear me?
Do you care?
Environmental studies,
dehydrated, the puffy knee...
We have one more test to run.
What happened?
Massive lower GI bleed.
We're taking him to surgery now.
Ethan, he could lose his colon.
Maybe worse.
I promised he'd make
a Naval reunion next week.
I'll do my best.
Hang in there, Chief.
Michelle's MRI?
No sign
of a Chiari malformation.
Just add it to the long list
of things I got wrong today.
Come on, Nat.
Look, I know something
had to be done.
I just think
we had other options.
Like what?
Like not breaking up a family.
I know how I'd feel
if someone tried to take Owen
away from me.
Look, this was the only way.
Remove the parent
and monitor the kid.
See what's really going on.
What about the trauma
of separation?
I mean, the guy loses his wife,
and now he's gonna
lose his daughter too?
It is traumatic,
but not fatal.
We don't step in,
Michelle could end up
in the morgue
from medication alone.
This hospital kidnapped
my daughter,
and I want her back.
- Mr. Joffe, you can't...
- And those two.
They're part of it.
No, I don't care.
I want my daughter,
and I want her now.
We'll talk
to the administrators.
See what's what.
I'm Chief of Patient Services.
Can I help you?
This man has a complaint
about his daughter.
I brought my daughter here
for treatment,
and they have kidnapped her.
- Can I speak to you, please?
- Yeah.
Mr. Joffe,
please, we're just trying
to help Michelle.
She's my daughter.
My daughter.
You cannot just take her away.
Well?
Mr. Joffe,
DCFS has jurisdiction over this.
There's nothing, at this time,
you can do here
about your daughter.
Are you serious?
My advice:
find yourself a lawyer.
How are you feeling?
I guess all right,
for a terrible friend.
We finally found out
what's wrong with you.
You have Lyme disease.
Seriously?
Lyme disease?
Yeah, it's probably
from a tick bite
on one of your field trips.
It explains your knee
and the rest of your symptoms.
So what happens now?
I'm putting you
on an antibiotic course,
and hopefully we got it
early enough
to avoid any long-term
consequences.
I hooked up with
my best friend's boyfriend.
There are gonna be some
long-term consequences.
Hello, hello.
Hey, what did Downey want?
Wish I knew.
Uh, he told me all about
his medical plan for the prince.
Yeah.
But then all he had me do
was make tea.
Moroccan mint tea.
Is he crazy?
- Yeah.
- Like, Mozart-crazy.
Guess I have to learn
how to make Moroccan tea.
Chief Mason...
he pulled through.
He's stable.
Thank you.
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
It's crazy.
A Saudi prince comes here
and gets the best
heart surgeon we have,
and a vet can't even
get a CT scan.
We didn't make the world, right?
I've spent all afternoon
justifying what we did.
I wish I felt better about it.
Me too.
Mr. Joffe?
The medical profession
isn't crazy about
doctors walking around
apologizing for things,
um...
but I'm very sorry.
What if it was me?
Look,
Mr. Joffe, we...
We all send out messages
that we're unaware of,
and not just you in this case.
Your daughter too.
I mean...
I just...
I don't understand how.
Look.
It is a very painful,
complicated idea to confront,
but if you are even
beginning to consider
that you might have had
a part in this,
conscious or not,
that is a huge,
very positive step.
I was trying to be
a good father.
And you are.
Nobody wants to cut you
out of this process.
And when the time is right,
you'll be allowed to visit.
Will you trust me on that?
Okay.
It's okay.
I appreciate that, sir.
Dr. Glass.
Didn't know you were Navy.
Please. Vicki.
Ethan.
Nice of the chiefs to allow
a couple Os in here.
Mason looks happy.
Thanks for taking
such good care of him.
You too.
Very resourceful.
I have no idea
what you're referring to.
Care for a drink?
Love one.
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -