Doug! Doug! Wait up a minute.
Hey.
I got to ask you
something in confidence.
Good morning to you.
So, how many people know
about me and Chuny Marquez?
Including the cleaning crew?
So it's everyone.
That would be an understatement.
It's great. It's just that, uh,
we've kind of run out
of things to talk about.
And you want out.
I think that would be best.
Well, you covered the spread.
Huh? The office pool.
I had you for next week
but what's five bucks
for a friend's happiness?
You've had experience at this.
How do I end it?
You know those
Chinese finger puzzles?
You know, the harder you
pull them, the tighter they get.
Yeah?
You got to just relax
see, and then, they
just droop and fall off.
That sounds ominous.
I tell you what you do. You
explain to her that you're doing this
for her own benefit,
that it's been fun
but it's starting to
interfere with work
and you don't want
to ruin your friendship
because that's what
you really care about.
You know what?
You're frightening,
you know that?
Morning.
You're late.
Hey, I was checking
the surgery schedule.
This is it for us
today... a hernia?
Is that what it says?
Wow.
Problem, Carter?
No. It's just that our
schedule has been pretty...
lightweight lately.
Hernias and Hickman lines...
You can do this
stuff in your sleep.
No Hibiclens?
No, we're out.
At least this gives
us a little more time
to prepare for the
firm conference.
You ready?
Mm-hmm.
Uh-uh. 3:00 sharp, right?
I'm doing the first half,
you're doing the second.
We'll brush each
other up over lunch.
Carter, if I need your help
I'll ask for it, okay?
Happiness is a
full nursing staff.
I hope everyone
is feeling healthy.
Peachy.
I'd hate to see us get hit
by the one-day flu again.
Oh, I think it's run its course.
I hope so. I can't
afford to get fired.
Oh, honey, that was
just management
rattling its tired old saber.
What if they decide
to replace us?
They won't; after our sick-out,
management got religion.
The contract negotiations
are going great.
So are we going to
get what we want?
Yep. County
commissioners are nervous.
They know the
public's on our side.
They won't be
after they read this.
Right there.
Oh, no.
What?
"Patient dies after nurses walk.
"An unidentified nurse
"at County General Hospital
"allegedly transfused a
patient with the wrong type blood
"leading to his death
in the hospital's
emergency room."
Somebody died?!
That's what they
get for hiring temps.
"Hospital sources say
"the nurse's error was a
direct result of understaffing
caused by an illegal, one-day
sick-out by ER nurses."
Oh, man!
Where's Carol?
She's on at 9:00.
Did this guy die because of us?
First name Gil.
Last name unknown.
Section Y-37.
No headstones?
They just get a number.
Of course, between
the wind and the snow...
There's nothing.
Friend of yours?
No.
Well, uh... he might
be one of these in here.
I think we buried them last.
Ah, Mark, I was
just reminding Kerry
that today...
Is prospective intern day.
How could I forget?
There are six fourth-year
medical students
interviewing upstairs.
Six?
These are top prospects
being hotly recruited
by other programs,
so I expect you two to show them
what a real ER is all about.
We'll do our best.
I'm sure you will.
Carol, can we talk
to you for a minute?
Sure. What's up?
This.
We're not going to
take the fall for this.
The negotiations
are going our way.
If some temp made a
mistake, that is not our fault.
What temp?
The one who gave the
patient the wrong blood.
It wasn't a temp. It was me.
God, they lied to me.
I filed an incident report
and they said that
was the end of it.
Need a hand back here!
15-year-old male.
Multiple GSWs to the chest.
Massive blood loss on scene.
He shot my partner!
BP's 50 palp, pulse 130.
Two liters saline in transit.
O2, 15 liters.
He got a name?
Hernandez.
Who's bringing up the rear?
58-year-old male, single GSW
through and
through to the thigh.
BP 130/90, Pulse 108, resps 26.
Help the boy!
Don't listen to him, Doc.
Look, we're going
to help both of you.
No, no. Officer, officer, we
need you to wait outside, okay?
We got to work on your partner.
Don't worry. Don't worry.
Just give us some room.
On two... hut one, hut two!
Need suction.
Decreased breath
sounds on the right side.
I need to intubate.
Pressure's down to 40 palp.
Pulse 160.
Lydia, draw up the blood gas.
Maybe this will teach
him not to shoot cops.
CBC, type and cross for six.
Get the O-neg
going, chest tube tray.
You got that thoraseal ready?
In a sec.
Alright, I'm in.
Will you tape it
up for me, please?
Mm-hmm.
I'll call Radiology
for a portable.
And respiratory for a vent.
I'm going to go check on Doyle.
CBC and a crit.
Update tetanus
and give him one gram of Ancef.
How is he?
Missed the femoral artery.
No neuro deficit.
Excellent.
Sergeant...
Mattimore...
Welcome to the
Purple Heart's Club.
Thanks. How's the kid?
We're working on him next door.
Hi. I'm Jeanie Boulet.
Hi.
Mike and Cindy Patterson.
Hi, Mike. Have a seat.
I understand you've
got a headache.
Oh, nothing serious.
Do you have a
history of migraines?
I used to get a few in college.
These are different.
They come on for no reason.
What caused them before?
Tubas.
We were in the marching band.
Okay.
You're also suffering from
insomnia and dizziness.
Anything else?
He just hasn't been himself.
How so?
Well, uh, last night
in his sleep, he bit me
and when he woke up, he
didn't know where he was.
Okay. Let's take a look.
Hi.
How's that kid who got shot?
Oh, he made surgery.
Oh, thank you.
Mm-hmm. My mother
was disappointed
you couldn't make it
for dinner last night.
Work, you know.
My brothers are starting
to doubt your intentions.
All five of them?
Chuny... Mark...
You first.
Mark... I'm not
sorry we did this.
It's been fun, but, um...
It's starting to
interfere with my work
and I really want to
preserve our friendship.
I know that's as important
to you as it is to me.
Yeah.
No hard feelings, right?
No, no. Of course not.
Okay.
Oh, what did you want to say?
Um...
Nothing.
You hung me out to dry.
No, I didn't.
Then who did?
Sit down, Carol.
Let me get you a cup of coffee.
I don't want a cup of coffee
and I don't want to sit down.
It wasn't me.
Who then?
Drummond?
Somebody who wanted
to influence negotiations
and somebody who had
access to your incident report.
Look, Carol, we have got a
threatened work stoppage here.
Emotions are running
high, the budget is shrinking,
and you have got a nursing staff
that seems to refuse
to acknowledge
the realities of '90s medicine.
This has nothing to
do with the sick-out.
I gave him the wrong blood.
Which I believe would
not have happened
if your friends had honored
their contract and
shown up for work.
This isn't labor politics, Mary.
A man died.
I'm sorry, Carol.
I killed a man
and nobody around here
seems to give a damn!
Tie.
Peter?
I think you're wise
to slow it down
after pediatrics.
Nothing like a simple hernia
to put you back in
touch with the basics.
Hand, blade, clamp, suture.
Peanut, please.
Carter...
What's the difference between
a prostate and a garden hose?
I don't know.
Let me tell you.
There's a vas deferens.
Oh.
Corky Butterfield told me
that one back in the day.
Good old Corky.
Blew a gasket in the latrine
at Soldier's Field.
Met his maker
with his pants down.
Metz.
And sometimes, you have
to step back to reassess.
Hell of a lot
easier to take stock
from a nice, puffy
blimp than an F-16.
Right?
It's the first mature breakup
of my entire life.
Oh, congratulations.
No histrionics, no yelling.
We just saw the
situation, we addressed it.
Right. Now, how'd she take it?
Well, she's hurting, you know,
but she's going to
get over it in time.
Mm-hmm. What time you got?
Mark?
I'd like you to meet Jay Musoff
Whit Haskell, Monica Campbell
Alex Ghandar, Matt
Collins and Leslie Wu.
Hello. Hi.
I've prepared an
introductory packet
to our emergency
medicine program.
You can refer to it
throughout the day.
The ER may appear chaotic,
but if you watch closely
you'll see a carefully
organized system at work.
I thought that I would
take Jay, Whit and Monica.
Fine.
We'll start with the
admissions desk
and go from there.
If you want to follow
at a ten-minute
stagger, feel free.
Right.
The heart of any emergency room
is the admit desk.
Information is the blood
that courses through it
and the desk clerk is
like the tricuspid valve,
if you will.
So, you guys want
to play doctor?
Let's go.
I chase number one,
lose him down an alley
I come back just in
time to catch number two
bleeding my partner
here with a cheap .22.
He doesn't even have his gun out
so I capped the punk, twice.
You were lucky your partner
came back when he did.
Two rounds, two hits.
I couldn't believe it.
You should have
seen his face, Pete.
He was so surprised.
Like, what do you
think I was going to do,
give him a hug?
And then when
he saw the blood...
You have to go now.
He needs his rest.
Oh, I'll wait outside, Sarge.
No, no. Go on home.
No, no. I'll wait outside.
Peno!
Home.
Bring me a chocolate frosted
in the morning.
He can do that, right?
If he gets a dozen for us.
All right, take care.
Yeah.
Talkative.
Ten months out of the academy
he thinks he's Dirty Harry.
Why didn't you shoot back?
32 years on the force.
I've fired twice
outside the practice range.
A cop who won't use his gun.
That's a first.
Your arm okay?
Yeah, yeah. It's
just a little sore.
Carol, can I speak
to you a minute?
Be right back.
We got a situation here.
Well, I spoke to Mary Cain
and she says she doesn't know
who leaked it.
And you believed her?
Yeah, I did.
We had an agreement on the table
to protect current
staffing levels
and management just pulled it.
They're going to use this
to renege on the whole contract.
I'm sorry to hear that.
You had no idea
they were going to use
this incident against us?
No, I didn't.
What? You think
I'm lying to you?
I don't know anymore, Carol.
You and management
can fight and scream
and tear each other's
hair out, for all I care.
I've got a patient.
Most interns send their samples
to the lab without knowing
what happens once they're there.
Let's pretend that we're a
urine sample and find out.
Okay. Let's see.
Scalded foot in curtain two.
That looks promising. This way.
Mark, I've got a
25-year-old male...
Headaches, insomnia,
behavioral tics.
His wife brought him in.
He's pretty young for a stroke.
What do you think?
Encephalitis or a mass lesion.
Could be. Let's do a CT first.
Who's on for Infectious Disease?
Greg Fischer.
Get him down. Okay.
Oh, hello, Dr. Greene.
Sasha, what a pleasant surprise.
Sasha's one of our five-star
chefs in the cafeteria.
So what's today's special?
Bratwurst.
Idiot busboy
carries out bin of hot water.
Shoom!
Right down my boot.
Pretty nasty.
Normally, I'd amputate
but I'm afraid you'd
put it on the menu.
All right, Alex. First step.
Assess the burn.
Leslie, what do you think?
Partial thickness
and there's a small blister
below the medial malleolus.
Good. Matt, what's next?
Uh, 100 of Demerol for the pain.
Then debride any broken blisters
Thermazine dressing.
Correct.
You snip, you dress
and you give the Demerol.
I thought we were taking a tour.
Consider it interactive.
I'll check in on you later.
Let me know if
you need anything.
Thanks.
Hey...
Regards to Kenny.
Will do.
You two know each other?
Yeah. I picked up
her cousin for B&E.
She doesn't seem to mind.
No. Best thing that
ever happened to him.
He's just like this
kid who got shot...
Young and scared and
gangs putting the heat on him.
What happened to him?
I got him into a work program.
You know what he is now?
A locksmith.
They used to have these dances
here called blue and whites.
You know, cops and nurses.
Lot of marriages
came out of that.
Yeah?
Yours, too?
No.
For me, it was always the job.
You were probably
just a lousy dancer.
Hey, if I didn't have
this hole in my leg
I could show you a turn or two.
Thanks. I'll take a rain check.
Do you know why so many nurses
end up with cops?
Similar schedule?
Shared appreciation
for life's vicissitudes.
That's beautiful.
Thanks.
I stole it myself.
Too much coffee.
Has that happened before today?
Hey, give me a break. I'm 58.
I can't have the shakes
after I get shot?
I thought only the
scheduling nurse
was allowed to change the board.
I like to erase my own
surgery when I'm done.
Gives me a sense
of accomplishment.
What are you up to?
I'm presenting
at firm conference with Benton.
There's a name I haven't
seen up here in a while.
Been a little slow lately.
There's a
splenectomy that's open
5:00 with Crosby.
Why don't you
sign him up for it?
Oh, he usually signs
up for his own surgery.
Just because Peter's
stuck in neutral
doesn't mean you have to be.
I'm doing a
Portacaval shunt later.
Care to join me?
I'd love to...
But I don't know what
Benton has planned.
Judging by this, not much.
Hi. I'm Dr. Ross.
Uh, Lisa Sayler.
This is my son, Benny.
You work at the hospital?
Yeah, upstairs in ICU.
I usually bring
him to the clinic
but I really didn't
want to wait this time.
Okay, what happened?
I'm not sure.
He was in the backyard,
and he hurt his elbow.
Benny, can you do this?
Can you straighten out
your arm like that for me?
You have to use
his special name.
Which is?
Right now, it's Clark Kent.
Hello. Hi, Clark.
Hey. All right. Let me straighten
your arm out just here a little bit.
Does that hurt?
It's okay. All right.
All right, we're going to
have to get some x rays.
Anybody here have x-ray vision?
Uh, no? Okay.
Well, we'll get Radiology
to take a look at it.
No idea how this happened?
No. I wasn't there, but I
think he was trying to fly.
Ghandar, Jeopardy time.
Tenderness in the
anatomic snuff box
indicates this common fracture.
What is first metacarpal?
Navicular.
I should try that
on my students.
I teach third grade.
Really? Nice.
Ow.
Heather, you have a
medial collateral ligament tear
otherwise known as
Gamekeeper's Thumb.
Playing goalie is
hell on a manicure.
Hockey?
Water polo.
Coed.
Sounds rough.
Last year, I took a
point-blank shot to the face.
Fractured my left orbit.
It's a Singles League...
Swim and mingle.
The guys I've met there
they're tough on the outside,
but emotionally, they're wimps.
I guess my type is more...
the reverse.
Need some help?
No, thanks.
But I did want to talk to you
about that cop, Mattimore.
Oh, isn't he great?
My dad says he's a
real legend on the force.
His right hand has a twitch.
No head trauma, no
focal deficits, right?
Right.
It's probably nerves.
I'd like a head CT to be sure.
The way his hand moves...
something about it bothers me.
I can't order a $1,000
test without indications.
I think it's recurring,
he's trying to hide it.
I'll do a neuro exam.
If something shows
up, we'll scan him.
Thanks.
Accommodation without
direct response to light.
Argyll Robertson.
Mrs. Patterson...
Cindy.
Cindy, how long
ago did did you notice
the change in Mike's behavior?
About a month ago
I found him down in the kitchen
at 3:00 am talking to himself.
There's a possibility
you have a low-grade
infection in your
central nervous system.
I'd like to do a spinal tap.
Uh... that sounds painful.
We give you plenty
of local anesthetic.
Takes about five minutes.
Jeanie, can you get
an LP tray, please?
Jeanie. I'm sorry.
I've been meaning to call you.
That's okay. I
didn't expect you to.
Hey, Dr. Benton.
3:00 conference.
Thank you, Carter.
Which leaves us plenty of time
for a splenectomy at 5:00.
We'll be in and out by 6:30.
You signed me up for
surgery without my permission?
Crosby needs someone to assist.
He does great work and
I know he respects yours.
Take it off. What?
My name, take it off the board.
It's too late. There's
not enough time.
Someone's going
to have to cancel.
The only sign of
fracture is the fat pad.
Very slight.
Will he need a cast?
I think the splint
is going to be fine.
It should be healed
in three or four weeks.
Can I talk to you outside?
Yeah.
We're gonna be right back, okay?
You just hang here.
Has he always been
this uncommunicative?
My, uh... my husband
died five months ago
in a car accident.
He was taking Benny
to get an ice cream cone.
Was Benny hurt?
No...
But it took about ten minutes
for the ambulance to get there.
Benny watched his father die.
I'm sorry.
Um... so when he
started to pretend
that he was Superman
I just... I thought
it was healthy
a way of coping.
I got him that
costume for Halloween.
Now he wears it every
day under his clothes.
Do you know Lyle Baker?
He's a child psychiatrist;
one of the best.
I want to have him
come down for a consult
see what he thinks.
Okay.
Yeah? Okay.
Benny?
Benny, come out, please.
How long will it take to heal?
About six weeks.
There go the playoffs.
I don't know what I'm
going to do with myself.
Would you like to
go out sometime?
Uh... that brings up
an interesting issue.
Wu, are doctors
supposed to date patients?
Uh, definitely not.
For my protection, right?
Right.
I mean, what if you
weren't my doctor?
Then it's hypothetical.
When do you get off?
6:00.
So, hypothetically
if I were at Finch's bar
on Dearborn tonight at 6:30
and you just happened to
come in and have a drink,
that would be legal, right?
Hypothetically... if I
weren't your doctor.
Hmm...
You know, this thumb
is starting to hurt again.
I think I'd like to
see a specialist.
Sorry.
Have you ever seen
an abscess this big?
Never. It's extraordinary.
Mr. Cliff, how did this happen?
I'm building a cabin up north.
No plumbing yet;
just an outhouse.
I sat down on the seat
without noticing the ice.
Ooh, when I stood up...
That would account
for the wide extension.
We need to drain.
11 blade.
Not to worry, Mr. Cliff.
Relief is on the way.
Hey, my two favorite ladies.
Still trying to charm us?
And they said man
would never fly.
Now they have
Air Jordan on a mission to Mars.
Nurse Hathaway told me
about the problem you're
having with your hand.
She did, did she?
I'm sure it's nothing serious,
but I'd like to do a
simple neurological exam.
So what I want you to do
is squeeze my
fingers when I say so.
I got shot in the leg.
The rest of me is fine.
We just want to make sure.
No, thanks.
It'll only take a minute.
I don't want it.
It's for your own good.
I said I don't want it.
The man doesn't want it.
Carla?
Hey.
What are you doing here?
Waiting.
What's wrong?
Are you sick? What's wrong?
No. We should
probably talk later, Peter.
Carla Reese.
That's me.
Dr. Coburn will see you now.
Coburn? OB?
Peter, I will call you later.
No, no, no.
Whoa, whoa. Hey, whoa.
What's up?
Are you pregnant?
Later, all right?
When Kerry asked
me to talk to you
about our program, I thought,
"What's a grizzled old
mucketymuck such as yours truly
have to say to the next
generation of sawbones?"
And then I realized, nope.
Everyone has a tale
to tell, and mine begins
in a cold, little farmhouse
in Hoobane, North Dakota.
Pa Morgenstern worked
at the local tannery
and Ma was a taxidermist...
How are they holding up?
Stick a fork in 'em...
They've been Weavered.
Still no sign of Superman, Doc.
Thanks, Malik, keep looking.
What is that smell?
Bratwurst on the house.
Compliments of
Sasha, the cafeteria guy.
Yeah, remind me
not to cure him again.
So, what do you think?
About you dating a patient?
Do the words Exxon
Valdez ring a bell?
Yeah. I'm still holding.
You should talk.
This is new territory for you.
It takes time to learn
how to read the signs.
I know the difference between
dependence and mutual attraction.
So, what are you
going to do about it?
Doyle. Gamekeeper's
thumb in four.
Check the splint, if it's
set, you discharge her.
Roger that.
Lisa? Yeah, not yet.
I know he didn't
get past security
so he's still in the building.
No. No, you stay put.
He knows where you're working.
He'll probably be
heading your way, okay?
Great. Bye.
When I held that dying
mole rat in my hand
when I felt its little heart
pitter-pattering in my hands...
Do you see it?
It's glowing...
Looks like syphilis.
Wow. Neurosyphilis.
I'm surprised.
Imagine how surprised
Mrs. Patterson's going to be.
How are we going to tell them?
We don't tell them.
We tell him.
And not her?
It's his disease.
We can't violate
his right to privacy.
Oh, and she has no rights
except the right to be infected?
Why don't I talk to him?
He's my patient.
I just asked you
down on a consult.
I appreciate that, but
this is a tricky situation
and I have more
experience in these matters.
It's my field. I've dealt with
these situations hundreds of times.
This kind of thing
can kill a marriage.
So can silence.
Dr. Carter?
Are you aware of the time?
Yes. I was waiting
for Dr. Benton
to go over some of these notes.
The entire surgical
staff is already here.
Right.
Any time now, doctor.
So, uh...
When were you going to tell me?
When I knew I had
something to tell.
You know, both my
sisters had miscarriages
during the first trimesters.
What did Coburn say?
Well, she said that it
was just some spotting
and that, you know
there was nothing
to worry about.
All systems go.
Carla, I don't understand.
I mean, we were careful.
Well, it's like they say,
nothing is 100% effective.
And you're sure it's mine?
I'm going to forget
you said that.
I'm just going to lay it all
on the stress and
the surprise, okay?
Carla, I'm sorry.
Look, honey, I don't...
What am I supposed to say?
Look.
We're two very
different people, Peter
and Lord knows
we both have enough
going on in our lives.
Look...
I've made the choice, Peter...
to have this baby.
All right, uh...
What do you expect
from me, Carla?
The truth.
You've always been
really honest with me.
It's one of your
finer qualities.
I got to get back to work.
I'll... I'll... call
you, all right?
Sure.
You can adjust these
if they're too short.
We'll probably
discharge you today.
Thought you could
use the practice.
Stop being so nice.
Makes me feel even more foolish
for speaking the way I did.
You know, when
I was in the alley
with the kid, Hernandez...
I've had guns pulled
on me a dozen times.
This wasn't a hard guy.
This was a kid
caught in the deep end.
30 more seconds,
he drops that piece
we both walk out of there.
What happened?
My hand jerked.
He thought I was
going for my gun.
In a second, he had to decide
whether he
wanted to live or die.
Does anyone else
know about your hand?
You mean, like the department?
They'd put me in the mail room.
Then who deals with
the next stupid kid
who panics and pulls a piece?
Some hotshot like Peno?
You need to get it checked out.
What is it?
Is it Parkinson's, is
it a brain tumor, or...?
I don't know
but those are
treatable disorders.
You could have years
to teach the Penos
to be better cops.
Or I could be here
lying flat on my back,
stuck full of tubes.
Well, at least, let
me do a CAT scan...
Find out what's going on.
I'll tell you what, angel.
I'll think about it, okay?
Good.
The Aortagram confirms
the unilateral renal
artery stenosis
and treatment was via
an aortorenal bypass graft
using a segment of
the saphenous vein.
Now, discussing the
causes and evaluation
of surgical hypertension
will be my colleague...
Dr. Peter Benton.
Except that he was detained
which is why he asked me
to s-s... uh, stand in for him.
The surgically correctable
causes of hypertension
include coarctation
of the aorta,
Cushing's syndrome and,
uh, pheochromocytoma.
What about Conn's syndrome?
And Conn's syndrome, of course.
And Hyperaldosteronism?
That, too.
Wasn't a trial of a
drug therapy warranted
before surgical intervention
was undertaken?
The surgery carries a
one percent mortality rate.
I see your point.
What were the results
of the renal renin assays?
They were high.
They were very high.
Of course, but
what was the ratio
of the affected to
the unaffected side?
That I don't know.
Obviously not.
So... uh...
Hey, anyone know
the difference between
a prostate and a garden hose?
Leave her alone!
Shut up! I ought to slap
some manners into you.
Hey, you got no...
Hey! What are you
doing? Let go of him!
I am trying to talk
to my lady, here.
This kid starts
kicking me in the leg.
You were being mean to her!
Sit down! Sit down and relax!
Call ICU, tell Lisa
Sayler we found her son
and get security down here.
What is that? What is that!?
What are you doing?
He was being mean to her.
Yeah, well, he could have
been mean to you, too.
No, he couldn't.
Yes, he could have.
No, he couldn't because
I have super powers.
Benny, you don't
have super powers.
You are a six-year-old boy.
You live with your
mother in Hyde Park.
Benny... you cannot fly
and you cannot attack grown men
who are arguing
with their girlfriend.
You understand?
Hey, are you listening to me?
How's it going?
Hey, somebody
who will talk to me.
You must not have
gotten the memo.
I read the paper.
You hanging in there?
By a thread.
The nurses think
I'm Benedict Arnold.
Management's using my
mistake to make the RNs look bad.
You're in a tough spot.
Yeah.
You know, I should
probably just go
to the Sun Times
myself, tell them
the death had nothing
to do with the sick-out.
Then what happens?
I don't know.
Lose my job, maybe?
You ready for that?
Good news?
Mrs. Patterson, I'm going to need
to speak to your husband alone.
Why? What's wrong?
Jeanie, will you show Mrs.
Patterson to the waiting room?
No. I want to stay
with you, Mike.
Does she have to go?
Only if that's what you want.
Mike I want to stay.
No, I want her to stay.
Mr. Patterson, this is
sensitive information.
It can be very
difficult to hear.
I want my wife
here with me, okay?
All right... if that's
your decision.
Our tests show that
you have neurosyphilis.
It's a disease that can cause
mild personality disorders
like the ones you've
been suffering.
Syphilis?
Neurosyphilis.
It's sexually transmitted.
But that doesn't mean it
was contracted recently.
It takes an average of seven
years for symptoms to arise
after the initial infection.
Seven years?
But we've been together
since high school.
We've always been
committed to each other
from the day we met, to the
day we got married, to now.
We can treat you
with IV antibiotics
and check Cindy for exposure.
In two weeks, you'll
be as good as new.
This is impossible.
We've only been with each other.
Cindy...?
Cindy?
I'm s... I'm sorry.
We've got a
35-year-old male, MVA.
Car skidded into a light pole.
ALOC, multiple lacs,
GCS 8 at the scene.
BP's 90/60, pulse
110 and irregular.
Passenger space intrusion.
We had to use the
jaws to get him out.
Extrication time?
Approximately 20 minutes.
No witnesses, no ID.
Clear, people... stay back.
Dr. Greene?
Yeah. Yeah. Come with me.
15 Liters O2, two IVs
normal saline, one liter in.
All right, everybody,
on my count...
One, two, three.
Go.
Ghandar, cardiac monitor.
What do you see?
Looks like PVCs.
Pupils are sluggish.
Good bilateral
breath sounds.
Lidocaine, 100, IV push.
Start a drip at two migs.
Should they be in here?
My students, my call.
Get a CBC, chem 20, enzymes,
type and cross for four units.
Pulse ox 95.
OD in curtain four.
We got a gusher...
pressure dressing.
Piggyback a gram of Ancef.
He's in fib.
Charge 200.
Wu, put gloves on.
You ever bring
somebody back to life?
No.
All right. Get over here.
Clear.
There you go.
Okay, charge to 300.
Clear.
Charging 360.
Excellent.
Got a pulse.
All right, Collins.
Put in a foley.
Don't be shy, it's not yours.
Ghandar, glove up.
You're going to help me
with a peritoneal lavage.
Doug, how's that leg?
Nasty. He got the
popliteal artery.
Dr. Ross?
Yep?
Benny, what are
you doing in here?
Benny! Benny!
Haleh, get him out of
here, will you, please?
Come on, baby, Come on.
That's it, Come on.
Yeah, Come on.
More 4 x 4s, grab a five-inch...
Where were you?
Uh... firm conference.
Yeah, the firm conference.
I got crucified in
there covering for you.
Yeah, well, you
shouldn't have tried.
I didn't have a choice.
We were supposed
to do it together
and you left me
twisting in the wind.
Not to mention
trashing my reputation
in front of every
surgeon in this hospital.
Carter, I'm sorry, all
right? Something came up.
You're sorry. Something came up.
That's your excuse?
Yeah. Right.
I've got a shunt with Hicks.
Would you do me a favor?
The next time that
you feel the urge
to ruin my career
I would appreciate a warning.
Tom Clayton?
Carol Hathaway?
Yeah.
You want something
to eat, coffee?
No. No, thank you.
So, you're the nurse
manager in the ER.
Is that right?
Do you mind if I take notes?
No.
Is this going to
be on the record?
Yes, it is.
Here you go.
Is that man going to die?
Maybe. He was hurt pretty badly.
Just like your dad, right?
I was thinking about
what I said to you earlier
and I was wrong.
Okay, sometimes, when
you try to help somebody
and you can't
and it gets inside
you and it, and it twists
and you... wonder why.
You should do...
what you think is right.
And you don't let me
or anybody else stop you.
Okay?
It's...
been a long time.
I can't remember if, uh,
Superman had a dad or not.
But if he did, I
know that he was
very, very proud of his son.
Okay?
Come here. Come here.
Hey.
I've never done this before.
Really?
This is exactly
the kind of thing
you should be doing.
So, should I be
worried about Peter?
What do you mean?
Don't play dumb,
Carter. It doesn't suit you.
Is his emotional state
impairing his surgical ability?
No. Not that I've seen.
I appreciate your loyalty.
But I want you to know...
If Peter can't use your talents
my team can.
Really? Are you serious?
I'm almost always serious.
I need Mr. Patterson's chart.
Why's that?
I couldn't convince him to stay.
Tricky situation.
Are you going to notify
the Department of Health?
It's the law.
Well, why don't you wait
a couple of days,
let them talk it out.
I'll give him a call
and he'll probably
come back in.
Are you refusing
to give me his chart?
It's my job to be an
advocate for my patients.
It's your job to assist me.
That's why it's called
"Physician Assistant."
Are you always this
arrogant, or is it just me?
It's just you.
Look, I owe you an apology
for the other night.
Greg, you don't want to date
a woman who's HIV-positive.
You don't owe me anything.
Did you see me zap that guy?
I had my hands inside his chest.
Unbelievable.
Thanks a lot.
Thank you. Bye-bye.
Well, I want to thank you two
for taking care of our charges.
What did you think?
Well, frankly, I
was disappointed.
I found a general
lack of enthusiasm
inattention to detail.
If I were you, Donald
I would seriously
reevaluate their applications.
Well, don't worry, Kerry
because none of your students
decided to apply
for the program.
On the other hand, Mark,
all three of your candidates
rank us as their top choice.
You really reached
those kids today.
You ever thought about
an academic appointment?
There is a tenured
spot available.
I never really thought about it.
I think it's clear
your place is on the faculty.
Really?
Absolutely.
Carol...
I just got a call from
a Sun Times reporter.
He wanted me to confirm
some statements you made.
I hope you did.
They're all true.
Why did you do it?
If you have to ask, you
don't know me very well.
I thought we were friends.
No, Mary, you're my boss.
I lost a patient.
I can't hide that,
and I can't forget it.
Neither should you.
Drummond wants to see you
right away.
Hicks offered me a
position on her team.
I'm taking it.
Effective Monday.
Okay.
You know, a month ago
you would have
ripped my lungs out
for going behind your
back to another surgeon.
Now you just stand there?
Since when did I start caring
about what you do, Carter?
Never.
But now, you don't
care about yourself.
You don't care
about your reputation.
I need an evaluation
before I can transfer
to Hicks' team.
You'll get it.
You know, in that
surgery today...
everything I did, you taught me.
Saul, I'll try your winter ale.
Yeah.
Mark Greene.
Heather Morgan.
What happened to your thumb?
Oh, it's a long story.
I had to go to
the hospital for it.
Saw this great doctor.
I hope he took good care of you.
She, actually.
Can I ask you a
hypothetical question?
I think we can dispense
with the hypotheticals.
Absolutely.
Did you order those?
No, they're from
table 14 in the back.
You bring them everywhere?
Haleh?
These are the
shifts for next week.
There's still a problem
with Wednesday.
We only have six RNs scheduled,
so you may need
to bring in a float.
There's supply reqs, a
memo from Mary Cain
and a note from
Buildings and Grounds
that two of our parking
spaces have been reassigned.
Don't go to the parking
firm. Go straight to Weber.
We won on this last year
but I think now,
they're getting serious.
That's not my job.
It is now.
I've been suspended.