Hi. I'm here to see Dr. Weaver.
She went that way,
handing out badges.
Excuse me?
"Creativity, accountability,
respect, excellence." Hm.
That's a lot to live up to.
Hm. Malik. Yeah.
This man's looking
for Dr. Weaver.
This way. Hurry
up, man, I'm dying.
You'll be all right. Let's
go. Have a seat right here.
This guy's got a cut. A
cut? The bitch stabbed me!
What'd she stab you with?
A c-carving knife. As if I was
a damn steak or something.
Whoa!
There goes the ulnar.
You're killing me!
No. Just breathe. I'm
sorry. Sit down, please.
Stay seated!
Get down. Hold still.
Don't be such a baby.
We can't help you
unless you stop.
Look me in the eye. Hold still.
Are you a doctor?
Just keep the pressure on it.
We'll use this to
make a tourniquet.
Get his arm out.
Put your arm out.
Wait.
Come on around this side.
Pump it up to 180.
Keep breathing. Just relax.
We got 180. Okay.
All right, take your hand
off. Take your hand off.
Hm. Creativity. That's what
it says on your badge, isn't it?
Who are you?
Gabe, sorry I'm
late. You all right?
Yeah, of course.
But get me a couple
of curved Kellys
and some 3/0 Vicryl,
and I'll be even better.
It's good to see you.
Lucy, this is Dr. Gabriel
Lawrence, our new Attending.
How do you do?
Mark.
I know, I'm late.
I want you to meet
Gabe Lawrence. Hi.
Gabe, this is Dr. Mark Greene.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
I've heard a lot about you.
Well, heh, don't
hold it against me.
Were you in an accident?
No, no, I, uh... I started
my shift a little early.
I'm sorry?
Uh, Gabe is coming
over from New Western
as our new Attending.
As our new Attending.
We're incredibly lucky to
have him, don't you think?
Absolutely.
We're gonna take the grand
tour. Would you like to come?
I've done the grand
tour. I'm gonna get this.
What do you got? A
28-year-old fell off his bike.
I didn't fall. A cab cut me off.
Passed out for two minutes.
Forehead contusions.
Vitals are stable.
So Reece might not be yours?
That's what she said.
Think she's lying?
I don't know. I wasn't with
her 24 hours a day, you know?
Oh, man. Oh, man. Oh, man.
She's gonna use this
against me, isn't she?
She can't.
If Carla had any doubts,
she should've raised them
at the parentage
petition three months ago.
She didn't, so it's
moot. It's not a problem.
You've put yourself
through a hell of a lot for this.
Maybe you should
make sure he's yours.
Do a DNA test.
No.
Peter, you hired me
to protect your interests.
If you're looking for a way
out, she just gave you one.
We're gonna have to intubate.
Okay, everybody, on my
count. One, two, three. Good.
What do we got?
We got a 16-year-old male.
Single GSW to the left chest.
I'm gonna put in a chest tube.
Can you, uh, intubate?
I think I can manage.
15 of Etomidate, 100 of
sux, number-eight ET tube.
Ten blade. Help me.
You're gonna be
okay. What's his name?
Joshua Fox. That's
the only I.D. he had.
Okay, Joshua. They're gonna
put a tube down your throat
to help you breathe, okay?
Haleh, can you call his family?
Off a video card?
It's all we've got.
- Thora-Seal's ready.
- Hook me up.
What's this about a rescheduled
surgery this afternoon?
We got a cancellation, so
I moved up a mastectomy.
Okay, well, you
can move it back.
I've got an elective hernia.
I'm sorry, I am not going to
torture a woman for two weeks
just so some man can
have his groin patched.
Male surgeons decide...
Okay, okay, I surrender.
Hormones talking. You
can have your surgery.
Okay, I'm in. Bag him.
Well, there doesn't seem
to be much blood in here at all.
I'm gonna sew
the tube in. 0 silk.
Good breath sounds. Carol,
will you call up the ICU?
See if we can get Joshua a bed?
Sure. Be right back, Josh.
So, Dr. Corday, the
mastectomy coming in today,
is that Elaine Nichols? Mm-hm.
Thought that wasn't until...
It wasn't, I moved it forward.
Sure that's the
right thing to do?
It doesn't seem kind of fast?
Why are you so interested?
She's a friend of the family.
Really? Mm-hm.
Then I shouldn't discuss
it with you, should I?
You make sure
you get a chest film.
You finished
assisting Dr. Carter.
Good. I have something for you.
The Chicago Gazette is
sending over a reporter today
to do a puff piece on me.
But they also
wanna look at the ER.
Well, why are you telling me?
You'll show 'em around to
see what heroes we all are.
How we save kiddies' lives,
et cetera. Blow my trumpet.
Won't you do that
better yourself?
Look at you, look at me.
Who would you rather
spend an hour with?
You have a point.
Next time wear a helmet.
Come on, doc, give me a break.
How 'bout a fractured skull?
You wanna be fed
through a tube, be my guest.
Okay, okay, I'll
wear the helmet.
So can I go now?
Not yet. We need a head CT.
What's that?
My Core Values badge.
Creativity, accountability,
respect, excellence.
Wow, all that and beautiful too.
You must be some kind of nurse.
I am.
Why doesn't Dr. Grumpy have one?
Guess I'm out of the loop.
Oh, looks like a broken arm.
We're gonna need some x-rays.
Any other sign of trauma?
Contusion to the right shoulder,
ecchymosis of the
face and right hip.
And slight
tenderness to the wrist.
How far did you fall, Lauren?
I'm not sure.
Can you tell me how you fell?
Uh, did you fall like this,
or did you fall
more on your hand?
Yes.
What, on your hand?
I... I don't
remember. I'm sorry.
No, don't worry, don't worry.
That's what we have x-rays for.
So I'll get an AP
and a lateral of the forearm,
as well as wrist
and elbow films.
Sure, we don't
wanna miss anything.
Uh, it's busy, I know.
Patient through-time's
longer than at New Western.
But our census is bigger.
Nah, busy is good.
Busy keeps you young.
I'll just take a look
at that fellow in Three.
Look at that. How cute
is that. Thanks, guys.
Now, what's in
here? It's so heavy.
Something to spice
up your wedding night.
Oh, Conni. You shouldn't have.
Spice up my wedding night?
Sure, nice hot gumbo
to keep up his strength.
Jeanie, is this your
last shift for a while?
Yep, catching a plane
at 6:00 to New Orleans.
Then in the morning, Reggie
will make me an honest woman.
Then I'm gonna
show him the town.
Show him a wild time
in New Orleans, honey.
I'm sure you'll be very happy...
Oh, didn't I give you
a Core Values badge?
A toddler chewed it.
There you go.
Always wear it. I will.
Guess you can, uh, take it
off on your wedding night.
All right, now, open your eyes.
Relax.
What three things did I
ask you to remember?
A dog, fire truck
and Brigitte Bardot.
Excellent. Ah.
Dates me, I know,
but your first love is
always your strongest.
You must be Dr. Lawrence.
John Carter, Senior Resident.
As usual, I'm learning how
to be a doctor from my patient.
Meet Mr. Ulman. Minor
head trauma, brief LOC.
Can you tell me what
reflex would indicate
increased intracranial pressure?
Blown pupil?
No, not a reflex. Here,
observe, Dr. Carter.
I scratch the thenar eminence,
and I look for
ipsilateral contractions
of the muscles of the chin.
I see none.
Therefore, I diagnose
no significant head injury.
It's called Radovici's sign.
You can get dressed, my
friend. We'll get you discharged.
Thanks a lot, doc. My pleasure.
Radovici's sign? Yeah.
That's pretty cool.
Try it on your next head trauma.
I will if I can remember.
Got that migraine
in Four? Yeah, sure.
I'll tell you how I remember.
Radovici sounds like radish.
I pluck the radish
with my thumb...
The daycare said
he was crying all day,
pulling on his ear.
His temp's 101.
Must be a load off,
having a daycare
center right here.
Does his mom work too?
Yeah.
It's gotta be tough
on the both of you.
Such a sweet kid.
So, ahem, how's his ear?
He's got a nasty-looking otitis.
Is he allergic to
any medication?
Nah.
Okay, some Tylenol for the pain,
and let's put him on
amoxicillin for 10 days.
Did you have ear
infections as a kid?
Heh. No, why?
It's just they often
run in families.
Yeah, well, you know, he,
um, probably got it in daycare.
I mean, there's a lot
of sick kids up there.
Do you wanna leave
him here with me
until his temperature goes down?
Um, yeah. Yeah, sure.
Hey, I know. Come on, come on.
Go ahead. There you go.
Hello.
Hey.
Randi, has the ICU found
a bed for Joshua Fox yet?
The gunshot wound
kid in Trauma One.
No. Well, call them again.
Chuny, have you
seen my bicycle guy?
Isn't he still in Three?
Spandex-butt? Yep, he
was discharged by GL.
Who's GL?
Gabriel Lawrence.
Oh, right, the
good-looking, older guy.
I just saw him go into the
lounge with Dr. Corday.
So a Frenchman,
Dr. René Laënnec,
rather than press his ear
to mademoiselle's
magnificent breast,
rolled up a newspaper instead
and used that to... You
know, to listen to her heart.
Voilà, the first stethoscope.
Voilà, the first sensitive male
doctor in history. Heh-heh.
Dr. Greene, you know who
invented the stethoscope?
I don't.
Did you discharge
one of my patients?
I don't believe
so. Uh, Mr. Ulman.
Fell off his bike.
I wasn't aware he
was your patient.
Well, he was. I'd
ordered a head CT,
which he obviously didn't get.
Don't worry.
I performed a thorough
neurological examination.
He didn't need a CT.
He had a loss of consciousness,
which put him at risk factor
for intracranial hemorrhage.
Yeah, miniscule risk.
I gave him a head-injury
instruction sheet.
If he has any warning
signs, he'll come back.
He lives alone. If
he slips into a coma,
no one would know about it.
This isn't like New Western.
County patients tend
to be a little less reliable
when it comes to follow-up.
I'm aware of that, Dr. Greene.
That's why I told him
to call me in four hours,
let me know how he's doing.
Difficult for Mr. Ulman
if he's passed out
on the kitchen floor.
Dr. Corday, what would you do?
Uh, well, without seeing
the patient, I'd really rather...
No, I-I'd like to know.
What'd you do?
Fell off his bike, had a
loss of consciousness.
You did a complete neuro exam?
Yes, he was alert and oriented.
Full balance, recall,
normal reflexes.
How long was loss
of consciousness?
Less than two minutes.
And did you visualize the fundi?
The discs were sharp.
I think Dr. Greene was
just being very thorough.
Sounds like a "no" to me.
Look at it this way. We
just saved Mr. Ulman $800.
"A" for accountability.
Right.
Oh, she really does
meet all the requirements.
Well, I couldn't agree more...
Can I talk to you?
You'll get back to me later?
Yeah, as soon as I
can. What's up, Mark?
Why didn't you tell me
you were hiring Lawrence?
Well, I only found out he
was available two days ago.
Oh, so in two days
you didn't have time
for a five minute conversation?
Mark. Look, I mean,
the man is a legend.
He's one of the founding
fathers of emergency medicine.
We are so lucky to have him.
Couldn't you have the
courtesy to at least tell me first?
It's called respect, Kerry.
Hey, look.
It's even on your stupid badge.
Elaine.
John.
Heard you were coming in today.
Did you?
I asked you to leave me alone.
Yeah, I know.
I know that you
did, and I'm sorry.
But I really needed
to talk to you.
Because it's...
Because I don't want you to
have the wrong idea about me.
I don't.
I want you to know
that I'm here for you.
And for me, this
wasn't just about...
Sex? Yeah.
It wasn't about
that. It was for me.
And if we're
talking needs, John,
I don't need you to
feel sorry or worried.
Or tender or anything.
I just need you to go away.
I don't wanna go away.
Lauren's Johnson's x-ray.
Mid-shaft fracture
of the radius.
No injury to the wrist or elbow.
She was lucky.
Maybe not.
What's this?
Some more of Lauren
Johnson. I pulled her records.
See these calluses?
Healed rib fractures.
And this, uh, some
kind of blunt trauma.
Maybe a baseball bat.
She said she wanted to go home
as soon as we splint her arm.
You know, this is only
her second visit here.
But she has been
to Mercy three times,
McGaw twice,
Ravenswood once. I...
This time, I don't
want her to go home.
Dr. Kovac? Yes.
Yes, hi, I'm Lauren's
husband Pauly.
I just wanna thank you
for looking after her so well.
Lauren wasn't clear on how
the accident exactly happened.
Maybe because she's a
little embarrassed about it,
isn't that right, Lauren?
So how did it happen?
She was up a ladder in our
bedroom hanging drapes,
and she lost her footing.
Asked her not
to do it by herself,
didn't I, honey?
Yes, you did.
Shall I splint her?
Mark, can I have a word...?
Lizzie, Paula Trancoso,
Chicago Gazette.
Elizabeth Corday,
Associate Head of Surgery.
Mark Greene, one of
our, uh, ER docs. Hi.
You're wearing scrubs.
Yes, it was my idea.
I wanted to blend in.
Elizabeth's gonna show
Paula around the ER.
You don't mind, Mark?
If you feel that
Dr. Corday has the time...
Had I known the Gazette
was gonna send you, dear,
I would have made
time in my schedule.
But as it is, I'll
have to leave you
to the tender
mercies of Dr. Corday.
Well, uh, this is the
ER, obviously. Heh.
This is Josh's cousin.
Oh, great. Josh.
Josh, your cousin's here.
How's he doin'?
He looks a lot worse than he is.
His lung collapsed so
we put a tube in his chest.
You can talk to him if you want.
He's taching at 140.
Josh, are you in pain?
BP's 180 over 120.
Call Benton.
Maybe he's hemorrhaging.
His pulse is up to 160.
You're gonna
have to wait outside.
Wait outside, please.
Go outside. Come on. Go on.
What is it? Does the
chest tube hurt you?
What have we got?
He's tachy at 160.
What's his crit?
Drawing it.
Trouble breathing?
You were shot. Yes, we know.
Oh, my God. He's the shooter.
I'll call Security.
Hey, hold it right there!
He's got a gun!
Drop it!
Get down. Get down!
Go ahead and call down.
We need a gurney over here.
Looks like an abdominal wound.
Get a backboard over here!
Strong carotid pulse.
His chest is clear.
What's his name?
Uh, McGinnis. Joe McGinnis.
You guys need any help?
We're fine, thank you.
I want two lines,
NG and a Foley.
Roll him gently. Gently.
Okay, on my count.
One, two, three, lift.
CBC, coag, type and
cross for four. Call the O.R.
BP's 130 over 80. Pulse is 96.
No visible GSWs to
chest and abdomen.
Let's roll him.
See anything back
there? Any blood?
Nothing on the back.
All right, check
the extremities.
Where's the blood coming from?
Looks like he cut his hand.
Did he even get shot?
No, he fainted.
Is this the guy who
got shot? You need me?
Yeah, his hand needs suturing.
Suturing? That's it?
I want every piece of
equipment checked for damage.
I don't want anybody seizing
because their IVs are punctured.
Nineteen patients
accounted for. Nobody's hurt?
Nothing serious,
apart from the guard.
Two flesh wounds from ricochets.
Some glass cuts and
contusions from diving to the floor.
That's all? I mean,
there must've been
about 20 bullets flying around.
Guess we got lucky.
MVA, SUV versus truck.
38-year-old male driver
broke his nose on the air bag.
Where's my wife
and child? Behind you.
Wife has a few minor
scrapes, little boy seems okay.
Why the cops?
What's going on here?
Curtain Three.
- What do we got?
- David. He's 9.
Slightly tachy at
110. BP's 115 over 83.
Complained of chest
pain at the scene.
One, two, three!
Hi, David, I'm Cleo.
Do you know what
happened to you?
We were in an accident.
This truck just hit us.
Son of a bitch came
right through the red.
Look, I know my nose is broken.
What are you fiddling
with my face for?
Just checking to see if anything
else is broken, Mr. Bradley.
If David's okay, we
don't have to stay do we?
Lungs clear bilaterally.
He's still tachycardiac.
What do you mean?
We called our doctor.
He said they should
take us to Ambrose,
but the paramedics
said you were closest.
Are the paramedics allowed to
go against the patient's wishes?
Let's get a crit and UA,
C-spine and chest film.
Until I've done these
tests, Mrs. Bradley,
there's no question of
David going anywhere.
Elaine?
Is everything all right?
Everything's fine.
I... I just think maybe this
has all been too fast for me.
So I... I wanna go
home and think about it.
You know, I could do
with some fresh air myself.
Why don't we take a walk?
You wanna say goodbye?
I've done that all day.
Hey! Where you going?
You weren't gonna
sneak out on us, girl?
This is so beautiful. How am
I gonna get it on the plane?
Leave Reggie behind,
put 'em on his seat.
Thank you. Take care.
See you. Thanks. Wow.
Jeanie, I need to see
you. You too, Reggie.
Oh, my shift's over. I know.
We've got a plane to
catch. I know. Come on.
Carlos.
What's going on?
Ask Adele. She really put
herself on the line for this.
We're gonna let you take Carlos.
Really?
On a temporary basis.
And once you get yourself
approved as a foster parent,
then we can consider something
more official and permanent.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
So I guess we're not
going to New Orleans, huh?
We can still get
married here in Chicago.
We could, uh, try
the courthouse.
When?
Today.
Dr. Lawrence.
Dr. Greene. I've got her.
Uh, but next time, could
you sign up on the board?
Paperwork. You can
run, but you can't hide.
She's really hurting this time.
You've been sick
with fever, Cristal?
Vomiting?
No. Just hurting. Mm-hm.
She's had a sickle
crisis before?
Same as last month.
We're gonna get you
something for the pain,
and then we're gonna run
some tests, okay, Cristal?
80 of Demerol, 40
of Phenergan, CBC,
chem panel and a UA, please.
Okay.
Chuny, is that
the sickle-cell girl?
Yeah.
Could you add a retic
count and a Beta HCG?
You got it.
Can we go now before
another gangbanger
starts shootin' up the place?
I need to talk to you first.
Sure, what about?
It's, uh, just some
forms to fill out. Please.
Something wrong?
I have to inform
you, Mr. Johnson,
that, uh, I believe
you're mentally ill.
What?!
"And because of your illness,
you can reasonably be..."
You're the one who's ill, pal.
What the hell do you think...?
Okay, okay.
I get it. I'm in the
nuthouse, huh?
I mean...
"And that because
of your illness,
"you can reasonably be expected
"to inflict serious physical
harm on yourself or on others.
"Therefore you are subject
to involuntary admission
and are in need of
immediate hospitalization."
Wait till my lawyer
gets ahold of you.
Dr. Kovac, you have
no criteria to hold him.
Her x-rays are my criteria...
If she doesn't press charges,
they don't mean anything.
She's gonna get up to Psych,
and they'll send him down
and he'll come home.
Hey, I don't care about
him. I care about her.
We can do nothing or
we can do something.
This way she has a chance.
I can't really run away.
Can I?
You can delay, but not for long.
Elaine, if you're worried
about reconstruction,
I can make an appointment
with a plastic surgeon...
What will happen to
it? After you cut it off?
Now you're being morbid.
Why? It's a part of me.
It'll go to Pathology
and then it'll be got rid of.
Just thrown in the trash.
Just medical waste.
And I'll have a
blob of gel instead.
What will it feel
like when I touch it?
When somebody else touches it?
Elaine, lots of women
have this type of surgery.
I can't imagine
feeling anything.
And if I can't, how
will anybody else?
I mean, how can I ever
be with anybody again?
You can't let this define you.
Well, it's hard not to. I
was happy with who I was.
That's exactly
who you'll still be.
I'd better come back in.
I may be vain,
but I'm not stupid.
Just...
Can you do something for me?
Of course.
When you cut,
you cut everything.
Don't leave
anything. You cut it all.
You know what the only good
thing is about the sickle cell?
There isn't anything
good. No, no, there is.
You know, there's a
disease called malaria
that kills almost a
million children a year.
What do you think protects
people against malaria?
Mmm-mmm.
The sickle-cell gene.
That isn't a bad thing, is it?
Thank you, doctor.
My pleasure.
She should drink
lots of liquids,
and bring her right back
in if she has anymore pain.
Sure. Say thank you, Cristal.
Thank you.
You're welcome. You can
get dressed and go home now.
Over here. Over here.
Thank you.
The labs come back yet?
No, not yet.
Let me know if they do. Okay.
Dr. Kovac. Carl
DeRaad, Psychiatry.
Your psychiatric hold:
way out of line, my friend.
Why?
Because to justify certification
the patient has to be a
danger to himself or others.
He is a danger to others.
Come on, just look at his wife.
She said she fell off a ladder.
Until she says different,
nothing we can do.
I'm sorry.
Have you talked to him?
I've seen him.
Dr. Kovac, I know
why you did it,
but I'm not even gonna take
him upstairs for an evaluation.
I'm going to release him.
Can you do me a favor? Can...?
Can you talk to him at least?
What's the point?
Please.
You and me, uh,
let... Let's talk to him.
It's the crazy foreigner.
They should put these
on you, you know.
Why? I'm not going
to hit your wife.
I never hurt my wife. Never.
Mr. Johnson, settle down.
We just want to talk to you.
Well, talk to her.
Go ahead, ask her.
Have I ever hurt
you, darling? No.
Will you let him go, please?
You want us to release him?
Please.
DeRAAD: Okay, let him go.
How long before
you hit her again?
On the way home?
Or maybe wait
till you get drunk?
Have a bad day at work?
What are you doing?
One thing I don't understand.
The x-rays show your wife
had three cracked ribs. Here:
How'd it happen?
Leave it, Kovac.
She fell off a ladder
again or what?
Uh, was it, uh, down
the stairs, maybe...?
Will you shut this guy up?
Or did you just kick her, huh?
DeRAAD: That's enough.
To break her ribs, huh,
you'd have to knock her
down and stamp on her chest.
Wow, what a man.
Shut up!
Go on, then.
Screw you.
I'll kill him!
No!
Hey... I'll kill him!
Calm down! Get him off of me!
I'm gonna kill him!
Come on! KOVAC: See?
Danger to others.
Oh!
Get out of here!
See?
All right. All right.
Mark, Beta HCG on the sickler.
Where are they?
They walked out a
couple of minutes ago.
Lawrence, we got a problem here.
Mr. Powell?
Mr. Powell.
I need you to come
back in to the hospital.
But we just left.
Your daughter
needs another test.
But we've seen the
doctor. Cristal feels better.
What's going on?
She needs to come back in.
Excuse me?
The ICON is positive.
Oh, she has to come
right back in. Now.
Dr. Finch, Sam Jacobs.
I just want to thank
you for looking after
one of my favorite
families so very well.
We haven't quite
finished the test.
I've made arrangements for
David to be transferred to Ambrose.
So if you would be
so kind as to sign him.
I'm not happy about moving him.
I looked at his
C-spine. It's clear.
I've got an ambulance.
He complained of
back pain at the scene.
I'm still waiting
on a second crit.
Then when you get
that, fax it over to me.
It'll be a half an
hour, that's all.
In half an hour, Dr. Finch,
he'll be under
observation at Ambrose,
not taking up
precious space here.
We ready to roll, Sam?
Are we, Dr. Finch?
There's the ovary.
Yeah, it looks pretty normal.
What are you looking for?
There.
Mass in the fallopian tube.
What is it?
Fetal pole and a heartbeat.
What did he say?
There's a heartbeat.
What are you talking about?
Your daughter's pregnant.
No. She's 12 years old.
Gotta be a mistake.
There's no mistake.
She's pregnant.
But the fetus is in
the fallopian tube,
not the uterus.
I want a second opinion.
I'm the second opinion. We're
lucky we caught it early enough.
Yeah, your daughter
needs surgery now.
If it ruptures, it could
be very dangerous.
I'm gonna call the O.R.
Were you checking up on me?
No, just, uh, watching
out for the patients.
Will there be video games?
Sure. Video games,
TV, your own room.
Just like a hotel, really.
What's your favorite game, then?
David?
David? David, can you hear me?
Stop!
What's happening?
Why are we stopping?
He's tachy. Get a BP.
I can't get a pressure.
No pulse on the left.
Let's go to Trauma.
I don't want him staying here.
- He has to.
Hey, need a hand?
Name's David. In
rapid deceleration.
MVA, crashed while being
transferred to Ambrose.
Probably a traumatic rupture
at the junction of the
subclavian and aortic arch.
Why was he being transferred?
All right, we're going
to have to crack him.
Oh, sorry. Sorry.
Thoracotomy tray.
Where's Kerry?
She said she'd be here.
You know, this
place closes at 5.
Yeah, we know.
Do we really need two...?
Two witnesses, yes.
Suction. Let's start a
round with the packed cells.
He's in V-tach.
60 of lidocaine.
Son of a bitch. I
can't find the source.
Dr. Carter, he's
still in V-tach.
Stand by with the paddles.
I've never done
one like this before.
Why don't you
talk me through it?
Keep suctioning.
All right, what
you want to do is...
Conni, would you get
that woman out of here!
Ma'am, you have to leave.
Peter, you need any help?
Get that woman out of here.
Okay, please go.
All right, get your
hands off of me.
Out!
Clamp distal to
the left subclavian.
Now, open the pleura to
identify the leaking area.
Scissor.
Release the clamp
distally to identify the leak.
I see it.
Now evacuate the hematoma.
Put a curved Potts
underneath the leak
to leave the aorta patent.
All right, now clamp
above the tear.
There you go, Carter.
You just isolated the leak.
Nice work, Carter.
Do you, Reginald Moore,
take this woman to be
your lawful wedded wife
to live together in
the state of matrimony,
to love her, honor and keep her
through health,
sickness and prosperity
whatever your future might be?
I do.
Um, I think he needs a feeding.
Yeah, okay. Here...
Just one second.
Sorry.
Hi.
Are you hungry?
It's okay. Go on.
And do you, Jeanie
Boulet, take this man
to be your lawful wedded husband
to live together in
the state of matrimony,
to love him, honor and keep him
through health,
sickness and prosperity
whatever your future might be?
I do!
No, it's not unusual.
This is a teaching hospital,
and Residents are here to learn.
So they're allowed
to practice on patients.
How else do they learn?
A bit tough on whoever
they're learning on, isn't it?
Residents are
carefully supervised.
What I saw wasn't
Uh, well, I'm sure you've
seen enough, don't you?
It was really, really
nice to meet you,
and I do look forward to
reading your article, okay?
Mark, thank God
I got rid of her.
Yeah, you better be careful she
doesn't turn up somewhere else
disguised as a surgeon.
Did she get in the
way in Trauma?
Yeah.
Mark, I didn't ask
to be her tour guide.
Yeah, well, you didn't say no.
How's it going?
Fine. Heard about
your Psych hold.
Hm!
Yeah, I'm very
popular with Psychiatry.
They took him
upstairs for assessment.
Maybe they'll hold him.
I don't think so.
I provoked him, in
front of witnesses.
Well, maybe now she'll see
what he's really like, you know?
You don't think she knows?
Yeah, I know, it's hopeless.
Maybe not. She didn't
go upstairs with him.
Lucy took her to the cafeteria.
Fingers crossed.
Yeah.
We got David stabilized.
He's in surgery.
Barring any complications,
he should be okay.
If you want to go and see
him, the nurse will take you.
Thank you.
Thank you, doctor.
Dr. Finch.
You did well to catch that.
If we'd waited for the tests
we would have seen this.
We could have operated
in a controlled manner,
rather than having to rip
an 8-year-old's chest open.
We had no choice.
I did.
I shouldn't have let
myself listen to you.
How are you feeling?
Okay.
It went well.
There was no evidence
the cancer had spread,
but we will have to wait
for the pathology reports
on the lymph nodes.
I got a plastic
surgeon in to close,
so we could minimize scarring.
And of course, within
the next couple of weeks,
we can begin reconstruction.
When can I go home?
Well, we had to
put in some drains
to collect any
accumulating fluid.
Like I'm a sewer system.
Most likely it'll just
be for the night.
So you'll be able to
go home tomorrow.
Now, I've given the
nurse all my numbers.
So if you need anything,
you have any questions,
just call anytime.
Thanks.
Oh, Dr. Kovac, now that,
uh, Dr. Lawrence is here,
I don't believe that we're gonna
be needing you anymore, okay?
Okay.
Hey, are you on tonight?
No. No, I'm not.
All right, how much
fluid did you give him?
Two liters. What do we got?
Seventeen-year-old. Two
gunshot wounds to the right chest,
one to the left.
BP 90 over 60, pulse
120. Intubated in the field.
Okay, he needs
bilateral chest tubes.
One for you and one for me.
Malucci, you do a
central line. Right IJ.
On my count. One, two, three.
Two chest tubes and a
central line. Let's move it.
I've only got one chest tray.
Then get another one.
We'll share. 10-blade.
Here.
BP's down to 80. Pulse ox 92.
Curved Kelly.
20 cc's for the labs.
Thanks. O-neg's here.
Chest tube.
Get this damn
thing out of my way!
Somebody grab
this badge. Flip it.
Here. Here you are.
All right. Stitch, please.
I'm in. Lock and
load the infuser.
BP's down to 70.
100 cc's on the right.
We got bleeding on
your side, Dr. Greene.
Okay, where's Benton?
He's o... Off at 6.
Conni, we need a
surgeon down here now!
Give me the Foley.
Foley. Come on,
come on, come on!
30 cc syringe for Dr. Greene.
What are you doing?
Check the balloon.
Check the balloon. Come on.
You can't put pressure on
the bleeder from the outside,
we'll do it from the inside.
Pressure's down.
Another tube of O-neg.
All right. Tell me when.
20 cc's. Uh-huh.
There's 30 cc's.
Chest tube output's
down to a trickle.
Pressure's up to 80.
Old Army trick for
tamponading the subclavian.
Cool.
Very cool.
Okay, let's get
him up to the O.R.
Dr. Carter?
How is she?
She's resting comfortably.
You can go in if you like.
Hey, Luka.
Hey.
Want a lift?
What, in that?
It's my mom's.
I had to pick up
some stuff from work.
What, baby stuff?
Yeah.
Okay.
Here we are.
Yeah.
Let's see...
Oh.
Oh. Ooh.
Hey.
Jeanie, let's get him
one of these, huh?
He's 9 months old.
Uh, yeah, but you... You're
never too early to start.
Ooh.
What do you think, Carlos?
You think your daddy's silly?
What about this, Carlos, huh?
You like one of these? Whoo!
"Pull over. Pull over."
He is silly.
Elizabeth, I wanted to
apologize for, uh, being abrupt.
You mean rude. Yes.
I'll think about it.
You know, you could apologize
actually for that head CT crack.
What? No way on earth
am I gonna apologize for that.
You put me on the spot.
Yeah, but I expected you
to give the right answer.
The right answer?
That Lawrence is still
bugging you, isn't he? Hm?
Yeah, well...
Just because he can
diagnose somebody
without having to order
every test in the book.
He may have some
fancy moves in Trauma,
but he doesn't know how to
function in an inner-city ER.
You're afraid you
might learn something?
He's too slow. He spends
hours with every patient,
and then he ties
up the Residents
chattering on about
the Radovici sign.
The what?
You... You don't
know about that?
No, what is it?
I don't think I should tell you.
Mark.
Look, just one more. Come
on, Reece, please. Okay.
Maybe not.
What are you doing?
Hey, Jackie, you
think he looks like me?
Hope not. He's got
enough problems.
When I was a kid, did I
have a lot of ear infections?
I don't know, Peter.
I was your sister,
not your mother.
You were a scrawny,
little thing, though.
Always coming down
with something or other.
No wonder you got into medicine.
Mm, thanks.
I'll take him up to bed, okay?
All right.
You do the
washing up, all right?
Alrighty. And dry up
and don't leave everything
just sitting on the side.
Yeah. Hey, hey. Hey.
I love you. Do you love
me? Do you love me?
All right, get out of here.
Come on, my baby.
You live here?
I told you it's in the water.
Yeah, but I mean,
is it sanitary?
Sure.
What do you do in winter?
In the winter I go south.
Like the birds.
Thank you for the lift.
Sure. See you.
Sure.
Well, you scratch
the thenar eminence,
which causes
ipsilateral contractions
of the muscles of the chin.
Definitely contracting.
Is that a good thing?
Sadly, no.
It indicates increased
intracranial pressure.
Disturbances of the brain.
Which explains why
you're working with Romano.
♪ Seems so far away ♪
♪ I fell in love with you ♪