♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
Can I go to school now?
I'm very good
at accepting apologies, Mark.
I apologized
over the phone.
"Fine. I'll bring her
to L.A." is not an apology.
Wh-what is that?
That's just a shadow.
That's the baby.
Where's the a.T.M.?
A.V.M., sweetheart.
A.t.m. Is where
you get money.
You're not gonna see
the a.V.M. Here.
That's just a cluster
of blood vessels.
That aren't supposed
to be there,
and if you pop them,
I'm gonna die?
W--no.
Um, Sloan, it's just
a tangled cluster of
blood vessels under the baby.
I'm not gonna go
anywhere near them,
so I won't be popping them.
I'm gonna go in,
uh, laparoscopically
and very carefully cut
one of the amniotic bands
from around the baby's legs.
And then he'll be okay?
He'll be able to walk?
Then he'll be perfect.
Well, that's what
you said last time.
That was my fault, Sloan.
I shoulda let her finish
the surgery the first time.
Now that is an apology.
What is that? What is
that thing right there?
Is that something growing
out of his head?
That is a penis.
Sloan, you're gonna make
yourself crazy
trying to read the ultrasound.
Has her blood pressure
always been this high?
Yeah, it's been going up.
She's scared.
So am I.
Mark Sloan, Pete Wilder.
Pete Wilder, Mark Sloan.
Hi, good to meet you.
Mm-hmm.
And this is Sloan,
Mark's daughter.
Sloan Sloan?
Sloan Riley.
She got her mom's
last name.
Oh, okay. Well, Sloan,
Dr. Montgomery asked me
to help you try
to calm down a little.
She says you're nervous
about your surgery.
What is he, a pharmacist?
No, alternative medicine.
Dude, you are not putting
those needles in me.
Most people barely feel it.
Dude, you heard her. You're not
putting those needles in her.
Dude...
Pete is doing me a favor.
With respect, I didn't bring
my daughter down here
for witch doctoring.
With respect, really?
Mark.
What kind of medicine
do you practice?
Plastics.
What are you laughing at?
Ah, nothing. Saving the world
one boob job at a time.
Hey, listen, pal--
okay, okay. Look, enough. Pete,
you're gonna do your thing.
Mark, you're gonna let Pete
do his thing.
No, I'm not gonna let Pete--
oh, yes, you are.
I'm in charge here.
And if you want me to do this
surgery again, then you're gonna
follow me out of this room
right now. Right now, Mark.
Right now. Let's go.
Hi, Dr. Cooper.
Hey, Cody.
Is your mom home?
Oh, she ran
to the post office.
She'll be home soon.
Could we wait inside?
My mom's a super good mom.
I know.
She's super nice.
I know. I've met her. You trying
to fix us up or something?
No. I just...
Okay, come in.
All right. Follow me.
Just be careful you don't
knock over any piles.
So, uh, your mom likes
to hold on to stuff, huh?
She's a super good mom.
I know. You said that.
I was thinking maybe
one of the reasons you wanted me
to come here was so I could see
- how much stuff she keeps.
- Cody.
Oh.
Oh, my god. Dr. Freedman,
what are y--what are you doing?
The itching
was killing me, mom.
I was gonna go crazy.
Cody, I would've taken you
to the doctor.
I know, but...
Dr. Freedman,
I-I know what you
must be thinking.
No, I'm thinking that, uh,
we're gonna have to take Cody
to the hospital.
What? Why?
Well, he's got a-a skin
infection, a pretty bad one.
Oh, god.
Cody, you can't scratch that,
okay?
Do you want to take him in
your car, you can meet me there?
Yeah. Yes, thank you.
Mm-hmm.
Thanks so much.
See you there.
She's crazy cakes!
That's your diagnosis?
Crazy cakes. There is
broken crap piled everywhere.
And I'm not just
talking unsanitary.
I am talking insane.
Okay. Well, it sounds like
she's a hoarder.
That--that's an obsessive-
compulsive disorder, Coop.
Maybe it's genetic.
Maybe it was triggered
by a trauma or loss.
Or we could go
with crazy cakes.
If you had seen this place,
you would.
Okay. Well, I will
talk to her.
It's actually
a very hard disorder to treat.
But, uh, I'll do the best
I can. How's the kid?
The kid is smart.
The kid is articulate.
I honestly thought maybe
he had called me there
as a cry for help so I could
see this, but he's got
what I'm pretty sure is
a staph infection on his arm,
so maybe he just needed
that cast off.
I've got him at St. ambrose
for the arm,
and he is staying there
until that house is clean.
Well, that might take
some time.
Okay, but if it takes
too much time,
I'm calling
child protective services.
Thanks for the vote
of confidence.
Hey, Coop. How's it going
with Charlotte?
I can't forgive her.
I'm trying, but I just...
I can't seem to forgive her.
What is the matter with you?
Me? What's the matter
with you?
You're as wound up
as I've ever seen you.
I am not the one
starting schoolyard fights
with other doctors.
You're wound up, Addie.
Just admit it.
Bizzy's a lesbian.
What?
My mother--she's a lesbian,
which means the captain
wasn't a cheater.
It was all a sham--
my whole childhood.
Everything I believed about
my dad, my mom, love, marriage--
it's all turned on its head.
So, yeah, I'm a little...
Wound up.
Wow.
Your turn.
Lexie dumped me.
Oh.
I asked her to raise
Sloan's baby with me.
Or, you know, raise it
with me and Sloan.
She's a little young for that,
don't you think?
Do not take her side.
I'm sorry.
It sucks.
Yeah.
Your thing sucks, too.
Bizzy's a lesbian?
Thank you.
When did we get so--
old?
I was gonna say sad.
When did we get so sad?
Don't you wish
we did heroin?
Addison Forbes Montgomery--
no, no, I mean,
don't you wish we did drugs,
drank too much,
shot something into our vein?
I mean, nothing, you know, that
would make you ruin your life
or kill you or make you
have to go to meetings
and say, "hi, I'm Addison.
And I'm an alcoholic."
But just...
You know, Nai--she eats.
She puts food on top of it,
and that numbs the pain,
the malaise,
the--the--the sad.
I mean, she puts food on top
of it, and she feels good.
But I... I don't...
I have green juice.
I mean,
that's all I really like.
And green juice, I can't really
put that on top if it.
I want to put something
on top of it,
but I don't have anything.
Mark, what are you doing?
I'm telling you how I feel.
And I hear you.
Numb the pain.
What--
numb the sad. Feel good.
Put something on top of it.
Mark, I said put something
on top of it,
not put you on top of me.
My life is in ruins.
It's a mess.
I'm about to be
a grandfather,
and I'm alone.
I don't know of a lot
of surefire ways
to numb the pain,
but I do know one.
Now... do you want
to feel better
or don't you?
♪ ...Outside ♪
♪ walk outside ♪
♪ girl, let's take a walk ♪
♪ ooh ♪
♪ let's take a walk ♪
♪ baby ♪
♪ I know it's cold out,
but I don't care ♪
♪ let's take a walk ♪
♪ walk ♪
♪ outside ♪
♪ walk outside ♪
♪ let's take a walk ♪
Oh.
Yes.
- Oh, my god.
- Oh.
I...
I can't
catch my breath.
Well, we could call in
the dude with the needles...
To help calm you down.
Oh. I forgot
how much fun you were.
Yeah, well,
that's what happens...
When you date children.
You forget what it's like...
To be with a woman.
Hey.
Oh!
No being mean about Lexie.
Did you just spank me?
Oh, what, what, you want
to start something?
Maybe.
Come on. Bring it, sister.
I will, right now, Dr. Sloan.
Oh, I'll give you
more of the same.
Really? Oh! My god.
Addi--aah.
Oh!
Sam, close the door!
Addison, this is
a place of business.
Uh, Sam, will you, uh, just
toss me that shirt there, buddy?
Sam, close the door.
Hey.
Oh, my god.
Sloan Sloan went right to sleep.
The needles worked wonders.
Thanks. Great job, dude.
Okay, then.
Too bad I joined
the other practice.
This place has perks.
Sam, close the door!
I keep everything of Cody's
because he might want it
someday.
Report cards, trophies.
Mm-hmm. Yeah, and there's
other stuff that,
you know, needs to be donated
to goodwill or somewhere.
Have you called anybody
about coming to pick it up?
You know what? I haven't
gone through all of it just yet.
Do you need help
doing that?
I know how overwhelming it could
be to be a single parent.
Well, it was easier
when his dad was alive,
but Cody and I are, uh,
we're okay now. We do fine.
When did he die?
Three years ago.
I'm sorry. What happened?
I know that you want to help,
but honestly, I don't need...
Any help.
Cody and I are just fine.
You get 30 seconds.
I'm sorry?
We are business partners,
so you get 30 seconds
to lecture me
on my business practices.
But if you start to lecture me
on something not related
to my business practices, I will
walk away. Those are the rules.
Oh, so our friendship
has rules now?
No. We're not talking
as friends right now.
We're talking
as business partners.
Well, I want to talk
to my friend.
She doesn't want to talk
to you right now.
So now you're talking about
yourself in third person.
Hi. Did you sleep
with Mark Sloan
on the floor of your office?
Yep.
Sam--
and she's making up rules
and she's talking about herself
in third person.
Yes, I am, because I have
earned that right.
When you have gone through
what I've gone through with
my family, you have the right
to be a little eccentric
for a few weeks.
You have the right
to refer to yourself
in the third person and have sex
on the floor of your office
and apply random rules to old
friendships. You have the right.
Okay. All right, Sam.
You need to leave Addison alone
because you're
making her scream.
Addison, I am here for you
if you need me.
You see that?
That is a friend.
Okay.
Okay, you came to me and you
were upset, you were scared,
you were a little desperate,
and I turned you down.
Now I turned you down
because I am a good person.
Mark Sloan had you naked within
an hour of his arrival.
Now what does that
say to you?
Addison.
You broke the rules.
I'm walking away.
Relative Harmony?
Well, as long as Betsey's
not with me, she seems fine.
She'll come around.
She hates me.
Maya hates me
for no discernible reason.
Try not to
take it personally.
Doughnuts help.
I'm not the one
who blew up the house.
with the drug habit.
And I lost someone, too.
I went through
a trauma, too.
Dell, she's 7.
I know, I know.
She's 7.
I know.
Hoarding is a mental illness,
Cooper.
I can't just tell her
to snap out of it.
No, but you can get
a dump truck,
back it up
and start shoveling.
Then she's just gonna start with
the behavior all over again.
I need some time to get
to the root of the problem.
He doesn't have time.
He's got staph eating his arm.
Which could happen in
a clean house. You know that.
And you're treating it
at St. ambrose.
Yeah, and Charlotte's
gonna slice me
for using one of her
precious beds for someone
that's not
on death's door, so--
for god sake, Cooper. A patient
needs a bed, admit him,
but don't keep blaming me for
everything. It's getting old.
If Andrea doesn't start
throwing stuff
out the front door tomorrow,
I'm calling d.C.F.S.
How long is he gonna
keep punishing me?
'Cause I'm about to stop
forgivin' and forgettin'
and get real nasty.
♪ caught in the middle ♪
♪ of a cross fire ♪
- Do you ever get used to this view?
- No.
So... you're doing
the surgery tomorrow, right?
- I am going to do the surgery tomorrow.
- This is so beautiful.
Isn't it beautiful?
And everything's gonna be okay,
right, after the surgery?
Yes.
I've always wanted
to learn to surf.
Do you want to learn
to surf?
Whatever.
Good night.
Good night. Mwah.
♪ Are we going down
or will we fly? ♪
I mean, do you ever
get used to this view?
Mark, that little girl is not
ready to be a mother.
How's she gonna handle it
the first time
the baby spits up in her mouth?
I'm gonna be there with her,
- every step of the way.
- Really?
How are you gonna handle
spit up in the mouth?
It happens quite frequently.
I can handle it.
I grew up, you guys.
You all ran off
to live on the beach,
and...
I went and grew up on you.
Okay, now that's just
crazy talk.
I think I might move here.
What?
- What?
I could join your practice.
This is L.A.
I'm a plastic surgeon.
I'd bring in a fortune.
And you could help me
raise the baby.
Are you out of your mind?
Please tell me you're not...
Serious.
Addison and I are good together.
Tell him.
Mark...
Lexie...
Like you said,
she's a kid.
But you. You know me.
You get me.
You all do.
You're my friends--
my old friends,
my good friends.
And this?
This feels right.
It feels really right.
♪♪♪
You hungover?
You were the one
who was drunk, not me.
I wasn't the one talking about
moving my whole life down here.
That wasn't drunk talk, Addison.
Oh, come on, Mark.
Let's not talk about it.
I want you focused
on the surgery.
Montgomery.
How long you gonna need
O.R. three?
Uh, two hours tops.
Good. Who's hot stuff?
Uh, um, Dr. Charlotte king,
Dr. Mark Sloan.
Plastics.
Sexology.
Mm-hmm.
My god. I love L.A.
I was just telling Addie
I could be persuaded
into relocating
if the situation were right.
I've been saying we need
a plastics guy.
Haven't I been saying
we need a plastics guy?
Oh, god.
Well, we'll talk, right after
my daughter's surgery.
Actually, you can talk now
on your way out.
On my way out?
Yeah, you're not allowed
within 1,000 feet of my O.R.
And don't let him join
the practice
while I'm in surgery.
Thank you
for letting me come see you.
Do you remember
when this first started,
this, uh, need
to keep everything?
Cody made that.
Did it have anything to do
with the death of your husband?
Cody will grow into this
in a few years.
These erasers--
they are all still good.
This can be repaired.
How would your life be different
if you threw this out?
I need it.
Why?
Because you never know...
When you're gonna
need something.
And then if you throw it out,
you don't have it anymore.
I'm not crazy.
Maybe I'm a little eccentric.
I know what people think.
But I'm not crazy.
Surgical time-out's complete.
Let's prep the belly.
Sam.
Is everything okay?
Everything is perfect,
'cause you can't
walk away from me in here.
Look who's making up
the rules now.
I am at work, Sam.
You're really
going to talk about
my very, very personal life
while I'm at work?
No. No, no, no.
Hello, everyone.
I am going to talk to you
about dogs.
Where's my mom?
Why isn't she here?
She's on her way.
How you feelin'?
I want to go home.
Yeah, I bet.
Hey, um,
I have a question for you.
Do you have any family
around here,
any aunts, uncles?
No, why?
Well, I'm working with your mom
on cleaning your house up,
and it'd be better
if you had someplace else
to stay for a while.
No, I need to be with her.
I take care of her.
Well, would you like that
to be different?
You don't understand.
Sh-she needs help, Cody.
She needs more help
than you can give her.
And this separation
would only be temporary.
You can't do that.
She'd be...
It'd be like when my dad
and my sister died.
Do you mind
if I ask you about that?
My dad had us weekends.
So they were divorced?
I was sick, so it was
just my sister that Friday.
They ran off the road
in latigo canyon.
I have to stay with my mom.
And then you have
golden retrievers.
Now golden retrievers,
like labs,
whether they be blond
or chocolate,
they're people dogs. They're
all about pleasing you,
all about making you happy.
You can neglect them,
you can ignore them,
you can walk all over them,
but still, making you happy
is their first thought.
Snipping the first band.
Now I would be fine
if you took up with
a golden retriever or a lab--
heck, even a schnauzer.
But Sloan?
Sloan is a dachshund.
Dachshunds like to eat poop
right up off the street--
other dogs' poop.
They're more concerned
with their own needs
than they are
with making you happy.
They're filthy and immoral--
immoral?
They're immoral dogs?
The owners of dachshunds
are desperate--
desperate for affection.
But it's the wrong kind
of affection,
the kind that makes you
always take care of them.
Oh, my god.
What happened?
The a.V.M. Just blew.
She's bleeding all over.
I can't see a thing.
Convert to open.
With the baby
still inside her?
Yes. 10-blade.
Was this my fault? I was
talking. W-We were talking.
I'm capable of talking
and operating simultaneously.
You blew the a.V.M.?!
- Not on purpose.
- I already told him that.
Well, then
what the hell happened?!
Stop yelling at her.
Don't yell.
She lost a lot of blood, but she's gonna be okay.
And the baby?
I think he's gonna be fine.
You think?
I hope. I'm sorry. The a.V.M.
Is very delicate, Mark.
It's directly below
the dissection,
and it--it--it--
it just blew.
I need to see her.
Okay, look, Mark, she's gonna be
in bad shape when she wakes up.
She hemorrhaged.
I had to open her up.
She's gonna be much worse
than last time.
The last thing she needs
is to look up
and see you hovering,
terrified.
What do you expect me to do?
Why don't we just take a walk?
We can just calm--
Naomi, don't talk to me like
I'm a child. I'm not a 12 year--
Mark, please,
just go with Naomi.
She knows
what she's talking about.
Fix this.
That baby has to be okay.
He will. He will.
I care about Mark Sloan.
I loved him once.
And he was our best friend.
And, yes, he's done
a lot of stupid things,
but he also let all of us
do a lot of stupid things.
He let us do
a lot of stupid things
and he never judged us.
He's not just a dog, Sam.
Sure, he's got a screwed up
moral compass, but so do I.
He's a good man.
This baby's gotta be okay.
I didn't even know
he had a sister.
Yeah, and the fact that she
didn't even mention it...
Yeah.
It has to be the root
of the problem.
Hey, where's Cody?
His mother took him home.
I'm calling d.C.F.S.
D.C.F.S. Is not
the answer--
she snatched Cody out of
the hospital
and brought him back
to the house of horrors!
Why are you shouting at me?
Because you have no concern
at all for this boy.
The best thing for that child
would be to have a healthy
mother, and frankly,
the best thing for you would be
to stop displacing your anger.
What is that
supposed to mean?
You're angry at Charlotte.
You're angry at yourself.
You keep lashing out
at everybody else
so you don't have to take
responsibility.
I am trying to help Cody.
By putting him
in foster care?
By ripping him
away from his mother?
By breaking his heart?
Get a grip, Cooper.
Deal with your problems.
Why do you think
Charlotte lied to me?
No, no, Cooper. You gotta
talk to her about that.
I'm serious. I am out.
Oh, you're out? You're out.
You don't get to be out!
How many times--how many times
have I had to listen to you
go on and on and on
about Allan
or Sheldon
or, oh, my god, Pete?
Pete this and Pete that,
Violet.
And look how well
that worked out.
Look how healthy I am.
Yay me. I am super normal.
Point taken.
Thank you.
Talk to her... not me.
Work it out or not.
You love each other,
you don't--figure it out...
With Charlotte.
I'm calling d.C.F.S.
Is there some reason why we are
eating in silence yet again?
May I be excused?
Maya, why don't you just
tell me what's going on?
We can talk about it.
Can I be excused, too?
Betsey, Naomi went to
a lot of trouble--
thank you for breakfast.
May I be excused?
Sure, honey.
Yeah.
Well, at least you know why
yours isn't speaking to you.
I didn't kill her mother,
you know?
I'm just gonna say it
to her, you know,
'cause at some point,
you gotta grow up.
Dell, she's--
I know she's 7. I-I know.
But I-I can't
feel like this every day.
You know, I can't keep being
treated like the enemy.
Well, maybe all she needs
is an apology.
What am I apologizing for?
I did the right thing.
Heather's faced
was burned off.
You know, she burned
her face off getting high.
You really think I should've
let Betsey into that room?
Okay, you're in mourning,
and, uh, you are my friend,
and you've been through hell,
so I've been
really gentle with you.
But I think I am not gonna be
gentle with you anymore.
I think I'm just gonna
tell you the truth
because that's what I would
want you to do for me.
Are you okay with that,
if I'm not gentle anymore?
Yes.
Okay.
I think you should've
let her in that room.
I think you should've let her
say good-bye to her mother.
I think Pete was right, and I
think you owe him an apology.
And I think that Betsey
has a right to be pissed.
I would be pissed, too.
7 or 37, I would be pissed.
Mom?
Hey, Sloan. It's Addison.
Where am I?
You're in the hospital
in Los Angeles.
You just had surgery,
but everything is fine.
You and the baby are fine.
Where's my mom?
I want my mom.
Well, Mark's here.
Your dad's here.
And he's gonna be here
in just a few minutes.
I don't want him.
I want my mommy.
I don't want any
of this. I don't want a baby.
I just want to go home.
I want my life back.
I want to go home.
I'm delirious.
I am delirious
with exhaustion.
Mm.
Lucas thought it was morning
at 2:00 A.M.
And then again at 3:00 A.M.
and at 4:00,
and i'm--i feel like
I'm underwater.
See? That's what
I'm talking about.
You're a grown man,
and you're a wreck.
That's what you were
talking about to who?
To myself...
In my head.
Sloan Sloan--she's...
She's pretty simple,
you know, and young.
And her mom had her
when she was young.
And I don't think she's
even thought about adoption.
I don't think anybody's
counseled her.
And I think she feels trapped,
and I think it's
my responsibility as her doctor
to give her her options.
Well, of course it is.
What's the problem?
Mark. He really...
Wants this baby.
He wants
to raise it with her.
Are we talking about
the plastic surgeon?
Oh, the contempt
that seeps
from your every word--
do you have that for
every plastic surgeon or just,
you know, ones that I sleep with
on the floor of my office?
I just--
I don't think there's
anything to debate, Addison.
You're her doctor,
she's a kid--
she's 18.
Yeah, well, still,
it's your responsibility
to counsel her,
give her the options.
Yeah.
Back in New York, you know,
Mark and I were together,
and, um...
I got pregnant.
And I told him about it,
and he was excited,
and... I... wasn't,
and I had an abortion.
I didn't talk to him
about it first.
I made the decision
for both of us.
And he wanted it.
And he wants this one.
One thing
can't inform the other.
Your loyalty to your friend
and your--your guilt
or your remorse, it can't
inform your patient care.
You gotta give her the options
and let her choose.
Maybe it'll go his way.
And I'm sorry.
It sounds just awful.
Thanks.
Don't fall asleep on my head.
I'm up. I'm up.
How's the baby?
Heartbeat's holding strong.
I haven't
taken my eyes off it.
Good.
That's, uh...
That's good.
What?
This midlife crisis,
uh, you're having,
all this talk about
moving to L.A.--
whatever is--is going on
with you,
something worse is going on
with Addison.
And I'm not about to let her
be your landing pad.
What the hell
do you care, Sam?
Well, she--she just spends
a lot of time, uh,
trying to take care of
everyone at the practice,
so, you know, I'm trying
to take care of her.
I'm saying, I like you, Mark,
but what you've been doing
around here,
it's not you at your best.
And I ask again,
what the hell do you care?
I just care.
Hey.
Looking for me?
Yeah. I wanted to let you know
I have a staff meeting tonight.
I'm not sure
when I'm gonna be home.
You lied.
Why did you lie?
I just want to know why.
I told you why.
No, y-you told me that there
are things you can't t--
I told you I didn't want
to go there.
Were you ever gonna marry me?
Was that a lie, too?
Oh, I cannot believe you have
the nerve to do this here.
What?
Can you answer the question?
Can you not ask it?
I have answered it?!
You, uh,
you seen Addison?
No, not recently.
Not down here.
Oh.
Your son?
Yeah.
And you bring him
to work?
Naomi is cool with that?
I'm sorry. I, uh,
I'm about to have a kid.
Or my kid--my kid
is about to have a kid.
And, uh, you can skip
the grandpa jokes,
because they have
all been made.
Anyway...
My kid, she's, uh...
She's young.
She's gonna need
a lot of help.
So I think it's really great
that you get to bring
your baby to work.
L.A.'s
a pretty liberal place.
Naomi's
a pretty liberal boss.
You know, I don't think
I've ever even held a baby.
I mean, obviously,
I held lots of kids
during my peds rotation
when I was a resident.
But I don't--i don't...
I don't think I've ever
even held a baby.
Here.
Go ahead.
Okay.
Just be gentle.
I just got him quiet.
Hi.
Ooh.
Hello.
Wow, you're cute.
Shh. It's okay.
So have I got this straight?
You think my favorite hobby
is sitting around
dreaming up ways
to emasculate you?
You humiliated me
when you bought me into
the practice without asking me.
That made me less of a man.
You made yourself
less of a man
when you spent all the money
in your bank account.
You know what? Let's just...
Start over here.
No, no, no, no. This is good.
Get it all out. This is good.
Charlotte king
finally opens up. Come on.
What's that supposed to mean?
I mean, I am there for you
and there for you,
but all you want to do
is screw and not talk and--
all I want to do is screw?
All I want to do?
Oh, you are gonna
have to look in the mirror,
because the pot is definitely
calling the kettle black.
Screw is all you know
how to do.
No, no, no. No, I'm a person.
I'm a whole person
with feelings and friends
and a practice full of patients,
and what do you have?
You.
Don't you say that like
it's an insult. Don't you dare.
I am not a freak.
I'm not the freak, Charlotte.
I'm not the freak that got fired
because I'm heartless.
Charlotte--
no, you're the freak
who needed me to bail you out,
which is how I know
I'm not heartless.
The 50 grand I spent to buy your
ass a place in this practice
proves I am not heartless.
And we're back
to the money again?
You are such a bitch
that you can't--
I do what needs to be done.
I do what needs to be done,
and you resent me.
Why, 'cause I don't go
all crybaby every five seconds?
It's not about crying.
It's about being a person.
It's about being
a normal woman, for once.
It's not my fault
you're not a man.
So don't tell me
I'm not a woman.
I literally--i am full
of hatred right now.
Oh, join the freakin' club.
W--
do you know how ridiculous it is
that you would take me aside--
could you answer one question?
You can't separate--
I have answered it.
There's the heartbeat.
And it's strong.
So... I have to ask you this.
Has anyone ever talked to you
about adoption?
What, like when you pick
a family from the "pennysaver"?
No. That's just in "juno."
No, in real life,
there are agencies,
and all they do
is screen families.
They find you safe,
wonderful families
who would love your baby
as much as you do.
There are agencies. In fact,
we have one at the practice.
Don't tell Mark that we're
having this conversation,
'cause I know that
he'd freak out, and, like,
all my stuff
is still at his apartment.
No, i'm--I'm your doctor,
so I can't tell anyone
anything
that we're talking about.
And--and for the record,
I think that you could be
a great mom, Sloan,
and I know Mark would be
an amazing--
so these agencies...
Like, what exactly do they do?
We are breaking up.
Coop, we're having a fight.
No, we're done.
I'm done.
You don't get to be done.
You don't get to decide
what happens to us.
Good-bye, Charlotte.
Okay, this...
This is the problem
right here.
You won't man up and face stuff.
You want to just cut and run.
We're having a fight.
No, the problem is...
You are a sex toy
I found on the Internet.
The problem is, you're just
a trashy little girl
who's trying to please
her dead daddy,
and I shouldn't have
expected much from you.
My bad.
You act warm,
all cute, cuddly Cooper.
But the bitch of it is,
you're the one who's heartless,
not me.
You. You're a mean, cold,
miserable bastard
who doesn't know a thing
about forgiveness.
You screwed another man,
I forgave you.
♪ What happened to... ♪
That's just sex.
I was talking about us.
I was talking about love.
You're supposed to love me.
♪ ...was flat ♪
♪ what happened... ♪
Were you ever planning
on marrying me?
♪ To that? ♪
Doesn't matter now,
does it?
♪♪♪
They can't just come
and take my boy.
D.c.f.s. Does not want
to take Cody.
They will,
but they don't want to.
But if you and I can show them
that you're fixing the problem,
then they will do anything
they can to have Cody stay here.
Mom, just throw
some stuff out.
Maybe Cody can go to his room
so you and I can talk?
It'll be okay, mom.
Just listen to her, okay?
You can do it.
I know you can.
I can't.
This doesn't fill the hole.
This doesn't make up
for divorce and death.
You didn't tell me
about your daughter.
You didn't tell me because
what happened was unthinkable.
It's unbearable. But this
isn't working anymore, is it?
It's not working
to keep away whatever it is
that's eating you
from the inside.
Did you divorce your husband
or the other way around?
How old was your daughter?
How did you find out
they'd been killed?
Did you have to identify
the bodies?
How did you tell Cody that his
father and his sister were dead?
I divorced him, okay?
I didn't love him anymore.
He was a good husband
and a good father, but I...
I tossed him out
like a sack of garbage.
And if I hadn't done that,
then my daughter
wouldn't have been in that car
in that place at that time.
You don't know that.
I do know that.
You want this gone?
There.
How about that?
How about this?
Maddy was 4 1/2.
She wanted to stay with Cody
because he was sick,
but I made her go with her
father because I felt guilty
because he only got them
on the weekends.
And he loved them
more than anything!
He loved them,
and he loved me,
and I didn't want him!
No. No, they can't.
No, they can't take Cody.
They can't take him.
Hey, hey, hey.
Did you see what you did?
You threw stuff out.
Can you leave it out there?
Can you do that?
I think so.
I'm Ellie farraday,
d.C.F.S.
Hi, Ellie. We're just doing
a little housecleaning.
I'm sorry.
For everything,
That's quite a punch
you've got.
You coming?
Oh, no. I'm just riding
up and down.
Lucas likes the motion.
Yeah.
You like the motion.
I don't care what Sam says.
This is ideal.
What did Sam say?
Nothing.
Forget about Sam.
This is ideal.
Three parents--
no one gets overwhelmed,
everyone still gets
to have a life.
Mark--
this is our second chance.
Don't you see it?
What if there wasn't
a baby?
Why? What happened?
Nothing. Nothing happened.
The baby's fine.
It's just, what...
What if Sloan changed her mind
or there wasn't a baby,
would you still want
to move down here,
join the practice,
be with me?
Because you keep asking,
and you paint a pretty picture.
And I'm just lonely enough
and I'm just scared enough
and I'm just freaked out enough
that if you ask me again...
I might say yes.
So I'm asking you
not to ask me again
if it's not about me.
If you're just heartbroken
or in love with someone else
or you just want me
to help you with a baby
that you may or may not
be able to raise...
Don't ask me.
Because I don't know...
Anything.
I don't know...
Anything anymore,
except, I can't fall in love
with a man
who's in love
with someone else.
That much I know.
I can't do that again.
So please, if you're still
in love with the grey girl,
then go back to Seattle.
But if you're not...
I mean, if you're serious...
And you want me...
Then ask again.
♪ Mm ♪
I'm so sorry.
♪ Uh-huh ♪
I'm sorry, red.
♪ I don't know where
I crossed the line ♪
Yeah.
Me, too.
♪ ...or didn't say this time? ♪
♪ And I don't know
if it's me or you ♪
♪ but I can see
the skies are changing ♪
♪ no longer shades of blue ♪
I was mad at her...
At your mom.
I was. I was so mad at her,
and I made a mistake.
I made a mistake.
I was scared...
And I was just trying
to protect you.
And I made a mistake,
not letting you see her.
♪ But that won't stop the rain ♪
I should've
let you say good-bye.
I should've let her
say good-bye to you.
And i'm...
So sorry.
Grown-ups...
We're--we're supposed
to know what to do.
But when we get scared
sometimes, we don't.
And I'm sorry. I-I...
I'm sorry for not
letting you say good-bye.
Mm.
I'm just so sorry.
You should've let me.
I know. I know.
I know. Come here.
Come here.
Come here, come here.
I know. I know.
♪ Please don't stop
the rain ♪
Sweetie, I know I'm not always
that easy to talk to.
My--my mother wasn't very easy
to talk to either.
But, um...
Whatever's going on
with you, Maya,
I hope you feel that you can
talk to somebody.
Talk to Dell or your dad
or...
Talk to someone, Maya,
because the hard stuff...
It always gets easier
once you let it out.
♪ And if it's going to be
a rainy day ♪
♪ there's nothing we can do
to make it change ♪
♪ we can pray
for sunny weather ♪
♪ but that won't stop the rain ♪
♪ you're feeling like
you've got no place to run ♪
♪ I can be your shelter
till it's done ♪
Addison...
Can I talk to you?
Sure. Come on over.
♪ Please don't stop the rain ♪
♪ let it fall, let it fall,
let it fall ♪
Hey. What's the matter?
Are you okay?
What's wrong?
What happened?
Sweetheart, whatever it is,
you can talk to me about it.
It's gonna be okay.
It's not gonna be okay.
♪ Let it fall, let it fall,
let it fall ♪
♪ please don't stop ♪
It's not gonna be okay.
♪ The rain ♪