Hey. Slow down, sister.
Actually, I need to speed up.
Rachel woke up
early with a fever
and she's been
terrorizing me all morning.
I'm already late.
Sorry, the stakeout went
longer than I thought.
Have you ever been to a rave?
Goodbye.
You're already late,
and Rachel's sick.
Neither of which can be solved
by you leaving right this second.
The entire hospital's depending
on a proposal I have yet to finish
and need to present at 8:30.
It's 7:30.
It's 7:37.
I'll have you on the
road in 10 minutes.
Come on, you don't wanna get into your
meeting all tight and stressed out, do you?
It's yours.
It's House. Ignore it.
It says, "Emergency page."
I said ignore it.
Sweet.
I'm sorry, it's hard
to pace yourself
when you've been thinking
about it for 10 hours straight.
That's great,
now I'm late, stressed
out and frustrated.
So, if you give me
a minute, I can...
It'll wait.
You can do it.
Do what?
I thought you were
coming in at 7:30.
Rachel woke up with a fever,
and then I just couldn't
get here any sooner.
There's a problem
in the pharmacy.
Hey, boss lady!
You don't answer
emergency pages anymore?
Tell them all I'll be
by as soon as I can.
And tell him I assumed it
was either about the wolf again
or the procedure I refused
to approve yesterday.
Turned out it wasn't
a resistant staph,
but I still say if it had been,
infecting him with malaria...
Seriously, House, I
don't have time for this.
You're lying. I have a
meeting in 20 minutes.
Not talking about your meeting.
I'm talking about
the phone call.
I didn't ask what you were
talking about because I don't care.
I was with your boy toy
on the stakeout last night.
You were with Lucas?
He needed someone who could diagnose a
soft tissue injury from across the street.
Apparently he doesn't
know any good doctors.
Or the ones he does know
actually have lives outside of work.
Things got a little slow,
so we made some wagers.
One being whether I could get
you to stop the miscegenation
with an emergency page.
What made you think we'd...
He said you guys
do it every morning.
Everybody lies, remember?
So you weren't actually...
Goodbye, House.
I'm gonna need a definitive answer
before any money changes hands.
Sorry to interrupt, but the
GRC called about the budgets,
the pharmacy is still waiting, and
your 8:30 just arrived on campus.
He should be here in 10 minutes.
Figures this would be the
one day he comes early.
Can you proofread this for me?
When are you gonna
find your own assistant?
Not today. Thank
you. I'll be back in five.
Dr. Cuddy.
I know we're usually
fine with two CS reps,
but I want a few extra
hands today, just in case.
And have IT recheck the network.
I don't want to hear later that
the new lines can only dial
out or the computer crashed.
What's going on?
Hopefully, nothing.
Just make sure you're
ready if people start calling.
You wanted to see me?
Hey, Dr. Cuddy, yeah.
I wanted to let you know there's
a problem with one of the orders
that came in last night.
Which is?
They sent double the
amount of meds we ordered.
Did you call and ask why?
Yeah. They insist
it's not a mistake.
So fax them the original PO.
Yeah, that's what I was planning
on doing, but I can't find it.
Actually, I can't
find any of them.
Oscar, I don't have time to
straighten out your paperwork.
Where's Stan? He
doesn't get in till 9:00.
And it's actually
not my paperwork,
it's Gail's paperwork,
and she's out sick today.
So put it on her desk and let her
figure it out when she comes back.
All right, but it's
not my problem if...
Oscar, not today, okay?
Was it the whole
shipment or just one med?
It's just one.
Vicodin?
No, 25-milligram
ephedrine tablets.
What? Call Gail.
Tell her I want to see
her in my office ASAP.
But she's sick.
This place is full of sick
people, just get her in here.
Dr. Cuddy, your 8:30
is waiting in your office.
Now.
I gotta make a
quick trip upstairs.
Can you get the guy in my office
a cup of coffee? I'll be right back.
I've gotten you coffee before.
What's wrong?
It's freezing in here. I
can hardly feel my fingers.
Please tell me you
didn't send a 911 page
to tell me the heater's broken.
It's not broken.
House bribed the physical plant
to turn on the AC so I'd hurry up.
So hurry up.
This man's abdomen is wide open.
His core temp is down to 95!
Fine, I will deal with it.
You better, or I'm gonna file...
I don't care what he told
you. Turn it back up, now.
Thought you had
an important meeting.
You're an idiot.
What are you gonna do the next time one
of your patients needs a liver transplant?
Go talk to Wilson about something
completely unrelated and see what happens.
Mystery infection guy
is now covered in boils
and has an abscess big
enough to put your fist in.
He needs to get into
an OR tout de suite.
Hourani will be done soon.
Good.
I'll have some hot
chocolate waiting.
Marina. Hey, how is she doing?
She vomited?
Give her some more ibuprofen
and put her in the bath for a bit.
And call me in a half
hour if it doesn't go down.
Sorry, Marina, I
have another call.
Just call me in a
half hour either way.
Hey, what's up?
Tell him I'm halfway there.
He's the one who insisted
on the early meeting.
All right, I'm coming.
Morning, Eli. Sorry
about the wait.
That's all right.
I hear you've got a sick kid.
Yeah, I know what that's like.
Or, I should say, my wife does.
So, you guys ready to give some
ground so we can make this deal?
Why would we do that?
We've been going at
this for eight months.
As soon as you decide
to get reasonable.
I'm the one that's unreasonable?
You've taken weeks to respond
to every proposal I've presented.
AtlanticNet Insurance is the largest
healthcare provider in New Jersey,
and you're not the only
hospital whose contracts are up.
So is your team ready
to come back to the table?
Yeah. We're not going to.
This is our final offer.
We're willing to go with
a capitated structure,
but we need at
least a 12% increase
in reimbursements
across the board.
Well, good news is I can
give you a quick response.
Not a chance.
But as always,
nice talking to you.
Say hi to your sister for me.
If you don't accept the offer,
we're gonna terminate the contract.
Gonna be hard to
keep this place open
if all your patients
have to pay cash.
Princeton-Plainsboro is the
smallest hospital in our entire network.
We're also the best.
It doesn't matter.
We are responsible for
covering 13 million people.
We don't have enough cash
to buy them all Maseratis.
I know what you pay Bergen, Newark
Beth Israel, Robert Wood Johnson...
It's because they have leverage.
You can be expensive or
small, but you can't be both.
I've engaged Jones/Curtin
to handle the PR
and I'm prepared to make the
announcement at 3:00 p.m. today.
First lesson every good poker
player learns is don't get emotional.
You don't have the cards.
And the sooner you realize that,
the sooner a reasonable
contract will get signed.
You have until 3:00
p.m. to change your mind.
I always did like your style.
Gonna be sad to see you go.
They're waiting for you
in the conference room.
Thanks.
Take this up to the call center
and tell Claudia to
give one to each CS rep
and to start going over the
answers to each question.
Okay.
And under no circumstances is any
of this info to go outside that room.
The scripts are numbered, and I want
a list of every person she gives one to.
Got it. Anything else?
No.
If you really wanted
to make a deal,
you should've
ditched the push-up
and gone with the demi.
Nothing makes a guy
wanna close like highbeams.
What have you heard?
Your meeting with the weasel
lasted less than five minutes,
which means you either agreed to a
completely sensible 30-day extension
or one of you issued a
completely ridiculous ultimatum.
Oh, goody, you or him?
Me.
Way to go, boss. You
said it was ridiculous.
Ridiculous to
make, fun to watch.
As long as it's
not just a bluff.
Please tell me it's not a bluff.
It's not a bluff, and
it's not ridiculous.
Just because we're
not some huge...
Mr. Pluta started hallucinating
before we could put him under.
His BP's plummeting, he
has an elevated heart rate.
Looks like congestive
heart failure.
Interesting.
I don't care how
interesting it is,
you are not infecting
him with malaria.
Since when is malaria
a cure for heart failure?
It's not. It's not congestive heart
failure, it's gotta be one of the...
I just got off the
phone with Hourani.
I'm sorry, Dave, I
don't really have time...
You think I had time to
listen to him go for 20 minutes
about the damn
temperature in the OR?
I took care of it.
It's not an "it," it's a "him"
you need to take care of.
You've got the entire staff
catering to House's every whim,
and I can't get approval to hire
a replacement for the surgeon
he stole from my department.
A doctor I only took on in the first
place because of pressure from you.
So you didn't want Chase, but now
you're pissed you can't have him?
You want to convene
a search committee
and start looking for a
new chief of surgery?
No, Dave.
Then you better stop
spending all your time
putting out his fires and
start doing your damn job.
There a problem with Dr. Thomas?
No, just refereeing a
dispute about the OR.
So, we don't yet have a
contract with AtlanticNet.
We gave you an extra week. And you
assured us you'd have a deal by today.
We could have a deal,
just not the deal we deserve.
So, what do you want,
approval for an extension?
We've been at this
for eight months,
an extension isn't going
to change anything.
So what's your plan?
I presented a final offer.
I told them that we would
agree to a capitated structure
if they increase
reimbursements by 12%.
A final offer. What
does that mean?
If they don't accept it by
3:00, we're gonna terminate.
Are you out of your mind?
If we don't accept
AtlanticNet Insurance
we'll lose 80% of our patients.
We'd be lucky to
last three months.
We're not asking for
anything they can't afford.
Their last offer
was a 4% increase,
and you're demanding 12?
They're paying even
more at some places.
Units that have lower
ratings than ours.
In a perfect world that
would definitely matter.
Sanford, they're
all about growth,
and they know they don't get new customers
by marketing themselves as the biggest.
They do it by claiming
they're the best,
and they can't do that if
their patients can't come to us.
What was Morgan's
reaction when you told him?
He didn't give in. But he will.
I told him I'd make the
announcement at 3:00.
He'll call back before then.
They need us.
No, we need them.
We need each other.
The negotiation is
your responsibility,
so we can't stop you if
this is what you want to do.
But just so we're clear, if we don't
have a contract with AtlanticNet,
you're not gonna
have a contract with us.
Guess who didn't
show up for clinic duty.
Don't tell me,
the guy with all the boils
needs a liver transplant.
No, his doctor needs a nap.
You want me to try to find him?
You really need
him? I need someone.
I have cancer.
Why do you think
you have cancer?
I don't think I have cancer,
I know I have cancer.
I had surgery to remove a malignant
polyp in my colon six months ago,
and now it's spread to
my liver and lymph nodes.
So you're under the
care of an oncologist?
Yeah, but he won't give
me the prescription I need.
You need more pain killers?
No, I need breast milk.
Human breast milk?
Yes, it has
cancer-fighting qualities.
Well, in newborns it's been
shown to reduce future risk...
No. In adults with cancer,
too. I've read studies.
Look, I even know a
place where I can buy it.
I just need a prescription so I can get
reimbursed by my insurance company.
They said they'd reimburse the cost
of breast milk as a cancer treatment?
They reimburse prescriptions.
So, if you write
me a prescription,
then they have no
choice but to pay.
Well, actually,
they have a choice.
What are you, some type of
shill for the insurance company?
No. I've been paying
premiums for 30 years
and I've never been sick a
day in my life till this happened.
Now I can't work.
I got no money,
and you want to help
them screw me over.
I'm not screwing you over.
Well, then give me the
script. It won't help you.
Will it hurt me? No, but...
Okay, so it won't harm
me and it won't harm you,
but it's this insurance company...
This is not about insurance.
Then give me the damn script!
I'm sick.
I need help.
I need something.
I'm sorry.
Bitch.
Anyone call?
Yeah.
The ER. They said the vascular
who's on call doesn't have privileges.
Then why is he on call?
Dowd's at a conference
and got him to fill in.
Be nice if he got somebody who could
actually work here. Call Ereshefsky.
Ereshefsky? She's
not gonna do it.
She owes me a favor.
She's still not gonna do it.
All right.
Oh, and there's a guy in your
office. I think he's a lawyer.
Why is he in my office?
Said he didn't want to sit
around a bunch of sick people.
I tried to stop him.
Hi. I'm Dr. Lisa Cuddy.
Ronald Westbrook.
I appreciate your taking
the time to meet with me.
Hard to avoid, since
you're already in my office.
Sorry about that, I just
got over a wicked cold.
I didn't want to...
How can I help you?
I represent Martin Acevedo.
He's filed a suit against
PPH and Dr. Robert Chase
for performing surgery
without consent.
Yes, I saw that. I also
saw the consent forms.
They were all signed.
Yes, but my client was assured
that the procedure would
just be a few minor sutures.
Wait, your client
accidentally cut his thumb off
with a table saw, right? Yes.
And Dr. Chase reattached it?
Yes.
You're saying he didn't
want it reattached?
No, he most certainly did not.
His insurance only covered
60% of inpatient expenses,
so he would only agree
to the cheapest option.
So what did you tell him?
I said I'd sew up the skin
over the exposed bone.
Then I put him under,
got his thumb from the
paramedics and reattached it.
What's he gonna do?
Tell a judge that I harmed
him by reattaching a vital digit?
Both he and the insurance company
are suing to get out of paying the bill.
It's over $80,000.
It was his thumb.
I couldn't just let him toss it in
the trash to save a few bucks.
The pharm tech who called in sick
is here. She's waiting in your office.
He barely even
looks at me anymore.
We haven't had sex in months.
You don't need
pills to lose weight.
There are healthier
ways, legal ways.
You don't understand
how hard it is.
Ever since our second
child, no matter what I do...
I just wanted to lose 10 more
pounds, and then I was gonna stop.
I'm sorry.
Forging pharmaceutical
orders, stealing...
Don't fire me, Dr. Cuddy.
Please, I'm begging you.
If Sam finds out, he'll divorce
me for sure. And my kids...
I will never do it again, I swear.
Just give me a second chance.
I won't report the
theft to the DEA.
But I have to fire you.
Just take a few minutes
to compose yourself,
then go down to HR, and
they'll give you your last check.
I've been a perfect
employee for seven years.
I know, but this is too big.
I'm sorry.
How's it going?
I've got three hours to save
this place from bankruptcy,
I just fired one of
my best employees,
and the woman taking care of
my sick child isn't returning my calls.
Rachel's gonna be fine, I'm sure
whoever he or she is deserved it,
and we're not going
bankrupt. Are we?
Don't worry. The board will fire
me before they allow that to happen.
They'd never fire you.
I just told AtlanticNet Insurance I'd
terminate unless they give us a 12% bump.
They might fire you.
Marina, hey, it's me.
I haven't heard back from you.
Can you call me as soon as you can?
Thank you.
You try Lucas?
He's either sleeping
or avoiding me.
You in a fight?
Not yet, but we're gonna be.
What do you think I
should do about AtlanticNet?
You're asking a guy who paid
full sticker price for his last car.
You ask House?
He is a master manipulator
who always gets what he wants.
This situation is out of
control enough already.
House is the last person
I want to get involved.
Get out of my chair,
and the answer's no.
Have you noticed how many porn
sites have "mom" in the domain name?
Hot moms, hungry
moms, mature moms.
That ought to make
you feel pretty good.
What do you want?
Looks like boils, altered
mental status and heart failure
was caused by
renal cell carcinoma.
I need your signature to
start treating it with malaria.
Don't worry. I'm
giving him chemo, too.
What is your sudden
obsession with malaria?
Just trying to play
my part, cutting costs.
Malaria is the simplest, cheapest
method of delivering hyperthermia.
Right, the only money
you care about...
You bet someone you could
use malaria as a diagnostic tool?
That doesn't sound like me.
Forget it.
Okay, let me see if
I've got this straight,
a bet that puts one patient
at minor risk is juvenile...
And irresponsible and dangerous.
But going all-in
against AtlanticNet...
Is not a bet.
That is a carefully
considered negotiating position.
I'm gonna put
this in your in-box.
I just hope it doesn't get lost
underneath all the other stuff
you're carefully considering.
Can you take a look at
these per diem schedules,
let me know if you see
any conflicts? Got it.
Oh, and Ereshefsky
actually did come in.
You catch her leaving a
sponge in a guy or something?
Wasn't a medical
mistake. What was it?
Can't tell you now. She came in.
Hey, Stan, have you audited
the ephedrine orders, yet?
Why? You told me
she confessed. Stan!
All right, yeah,
I'll take care of it.
Today.
You know he's
cussing you out now.
I don't care, as
long as he does it.
What a bitch.
What are you doing here?
Sounded like you were gonna
be too busy for lunch, so...
My specialty. Spinach lasagna.
Sure you didn't come
looking for more people
you could brag
about our sex life to?
Okay, sorry.
From now on I've got nothing but
bad things to say about our sex life.
Or nothing to say.
And what's going on with
Marina? She hasn't called me back.
She was gonna call, I told her I'd
let you know everything was okay.
So her fever broke?
What exactly does that
mean, when a fever breaks?
Lucas, I'm very busy, does
she have a fever or not?
That was gonna be your lunch?
And you didn't have
breakfast either.
No, she doesn't have a fever,
and the rash was just
like a little diaper rash.
What rash? She has a rash?
A little one.
Lisa, don't worry,
I'm telling you.
Come on.
Oh, God. I must have grabbed
Marina's cell by mistake.
And I turned the ringer off on
the home phone so I could sleep.
What are you doing to me?
I take it your deal's not done.
Not yet.
How about I take a quick look into the
guy who's in charge of the negotiations,
or better yet, the CEO.
If I get some dirt, you
can use it as leverage.
There's no time.
How do you even find these guys?
You should've
seen the guy's face.
I thought he was gonna have a
damn coronary right there in the tee box.
Excuse me, you're
Keith Tannenbaum,
CEO of AtlanticNet
Insurance, right?
That's me. How can I help you?
Well, actually, I think
we can help each other.
I am Dr. Lisa Cuddy, Dean of
Medicine at Princeton-Plainsboro.
Oh, yeah. Well, how are you?
Well, I'm a little unhappy.
You're aware that our contract
with your company is up this week.
Yes, and we have a negotiating
team that's working all that out.
Princeton-Plainsboro has the
highest rated ER in the state,
the most advanced ICU,
and the most innovative diagnostic
medicine department in the entire country.
Good to know. Now if
you don't mind, I'd like to...
While AtlanticNet Insurance
has a marketing budget
that is more than our pediatric
ICU's and transplant unit's combined.
Your PGA sponsorship
could pay for our walk-in clinic,
and the money you spend
to fuel your two private jets
could fund our air ambulance
service for the next three years.
Your point being?
Your growth may be
good for your bottom line,
but ours allows
us to save lives.
And I would rather not have
to announce to the press
how selective your company appears
to be when it comes to cutting costs.
Morgan was right.
You are one tough gal.
You can portray me as a rich
bastard in the press all you want,
just as long as I stay rich.
Stan is looking
for you. I'm busy.
He said it's urgent.
I don't understand how it's even
possible. I've checked it twice.
How much?
Ten cases.
Ten cases?
Going back three years.
What the hell have
you been doing, Stan?
You're supposed to
be managing this place.
All the paperwork I
signed was correct.
She must have altered
the orders afterwards.
Didn't you ever cross check
it with the bills that came in?
I delegated it.
To whom?
To Gail.
Well, she seemed perfectly
trustworthy, how was I supposed to know?
By doing your job! Sorry.
Have you notified
the DEA? The DEA?
Jeez, Stan, hello!
You don't steal $50,000 worth of
pills because you want to lose weight.
She's supplying a meth
lab. Just get her back in here.
All right. Now.
Well, you ever
want a job, trust me.
He'll double whatever
you're making here.
I take it he liked my proposal.
Enough to tell me to get
my ass back over here today.
Here. He's willing to go to 8%.
Eight? We were at four.
Your board's gonna
think you walk on water.
I want 12.
You're not gonna get
12. There's just no way.
8% barely covers
our cost inflation.
The capitated structure should
allow you to hold down inflation.
And shifts all
your risk onto us,
which is why we deserve 12.
Lisa, come on.
The guy who mows my lawn
makes more than my kid's teacher.
Hell, the two guys whose lunch
you interrupted could get fired,
their severance would be more than
most of their employees make in a lifetime.
It doesn't have anything to
do with what you deserve.
This is it.
Take it or leave it.
What are you doing? Hey.
Know any good
transplant surgeons?
Turns out his kidneys
aren't the only thing failing.
And I know what you're thinking,
but malaria wouldn't
destroy his liver that fast,
especially since we
never infected him.
I thought you said...
Apparently Foreman now thinks
that he has the authority
to overrule my orders
just because the
FDA wouldn't approve.
Don't worry, I'll deal with him.
If you could just
talk to Hourani...
What would you do?
If you paged me during sex?
About the contract
with AtlanticNet?
I got them to come up to 8%,
but we should get at least 12.
It's all numbers, do the
math, and nothing else.
It's not about my pride,
it's about the principle.
They're trying to screw us
over because we're small.
That's what they're
supposed to do.
They should be
pressuring other hospitals
to be more like us, not trying to
make us more like them. It's stupid.
And putting your job on the line
in an effort to stamp
out stupidity isn't?
You would.
Probably.
But then I also wanted to try to cure
cancer by infecting a guy with malaria
to win a $50 bet. You
really want to be like me?
As you know, for
the past eight months,
we've been trying to renegotiate our
contract with AtlanticNet Insurance.
It's been a difficult process,
but I wanted to let you all know
before we made the formal
announcement, that, as of 5:00 p.m. today,
our contract with
AtlanticNet will be terminated.
We've doubled the number
of customer service
representatives in our call center,
current patients will still be allowed
to remain in our care for 30 days,
but starting tomorrow we will
no longer be accepting patients
with AtlanticNet
health insurance.
Dr. Cuddy!
Why weren't we told
about this sooner?
Come on, Marina,
pick up the phone.
I'm busy.
We found a liver match.
All right.
Get him prepped. I'll straighten
things out with Hourani.
Hourani's not the
problem. House is.
Now he wants Chase
to do the surgery.
To prove to Hourani
he doesn't need him?
To prove to Thomas that Chase
was his department's best surgeon.
And what does Chase want to
do? Chase wants to do the surgery.
And you don't want
him to do it because?
I don't care who does it.
So what's the problem?
In order to get our
patient into the OR,
we have to get him on
the surgery schedule.
In order to do that we need
someone to put him there
who neither House nor
Thomas can overrule.
What?
Would you rather I
go back on Vicodin?
She's not massaging your leg.
She will eventually.
Why am I the only person here who
cares what happens to this hospital?
Get off your ass and get
your department under control,
at least for the next few days.
It's gonna take
longer than a few days
for a company the
size of AtlanticNet
to start feeling the squeeze
of your PR campaign.
If they ever do.
And you know this how?
From all the time you spent
researching them and their other contracts,
the way they handle
their press relations?
I know they have a NASCAR team.
Despite what you may have learned
at Hebrew school or from Jimmy Cliff,
sometimes the bigger they
are, the harder they kick your ass.
I'm not trying to be greedy.
But he's also not interested in being
forced into a medical bankruptcy.
Mr. Acevedo, I'm sorry you're
having financial difficulties,
but because of us
you still have a thumb.
I assume that's something
a carpenter might need.
And I assume you didn't ask for this
meeting so you could lecture my client.
You have insurance,
but by filing the suit you've caused
us to get paid nothing by them either.
That's not our problem.
Actually, it is, since
he's responsible
for any expense
we're not reimbursed.
But if you drop this
suit and make it clear
that Dr. Chase was
acting in your best interest
when he reattached your thumb,
then we'll be able to resubmit the claim.
And you'll cover his
deductible, attorney's fees,
and 50 grand for
pain and suffering.
Actually I was thinking more
like we'd cover half his deductible,
which means you'd
only owe $16,000.
You want him to pay you? Yes!
Do you have any
idea how much it costs,
how many years it takes to
train someone in microsurgery?
We gave you back your life.
You can still work, you can
button your own shirt, hold a fork...
Martin, let's go.
I'm sorry, I know I
should pay, but I just can't.
I still cannot work, I'm already
under water on my house,
and I have two kids with braces.
You think you'd be in better
shape without a thumb?
Right now, financially?
Yeah, I would be.
Well, so would we,
but when you came in,
we didn't think about that,
we just took care of you.
Made sure we did whatever
you needed to get well.
Yeah, right.
All you doctors
care about is healing.
That's why there are all those
BMWs and Porsches in the parking lot.
Damn it.
Come on, we're out of here.
We'll see you in court.
You're right, you will.
You still have a
thumb because of us,
and like everyone else in this
world, we don't work for free.
We earn this money, and if we have
to take your house to get it, we will.
What's going on?
I think they're fighting.
Out of my way.
Now! Out of the way!
What the hell is going on?
I told them to use
their words, but...
That pharm tech is
back. She's in your office.
You, there. You, over there.
I don't want to hear a word out of
either one of you until I get back.
You lied.
So? What are you
gonna do about it?
Well, for one, notify the DEA.
Good, I'm sure they'll
be very interested to hear
how Dr. House forced me
to help him steal the meds
and the administrator who he's having
sex with has been helping him cover it up.
You really think you can
lie your way out of this?
Yeah, I do.
Anything else you
want to know, bitch?
The hospital board's
chairman wants to speak to you.
Tell him I'm busy.
I did, but he...
Then tell him I quit.
You owe Lucas the money.
We were having
sex when you called.
The breast milk guy finally found a
doctor who'd give him what he wanted.
If it works, that's way
better than malaria.
It's worth a shot.
Great.
I thought they were
the ones bluffing.
No way they'd let us terminate.
They're not gonna fire you,
and you're not gonna quit.
Why not?
Because you're an idiot.
This place needs you,
and that matters to you.
What do you think of
that pharm tech, Gail?
She's a sociopath.
You knew she was stealing meds?
No. But have you seen
the way she opens the mail?
Why didn't you ever tell me?
Figured it might come
in handy one day.
Gail, I like you. I always have.
And I know you must've
gotten sucked up into a situation
you weren't able to control.
Really? Is that what
happened with you and House?
I'm not gonna back down just
because you threaten to smear me.
Now, if you agree
to tell the truth,
there are things
I can do to help.
Think about your
husband, your kids.
I know you're a good
person, deep down inside.
You can't completely hide everything
about yourself in seven years.
You're an idiot.
I started stealing from here
six months after you hired me.
You still don't even know the
half of it, and you never will.
You wouldn't have even found
out about this if I hadn't gotten sick.
And you aren't as tough
as you think you are.
There's no way you'd
let this job get taken away.
And if I go down,
you're going down.
Hey, can you tell Stan to give this
to the DEA agent when he comes by?
A flower?
Yeah, Lucas gave it to me.
Thought it might
come in handy one day.
I started stealing from here
six months after you hired me.
Nice.
Least I came out
on top once today.
Where you going?
To hand the board
my resignation.
Hopefully whoever they hire to
replace me can still get the 8%.
Marina, I've been trying to
get in touch with you all day.
It's all right. I understand.
How is Rachel?
And the rash?
Great. I'll be home early.
Perfect.
You bitch.
I didn't think
you'd actually do it.
I told you I would.
Call the dogs off.
You got your 12.
Congratulations.
Yes!
You gonna get that?