What are you doing?
Scrubbing in.
I appreciate your enthusiasm.
But you're an ED nurse.
You should've gone
to med school.
I'm reconnecting
with my daughter.
It's been over 20 years.
Are you sure about this?
Dr. Manning's mother
is in heart failure.
Our drug
could save her life.
There's no guarantee...
The drug works.
I unblinded a patient.
You've jeopardized
both of our jobs.
I'm not making
any exceptions
to the enrollment.
I found these trial meds.
Yep, those have to
go back to Kender.
I want you
to take these.
New meds?
They're from
a different doctor.
Mom? What are you
doing up so early?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I couldn't sleep.
My throat is dry.
Hmm. You've been
having that cough
for a while, now, huh?
Yeah.
Is anything else
bothering you?
No. But come
to think of it,
my cough began around the time
that I started taking these.
Who prescribed them,
anyway?
Is this the medication
that Will was suggesting?
No, Mom. Remember?
The trial closed.
Right. So, then,
what do they do?
They improve
your injection fraction.
They help your heart pump.
Oh.
Work?
Yeah. I gotta get going.
Okay.
But I will check
on you later, okay?
Very good. Mwah.
All right, love you. Mwah.
Sabeena.
Good morning.
Hi.
You're here early.
So, um...
Now, that I'm in front of you,
I realize I haven't rehearsed
my speech.
Anyway, I just wanted to say
again how sorry I am
for violating your trust.
I'm not gonna sugarcoat it.
I was wrong. No excuse.
Apology accepted.
Great.
And you know, if you're
free later, maybe a drink?
I'm sorry, Will.
While I want us
to still be friends,
I think it's best
we keep things professional
moving forward.
Oh. Okay. Yeah.
How'd you wrangle that
thing away from Maggie?
She's repping Gaffney
at some residency fair
this morning.
All that power
at your fingertips.
How's it feel?
Surprisingly natural.
Like I was born
to boss people around.
Oh. Hey, you're up,
Dr. Choi.
Car struck a kid
on his bicycle.
Driver and victim incoming.
Driskell, with me!
10-year-old male,
struck by a motor vehicle
at 35 miles per hour.
No helmet.
GCS four in the field.
Intubated in the ambo.
What about the driver?
Right behind us.
Dr. Choi?
Yeah?
There's something
you should know.
What is it?
Ms. Goodwin is the driver.
Get him transferred.
I'll be right back.
You got it.
Ms. Goodwin!
Dr. Choi, the boy...
Okay. I'm about to check
him out. Are you okay?
Are you okay?
It was so dark.
And he just came
out of nowhere.
There was no time
to stop.
It's okay.
So, I held his c-spine
until the medics got there.
But he wasn't moving.
And there was
so much blood.
I'll do everything I can.
Please... Oh, God.
This is gonna
sting a little.
Okay.
Any tenderness?
Yeah, it looks like
the seat belt
got you pretty good.
Yeah, I skidded
and hit a telephone pole.
The airbag caught
most of my impact, but...
Uh, I feel fine. Really.
No dizziness, no neck pain.
Good.
You all right?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm good.
Ms. Goodwin, I think
we need to get a chest X-ray,
a 12-lead EKG,
just to rule out
any blunt cardiac injury.
Okay, but later, please.
Could you
give us a moment?
Sure.
Thank you.
Of course.
I was headed
to meet my trainer.
Going under the speed limit,
no distractions.
I didn't even have
the radio on.
I don't know
where he came from. My side?
There was no way
I could have seen him.
Sharon, it was
an accident.
And it doesn't sound like
you did anything wrong.
Oh, Daniel, he couldn't have
been more than 10 or 11.
And he was out, biking alone?
I mean, in the dark?
And no helmet.
Do you know anything?
Any word on how he's doing?
I don't. I just came
straight down here
as soon as I heard.
Bert's on his way in.
Bert? Who called him?
I guess he's still your
emergency contact?
I thought you guys
were on good terms.
I don't wanna talk
about that right now.
Do you want me to
try and hold him off?
No, it's fine,
it's just,
please, I need you
to find out what's
going on with that boy.
And no HIPAA nonsense
right now.
I may have just...
Ms. Goodwin,
this a good time to take
your statement?
Shouldn't take long.
Traffic cams clearly show
you were not at fault.
Okay. Daniel, please?
I'll be back. All right?
All right. Okay.
Hang in there.
I tried to
call you this morning.
Yeah, um, I'm sorry.
I was in the shower,
and I've just been running
a little bit late today.
Yeah. Did you hear
about Goodwin?
No. What happened?
She was in
a car accident.
What? Is she okay?
Yeah, thankfully.
No serious injuries.
Oh, thank God.
But hey, I was calling
because I was doing
some research on AICDs.
I know you and your mom
have some reservations
about going that route.
Yeah.
There's some
preliminary evidence
that supplementing
the device with Digoxin
can lower the incidence
of arrhythmia.
Not a total fix,
but certainly can make things
more comfortable for Carol.
Thank you for
looking into that.
It sounds promising.
I sent you the literature,
in case you wanna
browse it yourself.
I will definitely look at it,
but I am late for work, so...
Of course. Bye.
Bye.
Excuse me, Miss? Uh...
Yeah?
I'm a nurse
from Chicago Med,
and I'm here for
the residency fair
and I'm a bit lost.
I'm looking
for Beecher Hall.
Oh, sure. At the end
of this hall,
you're gonna take a left,
then go through your first
doorway on your right.
After that, you're gonna
see a stairwell, and...
You know what,
why don't I just take you?
That would be great.
Thank you.
Okay. Here.
Oh.
A small token
of my appreciation.
Oh, wow.
You're hooking me up!
Don't you need these
to entice applicants
for your, um...
What's it called again?
Audition rotation.
Mmm.
Essentially, a mini
two-to-four-week tryout
for your top program.
I had the most
terrifying flashback
when you said "audition."
Oh, no, what happened?
Fifth grade.
Tried out
for the school musical.
They were doing The Wiz
and I froze.
Poor guy playing the piano,
he had to start my song
over three times.
You're kidding. The Wiz?
Yeah. What?
It's just, when I was
in middle school,
I was in The Wizard of Oz
and I played the Scarecrow.
Oh. Okay,
you must have had chops.
I was just one of the poppies
and that's tough to screw up.
Hey, miss. Thank you
so much for going
out of your way.
No problem. It was nice
to meet you. Wait, I'm sorry.
I didn't get your name.
Oh, I'm Maggie.
Maggie. I'm Vanessa.
I have to get to my lab,
but take care.
I didn't even
want to come in,
but my boss forced me.
Besides the abdominal pain,
any vomiting?
No, nothing. I'm also
about to start my period.
Maybe this is just bad PMS?
I don't think so.
Your abdomen sounds like
a hollow drum.
It means there's air
trapped in your bowel.
I'm thinking you might
be obstructed.
I so don't have time for this.
I just got my first huge case.
Can we wrap this up
in under eight hours?
It's hard to say, really.
Yeah, we need to get
an abdominal X-ray
and some bloodwork,
then we'll take it
from there.
Come on. There must be a way
to fast-track things.
I promise, we'll move
as quickly as we can.
Thanks.
She's gonna be a fun one.
No way to schedule
sickness, unfortunately.
Um... Hey.
I wanted to, uh, ask you.
Yeah.
Your trial medications,
is dry cough
one of the side effects?
It is. Yeah, we've seen it
in several participants. Why?
Oh, I just... I saw one
of your trial patients
in the ED the other day.
Really? Huh.
Usually,
I'd get a notification
if one of our participants
ends up in the ED.
No, no. It was nothing.
It just ended up
being indigestion,
but that was one
of the symptoms
that was an outlier,
so, I just wanted
to make sure.
Oh, okay, yeah. Usually
resolves within a few days.
Oh. Great.
Hey, hang on.
How's your mom doing?
I was gonna come around
the other day when
she was here for her exam,
but I thought there
might be too many cooks
in the kitchen.
I get it. Um, Mom is...
She's hanging in there.
Still having palpitations,
though, but...
You know this isn't
your fault, right?
That it turned out this way?
Thank you for
saying that, Will.
I'm serious.
And you need anything,
ask.
Thank you.
Is there anything
I can do for you?
Calls I can make?
No. Insurance
has been informed.
It's just, the boy...
You know what's going on?
Only that he's
getting scans upstairs.
I'm sorry.
Is Bert here?
I thought I saw him come in.
Yeah, he's grabbing
a coffee.
Everything been okay
with both of you
since you told him
that you only wanted
a friendship?
All right, well...
Oh. There he is now.
I gotta get back to work,
but is there something
I can get for you?
Yeah. Actually,
there is one thing.
I keep a dress
in my office closet.
I'll get it.
And my shoes.
I'll grab that, too.
Good morning.
Morning.
No, thank you.
What did Michael say?
He on his way?
I decided against
calling him.
I know you don't wanna
burden him, but he'd
wanna be here for you.
I'll put him in the loop
when I get more info.
Where is Daniel
with the update?
Why don't you have
a seat for now, try to rest?
I wonder if the boy's mother
is here yet.
Listen, I know
you want answers,
but you can't be caught
snooping around.
If this turns into a lawsuit,
the last thing you wanna do
is make yourself look guilty.
Matter of fact,
let me take you home.
We can wait
for news there.
No.
I'm not going anywhere.
Sharon...
Look, I need to make sure
that that boy is all right.
Bert, I don't need
any babysitting.
Please, just go.
Were you able
to find anything out?
Name's Jake Miller.
Okay.
Okay? He's 10 years old.
His mom is on the way in.
Okay, and what
about his injuries?
He suffered
multiple fractures,
and unfortunately,
uh, a traumatic pseudoaneurysm
in his brain.
Oh.
Also wanted you to know that,
as of a few minutes ago,
anyway,
they had yet
to stabilize him.
No.
No, no. That's right.
A small white box.
Well, listen, I'm sorry.
I'm not sure
what happened then.
Um...
Let me look into it,
and I'll circle back
with you.
Okay, thanks.
Hey. Is everything okay?
Yeah.
No, actually.
Remember my clinical trial
patient, Mr. Brady?
His remaining allotment
of medication was supposed
to be sent back to Kender.
But that was
the pharmacist.
She said the courier
claims someone
picked them up already.
Oh. I'm sorry. I mean,
is it even that big
of a deal, though?
Yeah, the pills
were my responsibility.
I'm gonna have to find them,
one way or another.
Uh, I'll catch you later.
Oh, God. Jake, no.
Jake, what's wrong?
Sam, honey, don't touch.
You must be Jake's mom.
I'm Dr. Choi.
Is he gonna be okay?
Why is Jake sleeping?
Shh. Honey, I gotta
talk to the doctor.
We have a daycare center
at the hospital.
Plenty of snacks and toys.
I'd be happy
to take him.
Thank you.
Sam, go with this nice lady,
I'll come see you in a bit.
Ms. Miller...
I'm sorry, but Jake
suffered what we call
a pseudoaneurysm.
The impact from the crash
tore a vessel in his brain
that has already leaked.
In his brain? Oh, my God.
Now, the pressure
is holding it closed.
But it could open up,
so, we need to get control.
How do you do that?
There are a couple
treatment options
I wanna discuss with you.
But if you need
a moment...
Who hit him?
Bet they were drinking.
I swear, whoever did this,
they're gonna pay.
Sorry.
Are you going
back to school?
Oh. I'm applying.
Hmm.
Some nurse
practitioner programs,
get certified.
Yeah. Got a top choice?
I did. Porter.
But unfortunately,
I missed the deadline.
Porter... Is Melinda Baker
still the head
of the nursing school there?
I think so, yeah.
You know her?
She married my cousin,
and then she divorced
my cousin, but we're
still on good terms.
I could make
a phone call,
and if I sing your praises,
I bet she'd make
an exception.
That's really nice
of you. Um...
Dr. Archer, April,
you have a patient
in Treatment Four.
I'm sending you
the chart right now.
Ah. Thanks. After you.
Okay.
Mr. Turner,
you're having trouble peeing?
I haven't relieved myself
in two days. It's killing me.
I'm sorry.
It's been going on
for months now.
Every few weeks,
I have to come back in
and get...
Okay. Have you
seen a urologist?
No, not yet.
There's no appointments.
I guess, there's a big backlog
due to COVID.
Okay. I'm gonna
refer you to somebody
here at Gaffney.
In the meantime,
let's give Flomax
and put in a Foley.
It's a type
of catheter.
I know.
I'm so sick of this.
Would you excuse me
for a minute?
I'll be right back.
Hey, Dr. Archer?
Yeah.
I was just thinking,
Mr. Turner's had
multiple Foleys,
and they're not
resolving the problem.
Mmm-hmm. You have
a better idea?
What about
a suprapubic tube?
It could give him
long-term relief,
there's a lot lower
incidence of infection
and stricture, right?
Yeah.
That's a good thought.
But an SP tube is
an involved procedure,
and the ED's hopping, so...
He's in
so much pain, though.
Still,
it's not emergent.
So, get a med student
to put in a Foley,
and discharge him
with GU follow-up.
Okay.
Hey.
Ms. Watkins' test results?
Yep. Her labs
and X-rays.
Thanks.
You were right,
bowel obstruction.
Ah. I'm thinking an NG tube.
Suck and drip,
it'll likely resolve
on its own.
Yeah, but I still want
a surgical consult.
Really?
Feels early for that.
Her scans and X-rays
show a good amount
of air in the colon.
I mean, something's
getting through. It might
only be a partial obstruction.
And Surgery may agree,
but better safe
than sorry, right?
Don't want to risk
her bowel distending
too much
and outstripping
the blood supply.
All right.
Hey, you mind paging Surgery?
I gotta swing by
the security office.
How come?
I wanna see
if they can pull footage
from last week.
Pills still haven't
shown up.
I'm just guessing
someone grabbed them
by mistake.
Is that really necessary?
It seems like
a lot to go through
for some medication
that'll probably just
get tossed out anyways.
Kender, they're gonna
want them accounted for.
Plus, I'm not exactly
on Dr. Virani's
good side right now.
What do you mean?
You're her star PI.
Yeah, well...
It's nothing,
forget I said anything.
You said your door
was always open.
And as you can see,
I ain't no fibber.
Come on in.
I was gonna talk to Sharon,
but given everything
that happened...
Oh, yeah, of course.
What's on your mind?
Um, I don't know where
to start, or how to start.
Don't overthink it, Mags.
Just tell me
what's going on.
Okay. I have a daughter.
Her name is Vanessa.
And this morning,
for the first time,
I met her.
Huh.
I'm just so sorry you had
to go through that.
I cannot even imagine
how difficult
that must have been.
Having a kid at 16.
Having to give her up.
It was devastating.
And now, you know,
giving Auggie up.
Yeah.
I guess it triggered
all these feelings.
Oh.
I mean, suddenly,
this need to know
who she was,
that she was okay, just...
It took over.
I just was...
I was just gonna
open the envelope,
find out her name,
and then look her up
on the Internet.
Right. But then?
But then I found out
that she was still
living in Chicago,
and she was in
medical school and
in the same field as me.
What are the odds?
You know, a lot of us
just go around and around
on the nature-versus-nurture
debate.
But it is amazing
how many of our behaviors,
our preferences
appear to be genetic.
It felt that everything
in the universe was
leading me to meet her.
I totally get how
it would feel that way.
I do.
I'm not trying to disrupt
her life. I swear.
I just had to see her.
And now, that I have,
I'm good.
Huh.
So, you don't intend
to see her again?
Of course I want to,
but I won't. She's safe,
she's thriving.
I got what I needed.
Hold on. Where'd you
get that information?
Never mind that.
Just what is
the treatment plan
for Jake's pseudoaneurysm?
All due respect,
you know I can't
disclose that.
Dr. Choi...
Ms. Goodwin, please.
HIPAA aside,
it's a conflict
of interest.
Considering your involvement,
this could look really bad.
Any lawyer
would advise...
Let me worry
about that! Please.
The vessel's still leaking,
so, Neurosurgery
is gonna operate.
A craniotomy.
Will he make it through that?
There is a significant
mortality risk.
There must be
a less invasive option.
There is,
a stent-assisted coil.
But due to the extent
of the injury,
it comes with a high risk
of long-term
cognitive deficits.
Still, we should err
on the side of life.
I agree with you.
But I presented both options
to Jake's mother, Wendy,
and she chose surgery.
Why? Why would
she do that?
She's low-income.
She doesn't feel
equipped to care
for a child
with extensive needs.
Says she can barely
keep food on the table
as it is.
You have to go back to her.
Ms. Goodwin, I know
you have Jake's
best interest at heart.
But this decision
didn't come easy
for his mother.
And I'm not gonna
push it further.
Surgery?
You gotta be kidding me.
I got a deposition
tomorrow morning.
Elaine, it's just
a surgical consult.
Doesn't mean
they'll recommend
an operation.
Honestly, your CT
looked okay to me.
We'll see what...
Ms. Watkins,
I'm Dr. Marcel.
I'm the surgeon
reviewing your case.
Let's have it.
I got work to do.
Right.
Cutting to the chase,
given that conservative
management with the NG tube
has failed to clear
the obstruction,
I'd recommend surgery
to remove the adhesions.
But let's be clear,
this is in no way
a mandatory operation.
I'm sorry, Dr. Halstead,
that's not my take on it.
Look. Your white count
is elevated,
you're running a fever.
Both of which are concerning.
Yes, they are. But still,
we haven't given the NG tube
much time to work.
But if we wait too long,
you run the risk
of perforation,
and then
a semi-elective surgery
becomes an emergent one.
Which is precisely
why we would
monitor you closely...
You two clearly
can't agree on anything.
So, let me solve this for you.
If I'm not dying tomorrow,
I'm not doing
the surgery. Done.
Great.
Right.
Hey, you got an issue
with me, you don't bring it
into the medicine.
Get over yourself.
This is my patient.
I had a difference
of opinion.
Then you pull me aside.
You don't openly
contradict me.
Seems like a bad habit
of yours lately,
inserting yourself.
You are one to talk.
Excuse me?
Oh, no. Come on.
Say it.
All right, you wanna
get into this now? Fine.
Carol chose the trial.
It's what she wanted.
There it is.
Everything was a go
until you stuck
your nose in.
Your memory must be
failing you, 'cause
I didn't force anything.
Natalie was fully
on board with the LVAD.
Because you got
in her head
when she was vulnerable.
She chose the LVAD
because it was the right
medical decision.
You think she still
feels that way?
Hey, Dean. I see
you've been clocking
quite a few 16-hour shifts.
Weren't you the one
lecturing me
about keeping
the troops fresh?
Do as I say, not as I do.
I just don't want
the ED to impede
your personal life.
Personal life?
What the hell is that?
Come on. I remember you
being a man of many interests
back in the day.
Life of the party, too.
All right, listen,
if you need cash,
all you have to do is ask me.
You don't have
to use flattery.
Seriously, though,
no man's an island.
I guess I'm one
of the lucky few.
Just don't work yourself
into the ground, okay?
Lean on your colleagues.
We've all got
each other's backs here.
Okay.
Speaking of,
I was looking over
your patient's chart,
Gerry Turner.
Oh, yeah?
It looks like
he's gonna need a fourth
Foley in two months.
Makes me think
it's time to try
something new.
Maybe an SP tube?
If nothing else,
it might...
No, you're right.
That's a great idea, boss.
Thanks for being
so open, Dean.
No worries.
Thanks for having my back.
Hey. Archer is gonna
give Mr. Turner an SP tube.
Oh, really?
I had suggested
the same thing.
I know.
Ms. Miller? My name
is Sharon Goodwin.
I'm the executive director
of Patient Services
here at Gaffney.
This about payment?
'Cause I have insurance.
Through my job.
What it doesn't cover,
I'll have to figure out.
I'm a single mom.
No, I understand.
But that's not why I'm here.
Uh... Well, not directly.
I wanted to speak
with you regarding
Jake's medical treatment.
Revisit your options.
I already told the doctor
I want Jake to have
the brain surgery.
Yes, and I'm sure
he informed you
of the risks.
That's right, he did.
So, what's this about?
Well, if you were to
reconsider and go with
the less invasive option,
the stent, and if by some
unfortunate circumstance,
Jake were to suffer
cognitive deficits,
the hospital has resources
that can help you
take care of your son.
You mean,
financial assistance?
Like, a loan?
No, not a loan.
More like a grant.
Ms. Goodwin,
may I speak with you...
Give me a moment,
Dr. Choi.
Ms. Miller, I wanted you
to hear me out first.
But there's something
you should know.
I am the one that hit
your son this morning.
What? It was you?
Yes, I'm sorry.
I didn't want
to lead with that.
Acting like
you're here to help me,
help my son?
Ms. Miller, please.
But I am.
If you'll just
allow me to explain.
No.
You're only here
to cover your own ass.
That's not true. I only want
what's best for your son.
Don't you dare
try to tell me
what's best for my boy.
You're not the one
who has to deal with this
after today. I am!
Okay, Ms. Goodwin. Please.
Excuse us.
Nurse Sexton,
give two of Versed.
We don't usually sedate
for SP tubes.
I just want to make sure
that Mr. Turner here
is nice and relaxed.
All right? It's not the most
pleasant procedure.
The Versed
will put you in a nice,
comfortable twilight.
When you wake up,
you won't remember
a thing.
You won't get any
argument from me.
Just the kind
of patient I like.
Nurse Sexton?
Okay.
Versed in.
It's nice you and Ethan
are still close.
Excuse me?
Didn't you guys
used to date? It's just nice
you're still friends.
None of my exes
will speak to me.
Oh. Sorry to hear that.
You know what?
Why don't you
do the honors?
What?
Yeah. Take over.
No,
I'm not allowed.
Oh, from what I've heard,
that's never
stopped you before.
And hey, nurse practitioner,
give it a go.
Here you go.
Okay.
I'm really not comfortable.
It's just a big needle,
is what it is.
It's no different
from putting in an IV.
I'm meeting
some resistance.
Don't be afraid.
Push harder.
The catheter's not going in.
Dr. Archer, can you
please take over?
His heart rate
is dropping.
Yeah, you're causing
a vagal response. Go faster.
Dr. Archer, would you
please take over? Now!
All right, all right.
Calm down.
In there.
All right, one milligram
Atropine.
Yeah.
And all's well
that ends well.
Okay.
Come in.
Hey there.
Hey.
I, uh...
I heard about
your run-in
with Ms. Miller.
Yeah.
How you doing?
I'm fine.
I was just...
All I was trying
to do was help, Daniel.
Of course you were.
I was hoping for the sake
of her son, that she could
get over her anger
and see that I was sincere.
I just think that
everything's still
a little raw.
You know? I mean,
her world is...
It is kind of spinning
right now, right?
Just like yours is.
He can't die, Daniel.
That little boy
has to make it.
I know how badly
you wanna fix this, Sharon.
But, you know, it's just
one of those situations
that as cruel as it
might seem, that...
I don't know,
it's kind of out of your
hands, you know?
I spend so much time trying to
be prepared for anything.
You know? Analyzing
worst-case scenarios,
trying to stay
two steps ahead.
Hmm. That's why
you're so good at your job.
And then this.
It makes me wonder,
what have I ever really
had any control over?
What do any of us really ever
have any control over?
In my experience,
not a whole hell of a lot.
It can actually
be kind of freeing
to remember that.
You know?
Helps you let go of it.
You know me,
and you know
that's not one of my
strong suits.
Is it anybody's?
Anyway...
I just know that for myself,
when I'm feeling scared,
it helps when I remember
that I have people
in my corner
that love me.
And God knows
you got that in droves.
What the heck was that?
I don't follow.
First, you force me
into a procedure that
I am not supposed to do.
You're upset.
Then when I ask
for your help,
you refuse to throw me
a life vest?
You should've
jumped in immediately.
I thought you'd welcome
the challenge.
Look, I know
you didn't want to
do this procedure,
but if you think that
I went behind your back
to Ethan or something...
No, excuse me. No,
I never suggested that.
I just believe
the best way to learn
is in the heat of battle.
As a nurse practitioner,
you're gonna be doing
these procedures on your own.
NPs don't put in
SP tubes here.
Okay, listen to me.
You just need to work
on your confidence.
You are an incredibly
skilled nurse.
Don't underestimate yourself.
Hey, Bert. Uh, about earlier,
I'm sorry.
Can you just come back
to the hospital?
What are you...
You're still here.
Never left.
Can we talk?
Look,
I shouldn't have forced you
to leave this morning.
But honestly,
I was scared and feeling
really exposed.
Yeah. I'm sure
I didn't help coming in,
trying to take charge.
It's just that, uh,
when I saw you hurt,
I wanted to
take care of you.
I went into husband mode.
But I know that's not
my role anymore.
Oh, no.
But you're my friend.
A good friend.
And you've more
than proven that.
I'm always gonna
show up for you, Sharon.
Doesn't matter our title.
It goes deeper than that.
We're family.
Yes.
You know, that boy Jake
is in surgery.
It's a risky operation.
Whatever happens, I'm here.
Thank you.
Hey, Dr. Charles,
did Dr. Archer
ever reach out to you?
No, he didn't. Why?
He looking for a consult,
or something?
No. It's actually him
I'm concerned about.
He's having a hard time
settling in or...
A bit.
Listen, I think he's
holding onto some
really heavy baggage.
Some of the same stuff
I was dealing with.
And he's self-isolated.
I'm worried he doesn't
have anyone in his life
he can open up to?
Got it. Okay, buddy.
Well, message received.
Thanks for the heads-up.
Thanks.
Hey, got your text.
Hey.
What's going on?
I'm sorry?
Something's off.
You say you don't
blame me for your mom.
I don't.
But it's clear
you don't want my help.
Or at the very least,
you no longer trust
my instincts.
I swear, it's not that.
Then what is it?
I've been open
with you, Nat.
I've shared a lot.
You have.
More than I've shared with
anyone in a very long time.
It's got to be
a two-way street.
Crockett, I promise,
it is not you.
Between my mom,
Owen, and work,
I don't have the bandwidth
for anything else.
To worry about anyone
else's feelings.
I'm not asking
you to do...
No, I'm sorry.
I can't do this right now.
Okay? I just
need some space.
Maggie?
Yeah?
I want to thank you again
for offering to rep Gaffney
at the residency fair
this morning.
Already have
several applications.
That was fast.
Only made it through
reviewing the first applicant,
but...
Actually, she mentioned
in her email that she
spoke to you this morning?
Do you remember her name?
Vanessa something.
Right. Vanessa Taylor.
Yeah. What was your
impression of her?
Uh... Good candidate.
Top of her class,
already published in JAMA.
It'd be great to get her.
Yeah, impressive.
I'll keep that in mind.
Yeah.
Right.
Oh, Nurse Sexton?
Do you still want me
to reach out to Melinda?
The head of
the nursing school at Porter.
Oh, right. Um...
And also, I'm sorry
about our misunderstanding
earlier.
I'd be happy to make a call.
For you?
Hell, I'll even write you
a glowing recommendation.
I appreciate that.
I'll let you know.
Yeah. Please do.
Okay. Good night.
Night.
Oh! Dean!
Quick question for you.
Yeah, sure.
Did they give you
a welcome packet
when you started?
Uh, yeah, I think so.
Admin is mandating
these little
mental health check-ins
for all ED personnel
during the pandemic.
Yeah, sure.
Quick, informal.
Completely off the record.
The only thing
they care about
is that you show up.
So, it'd great
if we could get
that on the books.
Sure. I'll check my calendar,
and I'll call you tomorrow.
Fantastic, thanks.
Yeah, sure.
Hey.
Hey, Nat.
Hey, you should know.
I just admitted
Elaine Watkins.
Fever's worsening
and her white count's up.
So, they're gonna operate
first thing in the morning.
Too bad the NG tube
didn't do the trick. But
surgery was the right call.
Yeah. That was Crockett's
thinking, too.
Well, good night.
Night.
Oh, hey. Um...
Whatever happened
with security?
Was Earl able
to pull video for you?
Dead-end, unfortunately.
They delete footage
every 72 hours.
Mmm. Sorry to hear that.
Night.
Thanks.
Hey, almost forgot.
What was the name
of that trial patient
you saw?
With the dry cough?
Uh...
I wanna properly record it
in their trial folder.
Just trying to stay
on top of things
moving forward.
Huh. Uh...
Shoot. I cannot remember
off the top of my head.
I saw so many patients
last week.
Yeah. Of course.
But you know what?
I can look
into it tomorrow.
But right now,
I have to get home to Mom.
So...
I understand. That'll work.
Okay.
Dr. Choi? You got news?
Jake's surgery went well.
Any complications?
No, ma'am. They were
able to reconstruct
the vessel
without clipping
any small branches.
He's still waking up,
but they expect him
to make a full recovery.
How soon
can he go home?
Uh, will they keep him
a few nights, or...
Unfortunately,
he's not going home.
What?
Why not?
While investigating
the accident,
the police uncovered
why Jake was out
biking alone in the dark.
His mom works an overnight
custodial shift across town.
Been leaving
both kids by themselves.
Wow.
PD notified DCFS
and they're on their way.
Does the mother know?
Not yet.
I need you to hold off DCFS.
Ms. Goodwin...
Dr. Choi.
Please. Just do it.
Ms. Miller.
I'm so glad that
Jake's surgery went well.
I told you to
leave me alone.
I just came by to apologize
for my behavior earlier.
Do I need
to get security?
Wait.
I know you left
your children alone
last night.
You trying to say
this is my fault?
I am not here to judge you.
You think I wanna
leave my kids alone?
I don't have a choice.
If I don't work,
they don't eat.
And I got no one to help me.
I'm sorry. You're in
an impossible situation,
and I can't even imagine
the pressure.
I told Jake to stay
in the house when I'm gone.
I never thought...
You're doing
the best you can.
Yeah, well. I'm failing.
You've got to give yourself
some grace.
Look, I had help,
but being a working mother
was still really
very hard.
I came by to offer you
a day shift on the hospital's
custodial staff.
If you want.
I know it's not much.
But at least you'd
have the peace of mind
of knowing that your children
are safe and in school,
while you're at work.
You'd really do that?
Please, let me.
Thank you.
Mom.
Honey, I'm here.
I'm right here.