♪ Can I take your hand?
♪ Do you understand?
♪ You found my heart broken
♪ And you helped me
make it whole ♪
♪ I'm starting to feel
♪ I found something real
♪ The thought
of you fills me ♪
♪ With a warmth
I've never known ♪
♪ Hold
♪ My heart...
Floyd, I need you.
Floyd, you're not still asleep
up there, are you?
♪ Hold
♪ Mm
♪ My heart
♪ Till it grows
♪ Old
♪ Our love stays the same
♪ Through time's
endless change ♪
♪ Ooh, I promise
♪ From now till death
♪ You'll never be alone
♪ Hold
♪ My heart
till it grows old ♪
♪ Ooh
♪ Say you'll
♪ Love me
♪ Say you'll hold me
♪ Through the stormy weather
♪ We'll be together
♪ Always
♪ Say
you ♪
♪ Love me
♪ Say
♪ You'll hold me
through the stormy weather ♪
♪ We'll be together
♪ Always
♪ Hold, ooh
♪ My heart
till it grows old ♪
♪ Ooh,
hold ♪
Mm.
I could stay here forever.
I am very open to that idea.
This is all I need.
Oh, I have to...
Yeah, absolutely.
Speaks Farsi...
Speaking Farsi...
Speaking Farsi gently...
Um...
Speaks Farsi...
Speaking Farsi
Speaking Farsi...
Everything okay?
Family stuff.
*NEW AMSTERDAM *
Season 03 Episode 04
Episode Title: "This Is All I Need"
Aired on: March 23, 2021
- You wanted to see me, sir?
- Whoa, prompt.
Good, I like that.
Already demonstrating you've
got what it takes.
To do what, exactly?
To take over Dr. Kapoor's
department.
Dr. Agnes Kao, interim chair
of neurology.
Sorry, I like to keep things
on the move.
- We'll work on that.
- I can't take over
- Dr. Kapoor's department.
- Why not?
I just finished
my fellowship.
I just took the boards.
- So how'd you do?
- 99th percentile, but...
- You're gonna be great.
- But...
Behold, the king of cardiac,
the duke of hearts
- returns to New Amsterdam.
- Stop.
Sorry, it's too much?
- Excuse me.
- I'm sorry.
You need to find someone else
until Dr. Kapoor comes back.
Someone qualified.
You know, I'm trying to give
her her own department,
- and she's playing hardball.
- Been there.
What if I were just
the interim-interim chair
of neurology?
Would that make you
more comfortable?
Only marginally.
Sold. You got it.
Now get out there,
and go get 'em, tiger.
Yeah, how you holding up?
Well, I'll take the fifth on
that, but at least I'm here.
Well, I would love to be here
to witness
- your triumphant return.
- But?
I'm off to Connecticut.
Assuming I survive rush hour
on the FDR
and awkward silences with
Georgia's parents,
I'm finally bringing home Luna.
I can't wait to see the look
on her face
- when she sees me again.
- That's great, Max.
- What should I...
- Oh.
Uh, see Helen for instructions
on your royal return.
Got it.
So, um...
where is he?
He's out there.
Got it, okay.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
Linus Wilding?
You Linus?
Hi, how you doing?
I'm Dr. Frome.
You can just call me Iggy.
I didn't do anything wrong.
No, I know.
I know that, I know.
I'm just here to talk.
That's all.
So, burning question.
You ever run away before?
- No?
- You ever wanted to?
Okay.
So then I got to assume that
something big,
something major happened,
right?
To make you want to do it
now.
And I know that this is hard to
talk about,
but I have to ask...
did somebody hurt you,
physically?
I didn't run away, okay?
My mom, she...
she threw me out.
Okay.
Well, maybe you can help me
understand this, then.
Why did she call the police and
file a missing persons report?
Okay.
Hi.
I'm so grateful you found
him, Dr. Frome.
- I haven't slept in days.
- Yeah, I can only imagine.
Um...
did you manage to bring
the things I...
Yes, everything
you asked for.
Linus's birth certificate,
immunization forms,
and recent school ID.
Oh, great, thank you.
Okay.
Ms. Wilding, can you think
of any reason why
there's confusion about the
events that led Linus to leave?
Did you guys have a fight?
- Anything?
- No.
Four weeks ago,
I sent him off to camp,
and he never came home.
Okay.
Okay, here's what I think
we should do:
The three of us should
have a chat,
maybe clear up any of this
confusion that's going on.
- Absolutely.
- Okay.
I think now would be
a good time.
Are you okay with that?
Linus.
What's going on here?
Well, I think your son
is feeling a little...
I don't know who that is,
but that is definitely not my son.
I'm...
I'm fairly confident that is.
He looks like my son,
Dr. Frome, I know.
But they are not the same.
No, that boy is an imposter.
A mother knows.
A mother can tell.
That's not my son.
- There he is, in the flesh.
- Good to see you, Max.
No place I'd rather be.
Hey. Calvin.
I hope your drive wasn't
too bad.
Yeah, it was okay.
We've got Luna's stuff all
packed up, ready to go.
Oh, that's very sweet.
Thank you, thank you, Gwen.
Where is she hiding?
Oh, she's just
in the living room,
- playing.
- Oh, great.
Please say you'll stay
for lunch.
I'm perfecting
my bread machine.
No, I couldn't...
Couldn't say no to that.
Of course.
I, um...
I would love that.
All this one-on-one time
with her was priceless.
Luna!
Guess who's here.
Dada's here.
Hammond Sims, 25-year-old
male, possible kidney stones.
More like boulders.
You'll be all right, brother.
How long have you had
this pain for?
It's been a minute.
Thought to come in
when it first hit...
But the nightclub got wiped out
by the 'rona.
No health insurance.
Oh, yeah, you and half
the city.
Oh, snap.
Okay, okay, we're gonna get
- you dialed in...
- Get away from me!
Stop!
No, stop!
Guy's on K2!
Call security!
- Ahh!
- Casey!
I will kill you!
I see you!
I see you all!
Brunstetter's in surgery.
Fractured ocular orbit.
That guy just snapped.
I knew he was on something
when we admitted him.
I should've paged security
right then.
No, it's on me.
I should've gotten there
faster or been closer...
Hey.
This is not your fault.
Or yours or yours.
How many of us have been
attacked while on the job?
Assaulted...
slapped, bit, kicked, clawed.
Come on.
How many of you feel unsafe
working here?
They said they were gonna
install metal detectors.
I heard
more security cameras.
Yeah, we keep waiting for
someone else to protect us.
And now one of our own.
We all deserve to feel safe.
And today, I am gonna
make that happen.
- Incoming!
- Oh, got another one.
Here we go.
No, no,
flight 117 isn't gonna work
because I need
to leave New York now
to get there in time.
Yes, I appreciate
it's short notice, ma'am,
but that's partly due
to the fact
that I waited 45 minutes
to talk to you.
I'm back and reporting
for duty.
Yeah, yes, I'll gladly hold
one more time.
Wait, you're back...
like, here?
Max didn't tell you
I was starting today?
No,
which is odd,
because he's usually so great
about communicating
important information.
Did he say
what I was supposed to do?
He said you have instructions
for my royal re...
Why don't I just pop
up to cardio and jump in
where they need me?
Sounds great, thank you.
Is everything good with you?
I'm just trying to book
a last-minute flight to Iran,
but no one's willing to help,
so...
Iran?
It's my brother.
Yes, n...
Yes, I'm here.
No. No, no, no, no, no, no.
A layover isn't going to work
because it's time sensitive.
Sorry, can I speak to
your supervisor, please?
God, she's so big.
- And she uses a fork.
- She's like a real person.
When you see the floor
after she's done,
it won't seem as impressive.
What about peas?
She used to love peas
for lunch.
Dada misses seeing you chomp
on those peas...
Mm.
- Yeah...
- What?
Luna's perhaps not as much of
a pea aficionado these days.
- No, she hates them.
- Truly.
- Really?
- That's new.
Anyway, what she really loves
is sausage.
- Sausage? No.
- Yeah.
- Gwen, show him the thing.
♪ Sausage, sausage,
sausage, sa... ♪
♪ Sausage, sausage, boop!
Boo-do-do ♪
Wow!
There's nothing wrong
with me. I feel fine.
I know you do,
but I'd like to run some tests, okay?
You don't understand.
He was supposed to come home
from camp, and he never did.
Doesn't make any sense.
And then that other kid
just shows up,
claiming to be my son.
Yana, I need you to take
a deep breath and hold it.
And exhale.
Doing great, Yana.
Good job.
So scary.
This random person trying to
convince me he's my son.
Pretending.
You're sure they're related?
Yes, I'm sure.
I checked.
Linus is definitely her son.
There's gotta be
a better explanation.
There is.
So, you won't believe how
fast HCC works
when you threaten
to call the media.
We're getting new
security cameras.
Better. They finally agreed
to cough up some cash
for actual security
around here.
Excuse me.
Is there a Dr. Bloom?
Ta-da.
Yes, officers.
Welcome.
Thinking we would plant
you here, there,
and how 'bout over there?
Private hospitals have had cops
in the ED for years.
About time we got our own.
Problem solved.
Speaking Spanish...
Put me in, coach.
Floyd, hey!
So great to see you.
We just heard you were
coming back.
- Just heard, like...
- Ten minutes ago?
Hm.
Should've seen that coming.
Max isn't great
with communication.
Yeah, so I hear.
Well, sorry to surprise you,
but I am back, I'm here,
I'm ready for action, and, uh,
yeah, just put me wherever
you want.
I'll do
that triple valve replacement.
Oh, Alvarez is already
on that one.
Oh, okay, well.
Can't expect to start
at the top.
What about the aortic valve
replacement in OR 2?
That's you.
It's been crazy around here.
COVID cut
our elective surgeries in half.
Wow, okay.
Um, hell, I'll do anything.
What about the
mediastinal node biopsy?
Okay, I know how
this looks...
Duke, wow.
Well, Duke,
he's still a resident.
- I could supervise.
- Already assigned.
Wow.
Hey, go set up your office,
and I'll page you
if something comes up.
I don't really have
an office.
No, it's on reserve.
They're just waiting
on the visa.
Well, couldn't you...
Y... okay, yes, I understand.
Yeah.
Yes, I'll have my phone on.
Hey.
Just wanted to check in on you
after that phone call
this morning.
It's fine.
I didn't know you spoke
Farsi.
Well, I do.
I don't know what's going on,
but I'm here.
Let me help.
I need an immigration lawyer,
not a trauma surgeon.
Well, I definitely didn't
come here to make things worse.
I've spent this day wrangling
travel agents and visas,
and it's been nothing short
of a bureaucratic nightmare.
I'm barely holding it together.
So I'm sorry, but I really
don't want to talk about it...
With anyone.
Best immigration lawyer
in Manhattan.
"The dear deer dart
and play,
while the crow crows
the night away."
Sorry to interrupt.
Cal, do you think you could
help get her
in the car real quick with me?
Come on, Luna.
We're gonna see Grampy
and Grammy real soon.
I mean, maybe stay
another few minutes.
I think she just needs a nap.
Yeah, I know. I just think
I need to get her home.
Okay.
All righty.
Oof.
All right.
Thank you, Cal.
No go.
No go!
Mama here.
We found small lesions
in your mother's brain.
And they are the reason why
she has been so confused.
Okay.
It's a rare
misidentification disorder
known as Capgras syndrome.
But what does that even mean?
Well, it's like her brain's
facial recognition system
has been rewired.
And the emotional ties
that she should feel
when she looks at you are lost.
She doesn't feel them.
She thinks
you're an imposter.
But... but I'm not.
I mean, I'm me.
She was fine when I went
to camp, and...
I don't understand
what's happening.
If the lesions were
in a different spot,
maybe we could do surgery,
but in your mother's case,
it's not an option.
Well, there's gotta be some
medicine she can take, right?
Yeah, I've already
prescribed it,
but the meds will only stop her
symptoms from getting worse.
Uh...
Linus, there's no easy way
to say this.
Your mother is never going
to recognize you again.
Her condition is permanent.
So she's never
gonna know who I am?
I am so sorry.
But... but she's my mom.
I mean, I don't have
anyone else who...
well, what am I supposed to do?
Where...
Where will I go?
She's my mom.
Okay.
Where are we on the pain scale
now, big guy?
Seven.
That's better.
Zero would be better.
Let's up his morphine
2 milligrams.
These kidney stones
ain't no joke.
Don't worry, it'll pass.
Get it?
"Pass."
Come on.
It's funny because it's true.
What? Nothing?
Wow.
Tough crowd.
Can we talk?
What's going on?
It's the cops.
But they're here for us.
To keep us safe.
You know what I see?
I see the people
who've been stopping me
since I was 12 years old,
making me sit on curbs
and face walls.
I got handcuffed coming home
from work one day in my scrubs.
In my scrubs.
Casey, come on.
You know that I would never...
Ask Weber and ask Mariana,
Lauren.
We all got stories.
Hell, why don't you ask
your little friend
who's always up in here
using our showers?
Yeah.
I noticed.
Ask her if she feels
any safer
with all these cops
hanging around
watching everything she does.
Okay. Right.
So what are we supposed
to do next time
there's another assault, huh?
Brunstetter's still upstairs
getting his eye socket
repaired.
You think he'd want
them gone?
You think cops make
trans people feel safe?
Casey, I'm not blind, okay?
I know that there
are bad cops...
You didn't just try to "not
all cops" me now, did you?
But it's not all cops.
And you know that.
- And we need them here.
- "We"?
Tell me who's "we."
Because the undocumented,
they're gonna stay away.
The homeless,
they're gonna stay away, too.
And what about the next patient
who comes in here
under the influence?
You suddenly want these cops
feeling compelled
to make arrests because, hell,
they're already here?
What could possibly go wrong?
They're not making us feel
any safer, Lauren.
It's just a different kind
of unsafe.
Got a diaphragmatic repair.
40-year-old model rocket
enthusiast
ironically failed to launch.
I'll need an OR.
Oh, and another set of hands.
Right in here,
but we're short staffed.
I'm available.
Who are you?
Floyd Reynolds,
cardiothoracic.
Ever worked
a diaphragm before?
Once or twice.
And we have liftoff.
Diaphragm is exposed.
Oof, rocket did some damage.
Yeah,
one small step for mankind,
one huge abdominal tear
for James Feller.
Biological mesh.
You know, a monofilament
mattress suture
might work better.
Mesh will provide
a tension-free closure.
Yeah, but why not close it
without introducing
a foreign object, you know?
Because the uneven edges
of the monofilament closure
would pucker.
Eh, sutures could be laid
down to minimize it.
- I'm sorry, Doctor...?
- Reynolds.
Dr. Reynolds was chair
of cardiothoracic...
Oh, it's fine, Kat.
Chair or no chair, I asked
for another set of hands,
not a second opinion.
This is my OR,
and surgeries will be done
the way I want them.
Now, you can either
get on board or get out.
On board it is.
Mesh.
No, it's above and beyond.
Truly.
Thank you.
Okay, you too.
Buh-bye.
Okay, so Linus's cousin in Ohio
is going to take him in
permanently.
That's good news, right?
It's better than foster care.
That's true.
Or worse yet,
a runaway shelter.
Oh, man.
So what's wrong?
It's Yana.
I can't stop thinking
about Yana.
I mean, she's still convinced
that her son is out there
somewhere, right?
And she's never gonna stop
looking for him,
and we will never be able to
convince her of the truth.
That's just facts.
It's all just so...
What?
You're looking at me.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I think this is usually
the time
when Vijay says
something profound
and gives me like a...
a good idea.
Well, I don't know
what to say!
Just try something.
Throw it at me.
Try what?
Yana thinks that Linus is
an imposter,
and you'll never be able to
convince her that he isn't.
I just said that.
Just like you'll never be
able to convince me
that I can fill
Dr. Kapoor's shoes.
These are facts!
I can't do this,
and Linus may as well be dead.
So no, I don't know
what to say.
That's...
that's genius.
What is?
Therapeutic fibbing.
That is a great success
in similar syndromes.
Wait, no.
You want to tell her that
her son is dead?
I didn't mean that literally.
Look, all she wants
is a way to move on.
Right?
A way to get on with her life.
Oh, what about Linus?
He lost his mom, and he knows
that she's not dead.
Yeah, he's looking
for a relationship with her.
He's looking for a connection.
That's it, so...
why don't we give him one?
One of you took it!
Hey.
Thanks for getting rid
of those cops.
Yeah, yeah.
Back to covering our own butts.
- Give it back!
- And right on cue.
It's my phone.
I know you took it!
- And I want it back.
- Sir, can you just...?
But sir... sir!
You told us you left your phone
at the bar.
- Not true.
- Everyone stay back.
- Where's my phone?
- No, Casey, I mean it.
If anyone else is getting hurt
today, it's gonna be me.
Think you can just
hold me here?
Sir, sir.
I need you to look at me.
We're gonna get you
sobered up,
and we're gonna get you
out of here.
But right now, I need you
to return to your bed.
I do not need to sober up.
What I need is my damn phone.
No, you need to return
to your bed.
Can you do that for me?
I'm not getting back
in that stupid bed.
And you can't make me.
This is my ED.
I make the rules.
Now put your damn mask on,
and get back in your bed!
I bet this whole "I'm a tank"
thing you got going on
comes in pretty handy when you
mess up someone's drink.
Actually, I was a bouncer.
Not sure how I missed that.
Thank you for the lawyer.
Did she help?
It was too late.
My brother died.
Half-brother.
We weren't close,
but...
I mean, I wanted to be,
I just...
I just thought
that I had time.
According to Islam,
he needed to be buried
before the next sundown.
But I ran out of time.
I keep...
I keep running out of time.
And I... I nearly got there,
but then my visa...
What does it matter?
I don't want to make excuses
anymore.
About him...
about you.
What was your brother's name?
Farhad.
Sorry.
We haven't visited since...
Since the funeral.
She just thinks
we're at the park.
She doesn't realize...
"Mama here."
I want to do the right thing,
but I...
I don't know what that is.
I love her so much.
I just don't know...
if I'm enough...
without you.
I don't know if
I'm ever gonna be enough.
Hi.
Just came by to check in.
I know this has been a lot,
with the diagnosis
and your son.
I can't believe he's gone.
And the strangest thing is,
a part of me feels...
relieved
to finally know the truth.
Is that awful of me?
No.
When I thought
he was still out there,
all alone, lost,
needing me,
and I couldn't find him, it...
it was excruciating.
Now...
Now you can grieve.
I get it.
Yeah.
So, listen,
I know that this might not
be the best time, but...
there's actually
someone here
that is going through
the exact same thing,
if you wanted to talk to him.
Now?
Yeah.
I think that it would be great
for you to talk to someone
who knows what this feels like.
You know?
But only if you want to.
It's up to you.
Yeah?
Okay.
- You!
- She doesn't want to see me.
No, no, no.
Yana, hang on, listen.
Just hear him out, okay?
He broke into my house!
I know, I know, and that
must have been really scary.
But I'm asking you if you would
please let him explain.
That's all.
Thank you.
Good, okay.
Okay.
I, uh...
I did break in.
And I'm real sorry about that.
Tell her why.
I, uh...
I...
I just lost my mom.
And, uh...
it was sudden.
And ...didn't know
what to do,
where to go, but...
your place...
Your place, it felt safe.
Felt familiar.
Like home.
I'm sorry about your mom.
I know how hard that must be.
I just really miss her.
What was she like?
I know.
Go on.
Tell her.
She was...
one of a kind.
She was funny
and smart and honest.
I lost my son, you know.
You on the list?
Am I what?
It's cool.
He's with me.
I'm with her.
I just came by to check
on Brunstetter.
No ocular damage,
and the bone is stabilized.
- He's gonna be okay.
- Good, great.
And what can you tell me
about them?
- We defunded the police.
- What?
While I was in Connecticut?
All these bouncers,
who know a thing or two
about de-escalation,
were out of work
thanks to COVID.
Now they have a job
that comes with healthcare.
Is this gentleman
bothering you?
I was just leaving.
Seriously?
I heard about your day.
And I came to apologize.
Epic fail on my part,
but then I pictured Cassian
not even knowing who you were.
Sorry, sorry.
Thanks.
It's kind of funny.
Right?
Sorry.
What did...
This is, like,
- the worst apology ever.
- I know.
Sorry, again.
I just, um...
I had kind of a day myself.
I got nothing left in the tank.
You got nothing left.
I'm living out of my suitcase,
with my mom,
my marriage was over
before it ever began,
and the one place
that I ever felt right
doesn't have a place for me.
I know lots of places that
would happily give you
their cardio department.
I don't care
about other places, man.
I care about here.
Look, you wanna stick me in the
classroom, teaching interns,
I'm there.
You want me to assist
in general surgeries,
I'll take it.
That's a huge step down
for you.
Huge step down from what?
I'm already there.
What I need is a hand
getting back up.
In Korea, women in mourning
wear white bows in their hair.
This is the best I could do
in K-town.
May I?
Yeah.
We had the same father.
♪ Don't let your mind
get weary ♪
He was younger than me.
I didn't even know that he
existed till six years ago.
I only met him once.
But once was all it took.
♪ Don't let your heart get
heavy ♪
I knew he was my brother.
Without a doubt.
Is this what your family does
when someone dies?
Martha and Tim Shinnler?
No, they wouldn't know
a Korean mourning custom
- from a hole in the ground.
- Wait, Shinnler?
I was adopted.
When I was three.
I shortened my name right
after college.
As far as the hairclip,
I learned about that
in my Korean lit class.
Huh.
So your family's...
German Irish.
I actually had to teach myself
to be Korean.
Still really don't know how.
♪ In you,
that's where you'll find ♪
So what else did you learn in
these college classes of yours?
Leyla, we should talk.
I knew using your showers
was too good to last.
Well, get it over with.
Grab your stuff.
It's not safe out here.
This is my secret spot.
Why do this for me?
I protect my people.
Here we go, you ready?
- Yeah.
- Here it is.
This is home.
You remember this place?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
There's a couch over there,
right?
This is our kitchen.
Remember the kitchen?
- Yeah.
This is where you're gonna
throw lots of food at Dada
until he figures out
what you want,
which I guess is not peas
anymore.
And this is our sleepy room.
This is my bed.
And this,
this bed is for you.
You like it?
Yeah.
And this place...
this is just for you.
I know it's not much,
but, uh...
Dada here.
Yeah.
Yeah, Dada here.
Dada's always here.
- Yeah.