We need four units of O-neg.
Bring that bench over here.
They went to cut off the door,
and all I could think was,
"He's gonna bleed out.
"We need more time."
I was pissed,
but then I thought,
"No, we need less
distance to the OR," so...
So, you brought...
The whole damn car.
Is he still alive?
How is he?
He's hanging on, barely.
I remember in school
someone telling me
I came from a broken home.
That's what they used to call it
when your parents got divorced.
This isn't the way
we usually do this.
I had to do it this way.
No, no, no, we
see why you did it.
Okay. Look, I just
wanted to give him...
A second chance. We
got a second chance.
Even though getting divorced
was the least broken
thing they ever did.
Hey, Keith, it's Meredith.
Thanks for having me over.
How's Joan?
What's the word on my baby?
We'll find out for
you. We got you.
When I heard that as a kid,
I wondered if broken homes
were where the broken people lived.
Still feeling those toes, Joan?
Yeah. Good.
Um, you guys, let's just stop.
Let's stop for a sec.
What's happening?
There's just a little bleeding,
which is normal
after a delivery,
but we're gonna
get you checked out
before you have your
spinal surgery, okay?
It was silly. I mean,
I was just a little kid.
We have to take her. No,
no, what are you doing?
What are you doing with my baby?
Just for now, while you...
No, please! We
were crushed in a car!
My fiance's dead!
You're not taking my baby!
Please, no!
Joan, your baby's
doing fine, okay?
Please! We just
need to check you out.
Okay, you need to take him
to the NICU and page Karev.
But to this day, I still wonder.
No!
It looks like uterine atony.
We need to move fast.
We move fast, we paralyze her.
We move too slow
and she bleeds to death.
Okay.
Yeah, I already spoke to Mom.
Amelia.
I don't know how fast
you're moving on the house.
I haven't even accepted
an offer yet, so...
I can have my stuff out next
week. Is that soon enough?
Ted, I don't care
whose side of the story.
I'm not sure I can make it
any sooner. You don't have to.
I should've been
out a while ago.
Derek is the one who invited
me, and he's gone, so...
I...
Yes, I am listening.
Dad...
I have to go.
Is Alex in the NICU?
Don't know and don't
care, 'cause apparently,
he thinks I'm some
sort of '50s housewife
who he can tell where
to be and what to do
and when to bake a pot roast.
I'm holding a baby.
Who's this? Come on, here.
There's been a lot of talking, but
not a lot of getting me out of the car.
That's still the plan, right,
get Keith out of the car?
That's the plan.
When Joanie called and
told me she was pregnant,
you know what my
first thought was?
Run like hell.
We'd only had the one date.
And she agrees,
it kind of sucked.
I think we had sex just to
stop the awkward silence.
And then boom...
Insta-family, like Sea-Monkeys.
It was scary.
Now I can't believe
I ever felt like that.
Now all I want
to do is see them.
Grey, we're ready
to cut the roof.
Okay, Keith,
it's gonna get real loud
and then it's gonna get scary,
and then we're gonna
get you out, okay?
Loud, scary, free.
Got it.
Okay.
All right, let's get in there.
- Let's do this!
Okay.
Arizona's having trouble controlling
the post-partum hemorrhage.
This just keeps getting...
Edwards.
What are you doing?
I'm scrubbing in.
No, you're not.
I gave you one job,
to keep her in the collar
until trauma cleared her.
It was the interns who...
And you left her in the
care of first-day interns.
They should've known better.
No, you should've known
better. You can go now.
You are no longer going
anywhere near this patient, got it?
Go.
Roof coming off!
Okay, guys, you're clear.
We need a trauma panel
and type and cross for eight.
Got it. Drawing labs.
No blood in the pericardium.
Penetrating
thoraco-abdominal injury.
Ultrasound, please.
Keith, talk to me.
How do you feel?
Popular.
Funny. That's funny.
Okay, guys, when you clear,
we're gonna cut away the piece
of the door here that's impaling him,
then you can get
him inside, okay?
All right.
Dr. Grey.
I have an update on his fiancee.
April certainly thought
outside the box.
I like this Kepner.
I never thought I
would like Kepner.
You know, old Kepner was...
There was pigtails and
bunny rabbits and smiling.
Lots of smiling,
but Kepner the reboot,
Kepner 2.0, she's crazy!
She's fierce.
She's woman-ed up.
Thank you, United States Army.
Bailey, Hunt has this.
I need you to handle
everything else in the ER.
You are in charge.
Get used to it.
Yes, sir!
I thought I made
myself perfectly clear.
You can't just
appoint a new chief.
There are rules and
recommendations that are being made,
and then the board votes.
Just because something's
been done one way forever
doesn't mean it
shouldn't change.
- It's called evolution.
- No.
What you're talking
about is called dictatorship,
and I did not sign up for a
dictatorship, Catherine Avery.
No one asked you
to, Richard Webber.
That's the problem, you
never ask, you only tell.
Well, let me tell you
how this is gonna...
Look, I don't want to listen
to another word about it!
Let's get back to it!
Excuse me.
I can't. I'm...
Hey, Keith. Stay with me.
I have some news for you.
Joan's okay.
She's headed into surgery,
and you have a baby boy.
A boy?
I have a son.
Okay, Joan, I'm gonna
put you out now, okay?
Uterus is flaccid.
She's hemorrhaging.
Okay, we got to put her under.
You got to get this under
control now. I know that.
I need a balloon catheter.
Is she out? CALLIE:
Not yet, why?
Joan, Keith is here.
He's here. He's alive.
Keith's here?
They're working on him now.
Wilson, go.
Pressure's at 70.
We're losing her.
Tension on the steering wheel.
Yeah, we got it.
Keith, hang in
there. Hang in there.
All right. All cut.
Okay, stop!
Hey, stop! Stop!
Stop! Okay, hold up.
What is it, Grey?
We can't do this. Not like this.
It's gonna tear him apart.
All right, hang on, guys.
We're gonna open
him up out here?
It's the only way.
We start an ex-lap.
Clamp everything we can.
It'll buy us time till
we get him upstairs.
We only have five or six
minutes till he bleeds out.
That's plenty of time.
Guys, guys, all ORs are full.
All of them? Tunnel
collapse victims.
No, no, we have a
plastics OR available.
That's all the way at the
other end of the building.
That's impossible.
Nothing's impossible.
We just...
All right, we clear a
path to the east elevator.
Move everything out of the way,
stop all foot traffic,
lock down the elevator.
Can he make it that far?
No, but he will.
He doesn't have a choice, right?
So, we run.
All out like Olympians.
It's plenty of time.
Let's prep him for
an ex-lap out here.
Okay. Okay.
I am not crying wolf.
Sir?
I do not make decisions lightly,
and I don't bow to dictators.
Miranda Bailey,
you will be Grey Sloan
Memorial's next Chief of Surgery!
Congratulations!
Thank you.
Catheter is working, and
the bleeding has stopped.
No tear in the dura, amazingly.
So, an intern opened her collar?
Oh, stupid.
Wait, was that the intern that
we thought was an attending?
You mistook an
intern for an attending?
Yeah, he was pretty
much running the trauma.
Like a boss. Like
a hot, hot boss.
Somebody should get into that.
Maybe you should get into that.
You know what? You
should get into that.
I don't think so.
I have started a strict
no-workplace dating policy.
I hear you.
It's all too... You know?
They see you, all of you.
Then they come to work
and they see you here, too,
and you try to
keep it professional
and get things done, but
suddenly you're thinking,
"I was naked on you before."
Or "I wish you were naked now."
"Hey, remember when you
were there at my very rock bottom
"and I went down the rabbit
hole and dragged you in with me
"and bared the darkest parts of
my soul to you in the midnight hours?
"So, now let's have
a budget meeting."
It's a solid policy.
Trust me.
I can't find the 8 ET tubes.
Yeah, but I need more.
Webber is making
me Chief of Surgery.
That's great, but I got to
get these... Wait, what?
Chief?
Wait, Chief of Surgery?
Ooh, say it again.
Hey, how you doing, man?
This is my wife,
Dr. Miranda Bailey,
Chief of Surgery.
No, chief of all these
damn surgeries.
Oh, I got to get these in.
Oh, yeah, go, go, go.
Who is the chief?
I am the chief.
Warren, you'll intubate.
Kepner, you and I
will do the ex-lap.
Get control of
whatever's bleeding.
Grey, I'll need you and Pierce
scrubbed and ready in the OR
when we get there, we got it?
Okay.
Meredith, do me a favor.
Tell Joanie that I
loved her and that I...
No. No, no, no.
No messages from
beyond the grave, Keith.
We're not doing that.
It's okay.
You guys have been great.
You went way above and beyond.
Keith, yes, a lot of people here
are working very
hard to pull this off,
and you have to work, too, okay?
I've seen the looks on
these people's faces.
This is not gonna work.
Hunt, I'm gonna need a minute.
Okay.
I'm serious. One minute,
that's all I'm allowing.
It's too soon. Fine, fine.
You talk to Wilson yet about
me and the kids moving in?
No. I was a jackass, and now
she's not even talking to me.
I can't even...
Is she moving out?
Is there room for Amelia?
Because you could take your old
room, I could take my old room back,
and then Amelia could
move into Cristina's room.
God, Mer, what the hell?
I know, I know,
but I hurt her feelings,
and she's mad at me.
I forgot I'm supposed
to be her sister.
You're a complete
tool sometimes.
I've heard.
All right, everybody
stop what you're doing.
Quiet, please. Make
a hole. Make a hole.
Let them through, guys.
Oh, there he is.
That's his baby.
Is he still conscious?
Okay, sweetheart.
I have something for you.
Oh, boy.
Hey, big man.
Look at you.
I'm sorry for all this crap.
Sorry, I just wish I...
I'm gonna see you when
I get out of here, okay?
You and your mom, yeah?
I'm gonna be there and
we're gonna be together, okay?
I love you. Daddy loves you.
Kiss.
Okay, okay.
All right, let's bag him.
Push 200 of ketamine.
Don't go.
No.
I'm right here.
That was a bad idea,
bringing him out here like that.
Why?
Because I'm gonna
be really pissed
if you don't pull this off.
Me too.
That was a really nice idea.
Well, it wasn't mine,
but I'll take credit.
Look, I was being a jerk.
Shut up.
I know. We were both jerks.
Can we just move on?
Please.
Good.
So, I have to ask
you something. Okay.
Meredith asked me
if she could move in.
She's selling her house
and she wants to move in.
What do you think?
With the kids?
No, she's selling the
kids with the house.
Yes, with the kids.
And I get a vote on this?
I didn't think that we did that.
I thought we were at this place
where you just told me
what was gonna happen.
I'm asking you.
Yeah, and I can't say
no to the sad widow
with the three kids
tapping on the window?
You said you were
putting down roots here.
Congrats.
Now you got a
house and a family.
So, I guess the wedding is off.
Yeah, what happened?
Did Richard talk to you?
No.
Was a complete surprise.
Complete surprise.
Are you okay? I'm fine.
I'm fine.
Ready to go, Cap!
Keep an eye on that generator.
Feels familiar, huh?
Feels great,
actually. You miss it?
Being in the field?
It's the only thing
I ever think about.
Sats and BP are
stable. Good to go.
Here we go.
Okay.
All right, laps.
More laps. Scissors.
Kelly. Kelly.
Looks like it's going
straight into his renal vessels.
Clamp.
I can't reach. Can you get it?
I got it. I got it. Crap! Crap!
No, I see it. I see
it. Okay, all right.
Damn it. Laps.
Okay. Gonna need
a whole lot more laps!
Doctors Hunt and Kepner
start Keith's surgery
outside in the car.
Doctors Grey and Pierce
are standing by in the OR
waiting to finish that surgery.
You need to help get
Keith from the car to the OR.
We estimate we have less than
three minutes to get him from car to OR.
Any more than that, he dies.
You make a mistake, he dies.
This has to be perfect.
We have one chance.
There are no do-overs.
His life and death depends on
how you handle the next few minutes.
Do not mess this up.
Come on, come on, come on.
His chest wall is hashed.
Now, can you get
that last clamp?
I got it. I got it. I got it.
You, keep these doors open.
You stay on this corner here.
All right, what's
your name? DeLuca.
All right, DeLuca, right here.
You got it.
That's it. Let's go.
Warren, watch the clamps when
they pull the piece out of him.
Kepner, be ready to
pack. Are we ready?
Ready. I'm good.
If this guy's not on the
table in five minutes,
this was all for nothing.
I'm starting the clock.
Let's all be careful, okay?
And go.
All right. What is
your name? Shaw.
Shaw, this elevator
does not move
until our patient
is inside. Got it?
I don't know, I can't see.
Me neither.
All right.
All right, give me a
hand with the doors.
I got it.
There you go.
Easy, easy.
All right, give them room.
Let's go.
Incoming!
Out of here! Clear the hall! Go!
No! No! No!
Sorry. Sorry. Move, move.
Move!
Hey!
Get out! Get out! Get out!
Incoming! Move!
Uh, just wait. Wait.
Wait, wait.
Come on! Come on!
Come on! Come on! Come on!
Move!
Who's on the elevator?
Why is it closed? Get it open!
Move!
Out! Out! Out! Out!
What happened?
He coded in the elevator!
Come on.
Ready? One, two, three.
All right. Let's get him back.
Hang some more blood. Paddles.
Push an amp of bicarb. Clear.
We have sinus.
Okay, we got this?
Yeah, we got it. Go.
Okay. Gonna have
to open up his chest.
Get me a thoracotomy
tray and scalpel.
Oh, got a pumper here, Jackson.
Right angle, bulky.
Come on, Keith. Come on.
Dr. Taylor to the ER.
Here you go, Doctor.
He's still alive? For now.
And the girlfriend?
Out of surgery.
Awake. Not paralyzed.
Excellent work.
Meredith told you
she's selling the house?
What, her house? Yeah.
It was news to me, too.
Where are you gonna go?
I'll find something.
Maybe she'll let
you keep the trailer.
Well, maybe I should
just get a house
that doesn't get
parking tickets.
Come on.
You won't miss being able to
reach your toaster from your toilet?
I might.
I really want this to work.
Yeah?
This family.
All three of them.
Right. Right.
What did you think I
meant? Oh, nothing, no.
That. Yeah.
Me too.
Jo!
Jo, come here.
The sad widow is my
friend, my best friend.
And I don't want to piss you off
and I don't want you
running off somewhere,
but I can't say no to her.
So, you're saying
no to me. Okay.
No.
Look, all that crap I said
about building a life here
and about putting down
roots... Look, I meant with you.
I want a house with
you, my career with you.
Maybe someday a dog, maybe.
It's all supposed
to be with you.
I thought you got that.
I didn't think I
needed to say it.
So, when I say that I
can't say no to my friend,
it doesn't mean
I'm saying no to you.
I want you and
all of it with you.
Okay.
Where are you going?
I just...
I have to think
about what I want.
Vitals are steady.
We may actually pull this out.
This will make a hell
of a wedding story.
Hey, what is going on
with your mom and Richard?
Ah, same old crap.
Clash of the Titans.
What?
They both want to be boss.
Both want to dig in,
And my mom is the
smartest person in the room.
She's used to it.
She's used to
everybody knowing that
she's the smartest
person in the room.
So, when you challenge
her, it's World War III.
And Richard is the same.
Well, that is just
ridiculous and pathetic.
I mean, you don't just shrug
your shoulders and call it quits.
You find a way to work
through it. You don't just
give up and throw it all
away like it was nothing.
Oh. Oh...
I'm sorry.
It's something else. She
doesn't want to talk about it.
Don't look at me. Ignore me.
Welcome to the family.
Thank you, Doctor.
I have something for you.
It's my old cellphone.
There's one voicemail on it.
Password is 1515.
And make sure you're
alone when you listen to it.
Who does the
post-anesthesia checks?
Shut up.
Isn't rounds when we're
supposed to ask questions?
I thought you weren't
allowed to go near that patient.
Did I not just say shut up?
Hi, Joan.
It's Dr. Edwards.
Give my hands a squeeze?
They fixed me up.
Can you squeeze a little
harder for me on your right?
I am, as hard as I can.
I can't really breathe.
Her sats are
dropping pretty fast.
What's happening?
Shaw, bag her.
Get a crash cart and an
intubation tray in here now.
Don't take that off. I did
that. You don't want to...
She's hemorrhaging. Blood's
compressing her trachea.
Gloves! Gloves!
She's losing her airway.
Scalpel.
Page Shepherd and Torres.
Betadine.
Scalpel, now.
Sats back up to 93, 95.
What happened?
Looks like a leaking
carotid pseudoaneurysm.
What about her right side?
Will she get her
motor function back?
I'm more worried about
brain death at this point.
She can easily throw a clot and
have a massive
hemispheric stroke.
Well, it's a good
thing that you caught it.
No, Edwards. Edwards did.
Dr. Edwards, is there any chance
the leak could cause
permanent... Will you hush?
Just sit back there
and stay silent.
Edwards! What?
These are your ducklings.
I'm sorry, what?
Today is the first
day of your new job,
and you have failed gloriously.
You are a teacher. Now,
these interns are yours.
They're your ducklings,
and you're letting them drown!
Well, I want them to drown.
I want to watch it.
Well, you can't.
You have to teach them
how to paddle their stupid feet
and stay above the water.
They're going to screw up.
And it will never
be their fault.
It will always be your fault.
But how you teach
them will determine
how they treat patients
for years to come.
They're your web-footed legacy,
and they're brilliant students.
Hand-selected for this program
by doctors wiser than you,
and they're your responsibility.
Raise your ducklings.
Dr. Toretto to radiology.
What is the matter with you two?
My husband is dead.
Yeah, I'm gonna play that card.
You.
You walked away from
Ellis, never got to be with her,
and now she's dead.
Adele is dead.
And you. I don't know
who's dead for you.
But the both of you are
very, very much alive
and breathing and
driving each other crazy.
And you yell and
argue and fight,
and you both should be thrilled
to be able to do those things.
I would give anything to
be able to do those things.
And none of those
things are reason enough
to not be with the
person that you love,
especially when
there just isn't enough.
There will never be enough time.
And you both know that.
So whatever it is that's
coming between you two,
will you just
please figure it out?
Figure it out.
It's amazing
anyone survived this.
You should be proud of yourself.
It was a little ballsy, huh?
It was, actually,
and you loved it.
And I don't know
why you're upset.
Because I need to say something,
and I don't know how to say it.
I don't even want to say it.
You want to go back.
There's another plane going to
Jordan in a couple weeks, and you...
And you want to be on it.
The way I felt today,
every day is like it out there.
I thought it was
just readjustment,
and then I thought it was, like,
an adrenaline addiction or
something, but it feels like...
I don't know, I...
I feel like I've been
called, Jackson.
Well, maybe you should go back.
Really?
When we lost Samuel,
a light went out in
you, and I miss it.
I miss it so much.
And whatever it was over there,
you know, whatever
it is, it got relit.
Thank you.
Wait. Wait.
April, I love you so much.
But I don't think I can be
here when you come back.
You understand?
What?
What? Why?
No.
It's only gonna be
a couple of months.
It's not gonna be a year. No.
I promise I'll... No.
You don't know what I've
been through this last year.
This last year,
what it was like...
I... I know.
I... It was... It
was hard. I know.
What do you mean you
know? You don't know.
You never asked.
Not once, in fact.
How was I doing?
How was I coping?
You didn't even ask.
I'm sorry.
God, I'm sorry.
But we talked. You know...
And... Yeah, you know what?
You got to have your
life-altering journey, okay?
And I stayed behind.
And I held stuff down.
And I silenced myself
so that you could grieve.
If you need to grieve, we can...
I did! I did need to grieve.
I needed to. Needed to with you.
That's what marriage
is to me, April.
So...
Okay, so you're
saying that if I go...
If I go again, then we're done?
You're just calling it?
Squeeze my fingers.
Good. Very good.
My baby... Is my baby okay?
He's doing just fine.
And Keith? Is he...
I'm right here.
You're here?
I'm here.
I'm looking right at you.
I saw our baby.
He's beautiful.
He's so beautiful.
He looks exactly like me.
Don't make me laugh.
It hurts.
Okay, but research budgets are
approved by one department head,
not a committee.
Agreed. Next point.
I have a say in all the
residency candidates.
Rejected. Never gonna happen.
I gave you Valentine's Day!
If I have to celebrate
Valentine's Day,
I get to review the
prospective residents.
And give a recommendation.
Nothing more.
I have final say.
That's fair.
Next point.
Miranda Bailey is the
next Chief of Surgery.
Miranda Bailey
is judged against an outside
candidate of my choosing.
Then the board
votes based on merit.
That's...
That's fair.
Agreed. Next point.
Now, when we're at home...
We are not at work.
We leave work at the hospital.
Rejected. Totally unrealistic.
Richard, our schedules. Come on!
Hey, I understand, but we
need some time for each...
The bedroom.
No work in the bedroom.
Next point.
I will provide a safe harbor.
What does that mean?
You need a place to
not be Catherine Avery.
To not be decisive
and set agendas
and rise to the level
of accomplishments
that the world has
come to expect of you.
You need a place to fall apart.
I will be that place.
Should you require it.
In perpetuity.
Richard, do you take
Catherine to be your wife
for as long as
you both shall live?
I do. And Catherine?
I do. I do, forever.
Then by the power vested in
me by the state of Washington,
I now pronounce
you husband and wife.
Hello.
Hi.
Hey, bottoms up,
Plastics Posse...
Let's just enjoy the party, huh?
Where's Kepner?
I don't know.
Hey. Where have you been?
Come with me. I want
to show you something.
Oh, congratulations, Chief!
Thank you, thank you.
And speaking of chief, um...
I had a talk with Catherine,
and there is going to be, um...
I don't know how
to say this, but...
You have got to be kidding me.
You're running just
against one other candidate,
but you're gonna have it.
Sir, I understand,
but it's just not fair.
Well, actually, it's
the only fair way...
No, no, no. To this
other candidate,
because I am going to
wipe the floor with her, or him.
It's gonna hurt.
Getting trounced hurts,
and it'll be embarrassing,
publicly and professionally,
losing by that wide a margin,
because I am
primed for this job, sir.
I deserve this job.
There isn't a single person
in this room who would...
Disagree.
Disagree that I am
not so ready for this job.
It's already mine.
Damn right it is.
Mmm-hmm.
Pardon me, dear, but Dr. Webber
has a couple of moves
I haven't seen yet.
I love you.
Why are we here?
It's a loft space.
Jo, it's a crime scene.
Stop! Stop it.
You're ruining it.
Someone beat me
to that. Oh, shut up!
It's all I can afford.
I took everything,
all my savings,
everything that I had,
and it was almost enough
to cover the whole thing.
Wait. You're buying this?
Well, um...
We are, if you want to pitch in.
I put in an offer.
Sell Meredith her house back.
Because this is what I want.
Our own place, for us.
And... And I just...
I saw this place,
and I thought that we
could make it anything.
Whatever we want.
Because I love you,
and I love living with you.
But we should just...
We should have our own place.
Just us.
If you want that.
If that's... If that's
what you want, too.
You've never said that.
Said what?
"I love you."
I didn't think that I had to.
Patient presented in
labor with a fracture at c5-6.
Radioulnar fracture
was reduced in the field.
Post-op, she bled from a
carotid pseudoaneurysm,
which was repaired with
an arteriotomy and a patch.
Patient now shows
no neuro deficits
and is expected to
make a full recovery.
Questions.
Would the chance for
recovery have been different...
Are high-dose steroids still
indicated for immediate treatment?
I know.
I know. I do.
Sorry. I was just...
You all right?
I was just about to
listen to a message.
But I can't
seem to bring
myself to hit play.
Hey, it's me.
I'm on the ferry.
I just wanted to say that, um...
God, I wish you could see this.
Weather's classic Seattle.
The water is so blue.
It may be the most perfect
ferryboat ride I've ever had in my life.
We're gonna do this a
lot more when I get home,
by the way. You,
me, and the family.
We're just gonna take a day
and ride the ferryboat.
All day if we want.
I love you, Meredith.
I know I just left, and I'm
not even at the airport yet,
but I just wanted
to say I love you.
I love our family.
And we're gonna keep doing this.
I'll see you when I get home.
I love you.
You okay?
Yeah.
I am.
What is wrong?
And don't say you're
fine. Nothing. I'm fine.
What... Did somebody die?
Oh.
My parents are
getting a divorce.
My mom called and told me today.
She's been having an affair
with the man that
services their cars.
For 11 years.
He's been servicing
their cars and my mom.
And my dad found out about it
years ago, and he was enraged,
and he stuck with it
for me, because I was...
I was still in town. I
was always around.
You know, so they held
it together for the kid.
Classic.
Except the kid's a grown woman.
They wanted to preserve my
happy, idyllic,
pathetic, crap-filled
lie of a childhood!
Why didn't you tell me?
I...
Your husband died,
and I am crying like a seven-year-old
over Mommy and Daddy.
I...
I didn't grow up like you. I...
I've never lost anyone.
I never even had a cat die. I
still have all my grandparents.
There's no darkness in my life.
Just, I've never had it.
So I'm not gonna
come talk to you about it.
Well, you should
always come talk to me.
Because whatever it is,
chances are, I've seen worse,
and I am qualified to
tell you how you'll survive.
You should always
come and talk to me.
What are you crying about?
Derek would have loved this.
He came from this
big, noisy family.
I want this to be my last
memory of this house.
That's what he wanted, to
fill it with noise and people.
You can build a
house out of anything,
make it as strong as you want.
Okay. We have to dance it out.
What?
What does that mean?
Let's go.
But a home...
A home is more
fragile than that.
A home is made of
the people you fill it with.
And people can be broken, sure.
But any surgeon knows
what's broken can be mended.
What's hurt can be healed.
That no matter how dark it gets,
the sun's gonna rise again.