He's put me on
a renal diet. If that doesn't
turn things around, then...
Dialysis? I'm so sorry.
I don't advertise
my immigration status,
but I'm undocumented.
My future always
feels precarious.
More money in our checks!
We are essential!
You're striking?
It's very important
that Liliana feels like
I have her back.
I'm going
with my friends to
celebrate. Come.
You have to come.
You're my boyfriend.
Oh, no...
Lil.
Daniel.
Oh, the time.
I didn't realize.
I... I'm almost finished.
I'm usually done
before you arrive.
I'm sorry.
Oh, no. No,
let me get that.
I'm the one
who should be apologizing.
No. No, I had
the interns in
for pizza last night.
Then they dragged me out
for a drink,
and we just left.
It's okay.
I've got it.
I apologize for the mess.
Really, I do.
It's okay.
Compared to other offices,
it's not that bad.
Oops.
Daniel,
have a good day.
You too.
Ah.
I think this
belongs to you.
Indeed, it does.
Where did you find it?
This time?
Waiting room.
Top of the
vending machine.
Hmm. You know,
maybe I should
just, uh, put it
in a little red-and-white
striped shirt,
put a bobble hat on it,
black glasses,
and call it my
"Where's Waldo?"
water bottle, huh?
You get it?
I get it.
You have to stay hydrated.
Thanks, Mom.
Dr. Cuevas.
Ms. Goodwin,
good morning.
Good morning.
Do you have a moment
to discuss your
DACA renewal?
Oh. Um, now?
Well, the paperwork's
not due for a few months,
but I want to make sure
we get everything
filed early,
just in case there's
an unexpected policy change.
Right, of course.
I appreciate that.
I just was about
to dig into these
overnight charts.
Understood.
How about we meet up
at the end of the day?
Yeah. Sure, that works.
I will...
I'll see you then.
Dr. Asher. Need you.
Oh, yeah.
Come this way.
Hi, I'm Dr. Asher.
Leah, what's going on?
Parents and
their daughter.
Came in a few minutes ago.
They're terrified.
Even scared me.
Going to two.
I didn't get a history.
Just came for you.
Excuse me, Doctor.
We need your help.
Our daughter.
All right.
Hi, I'm Dr. Halstead.
What's your name?
Um...
Maria. Her name
is Maria. Very sick!
I'm sorry.
I don't speak Spanish.
Get Dr. Cuevas.
I'm just gonna
feel your neck, okay?
Does that hurt?
¿Malo? Bad?
What are they saying?
They're saying that
she has the sickness,
and if we don't help her,
she will die.
Thank you.
Hey. How's Maria doing?
Uh, still a bit groggy,
but responding
to questions in English.
Whatever this is,
it seems to be sporadic.
Any guesses?
I don't know.
Maybe infectious encephalitis,
but her vitals were normal.
I'm hoping labs
shed some light.
What did Mom and Dad
have to say?
The sickness that they're
referring to has to do
with her older brother, Hugo.
About a month ago,
he came down
with an illness,
was admitted to Oakview
Community Hospital,
and then died
a few days later.
Oh, man.
Yeah, and even worse,
Oakview couldn't make
a diagnosis.
Well, explains why they're
beating down our doors.
They're afraid
whatever ravaged Hugo
is now attacking Maria.
But a death
in the family,
no answers,
plus the fear
that she might have
the same illness?
Since nothing's
jumping out,
I think it's possible
that her emotions could be
manifesting physically.
I want to talk to her,
see if there could be
a psych explanation.
Okay. Meantime,
I'll reach out to Oakview,
get Hugo's records
and autopsy results.
If Maria does have
the same illness, there
could be a clue in there.
Okay, Layla, you're
7 centimeters dilated,
100% effaced.
How long ago
did your water break?
About an hour,
hour and a...
7:02 a.m., I think.
This baby
is coming out sideways.
No, it just
feels like that.
Your fetus is OP,
meaning it's facing up
instead of down.
Something's wrong?
No.
Baby's just moving around,
letting us know that
it is time to come out.
I'll have a nurse
let L&D know.
Oh, my God. Quentin,
our son is coming.
I'm gonna be a mom today.
You know, I can't remember
if I turned off the oven
before we left the house.
Quentin, we haven't
cooked in days.
The oven is off.
I'm just gonna go home
and check.
Quentin, no!
Mr. Bell,
please don't go.
You know what?
Maybe you can have
a neighbor check on it,
or maybe it's just
nervous energy
that's making you think
that you left it on.
Yeah, I just don't
feel like myself.
I get it.
It's a big day.
You know, a lot
of new experiences
all happening at once.
But, Quentin,
this is not new for me.
I have been here
many, many times,
and I know exactly
how to help you and Layla
get through this.
Thank you.
Sorry, Lay. I just lost
my mind for a minute.
Nice save.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, Sam. This
is Dr. Tanaka-Reed.
He's gonna be
scrubbing in
with me today.
He's one of
my surgical residents.
Uh, technically
I'm a resident but
definitely not a beginner.
Okay.
Anyway, like
we discussed,
it's a straight
appendix removal.
You're gonna be
a bit sore afterwards,
but in a week or two,
you'll be back
to full strength.
Mm. Perfect, because
I've been itching to
get back in the gym.
Rugged Maniac is this summer.
Rugged Maniac?
The adventure race?
You know it?
Yeah, sort of.
A couple of guys
from the community
are putting a team together.
Community? You mean
other doctors?
No, uh, CrossFit.
From my Kalsu group.
Kalsu's a workout.
We do burpees
and thrusters
for time.
Anyway, back to the task
at hand. If you're ready,
we're ready.
Let's do this.
Great.
Nurse Trisha will be in
to get the prep started.
Anesthesia after that.
Sounds good, Doc.
See you on
the other side,
all right?
Appendix removal,
pretty basic.
Well, sorry Sam's
not sick enough
for you.
Oh, you know
what I mean.
OR 2.0 is a Ferrari...
sexy surgery. But a lap appy?
Well, not even
in that today.
Sam had a sigmoid
colon resection
18 months ago.
Likely adhesions
in his pelvis,
so we're gonna
do this appy open,
right lower
quadrant incision.
Okay?
Old school.
Gee, hope I'm
up to the challenge.
For a resident,
guy sure is
full of himself.
I'm not a fan.
Hugo's gone.
I'm oldest now.
I need to be strong.
For my other brothers
and sisters.
For my parents.
They've been a wreck
since Hugo died.
They can't sleep.
They can't eat.
Now I'm putting them
through it again.
I have it too.
No.
Hey, we don't know that.
All of the labs
Dr. Halstead ran
came back normal.
Then what's wrong with me?
In some cases,
it's possible
for grief and fear to lead
to physical symptoms.
No, I'm not imagining this.
No, you're not.
Your symptoms
are very real.
You suffered
a devastating loss,
a trauma.
Hugo's tests
were normal too.
And then he died.
I don't think we're looking
at a psych condition.
In conversion disorder,
it's rare
that patients can
express their emotions
the way Maria is.
But her awareness
of the situation,
her acknowledgment
of the fear,
it doesn't fit.
There's definitely
something physical going on.
I wish I knew what.
Medical examiner said
Hugo died of brain swelling
but don't know
what caused it.
And here's the kicker,
it was only three days
from when Hugo was admitted
to the time he died.
Okay, so whatever it is,
it moved really fast.
I think
he's stuck.
No, just a big head.
That's all.
Oh, my God.
Is he gonna fit?
Yes, he will.
We just need to open up
the birth canal a bit wider.
McRoberts?
Yes. Uh, call the OB
resident on call.
Layla, we're gonna adjust you
to a new position, okay?
It makes it easier
for the baby to come out.
Okay.
I'm right here.
All right,
Quentin.
Why don't you let him
take over for you, okay?
And I can use
some pressure.
Yep.
Okay, now
on your next
contraction,
I want you to give me
everything you've got.
Everything.
Okay.
I can do this.
Yes, you can.
You got this.
Okay.
I've got the head.
Shoulder.
I've got him.
I got him.
He's here.
Oh, my God.
I'm a mom. Our baby,
he's beautiful.
He's perfect.
Hey, Dad, do you want
to cut the umbilical cord?
Yeah.
Okay. Just right here
in the middle, okay?
That's not my son.
What?
Layla, who's the father?
You are, Quentin.
You are. That's our baby.
No, you're lying!
You're lying!
Hey, Quentin, it's okay.
We'll figure this out,
all right?
That's not my son.
That's our baby.
Of course it is!
No, get back!
I got to get out of here.
Hey, deep breaths, okay?
Quentin, breathe with me.
Breathe with me, Quentin.
Deep breaths.
I got to get out of here!
Stay! Baby, stay!
Hey, call security.
Help!
Oh, my God.
What's happening?
Hey! Hey, stop!
Hey, guards!
Quentin, stop!
Why are you chasing me?
Just leave me...
leave me alone!
Stay back! Stay back!
Hey, Quentin...
It's okay. It's okay.
Deep breath.
Please, just breathe.
I just got to
get out of here.
I just got to get out of here!
No, no, no, no, no!
All right, Quentin.
It's okay.
Oh, my God,
the scissors,
they're pulsating.
They're penetrating
the carotid artery.
I'll get someone
to turn off the machine.
No, the magnet is holding
everything in place,
including the scissors.
If gravity takes over,
it'll shift everything,
and we'll have maybe
20 seconds
before he bleeds out.
Okay, we need help.
Call Dr. Archer.
Dr. Charles too.
Yeah.
Do not touch
the scissors, okay?
We got you.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Coming through, excuse me.
Thank you guys
for coming.
Absolutely.
Hey, fellas.
Doctor.
He's conscious and calm
but out of it.
He's not being crushed.
He's able to breathe.
He's got to be
in pain, though.
Okay.
So let's give him
50 mics of fentanyl IM.
Syringe is plastic
and the needle nonferrous,
so it should be MRI safe.
Okay, I'll get it. Dr. Asher
went back to be
with his wife, Layla.
She's still in L&D.
Okay.
It's a rescue situation.
I just don't really know
where to start.
All of our tools
have metal in them.
So nothing is usable
as long as the MRI machine
is running.
All right, well,
let's say we did
turn the machine off.
Everything falls
to the floor. Bed alone
is a couple hundred pounds.
I can put two of my guys
in there to try and catch it,
then get it out of the way
so you can get to Quentin.
Scissors in his neck
are magnetic too.
Cut the MRI's power,
they're gonna move.
Quentin will bleed out fast.
If you could go in there
with clamps and stem the flow,
would that buy us some time?
Not enough.
Odds of survival
are less than 1%.
I'm running
outcome probabilities
on our options,
and turning off the machine
cold turkey is the worst.
So what's the best?
If CFD can secure Quentin
and ensure
the bed won't displace him
and Dr. Archer can
stabilize the neck wound
all before turning off
the MRI machine,
then the odds of survival
are roughly 61%.
Okay, we've got a plan.
Can it be done?
Well, safest way
to secure the patient
would be to do
a, uh, webbing harness.
We can throw the ropes
over the MRI machine,
and then two of my guys
can hold it on the other side.
Okay, the magnet's off,
the bed falls.
How do we ensure that
Quentin doesn't
go with it?
We can create a buffer zone
between him and the bed
using wooden cribbing,
wedges and airbags.
We can run some hoses
and inflate them
from a tank here
in the hallway.
All right,
we're halfway there.
Dr. Archer?
Yeah. I just need
to clamp the artery
in order to control
the bleeding.
Then I can take
the scissors out.
But the issue is
the tools needed to do it.
I can make them plastic.
3D printers.
There are four
in the robotics lab.
All right. Get on it.
And get a few of the
2.0 engineers to help.
We'll get started too.
Good.
Okay, you're
doing great.
Gonna give you
a little injection.
Some pain meds, all right?
To, uh, just make you
a little more
comfortable, okay?
Little pinch.
Okay.
Daniel?
I'm just gonna step away
for a second,
have a little chat
with my colleague.
I'm not going
anywhere, okay?
How's he doing?
Well, you know, I mean,
he's pinned to an
MRI machine, so...
Do you have any theories
on what sparked the break?
I've been really focusing
on trying to keep him calm.
But how's the plan
to get him off
the thing going?
Well, we've got one.
But it's a possibility
that it won't work, Daniel,
so I've asked Dr. Asher
to bring Quentin's
wife down here
to see him
'cause it may be
the last time.
Okay, thank you.
Okay,
making the incision.
Okay.
Okay, nice and easy.
Lap cut.
Yep.
Definitely feeling
some adhesions.
Point taken.
Open surgery
was the right call.
Go ahead, say it.
"I told you so."
Yeah, maybe later.
For now, why don't you
get some practice
old-school style?
Come around.
Okay. You got it?
Yeah.
All right.
Babcock.
You okay?
Yeah, it's just
a little heartburn.
I'm fine.
Oh, uh...
Uh... God, excuse me.
I'm sorry.
Stop it.
Stop.
It's no big deal.
It happens, okay?
Just focus on the field.
Stay focused.
Ah. Here comes another one.
Kai?
Kai, talk to me.
Hey, buddy! Hey!
Angel. Angel, check him.
Got a pulse.
All right. Give me
the, uh, babcock, please.
Maria!
Need some help in here!
I was helping her
to the bathroom,
and she started seizing.
Okay, 4 milligrams
of Ativan.
Please help her.
Please.
Ativan's in.
Okay, she's gonna be
postictal for a while.
Put her on a foley.
I don't want her
getting out of the bed,
not even for the bathroom.
A seizure expands
our differential tenfold.
We got to widen our net,
CT panscan,
MRI brain, sed rate,
autoimmune labs.
Let's rope in neurology.
Guys. Ms. Goodwin
just called.
She said stand down.
No more treatment.
What? What are you
talking about?
She's in the MRI suite.
Be here as soon
as she can, okay?
Hey, you okay?
This is overkill.
I probably just had
some bad oatmeal.
Well, bad oatmeal
doesn't drop you
in the middle of surgery.
So how about
you let me check you out?
How's Sam?
Appendectomy go okay?
Yeah, all good.
Dr. Graham is finishing up.
At least it's just
an appendectomy.
Not missing much.
Argh!
Oh, my chest. Pressure.
Oh, God.
I'm sorry.
That was weird.
Your heart rate plummeted,
but as soon as you
passed gas,
it came back.
Will you
sit up for me?
Take a deep breath.
All right.
Lean back for me.
Hey, Mike.
Let's get an X-ray in here.
What, did you hear
a murmur?
Honestly, I'm not sure
what I heard.
You're joking, right?
Come on.
Has heartburn
been an issue
before today?
I mean, I get it.
Even when I was a kid,
it would flare up
here and there.
But it's never
been an issue.
X-ray up. Clear.
What the hell?
That's my colon.
It shouldn't be in my chest.
No, it should not.
Her brother. Hugo,
was a patient treated
at Oakview.
So was Maria.
She was admitted yesterday
via ambulance,
but this morning,
her family just
walked her out.
They just left... absconded.
Well, her brother died at
Oakview, and they didn't
get any answers.
You see how scared
they are.
It's no wonder
that they didn't
want to stay.
Look, I agree,
but walking out
is the same as leaving
against medical advice.
It's triggered
an insurance nightmare
with the family's HMO.
They won't pay
for any more treatment
until Maria is placed back
with their preferred network
provider, Oakview.
Are you kidding me?
They're a community hospital.
They don't have the resources
to run the tests she needs.
Well, I've already
reached out
to the director
of patient services
at Oakview,
and she assured me
they'll do the best they can.
The best they can?
Ms. Goodwin, can't you reason
with the insurance company?
Hector and Gloria
aren't trying to
take advantage of them.
They're trying
to save their daughter's life.
Look, I know, and I share
in your frustration,
but they're...
No. No, I don't care what
the insurance company says.
I'm not sending Maria
back to Oakview
until I get a guarantee
she gets the treatment
she needs in time.
Dr. Halstead, the tests
that you ordered
will cost tens of thousands
of dollars,
and I know that's not
coming out your pocket.
The family has to decide
how to proceed.
Okay, Quentin, so listen,
we're gonna secure you
to the machine
while it's still running
with a harness.
So then, Dr. Archer,
who is an excellent surgeon,
is gonna come in here
and clamp your arteries
stabilize your neck wound,
and make it safer
when they pull out
the scissors. All right?
Then we turn off
the machine.
The idea is,
bed falls to the side,
you're held firmly in place
by the harness, okay?
Still with me?
Mm-hmm.
Great. Last thing.
Lower you onto a gurney,
shoot you off the ER,
and finish fixing up
your neck.
How's that sound?
Am I gonna die?
Look, this is
a complicated situation.
But some really
skilled people have
come up with this plan,
and it's the best option
we got.
All you got to do,
breathe in and out,
stay as still
as you possibly can, okay?
All right.
Take all the time
you need.
Hey, hold the work.
Everybody, out.
You're my everything.
From our first date,
I knew that I was in love.
And now we're parents.
The nurse took
a picture of him.
I named him Trevor,
after your dad.
I think he'd like that.
Tell Trevor I love him.
You're gonna
tell him yourself.
You're gonna be
a great mother.
I love you, Quentin.
I will see you again,
you hear me?
I will see you again.
Sorry.
I didn't know
what to say.
How do you
put into words when...
You can't.
But we can feel
your love for each other.
I just don't understand,
because Quentin is my rock,
and I don't even recognize
the man that's in there.
He just snapped.
How does that happen
all of a sudden?
I mean, usually
there are signs, you know?
Extreme expressions
of emotional frustration,
anger, confusion, outbursts.
You noticed anything like that
in Quentin recently?
I don't think so.
How about physical changes?
I noticed he had some lumps
on the back of his neck.
Have you...
Do you know what those are?
Lumps? I don't know.
I just wanted
to get to today
and to have the baby.
I've been so consumed
by the pregnancy
that I haven't noticed
anything else.
Oh, Quentin.
Give it to Spellman.
Thanks, Lori.
Mystery solved.
Your chest CT.
Hiatal hernia.
No, diaphragmatic.
Big enough that your colon
migrated into your chest.
So the gas
moving through it,
it puts pressure
on the vagus nerve,
drops your heartbeat.
Breaking wind
releases the pressure.
Heart returns
to a normal rate.
Yeah.
You said you had heartburn
since you were a kid.
Probably this.
Undiagnosed asymptomatic
congenital diaphragmatic
hernia.
I've never
passed out before, though.
Well, my guess is it's been
slowly expanding over time.
But you do CrossFit now,
so the thrusters, burpees,
other workouts...
Safe bet that
they've exacerbated
the condition.
Led to today.
Yeah, well,
I'll own that.
But I can't risk dropping
in the OR again, so let's
fix this hernia.
Okay. Well, you've got
a few surgical options.
Open.
No.
That's a huge incision.
Lots of digging around.
I'll be laid up
in the ICU for weeks.
Laparoscopic, then.
Be more incisions
for the scope and tools,
but less invasive...
No old-school approaches.
Robotic assist in OR 2.0.
Shortest recovery time.
I just want this
to be over with.
Okay.
I'm gonna scrub in.
I'll see you after, okay?
Holy cow.
Look at this place.
It's like you guys are living
in 2050 up here.
Listen, don't break
anything.
How's it going
with the surgical tools?
Almost there.
Scalpel's printed.
Two of the three angled
peripheral vascular clamps
are printed as well.
One Weitlaner
retractor printed.
One to go.
Oh, it's like the real thing.
It is the real thing,
just plastic.
These tools,
I think they can work.
They'll have to.
They're all we got.
They never wanted
to go to Oakview,
but the ambulance
took them there anyway.
Because Maria
didn't require
specialty care,
paramedics took her to
the nearest hospital instead.
I'm so sorry that you've
been put in this situation.
We can continue
to treat Maria,
but your insurance
won't cover the costs.
He said he'll sell the car.
He can get a second job.
His oldest son
can get a job as well.
No. Papa, no.
No.
Regreso. I'll go back.
No!
Maria...
Maria.
You know,
maybe Oakview
will figure it out.
All right.
Um, I'll set up the transfer.
What was Maria saying?
If she lets her parents
bankrupt the family
paying for her medical care,
then all of the opportunities
they've worked so hard
to give their children
will be lost.
She is risking her life.
No.
No, she's sacrificing it.
And it's awful,
but I get it.
Ready to inflate?
Up on blue.
Hold.
Up on red.
How's... how's Layla doing?
She's in shock,
full of grief,
and a first-time mom
all at the same time.
It's a lot,
but a psych resident
is with her.
And, um, how about you?
How are you doing?
Honestly, I didn't
see this coming.
I just thought Quentin
was a nervous
first-time dad,
like the ones
I see every single day.
Never suspected
mental illness.
You know,
I'm not sure it is, per se.
You know those lumps
on the back of his neck?
I have a very strong hunch
that they're indicative
of a physical issue
that could very well be
causing a sudden psychosis.
It's physical,
not psychological?
Yeah, I'm leaning
that way. I mean,
can't be sure
until we run some tests.
Maria, this is
a thumb drive
with all the work
we did here,
along with our notes.
You give this to the doctors
as soon as you get there.
Thank you.
All right.
Empty her foley.
It's okay, Mama.
Wait.
Will?
You smell that?
We have to run one more test.
I'll pay for it myself,
if I have to.
I'm scared.
Well, you'll be less
frightened if you
can't see it,
so I'm gonna drape
your face, okay?
Yeah. All right.
Here we go. Careful.
That's right. All right.
All right.
10cc's of lidocaine, please.
Okay.
Scalpel.
All right.
Grab hold of those scissors.
I don't want them flopping
after I make the incisions.
Here we go.
Okay.
All right.
Wheaties.
Watch your fingers there.
That's it. That's it.
Don't move it. Don't move it.
Clamp.
All right.
Carotid clamps in place.
CFD, you're up.
All right.
Spread out around the bed.
When it falls down,
we pull it away
from the MRI machine.
All right.
And no slack at all,
you understand?
If there's any movement,
his clamps could pop off,
and then we'll have a problem
we might not be able to fix.
All right.
On three, you're gonna
cut the power to the MRI.
We ready?
Everybody, ready?
Ready.
One, two, three.
All right.
Clamps are holding.
I'm gonna remove
the scissors now.
All right.
All right, we're clear.
Okay, bed.
Let's lower Quentin.
Lower him slowly.
One, two, three.
Slack!
Okay, ropes are free.
Incredible, Doc.
Freaking incredible.
Thanks. Can someone get me
a bottle of water, please?
Dr. Archer, you did it.
Dean, you all right?
Yeah. I got to get
to the OR, so...
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
Page Dr. Lanik to
take over with Quentin.
I'm just feeling
a little dizzy.
That's all.
Hernia fixed?
I'd say you're
as good as new.
Yeah, not quite.
I'm the fart doctor now.
A punchline.
No. What happened today
was a result
of a medical ailment, okay?
Like anyone's gonna
care about that.
All they're gonna
remember is the fart.
Oh, come on.
It'll blow over.
Sorry. Poor choice of words,
but it will.
I doubt it.
All right, look.
I'll check on you
a little later, okay?
So his neck
is fixed, then?
Yeah.
The artery repair
went very well.
What about his mind?
Because before...
Well, I gave him a very small
dose of an antipsychotic
called risperidone,
and he does seem
to be thinking more clearly.
And you think
he'll stay that way?
I don't think that
what happened today is
the result of mental illness.
You know,
tests are still pending,
but all indications are
is that Quentin has
a genetic disease called
neurofibromatosis type 2.
Is it curable?
It's not.
But there are a lot of
effective treatments
out there.
And the good news is
that with a little luck,
Quentin is gonna be
the man you know again.
Genetic means
he's had it forever.
Why'd it suddenly
go berserk today?
NF is thought to be
an inflammatory
ailment, right?
So possibly triggered
by changes in environment,
you know, lifestyle,
possibly diet, medication.
Diet.
Oh, my God.
The minute I got pregnant,
my hormones went crazy.
Smells were intense,
and Quentin's breath
was the worst.
Everything he ate
made me throw up.
So he gave up his entire diet.
No more fruits,
vegetables, fish.
For the past nine months,
he's been eating nothing
but bland,
processed crap for me.
Mrs. Bell,
Quentin's asking to see you.
Hi, honey.
Layla...
I don't entirely understand
what happened or why,
but I know I put you
in danger. I'm sorry.
No, Quentin.
I was so tied up
in the pregnancy,
I was oblivious
to what was
going on with you.
I should've
seen the signs.
Forgive me.
Oh, honey,
there's nothing to forgive.
I love you.
I love you too.
Someone's been
missing you guys.
Here you go.
Hi, sweetheart.
Look who's here.
Hi.
I'm your dad.
I love you.
Sweetheart.
Hi.
A metabolic condition?
Yeah.
It's called maple syrup
urine disease,
and it's a rare condition
that makes it difficult
for the body
to break down
certain amino acids.
The trademark symptom is
a distinct maple syrup smell
that shows up in urine.
It usually presents
in childhood, and it's
almost unheard of
to discover it in
someone your age,
or Hugo's.
It's likely
that he had it too.
And I suspect this is
why Oakview couldn't
diagnose him in time.
He didn't have a seizure
or a foley catheter.
It made his doctors'
jobs even harder.
Wait, this disease
killed Hugo.
Does that mean...
No.
No, you're gonna be okay.
You have an intermittent form
of the disease,
which can be
managed by closely
monitoring protein levels.
We've already reached out
to nephrology to discuss
treatment options.
Maria.
Hello, Daniel.
Ooh!
Hey, you're, uh...
You're a little early.
Oh, I couldn't wait
to see you.
What's this?
You cleaned your office?
No, I didn't.
I've been tidying up
a little bit.
Why?
I was very embarrassed
by what happened
this morning.
And, um, you know,
I just...
I don't ever want you
to feel that I...
I take for granted
the job that you do, or...
Or that I'm oblivious
to how hard you work.
I really don't want that
to happen.
You're very sweet.
I care about
you too, Daniel.
A lot.
Yeah?
Mm-hmm.
Hey.
Ah. Where'd you find it?
Nurses' station.
Oh, makes sense.
That's where I was when
the call about Quentin
came in.
Yeah, I totally get it.
I would have run off
and left it behind too.
But my kidneys can handle
some mild dehydration.
Yours can't.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, pretty sure
there will be another
emergency tomorrow,
and the day after that,
so I'm gonna
give you something.
It is a tracking device.
App connects it
to your phone.
And I haven't lost my keys
since I put it on, so...
Well, keep it.
I'm past water bottles.
Nephrologist just left.
My kidneys
are getting worse.
Dialysis?
That was
a big win today.
You saved that family.
Yeah.
I suppose it's time
to talk about my
DACA renewal.
I know I've been
dragging my feet.
It's been a long day.
We can speak
in the morning.
No. No, I'm ready.
Yeah? All right.
Truth is, I've been
thinking about leaving Med.
Really?
I've always been in school
or protected by
my residency,
so my immigration status
has always been stable.
But my parents,
despite them always
having jobs,
could never solidify theirs,
so they moved to Canada.
Mm.
But they can't enter
the country to come visit me.
And if I leave to go see them,
I might be denied reentry.
So...
I haven't hugged
my parents
in a decade.
That's...
heartbreaking.
But Maria today,
her bravery,
what she was willing
to sacrifice for her family,
reminded me that
"no one puts their child
in a boat
"unless the water
is safer than
the land."
Warsan Shire.
Oh, that's a beautiful poem.
So...
my parents' sacrifice
to get me here
put me in this boat,
which is why I have to stay.
And Dr. Cuevas,
I believe that you will
find a way
to see your parents again.
But until that day,
know that you have family here
in us at Med.
Thank you.