♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
I'm here. I'm here.
You paged me.
Why do you have that baby
in my hospital?
It's Lucas. Pete's son.
He had a child, remember?
You were there.
Why do you have
that baby in my hospital?
Pete is taking over for Nai
while she is out of town.
You paged 9-1-1.
I was looking after Lucas.
Why do you have--
the nanny is meeting me here
any minute.
Now come on. What is up?
Kayla Lindy,
the coma mama--
her husband's bringing in
the big guns.
Which big guns?
Dr. Geraldine Ginsberg.
Ahh.
He's flying in Ginsberg?
He wants her to wake his wife
up from the coma.
You gonna keep playing mommy
or you gonna get in there?
- Okay. Here.
- Take the baby.
Take the baby, Charlotte.
Take the baby. Okay?
Yeah. The nanny will be here
in about ten minutes, okay?
Here you go.
Take it. Mm.
Ooh. Be good.
Hello.
I'm Charlotte.
Please don't drool
on me.
And then drew got
a triple, slid into third
and scraped the hell out of
his ankle, but you know drew.
He didn't care. You'd have been
really proud of him. Hey.
So... Dr. Montgomery's here.
And Dr. Ginsberg will be here
any minute now.
I know you think
she can't hear me,
but, uh...
Maybe she can.
A-And when Dr. Ginsberg
gets here and wakes her up,
I just want her to know
that...
I didn't give up on her.
Eddie,
I need to talk to you.
Dr. Ginsberg is an extremely
accomplished neurosurgeon,
but Kayla has been...
She's been in a coma
for six weeks.
I just don't want you
to get your hopes up.
Did you know
Ginsberg revived a patient
who was comatose for 17 years?
I'll get my miracle.
We'll get our miracle.
I mean, she's gonna wake up.
I don't know why
you have to be so negative.
Eddie--
why can't you just believe?
I'm sorry.
It's just, uh...
I unplugged
the love of my life,
and she didn't die.
She didn't die.
That's gotta mean something,
you know? And...
I'm Dr. Ginsberg.
This is my team.
Which one are you?
Oh. Hello.
Dr. Montgomery or Dr. King?
Dr. Montgomery.
Pleasure to meet you.
And this is Eddie Lindy,
Kayla's husband.
Thank you so much
for coming all this way.
I prefer that family members
wait outside
during the diagnostic process.
Dr. Ginsberg--
no, no, it's, uh,
that's fine.
Whatever it takes.
Okay, uh, patient is
Kayla Lindy, 32 years of age,
surrogate mother
pregnant with triplets.
During the pregnancy,
complications led to
a pulmonary--
I'm familiar with the file.
All right.
I'm gonna need a complete exam
along with a repeat e.E.G.,
an m.R.I. And a cerebral
blood flow study.
Come on. Go, people. Go.
Oh, so nice of you
to join us, Dr. Shepherd.
I assume you didn't plan
on making a decision
without reviewing
the radionuclide cisternogram.
Amy?
Hey... Addie.
So long time no see.
You two know each other?
Yes. Uh, yes. I...
I was married to her brother.
Ah.
Don't worry.
Ginsberg is a beast,
but she's also a genius.
Amy, why didn't you tell me
you were coming?
What,
and spoil the surprise?
You knew I was here?
Your name is all over
Kayla's records.
Amy--
uh, Amelia.
Derek is the only one
who calls me Amy these days.
Amelia...
But Derek didn't tell me
that you were
one of Ginsberg's fellows.
Shocker.
Did he, uh,
did he even tell you
that I went
into neurosurgery?
Is that
the Geraldine Ginsberg?
My god.
Sam Bennett.
You stayed hot.
Amelia Shepherd?
Well, the last time I saw you,
you were, like, 14 years old.
What happened?
Now she is
a fancy neurosurgeon.
Oh! There you are.
Take your kid.
Oh.
Nanny was a no-show.
Oh, what is it?
I have to get to the office.
He spit up on me.
Oh.
I'm sending you
a dry cleaning bill.
Okay, apparently there are
a lot of things
that Derek does not say.
Oh, no, no, no.
He's--he's not mine.
He's, uh,
he's my boyfriend's son.
Dr. Shepherd.
Uh, duty calls.
We will talk later.
I missed you guys.
See you later.
Hurricane Amelia
made good.
What kind of family is it
where the black sheep
ends up being a neurosurgeon?
Wow.
Huh? Oh, what? Huh?
How you doing, buddy?
Are you gonna be
a doctor, too?
Is that what you're
talking about? Huh?
Yeah, that's Sam.
That's Sam. I think you are.
You're so good with him.
Thank you. Listen, I gotta
get him back to the nanny.
Can you, um, tell Ginsberg
I'll be right back?
Mm-hmm. Yeah. All right.
Say bye-bye. Say bye-bye.
See you later, buddy?
Bye. Say bye-bye. Bye.
Okay.
If she can help her...
I know it's asking a lot.
But... anything's possible,
right?
Wait. You know
this isn't your fault?
Look. Hey, look at me.
Look at me.
This is not your fault.
It is.
But thank you
for saying it isn't.
Oh, Charlotte. Good.
I'm glad you're here.
I-I can't do
the sex ed seminar
at the retirement home
tonight.
You are not bailing on me?
Uh, well, not by choice.
I have a patient.
We're doing an intervention.
It's a thing.
You know, I'm sorry.
Great. What am I supposed to do
about the male point of view?
Well, actually,
I have a pitch for that.
You know, uh,
what about Cooper?
No.
He's great with people.
He's great
with 5 year olds.
Come on, Charlotte.
You've been sitting on
your hands for a month now.
How do you expect
to win him back
if you don't just
reach out there?
Who said I wanted
to win him back?
You are never gonna have
what you really want
if you don't put yourself
out there and go for it.
You really do
give crappy advice.
No, actually,
I'm kinda... brilliant.
Application
for the fda approval
for the next stage
of my a.L.S. Study.
Naomi usually reviews the data
before we submit it,
but with her gone
and leaving you in charge,
it's your job now.
Oh, thanks.
Looks like a fun read.
Being in charge
is not my idea of fun.
I mean, I'm glad
that William finally told her
about his a.L.S.,
but I didn't know
she was gonna run off
to Switzerland to be with him.
Any word from them?
I heard from Naomi
a few days ago.
I guess he hasn't seen
any improvement.
Did Naomi say when, uh,
they're planning on coming back?
No.
Then move that
to the top of the pile
so they have a reason to.
Come on, Charlotte.
Sex ed for seniors?
It's a little out of
my wheelhouse, don't you think?
Actually, they're not all that
different from horny teenagers.
They got too much time
on their hands,
minimal supervision,
almost zero regard
for the consequences
of reckless sexual behavior.
Grannies gone wild.
It's a real problem, Cooper.
S.t.d.s are spreading through
the elder care community
like a brush fire.
The women can't get pregnant.
The men are all hopped up
on p.D.E.5 inhibitors.
Everybody's
screwing everybody else.
Nobody's taking
any precautions.
As much fun as that sounds,
it's old people, Charlotte.
I'm a pediatrician.
I need a man.
A male.
Oh.
The male residents
are often uncomfortable
broaching sexual matters
with female medical staff.
Why me?
I'm coming to you
as a physician,
a fellow partner
of this medical practice.
Put away your fear
of age spots. Help me out.
Kayla's repeat e.E.G.
Shows diffuse slowing
consistent with
a permanent vegetative state.
Surgery won't help.
Kayla is not
a viable candidate.
I'm sorry, Eddie.
There must--must be something
else you can at least try.
She can't just...
Stay like this.
I'm afraid I can't help.
What about cannulating
the aqueduct of sylvius?
Passing a stent
to drain the fluid buildup?
Dr. Shepherd.
Her c.S.F. Studies show
a slowing of flow,
not a complete obstruction.
It could work.
You know how to wake her?
No, she doesn't.
She's referring to
an experimental procedure
that has shown
very little success,
and in your wife's case,
it will not work.
I assisted
in two of the procedures...
Now is not the time
to bring it up.
So do it or don't, but don't
say that it can't work.
Amelia--
this procedure
is a bad idea.
If she thinks that
it can work, then we sh--
she is a teaching fellow who is
not qualified to make this call.
I graduated top of my class
at Harvard.
I did my residency
at Johns Hopkins.
I have done dozens of procedures
in the third ventricle.
I am more than qualified.
That's why you hired me.
Well, clearly I made a mistake.
You're fired, Dr. Shepherd.
And it goes without saying
that just because the risk
of pregnancy is gone,
the risk of contracting sexually
transmitted diseases isn't.
In fact,
in a place of this size,
where many of you are so...
So lucky to be enjoying
considerable leisure time...
Uh, e-exactly.
Yeah.
In a situation like this,
transmission rates can be
very high, which is why,
if you're
going to have intercourse,
we'd like to urge you to
flash back to high school
and start
using condoms again.
Alternatively, um...
There--there are many ways
to be intimate and safe
short of--
of actual penetration.
Can anyone name a way
to get pleasure
without penetration?
I just feel so awful
for the husband.
You know,
he's--he's gonna have to
watch her wither away
hooked up to a feeding tube
when it doesn't
have to be that way.
It's a crime. I mean, it's
a crime of medical omission.
In fairness, even Derek said
that this isn't doable.
I e-mailed the scans,
and he said it's a no go.
Derek is just like Ginsberg.
I mean, if he hasn't seen it,
it ain't so. This is just new.
This is a cutting-edge
surgical procedure.
The university of Wisconsin
did a study
on a series of 11 patients.
I've seen it.
I mean, I could do it.
I'm just saying...
I trained for it.
You do realize
we're talking about a woman
with three babies inside her?
And you realize that Kayla has
a husband and two children?
Addie, what do you think?
I th--
Oh. Could we pause
for a moment, please.
Here. I'll get it.
I'll get him.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I should get outta here
and go pick up Vanessa.
Vanessa?
His girlfriend.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Uh, all right.
I'll see you guys later.
See you.
Have fun. Have fun.
Okay, so you and Sam...
What is with the tension?
There's no tension.
I was sitting right here.
I mean,
you barely looked at him.
There was a thing.
With you and Sam?
With me and Sam.
And Naomi did not
take it well.
And now I'm with Pete, and Sam
is with Vanessa, and it's fine.
It's very adult.
Sounds very messy.
No, it's not, actually.
It's great.
My life is working.
Addison.
I mean, this is me
you're talking to.
I caught you with
my brother's best friend
and I kept your secret.
I mean, you can talk to me.
You used to trust me.
I chose Pete.
I choose Pete.
He's great. We're great.
And... I can't have kids,
and Pete has Lucas.
So that's sort of this...
Amazing icing on the cake.
Except for the fact that...
Pete's still in love
with Lucas' mother,
which is...
Oh, Addie.
So anyway... cheers.
I missed you.
You know, you were always
a better sister
than the ones I had.
And you were way better
than my brother.
Are things okay
between you two?
He's the golden child.
Everything's always okay
with him.
That was painful.
At least they took
some condoms.
Ah, do you have any questions
or--or want some more condoms?
Actually,
I do have a question
for the gentleman,
if that's all right.
The gentleman.
Of course.
I'll be waiting.
Hello.
How c--how can I... help?
I don't really know
how to say this.
Uh, it's somewhat
embarrassing.
No, i'm--i'm--I'm a doctor.
I've heard it all.
Come...
Okay.
Well... Nora and I...
We've been dating
for several months.
She's a really lovely woman,
really lovely.
And our, uh, our intimate time
has been very good
except lately, it's been
difficult for me to--
oh, you know,
as men get older,
it's, uh, it's very common
for them to have difficulty,
as you say, getting, um...
Trying to--
no, it's not that.
Oh.
I'm still able to perform.
Oh, good. Good, good, good.
It's just become uncomfortable.
My pelvis is sore.
It doesn't want to move
the way it used to.
So I don't find myself
getting, uh, in the mood.
Oh.
So... I was hoping
you would have some pills
to help with libido.
Given your discomfort,
I think you should have
a complete exam
before we prescribe anything.
And you can do that? I could
make an appointment with you,
and you could check me out?
It's--it's my associate's
specialty not mine.
But I can bring her up to speed
on everything we talked about.
But you really--
you really should make
an ap-appointment to see her.
With a lady?
She's no lady.
Y'all kept me up till
3:00 this morning.
Oh, oh, god. I'm sorry.
No, I'm just kidding.
Sorry, Sam.
I'm glad she's here.
I--me, too. It's nice.
I forgot... how much I like
having someone to talk to.
You can talk to me.
No, I can't.
It--
Sam, I can't.
I know. Oh, boy.
Amelia?
Uh, Eddie wanted to hear
more about the surgery.
So we started talking,
and one thing led to another,
and, uh...
And what?
And he asked me
to do the surgery.
And I said yes.
I can do the surgery
and save the babies.
I just need you in there
to keep an eye on them
and Sam to maintain
the cardiovascular function.
This can work.
It's reckless.
How--well, how--
how would this work?
Just for Eddie's sake, I want
to know how this would work.
Mm-hmm. I would relieve
the obstruction
by placing a stent
in the aqueduct,
and then
as the pressure drops,
the activity in the brain stem
will return,
and Kayla wakes up.
And if it works,
what state will she be in?
Will she
be able to function?
I don't know. But if we don't
do it, we will never know.
I'm against this.
I am, too.
Two neurosurgeons said no
to this, one being your mentor,
the other being your brother.
Derek looked at an e-mail
of a scan.
I mean, he--he didn't even
see the patient,
which ultimately
doesn't matter,
because Eddie Lindy made
a decision to save his wife.
He asked me to do it,
and I can do it.
Now will you give me
privileges here?
Yes.
Great.
I'll get you an O.R.
for tomorrow.
Addison, what are you
going to do to stop her?
Nothing.
Look, I was wrong.
I made a bad call.
Yeah, well...
I admit that. But we're both
on the same side with this.
We both want to give
those babies a chance.
What, do you really think
I can talk her out of it?
I couldn't talk you out of it.
I think you could try. I think
you could try talking to her.
Eddie wants this,
Amelia is set,
and she just got sanctioned
by the chief of staff.
You know her. You know
this is wrong. So stop her.
Have you reviewed
the application?
Not yet.
Overnight it to Naomi.
Really? You don't think
she has enough on her plate?
Why are you
rolling around here
with this gigantic chip
on your shoulder?
You should've never told me
about William's a.L.S.
You know, I-I get it.
You're upset that your study
isn't going fast enough.
I'll read the application,
I'll get--
this isn't about
the damn application.
I slept with Naomi.
And... then I told her
about William.
Y--
yeah, yeah.
You told Naomi...
That William has a.L.S.?
Why?
I don't know.
I wanted more from her,
and I thought it was
the right thing to do
or that she'd be pissed at him
for withholding.
I don't know.
Doesn't matter.
She's gone.
Prostate cancer?
I came in for loss of libido,
pain from arthritis.
Discovery
of prostate cancer
is often
an incidental finding.
You don't find it
if you don't look,
and then it's too late.
What is the treatment?
In your case, I recommend
radiation therapy--
either external
or with an implantable
radioactive seed.
What about...
What about my Johnson?
Will it still work after?
About half of all patients
do experience
erectile difficulty
following radiation.
And there are no
alternative treatments?
Well, given your circumstances,
not that I recommend.
But there are things we can do
if impotence occurs
as a side effect
of the radiation--
injections, pumps--
if I don't have
the treatment...
How long do I have?
Four, maybe five years.
It's been lovely
talking to you.
Thank you for your time.
Mr. Schmitt.
He's a man,
and you're talking about him
losing his manhood.
I get that.
No, you can't. You're a woman.
You couldn't possibly know
how something like that
would make him feel.
And you're a man,
so of course you do.
Yes, that's right.
I mean, is the guy
even making the wrong decision?
Prostate cancer's
pretty slow growing. He's 80.
If he wants to live the life
he has left on his own terms
and not have to talk to you
about sex,
who are we to tell him no?
So I should just let him die?
Oh, come on.
That's not what I'm saying.
He's in
extraordinarily good health.
And this cancer's aggressive.
His gleason level's a 7.
And if he's made it to 80,
statistically, he's got a good
shot of making it to 100.
Now he's got a woman
that he loves--
that he wants to be able
to love.
He doesn't want to be
emasculated, Charlotte.
Is it so hard for you
to see that?
Are we talking about Oscar
or we talking about you?
Excuse me?
Emasculation seems to be
your catch phrase for me.
I wasn't talking about you,
but truth?
Yeah, you like to be tougher
than everyone else,
and that makes
some people pull away.
I thought we were past this.
You brought it up.
I came to you for help.
Well, maybe that wasn't
such a good idea.
Clearly.
Dr. Shepherd.
Uh, this is
Angie and Simon McConnell.
They're the parents that
Kayla's surrogate for.
They wanted to meet you.
Well, i'd--I'd shake
your hands, but...
Dr. Montgomery told us
what's happening.
Eddie doesn't want
to hear this,
but our babies
are barely viable.
He's well aware.
We know
this is horrible to ask
after all that Kayla's
been through, but...
Please don't do this.
We are so close
to having our family.
Would you talk with me
outside for a minute?
You thought if I saw the parents
with their sad faces,
what, I was just
gonna back down?
Look,
I'm doing the right thing.
Not for the babies.
The risk is too high.
The Addison Montgomery I know
would Wade through fire
for a patient.
She wouldn't whine about
the risks.
I mean, she'd go
all super woman on me
trying to convince me
to do the surgery.
What is it? What, you're
settling in your personal life,
so now you're willing to settle
with your patients, too?
I am not settling, Amelia.
You have feelings
for someone else.
Pete has feelings
for his kid's mom.
You say it's great.
You don't seem great.
You have no idea
what you're talking about.
You seem sad, Addison.
And you should be.
Okay, what--you are way
out of line here.
You should want more...
More for yourself
and more for Kayla.
I can't decide
if it's worse
if she chooses William
and he dies
or if she chooses me
and he lives.
You don't want him
to die.
Right, right.
'Cause then I gotta compete
with his ghost.
Yeah, but he lives, you gotta
compete with all that money.
It's lose-lose either way,
right?
Yes, which is why
we're here. Move on.
Move on.
♪ I'm a romantic ♪
♪ I am indecisive ♪
Brings us back
to Cooper's dilemma.
Would you rather have
10 to 15 years of life
or four years of sex?
Sex.
That's not the dilemma.
The dilemma is how do I continue
working with Charlotte king?
Maybe that's why we're here.
Maybe it's you
who needs to move on.
No, I already moved on
from Charlotte.
I just can't move away from her
and her emasculating ways.
Right, right,
'cause offering standard
medical treatment to a patient
is clearly emasculating.
Hey, you know what? You're not
allowed to defend her.
That's against the rules.
You guys have rules?
All guys have rules, dude.
And he thinks
Charlotte has the problem.
Hey. Hey.
Hey.
Don't "hey" me.
♪ ...it in my eyes ♪
This is what you guys
do for fun, huh?
What, so what,
now you're leaving?
I'm moving on.
♪ ...seen it in your eyes ♪
Wow. That guy's
a piece of work.
♪ No one will ever do ♪
What?
I'm just drinking here.
You think
it's my fault, too?
I was not wrong!
So what you're trying to say
is that I overreacted
and I wanted to pick a fight?
I'm just drinking here.
Oh, man. All right.
Another round?
No, I'll pass.
R--why?
I don't need to move on.
♪♪♪
Oh, yeah?
You're here late.
Am I an emasculating bitch?
I assume this isn't
a trick question.
Is this a Cooper thing or--
my sex ed seminar
turned up a patient
with prostate cancer.
He's old, thinks his life
will be over without sex.
He won't even listen
to treatment options.
And I think I could help him,
but he won't take my calls.
Cooper thinks
I don't understand men.
I think you know
he's wrong.
We therapists are good
at helping people
talk through their problems.
I don't like talking.
Yeah, well,
maybe that's your problem.
Things I tell you
are privileged?
Of course.
Addison's patient,
the one in the coma...
I left her husband
alone in the room.
I knew he might...
End things.
Why'd you do it?
Well, he was there...
Staring at a woman
who wouldn't wake up.
It seemed so cruel.
I'm backing a surgery
to save her.
Three babies are at risk.
I'm putting my faith
in some 20-year-old kid
because I...
Because you wanted
forgiveness.
I want to believe
I didn't do the wrong thing
for the wrong reasons.
Well, maybe
you did the wrong thing
for the right reason.
This thing
with me and Cooper...
Why did you
push me back to him?
Because it's what you want.
Hey.
When did I become the man
other men
tell their problems to?
Could you tell me that?
Maybe the question is,
when did all the men I know
become women?
Because really, it's--
you know what? Amelia is
gonna operate on Kayla.
Okay.
And she thinks I'm settling.
I'm not settling.
Are you mad?
Yes, I'm mad. I'm mad.
You want to tell me
what it's about?
You said,
"I love you, Violet."
To me. You said it to me.
I--what? I said--
when you were sick
and you had a fever,
and I know
it shouldn't upset me.
But, you know, i'm--
I'm here babysitting...
Playing peekaboo
with your kid, you know?
And i--you said,
"I love you, Violet."
Yeah,
that was six weeks ago.
You been carrying this around
for six weeks?
I'm busy. I have a job.
I run a practice. I have
things to do--
I'm trying, okay?
I'm trying here, Pete,
and I just need to know if--
if you...
Don't want to do this.
Then--then I won't get
too attached.
Babe, I will
always love Violet.
She's the mother
of my child.
Okay.
Good. I'm glad
that we cleared that up
so--no--
so I can get my--
okay, Addison, Addison.
That doesn't mean
I don't love you.
Mm. I love you.
I love you.
I'm not sitting around
waiting for Violet.
I have moved on,
and I'm happy I've moved on.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Okay.
Okay?
Yeah.
Mm.
Are you here to talk me
out of this again? Because--
I'm here for my patients.
Ventriculoscope is in place...
And I'm moving down
to the aqueduct.
So far, so good.
You're doing great.
Keep going.
All right.
I am in the aqueduct.
Guide is in place.
Preparing the stent.
Almost there.
All right, heart rate's up
to 130. 140.
She's desaturating.
She's thrown another clot.
I'm gonna keep going.
The babies
are in distress. Sam.
All right. I'll need time
to remove the clot.
Fetal heart rates
are in the 80s.
Let's prep the belly.
I'm cutting her open.
Amelia, step back.
I can do this, Addison.
Just give Sam a chance.
So long as the babies
are in there,
she's gonna
keep throwing clots,
and they will not survive
the procedure.
I need
to deliver the babies now.
Amelia, step back.
Scalpel.
Baby number one.
Call nicu. Get three vents
and a central line set up.
Baby number two. Come on.
Why wasn't I paged?
I have a full team here.
I'm an attending on this case.
You could've used me.
Number three.
Sam, you're clear to go.
She's floppy.
No spontaneous respiration.
I can't feel a heartbeat.
Let me assist you.
I've got it.
Set up an intubation tray.
Let me help you.
We are here
because of you.
This baby is like this
The best thing you can do
right now is back off.
Give me an e.T. Tube.
All right. Suction.
She's aspirated.
Is she all right?
Okay, I'm almost there.
Almost there. Got it.
Okay. Hold c.P.R.
There's no pulse.
Resume c.P.R.
Okay.
Come on.
Come on, baby.
Hold on.
Good. We got a rhythm...
And a pulse.
All right.
Let's get her into nicu.
Call an ecmo unit. This baby
needs to be on bypass.
Have the techs meet us
at the unit. Let's go.
Is she gonna be okay?
Sam, you got this?
Yeah.
Apparently,
you've spoken to Dr. King.
Yes.
I told her
that you had the right
to refuse medical treatment,
which is true.
Thank you.
But I also think
it's wrong.
Impotence is not
an inevitable side effect
of radiation.
She said I have
a 50/50 chance
of losing function.
And if you come down
on the wrong side of that,
you still have
a woman that loves you.
But I won't be able
to love her back.
Well, maybe not in the way
that you can now.
But with the help
of Dr. King...
It's not the same.
Well, you're right.
It would be different.
But these options
that Dr. King mentioned,
they don't have to...
They don't make you
less of a man.
You know what it's like
to get old?
People start doing things
for you.
They stop letting you
do things for yourself...
Like work a job, uh,
or live in a house
or drive your own car
down the street.
I lost my wife.
My kids
have lives of their own.
I'm stuck here.
But there's one thing that
I can still do for myself,
one thing that makes me
feel whole.
And I'm not about
to let that be taken away
or--or have it made
uncomfortable or unnatural.
Well, I admit I don't know
what it's like to get old.
And when it comes to sex,
I get that.
And when...
You can't do it...
I mean, that is...
Look, it happens.
It happens to every guy.
I...
I was with a woman I loved,
and we were fighting a lot,
and, uh... I was stressed out,
and that made it
difficult... to perform.
And it was humiliating.
Oh... it was.
And so I pushed her away
and I treated her badly
because I was feeling like
I was less of a man.
I was... I was wrong.
I was just wrong.
Mr. Schmitt,
I can't promise you
that there'll be
no side effects
if you do this treatment.
But I do know
that you'll be alive
and you will get to continue
to love Nora
for a long time to come.
You will be
the man in her life.
And that's
the most important thing.
Sam.
Almost there. 30cc syringe.
And clots are dissolving.
Vitals are stabilizing.
The rest is up to you,
Dr. Shepherd.
I almost killed her, Sam.
And those babies--
they're in Addison's hands.
What am I doing?
You're a doing surgery
on a woman's brain...
A-A surgery you said
only you could do...
A surgery you fought for.
Stop standing there and start
acting like a surgeon.
You sound like Addison.
No, I sound like you
before you started
losing confidence in yourself.
Amelia, can you do this?
Can you wake this woman up
and bring her back
to her family?
Or were just spouting
a bunch of mess
because you like to cut?
I can do this.
Okay, then. Go.
We don't have all day.
Adjust the scope. Set up
the catheter for the stent.
Let's show your brother
he's not the only Shepherd
who can make magic.
Attagirl.
It didn't work.
You don't know that.
The other patients
were at least
marginally responsive by now.
I freaked out, Sam.
Maybe I took too long.
Maybe I should've stopped.
Maybe Addison was--
she's in pain.
Is that good or bad?
♪ wait a minute here ♪
♪ Let's just make it clear,
to the end... ♪
That's not a pain response.
Whoa. Neither is that.
Sweetheart?
Pupils are equal
and reactive.
- Positive doll's eye response.
- Is she waking up?
Her brain stem reflexes
are improving.
- She's waking up?
- She's waking up.
Baby?
She's waking up.
Application looks good.
I'm sending it in.
Of course it looks good.
I wrote it.
♪ It's just you and me ♪
♪ and me ♪
That was
some pretty good game
you were throwing last night.
You get her number?
Yeah, I got her number.
Gonna call her?
I don't think so.
Why?
Not interested.
Not ready to move on?
Naomi will come back.
I'm going to wait.
♪ You can go about your way ♪
♪ not while I am here ♪
Addison.
It worked. I was right.
No. No, you were not right.
You overreached
and you overstepped
and you forced me to take out
those babies way too early.
They all could've died.
But they're okay.
They survived. They're stable,
at least for now.
But don't kid yourself.
You got lucky in there.
No, that wasn't--
you could be a great surgeon.
But right now, you're not half
as good as you think you are,
and I say that as a doctor
with far more experience
than you.
♪ Now all I can see,
it's just you and me ♪
♪ and me ♪
♪ just you and me ♪
But as...
Your sister-in-law--
your former...
Sister-in-law--
look at that.
She's up, she's awake.
That's a family,
and you did that.
Those kids have a mother.
He's got the woman he loves.
So... celebrate that,
'cause it's a miracle.
♪♪♪
I'm glad to see you both
back here.
I decided to go
with the treatment.
Nora and I, uh...
We just came in to get
some advice for after.
I'm glad.
Why don't you two
get settled inside?
I'll be in
in a minute.
Thank you...
For talking to him,
for getting him
to come back.
Yeah, i'm--I'm sorry.
I was an ass to you.
Yeah.
You were.
But maybe we can
work together after all
and not kill each other.
Maybe we can.
I'm gonna go do work.
Hey, what do you say
to a drink after work?
I don't think so.
You afraid
to be friends, Cooper?
I'm not afraid.
Then what?
♪ It's just you and me ♪
♪ and me ♪
I don't know.
♪ And me ♪
♪ just you and me ♪
♪ and me ♪
♪ till we somehow found relief ♪
Hey. Big win.
Kayla's awake.
The babies survived.
Good stuff, huh?
Oh.
Look at how much
he loves her.
God,
they've been through hell.
And no matter how it turns out,
they have each other.
That's how
they got through this.
Mm-hmm.
Why didn't you
stand up for me?
In the O.R. with Addison--
she shut me out,
and you didn't say a word.
What are you
talking about?
If you're sleeping with Addison,
say it.
W--
If I'm just
a pit stop, say it.
Vanessa, please--
Stop wasting my time.
Addison is not
a factor here.
What does that even mean?
Do you love her?
That's what I thought.
How is it that a woman
can be woken up from the dead
and I can't even be friends
with Cooper?
Addison's patient woke up?
Yeah. Crazy, right?
Well, maybe you did
the right thing after all.
See, I-I told you.
No, I did the wrong thing with
her, and it turned out okay.
I did the wrong thing
with Cooper,
and it turned out badly.
Still no word
from your patient?
The opposite.
Cooper got him to come in.
He agreed to do treatment.
Then he wouldn't even
have a drink with me.
But you worked together
with good results. Right?
I mean, it's a start.
Stop getting my hopes up.
How long did that man wait
for his wife to wake up?
Ah, he'll come around.
In the meantime,
you come have a drink with me.
I mean, you and Cooper
might not be there yet,
but you and I
can still be friends, right?
Right?
Yes.
Ahh. Mmm.
Hey.
Oh, there you are.
Oh.
Thank you...
For letting me
stay here tonight.
Amelia is at my house,
and I just...
Just wanted it to be...
Us tonight--
just you, me...
And Lucas.
That sounds good to me.
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah. Yeah.
Hi, baby.
Oh.
Kayla woke up.
Wow.
That's incredible.
♪ ...time ♪
Yeah, yeah, it is.
♪ For forever to come ♪
♪ I'm right behind you ♪
Mm.
♪ Don't know
how to leave you ♪
I love you, too.
Oh, I ordered us
some Chinese.
Mmm. Yum.
Hi, buddy.
Hi.
Okay.
Ready? Ohh.
Ooh.
♪ Leave you now ♪
♪ in the corner of my eye ♪
♪ don't know how to... ♪
Hi.
♪ Don't know
how to leave you now ♪
Violet.
♪ Leave you now ♪
♪ I see... ♪
I, uh, I came
straight from the airport.
And...
♪ Don't know
how to leave you now ♪
♪ leave you now ♪
U-Uh...
♪ Now ♪
♪ oh ♪
♪ yeah, yeah ♪
♪ leave you now ♪
I want to see Lucas.
♪♪♪