- Keeping watch?
She's your sister?
What's your name, son?
- Maximus Leonard Goodwin.
- That's a nice name.
Do people call you Max?
How can I help?
And from that moment...
Because of those words,
I knew I was gonna be a doctor.
And, um,
well, I share this with
you now not just so you can
imagine me as an adorable
little five-year-old,
but, um, because...
I want you to remember what
that moment was for you,
when you knew this was
gonna be your calling.
Because this job
can wear you down.
Even on the best days,
takes a toll on your heart.
If you find yourself
in a tough moment,
thinking that all is lost,
feeling like what you
do doesn't matter,
I want you to remember
why you became a doctor
in the first place.
And let that moment
be your North Star.
Uh, I never imagined
I'd be standing here
saying goodbye to this hospital,
to this incredible
group of people.
But I think I did what
I came here to do...
Which is to make New
Amsterdam a place of hope
for those who need it most.
And now the time has
come for new challenges.
As many of you know, I'll be
running Global Health Policy
at the World Health
Organization in Geneva.
Even bigger systems to break
and hopefully put back
together stronger.
But, uh,
I'm gonna miss each
and every one of you.
And I wish I could stay
for even one more day.
But I made a very
special promise
to a very special person.
And, uh, I have to keep it.
Today is the annual
Manhattan Mermaid Parade,
and this year, we are
not gonna miss it.
So, um...
I don't know what to
say other than, uh,
thank you...
For everything.
- Dr. Max Goodwin.
When
you are in the market
for solid information,
I say go to the source.
- Sorry?
- Uh, information.
It's the information booth.
You...
You
got what I need?
- Are you lost?
No. Uh, no.
I'm just looking
for my assistant,
who I was supposed to meet here,
but I'm seeing no sign of her.
And I am, uh, kind of
sweaty from my commute,
so I'm thinking I need
to go take a cold shower
so that I can make a
good first impression
on everybody that I meet,
with the exception of...
What's your name?
- Bart.
- With the exception of Bart,
who has already seen
me in my natural state:
lost, harried, and slightly
dewy with perspiration.
- Who are you again?
- I'm the new medical
director of New Amsterdam.
- Yulia Salenko, female,
32, tachy in the field.
- Casey, check her heart rate.
Hi, Yulia. I'm Dr. Bloom.
Uh, we're just gonna
take some vitals, okay?
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be sorry.
Much rather be
taking care of you
than listening to Dr. Walsh
rant about inflation.
- The Fed's out of
control, and you know it.
- Let's move.
- She's hypotensive
and warm to the touch.
- Yeah, her spleen's enlarged.
Possible endocarditis?
- I was thinking stroke.
- Maybe part of a
broader infection?
- Never seen anything
like this before.
Look at her eyes.
- Uh, I'm sorry, can
you go wait over there
for me, please, by
the nurses' station?
- Let him stay with me, please.
- He'll be close by, I promise.
I just need the
space to work, okay?
- Hey. Hey, bud, we're
gonna hang over here.
- It's okay, Dimi.
Mama's right here.
- I think she's got
fluid in her lungs.
- Okay, this didn't
happen overnight.
Um, Yulia,
how long have you been
feeling sick like this for?
- Weeks.
But we don't have any insurance.
I kept thinking it
would get better, but...
this morning when I
was brushing my teeth,
there was all this blood.
What's happening to me?
- I don't know.
But we're gonna figure it out.
Walsh, let's start fluids.
Casey, page Wilder now.
- Your labs showed
abnormally low cell
counts, Ms. Salenko.
I'm not sure what's
making you so sick,
but I would like to
biopsy your bone marrow.
That's gonna give
us a few more clues.
- She's good to go.
- Okay.
Hey.
- We've numbed your mom's back,
but, you know, the
needles are scary.
You want to wait
outside for this part?
- After we came to America,
my son stopped speaking.
Before, he was such
a little chatterbox.
But I haven't heard
his voice in a year.
- You can stay if you want.
- Squeeze my hand as hard
as you need to, okay?
If I die,
who will take care of my son?
I'm all he has.
- What do you see?
- Well, her biopsy clearly
shows extreme phagocytosis.
- Can you spell that?
- Um, P-H-G...
P-H-A... no, actually,
I... I can't. I'm sorry.
Her white blood cells are eating
all of her other blood cells.
- You're thinking
hemophagocytic
lymphohistiocytosis?
- Come on, guys.
- Just say HLH.
- Uh, HLH is extremely rare.
- I know. I mean, we barely
even touched on
it in med school.
- Yeah, but it's the only thing
that explains her symptoms.
I mean, enlarged spleen,
excessive bleeding,
abdominal pain.
- And it is almost always fatal.
- I mean, I've never
even seen a case before,
let alone treated
one successfully.
- I have treated one
but not successfully.
- Same.
I only know of one doctor
who's been successful.
- Well, that's a start.
- Well, yeah, but I don't
want to call him in.
- Why?
- How can I help?
- Conco's at 23! LB!
Buy! Buy!
- Buy!
Buy!
Today
was insane, man.
You know, I... I thought
last year was peak,
but 2008, get ready.
Yo, it's gonna be next level.
Ugh.
Yo, I... I'm gonna buy me a boat.
- Ugh.
Pete, you get motion sickness
going down an escalator.
- So I'll snort Dramamine.
Wh-what are you gonna
do with all your dough?
- I don't know.
- Spare some change?
- Uh, yeah.
- Yo, get a job, man.
- Uh...
- Gross.
- Hey, hey.
Here.
- God bless you.
- You're just enabling
him, you know.
- You're a real
dirtbag, you know, Pete?
- It's all part of my charm.
- You gonna get that?
- No.
It's my druggie sister.
Oh, my God.
Call 911.
Uh... um, uh, excuse me!
Excuse me, can you help me?
Someone help, please!
I think he needs CPR!
Somebody help me, please!
Can somebody help?
Come on. Somebody, some...
Oh, my God.
Oh, God.
I don't know how to help you.
I don't know how to help.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- Hey.
Our friends down in
the cafeteria tell me
it's chocolate chip cookie day.
And I can hook you up, brother.
How many you want, hmm?
Two, three?
I'm working my best material,
but the kid's not
giving me anything.
- I got this.
Hi, Dimi,
would you come with me?
- His mother's in
critical condition?
- That's not why he won't speak.
She said he hasn't said
a word in over a year,
ever since they fled Ukraine
at the start of the war.
- Okay, well, maybe we need a
translator here just in case.
- No, she assures me
that he speaks English,
when he used to speak.
- Okay, so he's choosing
not to communicate.
That's, um... That's
selective mutism.
- Look, between you and me,
there's a real chance that his
mother's not gonna survive.
Look, if he won't
engage with anyone
and he ends up in
the foster system...
- Selective mutism is treatable.
It's okay. It's very serious,
and it requires
immediate intervention,
but I'm glad you
brought him to me.
I know exactly what to do.
Okay?
Hey, buddy.
So sorry, but I have a bunch
of boring old insurance
stuff to wade through here.
Shouldn't take me more than
an hour or two... three, tops.
You cool to wait?
#Adulting, am I right?
- Oh, come on, baby.
Okay, I am gonna be
so quick, I promise.
- No, Daddy, no.
- Hey, how long can
mermaids last out of water?
- Until they dry?
- That's right.
And that's why I'm
gonna be right back
and get you back in that ocean
before you dry out, okay?
Now, I am gonna give you this.
Why don't you draw
me a mermaid, okay?
I'll be right back.
Hi, Yulia. I'm Dr. Goodwin.
And I come bearing methotrexate.
It's gonna make you
feel a whole lot better.
- What is it?
- You know how we told you
that your white blood cells
are confused and they're
attacking your own body?
This should help,
uh, calm them down.
- I'm sorry.
It's just,
the last few hours have
just been so scary.
And no one seems to know
what's causing this.
- Well, HLH is an
aggressive syndrome.
But it's caused by an
underlying condition
that most people don't
even know they have.
So the real question is,
what's underneath this?
- How do we find out?
- I get to know as much
about you as I possibly can.
Have you had COVID?
That can be a trigger sometimes.
- Mm, no. Not that I know of.
- And where do you live?
What do you do for work?
- Um, my son and
I live in Queens.
But we came from
Ukraine last year.
- You got out?
- After the Russians bombed
a school in our village,
I took Dimi, and we fled.
- Must've been horrible.
- We hid in farms, stables,
stowed away in train cars.
But we made it out.
We left our home behind,
and I vowed to give my son
a better life here, but...
a new country,
no family...
It's been lonely.
And now this illness, it's...
- Mm.
- What's wrong?
- Um...
- What are you doing?
- Well, I'm very sorry,
but I think I made a mistake.
This is not gonna help you.
Hey, brucellosis! Brucellosis.
That's Yulia Salenko's
underlying condition.
- How'd you land there?
- Because when she fled
the war in Ukraine with her son,
they were hiding out
in farms and stables.
It... it's livestock. That's
gotta be how she got it.
- So in order to treat her
HLH, we have to completely
rid her body of all
traces of brucellosis.
- Yeah, I already started
her on a massive regimen
of antibiotics.
- All right, so if she fled
Ukraine when the war
began, that's a year ago.
I mean, the bacteria
would have spread
to every part of her body.
- Yeah.
- That's untreated endocarditis.
- I didn't say it
was gonna be easy.
- Max...
- Floyd, if we don't
at least try, then
she will have come
all this way just to die here,
and her son is gonna be
orphaned in a foreign country.
- I hear you, I do.
But what you're talking about,
this procedure, it
will literally take
dozens of highly trained
surgeons and specialists
to pull it off.
- 53.
By my count, it's gonna take 53.
- You know damn well that money
was for Courtney's braces.
- And if my garage
goes under, then what?
- Your garage is struggling
because you ran it
into the damn ground!
- You know I'm doing what's
best for this family!
- No, you're doing what's best
for Horace... like always!
- You never respect me!
I'm the man of this house!
- Then act like one!
Floyd?
What did you do, baby?
- I put it back
together... For you.
- Clamp.
Scalpel.
Forceps.
Popcorn on a stick.
Okay.
Now ready to implant
porcine aortic valve.
Dr. Wilder, uh...
- There's nowhere
else that I can stand.
- Well, can you...
Just a little...
- No. I have to be
right beside Dr. Gaffen,
and I need to be
able to see Ben.
- We got no wiggle
room over here, Floyd.
Try over there.
- Oh, God.
Oh.
- We just lost the
bypass machine.
- Our patient just died.
But hey, this is why
we rehearse, right?
- Max, we're packed
in here so tight
that if I just breathe, I'm
gonna knock something over.
- I know. We can
rework the plan.
We can do some of the
surgeries individually
instead of simultaneously.
- Anything that's gonna
give us more space
to work in here.
- But it's gonna add time
that we can't afford.
- I can help.
- How?
- I can replace the aortic valve
while her heart's still beating.
Then we can get rid
of this bypass machine
so it doesn't take
up so much space.
- Will that save time?
- Yes.
- While her heart's
still beating?
Have you ever done that before?
- No.
- Okay.
You better start practicing.
- All right, what do you think,
stripes, outrageous pattern?
Which one?
- Neither?
- What, no tie? Huh.
- What about a bolo?
Albert wore a turquoise
one on our first date,
and I found it quite fetching.
- Oh, yes, Albert, the new beau.
When do I get to meet
the lucky fella, huh?
What do you think,
dinner Saturday night?
- Uh, okay.
- Good. We can chat
about his affinity
for Southwestern apparel.
- What are you doing?
- Oh, I'm, uh...
I'm ignoring him.
- Yeah. I can see that.
- Mm-hmm.
- But why?
- Well, because with
selective mutism,
you do not pursue.
You create a path and
let them come to you.
I have set the
table, so to speak.
Now all he has to do
is come and feast.
- He doesn't appear
to be hungry.
- Not even a little bit.
Mm.
- Hey.
Hey, Lu.
- Mermaid Parade?
- I don't think we're gonna
make the Mermaid Parade
this year.
- No.
You said mermaids.
- I know. I know I did.
But then someone
came to our hospital,
and they need our help...
- But you said.
- I know I did, but I...
Look at me.
This patient, she
really needs our help.
And not just me.
This whole hospital,
everybody here, is gonna help.
So we gotta help her.
And hey, you and me,
we're gonna have so
many fun things to do...
I hate New Amsterdam!
- Drug overdose,
found in the park.
Patient's a 62-year-old
male, unresponsive.
- Got this one, boss.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I don't know, I...
I've given up hope on
Vanessa ever getting clean,
ever seeing her again.
But I'm in this
constant state of fear
every time someone comes
crashing through that door.
- Oh, she's bottoming out.
- Uh, we need help over here!
- Yeah, what happened?
- BP's tanking.
- Okay. We gotta do this now.
Let's get her to the OR.
- I thought we had
until tomorrow.
- So did I.
I hope you used
those ten minutes
to work out the kinks,
'cause rehearsal's over.
- What a waste of everything.
I sank all our money
into that thrasher.
Brand-new, made to
last, and what happens?
Snap beans are the top
cash crop 20 years running
until yours truly
starts planting 'em.
And then it's early frost
and seed-corn maggots.
You know how screwed we are now?
Maybe God has it out for me.
Maybe I even deserve it.
- This'll be three
Sundays in a row
I miss church.
People notice, start talking.
Lina Tompkins at Rotary had
to make her little comment,
and now I can't
even look at her.
Worse is the way
they look at me,
at that pathetic woman whose
husband is out catting around.
I just need to
lose a few pounds.
And then he'll
see me. I know it.
Why can't I?
Why am I just... this?
- So Tiff Stinson put
her hand on my arm,
and she "accidentally"
brushes her boobs against me.
That's a signal, right?
But she and Tiff
are best friends,
and I'm with Allie.
No way Tiff keeps
her mouth shut,
but I mean, good God,
she is so much
hotter than Allie.
So maybe I should just go for...
- Why are you telling me this?
- I don't know, freak.
I'm just making conversation.
- No, it's not.
You, Mom, Dad, everyone
just talks atme.
It's always weird,
private grown-up stuff
that they never share
with anyone else.
But why does everyone
feel like they can just
dump all their crap on me?
They act like I'm not even here,
like I'm invisible.
- Listen, you're the
opposite of invisible, Iggy.
You're like a rock or a
mountain or something.
You don't judge.
You just listen.
And I don't know why, but
you being here, listening,
just kind of makes
things better.
- You want something?
You don't have to
talk, just, uh...
Point.
Oh, Mamma mia.
This, uh, little experiment
of mine is not going
how I thought it would.
Can you tell?
Usually people just open
right up to me, you know,
my whole life.
It's kind of a big part
of why I became a doctor.
But you are a tough nut
to crack, my friend.
My biggest and
baddest doctor moves
are not having
any effect on you.
I don't know, maybe I need to...
stop talking like a doctor.
You know, we do have something
in common, me and you.
I know your secret.
Yeah.
Yeah, I didn't talk
much as a kid either.
People would always say I
was such a good listener.
But, uh, you and I both know
that they had that backwards.
I wasn't quiet because
I loved listening.
I was quiet because I was...
terrified of talking.
I hated it so much,
because talking...
You know, really talking...
Means revealing who you are.
Means being seen.
I figured if I just didn't talk,
nobody would ever see
how broken I felt inside,
how scared.
And that broken,
scared part inside
that all this silence
is protecting...
Talking is the only
way to heal that too.
So listen, I am not going
to ask you what you want.
If you want something,
you are gonna have to
reach out for yourself
and take it.
- We're behind, but if
anybody's gotta close,
I'm glad it's you.
- This plan won't work.
- Hello.
Hello, anyone?
Anybody from oncology around?
If this is a prank, hats off.
- Oh, there you are.
I've been looking
everywhere for you.
I'm Kate, your new assistant.
- Oh, so I am in
the right hospital.
- Yeah, of course.
Uh, do you need anything?
- Yeah. I need doctors...
Doctors to run the hospital.
Do you know where
all the doctors are?
- Yeah, well, things are always
a little crazy around here.
- Well, spread the word.
All department heads,
auditorium, 6:00 p.m.
It's about to get even crazier.
- We gotta go back to plan
A, put Yulia on bypass.
- No, it's, uh... We're
two hours behind, Floyd.
That's gonna take time
that we don't have.
What happened to your plan?
- Well, I didn't exactly
get the time I needed to
perfect the technique.
Look, stopping her
heart is tried and true.
- No, her lungs can't
afford the extra time.
She's got one shot left, Floyd,
and it's operating on
her still-beating heart.
- Just because she's got
one shot doesn't mean
that it'll work or that
it's even a good idea, Max.
- I know, but if I
had one shot left,
I would want youto take it.
And Yulia should get no less.
- Okay.
Blood pressure dropping.
Heart rate.
- No sign of hemorrhage.
- 80 over 40. 80 over 40.
Up on the monitors.
- Who are you supposed to be?
- Dr. Ross.
- Ah!
- Hey, give that back.
- Says the brainless monster.
- Give that back to her now!
- Why does she
need a stethoscope?
She can't even hear.
- She thinks you should
be something else,
something less hard for you.
Hey, hey.
Easy, easy.
Forget them.
It's just a costume.
- Lizzie...
- Scalpel.
- Blood pressure's
still dropping.
- Whoa. Whoa, whoa,
whoa, what are you doing?
- Forceps.
- No.
Hey, hey. Elizabeth, stop.
- No!
Starting fluid resuscitation.
Administering.
Filter is in. Filter is in.
Stable.
Thrombosis.
- Emboli are clear.
Emboli are clear.
Blood pressure rising.
- Heart rate stabilizing.
- Standing by.
- Close her up.
- Prep the tray.
- Pressure is elevated.
And normal.
- ♪ I never seen it coming
♪ I couldn't read the signs
♪ Now I know that
it means nothing ♪
♪ But you are
always on my mind ♪
- ♪ But the truth
can be deceiving ♪
- ♪ They told me everything
works out in the end ♪
♪ Everything works
out in the end ♪
♪ They told me everything
works out in the end ♪
- ♪ Everything works
out in the end ♪
♪ Oh-oh, oh, oh
♪ You got me treading
on the water ♪
♪ Because I never
learned to swim ♪
♪ And now I know
that it's all over ♪
♪ Everything works
out in the end ♪
- ♪ Everything works
- No.
- Mm.
- ♪ Long afloat
♪ On shipless oceans
♪ I did all my best to smile ♪
♪ Till your singing eyes
♪ And fingers
♪ Drew me loving
to your isle ♪
♪ And you sang
♪ "Sail to me
♪ "Sail to me, let
me enfold you ♪
♪ "Here I am
♪ Waiting to hold you"
- ♪ Did I dream
♪ You dreamed about me?
♪ Were you here when
I was forced out? ♪
♪ Now my foolish
boat is leaning ♪
- Hey, Lu.
It's time to go.
- ♪ Lovelorn on your rocks
Hey, Lu,
I know that you're sad 'cause
we missed the Mermaid Parade.
But guess what.
We did it.
It took the whole hospital,
even you.
But we saved someone's mommy.
You want to go?
You know what?
You're gonna have thousands
of good days ahead of you.
I promise, you won't
even remember this one.
- ♪ Child, I'm as
riddled as the tide ♪
♪ Should I stand
♪ Amid the breakers
♪ Or should I lie with death
♪ My bride?
♪ Hear me sing
♪ "Swim to me
♪ "Swim to me, let
me enfold you ♪
♪ "Here I am
♪ Waiting to hold you"
- Hi.
I grew up at New Amsterdam.
My mother died in this hospital.
My father spent every
waking second here,
breaking the system so he could
put it back together again,
better and stronger than before.
Doing whatever he could
to help his patients.
I remember my father's last
day as medical director.
He was supposed to take
me to this Mermaid Parade,
just a special day with my dad.
But then he got
called in to help
with an impossible surgery.
And I was so mad.
I thought, this place
has taken my father
away from me yet again.
But then, over the
course of the day,
I saw how hard he
worked to save one life
and how hard everybody
worked together.
And that's when I realized
that New Amsterdam didn't
take my father away from me.
This hospital gave me my father.
Showed me who he was,
who I could be.
And that's the day I realized
I wanted to be just like him.
It was the day I knew I
wanted to be a doctor.
So I wanted to start
by asking all of you
the same thing my
father asked his staff
every hour of every single day.
How can I help?
- ♪ Had a dream that
we were soldiers ♪
♪ Pillow fighting
on the lawn ♪
♪ When I woke,
trial was over ♪
♪ Sea-foam
♪ You are you, sea-foam