Good morning.
Morning.
I'm Jake. We met last week.
Yes, we did.
I was just gonna get some
juice. Hope you don't mind...
Are you a drummer?
Am I a drummer? No.
No, I'm a chef. Well,
actually, just a cook, but...
Lea dates drummers.
I played clarinet
in junior high.
Hmm.
What are you doing out here?
I told you to stay in my room.
I just snuck out
to grab some OJ.
Mmm-hmm.
I was really thirsty.
Okay.
I'm sorry. I should've told
you he was spending the night.
I like Jake.
That's nice of you to say.
I know it's difficult to have
a stranger in your home.
I have to drive Dr. Glassman
to his chemo appointment.
He's five days in
and doing very well.
I'm helping him.
Jake is very sweet.
You know, when you get to know
him, I'm sure you really will like him.
I said I like him.
Will he be spending
the night here a lot now?
No, not a lot.
But would that be a problem?
No.
So, is it cool if I have him
over tonight to watch a movie?
It's cool.
- I have to go.
- Okay.
Good morning, Dr. Glassman.
I let myself in. I'm downstairs.
How are you feeling today?
Good, actually.
Better than yesterday.
Yes, your skin was
a bit pale yesterday.
Today, your color
looks much better.
I brought you your electrolytes.
Thank you. Cheers.
Why did you do that?
I don't like the
flavor of the grape.
Are you experiencing nausea?
No. I didn't like the
flavor. I told you.
I'm fine.
I'm glad you're feeling well.
Let's go, or we're
going to be late.
Yep. The cancer's
not gonna kill itself.
Hey. I was just
thinking about you, too.
Actually, can I call you at lunch?
I'm with some people right now and...
Yes, exactly.
We'll talk later.
Love you.
New girlfriend?
Still in the "call each other
the next morning" phase?
Yeah, you got me.
Actually, no. It was Mia.
We're giving our
relationship another shot.
Wow.
Park, that's great.
Yeah, I told you because
part of the thing with Mia is...
I'm trying to be more open.
Thanks. You didn't need
to explain, but sounds good.
She sounds like
she's good for you.
Yeah.
Of course, if it
doesn't work out,
I'll have to talk to you
about that too, admit I failed.
Or I can be a supportive colleague,
regardless of what happens.
70-year-old female. Neighbor
saw her collapse in her yard.
Unresponsive. No
heartbeat. EKG is flatlined.
Then she'd be cyanotic.
Good capillary refill.
- She's perfusing.
- Stop CPR.
She's breathing. Your
EKG must be broken.
It worked fine on our
call right before her.
Everything works
fine up until it doesn't.
- Nothing.
- Told you.
Hook her up. Let's
check her vitals.
Blood is definitely
flowing to her extremities.
Should we push
epi? Get the crash...
Wait. Everyone, quiet.
Listen.
Is that...
She doesn't have a rhythm
because she has a mechanical heart.
Lana Moore, 34-year-old female, was
slurring her words, symptom passed,
but we found a Grade 2
arteriovenous malformation in her brain.
Are we going to do
endovascular embolization,
or stereotactic
radiosurgery, or resection?
Endovascular embolization.
Patient requests she's
only served green Jell-O
and that we dim all of our
incandescent light bulbs?
Lana has autism.
What are you looking at him for?
It's not like they all know each other.
I was just curious what
his thoughts might be.
I think we should go with
endovascular embolization.
Hmm. Now you know.
The AVM is dangerous,
but the embolization is a
relatively minor procedure.
We'll make a small incision in your leg,
so we can insert a catheter into your...
Are you okay, Javi?
The lights aren't
bothering you too much?
A little.
Lights.
Please, continue.
We'll insert the catheter
into your femoral artery.
Then we'll feed it up
into the arteriovenous...
You brought a dictionary?
Is there something I'm saying
that you don't understand?
Lana loves learning new words.
She's memorized the scientific Latin
name of every bug in South America.
Go ahead, name
any six-legged critter.
I love being quizzed.
Rhinoceros beetle.
Megasoma actaeon. Found in Guyana.
It's the heaviest insect in the world
and weighs as much
as 300 grasshoppers.
Is she right?
I have no idea.
I have to go.
Javi? Javi. Where are you going?
It's 11:15. I have to be home by
noon to watch Judge Judy before work.
It's important to us that your
girlfriend doesn't get stressed out,
so we'd prefer it if you stayed
with her as long as you can.
Lana's not my girlfriend.
We're just roommates.
Still stable?
Diuretics have her O2 sats
up, but she's hypotensive.
And we checked every center
approved to implant mechanical hearts,
but none have any
record of her as a patient.
- Check overseas. I'd start with...
- Mom?
Is it her heart?
The implanted device
appears to be malfunctioning.
Do you have any contact information
for the surgeon who implanted it?
Yes, of course.
Dr. Li Wei. He's in Beijing.
When did she have it implanted?
A little over nine months.
She just went back for a follow-up
exam last month. She was fine.
Can you fix it?
I'm gonna find out.
Hello.
- Don't be stupid.
- What? There's no cameras in here.
Dr. Lim. Dr. Melendez. How
were your respective weekends?
- Good. Checked out some bikes.
- Brushed up on some reading.
Excellent.
I hear the search for
Chief of Surgery is back on.
As is our legal department's
response to the DPH complaint
against both of you, so I
wouldn't get your hopes up.
Probably just as well. I'd rather not
see the two of you competing again.
You seem to be
getting along better.
It's weird.
Is it weird?
They act like a couple, right?
I live with Lea, but
we're not a couple.
Yeah, but you wish you were.
Do you?
Lea has a new boyfriend.
You must be a little jealous.
Why? Lea's my
friend and Lea's happy.
Okay.
Jake, Lea and I can
all be friends together.
Shaun, Lea's new boyfriend
doesn't want to hang
out with the three of you.
If Lea really likes this guy,
she's gonna want to
spend time just with him.
I know. For the sex.
Her AVM has microbleeds.
Her risk of rupture is doubled.
They paged Sunny's surgeon.
He's going to call you in an hour.
Tell them I can't wait that long.
Her cardiac output is low and...
Got it.
He's in surgery.
Excuse me, Dr. Melendez?
I'm Grace Lee,
Sunny Lee's daughter.
They told me downstairs
that you're my mother's doctor.
Yes.
Get them to send her records and
everything they can about the device.
Manufacturer, model
number, manuals...
Your mother's stable.
But we're struggling to
get the information we need
from her doctor in China.
I don't understand.
Her doctor's in China?
Like, on vacation?
No. Her cardiac surgeon.
Your sister can fill you in on
everything we've done so far.
I really need to get
back on this phone call.
Wait...
I don't have a sister.
We met 10 years ago, while I
was volunteering at a senior center.
We hit it off.
Neither of us had anyone
in our lives at the time.
People assumed we
were mother and daughter
because we did
everything together.
After a while, we
just went with it.
She'll be glad to see you.
You look like you've put
your problems behind you.
"Problems"?
She told me about
your issues with drugs.
Oh, my God. She
caught me smoking pot.
Once. I was a teenager.
- So, you're fine?
- Of course I'm fine.
Then you don't really have an excuse
for not calling for 15 years, do you?
They want her back.
They've arranged for transport.
They'll do the
repairs in Beijing.
Is that safe? Can she travel
for that long in her condition?
It's a specially-equipped plane
for patients requiring
urgent medical assistance.
And 20 hours in the air is
much safer than at least that long
on an operating table here
while we basically fly blind.
- Okay.
Prep her for transport.
The microbleeds indicate that it
may already be starting to rupture.
If it goes, you could suffer
permanent brain damage or death.
Because of that, embolization is
no longer our preferred approach.
We want to open
you up and cut it out.
Can you try talking to her?
Just because I
have autism doesn't...
I'm not asking you
because you have autism.
I'm asking you because you're
her doctor and I'm getting nowhere.
The sting of the Japanese giant
hornet can dissolve human flesh
and attack the nervous system.
Recommended treatment includes
oral antihistamine and acetaminophen.
Comforting choice of words.
It's 6:30. Dinner time.
I brought burgers and
Jell-O. This one's yours.
Lana can't eat now. We're
trying to schedule surgery to...
I could die.
Surgery sounds scary,
but necessary, so I'll do it.
"big feet got there first. Johnny
stumbled, caught himself,
"and swung silently
about at Dove.
"" Gosh, Johnny, I'm
sorry, ' snickered Dove.
""Sorry? You're going to be a
lot sorrier. I just didn't notice...""
Shaun, what are you doing?
Reading to you
from Johnny Tremain.
You're reading words.
You're not reading sentences.
This edition of Johnny
Tremain is 320 pages long.
To get through the entire thing, I
need to read 270 words per minute.
You don't have to finish
the book in one sitting.
Oh, yes, that's
how I read novels.
I want to know where
the characters end up.
You know what? Let's just stop.
I can go slower.
I'm not listening, anyway.
- Are you in pain?
- No, no, I'm not in...
You seem fatigued.
You know what? I
have a good idea.
Why don't you take
out the garbage?
Thank you.
Where is your recycling?
It's under the sink.
Dr. Glassman, this
cannot be recycled.
If it's broken, it cannot be
recycled, because shards of glass...
I don't care, Shaun. I didn't
ask you to re-sort the garbage.
I just asked you to take
it out. Can you do that?
Your call light is on.
How can I help you?
Any new symptoms or discomfort?
Lana?
Rhinoceros beetle?
I'm gonna get Javi on the
phone. You can talk to both of us.
Do these doors lock?
No.
Do you want them to?
Is there someone
you're worried about?
Is it Javi or someone else?
I'm nervous about the surgery.
Dr. Lim is an excellent
surgeon. I've seen her do...
I'd like Javi to come
and have sex with me.
I think an orgasm
would help calm me.
Do the blinds close?
She's gonna need
a norepinephrine drip
to maintain her
pressure during transport.
Mom?
You look pretty.
Mom, I've been so worried.
You shouldn't have. Teresa
takes good care of me.
I'm so glad.
Why did you never call me?
You made it clear. You
wanted nothing to do with me.
I just wanted to
live my own life.
So that's what you got.
Your own life, without me.
- This isn't a good time to...
- You were so good.
Straight A's, always so
smart. You threw it all away.
You never understood.
Dad did. Dad wanted
me to be happy.
He wanted you to have fun
as a child, not waste your life.
Singing is not a career.
Sunny, you need to calm down.
Grace, your mother cannot
handle this stress right now.
Teresa... Teresa is a teacher.
Mom, stop. Listen
to the doctor...
You forgot about me.
I wish you'd stayed away.
Would have...
Her arterial blood
pressure is dropping.
Start bagging and give her
40 Lasix. I'm calling a code.
Say, can you hear?
Is there a meaning
to your grief?
Where there is pain
You see grace
- Shaun?
- Yes, it's Shaun.
I've picked out a very good movie
that we can all watch together.
Not the time, Shaun.
I made popcorn.
Mmm.
I'm just gonna...
Just stay here. Sorry.
Shaun, we kinda need
some privacy right now.
I also bought orange juice for Jake.
He was looking for some in the fridge.
Okay.
I thought you said
you were okay with this.
Jake will like the movie,
Lea. It's about a chef who...
Shaun, but you're not
respecting boundaries.
If Jake and I are friends, then
we can all spend time together.
Shaun, of course
we can all be friends.
That would be great.
It's just, sometimes,
it's gonna be just me and Jake.
Without you.
For the sex?
And some other times, too.
Okay?
Okay.
Just give us a minute,
and we can watch the movie
in the living room together.
Okay.
Having sex right now
is extremely dangerous
for someone in Lana's condition.
I studied the pre-op list
of things I couldn't do.
Sex was not on the list.
We'll update the list.
Anything that elevates
her blood pressure
could rupture the AVM before
we get a chance to remove it.
You will definitely need to
abstain until you're fully recovered.
Seems like you two are
more than just roommates.
Why?
You care for each
other, you have sex.
It's convenient. He's available.
And it's frequently
better than masturbation.
- High praise.
- And he leaves afterward.
She doesn't like being
touched when she sleeps.
- Mmm.
- Are you two exclusive?
Lana and Javi don't have
to define their relationship
in order to make it
more digestible for you.
Clearly, whatever it
is, is working for them.
Now, you need to get some rest.
We're gonna do your
surgery at 10:00 a.m.
Sunny's on full life support.
Unfortunately, she
can't be flown to China.
Her condition is beyond the scope
of the plane's medical facilities.
Dr. Melendez is discussing next
steps with Sunny's surgeon in China.
No daughter would treat a wonderful
woman like Sunny the way you did.
Does a wonderful woman refuse
to go to her daughter's recitals?
Then, when she gets
accepted to Juilliard, cut her off?
Tell her she'll never make
it, that she'll wind up broke
and on the streets?
Gently incise the dura.
Nicely done.
And there's our
AVM. Aneurysm clips.
It'd be nice to have
what Lana and Javi have.
All the benefits of a relationship
without the emotional baggage.
The emotional baggage
is the relationship.
Everybody has their issues. The
point is to sort them out together.
"Yeah, that's all it takes," agreed
all the single people in the room.
I can't get under the AVM.
It's much closer to Broca's
area than the MRI indicated.
Any damage could
destroy her ability to speak.
And what if we use
stereotactic image-guidance?
That would only
show us where we are.
It wouldn't tell us if
we're affecting function.
But if we track Lana's vocal
function during the operation,
it will help us avoid the
speech center nerve tracts.
You want to operate on
her while she's awake?
We can barely get answers
out of her at the best of times.
How do you think it'll go while her
skull is open in the middle of an OR?
Well, it's a good thing she
has a roommate who can help.
It's hard to walk away.
We get angry, we
want to run away,
but when it's family...
I'm not angry.
When I got the call
telling me she was here,
all I could think about was
how my lousy, bitter mother
was about to die alone.
That it wasn't her fault,
it was just her nature.
So, I needed to be
here, to let her know
that she was loved,
in spite of everything.
And then I found
out about Teresa.
Saw them together.
Saw that my mother
was capable of caring,
capable of warmth and love.
Just not for me.
Dr. Park, please
report to ICU 2.
She's bleeding from her cannula
site. She's intolerant to the ECMO.
We can't wait for the new heart.
We have to try and
repair this one ourselves.
China thinks
Sunny's heart failure
is most likely due to a
broken blade in the impeller.
They're suggesting
we weld it back together
using an intraoperative
device, which we don't have.
We could repair it
with fibrin BioGlue.
The blade spins at 1,200
RPMs. The glue won't hold.
What if we use the schematics
to 3D-print a new impeller?
The plastic replacement
probably wouldn't hold up long term.
We don't need long term.
We just need it to work until the
replacement arrives from China.
Let's get these to the lab.
- You need me in the OR?
- Yes.
While you operate on her
brain with her head open?
You wouldn't be able
to see what we're doing.
You won't see any blood...
What's the central
illuminance of the OR?
- I don't know.
- 140,000 lux.
140,000 lux is way
worse than a grocery store.
I can't go to grocery stores.
We can provide you
with protective gear
and eye shades that can
filter out some of the lights.
Bright lights are like
needles in my eyes.
Megasoma actaeon.
Found in Guyana.
It's the heaviest insect in the world and
weighs as much as 300 grasshoppers.
Do you like playing
insect trivia with Lana?
This is crazy. You shouldn't
do it because of trivia night.
You should do it
because you love her.
Your life is better with her.
You're a better person with her.
You need her.
That's what love is.
Do it because you love her.
I don't love her.
She's my roommate.
The impeller blades are fine.
The bearings are
functioning properly.
Electrical consumption is good.
Maybe the machine
isn't the problem.
Heart failure is either caused
by insufficient pumping
or constricted outflow.
Since her pump is fine...
She doesn't have
valvular stenosis.
The surgeons removed her aortic
valve when they implanted this device.
It could be the aorta itself.
If it narrowed, that
would reduce her outflow,
cause her pressure to drop.
If we do an intraop-angio,
we'd see evidence of that.
Call X-ray. Have them
bring a C-arm, stat.
Dr. Glassman.
I got you cherry Gastrolyte.
Shaun, I'm fine. You
can go back to work.
At the Nathan
County Fair, I was 14,
and you got a cherry
slushy and said it was your...
Why do you have an IV?
It's just fluid, Shaun,
with potassium.
I had a nurse come
by from the hospital.
I could have done this.
You're busy.
I'm helping you.
You wouldn't need the
fluids if you listened to me.
I know.
You didn't drink the Gastrolyte
I brought you, but now...
Shaun, my head
really hurts right now.
How long have you
been experiencing pain?
It pretty much never stops.
That's not true.
I asked you if you were in pain
last night and you said you weren't.
I was in pain last night, Shaun.
I just didn't want you to worry.
Why would you lie
about a symptom?
Why would you lie, Dr. Glassman?
This could...
This is why, Shaun. This is why.
I can handle the pain. I
can handle the nausea...
- You have nausea?
- Yes, yes, I have nausea.
Okay, you should
stop the PCV chemo.
- Shaun...
- Okay. You should stop.
- I'm going to call Dr. Blaize.
- No, Shaun! No!
I am trying to help you.
I am trying to help you, but
you are not a compliant patient.
You don't rest...
- Shaun.
- When I tell you to rest.
You don't follow the
diet that I am giving you.
Shaun, will you just go,
please? Will you just go?
I promised that
I would help you.
You're not my doctor, Shaun!
I don't...
I don't want you here.
I'm sorry. I don't
want you here.
I don't know how to help you.
Then stop trying.
You're not helping.
You can't help, Shaun.
He's in pain and frustrated and
nauseous, and taking it out on you.
nauseous, and I can't help him.
- That may be true.
- So, what do I do?
When there is nothing you
can do, you have to accept that.
You have to stop trying to help.
That's what he said.
Thank you, Lea.
My life is better with you.
Mine, too.
We're in the aorta now.
If there is a narrowing, we should
see a sudden rise in pressure.
We should be able to replace
the narrowed part
with a graft. Metz.
This is a...
Horse.
Lana, what do you see here?
We need you to
keep talking to us.
- Have we already done damage?
- It's too soon, I think.
We need to stop.
If we leave the AVM intact
and it ruptures, it will kill her.
Lana, do you understand?
I have to keep going,
but if you stop talking,
you may never talk again.
Hand me the bipolar forceps.
Dr. Lim, there's a Javi Maldonado
insisting he should be in here.
I'm sorry to keep you waiting.
The surgery was a success.
You can see her
once she wakes up.
Thank you.
She wasn't great with you,
but she's great with Teresa.
That doesn't mean she
loves her more than you.
May just mean...
She's not the same
person anymore.
As soon as she saw me,
she started giving me crap.
The same crap.
Actually, the first
thing she said was,
"You look pretty."
Lana, what's on the screen?
A lion.
And what is that?
Lana, what's on the screen?
Javi?
Madagascan hissing cockroach.
Gromphadorhina portentosa.
One of the few insects
who give birth to live young,
rather than laying eggs.
Keep going. You
both are doing great.
Long-tailed South
African scorpion.
Hadogenes troglodytes.
Reaches a length of over eight
inches, the longest scorpion in the world.
You'll still need to fly to
China to get checked out,
but everything looks great.
Thank you.
Mom, Grace is outside.
- I think you should talk to her.
- Why?
Because she's your daughter.
- I'll step out.
- It's okay.
Mom.
Since we stopped talking,
there hasn't been a day I
haven't thought about you.
That I haven't missed you.
I'm sorry,
for everything.
I sat in the back,
at the Troubadour.
You were singing I Wish It
Would Rain with that band.
I cried.
It was beautiful.
Can you tell me your name?
Do you remember your name?
Of course I remember my name.
Lana.
And you're Javi.
I think I love you.
I think you do, too.
Do you want to stay in bed
with me after we have sex?
No.
Dr. Glassman?
I'm not here to help.
Take me to the station
And put me on a train
I got no expectations
To pass through here again
Once I was a rich man
Now I am so poor
But never in my sweet short life
Have I felt like this before
Thank you.