- Previously on
"New Amsterdam"...
- Dr. Helen Sharpe is
here in New York City
representing the NHS'
fight against cancer.
- Did you know she
was in New York?
- No, not until I saw her on TV.
- I wish I could
have seen your face.
It's not funny, all right?
Elizabeth did see my face.
Did she take a video?
No, she didn't.
Let's just say it
wasn't the best
way to start a relationship.
Wait, you and Elizabeth?
- Almost, until I saw
Helen and basically
frickin' short
circuited, which I'm sure
is what every woman wants
in a prospective boyfriend.
- Did you think that we'd still
be boyfriends at this age?
No, I did not.
Yeah. So you gonna see Helen?
I don't know. Yes. No. Maybe.
I... she hasn't even
reached out, OK?
I don't even know if
it's on the table.
- You're not even a
little bit curious?
- Of cour... which part?
- I mean, if she still
has feelings for you.
If some part of her wishes
she could take it all back.
I mean, what if she came back
to New York for a reason?
I know, I know, but I can't.
I can't be curious, OK?
Not about any of it, because
I can't open that door.
I can't fall back
into something that I
worked so hard to get over.
I just need to find
Elizabeth, apologise,
make this right, OK?
Hey.
Hi.
911.
And I have a coffee 911.
- Um, you know what, would
you mind interpreting for me,
because I'm just a
little more clear when
I'm not using the
wrong words, or, uh,
unintentionally swearing.
- Max, please do not include Ben
in our private conversations.
Oh, thank God.
Thank you.
Hmm.
- So, this is my emergency, huh?
- Oh, it's urgent,
Dr. Reynolds.
- Come here.
- Mm.
Mmm.
I can't believe it.
One more week before
you have to go.
- That is the beauty of
dating a travelling nurse.
- Mm-hmm.
What is that?
Less time, and more heat.
I might have a meeting.
Do you have a meeting?
I can't remember right now.
OK.
Manny?
- There's the guy that
sliced into the phrenic nerve
in anatomy lab.
- No, no, that's only
'cause the cadaver shook
when you dropped
that slice of pizza
in the abdominal cavity.
- What's up, man?
- It's been a minute.
- Yeah, too many. Too many.
How you doing? You look good.
What are you doing here?
It's my son.
He's in the ICU.
It's a fusiform aneurysm
in the vertebral basilar artery,
very close to the
Circle of Willis.
- That's deep in the
base of the brain, yes?
Yes.
Yes, where the blood travels.
But the aneurysm
can blow any minute.
Manny, we need to
operate immediately.
I've called Dr. Emilio Nieves.
He is the best neurosurgeon
on the East Coast.
- You know how delicate cutting
into that part of the brain is.
Slightest vibration,
my boy's own heartbeat
could throw Nieves
off by a millimetre
- and he could never wake up.
- Right. Right.
But that's not
going to happen, OK?
I'm going to stop
Manny Jr.'s heart
before Nieves starts.
We're going to get his body
temp down to 45 degrees,
put him in cold plegia.
All right, suspended
animation. All right?
That way there's no
pulse to throw Nieves off
as he makes the
incision to reconstruct
the basilar artery using
an internal mammary artery.
And when he's done, I'll
rewarm your son's body,
restart his heart, and
everyone goes home.
- Hearing it as a
doctor, it makes sense.
- But when it's your child...
- Hey.
I still owe you for totalling
that '66 Dodge Dart.
Don't I?
Let me make it up to you.
♪ ♪
Dr. Dyson, exactly how long
do you and your
team need for this?
- A quarter of New
Amsterdam's thallium allotment
is unaccounted for, Dr. Bloom.
- Right, and I'm not
trying to diminish
the severity of a missing
radioactive element.
But my ED is clean,
and my mood is bad,
so I would appreciate
a real measure of time.
Uh, as long as it takes.
- 50-year-old male, hypotensive,
experiencing shortness of breath
due to multiple bee stings.
- Oh, damn it, Dave.
- You know him?
- Yeah, only because this is
his third time here this week.
He's in anaphylactic shock.
- Yeah, I was
transferring a beehive,
and the cover ripped
for some reason.
- Maybe because
you're an accountant.
That's what I do.
Who I am is an
urban outdoorsman.
- OK, let's get him
on 250 milligrams
of hydrocortisone and 50
milligrams of Benadryl.
- My eye feels
like it's on fire.
Ahh! Ahh!
- There's a stinger in
the inner canthal region.
- Dave, I need
you to stay still.
- I don't like things in my eye.
- Then you should stop
leaving your office, hey?
Hold him still.
Max, Max, uh...
- Yeah, I got it. I got it.
- Hold him still.
- Got it.
- That was fast.
OK, let's take him to Bay 24,
and let's monitor him
for the rest of the day.
Got it.
- No, wait! No, stop!
- I can't be here all day.
- Why not?
- I'm taking my employees
on a Great Escape.
- Sure, as long as it's
in Bay 24, that's fine.
- Sorry, Great
Escape? What is that?
- Day-long team-building
trips that take New Yorkers
off the grid and up a mountain
for an eye-opening escape
from city life
and city problems.
The tickets are also
expensive and non-refundable.
Yeah, I'll take them.
I'll take all of them.
Fine, but I only do Zelle.
- You won't even
do patio seating
at a four-star restaurant
and now you want
to venture off into the wild?
- I just think it'd
be nice to spend a day
outdoors with my friends
and my coworkers, right?
- Hm, this is because Helen's
back in New York, isn't it?
- No, no, no, I just
want to spend more time
with the people who are
actually in my life.
And after everything that
you have been going through,
wouldn't that be nice?
Brunstetter, page Candelario.
- That's what I'm talking about.
Great idea, two words.
- Cape Cod.
- Nope.
Corporate retreat.
That is very different.
- It is very different,
but everything
is packed and prepared
and ready to go
so that we can have
some food, some fun,
and maybe a little adventure.
Max, I have appointments.
- That's why I've got
substitute doctors who
can step in at a moment's notice
so that we can take a day to
remember what truly matters.
Plus, we'll probably
spend some time in a, uh,
Tent, so maybe we
could, uh, you know,
do important doctor stuff.
- I'll go.
- Sorry.
So what do you think?
Yes! Thank you.
Value of shared assets.
Division of property.
Child custody rights.
I guess divorce comes down
to these little sticky notes.
- Hey, buddy, you want
to climb a mountain?
Yes.
Thank you. Thank you.
That was easy.
Throw on a backpack, amigo,
because I am taking you
to climb a mountain.
I guess Helen texted you.
She did.
I don't know if I want
to see her, though.
I don't even know if I want
to be in the same city as her.
- 'Cause you don't
want to be tempted?
It's like this.
I just found out Luna
has a peanut allergy,
so naturally I purge the
whole house of all peanuts,
all peanut butter, because even
though she knows that it could
make her stop breathing,
she still loves it,
and she probably always will.
So the only thing to do
is to remove it completely
so it doesn't, you
know, kill her.
Yeah, yeah.
Max, look, I got a big surgery
so I'm going to have to pass,
but I understand and
fully support you
getting the hell out of here.
Thanks, buddy.
You going to get that?
Max.
Get out of those scrubs.
Get ready for the
Great Escape, right?
♪ Poor old Granddad ♪
♪ I laughed at all his words ♪
♪ I thought he
was a bitter man ♪
♪ He spoke of women's ways ♪
♪ They'll trap you ♪
♪ Then they use you,
before you even know ♪
♪ For love is blind, and
you're far too kind ♪
♪ Don't ever let it show ♪
♪ I wish that I knew
what I know now ♪
♪ When I was younger ♪
♪ I wish that I knew
what I know now ♪
♪ When I was stronger ♪
♪ The can-can, such
a pretty show ♪
♪ Will steal your heart away ♪
Are we almost there?
'Cause this is a lot of steps.
- Welcome to the
top of the world.
- Wow.
- Oh, it's amazing.
- Whoa.
This is unreal.
Where are we?
Tennessee, this is amazing.
It's incredible.
- Nope. Nope. No.
- Oh.
Whoa.
Wow.
- How high up do
you think we are?
- I... 100, maybe, 150 feet.
It's 288 feet.
OK, well, that's, uh, high.
- Maybe Iggy had the
right idea hanging back.
Wait, Max, is Iggy OK?
Why didn't he come?
- He, uh, he just wanted
to be alone for a minute.
I think he's going
through some stuff.
- Yeah, well, he's
missing out on a lot.
Yeah.
All right, so now what?
We're going over the edge.
- We're go... how's that?
- One by one, we're
going to harness up,
use this belay line to rappel
down the face of the cliff.
Any questions?
Uh, I'll go first.
Are you crazy?
- All I heard is
"I'll go first."
- Cardiopulmonary
bypass initiated.
Time to stop the heart.
- Core temp is
down to 45 degrees.
- All right. Here we go.
ACT 466.
Wait for it.
OK, patient is in
suspended animation.
Dr. Nieves, you're up.
Time for you to show
off. You got one hour.
We'll need every second.
Three-hole punch.
- I always thought he was
throwing away his career,
with starting a family so young.
Now I realise how wrong I was.
And if I can't have it,
least I can do is make
sure he doesn't lose it.
Radiation safety team.
- Hey, hey, hey, get
the hell out of here!
- We are tracking
a radiation spill.
Get the hell out!
We are doing a surgery.
- We discovered our
thallium supply had a leak.
Probably spilled in here.
- Do not come into
the surgical field.
Found it! It's in here.
We need everybody to
evacuate immediately.
- My patient has a
blade in his brain.
If we try to move
him, he's dead.
- He also is being
exposed to potentially
lethal amounts of radiation.
Not just the boy,
everybody is being exposed.
- OK.
- Come on.
- All right, people,
here's the deal.
These excursions aren't
just about physically
getting out of the city.
It's about getting away
from the thoughts that
cloud what really matters.
If I stood in the
middle of Fifth Avenue
and I asked people what
their deepest desires were,
I'd probably hear a
lot of people saying
they want to be rich.
That is not what
they really want.
So what do they really want?
Can we speed this up, please?
It's different for everyone.
And in my experience, this
is the best way to find out.
Because when you take a
backwards leap off an almost
300-foot-high cliff, well,
what you really want tends
to become very clear.
Yeah, are we good to go?
- Oh, sounds like
someone's excited
for their first rappel.
- As you're in freefall...
- Yeah.
- Just think about what
you really want in life.
That's it?
We're just going to...
OK, uh...
OK.
Oh.
Whoo.
Ahh!
OK, last but not least.
- Yeah.
- Any questions?
- Uh, think I'm ready
as I'll ever be.
- All right, you
know what to do.
Yeah.
OK.
OK. Wait.
What if I don't
know what I want?
Step back and find out.
I'm a little bit jealous.
- Oh, my God.
- I got to be honest.
It's unbelievable.
Max.
Max, incredible, right?
Yeah, it's incredible.
Hey. Hey.
Oh, my God.
Let's get her on her side.
Easy, easy, easy.
How's her pulse? Anything?
Starting chest compressions.
- Non-responsive.
A broken femur, shattered wrist,
possible pelvic fracture.
Max!
- We need an evac.
Call an evac.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
- Who's got the SAV pump?
- Check around her body.
It might have fallen
out of the bag.
I know she has one.
- OK.
- Oh.
- Got it, got it.
- You got it?
Oh, yeah.
Damn it.
- All right, try
this cell phone.
Yeah, yeah. Give me a sec.
OK, OK.
No, we got a problem here, guys.
- All right, if we don't get
a rescue helicopter here,
she's got no chance.
- Wait, when was the last
time any of us had service?
- Back where we parked,
right? I'll go back.
I'll go back.
I'll follow the trail.
I'll get... I'll hit service
before then, probably, right?
What other option do we have?
I'm going. I'm going.
- These protective
lead shields were
designed for X-rays
and should offer you
some protection in here.
Closing sutures.
- You need to put
this on, Dr. Reynolds.
Not going to happen.
I'm not going to
compromise my mobility.
- You're risking
further exposure.
- I don't care. The
patient comes first.
This particular patient is
too important, all right?
Is it really necessary to
clear the observation deck?
- Thallium is an airborne
radioactive substance.
We clear the area.
That's protocol.
This is the last operating
room running on this floor,
so I would strongly advise you
and your team to find a way...
There isn't one!
All done here.
Surgical reconstruction
complete.
- You and your team
need to exit the zone.
- This way, please.
- Show-off.
Good luck, Floyd.
- All right, begin
reperfusion and rewarming.
Reperfusion started.
- Dr. Reynolds, these
dosimeters measure exposure.
The second any of
them starts beeping,
we need to pull you
out, no argument.
Fine, let me work.
Gonna have you back in no time.
OK.
Hello?
Hey.
Hi.
Uh, I'm Iggy.
Are you OK?
Just lost.
Yeah. Yeah, I'm OK.
I just... I fell.
It's nothing.
- My family is out here camping.
I just got separated from them.
OK, but they're nearby?
I don't know.
You lost too?
- No, I'm not lost, I'm, uh...
No, I'm looking for cell
service, but I got to...
I got to keep going, so...
Can I come with you?
Then you can call
my parents too.
Can you run?
OK, come on.
- What is that?
- Smart AED.
It uses the phone's
battery as a charge.
I got it the last
time Vanessa OD'd.
OK.
This one goes here.
OK, clear.
- Nothing.
Going again.
- Slow but steady.
She's alive.
This rock face is unstable.
We got to get her out of here.
Let's move these.
There's no way.
They're too heavy.
- It's bedrock, it's
not going to move.
She's wedged in.
Her rhythm is unstable.
- Her body is going
in and out of shock.
- What if Iggy doesn't
make it in time?
We need to build a fire.
- The smoke could
draw attention.
I'll help you.
Come on.
Oh, God.
You move fast.
- Yeah, I'm, uh, I'm worried
about it getting dark.
Work out a lot?
I try.
Good for you.
My family loves exercise.
I just really never
gotten into it.
Worried you're
going the wrong way?
My sense of direction is awful.
My brother says if
I have two choices,
I should choose one
and go the other way,
but he's also kind of douche.
- Hey, uh, is your
family anywhere nearby?
You think, like... does any
of this look familiar to you?
- I actually need to
tell you something.
I didn't get separated.
I ran away.
Why would you do that?
Don't get snippy.
It's not like you didn't run
away when you were my age.
What are you talking about?
- You ran away after
your dad found you
sneaking a candy bar for
your new secret hiding place
under the porch.
So he slapped you
in the head, hard.
And then you ran away.
A couple of hours
later, you wussed out,
and you went right back.
Who are you?
I'm you.
This is all my fault.
- It's your fault that
our guide's anchor
broke free from the mountain?
- We're only here because I
was trying to avoid Helen.
- Tennessee would
be here either way.
Only with a bunch
of tax accountants.
- Look, she'd be dead
if we weren't here,
and so would they.
So, thank God you're
avoiding Helen.
Clearly, the right move.
- Give me that.
- OK.
Done this before?
- Jewish summer camp,
when I wasn't sneaking off
- to smoke with the boys.
- Mm.
- You know, for months
after she left...
For months, I would have done
anything to see her, anything.
Just to ask her why.
I used dream of this moment.
- You're doing the
right thing, Max.
Look, you going to see Helen,
it would be like me going to see
a hundred milligrams
of Adderall.
- Whatever she has to
say, it's not gonna help.
Just keep looking
forward, not behind.
- Think I'll take
that as a sign.
What was that?
Rock slide.
I've got Ben.
Yeah, I got Tennessee.
Stop, stop.
This whole side
is going to fall.
Don't!
Just go.
I need you to listen to me.
We got to get you out of here.
I got to get you out of here.
There's only one way to do that.
My foot.
No. Please, no.
- The rockslide will kill
you. It's the only way.
Tennessee, look at me.
It's the only way.
OK.
- OK.
- My bag.
In here.
Bite down on this.
Hold her steady.
OK.
Look at me.
It's OK.
Here.
OK.
Are you ready?
- Did I hit my head?
- You wish.
That would mean you don't
have huge emotional issues.
- You're not real, and I don't
Yeah, right.
You can't even tell your
friends how sad you are.
I don't have time for this.
- Oh, like you don't have time
to sign your divorce papers?
I'm not going to.
I'm gonna ask Martin
for another chance.
- Come on, we both know
that's not going to happen.
Plus, you dumped him, which
frankly blows my mind,
because he's super hot.
Like, I'm psyched to meet him.
- You'll understand
when you're older.
True love is worth fighting for.
I had to leave because I
had to figure out who I was.
I did that.
Now I can go back.
Classic us.
Running away and going back.
Why did you go back?
I mean, you ran away, hung
out in a park for four hours,
and then you went right back,
even though nothing had changed.
Like, what's the point?
Uh...
I don't know.
It wasn't all bad.
It wasn't.
I missed my mom.
I, uh, I missed my brother when
he wasn't being a jerk to me.
I didn't want to say goodbye
to those things forever.
Eventually, you did leave.
Never came back.
Yeah.
I realised that was the
price of a better life.
Sometimes it's scary to walk
away from the good things,
but you have to.
It's what you have to
do to move forward.
- That's the funny
thing about being lost.
Clearly it's not about
knowing your way forward.
It's knowing that the
answer isn't looking back.
Got it.
All right, let's get her up.
Easy. Watch her head.
Got her?
OK, you're doing great.
- You're doing great, Tennessee.
- Keep moving! Keep moving!
Max, there's too much blood.
- All right, all right,
set her down, set her down.
Easy, easy.
How's she doing?
Fast and weak.
- All right, she's going to
go into hypovolemic shock
unless we tighten
the tourniquet.
It's soaked through.
- Uh...
Yeah, she's right.
We need to cauterise her leg.
We have the fire.
- We don't have...
Metal. We need metal.
A carabiner?
It's going to have to do.
- All right, we got
to get him off bypass.
What's the core temp?
- You need to step
out of the OR.
Now!
Core temp is 98.6.
OK. Come on.
Let's go. Follow me.
Ready, Dr. Reynolds.
OK.
We're going to take
him off bypass.
Suture?
Good. All right.
Get those paddles ready.
All right, restarting the heart.
Charging.
Clear.
OK, going again.
Charging, clear.
Going again.
- Dr. Reynolds, you need
to step out of the OR.
Going again. Charge.
- Dr. Reynolds,
you need to leave.
Come on.
- You shocked the
heart four times.
Three times is protocol.
- You need to come with me.
- Come on.
Come on.
The patient is unresponsive!
- Not going to lose you.
Not going to lose you.
- You've been exposed to
high levels of radiation.
You need to come
with us right now.
Come on. Damn it!
OK.
All right, hold her.
Hold her tight.
He's not going to die today.
Intracardiac epi.
On it.
Inject just above my fingers.
One milligram epi in.
Dr. Reynolds, call it.
Come on, come on, come on.
- There's nothing
more you can do.
Get yourself to safety.
Wait a minute, wait.
Dr. Reynolds, call it!
Wait a second.
I got something.
Yeah, I got something.
Oh, my God.
- All right, get him
to a new OR, now.
Lauren.
Over here!
Hey!
Iggy did it!
Hey, Floyd.
Thank you. Thank you.
Floyd, my oldest friend.
Thank you for saving my family.
Consider the car debt repaid.
Thank you.
- Um, I'm...
I'm sorry, the radiation
has got me all, uh...
I just...
It's just between, uh, you know,
this and you leaving.
- Why do you act like everything
is over and done with?
- It's 'cause you're
leaving in six days.
Yes.
Only 'cause you never
asked me to stay.
Iggy, hey.
You OK?
Hey.
Yeah, yeah, fine.
I'm just embarrassed, mostly.
- What were you doing
up on a mountain?
Um, I was gaining clarity.
I, uh... I signed
the divorce papers.
- We don't need to worry
about that right now.
Yes. Yes, we do.
Yes, we do.
Because I have been, um...
I've been having a really
hard time accepting
that what we had is over.
But sometimes to move forward,
you have to leave
something behind.
Our marriage is over.
I am certain of that now.
You seem pretty OK with it.
Yeah.
Because I finally
know the direction
that I want to be headed in.
Martin, will you go
on a date with me?
♪ Walk out the door ♪
♪ And I bet you ain't got
nothing left to learn ♪
♪ It's better that way
'cause you never get burned ♪
♪ And you try not to think
about what might have been ♪
♪ 'Cause you know this
town is just sink or swim ♪
♪ Do you miss me? ♪
Vanessa, Vanessa.
I'm really sorry.
I thought you were someone else.
Wait, um, I'm Lauren.
I'm three years sober.
And there's a seat right
next to me if you want it.
- Why do you care
what happens to me?
- Because today I
asked the universe
to let me help someone...
who used to be just like me.
- ♪ Now I hear
you're in love ♪
♪ With some big city man ♪
♪ And together you're
making your big city plans ♪
♪ And you hope he don't
find out about who you are ♪
♪ That we used to catch
fireflies in mason jars ♪
♪ And we used to go down
to the county fair ♪
♪ And we listened to
bluegrass in summer air ♪
♪ And we danced all night
as the rain came down ♪
♪ And you held my hand as
we slept on the ground ♪
♪ And we wrote our names
in the old oak wood ♪
♪ I guess some things don't
work out like they should ♪
♪ Do you miss me? ♪
♪ Do you miss me, yeah ♪