Previously on
"The Resident"...
Bell, yank that sucker
and get out of here.
Dr. Bell.
Oh, my God.
Did you hit an artery?
On an appendectomy?
Maybe we should move in
together.
So you can look after me?
If you're gonna keep being
a hero, somebody has to.
How to Go On Living
When Someone You Love Dies.
Those books
don't have the answer I need
when GiGi asks me
how her mother died.
Nic's dead.
Nothing's gonna change that.
If he doesn't find
what he wants, then what?
You'll be there
for him.
We all will.
"You're Not Here"
by Cynthia Erivo playing...
We need to get going.
Mm-hmm.
Five more minutes
in the love bubble.
Mmm.
Life.
Hey.
I heard about this...
♪ When I run ♪
♪ I'm running ♪
- ♪ To your arms ♪
- Nic?
♪ And when I sing ♪
♪ I'm singing to your heart ♪
♪ I feel you near ♪
♪ In my moments of fear ♪
♪ But when I open up my eyes ♪
♪ I see it clear ♪
♪ It's only in my dreams ♪
♪ That you are here ♪
♪ You're not here ♪
Ah...!
Good morning, angel.
You're up early.
What do you say we get you
changed into something fresher?
Huh?
Any objections?
I know we're all excited
for Halloween, but let's sit down.
Dr. Voss has
a very special surprise for us.
Spit spot, little ones.
Oh, don't we all look
wonderful.
Now, what do you suppose I have
in my magical bag?
I bet it's bones.
It most certainly
is not bones.
It's...
Oh.
Oh, wait a minute.
That is most odd.
It is bones.
Oh-ho.
Totally spaced
on getting GiGi a costume.
She doesn't know that.
Gonna be plenty
of costumes
in the dress-up bin.
You can be a spider
- or a firefighter.
- Mm.
Right, GiGi?
Mm-hmm.
- Mwah.
- Ba-ba.
- Yep.
- Bye-bye.
Love you, GiGi.
Bye-bye.
May I venture a guess
at your costume?
Are you perhaps an on-duty
physician who should be off?
I know you're understaffed
today, so I thought...
Well, if it helps...
to have something
to focus on,
we'd love to have you.
Distraction.
- That's what I'm hoping.
- Good.
Good.
Uh, please.
What happened, hon?
I was pumpkin carving
with my boys
and I sliced a big chunk off.
- Can you put it back?
- Um, no.
Consider it a souvenir.
Pro tip: if you put salt
and baking soda on it,
it'll mummify.
Now, this place is
incredible.
Incredibly creepy.
Look at the fixtures.
They're ancient.
- What?
- And there's a place to store the bodies.
I prefer an apartment
without
the annual
cost of an exorcism.
They can't be cheap.
You're joking, right?
You don't seriously believe
in ghosts, Leela.
Hey, if you spent the holidays
at my uncle's place
in the Himalayas,
you would, too.
There are some mean spirits
there.
But look at this place.
21st-century plumbing,
heated pool, city views.
And it's right
on the BeltLine.
And no personality.
No craftsmanship.
Dogecoin or death!
Too much?
- Yeah.
- Maybe lose the machete.
Hey.
I didn't think
you were coming in.
Are you sure you're ready,
Conrad?
No.
But GiGi needed a change.
Well, if you get the urge
to bolt, we got you covered.
Get me out!
Get me out of here!
No, no, no!
Responded to a 911 call
from a neighbor!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- One with head trauma.
All floridly delirious.
Tachycardic
but with stable blood pressure.
- Get off of me!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
You have to stay still.
- Calm down. -
- Get me out of here!
- How dare you.
- Let go of me!
*THE RESIDENT*
Season 05  Episode 05
Episode Title: "The Thinnest Veil"
Aired on: October 19, 2021.
Where's the high priestess?
I need to see her.
You will soon.
Your blood pressure is normal,
but your heart rate is fast.
I got to take a look at that wound,
- No, I won't stay here.
- Okay? Well, you have to.
I need to take a look at your head, okay?
Will you page Dr. Sutton,
have her meet you in CT?
- Sure.
- You're the one with the hat.
I hate those hats!
I can't help you
if I can't get a set of vitals.
They're burning
my skin!
Hundley,
can I get a hand over here?
Where-where are my girls?
Where are my girls?
Are they okay?
- L-Let me see them.
- I can take off your restraints
- as soon as you calm down.
- W...
- Can't let you hurt yourself.
- Aah!
That's just
the blood pressure cuff
inflating.
Everything is so...
strange.
Aside from the abdominal pain,
does anything else hurt?
Hey,
does your head hurt?
We need to draw some blood,
but I need to make sure
you're safe.
Can you hold still
for me?
Well,
this is certainly a distraction.
♪ Lord, I was born
a ramblin' man ♪
♪ Trying to make a living
and doing ♪
♪ The best I can ♪
♪ When it's time
for leavin'... ♪
Hey, Kit.
How's it there?
It's shaping up
to be a fun Halloween.
Although Conrad's here.
I'm not sure
that's the best idea.
So,
how was the sailing trip?
It was phenomenal.
It was a beautiful boat,
perfect weather, reconnecting
with my running buddies was...
U-Uh, lost you there.
Now, the whole trip
was like a time machine.
Took me right back to '76.
Just the-the innocence
and adventure,
- and freedom!
- Seems like you haven't returned.
Hello?
- You still there?
- Hey,
did I ever tell you
about the time I hitchhiked
across the country
between college and med school?
I can tell you're in the grip
of a powerful nostalgia.
But do be careful.
And don't you go picking up
any hitchhikers.
Yeah. I'll see you in a few hours.
♪ I hope you'll understand ♪
♪ That I was born
a ramblin' man. ♪
I want to see Holly and Cat.
They must be terrified.
We are caring
for them both.
Glad to see
you're calmer.
How you feeling?
Uh, like I could throw up.
Sounds like a wild morning.
Drugs?
- Alcohol?
- Oh, no, no.
Nothing like that.
No, we were just preparing
our Samhain ceremony.
Samhain?
What is that?
Witches' New Year.
When the invisible veil
that separates the worlds
of the living and dead is
at its thinnest
and we can connect
with those we've lost.
And this happens
on Halloween?
Halloween originates
from Samhain.
If you pay attention,
you'll see the spirits.
They're all around us.
When did you all
start feeling sick?
When I was cooking
for the "dumb supper,"
I started to see visions.
And then I had barely cut
the potat...
- Ugh.
- What's wrong?
Talk to me. Magdalena.
- Hurts. It hurts here.
- Sharp and stabbing
- or dull and throbbing?
- It's sharp. It's very sharp.
All right, I'll get an ultrasound
to take a look. Send off
another set of labs.
Hang tight.
I'll be right back.
What'd you think of that rental
property I sent you, huh?
We'd be neighbors.
One minute, 12 seconds
door-to-door.
I timed it.
I really liked it,
but Leela thought it was creepy.
Well, she should.
A guy did get murdered there.
How do you know that?
Oh, I-I track these things.
It's morbid,
fascinating.
Dude,
why didn't you tell me that?
Happened years ago.
I didn't think
it would bother you.
Well...
I mean, it doesn't.
I don't think.
Then you should grab it.
It's a steal.
Ethan.
I'm Dr. Pravesh.
- I'm Keitra, his girlfriend.
- Nice to meet you.
- Likewise.
- So I see that
you're having
some chest pain?
Weird...
bumpin' with my heart.
You know,
it don't feel right one bit.
I got tightness, too.
Like someone's got their hands
around my throat.
Okay.
Um, how long
have you been experiencing this?
Ever since we moved in.
Ethan believes some things
- about our new home.
- I know some things.
The-the place is crawling
with unruly spirits.
It's just old and a bit creaky.
But the English Regency
architecture
really
is something else.
It's inspiring, really.
- It's horrifying, more like.
- Okay.
I feel like I looked at
your house online this morning.
My girlfriend
and I are house-hunting.
Well, good luck.
Finding the right home isn't easy.
Doctor, I-I'm not some prankster
here to waste time.
But I-I've heard
and seen things in the house
that-that ain't right.
And it's them that's causing all
these problems with my health.
Oh.
Here they go again.
Oh, they followed me here.
- It's okay.
- Relax.
Just breathe.
- Relax. Breathe. Breathe.
- Breathe.
It's okay. It's okay. Breathe.
Ethan, we're gonna get a nurse
in here
to give you some meds
to bring down
your blood pressure
and your heart rate.
We'll figure out
what is causing this.
And I'm pretty sure
it has nothing to do
with haunted spirits.
Agreed.
You want evidence
ghosts exist?
I can prove it.
I have video.
No! Get off me!
You believe me now?
Look, lights flicker.
It happens.
A-And the sheets
flying off my bed?
A breeze, maybe,
from an open window?
There was something heavy
on my chest.
I-I couldn't breathe.
I-I was suffocating.
Okay, let's assume
that your house is haunted
by cruel, vindictive spirits.
You must challenge
the spirits.
You have to earn their respect,
man.
They're air,
not corporeal.
They're puffs of smoke
at best.
Fear alone
sustains them.
If you're terrified of them,
they win.
And you cannot
let that happen.
I'm sorry, you're...
you're joking,
right, Doctor?
I lived opposite a cemetery
in my younger years.
The view from my window
was row after row of headstones.
Imagine a graveyard full
of rowdy, disgruntled spirits.
They gave me nightmares.
They scared me witless
until I laid those suckers down.
I made them fear me
more than I feared them.
Right.
Wh-What'd you do?
I pointed out that they
didn't even have a working hand
to form a fist.
They couldn't hurt me.
Sure, they could blow
some wind.
They could stir
a curtain.
They could mess with the wiring
in the house.
But it was all to hide the fact
that they were powerless.
So, your treatment plan
is to stand up to ghosts?
If they are obstreperous,
yes.
But we'll also figure out what's
going on medically. All right?
That's right.
Thank you.
No, I'm dead serious.
Wait,
Al-Albert Collins is who?
Th-The Iceman.
- Just a le-legendary blues guitarist.
- Ah.
Anyway, his-his tour bus
was blazing down the highway
and they-they scooped me up.
The band had lost a roadie,
so I got to fill in.
Oh, that must've been wild.
Oh, it was a...
It was a great adventure.
I mean, I... I mean, I learned so much.
And, you know...
And for a moment, I mean, maybe,
I kind of thought
music might be my world and...
But then I...
On the road, I realized
I would never
be good enough.
Like, to get anywhere, you got
to figure out what you love
that you're good at
and then... and then do that.
Just play to your strengths.
- That is key.
- I'm still trying to figure out
what I'm good at, I think.
Well, I mean,
you... you will.
S... I mean, something
will grab you and then...
you'll realize you've found
your place and...
So d-did you grab medicine
or did-did medicine grab you?
That was a mutual embrace.
Just...
Hey, Kit. What's up?
Hey, Kit.
Hi, whoever you are.
Uh, yeah, this is...
This is Mike.
Just, uh,
giving him a quick lift.
Right. Well, uh,
this is nothing urgent.
Just, uh, call me back
when you've dropped off
your new friend.
Okay.
Ooh.
- She seems concerned.
- W...
It's probably 'cause
you picked up a hitchhiker.
Yeah, it would have been...
It would have been better
to just keep that between us.
What do you mean?
And not-not tell her?
Well, that...
She seems like she cares
about you.
- That would be dishonest.
- Y...
Oh.
Not good to be dishonest,
Randolph.
No. No, it isn't.
There's a trick-or-treat joke
that ends
with a Halloween arrhythmia,
but it escapes me.
All I've got is
a Halloween epidural hematoma
and some hyperkalemia in here.
But her colleagues could benefit
from your diagnostic acumen.
Dr. Angel?
Oh, he's hardly that.
His halo.
She's suffering
from wild hallucinations,
and I don't think
it's just the head injury.
Oh, Dr. Sutton,
my halo is no hallucination.
This is fact.
But let's take a look
at some EKGs.
Hey.
- So sorry...
- Hey. Get this.
Raptor, of all people,
believes in ghosts.
Seems like a lot of
people around here do.
Any word on the witch
with the head wound?
Epidural hematoma...
uh, that requires surgery.
Billie and Leela
are gonna do it.
You think they took something
that caused all this madness?
Magdalena said
no drugs or drinking.
I'm inclined to believe her.
I'll let you know
when I get the tox screens back.
Hey.
What were you listening to?
Hey. So sorry I missed your call.
That yoga teacher was a sadist.
Her session destroyed me
and I fell asleep.
I don't know if I got anything
from my retreat.
The pain of missing you and GiGi
was more than a mud bath
could make up for.
I love you both.
I'll see you soon.
Kiss GiGi for me, okay?
You know you can go home.
I got this.
It's worse at home.
I'd rather be here.
Come on.
- It hurts so bad.
- Hey, hey, hey. 'Kay.
Whoa.
Got ya, got ya. Okay.
She's bradying.
Let's get 0.5 of atropine
in here now!
I'll run an EKG.
Stay with us.
Can you grab that EKG printout
for me?
Got it.
Okay,
we're back in business.
If this wasn't just
a vagal response
to the abdominal pain...
It could happen again.
Leave me alone!
- No! Leave me alone!
- Hey. Hey.
- Ethan. Ethan.
- Y-You're good. -
You're okay. You're okay.
Just take deep breaths
and try to stay calm.
Hey, I'm seeing some things.
- Spirits or symptoms?
- The latter. -
I'm ordering
a head and chest CT.
Magdalena?
Hey.
You with me?
I'm dying.
But it's okay.
I'm gonna see him...
again.
Her heart rate's dropping.
Same thing happened to Cat.
I'll get the atropine.
No time!
We need a code cart.
Giving first round of epi now.
Besides hallucinating,
she was fine a second ago.
Pulse check.
No pulse. She's in V fib.
Charge to 200
and everybody clear.
Shocking now.
She converted,
but her pulse seems thready.
She's in complete heart block.
Start transcutaneous pacing
at 60 and sync.
This could be hyperkalemia,
so...
let's give her
an amp of calcium gluconate
and two amps
of sodium bicarbonate.
Whoa.
I died.
But I'm back.
I mean,
that totally happened, right?
Stop pacing.
There's no tunnel.
There's no light
at the end.
There...
There's no angels.
I didn't see him.
See who?
My son.
I just wanted
to see his face.
Let's get a full set of labs
and another 12-lead EKG.
Why don't we let Dr. Pravesh
take over?
This isn't the best case
for you, Dr. Hawkins.
No,
I want to see this through.
Thank you.
All right, Cat,
let's see how you're doing.
Code Green.
Missing patient.
Attention, staff.
Code Green.
23-year-old Caucasian female.
Last seen in ER Bay Seven.
What's happening to me?
We're figuring it out, hon.
Labs are back?
Tox screens are clear,
but they do have hyperkalemia.
Potassium levels are sky-high.
But their creatinine
is barely elevated.
So their kidneys are working.
- PH is normal.
- Just breathe.
Why are their electrolytes
going haywire?
It's okay.
See this here in your chest?
Oh, I knew it.
They've invaded my body.
Actually,
I believe it is a growth
called a pheochromocytoma.
It's a medical condition
that causes your body
to produce adrenaline
and make you feel flushed
and anxious,
like you're having
a panic attack.
So he's not possessed
by spirits.
- It isn't the house?
- No.
And it will disappear when
Dr. Austin removes it in the OR.
Thank you, Doctor.
Of course.
Police say they're on the trail
of a possible serial killer
near Reidsville,
about an hour west of Savannah.
A tip led them to this property.
Human remains were found
behind that shed.
And it's possible there may be
as many as three victims.
The suspect,
Michael Jonah Rellie,
is likely armed and dangerous.
If you see him, do not approach.
Call the authorities
immediately.
You've reached Dr. Bell.
Leave a message.
I'll get back to you shortly.
Randolph, you'll
probably think this is silly,
but I know
you picked up a hitchhiker
and I just saw something on TV
that made me a bit worried.
So... call me back, okay?
You all presented with a similar
constellation of symptoms.
Abdominal pain.
Abnormal EKGs.
Elevated potassium.
Hallucinations.
Your friend Holly said she saw
a halo above my head.
Do you see it, too?
And he has one, too.
Does everything look yellow?
- Yes. Very.
- Xanthopsia.
Uncommon visual side effect
of digoxin.
Well, that would explain
everything.
But are you taking
heart medication?
I've never had a problem
with my heart.
At least as far as I know.
Yeah, the others
aren't taking it either.
What plant is used
to make digoxin?
Highly toxic foxglove.
Is there anyone
who would want to poison you?
A, uh, rival witch
or coven, perhaps?
Uh...
- I don't think so. Uh...
- Well,
we'll get you the antidote
to digoxin,
see if it helps.
Okay.
You don't have to answer this,
but...
I've always wondered...
What's it like
to be a surgeon?
I mean, the-the knife.
Cutting into the human flesh.
I mean, that must be...
It's intoxicating.
That's-that's not something
I would normally tell a stranger.
But I...
Yeah, I don't think
a hit of heroin
could hold a candle
to the euphoria that I feel
when I have a scalpel
in my hand.
That's...
I'll bet.
All right. Mm.
This may be crossing the line.
Uh...
You ever killed anybody?
Mistakes happen
- in the OR. That's-that's...
- Yeah.
That's part of being a surgeon.
Sure. Of course.
But what I mean is...
have you ever done something
where y-you knew it was wrong
but you did it anyway?
Oh, I see I hit a nerve.
No.
You didn't.
Oh.
Whatever you say, boss.
Well, uh,
if you make a left up there,
I'm just about, uh, five minutes
down that road.
If it's not too much trouble.
I heard the patient is Wiccan.
She came into the ER
with two other witches.
Really think they believe
in spells and potions and stuff?
I think people believe
in whatever gives them comfort
in this world.
And I'm okay with that.
What do you think,
Dr. Sutton?
Right after Nic died,
I bought a copy of
The Tibetan Book of the Dead.
Read it every night for a week.
In Tibetan Buddhism,
when you die,
your soul spends 49 days
in the Bardo...
the place in between
life and death.
After 49 days,
you're reborn into
another body.
I want that
to be true.
I miss her so much.
Let's do this.
This-this is good.
You can... you can stop
right here.
This is in the middle
of nowhere.
There's not a house in sight.
Well, I know my way.
Okay.
- If you say so.
- Mm.
Well, it's been good
traveling with you, Mike.
Is there a problem?
Well, I think I have
to raise that question again,
about...
killing people
and doing the right thing.
Because I can't help but feel
like you have something
that you really have
to get off your chest.
Okay, I really don't.
And I'm not comfortable
- with this.
- Dr. Bell, we were building a relationship.
- I need to get back on the highway.
- We were bonding.
Get out of the car. Please.
- I feel like we are cut from the same cloth.
- I...
I barely know you, Mike.
I-I just picked you up.
Okay, that's a good point.
We are strangers.
But I'm really good
at reading people.
And I see things in you.
You've hurt people.
You've taken lives.
If you keep secrets...
they become burdens.
'Kay, you're making...
You're making a mistake, Mike.
Well, you're-you're lying to me.
And you know how I feel
about dishonesty.
So...
you should tell the truth.
I think that it would be
very good for you.
There was a-a time when, um...
out of hubris,
I operated
when I shouldn't have.
I had... I had a physical problem
that meant I shouldn't...
hold a blade in my hand.
And I, um...
And I thought
I could control it.
Did you really think that?
No. I knew I was a risk.
Mm.
And you killed somebody.
- In a simple operation that...
- Mm.
Shouldn't have been risky.
And the man bled to death.
And what was your punishment?
There was none.
Mm.
Because the white coat
is a shield.
So you got away with it.
No,
I didn't get away with it.
That death haunts me
to this day,
and I live with that guilt.
Ooh, guilt means
nothing to me.
Guilt is pointless.
There's a saying
in my line of work.
It's one that all surgeons know.
"Killing someone is so easy."
"What's hard
is not killing someone."
Well...
it is a pleasure
to make your acquaintance,
Dr. Bell.
Drive safe.
Another life saved.
I can't take all the glory.
His ghost gets partial credit.
Pericardial patch.
Sutures to me.
Should we enroll the ghost
in med school?
Ah, you joke, Dr. Devi.
But that spirit
scared Ethan enough
to bring him to this hospital,
where we unmasked
a life-threatening tumor.
Ghosts get a bad rep.
Some are vicious, yes,
but others are guardians.
And some
are just restless memories.
One thing they all have
in common is they freak me out.
With all due respect,
I just like them to stay dead.
Holly's doing well.
She's recovering from surgery.
Oh, such a relief.
- Sweetie.
- Oh.
Oh, how are you doing?
- Oh, like I had a horrible dream.
- Oh.
- What happened to us, High Priestess?
- That's what I'm trying
to find out.
When you made the tea
this morning,
do you remember
what you put in it?
Um, hibiscus,
blackberry leaves,
peppermint petals,
foxglove and some...
So you added the foxglove?
Was that wrong?
Oh.
- Listen, it's not... No, no.
- I did this.
It's not your fault.
I should have kept
that jar separate.
- I am so sorry.
- No, no, no, no, no.
It's okay.
- Everyone is well.
- I keep saying
we should label the jars
"edible" and "non-edible."
That sounds wise.
I'm usually such a stickler
for organization.
If you'd seen my bookstore
in Inman Park.
Book Zoo?
That was it.
Did you... did you visit?
Yeah. My wife and I,
we went there a lot
- when we first started dating.
- Oh.
I knew you looked familiar.
I just...
couldn't place you.
And I remember your son.
He would've been eight
this year.
Joseph.
So sorry.
Tell me about your wife.
You lost her recently?
I sensed something. Um...
I feel these things.
Also, I asked that lovely nurse,
Hundley.
She died suddenly.
My whole world stopped.
I feel like I'm living
in some kind of alternate space.
Nothing makes sense.
But I have a daughter.
And...
She keeps me going.
And I have to keep going
for her.
Has your wife visited you
yet?
Um...
I don't believe in ghosts.
But I do dream about her and...
feels very real.
Then I wake up.
And she's still gone.
Mm.
Actually...
she's with you.
She always will be.
Just like my son
is with me.
Your memories, your dreams
keep her alive.
It's like a conversation
between you and her
that death can't take away.
Joseph...
he lives in my heart,
always.
Just like your love
will always live with you.
We made way
more than we needed.
Feel free to offer it
to any kids who come.
Why didn't you answer?
Why didn't you call?
Oh, I thought you were
dead in a ditch,
you old fool.
It's a long story.
And let's just say I won't be driving
down dark roads
with strangers anytime soon.
The hitchhiker?
Yeah, not-not my best idea.
He didn't hurt you, did he?
- No, no. And...
- Police have captured
suspected serial killer
Michael Jonah Rellie
and are conducting a search
of his property
- in Reidsville after an anonymous tip...
- Is that him?
- Led to his arrest earlier today.
- Yeah.
- Oh...
- I... At some point,
I'll-I'll tell you...
everything.
But I, uh...
Right now, I just want to forget
it happened.
- You want to go for a drink?
- Yes, please.
Okay.
AJ, you got to level
with me here.
You don't really believe
in ghosts?
And why shouldn't I?
Well, you're a doctor, for one.
A surgeon.
A man of science.
Ah.
Perhaps you'll appreciate
the deep, dark history
of Chastain Park Memorial,
my friend.
The building that stood
before this one,
right below our feet,
one floor lower,
is where
the incinerator sat.
And the body chute, as it were,
was right here,
where the staircase is.
You're making this up.
Oh, am I?
Some 100 years ago, my friend,
tuberculosis overtaxed
this hospital.
And when the treatments failed,
this handy Slip 'N Slide
allowed the doctors
to discreetly dispose
of the deceased downstairs
in a superiorly
smooth fashion.
You laugh.
However, that is not where
they forever remain.
Nolan, please enlighten
these gentlemen on Room 2413.
It's haunted
and I won't set foot in there.
Happy Halloween.
Keep your eyes open, Pravesh.
You may see
something extraordinary.
Hello?
You startled me, man.
Hey, Leela,
if that soulless apartment on
the BeltLine is still available,
I say let's just take it.
Great.
What changed your mind?
Nothing.
I just want
to make you happy.
Raptor got in your ear,
didn't he?
No. No, he did not.
He didn't. But...
let's just make sure
that it wasn't built
on some ancient burial ground,
okay,
before we sign a lease. That's all...
Hey! I know it's last-minute,
but are you guys free for dinner?
Thought about having
some people over
and-and order takeout.
Nothing formal.
Sure. Of course.
You want us to bring anything?
No, no.
Just bring yourself, 'kay?
All right, great.
See you then.
Yeah.
Sorry I forgot
to get you a costume, sweetheart.
You still look cute though.
Next year, I promise I will.
What do we have here?
Whew.
Yeah.
Look what Mommy did.
I forgot about Halloween,
but your mommy didn't.
Ah.
Mommy got you a costume.
She's still looking out
for you.
for us.
Come here.
Ooh-hoo!
There you go.
Yeah.
Okay, now let's say good night
to your fans.
It's someone's bedtime.
Aw, not already.
Are you kidding me?
Can I eat you, baby chick?
- Could she be any cuter?
- Impossible.
Do they sell outfits like that
in my size?
Can Auntie Billie
put you to bed?
You sure?
Of course.
- She's my favorite person.
- Aw.
Say good night, everybody.
Good night. - Bye.
- Good night.
- Love you, GiGi.
Let's go upstairs.
- Smells delicious.
- Thai food.
Nic's favorite.
All right.
Everyone take your seats.
This is all very mysterious.
I... learned about something
today from my patient.
Something...
pretty special.
It's a ritual that helps her,
and...
I think it might help us.
It's called a dumb supper.
"Dumb" as in "silent."
Which I realize won't be easy
for some of you.
Yeah.
Good, good, good.
- Uh, it's a pagan ritual...
- Thank you...
To honor those we've lost.
It's really just a chance for us
to quietly reflect
on our memories,
in silence, among friends.
Magdalena told me that
on Samhain, which is tonight,
that the veil between the living
and the dead is at its thinnest.
So if you have something
you want to say to Nic...
"Naked As We Came"
by Iron & Wine playing...
we close our eyes...
and you speak without words.
Speak from your heart.
And we say it now.
♪ She says, "Wake up ♪
♪ It's no use pretending" ♪
♪ I'll keep stealing ♪
♪ Breathing her ♪
♪ Birds are leaving
over autumn's ending ♪
♪ One of us ♪
♪ Will die inside these arms ♪
♪ Eyes wide open ♪
♪ Naked as we came ♪
♪ One will spread our ♪
♪ Ashes round the yard ♪
♪ She says, "If I leave
before you, darling" ♪
Thank you, guys, for coming.
- I'm really glad you came.
- Yeah, me, too.
That was really beautiful.
Thank you,
Conrad.
Oh. Thank you so
much for being here.
- Hey.
- Mm.
Mm.
Good night.
♪ Eyes wide open ♪
♪ Naked as we came ♪
♪ One will spread our ♪
♪ Ashes round the yard. ♪
Ready?
- Almost.
- Well,
the candy will run out
if we take too long.
Don't say that, Daddy.
There's enough to go around.
Uh, I don't know about that.
Will the candy really run out?
Not a chance.
Daddy?
- Yes, bubble.
- You got me
the best costume ever.
Aw! Mwah, mwah.
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Sync corrections by srjanapala