- I wanted to meet my
daughter,
but I had nothing to do
with her
being hired by this hospital.
- I'm so grateful
that you're in my life.
- The Vas-COM business,
playing nice with the enemy,
it sucked.
The device rep, Jessa,
did you sleep with her to get
the information you needed?
- No.
- Good.
- My firm's been meeting
with patients
and families affected
by the Vas-COM.
- Will you get a case?
- Oh, yeah. Good one.
- Randall Shentu.
The board brought me on
to help Med
through this challenging time.
A scandal is playing out.
Med's in trouble.
- The focus should be
on Matthew Cooper
being accountable
and going to prison.
- There's something
I've been wanting to say.
- I'm not interested.
- You come at me
as hard as you want.
- Thanks for coming out.
- All good. What's going on?
- We got called out on a noise
disturbance,
Carmen and Terrell.
They were arguing and violent.
He took off before we got here.
- You said something
about their son
and something with his arm.
- Yeah.
It's what the fight was about.
Carmen said
it didn't look right.
Wanna take him to the hospital,
but Terrell said,
"No, money's tight."
Thought you should take a look.
When's the last time
you saw them?
Twelve years.
- You sure you cool with this?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. I'm fine.
- All right, man.
- Yeah.
♪
- Dylan?
- Hey, Carmen.
- What are you doing here?
- Zora called.
Said your son
might've hurt his arm.
So I figured
I come take a look.
- Yeah.
Come in. I'm sorry. Come in.
- That him?
- Yeah, Darius.
Come here, sweetie.
- Hey, man. I'm Dr. Scott.
You mind if I take
a look at your arm?
- Okay.
- All right. Let's see. Okay.
Is it all right
if I press it a little bit?
- Ow!
- I'm sorry. Sorry.
How long has it been
hurting like that?
- A couple days.
- Hmm. All right.
I wanna talk
to your mom for a second.
All right.
You were right to think
to take him to the hospital.
I'm concerned his arm
might be broken.
- That's what I told Terrell.
He got laid off
a couple weeks ago
so he's just been worried
about paying the bills.
- I understand.
- Yeah.
Okay, sweetie.
Let's get your coat on, okay?
♪
- Hey.
- What?
- Quite a look
you got going on.
Planning on hitting the lanes?
- It's mostly just
a fashion statement,
but I do enjoy rolling
the occasional game.
- Anyway, coming in
on your day off, what gives?
- All the paperwork
since this lawsuit started,
I haven't had a minute
to catch up.
- Tell me about it.
I just got here,
I'm already behind.
But more importantly,
do you have the matching shoes
in your car?
- Wouldn't you like to know?
- Please, somebody!
- Hey.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hey, someone get me a gurney.
Hey, hey, hey,
it's okay, sweetie.
What's your name?
- Nadia.
- Nadia. I'm Dr. Hammer.
I'm gonna help you, okay?
Can you tell me what happened?
- Just stick with me here.
I need to take a look.
Did you have surgery?
Nadia? Nadia?
Nadia? Where's that gurney?
♪
- Come in.
- Morning.
- Good morning.
- Café macchiato with 2%.
- I suspect you're not here
just to bring me coffee.
- Okay, I'm wondering
why you still haven't sat down
with Avery Quinn.
- Because her firm is bringing
a class action lawsuit
against this hospital,
and frankly,
I don't think we should be
so eager to cooperate.
- Ms. Goodwin,
these depositions
are just pro forma
to check all the boxes.
- This lawsuit shouldn't
be happening.
Every one of our doctors
associated with the Vas-COM
is listed as defendants,
but they didn't do
anything wrong.
They shouldn't be punished.
- You're right.
But what we need
to avoid right now
is an ugly legal battle that
gets played out in the media
because the place where
we're really being judged
is in the court
of public opinion.
Just think about it,
and enjoy the macchiato.
♪
- Mr. Shaw, how we feeling?
- Much better.
- So good news,
troponins are negative.
EKG is normal.
Your fall was not caused
by a heart attack.
- Thank God. And my wrist?
- Just a sprain,
but let me ask,
anything causing you
extra anxiety these days?
- Uh--
- Do you mind?
- Business just
hasn't been great.
I'm not getting much sleep.
A doctor gave me beta blockers
for when I start
to feel stressed.
But today I felt like
there was an elephant
standing on my chest.
- Well, you did
the right thing coming here.
Panic attacks can feel exactly
like you're having
a heart attack.
- So next time I should just
take the pills my doc gave me?
- Well, beta blockers
do often work well,
but I suggest you follow up
with your doctor
and come up with
a good long term plan
for handling your anxiety
moving forward.
- Will do.
- And Sean here's
gonna wrap your wrist,
and then we'll
get you outta here, okay?
- Thanks, doc.
- You bet.
- Dr. Marcel.
- Yeah.
- We got a patient coming in.
- Okay.
- Wes Tucker.
- Wes Tucker?
Hall of Fame Wes Tucker?
- Hey, uh, let's take him
to trauma three.
A little more private.
- We got a 42-year-old male
in liver failure,
BP 92/ 60, heart rate 112.
Gave him fluids in the field.
- Mr. Tucker,
I'm Randall Shentu.
These are doctors
Blake and Marcel,
two of our very best.
If there's anything you need,
please let me know.
- Appreciate it, sir.
- All right, guys. Here we go.
- I need a FAST scan, CBC,
CMP, LFTs, coags,
tox screen, and a hep panel.
- Copy that.
- All right.
Here we go,
transfer on my count.
One, two, three.
♪
How you doing, Mr. Tucker?
How long you been vomiting for?
- About a day and a half.
Thumb drive's got
my medical info.
Excuse me.
- Okay.
- Dorris.
- Yeah.
- Look at him.
- Shut that.
- Take deep breaths for me.
- There you go.
- No free fluid.
- Liver on his CT looks
nodular and cirrhotic.
Atrophy of the right lobe
and splenomegaly.
- How long you been
an alcoholic?
- You don't beat
around the bush.
- How long?
- Long as I can remember.
Tried to stop,
been in and out of rehab.
Just fell off the wagon again.
- Let's give him
four milligrams Zofran
for his nausea, please.
- We're gonna run some labs,
but I'm pretty sure
you're in
fulminant liver failure,
and you're gonna need
a transplant.
I'll get my team on it,
and we'll check back.
♪
All right, everybody,
show's over.
Back to work.
- Hey, is that the young woman
who collapsed in the lobby?
- Yeah.
- What's going on?
- It's the weirdest thing, I--
just hold on a sec.
Dr. Charles,
do you have a minute?
- Yeah, what's up?
- My patient in three is septic
from gluteal implant surgery.
But the thing is, she won't
tell me who did it or where.
- Is she otherwise being,
you know, transparent
about her history
and stuff, medical history?
- Yeah.
- You think this is something
illegal,
some back alley surgery?
- I do.
- Yeah.
Could be.
Why don't I have a quick chat?
- That'd be great. Thanks.
- Of course.
- Hey, Maggie.
- Oh, and good morning.
So my parents have been asking
if you wanted to come over
for a family dinner.
They wanna get to know you.
- They wanna get to know me?
- Yeah.
I--I've been kind of nervous
to ask,
but what are you doing tonight?
- Tonight?
- I know.
I know it's so last minute,
but tonight's lasagna night,
and that's, like,
my mom's specialty, so.
- Well, it sounds like fun.
I mean--
- Hey, Mags, you got a second?
I need help in five.
- Yeah. I'm sorry.
- All right, D-man,
let's get you in this chair.
- And I am going
to take you to X-ray.
- You nervous, sweetie?
- A little.
- Oh, no way you nervous
with those Bordeauxs on.
Check me out. Pow.
Yeah. You cool?
- Yeah, but I'm not very good.
- Let me tell you something.
Me neither.
- Okay.
Here we go.
- Hey, big guy.
Where's he going?
- To get an X-ray for his arm.
- All right.
Then I'll take him.
Come on, I'll drive.
- Actually, Terrell,
it's authorized
medical personnel only.
- Officer Scott.
It's nice to see you.
- Look, it's hospital
policy, man.
- Come on. This is my kid.
Can't bend the rules?
- Come on.
Tarrell, Darius is hurt.
Give it a rest.
We're ready.
- Mm-hmm.
♪
- Uh, everything okay?
- Yeah, it's complicated.
Knew them from way back.
Three of us used to be
best friends, inseparable,
and now we've gone
different ways.
- Well, that happens.
And didn't sound
that complicated.
Yeah, well, Carmen and I
started a thing,
then we broke up.
- Oh, I see.
Well, he got her
on the rebound, right?
- Something like that,
but there's more to it.
- So should I be thinking
of taking you off this case?
- No, no, no, no. I'm fine.
It was a long time ago.
- Yeah?
- Look, I owe it to Terrell,
and I promised Carmen
that I would take care of this.
- Okay.
- Dr. Blake, Dr. Marcel,
may I have a word?
- Sure.
- We have good news.
A liver just became available
for Wes Tucker.
So get your team ready.
It should land here in
under two hours.
- Unfortunately, we can't.
Mr. Tucker's tox screen
just came back.
- He tested positive
for alcohol.
Admitted he's an alcoholic.
- And since you have to be
six months sober in order
to get a liver
off the transplant list,
we have no choice but to pass.
- But the man's gravely ill.
Without the transplant,
he could die.
And the positive publicity
from saving Wes Tucker's life
would not only encourage
future organ donation,
it would also help to build
back the hospital's good image.
- And I understand that,
but the rules are the rules.
- They're not our rules,
Mr. Shentu,
they're dictated by UNOS.
So unfortunately, we can't
do the transplant.
Okay?
- Well, she definitely does not
wanna talk about her surgery.
- Did you get anything?
- Just, you know,
definitely get the sense
that she's protecting somebody.
- Yeah.
- Oh, Dr. Hammer, Dr. Charles,
this is Nadia's dad.
- Gregor.
May I see her, please?
- Of course. Yeah.
- Nadia, how you feeling?
You gave your mother
and me a terrible scare.
- The doctors have been
taking good care of me.
- Good.
What has happened to her?
- Is it okay?
Well, she had surgery,
and the wound is infected.
She has a blood infection now,
and it's traveled
throughout her body.
- Oh, my God.
Nadia, when did it start?
- I had a little fever
last night.
- My poor girl.
Doctors,
may we speak for a moment?
- Yeah.
- My daughter,
is she going to be okay?
- I hope so, but right now
she's in septic shock.
The first 24 hours
are critical.
- I understand.
Did something go wrong
with her surgery?
- As far as we can see
the surgery itself looks good,
but we don't know what
kind of implants were used.
- I mean, we're actually
having a hard time getting
any kinda detail at all,
and we're wondering
if you might be able
to help us out with that.
- I wish I could, but you know
how it goes when kids grow up.
We don't talk much,
but if she tells me anything...
- Yeah, please let us know.
- I will. May I?
- Yeah.
- That seemed a little odd
to you?
The way she reacted to him,
it was just--
seemed, I don't know,
it was odd.
- Yeah, he did say
they haven't spoken in a while.
- Mm-Hmm. Could be it.
- All right.
Let's check back in a bit.
- Okay.
♪
- Just got Darius's
X-ray results in.
- I'll be right back,
okay, sweetie?
Okay.
- Hi.
- So his arm is indeed broken,
and it's a bit more complicated
of a break
than what we usually see,
which is why I've consulted
our surgeon, Dr. Archer here.
- Whoa, whoa, wait, wait.
Well, can't you just
give him a cast?
- Well,
it's a two-bone fracture,
which means that we will
need to use a plate.
- A plate. What?
Are you kidding me?
Now, you said he was here
to help Darius.
- Okay, Terrell.
- No, listen to the guy.
- Terrell, they're just
trying to help.
- Now, if this was your kid,
what would you do?
- Well, actually, my son
had a similar injury.
I opted for the surgery.
Without it,
he would've suffered pain
and mobility issues
for the rest of his life.
♪
- Do the surgery.
- Good.
I just need the two of you
to sign
some consent forms, please.
- Hey.
- Yeah?
- Dr. Archer is the best.
- Okay.
♪
- Hey, Doris?
- Yeah?
- What's going on over here?
- You didn't see the tweet?
- What tweet?
- Wes Tucker's sister.
She asked people to come in
and see
if they're a match to donate
a piece of their liver.
All these people
are lining up for Wes?
- Yep.
- We're not taking a liver from
another deserving candidate.
We'd be taking a section
of liver from a living donor.
It's great publicity for live
donorship and the hospital.
- He can't stop drinking,
which means he's likely to ruin
his transplant within months.
- Yes, we have a patient
suffering from
alcohol abuse disorder,
but with therapy and medication
it's possible Mr. Tucker
can maintain his sobriety.
- Okay, let's talk about
the potential donors.
This is a complicated surgery
with a long
and difficult recovery.
- They've been apprised
of the risks.
They're trying
to save a man's life.
- Dr. Blake, Dr. Marcel,
please give us a moment.
- Sure.
- Thank you.
- Dr. Shentu, this hospital
runs on the expertise
and dedication of our doctors,
and I cannot stand by
and watch their medical
opinions being ignored.
- Ms. Goodwin, if the donor
were a family member,
there'd be no argument,
but because they don't
personally know Mr. Tucker,
there's an issue?
I don't see why.
- And as you've said
more than one time,
it's good publicity
for the hospital.
♪
- All right,
Weitlaner receptor.
Thank you.
- Hold on. What is that?
- Getting a better look here.
It's a mass.
It's coming from up
around the elbow.
Mm, I'm afraid we might be
looking at a synovial sarcoma.
- Any chance it's benign?
- It's possible.
I've seen crazier things.
- But you don't think it is?
- No, I don't.
All right, well, let's get
this thing out of here.
- I'll go get
his parents' consent.
- No, no, no, no.
We don't need consent.
It's part of the surgery now.
I got two bones to plate,
and I can't plate one of 'em
unless the tumor's removed.
- Dean, if their son
has cancer,
I owe it to them
to tell them first.
- Well, I hope
you're not opening up
a can of worms with this,
Dr. Scott.
But if you gotta be
a boy scout, then do it fast.
Okay. Radial plate.
- What happened?
- She became short of breath
as I was hanging
a bag of saline.
- Help me.
- She's not protecting
her airway.
Get me 20 of Etomidate,
100 of suts.
Nadia, I'm gonna place a tube
to help you breathe.
- What's going on?
- She's in respiratory
distress,
but it doesn't make sense.
She's been responding
to her antibiotics,
her fever's coming down.
- It's from the silicone.
- What?
- A silicone embolus.
The implant must have leaked
and infiltrated
the vascular system.
- He might be right.
Could have gotten into a vessel
and shot up in her lungs.
I'm in. Bag.
We need to get her up
for a CT angiogram stat.
- Hold on.
- Please.
- No, I don't think
I can let you go up there
because you're not actually
Nadia's father, are you?
You're her surgeon.
♪
- Hey, Maggie.
Maggie?
- Oh.
- Hey.
- Hey, Sharon.
- You okay?
- Yeah. It's nothing.
Vanessa's parents invited me
to dinner tonight.
They wanna get to know me.
- Wow. That's a big step.
But it could be good.
- Sharon, I just sprang myself
on those people.
I don't know
what they think of me.
- Well, you know, I kinda see
why you'd be
a little apprehensive.
- Vanessa's so excited.
- So what are you gonna do?
- Hey, how's Darius doing?
- Not good.
Just got the path report.
- Is he done yet?
- He's not.
Unfortunately, during
the surgery, we found a mass.
It's a cancer
of the soft tissue
called a synovial sarcoma.
- Oh no, wait,
I don't--I don't understand.
- Wait, you know,
he's 10 years old.
He--he can't have cancer.
- I--I know this is a lot,
but right now we need
to remove the tumor
and then follow up
with oncology.
- Oh, my God.
- No, no, no, no,
I--I want another doctor.
I want another doctor.
- Terrell,
there's no time, man.
He's under general and--
- He's done working
on my son, okay?
- Terrell!
- Okay.
Nobody's cutting into Darius
just 'cause you say so.
♪
- So now where do you
practice exactly?
- At first I practiced
in Russia.
I was a doctor
to many businessmen
and politicians,
very successful.
- But then you moved
to the States,
and then where did you
get your training here?
- I was forced to leave
my country,
and I could not afford
to spend 10 years
doing another residency.
- So just to be clear,
you never received
a license to practice here.
- People in my community
trusted me
with earaches, sore throats.
- Not exactly talking about
an earache here.
- My people need me.
What can I do?
- Gee, I don't know.
Refer 'em to
a qualified physician?
- The surgery I did was good.
It was the implants.
- That you got off
the black market
because you don't have a license.
♪
- I need to make a call.
- There's another patient.
Says he operated
on another young woman same day
using implants
from the same bad batch.
- So her implants
could be leaking too then.
- Name's Alexandra.
She's not picking up,
but we have this address.
- We may not have much time.
If she throws an embolus,
she could stroke out.
- I'll grab the transport team
and head out.
- No, wait, they just
brought a patient back
in the stroke truck, take that.
- So what do we do with him?
- I'll take care of that.
- Dean, we got a problem.
- What?
- Terrell refused
the excision.
- Are you kidding me?
I mean, we never needed consent
in the first place.
- Yeah, I know, but now that
one parent told us to stop,
we don't have a choice.
- I never should have let you
take this case.
- Dean.
- I cannot keep this boy
under forever,
so here's what's gonna happen.
I'm gonna finish
the radial plate,
and you got 20 minutes to get
Terrell to change his mind.
Yeah, you told me
you were his friend.
So take off your white coat
and talk to him.
Drill.
- Dr. Blake, Dr. Marcel.
I just wanted you to know
they found a live donor
match for Wes.
And in light of your opinion
that the transplant
is inadvisable,
they've asked Dr. Jones
to perform it instead.
- He's never done
a split liver transplant.
Dr. Blake here
is the only one who has.
- I understand,
but the decision's been made.
- And what did Ms. Goodwin
say about this?
- She voiced her concerns
strenuously,
but the board overruled her.
We're moving forward.
- Wait, that's the donor?
- It is.
- No, no. That's my patient.
Listen, he had a panic attack
this morning.
He's not in a position
to be making
any major life decisions.
I mean, resecting
a portion of his liver?
- I'm sorry, but he's a match
and he volunteered.
- I can't let him do this.
- You heard him.
There's nothing
we can do about it,
except to hope
that Jones doesn't kill him.
- Hey, Terrell.
Look, man, we gotta talk.
- I got nothing to say
to you, man.
- If this about back
when I was a cop, I--
- Yeah, and you arrested me!
- I was just one of the cops
on the scene, bro.
I didn't know you were
gonna be in that house.
- Would you get
outta here with that, Dylan?
You watched them
put them cuffs on me.
- Look, man, uh...
I'm sorry.
- Sorry?
You sorry? We were a team, man.
The three of us,
best of friends,
but you had to go off
with Carmen.
Then you watched me get busted.
I mean, what kind of friend
is that?
- All right.
You right.
I could've been
a better friend to you.
But this is not about that.
You got a sick kid upstairs,
man.
- Hey, man, don't.
- He's got cancer, Terrell!
You his father.
He needs you to make
the right call, bro.
- I don't need you to tell me
something I already know.
- Hate me.
Hate me as much
as you want, bro.
But I ain't walking away until
I get your consent
for that surgery.
♪
- Do it.
- Alexandra?
Take it in.
Alexandra?
Alexandra? Can you hear me?
Alexandra? Talk to me.
Bag her.
Let's get her on the truck.
♪
- Ready to roll in a minute.
- All right.
- How's she doing?
- Not good.
I intubated her,
and she's in septic shock.
Did you get the CT yet?
- The image just came up.
There's a silicone embolus
in her right ventricle
partially obstructing
the outflow tract.
- Oh, my--this is bad.
If it shifts, it could
occlude the valve and kill her.
We gotta move right now.
Let's go.
- No, wait. You can't drive.
The smallest bump
could dislodge it.
- Hold on.
- We don't have a choice.
We have to get her to IR.
- Will, you could do
the extraction there.
- In the truck?
There's no way.
I--I'd be going in blind.
- No, you could
take serial CTs
as you thread the catheter up.
I'll read them
and guide you through it.
- Stevie, in case you forgot,
I'm not an interventional
radiologist.
I could cause an arrhythmia.
I mean, I could perforate
a vessel, no way.
- Will, if that silicone
shoots into her valve
and you're not
in this hospital,
we won't have time to save her.
It's our only option.
♪
- All right.
Get the extraction kit.
- Hey, Mr. Shaw.
- Hey, doc.
- How you feeling?
- I'm okay.
- That's good.
So I--I hear
you're going into surgery.
- Did you see?
They're covering
the story on the news.
- Right.
- My Instagram is blowing up.
- Well, look, I gotta ask,
are you sure
you wanna go through with this?
- Dr. Marcel, I have always
wanted to do something
meaningful with my life.
And then this lands in my lap.
- But?
- But I--I guess
I didn't realize
what a big operation it is.
And--and--and then
only having half a liver,
and that list
of possible complications
I had to sign,
it was pretty long.
- Yeah.
Well, you know,
you can still back out.
No one's gonna blame you.
- I know.
But this is Wes Tucker.
He's gonna have a piece of me
keeping him alive.
I have to do this.
- Excuse me guys. Excuse me.
Pamela?
- Mm?
- Come here.
Look, you should do
the transplant.
Miles is my patient,
which means I need to fight
for whatever's best for him.
And right now that's you.
- Crockett, don't think
I haven't been
struggling with this, I have.
I wish there was an easy
answer, but there just isn't.
- Okay, but the fact is,
the transplant's happening,
and you have
the most expertise.
As chief of the department,
you have every right,
and I think an obligation
to take it over.
Please.
- Can you get everyone
outta here,
prep OR seven and open a trace?
♪
- About to thread the wire.
You sure we don't
need radiology?
- No, it's okay.
I can see where you are.
Okay, go slow and steady.
You've got 10 centimeters until
you're at the right ventricle.
- All right, 10 centimeters.
Threading the wire.
How many CTs can we get?
- I'm not sure.
You grabbed us before
we had a chance to refuel,
and we've never done
a test in here before.
- Okay, 10 centimeters.
Let's get one.
- Great.
The silicone is right there.
Turn 120 degrees.
- Okay. Turning.
- Will, something's happening.
- She bradying down.
Rate's in the 50s.
- Get another image.
Stevie, what's going on?
- The silicone. It's moved.
It's obstructing
the pulmonary valve.
She's not getting any blood
to her lungs.
- If it's in the valve,
I can't grab it.
- No, you'll have to float
the wire around it,
inflate the balloon and then
pull it back
into the ventricle.
- It's not gonna be easy.
Image.
♪
- Okay, five degrees
to your right then inflate.
- Sats at 71,
pressure's dropping fast.
- I think I'm there. Image.
What's happening?
- Can't do it--not enough
juice for another shot.
- No, no, no.
You gotta be kidding me.
- Hey, it's okay.
I've been mapping you
the whole time, you're there.
- Stevie, we are only gonna get
one shot at this.
- You gotta trust me, Will.
- Okay.
♪
Pulling back.
- Sats back up to 86, rate's
back into 70, sinus rhythm.
- Nice job, Dr. Halstead.
- All right, Lauren.
Let's roll.
- All right. Let's go.
- How's Darius doing?
- Arch is up there now
removing the tumor.
- So you got Terrell to agree?
- Yeah.
- I guess there's still
something between you guys.
- Nah, he didn't do it for me.
He did it for his son.
♪
- Scalpel.
Dr. Marcel?
- Yeah.
- Where are you?
- Clamping that
hepatic artery now.
You watching that
heart rate, Marty?
- I gave him 4
of dobutamine.
I can't get his rate above 60.
- Oh, come on.
- Is everything okay?
- He's hypertensive.
- Heart rate 52, BP 81/59.
- He keeps bradying down,
and I can't stop it.
- Is he bleeding?
- No. No bleeding.
- Well, nothing else
makes sense.
Vagal nerve stimulation?
Anesthesia sensitivity?
- Wait a second.
His beta blockers.
He takes 'em when he's nervous.
He must have taken it
before surgery,
and now it's slowing his heart.
- He's coding.
- Check the pulse.
We got no pulse
- Defib.
- Charge the paddles to 200.
- Okay, starting compressions.
- Charging.
- Clear.
- No pulse.
- Give me an amp of epi,
charge the paddles to 200.
- Charging.
- Clear.
- Sinus rhythm,
rate's back to 55.
- Okay, so beta blockers
have a half-life of four hours.
What do you wanna do?
- Marty,
put in a temporary pacer.
We've come this far,
we might as well ride it out.
♪
- Slow and stop.
You got it? Hold it steady.
- How's she doing?
- It's still too early to tell.
But, uh,
I don't know
about this one, Stevie.
♪
- Was that Alexandra?
- Yep.
- She had an embolus too?
- Uh-huh.
- Look, I know you judge me,
but in my country,
I was persecuted.
I had to flee.
- I understand.
But it doesn't give you
the right to come over here
and do plastic surgery
out of a garage.
- They would've gone
to someone else.
Someone just looking
to take their money.
At least I know what I'm doing.
- Oh you do, do you?
You know what you're doing?
- I'm a surgeon!
Show some respect.
- No, you were a surgeon
back in Russia, right?
Where you worked at a hospital
that had proper
medical equipment.
What you're doing here,
it is illegal,
and it isn't safe.
Do you even get that?
I mean, at this point,
you're gonna be damn lucky
if those two women survive.
♪
I'm sorry.
You left me no choice.
- I never meant to hurt anyone.
♪
- Want Mommy to tuck you in
like I do at home?
Like a sausage?
Two saus--
Hey.
- Hey, what's up, D-man?
Uh-oh. Bulls colors, right?
Uh-huh. I see you. Mm-hmm.
- Hey.
- I know you talked to Terrell,
and I can't thank you enough.
- Oh, of course.
- Mommy will be
right back, okay?
♪
Darius has a long way to go,
doesn't he?
- Unfortunately, I think so.
Oncology will be down tomorrow
to set up a treatment plan.
It'll likely involve
chemotherapy, radiation.
But Darius can beat this.
I want you to know
I'm here for you, and him.
Okay?
- Thank you.
♪
- Dylan, stay away
from my family.
- Hey.
- Hey. What's up, champ?
- Dr. Halstead, what are you
doing here this late?
- Offsite release forms
and insurance paperwork.
- You mean for going out
and saving that young woman?
- Yep.
- Did our compliance officer
make you do this?
- Yeah, and something about
the hospital
being under a microscope.
- Huh.
♪
Ms. Quinn.
Naming my doctors
on this lawsuit
is weighing them down
and keeping them
from their jobs.
They didn't do anything wrong.
- I'm not on a witch hunt,
Ms. Goodwin,
but every person associated
with the Vas-COM
needs to be held accountable.
- Okay, so then what's
going to happen?
You investigate them one by one
until their names
drop off your list.
So let's just cut to the chase.
Take their names
off your lawsuit now,
and hold me accountable.
- Do your attorneys know
that you're doing this?
- No, they do not.
- And you understand the burden
of what you're
getting yourself into.
- I do.
So.
Ask me everything
you want to know.
- Hey.
- How's Nadia?
- Much better.
Her fever's coming down,
and Alexandra's too.
- Good.
- Yeah.
Well, enjoy the rest
of your day off.
- I still have
a couple hours left.
Would you wanna go
bowling tonight?
Well, I am dressed, after all,
and I do have
the shoes in the car.
- Yeah, sure.
Just give me
a few minutes to finish up.
- Great.
- Dr. Hammer?
I have a delivery for you.
- Mm, thanks.
- Sign here.
- You okay?
- Yeah, it's nothing.
It's just--it's paperwork
for my divorce.
- Oh.
Didn't know you were married.
- It's over.
He's just dragging it out.
- Yeah, maybe we should
do this another night.
- Maybe we should.
- Yeah.
All right. I'll see you.
♪
- What's up? Whiskey, neat.
Thank you. Thank you.
- The past always comes back
to bite you in the ass,
doesn't it?
- I guess so.
- Yeah.
You and Darius's mom, huh?
- Yeah, 12 years ago.
Good thing. I screwed it up.
- I know--I know
what that's like.
My son hasn't spoken
to me in 15 years.
♪
- It does. Thank you.
- Can have the bread?
- Oh yeah, sure, here.
- Mm-hmm.
- So I hear
your husband's a teacher.
- Yeah. He is.
- Mm-hmm.
Ben.
He's a fourth grade teacher.
That's why he couldn't
be here tonight,
parent-teacher conference.
- Hmm.
I never liked those much.
Always got anxious.
But you know how it is,
you always do anything
for the kids.
- Yeah.
You do.
♪
- Bea, you really outdid
yourself with this lasagna.
- Mm-hmm.
- Thanks.
- Delicious.
And is that turkey
that I'm tasting?
- Yes, it is.
I find it's lighter
than sausage.
- You're right.
- Um, I could send you
the recipe if you'd like.
- That would be great.
♪