[SIGHS]
- Wow.
KEVIN: Yeah.
- I'm better.
- Better? What, than me? Ha-ha.
No. Better. My wounds.
I'm healed. I'm good.
- Ha-ha.
- Good.
I should probably get back to my place.
Oh, there are dishes in my sink.
That's why God made cleaning ladies.
Don't go yet.
Relax. Enjoy the luxury.
It's quiet again. I hate this.
ADDISON: Charlotte is driving every
referral from Saint Ambrose
to her practice.
And to top it all off, I'm addicted
to that coffee from the fourth floor.
Do you think they drug the beans?
Because it's just good. Too good.
- Ever think about doing billboards?
- Dell, no.
Pacific Wellcare does billboards.
- No. No billboards, all right?
- Well... No.
It's only a matter of time
before Charlotte's patients
see beyond the French-press coffee
and find a sea of overrated doctors
with questionable ethics.
Overrated doctor with questionable ethics
at 12 o'clock.
- You're looking good today, Monty.
- Dr. Lockhart.
Why are you here? Unless...
Are you bringing coffee?
No, I'm here to see
the other Dr. Bennett.
- Naomi?
- What do you want with Naomi?
Well, that's none of your business.
- You be sure to tell her I stopped by?
- No.
Yet something tells me
you'll remember.
This really is a nice office.
The wooden beams.
It's very Swiss Family Robinson.
I like the beams.
I don't like him.
What do you think he wants
with Naomi?
- Passion fruit papaya black tea?
- I'm thirsty.
Well, you're also relaxed and smiley.
And your shoulders.
I mean, usually they're like this.
But now they're like that.
You're being ridiculous.
You had sex.
- You had sex.
- I don't really wanna talk about it. I just...
- I wanna savor it.
- Okay, who's the lucky guy?
- Hey.
- I just wanna savor it.
Violet had sex.
Oh.
COOPER:
Six weeks on the road.
That's a lot of driving, man.
You must miss home.
A little.
But I don't mind being in the car.
I get to read a lot.
I read a lot as a kid too and my friends
thought I was weird. And I didn't care.
Because, you know, it was cool.
We're on the road.
I don't really have to worry about friends.
Have you been taking care of yourself?
Checking your blood-sugar level?
Before I eat. But sometimes I feel dizzy.
Okay, let's see what's going on.
You know the drill.
Okay.
You're reading Three Musketeers, huh?
You like the epics?
I like that world. I mean,
I like that no one can tear them apart.
It's 210. Which is kind of high, Porter.
Let's take a look at that pump.
Giving you any trouble?
- It gets clogged. But my dad fixes it.
- What about your mom?
She died when I was a baby.
It's just me and Dad.
- Let's see.
- Ouch.
Sorry. I think you have a little infection
near the insertion point.
It doesn't look like
you've been keeping that really clean.
- I've been trying, but...
- But what?
Hey, it's okay. You can tell me.
We've been sleeping in the car.
ADDISON:
Tell me what I'm checking for here?
- I'm not in med school yet.
- It never hurts to get ahead.
I'm checking your ovaries for masses.
Everything's great.
Good. I was a little nervous.
- Do you have reason to be?
- I've had more sexual partners lately.
- Okay. More than five?
- Mm-hm.
- More than ten?
- Eleven.
- This month.
- That is a lot.
- I wasn't going to tell you.
- What's going on?
Promise you won't judge me?
- I'm saving up to go to med school.
- Mm-hm.
I've been working part-time as a call girl.
- You're kidding, right?
- It's not as bad as it sounds.
- It's insane.
- I have to pay for school somehow.
- Take out a loan.
- And be in debt till I'm 50?
Carley.
The money's amazing.
And the guys are really nice.
Last weekend,
one of the girls met this guy
who flew a couple of us out to Dubai
for a party.
- And if I told you how much we made...
- I would still be concerned about you.
I'm fine.
Except for one thing,
which is kind of why I came.
Some of the girls think they picked up
something from the party.
- An STD?
- They were hoping you could see them.
[SIGHS]
They didn't wanna use student health.
They didn't want word to get out.
- I don't like this, Carley.
- Please?
I'm...
Give you my card.
I'm gonna write down my personal cell.
Thank you. That means a lot.
I'm worried about you.
So Porter's blood sugar is unstable.
And he has an infection
from not cleaning his cannula.
I'm gonna start him on antibiotics,
but he does need a new insulin pump.
How long will that take?
I need to order a new one.
So three days, maybe four.
Can't wait. Have to be in Oregon by
the end of the week. I have a job interview.
Without a working pump, his sugar levels
are gonna continue to fluctuate.
- Well, I'll be careful.
- Well, I'm sure you will.
Being on the road presents a unique set of
circumstances for a diabetic 12-year-old.
Porter told me
about your sleeping arrangements.
You think I want my kid
sleeping in a car?
You know, it was hard enough
losing my job and our house.
And now I gotta live with the shame
of not providing for my son.
I know it must be difficult.
- I need this job, Dr. Freedman.
- If you don't stop, your son could die.
It's not a choice, Frank.
You have to give me a couple of days.
I've known Carley for almost a year.
She's a nice girl, working her ass off
to get into medical school. I just...
- I can't believe she's doing this.
- She grew up with nothing.
Now she makes more money in a month
than her parents do in a year.
The worst part is that she doesn't seem
to be bothered by it.
Well, she's repressing emotion.
It's a defense mechanism
to help her cope with what she's doing.
Most prostitutes have low self-esteem.
Many were victims of sexual abuse.
I've met a few call girls in my day.
And we would discuss
why they got into the trade.
And it's not because they were touched
inappropriately or forced to have sex.
They don't want you to believe it
because it kills the fantasy.
- Don't kid yourself, these girls are victims.
- Try telling that to Carley.
Hey, Pete, you ever paid for sex?
Don't have to.
- What's up with him?
- I don't know.
I gotta get back to work.
- So you gonna tell us what he wanted?
- Who?
Wyatt Lockhart.
Oh, I haven't been down
to talk to him yet.
All right, fine. I will go.
Claudia Jenkins, 35-year-old woman.
Stage two, adenocarcinoma of the lungs.
Usually a patient with that type of cancer
dies within a year.
This x-ray was taken
when I first met her.
This was taken just last week.
- Oh, my God, that's amazing.
- That's full remission.
Thanks to my aggressive combination
of chemo and radiation protocols.
So you asked me down here
just to show off one of your miracles?
No. No, no.
I brought you down here
because my miracle wants
to get pregnant.
[EASY-LISTENING MUSIC
PLAYING OVER PHONE]
- What's with the elevator music?
- I'm on hold.
You know what I'd do if I ever met the guy
that picks these songs?
- What's wrong with you?
- Diabetic kid I saw this morning.
His insulin pump is registered
to someone else.
Okay, you can't reuse pumps.
I used the serial number
to track the doctor that installed it.
That's who I'm holding for.
But this kid's dad... Something was off.
And they're living out of their car.
You think they could have stolen
an insulin pump?
- Well, times are tough.
MAN: Hello?
Yes, hi. I gave your secretary
the serial number of...
Right.
Oh, that's awful. No, l...
I'm gonna call you back.
What did he say?
The kid who the pump is registered to?
He was kidnapped.
It's gotta be the same kid. Same age,
same height, same blood type.
We gotta call the police, then.
Let them know
we're dealing with a kidnapping.
I wanna talk to him first.
Coop, this kid
could be in serious danger.
We don't even know if Frank's
the real father. He could be anyone.
I saw them together,
Porter trusted this guy.
If Frank was some stranger, he wouldn't
let me examine Porter by myself.
The kid could've told me
to call the cops.
What if you're wrong?
Frank gets spooked, he takes off.
This could be your only chance
to save this kid.
Why are you giving me a patient?
When the rest of your practice
has done everything they can possibly do
to undermine us upstairs?
CHARLOTTE:
He's not.
Perhaps Dr. Lockhart wasn't clear.
Claudia Jenkins is our patient.
She's part of an ongoing clinical study.
She's continuing cancer treatments.
- You'd be consulting.
- Ha. You want me to work for you?
I have work upstairs. Tell you what.
If your patient wants fertility treatments,
have her give me a call.
No one who's survived this type of cancer
has been able to conceive.
- Thought you liked a challenge.
- With your help, I can get her pregnant.
We can get her pregnant.
[SIGHS]
[CHATTERING]
MARA:
Is this you?
- Yes.
- Wow, I write too.
Well, short stories mostly.
But I would love
to hear how you got started.
If you ever had some time.
You'll call me?
[CHUCKLES]
[GIGGLES]
- The kidnapped kid's coming back in.
- Oh, okay.
- Is it college day?
- I love college.
- Who are they here to see?
DELL: Addison.
Referrals from her coed call girl.
- They don't look like call girls to me.
- A room full of call girls.
- I've had dreams like this.
- Are you sucking in your gut?
[MOUTHS]
No. No.
- Hey, guys.
- Hey.
What's with the call girls?
I do this for a living.
VIOLET:
Hey.
- Hey, what are you doing here?
- Hi.
I had rehab down the street. Thought I'd
come by, see if you had time for coffee.
But it looks like you're booked.
- Is seeing hookers a sub-specialty now?
- Wait, you're seeing more prostitutes?
- I am seeing women.
- Of the night.
- Wait, you have a problem with this?
- Yeah, I do.
Look, I am all for free choice,
but these girls are damaged.
They can't make good choices.
So, yeah, I think that
if you only treat them physically,
then you're just
perpetuating their problem.
Is this really what our practice
is coming to?
Well, what should it be?
Another high-end Westside clinic
catering to an overly exclusive clientele?
Is that what we are?
This isn't exactly Hollywood Boulevard.
And you think that makes a difference?
You wanna hear the statistics on the links
between prostitution and drugs?
Prostitution and violent crime?
I'm not condoning their behavior.
But they're not streetwalkers.
And you think just because
they're in school every day
doesn't mean it's gonna lead down the
same path? They may think it's temporary,
but you wanna lay odds on how many
are still doing it five years from now?
I probably have patients.
- I have patients too.
- Well, I better let you get back to them.
PETE:
Hold the door.
- Oh, sorry, l...
- No, l...
- Right. Good idea. I was just...
- Yeah.
I should...
Hello, doctor.
Well, l... Uh...
- You look surprised to see me.
- I just didn't expect you until tonight.
Oh, I have some charts to pick up.
And I missed you.
I'm glad you're back.
I got your call. You said it's urgent.
Yeah, there's a couple more tests
I wanna run on Porter. Um...
It'll just take a minute, though.
You can stay here.
Oh, hey. One second, Porter.
Can you keep an eye on the father
out there?
- Make sure he doesn't go anywhere.
- Yeah, no problem.
Here. Have a seat, buddy.
What kind of tests?
Is something wrong?
No, no. I just... I wanna talk to you, Porter.
I wanna help you.
Your insulin pump is registered
to a kid named Evan Dawson.
- So?
- So I think that's you.
Is it you? Are you okay?
Is he hurting you?
Did he force you to leave your mother?
I wanna help you, Evan.
I'm gonna help you.
But I need you to level with me.
He was nice at first.
Told me we'd do
all kinds of fun things together.
- But then he started hitting me.
- I'm not gonna let that happen again.
I promise you. We're keeping an eye
on that man out there right now.
No, not him. Not my father.
My mom's boyfriend, Ted.
He moved in six months after
she kicked my dad out.
When my mom wasn't around,
Ted would get angry.
- Did you tell your mom?
- She would ask him about it.
But he would say it wasn't true.
But my dad believed me.
He was the only one who did.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Evan? I need some help in here.
- What?
- I need an amp of D50.
I'm on it.
- What's wrong?
- His blood sugar's tanking.
He's having a seizure. All right,
hold him steady. Hold him steady.
- What are you doing to him?
- Trying to save his life.
Please, don't let him die. He's all I have.
- Is he gonna be all right?
- I don't know.
Please. He was fine five hours ago.
I checked his pump. I checked it.
Right now, my priority is Evan.
You understand?
Do not move till I get back.
We're gonna go on my count.
One, two, three.
SAM: Hey.
- Hey, is that kid okay?
I hope so. He's at the hospital
with Cooper right now.
Good.
You all done with your prostitutes?
- First Kevin's moralistic Joe, now you?
- These women sell themselves.
They make people feel
like all women are for sale.
- They need a doctor. I am a doctor.
- What did Wyatt want?
Oh, um, he wanted me to consult
on one of his cancer patients
who wants to get pregnant.
- Consult? For him?
- You're not actually considering
working with this guy.
Working for Charlotte's practice.
I said I'd think about it.
They're trying to drive us
out of business, Naomi.
Look, all I know is that this woman
was supposed to be dead
and she's in remission.
She has a chance to have a baby.
And if I can help her...
Wyatt is not about helping people, Nai.
He's about helping Wyatt.
I'll see.
- Naomi.
- What? I said that I would think about it.
ADDISON:
Hey.
- What are you doing, Addison?
- What are you talking about?
I went by my house
to straighten things up.
They were straight.
Surprise. I wanted to surprise you.
I thought about you
worrying about things,
so I sent my housekeeper over
to tidy things up.
I don't need you paying for me.
- No, no, of course not.
- My place isn't disgusting and pathetic.
- No, I wasn't saying...
- I live in the Valley. It's not the slums.
[PHONE RINGING]
Kevin.
Oh...
Dr. Montgomery.
Carley? Are you okay?
But... No, no, no.
Don't worry, I'm glad you called.
Yeah. Don't... That's fine. I can come,
and I'll be there as fast as I can. Bye.
- Everything okay?
- It's one of the call girls.
The one that was my patient.
- A guy hit her.
- And she's calling you?
- She's afraid of the police.
- Whoa. You're gonna go there?
- No, you don't know what you could be...
- Don't be dramatic.
Addison, this is what I do.
You don't know this world.
It can be dark and ugly.
You are making too much out of this.
Hey, you didn't know she was a call girl
until today.
Look, I understand you wanna help her.
Maybe you think you can even save her.
But you're dabbling in a world
you know nothing about.
- I'm not letting you go down there alone.
- What? You're not gonna let me?
All right, I'm not about to walk in there
with her worst nightmare.
I'm going and I'm going alone.
So why am I here, again?
Because Kevin made me feel stupid
for going alone.
Kevin's a cop. If he says it's dangerous,
don't you think he's better equipped
to protect you than I am?
- We'll be fine.
- All of those girls, all of them, they're...?
- They're call girls?
- What is it with everyone?
They're college students earning money
in an inappropriate way.
They're just kids, they're students.
Of course, most students
don't get beat up by their johns.
[SIGHS]
- So, what are you not telling me?
- What?
You've been sitting here in silence
for 20 minutes.
Oh, I'm sorry. I was just...
What is wrong? You look like you're about
to throw yourself off of this building.
No, l... It's nothing.
Just a rough day at work. That's all.
- Okay.
- Okay?
If you don't wanna talk
about whatever it is, I'm not gonna push.
We're okay, right?
Yes, we are.
- I missed you.
- Good. Because I missed you.
[DOOR OPENS]
- How is he?
- He's stable for now.
The pump failed.
It released a sky-high dose of insulin.
- It's been replaced, he's responding well.
- This is my fault.
You know, I tried to look after it.
I tried to keep it clean. It's just so hard.
Have a seat.
Why did you run?
Why didn't you go to the police?
Do you know how hard it is
to prove abuse?
Or for a father to get custody
of his child?
I wasn't just gonna sit around
and wait for some legal procedure
while my son was getting hit.
- You need to turn yourself in.
- And then what?
Who's gonna protect my son
when I'm in jail?
You don't know what it's like
to know that your son is being hurt
and there's nothing you can do
to stop it.
- You cannot keep this child on the run.
- Well, I'm not taking him back.
Is there a problem here?
Nothing I can't handle.
I'm gonna go see my boy now.
ADDISON:
Carley?
CARLEY: Dr. Montgomery?
- Carley, what happened?
This is Dr. Bennett. We work together.
- Did your client do this to you?
- Yes.
- It hurts.
- Carley, you should have called 911.
I thought we were talking about
a couple bruises here.
I didn't wanna explain.
I didn't wanna get in trouble.
I had your number. I'm sorry.
Yeah, I need an ambulance
at the Grand Camden Hotel, Beverly Hills.
8600 Roxbury Drive. Room 210.
[GASPING]
She's got at least
two to three fractured ribs.
- One's puncturing the lung.
- Tension pneumo?
Gotta release the pressure
so she can breathe.
SAM: Easy. Easy.
ADDISON: Hold on. Stay with me.
- Okay. Do it.
- Ready?
Please. I'm okay. Don't let them take me
to the hospital. They'll call my parents.
You're over 18.
They can't call unless you request it.
I'm on my parents' insurance.
They'll find out.
They need to look at you, Carley.
When you get to the hospital,
they'll ask your name and insurance.
Tell them Jane Doe. And if you pay
in cash, they can't refuse you treatment.
COOPER:
This is for you.
"The Count of Monte Cristo."
Thanks, Dr. Freedman.
If you like The Three Musketeers...
That's where I got Porter, from Porthos.
My favorite musketeer.
I'm sorry I lied to you.
I'm sorry you've been through
everything you've been through.
- I'm sorry your mom didn't believe you.
- Are you going to call the cops?
Here's the thing. You can't keep living out
of your car, running from place to place.
- My dad will go to jail.
- Unfortunately, that part's not up to me.
I promise you,
I will do everything I can to help him.
It's not fair. He listened to me.
He was the only one who listened to me.
I'm all that he has. He's all I have.
So can't you just let us go?
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Wyatt. What a surprise.
Claudia Jenkins. Dr. Naomi Bennett.
- He's sung your praises.
- Yeah, I figured you two should meet.
Well, why don't you come back
to my office and we'll have a talk?
If you have time, that would be great.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Great.
You know what?
You two already know each other.
I'd like to talk to Claudia alone.
- Whatever you need.
- Okay.
See you.
CLAUDIA:
I can't believe I'm here.
I mean, that I've actually been
well enough, long enough,
to be sitting across from a doctor, having
a discussion about getting pregnant.
Well, your recovery
has been astounding.
Thanks to Wyatt. Every other doctor
I went to said there was no treatment.
Sometimes I think he cured me
by his sheer will.
He would not let me give up.
And I wanted to give up. He's tough.
You know, I think he might have
actually scared the cancer away.
[CHUCKLING]
Um...
Your body has been through so much.
And fertility treatments post-cancer,
it's a lot on the body.
You sure you wanna
go through with all that?
I mean, there are other options.
There's adoption or surrogacy.
I wanna have a baby. Myself.
My body attacked me and I fought back.
And I won.
I can do this. I want my life back.
I want my dreams back.
Do you know what I mean?
Yeah.
I'm here as a patient.
I need your professional advice.
Oh, okay.
- Well, leave the door open, so...
- Oh, door. Good.
Okay. Your time will start...
...now.
I had dinner with Meg last night.
It was unbearable.
- Why was that?
- She knows me. She reads me.
- She kept asking me what was wrong.
- And what did you tell her?
- That nothing was wrong.
- You think you should have told her?
- I don't know, what do you think?
- What do you think?
You gonna answer all my questions
with questions?
- That's what therapists do.
- Then stop being my therapist.
Be my friend.
Fine.
I think that telling about cheating
only makes the cheater feel better.
I think it would be a cruel thing
to put on Meg.
If you plan to move forward with her,
nothing good can come of it.
If you plan on moving forward with Meg,
then you, as the cheater,
need to suffer in silence for your crime.
Live with the guilt and move on.
- That was an ambush.
- But she's lovely, isn't she?
- Addison was right about you.
- Tell me you weren't moved.
Why me? Why me? There are hundreds
of fertility doctors in this city. Why me?
Because I did my research,
and you're the best.
If Claudia Jenkins wants a chance
at getting pregnant,
she's gonna need the best.
I'm supposed to believe
that this is motivated
purely out of compassion for your patient,
and not for personal gain?
I like to win. So what?
I like to find new ways to cure things.
I'm changing the way we cure cancer.
That's not ego. That's the truth.
Tell me you don't wanna
be a part of that.
Hey.
- How you feeling?
- Like I got beat up.
- You have to report this, Carley.
- Are you crazy?
- So, what, this guy just gets away with it?
- I can't risk it.
Tell me that you're not
gonna do this anymore.
How long will the bruises last?
You need to find another way
to make money.
- It's one bad incident.
- You were lucky last night.
- He could have killed you.
- In a few months I'll graduate debt free.
In another year,
I'll be able to pay for med school.
- That's not worth your life.
- I'm doing it so I can be a doctor like you.
- Find a different way to get there.
- Doing what?
Working for minimum wages and tips?
And dating guys who wanna sleep with me
because they buy me a steak?
At least this way, I get paid what I'm worth
and I call the shots.
How many part-time jobs did you have
to pay for school?
How many loans
did you have to pay back?
- I wouldn't have done what you're doing.
- If you haven't struggled,
if you don't know what it's like
to come from nothing,
then you can't understand.
What would your parents say
if they knew?
You can't call them.
I may not be in med school yet, but
I know all about doctor-patient privilege.
You're right.
I can't.
But I am tempted.
I know you're trying to help,
Dr. Montgomery, but stay out of it.
I know what I'm doing.
If I call the police,
he goes back to his mother
and her boyfriend who abuses him.
His father, whom he really loves,
ends up in jail.
- That's funny.
- How's that funny?
You're supposed to call the police,
but you're not.
I wanna call the police, but I can't.
I can't call the one cop
that I should be able to call
because he'll just say, "I told you so."
My college call girl,
she's not gonna quit.
- What people do to themselves.
- Yeah.
But I guess it's theirs to do, right?
I mean, we can save their lives
physically.
But we can't make them
live their lives differently.
I guess if we're not them,
if we're not in their shoes,
who are we to say what's best?
I feel like I'm gonna do something bad.
- Excuse me?
- I wanna do something bad.
Well, no, no, no. It's not bad. Actually,
I think it's gonna make me feel good.
Only Sam and Addison
are gonna hate me.
- Wyatt Lockhart.
- You're gonna sleep with Wyatt Lockhart?
No, no, no, I'm considering
consulting with him on a case.
- What? Sleeping with him?
- Oh. I'm sorry.
You said it was something bad,
but it was gonna make you feel good...
- So you went straight to sex?
- I did. I did. I went to sex.
I gotta get it together. I'm sorry.
Hey, wait. What do you think?
Am I bad?
Oh. Um...
Well, I won't, um...
I mean, I can't...
Well, I'm not...
I don't know. I just... I don't know.
Did you really think
you were gonna get away with it?
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- Cut the crap.
I know all about Frank and Evan.
Who they really are.
You're not the only one
who can do an investigation.
Porter's social security was bogus,
so I ran the serial number
on the insulin pump we pulled out of him.
Just stay out of it, Charlotte.
You don't know what's going on here.
I sure as hell do.
You are about two seconds away
from losing your medical license
for harboring a fugitive.
- Please tell me you didn't call the police.
- I did. Ten minutes ago.
You did this to punish me
for breaking up with you?
I did this to save your ass from your
misguided sense of I don't know what.
You shouldn't have done me any favors.
You're probably right.
You need to take a walk. Now.
Ten vials of insulin, some alcohol wipes,
two extra cannulas for the pump.
I put a journal in there. You need
to keep track of his sugar and his carbs.
You need to fill that out every day.
You need to keep that pump clean.
- I will.
- There's a service elevator.
Take it to the ground floor.
Exit out the loading doors. Go.
- How can I thank you?
- Take good care of your boy.
Thank you.
Thank you for listening to me.
You just promise me
you'll keep reading, okay?
All right, go.
PETE:
Are you looking for me?
No. No, no. I was just making some tea.
Hey, the... Thanks for that talk today.
That was...
It really helped put things in perspective.
Oh, good. Good. I'm glad.
[CHUCKLES]
- I better...
- Yeah. Yeah, you better.
Did you have something more
that you wanted to say?
Because I thought maybe you did.
Did l...? Did I cut you off?
[BOTH MOANING]
Uh...
Meg. Meg.
- I knew there was something.
- I wanted to tell you.
If you wanted to be with someone else,
why drag this on?
- I'm sorry.
- You pushed me away after I worked here.
I thought I was crowding you. I guess
I didn't realize what I was crowding.
- I didn't mean to hurt you.
- Well, I got hurt.
I know. Don't say it.
Good, you're both here.
I just wanted to let you know
that I have decided to consult with Wyatt.
- Naomi, this... It's wrong.
- I don't believe you. After everything?
I wanna be inspired again.
After the practice, I felt like
I'd lost something, like I'd given up.
And I don't wanna feel
like that anymore.
- It's just one patient.
- It's not just one patient.
It's a step in the wrong direction.
And you take this step
and soon people are gonna
not call the police on kidnappers.
And help patients to lie
to get into hospitals.
- Then what are we gonna become...?
- Sam.
No. We are our actions.
And if she sells out once,
then she's a person who sells out.
I am not selling out.
You talk about this practice.
The way it's supposed to run.
The way we're supposed
to treat our patients.
You talk about not wanting to give up.
And then you're gonna go downstairs
to that place,
to work with that woman who is doing
everything possible to undermine us.
To work for that man
who's more concerned
about getting recognized for his work
than which patient lives or dies.
How is that not selling out?
You agree with him?
I agree that once you start
doing something, it's difficult to stop.
The police officers showed up
in Evan's hospital room.
You know what they found?
- Your broomstick?
- This isn't a joke, Cooper.
You tipped them off.
You're obstructing a police investigation.
If they found out you were involved
in the disappearance, you could go to jail.
- I'll take my chances.
- No, you won't.
I covered for you.
- Why?
- Because now we're even.
You were right. I don't know what it's like
to walk in your shoes.
But don't kid yourself, Carley.
This isn't just a means to an end.
Because once you do this,
it's who you are.
We are our actions. They define us.
And you may think that
you're a med student paying for college,
but right now you're a hooker.
- That's not...
- That's the world you've chosen.
I can't be your doctor anymore, Carley.
[SOBBING]
I slept with Pete. There, I told you.
- You know, I expected better from you.
- I'm sorry, it just happened.
But you know what,
if that's how you wanna play it, fine.
- What are you talking about?
- When you're ready to be mature
and tell me who you really slept with,
I'll be around for you, Violet.
I'm not lying to you.
I really slept with Pete.
- Okay.
- Where are you going?
I don't wanna late for my date
with Angelina Jolie.
[BELL RINGS]
[ELEVATOR STOPS]
Uh... I use an inhaler.
I'm sorry,
do you need medical attention?
No, no, it's my breathing.
It gets bad when I get worked up.
So I need an inhaler.
When I get upset, I need it.
Uh... When I work out, I need it.
When I exert myself, I need it.
I'm prepared to line up ten inhalers,
if that's what it takes.
Because if you mess with Naomi...
If you even think
about screwing with her,
I will take you out.
[BELL RINGS]
[ELEVATOR STARTS]
Not even a last night?
I don't live here, Addison.
This isn't my home.
You're mad about
my ignoring your advice?
You've never been to my house.
You make fun of where I live.
You pay people to clean up my house
so I won't have to go back.
And you won't have to either.
I did a nice thing.
Tell me the truth, if I didn't get shot,
would we still be together?
All this because of my patient?
No, it just made me realize
how you see the world.
And the world that I live in
isn't always about beaches
and thousand-count sheets and hired help
to make everything look pretty.
When you were shot, I looked after you.
Here. In your comfort zone,
so you didn't have to give up control.
- Because that's how you like it.
- That is not true.
It's for the cleaning lady
and the gardener.