Is Owen asleep?
Yep, coast is clear.
See you in the morning.
So I bought a ticket
for Minneapolis.
I'm heading out tonight.
Really?
We'll see what she has
to say face-to-face.
Connor, you sure that you
don't want to...
I don't know, just, uh,
think about
letting it go?
I'm sorry, Dr. Charles.
I love your daughter.
I'm not going to lose her.
Get it away from me!
Dr. Choi, Dr. Manning!
You're going to Three.
I got LeAnn Crawford, 22,
found attached
to her newborn
on the sidewalk
in a pool of blood.
Combative in the field.
I couldn't cut the cord.
Drugs?
Wouldn't surprise me.
Get it away from me!
Ma'am, this is your baby.
Oh, no, it's a...
It's a monster.
She may be in withdrawal.
I need four milligrams
of Versed, IV.
On it.
Not until we cut the cord.
Please get this thing
away from me!
Let's get her in restraints!
Ma'am, I need you to
listen to me.
Get it away!
Whoa, she tore the cord!
All right, let's transfer
on my count.
Ready?
One, two, three.
Give her the Versed.
She's bleeding out.
We've got to deliver
this placenta now.
No, it's a monster!
Kill it. Kill it.
Baby's temp is 94.
I need more blankets!
Versed's in!
Let's start an IV.
Get two units of O neg
on the rapid transfuser
and start the MTP.
Vitals at 86.
Turn the O2 up
to 10 liters.
I got the placenta.
Heart rate's down.
Pressure's stable.
Baby's starting
to pink up.
Hey. Hey, listen to me.
You just had a baby.
That's your baby.
Baby?
Call Child
and Family Services.
No way she's taking
this baby home.
Baby? Baby?
Okay.
Temperature's back
to 98.
I'll be back to check on him
in a little bit.
Poor thing.
Let me know
if anything changes.
Hey, how's the mom?
Better, apparently,
after a little methadone.
I'm gonna talk to her
about detox.
Tox screen showed heroin.
Great. Odds are the baby's
going to have the same result.
Eh, never know.
Might be a high-stress user.
Baby could be fine.
Maybe.
Ms. Crawford?
I'm Dr. Charles. Uh...
Glad to see you're doing
a little better.
Anything we can get you?
Something to drink?
I just want to go.
I don't blame you,
but we do need to make sure
that you're stable first.
So, you do understand that
the DCFS is on the way
to arrange a custodian
for your child?
Yeah.
Okay.
I was looking
at your tox screen
and I'm just curious.
How long have you
been using for?
Roughly?
The reason I ask is that
we do have a number
of programs here
at the hospital that are...
That are available to you.
One particular, um...
I said
I just want to go.
I understand that, but this
would be an opportunity...
Dr. Charles, can I talk
to you for a second?
Yeah.
Uh, get some rest.
I'll, uh, check in
with you later.
You're wasting your time.
You do understand
that we have an obligation
to try and get addicts
into a program
before they leave
the hospital?
Yeah, but clearly,
she doesn't want our help.
We don't know that.
We almost never get through
on the first shot.
She won't even talk to you,
Dr. Charles.
Ethan, somebody puts up
a wall like that,
they're usually trying
to protect something.
That's often worth
chipping away at.
Barry.
Can you not see
that I'm working?
I'm just trying to get
a closer look.
Observing the charge nurse
in her natural habitat.
Aren't the paramedics
supposed to drop off
their patients and leave?
Not paramedics
with an agenda.
Mmm.
Have dinner with me tonight.
My answer's the same
as it was last time...
No.
Why not?
We went out for drinks.
Right, drinks.
That's not a date.
Having dinner is dating,
and we are not
having dinner.
Well, not yet.
It's not even lunchtime.
Hey, Miss Dempsey.
Mr. Goodwin.
Dr. Halstead.
Haven't seen you in a while.
What's going on?
Still no cure
for supranuclear palsy,
as you can see.
But we do therapy
three times a week
and try to get
around the block
every night after dinner.
That's good.
Let's get you onto
the bed here.
Oh.
I see they keep
making these things
higher and higher.
Yeah, it's completely
unacceptable.
I'll look
into it immediately.
How long have you had
that cough?
A few days now.
Temp's 103.
Has the palsy been making it
harder to swallow?
Uh, yeah, in the last
couple of months.
Bert keeps
making me smoothies,
but I sneak in a granola bar
every now and then.
Lean forward for me,
would you?
Sure.
Yeah, you're pretty
clogged up.
Wouldn't surprise me
if something went down
the wrong tube
and turned
into a pneumonia.
Well, you can treat that,
can't you?
Yes. I'm gonna start you
on some antibiotics
while we wait for
the culture results,
but for right now,
you do nothing,
and I'll be back soon.
I can do that.
Good.
Dr. Halstead?
I know she has
a degenerative disease,
and that I won't have her
forever, but, uh,
her mind's all there.
I want to be able
to take her home.
I promise I'm gonna do
everything I can.
Thank you.
Hey, dinner tonight?
Can't.
Going to watch
Noah's hockey game.
I know that stuff's
not a big deal to you,
but it's important to me.
"That stuff"? You mean
adult rec league sports?
I mean family.
Why do you think family's
not a big deal to me?
I don't know.
You never talk about them.
There's nothing
to talk about.
Okay.
Hey, Ava.
Can you cover
for me tomorrow?
Sure. Are you getting sick?
No, I'm headed
to Minneapolis.
That sounds even worse.
Why are you going there?
Oh, is that where Robin
moved to?
Yeah, it is.
So, this is what,
a misguided attempt
to win her back?
Forget I asked.
No, I'm happy to do it,
mostly because
I find your gift
for self-flagellation
fascinating.
What is that
supposed to mean?
Just that, from what
I gather, this sounds like
a fool's errand.
CT's own Dr. Phil?
Thank you.
Dr. who?
Dr. Rhodes, CFD just called.
They've got a man trapped
in a collapsed building
and need a surgeon.
You're on trauma today?
I am.
Good.
Ambo's waiting
to take you there right now,
and take Dr. Bekker, too.
You could use
a second pair of hands.
She is CT.
How about one of the other
trauma surgeons?
I'm already losing you.
I can't afford
to lose another.
I'll let Dr. Latham know
where you are.
Let's move it.
You wanted to see me?
Yeah, uh,
what's the status
on Dr. Reese's probation?
Well, she's been doing
daily individualized therapy
and a course
in hospital safety,
so she should be
in good shape
to start back up.
Uh, good.
I'd like you to give me
a detailed progress report
once she returns to work.
Well, actually, I'm not going
to be supervising her anymore.
She's going to be working
under Dr. Chapman.
Why?
Under my supervision,
Dr. Reese
assaulted a patient
with pepper spray.
You know, and... I don't know.
My clinical approach
might have had something
to do with it, so...
I just think for now,
Dr. Chapman might be
a better fit.
Okay.
Whatever you think is best.
Uh, Sharon, I heard that...
That Bert's back
in the hospital today.
Yeah, I heard that, too.
Dr. Manning.
What's going on?
He's inconsolable.
I've tried rocking him,
swaddling him,
singing.
Nothing I do calms him down.
Oh, hi.
Heart rate's in the 190s.
O2 sats have been dropping.
Has he been feeding?
No, nothing.
Is it possible he's still
in shock from the cold?
I don't think so.
I'll go see
if his labs are back.
That won't be necessary.
He's addicted to heroin.
He's going
through withdrawal.
Shh.
I heard about the baby.
Neonatal abstinence syndrome.
That's a...
That's a rough road.
Yeah, I'm giving him
fluids, Ativan,
and aspiration precautions,
but his numbers
aren't getting any better.
How's the mom?
Just wants to get out
and get her next fix.
Why?
Studies show that babies
who are not thriving
actually do
significantly better
when they have
physical contact
with their biological mothers.
So?
So I think we should
have LeAnn hold him
for a little bit.
You can't be serious.
She tried to kill him.
She would be supervised.
Even hearing
the mother's heartbeat
can lower cortisol levels
and stress.
LeAnn had nine months
to do right by her baby.
She lost that chance.
Dr. Charles...
Well, I appreciate
your concern for your...
For your patient,
Dr. Manning,
but I'm also
concerned for mine,
and here's the problem.
That baby's going home
with somebody else.
We let LeAnn bond with him,
and then just rip him away?
Any chance we have
of helping her,
pretty much gone for good.
Dr. Charles, we're talking
about an infant's life.
I'm aware of that,
but I just think that
we should take a beat
and look at all sides of this.
Excuse me, Dr. Manning.
DCFS is on their way.
They've got some
foster parents
that might be interested
in caring for your patient.
Good.
Um, just have them give me
a little bit of time.
Okay? Um, the baby's
not stable yet.
I'll do my best.
Thank you.
Oh, hey, Sharon.
Hello, Bert.
Uh, how's Miss Dempsey doing?
Well, hopefully,
we'll be out of here soon.
Dr. Halstead's
on top of it.
Well, that's good.
And how are you doing?
Me? I'm, you know,
the same,
hanging in there,
trying to help as best I can.
Well, I'm sure it isn't easy.
No, it isn't.
Watching her get
a little worse every day
and struggling
with the things
that were easy
just a few weeks ago and...
Ah.
Anyhow, I...
I should get back.
Yeah.
Once you return to work,
we'll round twice a day,
do a chart review
every morning,
and you'll observe
group therapy every afternoon.
By "observe," do you mean
I will be sitting in?
No, we have
a one-way mirror.
I don't believe in using
house staff as cheap labor.
You first.
Residency is a time to watch
and absorb.
Um, okay.
Uh, though,
speaking about therapy,
I've been reading up
on Erikson's theories,
uh, for strategic interaction,
and it's an interesting take,
focusing on a patient's, uh,
personal strengths,
rather than their pathologies.
Yes, interactional therapy
is interesting,
but you should spend the rest
of your suspension
learning these.
What are they?
Treatment algorithms
for the seven most common
conditions we see.
But these are flow charts.
How do you individualize
the therapy?
Step three.
Is the patient responding
to medication?
Yes, no.
Thursday afternoons,
we do journal club.
You're welcome to listen in.
What happened?
Building's condemned.
Supposed to be empty,
but we thought we heard
somebody inside.
Turned out to be a squatter.
Guy's name is Gary.
He's got a big
chunk of concrete
compressing his left leg
and a piece of rebar
straight up through his groin.
We got pressure on it,
but he's bleeding pretty bad.
If we stop the bleed,
can we get him out?
Hard to say.
Hey, Lieutenant!
Yeah?
Uh, the concrete's a bear.
We can't use the bags on it,
but we might be able to
break it up
with the air chisel.
Be careful.
We haven't been able to
clear a path yet, so we're
gonna have to sneak through.
Watch your heads.
Yeah.
Ah, here we go, Gary.
We got Dr. Rhodes
and Dr. Bekker.
Now, Gary,
we're gonna take
good care of you, all right?
All right.
Hey, you're okay.
All right, draw up
another round of labs,
and hang a gram of vanco.
Yep.
Hey, Ms. Dempsey.
The antibiotics
aren't working, are they?
No, they're not,
and it's possible
the bacteria
has spread from your lungs
into your blood.
Sepsis.
I've been reading.
Yes.
Now, I'm hoping this
new antibiotic we're starting
will turn things around.
But, as you know,
the supranuclear palsy
makes your immune system
less effective,
so there's also a chance
before we get there
your lungs will start
to give out.
Now, if it comes to that,
I am gonna have
to intubate you.
And put me
on a ventilator?
Yes.
But hopefully,
it's only temporary,
until we can clear
the infection.
Okay?
Hang in there.
I'll be back to check on you
in a few minutes.
Dr. Halstead?
I don't want that ventilator.
I understand
this sounds daunting,
but like I said,
if it comes to that,
we may very well be able
to get you off it again soon.
Or you may not.
I know how this all ends.
Lyla,
if your lungs fail
and I don't intubate,
you'll die.
I know.
Okay.
Ms. Crawford?
I told you,
I don't want to talk.
Uh, I'm not here
to discuss detox.
I want to talk to you
about your baby.
What about it?
He's a boy,
and he's withdrawing
from heroin.
He's, um, not eating,
not sleeping.
Breathing and heartbeat
aren't quite as regular
as we'd like.
So give him some medicine.
Well, we have been,
but it is not quite
that simple.
Okay.
Um...
So?
LeAnn, adults have years
to develop
the coping mechanisms
that help us get through
life's trouble spots.
Uh, a newborn
doesn't have any.
You know, for him,
his mother is the only thing
in the world
that makes him feel safe.
Being held by her,
you know,
feeling her skin...
You want me to hold him?
Well, it might be
the best medicine we've got.
I don't...
I don't know
how to hold a baby.
Well, we can show you.
We can teach you
how to do that.
But this baby's sick
'cause of me, right?
There's no way
that more of me
is gonna help it.
Well...
I said no.
Please leave me alone.
Ms. Dempsey?
You wanted to see me?
What can I do for you?
I'm sure I'm the last person
you want to talk to.
I know Bert
didn't do right by you,
but he's a good man.
He shouldn't be alone.
Well, he was fortunate
to have found you.
Thank you.
But he won't have me
for long.
I signed
a do-not-resuscitate order.
I see.
So when my time does come,
would you look after him?
You don't have to
answer now.
Just please think about it.
Let's see what we
got here, all right?
Wait, hold pressure,
hold pressure.
There.
Yep.
Move your hands.
Just a bit.
Can you see it?
No, can't clamp the artery.
Rebar's in the way.
Herrmann, any chance
of getting him out of here?
We're gonna try
the air chisels,
but it don't look good.
All right, we're gonna
have to do a REBOA.
What?
Gary?
An ER-REBOA
is a catheter
with a balloon at the tip
that I can thread into
your aorta.
Once I inflate the balloon,
it'll keep you from bleeding.
Okay.
One moment.
Ready.
Keep pressure there.
Got it.
Yep, hang on.
Watch it.
Hang on, bud.
Connor, we can't do that.
Once you inflate
the balloon,
we'll only have 30 minutes
to get him out of here.
He's lost
too much blood already.
It's gonna take
a lot of movement
to get him out of here,
and we won't be able
to maintain pressure.
So you're going to risk
prolonged loss
of circulation instead?
I realize it can
necessitate amputation,
but I promise you,
if we don't place a REBOA,
he's going to bleed out
right in front of us.
Hey.
Yeah?
Hey, what's going on?
Nothing, Gary.
We're gonna get you
out of here
as fast as we can.
Okay.
Easy.
Just breathe, buddy.
Hang in there.
All right, here we go.
Come in.
Dr. Reese.
How'd it go
with Dr. Chapman?
Uh, it was fine.
She's fine.
Good.
Is there an issue?
I prefer to come back
to your service.
I understand,
really, I do,
but I think it's very
important that you explore
a different clinical approach.
Yeah, well, Dr. Charles,
I'm not an idiot.
Um, I know you think
my anxiety,
my PTSD, if you will,
stems directly
from your being shot,
that our working together
is negatively affecting
my mental health.
But...
First of all, um,
these are my issues,
and I'm working on them,
and second of all,
you chose to bring me
into psychiatry.
So I'm not about to let you
pawn me off
onto that Dr. Chapman...
When you're the psychiatrist
I want to be.
Um... I mean,
I almost lost you once.
I don't want
to lose you again.
Oh. I...
I very much appreciate
what you're saying,
but as a clinician,
and as a...
Dr. Charles...
And as a teacher,
I just think that this is
the best course of action
that we stick
with Dr. Chapman.
Bert, stop.
Sweetheart,
this isn't right. No.
Mr. Goodwin,
it's not up to me.
Bert, please...
How can you
not do anything?
I explained all her options.
But you're her doctor.
Tell her what's best.
She made her wishes
very clear.
There's nothing else
I can do.
So you're just going to
stand around and let her die?
What the hell
kind of hospital is this?
Bert, Bert...
Bert.
She needs another doctor,
one who will do something
if she gets worse.
Bert, this is her choice.
She's got a fever.
She doesn't know
what she wants.
This is hard, I know,
but Dr. Halstead
is doing everything he can
within the scope
of Lyla's wishes.
The best thing
you can do right now
is go back in that room
and be with her.
How are you feeling?
Fine.
You don't think I should
go see my baby, do you?
That's up to you.
They say he's sick.
Yeah, he is.
I never planned
on getting pregnant.
You know?
Whatever.
You think I'm terrible.
I just wish things
had worked out differently
for you and your baby.
Yeah.
But I guess where you're from,
things work out great
for everybody.
Why would you understand?
Actually, I understand
a lot better than you think.
Oh.
Getting hungry yet?
I know you think
this is charming,
but it's not.
Hey, you remember
our first date?
Mmm-hmm.
Mexican food at the mall.
No, I mean afterwards.
We were throwing pennies
into the pond
where people made wishes.
You know what mine was?
A second date
with the pretty woman
sitting next to me.
Hmm. That's a sweet story.
Too bad it ends
with you cheating on her.
I've changed, Maggie.
So you say.
But this time,
I'm smart enough
to draw the line.
Maggie, just...
Barry...
Okay.
We're good.
Keep going.
This place is unstable.
Another shift like that,
and the whole thing's
going to come down, Rhodes.
Guys, you gotta
do something.
We could try coming
from another angle,
but it'll take 20 minutes.
His leg's already cold.
All it's doing now
is preventing us
from getting him to hospital.
Yeah.
Gary,
listen to me.
Your leg is trapped
and we need to get you
out of here.
I'm afraid that the only way
to do that
is to amputate.
What? No.
Gary, I'm very sorry,
but your leg has gone
without blood for too long.
Is that 'cause of that thing
you put in me?
That balloon?
We had to do that
so you wouldn't
lose even more blood,
but now that it's in,
every minute puts you
in more danger.
No.
Gary...
Dr. Rhodes...
Get away!
Gary, listen to me.
I do not want you to die.
We have to get you
to hospital.
Do you understand?
You are not
taking my leg.
I wish we didn't have to,
but you've lost
a lot of blood
and you are in grave danger.
You can't.
Please.
There's gotta be
another way.
I'm sorry,
there isn't.
And I know
how terrible this seems,
but you have
a lot of years to live
and a lot of life
to experience,
and I don't want you
to miss out on that,
but you will
unless you let us help you
right now.
But it's my leg.
I can't.
You can.
Good.
Now, Dr. Rhodes is going
to numb you up.
After that,
you won't feel anything.
Just keep looking
at me, Gary.
I've got you.
Dr. Manning.
What's happening?
He's having a seizure.
Give him a bolus
of Ativan.
O2 sats are down to 72.
He can't get any air.
Bolus is in.
He could suffer
an anoxic brain injury.
Give him 0.1 milligrams
of morphine.
Sats down to 67.
He can't go much longer.
Give him another 0.1.
Sats back to 77.
81.
He's breathing.
Get a pediatric
intubation kit.
If this happens again,
we're going to have to
put him on a vent.
Right.
You have a very
expressive face.
Easy to read.
I'm not sure
that's a good thing.
When I told Bert
that I was terminally ill,
my greatest fear was
that he would leave me.
We had only been dating
a couple of months.
But he didn't.
He stuck with me
through thick
and thin.
He doesn't deserve
to have me leave him now.
So if you need to take
extreme measures
to keep me alive,
do it.
Are you sure?
Yes.
And you understand
that means
I may need
to intubate you
very soon?
I promise,
this is my decision,
not his.
Okay.
I'll go change
the order.
And he's gonna die.
He could, yeah.
And you really think
that having me hold him
is gonna help?
I know it's a lot to ask,
and I just
wouldn't be doing it
if the situation
wasn't so dire.
But you're his mother,
and the baby needs you,
and if there's
any chance at all
that your holding him
might help him get better,
I think we should try.
This was my fault.
I did this to him.
Okay.
He's so small.
Go ahead.
Hold him close, now.
Against your skin.
Hi. Don't cry.
Hi. Hi, yeah?
Yeah.
Dr. Halstead?
She's in SVT.
20 of etomidate,
50 of cisatracurium.
Grab the intubation kit
and charge the paddles to 25.
What's happening?
The infection's
overwhelming her system.
She rescinded her DNR,
so I have to
shock her heart back
into rhythm and intubate.
Mr. Goodwin,
I need you to step back.
She's doing this
for me, isn't she?
She doesn't
want this. Stop.
Stop.
Lyla.
Lyla, this is
a shockable rhythm.
I can try to resuscitate you.
Do you want me to do that?
No.
You heard her.
Don't do this.
Don't.
I love you.
Baghdad.
All right, Karen,
tell the OR
we're on our way up
as soon as this rebar's out.
100 milligrams of ketamine.
Get me a cut-down kit.
And hang two units of O neg
on the rapid transfuser.
On my count.
One, two, three.
All right.
Thanks, guys.
Is that a REBOA?
Couldn't get it down
in the ambo.
Pressure tanked
every time I tried.
Of course it does.
A REBOA in the field
is a problem
waiting to happen.
Whose idea was this?
Mine.
Dr. Rhodes,
do you realize...
It was the right call.
There was no other way
to get him out of there alive.
All right,
wound looks good.
Taking down the REBOA.
Watch the pressure.
Pressure's holding.
Vitals are stable.
All right,
let's get this thing out
and get him up to the OR.
Ready?
Yep.
One, two, three.
No bleeding.
Let's go.
Nice job, Dr. Rhodes.
Yes, that's it.
Right there.
Oh, excuse me.
Can I just have a quick word
with Ms. Crawford first?
Okay.
Hey.
Oh, wow,
he looks great.
A lot better, huh?
He is great.
So, um, we have finally
made some room for him
in the intensive care unit,
so we're gonna...
We're gonna take him
up there now.
Okay.
Oh, do I carry him up,
or do we take him up
in the warmer?
Well, um...
Actually, LeAnn,
there is a...
There's a...
There's a foster couple
up there
who is gonna be looking
after him from here on out.
But he likes me
so much.
I know.
And he is doing so well.
So I should
just keep holding him.
I really wish you could.
Really, I do.
But you said
that he needs me.
I know.
I know I did.
I know how difficult this is.
I really do.
I'm sorry,
but we need to take
the baby now.
No!
I'm his mother!
I'm... I'm his mother.
Dr...
Dr. Charles, please.
I'm sorry.
You know.
You know. Dr. Charles,
please, can you help me?
Please!
I'm sorry.
Please, can you help me?
Please explain.
That is my baby.
Dr. Charles, please.
Please, can you just...
Dr. Charles,
can you please...
I saw Bert.
He's taking it pretty hard.
Yeah, I'm gonna send the kids
over to check on him.
Mmm.
What?
Sharon, do you think
people can change?
Maggie, I don't know.
Go call my kids.
LeAnn, you lost
a lot of blood today.
I'd really rather you stay.
Listen, it may not
feel like it,
but you did
the right thing today.
You were there
for your baby.
It's unfortunate
that you can't take him home,
but there's a methadone clinic
right upstairs.
We can help you
get cleaned up,
and if you can
get back on your feet,
that's the crucial first step
in getting him back.
I'm tired.
You know, I'm...
I'm just gonna go.
LeAnn...
LeAnn.
We had no choice.
We had to do
what's right for the baby.
Oh, yeah, of course.
It's just, you know...
It's sad. It's unlikely
either of them
ever really be whole again.
Ah, the old
Chapman flow charts.
Oh, yeah.
Number seven.
That there's a doozy.
Step seven?
Dr. Reese,
the truth is,
I feel responsible
for letting your situation
get out of hand
the way it did.
It was my job to,
well, guide you
and teach you
and make you a better doctor,
and I...
I let you down.
Dr. Charles...
But ultimately,
some relationships
are just better...
kept intact,
which is why,
if you'd still like to,
when you return,
I would very much welcome
you back on my service.
Really?
Really.
Hey, Gary.
How you doing?
It's weird.
I can feel it,
like it's still there.
Yeah, it's called
phantom limb pain.
Uh...
Takes some time,
but it will fade.
Listen, Gary, I am...
I am very sorry
about your leg.
At least I'm alive.
I'll find a way to move on.
All right, bud.
I'll check on you soon.
Dr. Charles.
I didn't want to believe
that it was over,
but you were right.
I need to let Robin go.
April?
Hmm?
Who's that?
It's my sister.
What?
Emily.
I should've told you.
I never talk about her.
It's painful.
My parents adopted Emily
when she was four.
She had a hard life
before she even came to us.
Still does.
She makes bad decisions,
acts out,
then blows up
when I try to help her,
and I swore the last time
that I wouldn't let myself
get involved again.
When was that?
It was four years ago.
Maybe I should
give her a call.
Hey.
Thank you for today.
Uh, you were great.
I did feel a bit like
Bonnie Henna out there.
Who?
South African action hero.
Have a good night.
Oh, and no need to cover
for me tomorrow.
I'll be here.
You're not going
to Minneapolis?
Nope.
Good evening, sir.
Can I help you?
I'm looking for a change.
What model is this?
The 911 4S.
Beautiful car.
Yes, it is.
You got the keys?
I'm sorry,
but we're actually
done doing test drives
for the night.
I don't want to test drive.
I want to buy it.
Oh, of course.
Just give me a moment.
Mmm.
I'll see you
in the morning.
Mmm.
No.
You should stay.
Yeah?
Mmm-hmm.
What about Owen?
Mmm.
He's got to
find out sometime.
Are you sure?
Mmm-hmm. I'm sure.
This is
so much better than
scraping ice
off my windshield.