She still isn't answering.
She's probably not allowed
to have her phone
at the poker table.
She shouldn't be
at the poker table
at 7:00 a.m.
She should be back
with my car,
so I can get to work.
Babe, it's your day off.
From the hospital.
Emily knows I check
on the kids
at the homeless encampment.
They count on me.
They'll understand
if you're a few minutes late.
If Emily's gonna live here,
she needs to get
her act together,
make a plan.
This isn't some vacation.
Come on,
I'll give you a ride.
I've come to recognize
your expressions pretty well.
This one's my least favorite.
I wish I had better news.
But look...
Even though
your cardiac output
is decreasing,
you are still highest status
on the transplant list.
You're first in line.
I appreciate your optimism,
Dr. Rhodes,
as always.
Hang in there, Bob.
Uh-huh.
You know, for my part,
I'm just not seeing
any organic causes.
Excuse me, I...
Sorry to interrupt.
Um... Sarah,
I've just been up
to see your father.
His stroke volume,
systolic arterial pressure,
and pulse pressure have all
decreased since yesterday.
I just can't keep
the fluid off of his lungs.
I see.
I promise you,
we're doing everything we can
to find him
a new heart, but...
If you wanna say good-bye,
I would consider
doing it today.
I'm very sorry.
Okay.
How long have
you had a fever?
A few days now.
And are you always
this short of breath?
Lately, yeah.
Athena, stop!
Hey, Dr. Choi.
Hey, Deb. Can I take
a look at your legs?
Yeah, sure.
How long have you been
getting these spots?
Why? Are they bad?
I'm not sure,
but I'd like to prick your
finger to check your blood.
Okay, yeah.
All right.
Ethan, I know, I'm sorry,
I promised I'd be home,
but I had half the table
on tilt,
and I just
lost track of time.
Whatever. Take the car.
I'll get a cab.
I'm not gonna just
leave you here.
What can I do to help?
I don't want your help.
Ethan, you don't
have to be like that.
He doesn't have
to be like that.
Hi. Emily.
Josh.
Nice to meet you.
Uh, cute dog.
Thank you.
What kind of tent do you use?
Uh, it's an old Coleman.
Has a rain fly.
Nice.
Hold on.
Josh...
I'm seeing some cells
in your blood
called lymphoblasts.
That plus your other symptoms
make me concerned enough
that I'd like to bring you
into the hospital.
Why? What do you think it is?
It could be
all sorts of things...
But what I'm worried
about is leukemia.
Isn't that a kind of cancer?
It is.
Josh, this is important.
Look, I mean,
Athena needs me out here.
And if I go back with you,
you're gonna have to
call my parents,
the people that adopted me,
and I don't think I want that.
Did they mistreat you?
No, no, no, they're okay.
It's just, uh...
Things didn't really work out
with them, you know?
You don't have to call
his parents, right?
Em...
Is that true?
You're only 16.
Legally, they need
to be notified.
I mean, if his life
is on the line,
you could make an exception.
I mean, if you could do that,
I'm sure I could get Deb
to watch Athena, if it's just
for the afternoon.
We could run
some tests first,
make sure we know
what's going on.
Hey, Deb,
could I ask you a favor?
You shouldn't have done that.
Eventually I'm gonna
have to call his parents.
What are you
busting on me for?
Got him to come in,
didn't I?
Wow.
One of our patients
is well-loved.
Actually, they came for me.
Really?
Mmm.
The enchanting Dr. Bekker.
What?
Uh, seems they're
from your father.
My father?
Yeah.
Uh, you've been seeing him?
Is, uh... Is that a problem?
No, no, it's not a problem.
Just... Uh, he's just...
You know what, forget it.
Enjoy the flowers.
Are you two still at it?
At what?
I've barely seen
you speak two words
to each other in a week.
Whatever this is,
you need to work it out.
Everything's fine.
Oh, everything's fine?
Mmm-hmm.
Good.
Dr. Manning, Dr. Halstead,
you're up, Treatment Four.
Hey.
Kevin Parks.
He's 10 years old.
He woke up with
8 out of 10
abdominal pain
and a fever of 103.
We gave him Tylenol
and a cool bath,
but nothing's worked.
Okay.
All right, Kevin,
let's get you up on the bed.
Ow, ow. That hurts.
That hurts? All right.
All right, you got it.
We're gonna figure out why.
There you go.
Hi, Kevin, I'm Dr. Manning.
This is Dr. Halstead.
Can you show us
where it hurts?
Right here?
Right there? Okay.
Has anything like this
ever happened before?
No, never.
Abdomen is tender
but not rigid,
with no rebound.
Bowel sounds are decreased.
I don't like it.
It could still be
his appendix,
Crohn's disease,
ulcerative colitis.
Temp's up to 104.
Give Ibuprofen
to start cooling measures.
Is there any other medical
history we should be aware of?
Yes, he's been
diagnosed with PANDAS.
PANDAS?
Uh, Pediatric Autoimmune
Neuropsychiatric Disorder
Associated with
Streptococcal Infection.
Kevin started getting
tics and OCD
after a strep infection
two years ago.
Nobody else could figure out
what it was,
until finally Dr. Kravitz
diagnosed him.
Okay, we'll be sure
to give him a call.
I've heard of Dr. Kravitz.
He sees a lot of kids
with PANDAS, right?
He's one of the nation's
top experts.
I'm guessing
Dr. Kravitz put Kevin
on long-term
prophylactic antibiotics
to fight the residual strep?
Yes, he did.
CBC, chem panel,
blood cultures,
abdominal CT, and hang
a gram of vanco, stat.
We're gonna start him
on some medication
while we run some tests
to try to figure out
what's going on, okay?
We'll be back
to check on him shortly.
Thank you.
Hey, you've heard
of this Dr. Kravitz.
He labels every kid's
neurological condition
as PANDAS.
It's not even an officially
recognized diagnosis.
Either way, right now,
that child is in real pain
with a real fever.
Right, because he's been on
three different antibiotics
for over 12 months,
which we both know
has wiped out
all the healthy flora
in his gut,
causing a massive
superinfection.
I mean, all because
his parents
shopped around for a doctor
willing to blame Kevin's
neurologic tics on strep,
instead of admitting
they most likely passed it on
to him genetically.
Okay, but dismissing them
isn't gonna help.
They are upset and worried.
And what they're doing
to try and fix him
might wind up killing him.
Dr. Sexton,
Treatment Six is open.
You're up.
We got Frank Larson, 74.
He was found unconscious
in an abandoned warehouse.
Bradycardic at 45,
BP's 90 over 60,
respiration's 10,
and satting at 91%.
Mr. Larson,
do you know where you are?
Let's move him
on one, two, three.
Dad? Dad, what happened?
Is he... Is he all right?
That's what we're trying
to figure out.
Frank, can you hear me?
Can you hear me, Frank?
He goes around
feeding the stray cats,
but he has dementia
and he gets lost.
Does he have any other
medical conditions?
No.
You're the one examining him.
What do you think it could be?
It's hard to say right now.
We need to let the doctor
run some tests.
It looks like
he doesn't have any injuries,
but, yes, I would like
to run some more tests
to figure out
what's going on.
Okay.
Okay?
Dad, I'll be
right here, okay?
I'm right here.
I'm not going anywhere.
Sorry. Big sister moment.
Yep.
Anyway, let's get an EKG,
CBC, chem panels, troponins,
tox screens, and a head CT.
We'll figure this out.
Dr. Reese,
I was just, um...
I was just
heading up to...
To check on your dad.
Okay.
Listen, I, um...
I know you've had a very
complicated relationship,
and this is really
none of my business,
but... I think that
if he should die
before you have a chance
to speak to him,
that could very
possibly be something
you would come to regret.
My father
has clearly stated
that he doesn't want me
to be a part of his life,
so, uh, whatever regrets
I may have...
I just don't think
any of them will be resolved
by me talking to him.
Okay.
You, uh...
You accepting visitors?
It depends.
Is it professional
or is it personal?
Uh... Personal?
Then by all means.
I, um...
I heard about
your situation. Mmm.
Really so sorry
that it's come to this.
Yeah, what can I say?
It's been kind of
a chess game
between the two of us,
hasn't it?
I regret that you see it
that way.
Uh... I would hope
that you would...
Ha.
It's ironic.
You made me cut Sarah
out of my life
to get a heart,
and I end up
with neither.
Robert, it was
never my intention
to have you cut Sarah
out of your life.
Semantics.
Uh, in any case,
you play a good game.
Dr. Bekker...
You're looking lovely.
Thank you.
And thank you
for the flowers.
That was
quite unnecessary.
Did you like them?
They're beautiful.
Though, I must admit,
the money would've been
better spent
as part of your donation
to the department.
Speaking of which,
I glanced
at that information
you gave me concerning...
Da Vinci robotic
surgical system?
Yes, that's, uh...
It was very impressive,
but a little technical
for a layman like myself.
Perhaps you could explain
the details to me?
Of course.
How 'bout tonight?
Over dinner?
Mr. Rhodes...
The flowers? Dinner?
Is it me or are you trying
to make your son crazy?
Dr. Bekker, you are
an intelligent,
attractive, dynamic woman,
and if this
makes Connor crazy,
then so be it.
Look, I and the entire
cardiothoracic department
truly appreciate
your patronage,
but you and I are going
to keep our relationship
on a professional level.
Oh. All right.
I'll have the head of
philanthropy services
give you a call
this afternoon.
Thank you.
Dr. Rhodes,
Trauma Three.
Yep.
All right, Brett,
what do we got?
David Gray,
50-year-old bystander
in an attempted robbery.
He got shot in the head.
GCS, 6.
He's only responding
to painful stimuli.
We couldn't intubate
in the field.
All right, give me
an intubation kit.
150 of mannitol,
500 of keppra.
Got it.
All right, on my count,
one, two, three.
Entry wound,
left parietal skull,
no exit.
Get neurosurg
down here ASAP.
And get me a Cordis kit.
Yep.
There we go.
No reactions to light.
All right, I'm in.
No corneal reflex either.
We're losing him.
Cordis kit.
Brainstem reflexes
are completely absent,
and his pupils are
fixed and blown.
He was responding to pain
in the ambo.
Dr. Rhodes, he's GCS 3.
Dr. Rhodes,
he's braindead.
Is he a donor?
Yeah.
Okay, let's get an angio
to confirm brain death,
then get a cardiac echo.
I've got a patient
who needs a heart.
You're wasting your time
on this one, Dr. Rhodes.
I heard significant mitral
regurg on auscultation.
There's no way
that heart is viable.
Maybe not now, but that
doesn't mean I can't fix it.
Let's get him up
to Radiology now.
A drug overdose?
Opioids.
Your father's tox screen
showed extremely high levels.
Bolus him with 2 of narcan,
then start a drip.
It can't be.
My dad doesn't do drugs.
I mean, he... He never has.
He doesn't even drink.
What about pain medication?
He doesn't take anything.
You need to run
some more tests.
Ma'am, Dr. Sexton has run
all the appropriate...
Is there anything
around the house?
Um, Vicodin?
Tylenol with codeine?
No, I... I cleaned
all the medicine cabinets out.
We don't have anything.
Hmm, then he may have
gotten it outside the house.
What? You think I'm letting
him shoot up or something?
No, I'm just saying...
Look, your test is wrong.
You need to redo it.
These tests, they are
usually pretty accurate...
And I know my father.
Look, if you need to consult
with another doctor,
then maybe...
No.
I'll redo the test.
But in the meantime,
I'm gonna give him
some medicine
to reverse the opioids,
just so we can try
and wake him up.
Okay.
Thanks.
Administer the narcan.
Hi.
So, Kevin's scans indicate
toxic megacolon.
It's a dangerous
intestinal infection
caused by an overgrowth
of opportunistic bacteria.
Which is most likely due to
his long-term antibiotic use.
So the new medicine you're
giving him should fix it?
It's not that simple.
Kevin's bowel is so inflamed,
it's become
dangerously dilated.
And if it perforates,
it's a life threatening
situation,
which is why
we need to release
the pressure from his colon
to try and prevent that.
We appreciate your help,
but we've spoken
with Dr. Kravitz,
and he wants Kevin
transferred over there.
Dr. Kravitz says
if we treat him incorrectly,
it's only going to
make Kevin's
neurologic symptoms worse.
He wants to give him
an infusion of IVIg
to prevent that.
Kevin's tics are the least
of his problems right now.
We need to focus on
treating his infection.
We want that too,
but Kevin's tics
are a big problem.
They're odd,
and the kids at school
are starting
to stare at him.
We just don't
wanna do anything
to compromise his future.
I understand, but...
We'll do the IVIg here.
Natalie...
That would work.
Great, we'll get started
right away.
Thank you so much.
Yeah.
Why are you indulging them
like this?
Indulging them?
You know full well the IVIg
will have exactly zero
therapeutic benefit.
It's keeping Kevin
in the hospital.
Why are you being
so negative?
I'm just being realistic.
The more you humor them,
the less likely
they'll ever be
to seek out an actual
effective therapy
for what is most likely
a genetic
neurologic condition.
So what do you want
me to do, Will?
Have them sign out and leave?
Nah, you should just
give them a placebo. IVIg.
If that's what's gonna
allow us to do our job,
then that's exactly
what I'm gonna do.
Just a little bit longer.
I need to get back to Athena.
I'm still waiting on
a few more tests,
so please,
don't go anywhere yet.
Dr. Charles...
I've got a runaway kid
with confirmed leukemia,
but I can't get him
to give me his parents'
contact information,
and Oncology
won't begin treatment
till they're sure
he's not gonna be living
in a tent on the streets
during his recovery.
Figure his parents
might have abused him?
Apparently not.
He's adopted, but he says
they're nice people.
It just wasn't a good fit.
And you're sure
he understands
the danger here?
Cancer? Life or death?
Says he does,
but I don't know.
Let me have a chat with him.
Thanks.
There's too much
retrograde flow.
The leaflet's
totally eaten away.
Shame to have an otherwise
perfectly good heart
go to waste.
It's not gonna go to waste.
Excuse me?
This heart
is an HLA match
for my patient.
I'm gonna do a valve repair.
You're joking.
Get him prepped
for surgery, thanks.
You're going to do
major surgery on this heart,
which by itself contains
significant morbidity
and mortality,
and then turn around
and transplant it
into someone else?
Uh-huh.
You'll kill the recipient
on the table.
So don't scrub in.
I'm sure with
your active social life,
there are things
you'd rather be doing anyways.
Now, if you will excuse me,
I am going to prep
for my valve repair.
Ms. Larson,
the retests once again show
high levels of opioids.
I'm sorry.
Well, then why
isn't he waking up?
Should we be doing
something else?
Well, with overdoses
that large,
it can sometimes...
Dr. Sexton...
Okay, um,
we need to step out.
Let's clear the room.
Wha... What's going on?
Step out.
That white powder
on his jacket,
I'm guessing
that's fentanyl.
What's that?
A synthetic opiate.
Now, he could have
either inhaled it
or even just touched it,
but it's 100 times stronger
than heroin.
That could explain why
the narcan's moving so slow.
But how did he get it?
They smuggle it in
from China
and cut it
in abandoned buildings.
All your dad had to do
was brush up against some
while he was feeding
stray cats.
We're notifying CPD, CFD,
anyone who might've
come in contact.
Now, um, you have to test it,
but I think we have fentanyl.
Okay, I'll set up
the decon protocol
out in the ambulance bay,
and I'll call Goodwin.
Doris, door.
Okay, got it.
We will get you back in
the room, but please come.
You gotta strip.
I feel fine.
Come on, Maggie.
You come on.
Even absorbed
through the skin,
fentanyl can cause
mental status changes
and respiratory distress.
Strip.
She's right, Cesar.
Go get some clean clothes.
I don't like this
at all, Maggie.
We got too many sick people
in here to take any chances.
We need to scrub down
the back half of the ED,
and put us on bypass
until we get the go-ahead
from the decontamination team.
Yes, ma'am.
All right.
All finished.
You okay, Kevin?
Can I have a word?
Kevin's latest scans show
increasing edema
across the wall of his bowel,
indicating lack of blood flow.
At this point, we need to
consider surgical resection.
Surgery?
Shouldn't we finish
the IVIg first
to see if it helps?
He can keep getting it,
but we really need
to move him upstairs.
We need to call Dr. Kravitz.
Mr. and Mrs. Parks,
your son
is running out of time.
My wife works tirelessly
to try to fix
our son's problems,
and if she has
any hesitation at all,
then we need
to listen to her.
How 'bout I call Dr. Kravitz
and explain the situation
to him, okay?
Could you do that?
Of course.
Is there a bathroom nearby?
Right down the hall.
So, you're just gonna
keep encouraging them
to follow this quack?
Now is not the time to start
an argument with them.
You know, it must be nice
always being right.
I'm sorry?
From the moment
we started this case,
everything's been your way.
"We can't do this,
we have to do that."
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about everything
always being done your way.
How we treat patients,
what we can
or can't tell them...
What?
Whether you and I are
together or split up
or on a break.
Is that what this is about?
You and me?
Because it definitely
wasn't my idea
to go hook up with
some woman in a bar.
I told you,
it went nowhere.
Oh, and that's supposed
to make me feel better?
I made a mistake.
I'm not perfect.
But at least I admit it.
I don't think I'm perfect.
Okay, all I can say, Natalie,
is that it's very hard
for us mere mortals
to measure up to you.
Thanks, Officer Burgess,
I appreciate your help.
What are you still
doing here?
I wanted to see
how Josh is doing.
He's not letting us
treat him.
Luckily, PD's got a lead
on his parents.
Wait, you said you weren't
going to call his parents.
I said I'd end up
calling them eventually.
Yeah, but you don't have to.
I mean, there are
other ways to do this.
This is what Josh needs
to stay alive.
You don't know
what Josh needs.
And you do?
Look, you're not adopted.
You don't know what it's like.
Josh needs
a bone marrow transplant,
and he won't get it
if he's living
on the streets.
So you're just gonna do
whatever you want?
Yeah, because you always
know better than everyone.
No, I don't,
but I do know that
when his immune system
is obliterated by chemo,
he's gonna need to recover
in a stable,
clean environment,
and if you're
too irresponsible
to understand that,
then stay out of my way.
Mrs. Parks?
I'm sorry,
I was just finishing up.
Are you all right?
I'm just stressed.
Does that help?
What?
The handwashing.
It used to...
In high school,
but I stopped for a long time,
till Kevin got sick.
Having a child with
uncontrollable tics
must be so stressful.
That's why we've seen
so many doctors.
My husband likes answers.
Does he know about this?
He's already got enough
that he didn't sign up for.
What would be the point?
It might help you and Kevin.
I don't see how.
Kathy, you have OCD,
like Kevin,
and it's not caused by
any bacterial infection.
It's genetic,
something a child inherits
from the parents.
I appreciate your concern,
but please,
just take care of
Kevin's intestines.
I'll worry about the rest.
Excuse me, are you all right?
Um, sorry,
I'm... I'm fine.
I'm Dr. Reese
from Psychiatry.
Can I help?
Uh, my dad ran into
some trouble today.
He has dementia.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I know that's really hard.
It's completely normal
to feel overwhelmed.
It's like
he's a different person.
And sometimes,
I wonder if maybe...
If maybe it would be
better if he...
Does that make me
a horrible person?
No.
No, it doesn't
make you horrible.
Almost anyone in your position
would have these thoughts.
Talked to your patient.
Nice kid.
Is he still insisting on
going back to
the homeless encampment?
He feels pretty strongly
about it.
Is he suicidal?
Nope, he definitely
seems to wanna live.
Then he shouldn't
object so much
to me calling his parents.
I need to spend
a little more time with him,
but off the top of my head,
I'd say that
Josh is dealing with
a classic case of
attachment disorder.
Does that explain
why he'd rather
risk his life
than live with his parents
for a couple of months?
I know it seems bizarre,
but those two years
that he was at the orphanage,
it's that critical period
when babies need
parental affection the most.
And if they're in a facility
where they don't get it,
their brains actually
become wired differently,
leaving them poorly adapted
to cope with the complexities
of giving and receiving love,
I mean, sometimes
for the rest of their lives.
I hear what you're saying,
Dr. Charles...
But Josh has his whole life
to live as far from
his parents as he wants,
if we treat his cancer.
Scissors to Dr. Bekker.
Scissors.
So, what's the story
with you and my friend
with the flowers?
I'm definitely picking up
on some rancor.
How do I put this? Uh...
My father and I
have always had an
unhealthy competition.
Competition?
You're a cardiothoracic
surgeon.
What is there
to compete over?
Well, next time
you two get together,
you can ask him about it.
Snip.
Let's take him off pump.
Paddles.
And clear.
No retrograde flow.
Congratulations,
we have a working valve.
I'm gonna go let
my patient know
that he's about
to get a new heart.
Okay, I'll let her know.
Sharon?
Yeah?
That was Peter Kalmick.
Apparently the board
is refusing to let us
go on bypass.
They're overriding
my decision?
They didn't find
sufficient reason
to take such drastic action.
There were enough opioids
on that man's coat
to drop
a herd of elephants.
Yep.
You keep us on bypass.
I'll deal with the board.
I got you.
Mr. and Mrs. Logan?
I'm Dr. Choi.
I've been taking care of Josh.
Thank you so much
for contacting us.
Of course. Please.
Uh, he's run away before,
but he'd always come back,
and then this time...
We contacted the police.
We tried every way
we could to find him.
I do have to warn you,
calling you was
my idea, not his,
but he's very ill
and he needs help,
so please,
no matter how this goes,
try to understand
and be patient.
Of course.
He's right over here.
April...
My patient in Two didn't go
for anymore tests, did he?
Doesn't look like it.
I'm sorry.
Just give me a minute.
Leah, did you see
my patient?
Sixteen-year-old boy,
tall, brown hair?
Yeah, I think so.
Left with a young woman
about 20 minutes ago.
Now, this shows distribution
of aggregate hospital costs
and stays by payer
for our last fiscal year.
Excuse me...
I'm sorry to interrupt.
Ms. Goodwin.
As Executive Director of
Patient and Medical Services,
the safety of
our staff and patients
is my responsibility.
There are few substances
more dangerous and terrifying
than fentanyl.
Even a minute amount inhaled
or absorbed through the skin
can cause an overdose
and even death,
and while I understand
going on bypass
costs this hospital money,
if just one person
goes into respiratory failure
from coming in contact
with this drug,
I guarantee
that the damage to
this hospital's reputation
will be far costlier.
So, I'm sure
you'll all agree
that keeping us on bypass
is medically and fiscally
the best course of action.
Well...
Since you put it like that...
Thank you.
I'll be in my office
if anyone has
anymore questions.
Sharon...
You shouldn't have done that.
I don't see that
I had a choice.
Listen, I'm up here
with them, okay?
I hear which way
the wind is blowing,
and lately, the board feels
that you are
not making decisions
that are aligned with
this hospital's interests.
Well, I'm sorry, Peter,
but I thought this hospital's
foremost interest
was in treatment of patients.
You're not hearing me,
and you keep taking
an adversarial position
vis--vis the board
and they will fire you.
Hey, Dad.
Sarah...
So nice of you to come.
I just wanted to, um,
see how you're doing.
Did you?
No ulterior motive?
What?
Sure you didn't come here
to make yourself feel better
by doing the right thing?
That this visit
isn't all about you?
Dad...
Maybe I'm not the only one
with personality disorder.
Are you serious?
Oh, don't be so sensitive.
Come now.
Let's see what I can do
to leave you with
a good memory.
Okay, this was
clearly a mistake.
Should we sit and reminisce?
Perhaps order
some hot cocoa?
Goodbye, Dad.
No, stay.
Let's focus
on getting you some closure.
I found your dad a heart.
Thank you.
We're gonna take him
to do the transplant now.
Dr. Choi?
Please wait here a second.
What do you think
you're doing?
He wanted to come
back to Athena,
so I called us an Uber.
Em, I get it.
He needs his dog,
and I don't
wanna take that from him,
but right now,
he needs our help even more.
This isn't a game.
Like I don't know that?
But you don't
understand him. I do.
I've been there.
What do you mean?
You've been homeless?
Yeah.
But that's not important.
What matters is that this dog
is the only thing in the world
Josh can relate to.
I think he needs her so much
that if he had to
go on without her,
he'd rather die.
All right.
Tell Josh to pack his clothes,
and we'll take the dog
with us.
Help! Somebody!
Uh, what's going on?
What's happening?
His lungs are full of fluid.
He must've been coming to
and inhaled against
his glottis.
Sats down to 83.
He lost his IV.
Uh, do something!
Save him!
Just so you understand,
with the lack of oxygen,
there's no guarantee
that he won't have
new physical
or neurological deficits.
Just save him, please.
Do you understand
what Dr. Sexton is saying?
He's my father.
Please, don't let him die.
Okay, give 20 of Lasix,
20 of etomidate, 50 of sux.
Open an intubation kit
and a central line kit, now.
Can you intubate?
Yeah.
Sats at 65.
He's in PEA. Bag him.
Give me a milligram of
epinephrine. I'll start CPR.
Epinephrine's in.
He's still in PEA.
Another milligram.
Second milligram in.
Come on, Dad.
Still in PEA.
Another milligram.
Third milligram's in.
What? No.
No, no, no, no.
I'm sorry.
Daddy!
Time of death, 17:13.
I'm sorry.
His abdomen's more distended,
and his pain is getting worse.
Like I was saying, we need
to take him up to surgery.
Dale, maybe
we should let them.
Are you sure that
that's necessary?
Did you even talk
to Dr. Kravitz?
He says that
general anesthesia will
exacerbate Kevin's PANDAS.
You're not hearing me.
At the moment, that is
not our biggest concern.
But Dr. Kravitz says...
Forget about Dr. Kravitz.
Kevin doesn't have PANDAS.
His tics are from me.
What are you talking about?
He has OCD.
It's not from strep.
It's genetic.
He inherited it from me.
It's a far more
likely explanation.
So the antibiotics,
the... All of it...
He never needed them.
It's... It's my fault.
All my fault.
Why didn't you tell me
you had OCD?
I thought if you knew
something was wrong with me,
you wouldn't love me.
Do the surgery.
Dale, wait...
We'll get Kevin
ready to go upstairs.
His temperature is 99.6.
It could signal
the onset of infection,
which would be
a contraindication
for performing the transplant.
He won't get the heart?
No, I'm sorry.
He always runs warm.
What?
My dad, um...
His temperature
always runs high.
It's normal for him,
which would mean that
this isn't an infection.
You're sure?
Because if that's the case,
then he could
still get the heart.
Yes, I'm sure he's fine.
Let's get Dr. Haywood
up to the O.R.
Yes, sir.
All right.
Ejection fraction looks good.
Normal rate and rhythm.
I think we did it.
Well done, Dr. Rhodes.
You as well.
Dr. Mehta,
will you please close?
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
I must admit,
despite your
overall surliness,
your determination today
in the face of great odds
was admirable.
I will take that
as a compliment.
You should.
I'm gonna go take
my flowers home.
Ava...
It's not that it's my dad
you're dating...
I wish that you weren't
dating anybody at all.
As long as we're making
confessions,
I was never
dating your father.
But you didn't mind me
thinking so.
No, I didn't mind.
Oh, Josh.
Hello, Josh.
Hi.
Uh, Dr. Choi told us
about what's going on,
and we're gonna get through
this, honey, together.
I'm sorry I caused you
so much trouble.
We're just glad
to see you again,
and that you're safe.
Josh will need to stay here
for about two weeks,
but after that, he's agreed
to go home with you,
if you let him bring his dog.
Of course.
Anything.
What's its name?
Athena.
Well, we'll take
care of Athena.
Please follow me.
Uh, we'll get Athena
after we settle Josh in.
Of course.
He's never really
gonna be able
to love them back, is he?
By our definition?
Unlikely.
I don't know who to feel
more sorry for,
the parents or him.
Thanks.
Really?
For what?
You did good today.
Maybe we could use you
around here.
Athena...
It'd be so hard
to do that all alone.
What?
It's just...
I know when mom
and dad get old,
at least we'll face it
together.
Kevin's fever
is coming down,
and his numbers
all look great.
I think he's gonna be okay.
Thank you, Dr. Manning.
At least they can
start getting Kevin
the help he needs.
Yeah.
Hey, Will...
I'm not perfect.
I have got a million
fears and insecurities
about being
a doctor, a mother,
everything.
It's exhausting.
But, yes, sometimes, I
push it too far.
It's okay.
I understand.
Good.
It still doesn't mean you get
a pass for the other night.
Looks like he's gonna live.
Yeah.
Now what?