There's a reason the punch line
to so many doctor
jokes start with,
"I've got good news
and bad news."
Bad news. The
air-conditioner coil is broken.
- And?
- And, it's hot.
That's all. There is no more.
Come on, it's
freaking fall already.
It's global warming already.
Close the fridge.
- Zola!
- Can you fix it?
Can I fix it?
I am a heart surgeon.
Right, I can fix anything.
No, I fix people.
That's an air
conditioner. You fix it.
I don't want to screw up
my hands. I'm a surgeon, too.
- Eh.
- What do you mean "Eh"?
- You work in a clinic.
- Shut up.
Close the fridge!
Can we just get the hell
out of this sweat box already?
Gladly. Zola, Bailey!
Often, the bad news is so bad
when something good comes along
we tend to go a
little overboard.
It's a glorious day
is it not, Dr. Grey?
Well, I could do with 20 degrees
cooler and an air-conditioner repairman.
It's the kind of day
when people say,
"Dr. Bailey, why did
you become a doctor?"
you think of a
day like this one.
Ask me why it's a glorious day.
Do you really need me
for this conversation?
I have a liver
transplant for a patient
who's been waiting
forever on the UNOS list.
Patient is a sweet old grandma.
Do you know how many people
pushing 80 get livers, Grey?
Not many people make
it to the top of that list.
Not many people have
Miranda Bailey in their corner,
but this one does and so today, I
am Ed McMahon with a big check.
It's a glorious day.
Dr. Reed to Medical Records.
Oh, hey, you're back.
Yeah. Of course, I'm
back. Why wouldn't I be?
No, I mean, you're back early.
Nope 29th. Always been the 29th.
Well, then I have
good news for you.
You still get three days with your
baby because today's the 26th.
Nope. 29th, see?
- Really?
- Oh, trust me.
I have been looking
forward to this day.
I mean, it's been great
and I love my baby...
but God, I missed work
and talking to people
who can actually talk back.
Talking to yourself
is overrated.
Hello?
Excuse me.
And I'm still talking to myself.
"Great to have you back, Kepner."
- Hey.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
Edwards. What are you doing?
I was inputting data into
Dr. Shepherd's amygdala hijack study.
Or you can scrub in with me
on a massive cardiac myxoma.
It's a very difficult procedure. I
need the best resident I can get.
I'm sorry. The best resident?
How is she the best resident?
You weren't
supposed to hear that.
- You up for it?
- How is that a question?
Let's go.
The best resident? What the
hell? Does everyone say that?
Come on define best.
DeLuca you're with me.
Oh, Chief, I'm free if you want
a senior resident over an intern.
I need DeLuca. That's
why I said DeLuca.
DeLuca move.
Here. Get up to speed.
- I think I'm on O.B. today, actually.
- You're with me, now.
I can do that. I have power.
Okay that's... Oh,
wait, am I in trouble?
You've had a rough few weeks.
I thought you'd like some unmitigated joy,
so today you're going to be Ed McMahon!
I don't know who that is.
Now see that makes me feel
old. I just said I was giving you joy.
Do you really want
to make me feel old
in response to my joy giving?
Do you think that's wise?
Do you think that will make
me more likely to give you joy?
- No.
- No, DeLuca. No, it will not.
You are quite young.
I'm a baby and Ed
McMahon is a god.
And here comes the joy.
My hero!
Now, hold on. Hold on.
Let's just make some
room so the doctors can sit.
The poor folks have
been on their feet all day.
We're fine. No, Lily,
I'm not taking your seat.
Well, then we're not listening.
Oh, come on, rest your doggies.
- Get over here.
- All right.
Okay.
I knew you wouldn't
want to take that off.
- Did I tell you?
- You were right.
I'm gonna have
something for you, too,
but today my hand's
just a little bit shaky.
That's okay. I wasn't
really expecting anything.
Well, you're gonna
get snickerdoodles
whether you were
expecting them or not.
- Samantha.
- Oh, yeah.
- Ta-da.
- Thank you.
- Dr. DeLuca,
you want to present?
- Oh, yes.
- June Crowley...
- No, call me Granny June, honey.
- Everybody does.
- Granny June Crowley.
Class 3, MELD 20,
end stage liver disease,
scheduled to receive
a transplant today after
waiting, wow, three years.
Three years.
Donor liver arrives at 16:30.
This time tomorrow you
are gonna be a new woman.
Mmm-hmm.
Well, I feel blessed
having the world's nicest
doctors taking care of me.
Karen.
He's a hottie, right?
No, he's a hottie.
Oh, my God, Granny, stop.
But, yes.
So, don't be shy.
Give him a hug.
Well, heck, I'll give him a hug.
See?
Granny's gonna
get a liver today!
- Yes!
- Yes, she is!
How can I help?
Chelsea here took a
run in the triple-digit heat.
Motorists found her collapsed
by the side of the road.
Core body temp... 40.2.
EKG looks fine. It's a
clear-cut case of heat stroke.
She'll need to be cooled
down and admitted.
Wilson call ICU. I'm
gonna need CBCs, LFTs,
- and a CK level.
- Okay.
We should get myoglobin
levels on blood and urine.
Chelsea, we're gonna take you upstairs
and try to get this temp down okay?
Why are all these
people here? Where am I?
Chelsea, you're in the hospital.
You got a little overheated.
- Is there someone
we can call for you?
- My sister.
She's my emergency
contact in my phone.
All right, let's get her
on the cooling blanket.
I'll grab one.
Try to hang in there, Chelsea.
Pierce says your
air conditioner died.
I thought maybe I could help.
- You can fix an air conditioner?
- No, I don't need to.
Mine's not broken,
and I'm willing to share it
with a colleague in need.
See I'm, I'm a giver.
See it's my weak spot.
That's not an offer
a colleague makes.
We're just talking
about the weather.
Colleagues talk
You need a cooling blanket.
I'm gonna get her.
Oh, hi.
Hi.
What do you need?
Cooling blankets.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Really? 'Cause you
look super sketchy.
Close the door.
You're not looking
for drugs, right?
- No. Meredith!
- Oh. Well, I don't know.
I mean, I'm supposed
to ask if I care, right?
I'm pregnant.
Congratulations!
I didn't even know you
were trying. That's wonderful.
We just started.
Oh, my goodness,
I'm thrilled for you guys.
- Owen must be thrilled.
- I don't know when to tell him.
I don't want to get his
hopes up until I'm sure.
He's really excited about this.
You just think you're pregnant?
I'm late. I'm never late. Never.
So, this isn't real?
I can't find the freaking
pregnancy tests.
Wait. I hugged you and you
haven't even peed on a stick yet?
I can't find the sticks.
Tell Owen now or
later. That's your call.
Tell me when it's real.
Hi.
What?
Do you have a minute?
Oh, hey. Bring a
Daughter to Work Day?
Yeah, it's April's
first day back,
but I got paged for an
emergency hand de-gloving.
Guy's got his hand
caught in a metal press.
Got to get her to the
daycare. You seen April at all?
I saw her in the pit.
Hey, you want me to
take Harriet up there?
- No, no, I wouldn't ask.
- Kepner's busy. I'm free.
- I'm happy to help...
- That would be
really great actually.
Thank you. Hang on.
I just want to get in there
'cause this poor guy just came in.
Okay, just walk her
around for like 15 minutes
and just get her to sleep, you know,
before you take her to the daycare.
- Thank you so much.
- All right.
- Did you need me for something?
- What?
- I said, did you need me
for something?
- Later. It'll wait.
What?
You can't just
steal my resident.
She's a resident
not your resident.
The best resident.
- Your words.
- She's mine. You can't have her.
- You can't say that.
- She doesn't belong to anyone.
Also, standing right here.
I can absolutely hear you.
That thing you need to do,
you don't need Edwards for that.
- So, we're good then?
- No, we are not good.
- Meredith. What?
- Did you tell Owen yet?
I tried to but he
already had a baby.
What's going on?
She's late.
Meredith, Edwards is right here.
Oh, now you're
aware I can hear you.
Oh, my God, you're
pregnant? Oh, my God!
No "Oh, my Gods", and no
hugging until she pees on the stick.
I'm so happy for you.
Can I have Edwards then?
No. No, you can't.
Yes, of course.
Hey, hey. I need
to get you into bed.
I beg your pardon?
You can't leave. You've
barely been hydrated.
I'm surprised you're
still on your feet.
- Nurse...
- Wait, wait, no.
I'm not Chelsea. I'm
Chandler, her sister.
We're twins.
Yes.
I just got that, yeah.
Chelsea, why would you even
go for a run on a day like this?
'Cause I'm not a wimp.
That would sound cooler
if you weren't hospitalized.
She's just dehydrated, right?
Unfortunately, Chelsea's heat stroke
has caused her to develop a condition
that's compromised her liver.
Compromised?
Her liver is shutting down.
We are treating the
symptoms aggressively,
but so far, the liver
is not responding.
What does that mean?
Worst case it means
she'll need a liver transplant.
I can be her donor, right?
No, stupid. You need your liver.
Actually, we'd only take
a portion of hers for you.
See, dummy? I told you I
can give you a piece of mine.
And it'll be exact same match.
We're like the
same person twice.
We're the same everything.
Just test me, please.
We're not quite there
yet but, yes, okay.
Wilson, let's get
her tested, okay?
- Trade places?
- You wish.
When we were kids
and we got in trouble
we had this joke that you
could call a "trade places"
and the other one
would go get yelled at.
And you had to do it.
Yeah.
Chelsea? What's
happening to her?
Wilson, she's seizing.
Get her on her side.
I'm right here.
Chandler, you need
to step away right now.
- I'm right here, Chelsea!
- You don't want to see this.
Get her out of here.
- Chelsea. Chelsea.
And let's push lorazepam.
So, what do you think?
She's fine. She's crying.
Take her to daycare.
Make her their problem.
Avery told me to take
her when she was asleep
and she won't go to sleep
and she won't take her bottle
and she has a clean diaper.
Maybe it's the heat.
It's pissing me off.
So I should take
her someplace cool?
No, you should
take her to daycare.
Here, let me see.
Okay, all right.
What did you do?
Nothing. Maybe it's you.
- What do you mean
"maybe it's me"?
- I don't know.
Babies can tell when
you're tense or freaked out.
It freaks them out.
Maybe you're not a baby guy.
Babies just don't like some guys.
It's okay. The bad man's gone.
I'm a baby guy. You
can see that, right?
You like me.
Andrew Billings, 59.
Admitted for resection
of cardiac myxoma.
6.2 centimeters
in the left atrium.
Otherwise healthy
with an ASA score of 1.
She's gonna help
dig out my ticker?
- You any good?
- The best.
Reputedly.
She'll do.
Let's skip to the
possible complications.
- Okay.
- Again?
Legally, we have to.
Excessive bleeding,
coronary artery spasm,
myocardial infarction,
valve regurg,
extreme risk of stroke
due to tumor debris
- or emboli to the brain.
- We get it. It's a dumb idea.
But, what else were
you gonna do today?
Andy was a shuttle commander.
He's been shot into
space on a big missile, so...
Wasn't so tough. No
traffic that morning.
- So, you're okay with risk.
- Yeah.
Besides, she tells
me without the surgery
I'll be dead inside a month.
That is true.
So, let's buckle in, right?
Let's do this.
Thanks.
She's stable.
I just got off the
phone with UNOS.
They did give her 1-A status,
which means she's
at the top of the list.
- What about me?
- I thought you were
testing for my...
- Yes, your results
did come back.
- So fast?
That mean good...
It's good news?
Chandler, you cannot
be a donor for your sister.
I can't?
Because you're pregnant.
- Are... are you serious?
- Yes.
Sorry if that's not what
you wanted to hear.
No, no, it's, it's good news.
It's the best news that
you could've given me.
My husband and I... It's good.
Just means I won't be
able to save my sister.
- Hey.
- Oh, can't talk.
My patient's seized.
She's in acute liver failure.
Why do you smell like Christmas?
These are homemade cookies
courtesy of Granny June.
- Granny June?
- Yeah, she's
the chief's patient.
She's getting a new liver today.
- You're calling her
"Granny June"?
- No, she asked me to.
It just feels right, you know?
She's like a human sunflower.
Wait, you get to scrub in
on a liver-transplant surgery
for a sweet old
cookie-baking grandma?
- With the Chief.
- Oh, God, I hate today.
- Have a cookie.
- Shut up.
You're pregnant?
Congratulations!
Oh, Owen must be so excited!
I'm sure he will be.
Wait. You haven't told him yet?
- How did you tell Jackson?
- Okay, stop.
Whoa! Stop talking right now.
What if I run into him today?
I'll be trying not to say it
which means I could
say it before you say it.
I just want it to be perfect.
Okay, just pretend that you
didn't tell me and tell him, okay?
Just make sure that
Owen is the first to know.
You can avoid a lot of
aggravating family court that way.
True story.
I got your page. What
are you doing in here?
Well, it's cool dark and quiet.
- How long is Avery
gonna be in surgery?
- No idea. I'm with Foster today.
- What's the matter?
- I'm fine. I'm just a little...
I was talking to the baby.
Oh. Hey, did Tuck cry like this?
Was there a way that
you'd carry him or...
Well, Tuck was four
when I met him so, no.
He just had some
chicken nuggets.
I didn't carry him much 'cause
it didn't seem appropriate.
- That's a good call.
- Yeah, I thought so.
- Maybe it's just colic.
- What is colic anyway.
Well...
- I don't really know.
- Yeah.
You want me to just
hold him for a little bit?
No, no, I got it.
- Want me to get Kepner?
- No, no!
I can stop a baby
from crying, Warren.
Of course, you can.
But, you know, if Kepner's
free then it might be...
Yeah.
We are hitting Chelsea with
antibiotics, lactulose, diuretics,
but look at these numbers.
We're buying time.
She needs a liver transplant or
she'll be dead maybe tomorrow.
I mean, we need a viable
liver in this hospital, right now.
What?
We might already have one.
Oh, hell no!
Our patient is in acute failure.
The liver coming to June is
a perfect match. I checked.
The liver's already
been allocated.
It's June's liver.
Surgery's been scheduled.
UNOS will allow her to
give up her place in line
and it will go to Chelsea,
but June has to agree to it.
The request has
to come from her.
Well, I haven't heard her
make any requests. Have you?
No, June can get the next match.
Damn it! Damn it.
Damn it. Grey, she's
been on the list three years.
Which means she's very
strong and she can wait.
Our patient will die in
hours. She needs this.
I know she does.
And so does Granny June.
And since this little old
lady is the closest thing
to Mother Theresa I've ever met
I know if I ask she's
gonna say "yes".
- Damn it!
- We have to ask.
I swear you try to have one
damn day of joy around here.
So, she needs a
liver, too? My liver?
This girl is in immediate need.
If she doesn't get a
liver... It's very dire.
You said "girl." How old is she?
Well, privacy rules
won't allow us...
She's 25.
- Oh, good lord.
- Oh, my goodness.
How long do you think she has?
Well, without a transplant
her doctors don't think...
She might not make
it through the night.
The poor lamb.
Wait, so she's gonna
get mom's liver?
- That's not fair.
- No, Samantha. Shush.
Let her finish.
If you do choose to go this way
you would go back on the list
and, hopefully, the
next liver would be yours.
Believe me, if this wasn't
an urgent situation...
Of course. We
totally understand.
It's your decision.
Yeah. It's my decision. Yeah.
But screw her.
You know how long I've
been waiting in this line
and if somebody's
gonna try and take cuts,
well, no.
Now, she can go find
her own damn liver.
No cuts.
- So, your answer is "no"?
- My answer is "hell, no".
Right?
Granny's gonna
get a liver today.
- That was... Really unexpected.
- Didn't see that coming.
You didn't. I've been
treating her for five years.
I didn't think she could
say the word "screw."
- Such a good baker.
- She's an organ hog.
I'm so sorry.
She could just be cranky from
not eating before the surgery.
Don't apologize.
It is absolutely her
right to say "no".
It's just so unlike Mama.
She volunteered for
Meals on Wheels. She...
I'm just surprised.
And that poor girl does
she get another chance?
There's no guarantee.
Look, Lily, that is why
we have a UNOS list
so that people can wait
their turn and get a chance
fair and square, and that's
what Granny June has done.
Well, I wish you luck
with the other girl.
I'll be praying for her.
Granny's getting a liver.
Oh, it's not funny.
I have to go call UNOS.
Oh, find the joy, DeLuca.
Yes, I'll hold.
Nothing?
No. I'm checking
incoming traumas.
You know, I still can't believe
Bailey's patient actually said "no".
Selfish old biddy.
I mean, I'm sorry,
but if living that long
doesn't teach you a little
compassion and generosity
then what have you learned?
Don't say that to Bailey
because she's full-on Team Biddy.
Maybe I'll change her mind.
That's admin. And
then enter, enter, enter.
- Okay.
- Bailey.
- Chelsea's in her 20s.
- And?
And June is almost 8 almost 80.
And?
Whatever offensive ageist
thing you are implying,
I'm gonna need you to say it.
Look, Chelsea, has her
whole life ahead of her.
And June has had a lifetime
of enriching experience.
And she can get
another damn liver.
I cannot believe that you
of all people are saying this.
Now what does that
mean, "me of all people"?
I mean, how can you be so ageist
- when you are...
- Yes?
So wise?
- Hey, who's ageist?
- Dr. Webber believes
that old people matter
less than young people.
That's terrible. I have
a lot of old friends.
- You're my old friend.
- Robbins.
- Older friend. Older than me.
- Why am I not just a friend?
See that's what ageism is.
I'm gonna go check on June.
You know, listen, you
don't look a day over 45.
You look amazing.
You can go.
I'm just saying, Edwards
has been like my right hand
and my right hand is no good
to me if it is in your pocket.
Amelia, I am not stealing
Edwards. I am borrowing her.
We do this all the time,
like when I got that sweater
and I needed your cute shoes.
Oh, I'm shoes now.
What happened to best resident?
You know, go check and see if
Andy's nitrous oxide study is done.
Thank you.
See? You should not be
ordering her around like that.
I should be ordering
her around like that.
You two need to learn to share.
I have a 25-year-old
with liver failure
who will die because old
ladies don't know how to share.
Your thing is not a problem.
I need her back.
I might really need her
back if I'm, you know.
Have you peed on the stick yet?
Because if you haven't
peed on that stick yet
- stop talking!
- Come on, Mer. She's excited.
I just... I don't know if I
should tell Owen before or after.
How did you tell Derek?
I gave Zola a shirt that
said "Best Big Sister."
That's sweet, but not helpful.
And then with Ellis, I was off
the hook because he was dead.
Well, this was fun for a minute.
This is it, Andy,
if you're ready.
Last chance to scrub
out of this mission.
Nah.
- I'll see you on
the other side then.
- Yep. See you then.
Okay, Andy, we're getting
ready to start the induction.
You're gonna feel a little
drowsy and then we can...
You know any jokes?
I'm sorry?
This could go one of two ways.
Thought it might be
good to go out laughing.
- You got a good joke?
- Yeah, yes.
Uh...
Um.
Shoot.
Hey, wait, wait. I got one.
No, that's... that's okay.
Andy. Andy?
Hey. Are you gonna
take her down?
Shh.
I just got her down.
- Was she crying the whole time?
- Just...
- All right, you know what? I could...
- Just go. Just go.
The liver's on its way here.
What are we doing out here?
I need some air.
This isn't air. This is steam.
I could steal the liver.
I could just like
run up and grab it.
Or I could walk up to the guy
and say, "Hello, I'm Dr. Bailey.
- "Right this way."
- Do that.
Then you'll lose your job, too,
and we'll have more
time for movies and stuff.
I mean, what's another
week or two to June?
She'll get another one.
People die every day.
Maybe I should
go talk to her again.
She probably didn't even hear
Bailey or understand a thing she said.
She said "no". You
go back that's coercion.
Oh, it's not coercion. I'm
just gonna reason with her.
You'll get the hospital
sued. You'll get sued.
Damn it.
- I'm gonna go talk to her.
- No!
Remember when you
talked to DeLuca for me?
You only made it worse.
You're gonna throw
DeLuca in my face now?
I'm not going to threaten her.
I'm just gonna maybe
show her a picture of the girl,
shame her a little.
Beg?
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Did you find out?
No. Not yet.
Please tell me you
at least told Owen.
I'm just not sure how.
Just tell him. I mean,
he'll be excited, right?
Yeah. I guess.
- I didn't have to
do this last time.
- What do you mean last time?
The last time I was pregnant...
I didn't have to tell the father
'cause he was dead.
Did you call UNOS?
Yeah.
You should go home
and get some rest.
You gonna stay?
Yeah. Gonna wait out
the clock on this one.
I'll let you know if I
have any good news.
You and Shepherd
don't wait around do you?
You always said that
you wanted a pile of kids.
So did you.
I remember up at the
lake when you and...
Yeah, Megan and
I talked about it.
She liked the name Bernard so...
That slowed the
conversation a bit.
- And the universe
had other plans.
- Yeah.
Owen.
Something's happened.
Something terrible.
Yeah. Yeah, it did.
- Grab that diaper bag, will you?
- Yeah, stat.
Oh. That's bad.
Wipes.
Whoa, that's a crime
against humanity.
Damn it, more wipes.
More, more. Thank you. Good.
So, what about you and Shepherd?
You guys, talk about it yet?
- Diaper cream.
Yeah. Yeah, we're
trying actually.
Oh, that's amazing,
man. Outstanding.
Diaper.
Okay.
You know, what?
Give me another diaper.
- We're gonna double up on this.
- Smart.
- Hey, you're good at this.
- Well, I just have a knack,
I guess.
Babies like me.
Yeah. Yeah, you do.
We'll know we were successful
when we see the
vasculature looks normal.
It's like fireworks.
Congrats, Andy.
Thank you for this.
It's like a
one-in-a-million shot
- and it was incredible
to be a part of.
- My pleasure.
You know, you have
a real knack for cardio.
Thank you, and that's very
flattering, but I love neuro.
Don't worry. I'll return
you when I'm done.
You're like a neighbor's
snow plow, you know.
There's no need to
buy one for yourself
but come in handy sometimes.
Can we go back to
when I was shoes?
V-tach.
Push 75 of lido.
I don't understand.
He was stable.
Damn it, Andy.
Crash cart.
V-fib.
Paddles now.
Charge to 200. Clear.
3-0.
I usually love a
good transplant.
Taking something
no longer needed
reusing it... It's
like composting.
- You compost?
- No, it's gross.
But it's good and
virtuous and people do it.
Dr. Grey, has
turned a compost pile
and turned it into a
regular old pile of poop.
Suction.
She stole the joy
from me, from June.
I was even trying to make a
little joy for you today, DeLuca.
Well, if it's any consolation
this is the best day
I've had in a while so...
No.
I'm sorry?
No, it's no
consolation. Scissors.
He must've thrown a clot.
Apnea test shows no
spontaneous respiratory drive,
no brain stem reflexes.
He's brain dead.
We'll do an EEG
to confirm but...
I thought we got
him back in time.
I'm sorry.
A stick.
What?
What do you call a boomerang
that doesn't come back to you?
A stick 'cause a boomerang's
supposed to return.
I get it. No.
- Why are you telling me?
- 'Cause he wanted a joke.
He just wanted one
joke and I went blank.
I could've thought of
something, anything.
He just wanted to laugh.
Well, the good news is
that was a terrible joke.
I know.
If the clot hadn't killed
him that joke would have,
so it's a really good
thing he didn't hear it.
- That's not funny. How can you...
- Edwards.
No, you have to find the good.
Andy did.
He knew this was a long shot.
He knew he might die,
and he could've died at
home from acute heart failure
instead of here in post-op.
But then he wouldn't have
been able to donate his organs,
and that was important to him.
And that's good. He...
Come with me.
Are you sure?
I don't want to get
excited if this isn't real,
and I don't want to tell
them if this isn't real.
He's ABO compatible.
And UNOS has been notified.
He's 180 pounds.
He's a non-drinker.
He's a non-smoker.
- His liver is...
- It's perfect.
It's real, Mer. We
have a liver for her.
Oh, Dr. Bailey was right.
This is a glorious day.
And the liver pinked
up almost immediately
which is a good sign.
Of course, we still have to
watch for signs of rejection
in these first 24 hours,
but so far so good.
Let's hear it, you guys!
Oh, shh.
- We can't thank you enough.
- Oh.
Oh, Karen, give him the scarf.
- Mama made me finish it so...
- Thank you.
Oh, group pic!
Group pic. Come on.
This is for the Christmas card.
All right.
All right, "liver" on
three. One, two, three.
Liver!
Okay, let's get ready for
the vascular anastomoses.
I've got the vena cava.
So how is the old biddy?
She's fine.
Hoarder.
No, I get it.
If it were you, if you
were in June's position
I'd want you to have it.
And if someone asked,
I'd say screw them, too.
Just how old do you think I am?
We not going home?
No. I want to see this.
I want to get as much
of my joy on as I can.
This is the worst day.
This is the best day.
I should be in that surgery.
My patient can't
catch a break all day,
and the second that
something good happens
I get bumped again
because Pierce told Grey that
Stephanie's had a really tough day.
She really needs it.
- That happened
to me today, too.
- Pathetic.
I'll take it where I can get it.
You should really
get that treated.
- What?
- Your self-pity gland.
It's incredibly swollen.
Go to hell.
I'm a doctor. I can
see it from here.
Well, I'm gonna
treat it with alcohol.
That's the recommended
course. I support that.
- And, push two more of these.
- Oh. Thank you.
So, she ate about an hour ago.
You had her all day? I thought
you were gonna take her to daycare.
Yeah, I wasn't that busy.
He didn't want to put
her down is what it was.
Happened to me all the time.
- It's the way her head smells.
- Yeah.
Yeah, I know.
I'm just glad she didn't
give you any trouble.
I was fine. She was great.
- Okay.
- Easy.
All right, thanks again.
You and Shepherd ought to
get on getting one of those.
Yeah, so she's getting
the transplant tonight.
So I'm, I'm just gonna... I
want to stay tonight, yeah.
I don't know when
I'm gonna be home.
Yeah me, too.
Oh, Rick, I'm pregnant.
No, I wanted to tell
you when I saw you
but then I... I
didn't want to wait.
I couldn't wait.
I couldn't know
without you knowing.
Every cloud has a silver lining.
Yeah.
I love you, too.
But it's still a cloud.
What is this?
Well, I was gonna
wrap it like a present,
but then I thought I
would hand it to you
and you'd hand it to
me and then I'd pee on it,
so that felt weird.
Um, but then I just
thought I would take the test
and hand it to you on a plate,
but then we couldn't use
the plates anymore so I...
Amelia, are you...
- Are you pregnant?
- I might be.
I think I might be.
A cloud can mean
a shower or a storm.
I was gonna wait until I
knew for sure but I don't know
I just wanted you to know,
too, so do you want to find out?
So you take your good
days where you can get them.
- We have to close it.
- One more minute.
One more minute of cool
air or a week of spoiled food.
- You guys, she's pregnant.
- We don't know that.
Who's pregnant?
It's my first sister's
pregnancy. I missed all of yours.
Amelia's pregnant?
- Maybe.
- I hope so.
- Yeah.
- Me, too.
She'll be talking for two now.
You try to stay positive.
Hey, did I tell you I spent
all day with Harriet today?
It was so much fun.
After a while it... it just... It
felt like I'd done it forever.
- Hey, how'd it go?
- Good. Got that part down.
- What's it say?
- Takes a minute.
Want to sit?
- Okay. Go ahead. Let's sit.
- Yeah.
So I was thinking that
we could turn the
study into the nursery.
Or maybe we should just
have the crib in with us.
I mean, we haven't
even talked about this.
- You see anything?
- Not yet.
You know, and then we can
turn the nursery into his room...
Or her room.
I mean, it's a good
room for a kid, right?
We don't need a study and...
What? What?
You try to remember that
even in the bad news...
That's okay.
You know, it's...
We just started.
We'll keep trying. Okay?
There's good news for someone.