Sure you don't want me
to wait with you?
Connor, I'm fine.
I'm not saying
that you're not.
I just know that waiting rooms
can be awfully boring.
All those old issues
of People Magazine.
Anyone else gets
a little anxiety,
they get a massage.
Daughter of a psychiatrist,
a full-blown psych eval.
Look, we both know
that you haven't exactly
been yourself lately.
So let's just do this right.
We'll get you back
on your feet, okay?
Fine.
Robin Charles?
Dr. Kwon just told me
Robin's coming in
to be evaluated.
I'm so sorry to hear that.
Yeah, thanks.
Just, um...
I'm hoping for the best.
He chose me as the resident
to do her initial evaluation.
Really?
Yeah, he said you spoke
very highly of me. Thank you.
Well, didn't tell him
anything that wasn't true.
I imagine
it must be hard
to have to stay
at arm's length
from your daughter's
treatment, but...
And this goes without saying,
but I just want
to say it anyway,
Dr. Kwon and I will
do everything we can
to make sure Robin gets
the best possible care.
Dr. Reese, I have
complete confidence in you.
And if there's anything
I can do to help,
you just let me know.
I will.
There you are.
What's up?
A buddy of mine had
to pawn off two Blackhawks
tickets for tonight.
You in?
Only if I can feel the chill
coming off the ice.
Mmm. Twenty-seven rows up,
you're gonna feel it
coming off your beer.
Pick you up at 7:00?
See you at 7:00.
All right.
Dr. Rhodes, possible
collapsed lung coming in.
We're going to
Treatment Three.
I'm on it.
Courtney? Talk to me.
Gayle Parks.
Twenty-one weeks pregnant.
Fell getting out of bed.
Baby's stable,
but mom's short of breath
and satting at 92,
bradycardic and hypotensive.
Doris!
Can you tell me
what happened?
Uh, she miscarried
her last pregnancy,
so we've kept her
on bed rest just to be safe,
but when she got up to go
to the bathroom, she fell.
All right,
thank you, sir.
All right.
Let's move her
on my count.
One, two, three.
Okay.
All right,
let's get it out.
Nice, easy breaths
for me.
I've got breaths
sounds bilaterally,
but they're faint
with crackles.
Let's get a stat
AP chest X-ray.
No.
Nothing that
could harm the baby.
Mrs. Parks,
I promise the radiation
will be minimal,
and the fetus
will be shielded
by a lead apron.
We understand,
but if there's
any other way...
I'm sorry, sir,
but your wife is having
a lot of trouble breathing.
We need to figure out why.
I said don't do it.
This baby is a perfect match
for my daughter.
I'm not taking any risks.
I'm sorry, excuse me?
I have leukemia.
My mom's having
this baby to save me.
Imagine that baby
being responsible
for keeping its sister alive.
Serial bone marrow donation.
Maybe a kidney one day.
Part of its liver.
Not gonna be easy.
No.
But if your kid
had advanced leukemia,
what would you do?
Whatever it takes.
Mmm-hmm.
EKG confirmed
a right inferior STEMI.
He's feeling better
after aspirin.
Gave him a dose
of beta blockers.
I spoke with cardiology,
put him on the list
for a cath,
but he's currently stable
and I think we're
gonna be in good shape.
Sounds like it.
Mmm-hmm.
All right, Mr. Walker,
you're in good hands
with Dr. Manning.
And those hands
couldn't be prettier.
Thank you, sweetheart.
Why is it that older men
always think they can
call you sweetheart?
I can't say it happens
much to me anymore.
Oh, maybe you should
be sweeter then?
And blow this rugged,
tough guy thing I got?
It's my meal ticket.
Hi.
Hey.
Don't even know why
I'm bringing you this,
Mr. I-slept-in-an-hour-late-today.
Well, that's because
you're so thoughtful
and lovely.
That's true.
Thanks. I better
get back to work.
I'll see you.
Have a good day.
Is it
Match List day already?
Uh-huh. Stohl's
yearly power trip.
Marching those
poor med students around,
telling them that
he's turning in
his list tonight.
So if they want
a residency spot here,
"Your last chance
to impress me."
Reminds me of
a drill instructor
I had in boot camp.
Nice guy?
Sweetheart.
Follow me.
We'll start over here.
First, I would like
to hear about what's
been happening lately.
After that,
I'm gonna send you
down to phlebotomy
so we can run
a few standard tests.
Then, later,
we can meet up again,
see if we can't
figure out
what's going on.
Sounds like a plan.
Good. Good.
Um, so can you tell me,
in your own words,
why you're here today?
To find out if I'm crazy.
Do you think
that's a possibility?
No.
Okay.
Though you did agree
to meet with me.
How come?
I don't know.
I mean, there is a history
of psychiatric issues
in my family.
I see.
Um, you want to tell me
about what's been happening
in the last few weeks?
I started hearing rats
in the walls of my apartment.
Mrs. Parks. Hi.
You breathing any better?
A little.
Good.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Leah just finished
a round of chemo. She's, uh,
been a little nauseous.
Got it.
Why don't you and Sam
go get a little
fresh air, huh?
I'll go with you.
Thanks, Doris.
So, your tests show
that you do not have
a collapsed lung,
but I'm seeing something
more concerning.
You're in heart failure.
Um... Uh, she had
a peripartum cardiomyopathy
during her last pregnancy.
So you understand
the danger you're in?
I had no choice.
Our son Sam wasn't
a donor match for Leah.
This is the only way
that I can save her.
We're well aware of the risks,
but we discussed this
at length and we, uh...
We're willing
to take the risk.
I realize that this
is difficult to hear,
but the safest choice
in cases like this is to
take the load
off of your system
and terminate the pregnancy.
My daughter can't make it
without getting
a marrow transplant
in the next year.
If I lose this pregnancy,
it'll be too late.
Three weeks, Dr. Rhodes.
That's all we need.
Can you help us do that?
Yes. Okay.
I'm gonna put you
on some medicine
that will help to
strengthen your heart.
We will get your
pressure back up,
and hopefully
you'll be breathing
easier again soon.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
Of course.
Dr. Charles.
Thanks for the help
with Robin.
Of course.
Hey, Daniel?
I understand Dr. Reese
is the resident
evaluating Robin.
Yeah, well,
it makes sense.
She's very good
with patients
in her own peer group.
Yes, she is, but
she's also your student.
One of my very best,
and I, uh, have the utmost
confidence in her.
Well, I'm sure
you do, Daniel.
I know this is complicated,
but I sincerely hope
you're not using Dr. Reese
as your surrogate.
Sharon, look, of course
I'm a big fan of Sarah's,
but Dr. Kwon's running
the show on this one.
My only job
is to be a good dad,
and stay out of the way.
He's in unstable v-tach.
Barely got a pulse.
A little help in here.
Right away.
He's peri-arrest.
Must be another
heart attack.
Will, start bagging.
April, charge
the paddles to 100.
On it.
What did his angio
look like?
Stented two small lesions
in the cath lab.
Charged to 100.
Clear.
No pulse.
I'm starting compressions.
Another milligram of epi.
Charge to 200.
How were his vitals?
He was fine.
He was totally stable.
Two hundred.
Clear!
Clear.
He's gone into v-fib.
Another milligram of epi,
300 amiodarone.
Keep up compressions
and charge to 200.
Then he must have had
a worse disease
than we thought.
Charge to 200.
Clear!
Clear.
Asystole.
Time of death, 10:32.
How did this happen?
And now,
for our final case...
Mr. Dayne passed out
this morning from
a cardiac arrhythmia.
He's stable now,
though still in a-fib.
Mr. Dayne, do you have
any idea how long ago your
irregular heartbeat began?
Nope.
Thank you.
We'll be back.
So, if the a-fib started
less than 48 hours ago, we...
Shock him back
into rhythm?
Correct.
But if it's been longer
than 48 hours,
that same shock
could throw a dangerous
embolus to his brain.
So my bright,
young minds,
one of you
needs to come up
with the answer.
Dr. Stohl?
How are we supposed
to do that?
Impress me.
Dr. Reese, what's up?
Hey.
Robin is down
in phlebotomy now.
Oh.
Great.
Well, sounds like
you're on top of it.
How's it, um...
How's it going?
I'm starting
to put together
a clinical picture.
Good stuff.
Once again, you know,
if you need
any family history,
any background...
For instance,
she's been talking
about her apartment a lot.
Has that come up at all?
I really can't
discuss this.
Of course you can't.
I'm sorry.
I just meant purely
from a clinical standpoint,
you know,
the home is a reflection
of the mind and all that.
It couldn't hurt exploring,
but you're absolutely right.
Keep up the good work.
Doing a great job.
Dr. Manning?
I thought you might want
to have a look at this.
Oh. Thanks.
Oh, God.
What?
My patient's
autopsy report.
I made a mistake.
Mr. Walker didn't die
of an MI.
Massive pulmonary
embolism.
I can't believe it.
I totally missed it.
Oh, come on. Even if we knew,
there's nothing we could've
done differently.
It happened so fast.
We didn't have time
to get heparin on board,
let alone send him upstairs.
I know, but still...
Wait.
How did you get this
so fast?
These reports usually take
at least three to four hours.
Nina brought it up to me.
She came upstairs
and gave it to you?
Yeah.
You know, I'm gonna
go back over the chart,
see if there were some clues.
Nat, listen.
You did everything
you could for that man,
so don't get down
on yourself over it.
Hey, you're
too good a doctor.
Thanks, Will.
Stohl's a-fib case.
Guy's holding
a residency spot
over our heads with this.
What's the case?
Forty-year-old male.
No records, no history,
and Stohl expects us
to figure out
when it started.
Where are you at?
I mean,
there's no previous records.
No previous episodes.
No family history.
I'm getting killed on this.
You got any thoughts?
Any recent caffeine
or alcohol use?
New-onset irritability,
perspiration, hand tremors?
To assess for
acute thyrotoxicosis.
Hey, that is good.
Thyrotoxicosis.
You got anything else?
You applied here
for residency, right?
Yeah.
Well, you're not gonna get it
by half-assing it
through your cases.
Get back in there
and start asking
some questions.
And don't come out
till you've done
a thorough and complete
history and physical.
You understand?
Yeah.
Okay.
Good.
Help! My wife
can't breathe!
Please, please,
we need help!
Mom!
Just stay here.
It's okay.
She's profoundly bradycardic.
Let's get 5 liters of O2.
Let's get
the external pads
on to capture,
and then we'll set up
for a central line.
Let me help!
Yep.
Mom, what's happening?
It's okay, angel.
What are you gonna do?
This is gonna fire electricity
through your skin
60 times a minute
to keep your heart beating
until I can get
an internal pacer on.
It won't affect the baby?
No, but it is
gonna hurt.
Okay. Okay.
Set to 60 beats
a minute.
Got it.
Pacer's set.
Not capturing.
Mom!
Leah? Leah! Baby?
Leah! Leah!
I got her!
Leah, baby?
She's not getting
enough air!
I need oxygen now!
Nat, she's got
stage four leukemia.
Just had chemo.
Save my daughter.
Try to stay calm, okay?
How are you feeling?
I'm a lot better.
Good.
Twenty more minutes of oxygen,
and then she'll be free to go.
I'll let her mom know.
Great.
I love you.
Can I ask you something?
Of course.
What's happening
to my mom?
I think that's something
you should talk to
your parents about.
They just tell me
everything's fine.
When you're pregnant,
your heart is pumping
for two.
And right now,
your mom is having
trouble keeping up.
Is she gonna die?
Dr. Rhodes
is the best heart doctor
in the hospital.
He's gonna take
the very best care of her.
She's doing this
'cause of me.
She's your mother.
She wants
to do everything
she can for you.
What about Sam?
Your little brother?
Sometimes,
it's like Mom and Dad
hardly notice him.
Like he's not even there.
Why should I get
all the attention?
Your parents are
worried about you
because you're sick.
I'm sure they love
your brother just as much.
What about the baby?
What's it gonna
be like for him?
I don't want everyone sad
'cause of me.
I want us to be
a regular family.
Have you told your mom
how you feel?
I think she'd
want to know.
Nina?
Hey.
Why did you give
that report to Natalie?
I'm sorry?
Why did you come up to the ED
and give it to her?
She missed a diagnosis.
I thought she'd want
to know.
No. You file the report
in the chart
and put an alert
in the doctor's mailbox.
That's how
you usually do it.
Okay.
You have it in
for Natalie?
What?
Are you trying
to make her feel bad
because you think there was
or is something between us?
Really, Will?
That's what
you think of me?
Just explain this.
Why would you go
out of your way
to make sure Natalie
knew about a diagnosis
she couldn't possibly
have done anything about?
I told you.
She made a mistake.
And you know what?
Anyone who refuses
to learn from their mistakes
is gonna repeat them.
Dr. Reese, how's everything
going with Robin?
I kind of have a problem.
Dr. Charles logged
into her medical records.
I see.
I haven't posted
any notes yet,
so there's nothing
much to see, but still...
Hmm.
Well, I'll go talk
with Dr. Kwon.
In the meantime,
hold off on
posting those notes.
Ms. Goodwin?
Yes?
I can't help but wonder...
Did Dr. Charles
have me assigned
to Robin's case
just so he could get
access to her treatment?
'Cause I get the feeling
he's just using me
to be his...
I don't know, his patsy.
Listen, uh, Dr. Reese,
the only thing
I can say is that
this is a very difficult
situation for him.
Try not to take it
personally.
Hey, there you are.
Showing Dr. Stohl
what you're made of?
Yeah. I guess.
Actually, problem is
Dr. Choi's been
riding me really hard.
Well, that's his style.
It's just you're
his friend, right?
You think maybe you could
ask him just to dial it
back just a little bit?
What do...
You know, just get him
off my case.
He doesn't hassle
the other med school
students like this.
I'm not doing that.
Okay. Fine.
I guess I'll just
get back to work then.
How's Leah's mom doing?
Even with the pacer,
she's experiencing a dangerous
number of premature
ventricular contractions.
She could have a lethal
decompensation any minute.
And if she does,
I'm afraid we won't
be able to get her back.
How's the breathing?
Uh, okay.
Let me see the EKG.
What?
What's wrong?
Your heart function
is deteriorating rapidly.
We need to surgically place
a device called an LVAD
to pump your heart for you.
How risky is it
for the baby?
Surgery on bypass
does carry significant
risks for the baby,
but if we don't do surgery,
we'll be forced
to intubate you
and put you on ECMO...
You won't get off
the ventilator.
You'll remain
in a persistent
vegetative state.
I am very sorry.
We'll get you ready
to go upstairs soon.
Will my baby survive?
If I were like that...
In a coma?
It's possible,
but the chances
are not very good.
Honey...
But it is possible?
Mrs. Parks, maybe
we're not making
ourselves clear...
No, I understand.
But I have the cure
to my daughter's
cancer inside me.
Maybe the two of you
should take some time
and talk it over?
Yes, yes.
We already discussed
every possibility.
Not this.
Yeah.
We said we would
do anything.
If the time comes...
Intubate me.
Hopefully,
it won't come to that.
We obviously can't let her
go through with this.
What choice do we have?
We can't force her
to have surgery.
We're talking about
letting her kill herself.
No. It's not that simple.
She doesn't see it
as suicide.
She sees it
as saving her daughter.
At what cost?
She'd be leaving
a three-year-old
and an infant behind
with no mother
to care for them.
And Leah would
survive leukemia.
I offered the surgery.
She declined it.
Wait.
You said doing
the surgery on bypass
came with some risks.
What about doing it
off bypass?
A lot more dangerous.
I wouldn't be able
to see through the blood.
I'd lose them both.
But what if we could
save them both?
I mean, brain death
shouldn't be an option.
That family needs a mother.
Hey, there!
Oh, hey.
You, um,
mind if I join you?
Go right ahead.
How's it going?
Fine.
Are you back
in your place yet?
Everyone says
I don't have rats,
so I am back at my place.
Wow. Great.
So, no more rats?
Mmm-hmm.
Everything's good.
Got it all under control.
Fantastic.
Yeah. And Dr. Reese
seems comfortable
with where I'm at,
so I think one more session
later on today
and I'll be done.
That's a relief.
Hon, you must be exhausted.
You want me to bring
some sushi by tonight?
Maybe we watch a movie...
No.
How about I just
drop off some sushi?
Dad, I just...
I really want
to get some rest.
Of course.
Hon, my knee
has been acting up.
Can you do
your old man a favor?
Just grab me
another creamer,
please? Or two?
Okay.
Hazelnut.
Mmm-hmm.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Hey, um, I know
you're helping
my brother with his case,
and I really appreciate it,
but could you maybe
go a little easier on him?
What do you mean?
You know, just lay off
the gas a little?
Where's this coming from?
Did Noah ask you
to talk to me?
April, there's
a good doctor
inside Noah.
But he has a way
of getting people
to make things easier for him.
And as long as
they keep doing that,
he's never gonna reach
his full potential.
I won't coddle him.
Who said anything
about coddling?
You just asked me
to give him a pass
on a patient.
Not a pass. Just stop
being such a hard-ass.
Well, maybe if he had
more hard-asses
in his life,
he wouldn't
have to leave Med
to do his residency.
Wow. Okay.
You know what?
You don't know
anything about me
or my brother.
You know, truth is,
I can't say I'm surprised
that you and that guy
didn't work out.
What?
Well, yeah, I just mean
a doctor and a lab tech...
He just can't understand you.
You know? The pressures
we face.
Holding someone's life
in our hands. It's...
Noah? Noah?
Yeah?
Have you solved
Dr. Stohl's case yet?
No, but, uh...
You can't keep having
other people carry
your water for you.
You have to commit.
Let them see that you're
gonna kill it every day
and get the job done.
I know, but I...
But nothing!
Go back to Dr. Choi.
Listen to every word
he says until you get
the case solved.
You got that?
Yeah. Okay.
I got it.
I got your page.
BP's 80 over 40.
Stats are down to 60.
Gayle, your heart is no longer
able to function on its own.
Please, let me do
the surgery.
Otherwise, we're gonna
have to intubate you now.
Honey, I know
we've come so far,
and we're so close,
but I don't want you
to do this.
I do.
No!
It's okay. You're gonna
have a beautiful life.
No, not without you.
We don't want you to go.
Even if the baby saves me.
We love you. We need you.
Pressure's down to 70.
Gayle, if you don't tell
Dr. Rhodes to do the surgery,
we are going to need
to intubate you now.
No! Don't!
Please, Mommy!
We could try
the surgery off bypass.
What does that mean?
Instead of diverting
blood from her heart,
I'll let it keep pumping.
It is an extremely
difficult surgery,
but I could avoid
using the anti-coagulant
that would harm the baby.
You could save us both?
The odds are very low,
and if we get into trouble,
I have to tell you,
I will try to save you.
I won't be able
to save the baby.
Mom, please!
Gayle...
Okay.
All right, tell the OR
we're on our way up.
Let's get her
ready to move now!
Okay.
Yep. Good?
Let's go.
Hey.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have
brought Natalie into this.
But you were right.
I am jealous.
I just miss you, Will.
I don't want us
to grow apart.
Neither do I.
I'll apologize
to Natalie.
No, no.
I'll talk to her.
Infections can
cause heart problems.
Have you had any
recent illnesses?
No.
Hmm. Okay.
Any past issues
with blood pressure?
No, I'm usually
around 110 over 80.
And your cholesterol
is good, too.
I watch what I eat.
I exercise a lot.
I'm a runner.
Okay. Do you track
your vitals with, like,
a Fitbit or an app?
Yeah. Yeah, that's how
I know what my BP is.
I've got it on my phone.
Can I take a look?
Yeah.
There is going
to be more blood
in the next two minutes
than you have ever seen.
I'll get the LVAD
into the ventricle
while Dr. Harper
cannulates the aorta.
Keep the suction coming.
Steady hands.
Once we make the cut,
the clock starts.
Are you ready?
Yes.
Okay. Ready?
Go!
I can't see anything.
Connor, baby's rate
is at 120.
More suction.
Mom's pressure
is dropping.
I need 45 seconds.
Baby's rate's at 98.
You there?
Not yet.
Mom's not responding.
We're gonna lose her.
All right, I'm in.
Baby's rate
is at 65 and dropping.
Mom can't
handle this.
We need to deliver
the fetus and get
the load off her heart.
There's too much blood.
You can still
save the mom.
We have
to deliver now.
No!
Dr. Rhodes.
I'm almost there.
Baby's rate is at 40.
Dr. Rhodes,
what do you want to do?
Hey, honey.
Where are you off to?
Uh, home.
Do you mind,
could we just
have a little chat?
I really have
a lot of things to do.
Sweetie, look, I'm, um...
Honey, I'm sorry.
I'm just really
very worried about you,
and I just want to make sure
that we're getting you
the proper treatment.
Yeah, that's being
taken care of.
No, darling.
Can we just talk
about this for a second?
Robin, stop.
Can we please
talk about this?
Not now, Dad.
Robin!
Excuse me,
I need to get through.
I'm so sorry, honey.
I can't let you do that.
What?
Get away from me!
What are you doing?
Just need you to stay here
a little while longer.
We need to keep you here
a little while longer
so we can get you
the help that you need.
No. No, I'm not staying.
Honey, I'm just worried
that you're gonna
hurt yourself.
I don't want you
to hurt yourself.
Who are you to decide
who's gonna hurt themselves?
Get off of me!
What are you doing?
I hate you!
I swear I'm never
gonna speak to you again!
Mrs. Parks?
Gayle? Hey.
You're okay.
The baby?
Even with the transfusions,
the blood loss was too great.
Your heart couldn't
keep up with it.
We tried.
There was no way
to save both of you.
I'm so sorry.
No, Mom.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I failed you.
No, you didn't.
No. I love you.
That girl has
an impossible battle
ahead of her.
At least she'll be able
to face it with her mother.
Based on our
patient's fitness app,
the resourceful Mr. Sexton
believes he has determined
when the arrhythmia began,
and he proposes
electrocardioversion.
If he's right,
shocking the patient
will return him
to a sinus rhythm.
If he's wrong,
we may soon see the effects
of an embolic stroke.
Mr. Sexton?
Charge to 75.
Clear.
Sinus rhythm.
Well done, Mr. Sexton.
I'm impressed.
I suppose you're looking
for a thank you?
Nah.
Just as long as I get
to say I told you so.
How dare you admit
Robin behind my back?
She is my patient.
You didn't examine her.
You didn't treat her.
You didn't see
her apartment.
I don't care what you saw.
You should've come
to me first.
I didn't have time, Dr. Reese.
She was leaving the hospital.
Yes, because
I gave her the night
to think about it.
I know she needs
to be admitted!
I thought...
I thought that she was
masking it from you.
No! We were
making progress.
I was trying to get her
to admit herself voluntarily.
To take ownership
of the idea,
so she'd be in the best state
of mind to accept treatment.
I needed to earn
her trust for that,
and now that chance is gone.
You had to run around
sticking your nose
in everything
instead of letting me
do my job.
Natalie,
I'm sorry about Nina
bringing that autopsy report
to your attention.
What do you mean?
She feels jealous.
We haven't spent a lot
of time together lately,
and you working here
all day alongside me...
Anyway, you shouldn't
have gotten dragged
into our issues.
Okay.
Listen.
If I'm being honest,
if I saw my boyfriend
working with another woman
the way we work together,
I'd be concerned, too.
Why?
We work well together.
There's nothing
wrong with that.
We don't just
work well together.
The way we laugh,
the way we talk...
It's special.
Well, we're good friends.
Are we, Will?
Are we just good friends?
Yes. That's exactly
what we are.
Okay.
Natalie!
No, you're right.
We're good friends.
Night, Will.
Reese! Hey.
Robin hasn't been
answering my texts.
Have you seen her?
I was about to call you.
I'm afraid I have
some bad news.
All right.
Let's do this.
Ah, man.
I'm sorry, but I'm gonna
spend a little quality time
with Nina tonight.
We need that.
Dude.
I know. It's on me.
I promise I'll get us
tickets for next week.
All right?
I gotta go. I will.
Hey, Nat.
Hey.
Do you like hockey?
Oh, uh, not tonight,
but thank you.
My brother just ditched me,
and the ticket's
gonna go to waste.
Mmm.
I guess Owen
is already asleep
at his grandma's,
and I could use
a hockey game?
Right? Cold beer.
Grown men on skates.
What's not to love?
Okay. Thank you.
Tough day.
Hope you're not here
to lecture me.
Well, it's a little late
for that.
I had her back,
and I lost her.