Ah. I wish the sun
would rise already.
This graveyard
shift's going forever.
- You okay?
- Mm-hm.
I love you too,
Carter, but it's over.
I'm gonna ask her tonight.
You're going to propose?
Actually, I already
did, but badly.
- She said no?
- She didn't say anything.
But this time I'm
gonna do it right.
Oh, wow.
That is a nice rock.
- That was my great-grandmother's.
- Wow.
Great-grandfather gave it to
her the day he left for the Army.
I don't think she'll mind
that it's secondhand.
Hey. You guys want something
from Magoo's? My treat.
- No, thanks.
- No, I'm all right.
Hey, Luka. KOVAC: Hey.
You dispo Mr. Lindsey?
- They took him up to Cards.
- He'll be all right.
- He's bounced back before.
- Actually, he died.
Oh.
- Way to start the day, huh?
- Yeah.
Can I buy you some breakfast?
Okay.
So, what's that you're reading?
The workplace sensitivity manual.
Weaver wants me to learn it.
What's...? What's "schmuck"?
- Schmuck?
It's one of the inappropriate
words. "Schmuck," "puts"...
No, I think you mean
"putz." KOVAC: Putz.
"Peckerwood." Is that a tree?
Hello? Anybody here?
Hello?
Oh, my God.
Gray matter.
No pulse. We
should get the police.
Oh, my God.
Oh, God.
GSW to the head.
Exit wound through
the spine. They're gone.
Trina. Oh, my God.
She's breathing. Go get help.
Do you remember the Rileys?
You guys stayed with them
when you were about 10 or so.
Yeah, they had a cabin
up by Mount Lutsen.
Yeah. Eric used to
call Sonia "Gammy."
- Grammy.
- Grammy. Whatever.
- Mm-hm.
- Maybe he went there.
Maybe.
They were really
good with you...
when things were bad.
They... They took you fishing.
- Remember?
- Yeah, in Grand Rapids.
- The Grand Rapids.
- I cut my finger.
Yeah, with a hook.
Eric caught this great,
big, old smelly fish.
He acted like he found
gold, for God's sakes.
- He'll be okay, Mom.
- I know.
I should pack.
- Is that John?
- No.
It's work, but guess what.
He asked me to marry him.
Really?
Well, he didn't really mean it.
I mean, it was... We
were on the roof...
it was freezing, there was a
helicopter flying around, and he was...
kind of shouting it at me.
It's every girl's dream, right?
- What'd you say?
- Nothing.
Really, because, you
know, he didn't mean it.
It just... It was just...
something that happened.
I don't know. Hi, it's Abby.
What?
Oh, my God. Was anybody there?
No, from the ER.
Okay.
I'll be right in.
- What's the matter?
- I... I have to go.
But come by the hospital later, and
I'll give you a ride to the bus station.
Okay.
Or you could stay
a few more days.
No, I... I have to
get back to work.
Be here waiting in
case he shows up.
What if he shows
up in Minnesota?
You're right.
Nothing confirmed. Looks like you
got multiple shooters on the loose.
She's dropping her sats.
Keep those people
away from the building.
Can we talk to her now
in case she can't later?
Setting up for multiple
traumas. How many?
- One.
- Three were pronounced on the scene.
- Luka, let me take this.
- It's okay, I got it.
Officer, make sure these
cars don't block that entrance.
- Breathe for us, Trina.
- Tracheal shift. Hold up.
Her lung is down.
- Sats, only 88.
- Miss, can you describe who did this?
- Decreased on the right.
- Needle her.
- Want me to do it?
- No, 18 gauge.
How many were there?
You're gonna get your ID as
soon as she's stable, I promise.
She's not moving air.
No pulse. Try the other side.
- No, pull the dressing off.
- What?
The dressing on the
chest wound, pull it off.
- Okay, pulse is stronger.
- Good chest excursions.
All right, let's get her inside.
Luka?
Just need a minute.
Dr. Lewis, patron
saint of lost causes.
- GSW to head and chest.
- Tension pneumo.
One's clear. Hey. You all right?
Yeah. I'm a little nauseous. It takes me
a couple days to get back up to terminal.
- What's going on?
- There was a shooting across the street.
- Anybody you know?
- No, but still.
- Kind of scary when it happens so close.
- Yeah.
So I heard you're
getting released today.
My next round of chemotherapy's
in about two days, so...
I thought I'd come
by, say so long.
- How's your mom doing?
- You mean is she still pissed at you?
No, I didn't mean
exactly that, but...
- She's still pissed at you.
- Good to know.
She's upstairs with the "doc."
Does she know you're here?
I kind of snuck off.
I actually might need
one of those basins.
I think you need
some IV Compazine.
- That sounds good.
- All right.
I'll go tell your mom you're here.
Will you watch him for a minute?
I'm not a child.
Yeah, Marky! Yeah, Marky!
- Yeah! Oh, yeah!
- Come on, man. Come on.
- I got this corner ball.
- Let's go. Come on.
- Let's go.
- What you trying to do?
- What you doing, man?
- It's our ball.
Back up! Hey, back up! Hey,
man, it's all right. We got this.
- I'm all right. Come on.
- David.
- Let's go.
- Come on. It's game point anyway.
- Let's get these clowns out of here.
- Play ball!
Let's do it. Come on, come on.
Yo, watch it, bitch!
It's a man's game.
Come on, man.
What, you wanna go?
Forget about it.
We won. Let's get some
breakfast. Come on.
- Next week.
- That's what I thought.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- I thought you were on later.
- I heard what happened.
- I thought we might need help.
- Actually, we only got the one.
Three went straight
to the morgue.
- Sorry I didn't come by last night.
- It's okay.
Maggie and I played
Scrabble. I got a 75-point word.
- Really?
- "Cyanotic." She challenged it.
Found brutally murdered
early this morning...
inside of this establishment,
Doc Magoo's...
a diner frequented by staff and
visitors of County General Hospital.
The crime was committed prior to
opening as the staff was preparing...
for a day of serving the
usual sandwiches and sodas.
What got served instead was a
cold-blooded robbery-homicide...
in which four people were
murdered execution-style.
- One of them's still alive.
- Police are trying to identify suspects.
- More on the story later.
- Any word on Eric?
I don't expect any. It's
like a bear hibernating.
He won't come out till spring.
Hey, what do you
say we go out tonight?
Sushi. Just you and me.
Maggie can fend for herself.
Told her I'd drive
her to the bus station.
- She's leaving?
- Yep.
- Is that a good thing?
- I don't know.
It was kind of nice
having a roommate.
Sushi? I hope you have
a better plan than that.
It's all about misdirection. I don't
wanna show my hand too early.
Well, the two of you have
had enough misdirection.
Trust me, show your hand.
Move your toes, Trina. Good.
- O-neg's here. WEAVER:
Put it right on the infuser.
Trina, do you remember anything?
They started shooting.
They just started shooting.
Threading the
catheter. Wire back.
- What'd she say?
- Hook me up.
- Ten blade.
- Trina, how many of them were there?
Two, in an SUV.
I saw them drive up.
- Another 50 of fent.
- Knife back.
- Curved Kelly.
- I might have seen them getting away.
Anything more specific?
It was a 4x4, gold or tan
maybe. It looked pretty new.
Anything about the
men? Height? Weight?
- What they were wearing?
- It was far away.
Into pleural space. Tube.
Chen?
OpSite and Polysporin.
Tube's in. Hook
up the Thora-Seal.
Any detail would help us.
Sats are back up, 91.
- Were they Latinos? Black guys?
- I don't know. It happened so fast.
Let's page Corday.
Hey, Trina, you did really
good. Rest up now, okay?
For us to get to work here,
we need a real description.
I saw one of them.
I think he was black.
Driver, get out nice and
calm. Face the vehicle.
- Welcome to the 'hood.
- Passenger, come around to this side.
Face the vehicle. Put
your hands up on the roof.
Grab the roof.
Hey, man, take it easy.
License and
registration's in the glove.
Hey, what are we being stopped for?
- Easy.
Where'd you get
money for a ride like this?
We're doctors at County.
- Where you headed in a hurry?
- Y'all can't just do this.
Just be quiet.
I see you guys brought a
lot of pals. What's the deal?
- Four people shot this morning in a diner.
- What diner?
We were just up at the Sedgwick Y in
a pickup game. Call the gym manager.
Why don't you search the car
and let us get the hell out of here?
All right, go ahead.
See, that's my boss right
now. Somebody's very sick.
Look, we're late for our shift.
Dealers got shifts now, huh?
- We are doctors, damn it.
- Relax, punk.
No, wait a minute, I can
explain that. I can explain!
Get on the ground right now, or
I'll put a bullet in your damn head.
Cuff them.
You belong to the Y?
I play ball there twice a week.
Who do you play with?
I don't remember their names.
Some live up the street from Greg.
You show proof to
the arresting officers?
Yeah, they took my ID.
I told the arresting officer
my ID was in the glove.
Did you ever hear of a
place called Magoo's?
I work right across the street.
Yes. We work right
across the street from it.
Did you ever own a firearm?
I already told you no.
No, I've never owned a firearm. Why
are you hassling me? Just call County.
- Where'd you say you were?
- You know, I told you where I was.
- What kind of a doctor are you?
- I'm a med... I'm a med student.
I'm a med student. What
difference does that make?
- What kind of doctor are you?
- I told you what I am.
Look, we brought you in
because you match the ID.
Because I match the ID.
What? Young, black and handsome?
That's... No, that's ridiculous.
I'll send them over immediately.
Jerry.
- Do we have photo IDs down here?
- Yeah, bottom shelf.
Messenger off personnel face
sheets for Pratt and Gallant...
to Area Seven Headquarters.
- Really? Why?
- Just do it.
Susan, Sean Simmons is being
discharged to home hospice care.
- I know, the cancer's back.
- While he's here waiting...
the mother has asked
that you keep your distance.
- What?
- She doesn't want you interacting...
with her son.
What does Sean say?
She's a grieving mother. I think
we need to respect her wishes.
Look, we should get
their names or something.
How else are we gonna file
a complaint against them?
Why don't you just be quiet?
Story checked out at the Y.
County confirmed
you're employed there.
It's not like we didn't
tell you guys that.
You can pick up your
stuff at the front desk.
Have a nice day.
Is her crit stable?
Holding at 29 with two units in.
Luka, if you wanna
take it easy for a while...
we can keep you out
of the trauma rooms...
assign you to
non-critical-care cases.
If you need me anywhere,
Kerry, you need me in here.
We all have times where we
could use a little less stress.
I'm fine.
There's nothing wrong with
admitting that you need some help.
I don't.
Even so, I've scheduled a meeting
with Dr. Meyers up on seven.
It's a formality.
Unless you wanna
make it something more.
But it's mandatory.
You shouldn't have
let them search the car.
That's what you do
when you're innocent.
I don't usually ride
around with a bloody shirt.
You guys hear what happened?
I thought none of
our people got hurt.
Jing-Mei was first on the scene.
- Is she okay?
- A little freaked.
I don't get it, man, how
you could just roll over.
- That's the way it works sometimes.
- Yeah, if you let it.
- What are you gonna do, file a lawsuit?
- That's one way to fight it.
- There is no fighting it.
- You know, I don't buy that.
Carter wants the output
on Bed 4 before he leaves.
Look, we could be perfect,
you know, like Gandhi.
But as soon as the crap goes
down, we'll be the first ones laid out...
with a gun to our head.
Now, where I grew
up, you see it every day.
And if it happens to you
enough, you get the message.
You are not equal.
You are not a full citizen.
You are first, last and, above
all, one thing and one thing only:
A suspect.
You sure you
wanna wait out here?
Yeah, there's too many
sick people in there.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Hey. Cold enough for you?
My mom went ahead to help set
up stuff for the home hospice team.
- Then she'll be coming to pick me up.
- I think you're doing the right thing.
I think it doesn't
matter what you think.
I'm sorry.
I don't know why
I'm so pissed at you.
Guess it all just feels
so much more real now.
I keep daydreaming about
the stuff that I wanted to do.
Get really drunk
at a college party.
Go windsurfing.
Get married and have
kids. Stupid stuff like that.
It's not stupid.
Even after I got really sick...
I kept talking myself
into believing...
that I had more time.
At least enough to do
some of those things.
Sean Simmons?
You know what? Hold on a second.
Sean, I can't get you into
college, and windsurfing's nuts.
But you know what? Come
on, let's get out of here.
- For real?
- Yeah, come on.
Not unless you have
someplace else to go.
- I'm supposed to get him home.
- Yeah, could you call his mom for us?
- Tell her we went on a date.
- I'll have him back by curfew.
Maybe. Say maybe.
Abby. Abby. Listen, I
got ahold of Sonia Riley...
and I told her to call you
here if she hears from Eric.
I'll keep my eye
open for messages.
Can you get this banana bag to that
guy? My leg-splint girl's screaming.
The Soupbox for lunch?
Oh, you're busy. We could go
to that place across the street.
- That's not really a good idea today.
- Abby. Triage needs extra bodies.
They got 20 kids from Kelton
Elementary with vomiting and diarrhea.
I'll be there in five minutes.
Abby. Abby, it's okay. I can
get to the bus station by myself.
No, I'll take you. I'll take you.
Mr. Levine, what's your problem?
I just got drunk at a
Valentine's Day party.
- Five days ago.
- Yeah, it was a blowout.
- I wanted to tell you...
- Hey. No. Why did you take that out?
It was itchy.
- Altered mental status. WEAVER:
Abby, send up admit labs...
two sets of blood cultures,
and grab an LP tray.
- Meningitis?
- Let's find out.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay, I'll call you when I get home.
Okay.
- Bye.
Nurses shortage, you know?
Oh.
Working in the ER can be a
very inconvenient job sometimes.
I'm sorry, John.
I just wanted Eric to
come home so bad...
so that I could be with
my family just for a second.
Abby and I were
getting along so well.
You should stay longer.
- You know, she would love it.
- I'm sorry.
Thank you, John.
I can catch a cab
out here, right?
I'm off in a couple of
minutes. I'll drive you.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Dr. Kovac. Dr. Meyers.
Please.
So, what brings you here?
Dr. Weaver. She told me to come.
Well, why do you suppose
she wanted us to meet?
- You tell me.
- Well, that's not quite how it works.
Hey, you're a doctor.
Someone comes to me with a
problem, I tell them how to fix it, so...
- Let's start with you telling me...
- My problem?
What's on your mind?
My family died during
the war in Croatia.
So I came to America.
I had a relationship with someone
I cared about, which I then ruined.
So I started to look for the
answers in the wrong places.
You know, like sex,
drinking, living fast.
I killed a patient I should have saved,
then I almost killed a medical student...
in a car crash, so...
Woke up one morning...
and everything I
thought I had was gone.
Gone or broken.
So, what do you have for that?
Well, Dr. Kovac, it's not
something that I can really...
Yeah, that's what I thought.
I should get back to work.
Tell Weaver I showed up.
Further complicating the commute,
a high-speed chase is underway...
snarling a two-mile
stretch of the I-40.
Police are in pursuit
of a tan SUV...
suspected of being connected
to the grisly murders...
of three people early this morning
in a coffee shop off South Foundry.
- A fourth victim...
- Do they consider...
the collateral damage
of a pursuit like that?
They're hoping they kill them, avoid the
wasted time and money of due process.
They might have
the wrong suspects.
Last time I checked, the
police were still on our side.
- Well, what exactly is our side?
- Tell her what happened.
They laid us out on the sidewalk,
they took us in, and they interrogated us.
- That's terrible.
- The real problem is you guys are guilty.
- Guilty of what?
- DWB. Driving while black.
Just forget it.
The police play the odds just like
us. They look for horses, not zebras.
Tell me you don't think
that's the same thing.
Look, it's about percentages.
Last time I flew to London...
they pulled two Arab men
out of line for a security check.
I hate to admit it, it made
me feel more secure.
You think they'd pull over two
Arabs driving through Highland Park?
No, because terrorist acts in Highland
Park aren't high on the list of concerns.
But violent crime by
African-Americans certainly is.
Like I said, we should drop it.
So you really believe racial profiling
is a legitimate law-enforcement tool?
A lot of people do.
- Hey.
I don't know whose day's
been worse, yours or mine.
- You okay?
- Yeah. You?
I never thought I'd
see something like that.
It's different when
they roll in on a gurney.
Yeah, but you stepped
up. That's all that counts.
I did my job.
At least we saved one of them.
- So I heard she gave an ID.
- Partial one.
I filled in some details.
What, you saw the guys?
A glimpse as they drove off.
- They were black, huh?
- I think so.
You think so?
Well, it was quick, you know?
But... And I only saw one of them.
So that's why the cops are
picking up brothers all over town.
I told them what I saw.
What you saw, or what
you thought you saw?
I was trying to help, Greg.
Can't you see you fed right into
what they always wanna jump to?
Look, I'm really sorry for what happened
to you, but that's on the cops, not me.
It's all part of the same thing.
What are you talking about?
- I don't know.
- So, what, now I'm a racist?
It's just hard not to
feel that everybody is...
when you're lying in the street with
a cop's foot to the back of your neck.
I've never seen it like this.
It's okay, there'll
be a later bus.
Yeah.
That's not your
music, that's Abby's.
She always liked that noise.
I'm getting used to it.
There's an accident up ahead.
Sit tight, we'll keep you posted.
- Thank... Thank you.
- Thanks.
- Well...
- Thank you for this, John.
- I know it's a huge inconvenience.
- It's no problem.
I'm sorry for getting so upset.
I hate being so pathetic.
Just the idea of going
home alone and waiting...
- Eric will turn up.
- Yeah.
Yeah, but I worry
about both of them.
Abby's good.
You know, we're both good.
You don't have to
worry about that.
She told me.
She told me you
might get married.
- Is that what she said?
- No, she told me you proposed.
I know she's work, it runs in
the family, but she's so worth it.
Yeah.
Yeah. I spend 23 hours a day wondering
whether we're wrong for each other.
Wondering whether we've got the
energy that we need to get through...
everything that we
seem to get into.
Whether the baggage we both
bring would sink a small ship.
But in the 24th hour, I realize I've
been thinking about her for 23 hours.
And I come back to, there's
something about her...
that I can't stay away from.
Something about her
that makes me wanna...
love her.
Julia, my sister, read this story about
a little Japanese girl who had cancer.
And she tried to make a
thousand paper cranes...
because she thought if she did,
it would make her wish come true.
- What was her wish?
- To get better.
So how many paper
cuts do you have?
A lot.
But my wish is
kind of different.
What is it?
It's hard to explain.
I kiss pretty good
for a dead kid, huh?
Not bad at all.
Cop wounded in a multi-car collision.
BP, 124/68, pulse, 96, good sats.
Jing-Mei, take him
in. I'll wait on the next.
- Find the guys?
- The guys opened fire.
- We have a bunch of cops hurt.
- Mitch Palnick, 41-year-old officer.
MVA with
passenger-space intrusion.
- Can't breathe.
- Hey, nice to see you again.
- You know him?
- He wears Florsheims, rubber-soled.
- Isn't that right?
- Correct.
He's got a couple of fractured
ribs, maybe his sternum too.
Set up for a chest tube.
- Pratt.
- Trauma panel, type and cross four units.
- He could've bagged his spleen.
- Look, I'll get the other one.
- We need you here.
- We'll be there.
- Now, Gallant.
- It's cool.
It's not cool.
Hurry the hell up.
- Come on, let's go.
- You've got two doctors. That's enough.
We've got a critical patient who needs
rapid assessment and prompt treatment.
What's the matter? Forget what
happened earlier and do your job.
- I... I can't help that guy.
- This is what we do, all right?
Now, get your ass in there.
Come on. Come on.
John, it's beautiful.
Absolutely beautiful.
Marriage can be a great thing.
- Can be.
- Yeah.
What the hell do I
know? Mine failed.
For many reasons.
You sure as hell
don't want my advice.
But I would think that kind
of commitment to somebody...
you have to be...
ready for anything.
Or nothing.
You never know
what's gonna happen.
Or you do.
You mean drinking?
I drank, I smoked
when I was younger.
It took having a baby
to make me stop.
Smoking, at least.
I always went
back to the drinking.
Maybe Abby will be stronger.
Have you two talked about this?
About having kids?
I know that she worries
about passing on the disease.
She and Richard never
communicated ever, I don't think.
Really?
I think they loved
each other at first.
But he had all these expectations
that she never realized.
He didn't understand her.
Well, I'm not
walking into this blind.
No, no, no, I
don't think you are.
I just don't want...
Yes?
I...
I just don't want
you to wanna fix her.
Abby doesn't need to be fixed.
- Or heal her or change her.
- I love her.
I just don't want you to be
waiting for her to change.
- I'm not.
- She's an amazing person.
- I know who she is.
- She's an amazing person...
with certain weaknesses.
And you'd be lucky to have her...
even with those weaknesses.
But you have to love her even
if she never changes anything.
- Pressure's only 85.
- Put two units on the rapid infuser.
- I don't want them.
- You don't get...
to choose your doctors.
Like we don't get to
choose our patients.
- No evidence of intra-abdominal bleeding.
- Twelve-lead.
- Prepping the chest.
- ST depression.
- Could be ischemia from hypotension.
- What about tamponade?
No, that gives you
low-voltage QRS.
We need to put a tube in
your chest to expand the lung.
Looks like a damn garden hose.
- There'll be some burning with the local.
- We were just doing our job, okay?
So let us do ours.
Gallant, there's no
pericardial effusion.
Start secondary survey.
- HemoCue's 14.8.
- Hold the transfusion.
No, no, no, prime the infuser.
Dr. Weaver, I don't think
he needs a chest tube.
It takes time for
your crit to drop.
Look, LV wall motion abnormality.
He's got a cardiac contusion.
That's not as bad, right?
Start dopamine
at 10 mics per kilo.
- Go.
- X-ray's back.
- I'll mix up some lido in case of ectopy.
- I don't see a collapsed lung.
Setting up cardiac
enzymes Q six hours. Yosh.
We'll bring you in
when the docs finish.
Good call.
So this must be a really
scary part for you, huh?
What?
Well, all the white folks left.
Now it's just you and a
couple of niggas with knives.
Sorry I'm late. Traffic.
- Why did you make me wait outside?
- Surprise.
- It's February in Chicago.
- I know.
It makes you feel
alive, doesn't it?
The visiting nurse waited an
hour, and then she had to go.
- It's my fault, Mrs. Simmons.
- No, it's not. I wanted a hot dog.
Sean, you should see your room.
They brought a bed with a remote.
No way.
I didn't mean to worry you, I just
wanted to make it easier for Sean.
- Easier?
- He wasn't ready to come home yet.
Mom, Sean wants to talk to you.
Well, he's home now. Good night.
Sean wants to know if she
could wait a minute, because...
- So you're Julia?
- Yeah, you're Susan.
Yeah, I work at the hospital.
I know. Sean said you were the only
doctor he ever met who was like a friend.
And that you were hot.
BP's up to 112/78 on dopamine.
- We need some more morphine.
- Yeah, push another four mgs.
How you doing, Mitch?
Your partner has an elevation
of his cardiac enzymes...
indicating a bruised heart.
It's the equivalent of
a small heart attack.
- Do you smoke?
- Yeah.
- I hear it's bad for you.
- Yeah, thanks for the advice.
No, you should be thanking this brother.
They profiled you as a collapsed lung.
But he kept an open mind, saved
you from surgery that you don't need.
- Yeah.
- Know what? That's not gonna cut it.
I think an apology's in order.
You think I'm gonna
apologize to you?
- No, to him.
- Hey, Pratt, forget about it.
I didn't do anything wrong.
There's nothing on your record.
You don't look like you're
hurt. You're here now.
- Lucky for you.
- And what is your damage?
You know, there
were three people...
butchered outside your hospital. We
were doing what we were supposed to...
You need cops like me
to catch animals like that.
"Sorry" would've
been a whole lot easier.
- You gonna tell me what this is about?
- I thought we both deserved a break.
- Especially after a day like today.
- Mm-hm.
Feels more like a month.
But what's it really all about?
So you think this is a keeper?
- The restaurant?
- Us.
You and me.
Are you okay?
I've spent a long time...
looking for a relationship
that I thought would stick.
Sometimes it was
the wrong person.
Sometimes I guess
I wasn't ready.
Or in the right place.
But I think I am now.
I really think I am now.
Are you?
- John...
- Because I really want this to stick.
Me too.
I know that...
we've had a rough time...
and that there's still a lot of
stuff that we have to get through.
But I think we're doing okay.
You know, I think
that we're growing.
We're changing.
Do you?
I don't know if people
ever really change.
But I... I know what you mean.
You do?
I think I do.
Mm-hm. Well, let's
see what's for dessert.
That's it?
You bought out this
whole place just for that?
That...
and the chocolate soufflé.
Hey.
Check this out.
Who knew it'd be
so much fun, huh?
Oh, here.
It's for you.
Open it later.
Sometimes...
if I think about what
comes next, it helps.
Maybe afterwards I'll know.
I'll know what it's all about.
What it all means,
if it means anything.
You'll know before any of us.
That sucks.
Yeah.
It does.
I want you to know what
you did for me, Susan.
It's mutual.
I want you to know.
I know, Sean.
I know.
How's Officer Palnick doing?
No cardiac ectopy on the lido
drip. Pulse ox, 99 on two liters.
That was good,
what you did in there.
But never make me ask
you twice again, okay?
Yes, ma'am.
A couple of cops
got real hurt...
trying to bring in those
guys that killed those people.
And that's why Mitch is here, because
he won't let scum like that get away.
Still, maybe we
overstepped this morning.
I think we did.
But thanks for
fixing up my partner.
They'll be moving him soon.
What was that about?
Almost sounded like an apology.
- One love, Gallant.
- Yep. Later.
Better day tomorrow
than we had today.
- Luka, how'd it go upstairs?
- Great. I feel a lot better.
- Hey.
It's so quiet now, you know? You'd
hardly know anything happened there.
- Yeah, except the police tape.
- Yeah.
You did good today. Probably
saved that woman's life.
Well, at least there's that.
Headed to the El?
No. I forgot something inside.
- Good night.
- Yeah, good night.
You know, ever since I was a kid, I've
always acted like it doesn't bother me.
But you know something?
It bothers me.
Well, at least they
caught the guys.
Let's get out of here.
Do you want tea?
Carter?
Hello. MAGGIE: Hello, Abby?
Mom. Are you there already?
No. No, I'm not. We're
delayed here in Tomah.
The roads are snowed in.
Tomah, Wisconsin?
Abby, I... I know I was in
the way, and I'm sorry. I...
- I never wanna be a burden.
- Mom, you are not a burden.
I just wish Eric
would've come back.
I know.
We could've all been together
just for one little minute.
I love you both so much.
Sometimes I don't
know what to do with it.
- I love you too.
- I'll call you in a few days.
Okay. Call me tomorrow.
- Get home safe.
- Bye.
- Who was that?
- Uh...
Maggie.
What did she want?
She wanted to
thank you for the ride.
What kind of tea do you want?
Whatever you're having.