Previously on ER:
I was thinking that maybe we
shouldn't be quite so together here.
- I thought everybody knows.
- I didn't tell anybody.
Dad's taking me to Florida.
You can take whatever you want.
But he's not going anywhere with you.
We'll catch the whales in the
fall. I'm going the other direction.
I know what you
want me to say and...
And I can't say it, okay?
But things with
Wendall didn't work out.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Yeah. It's weird. She's actually
not really even speaking to me.
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
- What? What?
- You have to get up. Get up, get up.
- What? What? What?
- It's 7:32.
- Yeah?
Rounds are at 8.
- I hit the snooze.
- No, you shut the alarm off.
Sorry.
I thought you were gonna
go home and change.
- It's okay.
- No, it's gonna look weird.
- No, it won't.
- You're back in the ER.
- People will think...
- What are they gonna think?
That I don't do my laundry?
That I sleep in the park?
- What?
- Abby needs to take a few pass-ons.
- She's late.
- Brushing up on your Spanish, huh?
It helps me relate
to the community.
- Oh, yeah? What's her name?
- Okay, one left.
- Asthma going to the ICU. Get an art line.
- Got it.
- Meaning...?
- I'll take care of it.
- Teach the residents how to do it?
- Absolutely.
That's the board.
Alex has soccer after school. I
thought you could drop him off.
Isn't the carpool
picking him up?
Yeah, but he needs to
work on his corner kick.
He's still pretty mad at me.
Well, think of it
as an icebreaker.
Maybe we should
give it a little more time.
- I'll see you tonight.
- All right.
Have a good nap.
- Morris!
- Sorry.
I came in to work on
our manuscript revisions.
We'll see if I have the time.
They're due by 5 p.m.
- Today?
- We don't wanna miss the deadline.
You two are publishing?
"Oligoanalgesia in Long-Bone
Fractures: A Retrospective Review."
Accepted in the annals next
month if we can make a few changes.
Some substantial changes.
Go to the doctors'
lounge. I'll be right in.
Consider it done.
You're working with Morris?
Yeah. You know, he's
thorough, good with statistics.
And the only resident
desperate enough to write it up?
- You got it.
- Dr. Lewis...
- would you let me run a trauma today?
- Do you think you're ready for that?
In a couple of months I'll be
an R2 supervising the interns.
It might be good to get practice.
- Need a bed.
- Hypothermia.
- All yours.
Elena Tabajas, 39. Passed
out at the immigration building.
- Tachy at 120.
- She's cold.
Some kind of a protest.
You need to call Benjamin
Coe. He's my lawyer.
- What?
- Don't do anything until he's here.
CBC, chem panel, EKG, a liter of saline,
O2 at 2 liters, and get a rectal temp.
- What are you doing? SAM:
We're giving you warm IV fluid.
Don't do that.
- It will help.
- No.
- What?
- I'm on a hunger strike.
They want to deport my son.
- Elena, you're cold and dehydrated.
- Maybe now the INS...
will give us a new hearing.
Do you know the risks
of refusing our care?
Do you know that you
could go into a coma and die?
I don't want to lose my son.
Okay. Cancel all the orders.
No fluid bolus?
No labs, no EKG?
You heard her. Nothing.
No one is going to
remember what I was wearing.
- No, people notice.
- Watch out. Watch out.
- Are you all right?
- Yup.
- Morning, Jake.
- Hey, Liza.
- How's the ER?
- Good.
This is Abby, my girlfriend.
Liza's the night
clerk on Surgery.
- Hi.
- We're kind of late, so...
- Me too. Hey, stop by sometime.
Did you say "girlfriend"?
- What?
- Nothing.
Takes me right
back to junior high.
- What do you want me to call you?
- How about introducing me as "Abby"?
You don't want people
to know we're going out.
- We're late.
- No. Hey, look, this is important.
Well, let's just
talk about it later.
Yeah. Yeah, I guess it can wait.
You look ridiculous.
What was I supposed to do?
They only had small and extra large.
What's up, homey?
- Sorry about being late.
- Nice scrubs.
- You should coordinate outfits every day.
- Yeah, it's cute.
Maybe we can find you some
matching stethoscopes or...
Victim of assault for Abby...
and low blood sugar
for your boy toy.
Okay. All right, all right.
It's rough when everyone
knows you're an item.
- That could work.
- What?
"This is Abby. She's my item."
Ninety-six point one.
- Do you want a warm blanket?
- Please.
- I am thirsty.
- Some orange juice?
Only water.
Elena?
Amigo.
- I'm Benjamin Coe from Legal Aid.
- I'm Dr. Lewis.
How's she doing?
Malnourished and
dehydrated, heading for a coma.
Maybe we'll see
some movement now.
This should get the INS
to grant us a new hearing.
- Her son's an illegal alien?
- Undocumented immigrant.
They can just
send the kids back?
Elena has her green
card. She came here in '89.
Her brother brought Santiago up
through Mexico seven years ago.
- How did the INS get involved?
- Santiago got into trouble.
Attempted robbery.
They locked him up
for two years in juvie.
Once he did time, they
transferred him to Immigration.
He won't last in El Salvador.
The police there round
up gang members.
Sometimes they get beaten to
death, sometimes they just disappear.
If he goes home,
they'll kill him.
I brought her durable power.
- What's that?
Says she's competent to start a
hunger strike and refuse nutrition...
even if she's unconscious.
We can't give her an IV?
That would be felony assault. If
you try to treat her, I'll call the police.
We need a kitchen.
The staff break room can
accommodate a refrigerator...
No, I mean a commercial kitchen.
The HIV daycare program should
be able to provide a hot lunch.
I'll mention that
to the architect.
So, John, if you're okay...
we're ready to go to
the contractors for a bid.
I'm thinking 150
million is in the ballpark?
That's a nice ballpark.
A leadership gift from the Carter
Foundation would help get it rolling...
and we've drawn up a list
of potential corporate donors.
We were hoping that you could make
some calls on the hospital's behalf.
No, thanks.
Your personal involvement would
be very useful in contacting the...
We weren't happy with the
idea of corporate sponsorship.
So we would be interested in
covering the construction costs.
The entire thing?
Mm.
Plus an endowment...
to supply the center's annual
budget to treat uninsured patients.
This is an incredibly
generous offer.
We would appreciate
a naming opportunity.
Of course. Do you
have some suggestions?
I do, actually.
But I would like to discuss it further
with a few family members first.
To the side.
Up and down.
How many times were you punched?
- Just once.
- Then he grabbed her purse.
- Where did this happen?
Twenty-third. BIRDY: Wabash.
Uh, well, it... It
was near the corner.
Did you file a police report?
What's the point?
They might catch the guy.
We didn't get a
good look at him.
Okay. I'm going to take you to X-ray.
- Wanna look this way?
Can...? Can I stay with her?
Uh, no, I'm sorry. Chuny, maybe
Rebecca would like some coffee?
- Can I have tea?
- Sure. You wanna come with me?
Stay out of trouble, sweetie.
Okay, Roberta. I just have a
couple more questions for you.
Birdy. Everybody calls me Birdy.
Um, who do you live with?
Just my sister and me.
Been that way for 50 years.
- Is there anything you wanna tell me?
- Like what?
Like sometimes
people are injured...
by their friends or
their family members.
It... It was a kid,
just some punk.
Are you sure?
And you feel safe at home?
Of course.
Okay.
I'm gonna order x-rays.
I left a voicemail for the
caseworker at the INS.
- Can you talk to her?
- And say what?
- Hey, Frank?
- Hold on.
Just tell them how sick she is.
Dr. Lewis, I converted
the tables to a TIFF file.
- You removed the P-values?
- Oh, crap.
They want differences
expressed as relative risk.
- I'll be back.
- Well, page Social Work again.
- I need a facial series in 4B.
- For Birdy?
- You know her?
- She and her sister panhandle on Wabash.
I give them a buck
once in a while.
It's a travesty what we
let happen to the elderly.
Hey, Wendall, I
have a consult for you.
- Hunger-strike lady?
- That's mine. Sorry. Elena Tabajas?
- I read about her.
- You did?
She was in the newspaper a few weeks
ago. Trying to get asylum for her son?
A few weeks. I had pancakes
for breakfast. I'm starving already.
I don't know what to say.
Well, I've been looking for some
time for the right thing to donate to.
It seemed only fitting.
Have you thought about any
future role in the outpatient center?
Yeah. I'd like to
sit on the board.
And I suppose I might
see a few patients.
You agree it's better to recruit someone
with more experience as director?
Definitely.
Yeah. I don't want to run the
place, Kerry. Too much paperwork.
Good. I've identified four
outstanding candidates.
Oh. Well, I'd be happy
to look over their CVs...
but I've actually been
talking to Todd Becker.
- Todd Becker from Stanford?
- Well, he's at Columbia now.
He's set up a network of clinics in Harlem
and the South Bronx. He'd be perfect.
- Why are you doing this?
- Oh, he'd be a great director.
No, I mean the whole thing.
The center, the 150 million.
- What's going on?
- City needs it.
There's no prevention,
there's no primary care.
The whole system's broken.
Well, that's not new. Why now?
For 11 years I've been here patching
up people who fall through the cracks...
and it hasn't been
enough. I wanna do more.
Dr. Carter. Tier-two trauma.
- MVC?
- Fell down a flight of stairs.
- Chest and hip pain.
- Good vitals.
You guys get started.
I'll be right there.
So you'll send me that file?
- What's that?
- The guy from Columbia.
Todd Becker. You're
gonna love him. I promise.
- Hey.
- Hi.
How are you?
I'm okay. I'm gonna finish an
eval before Psych gets here.
Trauma panel, C-spine, chest
and pelvis. Type and cross for two.
Did you fall down
a flight of stairs?
From the very top.
Mm. Was there carpeting?
- Cement.
I slipped while I was mopping.
- Pulse ox, 92.
- Decreased breath sounds here.
What's this gonna cost?
- That's what insurance is for.
- I don't have any.
Workers' comp will cover it.
I'm a temp.
Once a month, they pay me
$50 to clean the warehouse.
You're in County.
We'll take care of you.
Put your right leg down, please.
I... I can't.
Looks like posterior hip.
I should go home and rest.
It... It... It just
feels like a bruise.
You have a collapsed
lung, your hip is out of joint...
- and you could be bleeding internally.
- I'm okay.
- Jake, chest tube on the left.
- Got it.
- Ray, you take the hip.
- Etomidate.
Please! Just... Just... Just
take all this stuff off of me.
Ma'am? Ma'am.
Head trauma. She's
not thinking clearly.
- Yes, I am.
- No, you're not. Keep going with that.
You'll thank us
later for this, ma'am.
I spoke to Psychiatry. They support
her competency to refuse nutrition.
- Even if she's unconscious?
- Even then.
So we're all in agreement.
No treatment, right?
Dr. Lewis, she's seizing.
Probably hyponatremia.
You need to let this happen.
Her only intake has been water.
Her serum sodium is too low.
- Got a vein. COE:
What are you doing?
- Keeping her alive.
- She doesn't want to be treated.
- Sam.
- A patient takes an overdose...
we tie them down and
pump their stomach.
But we let this woman die?
- Yeah, what's the difference?
- She isn't suicidal. Wasn't depressed.
She's motivated by desire to achieve
an end, not by a desire to kill herself.
- Same outcome.
- We have to respect her autonomy.
We have a duty to
act in her best interest.
Heart rate's up, poor air
exchange, getting dusky.
Dr. Lewis, what do you wanna do?
- How about oxygen?
- Nothing.
- Five liters.
- Dr. Lewis.
It's a comfort measure.
Won't save her. Go ahead.
You may not like what she's
doing, but she has the right to do it.
How long can this go on?
After 30 minutes, there's a
very high risk of brain damage.
- She's bleeding.
- Oh, God.
Can somebody find
out if the INS has called?
She bit her tongue. Yankauer.
What is that? Stop.
Ativan, two milligrams.
Neela!
We have a document stating...
she did not want to be treated
for the consequences of her fast.
- Neela, get out of the room.
- It could have saved her life.
Thank you. You're off the case.
Your sedative's gonna
wear off in about two minutes.
- 32 French. RAY:
It won't budge.
Keep going.
I can't get this.
Try the Whistler technique.
I, uh, don't know that one.
All right. Your arm goes under
the bad knee, over the good one.
Stabilize the ankle
with your right hand.
- Pass the chest tube?
- Check the tract, wait.
Chuny, would you come
over here and help me?
Matter of fact, I'll
stabilize the pelvis.
Ray, get in the
position I was just in.
- Okay. JAKE: I
feel lung tissue.
Unh... MARQUEZ:
She's starting to wake up.
Okay, listen.
Arms level. Stand up
straight. The femoral head...
will slip over the
acetabular rim.
- Was that it?
- I heard a pop.
You got it. Good
job, Pratt, Ray.
All right. Let's
fix the lung up.
- There's some resistance.
- Okay. Just give it a little more muscle.
Hey, man.
- Nice.
- What are you doing? Pull your pants up.
- Sterile gloves.
- Oh, that's a bummer.
- Dr. Pratt, do you think you could...?
- Hell, no.
- Ray?
- No.
I need to do a
post-reduction exam.
- Uh, Chuny?
- That would be sexual harassment.
Okay. All right. Thank you very
much, everybody. 0-silk, please.
Yes, Roberta and
Rebecca Chaddock.
All inpatient records and
ER visits for the past year.
Thanks.
- Anybody to present?
- Yes. Elder assault, possible abuse.
Social Services on it?
Um, yes. And I'm
reviewing all the old charts.
- Good.
- Abby, I'm all yours.
I was just, uh,
filling in Dr. Carter.
- I can come back.
- No, that's okay.
Why don't you two go see the patient
and you can bring me up to speed later.
Okay.
- My head hurts.
- Yeah. That's from the seizure.
Elena, I don't know how much
longer your body can take this.
Do you have to do that again?
We're trying to
respect your wishes...
but I would hate for you
to do this unnecessarily.
It's not unnecessary if
it helps save Santiago.
What if they don't
give you a hearing?
Want your son to live with
your death on his conscience?
I wasn't there
when he was little.
My husband was killed
in the war, so I came here.
I sent Santiago
money for seven years.
When he was 12, I got tired...
of waiting for the
papers to come through.
He was old enough.
So my brother
Alfonso snuck him in.
You've done
everything you could.
You don't have to do
this. Let us treat you.
I'm so tired.
We'll let you rest.
I can't believe she
has to go through this.
She's a mother
trying to save her son.
I'd throw myself in front
of a train for Cosmo.
Where's Chuny?
Okay. All right.
We need a BOA kit.
His wife's having a baby?
- Okay?
- Should I get a gurney?
She's crowning. We need a
bulb syringe and some towels.
Okay, now push it for me, mama.
Okay? Come on. Push it! Push.
Uh... Puta.
Come on. Puta.
Puta. Come on. Puta.
What?
What are you
doing? Are you crazy?
Get off me!
Hey, get off me!
What the hell's the
matter with this dude?
Puje means push.
- You said puta.
- What does that mean?
You called his wife a whore.
Okay, here we go, honey.
Hey, Dr. Lewis.
- I'm getting coffee.
- Chuck's on line two.
- Sounds like Cosmo's sick.
- With what?
No, I'm at the hospital now.
I'll take it in the lounge.
- I've got the doctor right here.
- Wait.
- I've prepared the graphs.
- This is not a good time.
Four hours before
we have to turn it in.
Did you include the
95-percent confidence intervals?
Catch me later.
- Hey, Chuck.
- No, she'll be right with you.
Any vomiting?
He's alert? Good eye contact?
Okay. Well, just call me
when his fever comes down.
Okay, listen, I gotta go. All
right. Bye. Bye. Bye, Chuck.
I've got the INS.
This is Dr. Lewis.
Yes, I am.
She's dying.
No, but there's
something you can do.
You can give her son a new hearing.
She may not make it another day.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
I know she didn't want to be
overfed, but I gave her Ativan.
Ativan doesn't
have any calories.
Would you shock an end-stage
cancer patient with a DNR?
- What you did was just as wrong.
- She was suffering.
She was unconscious.
I couldn't just watch her die.
Then you should've
left the room.
It doesn't seem right.
It's not.
It's just the rules.
Pre- and post-reduction hip.
- No fracture.
- And the lungs expanded nicely.
Good. What happened to you?
Had a rough delivery.
Hip lady's labs.
- Crit's okay?
- Yeah, but calcium's 12.4.
What caused the bump?
- It's a long differential.
- But the top two causes are?
- Hyperparathyroidism.
- And cancer.
Yeah. You see these
rib fractures here?
There's lesions underneath that
may have weakened the bone.
- Metastases.
- That isn't where the malignancy started.
No. You have to go back and
find the site of the primary tumor.
- Damn.
- Well, that sucks.
- She's a nice lady.
- Yeah.
I hear that's a risk
factor for cancer.
The nose is slightly cracked, and
the knee is bruised. Nothing serious.
Oh, she's a tough one.
You two have been mugged
several times in the past year.
Occupational hazard.
How come you have to panhandle?
Because they aren't
hiring at Hooters. Ha-ha.
Well, I'm serious.
It's dangerous.
Don't tell me you haven't
been smacked in here.
What about Social Security?
We have rent and heating
bills, electrics, medications.
We should have Adult
Services make a visit.
Again?
They went out last summer.
The place was pretty messy.
Well, we would have cleaned it
up if we knew they was coming.
You didn't have much
food in the cabinets.
We like to eat out.
Is there anything
we can do to help?
We do just fine.
- I could request another home visit.
- Suit yourself.
I'll be back with your
discharge instructions.
Yes, ma'am.
Still tachy at 120.
She can have some more water.
Dr. Lewis, navicular
fracture has his thumb spica.
- Is that the hunger-strike lady?
- Yeah.
- There's gotta be a better way.
- She's got no money...
no political influence. This
is it. Ortho clinic in a week.
You got it.
She should at least
get to see her son.
If they know she's dying,
maybe they'd let him visit.
Maybe he can get her to eat.
- Worth a shot.
- He'd better get here fast.
Thyroid feels good.
You say I got holes in my bones?
It's in two of the ribs.
I should drink more milk.
I need to do a breast exam next.
What for?
Well, your bone lesions could have
been caused by the spread of a tumor.
You mean cancer?
Possibly.
Have you felt this before?
A mass?
- Upper outer quadrant, five centimeters.
- Five?
When did you first notice it?
A couple years ago.
Why didn't you see a doctor?
I've been fine.
Yeah, you could have
caught this before it spread.
Surgery might not be as
effective at this advanced stage.
You wanna cut
me? I don't think so.
An operation might be
part of the treatment plan.
- Where are my clothes?
- Okay, take it easy. You're all hooked up.
- I never should've come.
- You have to stay.
- I don't want you cutting into me.
- Okay, relax.
- Relax, please.
- No!
- It's okay. It's okay.
- You don't cut into cancer!
- Okay. We're not going to.
- I know what happens when you...
- Settle down.
- It spreads.
- Mrs. Graham.
It spreads.
And you die.
Okay. All right.
Okay?
- Wound check in two days.
- We'll see you then.
- Thank you, doctor.
- Bye-bye.
Hey, uh, hold on.
Um...
Why don't you guys
have a nice dinner tonight.
You are so sweet.
Was that a 20?
No wonder your patient-satisfaction
scores are so high.
- You waiting on a run?
- Sort of.
- See you later.
- Yeah.
Come on.
Keep moving.
Boxers would stick out more.
- It could be tighty whities.
- Thong.
- Maybe Abby can settle this.
- Settle what?
Boxers or briefs?
Actually, he goes commando.
- A hunger strike?
- It's been 41 days.
Damn. All I heard
was she was protesting.
She's weak. Lost
a lot of weight.
- Can't you make her eat?
- That's why you're here.
Do you want to go in?
Elena?
- Elena? SAM:
Someone's here to see you.
Ah. Take a step back.
- Is that necessary?
- He's still in custody.
Can you give them a minute?
As long as he
keeps his distance.
I'm okay.
I haven't seen
him in six months.
How long can she last?
- It's hard to know.
- A few days at most.
- You should be helping her.
- We're trying.
No, you're not doing anything. You're
doctors. You're supposed to help.
Please let these
people help you.
People think that about
cancer? It's an urban myth.
Not to her. To
her, it's a reality.
Yeah. Superstition.
Yeah, well. There's no screening,
no early detection in her community.
She only sees
friends diagnosed late.
Look. Check this out.
Guy with colon cancer...
he comes and he presents
with bowel obstruction.
Gets surgery, mets
are everywhere.
They do the colostomy,
they close him back up.
- Dead in six months.
- Exactly.
All his friends say, "He was
fine till he got the surgery."
How you doing, Mrs. Graham?
Had the chance to think
about what we discussed?
I don't want no surgery.
They put a thin needle into
the lump and pull out some cells.
What happens then?
Well, based on the findings, we can
recommend the appropriate treatment.
Like what?
Well, you know, that
really depends on the tumor.
Could be radiation.
Could be chemotherapy.
Oh, no. I don't want that.
Look, I'm sorry, ma'am,
but is this about money?
You know, because with
cancer, you qualify for state aid.
It's not about money.
Look, if the biopsy shows
a certain kind of tumor...
your options are very good.
You could take medication
once a day and survive for years.
You're telling me I got
cancer in my bones...
and all I got to
do is take a pill?
If it's the right kind of tumor.
I'll take the pill then.
Good. First we have to do the
biopsy to make sure it'll work.
No. No needles, no surgery.
I've had it for two years,
and I been doing fine.
We can't help you
if you don't let us.
Who's gonna help me get
to the doctor all the time?
Gonna stay with me when
I'm spitting up all night?
Who's gonna help me up the
stairs when I'm too weak to walk?
Who's gonna do that? You?
Why do you want to kill yourself?
- To save you.
- She needs food.
- We know that.
Then feed her. Give her something.
- She wouldn't eat it.
- You can force it down her throat.
- Please.
I don't need help. I
can take care of myself!
Where can we put him?
- Family room.
- Bring the van around.
- You want to help. All you do is mess up!
- Don't talk like that.
- You should've forgot about me!
I was better off in El Salvador!
Hey. Hey! What is your problem?
- She has the problem.
- She's doing this for you.
Well, I never asked her to!
Come here.
Maybe we will force-feed her...
because your getting deported
sounds like a good idea now.
- I'll go back home. I don't care.
- So you wanna die?
Look, it's not like she
says. I had a good life there.
- She ruined everything.
- She wanted you to be together.
Right. Yeah. She worked
two jobs. I hardly know her.
She wanted a
better life for you.
Oh, yeah?
You think it worked out?
She loves you.
She isn't doing this for me.
She's doing this
because she feels guilty.
- Let her go, if that's what she wants.
- You don't mean that.
Sure, I do.
Just let her die.
Do you have Mueller's chart?
Oh, yeah.
Sorry. I'm doing three consults.
That's all right. I
just need to cosign it.
You wanna grab some lunch?
I, um... I have to
get up to the unit.
- Dinner?
- I don't know.
Look, I feel bad
about everything.
- Me too.
- Well, I'm sorry.
You know, I'm really good at
getting in my patients' heads.
I wish I'd been able to figure
out what was going on in yours.
I have to get up to the
ICU. There's a family waiting.
You left some stuff at my place.
I can bring them by sometime.
- I can come by tonight and pick it up.
- Okay.
Leave them in a
bag on the steps.
Sure.
If that's what you want.
Thanks.
Doc, think she'll eat now?
- Probably not.
- Too bad.
She'll die, the kid
will get deported.
- What about the hearing?
- Not sure if it'll change anything.
We'll see what my boss says.
Good to go.
- Thanks for your help.
- Can't say we didn't try.
Dr. Lewis, Elena's unresponsive.
I checked the Internet.
Forty-five days.
- For what?
- I.R.A. prisoners in Belfast.
They started dying
45 days after fasting.
- How long has she been going?
- Forty-one.
Oh, Sam. Paramedic's
on the MICN.
Hey. Okay, I made all the revisions,
rewrote the abstract and conclusion.
- I can't deal with this now.
- We got an hour.
Look it over. I can e-mail
it. We'll make the deadline.
- It's important to me too. Sorry.
- Dr. Lewis, please.
- May I call you Susan?
- No.
I need this publication for
my Chief Resident application.
Trust me. It's gonna take a
hell of a lot more than that.
Convert the chest
tube to a Heimlich valve.
Call for an ambulance and
have a nurse drop in on her.
You're sending her home? We
need to put a bit more pressure on her.
- I just tried.
- Not very hard.
- Well, we can't force her.
- Yeah, but we can help her.
Maybe in a couple days she'll
change her mind and reconsider.
- If she goes home, she's not coming back.
- Respecting her wishes is first.
Then maybe she'll
get into Oncology.
- Or she's lost to follow-up.
- This lady does not have a doctor.
She doesn't feel comfortable
with the medical system.
That's what's making it tough.
I'm feeling a lot better.
Beta-blockers kicked
in. Your heart rate's down.
- Cool.
- Overactive thyroid can cause glaucoma...
- so I need to check your eye pressures.
- Go for it.
First, a drop.
Now, this might
feel a little weird.
Excuse me. I need
a Heimlich valve.
- Go ahead.
- It's okay. It's okay.
- You use proparacaine?
- Yeah.
- Here.
- Did my eyeball come out?
Oh, my God! ABBY: Chuny...
10 of morphine right
away. Jake, dribble the local.
Adrian, what's happening to you is called
a subluxed globe. Get me an Attending.
- Kovac is here. ADRIAN:
Everything's blurry!
That's normal.
You're gonna be okay.
- Adrian, we need you to stay still.
- I can't!
Okay, you have to.
Is that Legal Aid
lawyer still here?
No. He had to go to class. Turns
out he's a third-year law student.
Cocky little bugger.
Hey.
Five more minutes and I'd
have given her the Ativan myself.
Sam, your hunger-strike
lady's asking for you.
- In there?
- She's coming around.
Elena, what do you need?
The bathroom.
Where did this come from?
I don't know.
I didn't have an
order for an IV.
With an amp of multivites.
- Did you do this?
- No.
What's going on?
Uh, well, Elena's
awake. With an IV.
- Yeah, I can see that.
- What is this?
- We just...
- Could you two step outside?
I need to talk to Elena alone.
What happened?
It's okay.
Elena, it's okay.
- Wow.
- What?
Who knew Lewis could
start an IV all by herself?
All right, I'll stop by. Thanks.
Pratt, we'll run the board
as soon as I help Abby.
- I need to go up to Oncology for a bit.
- Okay.
Okay, Adrian. Keep looking down.
- You needed an Attending?
- Welcome to your night shift.
Subluxed globe. Scleral
pressure's not doing it.
- Okay. We need a Desmarres retractor.
- We don't have one.
Do we have a paper clip?
- A paper clip?
Yeah.
You're sticking a
paper clip in my eye?
Don't worry.
- You won't feel a thing.
- Oh, God.
Okay. How about some Versed?
Don't you have an eye
specialist or something?
Everything's okay,
Adrian. Stay still.
Nice and relaxed.
Okay, insert between the
upper lid and the superior rectus.
Right there.
It's... It's tough.
Jake, retract the lid superior.
Got it. KOVAC: Good.
- A little bit more.
- Cover the end...
depress with your ring finger.
You're doing great.
Take a deep breath.
Let it out. We're almost done.
Okay. The eyelid...
is past the equator.
Okay. Look up, Adrian.
Oh, my God.
I can see.
Nice.
I'm cold.
They're getting you
some warm blankets.
Did you do this?
It's just one bag.
After that, it's up to you.
But it was up to me already.
You know, I talked to some reporters.
You're getting a lot of attention.
Mm. Because I'm dying.
Here you go.
The INS is taking your demand
for a hearing very seriously.
They don't want the bad press.
You have done all you can.
It's okay to eat now.
Not until they let him stay.
He wasn't always like
this. He was a good boy.
He did a stupid thing, and
then, in jail, he joined the gang.
You try so hard, but you
never know how they'll turn out.
All he has now
is anger and hate.
But you want to keep going?
He's still my son...
even though he
doesn't care about me.
I think he does.
He just doesn't
know how to show it.
The last thing he said
to me on his way out was:
"Please don't let her die."
What time is the ambulance
coming to take me home?
Should be in about an hour.
There's someone
I'd like you to meet.
As long as it's no surgeon.
She's not even a doctor.
Debra Graham, I'd like
you to meet May Crawford.
- Hello.
- What are you?
The social worker?
No.
A psychologist.
I'm a secretary at an ad agency.
And a breast-cancer survivor.
It's been three years now.
We'll let you two talk.
I had some spots on my bones.
That's how they found it.
- Really?
- Okay, where did you find her?
A cancer support group upstairs.
They have patient navigators to
help people get through the system.
Think it'll work?
Maybe she'll listen to her
more than she'll listen to us.
Hey.
Thought you were gonna
leave the stuff on the steps.
Yeah, I got stuck doing
an LP on a 300-pound guy.
- It's cold, huh?
- Yeah.
Springtime in Chicago.
Wanna come in for a
second and get warm?
I don't think so.
You have my stuff?
Yeah.
Hang on a second.
Thanks.
You need to get that?
No. The machine will pick it up.
Sure you don't wanna
come in? I could make coffee.
Or some tea.
No, I should get going.
Yeah.
Good night, John.
Good night.
We did a good job getting
that kid's eyeball back in.
Yes. We're a pretty good team.
Yeah. "This is Abby.
She's my teammate."
"This is Abby.
She's my partner."
No.
It sounds like we work
at a law firm. How about...
"my special friend"?
What are you afraid
that people will think?
- What?
- This morning, that's what you said.
I just don't want us to go too
fast and get ahead of ourselves.
- You have two weeks to decide.
- Decide what?
How fast you want to go,
how you'd like to be referred to.
What happens in two weeks?
- Big family thing.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah. It's like a Saturday brunch.
- Okay.
And before that, we're
gonna have to go to church.
- Church?
- Yeah. My niece is getting baptized.
- I have to hold her.
- Oh, you're the godfather.
Yeah. If something happens
to the parents, I'm responsible.
- That sort of thing.
- Mm-hm.
So I'm going to a baptism
as the godfather's...?
Fill in the blank.
Dr. Carter? Ed Miyamoto.
The revised architect's plans will
be in my office Friday. Stop on by.
Hello. If your current
mortgage rate is more than...
Hi, John. About 6
in the morning here.
Just wanted to say hello.
You could call, but I'm
leaving for work in an hour.
Bye.
Hey. Hi.
It's me.
I wasn't sure I was
gonna catch you.
Well, I just got home from work.
It was good.
I looked at the plans today.
Yeah. And I've been thinking
about a name for the building.
Well, how would you feel about
"The Joshua Carter Center"?
Yeah, after the baby.
For the first two days,
it's pretty much all IV...
but we can try a small
amount of clear liquids.
- That's it? SAM:
Just a few spoonfuls...
until your stomach
gets used to it.
I swore I wouldn't
stop until he was safe.
Bless us, O Lord,
in these, thy gifts...
which we are about to receive from
thy bounty through Christ our Lord.
Keep my son away from harm.
Amen.
- Amen.
Hello? Uh, yeah. Hey.
Okay, hold on.
Dr. Lewis, it's
Chuck on line four.
Oh. I'll take it in the hallway.
Okay. Okay, put him on.
Hi, baby. It's Mommy.
Yeah. You need to go
to bed for Daddy, okay?
I'll be home soon.
No, I'm sorry. I can't
do that right now.
Yeah. All right.
All right, I'll try.
"One hippo, all alone...
calls two hippos on the phone.
Three hippos at the door...
bring along another four.
Five hippos come overdressed.
Six hippos show up with a guest.
Seven hippos arrive in a sack.
Eight hippos sneak in the back.
Nine hippos come to work.
All the hippos go berserk."