I believe it was Cicero
who said,
"In nothing do men
more nearly approach the Gods
"than in
giving health to men."
It's so humbling,
the responsibility.
They say
emergency medicine...
What's with the camera?
They're shooting...
The promo today.
The promo today. Yup.
A star is born.
Maggie?
Yeah.
This is Jason Dodd, 26.
Heart's racing pretty good.
Dr. Halstead,
you're up. April!
He was lugging
the crib out of IKEA
and he just collapsed.
All right,
you'll go to Treatment Two.
Hi, Jason.
I'm Dr. Halstead.
How are you feeling?
Kind of freaked out.
All right, we're gonna
take good care of you.
He's really tachy.
Might be SVT.
Copy.
Hey, we're gonna have
you lie down, okay?
Ready 6 milligrams
of adenosine
and get him up
on the monitors.
Got it.
Jason, you on
any medications?
No.
Any history we should
be aware of?
No.
All right, Jason.
I don't need to tell you
that your heart is racing.
What we're gonna do
is give you a drug
to reset your rhythm.
Reset?
Your heart,
it's gonna pause
for a few seconds.
Wait a minute, what?
It'll be all right.
Let's give
the doctors some room.
Get a flush, 10ccs.
Hold up. What's with
the monitors, April?
It's upside down.
Leads must be reversed.
No, they're fine.
Just breathe, Jason.
This is strange.
It's like everything's
on the wrong side.
Let's get
a chest X-ray.
On it.
What appears to be
the problem here, Doctor?
There appears to be
some irregularities
with the patient's heart.
What kind
of irregularities?
It's not where
it's supposed to be.
Basic anatomy is
usually covered
in the first year of
med school,
Dr. Halstead.
I think he might
be dextrocardic.
I'm about to get
a chest X-ray.
Let's wait on that.
Push the meds.
Mmm-hmm.
Uh, listen up, people.
We're tight on space,
so, if you're not
doing anything useful,
just take
a giant step back.
Heart rate's 120.
BP's ticking up,
100 over 87.
What just happened?
We just saved
your life.
Let's get that picture now.
And, uh, page CT.
I guess Cicero knew
what he was
talking about after all.
Why is this backwards?
It's not.
He's got situs
inversus totalis.
All his major
visceral organs...
Are reversed from
their normal position
inside of his body.
More like a mirror image,
but yeah.
So, uh,
how often do you
see someone with this?
Never.
Jason, Becca,
this is Dr. Rhodes.
Hi, I'm down from
cardiothoracic surgery.
I'm gonna accompany you
over to run some tests.
See if we can't figure out
what caused your
heart rate to spike.
Okay.
Shame he wouldn't
sign a release.
I wanted to shoot
the scan room in action.
That's the thing about the ED.
Another story's
just a heartbeat away.
Can you say that
again on camera?
Yeah, that'll be better.
Uh, Ms. Goodwin,
if you have a second?
You know, Dr. Halstead,
there was a meeting
last week, uh,
open to anyone who had
concerns about the video.
I don't recall
seeing you there.
I was not there, but...
Dr. Stohl has assured me
that the camera
won't get in the way
of us treating our patients,
if that's your worry.
That's one
of them, yeah.
I'm gonna tell you,
I'm proud of this ED.
I've assembled
the finest staff in the city,
and if even one patient
decides to come here
because they saw this video
on our website,
then I think
it's well worth it.
Don't you?
Dr. Halstead?
Come round with me.
Carry on.
Not the most
cooperative intake ever.
Woman in Treatment Six?
Yeah, Laura Green.
Age 39. MVC,
5 centimeter laceration
on her left upper forehead.
GS 15, no LOC.
Vitals stable.
Blood and personality,
both type A.
I'll take it from here.
Thank you, Jeff.
Sure.
So it's really over
between you two?
Uh-huh. Why?
Just impressed.
Personally, I could never
work alongside an ex.
Too much boil and bubble.
Jeff and I were good friends
before anything happened
between us.
Guess it makes it easier
to find that
equilibrium again.
Good for you.
No, no, no.
We're not waiving
the contingencies, no.
Oh, let me call you
right back.
I got another doctor
in here.
Hi, Ms. Green.
I'm Dr. Manning.
Can you tell me
what happened?
I hit a patch of black ice.
Driving too fast.
My daughter had
another meltdown
at school.
Got pulled out of a meeting
to go pick her up,
again.
Hello,
what's your name?
Ariel, a girl who has
zero appreciation
for what it's like to be
in her mother's shoes.
No wonder I have an ulcer.
An ulcer?
Nothing Tums
can't manage.
Look, can we make this quick?
I am super deep
in the weeds today.
Sure, let me take a look.
Sorry.
Ow!
Okay.
You okay, Ariel?
Did you get hurt
in the crash, too?
She's been complaining
like this for months.
I've taken her to every
GI specialist in the city
at considerable expense.
No one could find
anything wrong with her.
It's not my stomach
this time, Mom.
It's my head.
It's throbbing.
Now she's got a headache.
I think she's trying
to imitate me.
Some juvenile attempt to
mock her mother.
Okay, uh, Laura,
I would like plastics
to come down and sew you up
so you get the best
cosmetic result, okay?
I really do have to
get back to work.
I will try my best
to expedite things,
but since you're
already here,
perhaps I can take a look
at your daughter?
Yeah, yeah,
that's fine.
Okay.
CJ? Sorry.
Where were we?
I'm not just
making this up.
Oh, I get it.
You're creating a vacuum.
I read about this somewhere.
I, uh...
I don't know,
I really felt compelled
to say something.
Remind me again why
you're here, Sarah.
Dr. Charles said
undergoing therapy
would help me become
a better psychiatrist.
And thus far,
I'd have to say he's right.
I'm learning so much.
I hate to break this
to you, Sarah,
but what you're
doing here now is not
undergoing therapy.
It's not?
Feels more like you're
auditing a class.
Come here.
Come on.
Look.
What do you see?
Uh...
Do you feel
self-conscious?
A little.
Good.
Self-conscious is what
we're going for.
You know what makes you
better at this job?
Being present.
Being honest.
Especially with yourself.
Try it.
First thought,
best thought.
Um...
Yeah,
I don't know what to...
What to tell you.
I mean, I've led
such a mundane life.
My problems feel
so pedestrian.
Problems.
That's a great start.
Here.
Okay.
Hour's up
at 10 of, right?
Normally.
Then, same time
next week?
You know where to find me.
So,
given the patient's age,
I was thinking a woven graft
with a mechanical valve.
And once we adjust
for the inversa,
it should be
a simple plug and play.
Simple?
Yeah, I was saying to
Dr. Bardovi earlier,
once you situate your brain
in the right way...
You were talking to
Dr. Bardovi
about the way
I situate my brain?
What?
You said the way
you situate your brain.
Oh, no, I meant it more,
like, "Once one situates..."
I think
you're underestimating
the challenges here,
severely.
You may be right.
Um... In that case,
I have a suggestion.
How about we put the team
through a dress rehearsal?
A rehearsal?
Mmm-hmm.
I'll have a tech
print us a 3-D model
of this heart,
and that should give us
a very clear idea
of how we'll proceed.
If you think
it'll be worthwhile.
Yeah, I think it'll be good
for everyone to walk
through it.
Mmm.
Keep your hands off me.
Hey, we're trying to help.
We just wanna
take a look, okay?
What do we have here?
Dr. Choi,
this is Rey Ochoa,
who insists that
there is nothing at all
wrong with him.
That's weird.
Charge nurse said
he was found doubled over
on the floor of
a gas station bathroom,
screaming out in pain.
I wasn't screaming in pain.
Only gay-ass punks do that.
Rey, you might not be aware,
but I'm a navy
flight surgeon,
still in active reserve.
And, Jeff,
here was an army ranger.
Seen plenty of men
screaming out in pain.
Tougher guys than me.
So how about
we take a look?
How about you suck me?
Rey...
Come on.
Seen this movie before.
Even when he says
he has something
lodged up his rectum.
Seriously?
See how he's hunched up
on the gurney,
trying to take the pressure
off the rear end?
Plus all the lip.
The embarrassment
makes them combative.
All right.
I'll try and get an X-ray.
Thanks.
Mr. Mikulski's here
with a fever
and some sinus pain.
Really bad sinus pain,
just FYI.
Diabetic?
How's his glucose?
Totally normal.
They said something
in the waiting area
about signing
some kind of release.
Not necessary,
Mr. Mikulski.
We'd like to send you
on your way ASAP.
Let's get him on a Z-Pak.
Sorry, one second.
You see the swelling?
Under the orbit
of his left eye?
It's practically
imperceptible,
but I think
we should get a...
A head and sinus CT,
just to rule out
anything more concerning.
Fever plus sinus pain
equals sinus infection.
Let's Z-Pak
and get you home.
Check back in two days
if your symptoms persist.
Hey, I really
feel like...
No, uh, he's discharged.
Let's find you something
more compelling.
Let's go.
Hey, Mags,
let's get a CBC here
on Mr. Mikulski.
And don't let him leave
until the results come back.
Uh-huh. Go maverick.
Mr. Clarke,
what are we looking at?
Mr. Clarke?
Sorry, we have
a safety issue.
Everybody please step out.
Step out. Okay, thank you.
Step out.
Laura. Hey, Laura,
that's you?
Uh, security, over here.
What's going on?
Dr. Choi was right.
There is something lodged
in the rectum.
What is that, a gun?
He says he has no idea
how the gun got up there.
All right.
What are our options?
It's not gonna be easy
getting it out.
It's just past his sphincter.
Plus, the hammer's cocked.
So if there's
a live round in there...
Seriously?
Could do some real damage.
.22 single-shot derringer.
That's a big kick
for a little gun.
So we work up a plan
to get him to the OR.
Page the surgeon on call.
Ms. Goodwin,
I think it'd be safer
to do it here.
Jeff and I both have
weapons experience.
We sedate him.
Try to slide it out.
If we can't make it,
then we call in surgery.
I'm in.
Should we call CPD?
Yes.
We'll need enough
body armor and gear
to protect
whoever's in there with him.
And let's keep
this area clear.
And I'll keep the cameraman
away from all this.
It's unsafe, and frankly,
it's distasteful.
Thank you.
The second
you focus on one pain,
it disappears,
or shifts
someplace else entirely.
First it was her stomach,
then her forehead.
We move her
into another room,
and now it's her sinuses.
Mmm. Tricky hitting
a moving target.
And listen, I am predisposed
to side with anyone
against the mother,
but I don't know
that she's wrong
about her daughter.
You think she might be
faking it?
I had her record
sent over,
and amongst other things,
she's been worked up
for achalasia,
abdominal migraine,
cyclic vomiting syndrome.
All negative.
It does not appear to be
anything physiological.
Why don't I have
a little chat?
I would appreciate that.
Thank you.
What's up
with the limp?
Rehab.
My physio's got me doing
these Swiss ball squats.
It's frickin' brutal.
CBC's back on
your sinus infection.
Mmm-hmm.
You were right.
White count's elevated.
Not sure it's
elevated enough to change
Stohl's mind, though.
Hand me one of
those video release forms,
will you?
For a guy who's always
complaining about money,
you sure put your job
on the line a lot.
My mom keeps saying
I'm doing this
for attention, but...
God, who likes
seeing doctors?
Your leg okay?
All of a sudden,
my knee hurts.
Hmm.
This place freaks me out
even worse than school.
What freaks you out
about school?
Everything.
There's so much drama.
It makes me crazy anxious.
Sometimes I hide.
Sometimes I get into fights.
That's what happened today?
I looked up
schizophrenia online.
It says it can start
in late adolescence.
Mmm. Not usually
as early as 14, but...
I mean, are you
hearing or seeing things
that other people aren't?
No.
But sometimes, it's like
my feelings aren't my own.
Like they're
someone else's.
Hmm.
Do you think I'm crazy?
Uh, not really
my favorite word, but no.
No, I don't.
Thank you.
Let's get you
what you need.
Excuse me, Dr. Stohl?
About Ed Mikulski,
in Room Four?
I thought I already
discharged him.
But that was before
his blood work came back
with a white count
of 18,000.
I just wanted your approval
before I send him over
for scans.
He was willing to sign
a video waiver,
by the way,
if that matters.
Well, we haven't found
anybody to follow yet,
and I did wanna film
the scanning facility.
Plus, Dr. Halstead here
pops on camera.
Must be the red hair.
All right, uh,
send him over.
Wait a second, will you?
We gotta swap out a battery.
Sure thing.
Dr. Halstead?
You wouldn't be trying
to show me up on camera,
would you?
What?
Never mind.
I'll begin by placing
the venus cannula
in the right atrium.
Uh, I'm sorry, sir,
but in this case,
it's actually
the one that's on the left.
We have to remember that
everything here is mirrored.
I am not in a good
position for this.
Okay.
Let's switch sides, then.
Atrial purse string suture.
Where am I supposed
to be now?
To my left.
But then I'll be
out of the field.
I can't move, guys,
so don't look at me.
Am I okay, here?
Am I
in the right spot?
Yeah, you're fine.
Where's that suture?
I don't wanna
reach over the patient.
Beth, why don't you just
go stand on his right?
You two, switch.
This is why we're here.
Right, folks?
We're just trying to
work out the kinks.
I have to reach
across my body.
This is all wasted motion.
But there's nowhere else
I can stand.
I am sick and tired
of being mocked!
I will not abide
insubordination!
I have put up
with that ingrate
for seven years.
No more.
Beth, he's gonna calm down.
I'm done!
Ethan?
Yeah.
I thought we had a policy
about dealing with
polyembolokoilamania?
I'm sorry?
The insertion of
a foreign object
into an orifice.
All patients
are supposed to be
psychiatrically evaluated.
We've got a bit of
a mitigating
circumstance here, Reese.
The gun. Exactly.
To do what he did,
this kid must be
seriously troubled.
And now,
he's alone and terrified.
Are the restraints
really necessary?
For the safety
of everyone, yes.
Well,
I wanna go talk to him.
How do we make that happen?
Rey, this is Dr. Reese.
She's gonna help
with the procedure.
Hello, Rey.
How much longer
is this gonna take?
Not too much.
We're gearing up now.
Is it okay if I sit with him
until we get started,
if that's okay with you?
Sure.
You can stay.
Okay.
Dr. Halstead,
you got a second?
Yeah, of course.
I just wanted to say,
I appreciate you
going the extra mile here.
With the diabetes,
let's just say
I've seen my share of
doctors over the years.
So few of them
really listen to you,
especially in
the emergency room.
I'm just doing my job,
Mr. Mikulski.
You don't need to thank me.
I know, but I want to.
It's the first time
I felt like someone was
in my corner.
I'll tell anyone
who's listening.
This is the best hospital
in the city, hands down.
Thank you
for saying that, Ed.
Any time.
Your guy's scans came back.
Sinus opacification
and invasion
through the cribriform plate.
It's mucormycosis,
most likely.
Stohl wanted to
send him home.
Who looks like
he doesn't know
basic anatomy now?
It's an amazing catch,
Dr. Halstead.
I knew it.
Yeah.
You the man, Will.
But this is bad news
for your patient, right?
Yeah.
I like your tattoos.
Who designed them?
Me.
You're really talented.
You go to school for that?
No.
Just fool around on my own.
Huh.
I saw you
looking at my scars.
You're not gonna
ask me about them?
Do you wanna
tell me about them?
What are you,
a shrink or something?
Not yet. Officially,
I'm still training.
Do you cut yourself, Rey?
I'm not crazy.
I know.
What I'm discovering
doing this is
how we all do things
that we can't explain.
Things we say,
things we do to ourselves.
Maybe we're
just experimenting
to see how it feels,
or maybe we're
reliving something
that happened to us
in the past.
Did something
happen to you, Rey?
Dr. Reese? Mr. Ochoa.
The hell is this?
People are saying
you're some kind of freak.
It's not what it
looks like, Papa.
It was for Wilmer.
Your cousin?
That fool's
in Crook County.
He asked me to
smuggle a gun in for him.
Said he needed to
protect himself.
The guy in front of me
beeped going through
the metal detector.
They tackled him
to the ground.
I guess I panicked.
Ran out before
they could search me.
The pain must have
made me pass out.
Sorry.
I know I messed up.
No. No, mijo.
You done good.
You tell them
it was okay to remove it?
It's my son. No.
We understand...
No, it's not gonna happen.
I'm sorry.
We'll have to put
the procedure on hold.
Why?
Our patient just
confessed to a crime.
That means the gun is
considered evidence.
And since his father
convinced him to
withdraw consent,
we'll have to secure
a warrant to remove it.
Breaking bad news
is the most sobering
of our obligations.
No matter how
many times you do it,
it never gets any easier.
Excuse me. One second.
Yeah?
Any chance we can
do this off-camera?
Off-camera?
He didn't sign up
for this.
And it's probably not
gonna make the video.
You're wrong.
People wanna see
how compassionate
we can be.
But it's so intrusive.
You can't have it both ways.
You wanted a release?
This is what happens
when they sign it.
A fungal infection
in my brain?
That doesn't sound good.
No, not at all what
we were hoping for.
But let's just take this
one step at a time, okay?
And, uh...
Just so I know what
we're talking about here,
is this the kind of thing
that could keep me
in the hospital?
I would plan on that, yes.
Should I plan
on ever leaving?
If it's advanced enough
to require surgery,
then you should know,
there's about
a 90% mortality rate.
Oh, my God.
I'm so sorry.
Yes, it's a lot
to process.
I'm just glad you spotted it
when you did.
Thank you.
Thank you, both.
State's Attorney's
secured the warrant.
We're a go.
I don't believe that story
Rey's telling
about the gun, do you?
About smuggling it
into jail? Who knows?
Did you notice the scars
on Rey's arms?
I'm pretty sure
he's been cutting himself.
He's no stranger
to self-harm.
I'm sympathetic,
Sarah, I truly am.
I don't know what
you want me to do, though.
I just want another chance
to get him to open up
before he's swallowed up
by the system.
How about we start
by making sure
he survives this, okay?
That should do it.
Thank you, Dr. Pellino.
Looks good.
I am, however,
still concerned
about your ulcer.
Have you ever thought about
maybe speaking to somebody
about reducing your stress?
I can manage my stress.
If I don't,
then the next person will.
How's my daughter?
Did you find anything?
No, not yet.
Surprise, surprise.
Listen, Dr. Manning,
I appreciate your efforts,
but I'm going to need you
to discharge me
and my daughter.
I'll sign out against
medical advice if necessary.
Sure. I'll get
the paperwork started.
Thanks.
Hey. Any progress?
Definitely stressed out
and anxious.
Whether it rises to
the level of a disorder,
I don't know.
She mentioned a potentially
unhealthy association
with food,
but I'm not getting
an eating disorder vibe
from her. You know?
No, me neither.
Her weight is normal
for her height.
She's not showing
any signs
of malnourishment.
And she says her
stomach ache's gone,
her headache's gone.
Her knee
is hurting her now.
I was thinking we could
give her a benzo.
See if alleviating
her anxiety
might tell us something
about her physical symptoms?
Unfortunately,
we don't have time.
The mom wants to
leave now.
Dr. Charles?
Dr. Latham called.
Asked you to come
to his office.
He says it's urgent.
Tell him
I'll be right there.
Okay.
I've been staring
at these scans
all afternoon
in a mirror trying to
retrain my brain.
It's not working.
The TMS treatments
have elicited
a very positive response.
It made my brain
more flexible,
my thinking more supple.
Perhaps if I had
another treatment?
Wait.
You're saying
you want to undergo
a TMS treatment to
prepare you to operate?
Yes.
I was going to talk to
Dr. Weyland today,
but she's unavailable.
Yeah, well,
she would tell you
the same thing
that I'm about to,
which is "No."
Why not?
You shouldn't do
anything risky,
let alone perform
open-heart surgery.
It would be derelict.
Tell me, then,
what is the solution?
Well, the solution
is to realize
that you don't have to
carry all the weight
on your shoulders.
You have an excellent team.
Rely on your team.
Rely on Connor.
No, I can't. I see the world
differently now.
The sarcasm,
the hidden agendas.
Even when my window
is closed,
I know they're there.
I have no one to
rely on now but myself.
I think you'll find
that that's not the case.
It's like trying
to cut your hair
in front of a mirror.
Left is right,
right is left. Impossible.
Left to right,
right to left?
Dr. Halstead.
He's having a seizure.
Five of Ativan, stat.
On it.
Feet are flushed.
Flow Y-O2.
Suction ready.
Ready.
I'm going to be
working late tonight,
but Mai will stay
with you until then.
Don't even think
about using this
as an excuse not
to do your homework.
Watch his airway.
Seriously, Ariel,
you've made your point.
Stop putting on a show.
Ariel? Oh, my God.
Ariel?
She's having a seizure.
No, I don't think so.
There's no nystagmus,
and her muscle movements
are not asynchronous.
Then what is wrong
with her?
We need to
isolate her.
What?
She needs to be
isolated now.
I need an empty room, now!
We're going to get
started now, Rey.
If you feel any discomfort,
just tell us.
I need you to stop
moving your leg, Rey.
Where am I?
Just keep still, bud.
Almost there.
What?
Jeff!
Gun vacated!
Go, go, go!
You okay, Jeff?
I'm all right.
I'm all right. How's he?
Exit wound in
the right lower quadrant,
we need a trauma lab.
Pack the wound.
Let's get him to the OR.
Ready? One, two, three.
All right,
we're moving him.
Let me take a look.
All right,
watch your backs.
Coming through.
How we doing?
Okay.
How's that knee doing?
It feels fine, actually.
What if I told you
that that was because
I just took an Advil?
I don't understand.
Ow!
Why'd you do that?
Feel like
I just slapped you?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
I don't like this game.
I don't understand.
Ow! Why'd you do that?
Feel like
I just slapped you?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
What were you doing
to my daughter?
I was trying to confirm
a diagnosis.
Um, I want neurology
to run some tests,
but based on this
and Ariel's history,
I think that she has
a condition called
mirror-touch synesthesia.
What?
It's a condition that
causes her to experience
the physical sensations
and emotions
of the people that
she's interacting with
as her own.
My left knee hurts,
Ariel feels it
in her right.
I slap my right cheek,
she feels like her left
is being slapped.
She's mirroring me.
Her stomach,
she's responding
to your ulcer,
not imitating you.
She's literally
feeling your pain.
Whoever heard of
such a thing?
It's a pretty recent
discovery,
the existence of
these mirror neurons.
Is there a cure?
Not yet, but there are
coping strategies
we can teach her to help her
manage her condition.
I'm sorry.
I have to get this.
Yeah.
I cannot believe
this woman.
How's that old saying go?
"You can lead
a horse to water,
"but you can't make it gaze
at its own reflection."
Page me
when he's all set.
Yes, Doctor.
Oh, excuse me.
Dr. Rhodes? Looks like
I'm filling in for
Beth today.
Uh-huh.
I understand
there's some confusion
about where we're
supposed to be standing?
Uh, yeah.
Let me get back
to you on that.
Beth.
Forget it.
No, please, please.
I'm not changing my mind.
No, no, no.
Just one second
of your time.
Look, I am not gonna try
and defend
Dr. Latham's behavior.
He flung a tray
past my head.
Not the first time,
by the way.
But he is the guy
that's gotta try to save
that patient's life,
and while you and I
both know that he would
never admit it out loud,
he relies on you.
I mean, come on,
we rely on each other.
We're a team.
Someone should
tell him that.
He treats us like dirt.
Yeah.
But I do know this
about Dr. Latham,
he always has the patient's
best interests at heart,
and we should, too.
Really?
Dr. Rhodes,
my office, please.
Yes, sir.
Close the door.
Dr. Latham, I'm not sure
how much of that
you heard back there.
I believe most of it.
If I said anything
that may have
offended you, I'm sorry.
I was only trying...
There's something
I should share
with you.
I have been recently
diagnosed with an autism
spectrum disorder.
Asperger's.
Okay.
I'm not revealing this
to elicit sympathy
from you
or as a means to
justify my behavior.
I simply feel it might be
beneficial for you to know.
I think it might be.
I am unable to discern
whether you're being
sarcastic or not.
That's part of
the disorder.
It also makes it difficult
for me to improvise
from my set routine.
I confess, I...
I'm uneasy about the surgery
we're about to perform.
Can I rely on you to
help me through it?
Tell me there was
no brown in there.
You're right.
How's our
human shield doing?
Just finished
washing it out now.
That's what I get
for trusting a squid
with a firearm.
Hah.
Thank you, both. Really.
Ms. Goodwin?
If you have a second?
The fungal infection
is quite advanced.
Okay, Mr. Mikulski's
on his way up to the OR,
and at this stage,
he's not gonna survive this.
There's nothing
we could have done.
It was a bad, bad break.
I don't see how we can use
any of the footage we shot.
I disagree.
We couldn't have gotten
a better endorsement
for you or the hospital.
His endorsement
is meaningless.
He just said what he thought
we wanted to hear.
Not to mention,
we're exploiting him.
Exploiting?
He signed the release.
What are we arguing about?
He only did it
'cause I convinced him to.
I'm not sure he really
wanted to sign the release.
All right, let's...
Let's give
the patient a chance
to rescind the release.
What? Why?
Because it's
the right thing to do.
Thank you, Ms. Goodwin.
Dr. Halstead.
You convinced him
to sign the release,
yet you led me to believe
you objected to all of this.
I felt I needed some ammo
when I told Stohl I was
ordering the scans.
A-ha.
So, in other words,
you used the release
to get your way?
No, no, no.
Go talk to your patient,
and we'll talk about
your actions later.
Last thing
is to anastamose
the right coronary.
The right coronary...
I have an angle
to get you
a better position,
if you don't mind,
Dr. Latham?
No, please, go ahead.
Mmm.
It doesn't appear
as though it's gonna be
long enough to fit,
unless you're seeing
something different?
Let's get some
blood in there to see
how the vessel lays
when the heart's inflated.
Clamp your venus, Paul.
Give us some volume.
Yes, sir.
Looks like it'll fit.
Good.
Let's empty out
the heart and finish up.
6.0 Prolene?
Thank you, Beth.
There you go.
I like it.
Oh, hey, Dr. Halstead.
Thanks for coming up.
How do I look?
Where's that camera guy?
Hey, listen. About that...
I'm sorry.
This promo video
has been a huge violation
in your privacy.
I know you were hesitant
to sign the release, so...
You rip that up if you want,
and we will not use
any of the footage.
Let me ask you a question,
Dr. Halstead.
Do I look familiar to you?
I mean, from before today?
I don't think so. Why?
I recognize you.
You sometimes park
in that lot
across the street.
I work there
as an attendant.
Almost 20 years now.
Sorry, I never
really paid attention.
Oh, no, that's okay.
I don't make much
of an impression.
I've had more than enough
privacy for one person.
So I'm okay having that
violated now
if it means I wasn't
invisible to the very end.
I just want my life to
have meant something.
Dr. Halstead?
Are you ready, Mr. Mikulski?
Yes, I am.
Okay.
Hey.
I heard what happened.
Are you okay?
This?
Might leave a scar,
but that's it.
Well, at least you'll have
a good story to tell, right?
I don't think
anybody will believe
this one.
Okay, see you.
Yeah, see you.
It's a cylinder.
It's shiny.
Sorry to interrupt.
Not at all.
We're just, uh...
We're just doing
a visualization exercise.
Again. Close your
eyes again, Ariel.
And do you see
your shield?
Okay. Now keep
describing it to me.
It's gold.
It surrounds me.
It protects me
from other people's pain
and emotions.
Okay, keep seeing
your shield.
Now open your eyes.
What happens
when I do this?
It feels like you're
touching my arm still.
The shield's not working.
Visualization, it's a skill.
It takes practice.
And just so you know,
when I visualize my shield,
and be warned,
'cause I'm a total geek
about this...
Hey, come on, now.
You're not allowed to
get down on yourself.
This is our very first
run at this.
You're doing great.
It's not that.
I just got really sad.
Don't know why.
Will you excuse me?
Okay,
let's try it again.
Close your eyes.
Hey, Dr. Latham.
A bunch of us are going
for drinks over at Molly's.
Maybe you want to join us?
I don't go to bars.
Maybe another time, then.
I hear they're gonna
transfer you
to the hospital
at the county jail.
I don't believe that story
you told earlier.
I know you thought
it's what your father
wanted to hear,
but it would be
a shame to go to jail
for something you didn't do.
I'm not afraid
of going to jail.
That secret
you're holding on to
just put a hole
in your gut.
If you don't open up,
imagine what might happen
next time.
All you have to do is call,
and we can keep talking.
You don't understand
anything, do you?
You want me to talk?
Open up?
And say what?
That I'm some kind of freak?
I'd rather go to jail.
Forever.
She can really feel the pain
of everyone she sees?
Yes.
Oh, God.
I can't imagine
how hard
this has been for her.
I took her to
every specialist.
I did what the doctors
told me to.
I thought she was faking.
There's no way
you could've known.
I am hurting
my own daughter.
How am I supposed to
protect her from this if
I'm part of the problem?
It won't be easy.
But she feels
what she sees.
If she sees a happy person,
she feels happiness.
And if she sees someone
who's constantly anxious...
You really don't know
anything, do you?
There you go, Bardi.
There you go.
Cheers, everybody.
Cheers!
Dr. Latham,
you changed your mind.
Not yet,
but I am working on it.
Come join us.