- Previously on The Resident...
- So I wanted to go out with you.
I don't date patients.
Romantic love is just a
trick the brain plays on you
- to get you to pump out babies.
- I was just like you.
Closed off. Until I
learned to use that emotion
- as fuel.
- You were born
to be a surgeon, Randolph.
But you're a damn good CEO.
I think Lane's committing
insurance fraud by
overtreating her patients.
- We have to do
something about Lane. Nic,
can we meet at the
clinic at 4:00 a.m.?
- I will get you Lily's files.
- They set me up.
- Where are you?
- Atlanta Detention Center.
The world at your feet.
Always imagined
myself in a place like this,
with a man like you.
It just feels so... right.
You know, I sold my
house in Buckhead at a loss.
In debt. I was floundering.
And then you encouraged
me to go after that CEO job,
and I got it.
You're my good luck charm.
♪ Hey ♪
♪ They said it didn't
recede, so it all points ♪
♪ Back to you... ♪
I see the greatness
in you, Randolph.
Always have.
♪ Oh, ah ♪
♪ It all points back to you... ♪
I don't know who
you're looking for.
Her name is Nicolette Nevin;
I've been trying to find her
for 36 hours, but
there is no one...
Arraignments are in room 304.
She's already been arraigned.
I just want to get
her out of here.
Bail hearings will
be in a few hours.
- A few hours?
- She broke the law.
What do you think, it's like
paying for a parking ticket?
She's a nurse.
All she's ever
done is help people.
Who cares?
How do I get to see her?
Wait till they call you.
Wow. Wow.
We should not have done that.
- I think we could go again.
- Micah,
you're a heart
transplant patient.
You've only just been
cleared for sexual activity.
So you're saying
you can't keep up?
I'm saying we
have to be careful.
Come back.
I have to get to work.
I need coffee.
Even waking up together
was not what I had planned.
You may not realize
this yet, but we're a thing.
- We're not a thing.
- Oh, yeah.
Last night, and then
again this morning.
I think that's a thing.
You think I'm someone I'm not.
You have to understand, if
I love anything, it's my work.
I'm not built for romance.
This was sex.
Nothing more.
I don't even know how
you like to take your coffee.
Milk?
Cream?
Sugar?
Micah.
Did you hear me?
♪ ♪
Yeah, you got to work that.
That's what I'm talking about.
What?
- Hey.
- Are you all right?
Allie finally agreed
to give me the records.
So I went to meet her at
the clinic, but it was a setup.
Have charges been filed?
Breaking and entering.
A felony.
If I'm convicted,
I'll lose my license.
- I'll never work
as a nurse again.
- That's not gonna happen.
What was I supposed to do?
We both know Lane killed Lily.
What about her other patients?
We still have to do something.
I'm gonna find the money
for bail, and I'm gonna
get you out of here.
28-year-old male,
status: post-heart
transplant hypotensive,
with labored breathing
and a weak pulse.
Micah? It's going to be okay.
Hey, Micah, stay with me.
Get us up to speed.
It's Micah. Sudden collapse,
shortness of breath,
thready pulse.
Possible cardiogenic shock?
Trauma Two.
Mina, what are you doing here?
What's his BP?
80/40 in the ambulance.
Micah, can you hear me?
How long have you
been short of breath?
- More than a day?
- On three, two...
- Any chest pain?
- It started this morning.
- After...
- Exertion.
He needs inotropic support.
Start a dobutamine drip
at two and a half mics.
And add dopamine
for blood pressure support;
he needs a blood gas.
- I'll do it.
- Getting an EKG.
- We should add milrinone.
- Do it.
Start it peripherally,
and I'll add a central
line in the CCU.
Micah, we need your
heart beating stronger.
The drugs we're
giving you should help.
Could his body be
rejecting the heart?
Always possible.
Infection of the heart muscle?
- Myocarditis?
- We won't know
until we run more tests.
BP's 110/70.
He's tachy,
but no ST elevations
to suggest an infarction.
Get him to the cardiac ICU.
I will see you there.
You okay?
Just worried about him.
Like you are.
Sure it's not more than that?
I'm sure.
I'm due in surgery.
I'll keep you posted.
I got to be there!
You can't stop it!
You...
All right, breathe.
What's going on?
Elias Everett, 47,
kidney failure,
post-hemodialysis.
He's delirious,
ataxic and aggressive.
How long has this been going on?
He has been worsening
progressively for three days.
Tests were inconclusive.
Follow my finger.
Follow my finger...
Right eye's fixed.
Ophthalmoplegia,
ataxia, confusion.
All signs of Wernicke's
encephalopathy.
The dialysis is causing him
to lose water-soluble vitamins.
He has acute
thiamine deficiency.
Give him 500
milligrams of thiamine
three times a day for two days.
A few weeks, he'll be fine.
How the hell does he do that?
It's infuriating.
Hang a thiamine drip, stat.
Hello?
This is the Georgia Department
of Corrections.
You have a collect call from...
Nic Nevin.
To accept this call, press one.
Nic?
A lawyer from Lane's
clinic must have called
the prosecutions' office.
They're calling
me a flight risk.
Conrad, the judge
set bail at $100,000.
For a first offense?
That's insane.
Okay, don't panic.
What do you mean, don't
panic? What am I gonna do?
I told you, I will
get you out today.
You can't promise that.
I'll see you in a few hours.
What are you gonna
do, rob a bank?
Kind of.
Stay safe.
Conrad?
It's an emergency.
I-I need your help.
Well, tell me what it
is, and I'll have it fixed.
- How we doing?
- You tell me.
He's not saying anything.
He's making me nervous.
Well, you look a damn sight
better than you did an hour ago.
This is just like a bump in
the road, right, Dr. Hawkins?
I was due some blowback
from that transplant.
I'll be right back.
I'll find out what's happening.
Okay.
Images from the echo.
What's this here, where
the heart's attached
- to the aorta?
- Aortic root dissection.
A complication of the
original transplant procedure.
Exertion caused a-a
rise in blood pressure,
which worsened a small tear.
So, surgery.
We repair the aortic
root before it worsens.
We try to avoid operating
on a transplanted heart.
Sometimes it
doesn't start again.
But it's possible.
It's been done.
Yes, but the mortality rates
from this type of surgery
are extremely high.
It's likely to kill him.
Obviously, this
is very bad news,
but... I don't accept it.
Excuse us.
Dr. Okafor?
I'll tell Micah.
What will you tell him?
He has no chance?
He's gonna die soon?
In the OR, or at home?
You're too emotionally involved.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Uh, Mina, okay,
whatever you say, I just,
I think you should take a
step back, let me do my job.
Let me do mine.
Dr. Peterson isn't a surgeon.
Before you take all hope away,
let me get a
cardiothoracic consult.
Fair enough. I just don't think
you'll like what they tell you.
Nicolette Nevin's
bail has been paid.
They'll release
her within the hour.
I told you, all I needed
was ten percent
to pay the bail bondsman.
This was cleaner and faster.
Money makes problems
disappear in our legal system.
It's not a level playing field.
It's just like medicine.
Obviously, I'm grateful.
You're my son.
I'd do anything for you.
This is a...
new beginning between us.
And I have a plan in the works
for our future.
So, Mina and Micah.
That's a shock, huh?
Is it possible that
she's in love with him?
In love? Are you joking?
Mina doesn't do relationships.
She's just getting laid.
The sex must have been amazing.
It did give him a heart attack.
It's the way I'd want to go out.
Death by coitus.
Preferably with Mina.
Oh.
No. Olivia. Long time no see.
I feel like it's only
been a couple weeks.
- Eight days, actually.
- Olivia.
- Yes?
- You're not sick.
I most definitely
am very seriously ill.
The disease you
have is hypochondria!
I can arrange a
psych appointment.
I have a rash
- and a persistent cough.
- Okay.
- I...
- Just come here.
It's all good.
I will check her out.
Give me the chart.
- All good.
- Thank you. My hero.
Okay. Lay it on me.
I have rat-bite fever.
Have you been in close
proximity to rodents?
I hear them in the
wall sometimes.
Okay, it's called
rat-bite fever.
The operative word is "fever."
Your temperature is normal.
Can it be hantavirus?
Again, you would have a fever.
Leptospirosis?
Leptospirosis is contracted
by swimming in water
in which animals
have recently urinated.
Have you been
river rafting in Kenya?
Well, I read online
that there was a
factory worker in Arizona
who got it when he drank from a
rat-urine contaminated soda can.
Did you drink
from a contaminated soda
can in a factory in Arizona?
There's one more possibility.
Can this rash be
caused by lymphoma?
Because I just had
my first round of chemo.
Chemo? You had chemo?
Mm-hmm.
Who diagnosed you with lymphoma?
Dr. Lane Hunter.
Hey. Conrad... where is he?
Over there.
Hey, Conrad. Look at this.
Nevin, Nicollete. Let's go.
- Where to?
- Just hurry up.
Come on, come on, come on.
Your boyfriend
said you're a nurse.
He's not my boyfriend.
Well, maybe he is.
I saw him.
Nice problem you got there.
Let's go.
Name's Jenny.
She's been like that
for the last 30 minutes.
Confused, can barely speak.
And when it started, she
got really light-headed.
She's not my girlfriend.
Well, maybe she is.
Sounds like low blood sugar.
Hypoglycemia.
Are you diabetic, Jenny?
Are you taking any
new medication?
Antibiotics.
A sinus infection.
SMX-TMP. It's a sulfa drug.
Sulfa drugs can
sometimes make the body
produce too much insulin.
It's rare, but it happens.
You need glucose.
Do you have anything
sugary? Any candy?
- I have orange juice.
- Perfect.
You're gonna be fine.
You just have to get
your prescription changed
and then maybe go see a doctor.
It could be a kidney issue.
That should help.
Thank you.
What she said.
Oh, and you're free to go.
- What?
- You made bail.
Let's get you your clothes
and get you out of here.
Extremely high risk.
As in "bleed out, die
on the table" high risk.
Even if you manage
to get in safely,
the scar tissue makes
it hard to see the heart.
At that point, odds are you
could cut the wrong vessel.
Only someone with
a God-given talent
and an ego the size
of Texas would try it.
Well, well, well.
What do we have here?
You're not, uh, looking
to have lunch, are you?
Because I don't believe
crow is on the menu.
Don't fret, princess.
I can save your patient.
You know about Micah Stevens?
Whole hospital is
talking about him.
Apparently, the brother
has quite a fan base.
I spoke to three top
cardiothoracic surgeons
and they all say
operating on Micah
is likely to kill him.
Yeah, well, you spoke to hacks.
I wouldn't trust
them to cut cheese.
Micah is a gentle, decent man,
a great teacher
who loves his kids.
He has more integrity
in his little finger...
Blah, blah, blah,
spare me. Whatever.
I don't care that
he's Mother Teresa.
I think it's an interesting
case and I'll take it.
Micah's not a
science experiment.
If you don't believe
he has a chance...
Well, his odds do suck,
but in my hands,
they're not zero.
Besides that, I can't
give you a number.
I mean, we're all guessing
every time we scrub in, right?
I mean, there's always
art balanced with science.
And fortunately, I
happen to be Rembrandt.
Kill me now.
You know what I like
about you, Okafor?
You're arrogant, just like me.
What I don't like about
you is you're not me.
We'll schedule for
surgery if Micah agrees.
He already has.
Let me guess.
You're all-in because if he dies
within a year of his surgery,
it's a black mark on
Chastain's transplant program.
And without surgery,
that baby is going to blow.
I looked at the imaging.
It's sooner rather than later.
So, let's give Micah a chance.
And Chastain.
That's what you wanted, right?
Rembrandt, baby.
- Nic, hi.
- Hey, Jess.
What are you doing here?
Are they letting you come back?
Nic. We've been
jonesin' for you.
Hey, um, not yet.
Um, but look, where's Conrad?
- Nic.
- Oh, I...
- I'll see you later. Hey, Devon.
- Bye.
Hey, Nic.
How the hell did
you pull that off?
Later. This is more important.
What's going on?
Look at these labs.
Blood work from my
patient in the ER, Olivia Tan.
- Our frequent flier
hypochondriac?
- Yes. You see anything abnormal?
Nope. Perfectly
healthy, as usual.
Well, last week, Dr. Hunter
diagnosed Olivia with lymphoma.
And she just received
her first round of chemo.
She has no cancer
markers at all.
Lane's giving chemo to patients
who don't even have cancer.
Nic warned us that Dr. Hunter
was overdosing cancer patients
- with aggressive chemo.
- Which is Medicare fraud.
Tough to prove,
particularly since Dr. Hunter
keeps all of her patient
records at her clinics.
And Dr. Pravesh just discovered
that she's also been diagnosing
healthy patients with cancer,
which explains her
miraculous cures,
because some of her patients
were never sick to begin with.
Including Lily Kendall.
She had a form of cancer
that you can get from
aggressive chemo.
Look, th-this is absurd.
You're trying to tell me
Dr. Hunter gave
Lily Kendall cancer
and then killed
her to cover it up?
Lily was in the process of
getting a second opinion.
That oncologist would
have demanded her records.
Which would have shown
her original diagnosis.
Dr. Hunter consistently
refused to share them.
And Nic tried to get her
records after Lily died
and Dr. Hunter set her
up and had her arrested.
You're accusing Dr. Hunter
of cold-blooded murder,
one of the best
doctors in the hospital.
Wouldn't believe
that in a million years.
It's not necessary that you
believe us because we've already
contacted the FBI
and they're getting a warrant
to seize Lane's records.
The truth is gonna
come out, Dr. Bell.
You called the FBI?
Without telling me?
It's required by law,
considering what
Dr. Pravesh discovered.
We're here to make
sure you remove
all of Dr. Hunter's
patients from her care.
And if you don't,
moving forward,
both you and
Chastain will be liable.
Okay, well, this...
It's shocking.
And I don't know
what to believe.
But I will suspend
Dr. Hunter's privileges,
pending a full investigation.
And I would ask you
not to say anything.
This is her career
and Chastain's reputation
that is on the line.
These accusations will
have to be backed up
with hard evidence.
They will be.
You ready?
I'll be with you in
surgery all the way,
looking out for you.
I may not see you again.
Of course you will,
on the other side.
What other side? The
really, really far other side?
In recovery.
You can be honest with me, Mina.
I know a Hail Mary
pass when I see one.
Whatever happens,
I'm at peace with it.
Don't talk like that.
I've had one miracle...
My new heart.
If God gives me another miracle,
then this will be a great day.
If not,
His will be done.
I'm ahead already.
- My man, Harold.
- Hey.
Let's do this.
♪ ♪
We still on for dinner tonight?
Um, close the door.
- What's wrong?
- Um...
The FBI is getting a warrant
to search your offices.
The FBI?
Have you diagnosed healthy
patients with incurable cancer
in order to treat them?
What? No.
Why would you even
say such a thing?
'Cause there's a patient
in our ER right now
that you diagnosed
with lymphoma.
She doesn't have cancer.
Well...
I know, and you should, too,
that the difference between
a low white blood cell count
and actual leukemia
can be really small.
I mean, if an error was
made, or a judgment call...
How bad are the mistakes?
And how many
others like this one?
Is Chastain vulnerable?
I've told you over
and over again
that I'm on your side.
I have been there for you.
You've made terrible mistakes,
and I've helped you fight back.
Whose side are you on, Randolph?
I'm on your side.
Now, the FBI can't get a
warrant until tomorrow morning.
What are you thinking?
Go to your clinic
right now and...
get any records that
could be misconstrued,
and don't shred them,
'cause they can
be reconstructed.
And bring any files
you don't want found
back to my apartment.
And we'll-we'll burn them
in my fireplace, together.
You're protecting me.
I'm protecting us.
Quickly.
All right, please confirm
the name of the patient.
Micah Stevens, 11-22-85.
Attending physician, AJ Austin.
Procedure: aortic
root dissection repair.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
slow your roll, Beauregard.
I am not cutting anybody open
with the cast of
Deliverance assisting.
Where is Okafor?
Ah. Well, hello, Dolly.
Ah, I love that sound.
So sexy.
Median sternotomy.
We are cracking open the chest.
Stop. He has to go on pump.
If you go through the
bone and hit the heart,
the pump will save him.
You know, the
longer he's on bypass,
the more chance for poor
blood flow to the brain.
You want him to wake
up with pump head?
Nah, I say he
flies without a net
while I slice and dice.
And maybe hit his
heart and kill him.
Let's just make this
a smoother case.
Not tempt fate.
Fine.
We're goin' pump.
Hey.
Listen, Olivia, you
don't have cancer.
No, I-I have to have cancer.
It explains everything,
all my symptoms.
The stiff neck, I mean,
I'm pretty sure
that's meningitis.
You have been a victim
of a wide-ranging medical fraud.
I need you to expose
the doctor that did this.
There is a reporter here
right now tracking the story.
No, I ca-I can't.
You'll be famous.
Yeah, okay.
My name's Priya Nair.
I want to hear your story.
Finally.
- Be careful.
- Be quiet.
All right. Retract
dermis and rib cage.
Retractors.
There's too much scar tissue.
We can't crack open his chest.
All right. Then I will fix that.
Bovie cautery
and tissue forceps.
Thank you.
Please go slowly.
You can hit an
artery or the aorta...
Please contain your
emotions, Okafor.
I know what I'm doing.
Chest retractor.
Metz.
Heart is intact.
Don't sound so surprised.
Full flow on the pump.
And then we stop his ticker
and bring him closer to his maker.
News from the OR, guys.
They're through
the chest wall safely.
Isolating the heart and
preparing to operate.
Yes!
Dr. Okafor,
please clamp the aorta.
Starting cardioplegia.
Deader than a doornail.
That is, until I bring
Lazarus back to life.
Hmm.
Ah. Hello, trouble.
Meet the solution.
Get that to Pathology.
And then Dacron
graft to Okafor, ASAP.
Me?
Well, you're the
famous seamstress
of Chastain, aren't you?
I can't.
What do you mean you can't?
I just... can't.
Then what are you doing here?
Making sure you don't
behave like a madman
and risk Micah's life.
- Would you like me
to take over...
- No.
She's gonna do it.
You broke the
cardinal rule of the OR.
You are emotionally
involved with this patient.
Is that why you can't
operate, Dr. Okafor?
Or are you just
not up to the task?
Don't be mad.
UPS is hiring.
God, I hate you.
Ah, that's the first time
you've called me by my name.
Admit it:
you have feelings.
You care.
You can have passion, you
can love somebody, even.
It does not make
you less of a doctor.
No, in fact,
it makes you a better one.
You can help fix Micah
if you can harness that
passion to elevate your art,
because hear me out:
there is no great
art without passion.
Now chop-chop.
Lover boy does not have all day.
3-0 prolene.
♪ ♪
Slow the bypass flow.
Let's get this heart restarted.
Dr. Okafor, intermittent
cardiac massage
for circulation, por favor.
He's in V-fib.
Paddles, stat.
Continue massage.
Initial shock.
Ten joules.
Lidocaine's in.
Clear.
- He's still in V-fib.
- Another 20 joules.
No, no, no. This
is not happening.
Clear.
30 joules.
Okafor, clear.
We have sinus rhythm.
All right.
Well done.
If he wakes up.
♪ Take a hit, shoot me
down, shoot me down ♪
♪ I will never hit the
ground, hit the ground ♪
♪ Got to keep an eye on you ♪
♪ Patience is wearing thin ♪
♪ Paper-thin
promises broke again ♪
♪ What a sin ♪
♪ But it only feeds my energy ♪
♪ Smoke, fire,
it's all going up ♪
♪ Don't you know
I ain't afraid ♪
♪ To shed a little blood? ♪
♪ Smoke, fire ♪
♪ Flares are going up,
flares are going up ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Won't wave my white flag, no ♪
♪ This time, I won't let go ♪
♪ I'd rather die than
give up the fight ♪
♪ Give up the fight, give up
the fight, give up the fight ♪
♪ Won't wave my white flag, no ♪
♪ Oh, I won't go down slow ♪
♪ I'd rather die ♪
♪ Than give up the
fight, give up the fight ♪
♪ Give up the fight,
give up the fight ♪
♪ White flag never going up ♪
♪ Never going up ♪
♪ No, no... ♪
- FBI, Dr. Hunter.
- Oh!
I need you to put down
what you're carrying.
I-I think there's been
some kind of mistake.
I need you to put down
what you're carrying now.
Uh, all right. All
right, all right, fine.
- Slowly, slowly, please.
- Okay.
- There's some kind
of misunderstanding here.
- Put your hands
- on top of your head.
- Please, I am Dr. Lane Hunter.
- Hands on top of your head.
- I own this facility. What is this about?
- Put your hands on your head.
- Okay!
- All right, all right.
- Let's go.
- Collect the evidence, please.
- All right, listen.
My lawyers are gonna
have a field day with this.
- I need backup.
- What have I done?
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
- Hands up, ma'am.
- This is ridiculous.
- Ma'am.
- Spread your legs, please.
- What?
- Unbelievable.
- Ma'am, do you have any weapons
- on you?
- Of course not, I'm a physician.
Handcuffs?
♪ Flares are going up ♪
- Here we go.
- ♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh, won't wave
my white flag, no ♪
- ♪ Wave my white flag ♪
- ♪ This time, I won't let go ♪
- ♪ Won't let go ♪
- ♪ I'd rather die ♪
♪ Than give up the
fight, give up the fight ♪
♪ Give up the fight,
give up the fight ♪
♪ Whoa... ♪
All right.
♪ Whoa, whoa ♪
♪ Raise my white flag, no. ♪
Comes as a terrible
shock to the city of Atlanta.
So we are waiting right
now for CEO Dr. Bell
to make a statement...
I know, right?
Oh, here he is.
I'm Dr. Randolph Bell,
CEO of Chastain.
I have a prepared
statement to read.
Today, like much of Atlanta,
I am in a state of shock.
Our profession, the
medical profession,
has a sacred mission:
to heal, to save lives.
You know, we, uh...
We believed Dr. Lane Hunter
shared that mission.
And she fooled us all.
She stands accused
today of unspeakable crimes
that tear at the bond that
we work so hard to earn,
between patients and doctors.
But I must emphasize that
these crimes were
committed at her clinic,
not at Chastain Park Memorial,
which is why she eluded
detection for so long,
and we had no idea
what was happening.
But two of our heroic
young residents
and a very determined
nurse practitioner were the first
to see the warning signs,
and the moment they
brought it to my attention,
of course, I called the FBI.
Oh, well, that's amazing,
he's taking all the credit.
Is it true that you
personally helped
the FBI catch Dr. Hunter
as she was attempting
to destroy evidence?
Well, anyone with a conscience
would've done the same.
He's like a cat that
always lands on his feet.
Now, I'd encourage you to direct
the rest of your questions
to law enforcement.
Thank you very much.
I see he's off the vent.
They're going to do a head CT.
Well, we're all pulling for him.
And for you.
You see?
I told you I was right.
I knew we were a thing.
Yeah.
- There.
- Pancreatitis?
- I think so.
- Mrs. Arby, we're gonna
admit you just so we can
- run a few more tests, okay?
- I-I'm worried
about this place.
I saw the news.
A-Am I safe here?
You're absolutely
right to ask, Mrs. Arby.
You should always
keep a sharp lookout.
Because doctors,
they're like cops.
Some are heroes
here to save your life,
and others, you
need to be careful of.
Dr. Pravesh?
Rookie of the year. MVP.
He's one of the best.
But watch out for Dr. Feldman.
He's funny, right?
Very well.
♪ You don't know your time ♪
♪ Is something
that I need to have ♪
♪ Breaking all the rules ♪
♪ Because I've got
to have you bad ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Your time ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh... ♪
Conrad, it's...
I know, I know, I know.
It's still complicated.
It's just I...
I don't know where we're going.
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
I don't know where I'm going.
I mean, can I even stay
here with Bell in charge?
We are all asking
ourselves the same question.
But the patients need us.
♪ Your time ♪
I'm glad you're back.
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Your time ♪
♪ You don't know your time ♪
♪ Is something
that I need to have ♪
♪ I'm breaking all the rules ♪
♪ Because I've got
to have you bad ♪
♪ And you became the reason... ♪
- See you around.
♪ Oh, oh, oh, your time ♪
Nurse Nevin, Mrs. Franklin
didn't finish her breakfast.
Hawkins, I have a woman
with a fever of unknown...
♪ Your time ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh. ♪
People say you saved
the hospital, Dr. Bell.
Well played. Bravo.
Making you CEO was the
smartest thing we ever did.
I want to introduce
you to your new boss.
Marshall Winthrop.
I think you know each other.
We've crossed paths.
Marshall is our new
chairman of the board.
McKEE: Marshall
holds a majority stake
in several huge corporations
that could boost
our bottom line.
You navigated a PR
nightmare very cleverly.
Congrats.
Now it's time to
put this hospital
on a firm financial footing.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH