They say lightning
never strikes twice,
but that's a myth.
And it was so scary,
seeing Derek lying on
the floor bleeding like that.
So scary.
It feels good just to,
you know, get that out,
you know?
Thank you.
I feel like I'm...
ready to go back to work.
It doesn't happen often.
Lightning usually gets
it right the first time.
OK, let's, uh...
talk more about that tomorrow.
Come on.
Do you need a tissue or...
a hug or something?
Go hug yourself.
When you're hit with
30,000 amps of electricity,
you feel it.
Morning.
It can make you
forget who you are.
Just... just...
stay calm. Breathe.
Take some deep breaths.
We're... we're just married.
And we're just gonna get
up and go to work like always.
I've got this under control.
Now... now you need to
eat this, a little multigrain,
and then we're just
gonna go to work.
Work is what you
need right now, OK?
We're gonna get a little
blood on those hands.
That'll feel good. OK?
Let's just get up, get naked,
get in the shower, have
a little morning soapy sex,
then I'm gonna wash your hair.
I've always wanted
to wash your hair.
It can burn you, blind
you, stop your heart...
Sounds big. I'm betting M.V.C.
Multiple M.V.C. or
an apartment fire.
When is the staring gonna stop?
As soon as the novelty
wears off. Just Ignore them.
Owen washed my hair.
And he told me to
eat this grainy nut bar.
And he booked me
into surgery this morning.
He is in charge of me. I'm
a bride, and I'm going with it.
- Trauma guy didn't clear you.
- Yeah, but he said
he'll figure that out.
Yes. OK, I am the crazy one.
I am the one who freaks
out and screams at people...
like that.
Go gawk at each
other for a while.
Are you OK?
Would everybody please just
stop asking if I am OK? OK?
And cause massive
internal injuries.
He clear you yet?
- No? Still?
- I resorted to tears.
I wore bad mascara so
he wouldn't miss them.
- What... what did Derek say?
- Oh, I will be
avoiding him today.
So you don't have to talk
to him about the baby thing?
No.
Oh. Because you
left him in the pokey.
Yeah.
But for something that
happens in only a millisecond...
Did you feel different?
You know, after you
scribbled on the Post-it?
I mean, you're supposed
to feel different, right?
- Well, it takes time. Give it some time.
- OK.
I mean, your marriage is
filled with secrets and felons.
I mean, why am I
asking your advice?
It can change your life forever.
Dr. Shepherd, the
chief is looking for you.
I know.
- You missed the
wedding last night.
- I know.
- You smell like pee.
How was the wedding?
It was fine. I'm
sorry you missed it.
Yeah, well, I was busy
getting an incarceration record.
Do you know what that means?
It means you drive
too fast. Oh, God.
- Derek, you smell like...
- Yeah, I know
what I smell like.
I have go to the pit.
- They cleared you for surgery?
- No, but I can
still do consults.
So sorry. Bye.
We're not done
talking about this.
- - Oh, God. All
right. Did a bus crash?
OK, I'm not
saying rip out walls.
I'm saying throw
some paint up on 'em.
You know, soften it up. Yang
decorated the place for her,
and it's just a little
harsh and frowny.
Oh, OK. I'm gonna
stop you right there,
'cause Yang doesn't decorate.
I decorated that place.
It's my frowny place.
I meant modern and edgy.
If it's gonna be our place,
I just need it to be
a little more smiley.
Ugh. My God.
I... Frowny?
Edgy.
W... watch it!
Sorry.
Karev?
Dr. Bailey?
You still have that
bullet in your chest?
Uh, oh, yeah. It worked
its way to the surface.
It's fine. We leave bullets
in people all the time.
- It must hurt. Does it hurt?
- Uh, nope.
- Does it hurt
when I do this?
- Ow! Damn!
It is not fine.
It is foreign, and it has no
business being in your body.
Get it out, Karev, or I'll see
to it that you won't operate
until you're operated on.
Andrew Perkins
hasn't signed off on her.
You disagree with him?
No. Keeping residents out
of the O.R. until they're ready
is the right approach for most
of them, but not for Cristina.
She won't feel like herself
until she's back in surgery again.
- You know Yang.
- I do.
And you want to start her on
an ex vivo heart reconstruction?
This is a once-in-a-lifetime...
It is a hell of a
lot of pressure
- is what it is.
- Well, she operated on...
I mean, she saved Derek
Shepherd with a gun to her head.
I don't think that pressure
is the issue for her.
We owe her this,
Richard, and she needs it.
Put her back in the game.
Linda Cotler, age 51,
has been here three
times in the last eight years
for removal of malignant
myxomas from her heart.
But we won't be
doing that again.
No, by removing both atria,
and hopefully all
the cancerous cells,
you won't have to
keep coming back here.
Hello, Dr. Yang. Nice
to see a familiar face.
Finally, someone we know.
Mrs. Cotler was a
patient of Dr. Burke's.
You assisted on her
last myxoma removal.
Of course. Of course. Hi.
- You were getting
married, weren't you?
- Sorry?
Well, got married. I
mean, last night, actually.
You and Dr. Burke?
- Sorry?
- - Last time we were here,
- he said you two
were getting married.
- Oh, yes.
No. That... that didn't happen.
Oh.
What a shame. He went
on and on about you.
But you did get married?
We did, last night. Yes, we did.
Oh.
Well, nice to see you again.
Well, uh, sit tight,
and we'll be back in with
some forms for you to sign,
and then we'll take you up.
Thanks, Dr. Altman, and
congratulations to you two.
Thank you.
OK, multiple burn victims.
Two with paralysis,
three with vision loss,
one, uh, blown eardrums,
and one dislocated hip.
House fire?
- Explosion?
- Car wreck?
- Uh, act of God.
- Act of God?
- Yeah, lightning strike.
- All that from one
lightning strike?
One lightning
strike, eight victims.
Took out a whole
flag football team.
God was in a mood today.
How did it strike all of 'em?
Well, they're
mostly flash burns,
so it probably hit one of them
then conducted
off onto the rest.
Lexie.
T.M. rupture, trauma one.
I'll see you in there.
Tell me something.
When a person gets
out of the nut house...
what's the appropriate amount of
time to wait before you propose?
What? Long.
Longer. Long... A long time.
Not now.
Specifically, how long?
Have you seen my friend Kerry?
She's... she's a girl.
Sh... she's the only girl.
- Whoa. Whoa.
- You've just got
some ferning here.
It's superficial. It's where
the electrons entered the skin.
Well, what about my arm?
I still can't feel my arm.
- Sit forward.
- Hi.
Uh, hi. You changed.
Yeah, and showered,
twice, thanks to you.
- This is Russ.
- Uh-huh.
He was struck by lightning
while playing flag football,
and he's complaining of
paralysis in his left arm.
Can you move
your fingers for me?
Yeah, see, I couldn't do
that when I first got here.
It's probably just
transitory paralysis,
- which is common with lightning
strikes. Can you feel that?
- Little bit, yeah.
We're gonna keep watching you,
but your arm should come back
to normal in a couple of hours.
You know they almost
revoked my driver's license?
Can somebody please
check on Kerry for me?
- Happy to. Right away.
- Hey, we're still not done
talking about this.
Mm.
OK, wiggle your toes for me.
I still can't. Am I gonna
be in a wheelchair?
We're gonna take
you in for a C.T.,
but hopefully, it is just
temporary, from the lightning.
Couple of your
friends have it, too.
- They're already starting
to get some feeling back.
- OK.
- Try not to worry.
- Hey, Kerry. A friend
of yours, Russ Gammie,
is asking about you.
How's Warren Griffith? Is
he OK? Did he ask about me?
- Which one is Warren?
- Excuse me. Excuse me. I...
- Who's this,
Russ or Warren?
- Mitch?
Mitch now?
Hey, have you seen
Warren? Is he OK?
Kerry, I gotta say this.
We both could've died out there.
That lightning bolt was
like a one-in-a-million shot,
so I gotta take one, too.
I love you, Kerry, and
if we get through this,
I want you to know,
I will love you forever.
What?
Wh...
Sir, I'm sorry. If you're
not being treated,
then you're gonna have
to go to the waiting room.
- We'll... we'll keep you posted.
- Kerry, can you hear me?
Yeah, I can hear you fine.
I just didn't want him
to know that I heard that.
You're a popular girl.
No. I'm sure he's
just overexcited.
It is like a
one-in-a-million thing.
Actually, it's more like a
1-in-6,250 kind of thing.
Lightning kills between
150 to 300 people every year
- in the U.S. alone.
- Lexie.
Well, no, I mean,
it's... it's still rare.
I mean, it's not, like,
say, handgun death.
- I mean, that's... that's 1 in 325.
- Lexie.
You OK?
Yeah. No, I'm saying...
I'm saying she's lucky.
That's... You
know, hey, yay, you.
Can someone just please
check on Warren for me?
- I need to know if he's OK.
- Is Warren your boyfriend?
No. He's...
No.
OK.
Well, you've got
two burst eardrums,
- but they will
heal themselves, too.
- Great. Thank you.
Does that mean there's
no surgery? Can I go?
'Cause Dr. Shepherd's here,
so he might have something.
Maybe you should stick with me.
Kerry will need a workup.
I'm sorry. Why is this better
than what Dr. Burke did?
Dr. Burke's approach was
conservative and correct
for the first few surgeries.
This is radical
and risky, but...
Well, it sounds like
it's gonna kill her.
Linda's heart wall has grown
weaker with every surgery,
so there are greater
odds of cardiac rupture.
This may be her last chance.
Paul... Honey, every two years,
we come here, they cut me open,
and I watch it take ten
years off of your life.
I can't do it anymore.
And neither can you.
What about you?
Do you think this
is the best idea?
Oh, I'm not, um...
Because what you
and Dr. Burke did,
it's kept her with me so far.
If this was your husband,
would you let Dr. Altman
tear apart his heart?
Yes.
An aggressive approach
is your only option.
This is what you want.
OK.
All right.
We'll see you in there.
Mm.
Oh. What are these?
Choices.
They're all beige.
No, they're all subtle.
Look, pastels and earth tones.
If you look closely, that's
blue, that's green, that's yellow...
to take the edge off all
the chrome and concrete.
- What do you think?
- I think I don't want to live
in an Easter basket.
I know. You really want
to live in the Batcave.
- But meet me halfway.
- Uh, yes.
Schultz, Kerry? Yes, thank you.
OK, uh, my patient's
scans are up.
And, uh, seriously...
they're all beige to me.
W... well, then it shouldn't
be hard to pick one.
I'm looking for Warren Griffith.
That's me.
Oh. I feel kind of queasy.
You've got a little
fever. That may be why.
You got hit the hardest.
Looks like it went
into your neck and
came out your foot.
And you're saying
it bounced off me
and hit everyone else? I
took out the whole team?
It's not like it's your fault.
It kinda feels that way. I
don't remember any of it.
How about my friend
Kerry? Is she OK?
She's wondering the
same thing about you.
She what? She asked about me?
Specifically?
Well, what did she say?
Are you people in junior high?
I almost told
her. I tried to. I...
- I'm gonna tell her.
- What are you talking about?
Kerry. I tried to tell her
I... I love her, but her...
- Her ears are
all messed up and...
- Ah!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. You gotta sit down.
- Where are you going?
- I gotta tell her. I get to tell her.
- Guys, look,
leave her alone. All right?
She coulda died out there.
And besides, she's, like, mine.
No, I've been working
up to this for a year.
No, no, no, you've gotta sit.
- She's mine, and I love her.
- I've been working up
to this for a year.
- You need to come back here and sit down!
- Popular girl.
Oh, my God. Thank you.
Yep, C.T. looks clear.
No damage to your spine.
Which means I can go?
It means you should observe her.
Whoa. Hey!
Guys, you can't be in here.
Everybody, shut up. Shut up.
OK, Warren. You talk.
Oh.
Kerry, I...
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
Page Bailey!
Warren, you have a perforation,
a hole, somewhere in your bowel.
- We're gonna have to take you
up to surgery.
- Tell Kerry I'm sorry.
- Tell her I'm sorry
I hit her with lightning.
- Hey, don't you worry.
No, she's just the sweetest,
funniest... She's just...
- Please make sure she's OK.
- OK. We will. We're gonna
take care of you now.
All right, who do I
have? Who's free?
- I'm free. I'm good. I'll go.
- He's my patient. I'll take him.
- Ow!
- Book an O.R. You can observe.
- I'm fine, and I'm free.
- Oh...
- B... What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Other Grey, are
you free to scrub in?
- Absolutely. I...
- I'm available,
'cause you haven't been
cleared for surgery, right?
April, if we're
gonna be friends,
- you have to stop doing that.
- Sorry. Habit.
- I'm standing right here.
- Kepner, go prep him.
- OK.
- I'll see you up there.
I'm fine.
Well, great. Then you
can keep an eye on Kerry.
I'll resect both atria
and build new ones out
of bovine pericardium.
And during reconstruction,
Dr. Hunt will stay with Linda,
using a human donor aorta
to prepare the vessels
for reimplantation.
And all of this in
just four hours?
We have to be fast. We all set?
Let's go.
All right. Prep her and
page me when she's ready.
Cristina.
Are you excited?
Yes, absolutely.
Good. Good.
The fear of going back in is
worse than actually doing it.
It's just getting back
on the horse is all it is.
This is one hell of
a honeymoon, right?
Incision looks great.
Hey, I hear you and
Torres are shacking up.
Uh, uh, yeah.
Do I sound more
excited than you?
No, no. I am. I am.
How's it going with the
hot, hot trauma counselor?
I have to say...
it's great.
The conversation never stops,
and I feel, um...
I don't know.
I feel good whenever I see him.
No heart murmur. Good girl.
What do you talk
about? What's he like?
He's, um... Well,
he likes to, uh...
I guess I... I mostly talk,
and he mostly listens.
He's... he's an
amazingly good listener.
Well, he should be. It's
what he gets paid for.
Yeah.
Warren?
You love Warren?
Warren's bald, Kerry.
I know that, Mitch.
You guys don't love me.
I'm a girl who's down
with flag football,
so you think you love me.
Plus, we got
struck by lightning,
so that's...
Nice. You made her cry.
Oh, crap. You know, sorry.
You know, Warren's a good guy.
He could probably get a
hairpiece or something and...
She's crying because
everything's changed.
OK? Lightning struck,
and everything changed.
You were her team.
She was one of you,
and... and now you're just...
you're looking
at her differently.
Um, no.
I'm crying because I'm
worried about Warren.
Oh.
Could you please
find out if he's OK?
- $550.
- "N"...
Really?
This is what I'm cleared to do.
- I'm cleared
to solve this puzzle.
- Buy an "I".
Don't buy a vowel, you idiot.
Scarlet Pimpernel.
How did you...
There was one "C" and an "M".
Have you talked to
Derek yet about the...
Today's not the day.
Right. He just
got out of the joint.
Let him ease back into society.
You ready?
- You up for this?
- Up for what?
Teddy's rebuilding
a woman's atrium
- out of a sack of cow meat.
- But you're not nervous at all?
You're lucky. I get to watch
an intestinal perf repair.
- Bailey won't let me operate
till I get this bullet out.
- I'll take it out.
- I'll cut it out right now.
- You sound like a junkie.
What the hell is a pimpernel?
Kerry wants to know
how Warren's doing.
Intestinal perf.
Going to surgery.
I'm never gonna operate again.
Everyone thinks I'm gonna
carve my initials into a patient.
I'll never operate again
because one man thinks I'm crazy.
Hey, guys, look
at this. Look at this.
A bystander's cell phone
captured the shocking end
to a flag football practice
in Lawton Park this morning.
- Oh!
- Oh! Oh, my...
- Ooh.
- We've got that
amazing footage,
plus all your news
traffic and weather,
- coming up after this.
- Oh, my God. She never
saw it coming.
No. No.
No, no, no.
50 says she back in the
cuckoo's nest by lunch.
Hey, how was your night in jail?
You shank someone
right off the bat?
You gotta let the other cons
know not to mess with you.
That's not funny.
They almost charged me
with reckless endangerment.
I'm sorry. What?
You mean that's where
you've been all morning,
- in jail for reckless
endangerment?
- Nobody was endangered.
I can't have this,
Derek. I won't. Now...
Have you ever been over
120 miles an hour before?
Richard, have you ever
been over 80? It's fun.
It's really fun. I mean,
especially when you go
through a corner like
that at that speed, and...
and you're not sure if the
rear end's gonna stick or not,
and you lose control, and
then you put the throttle down,
and the car
corrects a little bit,
and you take it to the limit
and you don't lose control,
- you just grab it. Have you ever done it?
- Uh, uh, no, Derek, no.
- You want to? I'll take you.
- You should. It's... really great.
Let's go right now.
Let's do it. Come on.
- I'd like that.
- Yeah? Right? Good. We're going. Oh.
- You need to help me. I need your help.
- Hey.
She's paralyzed, and
it's not gonna go away.
- She's not gonna get better.
- Lexie, hold on. You're all right.
No, not me. It's Kerry Schultz.
She got hit outta nowhere,
and it's not gonna
get any better.
I need you to listen to me.
Look, this has nothing
to do with that. She's...
No, just shut up and
please listen to me.
Make sure she's all right.
I'm trying.
120 miles an hour.
I'm glad you're back,
that we're gonna
be in there together.
It makes me a little
less freaked out
is what I'm saying.
Is this gonna become a thing...
you sharing all your
sad, scared feelings
because we almost
got shot together?
There it is.
Now I know you're back.
This boy got it bad. OK,
throw a stitch in there.
Suction.
Hmm.
Staph infection,
which causes cellulitis,
abscess, possibly MRSA,
which could lead
to sepsis and death.
- Uh, I'm sorry. Where are you
seeing all of this?
- In Dr. Karev's chest
if he doesn't have
that bullet removed.
I'll cross that bridge
when I come to it.
- Can I leave now?
- No, you can stand right there
to make sure you don't
get into anyone else's O.R.,
not until you're lead-free.
All right.
The heart is ready.
OK. Here we go.
Start the clock.
Dr. Yang...
take the heart, please.
Badass.
All right. Here we go.
Excising the right atrium.
Welcome back, Dr. Yang.
Thank you.
See?
You went down before
the lightning even struck.
Oh, my God. Warren. I
never even saw him coming.
- Is he OK?
- He's in surgery now.
Kerry, your new scan
shows an epidural hematoma.
It's blood in your spine that's
compressing your spinal cord.
- We didn't see that before?
- Probably too small to see,
and it's been
bleeding for hours.
- It's an easy procedure
to relieve the pressure.
- And I'll walk again?
You'll be out on the field
in no time. Book an O.R.
- I'll see you in there.
- F... for an actual surgery?
Yes.
Thank you.
Oh, so stupid.
All this time... I
never told him.
And I... I had all these
reasons, you know?
And... they seemed
like good reasons
until we all almost died.
I was worried about, what,
about shaking up the team?
It's flag football. We
play once a week.
God, I'm an idiot.
I thought you were in surgery.
Yeah, the guy pulled through.
Is Lexie OK?
Why don't you ask her yourself?
She doesn't need
me talking to her.
Well, you're the
one who ended it.
Yeah, it ended the
way it always ends.
I get close to the chick,
the chick goes crazy.
Rebecca and Izzie, my mom...
I'm a lightning
rod for this crap.
You're not that special.
Lexie's not crazy.
She had a crazy
thing happen to her,
and her reaction
was pretty normal.
And Izzie had brain cancer.
Rebecca... she was crazy,
but that was the facial
reconstruction trauma.
You're not a
lightning rod, Alex.
You're just a guy who's
been through a lot of crap.
I wish I had a
scalpel right now.
Junkie.
- Time, please.
- 2 hours and 42 minutes.
We're behind. Dr. Hunt,
where are you at?
- Putting in the aortic graft.
- This tissue is more
than I need.
Dr. Yang, trim this
pericardium, please.
3 centimeters.
OK.
- Avery, give me some
irrigation in here, please.
- Sure.
Sorry. Sorry.
All right. Are we all right?
It's all right. It's all right.
It was just a tray. The
aortic cannula is dislodged.
Avery, some suction
in here, please.
Hunt, talk to me.
I need a purse
string in the aorta.
Avery, get me some more
visualization in here, please.
- Get in there.
- Yang, come help me. Yang?
Cristina?
Cristina, talk to me.
Oh, damn it. Grab
the aortic cannula.
Hold it there.
Cristina, you are OK.
Can you get up?
Avery, I need that tissue now.
- Is it usable?
- No.
Aah! No! No!
Time, please.
- Time!
- 2 hours, 45.
All right, Avery, call
down to the pharmacy
and get another
piece of tissue, please.
No, don't call. Cristina,
you go. Go now and get one.
Run. Go.
Look, I'll just go. I got it.
The dura is pulsatile.
Good catch, Dr. Grey.
Thank you, and, um,
thank you for listening to me
and for not being afraid of me.
Nobody's afraid of you.
Mark's keeping me
chained to his service.
He's keeping me
out of surgeries.
He's afraid for
you, so he hovers.
Other people might lock
you in a cell overnight
to be urinated on
by a meth head.
But it all comes
from the same place.
Oh, you... you can't be in here.
But we're friends
now, so I'll just shut up.
Good girl.
Dr. Grey, you
shouldn't be in the O.R.
Cristina.
I can't be in here.
I can't.
OK, so let's go.
Let's get out of here.
I can't... I can't
feel anything.
I know. I know.
Come with me.
No, no. I... I can't move.
I can't move my legs.
I can't... I can't
feel anything.
Um...
Uh...
F... feel my hand. Take my hand.
Do you feel that?
Uh-uh-huh.
Uh-huh.
OK.
You're OK.
We're gonna go
when you're ready.
- OK?
- Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
So you tell me when
you're ready, OK?
OK. OK.
Is it over?
How is she?
Oh, I'm... I'm sorry.
No, no, no.
She's fine. Uh, the
doctors are still working,
and someone will be
out when they're finished.
You're wrong.
Sorry?
There's no time to wait.
People get struck by lightning.
People die.
My best friend got shot, Torres.
Why are you telling
me to give it time
when there's no guarantee
that time is gonna be there?
I'm... not gonna wait
around to be happy anymore.
All right. Listen, this is
something that you and I do.
We skip steps.
OK, I pushed Arizona
to have a baby,
and I almost lost her
because I skipped
a bunch of steps.
But then I went back,
and now she's moving in...
and ruining my apartment.
Look, I'm saying,
proposing might be too much,
- especially if she's
not herself right now.
- I know who she is,
and if she's going
through her worst right now,
I wanna go through it with her.
She makes me happier than...
anything I've ever known.
And if I can have a part in...
in making her happy again,
that's all I want to do.
That's all I want to do
for the rest of my life.
All right.
All right. Go.
Go. Tell her that.
But just like that.
Is she dead?
She's fine. She'll be fine.
Can you give us a minute?
Whew.
You were wrong.
You were wrong about everything.
I know. I'm sorry.
Hey, I heard about
Cristina. Is she all right?
No, she's not all
right. No one's all right.
And that idiot is clearing
everyone for surgery
like they're fine,
and they're not fine.
Stop. Stop. I
need to talk to you.
Just leave it alone, Derek.
It was one night in jail.
You drive too fast.
Just forget about it.
I don't want to talk about
that. Don't worry about that.
Don't worry about it? All
I do is worry all the time.
I spend every minute
of every day worrying
that I'm gonna get a phone call
that you've wrapped
your car around a pole.
That's why I left you jail,
so that just for a little while,
I would know that
you weren't dying
like you were
dying on that table.
That's what I think about
every time you pull
out of the driveway.
I'm right here. I'm OK.
We're OK.
I was pregnant...
that day.
I was pregnant, and I lost it.
I...
You didn't say anything.
- I coulda helped you.
- If you want to help me,
your driving is
something you can control.
Just do that. Just do that.
OK. OK.
What happened in the O.R.,
we couldn't have seen that.
I... I can't...
I can't do it.
You said I could do it.
I know. I know. I... I
thought you were ready.
You've never not been ready.
Cristina, I know
what you're feeling.
I don't feel anything.
I can't be in there.
And if I can't be in there,
I don't know where
I'm supposed to be.
You're supposed to
be here. You're my wife.
You can just be here.
I'm sorry.
You up for a visitor?
Kerry?
Oh, my God. Warren?
Are you OK?
Um, they... they told me
that I slammed you really
hard on the field and...
Oh, it's OK. Accidents
happen. It's... it's football.
I'm fine.
Well, they also
told me that I...
I got you all
struck by lightning.
- That's...
- I...
That's...
I just... I wanted
to say, I'm sorry.
I'm not.
I love you.
I've been in love
with you forever.
Dr. Grey, can you please
push me a little closer?
Lightning doesn't
often strike twice.
It's a once-in-a-lifetime thing.
Oh.
Even if it feels like the shock
is coming over and over again.
You paged me?
I did. I have a surgery.
- You're actually gonna let me
near a patient?
- You are the patient.
- Get in there and
get on that table.
- Oh...
I don't need a
reminder of this thing.
I'm gonna carry that
day around with me
every day for
the rest of my life
whether I want to or not.
Now they've plastered over
every bullet hole in this building.
I don't need a reminder
every time I look at you.
And I'm tired of bullying
you, so I am asking you,
please, get in there
and get your shirt off.
Yes, ma'am.
Eventually...
the pain will go away,
the shock will wear off...
Oh, hey. You ready to go?
I, uh, I pushed our reservation.
Do I talk too much?
I'm enjoying you and, and this.
And I feel good
when I'm with you,
but it occurs to me,
well, that's your job,
I mean, to come in here
and to listen to people talk
and to make them
feel good, and I just...
I want to be sure that I'm not
using you for that, you know,
and that I'm not
doing all the talking
and the... and the good feeling
and that I'm... I'm... I'm not
treating you like a... like a...
Well, like a... like a shrink...
'Cause I'm enjoying this.
Now you talk.
Um...
Well...
listening to you is not work.
I'm happy to talk, but I
have listened a lot today.
I talked a lot, too.
And so for now,
I'd like to say...
I'm enjoying this, too.
And, uh... maybe we can
both not talk for a while?
OK.
Yeah.
And you start
to heal yourself...
Oh.
Did you know that
Webber went over my head
and cleared Yang for your O.R.?
We... we really
don't have to... to talk.
- Come here.
- Yeah?
Yeah.
Lexie.
Did I forget to clean something?
No. I just need to talk to you.
No... you don't, though.
I know that you want to be here,
but you don't have to.
W... wait. I...
I went through a rough
patch, and you helped me,
and I appreciate that.
But I am moving out of
it, and you won't let me.
You know, you're treating
me like I am a basket case.
And... and... and
everyone is watching you,
and they're believing you.
I had a good day today.
I saved a girl
today. I did that.
I am a good doctor,
and I don't deserve
for people to think that I
am anything less than that.
So could you please
just leave me alone?
Can you do that? Can
you just leave me alone?
You got it.
To recover from something
you never saw coming.
Charles was a good guy.
He was funny.
Reed... well, she was
kind of messed up,
but she wasn't a bad person.
I just don't...
I don't know why...
I shouldn't just get to
walk away, you know?
I don't know why
we made it either.
We just have to find
a way to be grateful.
Son of a bitch.
Agreed.
Paint it beige.
You got a girl...
you love who loves you back.
Paint it whatever
stupid color she wants.
Mm.
But sometimes, the
odds are in your favor.
50 percent of
marriages end in divorce,
so between the two of us,
you and McDreamy should be fine.
I thought it would fix me.
That's not why he married you.
Well, he didn't marry
me. He married a corpse.
I'm dead inside.
I told Derek.
About the
miscarriage, I told him.
You got married, Cristina,
for better or for worse.
This is the worse part.
The thing is, there
will be better parts.
You should go back.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Cristina...
You don't feel nothing.
All right?
You didn't feel nothing today.
You felt scared.
You were terrified.
And you felt anger.
You were angry at me.
And after what
you've been through,
you're allowed, all right?
That's what you should
be feeling. I know.
Because when I was
there, I felt all those things,
and I... I took
it all out on you.
And you were patient,
and you were kind,
and you stayed through
it all because you love me.
You love me.
So, uh...
you can be scared with me,
or you can be pissed
with me or at me.
I don't care, 'cause I'm
gonna stay through it all.
I'm not going
anywhere, Cristina.
anywhere without you.
Let's go home.
I had already fixed
her before you came,
but... that was a nice speech.
If you're in just
the right place
at just the right time...
you can take a hell of a hit...
I lost a baby,
I almost lost my husband,
and my best friend
may never recover.
So I don't care what you do.
Clear me or don't clear me.
I have no control
over any of it.
I'm giving up.
Well...
that sounds like a good plan.
You're cleared for
surgery, Dr. Grey.
And still have a
shot at surviving.