Shaun?
Oh, hello, Dr. Glassman.
If you're here to
talk about our argument...
I am, kind of, in a way.
Working under Salen
was making me
into a bad doctor,
so I quit.
I'm creating a spreadsheet
of residency programs.
I have 12 metrics.
Well, Shaun,
that's a problem,
because there aren't
a lot of programs around
that are gonna
take a resident
at your level.
And also...
You're somewhat vulnerable
because of the ASD.
I've already quit.
We got a plan, Shaunie.
We are talking to
an investigative reporter
for a story on the damage that
Salen has done to St. Bon's.
It'll put pressure
on the Pension Fund
that's financing
the hospital takeover.
The deal doesn't close
for eight days.
We still have time
to stop it.
We think you should
apologize to Salen
and ask for
your job back.
Apologize.
Save your career.
She will not say yes.
Oh, she will say yes.
You're on the poster.
What's she gonna do,
drag you out of the hospital
kicking and screaming?
It'd be a PR disaster.
I have nothing
to apologize for.
She does.
We agree, but if
we pull this off,
it is only for eight days.
But what if you don't?
♪♪
If we don't,
then we rethink.
I will focus
on the medicine.
We've got a morale problem
at the hospital.
Maybe it's just
aftershocks from what
happened with the baby,
but I'm hearing
a lot of complaints.
Even the board's unhappy.
Which is why I plan to
replace them as soon
as the deal closes.
Well, good doctors
are a lot harder to replace
than board members.
Any employees we lose,
we'll find others
better aligned with Ethicure.
We've got a lot
of great people
at St. Bon's,
and I'd like to
make an effort
to keep them.
How's your morale?
I'm fine.
I know yesterday
was tough,
the tracheal transplant.
I hope you aren't
doubting yourself.
Shaun warned me.
I didn't listen.
You took a risk,
and your patient
is better off for that.
And now you and I
are gonna make this
the most successful hospital
in the Bay Area.
♪♪
No headaches,
dizziness?
No. I feel fine now.
Blurry vision?
Dr. Murphy,
why are you here?
I'm focusing
on the medicine.
I don't have any
patients of my own.
Probably because
you quit yesterday.
Have you spoken to Salen?
This says
you lost consciousness
while running
and hit your head.
Uh, yep.
And no.
No blurry vision.
You recently flew in
from London.
Perhaps your fatigue
or dehydration...
It was
three days post-flight,
and the liver function tests
are only slightly elevated
despite receiving
a donor liver
six months back.
It doesn't seem
transplant-related.
Well, it was a very
high-quality liver.
From an even
higher-quality person.
You're the donor?
Ry's been my best friend
since kindergarten.
I was about to die,
with my wife
seven months pregnant.
He immediately stepped up.
Total hero.
Definitely is.
We'll schedule a head CT
to look for damage
from your fall,
as well as any reason
why you fainted.
Great. I'm sure
it'll be fine.
Yeah.
If not, good news.
You get your liver back.
That's not how it works.
♪♪
What are you
doing here?
I work here.
That's not
what I took away
from our conversation
last night.
Last night,
I wanted to quit.
Today, I don't.
You need to leave.
Now.
♪♪
No.
It's not a suggestion.
Goodbye.
No.
♪♪
I am on the poster.
You will not
drag me out of the hospital
kicking and screaming.
It would be a PR disaster.
So I'm staying.
I have to go to work.
♪♪
When did
the bleeding start?
About an hour ago.
Any dizziness
or nausea?
None. I told her that some
spotting was normal.
This is my last
viable embryo.
I've had more miscarriages
than I can count.
I've done this
five times already.
The baby is... Is fine.
You all have
five kids at home?
You are experts.
No, we're not a couple.
I actually don't have
any children of my own.
Grace is my surrogate.
Is it typical for
surrogates and their clients
to hang out together?
She has become
more like family now.
That's a healthy heartbeat.
S-Something is wrong.
MRI abdomen and
transvaginal ultrasound.
♪♪
No intracranial bleed,
no tumor.
I assume you know
some of us are going public
against Ethicure.
Dr. Glassman
and Lea told me,
but they think I should
stay out of it.
What do you want to do?
Is it possible
to be sure
what the right thing is,
but it's also wrong
to act on it?
All too often.
♪♪
And whatever happens,
I know you're
on our side.
Scan seems to be clear.
Then why is he
having a seizure?
♪♪
Grace's scans
look normal.
No placenta accreta
or previa.
I love what she's doing,
carrying a child
for a woman who can't.
I'd love it more if Grace
wasn't getting paid for it.
She created five families.
Do you really have
a problem with that?
It's not just me.
Commercial surrogacy
is illegal
pretty much
everywhere but here.
It's exploitative.
Funny how everyone
gets real concerned
about exploitation
when it's women's bodies.
Meanwhile, football players
give themselves brain damage
every Sunday,
and it's glorified.
Point taken.
You know,
it's not too late
to change your mind
about this Salen stuff.
You should join us.
Speaking of men telling
women what to do...
Look at this.
♪♪
I've had
to send children
to community
transition care units
because of how
she's minimized
pediatric beds.
That's his testimony?
It's the start
of his testimony.
The plan being
to bore them
into submission?
My plan is to let them know
exactly what she's done
and how it's impacted
the greater community.
Oh, it's the pizza guy.
Infant fatality.
That's our plan.
Let's stick to that.
We can't prove that.
But what we do have
are doctors and nurses
and stories
of systemic neglect.
It's not the pizza guy.
Don't worry.
I tipped him.
I love your place.
Smart play.
That's what I'd do.
Yeah? What play is that?
Getting that
investigative reporter
to write a takedown piece
about me
and using that
to pressure the Pension Fund.
Dr. Wolke, Dr. Park,
it's time
for you two residents
to get back to work.
I'm not leaving.
Me neither.
Gutsy, coming from
a second-year
who already
killed a patient.
And you really ought to take
lessons from your girlfriend.
She knows
how to play the game.
Audrey, Lea, Aaron,
I'm sorry,
but I have to terminate
your employment immediately.
You were saying?
Go.
That your plan?
Make us look like disgruntled
former employees?
You think that's gonna stop us
from going public?
No, of course not.
But...I think
this research will.
Despite your generous salary,
you were a no-show for months,
making wine in your garage,
vacationing in Montana.
All after years of intervening
to excuse your protege
Dr. Murphy's erratic behavior.
You hired your boyfriend,
then fired him
once the relationship soured.
Classic sexual harassment.
That's not... H-He quit.
You secretly changed
hospital metrics
to help your fiance.
Right now,
you've only lost your jobs.
Go public,
and I release all this.
Cheat day.
♪♪
J.L., Hawks,
and Colson are out.
The reporter?
She'll still talk to us.
It's still a good story.
Just much shorter
than planned.
Was she right?
Are we wasting our time?
Probably.
The Pension Fund's annual
meeting is in two days, right?
Yeah.
We meet the reporter there.
Big public setting.
Denounce Salen
in front of the investors.
Create a viral moment.
That might do some damage.
♪♪
She could ruin me in tech.
I'm in.
You're threatening
to ruin their careers?
These are good doctors.
Who've decided to try to
interfere with my company.
You can't expect me
to just accept that.
I've backed you at every step
because I believe
a great hospital
could be profitable, too.
But blackmail
is unacceptable.
Think big picture.
We just lost the president
of the hospital.
You're running this place.
Short-term.
The future is wide open.
For both of us.
♪♪
Where's Dr. Lim?
She's no longer available.
But I'm
the Chief of Surgery
and will be personally
involved in your case.
Unfortunately,
your imaging is consistent
with a bladder sarcoma
abutting your uterus.
Cancer?
But we did surrogacy testing.
It's small right now,
but it will continue to grow
as the fetus does.
Oh, God.
And what can we do?
The safest option
is to terminate the pregnancy,
resect the tumor,
and begin chemotherapy.
Are there
any other options?
There are a number
of chemotherapy protocols
that are safe for
second trimester fetuses.
But they'll all be
far less effective
against the cancer
than surgery.
♪♪
I want to do the chemo.
Grace...
Are you sure?
Yes.
So...
I heard.
You're lucky
to still have a job.
Well, I'm not sure
if it's luck or you.
Salen suggested I learn
to play the game like you do.
She's right.
I didn't realize
being a doctor was a game.
Why are you obsessing
about this?
We have a meeting.
I'm sure all of you
have feelings
about what happened
with our colleagues.
Shaun,
if you want to talk...
Ryan has encephalitis.
Lea is okay.
I'm focusing on the medicine.
You said
his head CT was clean.
Our scan was interrupted
by his seizure.
I went back
and reviewed the images.
There appears
to be hypodensity
in the bilateral medial
temporal lobes.
Interesting.
Suggests HSV.
That's just artifact
from skull base.
It's not encephalitis.
Clean CT plus clean blood test
suggests a cardiac problem.
I'm with Dr. Park.
Place Ryan
on telemetry and...
You should trust me.
I told you not to
do that surgery yesterday.
I was right then,
and I am right now.
♪♪
No reason not to rule out
encephalitis, as well.
Start him on acyclovir
in addition to
the cardiac monitor.
♪♪
We could try Ifosfamide.
Lim and the others
are speaking out
at the annual
Pension Fund meeting
the day after tomorrow.
Please help me find
a chemo regimen for Grace.
Okay, Ifosfamide
can cause pre-term labor.
I'm gonna
go with Adriamycin.
speak out with them.
That's gonna blow up
your whole career.
Blow up your whole life.
Wouldn't be the first time.
Come with us.
You're great at sales.
Help us persuade
the Pension Fund.
Sometimes you got to stand up
for what's right.
What I do or do not
stand up for
is my choice,
and my friends
should respect that.
♪♪
What have you
come up with?
There are
a few options...
Grace is crashing.
♪♪
I'm going to test you
for encephalitis
and place you on telemetry
to check for heart problems.
Okay.
Is your neck
bothering you?
Y-Yeah. It just started
feeling a little weird.
Okay, can you take your gown
off your shoulders, please?
♪♪
W-What is that?
Not encephalitis
or a heart problem.
♪♪
You had a uterine
vessel rupture.
We were able to treat it,
but your cancer's progressing
quicker than we thought.
Our recommendation
is to terminate.
We'll remove the tumor
and reconstruct your bladder.
But you said
there was a chemotherapy
that was safe for the baby.
The rupture made
everything more serious.
You need surgery now,
or the cancer
might kill you.
If you don't want
to terminate,
there is an experimental
cystoscopic surgery.
It should be able to clear
almost all of the cancer.
W-What...
What are the risks
to the baby?
30% chance of miscarriage.
♪♪
Gracie.
It's okay.
You should terminate.
You should do the surgery
that gets rid of
all of the cancer.
♪♪
I'd like to do the chemo.
You realize you probably
won't survive.
♪♪
As long as the baby
reaches viability.
Gracie, honey, you don't
have to do this for me.
I'm not.
♪♪
I went through
some of your recent cases.
W-Why?
Because of what Salen said.
You know she likes me.
What's the problem
with her liking me?
Because of your
paranoid reaction.
I reacted because
it seemed like
you were reading something
into her comment.
Like you didn't trust me.
And now you're
going through my files?
Apparently,
I'm not paranoid.
Nira Joseph.
I didn't realize
"playing the game"
is shorthand for losing
your entire moral compass.
Nira is half-blind
because of you.
♪♪
She had a tumor...
There is no mention
in her file
of the procedure
that could have
saved her sight.
A procedure you thought
wasn't a viable idea.
I didn't tell you
to hide it.
You can't offer every patient
every experimental surgery...
Ah, especially not
when "we're" trying
to win control of the clinic.
It was the right choice
medically.
It was her choice.
♪♪
Ryan's rash
plus seizure and fainting
suggests an
autoimmune disorder.
Makes sense.
His ESR's elevated.
ESR's a nonspecific
inflammatory marker.
Wouldn't matter
if it was through the roof.
Dr. Park,
are you taking offense
at the diagnosis?
Salen fired our friends.
I didn't know about
that in advance,
didn't support it.
And do you
support it now?
It doesn't matter
what he supports.
He's not the CEO.
No, he's just her bagman.
Salen came into this hospital
because it was going bankrupt.
And now it's become
Salen's ATM machine.
That's an improvement?
You have been against her
from the moment she came in.
Just proven right.
You're not facing reality.
The takeover's happening.
Someone's got to keep
the hospital running.
You think
you're being realistic?
You're being complicit.
We should start Ryan
on corticosteroids
for the autoimmune...
Don't you see how
being her apologists
is corrupting you?
Dr. Park...
You took a woman's
vision away
to get your hands
on the clinic.
Not fair.
And you stand by her
after she kills a child.
Dr. Park, do you have
an alternative diagnosis?
No.
Start Ryan
on corticosteroids.
♪♪
I'm done.
I'll finish up
with my patients
and then submit
my resignation.
If I get
a job downtown,
this would be a good place
to meet for lunch.
They have great
French pancakes.
Kind of eggy, but...
I should join you.
Lea, I'm the poster boy.
It made Salen take me back.
It could make the difference.
It'll make a difference,
sure, but...
That's good enough.
You are so close to
finishing your residency.
One more year,
and you can go
wherever you want.
Dr. Glassman,
Park,
Lim, they've stood up
for me so many times.
You've stood up for me
so many times.
Now I want to stand up
for all of you.
♪♪
Okay.
Okay, can you make fun
of my beard or my eye bags
or anything? I hate this.
How many times did I say
I didn't want to get involved
in the Salen stuff?
But you still
kept pushing.
I wanted you on my side.
You act like
I'm scared of a fight.
I'm a Black woman
in one of the top surgical
residencies in the country.
Do you know how hard
I had to fight to be here?
I don't have
the same luxury as you do.
I'm not scared.
I'm exhausted.
♪♪
I never thought of it
that way.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
♪♪
And I think I know
who Grace is fighting for.
She said she didn't have
any children of her own.
♪♪
But you had to have
given birth before you
became a surrogate.
We know what happened
to Willem.
It wasn't your fault.
What kind of a mother
loses track of her baby
at a playground?
A 19-year-old.
Who's overwhelmed.
I wasn't overwhelmed.
I wasn't
paying attention.
I was arguing on the phone
with my boyfriend.
And I turned...
I turned my back.
The crash was so loud.
♪♪
So now,
I give babies to people
who actually deserve them.
Killing yourself
won't bring Willem back.
It'll let
another baby live.
You have value,
not just in the children
you carry.
I lost myself
when Willem died.
This is what
brought me back.
It is the only thing
that means anything to me.
You're being selfish.
This isn't just
about you.
It's also about Amanda,
your friend, who loves you.
I'm trying to help her...
No. You're not
listening to her.
She does not want the price
of her child to be your life.
You don't
have to terminate.
Just let us do
the cystoscopic surgery.
It could let
Amanda have her baby...
...and you in her life.
♪♪
Minute, please.
I'm sorry.
That was unnecessary.
I'm sorry
this is how it ended.
We're not done yet.
She'll destroy you.
Only if you let her.
You think I control Salen,
because we're dating?
That's insane
and a little sexist.
Forget control.
How about taking a stand?
That's what
I've been doing
and will continue to do
from the inside.
You could've worked with me
to make things right.
Instead, you had to
burn the building down.
She lit the match.
You know that.
I feel a little sick.
Could this be 'cause of
the, um, autoimmune thing?
That's unlikely.
Oh. Your eyes
are jaundiced.
Which means it is your liver.
I will need you
to do a full-body
PET, CT scan.
Okay.
And you, as well.
♪♪
Okay, Nira,
we're all done.
I'm glad I had you
come in for a check-up.
Your vision's
actually improved a bit.
You have 53%
of your left peripheral field.
That's great.
How are you, uh,
doing these days?
I can't drive.
I lose things.
I had to go part-time
at the company.
It completely
changed my life.
I'm so sorry.
No, the thing is,
it needed changing.
I was working
seven days a week.
My partner and I
were about to separate.
I was watching
my son grow up
through videos
sent to me at the office.
Now...
I walk my kid to school.
My relationship
is in a great place.
I'm happier
than I've been in years.
It reminded me
what was important.
♪♪
You have liver cancer.
Your symptoms were from
a paraneoplastic syndrome.
The tumor put
your immune system
in overdrive.
It started attacking
unrelated organs.
D-Did I give him cancer?
Yes. There was probably
a microscopic lesion
in the lobe you donated.
But it was to your benefit.
Your scans are clean.
So what's next?
Surgery?
It's metastasized.
We can resect
the largest tumor
and chemo-embolize
some others.
That'll give you
a few additional months.
♪♪
Months?
I'm sorry.
♪♪
Salen's gonna fire you
and then come after you
publicly.
I don't care.
Well, you should care,
Shaun.
Think about
what she's gonna use.
Your outbursts
in the hospital,
your low scores,
the complaint
the nurse made
against you...
I am a good surgeon.
I don't believe
I'll never work again.
You're an excellent surgeon,
Shaun. That's the point.
You can't risk that.
But you can?
Lea can?
Dr. Lim can?
Yes, yes, yes.
We can.
You're exceptional.
What you've accomplished
is remarkable.
We can't risk that.
♪♪
This is my decision.
I'm an adult, Dr. Glassman.
What are you gonna do
if you're not a surgeon?
That's always been
what's most important.
It's not what's
most important to me.
Not anymore.
If I lose you
from the hospital,
if I lose Dr. Lim
and Dr. Park and Lea,
I don't want
to work there anymore.
♪♪
Okay.
Let's write that speech
to the Pension Fund.
I will do that alone.
Your speech
at my engagement party
was terrible.
♪♪
Cutting loop.
Debulking further tumor
from the bladder wall.
I see the deeper
tumor fragment.
We've got
significant bleeding.
Increasing irrigation.
BP's dropping, and baby's
in fetal distress, too.
Try bipolar cautery
on the tumor surface.
♪♪
It's not working.
If we can't control this,
we're going to lose them both.
Got to open her up.
♪♪
Heart and lungs
sound good.
We're cleared
for surgery.
Do you have any questions?
If it gives me a couple
more months, I'm all in.
Dom, this'll go great.
And then Alexa
and the baby
arrive tomorrow.
We're gonna have
an awesome few days
before I head back home.
♪♪
Wait, I'm...
I'm so sorry, Ry.
You stood up for me
when I was being bullied.
You took me in
when my marriage failed.
I tried to save you
one time...
...and I killed you.
Dom...
You gave me
eight more months.
I got to see the leaves turn
in Central Park.
I got to watch
my wife give birth.
And I got to hold
my baby girl.
Who you're gonna be
the world's best godfather to.
Or I'll come back
and haunt you.
♪♪
I promise I will.
Mom's mean arterial
pressure's 50.
The tumor's stuck
to the uterus.
We need to do
an emergency hysterectomy.
There's still time.
She's going to bleed out.
We have to take her uterus.
♪♪
S-Subserosal fibroids
are adherent, too.
What if we treat
the tumor like that?
Get deep
to the tumor plane,
stop the bleeding
at its source.
Good for mom, not for baby.
We could
close the uterine wall
with three layered
3-0 sutures.
That could keep
the baby safe.
♪♪
Yeah.
Good thinking,
both of you.
Let's get it done.
Myomectomy scissors.
♪♪
I'm gonna go public
about Nira's treatment
and the role
Salen played in it.
It should make
a big impression
on the Pension Fund's
directors.
♪♪
That could have real
repercussions for your career.
I have to make this right.
I'm not sure you can.
But it's a step
in the right direction.
♪♪
Speakers list
for the Pension Fund's
annual meeting.
Glassman, Lim,
that's hardly a surprise.
Murphy? Wolke?
Park and Reznick.
Surgery go okay?
Those doctors speaking out
at the Pension Meeting,
I think they're right.
We should go meet
with them right now.
I'm not hiring them back.
At least hear them out,
their concerns,
their suggestions.
Let's come up
with some compromises,
get them to agree
to not be at the meeting.
Marcus, you're being
incredibly naive.
You may lose.
It's possible.
You'll lose
more than this hospital.
♪♪
I need to go get ready
for tonight.
♪♪
Your beard
matches your eye bags.
I'm sorry.
What is this?
Oppo research.
♪♪
Oh, Marcus...
What do you think
you have here?
I wrote off a trip to Cabo,
had an affair
with a state senator...
Oppo research on me.
♪♪
I've made mistakes,
personally, professionally.
They're all there.
If you're gonna
go through with this deal,
you're gonna
have to destroy me.
♪♪
Walk away.
You have every reason
to not want this deal.
The Board
will not fight you.
♪♪
I'm sorry.
Me too.
♪♪
Well...
Good luck.
'Cause now this is
all your problem.
♪♪
I'm gonna sleep
at my place tonight.
Okay.
You sent this to Nira?
Mm-hmm.
This is an admission
of misconduct.
Well, you know me.
Go big or go home.
I hope you didn't
do all this for me.
No.
I did this because of
who I am when I'm with you.
♪♪
♪ The Devil's
in the basement
in my home
♪ A flight of stairs
is way too close
♪ He comes for me
when I'm alone
♪ Collecting debts
that I don't owe
♪ Am I looking for revival?
♪ Am I dressed in other's sin?
♪ Hold my breath
until I'm honest
♪ Will I ever breathe again?
♪ When the world's so heavy
I can't stand
♪ I close my eyes
and start again
♪ Though my heart
is in my hands
♪ I won't break
Give me faith to bend
♪ Am I looking for revival?
♪ Am I dressed in other's sin?
♪ Hold my breath
until I'm honest
♪ Will I ever breathe again?
♪ Will I ever breathe again? ♪