- Previously on The Resident...
- I'm gonna retire.
I'd like to float your
name to the network
- for a possible trial run.
- This is Bill Laundry,
owner of Georgia FC.
Well, you guys seem to
know what you're doing.
Guess it's good
that Dax landed here.
We only employ
the best at Chastain.
Dawn is a single
mom of seven kids
that she adopted through
the Foster Care program.
Will you let me fight
this cancer with you?
There is only a slim hope
this will buy you more time.
I will do anything
against any odds
to stay with my
kids as long as I can.
Good news. Your mother
is ready to leave the ICU
and go to a great
rehab facility.
Don't give up
before the miracle.
- Wondering about the timing.
- Meaning?
If you keep her
alive, you can claim
your patient survived
the mother of all surgeries.
Does it ever get to you?
These patients, kept
alive by machines.
They don't talk. We have
no idea what they want,
or even if they're still capable
of wanting anything at all.
First time moonlighting
at a vent farm?
Med school debt is no joke,
but I'm chipping away at it.
Well, we try not to get too
philosophical around here.
It's a job. Leave it at that.
Her BP's low. She's febrile.
Nothing new for this one.
Likely another pneumonia.
We'll have to put
her on a travel vent.
- You're gonna transfer her?
- Attending's orders.
If she stays hypotensive
and spikes a temp over 102,
- we send her back to Chastain
for treatment.
- Is that reasonable?
She has no meaningful
brain function.
This is Dawn Long.
The one from TV.
The Mother of All
Surgeries patient.
The one and only.
- When was she last conscious?
- Right before she went
into surgery.
She's practically a corpse.
We should be
planning end-of-life care,
- not an ICU transfer.
- Like I said,
we try not to overthink.
But if you really want to
make a thing out of this,
take it up with Dr. Cain.
I don't want Derek to
minimize his symptoms.
Doctors could use
that to dismiss him.
He will be seen by
the best of the best.
- You have to calm down.
- They'll send a resident.
- They're just barely
real doctors.
- This is a teaching hospital,
the residents
are very qualified.
Good morning. I'm
Dr. Conrad Hawkins.
Real doctor, by the way.
Conrad, thank God. This
is my son-in-law, Derek.
I've been trying to get him to
see a doctor for a month now.
- He's been complaining of
shortness of breath.
- Mom.
Let Derek speak for himself.
And my daughter, Molly.
Uh, it started a few weeks ago.
It's probably
just a little cough.
Uh, he's had night
sweats and fatigue.
What if he has
eosinophilic granulomatosis
- with polyangiitis?
- Molly's in her second year
of med school.
Oh, doctors raising
doctors. I love it.
Now, how about I
take a look at Derek
and everyone else
heads to the cafeteria.
And for this one, insider tip:
order the hot chocolate,
extra marshmallows.
Hot chocolate?
Fantastic idea.
Cocoa on me. Come on, you.
Smooth move, doc.
Deep breath.
They always like that together?
Uh, well, Molly can
get a little nervous.
And you're the eye
of the hurricane?
I try.
But I'm-I'm pulling double duty,
what with Molly in
med school and all.
Working and taking
care of the kid.
I'm even coaching her
softball team this year.
I get it, you're super dad.
That kind of stress
can take its toll.
Molly stayed home
when Josie was a baby,
so I figure it's my turn now.
Okay.
Well, my job is to focus on you.
So, let's get a chest X-ray
and find out what's
going on, okay?
Okay, yeah.
I guess that's why I'm here.
You're in the right place.
Randolph, you've done really
well with these guest spots.
I'm happy. Producers are happy.
So now it's time to
knock it out of the park.
Got any last minute pointers?
Make the show your own.
Not an ounce of sugar
goes into my body.
I-I've been tired all the
time, uh, muscle ache.
Now my gums have
started bleeding.
- Would you mind
if I have a look?
- Sure.
Well...
Albert, have you ever
heard of Dr. James Lind?
- No.
- Lind was an 18th-century
surgeon's mate
in the British Royal Navy.
And at sea, they had
a diet a lot like yours.
And that was back in the day
when more sailors were lost
to a mysterious illness
than to any enemy.
And ships' captains were
prescribing vinegar and cider,
and even sea water, until
James Lind discovered that...
with just a little bit
- of Vitamin C...
- Ooh...
he could cure thousands of
what I'm about to cure you of...
Scurvy.
So, save your money, throw
away your home remedies,
put a little citrus
in your diet,
or buy a peg
leg. It's up to you.
Need a doctor?
Ring the Bell.
Ring the Bell! Ring the Bell!
Ring the Bell! Ring
the Bell! Ring the Bell!
♪ ♪
Hey, I got your page, what's up?
Remember Dr. Cain's patient who
was on The Montel Williams Show?
Yeah. I thought
she was in rehab.
According to her chart, she is.
- She's been at an LTACH
this whole time?
- Yes.
And what's worse, she's
been hauled back to Chastain
for treatment five times.
Strokes, pneumonias, infections.
She's not getting better,
but Cain wants her
diagnosed, treated,
and sent back to the LTACH.
What I want is for
Dawn Long to get better,
so her children can
have their mother back.
- How's she doing?
- Not good.
Fever. Increased
sputum. Hypoxia.
All signs point to lower
respiratory tract infection.
She's such a good woman.
And her family...
- so wonderful.
- Dr. Cain,
are her children aware that
she's not gonna be waking up?
Absolutely not. Because we
don't know that for sure yet.
The brain is an enigma.
Anything can happen.
Of course, but...
I mean, it's been six months.
Doesn't look like it's
heading in the right direction.
Has it really been six months?
You want your
patient to wake up,
you want it so badly,
you just hold out hope.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe I haven't been
completely honest with myself
or with her family.
It's time we let this poor
woman pass peacefully.
In the meantime,
I need you two to
do everything you
can to keep her alive
until I can get
her family in here.
Those children deserve one
last moment with their mother.
Can you do that for me, please?
Sure thing, Dr. Cain.
Thank you.
I did not expect that.
Let's hope we don't
have to put her through
any more than we already have.
Wow, honey, nice.
Okay, Derek, your X-rays are up.
- We're gonna take a look at
what's going on in your lungs.
- Oh, I thought maybe
we should put mesothelioma
at the top of Derek's differential.
His office is old.
Might have asbestos.
Well, he's young
for mesothelioma.
But old office,
I'll keep that in mind.
Let Conrad be
the doctor, darling.
♪ ♪
Okay.
See this white
area on your X-ray?
That means your right
lung is filled with something.
Could be fluid.
If it is, we'll
drain it, run a CT
and see what's
causing all the trouble.
- And reevaluate from there.
- How bad is it?
The fluid, I mean.
- Well...
- It's not a big deal at all.
Right, Dr. Hawkins?
Kit.
♪ ♪
Whiteout of the right hemithorax
is absolutely a big deal.
I know, but I had to stop you.
Molly does not
handle stress well.
- In fact,
she utterly falls apart.
- Well, she's worried.
- That's to be expected.
- Trust me.
Her freshman year of college
she had so much anxiety
she had to drop
out and live at home.
Did you see her
clawing at her wrists?
- Mm-hmm.
- That's a tell.
She's about to
go into a tailspin.
Still...
there are a number of things
that could be wrong
with your son-in-law.
I can't...
- I can't withhold
information from a patient.
- Of course.
And I would never
ask you to do that.
Derek is the patient and
you can tell him anything,
'cause he can handle anything.
But if any bad news is coming,
could you please
filter it through me?
I will try to tell
you any news first,
so that you can be
the Molly whisperer.
Thank you.
You're lucky I like you.
It's the accent.
Executives are
coming in tomorrow.
We're gonna be selling "Ring
the Bell" T-shirts by Friday.
Y-Yeah. About
that catchphrase...
Hey, it's great, huh?
We paid that woman
to start the chant.
Just get the audience riled
up. Worked like a charm.
Yep. Yeah. Loved it.
So, listen, let's go by
the production office
- and you can weigh in
on tomorrow's guest.
- Oh, well, I can't.
I have a shift at Chastain.
Yeah, those are
good where they are.
You do realize that if
you take over this show,
you're gonna have to cut back
- your surgical schedule
drastically.
- Well, that may be an issue.
I'm already pushing
it at Chastain.
I really can't take much
more time off as it is.
- I am a doctor, you know.
- Yes, you are a doctor.
A TV doctor.
Which is not a part-time job.
What's the point of having
a famous doctor on staff
if he's not available? Man,
you got to make that shot!
I know you originally scheduled
this with Dr. Bell, Mr. Landry,
but right now he's very
busy outside of the hospital.
You requested a
top surgeon, right?
- Right.
- Dr. Austin is our finest.
Dr. Hawkins is too kind,
yet remarkably accurate.
I know you're good.
You saved my star rookie.
That's him right there.
See that dribble? It's thanks
to you he can still do that.
But I've been
- in and out of surgeries
for a decade.
- Yep, you had
that appendectomy back in '09,
which led to a
post-op infection.
Which led to recurrent
bowel obstruction
and small bowel resection.
Every time I lose intestine...
my dinner plate shrinks.
I just want to break this
cycle once and for all.
And we are gonna
make that happen for you.
This operation is
extremely delicate.
But I am precise and
I have the patience
of a western
diamondback rattlesnake.
Rattlesnakes are
patient. Come on, fellas.
Okay.
Okay, you cut me open.
Just do your best to
make it the last time.
Best is my only
mode, Mr. Landry.
- See you soon.
- Thank you, guys.
Oh, that's a handball!
Huh.
I wonder where Molly gets
her scratching habit from.
You see how wound
up my daughter is now?
You should have seen her
before Derek came along.
I'm not sure what
we'd do without him.
Mm. Let's not go there.
Derek has a mass in his chest.
Ring the Bell.
Aw, you got a case
of the scurvy, matey.
Let's-let's just not do that.
Ah, where's the Hollywood smile?
I loved the whole schtick.
It's not a schtick.
It's medicine, only on TV.
Right.
Now if you'll excuse me,
I have a gallbladder removal.
Oh, uh, we-we weren't sure if
you were coming back today,
so they moved
that up the schedule
and I covered that for you.
We... You were
off doing your thing.
Which is definitely
not a schtick.
Yeah.
Full day.
I got to jet.
Hey.
I just got a readmissions
alert in my e-mail.
Why is Dawn Long
back in this hospital?
- She's sick.
- Is that supposed to be a joke?
She's been back here five
times since her operation.
Her treatment costs
are beginning to add up.
You're supposed to be making
us money, not costing us.
The woman is comatose.
Why are we not letting her die?
We will. Tomorrow.
Care to elaborate?
After six months, Dawn
Long's survival statistics
will no longer be
tracked, and our famous
Mother of all Surgeries
will have an official survivor.
It's one for the record books.
- And that six month mark...
- Is tomorrow.
She lives through the
night, then all of the publicity
we got from that surgery
will not go to waste.
We just need to keep her
breathing until the morning.
And the family is
on board for that?
They will be.
Okay.
One more day, then
end this charade.
Question.
Why is she so sick?
She's bedridden, on a vent,
decrease in swallowing function.
All adds up to
pneumonia. Very common.
Are you sure?
It's pneumonia. Trust me.
A mass?
- What kind of mass?
- We're not sure yet.
Is there a chance he'll
have to stay overnight?
We've got softball
tomorrow, Dad.
I know, honey. Don't worry.
We're just gonna do a biopsy.
It's a quick
procedure in the OR.
But you must have some
idea what the mass is.
There's no point in speculating.
Yeah, let's just wait
for the biopsy results
before jumping to
any conclusions.
A nurse will prep
you in a few minutes.
I'll be watching
the entire time.
Mom.
What are you hiding?
- Pardon?
- I saw how you stopped
Dr. Hawkins from
talking earlier.
You're not fooling me. I know
how you get when you're worried.
My husband has
a mass in his chest.
It's perfectly rational for
me to look for answers.
Why don't you take
Josie and grab a bite?
- The biopsy won't take long.
- Josie's coloring. She's fine.
Mom, quit sidelining
me. I'm not 18 anymore.
I can handle whatever
it is you're worried about.
I'm not worried about anything.
Everything is gonna be okay.
Retractor.
Molly's nerves are sky high,
and mine are catching up.
We need something
to go smoothly today.
Thank you for
being here, Conrad.
Well, you're family. Of course.
Thank you for taking this, AJ.
Anything for you, Dr. V.
Dissecting down
to the mediastinum.
Scope to me.
Passing the scope anterior
to the trachea.
Identifying my landmarks.
Uh...
All good down there?
I'm flush against
the pulmonary artery.
How close is it?
Biopsy forceps.
Oh, please, don't
nick that artery.
He won't.
And...
- fin.
- He didn't.
Let's get this little nugget
to the lab, shall we?
And now we wait for
the pathology report.
I hate this part.
Mr. Kim.
Welcome back, Dr. Bell.
Can I help you?
I'm just gonna take a
wild guess and assume
you're behind my removal
from the surgical schedule.
That's what you wanted, right?
Why would that be what I wanted?
From what I hear, you've
been AWOL for weeks,
working your second job.
My second job? I'm on a TV
show bringing publicity to Chastain.
And if a surgery has to be
handed off to an alternate
once in a blue moon,
it's a small price
- to keep a top surgeon around.
- Is that what you are?
We all pass our prime,
but we don't all retire
into fame and fortune.
Maybe don't look a
gift horse in the mouth.
I see you're having trouble
understanding. I'll simplify.
You lose me, you lose
more than a surgeon.
I know you'd love any reason
to get rid of me, but trust me,
you want me cutting
and you want me happy.
Don't be dramatic, Dr. Bell.
I don't want you gone.
I just don't care
if you're here.
Feldman.
- Got your page.
- Dr. Bell.
I didn't expect it to
be you. I just asked
for any available
general surgeon.
Well, I'm between
patients at the moment.
What's the problem?
Well, uh... follow me.
Uh...
Perirectal abscess.
You expect me to lance
a boil on a patient's ass?
It's too close to the rectal
muscle for me to do it.
Rules dictate a general
surgeon drains it.
Sorry.
Good afternoon, Nurse.
Have Pravesh and Nevin
learned anything about Ms. Long?
Uh, not yet.
Her prelim cultures
are negative,
but her BP has hardly improved.
Okay, let's open up the box.
Order fungal markers,
MALDI-TOF, the whole gamut.
Uh, what are we testing for?
Everything. Uh, you know,
I just want to be thorough.
Okay. I'll have Dr. Pravesh
put in those orders.
Nurse...
this case is deeply
personal to me.
I brought Dawn
Long into Chastain.
I was her surgeon.
I held her children's
hands through the post-op.
I am gonna be the last
person to leave her funeral.
I put her care entirely
on my shoulders,
and I'm gonna continue
to do so moving forward,
because...
I am her doctor.
Nobody else. Am I
making myself clear?
- Absolutely.
- You're gonna order
that fungal culture
under my name.
And who are you gonna
send the results to?
- You, Dr. Cain.
- Anybody else?
No.
Attagirl.
Dr. Bell.
To what do I owe this pleasure?
I heard you're operating
on Bill Landry today.
I am. 5:00 p.m. sharp.
Don't you love punctuality?
- Need an extra hand?
- I do not.
I'm free at 5:00 p.m.
Excellent. I've got some
book recommendations.
- I've done a lot
of bowel resections.
- As have I.
AJ, come on, man.
I'm going stir-crazy.
My whole schedule's
been cleared for the day.
Right, so you could
be on television.
- Wow. You, too. Okay.
- I'll tell you what.
I will keep you in mind
for surgery. All right?
And if I do need you,
- I will make sure to ring the...
- Don't.
- Ding, ding, ding,
ding, ding, ding.
- Don't...
Derek has an aggressive
B-cell lymphoma.
I'm so sorry, Kit.
From here on in,
there are two parts
to a patient's life.
Before you know you have
cancer and after you know.
Right now, they're
in Derek's room
living in the before.
I heard them planning
tomorrow's dinner.
Brainstorming vacations
for after Molly's
school is finished.
But you and I...
We're already
living in the after,
where you don't plan vacations,
where you know everything
is not gonna be okay
for a very long time, if ever.
And we must drag them
into the after with us,
and that is a terrible,
terrible thing to do.
I could tell them for you.
No. No.
This is my family.
They're gonna remember
these words forever,
and they must come from me.
Cancer?
Mommy, what's the matter?
- Daddy?
- It's all right, honey.
It's okay. Everything's okay.
Kit, can you
please have someone
take Josie to the play area?
Of course.
- I don't want to go.
- I know, sweetie.
It's just, it's, uh, it's
grown-up time right now.
It's fine.
Oh.
Thank you, honey.
What's next?
The oncologist, Dr. Jones,
will be in to talk to you soon.
He's a specialist in
this type of lymphoma.
What are the chances of
me getting out of this alive?
It's survivable.
How survivable?
Dr. Hawkins.
I have a daughter...
and I have a wife
to think about.
I need to know if we
should start making plans,
so please, just
lay it out for me.
There's still a lot
we don't know.
The chemo is called
R-CHOP, and it is not easy.
It'll make you feel
tired, nauseous.
Your white blood
cell counts will drop,
it could cause an infection.
But when you make
it through that...
Please. What are my chances?
You have a 50%
chance at being cured.
Molly.
It's okay. Just...
just give her a minute.
I asked you to
let me handle this.
Molly had ten seconds to
process her husband's lymphoma,
and you're discussing
survival rates.
I know. But he was
desperate and he asked me,
so I had to honor that.
We had a deal.
You said you would funnel
everything through me,
that I would tell them, I
would soften the blow.
But you didn't.
And now look what happened.
You told them he could die.
You made it worse, Conrad.
You made it so much worse.
I understand.
You're not mad at me.
You're mad at cancer.
You're scared for Derek.
You're scared Molly will
fall apart, or that you will.
I know. I'm sorry.
But that poor man.
That poor, darling man,
- he doesn't deserve this.
- No, he doesn't.
No one does.
But you and I...
We're gonna do
everything we can.
And when we're done, I
know you will be strong enough
to put yourself and
everyone else back together.
Okay.
Thank you.
- I'm fine.
- I know you are.
And for the record,
I absolutely can be
mad at cancer and you.
I gave her 0.5 of
lorazepam, but it didn't work.
And I-I didn't know what to do.
She's been seizing
for nearly a minute.
All right, give her
another two milligrams.
Turn her up to 100% O2.
Okay. She's settling.
- She's in V tach.
- Get the crash cart,
pull up 300 of amio.
We're gonna save
this woman's life
just so she can die again
when the family pulls the plug.
If they pull the plug. She's
not DNR. We have to save her.
- It's not right.
- I know, Devon,
but we don't have a choice.
We're torturing her.
She's coding. We
have to bag her.
All right.
- I'm sorry.
- No, Molly...
I ran out of the room just
when Derek needed me most.
I was thinking of myself.
I fell apart when I
should have been strong.
That's all I ever do.
And that's why
you're telling doctors
not to talk in front of me.
Letting my sick husband
hear about his condition,
but not his totally
healthy, medically trained,
"should be able
to handle it" wife.
I'm proud of you.
I know sometimes
I try to protect you
like you're still a kid,
but that's my mistake.
Look at you.
You're in your second year of
med school, top of your class.
You have a wonderful
child, a strong marriage
and I am endlessly proud of you.
Sometimes I think, without
him, I couldn't breathe.
He's my rock.
You may not see this,
but you're his rock, too.
All right, Chu. We're
looking at an hour or less
- with Mr. Landry here.
- Roger that.
10 blade to me.
All right. Let's give
this team owner
a new lease on life, shall we?
Uh, all right, Chu, let's
make it 90 minutes.
There's a country mile of
scar tissue in this bad boy.
90 minutes. Got it.
Retractor.
Make that two hours.
Uh, in fact, you know
what? Make it four.
It's like tissue paper in here.
You know, I'm gonna
need another set of hands.
I'll page Dr. Singh.
Actually... make it Dr. Bell.
Bell? Is he still
full-time here?
Check the cafeteria. And
when you find him, tell him
not to let it get to his head,
but I need him in my OR, stat.
Hey.
You okay?
Well, I just saved a
woman's life. A woman who,
by all rights, should
be long dead, so...
Anyway, you paged. What's up?
Told Dr. Voss that you
used to be a chemo nurse,
and that you were great at it.
The best, is what
I actually said.
We fill the patient with toxins
and hope it only
kills the bad stuff.
- It's hell on them.
- I know.
And it can take its
toll on you, as well.
Yeah, I mean, the oncologists,
they just give the orders.
The nurses stay with the
patients, watch them struggle.
It's... it's heartbreaking.
You don't have to do it.
No, it's okay.
For Kit, her family, anything.
How about we get a family
member to sit with you,
track how you feel?
That way you don't have
to spend extra energy
communicating with the nurses.
That would be me.
Sorry I'm late. The vending
machine line was crazy.
I read snacks are important
during chemo sessions.
Sweet or salty? Sweet.
Are you comfortable?
I-I ordered pillows.
I'm good. Really.
I know you are.
You're always good.
In fact, you're the bravest
person I've ever met.
But today, you focus
on getting better,
and I'll handle the rest.
Come here. It's okay.
It's okay.
Come here. I know.
- I'm so sorry.
- I know...
We got this, okay?
I promise.
I love unicorns.
What's going on with Mom?
Do you mind if, um,
- just you and I talk?
- Of course, yeah.
I'll meet you guys in
the waiting room, okay?
Waiting room, okay?
I don't know exactly how
to say this to you, but...
your mother, she's...
she's not really there anymore.
What do you mean?
We haven't measured any type
of meaningful brain activity,
and we haven't
for some time now.
Now, I know that we were
holding out hope for a miracle.
I truly, truly believed
that it was gonna happen.
But the chances are
getting slimmer by the day.
You think we should let her go?
Your mother's
fought a good fight.
And we all love her.
We did our best
to heal her, but...
yes, it's time.
Um...
How would it happen?
Would you just...
turn off all her machines?
Yes, we'd make sure
she's comfortable.
We'll give her some morphine,
so she doesn't feel any pain.
You can have a ceremony
right here in the room.
Just the family.
Can I arrange that for you?
Okay.
Done and done.
What made you change your mind?
Multiple previous
abdominal surgeries.
There's scar tissue
everywhere, man.
I can barely lyse the adhesions
without tearing
into the intestines.
This is a mess.
Tell me about it.
This could take till
daybreak, you know?
You got someplace to be?
I'm a surgeon.
Where would I have to be?
Retractor to me.
Uh, Nic, I think he's shivering.
Well, that's normal
with chemo. Here.
Are his Ts peaking?
Let me print an EKG.
And get Conrad in here.
We're just checking
with the doctor.
I'm sure you're fine.
You're right... good catch.
Let's get a crash
cart in here, come on!
Push one gram of
calcium gluconate.
Derek, honey, it's gonna
be fine... I'm right here.
Derek wasn't
shivering, he's twitching.
He must be hypocalcemic.
And with his high
potassium, he's in danger
of cardiac arrest. He's in TLS.
Let's get the pacer
pads on him now!
Give him ten units of
insulin, an amp of D-50
- and an amp of bicarb.
- Derek has Tumor Lysis Syndrome.
As the chemo kills
his cancer cells...
Dying cells release toxins
into his blood and organs.
In other words,
the cure could kill him.
So we have a
catch-22. Before his first
round of chemo's complete,
we need to give him
fluids in order to prevent
his kidneys from failing.
But doing that puts his lungs
in danger of filling
with fluid again.
It's gonna be
touch-and-go till sunrise.
Okay.
♪ Hush-a-bye ♪
♪ Don't you cry ♪
♪ Go to sleep ♪
♪ My little baby ♪
♪ When you wake ♪
♪ You shall have ♪
♪ All the pretty ♪
♪ Little horses ♪
♪ Blacks and bays ♪
♪ Dapples and grays ♪
♪ All the pretty ♪
♪ Little horses ♪
♪ Hush-a-bye ♪
♪ Don't you cry ♪
♪ Go to sleep ♪
♪ My little baby. ♪
♪ ♪
Man, I thought we'd
lost him when that tear
in his IVC opened
up, but your patchwork
using peritoneum?
Good work, my brother.
Can you imagine if we killed the
owner of Atlanta's soccer team?
We'd be run out of Georgia.
Listen, man, my apologies
about the surprise marathon.
But if it wasn't for you, old
Landry would be spending
the rest of his life drinking
his meals through straws.
There's no apologies necessary.
I, you know...
I haven't pushed myself
that hard in... years.
Just exhausting.
But exhilarating.
I got to go.
Oh, so you're really gonna
walk away from all this, huh?
This is who I am.
I'm a surgeon... it doesn't
mean we're one-trick ponies, AJ.
With a show I can
reach more people.
I can do a lot of good, I...
And yet here you are,
after a brutal
surgery like this one,
glowing like an intern
on his first day of rotation.
He's been up and down all night.
Didn't eat, he said he was cold.
Dr. Hawkins told me you
caught Derek's potassium spike.
You know, you might
have saved his life.
We'll see.
He's afebrile. Um...
BP looks good.
Electrolytes are stabilized.
He made it through
his first round of chemo.
♪ ♪
Ah!
Good morning!
Good morning, good morning.
Uh, sorry if I look
a little ragged.
I had a... big night last night.
Uh, we performed an unexpected
overnight surgery.
The patient had a
dozen bowel obstructions
over the years, and every
time he went in for a repair,
he lost a little bit
of his intestine.
Before I bring out
our-our scheduled guest,
I-I'd like you to
meet that patient.
So please say hello to the owner
of the Georgia FC Soccer Club,
Bill Landry!
Bill, how are you feeling?
- Any soreness, nausea?
- Yeah.
A little pain
around my stitches.
Still pretty tuckered out.
Well, that's, as we discussed,
because your intestine ruptured,
and you were open all
night while we repaired it.
You'll be back
watching Georgia FC
with a beer and
burgers in no time.
Although I cannot recommend
the burger.
The beer...
in moderation.
Dr. Bell, I don't know
how to thank you,
but I'm sure gonna try.
I'd like to offer you and
your audience members
tickets to this week's
match against United FC.
Wow.
They seem pretty happy, Bill.
That's very generous,
thank you so much.
So that's what you'll get
when you tune into
The Dr. Bell Show.
I will bring my hospital
into your living room.
Real patients, real stories.
Which only an actively
working doctor can bring you.
And now, before
we go to break...
Mr. Landry?
If you need a doctor,
just ring the Bell!
Ring the Bell! Ring the Bell!
Ring the Bell!
So, Dawn Long has passed on
and the Mother of All Surgeries
is now officially a success.
Great work.
I'll draft a press release.
Yes, this is Dr. Cain.
Dr. Cain,
this is Dr. Vincent
down in microbiology.
I have Dawn Long's
blood culture results.
Ah, yes. Unfortunately,
Dawn Long has passed
away, so there's no need.
A-Actually, you're
gonna want to hear this.
Your patient had Candida auris.
The superbug?
Exactly. The hospital will have
to lock down the patient room,
sterilize it from top to bottom.
Anybody who'd come into contact
with Ms. Long will have to
take extreme precautions.
Okay, thanks for
the call. I'll handle it.
I-I don't need to
remind you, Dr. Cain,
but once Candida auris
spreads throughout a building,
it's nearly impossible
to eradicate.
A superbug like this
can destroy a hospital.
What is it?
Hey!
Barrett!
♪ ♪
Good morning, Dr. Cain.
Logan.
We have a problem.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH