Previously on The Resident...
How's Jessie?
Her kidneys are failing.
So my kidneys will
never work again?
The drug trial did
irreversible damage.
I will have a triple
transplant and make history.
Maybe even come
here as an intern.
I can't think of
anything more amazing.
Red Rock Mountain Medical
is the top health
care conglomerate
in the southeast.
We don't need Chastain.
We will be stronger together.
We have to keep fighting.
The risk is pretty
low for the donor.
Anybody need a
kidney around here?
Thank you, Dad.
Dad.
- You're my baby girl.
- It's gonna be okay.
Where's the crash cart?!
Mm.
Black-eyed Susans
are my favorite.
Remember that time you ran
away from our family picnic?
Must've been,
like, four or five.
Yeah.
Mom and Dad were frantic,
but I knew where to find you.
Here.
Dad was so sweet that day.
He... he was crying when
he picked me up, and...
I... I remember
I was so happy in his arms.
I keep trying to
rewind the clock.
There must have been something
I could have done differently.
Remember what I told you, Nic?
This is not your fault.
It's getting late.
It's time.
We need to scatter her ashes.
Nicky, honey, it's
been almost a month.
I'm not ready.
♪ ♪
Welcome to another
rewarding day under the heel
of Red Rock Mountain Medical.
"Red Rock, Red Rock."
How's Nic?
Uh, the same: not good.
We're all worried about her.
We miss her.
How can we help?
She'll be here this morning
for her dad's post-op.
I'll talk to her.
Sounds good.
Where's Jonah?
I took my eyes off him
for two seconds
and he disappeared.
You know, he's probably
hiding somewhere.
He's afraid of needles.
How much do you expect to make
with this new
neurosurgery center?
A steady churn of
high-risk invasive brain
and spine procedures
generates half a billion a year.
And this new neurosurgeon
you want to have...
He's a rainmaker?
He was at his last hospital.
He will be if he comes here.
- When are you seeing him?
- Lunch today.
He won't commit to Chastain
unless the two of you get along.
I'll work my charm.
I couldn't sleep last night,
thinking about coming back here.
Come on.
Jessie!
Keep trying!
You ever gonna be able
to work in this place again?
I don't know.
This is where Jessie was killed.
No one killed Jessie, Dad.
She went into surgery
with a weakened heart
and died of a
massive blood clot.
It's a known complication
that could happen to anyone.
Yeah, well, I just want
to see her records.
Get another opinion on
what caused her death.
Why?
They did the autopsy.
I saw the results.
Yeah, we should just get
an expert to check it, that's all.
I... We may have a
case to bring a lawsuit.
Unbelievable.
Always looking for an angle,
even in your daughter's death.
No, I'm not looking
for an angle.
And this is not about
money. But somebody here
- has to be held responsible.
- Jessie's gone.
And she's not coming
back. There's no point
in affixing blame. I mean,
I don't blame you, after all.
You... Me? What? Why would you?
I put my life on the
line. I donated a kidney.
Eventually.
It did no good.
So you blame me, because...
you're down a kidney
and Jessie still died.
- No, I don't.
- Yeah, you do.
You blame me because
I pushed for the surgery.
It was her only chance.
I did everything I could
- to protect her.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. Whoa, whoa.
Nic, I do not blame you.
Do the post-op on your
own. I-I got to take a walk.
Oh, come on.
Okay. Excuse me.
Just one second.
I'll be right back.
Welcome, Eloise,
to your first day
as a sub-intern at Chastain.
I feel like I'm dreaming.
I've imagined this
moment so many times.
I-I can't believe it's real.
Devon.
- You remember Dr. Pravesh?
- Of course. Eloise.
Last time I saw you,
you were recovering
- from a triple transplant.
- Now I'm hoping
to match here, and become
a doctor at the hospital
- that saved my life.
- Well, you can learn a lot
from this guy.
He's our top intern.
And soon he'll be a
second-year resident
- with an intern of his own
to torture.
- Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah.
Don't do that.
Now, Dr. Pravesh
is gonna go over
all the additional
safety precautions
you need to take when
you're around patients.
You do know that
I've been dealing
with cystic fibrosis
my entire life.
I'm kind of an expert
in infection control here.
I promise, I can
take care of myself.
I'll hold you to that.
Dr. Hawkins, I need a hand.
An eight-year-old has gone
missing. His name is Jonah.
♪ ♪
He, uh, he was
right here in the bed
and I went to get some water.
Someone thinks
they saw a little boy
enter the stairs
to the basement.
I don't know why
they didn't stop him,
but I'm going to check.
Annie?
Conrad. What?
- Wow.
- What?
Oh, I haven't seen you since...
Oh, the mountain bike race
at Stone Mountain. Right?
What, two years ago? Yeah.
- Oh, it's so good to see you.
- You too.
So they needed another
PhD particle physicist
- to fix this thing again?
- Yeah, well,
you know, the plumber tried to
snake it, but you know how fussy
these proton beam
accelerators can be.
They are fussy.
Is everything all right?
Came down here
looking for a little boy
who ran away from the ER.
Oh, well, I didn't see anyone.
You know what, let's
check the treatment room.
Hey, hey, hey,
wait, I smell gas. W...
What the hell was that?
What happened?
An explosion in the proton
beam accelerator room.
Fi-Fire.
Don't move.
I have to find the boy.
Jonah.
Let me go. Let me... I
just... I have to find Jonah.
My baby. I... No, no, no. I
have to find him. I have to find...
What's going on? Where's Conrad?
He went down there.
Oh, my God.
Right here, right here.
Conrad!
Conrad, it's Nic. Open the door.
Open the door.
Oh, my God. You're bleeding.
No, I'm okay. I'm okay.
- I can't get the door.
- Let me-let me try, let me try.
Oh, it must have been
damaged in the explosion.
It's jammed shut.
Get out of the
building. There's a fire.
- The whole place could go up.
- We're not leaving you.
Is anyone else with you?
A woman and the boy,
both badly injured. Go back,
get somebody to
break down the door
- and then get out of here.
- Go! Go!
Nic, get out of here!
- Go.
- No.
Go!
Annie. Annie!
Annie. Can you
crawl to the door?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Go. Go.
Conrad?!
Oh, my God.
Wake up.
You're okay.
We need some help over here!
Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
Hey, hey. You're
safe. The fire's out.
There was a gas leak,
but they capped it off.
Where are Annie and Jonah?
They're both alive and
they're being treated now.
Dr. Hawkins, I'll strap you down
if I have to.
You were exposed
to a lot of smoke
and the blast may have
caused other injuries.
- You have any pain?
- All over.
He may have a fractured rib.
My left ankle's killing me.
It's really swollen.
Add it to the list of
imaging we need.
Okay.
- Pupils equal and reactive.
- Have we scared you off
- your first day?
- Are you kidding? I'm good.
Eloise, the ER is no place
for a triple transplant survivor.
I'm gowned, gloved,
masked, safe as everyone else.
Please, let's focus
on the patient.
My neck... it hurts.
- We need to maintain
his C-spine.
- We got you, buddy.
I know it's hard. Try
not to move your head.
Airway intact. Breath
sounds clear bilaterally.
We should put him on high-flow
oxygen in case of possible
- carbon monoxide exposure.
- Good call.
Let's get him in a face
mask. Make sure to send
- a carboxyhemoglobin level.
- Eloise, help me out.
- How's he looking?
- Minor injuries and burns.
But I'm concerned
about his C-spine.
Jonah, can you
squeeze my finger?
Possible spinal cord injury.
Let's get him to CT now.
All right. Let's go.
BP 60/40, tachy in the 140s.
- She's crashing.
- Bolus a liter LR
and get blood
ready for transfusion.
No breath sounds on the left.
- Trachea deviated on the right.
- Tension pneumo.
The shrapnel must've
pierced her lung.
- Chest tube kit.
- No time.
Scalpel.
Sats are coming up,
but her pressure's
still tanking.
Irving, chest tube.
Okafor, ultrasound.
Abdomen is filled with fluid.
- She's hemorrhaging.
- Damn shrapnel.
She's not stable for CT.
Let's take her to OR. Now.
- Where are you taking her?
- OR Two.
Hey, can you finish this?
Thanks.
Nic.
What the hell...
Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
- What about Conrad?
He's banged up pretty
bad, but he'll be okay.
Thank God. The other
two weren't so lucky.
What can I do to help?
Nothing. Just go
home. Take the keys.
- Nic, come on. Hey.
- I'm gonna stay with him.
Nic, Nic. Nic.
Shrapnel everywhere.
This woman has
saved a lot of lives.
It's time we save hers.
I'll take the chest.
You got the abdomen.
Here, sit down.
Yes, ma'am.
I did triathlons with Annie.
I saw her once give up the lead
in a race just to help someone
who took a fall.
That's Annie.
Does she have any family
that we need to notify?
I'm not sure.
I know she got a divorce.
And then, not long after that,
her son died in a car accident.
God, that's awful.
Just ran the bowel.
No obvious injuries.
Shrapnel by the abdominal wall.
Well, I took out three
from the chest wall.
The last one I see is there.
Lodged into the aortic arch and
abutting the pulmonary artery.
Of course.
We pull this out,
she might blow.
She might blow if
we don't pull it out.
Well, she won't, because
you know what to do, right?
Yes, I do.
I'll clamp the proximal
and distal aorta
and control the PA with
vessel loop, just in case.
Nice job. And pull on three.
One, two,
three.
Pressure's dropping fast.
All right, we got this, Chu.
Just buy us some more time.
We're maxed on pressors.
All right.
We are... done.
Look at that.
Pressure's coming back.
Of course it is.
I love this game.
Wonder Twins do it again.
5-0 Prolene.
Hey, what's going on?
I'm, uh...
faking a fainting spell
to get your attention.
Come on, lie down.
Careful.
I told you it was too
soon to get off that gurney.
I just...
I just need some fluids.
- I'm light-headed.
- Okay.
- I'll get you an IV.
- No, don't.
Stay with me.
Okay.
When I saw you lying
on the ground I thought...
I was so scared.
I'm not going anywhere.
You're stuck with me.
I love you.
I love you, too.
I've only seen this one time
before in my entire career.
Occipital-cervical dislocation.
What does that mean?
Internal decapitation.
It's when the spinal column is
separated from the skull base.
The blast from the explosion
must have done this.
Well, the patient
you saw before...
did they make it?
No.
Most don't.
Let's get him to the OR.
SSEPs and MEPs on.
Fusing C1 and C2.
Blast.
Again.
It's the cord.
Gonna have to perform
a laminectomy to give
the cord more room, then fuse.
Doesn't that mean he
could end up a quadriplegic?
Not if I can help it. Rongeurs.
What are you still doing here?
You're supposed to
be meeting Dr. Cain.
Two of today's
patients are still critical.
And they're being taken care of.
You're not needed here.
Dr. Cain is not a
man you keep waiting.
Do you know how much he bills?
Uh...
$80 million a year.
80...
million.
I want you to focus
on that number.
Got it. Oh!
Oh.
Kit Voss just reattached
that boy's head.
If she'd been off by a
fraction of a millimeter,
an eight-year-old would
be paralyzed for life.
Or dead.
Dr. Voss bills
two million a year.
Cain is our future.
Voss is our past.
I can't guarantee her
contract will be renewed.
What we need
is more doctors like that.
♪ I pray ♪
♪ I pray it's not too late... ♪
Ah.
Thank you.
♪ Wading in the wa... ♪
♪ You know I love it ♪
Dr. Cain.
- Call me Barrett.
- Randolph.
It's an interesting
hobby you got here.
Yeah, it's outsider
art, all from Georgia.
Wherever I live, I
try to immerse myself
in the local culture.
Can I get you both
some champagne?
No.
That would be lovely.
Yes, please do.
Are we the only ones here?
- Show's not open yet.
- Oh.
They offered me a
preview. I don't know...
Probably thought I
was more likely to buy
if I had first pick.
They were right.
Hey, I'm sorry I'm late.
We had a bit of an
emergency this morning.
Yeah, I heard
about that. Is it true
that the proton beam
therapy facility is a total loss?
Yeah.
$220 million
investment destroyed.
If I didn't know better,
I'd think Red Rock
blew it up themselves.
I was thinking the
same exact thing.
Proton beam therapy facilities...
They lose millions annually.
Well, when Chastain built it,
they had profit projections
way north of reality.
How far north?
The arctic circle.
And now Red Rock walks
away with a big insurance payout.
Where I grew up, they
call that insure and burn.
Or a stroke of good luck.
Except, of course, for the
two people who nearly died.
See anything that
tempts you, Dr. Cain?
Most definitely.
I'll take that one.
Great choice.
I'll get the paperwork going.
This is gonna double
its value in five years.
And if it doesn't,
is it still art?
Oh, it will. It will.
Lunch at the Provence Grill?
- On Red Rock Mountain Medical.
- Oh, well, in that case,
I'll have the oysters
and... more champagne.
Thank you.
I want to go check on Annie.
Okay, let's go.
Uh, Mina wants to talk to you.
I'll be fine. I won't
do anything crazy.
I'll come find you.
How's he doing?
The ankle's gonna be
an issue for a while, but...
I'm just so glad he's okay.
Mm.
And how are you?
We've all been worried.
You're probably the
one person I know
who understands how I feel.
Does it ever get any easier?
I wish I could
promise you it would.
Walk with me.
When my sisters died,
I could hardly get out
of bed for two years.
I do not want that
to happen to you.
Every day, I wake up,
and the first thing I
think is she's not here.
And she's never
gonna be here again.
It's like there's a
hole in your heart
that you'll never fill.
My whole life, I had one job.
Take care of Jessie.
Okay, that was
not your only job.
You take care of so many people.
I know, I know. My
patients need me.
No, I was not gonna say that.
What I was gonna
say is that you...
you need your patients.
Work, Nic,
is the only way out of grief.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
See the mother and child?
Think something's wrong.
- Hey.
- I know.
- You okay?
- Um...
It's my baby. She's been
sick, coughing and wheezing.
Well, let's get her
in to see a doctor.
No. The last time
I went into an ER,
it cost me $6,000.
The hospital sued
me when I couldn't pay,
and now they're docking
it from my paycheck.
We can't live off
what we have left.
I came here to have her seen
in the free clinic,
but it was closed.
That's horrible.
So I've been waiting out here,
hoping Diana would get better.
She's wheezing badly. We
need to get her in there now.
Oh, it's okay.
- Come on.
Surgery was successful.
We're certain we
got all the shrapnel.
How do you feel?
Like I just got split in half.
How are you doing?
That's typical Annie Diamonte.
Worried about
everybody but yourself.
I got a few bruises.
Small fracture of an ankle bone,
but it won't even need surgery.
We should stop talking.
You need your rest.
In the injury Olympics,
you solidly got me beat.
When can I go home,
Dr. Hawkins, do you think?
I'd rather not stay here
any longer than I have to.
What... like, what,
a week or two?
Temperature's 102.5.
- Sats are back up in the 90s.
- Is she okay?
She has bilateral wheezes
and is using accessory
muscles. Likely an infection.
Labs are back. Viral
swab is positive for RSV.
Everyone put on a mask and gown.
Eloise,
RSV is extremely dangerous
for people who have
had a lung transplant.
I'm aware. I'm gloved.
I'm gowned. I have a mask.
Can you all please
stop coddling me
and treat me like
any other sub-I?
No, because you
aren't any other sub-I.
This has gone on long enough.
Please leave.
Now.
Dr. Feldman's right.
I'll come find you
when I'm done here.
Right lower lobe infiltrate,
and her white blood cell count
and procalcitonin
are up. I'm afraid
she might have developed
a bacterial pneumonia.
Oh, God, I'm so
sorry. What did I do?
Even with continuous nebs,
her respiratory rate
is still in the 40s.
We might need to
intubate. Let's get her
on IV ceftriaxone and azithro,
and let's get her
to the PICU now.
What?
So, it looks like RSV plus
a bacterial pneumonia.
Probably strep, if I were
to put my money on it.
The most common
bacterial pathogen
- in children her age.
- Not bad.
You know your stuff.
My expertise in
infection control
is only surpassed by my
encyclopedic knowledge
- of lung disease.
- Cystic fibrosis will do that.
Sure will.
Some of your antirejection
meds will cause that tremor.
Goes away over time.
Shouldn't be a
problem by intern year.
Look, I'm sorry that Dr. Feldman
was harsh back there,
but it is our job
to keep you safe.
This is my body and my life.
I'm not anybody's
kid to protect.
Safety isn't my main priority.
I go white water rafting
every chance I get.
I even go skydiving.
You're not scared?
Course I'm scared.
Every time I cough, I
think about rejection.
But I want to live,
and that means risk.
What you all need to remember is
I'm a doctor in training
now, not your patient.
I couldn't understand what
was going on in the ER.
What's wrong?
I promise you
she's in great hands.
She has RSV and
bacterial pneumonia.
She needs oxygen, antibiotics
- and fluids.
- I can't believe
I let it get this bad.
- If only I...
- It's not your fault.
You were put in an
impossible situation.
The system is broken.
Yeah.
- You the mom?
- Yeah.
You can come in now.
She's doing better.
Thank you.
Hmm. If the clinic
were still open,
we could have
treated her daughter
with antibiotics and
avoided all of this.
Red Rock cut the funding.
You can't run a
clinic without money.
Mm-hmm. But if you came
back, we could find the money.
One way or another.
I can't do it alone,
but we can together, Nic.
Yeah, it's palinopsia.
She's continuing
to see something
after it's no longer there.
Very common after head trauma.
Don't tell me we got
this woman through a fire,
an explosion and a
life-threatening injury
only to find out she
has a brain tumor.
♪ ♪
I just heard.
Annie has a brain tumor?
I'm so sorry.
How bad is it?
Well, she has a
posterior cortical lesion,
a small hemorrhagic
component and edema.
That accounts for
her new symptoms.
No signs of cancer
anywhere else. Yet.
So it might not be metastatic.
The radiologist
couldn't be certain.
We need to see
the pathology report.
Cain is certain he can remove
- all of it.
- What? He can't know that
until he's actually in there.
Dibs.
Would you like me to start
your playlist, Dr. Cain?
You know it.
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh... ♪
Texas born and bred.
♪ Yeah, I'm gonna
take my horse ♪
♪ To the old town road ♪
♪ I'm gonna ride till
I can't no more... ♪
Probe.
♪ To the old town road ♪
- ♪ I'm gonna ride ♪
- ♪ Kio ♪
- ♪ Till I can't no more ♪
♪ I got the horses in the back ♪
♪ Horse tack is attached ♪
♪ Hat is matte black ♪
♪ Got the boots
that's black to match ♪
♪ Ridin' on a horse, ha ♪
♪ You can whip your Porsche ♪
♪ I been in the valley ♪
♪ You ain't been up
off that porch, now ♪
♪ Can't nobody tell me nothin' ♪
♪ You can't tell me nothin' ♪
♪ My life is a movie ♪
♪ Bull ridin' and boobies ♪
♪ Cowboy hat from Gucci ♪
♪ Wrangler on my booty ♪
Forceps.
♪ Can't nobody tell me nothin' ♪
♪ You can't tell me nothin' ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm gonna take my
horse to the old town road ♪
♪ I'm gonna ride
till I can't no more ♪
♪ I'm gonna take my horse
to the old town road... ♪
I can promise the
margins will be clean.
That's one for the win column.
Send that to
pathology. Close it up.
- Cain did that
in under five minutes.
- Yeah, but
can we be sure he got
it all and left her intact?
Haste usually isn't
a virtue in surgery.
Especially on the brain.
He's trusting a resident
he's never met to
close, unsupervised.
I wonder if he even cares
about the pathology report.
His job is done, guys.
Is that thing in my head?
You know none of this would've
happened if you hadn't run away
from me in the ER in
the first place, right?
You have to promise me you
will never do that again, okay?
This is a bummer.
I know, but the good news
is you'll make a full recovery
and be as good as new.
Thanks to Dr. Voss.
Thank you so much.
Oh. You're welcome.
That was fine work.
I fully admit I live
for days like this.
It's why I love my job.
So Dr. Cain is throwing a
private party this Saturday.
I heard.
Just for our top doctors.
How lovely for you all.
- You're invited.
- No, I'm not.
I'm inviting you now.
I want you to meet Cain
and get to know him.
Do you like him?
He's impressive by any measure.
So far, I like him very much.
I just... I want him beside
me as your advocate.
I need an advocate?
Yes.
Because I don't bill enough.
If... It doesn't matter
what the reason is.
I know your value as a
doctor and as a friend.
And your place at Chastain
will always be secure
as long as I'm CEO.
I would just like you to
have this man as an ally.
I'll pick you up at 6:00.
Looking very distinguished
with your cane.
Thank you.
Small consolation
on a rough day.
What did Annie's
pathology report say?
It's melanoma.
Which means Annie
probably has Stage IV cancer.
God, I'm so sorry.
Not exactly one
for the win column.
Cain already broke the news
that she has a
terminal diagnosis.
I'll at least give the
guy credit for doing that.
Annie.
Mm-hmm.
It is so good to see you.
This is Nic Nevin.
She's been with me,
following your case
throughout the day.
I just wanted to say
thank you so much
for everything you
did during the fire.
Oh, it's nothing that you
wouldn't have done in my place.
Is there anything that
we can do for you?
How are your spirits?
That's what we want to know.
It's crazy, but my
spirits are really good.
You know, after
talking to Dr. Cain,
I feel like the luckiest
unlucky person ever.
- What did he say?
- Well, he said if I hadn't
have been in the
basement and gotten injured,
it's possible they might not
have caught my cancer in time.
What did Dr. Cain say
about what's ahead?
Well, if this was
a few years ago,
he would've been
arranging hospice care.
But today, with all the
drugs for melanoma,
I could be around
for decades to come.
That's true. Immunotherapy has
had great success with melanoma,
and they're always
coming out with new things.
And Dr. Cain said I
just need to be positive.
- Fight through it, right?
- Right.
I don't want to
think about death
any more than I already have.
Conrad told me
you lost your son.
I'm very sorry.
Yeah.
That's when I stopped racing.
I see it was a big mistake now.
Y-You can't stop
living your life
just 'cause someone
you love has lost theirs.
You got to remember
the good times.
Get rid of the bad
times and go on.
I'm gonna compete
again real soon.
I'm just gonna fight to get well
and fight through the chemo.
And you know who's gonna
be with me right through it?
My son.
Because, you see, he...
he never really left me.
He just came to live here,
in my heart.
♪ Let's make it last forever ♪
♪ 'Cause the
night's still young ♪
♪ It's true, I feel the pressure
♪ Every time you're gone ♪
Wow.
His office has a
better view than mine.
And what does that tell you?
That he bills 80 million a year.
You're kidding.
You didn't tell me that.
Well, if I had, you
wouldn't be here.
You know as well
as I do that anyone
-who bills that much runs
multiple ORs -Shh, shh.
-at the same time,
overtreats, -Okay. Okay.
Has side deals with
device companies.
Okay, okay. So I shouldn't
have told you, just don't start.
This-this is the reality
of health care today.
We'll fight it when necessary,
we'll accommodate when possible,
and we'll deal
with it to survive.
Barrett.
I would like you to meet our
very best orthopedic surgeon
and my good
friend, Dr. Kit Voss.
I'm glad to finally meet you.
What you pulled
off... Saving a child
who suffered an
internal decapitation...
- That was miraculous.
- Oh, thank you.
Flattery will get
you everywhere...
with anyone but me.
A word, Randolph.
- When you get a minute.
- Absolutely.
Pleasure.
Why'd you do that?
W-What is the point
of alienating the man?
What is the point of making
nice when I know who he is?
I am still trying
to wrap my head
around the fact that
you hired someone
who so obviously has
an ego the size of Texas.
I... Red Rock Mountain
Medical hired him,
and I understand why they did.
Health care is a
business. I'm a realist.
This is what's happening
from coast to coast.
They're recruiting guys
like Cain. It's everywhere.
And doctors like me,
who put our patients first,
- are collateral damage.
- No.
- I'll start interviewing
elsewhere immediately.
- No. K-Kit.
- Please, don't. Don't.
- I'm sorry.
But I don't belong here.
I see your, uh,
your companion left.
- Yeah.
- You know what, I don't want you
to spend this evening alone.
See that young lady right there?
I can introduce you.
I'm telling you,
Randolph, stick with me
and we'll rise together.
The sky's the limit
for men like us.
Ladies, thank you for coming.
♪ ♪
♪ Silent soldier
in the night... ♪
I need you to help
me with something.
I, uh, I can't rest.
I can't let Jessie go without
knowing what really happened.
Please, just take
a look at this.
It's Jessie's medical records.
I just-I just want to know
that nothing terrible happened,
everything was done right.
You know how
Nic feels about this.
This isn't about a lawsuit.
I gave that up.
I just want the truth.
I must have the truth.
For Jessie.
Mwah.
Think I'm ready.
I know.
♪ Peace will find
the restless ones ♪
♪ Find me... ♪
Thank you.
I love you.
♪ You were... ♪
I love you, too, Jessie.
♪ Born to fly ♪
♪ Fly ♪
♪ To fly ♪
♪ Born to fly. ♪
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH