You know your tailbone?
It used to be a tail.
Sofia!
That pink part in the
corner of your eye?
It used to be a third eyelid.
Skull is cracked. They said
he went through the windshield?
V-tach. No pulse!
Paddles! Charge to 100!
Donald Mercer.
The appendix used to
help us digest tough foods.
Now it does nothing.
Clear!
The story of our evolution
is the story of what
we leave behind,
what we've discarded.
Oh!
Uh, explain, please.
Oh, sofia got fruit
juice all over it.
And, as you know, she could
fry the microprocessor in here.
Now I'm gonna be late. And I've
told her not to play with my leg!
Uh, no, you haven't
actually, ever.
Hey, um, I found these.
Um, where should I put them?
What?
Your wheelie sneaks.
Oh. Trash.
Really? Yeah. Callie, it's fine.
Our bodies only hang on
to the things we
absolutely need.
Clear!
Okay, I've got a
rhythm. I got a pulse.
Wait.
The things we no
longer have use for...
No pupillary response,
no pain response,
visible brain matter, no
evidence of brain activity.
- I think we lost him.
- We give up...
Maybe there's a mistake, please.
I need to see him.
We let go.
Jared Cole, suffered
Byler's disease since birth,
complains of increasing
jaundice, edema, frequent fevers...
So his condition has
gotten much worse.
And if the bile
continues to build up,
then we're looking at
cirrhosis or possible liver failure.
He has to go on the
list now, for a transplant?
We have one more chance to
avoid it, uh, a diversion procedure.
We'll take a piece
of his intestine
and create a detour for the bile
to drain out through his abdomen.
I'll have a hole in my stomach?
I know, that sounds weird.
But it's our best shot
so that you don't feel like
you're getting sick all the time
and so you don't look
like an Oompa Loompa.
Does that sound good?
Sweetie, the doctor
asked you a question.
Are you a robot?
Jared Cole, manners!
I am so sorry.
No, no. That's a valid question.
No, I'm not a robot.
I'm almost that cool.
I got into an accident
and I lost my leg.
And then they gave me a new one.
Can you jump super-high?
No.
See you in there.
After all he's been through,
we gotta cut up his
perfectly healthy intestine
and put a hole in his belly?
Hey, you saw his
bilirubin. He's out of options.
Wilson, go check on his
coags before we go to surgery.
You're gonna need to
assign someone else.
Wilson's no longer in peds.
What? Why?
You, you're suspended
from surgery.
What?
You broke the
non-fraternization rule.
And it was just gonna be
a slap on the wrist, Karev,
until you decided to
give the board the finger.
Three days, no
surgery. Wilson, the ER.
I have my Byler's kid.
You're gonna let this rule
mess with patient care?
Robbins can take that case.
Thanks. Makes my day real easy.
Well, I'm afraid it's
about to get harder.
HR wants to talk
to you today. HR?
The anonymous
harassment complaint
came from Leah Murphy.
Oh, God. Yeah.
And, legally, HR
has to investigate,
and they want you to
answer some questions.
And that might be the
end of it. And if it's not?
I have no time for this today.
No contact with Murphy, okay?
Hey, Derek! Are you
coming by the lab today?
We're starting to lose all
our phase-two momentum.
Yeah. Actually, they're
setting up my new office today.
Oh, you know what?
I got to grab a sensor.
The guys are going
to duplicate one. Yes.
The Washington
guys, mappin' the brain.
You're actually gonna have
time to do this, too, though, right?
Yeah. I hope so. I plan to.
All right. Well, let me
know when you're ready.
"Oh, yeah. Call
me. We'll hang out."
I haven't seen a blowoff
like that since high school.
It was not a blowoff. Okay.
I have nothing against Ross.
I just don't think he
should be on my service.
Look, he needs to feel
that he has your support.
He's trying to find his footing.
I know, and I think
he lost it because
I was not the best influence.
Also, we had...
inappropriate...
Shenanigans. I know.
That's what the
rule is for, Dr. Yang,
so we can work together
without the shenanigans.
I think it's a bad idea, sir,
and I think the Chief will, too.
Huh.
Well, the Chief asked me
to keep an eye on Ross.
So it's my call, not his.
And as far as you're
concerned, Dr. Yang,
I am still and will
always be the chief.
Yes, sir.
Sorry...
About what I said. I
was a complete jerk.
I heard you got busted.
Yep.
I have to miss out
on my education
so they can keep me on
a separate floor from Alex.
See, I want that rule.
If I find myself alone
in a room with Jackson,
I'm afraid I'm gonna
nut-punch him.
So every time he has a
consult in the ER today,
I'm taking a break.
You shouldn't.
You should nut-punch him.
We'd all want to see that.
He married her, Jo.
One day, he's with me,
the next day, he's not
just with her, she's his wife.
So, what the hell was I all
that time, that he could just
toss me aside like garbage?
Oh, my God.
It was right outside...
By the dumpsters.
He's warm, pulse is
weak. He's breathing fast.
Shh! Shh! Shh! Shh!
Hey, little one. How are you?
What are you, like eight
months, nine months?
Oh, what do we have here?
You've had some surgeries before.
Okay. Let's get him
up into the PICU.
Uh, I'll get a peds gurney.
So, page cardio
and call the police.
Get prints, any
identifying marks,
find out if he was
born here, seen here.
We're gonna find out
who this little guy is.
Oh! Oh! Oh!
I'm sorry! I'm so sorry!
Are you okay?
Oh, I think you broke my leg.
Oh! Oh, my God!
It's all right.
I have another
one in my car. Oh.
What happened? Oh, I'm fine.
I was walking, and...
What happened?
I'm fine! I had an
accident, my leg got broken,
and someone's bringing
me a spare. I'm fine.
Oh, God! I'm sorry!
I got it. I got the leg. Uh-huh.
Oh, Dr. Robbins, I am so
sorry. Edwards, you know what?
You should go page cardio and
then go do a work-up on the baby.
I'll go with her.
Whoa, Wilson, what baby?
We found a baby in the trash.
No, you're not
doing the work-up.
But it's my dumpster baby!
You're not on peds. I
have a patient for you.
Oh, Bailey,
I have a Byler's biliary
diversion surgery today,
and I lost Karev,
so can you assist?
You got it!
Okay, everybody out. Please.
Oh.
Hey. Are you okay?
Hey.
Yeah, my neck's a little
sore, and my leg is totaled.
Oh, geez. Now I have
to wear my old beater leg.
I thought you said
this chafes you.
Well, it's better than nothing
until my other one's fixed.
All right. Here.
Oh, um, can you make it
to round on Alyssa Cramer?
The club-feet girl? She's back?
Yeah, scar revision.
Oh, yeah. Okay. Hey, um,
listen. HR wants to talk to me.
Mmm-hmm.
The anonymous harassment
claim came from Leah Murphy.
All right. You good here?
Yeah. Thank you.
Mmm-hmm.
I understand
that I broke a rule,
but I don't think it's fair for
this to affect my education.
You spend more time on
peds than any other service.
Because I'm interested in peds!
Yeah, well, I'm interested
in giving you a
well-rounded education.
So today, you're on trauma,
and this is your patient.
Mr. Donald Mercer
is an organ donor.
He was injured in
an MVC this morning.
We're waiting the six hours to
confirm the diagnosis of brain death.
Okay. Now, you
will make sure that
his organs are in optimum
condition for donation,
and then you will get to
scrub in on the organ recovery.
You got it? But that's like
six surgeries in one! Mmm-hmm.
Trauma's not so bad now, huh?
So sorry.
She's filled out all
the donor paperwork.
She just wants a couple
minutes with him before
she starts making
arrangements. Of course.
Excuse me, uh, Doctor?
This isn't the right time for this,
I'm sure. I mean,
there probably isn't one.
But I feel like it can't wait.
How can we help?
Donnie had a kidney
transplant about four months ago.
Yeah, we knew about
that. That was me.
I donated my kidney
for him. Wow. That's...
He was lucky to
have friends like you.
He was. Yeah. Uh,
amazing. So, um...
I was wondering,
about the kidney.
Can I get that back?
Yeah, I can see you. I don't
know why you can't see me.
But we're still
setting up here, so...
Yes. So, then you did
get all the proposals?
Um...
Uh, yeah. Yep. Yep. They're
right here. Great, great.
And, um, you're sending us a
prototype of your asymmetrical sensor?
Yeah, sending it out today.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
And, obviously,
discontinue any other work
you'll be doing
with the sensors,
and I will e-mail you a
release for the patent.
Wait, I'm sorry, "Discontinue"?
My work with
Dr. Torres is ongoing.
Uh, well, not with your sensors.
They have to be proprietary
to the work that we're doing.
Our NIH grant is dependent
on that. You understand?
I'm not sure Dr. Torres will.
And I have to say,
Lloyd, I don't like it.
Uh, well, I'm, uh...
I'm sorry, Derek,
but it's pretty clear
from our agreement,
we and the NIH hired you,
and your sensors come with you.
Oh, hey, little guy.
What do we know?
He's had a median sternotomy,
a couple of chest tubes.
Low sats, high BP, failure to
thrive. Have you cuddled him?
No, I have not.
Well, if I were left
in a cardboard box,
all I'd want is cuddling, right?
Oh, I think I'd
want a cardiac cath
to confirm I've had a
coarctation of my aorta.
He is like a puzzle that I can't
solve... If you're gonna do that...
Do you have a coarctation
of your aorta? Do you?
No record of the baby
being a former patient.
The police are getting statements
from Edwards and Wilson.
Ooh!
God, sorry.
Um, I have a patient,
so will you call me
when you're done with
his cath? Mmm-hmm.
Ross, you want to take
the baby? I'd rather not.
Ross, take the baby. Come here.
Are you squeaking?
Long story.
Can I put him down now?
No. She's right. He
should be cuddled.
You're not gonna hurt
him. And I don't want to do it.
Did I hear you found a baby?
Yes. In a box, abandoned.
Oh, is it all right?
I don't know.
I imagine it's
pretty traumatized,
having been
suddenly left behind,
thrown aside... Stephanie...
dumped, as it
were, in the trash.
Would you please let me talk?
You really want to
get out of my way.
Three days I'm
suspended from surgery.
You bang a co-worker, and
you get a house and two kids.
I do it and I get suspended.
I know. I'm a
hypocrite, I've heard.
I'm supposed to do a
biliary diversion. I like this kid.
I've been treating
him for years.
I want to make
sure it's done right.
But do me a favor. Talk to Hunt.
See if he'll start my
stupid sentence tomorrow.
I will. I'm gonna talk
to him. Thank you.
You're a hypocrite and you suck!
Hey, did you hear, uh, Grumpy
and Hairball found
a baby in the trash?
Emma Marling came by
to get a key for the trailer.
Why are you telling me this?
It's gossip. I'm gossiping.
Oh, okay. Shoot.
To get her things because
her and Owen are through.
Through? Why? I don't
know. She didn't say.
But I don't think
it was her idea.
I can't tell if you're
happy or sad.
Neither can I.
It hurts like a bitch, Dad!
Don't talk like that!
Don't talk to me
like I'm a baby!
We've gone over this and...
- Hey! Hey!
Hey, Alyssa. Herb.
Guys, what's going on?
We're just gonna do another
stupid surgery, and I'll still be in pain.
- Simmer down.
- No, no. I know.
Your arthrogryposis
symptoms are worsening,
but today's surgery
will alleviate the scarring
and hopefully the pain, too.
You said that before
my last surgery.
I know.
And the one before that
and the one before that!
Stop it. They are trying to help
you! You keep lying to me about...
I have had braces and castings
and surgeries, and none of it works!
So, I want to know... Don't.
If you can just cut them off.
Just give me the fake legs.
Then I can still do all
the stuff I want to do.
Yeah, she's been talking
like this for a month now.
Please tell her that I am
not gonna allow anybody...
What? Disable me?
Dad, I am disabled
now! I still can't walk!
It hurts when I stand for
more than three minutes.
I'll never run! It hurts
when I try to sleep!
Tell her she's being
ridiculous. You are!
She won't talk to me.
I live in a bed, Dad,
and there are girls running
marathons with fake legs!
Alyssa.
It has. It has been a long
road. Look at how long.
And I know. I know it hurts.
And it feels like you
can't go any further,
but this is the time
you have to be brave
and push through
it and have faith.
Even if it's not working yet,
it's going to work.
Right?
I'm not so sure about that.
I cannot believe that you
didn't back me up in there.
I mean, a kid wants
to cut off her legs!
I'm just suggesting that you
don't dismiss it out of hand.
Hey, Callie, you got a minute?
Something kind of
unexpected came up.
Hold on a sec. Really?
Because it sounds to me like
you're asking me to just throw away
three years' worth of hard work
and investment in this girl,
just cut it off and throw it
away like it never happened.
And I don't want to do that.
I'm sorry, Derek. What is it?
Nothing. I'm good.
Somebody tried to
fix his coarctation.
Did a hack job.
Look, it's closing up already.
Um, I'm going to reopen, um...
Prep a balloon catheter.
Did you notice anything
about his mitral valve?
I don't know.
Shane, come on.
This is like a puzzle.
I found the corner pieces.
I need help with the sky.
The valve leaflets were
thickened and shortened.
A parachute mitral valve?
Yes. And there's a
supravalvular mitral ring.
The three indicate...
Coarctation,
supravalvular mitral
ring and parachute...
Shone's Complex?
Bingo.
A trifecta of congenital
heart defects.
That answers another
question. What?
Why they abandoned him.
The kid had one heart surgery.
He needed at least two more.
Someone thought he was
more trouble than he's worth.
What are you doing
here? Go away.
What are you doing? Organ donor.
I have to keep him alive
until he's actually dead.
Nice. I'm off peds, and Hunt's
got you arranging a meat platter.
I know. But I'm gonna show him.
I'm gonna keep his
organs so healthy,
someone could use his appendix.
You should go. If Hunt
shows up, he's gonna...
We could use his appendix.
It was a joke. We don't
donate... No, that could work.
Karev, don't make me
turn three days into a week.
Did I get too close to Wilson?
Did an alarm go off somewhere?
But it's a donor organ,
so it can't be regifted.
I don't understand,
though. It's mine.
Yes. Yes. It was yours,
but then you gave it to him.
And now he's not using it,
and I'm still down one kidney.
I loaned him my bike. I'm
probably gonna get that back.
I should wait a
month or so. Sir, um,
transplanting the kidney put a
pretty big strain on the organ.
To do it again would be
risky for you and your kidney.
See? His kidney.
You said "my kidney." You
think I should get it back.
Um, I actually... I have
to be elsewhere right now.
Oh. Oh, no. Of course.
Yeah, no. I'll wait here.
Ouch.
We don't have to
cut Jared's intestine.
What? Jared Cole.
Instead of the intestine, we use
the appendix to make the stoma.
It's easier on him,
and it's repurposing
something he
doesn't need anyway.
That's the same procedure,
resulting in a
cutaneous end-stoma?
Even easier. And the
appendix is narrower,
so a smaller hole in his
stomach, more normal life.
Reduces complications,
recovery time and...
Oh, crap.
Uh, sorry. I didn't
know you were, um...
Uh, I can wait
till you're finished.
No, Alex, it's fine.
'Cause I never see
you like that. You okay?
Yeah. It's a blister.
I think using the appendix is
a great idea. Let's look into it.
Well, I can get him prepped.
Whoa, oh. This does not
mean that you're scrubbing in.
I'm sorry.
He just came off his
hinges when he saw you.
Yeah, there are two
different looks that you get.
Without the leg on,
they feel sorry for you.
And with the leg on, they think
that you're amazing and brave.
Yeah. Or a robot.
Hey. Any word from the police
about my mystery baby in a box?
No. Social
Services is on it now.
What's his status?
Uh, he needs a
mitral valve repair,
which I'm gonna do tomorrow.
He's already been
through enough for one day.
Yeah.
So, what's this I hear
about you being an idiot?
You broke up with
her? She was it, Owen.
The picket fence, a dozen
kids, fresh baked goods.
I don't want to talk
about that, okay?
Because you're dumb? No,
because it's between her and me.
And I hurt her, and I feel bad,
so I don't want
to talk about it.
Why throw that away?
Is it because of what
happened at the trailer?
That was... Give me some credit.
I know what that was.
Then why?
Okay, all right. Why are
you so upset about it?
Hmm? Uh, uh, because...
Because, why?
Because of what
happened in the trailer?
I don't care for the
direction this is taking.
I'll tell you if you tell me.
No.
Dr. Robbins.
Hey, Herb.
Can I ask you a question?
Do you have kids?
Yes, I do. I have a little girl.
You have a little girl,
and you can still tell me that I
should cut my daughter's legs off?
No.
Ultimately, that's her decision.
But she can't make
it without your help.
You think her life's gonna
be better with no legs?
You think kids aren't
gonna stare at her,
that they're not gonna make
fun of her if she's crippled?
Disabled... Crippled, disabled.
What difference does it make?
I don't care what you call it.
How can you say that?
I never thought that
I'd carry my daughter
or be a doctor again.
And now there's very few
things I can't do because of this.
When did that happen?
I've had it since before we met.
I didn't notice. Why would you?
Herb,
Alyssa's arthrogryposis
is so severe,
and her muscles put too
much strain on her joints.
And it won't get worse,
but the pain will never stop.
It's just me and
her now, and I don't
want to make the wrong
decision. I know. I know.
She's your little girl.
46-year-old male, complains
of tightness in chest,
possibly heart-related,
probably enchilada-related.
Pulse in the 70s, BP 170/110.
Trauma two.
You do any more
bowling for doctors today?
What? You heard?
Oh, it's all over the radio.
Oh, my God.
Oh, I'm just
saying, the next time
you do it, try and
take out Kepner.
Oh! Oh, God!
That'll work, too.
Guys, I'm fine, okay?
I'm so sorry.
No, no. You warned me
to stay out of your way.
Was Robbins your warm-up?
I didn't do this on purpose.
Edwards, I'm about
to take his pants off.
Go be someplace where you
won't be a danger to others.
What happened? Oh, God.
Um...
I'm fine, okay? I
got hit by a gurney.
There she is!
All right, Dr. Edwards!
Welcome back!
Yeah! Two for two!
Hey, Chief. Can I talk
to you for a second?
Yeah. What is it, Grey?
So, it's about Alex
Karev. Uh, sorry.
Um, Robbins? Have
you been up to HR today?
Oh, no. I haven't had a chance.
We've been developing a biliary
diversion using the appendix.
Right. I was gonna have
all the interns observe.
That is a pretty
inventive approach.
But, Robbins, HR needs
that statement today.
Yeah, okay. Um...
Bailey, why don't you
go on up without me?
And by the time
that you have Jared
on the table, I'll be
done with this thing.
And you should get
someone to assist you, too.
Oh, uh, I'll take
Grey. Right, no!
Well, that's what I
wanted to talk to you
about, because
it's Karev's case.
It was his idea, so
he should be on it.
Karev's suspended. You're on it.
Terrific.
Hey. I have to tell Karev
that I stole his surgery.
Oh, I have to tell Torres that
the President won't let her
use my sensors anymore.
Just tell her you made a
promise to her, but instead,
you're gonna spend your time
and energy on something else.
It worked when you told me.
I thought we were
gonna help each other.
You left yourself
wide open there.
Callie's a grown-up.
She knows how research
works. Just tell her.
And Karev will be
understanding about it.
Oh, no. I'm not telling him.
Did you get to talk to her?
No. I was on the floor.
She didn't do it on
purpose, did she?
No. No. I don't think so.
Maybe.
Well, what about you?
Did you talk to Matthew?
I left another message.
Nicole said he quit,
and then she called me a
name. So that's all I know.
Can you just talk to her,
apologize for both of us?
I'm trying.
Nurses' station.
Oh!
God, you scared me!
Any word on my kidney?
You were gonna
give it some thought.
Uh, no. No, I wasn't.
Oh, Dr. Hunt!
Um, do we return
donor organs to donors
when the recipient passes on?
Absolutely not. UNOS
is very strict about this.
Um, why do you want it?
Well, it's the
principle, isn't it?
You know, these are not
the terms of the agreement.
I donated my
organ for a purpose,
to filter my buddy's
pee or whatever it does.
And now it's just
being discarded.
So I think I have a right
to get my kidney back.
I'm not quite following. Is, um,
your other kidney failing?
It could. You never know
what's gonna happen, right?
You're just fine, sir.
Am I?
Oh, wow! Uh, that's
my pager vibrating.
Uh-huh. Oh! Oh! Is
yours vibrating, too?
Oh, yeah, it is. It's
urgent. Um... Okay.
We're very sorry
about your friend.
I'm sorry.
Is he stalking you?
Uh...
Hey.
Herb Cramer just told me that
you were pushing him toward
an amputation for Alyssa.
No. I wasn't pushing
anything, Callie,
but, I mean, it's
the right thing to do.
And you've done palliative
amputations before.
Yeah, on a soldier! A grown man.
Not a child whose
legs I have been
trying to correct
for three years!
And failing. I'm
sorry. It's true.
And honestly, I
mean, before last year,
I think that you
would have seen it.
Okay. So you think
this is about you?
It's about Alyssa. It's
not about me. Yeah.
But it's not about you, either.
Why would you say
that it's not about me?
I didn't say that
it... Because I am...
I think that you're afraid
to do this amputation,
and I'm afraid that
that might be my fault.
Dr. Robbins? Hi.
I'm Anne, from HR.
We're ready for you upstairs.
Okay, thanks.
I... Yeah.
There's just a few
questions we need to go over.
It shouldn't take long.
I'm sure you're busy.
Clear!
Shane, no! Don't shock him!
His heart can't
take defibrillation!
I thought so, too.
So I tried to stabilize
him with cardioversion.
One shock, timed in the
refractory period of his heartbeat,
to get a good sinus rhythm.
And I think it worked.
Good call, Ross.
He could have a
mitral valve rupture.
Uh, clear an OR, page Robbins
and set up for a redo sternotomy.
Okay. CALLIE: They what?
They want my sensors
proprietary to them,
which means they can no
longer be used for our research.
Well, we can't do our
research without them.
I know. Well, what
are you gonna do?
This isn't gonna keep you
from doing their project, is it?
Ah. Callie, I never
expected them to do this.
Okay.
I'm going to try to fight them
on this, but in the meantime...
You understand?
Uh, I think so.
You partnered up with me,
but now you're taking our ball
and you're gonna go
play with your new friends.
I understand that
the last six months
was a complete waste of my time.
She understands.
And at that point, Dr. Torres
handed her the drill, correct?
And that's when Dr. Murphy drilled
through Dr. Torres' patient's leg
and into the table?
That's correct, yes.
At the time of that incident,
you said you had terminated
any romantic relationship
with Dr. Murphy?
I had, yes.
There was no
contact of a romantic
or sexual nature
after the incident?
No. There was not.
Okay.
Oh, I have an emergency.
I'm sorry. I have to...
No problem. That's
really all I need.
Well, you... That's it? You
don't need me to come back?
Mmm, no. Or do you have more...
No. No. It's just, I mean, if I'm
being accused of something,
I think that I should
have a little more time to,
you know, to speak
my... Oh, no. Don't worry.
Dr. Murphy didn't lodge
the complaint against you.
Thank you.
Hey. What happened?
Oscar had flash pulmonary edema.
His mitral valve blew.
I'm gonna go fix it.
I was stuck in HR.
Is Murphy coming after you?
Worse, actually. Her
complaint is against Callie.
Callie? Why? I don't know.
No, I mean, I know, but
I didn't want to believe it.
Right. "Oscar."
'Cause you found
him in a trash can.
Hey, do you need to be
in your Byler's surgery?
'Cause I'm good here. You sure?
Yeah. I've got Ross.
Oh.
Okay, that's Callie now.
Um, come find me after?
Yeah. Okay.
Tell Dr. Bailey to go
ahead and start without me.
I'll be there as soon as I can.
They asked for you.
I just need to hear it again.
Tell me that you think
this is the right idea.
I do.
Dr. Torres has
done everything that
anyone could do
to stop your pain,
but... It's not working.
And by every indication,
more surgery will just mean
more time in a hospital bed,
more scarring and
the same results.
Pain for the rest of her life.
She'll never run?
I'll never walk her
down the aisle?
Not unless we amputate.
Instead of the surgery that
you have scheduled for today,
please schedule a
double amputation.
I want her pain to stop today.
Okay.
Thank you, Daddy.
Callie. No, it's fine.
It's just one more thing today.
Thank you, Doctor.
HR wants to see you.
Leah Murphy's
complaint is against you.
They wanted Hunt to tell
you, but I asked if I could.
I thought that I, you know...
Okay, well, um...
I, uh, have to push
this amputation...
No, I'll take that off your
plate. I mean, I'll do it.
And you come find
me when you're done?
I'm sorry.
You know, I just got
through a malpractice suit.
Now I have to deal with
your jealous ex-girlfriend
trying to ruin my reputation?
I swear to God, I can't
take any more of this!
The heart has so
many abnormalities.
It's incredibly fragile. Cut.
Uh, 4-0 prolene.
You have to really be delicate.
I want to ask you
about something,
but there are all
these new rules,
and, uh, the act of me
asking might be breaking them.
You can ask.
There was a complaint.
That's a question?
I thought it might be you.
It wasn't.
I know, but it made me wonder
if you ever felt compromised.
Because I didn't want you to.
I didn't.
Good.
Oh, now that
sounds like coercion.
Like I'm telling you how
you were supposed to feel.
I didn't take it that way.
Really?
You're not just saying
that to curry favor?
No. I'm not "currying" anything.
Because you never
have to do that.
You don't have to
get Shepherd coffee
or fix Callie's baby schedule
or relax me.
You're too good
of a doctor for that.
And when you look
back in 10 years,
you'll be relieved you didn't.
I don't know if I'll even
be a doctor in 10 years.
Oh, shut up. You
will. You better.
Now, that's coercion.
That should be you down there.
Who cares? I'm doing
an organ recovery.
Screw peds.
I'll basically be on general,
cardiothoracic, ortho, plastics
and pulmonary in one operation.
Wow. I've got to go up to HR
to fill out an accident report.
Oh, for hitting
Robbins with a gurney?
For hitting Jackson
with a gurney.
Yeah.
Ahem!
Robbins should
be here to see this.
Looks good.
Appendix is holding.
Uh, Grey, will you intubate the
stoma, make sure it's patent?
Oh, crap. What? What happened?
What? What's going on?
He's gone into v-fib. I
pushed epi and atropine.
Did you shock him?
You gotta shock him!
Dr. Wilson, he's already gone!
No! There are at
least nine people
counting on him not to be gone!
Move! Clear!
What are you doing here?
You asked for a resident.
I'm the only one available.
I'll do it myself.
Are you actually gonna do that?
You're gonna refuse
to work with me...
Leah, I cared for you.
I liked you, and
that's all that it was.
And I am sorry that I hurt you.
But if you're gonna come after
my wife now because of the...
I know what our relationship
was. I'm not a child.
I never thought of
it in terms of work.
It was you who brought
it into the hospital.
You told Dr. Torres about us,
and Dr. Torres
chose not to teach me
in a moment that put
a patient in danger.
She made me put a
patient in danger. So did you.
I never thought that...
You were thinking
about yourself.
It wasn't safe, it wasn't fair,
and I had to say something.
Because it shouldn't happen
again, to me or anyone.
You want to cut the fibula 1 to 2
centimeters proximal to the tibia.
Then you're gonna
reshape the end with a bevel
so that the prosthesis
will fit better.
You watching? Good.
'Cause you're gonna
do the other leg yourself.
Hey. Hi, Kim.
How are you feeling?
I feel pretty good.
Yeah. And you don't
look like a basketball.
You did a good job.
Yeah, well, I had to watch them,
make sure they
didn't screw it up.
Get some rest?
All right.
That was having my back?
I knew you were a hypocrite,
but that was really cold.
Stop it. You're suspended.
Somebody had to be in there.
Read this.
What is it? It's me
having your back.
I got it from HR.
It's a love contract.
A what?
It's a declaration
of a relationship.
If you sign this
and Wilson signs it,
it clears everybody
from any claims
of favoritism or
sexual harassment.
That's the stupidest
thing I ever heard of.
Well, it sounds stupid,
but HR said if you sign this that
it makes the whole thing go away.
So, sign it. No!
Well, then I'm done
trying to help you.
I can't go to her with this.
Look, I asked her to marry me
when I was freaking
out about my dad.
I scared the crap out of her.
If you guys keep
screwing with us...
How are we screwing with you?
Jo wants to be a surgeon, Mer.
She came from
nothing to be here.
Now, 'cause of me, there are
suspensions and punishments.
If you keep making it
harder, she's gonna leave me.
And if you make it too hard,
she's gonna be like
Izzie and she'll walk.
Will you just sign
the stupid paper?
Watch his sats
through the night.
Below 85, page me.
Uh, is that Oscar's file?
The baby? Yes.
And that stays with him, right?
And his name, Dr. Shane Ross.
The adoptive parents
will have questions.
In 10 years, Oscar
And you will answer them.
You know, I could sue you guys.
I could sue this
entire hospital.
Sir, you signed away your
legal rights to the kidney
when you agreed to be a donor!
No, he broke our deal.
The terms were I give
him my kidney to use,
and he has broken our deal!
It was a gift! He threw it away!
Thom! Step back right
now, or I will call security.
Dr. Kepner. Wilson...
Donald Mercer
suffered cardiac death.
Organ recovery's called
off. It's all going in the trash.
Dr. Wilson, Thom here
is Mr. Mercer's friend.
Oh, I'm sorry.
No. No, he what? Donald what?
He died, Thom.
No, I don't understand. You
said he was just brain dead.
He was.
He was, and his heart
was sustaining his organs.
But now his organs
are no longer viable
for donation because he's gone.
Donald is gone.
This is not right.
This is not fair.
I know. I know it's not fair.
It's not fair at all.
No, no. He's my best
friend, since 7th grade.
I saved his life. I
gave him my kidney.
I was...
I was supposed
to have saved his...
I just... Okay.
All right, come on. I know.
Let's just sit down.
Ohh.
Hey. Oscar's doing well.
He needs more
observation, but...
Ooh!
Oh, yeah. Bad leg day.
Yeah, me too.
What would have happened if
they hadn't found him out there?
He'd be dead.
Yeah, but he's not.
He'll grow up. He'll be,
you know, who knows who.
He'll have a whole life.
Yay.
Yeah.
Do you still have
dreams about it?
Oh, yeah.
Usually when I'm anxious.
The day, um, before Sofia
started her first day of preschool,
I dreamt about it all night,
about Mark and
Lexie and the pilot,
Jerry.
Jerry. Jerry.
For me, I dream
about you screaming.
You wouldn't stop screaming.
So thank you for that.
Good job today.
Yeah. Lucky kid.
Ohh.
Lucky kid.
Just the accident report and
the worker's comp paperwork.
Shouldn't take long.
You can sit in here.
Dr. Edwards is filling out
an accident report, as well.
You two mind sharing? Brilliant.
You know what? I can come back.
No. It's fine. I'm almost done.
Okay, then.
How's your leg?
My knee is...
I'm fine.
How about you? How are you?
I didn't see you coming.
That's not what I
meant. No, I know that.
I'm sorry, Stephanie.
Will you let me say that to you,
please? Okay? I am so sorry.
I had no idea I was
gonna do that. None.
I thought I was... I told
myself that I didn't want her,
that April didn't want
me. And you and I...
Steph, you are so...
Please don't.
Don't do that. I'm trying to
say I didn't see it coming.
Okay? There's no way
I wanted to hurt you.
And I don't know how
I can make that better.
You can't.
And, anyway, we both
got a day we'll never forget.
Steph...
You got a day to tell
your grandkids about,
and I got something I'd never
gotten before. I got pitied.
I was suddenly the girl
who wasn't good enough
or smart enough or pretty
enough or not deserving.
I've never gotten that look
before because I'm not that girl.
I know that.
Look, you can hit me with as
many gurneys as you want to,
because I'm gonna
feel terrible about this
for the rest of my life.
Okay. Well, you do that
if you want to. I'm not.
I'm not going to feel sad
or angry or pitiable
for one more minute,
because I'm not
gonna care about you.
So, if I don't say hello or
make small talk in the elevator
or acknowledge your birthday
or even acknowledge you're alive,
it's because, to
me, you just exist.
Because I don't care.
Why does it feel so
good to get rid of things...
To unload...
To let go?
How did it go?
I'm going to bed.
I think Murphy was right.
Oh, of course she
was right, Arizona!
I mistreated her! And I was
petty and jealous and at my worst
because you slept with
her! Of course, she was right!
I keep thinking we're okay.
And we buy a house,
and then this happens, and
I'm not sure we'll ever be okay.
And today I lost my
research, I failed a patient,
and now I have a
disciplinary report
that's gonna follow me forever.
So I'm going to bed! I'm sorry.
I feel like all I've been doing
is thinking about myself.
God, I swear! I swear
I cannot listen to you
apologize one more time.
You have made it very
hard to keep forgiving you!
For over a year,
since the plane crash,
all I have been
thinking about is myself.
I had to figure
out how to be me.
I used to be someone
who was always happy.
I woke up happy.
I was someone who
used to skate at work.
And then this happened,
and everything was hard
and everything took
thought and planning.
And my life felt like it
didn't fit me anymore.
And I just... I wanted to
tear it all down and start over,
just throw it away and find
a life that fit who I am now.
But I'm starting to feel
like I know who I am again.
And I've had to give up things,
but what I've learned is
that I don't need much.
I don't need much to be happy.
I don't even need two legs.
But I do know that I need you.
I need Sofia,
and I need you.
And I'm afraid, now that
I've learned all of that,
that I made you give up on me.
Maybe because when we see
how little we actually
need to survive...
You shouldn't have
to give up anything.
It makes us realize how
powerful we actually are,
to strip down to
only what we need...
You want to know why
I'm upset? I'll tell you why.
Okay, why? She's
what you wanted.
You don't just throw
away a future like that.
I want you to be happy.
Oh, do you? Of course!
Or do you just want to
see me squared away?
What does that mean?
It means, uh, you want
to see me, you know,
get what I want so you don't
have to feel guilty anymore.
About what?
About not giving it to me.
Oh, whoa!
Right? Mmm.
It's either that, or you just
want to see me get married off
so you're forced to
stop thinking about me.
Oh, that's it. That's the one.
Yeah. Mmm-hmm.
To hang on only to
what we can't do without,
what we need,
not just to survive...
Yes!
But to thrive.
Oh! Oh!
Hold on to me. Okay.
Here we go!