Previously on Grey's Anatomy...
Aah!
Superman here broke protocol
and ran into the crash to
shield a kid from the blast.
Ethan. Dad.
Stay with Mom, all
right? Where is my mom?
Who are you? It's
me, Mom. Ethan.
No, it's not. Who is he?
No, I'm not going anywhere!
How about we set
you up in a room,
and you can stay with him there?
Brooks, why don't you
step up? Switch with Ross.
God, you have
fast hands, Brooks.
I know what you're doing.
Just so we're clear, I'm not
going down without a fight.
I want you to map me.
I want to know if I'm
gonna get Alzheimer's.
Patients say it all the time.
"Tell me straight up. I just
want to know what's going on."
Okay, so I've got the results of
your genome sequencing here.
Now we weren't able to get
a clear read off Zola's sample.
Sometimes we just
have to run it again.
But yours came out.
And?
"Tell me. I can handle it."
And, oh, uh, first off, I just
need to ask you a few questions.
We have a couple of different
kinds of, um, information here, so...
I have the gene. Just say it.
Look, this test gives
us tons of information.
Some of it's clear.
And some of it isn't.
So, you know, we don't
want to jump to anything
without careful
consideration of...
Yeah, I've carefully considered.
Do I have the Alzheimer's gene?
You gonna let me get
through this questionnaire?
Bailey, you're my mentor
and my friend, and
I respect your work,
but I'm telling you, if you
don't answer my question,
I will punch you in the face.
We don't dodge your
questions 'cause we're mean.
Okay, you have tested positive
for more than one of the
genetic markers for Alzheimer's.
We do it because when
you say you want the truth,
you have no idea what
you're talking about.
Shepherd says his wife's
still unconscious, too.
Oh, what did you
do with her kid?
Oh, he was in peds
overnight, just so
social services
didn't haul him off.
His grandmother comes today.
You know what? I thought I
was gonna see you last night.
Oh, I got caught
up with a patient.
Ah, that's too bad.
I put on that T-shirt
you said I'm not allowed
to wear when we're arguing
'cause it makes you
forget what your point was.
I can't believe I missed it.
I can throw it on again tonight.
I mean, why is he still out?
You said that he would wake up
when you reversed his hypothermia.
Yeah, I said he might.
Or he might eight hours
later or eight days later.
If it's any more than that, we
have a problem, but not until then.
You talk to Russell about it?
He knows about
the eight days thing.
Maybe you should
just check in with him.
You said yourself that he's not
supervising you
that much lately.
There's no news.
If I go to him with this information,
he'll think I've lost my mind.
Well, then he can
come talk to me.
Your hair looks
really nice today.
My hair looks nice every day.
I'm on Bailey's... No.
Last time I was with her, I
ordered the wrong test, twice.
If she has a three-strike
policy, I'm out.
I'm on Jackson's service today.
So even if I cared,
I wouldn't trade.
What is this?
I don't know what that is.
It is a crumb, and it
was stuck to my laptop
after you used it to update my
notes right next to a splotch of
what could either be
pizza sauce or blood.
I think it's pizza.
I was hoping it was
blood, and you were dying
and not just getting pizza
all over my computer.
I'm so sorry. I was
doing my notes late,
and I hadn't eaten...
I'll go clean it off.
These interns are sloppy.
You people are
training sloppy interns.
And I trained you,
which means you're bringing
shame to the whole family.
I just got here.
Swag bags for the Syrians.
Some, um, sweatshirts
and baseball caps, Post-its.
Really cool penlights.
Ooh, those are nice.
You're sending
Post-its to Syria?
Yeah, I'm working with
Doctors Aid International.
We've flown in
two Syrian doctors.
They're general practitioners,
but now with the war,
they've been recruited
to staff the field hospitals.
They're getting
advanced trauma training
with Seattle Pres,
and they're here
for a crash course
in basic surgical skills.
They need to learn what
they can do quick and dirty.
They rope you in?
Mmm-hmm. Which must mean that...
Yeah. Yeah, they're
losing a lot of kids.
Godspeed.
All right, let's get this stuff
with the boxes of supplies
we're sending back with them.
So Bailey got her
genome thing funded.
You got this thing funded.
I need to get my
cartilage project bankrolled
while we still got bank.
Dr. Hunt? Hmm?
Dr. Avery's recommendation
on your burn patient.
Oh. Oh.
Hey. Have you rounded
on Matthew Taylor yet?
He was one of Avery's
patients yesterday.
He was here overnight
for observation.
They were worried
about a concussion.
He'll probably
leave this afternoon.
I think his mom's
coming to get him.
Tell Avery that is fine.
Ready? Yeah.
Um, wait.
His mom is coming
to pick him up?
What, can he walk?
You'll have to ask Dr. Avery.
Joyce Basche.
You and I put in a dialysis
graft two weeks ago.
She's had fevers to 102
and the site is red and tender.
It looks infected.
Maybe you dropped a
pizza crust on her wound.
I told him it's normal, right?
It's red and swollen.
She said come in if
it was swollen or red.
He loves doctors,
you in particular.
You do like spending
time with me.
Get her healthy, we'll
have you over for dinner.
Okay, well, he's right.
So give her a gram of Cefazolin.
It's probably a
post-operative infection.
Dr. Murphy is gonna run some
labs and get an ultrasound.
We'll figure out
what's going on.
Okay.
You tested positive
for the risk factor genes.
It doesn't mean
you're gonna get it.
I know what it means.
It's entirely possible
it means nothing at all.
We need an updated will.
I want you to call the lawyer.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa. Slow down.
Even if you get the
disease, it's decades away.
It might not be.
We have a child and
we're having another child.
Look, right now, it says that
Lexie is Zola's legal guardian
if anything happens to
us. That's not going to work.
No, but...
Derek, we were in a plane crash.
We don't need Alzheimer's...
Potential Alzheimer's.
We need an updated will.
Okay. You're right. I
will contact the guy.
Okay.
Okay, we're gonna
try as closely as we can
to replicate your circumstances
in the field hospital.
The most important skills
you need in a wartime situation
is controlling bleeding.
Normally we'd use lasers
and argon beam coagulators,
but as you can see, for now,
we're only using
the contents of this tray.
Is something wrong?
We... Before had
all of these things,
but recently the supply
trucks cannot reach us,
and the electricity
is unreliable,
so many of our
instruments we cannot use,
so if you want to replicate
our circumstances,
we may need to
adjust this slightly.
Please. We're here to
make this work for you.
Thank you. Um...
This is more right.
Also...
Now we go.
Mmm.
Dr. Shepherd, hey.
I wanted to follow
up on the patients
we saw yesterday, 'cause I care.
Ross, you should be learning
something else from someone else.
Oh, I am. I'm covering the pit,
which I can do and
manage your post-ops.
Also, I brought you a latte.
It's not your job
to bring my coffee.
Sorry. I'm here. I had
to get a piece of gum.
I had epically bad breath.
I didn't want it to bowl
you over in the OR,
but I'm all set. See?
I didn't need to see it.
Okay. Well, I'm going
to check your post-ops.
Anything you'd
like me to look for?
Ross already did it.
Spectacular.
Anything we should know?
Yeah, Rachel Dawson's awake.
Um...
Tell Hunt she's up.
We're gonna send you back
with a bunch of equipment,
but if supplies aren't reaching
you and there's no electricity,
then we're gonna have
to figure out another way.
Yeah, so take a look around
and see what items you do
have left in the field hospital,
and, uh, put it in the box.
Mmm-hmm.
Dr. Hunt. Can I borrow you?
I don't think I
should go in there.
She's okay now, Ethan.
She was really mad
when she saw me before.
She wasn't mad at
you. She was confused.
There's something in her
head that they needed to fix,
and they've done that.
She's back to
her old self again.
You sure?
I don't know 100%, Ethan,
but I think we should try, okay?
All right.
Ethan?
You're okay?
Come here.
Oh.
Oh, God.
I love you so much.
Did you get hurt?
No?
You look really good.
My car crash mom woke up.
And the lawyer sent over
an e-mail with the forms.
We need two names, a
guardian and a backup.
Before it was Lexie,
Cristina, and Owen.
So Cristina and then
which one of your sisters
do you want as a backup?
Cristina doesn't want children.
This isn't children.
It's Zola and fetus.
Stop calling the baby fetus.
Well, she will love him
whatever his name is.
All right, talk to her
and see what she says.
I know what she'll say.
And I'll be wrong, and
that'll be good for everybody.
My talk was a viral sensation.
Cartilage is trending.
Because of me.
I couldn't be happier.
A cartilage regeneration lab would
be a huge boon for the hospital.
I am not an ATM.
I have one vote just like you do
and Arizona does.
Oh, no. Arizona has to vote
for me 'cause she's my wife.
And your vote is
like a vote and a half.
Uh-huh. I'll vote for myself.
Now that is a
solid voting block.
You put a lot of
thought into this, huh?
Is this how it works?
You all whisper to each
other in your board meetings
about your pet projects, and
that's where all the money goes?
That's exactly how it works.
That is not how it works.
Everybody's supposed to
submit their proposals in writing.
You can't have people
bugging board members
while they're trying to work.
Uh... You're sitting in a chair.
I need money for my orphan
thing. I want to take it global.
You see what you've done?
Who canceled my
valve replacement?
Hunt canceled half
of everybody's day.
Thank you for coming, everyone.
Sorry we had to
rearrange your schedule,
but this is important.
We've got two
Syrian doctors here.
They used to be GPs,
but now they're
operating in a field hospital
in a war zone.
We were planning on teaching
them surgical procedures
they could do with
limited resources,
but it turns out they
have way less to work with
than we anticipated.
Just give 'em more stuff.
When it runs out in two weeks,
they'll be right back where they started.
He wants to help them function
with what they know they have.
Which is this.
So, we need to
be able to do the
procedures on this list
using only what is in this box.
Are you kidding
me? There's no way.
There has to be.
We gotta figure it out.
Joyce Basche's labs.
She's in ultrasound now.
Her white count's pretty high.
And her electrolytes are off.
Um, I think we err on the
side of caution and admit her.
And, uh, this is kind of weird.
Um, we have another
post-op complication
on the same day as Mrs. Basche.
And, uh, I scrubbed in
on both of them with you.
And you managed
their post-op care?
Okay, you better go through all
your notes on both these charts
and figure out what
the hell went wrong.
Edwards, you're with me today.
I'm with Dr. Avery today.
Ditch him. Murphy's
having a time-out.
What did you do?
So the second post-op
infection was your patient, too?
Kathy Dong. Mmm-hmm.
Does she need surgery? Probably.
And Bailey got Medusa to
scrub in with her this afternoon
on the first lady that
came in with an infection.
They've gotta
take out her shunt.
It's got this huge
abscess under it.
It's a mess.
They're gonna kill me.
What did you do?
Did you forget the pre-op
antibiotics or scrub too fast?
I was sick. I had
the flu or something.
And you came in?
Of course I did.
We all work when
we're sick, all the time.
Patients have post-op
infections all the time, right?
Okay, so they can debride the
wounds with a basic instrument set,
but now they're faced
with a huge risk of infection.
Well, I guess wound vacs
are out of the question then.
Simple wet-to-dry
dressings might work?
Mmm. No.
They'd have to change
those out three times a day.
They would use their entire
gauze supply with one patient.
Sugar.
Excuse me?
It's not in the box, but
they may have it around.
It's an osmotic dressing
that allows you to avoid
multiple dressing changes.
Okay. Well, somebody go
find out if they still have sugar.
Okay.
Anything? DEREK:
You've barely made a dent.
It's gonna take forever.
Well, you try
using this hand drill,
Mr. Backseat Driver. Let me try.
If they had an infrascanner,
it would be a lot easier.
Well, they don't. I think
whoever it is, you just killed him.
You know, start
with a fresh one.
Does anybody have any Betadine?
I just have bleach.
Yeah, that'll work. Sure.
All right.
So anybody ready
to start teaching?
Uh, me. I can do
fracture repairs.
Yeah, you can put me down.
I got a blade I can
use for skin grafting.
Great. Get to the lab.
Uh, Shepherd, how long till
Rachel Dawson's out of the ICU?
Oh, check with Ross.
He's tracking her
through post-op.
Wait. I thought Brooks
was on your service today.
Ross gets connected
to the patients.
He likes to follow through.
Owen, peds just called.
Ethan Dawson's grandmother
got stuck back east.
Her flight got canceled,
and she's not gonna
make it here until tomorrow.
So I think you should
call social services
and see if they can
take him for the night.
But this is pretty
standard, right?
This must happen all the time.
It's an unusually
aggressive infection.
But we're gonna take care of it.
She said it was
nothing, and I knew it.
Steven... No.
I waited a whole day.
I am going to take care
of her, you hear me?
And now even if you don't
have an electric dermatome,
you can still do skin
grafts using blades.
But you want to be very careful
about how much
pressure you apply.
You don't want to cut too deep.
Is that okay?
That's good. But no deeper.
Yeah, that's better.
Okay, so you want to place the
screws medial to the tibial crest
so you don't interfere
with intravascular bundle.
Medial to the tibial crest.
Mmm-hmm. Now advance
the screw by hand. Yeah.
Until it's anchored
in the far cortex.
Don't be afraid
to push too hard.
Sorry. I'm just... I'm
trying to figure out
how to hold down the patient
to keep him still while I do this.
Oh, the patient's sedated.
Not when you don't
have anesthesia.
Okay.
Um...
Let's go at this another way.
I am so sorry I
wasn't here earlier.
It's okay.
We've got these two
Syrian doctors here
and we're trying to
get all the surgeons
to figure out how to
do these procedures
with, like, a piece of
gum and a matchstick,
and this was our
first pee break.
And meanwhile, you're sitting
here and you can't even walk?
I thought it was just
a small laceration.
It is. I'm fine.
But is it infected? Because
you should be able to walk.
April. April. I don't
know why you can't walk.
April, I can walk. I'm...
You can?
Yeah.
They said that you...
You couldn't leave
till your mom came
to pick you up.
Oh, uh... I, um...
My mom's not coming here
because I can't get myself home.
She's coming here because
I wanted her to meet you.
Oh...
I had a low-grade fever.
I felt bad the night before,
but when I woke up, I figured
I could muscle through it.
So I came in.
I felt okay for most of the day,
so I figured it wasn't...
Of course I'll take
Zola and fetus.
That's what I told Derek.
You're not shipping
them off to Ohio
or wherever his
stupid sisters are from.
I knew you would say that.
I will oversee the
most competent herd
of child care
professionals ever.
I'll get only German nannies.
They're super organized.
I'm not sure a herd of German
nannies is what I had in mind.
Wait. You don't want me
to be a stay-at-home mom?
No.
Yeah, 'cause you're not.
Right, but Zola is at the day
care here when we pick her up.
Yeah, and you do 30%
less surgeries than I do
'cause you're not putting
in the hours anymore.
You don't want to do this.
Hey, I love Zola.
I know you do.
But you don't want
to be her mom.
No.
You really hate those sisters?
Kind of.
Mmm.
Not all of them.
Kathleen seems like a good mom.
I mean, I don't want to
hang out with her all the time,
but her kids seem sane.
Yeah, well, that's not nothing.
Okay, how about this?
You write in the will
that I get your children
three weeks every year.
We'll travel.
I'll take them to
get their first tattoo,
someplace clean.
And I'll teach 'em how to
put a condom on a cucumber.
Come on, Sierra! Come on!
Okay.
I will be the coolest
aunt in the world.
I just can't be a mom.
Oh.
They deserve a mom.
They already have a mom.
I know.
You're not dying right
now. You know that, right?
Dr. Webber. I paged you.
Can you check out bed
three? Patient is Seth Lepik.
Erythema and swelling
along a surgical site.
Febrile. Looks pretty sick.
Probably needs to be admitted.
Sorry.
I'll be right back.
Dr. Shepherd just ordered
an MRI on one of his patients.
I thought you were
covering the pit.
Oh, I am.
My generation's all
about multitasking, sir.
Dr. Horowitz...
Mr. Lepik, I'm Dr. Webber.
I understand that
you're not feeling well.
Yeah, um...
I've been dizzy for
a couple of days,
and they said to come
back in if I didn't feel good.
"They" who?
You guys.
I had surgery here a
couple of weeks ago.
Here it is. Dr. Bailey
operated on you.
Yep.
Okay, well, let's
see what we have.
So you want to
stop the bleeding,
but you don't want to do a
blind clamp in a bloody field.
Your goal is to get
control of the hilum.
Since you won't have a stapler,
you can get control by
using finger pressure,
like that.
So, just reach in here?
Yeah, you want to
feel for the bronchus
and then you'll know
you're near the hilum.
Matthew's mother is coming here.
I can't meet her.
I can't lie to a mother.
Don't sell yourself short.
You thought you couldn't
lie to Matthew either,
but somehow you had it in you.
What kind of grown man gets
his mommy to pick him up?
They have a good relationship.
He respects women.
He has good values.
I think I'm there.
Okay, so if you
don't have a clamp,
you can just use your hand
and twist the lung
on the hilar axis.
That's it. I see it. Thank you.
You know what? He
doesn't make fun of me.
He thinks I'm brave.
He likes it when I babble.
He's a unicorn.
He's an amazing guy.
Well, then you should
tell him the truth.
I have this really cool
technique for autotransfusion
that I would love to show
you when you're done here.
Mmm.
Not bad, huh?
Who needs a fancy splint
when you have duct tape?
It holds quite nicely. Mmm-hmm.
Twenty-seven new e-mails about
where my research goes next.
It should sound like
a cash register to you.
Can you go bug Shepherd
for his vote, please?
Oh, I plan to, and
I'm sure I'll get it.
Shepherd knows we
bought this hospital so that
we could all be the
doctors we want to be.
I'm not living my dream.
My dreams are big and bright
and filled with
extremely shiny machines
that grow cartilage
out of thin air.
I have that dream all the time.
Since you have limited
blood supply, you do this,
and you're giving your
patient their own blood back.
Do you want to give it a try?
Sure.
Mmm.
So,
are you going to
tell this man the truth
or include his
mother in the lie?
Because I cannot get on that
plane without some closure.
Uh, I am so sorry.
You do not need to bother
with my stupid problems.
You have real problems.
Courtship troubles
are everyone's troubles.
Wooing my wife was very tricky.
Well, how'd you win her over?
Ahh.
A picnic of spiced lamb
under the cypress trees,
almonds dipped in honey,
the words of my heart.
Dr. Kepner,
we went to see Terminator 3.
You were right. Cristina
only wants to be the cool aunt.
I'm sorry. I wish I was wrong.
That's okay. What
about Kathleen?
What about Lizzie?
You two got along.
Oh, I forgot about Lizzie.
You know, I don't
want to leave our kids
with somebody you forgot about.
Well, she's the alternate.
Well, it's a disaster plan.
Most disasters don't happen.
They do to us.
That's true.
We have survived an unusual
number of very bad things.
At this point, it ups our odds.
Just send the papers.
Uh, apparently we have never
filled out a health care directive.
The lawyer wants that, too.
Oh, well, I mean,
you know all of this.
I don't want to be a potato.
No extraordinary measures
taken if it's obviously at the end.
He wants it in writing.
It doesn't matter.
We both know you're gonna
give me a lethal dose of morphine
the second I start to
forget where my keys are.
I'm not kidding.
Before we knew
my mother was sick,
she couldn't remember
anything I'd ever said to her.
And I thought it was because
she didn't give a crap about me.
I don't want to put
my kids through that.
You'll give me a lethal
dose, we'll hold hands,
and I'll fade off
into the night.
We will cross that bridge
when we come to it.
More irrigation.
Looks like I'm gonna
have to open this all up.
You doing okay? I'm fine.
You sure?
Dr. Bailey, don't
get all weird on me
because you think you
shattered my psyche.
I knew what I was asking
when I took that test.
Well, if you ever
need to talk...
Stop it.
All right. Fine.
How about we talk about
the sloppy job you're doing
raising those crappy interns?
There you go.
What, she sneezed
all over my patients,
now I have two
post-op infections?
They have no judgment
or common sense.
Mmm. Sorry to butt in, Bailey.
I saw a patient of yours
from a couple of weeks back.
Post-op infection,
pretty extensive.
He's on IV, antibiotics, but
he's gonna need surgery.
You have time today or
you want me to handle it?
What do you mean, "he"?
He's a she, and I saw her.
I'm dealing with her after I
deal with this post-op infection.
It's not a she.
Seth Lepik.
It's not the same patient.
It's a third one.
Three? Have you spoken to Hunt?
No, not yet. I thought
it was just two.
Look, I'll take care
of your third patient.
You need to find Hunt.
Which intern was it?
It's Leah Murphy.
Dr. Darwish, can I
get you something?
Oh, no. I'm just looking.
It's quiet.
We don't have a
lot of quiet anymore.
So there's been a big
rainstorm back east,
and your grandma's flight
isn't gonna be able
to get in until tomorrow,
so Carol here
from social services
is going to take you to a
place that you can sleep tonight.
Why can't I stay here
like we did last night?
Well, that's not
going to work out.
I don't want to go with her.
My mom and dad are here.
It's gonna be fine, okay?
They're gonna give
you a great dinner.
And they'll probably give
you ice cream for dessert,
and they're gonna let
you play video games, so...
Hey. Hey, hey, hey. Come on.
It's going to be
fine. I promise.
Okay, is that
better?
Yeah, uh... But, uh, practice
it a bunch more times.
The faster you get in and out,
the better your outcomes will be.
Promise me you'll kill
me with a lethal injection
before I start to forget
where my keys are.
Of course.
Early.
Not when I set the house on fire
because I forgot
to shut the stove off
or when I'm sitting
in the rocking chair
in the corner of
the nursing home.
I don't want my kids to go
through what I went through...
Mer, you had me
at "lethal injection."
Wow. Is that my door prize?
Okay, so you know I was working
with these two
Syrian guys today?
They barely get any
supplies anymore.
I mean, this is all
they have to work with.
But the attendings
all pitched in,
and we figured out a whole bunch
of lifesaving
procedures they can do.
That's great.
Yeah. Um...
My point is,
you think you need everything,
but you don't.
We could get by without
a lot of stuff, right?
Sure.
What exactly are we
getting by without?
Uh...
My virginity.
I was...
I was a virgin for
a really long time,
and then I wasn't.
I really wanted to wait
for someone like you,
for marriage, but I screwed up.
And I was just... I was
so scared to tell you.
But then I was watching
these guys today,
and they... They
literally have nothing left,
and they're making do.
And then I just felt like
I was being so stupid
to worry about
this one little thing,
like you couldn't
even get over it.
So,
I guess I would be
an ungrateful jerk
if I worried about
your virginity
while there's a war going on
somewhere and people are dying?
That what you're saying to me?
No, no. I didn't...
You didn't think I'd be
more hung up on the lying?
'Cause I bet even in a war,
people still value honesty.
He's still not awake?
Uh, no, not yet.
I gave him a bolus of
D50. We'll see if that helps.
Why didn't you talk to me first?
Because I talked to Russell
about it, like you asked me to.
But you knew that I was
concerned about this case.
You really want me to have
three highly trained surgeons
supervising one man's recovery?
It shouldn't be news to you that
we work as a team at this hospital.
Yes, and the entire team is
helping you save Syria from itself.
I came up with, like, 14 ways
of doing thoracotomy procedures
without a chest tray.
I didn't have time
for a groupthink
on perfectly
straightforward post-op care.
Tomorrow, you, Russell, myself
will round on Paul
together, all right?
Are you serious? I am.
Uh, Dr. Hunt, I need
to speak with you.
Could you give me moment?
It has to be now.
And Webber's in
the OR with the third.
So we have no idea
how extensive this is?
All right.
You and I are gonna need
to talk to infection control,
let them know
what we know so far.
I need you to find all
your charts from that day,
figure out every patient
you touched in post-op,
or anywhere, for that matter.
We're gonna need to
call every one of them,
have them come in,
and examine them.
This is going to be a nightmare.
They're gonna
fire me, aren't they?
Just go.
Still unconscious?
Bummer.
It's okay. He'll wake
up in a couple of days,
if we can all relax
and be patient about it.
Good. Yeah, tell that to Owen.
We may be losing Leah
Murphy from the program.
Did I like her?
I think you said once
that she didn't suck
as much as you
expected her to suck.
Oh. That's too bad.
You know, maybe Owen
doesn't like being Chief.
What makes you say that?
I thought he did,
but lately, he's had
a bug up his butt
about Russell not
supervising me.
You know, maybe it's
because he misses teaching.
I mean, Derek, he hated
all that administrative crap
when he was Chief,
right? Mmm-hmm.
Owen's had nothing
but that for weeks.
Maybe he feels like he's
losing touch with the medicine?
Or maybe it's because
Russell's not supervising you.
Okay, I just agreed to off you
the minute you started acting dotty.
Shouldn't you be on my
side for the rest of the day
just as a courtesy?
Ross was working
the pit today? Yes.
Okay, I just took out
an infected dialysis graft.
Mmm-hmm. He saw
the patient before I did...
Right. but he didn't
scrub in with me
because he wanted to make sure
your MRI was just the way you liked it.
Hey, Dr. Webber.
Someone just put a
glioblastoma resection
on your schedule for tomorrow.
Did you want to do that
before or after your aneurysm?
Shane, you have to stop.
I am working with Brooks now.
Yeah, but she annoys
you, doesn't she?
Mmm. I mean, you
and I kind of get along.
Brooks has an instinct
for this that you don't have.
You make up for it
with a ton of work.
Well, if I'm making up
for it, who cares how?
I care.
And you should, too.
You should find a
specialty where you shine.
This is what I'm
passionate about.
Doesn't that count for anything?
She's better at
this than you are.
And that means, to me, I
have to teach her, not you.
You're gonna be a great surgeon.
Go figure out where.
Hey.
Guy can't take a hint, huh?
Mmm-hmm.
Where are we going, sensei?
We are going to check
in on Rachel Dawson,
see if her neuro
exams have improved.
You went with
spearmint gum this time.
Yeah. You can smell it?
Mmm. I can.
Do you like spearmint?
Not really, no.
Just use peripheral
vascular instruments
if you don't have
stuff for peds. Mmm.
Okay, so pass the umbilical
tape around the vessel.
And then thread both ends
through the short
rubber catheter
and place the hemostat.
There.
Uh, could I borrow
her for a moment?
Yes, but not for long, please.
Uh, I would like to admit Ethan
Dawson to peds for the night.
Oh, he'll be fine with social
services. Kids go with them every day.
This kid doesn't have to.
Owen, there's
protocol for a reason.
Yeah, but we're
human for a reason.
I know that you've taken a
special interest in this kid...
Why is everybody acting like this
is some kind of a character flaw?
He ought to stay. He's sick.
I got a look at him
when I checked his wrist.
Short limb syndrome.
Karev.
Right. He's right.
Uh, limited growth,
excessive sleeping, and eating.
Impulse control problems.
These are all the
symptoms of childhood.
Can't be sure.
Not until we confirm it
with testing and observation.
Guys, guys, I love
the enthusiasm,
but it's not gonna happen.
All right.
Hey.
Cristina said she would pull
the trigger if it comes to that.
You're my wife.
Can we make the
decision together
if we're gonna
throw in the towel?
That sounds fair.
It's not gonna be easy
on you if I start to lose it.
Oh, don't worry.
You're a project even
with all your marbles.
I brought you
something. You did?
I had Bailey do my genome.
You did? Yeah.
High-risk for liver cancer
and prostate cancer? Whoa.
Yeah. You're telling me.
Male pattern baldness?
Late onset, apparently.
Mmm-hmm.
Heroin addiction?
I'm a real prize. Oh.
It's all a crapshoot.
We didn't get
one single definite.
We only got maybes.
Ah, maybe we live forever.
Maybe we do, and maybe I
become a bald heroin addict.
Honey, I'm gonna take
these bags down to the car.
Thanks, Mom.
Wrapping it up for the day?
Yep.
How about you let
me buy you dinner?
I want to bend your ear about
a project I'm thinking about.
You and everyone else
are free to submit
your proposals in writing
to the entire board.
And then I will vote
like everyone else does.
Hell, maybe I'll
submit one myself.
Maybe I have an idea,
but I'm not out here
hawking it to people at work.
'Cause I'm gonna
write a proposal
like you're supposed to.
Um... Son,
nobody's ever saying
yes to your proposal.
You're the most powerful
vote on the board.
You're the person who says
yes to other people's ideas.
We still let you be a surgeon.
Nobody wanted to
take that away from you.
But your project
is this hospital.
Yeah, it's exhausting sometimes.
Yeah.
You know something I
learned when I was the Chief?
What?
Somebody offers
to buy you dinner
while they talk
your ear off about
something you
don't want to hear...
You say yes.
Look at that. You're a natural.
Oh, looks like you got this.
Yes,
but not as fast as it could be.
Practice, practice, practice.
Thank you for all
you've taught us.
I wish it could be more.
It feels like nothing.
If we will help even one child,
it's everything.
Short limb syndrome?
Mmm-hmm. Yeah, we're not sure.
At this point, we're just
admitting him for observation.
We'll know more in the morning.
Thank you.
Hey. So got your own TV,
they serve a chocolate
pudding that's not half bad,
and I'm gonna see if I can scare
up some comic books, okay?
Hey.
You okay?
You just told the
nurse I was sick.
Yeah, you're fake sick.
The nurse knows that. Even...
All the doctors know it.
We're just pretending so
you can stay here tonight.
There is nothing wrong with you.
Is it fake with my mom and dad?
No.
No, I wish it was.
My dad's still not awake?
No, he's not.
Is he ever gonna wake up?
I don't know.
So, you played soccer.
I did.
Hey. Owen's been acting crazy.
I think this is why.
The left defender is crucial.
Kids make you crazy.
Yeah.
Kind of cute, though.
Dr. Grey.
I'm not gonna get fired.
We'll cross that bridge
when we come to it.
No, it's worse than that.
Dr. Bailey, Joyce is crashing.
What?
Dr. Kepner, you have given
us piles of supplies already.
This equipment is expensive.
Yeah. Yeah, but
this will really help.
Oh, and you should
definitely take this.
It's an infrascanner.
It can detect a brain bleed.
Oh. Oh.
Uh...
Are you sure this is all right?
Perhaps you need
to talk to Dr. Hunt.
Don't worry about it.
Honesty's not all
it's cracked up to be.
They say the truth
will set you free.
What the hell do they know?
The truth is
horrible, frightening.
The truth is more
than you can bear.
Bailey said the second patient
isn't responding to antibiotics.
So she's going to need surgery.
I just operated on the third.
He's hypotensive and
still pretty unstable.
Once Murphy's identified
all her patients for the day,
then we'll get them in here,
make sure no one else is infected.
We're gonna need to make
some kind of statement.
Before this gets
out there on its own.
Hey, uh,
the first patient, Joyce Basche,
she didn't make it.
I thought that the surgery
would get rid of the infection,
but...
You need to get cultures
on the other two right away.
And we need to make sure that
we're using the right antibiotics
so that this doesn't
get out of control.
Okay.
We just lost Joyce Basche.
Dr. Bailey...
No, she's her patient.
She should know.
Leah checked all the charts.
She was only on two of the
patients that got the infection.
She never touched the third one.
What, is that supposed to
reassure me? A woman just died.
It couldn't have been Leah.
The only doctor who
touched all three patients
was you.
We're gonna need
to get legal down here.
Wait. Anything could've
caused this kind of infection.
Yeah, no...
Well, we know that, but
until there's an investigation...
No, I gotta go, 'cause I
have two more people...
Owen?
Dr. Webber will deal with them.
Yeah, this is Dr. Avery.
Get me Joelle Geller from legal
down here, conference room two.
I will
go over my notes.
Sit down, Dr. Bailey.
No. My patients are in danger.
Dr. Webber will
take care of them.
I haven't even told
Joyce's husband
that she didn't make it.
I know the man!
I don't need Grey to tell
him that I killed his wife!
Dr. Bailey, please sit down.
We're supposed to
be straight with you,
so be careful what you ask for
when you walk into a hospital.
What are you saying?
I'm asking you to sit down.
Because when you find
out what's really going on,
you may never recover.