Mom?
Next Tuesday's fine.
Let's do that. - Yeah.
Keep him on the leash, honey.
Thank you.
Mom!
Mom?
Shh, shh... It's okay, honey.
It's okay. How can I help?
I can't find my mom.
I don't know where
she went. It's okay.
We'll find her.
What's your name?
Luna. Luna.
That's a pretty name.
What about your dad?
Do you know where he is?
I don't have a dad.
My dad died.
All right, I've got two infinity pools,
I got a swim-up Jacuzzi, and this?
This is where the
Millennium Falcon lands.
So...
What?
No, Jeffrey, it's, it's great.
It's just, it's safe to say
you followed the letter
of the exercise and
perhaps not the spirit.
I mean, you said
envision our futures, right?
- Well, y'all, this is mine.
- Yes, Jeffrey.
It's just, your future
contains a few more
two-piece bathing suits than
I had anticipated. That's all.
Can I go next, Dr. Frome?
Yes, Avi, please.
Talk us through your
vision of your future.
Jeffrey, it's fantastic.
Thanks.
Okay, so right here is
Parthenon in Athens.
I'm gonna go after I learn
some Greek, you know?
So I can speak to the locals.
I hate that everybody just
assume that everybody's
just gonna speak
English, you know?
That's smart.
And this?
This is Table
Mountain in Cape Town.
One day I'm gonna hike it.
Right to the top.
What drew you to Cape Town?
I guess I just, you know,
want to see the world.
Go places I never been before.
I mean, come on.
Look at that view.
That's spectacular.
It's beautiful.
It is, Avi. Fantastic, truly.
Now, guys, it is more than fine
to look forward to material things...
Yeah. Yes.
But... But sometimes
goals are stronger when
they affect who we are.
You know what I mean?
Iggy. Yes.
You have a visitor.
Ah... It's my new Jet Ski.
Guys, keep filling out your
vision boards. I will be right back.
And Jeffrey, ease off the
swimsuit models. Thank you.
Hi. Hi.
Tiara Dobbs. Avi
Mantell's social worker.
It's good to finally
meet you in person.
Yeah, likewise.
So, what brings you down
to our neck of the woods today?
Avi's mother's been
offered a job in Missouri,
her hometown, and she
can't pass it up... Mmm.
So she's gonna be moving
back there next week.
Oh, wow!
With Avi, obviously.
Yes.
I've reviewed Avi's case and it appears
that he has made huge strides with you,
so I can't think of any
reason that he can't transfer
from inpatient care to weekly
visits with a local therapist.
I just need you to sign off
so I can begin Avi's
official discharge procedure.
Unless you don't agree.
Uh, I did. I did have
a pretty huge breakthrough
with him recently.
Well, that's certainly
good to hear. Yeah, it is.
Yes, I think that Avi is
ready for the next step.
Wonderful. Okay.
I'll tell Avi to
pack his things.
What is so funny?
I've just discovered that New
Amsterdam has a listing on Yelp.
"Yelp"?
Yeah, you know, where
people post online reviews
about places they love, things
they hate, their experiences.
Oh, like Facebook
but on the internet.
Yes, exactly.
Listen to this: it was
posted two minutes ago
by @NancyPants.
"The rooms at New Amsterdam are freezing,
the lights are horrifically bright,
"and the only thing
older than this mattress
"is my bald doctor who can
never seem to find his glasses.
"One star."
Let me see this.
I know this patient.
This is Nancy Nan.
She's doing a
sleep study with me.
One star, Vijay. Ouch. One star?
That's absurd. All she
has to do is to sleep.
I'm joking. Don't
worry about it.
Forty-plus years of practice
and an expert in my field of study.
I should be able to
do better than one star.
We shall see about this. Vijay.
My phone and your glasses.
Yeah.
Nice cap, Williamsburg.
When does your artisan
pickle shop open up?
Proud of 'em? I'm
proud of all of them.
So, today's schedule
isn't too terrible.
Fist up: Quarterly
Allocation Review Committee.
Pass. You can't really pass.
No? Watch me. I'm skipping
that redundant meeting.
What's next?
Then there's a new pharma
vendor show-and-tell.
Pass. Okay.
The Board requested
your presence
at the Strategic Objective
Luncheon in Midtown.
Pass. Next? Max...
Pass. Next?
Police commissioner
called again.
I'm guessing it has to do with
what happened to Officer McNeil.
Yeah, hard pass.
Max. No.
There's not a single essential
meeting on that entire list.
They're all just arbitrary,
and I'm not wasting any
more time on arbitrary.
Well, what... Well,
now that you've cleared
your entire schedule,
what do you intend to do...
I don't know, something that matters.
You know, something worth my time.
Maybe something life and death.
What was that all about?
He's in a mood.
It's okay, honey.
Whoa, whoa.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What the hell happened in here?
You might want to ask him.
Okay, I got this.
It just came out of
nowhere. It's okay.
All right, let's go.
That was your vision board, bud.
What's going on?
I'm not going nowhere!
Avi...
You're gonna do great today.
I've been to plenty of morbidity
and mortality conferences.
Just never had to lead one.
Well, you're my chief resident
now. It comes with the job title.
Been going over your case
and it sounded just awful.
Officer McNeil
just bled out so fast.
Yes.
I'm sorry, Dr. Reynolds.
So am I.
Look, I just want you to
know I'm not gonna throw you
under the bus or anything
during this discussion.
No, no, no. Look, M&Ms
are not about blame, all right?
They're a teaching tool.
We come together to see
if our actions contributed
to the patient's death, so we
never repeat those mistakes.
But that's just the thing. I've
been preparing this for days.
I haven't found any mistakes.
Hey, that can
happen, too, all right?
But we still study the case so
we vow to do better the next time.
That's it.
Today's case is a white
40-year-old female trauma patient.
She initially presented with...
Go ahead.
The patient presented
with a fractured femur,
cervical and
thoracic abrasions...
Was Officer McNeil
on any medications?
She was on
low-dose birth control.
Twenty-five
minutes post arrival...
Did Officer McNeil have
a history of heart disease?
Uh...
No, the patient did not.
We all know you're talking about
Officer McNeil, Dr. Nottingham.
No need for anonymity.
Okay.
Um...
Twenty-five minutes post
arrival, Officer McNeil developed
a pneumomediastinum,
necessitating...
Before the pneumomediastinum,
were there any other signs
in her vitals that could have
predicted her eventual death?
Not that I'm aware of.
Hmm. What did Officer McNeil
look like as she went into surgery?
I don't know. You don't know?
I wasn't there.
You weren't there.
Well, if we have any hope of
getting some real answers today,
then we need someone
presenting this case
who was actually there.
Dr. Reynolds?
She was your patient, right?
Yes, she was.
Hmm. So you would have the
most salient information on this case.
I think Nottingham is providing
an accurate case review.
Hmm. Indeed. But, to really
get to the bottom of how she died,
don't you think that you
might be better qualified
to lead this discussion?
If it's not too much trouble.
Okay. Let's go to the
chest X-ray first. Okay, good.
All right.
So here we have Marie
McNeil's chest X-ray.
You will notice the mediastinum.
It measures just over
nine centimeters in length.
Now, Dr. Nottingham,
can you give us the criteria
for pathological widening?
Eight centimeters
on a supine AP chest.
Very good. We have met the
criteria for pathological widening.
If we take a closer look
right about here... See that?
Air bubbles.
That's the cause for the
widened mediastinum.
Now, that's actually caused
by tears in the esophagus
called Boerhaave
syndrome, all right?
And also of note:
normal pulmonary parenchyma
and normal cardiac silhouette.
Next.
Wait, go back to
the chest X-ray.
You said cardiac
silhouette was normal?
Yes.
But the chest X-ray is
a rather blunt instrument
for examining something as
delicate as the human heart,
wouldn't you say?
So what other
modalities did you use?
An EKG and a transthoracic echocardiogram,
both of which came back normal.
Good. Can we see those?
Dr. Nottingham
didn't include them
in today's presentation
because they were normal.
Well, I can't tell if they were
normal if I can't see them for myself.
Well, I don't have them here.
No?
The entire purpose of an
M&M is to analyze the data
to ensure that if mistakes were made
those mistakes will not be made again.
It is particularly difficult
to analyze that data
when that data isn't here.
So why don't we take a brief recess
to allow Dr. Reynolds to compile
all the necessary cardiac data.
Why are you moving me?
I honestly have no idea.
To get better results
on your sleep study
we wish for you to
have a warmer room
with better lighting and
much, much softer bed.
Okay.
Uh, hello. What's
up with the lamp?
Uh, we're moving this
patient to a nicer room
for some random reason.
What? No.
We have a reason.
The reason is
because we are trying
to provide Ms. Nan with the
most comfortable care here
in the New Amsterdam
because patient comes first.
Right?
Yes.
Finally, someone
who gets it. Thank you.
You are welcome. Yeah.
We gotta go the
extra mile, you know?
Our patients do come first.
I mean, this is what
I've been saying.
You know, these people
depend on us for care.
They put their very
lives in our hands.
My boyfriend just
hates my snoring.
You know, we can do better.
We can do better than just
provide her with comfortable care.
We can? Yeah.
How would Ms. Nan like a
stay in our Presidential Suite?
I imagine she would
like that very much.
Yes, thank you. Mmm-hmm, good.
Okay.
Come on, before
he changes his mind.
Hurry up.
Why does she have to be here?
Ms. Dobbs and I are
both your advocates, Avi.
She's part of the team.
I don't have a team.
You don't. You have
an entire network.
Me, Ms. Dobbs, your mother.
The All Stars, man, you know?
Everyone wants to
see your transition
to life outside of the
hospital go smoothly.
I'm too big of a freak to be in
the real world with normal people.
What is... What are you
doing? Time out, time out.
You know full well on this ward
we don't use words like freak.
"Real world," "normal,"
whatever that is.
All right?
Those are day-one
ground rules, Avi.
Come on.
I think you're breaking the rules
on purpose. That's my theory.
I think you're scared
of what's to come.
You're scared of these changes,
so you think if you act out
now you can get out in front of it
and stop these
changes from happening.
Talk to us.
When they kicked me out of school,
I didn't care where they sent me.
I didn't care about anything.
It was like, whatever.
But then...
Yeah?
Things just got better here.
That's right.
Things were starting
to make sense.
I felt like I belonged here.
But now that I'm starting
to get the hang of it,
my mom is trying
to ruin my life again.
No one... No one is
ruining your life, Avi.
I don't even think
anyone has that power.
All right? You put in the work.
You learned the tools.
You can cope anywhere.
Even Missouri.
How do you know?
Just listen to me, okay?
'Cause I'm good at what I do.
I can promise you this:
you are ready.
He is not ready. What?
Were we both in
the same session?
Avi accused his mother
of ruining his life again.
And?
Avi was admitted for a
serious outburst at school.
Kids were teasing him
over his learning disability,
but it had nothing
to do with his mother.
What are you saying?
I'm saying whatever's
going on with him
was triggered only once
he learned he was leaving.
Avi's mother can't just
change her travel plans.
Her new job is expecting
her there on Monday.
I need more time with him.
Dr. Frome, his discharge
paperwork has been filed.
I know. I know.
Just let me talk to him.
Alone.
Let me see if I can
get through to him.
That's it.
Thank you.
Oh, um, Dr. Kao?
How do you spell your last name?
Uh... K-A-O.
"Dr. Agnes Kao..."
Thomas Jefferson once
stayed in our Presidential Suite.
Is that right? Mmm-hmm.
This room has housed the architect
of the Declaration of Independence.
And now @NancyPants from Yelp.
I know how this looks.
Yeah, I feel like if you did,
we wouldn't be having
this conversation.
This was not my idea, I swear.
It was Max's. Hold on.
The ludicrous
coddling of Nancy Nan,
a woman who isn't even
sick, came from Max?
Yes.
And if his error in judgment
leads to an enhancement
of my online status,
well, this is just a
happy coincidence.
Did Max seem
like himself to you?
He seemed erratic.
Annoyed, then
excited, then distracted,
all in quick succession.
And if it was anyone but
Max, I would have got worried.
Should I be worried?
Aw... She found the fizzy water.
Brought everything I could find.
Action logs, nursing
notes, imaging studies.
And here are those
ultrasounds. Good work.
I'm sorry about
this, Dr. Reynolds.
I didn't really expect Dr. Goodman
would want to see every last scan.
It's not your fault.
This level of due
diligence is extreme.
That's one way to put it.
But my work on Officer
McNeil was solid, you know?
Our job now is just to
present the case clearly.
Hey, can we talk?
I'll get these loaded
onto the computer.
Thanks.
Hey.
I don't like this,
Floyd. It's fine.
It doesn't feel fine.
Feels like you're putting
yourself on the line.
Okay, these conferences
are for internal use only.
They're protected.
But we both know that Max has
been fielding calls on this one.
From the mayor, the
police commissioner.
Board of Directors,
malpractice department at HCC.
Evie...
There was a police officer
that died on your table,
under your knife.
You know that they're gonna
be looking for someone to blame.
Hate to say it, but it sure
feels like Max is trying
to make sure that person is you.
Dr. Reynolds?
Are you actually ready?
What we have here is the pre-op
echocardiogram for Officer McNeil.
Now, let's focus on
where the rupture occurred.
Here to here, all right?
.34 centimeters
at the thinnest width of
the right ventricular wall.
Normal.
Also, normal valve function.
Normal papillary musculature.
And, as noted
before, normal echo.
Hmm.
How about a second opinion?
Dr. Jessup?
Yes, it appears normal.
How about you, Dr. Flores?
Don't you think the right
ventricular wall looks a little thin?
Uh...
No. It looks like a
normal thickness to me.
Is there anyone
here who disagrees?
Dr. Nottingham?
I see what Dr. Reynolds sees.
Normal ultrasound.
Well, an ultrasound is just an
approximate image of the real heart.
But, fortunately for us,
the real heart is still here
down in pathology, so I think we
should all take a trip down there
and have a closer look for
ourselves. You can't be serious.
Oh, but I am serious.
Once we examine the
real heart, then we'll know
if these readings were in
fact, as you say, normal.
Right now. Here we
go. Everybody up.
You know you can
talk to me, right?
It's just me and you.
In here, just like before.
It'll never be
like it was before.
Not where I'm going.
Okay, let's talk
about that. Let's not.
Avi, I believe there is
something in your life
that really upsets you.
Something you've worked
very, very hard to lock away.
And now, for some reason,
that thing has snuck back around
to the front of your mind.
For some reason, that's all
you can think about right now.
You know I can help you. I can
help you manage these emotions,
but first you have to let me in.
I don't want to move back there.
I hate it there. You
hate it in Missouri?
Why do I have to go with her?
Why can't she just go back there
and do her dumb job there
and I could stay here, right?
Don't make me go.
Does this have something
to do with your mom?
No!
My mom doesn't
know anything about it.
Doesn't know
anything about what?
No, no, no, no.
No, Avi, what doesn't
she know about?
You have to tell me.
You gotta let me in so
we can face it together.
I don't want to face it!
I want to stay here, but
nobody cares about what I want!
That is not true. It is true!
If you cared about me at all,
you'd be on my side right now.
You'd be on my side
instead of working so hard
to ship me off to Missouri!
I can't go back.
Hi. Hi. Have you got a minute?
Well, despite this whimsical
tableau, I'm actually quite busy.
Tough case? Understatement.
But, you know,
nothing fires up the brain
like sugar and titanium dioxide.
Well, before you
slip into insulin shock,
I... I want to get your
professional opinion.
About?
About Max.
You know, speculating
on the boss' mental health
is not my favorite thing.
Nor mine, but if the medical
director of New Amsterdam's ability
to make decisions is compromised,
then I need to know about it.
Every cancer patient struggles,
but in the past few days,
he has been exhibiting
behavior that's erratic.
Unstable, even angry.
That's not Max.
Well, I do, um... I
have a theory, but...
I don't think
you're gonna like it.
Go on.
It's you.
Me?
This all started once you passed
him off to Dr. Stauton like a hot potato.
That's irrelevant. Our treatment
plans are almost identical.
Yeah, but your relationships
with Max are not, are they?
Dr. Stauton is an excellent
doctor. Max knows that.
Yeah, and he respects her.
But he believes in you.
I need your help right away.
Hey. Not now.
Okay.
This better be important.
I am at the end of my rope now.
I have a patient who,
no matter the treatment,
cannot be helped.
Is this about your spinocerebellar
degeneration patient?
No, he's fine. It's
about @NancyPants.
I brought this on
myself, didn't I?
Look at this.
"The 100-year-old doctor
just tried to buy me off.
"Pro-tip: want a better review?
"Don't give me the scratchiest
sheets on the planet.
"One star."
She is insufferable.
Isn't she in the
Presidential Suite?
Yes, and she's still displeased.
Wait, we use 600 thread-count
Egyptian cotton in there.
Nothing will ever be good
enough for this woman.
It's hard to believe she's
a woman of refined taste
given her screen
name is @NancyPants.
I don't know what more to do.
Wait, what if she actually
had incredibly sensitive skin?
It has to be the most
sensitive skin on this planet,
or...
Oh, dear. Exactly.
Max, we should talk.
Not really a good time.
What is this?
A fool's errand.
If we look at the patient's heart,
we see the chambers intact.
Normal in appearance.
But let's turn to
the cardiac injury.
Even after this dramatic
free wall rupture,
the actual cardiac tissue
itself is amazingly normal.
No thinning?
None. No?
No, uh, infiltrative process
like amyloid or fibrosis?
No, no abnormalities whatsoever.
Dr. Reynolds, what about
your, uh, mental state
during the surgery?
Nothing of particular
note. Really?
Because I know for a fact on
that day that you were distracted.
No, I was fine.
If you recall, you spent the entire
morning going over your budgets.
It's unrelated and you know it.
Not if it compromised your
concentration during the surgery.
You honestly believe I was still
thinking about your stupid budgets?
I don't know.
You tell me, Floyd.
The woman died on your
table. You know what? That's it.
This M&M is over.
Everyone back to work.
Now!
Except for you. We got business.
You were way out
of line. Not if I'm right.
Well, you're not right,
and that wasn't an M&M.
That was a public shaming.
I am only asking
the tough questions.
No, you are undermining
my credibility at this hospital.
In front of my staff. In
front of my colleagues.
Are you really making this
patient's death about you?
No, you made it about me when
you brought up my mental state.
The whole point of this exercise
was to determine, once and for all,
if Officer Marie McNeil's
death was preventable.
We have sifted through
every notation, every scan,
every piece of recorded imaging.
Hell, 50 people just watched you
poke and prod at the poor woman's heart.
There's nothing
else to investigate!
Then we start over! Max.
You are unbelievable,
you know that?
Yeah, no, we start
over. We dig deeper.
We keep looking
until we find... No!
What did you say?
In what world do you think I'd
stick around for more of this?
I was so excited when
you offered me chair.
To build a department that...
That we could both be proud of.
An environment based
on mutual respect.
But in one afternoon you
managed to tear it all down.
In one afternoon you
showed how little you trust me,
and you did it in
front of everyone.
You can expect my resignation.
Do you want to tell me
what this is really about?
You're not my doctor, remember?
We must examine you right away.
I'm trying to sleep, here.
You're on your phone.
That's how I get to sleep.
Blue light disrupts the
production of melatonin,
but we'll talk about that later.
Do you mind showing
me your legs, please?
Um...
Dr. Kapoor believes your discomfort
has nothing to do with the sheets.
Okay, sure.
Ugh.
How long have you had this rash?
I've never noticed it before.
Can I have that glass?
The rash doesn't
blanch under pressure.
We must get her to the
procedure room now.
Wait, why?
Ms. Nan, it appears you have
contracted meningococcal meningitis.
If we don't treat you
now, you could die.
I need a procedure room, stat.
Dr. Sharpe.
Something I can help you with?
I need to talk to you
about Max.
Somewhat irregular.
I know.
Come in.
Hey, Avi. Hi.
Yeah, come in. Come in.
My mom's waiting.
I just wanted to, you know...
Say goodbye real quick.
You have my number, you know.
You can call me
anytime. Anytime.
Thank you...
For, you know...
Trying to fix me.
I know I let you down.
I'm really sorry for that,
Doc. You never let me down.
But you couldn't fix me, so...
Hey, stop, stop. Listen to
me, listen to me. "Fixed"...
That's not a thing.
It doesn't exist.
Nobody leaves
this hospital fixed.
Do you understand?
My job is to give you the
tools to get through the day.
That's it.
I wish I could just stay here.
Hey, hey.
You're gonna
make it to Missouri.
But that's just the beginning.
Don't forget about
Table Mountain.
The Parthenon. Right?
Gonna hike all
the way to the top.
Right to the top.
Yeah.
Use the tools.
Use the tools. Every day.
Every day.
Come on.
You're gonna be great.
Avi.
Hi.
It's time to go.
All right.
Bye, Doc. Bye, Avi.
Pulse ox 97, BP 100 over 60.
When you feel the pop...
You know you're in.
There. HR normative range.
Nancy? Here you go.
You okay?
I guess so.
We are collecting the fluid
to identify which bacteria
is making you so sick.
Additional LP tubes on the tray.
I just came in for a
simple sleep study.
Nancy?
She's unresponsive.
Heart rate is up to 124.
BP's down to 80 over 40.
She's going into septic shock.
Deliver to the lab. Hurry.
Rapid response,
procedure room number two.
What the hell was that?
I did everything in my power
to save this patient's life.
I did everything right, and
now it's gonna bury my career?
This doesn't need
to land on you.
Max was... I don't
know what that was.
Out of control.
Insane. Tyrannical.
Babe, you have
legal recourse here.
I have a friend
at Adler & Morgan
who would take on this
case at the drop of a hat.
Yeah?
Not the best time.
We should talk.
Text me later.
This better not be
you defending him.
Not after what he did.
No, I can't defend that.
But, uh... But?
But?
Max's cancer.
It's not responding
to chemo or radiation.
How bad?
It's bad.
When did he find out?
Stauton told him this morning.
Got enough light on the keyhole?
Passing through
the cerebral cortex.
The center of the infection's
in the third ventricle.
I don't think you'll
be able to hit it.
Keep looking at the CT.
Go ahead and remove
the trap set from the tray.
Four centimeters to
the lateral ventricle.
You're too close.
I can make it.
If you clip that, she'll
never walk again.
Just imagine that review.
Advancing caudal to
the corticospinal tract.
You're clear.
And I am into ventricle.
Injecting
Cephillicam.
Heart rate and blood
pressure are stable.
Check that bone flap
cover. See if it needs sealing.
Forty-three years ago, I
made a decision to be a doctor.
Dedicate my life to
the service of others.
It was never about reviews.
I heard.
Yeah, well, what can you do?
I get why you pushed hard.
I'd want answers, too.
How do we just
accept that her death,
or anyone's death, was random?
Life, death.
It can't be arbitrary.
It's not.
I just thought maybe
there was something...
That we missed.
You know, maybe
there was something
that we could have
done differently.
Maybe... Maybe I could
have done a lot of things...
Differently.
Sometimes you
do everything right.
You know?
And get the same result.
As though you've done nothing.
I'm sorry, Floyd.
I don't know
what else to say or
how else to say it. I just...
I don't know who that...
Who that was today.
I mean, I look in the
mirror and then I...
I don't recognize that person.
What's happening
to you is not fair.
There's no reason behind it.
No answer that
will make it better.
I know.
I just don't want my life...
Or my death...
To be...
Arbitrary.
Okay.
Okay, well, the way I see it,
you got a choice.
You either let the
randomness of this
beat you down
or you pick yourself up
and you just keep fighting.
Endings be damned.
Hey.
I know what you're gonna say.
I like your hat.
I have been sitting
here all afternoon
researching alternative options.
Have you heard of the
Norton-Simon model?
No. It's called DDC.
Dose-dense chemo. "Dose-dense"?
Essentially, it's the same
dose of cisplatin that you're on,
but we would administer
it twice as frequently.
By amping up the quantity
and frequency of your treatment,
we could interrupt
the rapid growth phase
of your malignant tumor cells.
What's the catch?
If you were experiencing side
effects from your normal dose,
DDC is the equivalent of
napalming your internal organs.
Essentially, it's a human
scorched-earth policy.
Take time to think it
over. It's a big decision.
So read that article,
and then tomorrow...
Can we start tonight?
I wanna keep fighting.
Endings be damned.
Hey. Still here?
I had a lot of
paperwork to finish,
given everything I saw today.
Yeah, yeah.
Days like today,
they hit hard, man.
Don't always get the time
you need with a patient,
so we do what we can, and we find solace
in knowing that our contribution helped,
if even just a little bit.
Dr. Frome, I wasn't
filling out paperwork
for Avi Mantell.
No?
I was opening a formal
investigation on you.
I don't understand.
What I witnessed today
was a therapist
actively and knowingly
forming non-therapeutic
alliances with his patients.
No, that's not right.
The physical exchanges with Avi?
The emotional boundaries
you overstepped with him?
It crossed a line, Dr. Frome.
This is my official report.
I wanted you to hear it from me.
I'm sorry...
But our patients
must come first.