Your weight is 113.9 pounds.
You gonna make me hurt you?
I didn't think so.
Are you all right?
Did I hurt you?
Bob!
Bob! What's wrong? What
happened? Talk to me.
Oh, my God! Okay,
honey, hang on, hang on.
911, what is your emergency?
Yes, we need an ambulance
at 10600 Xavier, unit 4-B.
My husband can't breathe.
Oh, my God, he's turning blue. You
have to send someone now, please!
Hurry!
You blow-dry your hair?
Oh, sorry. Did I wake you up?
Excuse me for actually
caring what I look like.
I think the word you're
looking for is "obsessing."
You've been at it
for almost an hour.
If you wanted in, all you
had to do was say so.
I don't want in. I want sleep!
It's about time you got up
anyway. It's almost 9:00.
This isn't gonna work.
What? You staying here.
You're kicking me
out? After one night?
Why, you think we
should try counseling first?
Why do you want to
sleep on a couch anyway?
You got money. At least
until the divorce is finalized.
I'll be out of your hair
tomorrow. What's left of it.
It was three days ago.
My throat got really
dry and then my tongue
felt like it was blowing
up like a balloon.
I assume somebody
checked for food allergies.
The first two doctors both did.
Next one said it
was a panic attack.
The one after that wanted
to take his tonsils out.
The last one had no idea,
just referred us to Dr. House.
It says the attack was preceded
by some sort of
strenuous physical activity.
Yeah. What were you doing?
Awesome.
A sex fiend with
a swollen tongue.
Just think of all the places I
can make Foreman search.
He's not a sex fiend. He's
a happily married man.
No such thing.
What are you doing?
Testing a new caffeine
delivery system.
He didn't get his beauty sleep.
Wilson's moved in and apparently
has unusually loud toenails.
If they're into rape fantasies,
S and M is on the menu as well.
Neck trauma could cause vocal cord
paroxysms, which could cause choking.
I didn't see any sign of trauma,
and they were remarkably open.
I asked about STDs
and they admitted participating
in a threesome a few months ago.
A hundred bucks says they're
as miserable as the next couple.
Another guy, or girl?
Girl. His wife's
college roommate.
If he's not happily married,
I don't know who could be.
They're looking for something.
If you're happy, you've
got nothing to look for.
His wife arranged it for
an anniversary present.
If you ask me, if two
people really trust each other,
a threesome once
every seven years
might actually help a marriage.
Okay, I say we stop the DDX
and discuss that comment.
I'll take the bet.
Maybe the first
doctor was right.
Food allergy explains
the anaphylaxis.
Could be neurological.
Progressive bulbar paralysis
would explain the symptoms.
No. ALS would affect his
facial muscles before his throat.
What if the problem's
not in his throat?
That would be a little odd considering
that's where all his symptoms are.
Says who? The patient.
And since most patients can't
tell their ulna from their anus,
I'm guessing this
guy also doesn't know
the difference between
choking and suffocating.
His throat might be fine, his
lungs might be messed up.
Get more blood, a chest CT
and a body plethysmograph.
Unless, of course, you think
we should be asking the patient
where his anus is first.
It feels like I have to urinate
and then when I try to go...
Pull up your pants.
It's my prostrate, isn't it?
Nope, not your prostrate.
Herpes.
Herpes?
Herpes. Your turn.
If it makes you feel any better,
half the patients who come into
this place have some sort of crotch rot.
No, it doesn't.
Look, this is impossible.
I've been married for 20 years.
Have you had any
sex in those 20 years?
Yes, of course. Then
that's how you got it.
The only person I've
had sex with is my wife.
Bummer.
Take this once a day. Tell
your wife to do the same.
It's not going to cure it,
but it will lessen the
frequency of the outbreaks.
But, there must be some mistake.
You got any kids?
Yeah. Any of them
take guitar lessons?
No. Tennis? Art? Acting?
My daughter does karate, why?
Give this to her sensei.
Oh, wait.
Does your wife play tennis? No.
That's what I figured.
Never hurts to make sure.
For Miyagi.
I'm gonna close the shutter now.
I need you to pant,
kind of like a dog.
That's good. Keep going.
Can I ask you a
personal question?
I guess.
The threesome
and the role-playing.
Is that because
things get boring?
No.
We just enjoy our fantasies.
Are you married? No.
You can go back to taking
the deep breaths now.
Marriages don't fail
because couples get bored.
They fail because
while they're dating,
people pretend to be the person
they think their partner
wants, and then...
Well, there's only so
long you can keep that up.
Maybe they are that person while
they're dating, but then they change.
People thinking their
partner will change?
That's another
reason marriages fail.
People don't change, at least
not in any way that really matters.
I think you've had
enough caffeine.
You were right. It's not
his throat, it's his lungs.
The plethysmograph revealed
decreased lung capacity.
And the CT showed lung scarring.
It's definitely interstitial
pulmonary fibrosis.
What's not definite
is the cause.
There's no arthritis,
no sarcoidosis.
He's not on any
prescription meds.
And he's a wedding photographer.
So I doubt he got exposed to
coal dust or asbestos at work.
Cause could be idiopathic.
Can't be idiopathic.
Idiopathic means without a known
cause. What I meant was that...
What you meant was you
don't know what the cause is.
Just say that and we can
avoid this conversation.
No applause?
What's his current
condition? Stable.
Well, then we can
wait. Wait for what?
For whatever you can't figure
out to cause something else.
You know it's going to.
It's possible the IPF
could just continue to...
There's something wrong
with his skin. Do something.
Okay, stop scratching.
Let me look at it.
I can't. This is
driving me crazy.
Stop scratching, so
we can... Make it stop!
Okay. Make it stop!
Make it stop!
Now we've got
something to discuss.
What causes both lung scarring
and the itchy, splotchy red blotchies?
It's obviously not a reaction to
medication. We haven't given him any yet.
Right. But what besides
what it's obviously not,
can cause both lung
scarring and the splotches?
Where are you going?
To complete the second half
of the caffeine delivery system.
Either talk louder,
or get in here.
Same color coming
out as going in.
Do you think that's
a marketing thing?
A lupus could cause
lung scarring and a rash.
Or could still be
a food allergy.
We've already ruled
out allergies. Did we?
Where's Cameron?
We're in the men's room.
We need an allergy
expert in here.
This can wait two minutes.
You don't know that.
Chase thinks that food allergy
should still be on the table.
No, it wouldn't explain
the lung scarring.
Some homeopathic studies
have found a connection
between food allergies
and autoimmune reactions,
which could cause
lung inflammation.
Yeah. And some homeopathic
studies have also found
that ground-up
spiders can cure cancer.
Can I go now? No.
Lungs, skin, skin, lungs.
Sklungs?
Lungs, skin,
throat.
Heavy metal toxicity.
It explains the
lungs, the itching,
the swelling in his
tongue and throat.
I thought you didn't believe there
was anything wrong with his throat.
I never said I
didn't believe it.
I just said I had good
reason to doubt it.
And now?
I have good reason
to doubt those doubts.
The patient's a little old to
be chewing paint off the walls.
Nor does he drink well
water, eat fish every day,
or do anything else that could
have exposed him to heavy metals.
He and his wife worked a wedding
at Cabo San Lucas last month.
A lot of pottery in Mexico is
contaminated with lead-based paint.
Now aren't you
glad you joined us?
Search their house, screen
his blood and hair for lead.
Test for mercury and
arsenic while you're at it.
And, Chase, find out
what the resort cooks with,
if they repainted recently
or did any plumbing repairs.
But I don't speak Spanish.
Then it'll be challenging.
Good Lord, what is that smell?
Stuffed pepper.
Stuffed with what? Vomit?
I thought you were
going to a hotel.
I found an apartment. I
can move in on Monday.
Is that fast enough
for you? What's today?
Where'd you get all that
stuff? Not from your kitchen.
Don't you ever eat anything besides
canned soup and peanut butter?
Don't you ever eat
anything that doesn't look like
it's been rolled onto your
plate by a dung beetle?
Try it.
It's good, isn't it?
No.
Just better than it looks.
How much beans and rice
do you think you'd have to eat
from a ceramic pot painted
with lead-based paint
to get enough lead into your
system to damage your lungs?
Are we talking a child,
or an adult? Adult.
Then I would say a lot.
You'd have to eat beans
every day for months.
Now, why do you have a season
pass to the New Yankee workshop?
It's a complete moron
working with power tools.
How much more
suspenseful can you get?
I'm... I was watching something.
No, you were about
to watch something.
I'm watching something.
See the difference?
If the water was contaminated,
wouldn't I be sick, too?
People can metabolize
toxins at different rates.
We'll test it to be sure.
Have you done any
recent renovations? No.
Have any problem
with bugs or rodents?
Just the occasional ant.
Use bug spray?
No, I hate the smell.
Luckily both of us are pretty
anal about keeping things clean.
Yeah, I can tell.
You think ants are the problem?
Can you stop stuffing your mouth
with pancakes for one second?
These aren't pancakes. These
are macadamia nut pancakes.
Wilson made them
and they're amazing.
She says she
doesn't use bug spray.
Like little silver dollar
slices of heaven.
Some ants are
poisonous, maybe...
Forget the 72 virgins.
If I blow myself up in
a crowded restaurant,
I'm going to be asking
for a plate of these babies.
Was the ant big and
red or small and black?
Medium and brown.
Halle Berry brown
or Beyoncé brown?
Is there a difference?
Army ants could devour, dissolve,
and eat a cow in a matter of hours.
Australian Bull ants,
on the other hand,
nasty little bastards, but more
of a nuisance than a threat.
No surprise there.
Beyoncé.
Well, then that's not it.
How much clay did
he eat at the resort?
It's a five-star,
$400 a night place.
They don't cook
with ceramic pots.
Tox screen? No evidence
of lead, mercury or arsenic.
Run them again.
Call the resort, find some
disgruntled employee to talk to.
Go back to the home...
It's not heavy metals.
The symptoms say it
is. The tests say it's not.
Well, who you going to believe?
The symptoms or the test?
It could also be a food
allergy. Cameron says it's not.
If your test could be
wrong, why can't hers?
His diet hasn't changed
since he was a kid.
His favorite food is cornflakes.
Which, I assume,
he eats with milk,
one of the most common
adult onset food allergies.
Start treating him
for lead poisoning.
It's the most
likely heavy metal.
And, yeah, you can test him for
allergies for dairy, wheat and legume.
I am not having an affair with
my daughter's karate instructor
and I did not give
my husband herpes.
Find out where House is.
If you're convinced
it's allergies,
why are you giving him
drugs to treat lead poisoning?
We're not convinced
of anything yet.
I think I need something
else, this cream isn't working.
We're doing everything we can.
Sorry. No, no. It's not
my back, it's my feet!
I think I stepped in something
when I went to the bathroom.
Oh, it's on my
socks. It's burning.
I don't see anything.
Please, take my socks off!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Stop! Stop! What did
you just scratch him with?
If there was an
allergic reaction,
it would be on his
back, not on his feet.
Oh, it's burning,
please make it stop!
We need some gabapentin in here.
Excruciating pain in
the lower extremities.
Not a sign of a food allergy.
Means there's a
neurological problem.
More significantly, it's yet another
classic sign of heavy metals.
And I just did yet another
hair and blood test for lead,
and everything else he could
have possibly been exposed to.
They're all negative. It's
gotta be something else.
Lupus could cause... HOUSE: No.
Lupus progresses slower.
There'd be joint pain.
So it's not a typical case.
We should get an
ANA. It's not lupus.
The symptoms don't match.
And the tests don't
match heavy metals.
It's happening again.
He's not breathing.
Tongue swelling, airway's
closing. He's not getting any air.
His lungs are clear. We're
gonna have to intubate.
Try to relax, Bob. This is
gonna help you breathe.
Oh, my God!
He's gonna aspirate!
Need suction!
What's happening? Suction.
There's too much vomit. We're
never going to be able to intubate.
We're gonna have to trach
him. He's not breathing!
His urine has elevated
proteins and red blood cells.
It's lupus-induced kidney
failure. If we don't start treatment...
Heavy metal toxicity
could cause vomiting.
So would lupus nephritis, and
it also causes tissue swelling.
He's choking on his
tongue, not his feet.
The corticosteroids we gave
him to control the inflammation
can cause facial swelling.
Still not his throat, but
you're getting closer.
I'm doing an ANA and
a serum compliment.
If you're so sure, why waste time
with tests? Just start treatment.
Oh, no wait. We
can't do that because
we already have and
it's not working! Ergo.
Corticosteroids aren't the only
treatment for lupus nephritis.
We could also try cyclophosphamide
or immunosuppressants.
Only if we confirm the diagnosis
with an ANA serum compliment,
anti-DNA, IV pyelogram
and kidney biopsy.
So, now you suddenly believe
in tests? The symptoms...
The symptoms all point
to heavy metal poisoning.
Yeah, we all get it.
Unless you've got proof, and
can tell me which heavy metal it is,
I'm starting
treatment for lupus.
Systemic lupus erythematosus
causes the immune system
to become hyperactive.
Attack normal tissue.
Now, it could be what
caused the lung inflammation,
as well as the
swelling in his throat.
And now what appears to
be damage to his kidneys.
The treatment's
usually steroids.
But he's already
on the steroids.
If the tests confirm
we're on the right track,
there are other
medications we can try.
And if those don't work?
Well, lupus, it's a
chronic condition,
but it's generally controllable.
What do you mean, "generally"?
In rare cases, it can cause
cardiovascular or renal failure.
Cardiovascular and renal.
That's the heart
and the kidneys.
Right? Yeah.
Don't worry, it'll be all right.
Enjoying the salad?
There's no lettuce.
I'm aware that
there's no lettuce.
But do you know when I
obtained this knowledge?
Actually, I'm in the middle of
something. When I made it. For myself.
Well, how was I
supposed to know?
Well, I was hoping
this might tip you off.
That's kind of selfish,
don't you think?
I offered to make you
some. You said no.
That was before I
tasted the pancakes.
It's a compliment.
You should be flattered.
Here.
It's Mrs. Lambert's
herpes test results.
Mrs. who?
You've told more
than one patient
his wife is sleeping with his
daughter's karate teacher?
You wanna stir the pot, you
have to clean up the mess.
What would you
do if you got herpes?
She's coming in at 5:00. Don't
make me come looking for you.
Actually, I'd know what you'd
do. But I mean, a normal guy?
And don't be calling in
sick, or saying that your team
needs you for some
kind of emergency consult.
He suspected that maybe his wife
had also been playing pickle games.
He could just keep
it on the down low,
just wait till she got infected.
You'd give your own wife
herpes, just to shift the blame?
He'd give his own mother herpes
if it got him out
of clinic duty.
Course, maybe it was the wife.
Maybe she was the one who...
Where's Mrs. Nympho?
She's waiting outside, why?
Go search her. What, you
mean her medical records?
If I meant that, good
chance I'd have said that.
You think she's poisoning him?
His symptoms should be
getting better the longer he's here.
Instead, they're getting worse.
So, either she's poisoning
him, or it's not heavy metals.
We've done over 10 different
heavy metal tox screens.
Because there's no reason
to test for the other 30.
They don't get
into the air or food.
They only get in you if
someone puts them in you.
And the only way
we're going to find out
what she's sprinkling on his
cornflakes, is to search her.
I am not going to accuse a woman
of trying to murder her own husband
based simply on
some paranoid theory.
It's the only explanation.
We've eliminated
every other possibility.
We have not eliminated
every other possibility!
Has he responded to
the latest lupus treatment?
He's only been
on it a few hours.
He hasn't responded
because it's not lupus.
It's not allergies, ALS,
arthritis or sarcoidosis.
She's all that's left.
Do it!
Hi.
I'm Dr. House.
Mind if I take a
look in your purse?
Why?
Because I'm going to
need to search it and you
for whatever you're using
to poison your husband.
Why would I want
to hurt my husband?
Then you won't mind
if I search your things.
Go ahead.
You satisfied?
Absolutely not!
She agreed to let me
search everywhere else,
but this she says no to.
Doesn't that tell you something?
Yes, that she doesn't want some
lunatic doctor searching her vagina
with a flashlight.
Cameron can do that.
I am not going to...
The woman hasn't left the
hospital since they arrived.
Whatever she's using, she's
obviously hiding somewhere.
She's not poisoning him!
It's the only explanation!
No, it's the only explanation
your twisted mind can come up with
because you're angry that
you can't find the answer,
and you're taking it out on her.
And you are protecting
a complete stranger
based on some childishly romantic notion
that people are all so happily married
they don't want
to kill each other.
You're calling me
childish? Grow up!
Shut up! Both of you.
And stay away from his wife.
Sorry, I'm not giving you
permission to assault someone.
Let's see.
I'm thinking, Colonel Mustard,
in the music room
with a candlestick.
There's no music room.
It's the conservatory.
Same thing. No, it isn't.
If we don't find out
what she's using
and start treatment immediately,
he'll be dead in a
week. If you're right.
If Foreman's right, you'd have
basically raped an innocent woman.
My wife fired the maid.
Apparently she's getting rid of
everything that reminds her of me.
You did your maid? I
was nice to our maid,
which annoyed
her, God knows why.
Maybe she was doing her.
No one was doing her, all right?
But you still feel responsible?
Even though nothing or no
one was done, it's still your fault.
I offered to keep paying her
salary until she found another job.
But she refused to take any
money without doing any work, so...
You want someone to clean
your apartment? It's on me.
You're supposed to be moving
out, not moving more people in.
She's not moving
in, she's gonna clean.
Maybe I should just move
out, and the two of you could...
Oh, God!
- Oh, God, no!
- Call a code!
Please!
Charging 360. Give him Epi.
Clear!
Still no pulse.
Charging! Clear!
I got a pulse.
Pupils are reactive.
You still with us?
He was without oxygen for less
than a minute. It can't be hypoxia.
Could be a stroke.
Bob, can you hear me?
Back up. Bob?
Bob, talk to me.
Bob! Honey, please!
Bob, can you hear me?
He's awake. Can you hear me?
Honey?
Honey.
Yes, she is quite
the little actress.
So, let's say she's
not poisoning him.
There's nothing more to discuss.
We've got lung
and kidney failure,
neurological symptoms
and now, cardiac arrest.
A systemic disease with multi-organ
involvement is the definition of lupus.
The auto-immunosuppressants
aren't helping.
We should start him on cyclophosphamide.
See if it makes a difference.
Yeah, and interferon.
Interferon isn't an
approved treatment for lupus.
You're not still thinking...
Interferon isn't an
approved treatment
for heavy metal
toxicity, either.
True. But it's pretty much the only
thing we can do for a viral infection.
We didn't consider it because...
Because it doesn't make sense.
There's no fever.
Because he's got
no immune system.
Thanks to the immunosuppressants
you prescribed
for lupus treatment.
He didn't present
with a fever, either.
Because at that point,
he was a post-viral autoimmune
reaction, which again,
thanks to the immunosuppresants
you prescribed
for lupus treatment.
His immune system basically rolled
out the red carpet for the dormant virus,
waking it up and turning it
into a present viral infection.
Give him interferon.
But if it is lupus, interferon
could make it worse,
suppress his bone marrow
even further. Which is more likely?
Rapidly progressing, acute onset
lupus in a patient already on steroids,
or a team of doctors
missing a post-viral reaction?
We didn't miss anything.
Well, then I'm wrong.
And you shouldn't
give him interferon!
Intravenous interferon has been shown to
be effective against some viral infections.
But I thought you said it wasn't
an infection. You said it was lupus.
The increasingly rapid
progression of the symptoms
has caused us to reconsider.
And what if you're
wrong here, too?
What if it's not a virus?
There are risks with interferon,
especially in a patient who's
already immunosupressed.
Look, at this point, your lungs,
kidneys and heart are all failing.
We really don't have any choice.
I cheated.
What?
Ninth grade, Earth Science.
Mr. Foley.
I sat behind you, so I
could cheat off of you.
And I let you cheat,
so you'd sit behind me.
I thought we were going
to grow old together.
In ninth grade?
No, tenth.
What, you had to
make sure I put out first?
No, I knew you'd put
out in the seventh grade.
I love you.
Yeah, I know.
Say you love me.
No.
Why not?
Because you're not dying.
Say it anyway.
You gonna make me hurt you?
I love you.
It's not working.
Both his lungs and kidneys
are continuing to deteriorate.
Up the dose.
We already have.
Apparently not enough.
I don't think it's a virus.
We've been running titers for everything
we can think of. They're all negative.
Increase the interferon. House.
You got a better
idea other than lupus?
No.
Then up the dose.
Mr. and Mrs. Lambert's
appointment was over an hour ago.
Sorry, I was sick. And my team
needed an emergency consult.
Your wife has herpes.
What?
That's impossible,
I don't have any...
You haven't had an outbreak
yet. Don't worry, you will.
You rutty jackass! Me?
I haven't been with
anyone in 20 years.
You're the one with
the blisters on his...
Doesn't mean
that he got it first.
You don't need to have an
outbreak to spread the virus.
Yeah, and you're the one always
talking about wanting more sex.
From you.
And maybe I'd get more if you
weren't getting it somewhere else.
Well, you two obviously
have a lot to talk about.
Don't even think of
dumping this in my lap.
There's gotta be some
way to prove that it's him.
I'm sorry, there is no test.
Either of you two ever
sit on a public toilet?
Well?
Of course.
Herpes can live for short
periods of time outside the body.
Dr. House, you know
you can't get herpes...
Some politically correct doctors
will tell you that it's impossible
to get infected
by a toilet seat.
But they'll also tell you not
to use the same bath towels
to dry your crotch and
your face during an outbreak.
See the contradiction?
I always use a paper cover.
Always? Yes, of course.
What about you?
No. I never knew.
Oh, please. This is ridiculous.
Damn, I was sure it was Miyagi.
What?
He could believe that you can
get herpes from a toilet seat,
or he could be cheating on you
and just be happy to have an out.
The toilet seat makes sense, doesn't it?
- Sure.
But she'd only
refused to believe
such a well presented
lie if she were innocent.
And since you both can't be
innocent, you rutty jackass!
You!
Thanks a lot. My pleasure.
Honey, wait. Please!
Wow!
Not bad.
She has a family history
of arthritis, doesn't she?
Yeah, she does. What does...
Stop the interferon,
and do another heavy metal
screen, only this time test for gold.
You don't still
think that she...
Don't let her go
to the bathroom.
Why would you care if she...
Hello?
Oh!
Hi, I'm Lady.
What did you do to my closet?
I cleaned it.
Dr. Wilson said that
I could go ahead...
It's not Dr. Wilson's closet.
Where's the wood box?
Wood box?
Yes, the wood box. It's made
of wood, and it's box shaped.
It's been in the back of this
closet since the day I moved in.
I didn't see any kind of...
You may not have seen it,
but you've obviously moved
it. The question is where.
Well, I did not move
anything, I just...
It was in this closet.
Then you came, now
it's not in this closet.
Okay. What type of box?
Wood! Wood!
A brown wood box. It's got
a metal handle on the top,
looks like a tackle or tool box.
Ah, you mean the chest.
The one that's under the bed?
Do you need to fix something?
Thanks.
Well, fine, then I'll go
to one on another floor.
Actually, they're not
working there either.
Every bathroom in the
whole hospital is out of order?
Well, the water...
I'm going to the bathroom.
Where is she? Had
to go to the bathroom.
I told you not to let her.
What was I supposed
to do? Tie her up?
Why not? She likes that.
What are you doing?
Your hand is wet.
Sorry, must be nervous.
I've got some bad news.
What?
The damage to your
husband's lungs is permanent.
The kidney damage is reversible,
and with the right therapy,
he should regain full
neurological function.
Other than the fact that he's not
going to be running any marathons,
he should be fine.
But that's good news, isn't it?
Not finished.
When I was a kid,
my dad was stationed
at a Marine base in Egypt.
We were in the middle of nowhere
and there was absolutely
nothing for a kid to do,
except look for a mummy's tomb.
You didn't want me to go to the
bathroom because you wanted to tell me
my husband is going to be fine
and that you used to live in Egypt?
I didn't have a problem with
you going to the bathroom.
I just didn't want you
to wash your hands.
I never actually found a mummy,
but I did learn a fair amount
about the ancient Egyptians.
For example, they discovered
that stannous chloride
is not only great for toughening
ruby glass, but if it's mixed with gold,
it turns bright purple.
Now, either your fingers actually
are worth their weight in gold,
or you've been sprinkling your husband's
cereal with gold sodium thiomalate.
It's an arthritis remedy. It's
rarely used here in the U.S.,
but it's still popular in
Mexico. Gotta give you props.
Never heard of anyone
using gold before.
It's almost poetic.
That's ridiculous.
Heavy metal tox screen
for gold was off the chart.
Why would I... Because
you were trying to kill him.
I'd love to know the
why behind that why.
But you're not gonna
tell me, are you?
You're wrong.
I love Bob.
I never said you
didn't love him.
How could somebody do that?
Sit by someone's
bedside day and night
helping them, comforting them
and at the same time killing them?
Maybe he was having an affair.
Maybe she was having an affair.
Or maybe she just
gets her kicks out
of slowly sucking
the life out of a guy,
watching him suffer.
He must have done
something to her.
Yeah, he had it coming.
I didn't say he deserved it.
The only thing he did
wrong was marry a sociopath.
Or maybe she just got
tired of being married.
Didn't want to admit
to family and friends
that the marriage everyone
thought was perfect, wasn't.
Shouldn't one of us stay with
her? What if she tries to run?
Yeah, Cameron, go back there.
It'd be weird if we were
all in the ladies' room.
We started chelation
therapy with dimercaprol.
Thrilled to hear it.
His kidney function
hasn't improved.
It will.
He's gonna need
a lung transplant.
He's becoming more
attractive by the minute, isn't he?
You're pleased.
You think you've proved that
every marriage is a mistake.
Do I look pleased?
Ignorance is bliss.
You have one new message.
Hi, this is Blake Hanson
calling for Dr. Wilson.
I got a better offer
for the apartment.
I know I offered
it to you already,
so if you match the offer
you can still have the place.
Make sure you call me first thing
in the morning and let me know.
Otherwise, well,
you've got my number.
Message deleted.