Previously on ER:
I understand you want
to define yourself as chief.
Are you sure that this is
the way you want to do it?
I suck.
No, you don't suck.
You're still learning.
So how are you doing?
I processed my feelings of anger, shame and
guilt in an emotionally safe environment.
I've addressed the
urge to use alcohol.
And I've consulted both a
shaman and a guru, so I'm all good.
I must've really made an impression on you.
You didn't notice I was gone for a week.
Are you high?
Alex, hurry up! The
bus is gonna be here!
- What time do you start?
- Noon.
- Is Neela on today?
- Hmm?
- Is Neela on?
- I don't know. I think she is.
It's funny how that
keeps working out.
- What?
- Nothing.
Come on. She's young, single,
lonely. She's got a crush on you.
I'm her teacher. She's
just trying to learn.
Yeah, bet she is.
- Ah, come on.
- What? Everyone can see it.
- Who's everyone?
- Uh, Pratt, Frank...
Jerry, Morris, Chuny, Haleh.
Even Murray.
- Murray?
- That guy who works at the roach coach.
It's not funny, Luka. You're
doing everything to encourage it.
Mm.
- That's not true.
- Yeah? Well, it better not be.
Or else I might have to get into
some nasty chick fight with Neela.
In the mud? Just don't hurt her.
The only person who's going to get
hurt around here is you. You got it?
Yeah, I think it was April.
But the fact that I need a calendar
to figure it out is not a good sign.
- Did I meet him?
- No.
He drove a motorcycle.
- That was his defining characteristic?
- I'm afraid so.
- What about you?
- Third year.
My gross anatomy instructor.
He was very skilled at
prosecting the brachial plexus.
You slept with your instructor?
Dr. Gibson had a very
tender way with cadavers.
And you called him Dr. Gibson?
Only in bed.
So basically, neither one of us has
gotten any in a ridiculously long time.
Well, at least we have
work to keep our minds off...
men, romance, sex.
Yeah, at least we have that.
- Morning.
Hello, Luka. NEELA: Dr. Kovac.
Uh, multiple MVA
on their way in.
Patient-satisfaction scores were
up 0.6 points from two weeks ago.
- Is that good?
- Yeah, it's good. Very good.
I'm gonna post it. Um,
Carter, I wanna thank you.
I know that my taking over
as chief has been stressful.
It's been a little
weird for you...
but you've made the transition
a lot easier, and I appreciate it.
Susan, I can't think of anybody
I'd rather have as a boss than you.
Sixteen-year-old driver
backed into a utility pole.
Okay, hop to it. And don't
call me Susan at work.
What happened?
- Dad was teaching her to parallel park.
- She just got her learner's permit.
I got a little bit dizzy, and
maybe I got the pedals mixed up.
Uh-huh.
New scores?
Yep, we don't suck as bad as we used
to. Maybe by next week, we'll suck less.
- Must be your motivational speeches.
- We're pairing Attendings with interns.
- Abby, you got me. Neela, you got Kovac.
- What?
Big Croatian guy.
You can't miss him.
We've got a double MVC rolling
in. Abby, he's all yours today.
Who? STUDENT: Hey.
You guys know each other, right?
Hi.
You know how to clear
a C-spine clinically?
Uh, you mean, if
it's not, uh, tender?
That's a no. Check the NEXUS
criteria. Get back to me tomorrow.
I give you Rodney
Dixon and Amanda Field.
Rear-ended by a truck
while having sex in his car.
Good vitals on both. - I'd say.
- Are they stuck together with super-glue?
- We tried to disengage them, but...
- Oh, it's killing me, man.
- Broken pelvis plus lust equals...
Oh, God!
Chest is clear, belly's benign.
- Back seat of a car, huh?
'66 Mustang fastback.
I hope it's not totaled.
- Fastback? That's a pretty tight squeeze.
- I do Pilates.
It's got a 389-1 rear
gear with a 31 spline axle.
- Nice.
- You were screwing in an old Ford?
What were we supposed to
do? My husband was home.
- Oh, God.
- Probably a small crack in the pelvis.
- Aah!
- You've got this, right?
Oh, I'm all over it.
We'll give you morphine and
wait for your Viagra to wear off.
Dr. Lewis told me to
present to you today.
- She did?
- Something about interns...
having a primary Attending.
- Okay.
- I hope you'll show me...
that combat procedure
you mentioned last shift.
The femoral tear.
Oh, it depends on, uh,
whether we get a patient...
- who needs emergent central access.
- Well, whenever we do.
- Uh...
- Sorry.
Uh...
- Infected anal fissure in the hallway.
- Okay.
- Pupils, four millimeters and reactive.
- Ten centimeters JVD.
My wife is not gonna be happy.
It's okay, Dad. It was my idea.
I take it Mom wasn't
aware of the lessons.
Uh, if she had it her way, I
would never be allowed out.
We're kind of separated for now.
Uh, Katie was with me this week.
Does she take any medications?
Prednisone, tacrolimus...
- The anti-rejection drug?
- She had a kidney transplant.
I have polycystic
kidney disease.
We were on the UNOS list for
seven years waiting for a donor.
Yeah, I'm a big fan of dialysis.
She's got blood type O...
with an 80 percent
reactive antibody panel.
- Tough match.
- Yeah, well...
finally got big enough that I
could give her one of mine.
Your kidney?
What a dad, huh?
Any other meds?
Uh, yeah, she's on an
anti-seizure drug too.
The PKD gave her an aneurysm.
Mom's on the way, sweetie.
Thanks.
Okay. A few
crackles at the base.
Bradycardic at 48.
Whoa. Peak T waves, widened QRS.
All right, amp of bicarb,
10 cc's of calcium gluconate.
What do you think is going on?
- Um...
Well, low heart rate,
dizziness and EKG changes.
Could be hyperkalemia.
What?
No, no, that can't be.
- Hey, John.
Since the transplant,
her kidney has been fine.
Why don't we see what
the blood tests show...
then we'll take it from there.
Excuse me for one second.
- Do you have an intern on this?
- I got Ray.
Uh...
- What do you think about taking Neela?
- Why? Is there a problem?
Just do me a favor, okay?
All right, send the Punjabi
Powerhouse my way.
Painless jaundice in 3
and ulnar styloid fracture.
I'll take those.
Uh, there was a change.
You're with Carter today.
- I thought I was with you.
- No, he needs you in Trauma 1.
Isolated pubic ramus fracture.
Will I be, you know, all right?
No cast, no surgery.
Just rest and pain meds.
But you're gonna have to be careful
for a couple of weeks until it heals.
- Careful?
- Yes, as in abstinent.
The safest sex of all.
- Abstinent? Are you serious?
- Can't put any pressure on your pelvis...
or you'll end up back
here. Not what we want.
- It's the pelvis we should worry about?
- That's right.
But other positions?
Yeah, sure.
Get yourself a six-pack, the
Kamasutra, and shoot out the lights.
Did we do something
to offend her?
Pulse is up to 61. BP's stable.
Looks like the QRS
complexes are narrowing.
- That's good.
- That is good.
The chemistry machine is
down. Should be up in an hour.
- You can't say if it's a kidney problem?
- The urine dip shows four-plus protein.
- We won't know till the labs come back.
- I told them to hurry.
- Honey, are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine, Mom.
- Sweetie...
- It was nothing.
I told you it was too
soon for her to drive.
- What were you thinking?
- She's 16. She wants a permit.
You never know when to stop.
- Let's not do this here.
- Please.
I need more of Katie's family
history. Could we step outside...
and give Katie a chance to rest?
I'll be back, okay, sweetie?
I've been sick for so long, it
just got to be too much for them.
She was on, uh,
Dilantin for a long time...
but, uh, she didn't like it. It
changed the way she looked.
- She was still having these seizures...
- It was manageable.
No, honey. She had them
at school, in the movies.
- She hated it.
- So you switched her medication?
- Three months ago we put her on Zarictal.
- It was not my choice.
- Zarictal?
- It's new.
And we can't afford it.
Medicare does not cover it.
I took a second job working night
security at the Mallers Building.
- We lost our apartment.
- She's been doing great.
Katie has been
seizure-free for three months.
- No infections?
- No.
No febrile illnesses?
Have they switched her
dosage of, uh, Zarictal?
- Everything's been steady.
- But she was doing fine before.
- I don't know why...
- She wanted to drive.
Like other kids.
With seizures, she
couldn't get a license.
We almost lost her...
and you're worried about
her being able to drive?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Look,
I don't want to fight, okay?
I think it's time that we accept the
fact she will never be totally healthy...
- Why?
- That's reality!
Not for me.
I...
You have a neurologist?
- Yeah, he's been great.
- Good. Why don't we give him a call.
I'd like to talk to him
about the medications.
- Sounds like a hard situation.
- Look up this new drug for me.
I had a patient on that last year
during my internal medicine rotation.
Really? Never
heard of it before.
It's pretty new. Expensive, but
very effective for seizure control.
You kids and your
fancy book learning.
- Yeah, well, I try to keep up.
- Do a PDR and check a Medline.
See if there's renal dysfunction
associated with the drug.
Okay.
- Hi.
This is George Guidry.
He's got a skin breakdown
around the shaft of his penis.
- No, he doesn't.
- I think I do.
- Any discharge?
- Oh, yeah. Definitely.
- I'm not talking about that. JAKE:
No discharge, no fever, no blisters.
Do you use a condom?
Not since my girlfriend
broke up with me.
No vesicles, no chancre,
no lymphadenopathy.
Okay.
- Let's take a gander.
- Yeah.
You know, I just thought of something.
Could this be from too much...?
You know...
Too much what?
Since Lily left, I've
been lonely, you know?
Really...
really lonely.
How lonely?
Uh, six, sometimes
seven times a day.
I found a report in the
Western Journal of Medicine.
It suggests a correlation
between renal failure and Zarictal.
- Hmm. Well, that ain't much.
- No, but these might be.
From the adverse drug coordinator
from the Department of Health Services.
Three possible cases
they've forwarded to the FDA.
Four? That could be a pattern.
The Physician Relations number
at Keating-Ward Pharmaceuticals.
They make Zarictal. Might as
well see what they can tell us.
- Yes. WOMAN:
Keating-Ward Pharmaceuticals.
This is John Carter. I'm a physician
at County General in Chicago.
- How are you today, doctor?
- Very well. I have a 16-year-old girl.
Status: post-renal transplant who's
been on Zarictal for three months.
You say that's three months?
Could I talk to somebody about
the incidence of renal failure?
- Hold.
- Yes, I will hold.
Does anybody even listen
to that music? It's terrible.
Carter, QRS is
widening on our PKD girl.
- Lots of ectopy.
- I'll hold.
- Multifocal PVCs, runs of six.
- Push 80 of lidocaine, and mix up a drip.
- What's going on?
- It's possible the elevated potassium...
is irritating Katie's heart.
BUN, 98. Creatinine,
12.3. Potassium, 7.2.
Most likely she might
be in kidney failure.
V-fib. Starting compressions.
Charge the paddles to 200.
It's going to be
okay. It's okay.
Everybody clear. - Clear.
- Procainamide's onboard.
- And clear.
- Sinus.
- There we go.
Set up for a femoral Quinton.
Call Dialysis for renal orders.
Katie, honey? Katie, honey?
- That's it. CARTER:
Yeah, she's responding.
- O2 on 15 liters.
- Are you sure she needs dialysis?
Uh, it's the best way to remove the
excess potassium from her system.
- She has to have another transplant?
- That's a distinct possibility, yes.
- Oh, no.
- Betadine the area.
They said they'd be
in contact in a week.
- And one percent lido. A week?
- That's the standard procedure.
- What's that?
- We telephoned the company...
that makes Katie's medication.
So is it the drug? Is that
why this is happening?
The timing of the med switch makes
me think that is a possibility, yes.
But her kidney is being
damaged by the Zarictal, is that...?
Gabriel, Hannah, I
came as soon as I heard.
- Was she in status?
- No, it's her kidney.
This is Katie's
neurologist, George Henry.
Dr. Carter, um, I don't
know if you remember me...
Yeah, how are you, Henry?
What has it been, six years?
Give or take.
Can you take them to the family
room? I'll be right in to see you.
Oh, okay. Yeah, that's fine.
I think I remember the way.
Come on. It's all right.
I gave pleasure boy some Neosporin, a
therapist's number, and sent him packing.
- Well done.
- How about you? Is everything all right?
Um...
Yes, I'm fine. Busy. Why?
Well, last week when I ran
into you on the El platform...
I didn't realize your situation.
My situation?
It's just that I...
I heard what you went through. I
didn't want you to think I was insensitive.
Um, no, I was happy not to
have to talk about it actually.
Okay. Guess I'm
blowing that now.
I just...
I wanna make sure that there
isn't anything that I can, uh, do.
Um, well, that's... That's nice.
It is. Thank you. It's, um...
I... Here's an H & P,
and get back to me.
Right.
Why did you put
me with this guy?
When did everyone
become schedule divas?
I don't need a med student. I don't
like them, and I'm better flying solo.
- Is there something wrong with him?
- No, he's excellent. He's very good.
- He's excellent. I just...
- Oh, no. You like him?
- You know what, forget it.
- Yes, you do! You do! You're blushing.
We never had this conversation.
Hey, haven't you had
enough of doctors?
Put a message on the neurology and renal
newsgroups, see if there's anything...
- on the drug's renal toxicity.
- That could cause a bit of a stir.
Yeah. Uh, all right...
just ask for any information that
might help us best determine treatment.
- You heard what he said.
- I don't believe it's the drug.
- I think that there are other options.
- We have a dialysis tech coming down.
I called UNOS. They're
gonna put Katie on the list.
John, that may be premature.
Why don't we do a biopsy.
This may be a case of rejection, not
failure, and a biopsy would show us that.
What's the difference?
Well, a drug-induced failure
would require a transplant.
But, uh...
rejection...
Rejection could be reversed
with immunosuppressive agents.
Well, let's do the biopsy.
Okay, I'll put that in motion.
Dr. Henry, can I have a
word with you outside, please?
Excuse me one second.
Um...
My intern's been doing
research. She's found four cases...
- of renal failure in patients on Zarictal.
- Well, that doesn't prove causation.
It gets you going that way.
Keating-Ward sponsored a
series of phase-three clinical trials.
If there was any real risk, the FDA
would never have approved the drug.
What, you never heard
of Vioxx or Rezulin?
This is a successful
anti-seizure medicine.
It has improved Katie's
quality of life dramatically.
Dr. Carter, dialysis is here.
Uh, page Dubenko to
come down for the biopsy?
Sure. These need your signature.
- Well, I hope you're right.
- Let's be certain.
I was really surprised to
find you still working here.
- Why is that?
- I don't know.
I just guess I thought you
would've moved on by now.
I guess I'm just a
masochist that way.
How about you? I thought you
wanted to go do, uh, bench research.
- Yeah, well, I got tired of it.
- You were good at it.
Well, I've got a wife and
two small children now.
It changes one's priorities.
You mean, money?
My practice does offer me three
times the salary of an academic position.
Well, what about you, huh?
Married? Children?
Not yet.
Thanks.
I'll find you when the
surgeon comes down.
Are you moonlighting
as a word processor?
Our PKD girl's on a new drug
we're trying to get information on.
- Hey, Sam.
- Hey, Dr. Lewis.
- Morning.
- Hi. Has anyone seen...?
Is that your coffee?
Sorry.
It's a schedule, not
a cocktail napkin.
GCS, 12. BP, 60
palp. Brady at 52.
- Fell from the roof?
- Taking down lights.
He's gonna need central access.
- Need help?
- Come on down.
- Carter doesn't need you?
Not at the moment, no.
Okay, prime the rapid infuser.
- Can't find a vein.
- Pressure's only 50.
- Heart rate's 42.
- Blood in the belly.
He needs access.
He's about to arrest.
- Set up for a saphenous cutdown.
- Wouldn't a femoral be easier to find?
And faster.
Probably the same difference.
But, okay, femoral tear.
Cool, I've never done one.
You'll do the next
one. Scalpel to Neela.
What? She's along for the ride.
- I promised her.
- You promised her?
Ten centimeters, vertical flash.
- Starting here?
- Deep into the sub-Q.
Level one is primed.
Okay, and now you tear...
- Whoa.
- Got any sterile surgical markers?
There's the femoral vein.
Cannulate it with the 9 French.
- Let me try.
- No, I'll get it.
Just reach under.
Neela, focus on the field.
Seldinger technique.
You know what to do.
Two units ready to go.
Sam, can you ask Dubenko
to come here when he's done?
Yes, sir, Dr. Kovac.
That's the lower lobe
of the kidney there.
- Mark the depth.
- Purple okay?
That's my favorite color.
- Ah, me too.
- Three centimeters.
- They need you next door.
What is this gonna do?
It'll tell us if your body is
rejecting the kidney. Lidocaine.
That's a good thing, honey.
- All right, hold still.
Little pinprick here.
There you go.
It's going to be, like, 20-something
before I can get another one.
- No, that's not going to happen.
- Um, biopsy gun.
You just need to tell your immune
system to stop being so picky.
Firing.
Dr. Carter.
Dr. Weaver's on the phone.
- She sounds kind of...
- Kind of what?
- Weaver-like.
- Um, I'll call her back.
Purple, huh? I've always
been partial to azure myself.
- What's azure?
- Like your eyes.
Send that off for light
microscopy, EM and IF staining.
Pack the wound
with a moist gauze.
- What do we have here?
- Belly bleed needs a post-op head CT.
- We have FFP thawing.
- Send it upstairs.
Pressure's up to 100
systolic. Heart rate's 90.
Dr. Kovac, I, uh...
I never knew it was
possible to transfuse that fast.
Well, that's the beauty of
the central venous cutdown.
Now you know how to do it.
- What made you recommend Zarictal?
- A luncheon at Northwestern.
I heard a neurologist
present on its efficacies.
A neurologist who's a paid
consultant of Keating-Ward.
- So what? It stopped...
- George? Dr. Carter?
- Is everything all right?
- Um...
If the biopsy doesn't
give us what we want...
if she needs another kidney...
could I give her my other one?
That would require you being
on dialysis for the rest of your life.
- No, I understand that. CARTER:
I don't know it's even ethical...
for someone to donate
their only remaining kidney.
So it's not possible.
I don't know of any responsible
doctor that would agree to do it.
Gabe, listen. I... I
know that you're scared.
But let's just take
this one step at a time.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Go in there and be with Katie.
- Carter.
Some neurologist in
Skokie sent this fax for you.
Thanks.
Whew.
It's a "Dear doctor" letter from
the pharmaceutical company.
It says there have been isolated
cases of renal failure on Zarictal.
Yes, I know. It recommends
monthly monitoring of renal function...
which I've been doing
with Katie. BUN, creatinine.
- You got one of these?
- Yes, so did you.
Letters were sent to every physician
in the country. They're a caution.
- So you knew about this.
- Private practitioners...
get letters like that all the time.
I followed its recommendations.
But you know what the biopsy's
gonna show, says so right here.
- Well, I'm hoping that's not the case.
- Dr. Carter, do you have a moment?
- Problem?
- No, Kerry just...
You posted a warning about
Zarictal on an Internet message board?
I posted a request
for information.
I'm getting a lot of phone
calls. I hate phone calls.
Neurologists, our head of nephrology,
the director from KW Pharmaceuticals...
Just wanted to
be better informed.
By jumping to conclusions
based on skimpy evidence?
Tell it to the Milners, their
daughter needs a new kidney.
You have one sick girl, that's unfortunate.
The drug companies have access...
to thousands of patients
before they release a drug...
They didn't use any
renal patients when...
They can't document every side effect.
You're working beyond your responsibility.
You telling me how to do my job?
I'm telling you the FDA has an
Adverse Drug Event division...
Which is run by political appointees
funded by the drug companies.
The number one lobbyist in the
country is the pharmaceutical industry.
Come here. Come on.
- Pick up a bottle.
- Kerry...
Do it.
Pravastatin.
Saves millions from
heart attacks and strokes.
- Enoxaparin. Know what this is?
- Yes, I do.
It offers better PE prophylaxis and
allows DVT patients to be treated at home.
Linezolid. Fights off strains
of MRSA that used to be fatal.
- I think he gets it.
- Does he?
- Yeah, he does.
- These drugs save lives.
The companies that make them donate
$20 million to our academic programs.
Without that, we have no hospital.
We'd be standing in a mini-mall.
- That makes it okay to suppress results?
- Who says that's what they're doing?
Putting these drugs out here,
seeing how they work is how we learn.
- It's how medicine advances.
- And that's not naive?
Your job is to take care of
your patients, not start a crusade.
Susan, you're the boss. Tell
him to keep his eye on the ball.
No more computer access for you.
It's like I forgot where I was.
I was just looking at
him like he was a huge...
- cupcake. CASHIER:
You want one?
Ah, it's just a
metaphor. Thanks.
So you have a crush on Luka.
That's kind of weird.
It's just a crush.
Crushes are by nature
idealized, unrealistic.
What about Dr. Gibson?
That sounded real.
Gross, but real.
My God, you're
right. It's a pattern.
- I'm a slut for authority.
- Stop it.
- Well, what about you?
- What about me?
- I heard you punched your med student?
- So?
He was bugging me.
- So you're hung up on a subordinate.
- No, I'm not.
- I have a thing for a supervisor.
- So, what, I'm like the yin to your yang?
What are we gonna do?
Ignore it, hope it goes away.
- Right. No need to discuss it.
- No, denial works.
- Sam, dog bite in 3. I wrote for Unasyn.
- I'll get to it.
- You check on my biopsy results yet?
- Yeah, Dubenko is on his way.
- What about my patient in Exam 2?
- I'm waiting on a repeat CBC. Sam?
Done and sent.
Nice seeing you all.
Isometric vacuolization
of the renal tubular cells...
- consistent with drug toxicity.
- No chance that this is rejection?
No tubulitis, no
edema, no inflammation.
- The girl needs a new kidney.
- And it's from the drug?
I'd say so...
- but I don't want to encourage you.
- Encourage me?
Some of my colleagues
were suggesting
you've been all over
the Internet with this.
- I was trying to be thorough.
- Word of advice?
Don't piss off the money people.
Hi, everybody.
This is Katie's biopsy results.
And unfortunately, they are
not what we had hoped for.
So it's not rejection?
No.
No, it's irreversibly damaged.
And is this, um, ahem...
Is this from the Zarictal?
No, it could be from the
tacrolimus she's been on.
I doubt that. Her levels have
been therapeutic for two years.
Wow. So this, uh, drug I've
been working two jobs to pay for...
just to make her life better...
has ruined her donated kidney?
I'm afraid so.
You told me... You
told us it was working.
Sometimes drug interaction
can only become apparent...
after the first year
or two of release.
This couldn't have
been anticipated.
So we're back to waiting?
Well, UNOS will prioritize
her for a new kidney.
That will take three,
four years, if we're lucky?
In the meantime, I'm gonna
recommend we get a surgeon down here...
to see about creating a forearm
shunt to facilitate dialysis access.
I can take care of that. - Okay.
- We're back to where we started.
- She'll be on that machine...
all through high
school? Through college?
Just because it took a
while to get the kidney...
No, it didn't take a
while, there wasn't one.
I gave her mine.
We have given up a lot.
Made a lot of sacrifices.
You told me this
drug was worth it.
Okay, uh, show me your incision.
Fifth ICS, anterior
axillary line.
Go for it.
Pulse ox is 92 on five liters.
Push that in just
superior to the rib.
Okay, spread the clamp.
Sats are coming up.
And slip your finger
into the pleural space.
- Ah, I lost the tract.
- That's okay. Keep your finger in there.
Just guide the tube.
Uh, I'm above the
rib, but it won't pass.
There you go.
Okay.
That is where you want to go.
- All right, I got it.
- Okay.
Keep advancing.
A little bit deeper, because you
want all the ports in the pleural space.
Thora-Seal's
ready, so is suction.
That's very good.
Hello?
Uh, okay, sew it in.
Somebody put something
in the water today?
Call it "pulseless electrical
activity following trauma."
- Right. KOVAC: Change
"blade" into "scalpel."
Don't say "torn," say "dissected."
Call it the "field of exposure."
Uh, you left out the
size of the cordis.
- 9 French.
- Okay, write it down.
And, uh, not "blood."
"Packed red cells."
Okay, good job.
- Just make the changes, and I'll co-sign.
- Okay.
Hey, Neela.
I hope I didn't give you
the wrong impression.
You're a Resident and I'm an
Attending, and I want to help you learn...
Yeah, I got it. I
understand. I'm sorry.
No, it's just... I wouldn't
want anything to get...
I got it, I got it.
I got it, thanks.
Vitals are stable.
- I need to grab an amp of bicarb.
- Okay.
Katie's T waves
are back to normal...
which means her potassium
has come down. That's good.
He went to work.
- Mr. Milner?
- Mm-hm.
He took a second job...
as a security guard over
at the jewelry center...
just to try to help pay
for everything, you know?
Nothing means more to
him than Katie getting well.
Nothing.
Her illness just changed him.
Ruined our marriage.
It's important to
stay optimistic.
A lot of good things could
still happen, Mrs. Milner.
MVC with passenger-space
intrusion. ETA, 7.
- Okay, we'll take it.
- What's MVC?
Motor vehicle collision,
another new protocol.
- No such thing as an accident.
- Ah, I liked MVA.
- I like walks in the springtime.
- John, a minute, please?
- I'll catch up to you.
- Um...
I was aware of the
potential for toxicity.
But it was only one case
report in an obscure journal.
Well, you could have found out
more doing a simple Medline search.
I can't do a Medline search every
time I put a patient on a new drug.
I've got 20
patients on Zarictal.
- Twenty?
- They're all doing well.
What, are you on the
Keating-Ward payroll?
Listen, as part of
an ongoing study...
I send in a monthly update
on each patient's progress.
And they compensate you?
A small stipend for my time.
- Hope your malpractice premiums are paid.
- There's nothing wrong with it.
I am reimbursed for helping monitor a
drug by doing thorough patient evaluations.
That the company only pays attention
to if it says what they want it to.
Her seizures stopped.
She was very happy.
- The father was thrilled.
- He's real thrilled now.
Listen, I am trying to be
a cutting-edge clinician.
That's what the patients want.
- Guys.
I have to offer the most
efficacious meds on the market.
Well, the problem is that
last part, isn't it? The market.
Yo.
What?
Mr. Milner?
- Hey.
Uh, ahem...
I was, uh...
I was going to work,
and I thought, "Why?"
What is the point now?
- Um...
- Gabe, put the gun away.
I put everything in your hands.
Everything. And
you let her down.
Listen, Katie can still live a
long, productive life on dialysis.
Okay, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Come on, why shouldn't I?
- Please.
You know what we should do?
Let's go inside and see your family.
Come on, let's go inside and
we'll see your family right now.
I want to give my kidney to her.
Okay.
Hey, maybe I was wrong about
that. Maybe you can be the donor.
You're lying. I
know you're lying.
I...
- Fix her, okay?
- Yeah.
- For me.
- Yeah, we're gonna fix her.
- Sats down to 88.
- Can you see the cords?
Lots of blood.
All right, somebody go find his wife.
- Okay, tube.
And get that girl out of here.
Come on, move her to another room.
Gray matter covers the occiput.
- Why the hell would he do this?
- He was distraught.
Pupils fixed and dilated.
Pressure's only 80/60.
Start dopamine at 10 mics.
- No gag when I tubed him.
No. No corneal reflex.
- Can he regain any function?
- No, he's as brain-dead as they come.
- I'll go talk to her.
- No. No, no, no, wait. Let me.
I'm her family's doctor.
Transplant coordinator's down.
Technically, there's nobody
else who can give consent.
The girl has a very
rare tissue type, Amparo.
- The father is a match.
- I've made that clear to UNOS.
Look, I'm trying to get
them to allow us to proceed.
For now, keep
him on Fi02 of 100.
Make sure the girl's NPO in
the hope she goes to the O.R.
- Just do everything that you can, okay?
- I will.
- Go back under your rock.
- I'm from the Trib. It's a good paper.
Yeah, right. You
guys endorsed Bush.
Man, a guy shoots himself.
What's next, a plague of frogs?
There's a gang of press outside.
Someone has to go talk to them...
- get them the hell out of here.
- Obviously, the guy was depressed.
All we know is he's in critical
condition. We can't go into any details.
"Heartfelt sympathy to the family.
We're doing everything we can." Good?
- You want me to talk to them?
- You treated these people.
Just play up the fact we're
respecting the family's privacy, okay?
M.A.P. is only 90. Can
we go up on the dopamine?
We're maxed out. I got
a p.r.n. for Levophed.
Sounds good.
Maybe we need to talk?
No, we really don't.
It's just he helped me to
adjust coming back to work here.
He made things a lot
easier, and I guess...
I don't know, I got confused.
I get confused every
time I look at him.
Did you work on this family?
His daughter, yeah.
I'm sorry.
Levophed's going at two mics.
Does Gabriel Milner have a
daughter being treated in ER?
- Ahem. Yes, he does.
- Now, is it true...
- she's suffering from kidney failure?
- Uh, I can't say.
Didn't you indicate that
earlier on a medical website?
General queries... Abby.
Hi. JAKE: Hey.
Do you want to go
get something to eat?
I know this, uh, awesome
little Ethiopian place.
They, um... They make
you eat with your hands...
but I got sterile gloves
in my bag, so it's okay.
- Dinner?
- Yeah.
No.
But don't take it personally.
Okay. Uh...
I'm not really a subtle guy.
But I was under the impression that
there's sort of a thing happening here.
Maybe not a big
thing, but still, a thing.
A thing?
Um...
Yeah. Yeah, maybe
there's a thing...
but you know what,
nothing's gonna happen.
- Why is that?
- Well, a lot of reasons...
which I won't mention because I don't
feel like sharing my checkered past.
- Why?
- Or my various neuroses.
Uh, but there's one really big
reason that's a deal breaker for me.
You miss the beard?
No.
You're my student.
Ah...
I'm grading you.
Uh-huh.
Well, I think that that
is not appropriate.
Uh-huh.
And have a good night.
You know, um, what if I was
willing to take an F right now?
Yeah, I forgot to mention to you
that I'm dropping out of med school.
Yeah. Who wants to
be a doctor anyway?
It's incumbent upon you
to share the information...
if you have possible fatal side
effects of a popular new drug?
Katie Milner was on
Zarictal for three months...
and, yes, I believe the
drug ruined her kidney.
"Out of respect for the family,
that's all I can say." Is that so hard?
- They knew it all already.
- No, they didn't.
You're alleging
potential slander that
could cost the hospital
millions in support.
What are you worried about, free
pens, coffee cups and drug samples?
I'm worried about research grants, a thing
HIPAA calls "patient confidentiality."
- I didn't want to talk to them!
- "Out of respect for the family."
You wanna talk to them, then
you do it. It's your damn ER.
- You're right, I will.
- Dr. Lewis, Dr. Weaver.
Oh, I wonder what she
wants to talk to me about?
It's true, right?
You did a good thing.
You say that like it matters.
- You ready to go?
- Yeah.
UNOS gave us the go ahead.
We're gonna do the transplant.
- Oh, thank God. NEELA:
They're bringing Mr. Milner up.
She doesn't know where the kidney's
coming from. I haven't told her yet.
That can wait. Let's go inside
and talk with the anesthesiologist.
You a medical student?
First-year Resident.
How's that going?
Some days are better than
others. I like it well enough.
What do you think
they'll tell Katie?
They'll tell her that
her father loved her.
Maybe too much.
Transplant surgery's underway.
I can't take responsibility
for how the system works...
but I can try to
do my job better.
That's all any of us can do.
I don't know why I was
surprised to find you here.
Of course you're still here.
Hope we see each other again,
under more favorable circumstances.
You were always good to
me when I was a student.
I remember that.
Anspaugh wants to see us and
Weaver in his office tomorrow morning.
- Suture removal in Curtain 3.
- Hey...
if any of this rolls back
onto you, I'm sorry.
- Mr. Klossey?
- Hi, doc.
How are you today? What
are we looking at here?
I did this skiing on Michigan Avenue,
cross-country, during the last big snow.
- Mm-hm.
- Little fall, gashed my arm.
But I hadn't done it in 10
years, so even that felt good.
- Why did you stop?
- Arthritis. I had it bad.
Couldn't bowl, couldn't sit
in those seats at Wrigley...
take my niece for a walk.
So, what happened?
I saw an ad on TV for Renuvium.
A doc at the clinic
gave me a prescription.
Fixed me right up.
- Renuvium?
- Yeah, a little red pill...
once in the morning, let
me do all those things...
I thought I had
given up forever.
- That's something, huh?
- Yeah.
Okay, this might
hurt just a little bit.
Damn miracle of
medicine, that's what it is.