Okay, I know, I know.
I know--come here, come here.
Hi, hi, hi, hi.
You're okay.
Hey, you're okay. You're okay.
- Look, the air
quality's terrible.
My guess is allergies.
When you hear hoofbeats,
think horses,
not zebras, okay?
Our treatment's been working,
your tumor's been responding.
Let's not panic just yet.
- Felt like the city was...
screaming in my face all night.
Well, that means you definitely
should stay right here in bed.
Is everything all right?
- I'm just tired.
Give me a few minutes,
and I'll be right.
- Hey, you.
- Ah, so this is where
the party's at.
- Uh, yeah, I do feel good.
- Thanks to the 12-straight
hours of morphine
Dr. Handler has been pumping
into your system.
- Okay, whatever. I mean,
like I even need morphine.
With my tolerance,
I'm not even high right now.
- Well, I must say,
for a woman that just
went through major
reconstructive leg surgery,
you look absolutely ravishing.
- Really?
- No.
And if you believe that,
then you're
most assuredly high.
Party's over.
- Martha Randle, collapsed
in her cell at Rikers.
She's G3P4 with
a history of fibroids
producing heavy menstrual flow.
Hypotensive,
tachycardic, and febrile.
Also complaining
of numbness in her leg.
- Can you please tell me
where is the numbness?
- Up and down my right leg.
- Okay.
Can you please lift
your leg for me?
- Wait.
What's wrong with me?
I can't move my leg.
- Dr. Proctor, this is Martha.
- Martha, I'm an OB/GYN.
We're going to get
you sorted out, okay?
I need to order blood
and urine cultures.
- I think you'll
find Staph aureus.
- Toxic shock?
- Martha,
have you been using tampons
for longer than recommended?
- I used my last one...
for nine...
- Nine hours shouldn't
cause this much damage.
- She means nine days.
Alert me the moment
the MRI is ready.
- Nine days?
How did you know?
- Martha is not my
first patient from Rikers
with toxic shock.
How many more
before someone dies?
- Where are we going?
- To find Max.
- Mm.
- Max, I didn't think
you were gonna make it.
- Well, it's a very busy day,
then I heard you were
running my best doctor out
of town, so I made some time.
- Honestly, Max,
I can handle it.
- Yeah, I know you can,
but you shouldn't have to
because you did nothing wrong.
- She was arrested
in a heroin den.
- Safe injection sites
aren't flop houses.
They're the future.
And for helping her patient,
who most doctors would
have let die in the street,
you want to reprimand
the most accomplished,
most selfless,
not to mention coolest
doctor in this hospital?
- She broke the law.
She got caught.
You'll have our disciplinary
action by end of day.
- Imagine if you
hadn't have turned up.
That might've gone poorly.
Why didn't you tell me?
I didn't hear any
of this until I--
- I didn't want to burden you.
Burden me.
- Please, always.
- Max...
we need to talk about Rikers.
Martha Randle is in Rikers
for marijuana possession,
and now she may not live
to see the end of her sentence.
- It's not just tampons.
I've had a dozen patients
tell me that pap smears and
mammograms are being withheld
as punishment,
and now they have cancer.
- So much of this
is preventable.
One routine visit at Rikers,
and most of my inmate
patients wouldn't even be here.
- Hey, guys, I got the 911.
What's going on?
- Uh, Rikers.
- Rikers again?
Man, that place
is a mental-health catastrophe.
My patients go in for a month,
they come out
with a lifetime of trauma.
- Hey, anybody else thinking
what I'm thinking?
- That basic preventative care
would cut the rate
of illness in half there?
- That's not what
he's thinking.
- No?
How many more guesses do I get?
- Casey, grab me
ten exam table rolls,
ten boxes of paper
patient gowns, and all
the female hygiene products
you can fit in the van.
- The van?
- Yeah, also get a van.
- Oh, that's what
he was thinking.
- Wait, you're not
serious, are you?
- Whatever you're in jail
for doesn't mean you deserve
to die because you
couldn't get a checkup.
These women are our patients.
They need our help, and we're
gonna give it to them,
so we are going to Rikers.
- ♪ You can't hide,
you can't hide ♪
♪ You can't hide because
you don't know how ♪
♪ God's got your number
♪ He knows where you live
♪ Death's got
a warrant for you ♪
♪ You can't hide,
you can't hide ♪
♪ You can't hide
because you don't know how ♪
♪ God's got your number
♪ And He knows
where you live ♪
♪ Death's got
a warrant for you ♪
♪ You may run to the rock
♪ To hide your face
♪ The rock cried out,
ain't no hiding place ♪
♪ God's got your number,
and He knows where you live ♪
♪ Death's got
a warrant for you ♪
♪ You may run around
♪ Till you lose your soul
♪ Heaven won't be your home
- Sir, New Amsterdam
doctors are here.
- Warden Hughes,
I'm Dr. Goodwin.
Thanks for having us.
We're very excited
to get our clinic under way.
The mayor said that
you could show us around?
- Did he?
- Let's go, ladies!
- Well, this is
the dining hall.
Upstairs is the rec room.
Through there
are the cell blocks,
and that concludes our tour.
- Thanks for your hospitality.
- Look, I tried to stop this
fiasco every step of the way,
but seeing as the mayor
answers your calls
and not mine, follow me.
- Play nice.
- Warden, I get that you
don't appreciate me
going over your head
to the mayor, but our goal
is not to embarrass you
or to get in your way.
- You're 0 for 2 there, Doc.
- We just want
to provide basic checkups.
A one-day clinic to treat
your female inmate population.
- For everyone?
- That's right.
All 600 of the women
incarcerated here.
- With zero prep time
and no additional COs--
hell of a plan.
- I imagine Martha Randle
would say that any plan
is better than
what you have now,
or she wouldn't
be in our hospital.
- If you'd like to donate a box
of tampons, we'll take them.
Beyond that,
if inmate Randle felt sick,
she should've gone
to Sick Call.
- She did, and they said that
she didn't seem sick.
This was a full day before she
collapsed from a massive stroke
caused by poison, so I can see
how she'd seem fine.
- What happened
to playing nice?
- I said you play nice.
- Oh, good cop, bad cop.
I love it.
Very appropriate.
- Liars, liars!
You're all liars!
Oh, that's right!
I'm crazy, huh?
- That's enough!
- Get off of me!
- This is the examination room.
Your attention.
The New Amsterdam doctors
are here to tell you
how to do your job.
- Sorry, this is it?
Um...where do you provide
pap smears or procedures
that require undressing?
- Right here.
- What about mental health?
You--you do that here?
- Everything, right here.
- But no one is going to ask
for care without privacy.
This is what's
causing your problem.
- Our problem is
a health-care budget
of about
$5 per inmate per day.
We had a heroin overdose
this morning, and that's half
of today's cash gone--
it's not even lunchtime yet.
We're doing the best
we can with what we have.
Now, I'm a results guy.
If you can improve things, I'll
be the first to say thanks.
And if you can't,
I'll be the first to tell
the Mayor all about it.
- Suspected heroin OD
from Rikers.
Severe pulmonary distress.
- Did you push Narcan?
- Two amps, no response.
- She might be having
pulmonary edema.
Renal function?
- Creatinine is 1.8 and rising.
- What's that mean?
- Push 60 mg IV Lasix.
Set up an intubation tray
and a stat cardiac echo.
It means she's in trouble.
- Just breathe.
I want a pill.
- I bet you do.
- No, I am serious, Zach.
- You asked me
to monitor your hydrocodone--
a job I happen
to take seriously.
So here's the deal.
Over the next 24 hours,
you're allowed four pills,
so this
has to last you six hours.
What I recommend
is that you wait...
you take this in one hour.
- Can I take, like,
half now and then half later?
- If you want
to sacrifice pain management
in the name of a quick
and dirty fix, go nuts.
But for maximum pain relief,
wait one hour.
Fine.
- Brilliant.
See you in 60.
Lucky me.
- Martha, count backwards
from five, please.
- Five...
four, three...
- Very good.
I'm going to ask some
questions and your answers
will let me observe
your brain function.
Do you have children?
- Yes.
- Very good.
Now, if you could
share a memory.
Any happy one will do.
- My son's fourth birthday...
we went to this play center.
Ball pits, arcades...
Man, he loved it.
There was this--this room
full of trampolines,
wall to wall.
And Darrell charged in like
a lunatic, doing flips,
making faces.
And his smile was just...
- Do they visit?
- Some people at Rikers,
if they know you got kids
and they want
something from you...
It's better that
they don't come.
Did you find what you needed?
- Martha, it appears
you have a marantic embolism.
The bacteria
from our vaginal infection
has traveled to your brain.
We need to remove
the clot surgically.
- Um, hi.
A moment of your
attention, everybody.
- Everybody, listen up.
- Uh, yeah, hi, guys.
My name is Dr. Frome,
I'm from New Amsterdam.
And I noticed that
your exam room here
is a little on the small side,
so I'm setting up shop
in the consult room to discuss
really anything
that's on your minds.
Free of charge.
- Yo, we got
this old Humpty Dumpty-looking
fool up in here.
Yo, Dopey, where the rest
of the seven dwarves at?
- That's good.
- Show some respect, inmate.
- That's okay, I can handle it.
I've been to middle school.
- Ooh, Doc got jokes.
- What'd I say, Pearl?
Keep talking, it's a write-up.
- May I?
Hi.
It's Pearl, right?
- Mm-hmm.
- Is it always like
that between you two,
or you just putting
on a little show for me?
- That's how CO Sanchez is.
Want to know why there
ain't no trees on Rikers?
- I don't know, do I?
- Sanchez needed 'em all
for the big stick up...
Wait, you writing me up?
- I said you keep talking,
it's a write-up.
You just kept talking.
- Oh, no, no,
I asked her a question.
She was answering my question.
- Take her out of here.
Rec privileges revoked.
- Hold on, hold on,
I asked her a question.
- You a punk, Sucia Sanchez.
No wonder you're
free of charge.
- If this is real,
I swear to God...
- They set up in the cafeteria.
- Nurse Kamoe, can we get these
two to the urgent-care table?
- Right this way.
- Not a word.
Shut it down.
This is over.
- Warden, you said
that if I can improve things,
you'd be the first to admit it.
Well, this is an improvement.
- Improvement?
You're in flagrant
violation of regulations.
The exam room isn't small
for the hell of it.
The COs need
a clear line of vision
on the inmates at all times.
- Yeah, and they've got one.
The patients get privacy,
and the COs can still see.
- You were given enough COs
to secure a hallway,
not an open area.
There are 50 people
in this line.
The regulations regarding
COs-to-inmate ratios are clear.
Shut it down.
- Can we rotate more COs in?
- With written permission
from their union.
Should take about a month.
- Yo.
You here for back pain?
Form a line in A Block hallway.
Come on.
Let's go--A Block.
Did I stutter?
Let's do this.
Word's got out
y'all got new mattresses.
Most folks here crying back
pain are just angling for dibs.
- Lambona.
- Ignore her scheming ass.
A Block's got their own Cos,
so that should ratio
y'all's ratios, right?
Game on.
- Thank you.
Max Goodwin.
- Jackie Connor.
- Farther...
Almost there.
Mm.
A little farther...
Looking good.
And the clot is out.
Will you please inform
Ms. Randle's family?
- Can't do that.
- They should know Martha's
procedure was successful.
- No can do.
It's a security risk
to let them know
she's out of Rikers at all.
- She almost died.
You don't want
her children to know?
Her husband?
To offer comfort?
- Pearl, you got a visitor.
- Seriously, dude?
You trying to get me
thrown in the SHU?
- No, no, I came to apologize.
I did not mean to cause
any trouble for you.
- It's not your fault.
Sanchez is always
up my ass for no reason.
Last week she gave me a shot
for excessive eye-rolling.
- Wow.
You know, power structures,
they can--they can get muddy.
- Save it, Doc.
Sucia Sanchez is just mean,
always has been.
- You mean
since you've been here?
- Since Mrs. Brenneman's
second grade class!
- Oh.
- Yeah, we were friends.
Sucia Sanchez and Burly Pearly.
- Yeah, so what happened?
- She got her ass arrested
and put in my jail.
Doc, I know half
the women in here.
I treat them all the same.
- Yeah, except you don't.
That write-up you gave Pearl
felt pretty personal.
- I'm a female CO.
The men watch.
They see you
go soft for one second,
that's your career.
- Right.
- So, yeah...
it's a tight leash on Pearl.
That's Rikers, bro.
That bridge outside--
you leave your friendships
at the other end.
Okay...
Oh, come on...
Oh, yes.
Oh, God, okay.
- And table three is now open.
Don't make me repeat myself.
Natasha, get on up there.
Yeah, Lindsay, it's cool,
just take your time.
It's not like
there are, you know,
sick people here or anything.
- When you get out of here,
just call me for a job.
- Do I look like
I have time to chitchat?
Just move the trash.
- You okay?
- Uh, yeah, just,
um, swallowed funny.
- You didn't look
like you swallowed funny.
- I keep telling my face
to do the swallowed-funny
expression better.
- You keep asking me to burden
you, but that goes both ways.
- Hey, you have a second?
- Sure, what's up?
- It's not for me,
it's my girlfriend.
She's got some intense
symptoms going on.
Big mood swings out of nowhere,
putting on some weight.
But she's too embarrassed
to ask for help.
Could you--
- Of course, where is she?
- Solitary.
- Well, you're gonna have
to hand over those bags.
You can't bring those in here.
- Well, we need
tools to treat her.
- Right, and I need
the dangerous inmate
not to get her hands on things
she can kill you with.
The bags?
- Makes sense.
Charly, you got company.
- Charly, these folks
are here to see you.
- It's okay.
Hi, uh, I'm Max Goodwin,
and this is Helen Sharpe.
We're doctors,
and we're here to help you.
- Your girlfriend, Dezi, said
that you were experiencing
some problems, uh,
so she asked us to come by.
How are you feeling?
- Um...
can you...can you describe
your symptoms?
- Uh, are you
pulling your hair out,
or is it coming out on its own?
- You mind if I take a look?
Is that okay?
Just...
Your specific pattern
of hair loss may be--
- Don't touch me.
- Watch it, Charly.
- We're okay.
Sorry.
- Back up.
You back the hell up.
Coming in here laughing at me?
You laughing at me?
Huh?
Answer me.
- Nobody
is laughing at you.
- Oh...
you don't laugh at me.
I laugh at you.
Okay.
- Charly, Dezi said...
- You don't say her name!
Get out! Get out!
- Are you okay?
- Yep.
- Get the hell out of here!
- Come on, let's go.
- You know,
holding down that call button
won't get me here any faster.
- I'm sorry.
I-I need another pill.
- What happened
to the one that you had?
- It's gone. I have looked
everywhere for it.
- Gone?
- Look, someone
must've come in here
and cleaned
while I was asleep--
- Dr. Bloom, we can't just
give you another pill.
- Says who?
- Says you, remember?
"No matter what I say,
don't give me anything
more than what's prescribed."
- That was different.
That was to stop me
from abusing the medication.
Just test my blood.
You'll see that I'm clean.
- We can't.
The morphine from
this morning
is still in your system.
- Oh, my God,
all I'm asking for
is that you replace one,
tiny little pill.
Is that too much to ask?
- I will page Dr. Ligon, okay?
- No, Eddie, you know what?
I'm sorry, I'm just...
I'm just in so...so much pain.
- So why not thyroid disease?
That would explain the hair.
- Charly was
the opposite of restless,
and she wasn't sweating.
- Keep it moving, please.
- Then ringworm
or a fungal infection.
- Makes sense with the hair,
but you're ignoring
what we saw when she just
stood up--she was wobbling.
- If the muscular weakness
started around the same time
as the behavioral changes,
then it could be heart disease.
- You're thinking about the
distention in her neck veins.
- Yeah, or even
rheumatoid arthritis.
- Time to go.
- Uh, just--not done.
- Let me save you some time.
She's nuts.
- Hair loss, venous distention,
weight gain--
she's got so many symptoms
that any doctor would want her
under observation
yesterday, but to simply
dismiss them because of her
psychological issues is...
They're not psychological.
- Hey!
- So I would like to start
by saying thank you both
for being here.
- I'm just here 'cause
Warden said I had to.
- I'm just here
'cause the door is locked.
- I know, I know.
Just when you thought nothing
could get worse than jail,
along comes
couples therapy, right?
I'll make this quick.
There are issues from your past
that are impacting
your ability to get along
in the present, right?
So I would like to help
you navigate those issues.
- Issue is she
needs to obey me.
Our past ain't got
nothing to do with it.
- So why did you
stop being friends?
- She drifted
into a bad way of life.
- Girl, I'm in here
on a misdemeanor.
You talking like
I'm Pablo Escobar.
- Okay, Pablo,
then why don't you tell me--
why do you think
you two fell out?
- I don't know.
She wouldn't tell me,
even though I asked.
- You hooked up
with that loser Justin Karn
and never wanted
to do anything ever again.
Don't lie.
- So why did you being
with Justin mean that
you couldn't spend
your time with Sanchez?
- You know how it is.
If I spent time with
my friends without him, he'd...
hit me or whatever.
- I didn't know that.
- So, when you get
an infraction in here,
does that feel similar?
- Like I'm right back there.
- Right.
- So what, then,
that's on me?
- No, nobody's saying that.
- Good, 'cause
I didn't put you in jail.
I'm just doing my job.
- Right, and like you told me,
if you don't do your job,
the guys see it.
- Damn right.
- Right, so you both
have been controlled by men.
- Look, I need this job.
I got kids.
- You got kids?
- Hector and Ruby.
- Ruby like your tía.
- You remember her?
Look, I can't be talking
about this with you, chica.
I'm a CO, you're an inmate.
That's all we can be.
- That's true.
You--you can't be friends
while you're in here,
but you can look
at each other...
just for a second
and remember that
there's more to who you are.
I told y'all to go.
Charly, just look at me.
- Dr. Goodwin.
- I'm good, I'm good.
Dr. Sharpe, can you
stand in the doorway
and hold up your hand, please?
- Take five steps back,
little man.
- Just look at me.
Focus on my eyes
and don't turn your head.
Just stay with me.
- I don't want to look
in your dumb-ass eyes.
Why would I look at you?
- Because you
can't see the walls.
Right? How many fingers
is she holding up?
Without looking--
can you tell me?
You're having
peripheral-vision problems.
They probably started around
the same time as your hair loss
and your leg weakness--
maybe neck pain, too.
We think you have
a brain tumor
and it's pressing
on your optic nerve,
and that is what
is causing all of this.
That's why you feel
the way you do.
It's why your emotions
have been so intense,
the behavior that
got you in the SHU...
it's not your fault.
- So I-I'm not...
I'm not...
- You're not crazy.
You're sick.
And we're gonna get you
to New Amsterdam,
and you're gonna get better.
Okay?
Okay.
- You stay strong.
Your surgery was a success.
- So I get to go
back to Rikers.
- In order to confirm
that Ms. Randle's embolism
is fully cleared,
I need to perform
a radionuclide scan.
It emits a great
deal of radiation.
- And?
- I suggest
you stay out here,
unless you prefer
not to have children.
Got to be quiet.
- Darrell!
- Shh.
Mom, The doctor
said we have to be quiet.
- Okay.
Come here, babies.
Oh, look at you.
You got so big.
Are you okay?
Look at you.
- I forgot how nice
it is to have you so close
that I can stop by
just to steal a kiss.
- Can't steal
what I want to give.
- Come here, you.
Mwah.
Hey, about this morning,
I know I need
to give you some space.
- Don't even.
We're all good.
- I'm just really excited
that you're home.
So, sorry for
misplacing my chill.
- San Francisco Memorial
offered me
a full-time position...
- Hmm.
- As Head Legal Counsel.
I didn't know how to tell you.
And I'm so sorry to drop
this on you in the middle
of the day,
but I-I love you...
- Well, what did you tell them?
- I said I'd consider it.
- Get off of me!
- Excuse me.
Excuse me.
What happened?
Where are you hurt?
- Blood's not mine.
I just got
knocked against the wall.
- Go, go.
- Stay back.
Tell me what happened.
- Four injured!
We need the medics.
- She's got three deep lacs.
- I need two ambulances--
four inmates,
multiple lacerations.
Get 'em to New Amsterdam.
- How's she doing?
- To be honest,
Dr. Ligon, not great.
She's exhibiting
drug-seeking behavior.
She was just trying to lie
to me about losing a pill.
I mean, I knew that Bloom
had a bit of a reputation,
but this was--
She was screaming at me.
- You mean Dr. Bloom?
- Yes, I-I didn't mean
any offense.
- Dr. Bloom is
one of the finest doctors
I've ever worked with,
and I trust that
you're not one to put stock
into petty rumors.
- No, of course not...
- If Dr. Bloom said
that the pill got lost,
then the pill got lost,
understand?
- Yes, Doctor.
- Hey, how you feeling?
- Thank you...
for what you said.
- Oh, you heard that.
- I looked everywhere for it.
I mean, I seriously thought
that I was going crazy.
I mean, at one point...
I thought
that I must've taken it
and then forgotten
that I'd taken it.
But I know in my heart...
I didn't do it.
And you believe me?
- Well, let's not write
a sonnet about it, shall we?
- Why do you believe me?
- Why?
- You've got no reason to.
- I don't follow.
- As one addict to another...
The only way
that you could be...
Certain that
I didn't take it...
Is if you did.
- Addicts do two things.
Get high and blame other
people for their mistakes.
You're doing the latter...
or is this both at once?
- Yes?
Ella, I want to offer you
support I learned
from the blogs I found.
- You read blogs?
- About how to be
a helpful grandparent.
Have you heard
of "meal trains"?
Perhaps I can conduct one.
- Uh, Vijay...
- What is it?
- I have
obsessive compulsive disorder.
- I understand.
It is not uncommon
for pregnancy to cause OCD.
- Right, uh...
but this is not
from the pregnancy.
- Okay, so
when was it diagnosed?
- About 12 years ago...
uh, after I was hospitalized.
Uh, they put me on high doses
of Zoloft and Trazodone,
but now I'm pregnant,
so no more meds.
I've been talking
with Dr. Frome,
'cause I don't...
I don't know
if I can do this.
- You will make
a wonderful mother.
- But in order
to be a wonderful mom,
I have to put this kid first.
And so I made a plan
to make sure that
I can manage my OCD.
And I'm gonna move
back in with my parents.
- That sounds very wise.
- In Idaho.
I-Idaho.
- Mm-hmm.
Mm.
- Rough day?
- Just...tell me.
Is it getting worse?
- See the lack
of signal right here?
Tumor's gone.
- But my--my throat.
I was--
- Allergies.
Max...
You're in remission.
- Hey.
- Hi.
I just heard
that Jackie's stable.
That's great news.
- Yeah, all four of them are.
How'd you leave it
with the warden?
This was not his
favorite day at the office,
but he surprised me.
- Yeah, in that he didn't
stab you as well?
In that he...
has asked us to go back.
The warden is a results guy,
and he liked our results,
so I suggested
that Rikers become part
of our med school rotation.
We could send students over
during OB/GYN
and Behavioral Health...
and he's requesting extra
COs to ensure their safety.
- That's great--
that's great work.
I thought
you'd be more pleased.
- No, I am, I am.
It's--
Sorry.
- I have to go.
- Are you okay?
- I'll burden you
if you burden me.
I'm in remission.
My God.
- Yeah.
- Max, that is wonderful.
So...so why isn't it?
- ♪ My soul, I...
- I don't know.
♪ Am broken
♪ By you
- Your turn.
- ♪ One morning...
- It was Brantley.
Time to get my wrist slapped.
- You need backup?
- No.
- ♪ Don't go, love
- Do you?
- No.
- ♪ To stay
♪ My soul
♪ I am broken
♪ Today
♪ And I'll work out
♪ What it meant
- It's what you've
been waiting for.
Remission, Max--
you're better.
- I only wanted
to be better for you.
But you don't even
get to know that.
You don't get to know...
Luna.
- I met her.
I got to hold her.
It's not enough.
- No.
But it's what we have.
And nothing you do
can change it.
Nothing you do
will bring me back.
You just have
to say the words, Max.
It's okay.
It's okay to say it.
- ♪ It may not be easy
♪ To see
- You're not here.
- ♪ But I'm ready
- And you are.
- ♪ I need to
You're still here.
- ♪ Believe
♪ And I will work...
- I'm not gonna
see you anymore, am I?
- Every time
you look at Luna.
- ♪ And I will mend you
♪ In the end
♪ 'Cause I'll do anything
♪ I love you
♪ Love you
♪ I'll do anything
♪ I love you
♪ Love you
♪ You, ooh, ooh, ooh
- The board has
reached a decision.
- Good.
Let's discuss,
and then I'd like
to share some plans
from today's visit to Rikers.
- Those plans are
no longer yours to make.
- Effective immediately,
you are stripped of your title
as Co-Chair of Oncology,
as well as your duties
as Deputy Medical Director.
- Huh? What?
- Fran, I'm Dr. Jessup.
- What's going on?
Where am I?
- You're in
New Amsterdam Hospital.
You're here from Rikers.
You overdosed,
and it damaged your heart.
- No, that--that's not right.
You need to stop.
I-I need to get out of here.
- You're okay.
You're through the worst.
- I don't do drugs ever.
This is because
I turned state's witness.
Someone's trying to kill me.
- It's okay.
- No.
- You're safe here.
- No, please, get me
out of here.
Get me out of here.
Someone's trying to kill me.
Please. Please.
- Can you buzz us in?
I can't find my ID.
- Hey, Officer.
45-year-old man--
acute onset tearing chest pain.
Heart rate 110.
140 over 56--
- Guard?