Previously on ER: - I
told you about Keith, right?
- Sarah's dad? GATES:
He just snapped.
I said, "You're not
my problem anymore."
You know, I turned my
back on my best friend.
I heard you were looking for me.
- I was worried about you.
- That means something.
- Alex.
- Did I miss Christmas?
Alex always wanted a
dog. I thought it'd be cool...
Tony, it's over.
- Good thinking.
- You're blushing.
So I was thinking
about us having a family.
Starting again.
Coming through. BARDELLI:
Multiple GSW's to the chest.
- Pulseless.
- Out of the way.
- Two rounds epi, atropine.
- O-neg, prime the infuser.
- What you guys got?
- Drug-deal shootout. He got it worst.
- Need help?
- Sure, jump on.
- He's gonna need a thoracotomy.
- No vitals, doesn't make sense.
Let's open him up for MRB.
MRB? Maximum resident benefit.
- I know what it is.
- Good idea.
- Grab interns, assign procedures.
- You're gonna practice?
They've done
thoracotomies, we'll be ready.
- Besides, it could save his life.
- Open up a tray, please.
Central line kit and, uh,
prep for a chest tube, huh?
Coming right up.
Okay.
Maybe we did the chart wrong.
The timing could be off,
the book said that we...
And it was just a month.
- We don't need to do this, you know.
- I thought you wanted this.
I mean, we have other options.
There's a lot of kids out
there that need good homes.
I want to have our baby.
So do I.
So, what are you saying?
Nothing, just
trying to be realistic.
- Oh.
- Mm-hm.
So are we crazy even
thinking about this?
Probably.
But why should
we let that stop us?
Hmm? Stranger things
have happened, right?
- And you know I so do love trying.
- Oh, I bet you do.
Asystole.
Two more liters are in.
- We almost done here?
- We're teaching, Sam.
You're doing procedures
on a dead body.
The interns need practice.
You got a problem?
No, but there are some living
patients that could use our help.
Feel free to step outside.
Looks like they're bringing
in three more GSW's.
Why's it feel like we get
gunshot victims every day?
- Because we do.
- Guns don't kill. People kill people.
Great about Alex. I
know it's been hard.
- Thank you, Dawn.
- What about Alex?
Coming home today.
Discharged him?
When did you find out?
Couple days ago.
Jermaine Bennett, 17,
abdominal GSW left costal margin.
- Please, it hurts so bad.
- 100/60, tachy to 120.
- You on medications?
- No.
- Any allergies? JERMAINE:
No. Where's my brother?
His brother, Quincy.
Through and through.
- How you doing, Quincy?
- I'm all right.
Pedal pulse intact.
Daria, Gates, go
with Sam, Trauma 2.
Let's start him off
on a gram of cefoxitin.
- We use cefotetan now.
- All right. That'll work too.
- Get off of me.
- Yeah, you gonna love this one.
- Shot the guy they brought in earlier.
- Don't touch me!
Serena Diaz, graze wound
to the left triceps, good vitals.
- A real pain in the ass.
- Wish you'd get some of this.
- Lot of lip on you.
- Shut up, bitch!
- Trauma 1's open.
- Looks pretty superficial.
Take these things off. Not
like I'm going anywhere!
- Relax.
- Grady, you should take her.
I cannot feel my arm!
Do I have to?
Anastasia Johnson, 13
years old, sickle-cell disease.
Has had abdominal
pain since yesterday.
Any fever?
No. Her CBC and her
chest x-ray are still pending.
Okay, um, does this feel like
your usual sickle-crisis pain?
No, this hurts more.
Start with 10 IV morphine,
titrate up from there.
Isn't that kind of a big
dosage for a 13-year-old?
Not for a sickler with pain.
Aren't you worried
about addiction?
Would you withhold morphine
from a cancer patient?
Exactly.
- You guys are going to admit me?
- Not sure yet.
I always get admitted.
- Does it hurt here?
- Ow! Yeah.
Get a right upper
quadrant ultrasound.
- Do you think I'll be out by next week?
- You might not have to stay.
But if I do, do you think
I'll be out by next Saturday?
Why? What's next Saturday?
I'm going to New
York to meet Yo-Yo Ma.
The cellist?
I baked cupcakes for three
days straight and sold every one.
Wow.
And I haven't touched my allowance
in months. Airfare's expensive.
You're paying your own way?
- You must be a big fan.
- I'm not just a fan.
It's my destiny to meet and someday
perform with the great Mr. Ma.
I'm sorry. Uh, this is new, and I
haven't figured out how to mute it yet.
Want me to fix that for you?
My dad has the same phone.
- Would you?
- Mm-hm.
Thank you.
At your age, the chance
of conceiving on your own...
and carrying a pregnancy to
term is about 1 percent per cycle.
It's not great odds.
Oh, um...
- What about in vitro?
- It's a long shot.
- So is 1 percent per cycle.
- Ha, ha. It's an expensive long shot.
But possible?
How does your
husband feel about this?
It's something we both
want. We're in it together.
All right. Well...
I would need an FSH level to look
at your ovarian responsiveness...
- as well as estradiol and prolactin.
- Okay.
Can you stop by the, uh, outpatient
lab today? I'll write up a slip.
Or if you have the time I could
do a quick blood draw right now.
- I'm not on for half an hour.
- Okay.
Okay, um, any chance you can
just hold still while I check you out?
- So how did this happen, Quincy?
- I don't know.
The guy just started shooting.
Posterior tibial and
D.P. sound good.
Is my brother okay?
Um, let me check on him for you. A
gram of Ancef and update his tetanus.
- Okay.
- Thanks.
A small amount of fluid in
the sub-diaphragmatic space.
His splenorenal recess?
Distal neurovascular's
intact on the thigh wound.
Get a CT angio. It's a little
close to the femoral artery.
- Uh, it don't even hurt no more.
- That's the morphine.
- Systolic's up to 120.
- You're not gonna need surgery.
- Where's my brother at, man?
- Next room over there.
D-five half at 100 an hour.
- Yo, Quince, you all right in there?
- Yeah.
There's nothing to worry
about. You just chill out, okay?
All right.
He wouldn't be here if you
didn't have him selling drugs.
- Did I ask you? DARIA:
Good breath sounds bilaterally.
- Sam, how's the hemocue?
- I'm doing it right now.
You could have told me about
Alex. I was worried, you know that.
How would I know that?
- Hemocue's 13.2.
- Set up the rapid infuser to be safe.
Out being serviced. I'll
grab one from the O.R.
Uh, we need to uncuff him.
Gotta get some work done here.
- That really necessary?
- Yeah, it's really necessary.
We should have results
by the end of the day.
- That soon?
- Well, I have friends in the lab.
- Janet, I thank you.
- Don't thank me yet. We'll talk later.
Whoa. Hold that.
- Oh, hi, Dr. Banfield.
- Sam.
Got three GSW's.
Drug deal gone bad.
Just in time to start my shift.
- Oh, how's your, uh, boy doing?
- He's better. He's coming home today.
- You must be relieved.
- Yeah. You can say that again.
I just gave blood.
- Get off!
- I need to examine you.
You're not gonna
examine. Get off!
- Lady, come on now.
- Nobody touches me! You hear me?
Hey, Jermaine.
You and your brother better come
up with 5 grand or you're dead.
- Ma'am, please.
- Get the hell away from me.
- No rebound or guarding.
- Repeat CBC in an hour.
Dr. Morris, may I
please join you?
- Why, you can't handle your patient?
- She's a lot.
- One crazy bitch is what she is.
- Fine. Go clear some patients.
- Infuser's primed if you need it.
- This one going to O.R.?
- Maybe.
- No.
Dr. Rasgotra?
Probably doesn't need
an ex-lap, but we'll wait.
- Who's next door?
- Little brother.
- Stable lower extremity wound.
- We have to rule out vascular injury.
- Do you want the findings?
- I got it. What's his name?
Quincy.
- Hi, Quincy. How you doing?
- Fine.
- Any pain in this leg?
- No.
Quincy, we need to call your parents.
Do you know how we can reach them?
Are they at home? Or work?
Is Jermaine all right?
Well, we're working hard
to make sure that he is.
Honey, it's scary. But it's important.
Know how we can find your parents?
They're dead. They're both dead.
I'll be right back.
- Pressure down to 60 systolic.
- Taching away at 120.
- Two more units on infuser.
- He may have opened his spleen.
- CT can take him.
- See blood?
- Can't tell. SAM:
Bradying down.
- Oh, I'll get the crash cart.
- You missed the decreased breath sound.
Bullet went through the
chest, not the abdomen.
- Tracheal shift and elevated neck veins.
- Tension pneumo.
Heart rate's coming up.
So's the BP.
Open up a chest
tube tray, 32 French.
- You want some help?
- I think can handle it.
Get that off me.
Man, what you doing?
Some pressure here.
- Got your oh-silk.
- Trachea's midline.
Good breath sounds on the left.
Where'd Quincy go?
Getting an x-ray to
make sure his leg's okay.
- Sats are up to 98.
- Oh, man, I can't believe this.
What? That you got shot doing a
drug deal? Occupational hazard.
All right. Keep him at 5 liters.
- Ready for dressing.
- We're out of xeroform. I'll be back.
Is this Jermaine Bennett?
- I'm Dr. Banfield.
- Detective Reitz.
Uh, I need to ask
him a few questions.
I ain't got no answers for you.
- Well, is that right?
- Probably not a good call, Jermaine.
I'll see you at the arraignment.
How soon till you can move him?
Still has to do a CT, may
need surgery. Let you know.
Okay. Hey, you have
yourself a good day, Jermaine.
Elastoplast and
bandage scissors.
Dr. Gates, go. You
were off an hour ago.
- Oh, thank you.
- Another ABG in 20, please.
I'm gonna be back, Dr. Banfield.
- Hey, Tony. Is everything all right?
- Yeah. Why?
- I don't know. I was just wondering.
- I'm fine.
So, uh, this is how it's
gonna be from now on?
- What?
- You and me. This is how it's gonna be?
Tony, I don't wanna have
this conversation now, please.
Sam, I apologize. I
take full responsibility...
You taking responsibility
now doesn't change anything.
You put my kid in the ICU.
How long you planning
on being pissed?
You know, I don't know.
Okay? This is not easy for me.
I shouldn't have to
put up with this working.
- That's your problem.
- What?
How is any of this about you?
You giving me crap
makes it about me.
You've no idea what
I've gone through.
- Because you don't tell me.
- You don't listen!
- What's that mean?
- Never mind. Damn...
I am not gonna do this
right now. Okay? Please?
- Please.
- All right, Sam.
It doesn't have to be like this.
Look, what happened
was horrible...
but Sarah and Alex
are gonna be okay.
A girl died, Tony.
And my kid came pretty close.
That is not okay.
You know what?
You do you and I'll do me...
and we'll just go our
separate ways, okay?
She needs a good exam. There's
risk of a neuro-vascular injury.
She's very intimidating.
Learn how to deal
with a difficult patient.
She threatened to kill me, Dr. Morris.
My family, my friends, my dog too.
I don't even have a dog.
- How's she been?
- Pretty quiet.
For a change.
All right, kid, watch and learn.
- Ma'am, we need to examine you.
- You're not touching me.
You could have an injury
to a blood vessel, a nerve.
- So?
- We need to give you a full examination.
You touch me without consent,
I'm gonna sue you for assault.
- Listen, ma'am...
- Damn it, no!
What? I gotta spell it out
for you jerkoffs? Go away!
I am totally learning.
Hey, Tony.
Hey.
- I thought you weren't coming.
- Sorry. I got stuck at work.
- How are the new digs?
- It's kind of a dump.
Beats the hell out of
sleeping in the park, though.
- Johns Hopkins? You leaving us?
- Frank.
This is my turf. I don't go up to the
O.R. messing around with your stuff.
- You going to Johns Hopkins?
- No. I'm just looking at a program.
Johns Hopkins?
Who's going to Hopkins?
- Dr. Rasgotra.
- I'm just looking.
Pediatric surgery?
Yeah, I'm thinking
about sub-specialties.
- Should talk to Banfield.
- Rather not.
Went to med school there.
Ultrasound results
for Anastasia Johnson.
Oh, gallstones. With wall
thickening and pericholecystic fluid.
Cholecystitis. I'll talk to her.
Apparently he jumped the
divider, hit them head-on.
Dr. Banfield, Dr. Coburn
called for you earlier.
- How much earlier?
- Uh, maybe 20 minutes.
Their parents, driver
of the car, killed.
Oh, my God.
For the last two years
Jermaine's been in a group home...
and Quincy has been in... One,
two, three, four different foster homes.
He keeps running away...
travels across the
city to see his brother.
So, what now?
Jermaine's in police custody.
And Quincy's foster mom told me
to give him bus fare, send him home.
- What?
- She's got three kids...
and a full-time job.
I'm gonna go find him a ride.
Keep me posted on his brother.
Uh, Dr. Banfield, I need you
to sign off on my Bell's Palsy.
Okay.
And my broken-ankle lady.
Dr. Martin, will there
be anything else?
Yes, yes. Uh, yes,
Dr. Coburn, Cate Banfield.
Oh, uh, yes, of course. Um...
The PID patient got
cefoxitin and doxycycline...
we sent her up to the GYN floor.
Mm-hm.
Uh, yeah, anything else?
Yeah, I understand.
No. No hurry at all.
- Hi. How you feeling?
- Much better, thanks.
Can I get you anything?
- You're admitting me, aren't you?
- Yes.
You have an infection in your
gallbladder. You'll need IV antibiotics.
I knew it.
I'm sorry about New York.
I'll catch him in San Francisco.
Gonna need some
new cupcake recipes.
- Oh, and I fixed your phone.
- Oh, thank you.
I downloaded some
ringtones, couple games...
and also this cool koi pond.
Koi pond. Great.
Oh, and you got a text
from somebody named Ray.
- And, girl, he is cute.
- Wait. What?
I had him send a picture.
Don't worry. I told him it
was for whenever he called.
I'm sorry, I hope you're
not mad. I couldn't resist.
What exactly did you text him?
I told him... I mean, you
were thinking about him too.
He said he was
thinking about me?
Well, look at you. You
clean up nice, man.
The suit's a little big,
but, uh, it looks good.
Looks like I'm getting
married or something.
Let's get you a job first
then we'll get you a girl, huh?
Dude in my squad used to carry a picture
of him and his wife on their wedding.
- He was wearing a suit just like this.
- Yeah?
Nineteen years old and
married, you believe that?
Carson, Teddy Carson.
Used to brag about how he waited
to have sex until they got married.
High-school sweethearts,
the whole nine, you know?
But he actually waited.
Guys used to clown
on him about that.
Especially...
Especially Montoya. Ha.
God.
God...
He used to carry that
picture everywhere.
BP 122/77, pulse
90, satting at 98.
- What's...? What's all that mean?
- You're stable.
CT's negative for
bleeding in the belly.
Really? I thought it was an
abdominal entrance wound.
When he was shot he must've taken a
breath, damaged the chest and lungs.
How long is this
garden hose in me?
Two, maybe three days.
Man.
- When are they bringing Quincy back?
- Oh, he's back.
He's... Can I see him?
They don't let minors visit inmates.
Don't worry, you're teaching him young.
- You might get to share a cell someday.
- Not like that. He's a good kid.
Looks to me like he
takes after his big brother.
- He ain't nothing like me.
- Except for today.
Look, I do what I do so
he don't have to. All right?
Well, you could get
a real job, you know.
- Oh, a real job?
- Mm-hm.
What? Flipping burgers? Huh?
- Bussing tables?
- Why not?
Could you make it on that?
Now, I'm saving up for a nice
place in a nice neighborhood.
I'm gonna turn 18, file for custody,
make sure he goes to a good school.
Custody? Not in prison.
And when you get
out, he'll be grown.
You wanna do
what's best for him?
Cooperate with the police
and keep your ass out of jail.
Cooperate? Man, you must be crazy.
Know what happen to me if I snitch?
- You gonna give it another try?
- Part of the job, boys.
Be our guest.
Oh, my God, not again.
- You need an exam.
- I got rights.
Technically you're in
police custody, okay?
You either consent to an exam...
or I'll get 10 cops in here
and make you consent.
Come on. You could
have long-term damage.
Look down my shirt.
I'm sorry?
Underneath my bra, look.
Look.
I'm a cop.
Your radial pulse is intact.
Good cap refill. That means
you didn't injure any blood vessels.
- Okay.
- You feel that here?
Mm-hm.
- How about here?
- Mm-hm.
Okay, squeeze my fingers.
You know, they should
come in, uncuff you.
This is Chicago, sweetie. You can't
trust anyone, especially the cops.
They don't know about you?
It's a narcotics assignment.
Just my supervisor, his supervisor
and the chief of police know.
And, well, now you know.
Oh.
Can you bend your
wrist back for me?
Now, push against my hand.
- So you're, like, in deep cover?
- Mm-hm.
- How long you been under?
- Five months, 23 days.
Wow.
What?
Nothing. No.
Okay, let's, uh... Let's see
how strong you are, here.
- How are those kids I came in with?
- Uh, both okay. For now.
Jermaine pisses me off. He's
smart. He could be something.
I can't find a way to get him
out without blowing my cover.
You know, those kids?
You can't blame
yourself for that.
He came out of nowhere.
Me and Jermaine, we're doing this
deal. All of a sudden a guy pulls a gun.
Next thing I know, Jermaine's
brother is running up, screaming...
and this son of bitch,
he shoots at him.
I hit him three times and I don't
even remember grabbing my gun.
That was the kid they
brought in this morning.
Hey, you know, you
did what you had to do.
You know, things I've seen doing
this job, you wouldn't believe it.
But who shoots a little kid?
All for a backpack full of blow.
Must be hard.
Always... Always pretending
to be somebody else.
Hey, you got a career
out in Hollywood...
if this whole narc
thing doesn't work out.
My real name is Claudia.
Archie.
Mm-mm. No pericardial effusion.
Any pain in your belly?
No, it's just my chest.
Try a mig of dilaudid.
Your brother's CT is negative
for any internal damage to his leg.
I think he's going to be fine.
Thank you.
Man, the little dude was so
scared, all that blood. You know?
I just hate to see him scared.
Tell him all the time...
you can't be brave
and not scared.
- Heart rate up.
- IV infiltrated.
- He hasn't been getting fluids.
- Other side?
- Antecubital blew.
- Okay, I'll do a subclavian.
What's happening to
me? What's happening...?
All right, I need to put an IV in
the vein under your collarbone.
A little burning here, Jermaine.
Introducer needle.
- Am I gonna be all right?
- Keep still.
- BP's 110/70.
- Okay, another 2 of morphine.
Hi, you must be
Mom. I'm Dr. Rasgotra.
- Sheila Johnson.
- Hi. How you feeling, Ana?
Hmm. Not too bad. Except tickets
to San Francisco are 600 bucks.
So she has an infection
in her gallbladder...
and we're admitting her
to the surgical service.
- She needs surgery?
- We'll treat with antibiotics...
until the infection cools off. And
then we'll remove her gallbladder.
I'm so sorry, baby.
I hate this. I miss everything.
What do we always say?
Strongest trees in the forest.
That's right.
The strongest trees in the forest
can withstand the strongest winds.
One of her
grandmother's sayings.
- She's got, like, a thousand.
- It's nice. I like it.
Mrs. Johnson, if you'd like to sign the
admission forms, Dawn can take you.
Sure thing. Right this way.
I'll be back in a flash.
So, uh, do you
have any questions?
- Yeah. Why did I have to get sickle cell?
- I'm sorry.
I just want to see Yo-Yo
Ma, is that asking too much?
No. It's not.
He's playing
Mozart's cello sonatas.
Mozart barely wrote
anything for the cello.
My friends go see the dumb Jonas
Brothers and I can't catch a break?
You know, you have
every right to be upset.
I'd be upset too.
I wish there was
something I could do.
Huh. Give me a new gallbladder
and get me the heck out of here.
- I put some more stuff on your phone.
- Thanks.
And you got another text.
From Ray?
From some other guy named
Simon Brenner. From Australia.
And, girl, he's cute too.
Uh, I thought we
agreed no more texts.
We agreed no more texts to Ray.
So does he have an accent?
I knew it. I love accents.
You're a total player, huh?
Catheter's in. Okay, go.
How's the chest-tube output?
Less than 100.
All right, I think we just
got behind on the fluids.
Heart rate's down to 90.
Pressure's coming up, 112/78.
Put a dressing on this.
Uh, repeat CBC and chest.
What happened?
What're you guys doing?
You were sick because you
weren't getting enough fluids.
We filled up your
tank with two liters.
Detective.
- How can I help you?
- Jermaine Bennett.
You should try talking to him.
- I got a feeling about him.
- A feeling?
- Yeah.
- You mind elaborating?
I see a lot of knucklehead kids
come through here. He's, uh, different.
He was pretty clear,
he's got nothing to say.
- Um, just talk to him again.
- It's a waste of time.
Just... Just try.
Dr. Coburn.
Cate, hi.
- Glad I caught you.
- Yeah.
Know what? We
should talk tomorrow.
I have an appointment, I
gotta be back in one hour.
- Janet, please.
- Okay.
Uh...
All right. The labs, they show that
your estradiol and prolactin are fine.
But your FSH is 13.5.
- It means your ovaries aren't...
- Yeah, I know what it means.
So the chances of
IVF being successful...
No, not good.
With your own egg, the
chances are approaching zero.
But they're not actually zero.
Many fertility clinics
won't even attempt IVF...
on someone whose
FSH is that high.
It wouldn't be ethical
to take your money.
- Money's not the problem.
- Well, then consider how you spend it.
I mean, adoption, surrogacy,
egg donation, those things cost too.
Yeah, well, what
if I wanted to try?
- I couldn't recommend it.
- But would you help me?
I wouldn't be
comfortable with that.
I am sorry. I know
that it's rough.
But you do have alternatives.
There are other ways to have a family.
Ceftriaxone and
metronidazole have been given.
- We're headed up.
- Not much of a selection at the gift shop.
Oh, my God, Mozart?
Thanks, Neela.
No problem. I'll be up
later to check on you.
- Two of morphine when she gets settled.
- Hey, you get any texts lately?
Uh, she's a handful, this one.
Oh, I see you've
met my daughter.
She's taking the
bus up next week.
Haven't seen her
since I shipped out.
Three years.
- She's gonna cry.
- Yeah, well...
that's what moms do
when they're happy.
Remember, Tuesday, 2:00, right?
- Dr. Grasso. Second floor.
- Right.
Yeah, she's great.
If you have any
problem with your meds...
get a hold of me, okay?
- I don't know how to thank you.
- Not necessary.
- I need one more favor.
- Hmm.
It's Jake.
Oh, yeah. I'll drop him
off when I have time.
No, they don't allow dogs here.
I was hoping you could hold
on to him for a little longer.
Really?
- If you could.
- Yeah. Yeah, I could.
I'm sort of, uh... I'm sort
of getting used to him.
I appreciate it.
Been weird being alone. I
don't mind being on my own...
but totally alone gets hard.
I can imagine.
This is me.
- I want you to have this.
- Come on.
Take it. You deserve it.
Open it later.
- I'll see you around.
Make sure you give
Jake some bacon.
He loves bacon.
And chicken too.
I'll remember that.
- How's he doing?
- Hungry.
I'm gonna go upstairs,
grab him a sandwich.
He keeps asking
to see his brother.
- Hello, Quincy. How are you?
- Fine.
You getting the hang
of those crutches?
Yeah, it's easy.
We're keeping an eye on your
brother, he seems to be doing okay.
I'm not leaving until I see him.
You miss him pretty bad, huh?
You know, I hear
you run away a lot.
- I ran away once.
- You?
You're a grown-up.
Well, sometimes we get so sad
we get angry. We run away too.
I only do it to see my
brother. Foster home sucks.
- What do you guys do together?
- Everything.
- Play ball. Video games. Do homework.
- Homework?
Jermaine hates it when
I don't do my homework.
Quincy, Jermaine broke the law,
put you in a very dangerous situation.
It's not like that. He told
me to go home, but I didn't.
That doesn't make
what he did okay.
- You don't get it.
- No, I don't.
- Why don't you explain it to me?
- He doesn't do that stuff.
Well, he did it today.
You saw for yourself.
No. My parents worked all the
time. It was always just him and me.
He picked me up at
school, cooked dinner...
Sometimes the
truth hurts so bad...
we don't want to
believe certain things.
- He's not a drug dealer.
- The police say he is.
Whatever. When
do I get to see him?
Hi. How are you feeling?
Good.
- Why are you whispering?
- No, no. I'm being inconspicuous.
- It's not working.
- No? All right.
So you've, uh... You've been
cleared. You're healthy as a horse.
- Jermaine and his brother?
- Jermaine is stable...
getting admitted
for observation.
Quincy'll be on crutches for a
while, but he's going home today.
- See? It's all good.
- Hmm.
Can I ask you something?
Your family? They
know about you?
They know I'm a
cop. But not about this.
My mother would kill me. She
already thinks it's too dangerous.
And how about your husband?
- Does he know?
- I'm not married.
Boyfriend?
I don't have one.
Wow.
Why do you keep saying that?
No reason.
I have to say
goodbye to you now.
No.
Really? Okay.
My supervisor's coming
in to take me into custody.
You know, the show must go on.
Nobody knows, you know.
I broke protocol when...
Shh. I'll take it to the grave.
Ugh.
- Shut up and stop touching me.
- Make sure you keep this dry.
- Sorry about this one, doc.
- No, you know what?
Don't sweat it. We get
this kind all the time.
You got some mouth
on you, you know that?
Time in the pokey
ought to do you good.
- Get her out of my sight.
- Appreciate everything.
Well, it's just another day in the
life. Hey, you be careful out there.
And you. Big attitude
adjustment. Big one.
Punk ass. Where's the ladies'
room? I gotta take a piss.
Come on.
Really making headway
with that one. I'm taking notes.
Check with Frank, see if
ICU has a bed ready for him.
So how am I doing, doc?
Uh, you don't seem to
be bleeding internally.
Well, that's good, right?
You're going to the Intensive
Care Unit. While you're up there...
- you talk to the police.
- What is your problem?
I told you I'm not
snitching on nobody...
And you are going to tell
them everything that you know.
Oh, I... Oh, I...
Boy, you think this is funny?
Go ahead and laugh.
Laugh your dumb ass all
the way to the penitentiary.
You wanna know why you're
gonna tell them everything?
Come on.
- Yo, Quince.
- What's up? How you doing?
I'm all right.
He's why.
You wanna raise him?
Do what's best for him?
Then set an example
and cooperate.
You know what? It's fine.
Don't worry about me. I'm good.
No, I'm... Yeah, I'm
sure. I'm totally sure.
You go have fun with your
friends and I'll pick you up, okay?
I promise. Okay.
Hey, Sarah. I love you, okay?
I love you more.
Charlie.
I was called down for a
consult. Where's the patient?
I'm right here. I
want to try IVF.
- What?
- Will you please help me?
You called me down
for a consult on yourself?
I couldn't leave the floor
and I want to try in vitro.
This may be my last chance.
I told you I'm not comfortable.
It's only a small
chance, but it's a chance.
Yes. But hormone treatments
have risks. Polyps, fibroids.
Do you really wanna put
your body through all that?
I have to give it a try.
Even though failure
is the likely outcome?
If it doesn't work, I'll
move on. But one try.
Let me think about it.
But I'm not promising
anything, okay?
I'll call you.
Hi, this is Sam.
I can't get to my phone
so leave a message.
Hey, Sam, it's Tony.
Uh, I just wanted to say that I'm
really happy that Alex is home...
and that he's okay
and, uh... Um...
Uh, that I want you to
tell him that I said hi...
and, um, that I'll... I'll
see you soon, I hope.
Okay, bye.
- Tony! Hey.
- Daria.
- Top of the morning.
- How are you?
- Top of the evening.
- You working? Ha, ha.
- You working?
- No, no, no. I have a few days off.
Actually, I'm drinking.
- Oh, how's that going?
- It's good. Good.
Having a good day. I
did something good.
Really?
Which I thought would
make me feel better, but...
See, I had this, uh...
My best friend died.
And my kid, she never...
Never mind.
- How are you?
- Fine.
Why are you looking
at me like that?
And I'm... And you know
what? I'm trouble. I'm trouble.
Everything I touch turns to...
But, you know, if you...
You wanna come home with me...
no strings attached,
just for one night.
We should have Quincy
moved by the end of the week.
That's great.
Jermaine is still
upstairs with the police.
Must be telling them
something, been a while.
- I'll keep you posted. Good night.
- Good night.
Hey. What are you doing here?
Taking you on a date.
What?
I have reservations at
your favorite, Mia Francesca.
What's the occasion?
Pretty soon we may
not have time to go out.
And you know, I
thought I might get lucky.
Since we're trying and all.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Come on, let's talk about
it at dinner. I'm starving.