Previously on Grey's Anatomy...
I got to open him up
now. If I don't, he's dead.
Again, I'm not gonna allow you
to open up a man in my ward.
This is not an OR. You
are not an attending.
No. No, no, no.
Are... Are you insane?
Dr. Siegel, this
man is going to die.
Warren, what are you doing?
I got it. I got his
aorta in my hand.
Yeah, I got a pulse.
Right now, you better be praying
that this man doesn't die on the table.
This was a judgment call.
I took a risk, it paid off,
and this man is alive.
I feel like I'd get in trouble
for something like that.
It must be nice being
married to the chief.
I don't think that's
what's going on here.
Really? Warren's
married to the chief,
so he's scrubbed in
down there on a surgery
while we're stuck
watching up here.
You don't think the two
are related? I know they are.
It was a unique situation...
I got an earful on
how unique it was.
I'm clear on the situation.
I was trying to save a
life. The man was dying.
And how is he now?
Alive. Stable. I
got to him in time.
No, you got lucky.
If you'd been left with a
dead man on that table
after you did what you did,
I wouldn't be letting you off
with just a 3-day suspension.
You're suspending me?
I used to spend hours
studying old footage of
my mother's surgeries.
I dissected every move,
every cut, every decision.
I was piecing together a puzzle,
watching, studying, learning.
It's a luxury we don't have
when a patient is
splayed open in front of us.
Where's the main lobby?
There.
We can't rewind.
And the garage?
Over there.
There's no replay.
But he won't get that far.
I got guys at all the doors,
guys rolling back tape.
We'll find him.
Yeah, you don't know that.
Look, it's my job to overreact,
and I'm not there yet.
I'm telling you, this is
not a Code Pink situation.
We just have to cut,
and hope to God we know
what the hell we're doing.
You need to call a Code Pink
now. We're not there yet, Karev.
The kid's hiding. It
happens all the time.
Dad's got anger issues.
Custody battle with a
huge fight just this morning.
If he took the kid...
Statistically speaking,
that's not what happened.
Not to mention, my
patient's infection puts him
at risk for an airway obstruction
if we don't find him right away.
Attention, Gage Dean,
please return to your room.
Attention, Gage Dean.
Are you kidding me
with that? He's six.
He's not listening
to announcements,
but I bet you his dad
is, which means you just
scared the guy into
moving even faster.
I don't think you understand how
a Code Pink disrupts this facility.
All automatic doors lock.
Elevators stop functioning.
Good. It'll stop the dad.
No, it'll potentially
put patients in danger.
There's a kid who's in danger,
and the longer we
stand here debating this,
he's getting further away.
Code Pink is a nuclear option.
Just let my guys look
around for a little bit.
What if it was Tuck?
Call it.
You sure you want to
pull the trigger on this?
Sounding the alarm?
Initiating a lockdown?
Yes, now. She's sure.
Hey.
She's calling it.
Jackson, I had no idea,
or I never would have...
I wasn't trying to...
Yeah, I'm pretty sure
I'm supposed to be, like,
100 feet from you or something.
If I had known that
you weren't trying...
I thought you were
gonna take my baby, and...
Did you set that
off for me, too?
Oh, no.
Quick, go, go, go, go, go.
Why are we suddenly
running a relay race?
Code Pink. Hospital's
on lockdown.
Those doors just
bolted shut behind us.
If we're gonna be stuck somewhere,
we need to have access to an OR.
What is that, an alarm?
Code Pink. Missing kid.
Huh.
It's almost relaxing.
They don't want
to freak people out.
It seems like they
would want that.
Esophageal atresia,
pulmonary sequestration,
spina bifida boy,
spina bifida girl,
and teratoma cutie, so great.
Everyone's here.
It says here the code's
for a 6-year-old kid,
not an infant. I don't care.
If someone's stealing babies,
you count all the babies.
Brown hair, green shirt.
Named Gage Dean.
Well, it's not like we can
do anything from in here.
Gage?
Gage Dean, are you in here?
There. We did something.
- Wire cutter.
- Mmm-hmm.
I just need a description
of your husband, ma'am.
Ex-husband.
I know the guy. I'm just
gonna start looking...
The only way to get
through the doors right now
is with one of these badges.
My men will fan out from peds.
They'll take it room by room.
We've got it
handled... Dr. Karev.
Out of my way, Cross.
No one came through
here with a kid, right?
Six years old, green shirt?
Uh, I don't think so, but
we're kind of slammed.
I've got these other
kids from the accident.
I don't know.
Bailey should have
called this thing earlier.
Hey, hey. He's probably
just hiding somewhere.
That's what kids do, right?
Yeah, right.
We've walked the
western perimeter.
Tell Stokes to report in with...
Hold it.
What?
Karev found him.
Kill the code. Start
running the reports.
He's okay.
Oh, thank goodness
they found him.
All right. How is he?
Well, he's a little shaken up, but
no worse for the wear, right, Gage?
We're all making overtime today.
All righty.
He was hiding. Like I said.
Uh...
That's...
Excuse me! Excuse me!
What?
What happened?
Please. You have to help.
I have to go. I have to go now.
This baby's lost
almost all its volume.
I still can't get a pulse.
I have to get to the NICU.
I was paged. I...
Oh, my God. What...
What is going on?
What happened? What did you do?
Chief, I don't think
she's gonna make it.
You do not stop what you're
doing. Get us some free hands.
She needs central access
and multiple units of blood.
Tube's in. Call upstairs and tell them
Robbins is gonna need a clear OR now!
All right.
You're getting tired.
Let's switch. Okay.
Gloves. Who
butchered this woman?
I need cricoid pressure!
I know this patient.
This is Gretchen McKay.
What's your name, honey?
My kids, please.
Are they okay?
There's three of them,
one girl and two boys.
Thirty-five-year-old female,
restrained driver, five-car pile-up.
Thirty-four weeks
pregnant. Pulse is 120.
Complaining of abdominal pain.
My kids, and... Oh, God.
Omar Singh, my husband?
Okay, we'll take
care of them and you.
I promise. What's your name?
Gretchen McKay.
Thirty-six-year-old
male, Omar Singh,
unrestrained passenger,
hemodynamically unstable,
GCS at 11, obvious
abdominal and chest contusions.
Sir, can you follow my light?
I barely have a pulse.
You said he was unrestrained?
Yeah, family of five in the
car. Three kids in the backseat.
Dad got T-boned on the
side and took the brunt of it.
We need to get
him inside right now.
Okay, Gretchen, I see you're
holding your belly pretty tight there.
You hurting? GRETCHEN: Yes.
Don't be scared.
We got you now, okay?
Yeah. Come on. Let's go.
All right, you guys go.
I'm gonna wait for the kids.
Karev! I need you!
Chief, I've got a
situation upstairs.
I've got a situation right here.
No, it's a possible Code Pink.
You sure?
Hey, Grey!
Got a possible
Code Pink. Can you?
I got it. Go.
Okay, clear a path, people!
Coming through. Watch out.
Dr. Warren thought it
was a delayed abruption
from the car accident.
Is Robbins in the
OR? Is she ready?
She needs to be scrubbed
when we get there.
I know. I paged her. She
hasn't stopped bleeding.
I can't tell if it's
uterine atony or...
Keep shoving in
more packing, DeLuca.
I am. It's just... It's coming
out faster than it's going in.
How long's she been hypotensive?
Uh, at first she was
fine, then she just...
How long?
Maybe five or six
minutes before you arrived.
I'm not sure. You need
to get sure, DeLuca.
I'm gonna ask you again.
How long since her
pressure bottomed out?
I'm sorry.
Sweetie, never do that again.
I was scared about the perit...
The peritonsillar abscess?
Look, don't be.
You've got this, buddy.
Once I get in there
and fix your throat,
you're gonna feel
so much better.
You're gonna be eating ice cream
and sliding down the
rails of those stairs.
And riding the elevator?
Sure, whatever you want.
Just no more running away, okay?
It scares your mom, and I
need to know where you are
at all times.
I'm sorry. I need to go
check on something.
Hey, do you know what happened?
I just heard that Gretchen
McKay needs a crash-c.
Okay, you should tell the
NICU that the baby's coming.
Arizona. If she's lost blood,
then the baby's lost even more.
Has she even been cross-matched?
The crash-c already happened.
What?
He's not oxygenating.
Page cardio and neuro. Okay.
How old is this baby?
How far along was she?
Thirty-two, no,
34 weeks, I think.
You think? Was she preeclamptic?
Diabetic?
Was there evidence of
an abruption or a previa?
No, no, I mean, yeah.
It was a delayed
abruption, or seemed to be.
She was hypotensive...
History of Rh incompatibility?
Talk to me, Warren.
I need to know what
I'm dealing with here.
All right, I need some
retractors here, Kocher clamps.
I can't see a damn thing.
Now! APRIL: Keep
the laps coming.
Come on, I need more laps now.
Is she... Is she gonna make it?
Be quiet. Suction.
I'm trying to
get you visibility.
You got this?
Okay. Retract there. - On it.
Robbins, do you have this?
No, Bailey! No. I
do not have this.
Now, stop talking to me so I
can concentrate on getting it.
Who did this?
Is my baby gonna die?
Crap. He's bradying down.
The mom abrupted.
She needed an
emergent C-section.
In the middle of the hallway?
What the hell happened?
You have to understand, I
would have lost them both.
Well, now we might anyway.
Send for an ABG now.
Okay, what else can I do?
Nothing. Just...
Just stand there.
No, I want to help.
Dr. Warren, I need to
speak with you, privately.
When the baby's
stable, I'll find you.
I need to stay.
I need to assist.
We need to increase the
frequency to 600 BPMs,
and set the IT to 33%...
Dr. Warren, I'm not
asking. Come with me.
Right now.
Look, she was hypotensive.
She was bottoming out.
She... Stop talking!
Do not tell me a single thing.
Nothing.
I am the chief of surgery.
Every single thing you
tell me I have to use.
So, do not speak, got it?
Yeah.
Just stay right
here in this office.
Don't come out.
Don't talk to anyone.
Just wait for me to come back.
One thing. Benjamin!
How is Gretchen?
Not one word.
Edwards, I could use
some traction here.
Nice work, Grey.
Balloon catheter. Good idea.
We almost did a
thoracotomy in the ER.
Yeah, this bought us some time.
No, I mean, we almost got
to do a thoracotomy in the ER,
which, you know, would
have been amazing.
They must have
found the kid, right?
You think he was
hiding somewhere?
'Cause, I mean, how many
times do you get to operate
outside the operating room?
Okay, for the record, it
sounds fun until you do it.
Grey.
Gretchen McKay. How's she doing?
Uh, well, she just had an emergency
C-section performed by a resident.
What? She was
fine when I left her.
Okay, well, that's
what I'm asking.
Your name is listed as the
attending, so, why did you leave her?
Uh, well, I just did
the initial trauma eval,
and then I got pulled
into her husband's room.
It was Robbins' case.
But, I handed her off to you,
and you left her with Robbins?
No, I left her with Warren.
Did Warren do
the C-section, or...
Just tell me what happened.
Gretchen McKay,
34 weeks pregnant.
No sign of abdominal trauma.
She does need an OB
consult. Where's Robbins?
On her way. How can I...
You can help DeLuca
get her off this board.
Omar wasn't
wearing his seat belt.
Spencer dropped a book.
Omar reached back to get it.
Okay, he's right next
door being checked out.
The car in front just stopped.
I hit the brakes.
Her BP's dropping. Okay,
Warren, what do we do?
DeLuca, move.
Uh, third trimester can't
always tolerate supine position.
Puts pressure on her IVC,
so, we roll her
to her left and...
Okay.
There you go. BP's back up.
Good job.
All right. Gretchen,
are you comfortable?
My kids... How are my kids?
I'll have someone
find out, okay?
They're fine. They're fine.
Jasmine has a
bit of a stiff neck,
and Trevor's just
a little nervous,
but Spencer has two loose front
teeth that he can't stop wiggling, but...
Those were loose before...
"Before today." Yeah,
that's what he said.
Don't worry. We got them.
Thank you.
Grey! We need an extra
set of hands over here!
Okay, I'll be right there!
That's my husband. That's
my husband next door.
Okay, so, I will go
check on him for you.
Robbins will be by to scan her
and admit her for observation.
Are you okay here?
Yes. Go. Okay.
Did you ask him?
Did you ask him if he was good,
or did he tell you he was good?
Bailey, he was fine.
But you didn't even
wait for Robbins.
How do you even
know she got there?
Dr. Bailey, I saw Robbins.
What do we got?
Okay. Abdomen is
tense and distended.
His belly's full of blood.
Pressure's 60 over 40.
Edwards, let's prep
for a thoracotomy.
Oh, my G... Uh, okay. Okay.
Edwards, what if we
did a balloon catheter?
Robbins was in there. I saw her.
You saw her?
I did.
I mean, so, how is
she? Is the baby okay?
Bailey?
I heard there was
blood on the walls,
and the ceiling.
Well, you know how
amputations bleed.
You hit the femoral
at just the right angle,
and it's...
Amputations? Mmm-hmm.
I heard he cut into
some lady in a hallway.
No, I heard he cut the leg
off of some lady in an elevator.
Below-knee. Very clean cut.
That doesn't even make sense.
What the hell are you two doing?
This isn't a movie.
Dr. Warren is not here
for your entertainment.
What is this?
Concessions?
I, um... I apologize.
Sorry, Dr. Torres.
Why are you still here?
You heard her. Scram.
What's that?
Oh. It's... It's nothing.
I was holding on
to it for Gretchen.
Her kid lost a tooth.
Okay. I need to know
everything. Yes, Chief.
I need to know what
you two were doing.
I need to know exactly how
and exactly why this happened.
Yes, Chief.
Look, her scans all look clear.
I know. We thought so, too.
We're done? Already?
Yep. You did great.
Scans look clear, Gretchen.
Good, then, can we get my kids?
I'm sure the boys are destroying
the emergency room by now.
One, two, three...
Yeah, well, let's
get you up in OB,
and then we'll bring
them up to you, all right?
Let's roll her.
You cold?
Maybe a little.
Okay, I'll get you
another blanket, all right?
Can you find out
about my husband?
Yeah, absolutely.
You okay? You comfortable?
It's just... My stomach hurts
one way, my back hurts another.
You know, let's...
Let's stop for a sec.
I'm gonna prop you up
a little more, all right?
DeLuca, grab a pillow. Yeah.
There you go.
Is that better?
Yeah, it's...
Oh. No. My stomach hurts.
Oh, it's just...
I don't feel so good.
Her pulse was a little high.
She was clammy and shivering.
So, Dr. Warren made a call.
You know what? We're
gonna get you up to OB
and call Dr. Robbins, okay?
Okay. This way.
She's hypotensive.
Ow!
Gretchen, you're doing great.
You're doing great. We
have to get her up to...
All right. I got her.
Hang in there. Almost there.
I've lost the heartbeat.
What? DeLuca!
Well, it might just be that
the transducer slipped.
Oh, it hurts!
Yeah, I know. I
know. We are so close.
Go. Get Robbins
or anybody from OB.
I'll take her up.
By yourself? Go!
Okay.
Okay, Gretchen, as soon
as the elevator gets here,
we're gonna take you up
and take care of you, all right?
Oh, no.
Go! Go faster! Right now! Go!
What the hell?
They... They're locked.
Go, go, go, go, go!
They're all locked!
We were trapped in there.
Okay, we waited for
someone to come, but...
And she was... She was crashing.
We were gonna lose them both.
All right? There
wasn't a choice.
And you're certain of that?
Yeah.
That's what Dr. Warren said.
They put the McKay
baby on an oscillator.
It was hard to watch.
So little, doesn't
have a name yet.
Warren didn't come out yet?
No. No one's gone in, either.
At least, not since
we've been here.
I just don't know why he
did it. Why didn't he wait?
Well, I guess he thought
he didn't have a choice.
They didn't know how
long they'd be stuck there.
Damn it.
NICU.
Thanks for the chip.
Still, though. In a hallway?
Look, I get it.
We almost opened up
the husband in trauma,
and it was all I wanted to do.
Surgery is a drug.
And operating outside the OR?
That is mainlining.
But, he's a level head.
He's Gramps.
We are talking about
the same person
who used a clipboard
to slice open a patient
in the psych ward.
Gramps goes rogue.
What do you think
will happen to him?
I don't know.
If it was us?
Yeah. He's married to the chief.
Maybe he's invincible.
Mmm.
Yeah.
Sir. Oh.
Hi. Oh.
Doctors.
Diffuse loss of muscle tone.
I can't get him to oxygenate.
He needs to go on ECMO.
You think this little
guy can handle that?
No.
Neither do I, but it's
the only chance he has.
Sats are in the 80s.
I'm with you. Do it.
We need parental consent.
Where are the parents?
Mom's in OR 1, Dad's in OR 2.
Just go ahead and do it.
The uterine
arteries are clamped,
but there's still
blood everywhere.
She's not clotting.
She's in DIC.
Order eight more
units of blood and FFP.
Well, how's she doing?
Good. Bailey, where's Warren?
I want to talk to him.
What the hell happened?
Well, that's what
I want to know.
Grey handed this patient
off to you in the ER.
Yeah. Suction.
And then DeLuca said they
got stuck, and then they had to...
Well, where were you
when all this happened?
Hang another two units
of blood on the Level 1.
The suction's
not working. Fix it.
Robbins.
Um, I had Warren take her to CT.
Well, why didn't you take her?
What were you doing?
I don't even know,
Bailey. She was stable.
A resident can take
a stable patient to CT.
Well, not when her
fetus is in distress.
You think a resident should...
Bailey, they were both stable
when I left them with Warren!
Gretchen, good news.
Your baby is great.
The heartbeat is strong.
There's no signs
of any problems.
Hang in there, Cosmo.
Cosmo?
Yeah, that won't
be his real name,
but it's what we're calling
him till he gets here.
Omar had this really boring partner
dinner that I agreed to go to, because...
Hello. Night out
like a grown-up.
And three cosmopolitans later...
Baby on board.
Aww. Yikes.
Gretchen, your husband's on
his way up to surgery right now,
but, uh, I have
a visitor for you.
Come here, peanut.
Are you okay?
Yeah. Are you?
Spencer's tooth
came out, one of them.
He wants you to see it.
Huh.
Did he pull it out, or did you?
I helped.
Mmm-hmm.
All right, we'll get you to
CT first and then up to OB.
Uh, the kids can meet you there.
Oh, DeLuca, do you mind
finding something to put that in?
Yeah. Thanks.
Okay, just a few more minutes.
Hang in there.
And, Jasmine, you're in charge.
Okay, just keep your hands
out of your brother's mouth.
Okay.
So, take her up to CT
and then let me know
when the scans are up.
Mmm-hmm. Okay.
She was fine when I left her.
Oh-chromic.
Besides, it's Warren.
Clamp.
What do you mean, "It's Warren?"
I mean, if there was
any resident I'd want
to do an emergency
C-section, it would be Warren.
He's good.
He has done them before.
If he said he had
to, I believe him.
He had to. He saved her life.
All right, be quiet!
Basin.
Suction.
Here.
Robbins.
Okay, DeLuca, start CPR.
You can stop now.
Stop, DeLuca.
Come on.
Come on. ARIZONA: I said stop!
Time of death, 17:02.
The dad made it.
The mom didn't.
I hate it when it's babies.
Me too.
Um, Dr. Webber, I wanted to
talk to you about Benjamin Warren.
Yeah, I thought you might.
Yeah, well, as head of
the residency program,
I thought disciplinary action
would be more appropriate
coming from you.
Thank you. I see.
Yeah, I mean, nothing
too harsh, of course,
but, substantial enough.
Whatever you think.
Whatever I think. Yes, sir.
No.
Excuse me?
I can't do that.
I can't take this
out of your hands.
Oh, sir...
A surgical resident
could be responsible
for the death of
two patients today.
I'm not the chief anymore.
This is above my jurisdiction.
Oh, come on. Especially
if we're dealing with
a resident who's out of control.
Don't... Ben isn't a danger.
How do you know that?
Are you sure?
Was this a mistake,
or was it hubris?
Did he do his job,
or did he overstep?
Bailey, I know it's hard
being his wife and his boss,
but you're the chief now.
This is your call.
It's your job.
Do your job.
Hey, just wanted to see
how you're holding up.
I'm not.
Look, she was dying,
and I'm telling you,
I did the right
thing... No, no, no, no.
You probably should not be
telling me any of this, right?
Right. Of course. Um...
Okay, um...
How are you doing?
All right. Ten minutes.
What? You got 10 minutes.
Anything you tell me in those
10 minutes you never told me.
You got 10 minutes, and I'm out.
I was never here.
Go.
Look, I didn't want to do it.
I was out of options.
She was crashing.
She got hypotensive.
It was the only
way I could help her.
We lost the baby's heartbeat.
Oh, it hurts!
Yeah, I know. I
know. We are so close.
Go. Get Robbins
or anybody from OB.
I'll take her up.
By yourself? Go!
Okay.
Okay, Gretchen, as soon
as the elevator gets here,
we're gonna take you up
and take care of you, all right?
She was crashing.
Oh, no. No, no, no!
Go! Go faster! Now! Go!
What's happening?
They... They're locked.
Go, go, go, go, go!
No, no, no, no, no.
They're all locked.
Start paging people right now.
Robbins, Karev, Hunt, anybody.
Just tell them we're
trapped down here.
It's gonna be just a
minute longer, okay?
Now, hang on. I am
taking care of you.
Dr. Warren. Yeah?
Dr. Warren.
I'm right here,
Gretchen, all right?
I'm not going
anywhere, I promise.
We're gonna have to
wait it out a little longer.
I know, but...
Is my baby gonna die?
I told her no.
No fevers.
Bandages look good.
You guys are superstars.
Uh, hey, guys,
say hi to Dr. Bailey.
I just, uh, wanted to
see if you settled in.
You guys are
staying here tonight,
like a little slumber party.
Uh, in the morning,
you can pick out
your own breakfast
in the cafeteria.
Where are Mom and Dad?
They're... They're upstairs.
Dr. Bailey, can I talk to you?
Sure.
I'm in charge now.
You can tell me the truth.
Jasmine...
Well, your dad
had a long surgery,
so he's gonna be asleep
for a while, so he can heal.
What about my mom?
Did she die?
I'm so sorry.
I thought so.
Trevor lost his tooth.
Yeah, I... I heard.
I have it here.
Do you have any money?
The tooth fairy's
supposed to come.
Ah.
Um...
Just... Here.
Thanks.
Dr. Fields, medical records.
I have the damage
report for insurance.
There was no damage.
Which is what the report says.
Need your signature.
The PD's gonna want to know
who ordered the false alarm.
Check to make sure your
name is spelled correctly.
There's X's next to every
place we need a signature.
Chief?
Run that back. SECURITY
GUARD: Mmm-hmm.
Miranda.
Come here.
Okay.
So, I've spent the
day, trying to uncover
why you did what you did.
I wanted to prove that you
were put in a position that...
No, I wanted to know
that you made the right call.
Right. There was
no other call to make.
I believed that.
I wanted to believe that.
The patient was dying.
I made the decision
to save her life.
You made a decision that
you didn't have to make.
Yes, I did.
You need to save
a life, you do it.
No... You weren't there.
No. I wasn't.
Okay, so you cannot understand
what I was dealing with.
Okay, then tell me.
Tell me what happened
at the elevator.
It's time for you
to talk to me now.
All right. All right, the...
The patient was in
distress, but she was lucid.
Dr. Warren. Yeah?
Dr. Warren.
I'm right here, Gretchen, all right?
I'm not going anywhere, I promise.
We're gonna have to
wait it out a little longer.
I know, but...
Is my baby gonna die?
No.
No, we're just a
little stuck, that's all.
I really don't feel good.
Yeah, I know. I know.
Save the baby over
me, okay? Please.
Gretchen, don't
say that. Don't say it.
You just hold on a
little longer, okay?
Please, I know you're
doing your best, but...
Just in case.
Gretchen, Gretchen, okay,
you just keep on
breathing for me, okay?
Gretchen, just rest and breathe.
Gretchen. Gretchen.
Gretchen.
DeLuca.
I need a crash cart or a
cut-down tray, anything.
We got to wait for someone.
She's bottoming out
right now, DeLuca.
Find something! Go!
DeLuca!
I got it. I got it.
What, you're gonna...
You're gonna cut her open?
Here?
Look, there isn't a choice.
Her heart is about to stop.
The minute it does, we
lose her and the baby.
Okay.
Open that cut-down tray.
I paged.
Someone is coming, okay?
They can't get to us.
We are in a lockdown.
And even if they come,
there's no more time.
The doors were locked.
The elevator was closed.
There was nothing else to do.
You didn't know when
they were gonna open.
Yeah. It could've been
seconds, or it could've been hours.
I didn't have a choice.
You didn't have a choice.
Hindsight is always 20/20.
What?
I had to do it, to save her.
There was no other option.
You understand that.
Right?
It's easy to figure out
what you should've done
when you replay it.
I found something.
You see your mistakes, you
know how you'd correct them.
So, the doors were locked. The
elevator wouldn't open. Mmm-hmm.
Gretchen was unconscious,
and DeLuca found
a crash cart, right?
But that's the kicker, isn't it?
You were trapped.
We were trapped.
Hmm.
You got ready to open her up.
You lifted the scalpel.
You had a choice.
No, no. No, no. That's not...
That's not what happened.
I didn't know that the
doors had opened. I...
Well, I'm looking
at it, and so are you.
No, no. I don't care!
Look. I didn't know!
No, you saw what
you wanted to see.
You made a choice
that you wanted to make.
Do you really believe that?
What else am I supposed to
believe? Oh, shut up with that!
I am your damned husband!