Morning Zelda.
All deseases
have a genetic component.
- Auntie Maggie?
- Yes.
Is Grandma Ellis
your mom?
Biologically, yes.
But Diane and Bill
raised me,
so they're
my mom and dad.
Just like my mom and dad
raised me.
Yup.
But of course,
genes are not always to blame.
Margaret, before you
publish your next piece,
you really ought to let me
proofread your work.
It's riddled with typos.
What?
No, it's not!
- And don't make that face.
- What face?
That face... like you've got
some secret we don't know.
The Meredith face.
Well, Meredith got it from me,
so it's the Ellis face.
In diagnosing a disease,
physicians must take into
account other factors.
Who are you?
I'm Derek's sister.
We must have met before.
I think I'remember.
Would you, though?
Their environment.
Their lifestyle.
What does that mean?
Your mom will know.
Quick, write it down.
Don't forget to take
your vitamins, dears.
However, some genetic traits are,
annoyingly, unavoidable.
Thanks, Mom.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 15  Episode 16
Episode Title: "Blood and Water"
♪ On the move, out of control ♪
♪ Mama said,
"Bless your soul" ♪
♪ Everybody,
move with me now ♪
♪ Wanna see your body
groove with me now ♪
Hey, Mom.
- Uh, I'm actually kind of busy...
- Hi, Mrs. Schmitt!
Right. Okay.
Yes, I'll... I'll...
I'll call you later.
♪ I just wanna get loose,
I just wanna live life ♪
- Ohh.
- Oh. What the hell was that?
- Did you just shush me?
- No.
♪ I'm feelin', I'm feelin',
I'm feelin', I'm feelin' a vibe ♪
I mean, yes, I did,
but not in a shame
spiral-y way.
Y-Yeah, you just...
You just shushed me.
It... It's just she...
It is not that
I don't want her to know.
She's just... a lot.
She has a lot of opinions
about everything.
Then, what... you think
she won't like me,
or she won't like that
I'm male?
I just don't want her
to learn about you
as the hot shirtless guy
I'm in bed with.
- ♪ Let it loose, just let it go ♪
- Even though you are hot
and shirtless
and in bed with me.
Not anymore.
♪ Wanna see your body groove
with me now ♪
♪ Wanna see how you lay it down ♪
♪ Lay it down ♪
♪ Day and night ♪
Hey, you.
Helm says you, uh, handed off
all your surgeries.
What are you
working on?
I'm not totally sure yet.
It... It came to me
in a dream.
You dream science?
Rarely,
but thank you.
How's it going
with your dad?
Weirdly, not terrible.
He seems stable,
but it's hard to tell.
- He's here today with a pitch.
- A pitch?
A medical breakthrough,
he says.
"It's gonna
change the world, Andrea."
He gets these big ideas,
he gets obsessed with them,
and then he just cycles out
and loses interest.
It... It probably won't
amount to much.
- Is there a diagnosis or...?
- No.
But Carina seems to think
he's got bipolar,
but he refuses treatment,
of course,
so we don't really know.
He just says he, uh,
feels the world deeply.
Well, that's poetic.
Oh, he has his charms.
♪ Whoah, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Put upyour hands ♪
♪ Just dance ♪
I got to go.
Keep me posted.
Okay.
♪ Put up your hands ♪
- We have rules.
- Okay.
♪ Just dance ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Whoah, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Hey! ♪
- Hey.
- Hello.
- More interviews?
- Yeah, some medical podcast.
She's on fire, though.
Why do they call it that?
"Podcast."
I mean, there's pea pods.
There are certain pods
in aviation.
Whales swim in pods,
but that word has nothing to do
with audio recording.
Right. Uh,
I got a rotation-plasty.
What does that have
to do with...
Nothing, sir.
We hear
you were a bit of a prodigy.
You finished med school at 19.
You made chief of cardio
at Tufts at 27.
- Impressive.
- Yeah.
Thank you. Yes.
Um, I had a very strong family.
My parents told me I could be
whatever I wanted to be.
Are they surgeons, as well?
Oh, God, no.
Then what drew you
to the field?
You know,
I can't really remember
ever not wanting to be a doctor.
I knew at age 12 that
I wanted to be a surgeon.
By 14, that it was cardio.
Wow. Born to be a surgeon.
Yeah, yeah. It makes you wonder
about a genetic component.
Uh, genetic?
Yeah. Well, both my biological
parents were surgeons.
Although Ellis and Richard
were both in general surgery.
Same with my sister, Meredith.
So I don't know where
the hearts come in.
That must be nurture over nature.
I'm... I'm sorry. Did you say
Ellis and Meredith?
- Hm?
- As in Grey?
Ellis and Meredith Grey?
Oh.
Well, ah...
M-My point was that...
And... And Richard is...?
Uh, my... my biological father,
Richard Webber.
- I'm sorry.
- Are you saying that Ellis Grey,
two-time Harper Avery Award winner,
mother of Meredith Grey,
is your birth mother?
Um...
M-M-Maybe we can edit that.
- Holy crap.
- Wow.
I mean, it's not exactly
a real library, but it's...
Would it be okay if I did
a little sorting?
Seems like
doctors don't put books back
- where they found them.
- Oh, sure.
Sorry, but I have
back-to-back meetings.
I'll come back
and grab you for lunch.
Okay?
My son, the chief.
Oh, my God.
This is so cute!
Thank you.
Those are for my grandchildren.
Oh!
Is Amber having another baby?
No. Those are for yours.
- Our... Our what?
- Kids.
Uh, you know, I was reading
an article about how gender
is a more fluid concept than
previous generations realized.
So I figured that purple, green...
Neutral colors.
Mm-hmm.
Hm.
We're in the baby hat place?
Are you pregnant
and you didn't tell me?
She asked me if we wanted kids,
and I said yes because we do.
And she's making
the hats extra big
because I had an extra big head.
Which, now that I say it out
loud, probably sounds daunting.
I have a surgery.
What surgery?
Hey... Hey, Bailey.
Dr. Hobb to...
Dr. Hobb...
Hunt and Altman are both
taking personal days,
so I need you to cover the pit
today.
Please?
- How many?
- How many what?
- Days left.
- Till what?
Till I stop taking orders from you.
22.
Mm-hmm.
Dr. Oliver to Radiology.
Dr. Danny Oliver to Radiology.
- Maybe.
- Kidding.
- Hey, Link!
- Hey, number 20.
Yeah. Heh!
All right.
Jackson Avery, plastics.
Jenny Martinez, mother.
- Nice to meet you.
- You I know.
Come here with that face.
We miss you
at the clubhouse.
You're gonna get him squared away
so he can get called up
next year, right?
That is the hope.
But it's gonna be
a long road.
Dr. Kim, all you.
Okay.
Hunter Martinez, 20 years old,
diagnosed with osteosarcoma
of the distal right femur,
here for a rotation-plasty.
Uh, what exactly is that?
He only told me
about this last week,
so I'm playing catch-up.
She worries too much.
Show her the cartoon.
Okay.
We will begin by removing
the lower end of the femur,
the knee joint,
and the upper tibia.
Then rotate
the lower leg 180 degrees
and re-attach the remainder of the leg.
The ankle joint will serve
as the new knee joint
to fit in for the prosthetic leg.
Oh, my God!
Now, don't worry, Jenny.
He's already done
his three months of chemo,
so this surgery will leave him.
- Three months?
- Cancer-free...
You've known
about this for three months?
I didn't want to freak you out.
Freak me out?!
We'll, uh...
talk about this later.
Please, um... continue.
Okay.
Well, the first step would be
to make an incision in the thigh.
Dr. Swan to Oncology.
Nice to meet you,
Mr. DeLuca.
Or should I say "Doctor"?
It is, grazie.
Uh, bambini, you can go now.
I can help with the English.
You?
You can barely speak it
yourself.
I can help.
And, plus, I'm curious to see
what this research is
you're presenting today.
Okay.
It is a baby
in a bag.
Okay.
1 in 10 babies is born
preterm
because mother can't
carry child to term
due to trauma or accident,
so many reasons.
And the baby, she dies.
Premature babies cannot survive
outside the mama.
But what if it could?
What if we transferred the baby
from the mama
to an external gestational sac
so her little lungs
and her brain and her heart,
they can develop?
And then
we give her the birth, yes?
From the bag,
a beautiful, full-term, healthy baby!
You want to create
an external gestational sac?
No. I have already.
I am in animal trials.
Four ovine subject subjects.
The latest showed normal pH
and lactate levels,
good fetal circulation,
and then...
Eccolo!
Born at 125 days.
- That lamb gestated?
- In a bag.
It's a baby in a bag.
You'll fund this, yes?
Britney's signature,
her parents' signature...
Everything's notarized.
Well, I have good news
and bad news.
Is something wrong?
No. That's the good news
and the bad news.
This is so straightforward,
I'm not gonna be able
to bill you for many hours.
Oh.
So, let's get started
with you two.
Uh, what is Leo's address?
Uh, trick question.
It's really your address.
No, it's... it's not that.
Just we don't live together.
- We used to...
- Yeah.
- Uh, but not anymore.
- Mnh-mnh.
Oh.
- Is that a problem?
- Well, you tell me.
Because if the two of you are
gonna be fighting for custody,
- I mean, that's...
- No, no, no, no.
Neither of... of us wants that.
- We are totally committed to Leo...
- Yeah.
And, um, we want what's best for him.
Then we should be good.
But I am gonna have to
take back what I said
about this not being complicated.
Wait, wait, wait! I, uh...
I need you
to put me on a surgery.
- Any surgery.
- Why?
Because I told my husband
I had a surgery.
Got it.
What are you avoiding?
Telling you would defeat
the purpose of avoiding it.
Oh, God.
Oh, what's happening? No.
Eye contact. Oh.
God, I am so embarrassed for you both.
We're doing a rotation-plasty, so...
You're turning an ankle into a knee?
- I want in.
- Okay.
Schmitt, you're out.
I've been studying for this
surgery for three weeks.
- Seniority.
- Special treatment.
Oh, yeah?
How'd you get in on it?
Oh.
Sorry, bud. Too many cooks.
Karev, prep the patient.
Oh, and, uh,
tell his mom where to hang.
- She's a little freaked.
- Okay.
Ooh, whatcha working on?
Well, Ellis came to me
last night in a dream
and gave me the answer
to something.
I just don't know
what the question is.
Huh.
Ellis got into
my head this morning, too.
Did she give you
the question?
No, I was doing that podcast,
- you know, for my article...
- Uh-huh.
And I accidentally let it slip
to the entire medical community
that I'm her secret love child.
Oh.
Well, that's not
that big a deal.
You said, "Oh,"
and you made a face.
Maggie, that's your life.
Well, yeah.
And...
And yours. And Richard's.
- Biomarkers?
- What?
Ellis. The question.
Was it about biomarkers?
You're a genius.
Yeah, it's in our DNA.
- Ugh.
- Maggie, Richard will be fine.
He's Richard.
Okay.
Rhys Joseph to Peds ICU.
How long will that take?
It could be around eight hours,
but we'll make sure
to update you.
And what time will that be?
Every couple of hours.
It's normal to be scared.
I'm not scared.
I'm enraged.
This child, who I poured
my blood and sweat
and soul into...
my child didn't tell me
about three months of chemo
'cause he didn't want me to freak,
so now I-I-I'm not allowed
to freak or I prove him right,
and I'm not allowed to rage
because you're turning
his ankle into his knee,
so I have to be supportive!
Is there a gym
in this hospital
with some kind of
punching bag?
I'm sorry, Dr. Bailey.
I was on the OR floor,
- so it took me a minute.
- Stop, Schmitt.
I'm bored already.
Bed 3. Frank Nelstadt, 47.
Chief complaint... fever,
sore throat, productive cough.
O2 sat 88% on room air.
Enjoy.
- It's Dad.
- I'm kinda busy, Ella.
Mr. Nelstadt, I'm Dr. Schmitt.
How long have you
had that cough?
Uh, I don't know.
A few days?
It's not as bad as it seems.
Don't think I didn't see you
just decline my call, honey.
You're supposed to be
at a conference.
I was, until
our daughter ratted you out.
"Dad hacking up lung.
Sounds like dying moose.
So gross."
We've raised such a sensitive
and supportive young woman.
Sir, do you have any chest pain?
I'd like to get an X-ray, maybe a CT,
just to rule out anything
more serious.
- A CT? Really?
- Dan.
- How old are you?
- Danny!
Sorry, Doctor, my husband
spins out over a hangnail.
- Dan...
- Excuse me. Hi. Are you in charge here?
Because, uh, there's a child
doctor working on my husband,
and I would like for you
to change that.
- Uh, Dr. Schmitt is a surgical resident.
- All right, deep breath in.
And although he looks young, he does...
All right, I-I'm sorry.
It's not in my nature to be rude,
so I-I'm hoping
you're gonna forgive me
and know that this is just
the fear talking when I say...
if my husband needs a CT,
then I need for him
to have a grown-ass doctor.
Sir, lean forward.
Frank? Frank!
Can he breathe?
Let's prepare for a possible RSI
with 100 sux, 100 propofol,
and get an intubation tray ready.
- Oh, my God!
- Ohh.
I do not enjoy this.
Okay.
Oh, that feels better.
♪ I-I-I can feel it ♪
♪ I can feel it ♪
All right.
Upper dissection complete.
Let's go ahead
and remove the specimen.
We're ready
from the lower end.
Jo, the honors?
Yes, please. Ohh.
I can't believe Hunter didn't
tell his mom he had a tumor.
Oh, he told her.
Just not till last week.
Ah, he was trying to protect her.
Stupid, but I understand
the impulse.
All right. Let's rotate the leg.
Okay.
Can you get the tibial plates
and screws ready, please?
Speaking of parents,
how's it going with
the mother-in-law?
Still here.
Still sleeping on our couch.
Oof. In a loft?
That sounds cozy.
No, it's fine.
She's sweet, and she doesn't
take up a lot of space,
and she just makes tea all day,
and she knits.
So that's what
you're avoiding.
- No.
- Who's avoiding?
Jo wanted to scrub
in for a distraction.
It's not Helen.
Helen is fine.
I'm happy that she's here
and that she's doing well
and that she is knitting hats.
A lot of them.
For babies.
For our babies, apparently,
that her and Alex are planning
just full steam ahead...
gender neutral, big-headed
baby hats and all.
Lap pad.
♪ Ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh ♪
I think we got what she's avoiding.
- You paged me to the lab?
- I did.
What... you couldn't come
to my office?
I couldn't.
Why not?
Because that would be a concession
to your superior job title,
and that's about to end.
But it hasn't ended.
No, but when it does,
I just don't want the fall
to hurt too badly.
What are you working on?
My mother gave me a tip.
- About what?
- Never mind.
How'd it go with
Vincenzo DeLuca?
Oh, his pitch was awesome.
It's a freaking baby
in a bag.
A baby in a bag?
Yeah, an external womb.
He's already made a prototype.
He showed us the video of
the baby lamb.
- In a bag?
- Yup.
10 years in peds,
and I have never thought
of something so cool.
Almost sounds too good to be true.
Yeah, well, I asked him
to give me a day or two,
but I wanted to say yes
in that room.
Did you call his hospital
in Italy?
Yeah. They love him.
You should dig a little deeper...
kick the tires on that one.
Why? What do you know?
What?
Read my face.
Constipated?
My face is saying something
that I cannot say.
Oh, this is about Jo.
Did she talk to you about my mom.
and the baby hats?
Oh.
Never mind.
Fine.
So, are you planning
on alternating weeks
or splitting weeks?
2-2-3?
2-2-3 is...?
You each get two days,
and then whoever went
first gets three,
and then, the next week,
you flip it
so the time balances out.
Um...
W-We haven't had much time
to discuss it, so...
The judge is gonna want to know.
Well, I don't want to spend
half my time away from him.
She gave custody to both of us.
Yeah, but she didn't know
that you'd just left me.
Maybe she would've made
a different decision.
Okay, so you don't even
want me on the paperwork.
No, no.
That's not what I'm saying.
I'm just saying there's
an argument to be made
in favor of consistency.
Okay, folks, uh,
we're done here.
- Uh, no, wait. We will...
- Uh.
- We're gonna figure it out.
- "We'll figure it out"
isn't the kind of answer
I can give a judge.
Listen, this went longer than
expected
and I have another meeting,
but use the room.
If you want this child
in your life,
you're gonna need
to get on the same page, fast.
She said,
"Dad's coughing up a lung,"
and now he just coughed up a lung.
It's not his lung, or he would be dead.
Uh, according to image search,
it's a... a bronchial tree.
Uh, it's actually a blood clot
in the shape of a bronchial tree.
Somehow, the coughing
must've cause bleeding
in his airway,
but how it became
so congealed and...
- What's happening?
- Dad?
Are you okay?
Okay. Schmitt, intubate
while I do an ultrasound.
Um, I'm sorry.
Move back, please.
Let's get a crash cart in here
and the sux and propofol
that I asked for
and an EKG.
What happened?
He was just fine!
Dad, come on. Let them work.
Come on, let's move, Schmitt.
This could be a massive
pulmonary embolus.
You ever hear
an idea that's so good
that it makes you angry
you didn't think of it?
Yes.
But it usually means
my meds aren't working.
I spent several years
in an outright rage
that I didn't invent
the cordless phone.
When I was little,
what did you think I was gonna be
when I grew up?
Well, you once asked me
what the inside of a doorknob
looked like.
I mean, you were 6,
so I just took it apart
and showed it to you.
But then you wouldn't let me
put it back together again.
Eventually, you did it yourself,
so I thought you were
gonna be an engineer.
Oh, yeah, well,
taking things apart
and putting them back
together again
is kind of what I do all day.
That's true.
But I'm not really a thinker.
I mean, I'm a fixer, not an innovator.
Oh, I don't know about that,
honey.
I've never been anything
but in awe of your brain.
God knows where you got it,
'cause you didn't get it
from either of your parents.
You know, you really freaked out
Jo with those baby hats.
Well, I didn't mean
to freak her out. I...
Give her a little nudge, maybe.
Chris Boddam to Admitting.
Mm. Okay. Thanks.
Why do I have
a request for a comment
on the "Maggie Pierce/ Ellis Grey" story?
Oh, my God, Richard.
I'm so sorry.
I was doing that podcast,
and we started talking about
how I got into surgery and
genetics, and then suddenly...
You were telling the entire
medical community
that Ellis and I had an affair?
Richard, I'm so sorry.
I-I-I didn't think...
No, you didn't.
Thank you. All right.
Neurovascular bundle
seems to be intact
and tension-free.
Blood flow looks nice.
And I'm liking the bone alignment.
- Nico, we good?
- Beautiful.
Excellent. Rounding third.
So, what's up with Karev?
He wants a kid and you don't?
Well, I thought
I did someday...
until someday started
sounding like today.
Well, I can tell you
that it's not all bad.
I mean, Harriet right now
is learning how to pronounce
her "K" words,
which sound more like T's.
So she's got a little friend
named Coco...
she calls her Toto.
And it's got to be
the cutest thing ever.
Right, but does the cute
outweigh the terror?
- The what?
- You know, all that potential heartache.
Little humans with giant heads
who are gonna get hurt
and picked on
and have nightmares
and wonder
why they were born.
And even when
they're grown up,
you never stop
worrying about them.
I mean, look at Hunter.
He's a freaking
major league
- baseball player...
- Minor league.
Top of his game, the best genes,
and out of nowhere, cancer.
And now his mom is having
a nervous breakdown,
all because
she made the choice
to ruin her life
with a child.
No offense.
Why would I possibly
be offended?
Irrigation, please.
So, on the days we trade,
one of us will drop him off
at daycare
and the other one will pick him up?
Yeah.
That makes sense.
Okay. Done.
Huh.
You know this will probably
all go out the window
once Teddy has her baby.
You're not gonna know
your 2s from your 3s.
Well,
Teddy is with Koracick now,
and they're on their babymoon
in Palm Springs.
I still don't know what that is.
Owen, this is not the time
for Teddy feelings.
W... It's not a feeling.
- It's more of...
- Okay, still not the time for it.
Yeah, okay.
Yeah. I'm gonna
text the lawyer
and let her know that
we made a plan.
Amelia.
I don't just want you in Leo's life.
I want you in mine.
Let's not do this.
I chose you.
I choose you.
That's never changed.
Yeah, it did change.
Everything changed.
Things went bad
when Betty went missing
and we thought that
we'd lost Leo, but...
- Amelia, we... now...
- Owen, stop.
It changed with Teddy.
That's when it changed.
And I know that this is messy
and it's painful
and it's not what you wanted,
and that is no one's fault.
But breaking up with you was
a moment of clarity for me.
And it hurts,
but it hurts
less than the alternative.
Well, you can have your clarity,
if that's what you want to call it.
This is not no one's fault.
This is your fault.
What?
"The clarity hurts less
than the alternative"?
The alternative is loving me.
The alternative is letting me love you,
but you just can't do it.
You have to just sabotage it.
I tried to convince myself that
this was all the brain tumor,
but, apparently, there's just
some fundamental part of you
that can't love or be loved.
Did I hear we've got a plan?
- "Heepsters."
- Hipsters, Papa.
It's my new English word.
They're making a statement
that they are unique, yes?
Yeah, by dressing exactly the same.
- Papa... Speaking Italian...
- Please.
In English. So I can practice.
Va bene.
Papa, this research really
is incredible.
- Yes, it is, my boy.
- But we need...
And you... your life is incredible.
Your city is incredible.
I'm so proud of you.
Thank you.
But... how are you?
- Really. Because Carina seems to think...
- Ay,
Carina. Ay.
She's like your mother.
She worries. She controls.
You are like me.
You know
a good idea when you hear one.
Carina worries
for good reason.
It hasn't been easy between us,
I know.
Your mother come
between us...
- My mother has nothing to do with this.
- Andrea, let me finish.
You move away
from me with Mama.
Then you stay away
for college.
And now residency.
You are distance.
And I know some part is my fault.
Let me make good.
Andrea,
you do this with me,
I put you in the map!
On the map.
On the map, yes!
Look at you. You are a man,
all on your own.
A good man, too.
I see that.
And handsome like me.
I see you.
But this woman of yours,
she is beyond you.
Wow. Thank you.
Andrea, even I have
heard of Meredith Grey
all the way back home.
She's more than a beauty...
she is brilliance.
Yeah, I'm aware.
So, then,
we change the world together.
We save the babies.
My son, I owe you this.
Let me put you on the map.
Huh?
What can I get you?
- Mm-hmm.
- Easy. Yeah, easy.
So, it uses the ultrasound
to drive the clot busters
directly into the clot?
Not bad for a child doctor.
What?
Nothing.
Um, less of a chance
of intracranial bleeding.
The TPA will release
over the next 12 hours,
and... boom.
No more creepy-looking
blood clots for you, Frank.
Thank you for saying that,
because I thought
I was the only one.
I almost forgot I was
a doctor there for a minute.
Right?
Now we have to figure out why
he's had two major blood clots
over the last 24 hours.
All right. Almost finished up here.
Looking good.
Let's update his mom.
Where are they?
They're closing.
You're mad.
No, I'm not mad.
It's your story,
and you have a right to tell it.
Okay. Right words.
Wrong tone.
It is my story, and I do have
a right to tell it.
Catherine has cancer.
She's living with cancer.
Yeah, I know that.
And what I think she maybe
doesn't need added to her plate
at this moment
is the world knowing that her hus...
that her husband is an adulterer.
I'm... I'm confused.
Are you cheating on Catherine?
- Huh? Don't be obtuse.
- I am not trying to be.
I had an affair with Ellis,
which you just made public.
And you think that that
somehow reflects on Catherine?
Well, it's not part of my story
I'm particularly proud of.
It's the part of your story
that culminated in me, Richard...
in my existence.
Speaking Italian...
Hey.
Hi.
Everything okay?
My sister is trying to shut down
my father's research project.
She knows. And she speaks
Italian, so it's okay.
Only a little.
Andrea,
we cannot let him do this.
Wait, you want your father
to do research here?
Yes. I-I think it's a good idea.
I thought you said he has
an untreated mental illness.
- He does.
- He has episodes, okay?
But it's not like
he's dangerous.
Until he is.
It's complicated.
No, it's not complicated,
Andrea.
He didn't even train in this field.
Yeah, but you did.
So you know better than anyone
how important this research is.
Right, but I also know
better than anyone
just how bad he can get.
Andrea, I spent the last
three months with him.
He's not well.
You didn't grow up with him,
so when he comes calling,
you go running.
And he knows that.
He knows he can manipulate you,
and you're letting him.
I'm signing on to participate
in a groundbreaking medical study
that could change
and save a lot of lives.
Excuse me.
What would you do if you were me?
Talk to the chief?
Hm.
Dr. Harrington to the OR.
Dr. Paige Harrington to the OR.
Did you know?
I know a lot of things.
You'll have to be more specific.
About DeLuca's dad and the mania
and the four patients.
I did.
You could've told me.
I did. I said dig deeper,
read my face.
You could've just told me.
No, I couldn't
because I was confided in
by somebody
I care quite a bit about.
So, no, I couldn't.
I don't want to be the guy who
says no to something amazing
because of a little mental illness.
I mean, look at my mom.
Have you thought about
the ethical ramifications
if this got into the wrong hands?
Honestly, if it wasn't
for the guy's history,
I wouldn't even think twice.
Does that mean
you're going to approve it?
Mer, it's a womb
outside the mother.
If he pulls this off,
it's an honest-to-God medical miracle.
Sorry you had
to grow up like that, man.
You told him?
Carina did.
But I told her to.
Mer, he's my dad.
I'm telling you,
I think he's okay.
I know, but, listen,
I have my own complicated
history with my parents,
and I know that my judgment
was very often clouded.
I need you to try
to trust me on this, okay?
Dr. Thatcher to ICU.
- Dr. Rachel Thatcher to ICU.
- Hey.
He's okay.
We're moving him
to an ICU room,
and we were able to place
the catheter
to break up the clot.
Oh, my God, Frank.
We ran some tests,
and we think he has something
called Factor V Leiden.
It's a blood-clotting disorder
that can lead to
an abnormal amount of clots.
- How did he get that?
- It's genetic.
He's had it his entire life.
It just didn't cause any issues
until he became so sick.
His cough may have actually
saved his life.
He could've died?
Well, yes.
But we were able
to get to it in time.
And it's genetic?
Dad, what are you...
Okay, you need to test her
right away.
Wait. I thought you said
you and Dad didn't know
which of you was my biological father?
We don't.
We never wanted to know,
and we always said
that we would only find out
- if you wanted to.
- Which I don't.
But if it's any chance that
you have this Factor V thing,
we need to find out.
Hey.
I said a crappy thing,
and I'm sorry.
Harriet's incredible,
and I know that not all kids
ruin everyone's lives.
They're sleep-depriving,
sticky little monsters
that demand snacks endlessly
and want you to sing
"Row Row Row Your Boat" to them
50 times a day.
But they also think everything
you say is hilarious.
And when they lay their head
on your shoulder...
Everything seems right.
Yeah, kids can ruin your life.
But they also give you
a reason to live when...
when life tries to ruin you.
Now, I don't want
to get panicky phone calls
when this takes time, okay?
It always does.
It's the nature of the beast.
But I think
you two are in great shape.
Thank you.
I need to make a change.
I'm sorry. Um.
I don't think I should be
on the paperwork.
Amelia, what are you doing?
I'll be in his life
because Betty wants me to.
Um, I'll see him as much
as you'll let me.
I can be his friend. I can help.
I will be Auntie Amelia,
who is fundamentally incapable of love.
Hey, hey. Come on.
We're over, Owen.
So this is what's best for him.
You heard her... one home is ideal.
You don't have to do this.
I have clarity on this, too, Owen.
Leo is yours.
He's always been yours.
I'm sorry for wasting your time.
Wow.
Okay. So, that's, uh...
That is your tumor-free leg.
Oh, thank God.
You can be honest now.
You really think
I can play again?
Well, I'm not gonna make
any promises,
but I've seen plenty of athletes
return to their sport
after this procedure.
Yep. And when you're able,
we'll start physical therapy
and then fit you
with a prosthetic.
It's gonna be a lot of work,
though.
You're gonna have
to re-train your brain
now that your foot
is your knee.
♪ Always searching
for a place to hide away ♪
Training I can do.
Jenny, this is a good thing.
I know.
Maybe if I'd had three months
to process all this,
I would be crying
a little less right now.
Or... maybe not.
- Yeah.
- Maybe not.
♪ Counting my conclusions
and my "You shoulds" ♪
- Hey.
- Mm?
♪ And I don't know what to say ♪
Your head turned out
perfectly fine.
Thank you?
I mean, maybe...
maybe it was too big
for regular hats,
but who cares?
You turned out perfect.
But it's my mom's head
you're worried about, right?
You don't want to pass on
the crazy gene to our kids.
Alex, I love your mom. I do.
I am not afraid of your genes.
I'm terrified of mine.
You know, every time I go to the doctor,
I have to write "unknown"
on my medical history.
On both sides.
And I've learned to live with that
and define myself by my own terms.
But when it comes to our kids,
I don't want to not know.
Okay, so, we will hire someone
- to track down your family and...
- No, no, no. I don't...
I don't want to meet them.
I am going to spit in a tube.
Cool.
I'm gonna grow
a baby in a bag.
- Wait. What?
- Yeah. A baby in a bag.
♪ Count your sheep and... ♪
Okay.
♪ ..Wake on a brighter day ♪
Mr. Nelstadt?
Frank.
We got Ella's test results back.
♪ I'm running out of ways
to see this place ♪
- Dad.
- Yeah.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
- Are you?
- Yeah, I'm good.
I get to wear
one of these things now.
Oh.
I'm gonna need one in gold, too.
It never mattered to me
which one of you
was my biological dad,
'cause you're both my dads.
Period. Okay?
So let's not flip out
about this.
I'm talking to you.
I am not flipping!
I mean, he coughed up a lung.
I'm allowed to have a feeling.
Annie Abrumian,
return to the Admin Desk.
Annie Abrumian, return to the Admin Desk.
I'm ashamed of
what I did back then.
But I'm only grateful
for your existence.
I know.
It's a scandal.
I'm a scandal.
No, I'm a scandal.
You're a miracle.
The best of Ellis,
the very best of me,
and the best of a mother and father
who raised you so beautifully.
I am proud to be any part
of you, Maggie Pierce.
And if the press asks,
that'll be my only answer.
My dad's gonna listen to
that podcast.
He's gonna be
so proud and excited.
And then he's gonna hear me
giving all the credit
to you and Ellis.
Then he's gonna be even more
heartbroken than you were.
I-I love you.
And I haven't come out
to my mom because...
she will spin out.
And not because
you're not amazing,
and not because
you're a man.
- Asian?
- No.
No, she will... she will flip out
because it's what she does.
She flips out when I try
to purchase a backpack.
Literally, I-I...
when I bought this backpack,
she counted the pockets,
and we had three conversations
about whether it would
hold everything I needed
and all the ways that it could
accidentally choke me.
You are my first love.
I know I'm not yours,
and that's okay.
But you are mine.
And I want to lock you
in through my eyes
before I see all the death traps
through hers.
- ♪ Diving in while the current's fast ♪
- Blood is thicker than water.
So, you love me, huh?
♪ Gotta leave the past,
it's in the past ♪
It means the family you're born into
is important
above all else, right?
♪ Strike a match ♪
♪ Watch the flames grow higher ♪
♪ We can burn much brighter ♪
Wrong. The original proverb
goes a little differently.
So, er,
you're not gonna say it back?
♪ What does it take
to leave it all behind? ♪
I will in two minutes.
I just love to see you
sweat it out.
♪ We'll see it happen
one step at a time ♪
It actually says,
"The blood of the covenant
is thicker
than the water of the womb."
♪ Here we go ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ No, we're never slowing down ♪
Speaking Italian...
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
- Hey.
- ♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ We'll get lost until we're found ♪
- ♪ Darlin', here we go ♪
- Ah!
Meaning the blood shed
on the proverbial battlefield
bonds us more than simple genetics.
♪ Feel the blood
rushing through my veins ♪
♪ Got some brand-new wings ♪
♪ No, we won't go back ♪
♪ What does it take to make
our dream collide? ♪
And, yes, DNA matters when
it comes to medical history.
♪ The smallest change... ♪
- Look who I found.
- Hey!
♪ ...can make you feel alive ♪
♪ Here we go ♪
I'm not ready to talk about it.
Okay.
I'm cooking.
Wow. I hope his apartment
never gets repaired.
How expired is too expired?
But I'm a doctor,
and I say family is family.
Did you find the question?
So, what if there was
a non-invasive way
to diagnose disease
as easy as taking a vitamin?
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ No, we're never slowing down ♪
♪ We'll get lost until we're found ♪
I don't give a crap whose blood you have.
♪ Darlin', here we go ♪