Here at Gaffney
Chicago Medical Center...
We'll want to get
as much press as possible.
They're doing infomercials
for 2.0 now?
When you were a kid, you
started having your problems,
and I wasn't there for you.
You're here now.
I could construct
a neural network
and compare it against tens of
thousands of known mutations.
I wonder if you might train me
on that new program you were
talking about.
Dr. Halstead,
can you give Dr. Song a hand?
You can't play
with the bumpers up.
So what? I'm not embarrassed.
How are you supposed
to improve?
Who said anything about
improving?
I'm here for the drinks.
Maggie's buying first round?
That's what I heard.
This is why I don't invite you
two out, because you're cheap.
Where's Ben?
The science fair is tomorrow.
He's prepping the gym for
a mass eruption of baking soda
volcanoes.
But don't you worry,
I got a fourth.
Oh, yeah? Who?
Hey, Grace. Over here.
Word is she's single. Mm-hmm.
What, you're trying
to set us up?
Hi.
Hey.
We're hitting the bar.
Can we get you anything?
Oh, my gosh, yeah.
Guinness.
Anything dark, really.
Anything dark.
Just like Halstead.
Go figure.
Well, be back in a flash.
Didn't know you bowled.
Neither did I,
until undergrad.
It's the least physically
demanding gym credit
I could get away with.
Not too analog for your taste?
It's not gonna do much
for my street cred, but
I fell in love with it.
The physics of the game,
it's just really elegant.
Besides, Jack has me
all over the place
these past few years,
and it's easy to find
an alley pretty much
anywhere in the world.
It's comforting,
finding something familiar
when you travel all the time.
Maybe it's the smell.
Floor wax, sweaty shoes,
and old beer.
It's the sweaty shoes
that do it for me.
You're gonna have to tell me
if I'm any good, though.
Rarely in one place
long enough
to see how I stack up.
All right.
Dr. Berger said placement
went smoothly.
So I can get out of here?
I'd say so.
Remember to keep the site
sterile every time
you connect to the cycler.
Yeah, spare me the speech.
I've placed hundreds
of PD catheters.
You sure?
It's a pretty good speech.
Just take it easy
on yourself.
Peritoneal dialysis
will let you keep working,
but you won't be feeling 100%
anytime soon.
I'll take it under advisement.
Hey, sweetie. Still at it?
Yeah.
Well, I just have one more.
I'm almost done.
But Notre Dame, Northwestern,
and the University of Chicago
are all finished.
I just need to submit them.
Wow.
So proud of you, sweetie,
how hard you've worked.
What's the last one?
Um, Stanford.
Stanford?
Well, their school of
sustainability
has all these research groups
on everything
from decommissioning
combustion engine
s to carbon storage.
The opportunities are unreal.
And I think I'd actually
have a decent shot at it.
I guess I just thought
that you were
planning to stay closer
to Chicago.
Well, yeah, I mean,
obviously I do.
I mean, I was just
considering all the options.
As well you should.
Um...
Honey, I don't want
to slow your roll,
so keep up the good work.
And just give me a shout
if you need anything.
What can you tell us
about Kuan-yu's journey?
Kuan-yu has a condition
called ankylosing spondylitis.
It's an inflammatory disease.
As it progresses, it fuses
the vertebrae of the spine.
I took him many places,
but no one fixed him.
No, it didn't work at all.
We always hoped
that it would stop,
but he got more bent over.
Kuan-yu, how long have you
been in this position?
I have not laid
on my back in 19 years.
It must be hard to function,
to do everyday things.
Yes, but my mother
helps me in all ways.
She keeps my hope alive.
Can you tell us
how they came to Chicago Med?
An international aid
organization
tried to pair Kuan-yu with
a number of renowned surgeons,
but they all declined
his case.
They were too scared.
Yeah, there are significant
technical challenges
to a surgery like this.
A similar procedure was
performed in China
a few years ago,
but it was spaced out
over several months.
Not everywhere is equipped
for something like this.
But thankfully, social media
jumped to the rescue
and tagged Dr. Marcel.
Yeah, I knew we should
and could help,
so I presented Kuan-yu's case
to Jack Dayton,
and he immediately agreed.
Mr. Dayton flew us here,
paid everything.
He asked nothing
but to make this film.
Mr. Dayton and Dr. Marcel
are my angels.
Kuan-yu has candidly
discussed the risks,
and he's mentally prepared.
But are you concerned?
Tomorrow's surgery
has been meticulously planned
for months,
and I have full faith
in our doctors and nurses.
And we have OR 2.0.
Because Kuan-yu's spine
is one long, rigid bone,
there are severe risks
involved in separating
and reconstructing it,
which is where 2.0
is a gamechanger,
allowing us to be more precise
as we perform a series
of osteotomies, meaning--
Sorry to interrupt the
infomercial,
but would you rather hear this
from the surgeon
who's actually performing
the procedure?
This is Dr. Abrams,
our chief of neurosurgery
and lead surgeon
on Kuan-yu's surgery.
Yes, and Dr. Marcel,
our esteemed general surgeon,
will be assisting.
Yes, I will be helping
Dr. Abrams
gain access to Kuan-yu's spine
via anterior approaches.
So as we discussed,
we'll be placing screws
along every level
of the spine,
connected by
at least four rods
from the skull to the pelvis,
along with multiple pedicle
subtraction osteotomies
and cerebral column
resections.
Dr. Abrams, this is wonderful,
but could you turn
and face the camera
and give us that information
again in layman's terms
for our documentary audience?
Your show pony's right there.
Yes, I'll be happy
to translate.
Hey, Sharon.
How was filming last night?
Fine.
I'm relieved my part is over.
And the filming
will be completed
after the surgery today.
You don't sound too happy
about the documentary.
Well, I think Jack
has a unique
and commendable understanding
of the power of PR.
Go on. I'm listening for the
"but."
Having cameras in the hospital
doesn't exactly create
a therapeutic environment.
Yeah, I hear you.
But, Sharon, this is
the kind of case
that puts Gaffney on par
with the Mayo Clinic.
Well, I can't pretend that
I don't like the sound
of that.
So for everyone's sake,
let's hope that there's
a good outcome.
Now that sounds like a plan.
So that four-bagger earn me
a spot on the practice team?
I think you had us all
outclassed.
You held your own.
Maybe we could square off
sometime, you and me.
Sure. Sounds good.
Got to run. Big day in 2.0.
Good luck.
Uh... Kind of
flat-footed, Halstead.
What?
Will and Grace.
It has a nice,
familiar ring to it.
If I'm correct,
they were just friends.
Okay, come on.
You can't talk to your ex
about your new crush?
I think you misread
the situation.
Hey.
Mornin'.
Whoa, whoa.
What's with the jacket?
I work here now.
Yeah, that much I guessed.
You all right?
Yeah, I slept funny.
So you're parking cars.
Hannah--
Dr. Asher hooked me up.
Sent over the job opening.
Put in a good word.
How considerate of her.
Well, I wanted
to surprise you.
Hey, you think I should, like,
write her a thank you note?
Is that weird?
Maybe I'll buy her
a cup of coffee.
I'll pass along your regards.
Hustle up.
You don't want
to be written up
for loitering on the job.
Dr. Archer, good morning.
How are you?
Fine. Why would you
ask me that?
No reason.
Anything you need? Water or--
Yeah, I need residents
to talk less.
Hey. Hey, how'd
the PD cath go?
Okay. Why would you get
Sean a job here?
Excuse me?
Every person in this place
knows what's going on with me.
How long do you think it'll be
before he finds out the news?
Wait. He doesn't know
about your renal failure?
And I had planned
to keep it that way.
Listen, I just got this kid
back, all right?
With his sobriety,
I don't want
to burden him with my stuff.
Okay, Dean, I'm sorry
if I'm butting in here,
but sobriety depends
on both of you being honest.
If you really want that
real relationship with Sean,
he needs to know.
You are butting in, all right?
And I'll tell him
when he's ready.
Okay, hey.
If you need a hand with
anything, I'm here.
I know that the first
few nights of dialysis
can be really rough.
Yeah, I'm not in the market
for a nursemaid.
I can help. His veins roll.
Oh, I've got it. Thank you.
He can't keep it?
No, I'm sorry. He can't wear
anything during surgery.
Hey, Dan. Everything good?
Yeah. Ms. Goodwin asked me
to come down, you know,
check up on your patient.
Big, stressful day,
even without the damn cameras.
But he seems
to be doing great,
you know,
focused on the positives.
Well, looks like
we're ready to go.
Exciting day, huh?
Good luck.
Thanks, buddy.
Hey, Kuan-yu.
It's Dr. Marcel.
Ready to see the world?
I am born ready.
Oh, that's the spirit.
Good, buddy. Great. All right.
I'm gonna have you guys step
back for a moment. Thank you.
Can I give you a hand?
Did you need an extra bag
or anything?
I can't keep still.
Worse today.
Perfectly normal
to be worried.
Every day, I get older,
less strong,
and he gets worse.
So yes, I am worried today.
But I am also hopeful.
Good.
Maybe I go into surgery now.
You know what? I'm afraid that
that's not gonna be possible.
It's against hospital policy.
No. No, I must be there.
I'm so sorry that this wasn't
made clear to you earlier,
but it's actually
for Kuan-yu's safety.
But I can be useful.
Maybe they have questions
or need help moving him.
Mrs. Wu, your son is
in the best possible hands.
Look, how about
if I find you a place to wait
right next to
the operating room?
That way, you can be
as close as possible.
Would that make you
feel better?
Dr. Archer, incoming MVC.
Going to Trauma 3.
Zach, you're going with them.
Court! Vincent Jones, 40s.
T-boned at Cermak
and Clark. GCS 8.
Sats have been hovering in the
high 80s.
Pressure?
105 over 80. Heart rate's 135.
All right, let's go. Get ready
to transfer on my count.
Should we get
an extra set of hands
so you don't have to--
No.
Ready? One, two, three.
Dr. Archer, are you--
Yeah, just worry about your
patient, all right?
What's the first order
of business?
Airway.
Airway, right.
Trini, I need ET kit,
RSI drugs.
I need X-ray in here, please!
All right. Feeling some
instability in the pelvis.
What is taking so long?
I think I've got it.
You think?
I'm in.
Breath sounds bilateral.
Sats rising.
Pressure still soft.
All right. What's next, Zach?
X-ray chest and pelvis,
and then a fast.
You want to resuscitate
this guy
or just let him die
while you order stuff?
Right. Two units whole blood.
Negative fast.
All right. Where's my X-ray?
All right, clear!
Let's see it.
Left-sided posterior hip
dislocation.
Got it in one. And?
We'll need to reduce.
Set the scoreboard
back to zero.
He needs a panscan.
Rule out cavitary hemorrhage.
He might need surgery
before we reduce him.
All right, let's move.
Here we go.
Kuan-yu's ready,
and the cameras
are in place.
I had the one at the head
of the table moved back.
Better if you moved them
all the way out of the room.
What, are you afraid
they're gonna
throw you off?
Nothing throws me off.
I just don't think publicity
has a place in my OR.
I'm surprised
you took this case then.
Well, I thought
about refusing,
but any other neurosurgeon
would probably paralyze
the poor guy.
No, sadly, at the end
of the day,
you and I are just
shilling for a billionaire
padding his pockets.
Well, if you want
to look at it that way, okay.
But this surgery never would
have happened without 2.0,
and it never would have
happened without Jack.
Right. In other words,
your participation in it.
Ms. Wallace, I'm Dr. Halstead.
My mom's looking after my son.
Trying to explain
how to swaddle
a six-week-old via text.
Take your time.
She'll manage.
I turned out okay.
So what brings you in today?
Here it comes.
Asked and answered.
How long you
been feeling this way?
A few days now.
I thought maybe
it was food poisoning,
but it shouldn't last
this long, right?
Could be
viral gastroenteritis.
Stomach bug. Easily treatable.
But we'll start with some labs
and IV fluids.
I can also prescribe you
something for nausea.
That would be
much appreciated.
All right.
Here we go.
You know, I did the whole
single-mom IVF thing.
Everyone warned me
about the risks of
a geriatric pregnancy.
I didn't know the effects
would last postpartum.
Well, we're gonna get you
sorted out and back to
your son as soon as possible.
All right, CBC, BMP, KUB,
and bolus a liter
of normal saline.
You got it.
Thanks, Doc.
Of course.
Hey, can I get your eyes
on this?
Yeah, sure. What's up?
40-year-old IVF primip came in
with nausea and vomiting,
but her labs are normal.
Tox?
Clean.
Okay, yeah, her BP is up.
147 over 92.
Yeah, been that way
since intake.
Could be preeclampsia?
This far out?
Yeah, it's rare,
but it happens.
I'd check a CMP and
PC ratio and consider mag,
just in case.
I can do the order
if you want.
Sure. Thanks.
Yeah.
Hey, Will, about earlier,
you know, you and Grace...
Hannah--
No. I never should have
teased you.
Obviously, men and women
can be friends.
Okay, look, even
if I were interested in her,
Grace is a nomad.
Jack has her
all over the world.
It's tough to start something
with someone like that.
Yeah.
I'll let you know
when these labs come back.
Cervicothoracic PSOs
look good.
I think so.
Let's see if 2.0 agrees.
I don't need another opinion.
Well, it could
only help us, Sam.
Standby.
Okay, so 2.0 would determine
if the osteotomy
is at the ideal depth,
height, and angle
to achieve correction.
Acceptable C7 and T1
osteotomies.
Acceptable? It's perfect.
Can you explain
how those lasers are helpful
for the surgeons?
Yeah, Dr. Marcel,
could you explain that?
Sure. Yeah.
Could you move over?
In fact, direct your camera
towards the screen there.
You'll see that 2.0 will
superimpose lines
onto the spine to help guide
the surgeon where to drill
and the extent of bone to
remove.
Dr. Abrams, I'm seeing
50% decreases in amplitude
and increased latency in
both legs. Running a motor.
Put the evoked potential
response on screen.
Dr. Marcel,
is there a problem?
Are we concerned with
cord injury and compression?
Yeah, 'cause I'm assuming
that our patient's goal
wasn't to become paralyzed.
Push his MAPs. Reverse
everything that's reversible.
Find out if this
IOM change is real.
And if it is, close him up
and get him down
for an MRI stat.
MRI? No, hold on.
We don't have to move him.
2.0 can do an intraop CT.
Yeah, which won't show me
anything about cord edema
or ligamentous buckling.
But if I can merge a CT with
an intraoperative ultrasound,
you'd have everything
you'd need right here.
That would work, and we
wouldn't have to move Kuan-yu.
Look, experiment with
this thing on another patient.
I want to be 100% sure.
Sam, there are
a hundred reasons
why we should not move him.
Pick one. Infection risk.
Prolonged time
under anesthesia.
Hell, he could even be
unstable after the move
to even continue surgery.
Do it.
Let's hope you're right.
Otherwise, you're committing
a career-ending mistake
to film.
You sure there's nothing
we can get you?
Maybe something to eat?
No.
How are we doing?
Any updates?
Not yet.
Oh. Excuse me.
You know,
that's a lovely stone.
I was noticing it earlier
when I was talking
to your son.
From the river.
Kuan-yu found this as a child.
It was smooth and shiny.
He thought it was a gem.
It was one of the last times
he was able to move,
to play.
I made this to give him hope
that one day,
he would play again.
I promised I would help him.
Well, you have certainly
kept that promise.
What's going on?
I need to talk to Da-xia.
About what?
There's been a complication,
something about
a cord compression.
I've got to get
her point of view.
Now is not the time.
Ms. Goodwin, this is
one of the major risks
they knew he was facing.
Narratively, that's important
to their story.
Well, this is not
about a story.
It's a complicated
medical procedure
involving real people.
I have a directive
from Mr. Dayton.
She signed a contract
to be filmed.
You film at my discretion,
not Jack Dayton's.
And you can speak to Da-xia
after the doctors provide
an update and not before.
Well, I need to call
Mr. Dayton.
Well, you just do that.
Did he need to speak to me?
Did he have news?
No, nothing concrete.
But the surgeons will
check in with you soon.
Why don't we go wait
in my office?
It's right upstairs,
and, you know, we'll be
more comfortable there.
Thank you, Dr. Charles.
You bet.
I'm not seeing
any obvious cord compression.
That's why I'm also checking.
His evoked potentials
look better.
All right, I'm satisfied that
the cord was merely
compressed, not injured.
We can continue.
Dr. Marcel?
Yeah?
Would you ask 2.0 to prepare
the next osteotomy, please?
Certainly. Grace?
Will?
I'll call you back.
Results for your patient,
Cara.
Good news, doesn't look like
postpartum preeclampsia.
Bad news is nothing definitive
to explain her symptoms.
Yeah, I'm thinking stress.
I mean, she did just
give birth six weeks ago,
and pregnancy puts the body
at the literal limit
of human endurance
for nine months.
Makes sense that stress
would manifest physically.
Yeah, I'll look into anything
else to test her for,
but I think you're right.
Dr. Archer,
do you want my seat?
Uh, I'm good.
I got to turn six over anyway,
so it's not a big deal.
For crying out loud.
Listen, I'm not an invalid.
I'm fine!
Dr. Archer?
What?
I have Vincent's CT results.
He has a pelvic hematoma
with a blush.
We need to embolize him.
Now we can reduce his hip.
Send him up to IR.
You ever done
an Allis reduction?
I've observed one.
All right. Well,
you're assisting me.
What now?
I just know an Allis reduction
can be physically taxing.
And?
I just don't think
it's the best idea
for you to do this procedure.
Yeah,
I'm an attending physician
and the chief
of this department.
I will not be advised
by some resident
who barely knows
what the hell
he's talking about!
I'm sorry.
Yeah, you know what?
Go get yourself
another case, man.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, you said that! Go! Go!
I have another patient
for you in two.
Need a hand
with a hip reduction?
Mm-hmm.
Dr. Archer, I will not
have you speaking
to residents like that.
Can we just get this done?
Murphy,
will you assist, please?
Sure. No problem.
Over here. Push down on the
pelvis and give Dr. Archer
counter traction.
All right, we're gonna
do this on three.
Ready? One, two, three.
That's good. It's in. Oh.
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
No, you're not.
I just got to get him up
to IR.
Stop talking. Murphy,
you take him up.
We need to get you in a bed.
Come on.
All right. All right.
So you think
this was all stress?
We could not find any
other clinical explanation.
Stress takes
a real physical toll--
nausea, vomiting,
hypertension.
All common and treatable
presentations,
even in the case of
happy stress.
We'll prescribe you
a low-dose antihypertensive
for your blood pressure.
But the best thing you could
do for yourself right now
is find ways
to reduce your stress levels.
I waited so long
to become a mother,
probably too long,
if I'm being honest.
I naively thought
the perfect moment would
just waltz into my life.
Now that my little Lee
is here,
I don't want to miss anything.
Well, he's a lucky boy.
Don't forget to take care
of yourself too.
Thank you.
Cara?
You okay?
Help me.
Aphasia.
Stroke alert!
Need some help in here!
You're okay. Just breathe,
breathe, breathe.
Okay, try to relax.
All right.
Nope. No, no, back away.
Let's close up the lumbar PSO.
Compressor and set screws.
So Dr. Abrams and Gottfried
are placing the final bit
of instrumentation.
Then they will collapse
Kuan-yu's spine,
which will correct his posture
to an upright--
His sats are dropping.
Heart rate and BP
are down too.
Airway pressures?
Peaks are 50s.
Still dropping. Sats at 80%.
It must be
due to his position.
Well, there's not much
we can do about that in
the middle of a spine surgery.
It's got to be
a tension pneumothorax.
Stethoscope?
Hey. This isn't a trauma case.
Just bronch him
and check the tube's position.
Kuan-yu's chest
and abdominal muscles
are probably atrophied.
When we straightened him,
we likely cracked a rib,
punctured the lung.
There. Diminished breath
sounds on the right.
Chest tube kit for Dr. Marcel.
28 French.
No, he needs a rescue now.
What's happening?
Has Kuan-yu stopped breathing?
I need
to needle decompress him.
Chest tube later.
Can you reach
the anterior chest?
- I've got no other option.
- Just get it done.
Heart rate's 40. Sats at 50s.
Running out of time here,
Crockett.
Yeah, I don't want
to stick his heart.
Not a ton of room to work.
Dr. Marcel, can you explain--
Be quiet!
Okay, needle's in.
Oxygen saturation
climbing. 85%.
Airway pressure's down to 30.
BP's back up to 120 systolic.
Okay. Let's finish up
the spine.
I need you to back up.
Back up.
Doesn't look like
you tore the stitch.
Probably just overexerted
yourself.
Wonderful.
There.
Who do you think
you're kidding
with this tough guy act?
Everyone here knows
what you're going through.
Well, see, that's the problem.
That's all they see: a sick,
weak old man.
"Let me get that for you."
"Take my seat."
"Should you be doing that?"
I can't stand that.
There's no shame
in having an illness.
Listen, I'm the doctor
in this ED, all right?
I'm not a patient
Oh.
You know,
I once thought like you.
After my cancer diagnosis.
I thought folks would only see
what was wrong with me,
that every kind word
or offer to help
was just an act of pity.
Then someone who lived
through my experience
made me realize how far
from the truth that was,
that I was the only one
defining myself by my illness.
My friends, my family,
my community,
all they wanted to do
was support me.
And all I needed to do
was let them.
It's not weakness
to let people be kind.
It's strength.
Okay.
Oh.
And Zach's a good doctor.
He just needs
to be encouraged.
And that's our job.
Message received.
One chamomile tea.
My mom drinks this
to help her sleep
because she insists
on drinking coffee
till late in the afternoon.
Go figure. Ooh.
Yes?
Okay.
Well, good. I will tell her.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
So the surgery is complete,
and Kuan-yu
came through it very well.
As a matter of fact,
the next time you see him,
he will probably be
sitting up.
You mean he'll stand?
He'll walk?
Yeah.
With time, rehabilitation,
he should live
a pretty normal life.
Oh, my.
I'm so sorry.
No, you have absolutely
nothing to apologize for.
There's a lot to take in.
This is the day we've been
waiting for.
All these years,
I take good care of him.
And now, what will happen now?
This surgery has upended
a life that you and your son
have known
for, what, almost 30 years?
And it makes perfect sense
that you would grieve
the loss of that life
and be apprehensive
about the future.
But this is not right,
these feelings.
How can I think of me
at such a time?
How can I be so selfish...
Oh, no, no.
And not be happy?
No, no, no.
You are not selfish.
Every parent in the world
understands what
you're feeling right now.
From the moment
our kids are born,
they start
to move away from us.
And when they finally leave,
it's only because
we've actually
done our jobs well.
But this, I can promise you:
you will always be his mother.
Always.
One half of the same stone.
As you can see...
That's in my head?
It's a condition called
Moyamoya disease.
Moyamoya literally means
"puff of smoke" in Japanese.
It's a progressive disorder
which blocks blood flow
to your brain's arteries.
So to compensate,
your body created
all these smaller vessels,
which are prone to bleeding.
So your symptoms were
caused by small strokes.
Progressive.
So this is going to get worse?
Keeping you on aspirin
and calcium channel blockers
will help reduce the risk
of another stroke.
Just reduce but not prevent.
It'll keep you stable
for the foreseeable future.
There is a surgical option,
but we don't think
that you're there yet.
Surgery? I want the surgery.
It's an invasive
neurosurgical procedure.
You have a newborn.
You've been through a lot.
The surgery can wait
for a more ideal time.
I don't want this cloud
hanging over me.
I've waited
for ideal times before.
They don't come.
Please, the surgery.
We'll have neurosurgery
come speak to you.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Dr. Hudgins.
Yes?
I hear our patient, Mr. Jones,
is resting comfortably
in the ICU
after successful embolization.
Oh, good.
There's a sim dummy in seven.
I'm gonna show you
how to reduce a hip.
You said it was a physically
demanding procedure,
so you can do it.
Mama.
I can see you.
Yes.
And you look so beautiful.
I'm so old.
No. No.
I'll see you.
A word, please.
Yes?
Look.
It's one thing
to bar them from
filming her during surgery,
but, Sharon, this is what
audiences would want to see.
And you've stopped them
from capturing it.
After all they've been
through, George,
they deserve this time
without cameras.
They wouldn't even have had
a chance to get this surgery
if it wasn't for
Jack's generosity.
Yes, and I still have
to look out for my patients.
George, you're a doctor.
You know that.
I do.
But I also believe in Jack's
vision for this hospital.
He wants us to be the leader
in cutting-edge healthcare.
Sharon, this film tells
the world exactly who we are.
And who are we, George,
if we forget about
our patients
and their loved ones?
But Jack is a man who's not
used to hearing the word "no."
Well, maybe it's time he did.
Yeah.
Hey, neurosurgery is getting
ready to operate on Cara.
That's great.
Woman's braver than I am.
And me.
Hey, you weren't wrong.
I am interested in Grace.
Okay.
So why did you give her
the brush-off this morning?
And don't give me that stuff
about her being a nomad.
I mean, look at
my dating track record here.
Hasn't been exactly stellar.
No offense.
Yeah.
Well, I might be crazy
or out of line,
but I wonder
if all of these excuses
are really just about one
reason, or rather one person.
Natalie.
Natalie?
It did always feel like
you were still carrying
a torch for her.
Yeah, maybe.
Maybe I still was.
But now, I mean, it's just me
trying to get it right.
Good.
You're a really
great guy, Will.
You deserve to be happy.
Thanks, Hannah.
Now, what was
particularly difficult
about this operation?
Well, the angle
was slightly unusual.
But fortunately, we were able
to relieve the pressure
and reinflate his lung.
You were basically
folded over yourself,
and alarms were blaring, so...
Right.
Why don't you tell us
what you felt in that moment?
I guess the real headline here
is successfully aligning
Kuan-yu's spine.
You saw firsthand
a revolution in medicine,
thanks in part to OR 2.0.
I mean, this is
just the beginning
of what this Dayton
partnership can--
can produce.
Hell of a day, huh?
Hope you're off to celebrate.
You know, you're not
a terrible surgeon,
but you do have
awful taste in heroes.
Heroes? Come on, Sam.
At least
he's using his billions
for some good, right?
Oh, yeah, confident
that's why he
amassed his fortune.
Point is, we can help
so many more people
with Jack's vision
and money in our corner.
No, his vision of whom to help
seems a bit more narrow
than yours.
What does that mean?
I just found out.
Dayton says from now on, 2.0
is for paying customers only.
Wait, what?
You heard me.
No more subsidized care.
Well, if that's true,
then your fight's with
the insurance companies.
We're all out
of the good stuff.
Radiology's got
a secret stash, though.
Thanks for the tip.
Or maybe I could buy you
a cup of coffee.
I don't think
that's a good idea.
Okay. Have a good night.
What about a drink instead?
Guinness, right?
Mm-hmm.
Guess that
made you happy, huh?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
I gather you told him.
More or less.
Told him I needed dialysis.
Left it pretty vague.
But I don't want to
make him a caretaker.
He doesn't need that
right now.
It's a good thing
you told him, though,
not just for his sake.
Good night, Dean.
Wait, hold on.
I have a favor to ask.
Hey, Dad. There's pizza
in the fridge.
I promise it's not Hawaiian.
Wait. Are you finished
with your applications?
Yeah.
All proofed, agonized over,
and submitted.
And I chose early decision
to University of Chicago.
What happened to Stanford?
Nothing.
I wasn't really
all that serious about it.
Plus, I'm...
not exactly a California girl.
I don't really know
what that means,
but, I mean, you seemed
pretty serious about it to me.
There's other schools
with sustainability stuff.
Plus, I would miss
Italian beef too much.
And, you know, and maybe you.
You know what?
I'd miss you too.
But the right school,
is the right school.
Why go so far
and leave you all alone
when I have
great options at home?
Okay, first of all,
I'm not gonna be all alone.
And guess what?
It's actually not your job
to worry about me.
Anna, when you've accomplished
what you have in school,
you get to go to whatever
school you want to.
I don't care where it is.
And honestly,
I've really started
to kind of look forward
to having an excuse to go
to California in February.
So, you know, don't step
on my dreams.
Thank you, Dad.
I'm gonna apply.
Why not?
Yeah.
Let's see.
Okay.
All set.
Is that all right?
Are you in any pain?
No, it's fine. Thanks.
Uh... Front door sticks,
so just lift up
when you close it.
I know it's late.
Actually, I'm a--
I'm a bit of a night owl.
Occupational hazard
of being an OB-GYN:
always on call.
Hannah,
you don't have to stay.
There is a quiz in here,
and I have always
wanted to know
which classic car matches
my sparkling personality.
Oh, easy.
You're a Prius.