How am I supposed to walk into
that meeting with no presentation?
How the hell did
you screw this up?
It wasn't me.
She's lying. No. We agreed...
Her team had all the financials.
And we were swamped
modeling them,
that's why we agreed that
you would do the slides.
Well, one of you screwed up.
So please try to figure it out,
'cause when the client dumps me,
I need to know who to fire.
I confirmed in the
e-mail. Hold on. Here.
She did tell you about it, Russ.
I never got this.
Russ, are you okay?
Are you drunk?
I'm not drunk.
I'm not drunk. I'm...
I had no idea he
was drinking again.
Well, you should have.
Give me five minutes, I'll
go to the business center
and print the graphs directly
from the spreadsheets.
Run. And bring me
some paper towels.
What?
Oh, it hurts.
Don't tell me you
were drinking, too.
No.
My ears. Oh, my God.
Twenty-seven-year-old female, intense
intermittent ear pain, saw six doctors...
Tell her to stop
lurking in the front row.
If she wants to
hit on musicians,
that's what tour
buses are for. Next.
If I ask why we're
in Wilson's office,
is there any chance I'll
get a straight answer?
Try it, try it.
Fourteen-year-old boy, joint
pain and excess hair growth.
Tell him to masturbate no
more than three times daily.
With meals. Next.
Did I mention that the
27-year-old female is really hot?
And her husband is really not.
Wild guess. He's rich.
Not unless social workers have
begun pulling in the big money recently.
Give me.
You're taking the case
because she's hot?
No, that would be an
accident of genetics.
It's because she's hot
and her husband is ugly.
That's a fascinating window into
the mysteries of human psychology.
Also, she's "really" hot.
Or she, you know,
loves her husband.
She loves something about him.
Vitamin deficiency. She changed
her diet a few months ago.
To a healthier diet.
Raw foods, lots of nuts.
It's not the ear,
it's the heart.
Her protein was cheese,
which can raise cholesterol.
Hers was already elevated,
gave her arterial blockages.
Cardiac arrhythmia presenting
as ear pain. Very rare. Cool.
So Beauty and the Beast.
Who wants to go see?
Let's see. Dr. Taub,
Foreman, Chase and Hadley.
Four for four.
Wow, I can't believe
I get all these doctors.
And such good-looking ones, too.
Yeah, it's almost like we
don't all need to be here.
Your case presented a very
interesting diagnostic challenge.
Oh.
You can't sleep
in your own office?
Or bedroom, for that matter?
Got to avoid my natural habitat.
Some idiot I went to med school
with keeps leaving messages,
wants to drop by for lunch.
So tell him "no."
It's complicated.
It's too complicated
for you to tell someone
you don't like to screw off?
That's practically your hobby.
A few months ago, he was
sort of part of my therapy.
My shrink told me write a letter
of apology to someone I hurt.
And how did you hurt him?
We were in a seminar
on flatworm genetics.
I switched my
final paper with his.
You plagiarized?
Doesn't sound like you.
I was testing a theory.
I thought that our professor
was biased against me.
I assumed he'd get a
high grade with my paper,
and I'd get a low
grade with his.
Interestingly, I was
wrong. I got an A.
So you're in this
mental hospital,
delving into your subconscious,
and this is who you
choose to apologize to?
Yep. Lorenzo Wibberly.
Of all the people in
the world you've hurt...
Not everyone has a name that's
so easy to find in the White Pages.
I'm in there. And so is Cuddy.
Yeah. Yet I picked
him. It's funny, isn't it?
Yes, it's hilarious.
Great to see what a
success your therapy was.
We said we'd never
to go to sleep angry!
We did find an arrhythmia, but it's
not from your arteries, they're clean.
Will the pain come back?
We'll start her on cardiac
meds, that should help.
But we still need to figure out
what's causing the arrhythmia.
Hey, Valerie.
Russ.
It's so nice of you to stop by.
I got lots of free time now.
You don't blame me, do you?
You were drunk
in front of Norris.
No, no, no, no,
no. I'm drunk now.
Then, it was like someone
poisoned me or something.
Maybe you should
come back later.
Okay.
I just wanna say goodbye.
Okay, Russ. Thank
you for coming by.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
What are you doing?
You poor son of a bitch.
She doesn't love you any
more than she loved me.
Okay, you need
to leave right now.
You're pretending you
had an affair with my wife?
Yeah, we're all pretending.
You got nothing to worry about.
Tell them where you
were six months ago, Russ.
I had a breakdown. I had some
paranoid tendencies, as they say.
But it turns out, I had
a right to be paranoid.
You need help.
Get him out of here.
Okay. Okay.
Oh, my God.
Are you okay? You okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
We'll keep an eye out. He's
not getting back in the hospital.
He's making all that
up. You know that, right?
Yeah, of course.
Where are you?
Undisclosed location.
Who are you hiding from?
Wilson.
And the lunch
date that Wilson is,
no doubt, right now,
trying to sic on me.
But in the great game of
chess that is our relationship,
Wilson sees only one
move ahead, I see dozens.
That is why he
will never mate me.
That's a chess term.
That's great. A co-worker
confronted our patient.
Altered mental status. Basically
accused her of poisoning him.
We think he was projecting.
So he's poisoning her.
What could he get his hands on
to cause supraventricular
tachycardia?
Does he have dry
skin, thin eyebrows?
If you're sharing an amazed
look, please do it louder.
He might have. How
did you know that?
He has hypothyroidism,
he dumped his
meds in her coffee,
that would make her heart
go boom, in a bad way.
We'll treat with beta blockers.
I'm sorry, but I
totally disagree.
- With what?
- With everything.
Why are we assuming he's
lying and she's telling the truth?
Because she's a successful,
happily married consultant,
and he's a crazy, drunk weirdo
who we just tossed
out of the hospital.
And she's hot.
Maybe she picked him
because he's vulnerable.
There's something off
about her, I can feel it.
If you had any evidence...
Why didn't she tell us a
co-worker puked on her shoes
right before she collapsed?
Because it's medically irrelevant.
He was drunk, she was sick.
You don't think it's suspicious
she didn't mention
it to her husband?
Yeah, Foreman, why did
you break up with Thirteen?
Oh, no, wait, the non-subtextual
thing she was saying, why that?
This is about the case,
not some imaginary issue that
you think Foreman and I have.
Great. Start her
on beta blockers.
You'll do it?
I don't think he
was talking to me.
Well, I am.
I'm the only one who
thinks you're wrong.
Maybe that's why
I'm asking you to do it.
Greg? Lorenzo Wibberly.
Dr. Wilson said you'd
be here. How you been?
Check and mate.
Look,
I'm sorry this is
awkward or whatever.
I just thought it was nice
of you to write that letter,
and I wanted to tell you that
you don't have to feel bad.
Thanks.
So, where you
working these days?
You got your own practice
or you at a hospital?
I thought you knew. Dani's,
the organic supermarket chain.
As an in-house doctor?
I actually never got licensed.
I didn't graduate med school.
I planned on going back,
and then my father got sick
and I had to take care of
him, and I had some bad luck.
Why didn't you graduate?
I was one credit short.
And I was sort of already
on academic probation, so...
Which credit?
I got a...
He failed me on that paper
you switched. I thought you knew.
So I'm guessing you're the
CEO of this supermarket chain.
I bag groceries.
Life works out weird sometimes.
We were going to do it in Santa
Barbara because of his parents,
but then I found this beautiful
hotel in Montauk and...
You're testing her
for a brain tumor?
That's what I told her.
You can chastise me
after you look at the monitor.
Look what's lighting up.
Lateral frontal cortex,
Broca's area. So what?
I told her it was customary
to talk during MRIs, to relax.
I spent the last 30 minutes asking her
about everything in life that she loves,
then hates, then feels
any emotion about at all.
There's nothing in the
paralimbic system, amygdala.
Because she's using the
language part of her brain
and bypassing the emotional.
She can understand love
and pain and empathy,
but she can't feel them at all.
She's a psychopath.
Why do you want
to meet her so badly?
Psychopaths always fascinate me.
I think it's their
cultural literacy
and strong family
values. Or is that Jews?
We're not gonna be able
to get an honest read on her
unless we figure out a way to
get the husband out of there.
Hmm. I got an idea.
Can you get out of here?
Thanks.
It was the "thanks" that did it.
Hi, I'm Dr. House. How long
have you been a psychopath?
Are you kidding? He's not.
Are you saying I'm like
Ted Bundy or something?
Psychopathy can get a bad rap.
Doesn't necessarily
mean you're violent.
Just that you're completely
without conscience,
you lack any normal emotion,
you manipulate
everyone around you,
you're promiscuous,
you lie pathologically.
Any of this ringing bells?
Is that why you were asking
me all those weird questions?
Yeah. Well, you have
Darwin to thank for that.
She got the creeps around you.
Which, oddly, is an actual medical
phenomenon around psychopaths,
probably an evolved
response to predators.
I'm sorry. You're really freaking
me out. I have no idea what...
Relax. We have a
duty of confidentiality.
And you have an
undiagnosed heart problem
that could kill you
at any moment.
We believe that your
mental abnormality
is related to your physical one.
So if you want to
keep on "predating"...
What do you want to know?
Your co-worker's story
was true. You poisoned him.
No. I gave him a little
Valium and an emetic.
You sure you understand
what the word "no" means?
I've had them both
before, why can't he?
So you were just
helping him out?
I assume he was cool with the
whole seducing and firing part, too.
Russ knew what
he was getting into.
He got sex every Thursday night,
and I got to take
credit for his best ideas.
And what are you getting
out of your marriage?
Same thing you
get out of your job.
Bill has a trust fund, and I have a
prenup his parents made me sign.
Told you he was rich.
She's not that weird.
I'm not so different
than anybody else.
Everyone I've ever known, my family,
my classmates, the people I work with,
they're all out for themselves.
Difference is, I can
admit it to myself.
She kind of reminds
me of someone I know.
Tell me about it.
Some of my co-workers will
insult people right to their faces.
How long have you been this way?
Just how I am.
Are you gonna cure
my heart problems now?
So, psychopathy plus
cardiac arrhythmia. Go.
I thought you were
bluffing to get information.
You really think
they're connected?
Two rare conditions
in one patient,
it's a fair assumption they are.
Psychopathy is
generally just genetic,
nothing you can do about it.
Something that hits 30 years after
birth isn't going to be connected.
There are diseases that
could lie dormant that long,
hit her heart, warp her brain.
Maybe a handful of diseases.
It'll be super awesome
when we find it.
Tertiary syphilis can
cause pseudopsychopathic
syndrome and cardiomyopathy.
Fits best. Start
her on penicillin,
rule out Wilson's
and Hashimoto's.
There's your handful.
Wasn't so hard, was it?
You gotta do something
about Thirteen.
She flouted both my
authority and yours.
Yes. And she got it
right and you got it wrong.
Which just aggravates
the problem.
She'll do it again. Next
time, it won't work out so well.
You got to punish her.
You're her boss,
in some vague, never to
be usefully defined way.
You punish her.
I'm also her ex,
which, as you know,
makes it a little complicated.
The fact that you also fired her
takes it from a little
complicated to a little moronic.
It was the only way I...
It wasn't because you
were too in love with her,
it was because you were
too in love with your career.
We're almost at my floor, so I'll
summarize. Your problem, not mine.
You cut up my only
copy of that photo.
That rare daguerreotype?
You can charge me
for the effort it takes
to search your hard
drive for a new copy.
Not the one of me and
Lucas, the one from Ecuador.
Right, I'd forgotten about your
deep emotional attachment to lemurs.
To my dad.
You got his tail.
He was holding the camera. That
was the last trip we ever took together.
And I don't have a digital copy.
Well, I could stand
here all day apologizing,
but I'd rather expiate my
sins with good, clean work.
You ignoring my texts?
The crazy ones you sent, trying
to get me to make you feel better
about destroying your classmate's
life? No, I never got those.
Wibberly's got some agenda.
Probably trying to guilt me
into getting him a better job.
How pissed was he? Not at all.
That's how I know
he's got an agenda.
If you feel guilty, you
should do something to help.
You are responsible.
Thanks.
What? All I'm responsible for
is the foreseeable
consequences of switching papers.
A bad grade or a sleepless
night. Worst case, a retest.
There was no way to
know that one seminar paper
was gonna destroy
this idiot's life.
If there's any
karma in all this,
he's probably
happier than you are.
Good point. If he is happier,
there's no harm done.
I'll go find out.
That is absolutely
not what I said.
Always with the
modesty, this one.
You want something to eat?
I'm cool.
How's work?
You happy with it?
You know, it's a job.
I don't need to take any
work home with me at least.
Free time. Wouldn't have
any of that if you were a doctor.
Yeah. True.
You like chili? I
could reheat some.
Is that your yard? That's nice.
Yeah. That sugar
maple, 100, 150 years old.
The most beautiful
leaves in the fall.
Sit underneath on the bench,
it's like paradise.
I don't have a yard, myself.
You got a good thing going.
I know.
So, what are the boxes for?
I'm moving.
From paradise?
Well, with my
dad's medical bills,
and me being one of those idiots
that got an adjustable
mortgage, so...
You're losing your home.
Hey, could be worse, right?
How?
Even if the tests are positive,
you don't have to worry.
You're testing for
syphilis, not a cold.
Honey...
At this stage, it's probably
not communicable.
You think I'm
worried about myself?
I just want my
wife to get better.
She might have
caught it at birth,
so it doesn't prove
she was cheating.
If you were worried about that.
Of course not.
How many weeks
am I gonna have to...
You okay?
- Why is she coughing?
- I don't know.
You want some water?
Are you threatened by me?
Not at all.
Well, you should be.
You let him know
what I told you,
I will not only have
your license pulled,
I will sue you for everything
I lose in the divorce.
So the fun you get out of making
those snotty little comments,
is it worth $90 million?
Oh, wait. Will
you hold that look?
I'm really bad at showing
emotions. How's this?
Thanks, baby.
Can I have your arm, please?
My arm! You broke it!
- I don't know what happened.
- Neither do I.
But I know what happened after.
She called Cuddy and
demanded I kick you off the case.
I backed you up
because I trust you,
but you're gonna have
to earn that trust now.
Thanks.
Actually, he backed you up
because of the new
BUN creatinine numbers.
Brittle bones were
from kidney failure.
There is that. So
heart and kidneys.
And brain.
Nope. The psychopathy
is not a symptom.
It was yesterday.
In the meantime, kidney
failure ruled out syphilis,
and testing ruled out the
other ideas that would have fit.
Protein levels,
kidneys, arrhythmia.
Could be paraneoplastic.
I'd say lymphoma.
Get her to radiotherapy.
We can't start radiation without
immunoassays in her urine.
Great. So, you cast a spell
and magically fix her kidneys,
she can give us
some urine to test.
We have some
left from admission.
Not enough for a
completely accurate reading.
Then how about
partially accurate?
Those of you who haven't
slept together, you can go.
Everyone else, stay behind.
Oh, sorry, that was
our secret. Right.
Go have sex. No, thanks.
Fine, I'll cover the Viagra and
the lubricants, just get me a receipt.
We have zero
feelings for each other.
That's too bad,
'cause things worked
much better when you did.
Would it help if
I slept with her?
We were getting to a diagnosis.
No, we were already
at the diagnosis.
You were creating
a fake argument
about an irrelevant
treatment issue
'cause you can't stand
to be around each other.
So have sex, fight,
or quit, I don't care.
Whatever you're
doing now isn't working.
You okay?
Yeah.
Look, I get that you gotta
act fast, but radiation?
You definitely ruled
out everything else?
I'm sorry, but...
We could still check
for environmental toxins.
Where does she
spend most of her time?
Mostly at work, at home.
Hobbies? Recurring
activities outside the home?
No. Not really.
She took a landscaping
class at the Y.
When did it meet?
Every Thursday
night this summer.
You dig in soil, you can
be exposed to pesticides,
heavy metals,
lots of bad things.
Can you find out all about
her landscaping class,
where it was, details like that?
Yeah. I'll do it now.
So when you watch Star
Wars, which side do you root for?
Dr. House, what are you doing?
Just checking in on
your radiotherapy.
From what I hear,
you never visit patients.
And now you've come
to chat with me twice.
I wanna know how you like
being a management consultant.
I'm thinking of getting into it.
That or psychopathy, maybe.
Which pays better?
I think you're already
into one of them.
Dr. Hadley made
a joke yesterday.
She said I sound like you.
You sure you understand
what "joke" means?
So you're not just
out for yourself?
For example, you would never
interrupt a sick woman's treatment
just because of some
personal obsession?
Of course I'm self-interested.
We all are, we're born that way.
The rest of us are
born with consciences.
Which is something you
just sound ecstatic about.
I'm not saying it's logical,
I'm just saying it's human.
So if you know your conscience
is just an animal instinct,
you don't need to follow it.
I think you realize that.
That's why you're talking to me.
You lied about your
landscaping class.
Dr. Hadley thought the
soils might be poisoned.
You told him that?
I just thought...
Russ said you were
having an affair.
Was that your cover?
Every Thursday night, you'd...
I'm so sorry.
Oh, God.
It's not what you think.
Do you remember
that telecom case
I said that we
didn't get last year?
In fact, we did.
And I was swamped.
Every Friday morning, we had
a conference call with London,
so the night before I would...
That's your excuse? You expect me
to believe that you were at the office?
What's the biggest
argument we've ever had?
You said I spend too
much time away from home,
that I don't need a job, that
you would take care of me.
Yeah. That's all true.
You yelled at me.
You made me feel like you
didn't value anything that I did.
I need this job
to feel like I'm accomplishing
something on my own.
That's why I lied to you.
If I call your office
tomorrow and I check...
Call my office,
call my secretary,
call my clients,
interrupt their dinner,
wake them up, I don't care.
I just want you
to know the truth.
You know I love you.
Come here.
Please.
It's okay.
Fire her.
What for? You seem to have
lied your way out of any trouble.
Until Bill checks
up on my cover,
and I have to create a whole
new one to cover that one up.
I've done it before,
but it's a pain,
and I would like Dr. Hadley
to share that pain.
She didn't reveal
any confidences,
and she had a
valid medical reason
to ask about your
landscaping class.
We can see what a
jury says about that.
And admit to your
husband the truth?
You're not going to sue us.
We will remove Dr. Hadley
from all patient contact.
What?
But it's for Dr. Hadley's
benefit, not yours.
We have no obligation
to inflict you on her.
Fine.
But just so you know,
this is not for your benefit.
Dr. Cuddy is furious that
you put her hospital at risk.
She just knows it's a bad idea
to admit it in front of me.
Think what you want.
By the way, your
orderly's outside.
But I'd wait about
another 10 minutes
if you really want
your husband to think
you're having
radiation treatments.
Dr. Hadley?
Are you, by chance, gonna cry?
'Cause that's the
one I just can't do.
Hello? This is Dr. Hadley.
What?
You called the medical board?
What is she talking about?
"Accusations of
sexual harassment."
You don't think I know it's you?
Thirteen, come on.
You already got me fired from
the case, what else do you want?
Dr. Hadley, get out here now.
You're acting like an idiot.
She's trying to make
me lose my license!
She'll fail, unless
you're stupid enough
to go in there
and scream at her.
Sexual harassment
accusations are incredibly serious.
If she made them anonymously,
the case goes away.
If she used her name, we
all back you up, it goes away.
You're completely overreacting.
You'd be pissed off,
too, if you were me.
Or maybe not, I don't know.
You're just about as
emotional as she is.
I'm doing you a favor. I know.
And even when you try to do
something nice, you sound like a jerk.
I'm sorry.
For what?
For firing you.
Don't do that. That's
not what this is about.
Then I'll apologize anyway.
I did it for me, not for you.
I realized that right
after I fired you,
but I couldn't admit it.
I screwed everything up. I hope
that we can still work together.
Something's
wrong with her liver.
Blood flow's backing up,
spilling into her esophagus.
From the cancer?
This isn't lymphoma.
We don't know what it is.
We can wrap bands
around the veins,
but the bleed is so
bad, that might not work.
We want to try
something called the TIPS,
a shunt that makes the
blood bypass the liver.
That'll save her?
It should help preserve
her liver and heart.
But the liver cleans out
toxins, so bypass it too long,
she'll get brain
damage, eventually die.
But that's still probably less
dangerous than bleeding out now.
Probably?
Valerie usually
makes the decisions...
You gotta step up now.
Was she cheating on
me? I can't discuss...
Just tell me she wasn't
lying. Just tell me that.
I'm supposed to
make this decision?
I don't even know
who she is any more.
Either way, you
gotta do it right now.
Do whatever you think is right.
I'd give her a day,
two days at the most.
Great. You be the clock,
everyone else will be the doctors.
Heart, kidneys, now liver.
Amyloidosis.
No speckles on the MRI.
Alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency?
Too much kidney failure.
Primary hepatic fibrosis.
It's our best guess.
Start her on steroids.
Even if we're right, the
liver's probably too scarred.
We got to list
her for a new one.
With an unconfirmed diagnosis?
Not gonna happen. FOREMAN:
How about a family member?
I don't think the husband's
the right blood type.
Even if he was, he's not
going to give his liver now.
He left her, I assume?
Not yet.
He says he won't abandon
her while she's sick.
She have any other
family members?
No one's going to risk
their life to save hers.
Man, one false accusation
from a psychopath,
and you turn out to
be a real bummer.
I'm gonna go see if
Wilson has any liver left.
What are you doing?
Paying Wibberly's
mortgage for a few months.
Congratulations on another
successful round of hectoring.
Wait a minute. Is that
actually a check for him?
No, it's a giant novelty
item for winning the lottery,
you're just standing
really far away.
Of all the people to go the
extra mile for, why this guy?
I don't know, he just kind of
smells good and makes me laugh.
Why not Cuddy? You never
apologized after you defaced her photo.
Maybe because I recognize that
sending someone to the poorhouse
is a little more serious
than editing a snapshot.
No, it's because Cuddy
actually means something to you,
which makes it much
harder to apologize.
If it'll make you shut up, I will
tell her I'm sorry about the photo.
Forget the photo. House,
she was in love with you.
And all she got in
return was abuse.
For years, you toyed
with her emotions.
She wasn't in love with me.
The fact that you still can't
admit it just proves my point.
What do you want? Helping
the guy was your idea.
No, help the guy, whatever.
I'm just pointing out that it's
much easier to soothe your guilt
by throwing money at a stranger
than by making amends to a
person you actually care about.
You had me at "much easier."
I'm going to pretend
to go to work now.
Ping.
Sarah?
I'm Dr. Hadley. I'm
sorry to bother you,
but I was told that
you're Valerie's sister.
Mmm.
I was just surprised
you came to visit.
So is the rest of my family.
I was even more surprised
you got tested as a donor.
Wrong blood type.
But why? I mean, you
know what she's like.
She's not that bad.
Yes. She is.
Our dad was a mean drunk.
I was the older sister.
I was supposed to stand up
for her, not the other way around.
She protected you
when you were kids?
Yeah. And then all of
a sudden, all of his crap
and all his abuse,
it just changed her.
It made her cold.
When?
We were wrong.
Psychopathy is a symptom.
I spoke to her sister.
She wasn't always like this.
She changed, and right
around adolescence.
So, liver, heart, brain lie
dormant, and it starts at puberty.
The raw food diet made it go
fulminant. Nuts are high in copper.
It's Wilson's disease.
We ruled that out. No
Keyser-Fleischer rings.
There is one other sign. I
know there are lipstick lesbians.
Are there
nail-polish-remover bisexuals?
She's not supposed to be here.
As a doctor.
You didn't say anything about her
capacity as a beautician's assistant.
Her fingernail's blue?
Yep.
Start her on chelation.
What just happened?
You're gonna get better.
Your body has an
inability to process copper.
It caused all of your problems.
Even what's wrong
with your brain.
That's going to change, too?
It's probably rewired her
neurons permanently by now.
But it's possible?
Maybe.
I have to go get the
chelation equipment.
Bill, I need you to
sign some forms.
You don't see what she's doing?
She's laying the groundwork
to get her treatment,
wake up a completely
different person
so that you and all of
your money stay with her.
It's a lie.
You said there was a chance.
Okay, there's a teeny chance.
But even if it cures her, it's
not going to make her love you.
I was happy before.
I know, and I'm
sorry, but it wasn't real.
It felt real.
I don't know...
Maybe that can be enough.
You're really doing this for me?
Tax shelter.
I'll take some
of that chili now.
I can't accept this.
Fine, forget the chili.
Bye, Wibberly.
I got an A plus with your paper.
I was an orthopedic surgeon
for 10 years at New York Mercy.
I had a gambling problem.
I tried to cover it by overbilling
some Medicare patients.
Lost my license.
That's why I'm here.
Not because of you.
Why are you telling me this now?
Because I thought you'd
be the same bastard
you were in med school, but...
Keep it.
No. I can get another place.
Just take it. I
screwed you over.
You got me an A plus.
Take it. No.
Do I have to shove it down your
throat? Take the damn check!
Your vitals are up.
Treatment's working.
I'm not sure we
can fix your liver,
but we can definitely
list you for a new one.
When you're better, we're
gonna take a long vacation.
You want to go to Vietnam,
one of the beaches?
We're gonna get a hut, just you
and me, nothing to worry about.
You're pathetic.
What?
I mean, when you had a
suspicion, fine, but you know now.
How can you be this pitiful?
You don't mean
this. You're sick.
I'm not sick.
I almost died,
and I still might.
And who knows, maybe
it's focusing my mind
because the idea of spending
the rest of my life with you...
Valerie...
Why'd you do that?
Because he's pathetic.
He hasn't changed.
But you have. The treatment
actually worked on your brain.
If you were still a psychopath,
you would have just
kept draining him dry.
What do you want?
You're feeling something.
What is it? What do you feel?
I don't know.
It hurts.
It will.
Heard about the
diagnosis. Nice job.
Thanks. Why are
you here so late?
Discharge summary. Taub's
handwriting isn't helping much.
Apparently on the
third day of admission,
the patient underwent
"rabbit thumping."
"Radiotherapy."
Ah.
"Third day after admission,
"patient underwent radiotherapy
"including external
beam radiation
"to treat B-cell lymphomas.
"First treatment was
"full-mantle therapy..."