Remember how I told you my
parents drop in unannounced?
Mm.
I just got a text. They
are coming here tomorrow.
- Okay.
- It's not okay, it's an ambush.
My parents don't
visit, they judge.
They hate everyone I date, which
means they're going to ask you
a ton of awkward questions.
It's going to be uncomfortable.
Very.
Okay.
You hate surprises. Why
aren't you thrown by this?
Because it's not a surprise.
They're behaving
exactly the way you said.
So a disaster is fine as long
as it's a predictable disaster?
A disaster implies consequences.
We're adults.
Why would it matter
what your parents think?
I don't know, because
they're parents.
Doesn't it bother you that your
grumpy second dad Glassman
still doesn't like me?
Dr. Glassman likes you.
No, he doesn't.
I have to go.
Fine, but I'm going to text
you some talking points.
Mostly subjects to avoid.
And it's gonna
be a very long list.
- How long has she had this wound?
- Uh...
She fell off the vault
two months ago.
Slow healing and signs of oral
bruising. Are you on a restricted diet?
Coach put me on a performance
diet. High protein, fiber...
I can show you her
training log. It's standard.
Although the noodles she likes
did a number on my stomach too.
- What noodles?
- Konjac. Girls on the squad eat them.
Konjac noodles were banned
in Australia several years ago.
They're dangerous,
basically indigestible.
We will get another
doctor to do a workup.
We need to get Darya
to Imaging right away.
I review my schedule starting
with the last appointment
and working backwards.
It's an effective technique.
You might wanna write this down.
Uncle Marcus, we had a
deal. No special attention.
That deal's off. Livy,
you're struggling.
I can't sit on the
sidelines anymore.
But special treatment from
my uncle will make things worse.
I owe it to you, and I
owe it to this hospital.
I know you have unique talent.
So you've noticed both that I'm
screwing up and that I have unique talent?
I noticed the talent long
before you started here.
Aunt Tilly's annual barbeque?
You gave this to
me when you were 5,
and at that moment, I
knew you were special.
Huh. Giant mass of fiber
blocking entry to her intestines.
Her blood tests also show low
calcium and other nutritional deficiencies.
Can I see the 3D
reconstructed images?
It's unlikely to
pass on its own.
We'll have to break it up
and remove it endoscopically.
She also needs
to quit gymnastics.
She has severe osteoporosis
with compression fractures
in almost all of the
thoracic vertebrae.
- Hmm.
- Interesting.
She is a 14-year-old girl with the
bone density of an 80-year-old woman.
You have kyphoscoliosis caused
by insufficient diet and overtraining.
We need to surgically
stabilize across the deformity
to prevent the spine
from failure and paralysis.
Spinal fusion,
that means that she
can't compete, right?
Yes.
The games are less than
a year away. Could we wait
until after to have the surgery?
If left untreated, there's
a 20 percent chance
of progression, which could lead
to respiratory failure and death.
It's your call.
I take risks every day.
I'm not giving up my dream.
You're 14. It's not your call.
Her mother passed away
when she was a baby.
And my father just
told you it's my decision.
Coach is my dad.
Do what you need to
do to clear the blockage.
But...
leave her spine alone.
She wants to risk
her life for a trophy
and her dad is okay with that.
I mean, that has to
be some form of abuse.
This hospital is not going to win
a lawsuit against a caring father
who supports his
daughter's dreams.
All you can do is pull him
aside and try to convince him
to be responsible.
Yeah. Convincing
people to be responsible
has not been my
strong suit lately.
We're not still talking
about Coach Dad, are we?
- You've been avoiding me.
- I've been busy.
Recovering from a motorcycle
accident that you lied about?
There's nothing to tell. I
hit a patch of wet pavement.
No, Audrey.
You have PTSD.
I'm dealing with it.
I don't think you are.
Well, I also have a truckload
of other things to deal with,
including the annual surgical
fundraiser Glassman dumped in my lap.
Yeah, parties,
they're important.
I am dealing with it.
Okay.
How long have you had
the severe heartburn?
Uh, six months, maybe a year.
BP is 142 over 90.
That's a little high.
Yeah, well, Darya
and I travel a lot
for competition. I don't
take care of myself.
Prioritizing your work
over health is bad.
For you and your daughter.
Thank you. But may
I kindly remind you:
How long are the shifts
that you doctors work?
High stress, no sleep.
When something is important,
you give it all you've got.
True. But we're
adults. Darya's not.
Yeah. But she's very different
from other girls her age.
I mean, Darya, she
works her butt off.
She's earned my respect.
You okay?
I'm feeling some
kind of chest pain.
His oxygen sat and
pressure's dropping.
Possible MI, lung
problem, or aortic aneurysm.
Secure his airway.
Poor perfusion. I
think he's septic.
Vitals aren't improving.
It might be a spontaneous
pneumothorax and trapped air in his chest.
No, his chest would sound like a
kettle drum. There's fluid in there.
Give me a blade, curved
clamp and a chest tube.
Boerhaave Syndrome
is easily misdiagnosed.
Nice catch with the
percussion technique.
You may have
saved this man's life.
Give me more retraction,
the tissue planes are terrible.
We're going to have to
debride the mediastinum.
And there's too much
damage to repair the esophagus
without risking
a chronic fistula.
The ongoing leakage into
his chest means it would be
a matter of time before
he dies from an infection.
The safest approach would be to
permanently divert the esophagus.
He'd eat through a tube the rest of
his life, but I don't see a better option.
In 24 hours, with
broad-spectrum antibiotics
and drains, the
infection could clear
and give us more options...
which buys everyone time to
come up with another brilliant win.
Does she really call
her own father "Coach"?
He is her coach. What
do you call your father?
Abba.
Pass.
Frank.
That's his name.
Do you respect any traditions?
Not random ones. Why
should we create labels
for things that
already have names?
It's not just what
Darya calls her dad,
it's how they act with each
other. They're like co-workers.
That doesn't sound
bad. If I were meeting
Lea's co-workers tomorrow,
she would be much less anxious.
Family is supposed
to make you anxious.
Introducing a new boyfriend
to your parents, it's a big deal,
it's a rite of passage.
Polymorphic
ventricular arrhythmia.
Torsade de Pointes.
We need magnesium
sulfate, 2 grams IV.
Heart rate's 170.
She's not responding.
Move in the defibrillator.
- Charged to 100 joules.
- Clear.
Did we do something wrong?
No, which is puzzling.
Mistakes by first-year
residents are expected,
but cardiac arrhythmia in a
14-year-old is definitely unexpected.
I was going to ask if you wanted
a ride, but if you're working late...
Twenty hours to figure this
out. Sure you wanna waste
one of them driving
home and back?
I think while I drive.
Not as well. Not in
the car. Not at home.
Too comfortable,
too many distractions.
Better to buckle down here,
where your colleagues can see you.
I was under the impression
results are more important
than how a doctor is perceived.
Jordan is running rings
around you there too.
Results don't matter if you
can't make people listen.
Is that why you didn't want to
perform the esophageal diversion?
You didn't hear me?
I made a decision for
the good of the patient.
Now it's up to you
to prove me right.
She has a prolonged QT
interval and sporadic extra beats.
I'm going to get the newbies
to recheck the renal panel
and order endocrine
and genetic studies.
I already did. Also a
tox and drug screen.
Are you okay?
Mm.
Lea's scared.
Then I should prepare myself.
There is definitely something
about me her parents won't like.
No, Shaun, you are who you are.
Who you are is great.
You've been preparing
for this your entire life.
When you do something important
for the first time, like surgery,
you practice.
I should practice
meeting her parents.
How? It's not like there's
a simulator for learning
how to navigate awkward
social interactions.
There is.
But I need pizza.
Shaun, I'd like you to meet
my parents, Pam and Mike.
Hi, Pam.
Hi, Mike.
Lea tells us you're a
doctor. What specialty?
I am a surgeon.
What a shame. I hear surgeons
are arrogant and overrated.
Okay. Morgan, I'm sorry but
can you give it a rest for a second?
I'm in character.
Address me as Pam.
I read recently that
while you're sleeping,
you accidentally eat
eight spiders every year.
Yes.
And I read that sometimes
they lay eggs in your stomach.
And then you can have
thousands of spiders...
Shaun...
You said not to disagree when he
says something wrong and pointless.
I didn't tell you to agree.
That only gives him more
wrong and pointless things.
Good.
That's helpful.
Let's continue.
Did you know Arizona doesn't
have Daylight Savings Time?
Saving.
It's "saving," not "savings,"
that's grammatic...
Well, how am I supposed to know
what is pointless? Facts are facts.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
This isn't gonna work.
We could spend the rest of the evening
teaching Shaun the fine but trivial art
of how to finesse trivia.
But the real problem isn't
gonna be small talk and bickering.
The problem is what happens
when Lea's parents express
real concerns
about their daughter.
What concerns?
Concerns any parent would have.
You barely know each other.
Haven't been dating long,
now you're living together. This
relationship is moving too fast.
You're wrong.
I thought you said we
shouldn't argue with your dad.
That wasn't my dad, that
was 100 percent Glassy.
You can't prepare for how
these evenings can go wrong.
Families are full of surprises.
Like how you don't like Lea.
I never actually said that.
Wow, a first-year all-nighter.
Brings back memories.
Not of myself, but of
the losers who thought
staying up all night drooling on their
laptops made them better doctors.
So, cure cancer yet?
I'm trying to find a new way
to repair a ruptured esophagus.
"Fundic reinforcement
with intercostal muscle flap."
Cutting-edge stuff. Why not
go with diversion? It's safer.
Because safe is
ordinary and boring.
Like me.
My uncle thinks I need a win.
And the only way to do that is
to be impressive, like Jordan.
Makes sense.
You agree?
That Dr. Allen is impressive?
Yeah. Everybody knows that
because Dr. Allen makes
sure everybody knows that.
She and your uncle are cut from
the same fashionably high-end cloth.
So I don't just need to be a better
doctor, I need to be a different person.
Wow.
You might wanna start by being a
person who feels less sorry for themselves.
Either you are an
awkward, inconsistent loner
who's irritatingly apologetic
about your best qualities,
or you're a quietly brilliant surgeon
whom others ignore at their own peril.
If you're the first one, quit
now and stop wasting resources.
But if you're the
second, be that.
Maybe a little louder.
Where should we start?
Centerpieces?
Appetizers? Color schemes?
Please tell me you're at a
hotel in the middle of the day
because you're having an affair.
There were no surgeries scheduled,
so I decided to volunteer to help.
How helpful.
Mm. We can get the job done in
half the time and still have time to talk.
Or we can just talk.
I am not a 14-year-old
girl whose next backflip
could kill her, Claire.
I don't need saving.
What do you think
about twinkle lights?
Too prom?
Tests show your heart problems
are caused by
excess estrogen levels.
And we wanna know
how it got in your system.
Medication? A supplement?
Coach gave you my training
logs. You know as much as I do.
We also know that you're
in a very competitive sport.
So maybe there's something
you're taking not on the log.
If you are, we can't
divulge that to anyone.
You think I'm doping?
No way.
- If your coach is pressuring you...
- He's not.
I'm sure it's a one-time thing.
Keep monitoring
me. I'll be fine.
Darya, you've made your dreams
come true by being stubborn.
Being relentless. And
just making things happen.
But that's not how your
heart works. Or your spine.
She's not being stubborn.
It is going to
go away, isn't it?
Because you are
taking something.
And now you're going to stop.
Which means it wasn't
performance enhancing.
What is it for?
You took drugs for boobs?
The girl on YouTube said
it would make them bigger.
Phytoestrogens used in herbal
remedies can cause swelling
in breast tissue, but there are
potentially dangerous side effects.
- What were you thinking?
- I didn't know it would make me sick.
I got tired of hearing the boys
talking about women with curves...
What if it showed
up on a drug test?
What if you got banned
from the Olympics?
It's natural, it doesn't mess
with performance, other girls...
I don't care about other girls.
And I didn't think you cared
about other girls. Are you...
I can't believe that you're
willing to risk everything...
for something so...
childish.
It's not childish.
I give a lot to my sport.
I just wanted something for me.
You're not an adult.
Hmm.
Fix her heart... and her spine.
Wha... What? You can't do that.
- Are you punishing me?
- I'm doing my job.
I'm your father,
and we're family,
and it is my job to make
good decisions when you won't.
Since when is being
my father your job?
We never do anything but talk
about gymnastics, not even Mom.
If you didn't think I needed my
father after she died, why start now?
Darya.
I'm calling the team lawyer
and filing for emancipation.
You think I can't make my
own decisions? Try this one.
You're fired, Coach.
We could try T-tubes. Using them
forms a controlled fistula
and route for drainage.
But the patient would still have a
long recovery and chance of reinfection.
- What else?
- I found
very interesting research on
endoscopic vacuum therapy.
It's under investigation for the
management of esophageal leaks.
Definitely innovative,
Dr. Allen, but a little too much so.
This hasn't gone through clinical trials,
and we need to perform surgery today.
Dr. Jackson, you've been quiet.
I was thinking
fundic reinforcement.
My idea is to use a
patient's own good tissue
to reinforce a primary closure,
in this case using the stomach
as the patch.
Like the way we use a skin
graft for third-degree burns.
He'd be at risk of a
diaphragmatic hernia.
Not if we cinch up the lower
esophageal sphincter with a fundoplasty.
Shaun, Lea tells us you're a
doctor. What's your specialty?
I am a surgeon. But
we're not all arrogant.
Though many of us are. I'm
still not sure if that's good or bad.
Is it hard for you?
I mean, it's a difficult job.
Shaun is excellent at his job.
- So how do you feel about vaccines?
- Oh, my God.
Because, um, they worry me.
They don't worry me.
- Oh.
- Really? We've read a lot of stuff.
Especially since
Lea told us about you.
Vaccines don't
cause autism, Mom.
Want to talk about religion now?
Lea, that was on the list
of things not to talk about.
- Mm.
- Lea wrote you a list?
- Dad.
- Well...
Honestly, Lea, if we're so impossible
to talk to, why even have us here?
Hemorrhoid surgery.
- Excuse me?
- Want more wine?
I removed a hemorrhoid from
a patient with terminal cancer.
He only had a few months to
live, and nothing would change that.
But the surgery did make
him more comfortable.
I suggest we treat this
evening like hemorrhoid surgery.
No, that's... That's
a good point.
You don't have to give him any
more lists. Let him talk. I like this guy.
Okay.
To hemorrhoid surgery.
♪ Everybody's feeling
warm and bright ♪
♪ It's such a fine
and natural sight ♪
I went.
I went to see a psychiatrist.
- I'm... I'm so relieved to hear that...
- Well, once.
The doctor said my symptoms
warranted medication,
so I haven't been back since.
Why? If you need medication...
Why did you keep
your PTSD a secret?
You chose to deal with
your issues privately,
on your own terms.
Why am I not entitled
to the same choice?
Doing something...
self-destructive is not
a choice, it's a mistake.
- Just like it was when I did it.
- So...
when I do something
you agree with, it's great.
I do something you disagree
with, it's because I'm sick.
- No.
- This is why I don't want to talk to you,
because it's not a
conversation, it's a lecture.
Audrey.
Please, Claire. Let me go.
No.
I just want to go
home. I'll be fine.
Let me give you a ride. You
can't drive like this. Come on.
I said I'm fine.
No, you're not.
There. Now no one's
driving home. You happy?
♪ Celebrate good times... ♪
The two main challenges
of Boerhaave Syndrome
are timely diagnosis,
followed by viability of repair.
With this innovative
surgical approach...
I think we might achieve both.
I need silk ties and Ligasure.
His chest infection leaked through the
diaphragm into the intraperitoneal space.
There's an abscess
behind the stomach.
It's making the entire
posterior stomach friable.
Let's use an intercostal muscle
flap to patch the esophagus instead.
If we do, it raises
the risk of sepsis.
The patient signed
off, we should try.
Not this level of risk. We
need to do the diversion.
Your idea was good,
don't give up on it.
Reverting to diversion
doesn't mean failure.
I searched "eating meat
near me," which was a mistake,
but I did get a recommendation for
a steak house your father might like.
You don't have to be nice
to my parents anymore.
- We won't be seeing them again.
- Why not?
"We need to talk about Shaun."
Mm.
They don't think I'm mature enough
to be in a challenging relationship.
Leave it to my mom, she
took us both out in one shot.
You do get that this is
insulting, to both of us?
From the people who supposedly
love me most in the world.
They don't.
Not the most.
Not anymore.
Lea.
People who meet me
are usually uncomfortable.
And most of the time,
that doesn't go away.
How do you handle that?
I try to be patient.
Sometimes it works.
Maybe you're a more
mature person than I am.
But I'm not sure if that
is going to work for me.
- Have you see Dr. Lim this morning?
- Uh, no. Why?
- Darya's lawyer called.
- I need Dr. Lim.
Dr. Lim's not here, I
don't know if she'll be in.
If it's an emergency,
maybe Dr. Glassman...
Dr. Glassman's in meetings
this morning. Who needs me?
Darya's lawyer is demanding
the hospital release her client.
We're not releasing our patient
until she's healthy unless
we receive a court order.
What's your problem?
Dr. Andrews
encountered complications.
He asked me to inform
you the surgical plan
needs to change
without consent...
That's Andrews' call. I
don't need details, just coffee.
I changed my mind,
I need the details.
Stay here.
Long, painful recovery with a
feeding tube, or risk of death.
As his next of
kin, it's your call.
I have to decide?
You made a life-or-death
choice for yourself.
In fact, you insisted on it.
The doctors were asking me
to give up something I wanted.
Difference is your father
is on an operating table
waiting for you to grow up.
If something bad
happened, I'd be responsible.
Yes.
That's the definition
of adulthood.
I don't know what to do.
Of course you don't.
It's an impossible choice.
Terrible things
happen either way.
And yeah, it's on you.
I can't do it.
I just can't.
You're not a grown-up, Darya.
Luckily.
So those of us who are will make
the impossible decision for you.
Dr. Andrews will
do the diversion.
Someone will bring you to see
your father when he's out of surgery.
What was that?
I saved that girl
when you couldn't.
Yesterday, you told me
to respect her decision.
Today, you tortured her
into changing her mind.
Oh, did I make
a little girl cry?
I can't do this. I'm
done trying to help you.
Please. You're
never really done.
You know who
you were last night?
My mom. Drunk. Angry.
Refusing to lift a finger to
help herself, lying about it,
and taking your pain out on me.
That's going to keep
happening until you get help.
Take the medication,
talk to someone.
Do something.
Please.
I'm not your mother, Claire.
I'm not your responsibility.
I'm your boss. And I
don't owe you anything.
Shaun? What are you doing here?
You're wrong about me and Lea.
Oh. Well, no offense, Shaun,
but this is between family.
Lea is my girlfriend.
And the texts you
sent were about us.
We're sorry you saw those.
Shaun, you're a very nice young man,
and we enjoyed meeting you.
It's just...
We've known Lea a lot longer.
Yeah, she's, um...
Well, she has a good heart,
she just doesn't think ahead.
She will do anything
to get under our skin.
You wouldn't believe some
of the people she's dated.
I'm different than
anyone she's ever dated.
How is that not a change?
That's true, Shaun. I'm
just not sure it's a good thing.
You knew her then.
You don't know her now.
All you know are her
mistakes. And you don't trust her
because you aren't sure
you were good parents.
You said our relationship
has challenges.
You're right.
Lea and I go through
challenges together.
It's one of the things
that makes us stronger.
Lea challenges me to try things,
even things I know I won't like,
because it is not always better
to stop and think.
And I make Lea patient,
because I can
be very frustrating.
So can the two of you.
Maybe this challenge will make
your relationship stronger too.
If you really think I should
have the spinal surgery...
I trust you.
I do.
I'm sorry.
Ever since your mother died...
I've been scared.
What did I know about
raising a little girl by myself?
And you... You were a handful.
Bouncing off the walls,
backflips off the furniture...
You couldn't get me
to the gym fast enough.
Because when you
are on the beam...
or flipping through the air...
you're not just a little girl.
You are an amazing athlete.
As your coach, you
make me feel amazing too.
All this time, I thought
I was giving you
exactly what you needed.
But I was wrong.
What you needed was
for me to be your dad.
And what your dad
would have told you:
That no matter how you look...
or what you achieve...
you will always be a beautiful,
strong superstar to me.
- Thanks, Dad.
- Yeah.
Thank you.
I like you, okay?
Stop. You're gonna make me cry.
You're a very cynical
person, you know that?
Actually, I'm not, but
you're a very grouchy person
who cannot give a compliment.
You're funny, you're smart,
and you make Shaun happy.
Which I guess is a good
thing, but it also means
you can also make him very, very
sad, and that worries me, frankly.
I am not planning
on hurting Shaun.
It's rarely intentional,
you know?
My parents have
an issue with Shaun.
And I just don't
want Shaun's parent
to have a problem with us too.
Too bad.
Everything Shaun
has gone through...
all the rejection
and the pain...
the victories, they
all belong to him.
But I feel every single
high and every single low.
So I'm sorry, I'm...
I'm not gonna stop worrying about
him, even if he doesn't need me to.
Well, if Shaun saw
that stain on your tie,
it would drive him crazy.
Hey, Liv.
I'm sorry we didn't get
to perform the surgery,
but I'm really proud of
the way you stepped up.
That surgery wasn't mine.
Of course it was,
and it was brilliant.
And neither was the stone.
That story you told me about
how you spotted my talent?
I don't remember any of it.
I didn't paint that rock,
and if I handed it to you,
it didn't mean anything,
because I was 5.
You've been carrying around
a memory for over 20 years
that represents
your dream, not mine.
Clearly that's not entirely true.
You went to medical school.
Because I do want
to be a great doctor.
I wanted it so bad
that I let you push me
to think up some flashy
surgery, even when my instincts
already told me to do what
I thought was the right thing,
and was the right thing.
- I want you to be the best...
- You want me to be Jordan.
If you're looking to mold someone
in your image, she's perfect.
But, Uncle Marcus,
I've got to be me.
And you can't help me do that.
Hey.
I'm still gonna brag on you like a
proud uncle. You know that, right?
Dr. Jackson.
- It's your parents.
- Yep, Shaun. I saw.
They probably want
something. We should prepare.
Either they want to
yell at us, in which case
we should not answer the
door, or take us to dinner,
but we are already
halfway through...
They want to take us to dinner.
Should I open the door?
What do you think?
I think...
they must have
been good parents.
We should have dinner with them.
Do you want to text them back?
Last year, after my mom died,
I was going through some
problems, emotionally.
I was diagnosed with PTSD.
I see.
Melendez knew.
Um, Morgan found out
because she's Morgan.
But I didn't tell anyone else.
I didn't want anyone to know.
Why are you telling me this now?
Because...
Lim is going through something
like it, but maybe worse.
She isn't going to therapy, she
has refused medications, she...
Okay.
I don't think you
should be telling me this.
Whatever Lim told you,
she told you in confidence
and as a friend.
But she's not just a
friend. She's my boss.
And you're her boss.
So I'm telling you because
I have no place else to turn.
She won't let me help
because she says it's not my job,
and she's right.
But it's your job to
protect the hospital.
And her.
So...