The form asks
for an employer.
I'm retired,
so... Should I just
leave it blank?
Sure, they'll figure it out.
Hey, Emily.
Hey!
How's the first day going?
I've helped four people
with the vending machine,
three with directions
to the cafeteria.
Closing in on 2,000 steps
carrying paperwork.
Oh, and I'm wearing
a triple-XL vest,
because the one in my size
has barf on it.
I wish I could say
the waiting room
gets more glamorous,
but it doesn't.
Yeah.
She's gonna quit.
You don't know that.
Volunteering could be
huge for Emily.
Responsibility, purpose.
I'm just worried
she won't see it through.
Give her a chance.
Remember those tickets
we bought for The Revivalists?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, it's next weekend.
Well, you go. Take Jay.
I'm not going on a date
with my brother.
Don't you want them?
I promised Owen
I'd take him to Navy Pier.
You use 'em.
Faster scan rates,
a greater resolution,
a host of diagnostic
improvements
in cardiac calcium scoring,
TAVR planning.
I get it, okay?
The... The ED would put
a new CT scanner to good use,
but the machine alone's
upwards of $2 million.
Okay, then there's
maintenance.
You got tech support...
And higher patient throughput,
which is increased
revenue, Peter. Come on.
I'd go to the board myself,
but considering my stock
these days,
it'll sound better
coming from you.
Well, so much for
a free cup of coffee, huh?
I need help over here!
What the hell?
We just piled
them in and drove.
I need a doctor!
What is going on?
Some lunatic opened fire
with an automatic rifle
at Millenium Park.
How many victims?
A lot.
Clear every treatment room
and trauma bay.
Patients go to
the waiting room.
We need more space
on the floor.
Chairs, COWS, carts,
pile everything
in the consultation room.
Lock down the
walk-in entrance.
From now on,
all patients funnel through
the ambulance bay.
Maggie, trigger an
All Hazards Disaster Plan.
Every doctor, nurse, and tech
on call gets in here now.
Already on it.
How many victims
can we handle?
Sixteen yellow tags,
four, maybe five red tags.
We're gonna have
more than that.
You're going to Trauma 1.
Deb?
She's pouring blood
everywhere.
Prep a chest tray
for an ED thoracotomy.
No, no, no,
Mass Casualty protocol.
No chance of recovery,
no resuscitation.
Save the living, Dr. Sexton.
Doris, move her out.
Dr. Choi, April, Baghdad.
On it.
Go, go, go.
All right, weak pulse,
not breathing.
One, two, three, four holes,
face, neck, chest.
Belly's hard as a rock.
He's bleeding
into his abdomen.
Okay, we'll deal with that
after we get him an airway.
Intubation kit?
Yes, Doctor.
Half his face is gone.
No chance I get a tube in.
He needs a crich.
Here we go!
They're coming in!
Noah, you're going
to Treatment 1.
Dr. Reese,
you're going to Treatment Two.
There you go, sir.
Dr. Charles?
Yeah, Maggie?
You're going
to Treatment 3.
Okay, file in down the line.
You're going to 4,
you're going to 5...
There you go...
And you're going to 6.
There you go.
Be careful. Rotate.
Rotate here.
FAST scan.
I can't get the tube in.
Too much blood
in the airway. Suction.
Blood in the pelvis.
Two more units of O-neg
on the rapid transfuser.
Block party today
at Millennium Park.
Saturday plus tourists.
Gotta be a few thousand people
down there.
Owen's nanny sometimes
brings him down there
to ride his scooter.
I don't know
if they went today.
I'm sure
they're fine, Natalie.
Yeah, that's what I keep
telling myself.
Okay, I'm in. Bag him.
Maggie?
Yeah?
I don't know if Owen and his
nanny went to the park today.
Can you...
I have her number.
I'll call her. Okay.
Thank you.
Oh, my God.
Where do we begin?
Maggie?
Yeah?
We need to prioritize
surgical candidates.
Where are they?
Everywhere.
Connor, I need you.
All right, start in
the treatment rooms.
I'll meet you
on the other side.
Sinus tach.
Pressure dropping.
Trach tube.
All set up.
He's crashing.
Asystole. I'm on his chest.
No compressions.
We can't save him.
Dr. Choi, I'm losing
her pulse.
She's apneic.
Okay, time of death, 14:38.
Him out, her in.
April, Stohl needs you
in Triage.
Come on, come on, let's go.
Go.
Doris, can you move him?
Morgue's full.
Okay, then just find
a place up here.
Bag her.
Two IVs? What's that mean?
Is it bad?
No, no, no,
it's just a move now
to save time later
if there is an emergency.
Emergency?
But I have a yellow tag.
That means stable, right?
Red's the bad one and black...
No, no, no, it's just
a preemptive measure.
That's all.
The shots,
they just kept coming.
I... I ran,
but I got knocked down
and I couldn't get up.
I can't imagine.
I... I'm so sorry.
All around me,
people were just being...
Torn apart.
This blood is not mine!
Shh. Okay.
Shh. Look at me.
Look at me.
Slow, deep breaths, okay?
Like this. Loo... Look...
Dr. Charles,
she's reliving the moment.
No! No! Who are you?
Hey, here, take my hand.
Okay, it's okay.
Look at me, look at me,
look at me, look at me.
Look at my hands.
You see me holding your hands?
You feel me
holding your hands?
You're safe.
You're in a hospital.
You're here with me.
We're gonna take care of ya,
all right?
I'm Dr. Charles.
Can you tell me your name?
Uh, Jill.
Okay, Jill.
We got this, okay?
Okay.
It'll be all right.
...appears to be
a mass shooting in Chicago...
Water?
Uh, would you like a water?
Oh, my God.
Uh, help? Help!
Uh, he... He just
looked at me
and slumped.
Okay, he's breathing.
Weak carotid pulse.
Nothing radial.
I need a gurney!
Help me elevate his legs.
Emily?
Uh...
What happened?
BP dropped too low.
He passed out.
Sometimes a fracture can
trigger a sudden dip.
There could be a broken bone
beneath the swelling.
What's going on?
You passed out.
Sorry.
I'm gonna get you
on some IV fluids
and send you in for an X-ray
of your right arm.
Feels busted.
Good thing I'm a lefty.
Sorry.
I shouldn't joke right now.
It's just... This is a lot.
It's okay.
I get it. Don't feel bad.
This is madness.
Dr. Stohl,
we've got incoming.
Yes. How many?
Twenty-five,
at least 10 critical.
That's too many.
We're already swamped.
They need to be rerouted
to East Mercy
or Lakeshore Memorial.
They can't.
They're choked up too.
They're trying to send
patients to us.
So let's get Maggie
to double up patients
into treatment rooms
and trauma bays.
Remove the dividing walls
to make the space.
April, with me, we need
to help unload these ambos.
Two per room?
That's not gonna do it.
No, not even close.
Hey, Maggie,
where do you want us?
Treatment room,
wherever you can fit.
Copy.
Maggie?
Follow Noah and make space.
Mmm-hmm.
No, no, no, no, no,
I gotta stagger the intake.
Find a trauma bay.
They're all jammed.
Well, elevator hallway?
Did you get to Liz?
No, voicemail.
Please keep trying.
Yeah.
Two hemostats
and 10 ml of lidocaine.
We're out of lidocaine.
Waiting on resupply.
50 mics of fentanyl instead?
25.
He's gonna need a neuroexam.
Can't dope him up.
All right, squeeze my hand.
Come on, it's only
gonna take a second.
Okay, keep squeezing.
We're almost there.
Done.
What do you got?
Lacerated right carotid.
Bleeding's under control
for now.
What's his pressure?
Low but holding. 89 over 50.
All right, up his volume.
I'll get him in the OR
as soon as I can.
He can't wait.
Connor, I clamped off
blood flow to his brain.
He sits too long...
He hasn't stroked.
That means he's got adequate
flow on the other side.
He can wait.
Dr. Rhodes, I need you in
3, 4, 6 and 7.
Who's first?
Ava and I are running
all over the place.
We get to one patient, three
more pile up somewhere else.
This isn't working.
Oh, heads up,
next wave five minutes out.
Ms. Goodwin,
we're stabilizing patients,
but if we can't get them
to surgery,
we'll start losing them.
Unless something changes,
the ED's gonna collapse.
Well, if you have an idea,
now is the time.
Casualty collection areas.
Designated zones for
specific treatments,
especially surgical eval.
Doctors stay put,
patients shuttle
between zones.
An assembly line?
All right,
you set it up in Triage,
I'll spread the word.
Yes, ma'am.
I saw the shooter.
I should've run at him,
tackled him,
done something,
but instead,
I just stood there,
like a coward,
while he mowed people down.
Have you heard of
fight-or-flight?
Before that is the freeze.
It's an instinct that kicks in
when there's no time to think.
Not running at that shooter
might've saved
your life, okay?
Can you tell me your name?
Sir, do you know
where you are?
Wow, you were, uh...
You were right there, huh?
Dr. Charles, uh, Dr. Reese...
Paramedics are bringing in
personal belongings
from the scene.
Uh, what should I do
with them?
Oh, this is awful.
Uh... Uh, people are gonna
wanna go through those,
so, um, we should put it
on display.
There's at least
three dozen boxes already,
and they said
there's more coming.
Um... Use the cafeteria.
Dr. Reese, can you oversee?
People are gonna be,
you know, overwhelmed and...
Yeah, got it.
Uh... Uh, I'm Dr. Charles.
What... What's your name?
Can you tell me your name?
Roger.
Where am I?
You're in a hospital.
You were... You were
involved in a shooting.
I was?
Yeah.
You know, you have
a wound on your head,
and I'd very much like to get
one of the ER doctors
just to take a look at it.
Would that be all right?
Yeah. Okay.
Okay, good.
All right, CTs and X-rays
are in the elevator hallway.
If the line gets long, just
snake it around the corner.
Monique, 1 and 2
are now laceration repair
and hemorrhage control.
You lead.
Dr. Sexton, Trauma 2 is now
strictly for chest tubes.
Once they're in,
move them to Baghdad
for surgical eval.
Okay.
Ms. Goodwin...
Yes?
We're abandoning protocol?
Uh, have to.
Our disaster plan
wasn't designed
for an incident this massive.
But a change on the fly?
That makes me nervous.
Noted.
Uh, Dr. Halstead, you now live
in Treatments 6 and 7.
Nothing but intubations.
Any person with
respiratory compromise
will be coming
straight to you.
Okay, but, uh,
meds are a problem.
It's taking forever for nurses
to run back and forth
pulling etomidate and sux.
All right, I'll override
the fingerprint scan
on the medication dispenser.
Leave the door open,
so nurses can stuff
their pockets.
We'll have no idea
who's getting what.
You mean who's being charged
for what, right?
Let's figure out
billing later.
I need help!
Trample victim. No pulse.
No breath sounds either.
On his chest.
April, quick look
and an intubation kit.
Then start a line to
push meds.
No, triple zero.
Pupils are fixed and dilated.
He's dead.
Where's his family?
I don't know.
Good Samaritan found him
on the ground not moving,
drove him in in his own car.
Dr. Bekker,
Dr. Rhodes is calling you.
If Owen and his nanny
did go to the park today,
what if they got
separated too?
Until you know for sure,
don't let your mind
lead you to a bad place.
Stay focused on right now.
Natalie, need extra hands.
April?
I'll move him.
I need a hand in here!
No! No, no, don't touch me!
I'm sorry, honey,
but I have to.
I'm a doctor, okay?
I promise you I'll be quick.
It hurts. Where's my mom?
We're gonna do our best
to try to find her,
but right now,
I have to help you.
Can I do that?
Thank you.
Bullet wounds
to the left hand,
the left thigh...
Where is she?
Good pulse
in the wrist and feet.
No life-threatening issues.
Four of morphine for the pain,
then bandage her wounds,
send her upstairs.
They can dress her up there.
I'm gonna send you
to another doctor, okay?
Be brave, sweetheart.
Okay.
Hole in the left
anterior chest wall.
Breath sounds present
and bilaterally.
Get him in line
for a chest X-ray.
Yep.
Things moving
smoother in here?
Yeah, bringing patients here
instead of us trying to
find them, it's a great call.
Uh, heavy confusion,
memory loss,
no recollection of
what... What happened today.
He could barely
tell me his name.
But, I mean, I guess
it could be neural.
I'm just thinking shock.
Yeah, him and everyone else,
including me.
We'll stitch that up
when we get a chance.
Oh, my God. What...
Roger...
So, listen, I... I know
it's difficult to make sense
of what's going on
around you right now
and... And what
happened today,
but I can help you put
that puzzle together, okay?
Just keep some pressure
on this right now.
Dr. Charles?
Unconscious when he came in.
GSW nicked the external
jugular vein.
As long as he keeps
pressure on it,
his vitals are stable,
but he refuses to do it.
You keep pressure on that.
I'll be right back, okay?
I got it. How we doing?
You don't have to help me.
Yeah, well, I...
I mean, I kind of do,
'cause if... If somebody
doesn't hold this,
you're gonna die.
I'm okay with that.
Yeah, well, I'm not,
so I guess
you're stuck with me
for the moment anyway.
I'm Dr. Charles.
What's your name?
Uh... Uh, Trevor.
Good pulse and BP,
but diminished breath sounds
on the left.
Chest X-ray.
Hey, man, how are you doing?
I'm fine.
Yeah?
All right, log roll.
Okay, okay. One...
Two holes, left delt,
right upper back.
Chest tube, then CT chest
and thoracic spine.
Keep him on his side.
You're gonna be fine, man.
You're gonna be fine.
Go.
More ambos inbound.
We'll be ready.
Hearing PD hasn't
found the shooter.
If he's still out there...
Yeah... This could get worse.
Dr. Choi,
we need you in Baghdad.
April, take over Triage.
What?
You've seen enough
bullet holes to gauge risk.
Ethan...
Dr. Choi!
April, hey, hey, hey,
eye the wound,
assess trajectory,
predict potential injuries,
then send them
where they need to be.
You got this.
One, two, three.
Heart rate's jumping,
BP's crashing.
There's only a trickle
of blood coming from
the chest tube.
Guy has two holes.
He was stable.
Hemorrhagic shock?
The GSW must've
traversed the liver.
FAST scan.
Two units O-neg
and two of plasma
on the rapid transfuser.
Chest tube must've clotted.
It took a bit,
but now he's coagulopathic.
Yeah, FAST scan's positive.
He's bleeding into
his chest and belly.
We need to replace the tube.
Scissors?
Connor, what's up?
This guy needs surgery,
but the OR is packed.
I need to convert Baghdad
and do it here.
Okay, I got
more victims en route.
You can have half the space.
No, I'm not opening him up
with people running in
and out.
Then take the doctor's lounge.
Four walls and a door,
as quiet as you're gonna get.
Doctor's lounge?
No gas lines, suction lines,
airflow capabilities,
it's short electrical outlets,
lighting?
Come on.
I'll take it.
Excuse us.
I'm sorry it took so long.
The police had
the streets blocked off.
Never mind, unimportant.
Where is Dr. Rhodes?
Operating in
the doctor's lounge.
Yeah, I know.
Dr. Latham,
good, you're here.
We're gonna do a laparotomy.
This is not a surgical suite,
Dr. Rhodes.
Oh, I know,
but I'm afraid
it's all we got.
We'll also need
an electrocautery machine
and an ultrasonic
cavitation device.
There's no
frills today, sorry.
No, no, no!
There can't be any shadows.
Dr. Latham, I know this is
a lot of change all at once,
but this patient is
running out of time.
I can't do the surgery alone.
I really need your help, okay?
Yes. Yes, of course.
I'll scrub in. Where?
Yeah.
All right, Connor,
anything else you need?
Uh-huh, Noah.
Hmm?
For what?
Anesthesia
and airway control.
Uh...
Dr. Rhodes, I... I have,
like, three hours of
surgical experience.
And now you get more.
Bring in the patient.
So, I gotta be honest,
I really feel like
I've been doing a little bit
too much of the talking here.
No way I can
get you to tell me
a little bit about
what happened today?
I thought I had a jacket.
Did I drop it?
You know what? You could've.
Our memory tends to
come back in fragments,
and so time and space
tend to be a little mixed up.
Um...
Hey, Trevor, you think
I can get you to take over
putting pressure
on the wound for me?
My wife, uh...
I lost my wife this morning.
That's awful.
That's really awful.
I'm sorry to hear that.
She was a good person.
I really don't deserve
your help.
You should just, like...
Just let me go.
You know that feeling of...
Of it being unfair,
you know, that your wife
was taken and you weren't?
Maybe even feeling
a little bit guilty
that... That you survived?
Well...
That's... It's just normal
for this horrible thing
you've been through,
and if it's any consolation
at all,
there's probably a lot of
people in this hospital
who are feeling...
The same way right now.
Well, then you should
go be with them,
because you can't help me.
You know what, though, I can.
No, you can't!
I just need you
to meet me halfway
by putting pressure
on your wound.
I just need to go over
and talk to this gentleman
for just a minute,
and I'll be right back.
I, uh...
I collect things...
Uh-huh?
And my wife, she said
that I was a hoarder,
and that...
She was gonna
throw it all out.
God, I would get
so mad, but I...
I was wearing a jacket.
I had it at lunch.
God...
I got this.
You sure?
Yes.
Thank you.
So the officer saw the guy
ditch the assault rifle,
then he got a shot off,
and then he lost him
in the crowd.
And you think now he's here?
Yeah, maybe.
He was wearing a hoodie.
We recovered it at the scene.
Tested positive for
gunshot residue,
and there was blood on it.
So the officer
might've shot him?
Well, that's the theory.
We're thinking either
the paramedics brought him in,
or he's hiding among
the injured, so we're checking
all the hospitals
against the officer's
partial description.
White male, brown hair,
medium height, build,
dark pants.
Do you mind if my guys
just go through the ED?
Please.
All right.
But, uh, we're barely
keeping it together here.
What's happening out there?
People are scared.
The cell network
is probably down from
the boost in traffic, right?
Probably why Maggie
can't get through?
Yeah, I think you're right.
All right, I'm in. Bag him.
Then CT zone
for head and chest.
And then up to the ICU
for neuro. Let's go.
Hey, Jay, uh, my son, Owen,
he and the nanny may have been
at Millennium Park today,
but I can't reach them.
Can you...
Every cop in the city's
looking for the shooter.
I'm so sorry, Nat.
Okay.
Natalie, if you need to
go home...
How can I leave?
20 of etomidate, 100 of sux.
How do you know which parts
of the bowel are viable?
Peristalsis? Color?
Right now, I don't care
about viability. I only care
about the bleeding.
Ooh, this is wild.
Being a trauma surgeon
is intense.
No time to think.
Just react...
Stop talking.
I haven't been inside
an abdomen since my residency.
It's okay, Dr. Latham.
Surgery is surgery.
GIA stapler
for the anastomosis.
Skip it, it takes too long.
But I've already resected
a portion of the bowel.
It needs to be reconstructed.
Just leave it
in discontinuity.
That doesn't make any sense.
We'll have to open him back up
again to make the repair.
No, 'cause we're not
gonna close him.
But he'll be susceptible
to infection.
Dr. Latham,
this is damage control.
Stop the bleeding,
stop the spillage,
move on to the next patient.
Are you good?
Yes.
Let's continue.
Okay.
This is my brother's.
It belongs to my son.
I bought it for him.
Lady, if you don't let go
and back off...
Hey, maybe I can help,
maybe I can help.
Look inside.
You'll find sheet music.
He plays the bass.
May I?
Told you.
I know my son was
at the park today.
If he was okay,
he would've called.
He always calls me.
His name is Jared. He's 16.
Oh, I've seen him. He's here.
Is he all right?
Uh, when I saw him,
he was conscious, talking.
He had a broken arm.
Oh, my God.
I'll find him.
Thank you. Thank you.
Emily?
What do you need?
Emily? Hey, what do you need?
Uh... Uh, there's...
There's a lot of people
bleeding in the waiting room.
The nurse needs help.
But I don't have anyone else.
Wait a second, I got an idea.
Come with me.
Come, come,
come, come!
Caprice?
Yes?
I know you're busy,
but I need some help.
Sir, ma'am,
can I borrow you for a second?
So, we have a lot of injured,
but not enough nurses,
so we need volunteers.
Caprice here is gonna
teach you
how to apply pressure,
hemostatic bandages,
and tourniquets.
Are we all still in?
Em?
Yeah, okay.
Great. Okay.
Got two. Two.
Go be sharks.
Find some blood.
Come with me.
Okay.
Sir, would you like to help?
No.
I will.
Oh, thank you.
There you go.
He's right there. White man,
medium build, dark pants.
Fits the profile.
He was acting kind of sketchy.
He stared right through me.
I see him.
What's going on, Ms. Goodwin?
They think they may have
the shooter.
Chicago Police, sir,
I need to talk to you.
I didn't do anything.
Put the bag down
and show me your hands.
I didn't do anything.
Drop the bag
and show me your hands!
Get up! Get up!
Do not move.
He's a thief.
He looted the bodies.
Opportunist scum.
Detective, I understand
you have a job to do,
but this description
of the shooter,
white male, dark pants,
it's vague.
Ms. Goodwin, if I think
I found the son of a bitch
that did this,
I'm going after him.
ICU for rewarming
and resuscitation.
Okay, bring in the next one.
Dr. Latham, I'm sorry
if I overstepped earlier.
I certainly wasn't
trying to criticize.
No need for an apology,
Dr. Rhodes.
I realize that my rigidness
can be frustrating.
While your tone was unnerving,
your words were enlightening.
They were?
Stop the bleeding,
stop the spillage,
move on to the next patient.
Precisely the structure
I needed.
Well, then
I'm glad I could help.
Okay, let's do this.
He was hit by a car
trying to escape the scene.
Broken ribs, diminished breath
sounds in the left chest.
He needs a tube.
Emily, what are you doing?
Uh, looking for
more bandages, gauze.
I'm helping the nurses
in the waiting room.
While he was waiting
for his X-ray?
Epidural hematoma.
By the time
they got him to me,
he was gone.
There was nothing
I could do.
His mother is here.
Thinks he's all right.
Poor woman.
Am I doing this right?
I think so.
You're good at this.
Blood doesn't bother me.
I can see it.
There was a band.
Every song was an '80s cover.
This woman started
dancing with me.
Uh-huh.
And were you guys
dancing together
when the gunfire broke out?
Uh, Doctor, I...
Yes.
Did you happen
to look and see
what direction the gunfire
was coming from?
Uh, yes.
Doctor, there are so many
people here who are in
worse shape than me.
I really... I should just go.
Well, you... You can't
go yet, Trevor, because
you still need treatment.
You're bleeding
from your neck.
But I just... I need to be
just anywhere else.
I'm... I'm fine.
Okay, okay. Um...
I'll be right back.
Look, what I'm hearing is that
actually you're not fine.
You're trying to convince
yourself you're fine.
I am.
Look, I get it,
but I can also see
how much pain you're in,
and you have
every right to be.
Uh, listen, I don't expect
you to believe me right now,
but I promise you will
get better, but you...
You need to hang in with me
a little bit longer,
okay? Okay?
What you looking at, Roger?
Him.
That guy?
You recognize him?
Yes.
I'm in. Bag her,
then chest tube zone.
She's getting
our last ventilator.
What? We're out?
Yes.
We can switch to bags
full-time.
Who's gonna work 'em?
We don't have enough nurses.
We'll get extra tubing
and split it,
put two patients
on a single ventilator.
No, the vent
isn't strong enough.
I'm in. Bag him.
Yeah, if we match patients
who are roughly the same size,
double the tidal volume,
should be enough to hold.
Okay. Okay.
Oh, my God, Owen? Owen?
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
I just need to... I need
some... I need some air.
Just five minutes, okay?
Of course.
I'll take care of the vents.
So this guy, Roger,
I've been working with,
his memory is still very hazy.
The one thing he is
absolutely certain about
is that he saw this fellow
over here in the kiddie chair
with the blue shirt
right there,
and that he had, quote,
"A look of rage in his eyes."
We've already had
one false ID, Daniel,
and witness statements...
Notoriously unreliable,
I know.
I'm just saying,
this guy, Roger, very well
could've seen everything.
I mean, that's why
I'm spending
so much time with him.
You think it's possible
that he can ID the shooter?
Yeah, it's possible.
I mean, he knows he saw David.
And I gotta tell ya, I've been
watching them for a bit,
and he is a little
overly enthusiastic,
in terms of helping
all the other victims.
You know, create a disaster,
so that he can then rise up
and become the hero,
you know, I don't know.
We got a name.
Trent Harris, 43.
Well, Dr. Charles
was wondering
if it could be this guy
behind you in the blue shirt.
But he's been telling us
his name is David.
Well, he would definitely
give a fake name.
Yes, but he looks like
he's in his 20s,
not his 40s.
Yeah, how'd you make your ID?
Registered AR-15
we recovered at the scene.
You sit tight, tuck in,
just watch him.
PD is pulling DMV photos.
If we do get a positive ID,
be ready to clear as many
people out of here as you can.
I'll find Maggie
and spread the word.
Okay.
Thank you, Jay.
Yeah.
So SWAT raided
Harris' house,
crap floor to ceiling,
major hoarder.
They found another body.
Guy shot his wife.
Where is he?
Where'd this guy go?
I don't know.
Little help? I need help!
Trevor, hey. Trevor!
Ethan, April, I need you.
Thready pulse,
hole in the neck.
Slashed his wrist.
Multiple stab wounds
to the abdomen.
Guy's lost a lot of blood.
Let's give him
two units of O-neg
and start bagging.
I need to intubate.
20 of etomidate, 100 of sux.
Detective Halstead said
he'll have a photo
of our suspect, Trent Harris,
an... Any second now.
He's not the guy.
Sats, 82. Heart rate, 130.
Interior abdomen
stab wounds.
Belly's distended. FAST scan.
Wrists are
slashed to the bone.
I'm in.
FAST scan's positive.
Where are we?
Belly's full of blood.
He needs surgery now.
We'll take him to
the doctor's lounge.
Let's go.
Connor, that's our guy.
Don't let him off the hook
by dying.
When did you realize
he was the shooter?
When I heard
about his wife
and the hoarding.
You knew?
We're struggling to keep
innocent victims alive,
and you pull us away
to save this monster?
Damn it, Dr. Charles,
my son is missing!
I'm so sorry.
Jared's gone?
That's it?
I'm so sorry.
No.
He'll live.
Tired?
I am exhausted.
Yeah, me too.
They still need help upstairs
in the ORs.
Let's go.
Natalie?
It looks like Liz's phone,
Owen's nanny.
Owen?
Mommy!
There she is.
How?
Once they found the shooter,
I had Jay make some calls.
Owen and Liz,
they were at the park.
They ran as soon as
they heard the gunfire
and left everything behind
and got to the 51st District.
Great work today, Dr. Choi.
Thanks.
So much blood.
I can still smell
the iron in the air.
You okay?
Still shaking.
Crazy thing is,
it's the most gratifying day
I've ever had as a doctor...
But I don't know what to feel.
Emily stepped up.
Yeah.
Yeah, she did.
Since the first victim
rolled in, it's only been
two hours.
Feels like two weeks.
This is the world
we live in, huh?
Yeah... Unfortunately.
Hey, phenomenal job,
Sharon, okay?
Approval for a new CT scanner,
done deal.
You know something, Peter,
just a CT scanner
is not gonna cut it.
The numbers we saw today,
we need multiple scanners,
triple the number
of trauma bays.
Waiting room
and hallway walls wired
for monitors and oxygen,
and that's just the beginning.
So basically, you're talking
about a... A whole new ED?
Yeah, I guess I am.
Okay.
Daniel?
Of course you had to save him.
I know that,
and she does too.