I gotta get this hospital ready for
the worst storm that we've seen in
I don't know how many years.
If you pull me off, won't I die?
If we stay here,
you definitely will.
Help me.
Get me a gurney!
If people can't
get to this hospital,
then we need to bring
this hospital to them.
Max, as your doctor,
I cannot let you
traipse through a storm.
And I will take care of myself
because I love my doctor.
Honey, I'm sorry,
but it's never gonna work
out between you and Max.
We need to talk.
This thing between us...
Max.
We lost power.
Shouldn't the generator
be coming on? Any second.
What's happening?
Uh, sorry folks. Uh, it
appears we lost power,
but the generator should
be kicking in shortly.
Is everyone all right?
My baby's cold.
Can I get a blanket?
All right, everybody
huddle up. Newborn?
My husband couldn't get here for
her birth, and we've been discharged.
The insurance company
wouldn't let us stay.
It's okay. Here,
just take my coat,
and I'll get you a blanket
as soon as possible.
Is the heat coming
back on? Yeah, shortly.
Come on in, guys. Just
head right over here.
We're gonna fix this.
Max. Yeah?
The generator should
have kicked in by now.
The circulatory
machines, the ventilators...
Okay, just do a
quick status run,
check all the wards, and
I'll meet you in the ED.
No... should someone
else... I'm fine.
You wanted to tell me something.
It can wait.
Henry. Dr. Goodwin.
How many on maintenance
tonight? You're looking at him.
Why isn't the
generator coming on?
I'm on my way to find
out, but it looks like
the entire lower
Manhattan grid is down.
Every minute we're
without power...
No, I get it. Patients will die.
Status? Improvising.
Call it out, April.
Mr. Ayers, blood
pressure: 130/75.
Pupils sluggish to react.
We have someone on
each of the ventilator patients
working an AMBU bag, taking pulses,
visually monitoring stats and meds...
Uh, what do you need?
Besides power? More people.
Since the storm, we've been
working with a skeleton crew.
Thermal socks. We
have to clean the feet.
Keep his clothes
on for the time being.
No monitor. No suction.
No cautery.
But you still have me, right?
Oh, yeah, holding firm.
Hey, can we get a
battery-powered fan?
Reynolds.
It's all good, Dr. Sharpe.
I'm holding Hugh's heart
together with my fingers,
but without power, we've got
no cardiopulmonary bypass...
No way to titrate anesthesia.
We can't operate without them.
Max is working on the generator.
All right.
How are you doing, sir?
Uh, you know... Eh...
Can I get another
micro-insertion kit?
On it.
Hey. How you
doing in there, Burl?
Get me out of here.
It's tight! Yeah.
Hey, guys, is there any way to
slide this out while the power's off?
We're safer with
him in the machine.
Danny, come on. He's here
'cause he attacked a guard.
No, he's not. He's here because
a guard bashed his head in.
In self-defense.
Oh, give me a...
The guard is my friend.
Your patient went off.
Hey, hey, Burl. Burl, listen.
Take a few deep breaths
for me, okay, buddy?
Deep breaths? We're
all in this together.
All right? Burl?
Iggy. Yeah.
It's midnight. Why wasn't
this scheduled for earlier?
We only bring the prisoners at
night, ma'am, for everyone's safety.
Can you handle this?
Sure, we're all
in this together.
Yeah.
Okay, Burl.
Get me out!
Um, where's that sound
coming from? Elevator?
Can you tell everyone to get
to ED? I'll be there in a minute.
Hello? KAPOOR: Helen?
Vijay?
Yes, I'm here with Dr. Hartman.
You know my name's Clint, right?
Are you okay? Yes, we are fine.
You don't look fine.
Are you claustrophobic?
Hardly. It's been
a very long day,
and I'm stuck in this
very small box with you.
Helen, why hasn't the
generator kicked in?
We're working on
it. Keep working on it.
What? Talk to me, Henry.
I mean, this thing took a big
hit during Hurricane Sandy.
A lot of these parts, they
should have been traded out.
And they weren't?
It doesn't look like it.
I mean, this fuel oil pump is failed,
this main pipe, it's still cracked...
So?
So, I could really use
some more light down here.
Wait. Wait.
I just remembered something.
I hope it's still here.
This. This could
buy us some time.
What is it? Emergency battery.
They got it after Sandy.
Is it enough to
power the hospital?
No way, but it could
cover a floor for an hour.
Okay, we got a
battery. That'll buy us
a little breathing room
while Henry keeps working.
Reynolds is literally
holding a man's heart
together with his fingers.
Yeah, I understand.
And we got a NICU full of babies
getting colder by the minute.
I can buy us a little juice
for one floor for one hour.
Okay, so ICU,
ventilators, IV pumps?
Yes. SHARPE: Yes?
What do you mean "yes"? We
need to pick one. We need to triage.
Nope. Shouldn't
we be evacuating?
No. CANDELARIO: To where? How?
In this storm, we can't
even get across the street.
Yeah, it's true. She's right.
We're one of the only
hospitals with the...
I was gonna say "with
the lights still on," but...
We could move
everybody to the same floor.
Yes. KAO: That's crazy.
Well, why? We're
not at capacity.
Look, it's Helen's idea.
But that's only because
you won't let me triage.
No triage. Look, Henry
is having difficulty seeing.
Would you grab a flashlight
and meet us down there?
Yeah, yes.
Max.
We cannot... Huh? We will.
Yo, hand me those soft-grip
pliers. Yeah, yeah, you got it.
Going with the
soft-grip. Here you go.
So, are you gonna check
those rotors or what?
Yeah, I'm doing
it now. Yeah, cool.
Boom.
I'm very impressed.
Yeah, are you?
Well, that's what growing
up on a farm does for a man.
Teaches him to say
"boom" a lot? Mmm. Yeah.
These rotors seem fine, but
the connections are damaged.
Tweak the rotors.
If I could just
get them to turn a little bit, there might
be enough power left inside the system...
Whoa!
Henry!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
One, two, three... Nothing.
Come on, Henry. Stay with me.
Stay with me, come
on. Three, four...
Come on, Henry. Five, six...
Seven, either, nine, ten.
No, nothing. Let
me get an AED...
No, no, no. There's
no time. Here we go.
All right. Yeah?
Come on, Henry. Going again.
Yeah?
Nothing. No, Max, that's enough.
No, one more try, one more try.
Come on, Henry.
NICU and ICU are priority zones.
But they're different floors.
We could move the
babies to the ICU.
And everyone else?
Yeah, move everyone to
the ICU, all the patients.
Keep the NICU separated, and
bring the people up from the lobby.
We can turn off
all nonessentials,
convert IV drips to
subcutaneous injections.
What about Reynolds'
man in the OR?
I can help with that. Go ahead.
What...
What happened?
He was electrocuted, V-fib arrest
with ROSC after pericardial thump.
He should be okay,
but we need to monitor
his rhythm and treat
the burns on his hands.
All right, okay.
So, no generator?
Uh, not unless you can fix it.
Guys, I may know
someone who can.
Who? Well, he's, um...
He's currently stuck
in an MRI machine.
The Rikers patient?
Yes, the Rikers patient.
But he used to work
for DWP, he's smart...
Okay, great. Yeah.
Full disclosure, though, he
sort of murdered his coworker.
Oh, my God. Right.
But it wasn't premeditated.
He's not a psychopath.
He just has behavioral issues.
A rather big one,
don't you think?
Yeah.
I'll take full responsibility.
Plus, there's a
guard there, so...
It's our best shot.
Keep this tray in place.
His blood pressure's
dropped down to 90/64.
Hang in there, Hugh.
Is that a fence joke?
Just keep talking.
Make a list of all the
things you're gonna do
with your husband
when you get home.
Scrub the baseboards,
fold the towels...
though, Eric always
says three folds is overkill.
Eric can have an opinion on three
folds when he starts doing laundry.
Good point.
You have to help me remember
to tell him all this if I make it.
You're gonna make it.
BP's dropped to 82/40.
We need to do something now.
Hypothermic coma.
Lower his body temp to near
freezing and slow his metabolism.
Wasn't I freezing outside?
No, no, no, this
will be controlled.
I'm afraid it's our only option.
Respectfully disagree.
You bring me some power?
No, but we can do
his surgery right now.
With what? We have all
the equipment we need here.
I worked in far worse
conditions in Afghanistan.
Dr. Candelario, this
is my patient, my OR.
Your OR has decent
lighting and electricity.
We can save this man, but
I'm gonna need you to let go.
Literally.
Go ahead with the
IV, it'll help BP...
We'll have battery
power at any moment.
It's all right. We're
all gonna get there.
Will you just take your time,
please? And don't panic!
Will you hurry up?
Take your time.
I just wanna get out of here.
What's going on here?
Do you know what's
going on here?
Calm down, okay?
Everyone...
Hey! Hey!
We have light. Heat will follow.
I know that the circumstances
are less than ideal, but we...
Hey, there's something
wrong with this woman.
Help that lady. Help that lady.
It's a baby.
Agnes.
I'll hold her.
She was complaining
of a headache earlier.
Want me to get Dr. Kapoor?
He's stuck in an
elevator... With Hartman.
You're gonna have
to take care of her.
It's all right,
Dr. Sharpe. I've got her.
You can write .6 mg per minute.
Confirming he said
he was 162 pounds?
Confirmed.
I've never managed anesthesia
levels without a monitor before.
Hold my beer.
That's okay.
Though neither of you learned
these techniques in medical school,
I can assure you they've
been practiced for ages.
That said, you may
wanna stand back.
Hello, Agnes.
Hi, Dr. Kapoor.
Are you all right?
I'm fine. Better now.
I'm here, too.
Yes, he's here, too.
I need your help. BOTH: Mine?
Both of you, I think.
What's the matter with her?
She gave birth yesterday,
complained of a headache,
then collapsed when we
moved everyone up to the ICU.
Have you assessed her reflexes?
She has a motor deficit
of the left upper extremity
and left lower
extremity, sensory intact.
It sounds like an amniotic
stroke. What do I do?
Nothing. There's nothing you can
do, not until the power comes back on.
Get a 60cc syringe,
a 7 French catheter with
a metal tip, and a magnet.
A magnet? Yes. Hurry.
Okay, you're kidding, right?
The woman will die if
we don't try to help her.
Yeah, but we
don't have the tools.
You don't have the tools.
Where are your
maintenance people?
Uh, all but one were
sent home, and he's hurt.
Hurt trying to do the
job you want me to do?
Afraid so.
Is this your idea? Not remotely.
I'm gonna need a set of plans.
For the generator?
For the hospital.
Not exactly state
of the art. Yeah.
What exactly do you need
the plans for? He doesn't.
Hey, nothing gets
fixed in a vacuum.
An old building...
Could be a wiring issue.
Your man get fried on the pump?
Honestly, I'm not sure.
If you want me to, I can fix it.
I'm gonna need a
set of plans and, um...
And a reduced sentence.
Burl... Pardon from
the governor works, too.
Okay, we're done here. Let's go.
Hey, hey, hey. Hold on. Well,
how much longer do you think
the guards and the
prisoners are gonna play nice
if they're freezing to death?
- Look, Burl,
I'm not in a position
to negotiate terms.
Well, then I guess
people are gonna die.
Hold on. No, but you
don't want that, Burl.
None of us want to lose anyone.
Now, this man, whom I
know to be a good man,
he doesn't trust you.
But that's a familiar
scenario, isn't it?
You could be a
hero tonight, Burl.
I'm trusting you to come
through for everyone.
Has anyone ever
said that to you before?
Has anyone ever given
you that opportunity?
Burl, you said you
wanted to change, right?
This is it. This
is where it starts.
Okay.
I'll help.
But I need those plans...
And these off. No way.
Can't work tied up.
Okay, there's a set of
plans in my office closet.
Okay.
He's playing you, man.
Maybe, but tonight's not
gonna end well for anyone
if he can't get this
thing fixed, so Reyes,
please remove his restraints.
Right ventricle's exposed.
- Lung sounds bilateral.
In a traditional surgery, this is
where I'd stop the heart from beating.
But we can't do
that. No, we can't.
But you've been holding
the heart for a long time.
Perhaps you've got
the rhythm down right.
You want me to time each
suture to the relaxation phase.
Exactly.
Time to let go.
Um...
Can you slow him
down a bit more, Alicia?
Give me time to sew? I'll try.
Kat, I'm gonna need a 3.0
Prolene on a needle driver.
You're doing great.
It's not much
different, actually.
I mean, it is, but
I never realized
how much I relied on machines.
Doing it old-school like this
makes me think I might be a
better surgeon than I thought.
- Oh, no.
- Alicia?
What...
What are you...
Alicia... Alicia, get
him back under!
Sir?
Sir, we need to be
able to get through here.
She's hungry. I tried
giving the formula,
but she wouldn't take it.
She needs her mother.
His heart's racing!
Uh, I'm trying.
We need blood, O-neg.
There isn't any. We exhausted
the supply earlier tonight.
Then find some.
We're not losing him.
Sorry, can I have
everyone's attention?
Um, we have a, uh, medical
emergency in one of our operating rooms,
and we need, um,
type O-negative blood.
So, the process is quick
and relatively painless,
and, uh, you can
help save a life.
So if anybody knows that
they are O-negative already,
go ahead and,
um, raise your hand,
and we'll, um...
Uh...
Sorry, guys, but, um, I need
your attention just for a minute.
Would everybody look down?
Just look directly below you.
Um...
If you had X-ray vision,
what you would see
is our second-floor OR.
You would see a man
on the table in the dark.
His name is Hugh. Hugh is
having open-heart surgery right now,
in a no-electricity setting,
and he is running out of blood.
So however difficult
you're finding today,
I promise you, Hugh's
day is going a lot worse.
So, here, I will go first.
We're in the middle of a night
that we're gonna remember
for the rest of our lives.
We're gonna tell
the story of how,
in the worst blizzard New
York's seen in a century,
we were trapped in a hospital.
And it can be a story
about how tired and hungry
and cold and angry we were.
It can be a story
about how we couldn't
stop fighting with each other or
how Dr. Sharpe kept yelling at you.
Or it can be a story of how,
when every instinct
told us to be at our worst,
we were at our best.
And if we do that,
then maybe Hugh
gets to stick around
and tell that story, too.
So... would anyone
like a blood test?
Yeah, I will.
- Yes? Thank you.
- Yeah, me too.
Yeah? Great. Thanks.
You just see Casey right
here, and he'll help you out.
Thank you. Thank you.
Nice work, except
for the yelling part.
Mmm. You need to sit down.
Max, as your doctor... I'm fine.
You're not well. Thank
God for adrenaline.
Dr. Sharpe, the baby...
The introducer's in place.
Good. Now thread the
catheter into her arteries.
Done, now what?
Oh!
Dr. Kapoor?
What's wrong with you?
Oh, God, my foot is cramping.
I spent too long in the snow.
I need you to apply acupressure
to K-6 point, please.
On your foot?
Dr. Hartman, as you
often enjoy pointing out
that I'm not a young man,
I cannot contort
myself to do this.
So that's why you
treat me like garbage?
Because I made a couple
of jokes about your age?
More than a couple.
Okay, I got into neurosurgery
so I didn't have to touch
my patients' bodies,
much less their feet.
Dr. Kapoor?
If you don't help me,
I cannot help Agnes.
All you have to do is to
apply pressure between
the second and third metatarsal,
one third the way between
the MTP joint and calcaneus.
Please.
Oh, God. Yeah.
Open the laces, please.
Yeah, I have shoes.
Just calm down.
Without the socks, please.
There.
Gently.
- Put some pressure, no?
- Oh, my God.
I'm ready with the magnet.
Agnes, the baby needs to be fed.
Station her here. But
she's unconscious.
Well, I don't think
we have a choice.
When was this
place built? Uh, 1766.
You know, there used to be an
old swimming pool in the basement?
Uh...
No, I didn't. No, I did not.
Neat.
Damn it! Whoa, whoa! Wait!
Hold on. Burl?
Burl, are you all right?
What?
Well, you screamed.
Yeah. I got frustrated.
Okay.
Anyway, I think I
know what to do.
I'm gonna need
welding equipment.
Yeah, we can get that for you.
It shouldn't take me
more than 10 minutes.
All right.
Problem is, it's gonna
suck up a lot of your juice.
You said you had a portion of
the hospital running on a battery?
The ICU.
I'm gonna need that power.
If you can't fix it...
Then we'd all be done.
No more juice for anybody.
It's your call.
How can you put your faith
in this man, a violent man?
Well, his violence was
triggered by abuse at work
and years of beatings as a kid.
The guard will be
with him at all times.
He gets the power he needs, we
get New Amsterdam back on its feet.
It's the only way. No,
it is not the only way.
The latest emergency
bulletin said
the storm should
break around 5:00 a.m.
With the wind down, we could
get a helicopter on the roof
and a new generator. Yeah,
but there's no guarantee
the storm's gonna break.
As opposed to the iron certainty of
us trusting a homicidal electrician?
Uh, in a half an hour, the
battery will be dead regardless.
We may not be able to keep
our most critical patients
alive until 5:00 a.m.
Right, so your prisoner uses up
all of our existing power and fails,
and that's a half an hour
less time that we have to try.
Not to mention all the
people that we'd be putting
back into the cold. Just think
about the greater good, Max.
Yeah, I am, Helen. Okay?
I'm not signing off on any
plan that requires me to triage,
to give up on anyone.
Well, then you are
risking everyone's life.
I'm trying to save
everyone's life.
That is not possible.
Dr. Sharpe, please inform
everyone that in a few moments
the power will go down for
approximately 10 minutes.
After which, God willing, New
Amsterdam will be fully back online.
Okay?
What are you...
Kira...
What happened?
My arm. You've
had a mild stroke.
And my baby? How did she...
She's fine.
Agnes, it's time to
place the magnet
on the right side of
the patient's temple.
Okay.
And surely your
foot is better by now.
Of course, but you seem
to be happy holding it.
Okay, Agnes, now when you
feel the tug on the catheter,
you will know when
it's in the right place.
I feel it. It's working.
Good. You have Hartman
and his youthful fingers to thank.
Okay, this is all the welding
gear that we could find.
Yeah, we got this thing
and whatever this thing is.
I thought you grew up on a
farm. Yeah, I can make that work.
How can we help?
Run the cables
up to the battery.
Okay. Yeah, I'm on it.
And then you should all go
out in the hall before I light this.
So you don't, you know, blow up.
Thank you. No, thank you.
The minute you're
done with this little game,
I'm dragging your ass
off to a cold, dark corner.
You understand me? Reyes.
All right, everybody,
here we go.
Think about it
There must be a higher love
Down in the heart
Or hidden in the stars above
Without it
Life is wasted time
Look inside your heart
I'll look inside of mine
Things look so bad everywhere
In this whole world What's fair?
We walk blind, we try to see
Falling behind in what could be
Bring me a higher love
I could rise above
On a higher love
Is he done?
Yeah, I guess.
Hey, Burl, you okay
in there, buddy?
Burl?
Burl, hey, buddy. How you doing?
Uh...
Damn it. I told you.
Max. Max!
Where you going?
Where's Henry? In the ICU.
Where's his notebook?
He had a notebook.
He was making notes.
We can wake him up,
he can look at
them with fresh eyes,
and then we can come
up with a different plan,
a better plan, and
we can fix it. Okay?
'Cause there's
still time to fix...
Damn it! Max.
Just stop.
It's nearly 2:00 a.m.
Hopefully the
storm breaks at five.
And that gives us at least three hours
to disburse extremely limited resources,
but you and I need to
decide which patients
are gonna get them
and which ones aren't.
That's not who we are.
No, but it's where we are.
Helen... Max.
We have no power,
no blood, it's freezing...
That doesn't mean
someone has to die.
But someone will.
That's just a fact now.
Your job is no longer
to save everyone.
It's to try and minimize the
damage. Do you understand that?
I thought it would work.
I just couldn't see a
scenario where it didn't.
I know.
But now we have to choose...
who to let go.
I can't...
Choose.
I won't.
Then I will.
The city's still out.
That means the generator...
We got power. Hook him up.
Assess the ABCs.
Continue monitoring
manually until...
Come on, man. You just
have to hang on a bit longer.
Okay, the catheter's
all the way in.
End of the line.
Good, Agnes. You're
doing a wonderful job.
All you have to do now is
to attach the syringe and...
Dr. Kapoor?
Agnes?
And what?
I've got this.
Where's the blood?
Kira, try to move
your left arm for me.
Thank you.
Hey. Hey.
How'd you get us
the juice? I didn't.
Okay.
Hey.
Did you fix the...
Welding wasn't gonna fix that.
I couldn't tell you that or Reyes
would have dragged me off.
I just figured if this place
had an old swimming pool,
it might have a fuel pump
system I could switch out.
It did.
What do you want?
Anything. I'll make it happen.
I wanna get better.
Think about it
There must be higher love
Down in the heart
Or hidden in the stars above
Without it
Life is wasted time
Look inside your heart
I'll look inside of mine
Things look so bad everywhere
In this whole world what's fair?
We walk blind, we try to see
Falling behind in what could be
Bring me a higher love
Oh, and the baseboards...
Never another speck of dust.
Did you tell him about
the towels? Three folds?
How do you know about
that? You wanted to tell him.
And I'm gonna
fold all the towels
just the way you
don't like them.
Uh, I was brilliant
last night, wasn't I?
Oh, yes, exceptional
with all your
years in the field.
Thank you.
You were bloody
magnificent last night.
I just said "bloody."
I could think of a better
expression under the circumstances.
It's a UK thing.
So I've heard.
Mmm-hmm.
Really.
There's no way I would have
gotten through it without you.
We make a good team.
That's what I wanted to
speak to you about, actually...
before the power went out.
This thing where I am your
deputy and your doctor...
and your confidante
and your friend...
That is a lot. Yeah, it is.
And it's not working.
All last night, we needed
to choose who to save,
and every time, you
chose all of the above.
Yeah, I... No,
that's not a criticism.
I'm glad you did.
You saved everyone.
We saved everyone. Yes.
It worked out, but
sometimes it doesn't.
Sometimes you have to choose...
And you couldn't.
You just said it all
worked out, and...
I don't see what me not
triaging patients has to do with...
with us.
It's what you do with
your cancer as well.
You wanna stay
healthy for your family,
but you want to stay in
charge of the hospital.
You want the chemo,
the strongest that we have,
just not any of the side
effects that come with it.
From the day this began,
from the day we met,
you have refused to choose.
I'm not refusing,
it's not that easy.
Look, Helen, all I want is...
Max.
You want everything.
It's who you are.
You are all of the above.
And then you come to
me with these demands,
these inspiring...
completely impossible demands,
and I don't know who
I'm supposed to be.
You're supposed to be you.
I've tried.
I have tried to be
all of the above.
I can't.
I can't be your
friend and your doctor
and your deputy,
so I have to choose.
I have to triage us.
I'm gonna ask Dr. Stauton
to take over for me. No.
She's an exceptional
oncologist. No, no! You don't...
She'll be your new doctor, Max.
She'll handle your care,
effective immediately.
But what if I want you?
Well, I'm afraid that's
no longer an option.
Because we all want you.