Incoming, peds
in respiratory distress.
Thirty seconds out.
We got this.
Hey, love.
What are you doing here?
Aren't you
supposed to be home,
taking care of yourself?
I don't wanna stay at home.
Just can't stop
thinking about things.
I'd rather be here,
busy.
You sure?
Since we lost the baby,
things with me and Tate
are different.
I need to work.
All right, well,
you tell me if
you need anything.
Okay? You got this?
Mmm-hmm.
You're going
to Treatment Two.
Emergency landing at O'Hare.
Seven-year-old girl
collapsed mid-flight.
Acute shortness of breath
started on the plane.
One Albuterol
and one Racemic epi
given en route.
Sats?
Low 90s.
Meds didn't do much.
All right, gently.
One, two, three.
Mommy?
She's just telling
her daughter to be calm.
We speak English.
Lungs sound congested...
Rhonchi throughout.
Let's get a chest X-ray.
I'm Dr. Choi.
I'm gonna be taking
care of your daughter.
Where are you traveling from?
Ecuador.
Has your daughter
ingested any drugs?
Alcohol?
Anything we
should be aware of?
No.
Any medical issues
we should be aware of?
She can never
get enough air.
Her lips are always blue.
Her whole life...
The doctor in my village,
she says she can't help.
We were going to Minneapolis
to see a heart doctor.
Definitely volume overloaded.
Let's get five milligrams
of lasix IV.
BP, 108 over 82.
Heart rate, 110.
Could be
a pulmonary issue,
or any number
of congenital heart defects.
Let's get an EKG,
and call CT.
We're gonna do
everything we can
for your daughter.
Thank you.
Incoming. Dr. Manning?
Yep.
Teresa Azen, 25.
Persistent vegetative state.
Brought in by her
long-term care facility
after blood was
discovered in her urine.
Now, let's get vitals,
a temp, CBC, CMP,
UA with C&S.
Could just be a UTI,
but let's look at her kidneys
with an ultrasound
to rule out
hydro from a stone.
Got it.
All right, on my count.
One, two, three.
Brain injury?
Car crash.
Teresa, I'm Dr. Manning.
I'm gonna take good
care of you, okay?
G-tube looks good.
Temp, 100.6.
Unresponsive.
No kidney stones.
Let's look at the bladder.
How long did you say
she was in
a vegetative state for?
Five years.
We need to call the police.
This woman is pregnant.
There's vaginal trauma,
which explains
the blood in the urine.
Thank you.
Is this our victim?
Yeah. It's awful.
You ever see
anything like this?
I wish I could say I hadn't.
Okay, let's lift.
One, two, three.
So helpless.
We're looking into
all of the employees
at Teresa's facility.
We're checking visitor logs,
security footage.
We'll find out who
had access to her
and to her floor.
But the rape kit's
only supposed
to reveal DNA
for the past
five days.
How is this
gonna help?
I hate to say this,
but the likelihood
in a case like this
is that the offender's
been assaulting her regularly,
maybe even daily.
Hey.
Teresa's parents
are here.
Okay.
David and Angela Azen,
this is Detective Lindsay
and Dr. Manning.
I am so sorry
for what happened
to your daughter.
How could someone
do this to her?
Are you gonna
catch this monster?
Yes. We've already
opened an investigation,
and finding whoever did this
is a top priority for us.
I just want you to know,
we are gonna
give your daughter
the best possible care.
Why don't you go
spend some time
with your daughter?
We have 18 patients
on this floor,
all suffering from
serious mental illnesses.
Since age 13, Henry
has been battling
Anorexia Nervosa
coupled with borderline
personality disorder.
Evelyn struggles
with schizophrenia,
auditory hallucinations,
paranoia.
We have her on
a new anti-psychotic,
hoping that'll curb
her violent tendencies.
Patients might be here
anywhere from six weeks
to six months.
You're not listening!
You don't belong here.
Get out!
That's enough, Tom.
Why don't we go work
on your art project?
Who are you?
Uh, I'm Dr. Reese.
I'm visiting
from Chicago Med.
He's right.
I don't belong here.
All the doctors think
I'm crazy, but I'm not.
Dr. Reese,
we're moving on.
She's the worst.
Hey, just so you know,
"Crazy" is a word I never use.
And we've got Ms. Perreira...
Post op day two.
We removed her chest tube
and wires this morning.
She is tolerating a diet,
and looking good.
She's on a solid
dose of morphine.
Ah. And what
about consults?
Uh, we have two
in the MICU,
one for an aortic valve,
and the other for
a potential bypass.
All right. Let's go
have a look, everybody.
Uh, just a moment.
One more thing.
More of a question,
really.
What does
a Jewish pirate say?
I beg your pardon,
Dr. Latham?
Ah. What does
a Jewish pirate say?
Ahoy vey.
Get it? Ahoy vey.
All right. That is
a good one, Dr. Latham.
Jewish humor. Long tradition.
Shall we move on to the MICU?
So, I take it that
your TMS treatments
are going well.
Yes, I've been picking up
on all sorts of subtleties
in the way
people communicate.
For instance,
it never dawned on me
the profound purpose
behind sharing a joke.
Oh! Well, what is it?
Camaraderie. Dr. Rhodes.
Camaraderie.
Hey, check out
what I got you.
Mousse de Maracujá.
Your favorite.
When I was, like, eight.
Well, still...
I thought it might
make you feel better.
He's trying, April.
No one knows
what to say.
There's nothing to say.
How were rounds at
the youth hospital?
Brutal.
I'm sure there's
a more clinical term, but...
I hear ya.
It's really hard
to see so many teenagers
suffering from
psychological trauma.
Yeah, younger patients
are the hardest.
Very tough to draw a line
between an actual disorder
and good old-fashioned
adolescence.
How do you learn
to make that call?
Tourist asks
a New Yorker,
"How do you get
to Carnegie Hall?"
Practice.
Hi.
So, Teresa is
approximately 10 weeks
along in her pregnancy.
Oh, God.
Fortunately, termination
will be a painless procedure.
Wait, termination?
We don't want that.
We wanna keep the baby.
I'm sorry. I thought,
given the circumstances...
Mr. and Mrs. Azen,
nothing has to be
decided today.
No, we've made up
our mind.
It is terrible what
happened to our daughter,
but even if it
came from a rape,
the baby's still
part of Teresa.
The only part
we have left.
Yes,
I can understand that.
But in your
daughter's condition,
I have to tell you,
taking this pregnancy to term
would be extremely difficult.
Why?
Her brain has been injured,
but her body's healthy.
No.
At five years in a persistent
vegetative state, it's not.
This is a high risk situation
for pulmonary embolism,
sepsis, colonic obstruction,
respiratory failure.
But those are
just risks, right?
It could all work out.
They are
extremely high risks.
If you have your daughter
go through with
this pregnancy,
there is a chance that
she will not survive.
She's hardly living
as it is.
If she dies giving birth,
maybe that's
a merciful outcome.
Sometimes,
I've wished for that.
There is another
issue to consider.
Given the abuse
your daughter
has undergone,
do you believe
that she would want
to keep this pregnancy?
In any case,
you are Teresa's guardians,
and therefore
speak on her behalf.
Your wishes
will be honored.
So, based on the echo
and the CT scans,
your daughter
is suffering from
a congenital heart condition
known as
Tetralogy of Fallot.
It's a condition
that puts a significant
amount of stress on the heart,
and it's something
that needs to be
addressed surgically.
I can pay.
I bought travel insurance.
It's an emergency surgery.
We would operate regardless.
We'll take your daughter
to the pediatric ICU
and get her ready.
Are you all right?
I know this is a lot.
I'm fine.
Mommy?
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
You sure you're okay?
Maybe I should
take a look at you.
No, no.
I haven't had anything to eat.
No sleep. I'll be okay.
Hey, April, so sorry
to hear about the baby.
How you holding up?
It's okay. I'm okay.
T-2. Talk to me, Cesar.
Suicide attempt.
Fifteen-year-old female
from county psych.
She swallowed bleach,
sodium hydroxide,
and some sort of rust remover.
Hydrofluoric acid.
Okay, call Toxicology,
get an NG tube in her,
push an amp of
calcium gluconate,
and hang a magnesium drip.
Watch for v-tach,
and get a psych consult.
Got it.
You have to
get Dr. Reese for me.
I need to talk to her.
I wasn't trying
to commit suicide.
I was trying to see you.
Do you believe
it's okay
to hurt yourself?
How else could I get to you?
It's not like I can
ask for a phone call.
Nancy, you could have
seriously hurt
or even killed yourself.
You have to help me
get out of there.
They locked me up after
I got in a fight with my mom,
but she's Bipolar.
Has been for years.
Hey, I'm sorry, but
I'm not your psychiatrist.
My mom came at me
with a hammer
while I was sleeping.
I was trying to defend myself.
It doesn't make me crazy.
No. If that were
the situation, it would be
reasonable to defend yourself.
See?
You're the only
one who said that.
All the other doctors
think I'm psychotic,
but my mom's
the one who's crazy.
Dr. Reese?
Could I speak to you
for a second?
I'll be right back.
Yeah, could you...
Could you fill me in?
I understand that
you ran into Nancy
on rounds this morning?
Yes.
Uh-huh.
Could you have
said anything
to make her think it was
a good idea to come
over here and see you?
All I said was "crazy"
isn't a word I ever use.
Huh.
Gotta be very careful
the way we talk to
younger psych patients.
They're much more vulnerable
to mixed messages.
She seems to think
that you're
some sort of ally.
I am. Aren't we all?
To get her the right
treatment, of course,
but this is a young woman
who purposefully drank
extremely toxic chemicals.
I mean, Nancy's been
diagnosed with borderline
personality disorder.
She has severe bouts
of manic depression.
Uncontrollable hysteria,
paranoid delusions.
People who suffer
from these disorders
can be very persuasive,
very manipulative,
and a danger to themselves.
So, we just...
We have to be careful.
We wouldn't wanna
put her in a position
where she wanted
to harm herself again.
Ms. Cespedes?
Can I get your signature
on this consent?
This gives us
permission to operate.
Ms. Cespedes,
you don't look well to me.
You could've picked up
a virus while traveling.
May I please
check your pulse?
Is everything all right?
I told you I'm fine.
Please.
Let's go back to
the emergency department
and let me take a look at you.
Just show me where
the bathroom is, please.
Yeah.
Follow me.
Hey.
Her parents here?
No, making calls outside.
Looking for
a new care facility.
Hmm.
Did you hear they
wanna keep the pregnancy?
Mmm-hmm.
When you can't talk,
you don't get to say nothing.
Yeah, well, I don't
think it's the right thing.
Mmm.
Maggie?
Did you see that?
Mmm-hmm.
I know PVS patients do that,
and it's just a reflex,
but didn't it seem like
there was more going on?
Wishful thinking.
Teresa, can you hear me?
If you can hear me,
please open your eyes.
Teresa, if you can hear me,
squeeze my hand.
In my time at the Vent Farm,
I've seen this a lot.
Blinking, spasms,
sudden jerks of movement.
Never ends up meaning
what you want it to.
Let's get a CT brain.
On a five-year
coma patient?
Just in case.
Hey, Sarah.
You got a second?
Hmm.
I heard that
most of the psych
residents get therapy.
Yeah.
Have you tried it?
Uh-huh. Um...
I'm sorry.
Can we talk later?
Sure. Yeah.
How's she doing?
Well, we've
flushed her pretty good.
She'll be
medically cleared soon
and will have to go back
to the psych hospital.
You buy her story?
I don't know.
She's on
a six-month psych hold.
Does she seem like
she requires that
much time locked up?
Don't ask me.
Psych's way too spongy.
In med school,
my head-shrink professor
took us to the mall
and asked us to
point out people
we thought were mentally ill.
No one could agree.
Hmm.
That is when I knew
I wanted to be an ED doc.
Much clearer business.
Yeah.
I wish there was
a way to evaluate
Nancy like an ED doc.
Well, maybe there is.
Like I tell my residents,
always go back
to the history.
Mommy?
Mommy? Where's my mommy?
Hey, Bruna, she's out
in the waiting room right now.
I need her.
You're gonna be okay,
sweetheart.
We're gonna take
very good care of you.
Marty, now might be
a good time
start the sedation.
Please, I want my mommy.
Hold on, Marty.
I would want my mom, too,
if I were in a new place
with new people.
You know what?
Everyone here has one job,
and that is to
make you feel better.
And by the time
we're finished,
you won't have
trouble breathing.
You won't faint
on airplanes.
You'll be
a healthy little girl.
How does that sound to you?
You can really fix me?
Yes.
Now, I need you to
do something for me.
Can you count to 100?
In Spanish?
Mmm-hmm.
And by the time
you're finished,
your mother will be
right next to you.
I promise.
Hey, April.
Is she still in there?
Says she's okay,
but keeps vomiting.
Won't open the door,
so I called maintenance.
Zulmira.
Zulmira,
open the door, please.
Hold on. I got this.
Just give me a minute.
Stay away.
It was the only way
I could get her to America.
April,
what's going on?
I'll be fine.
She just needed
a good hospital.
Okay.
She's overdosing!
How do you know?
She's a drug mule.
Blood glucose is good,
but tachycardic as hell.
BP is 115 over 110.
Heart rate 150.
There is still two
packets in your stomach,
one of them
appears to be leaking.
We need to know.
Is it cocaine?
Just so we can help you.
Yes.
Okay,
we need to get these out now
before they burst.
Let's get an EGD scope
and 70 milligrams of ketamine.
You can't take it out.
You'll die of an overdose
if any more cocaine
leaks into your intestine.
Can you give me medicine?
No, we need to remove them.
Would you give it
to the police?
We'll explain
the situation to them.
No, I can't go to
prison in my country.
They'll kill me.
Bruna needs me.
She will starve without me.
Tell Goodwin we
need a court order
to remove the drug packets.
She'll be dead by
the time it's approved.
Call PD.
Maybe they can
bring a warrant in time.
Please, just leave me alone.
Zulmira, if you don't let us
remove those packets,
you will die.
I...
I can't go to prison.
Do you want Bruna to
wake up from surgery
and learn that
her mother has died?
You can't help her in
any way if you're dead.
Let us keep you alive,
please.
Okay.
All right,
come on, let's go.
Yeah.
You think
there's any chance
of brain activity?
I don't see how.
A lot of brain
volume loss and atrophy.
This is not the healthy
brain of a 25-year-old.
But even with some atrophy,
couldn't there still be
consciousness?
What was her
Glasgow Coma Score?
There was no response.
This woman is in
a persistent
vegetative state...
My guess,
for the rest of her life.
But I'm almost sure
I saw something in her eyes.
Like she was aware of us
talking about her
or something.
Maybe you want that so much,
you're projecting?
Um, I don't know.
I do feel terrible for her.
She's pregnant.
She was sexually assaulted
at her care facility,
and her parents wanna
keep the baby. I just...
If I could somehow
get through to Teresa,
she might finally have a say
in what happens to her.
I'm sorry, Natalie.
You know what,
I want a neurology consult.
Have Abrams take a look.
Dr. Charles,
do you have a minute?
I do.
In order to get
a more complete history,
I contacted the officer
who arrested
Nancy and her mother.
He sent me his report.
It said they often get
called to Nancy's house
on domestic disputes
involving the mother.
She's been in and out
of jail for assault.
In fact,
she is at County right now.
Please take a look.
This could just
mean that, you know,
mental illness runs
in Nancy's family,
and she and her mom suffer
from the same disorder.
Or it could mean that Nancy
was wrongfully committed
by an unstable mother.
The one thing
we know for sure,
it was her mother's testimony
that got Nancy committed,
and her mother's
an unreliable witness.
We have
a seven-year-old female,
here for reconstruction
of Tetralogy of Fallot.
Once we are
in the chest and on bypass,
we will relieve
the right ventricular
outflow tract stenosis.
Scalpel?
I want you to observe
as I start at
the sternal notch
and cut to the xiphoid.
Dr. Latham?
Dr. Latham,
is everything okay?
Yes, yes, Dr. Rhodes.
All right, I got it.
Okay, one left.
She'll be waking soon.
Dose her again with ketamine?
No, let's just finish this.
Okay.
Go ahead, Jeff.
Almost there.
All right, I got it.
Okay, pulling it out.
I think it burst
in her esophagus.
Give her 20 more of labetalol,
and start an esmolol drip.
Jeff,
get the crash cart ready,
and give me the nitro.
Got it.
Just lie back. Stay calm.
She's having
a cocaine-induced
heart attack.
Give her two of Versed IV.
Open your mouth.
I'm gonna spray nitroglycerin
under your tongue.
It'll make you feel better.
ST segments
are improving.
Does your chest still hurt?
No.
Sats are good.
Okay, heart rate, 120s.
She's out and stable.
Okay, what's the call?
We don't have a choice.
We got to report it.
But this was the only way
she could get her daughter
the operation she needed.
Why can't we destroy it?
Who would that harm?
Smuggling cocaine
is a serious crime.
If she made it to her dealers,
people would've been harmed,
possibly kids.
She can't just
get away with that.
She hasn't.
Look at her.
Five minutes ago,
her heart wasn't beating.
April...
No.
She wasn't
trying to deliver it.
She was trying to flush it.
Destroy evidence.
As of now,
it's a victimless crime.
She is a good mother
who did the only
thing she knew how
to help her daughter.
If we destroy this packet,
we'll be committing a crime.
We don't have a choice.
He's right.
Sorry.
Dr. Manning.
Yes.
Where are we with
Teresa's treatment?
I'd like to run
a few more blood tests
to rule out any
potential infection,
and I'd also like to look
into physical therapy.
Are there any medical issues
you're still treating?
No. Um...
We've treated
the vaginal bleeding.
Then it's time
to discharge her.
Her parents have
found a new care facility,
and they're eager to get
their daughter settled in.
How do we know
Teresa will be safe?
she won't get abused again?
She has suffered so much.
I just...
Just what?
What can you do?
We all wish we could do more,
but our job is to
treat the ailment
that brought the patient in,
and that's all.
It's time to give her
back to her parents.
We've finished the repair
and now coming off bypass.
We're off bypass.
At the end of any surgery,
when the patient has been...
Pulmonary artery
pressure is 50.
Coming up to 70.
And the left ventricular?
One hundred.
Well, let's not get excited.
She'll ride it out.
It's dropping. Eighty.
Should we put
her back on bypass?
Uh, I think we should...
We should...
She's throwing PVCs.
Seventy-five.
Pulmonary
hypertension's getting worse.
Your graft has to be stenotic.
Bypass, Dr. Latham.
We need to fix the graft.
We could try
a pulmonary vasodilator.
Vasodilator's not gonna do it.
We need to open her back up.
Blood pressure's
dropping rapidly.
We're losing her.
Dr. Latham...
She's peri-arrest.
Step away, Dr. Latham.
Step away.
Marty, re-dose of heparin.
Let's get her back on bypass.
I'm reopening the heart.
There you are.
Hey, how 'bout we...
How 'bout we
hang out after work?
Yeah, maybe go get some
of your favorite fries
or something.
Noah, please.
I get it, but just
give me some space, okay?
So, I understand
that you believe
that you've been
wrongfully committed.
Is that right?
Mmm-hmm.
Yes, definitely.
Ever been
hospitalized before, Nancy?
Besides for the night
my mom attacked me
with a hammer? No.
Hmm. You wanna tell me
a little bit about your mom?
I would. Finally.
Hi, Nancy. How are you?
Okay.
I'm Dr. Baker,
Nancy's psychiatrist.
Dan Charles.
Nice to meet you.
This is Dr. Halstead,
and I think you know
Dr. Reese.
Yes, I'm glad to see
our girl here
is in good hands.
When will she
be discharged?
She's clear.
We just need to
remove the NG tube,
and she'll be ready to go.
Good.
Do you mind?
Could I get
a quick word outside?
Of course.
Are you aware
that Nancy's mother
has an extensive
arrest record?
No, I wasn't. Why?
Well, it seems
that she might've
been committed
largely based on
her mother's
version of events.
Dr. Charles,
Nancy was committed
because I deemed her
a threat to herself
and others.
I was just wondering
if you thought that
there was any chance that
your assessment
might've been colored by
a potentially
unreliable history
given by the mother.
My assessment was
colored by 20 years
of experience
in adolescent psychiatry.
And quite frankly,
I don't appreciate
being second-guessed
by a doctor
who's only known my patient
for one afternoon.
I just saw the potential
for a biased narrative,
and I wanted to make sure
you had all the facts.
A biased narrative.
As Nancy's
court-appointed doctor,
I'd advise you to worry
about your own patients,
Dr. Charles.
Hey, you're
discharging her?
I just finished
the paperwork now.
Dr. Manning.
Yes.
Your coma patient,
given the abysmal treatment
she received at that facility,
I couldn't help but wonder
what other ways they
might've failed her,
so I reviewed
her history.
Did you find anything?
I'm afraid not,
but I do have one question.
What time of day
did you perform
that neuro exam?
Morning. Why?
Sometimes,
traumatic brain injuries
result in a patient developing
irregular sleep/wake
circadian cycles.
So, it's possible
Teresa's become nocturnal.
I suggest we try
that test again.
Great.
Mr. and Mrs. Azen.
This is Dr. Abrams,
Chief of Neurosurgery.
Do you mind if we perform
one more test
on your daughter?
Well, the EMTs
from her new facility
are on their way.
It should just
take a moment.
Teresa, if you can hear me,
please open your eyes.
I've asked her that
a million times.
I know.
Just bear with me a moment.
Teresa, if you can hear me,
please move your eyes
side to side.
I'm sorry.
I finished
Teresa's discharge.
As soon as her
transportation arrives...
Hold on.
There's a condition
called Locked-in Syndrome.
If your daughter has it,
she'd be conscious,
but she wouldn't be able
to move her eyes side to side.
She could,
however, move them...
Well, let's see.
Teresa,
I need you to move your eyes
up and down for me, please.
Up and down.
Did you see that?
What was that?
Teresa, if you can hear me,
please move your
eyes up and down again.
Oh, my God.
I don't understand.
How did you wake her
from the coma?
I didn't.
I don't believe she
ever was in a coma.
What?
We need more tests
to be certain,
but it's my opinion
that her accident
caused a stroke
to the brain stem,
which included
the basilar artery.
What does that mean?
The stroke left her
completely paralyzed,
but still conscious.
Locked-in Syndrome.
She's awake,
but locked in her body.
All these years?
She's always been awake?
Yes.
She heard
everything we said...
I said.
And she was conscious
while some monster
assaulted her?
My poor baby.
I know, it's so terrible.
I'm so sorry.
But at least you
haven't lost her.
It's possible
that some of her paralysis
is the result of spasticity,
and it's therefore treatable
with muscle relaxants
and physical therapy.
Wait, will she
get better?
She'll never be
fully functional,
but she should
regain some movement.
We can also order
an infrared
eye-tracking device
that'll allow
Teresa to communicate
through a computer.
Communicate?
Yeah.
She'll be able to put together
words and sentences.
You'll be able to
have a conversation
with your daughter again.
A conversation?
With my little girl?
Thank you.
We'll give you time alone
with your daughter now.
Thank you.
Sarah, they're
telling me to get dressed.
They're sending me back.
I know. I'm sorry.
Sarah, please.
Help me.
I tried.
I did, but Dr. Baker has
conservatorship over you.
According to the courts,
she has to be the one
to change the diagnosis,
and we couldn't
change her mind.
Hey, I'm not giving up
and you can't either.
Stay strong.
We'll figure
something else out.
Okay?
Give me a second.
Dr. Charles, I know I don't
have any definitive proof,
but she is sane.
I know it.
We can't let her go back.
Slow down, Dr. Reese.
Dr. Baker just
doesn't want to admit
that she misdiagnosed her.
You know what?
I happen to agree with you.
I'm filing an appeal.
You don't think
she's mentally ill?
Can't be positive,
but either way,
she should not be locked up
on a long-term hold
based solely on her
mother's testimony.
Need some help!
Treatment One.
What happened?
Give me some pressure.
Must've grabbed
the scalpel from the cart.
Tourniquet her arm,
and give me a hemostat.
It's tied.
I'm not crazy,
Sarah. I'm not.
Surgery turned out
well today.
Thanks to you,
Dr. Rhodes.
It's been a long day,
Dr. Latham.
How 'bout a drink?
We need to talk
to Goodwin.
Trafficking of cocaine
is a felony.
That means calling
the DEA, Homeland,
the whole nine yards.
All that over one packet?
Well, if the evidence
is just this one,
that doesn't
demonstrate intent
to traffic and sell.
Were there more?
No.
The one packet
is all we found.
That's correct.
Dr. Choi?
Anything to add?
Dr. Choi...
No.
Then that's that.
Thank you, Dr. Choi.
Do not put me
in that position again.
Either of you.
I don't know that
I helped Zulmira.
She still has to
deal with the people
whose drugs she lost.
She is
a resourceful woman.
She's gonna do
what she needs to take care
of that little girl.
I had to at least
try to help her.
If I had a child,
I would've done
the same thing.
I know.
Thank you.
And thank you
for earlier.
About the baby.
It's my fault.
Why'd you say that?
I gave her
false hope.
I told her
I believed she was stable
when she clearly isn't.
I'm not sure I agree.
I mean,
just made her case
a little tougher,
but I'm still
gonna file the appeal.
Why would you do that
when she just
tried to kill herself?
Losing hope is not
a sign of mental illness.
It's a sign of being human.
I mean, the poor girl...
She has a violent,
unstable mother,
and her fate is
in the hands of
this psychiatrist
who doesn't believe
a word she says.
Given those odds,
I can absolutely
understand
why she'd fall
into despair.
Had to prove me wrong,
didn't ya?
Looks like you're
gonna get your wish.
She will have
a say in her future.
Dr. Latham, you decide
on that drink after all?
Maimonides.
Twelfth century
rabbi and physician.
He said that the risk
of a wrong decision
is preferable to
the terror of indecision.
I have never had
a moment like today
before I started
my TMS treatments.
I wouldn't worry.
I doubt it'll happen again.
That girl was more than
just a surgical challenge.
She became
a human being to me.
I lost my detachment.
I cannot afford that.
I'm ending my treatments,
at least for the time being.
Well, I'm sorry
that you feel like
you have to
make that decision,
but I trust your judgment.
Hmm.
When you started
your fellowship,
I told you that you
were not my first choice.
After working with
you these last months,
I would like to say
that I cannot imagine
a finer surgeon or person
than you, Dr. Rhodes.
Thank you.
Well, let's leave it
at that.
Yeah.
I would like a drink.
Scotch for me. Neat.
And another for my friend.
Hey.
Look, I'm sorry.
Okay, I...
I don't know what to say.
I got no clue what
you're going through,
but I wish I could help.