- Previously on The Resident...
- I have multiple sclerosis.
Darling, I'm so sorry.
We're here for you.
The doctors at the Mayo said
you could return to surgery.
I'm hopeful and I'm reassured.
Promise me one thing...
You won't give up on the OR
just yet.
Do Billie and AJ know
that you want to be
double board-certified
in the hardest field
of medicine,
neuro and cardiothoracic surgery?
I've mentioned
that I want to do this.
Bob Porter.
University Hospital, Augusta.
So you must be the other name
on the governor's short list
for a seat on the medical board.
So we are competitors.
You mind if I ask you
why you want a seat?
Just want to give back.
No, I need a letter of recommendation
for the Georgia State
Medical Board.
I'm competing with
another doctor for the spot.
Who is he?
This is him.
Robert Porter is angling
for a seat on the board.
He raped me
when I was 13 years old.
You want to go before the board
and tell them?
I want to make a statement.
Yes, a chronic back,
elbow, knee issue
might not be a terminal disease,
but
it can feel like one
due to the impact it has
on your life.
But
with 3D printing, soon,
we will be able to create
patient-specific implants.
Customized. Targeted. Personal.
This will be revolutionary.
"Advancements in medicine have inspired
"promising new treatments,
empowering patients and giving
them more say in their care."
Thank you.
"And clinical research
"can advance it even further,
resulting in progress
that can change..."
Oh, my God.
Could this be any more boring?
Doubtful.
But never underestimate the draw
of your geeky
clinical trial sexiness.
I wish you were coming with me.
Me, too.
But this conference
might be more enticing
than gender reveal festivities.
About you doing both
cardiothoracic and neurosurgery,
obviously, it is entirely,
100% your decision.
But, I mean, this is going to be
a massive,
massive challenge, Leela.
I know. I won't make a decision
until I have a real conversation
with Billie about it.
Okay?
Okay.
And that's Jessica.
Good luck
with your presentation.
This is the best macaron
I've ever tasted.
Your sister is so elegant.
She is. Beautiful and rich.
We've always been so different.
Just look at her.
Look how skinny she is,
and she's
three months' pregnant.
It must be nice that you
and Padma are so similar.
You get to avoid comparisons.
Oh, no, there are comparisons.
One of us is fun
and spontaneous,
the other serious, rigid.
I'm sure
- you can guess who's who.
- No.
Way to stick to
the pink and blue theme, Jess.
There's a theme?
I didn't know.
Funny, lady.
You look lovely,
even if you're dressed
for a funeral,
not a gender reveal party.
Considering that gender is
a social construct...
It's an amazing party.
Thank you so much
for inviting me.
And thank you for coming, Leela.
And the real fun
is about to begin.
Have we got a surprise for you.
She's so funny.
- Oh, my gosh.
- Yeah.
Oh, photo op.
And that photo will be online
in three, two,
one.
They're so cute.
How did they meet?
Scarlett was bartending,
doing some modeling on the side.
Will came in for a drink and he
couldn't take his eyes off her.
She went from being behind
in car payments
to flying on private jets.
All right, boys and girls,
let's gather round!
Thank you all for being here.
Let's find out if our firstborn
is a lad or lassie.
Our OB and the guys
who built this
are the only ones who know.
Is that a cannon?
Wait, like a cannon-cannon?
With these two,
it's go big or go gigantic.
On the count of three.
One!
Two!
Three!
Is this thing broken?
- Babe!
- Oh, my God.
Someone call 911!
See if he's okay.
I'm thinking we'll pick up pasta
from Luigi's or...
Yes! I love their "carbon-ye-ara."
Carbonara works.
With ice cream on top?
No, Daddy.
Just parmesan.
But I thought you liked
ice cream on top.
Bye, Daddy!
Okay, well,
I'm having ice cream.
She's already reading?
That's amazing.
Way sooner than I ever did.
She must've got that
from her mom.
- I'll be back in a sec.
- Thank you.
You working in the ER today?
Yeah, yeah,
I'm covering for Devon.
He's at that clinical
trial conference.
Ah, right. Yeah.
For some, being
an ER doc isn't enough.
He's got to be
a fancy scientist, too.
Well, our patients are lucky
to have you here, too,
my friend.
Help!
My passenger is dying.
What happened?
I picked her up
from her apartment,
she got in all pale and shaky,
asking for a hospital,
and slumped onto the seat.
I'm Dr. Hawkins.
You're at Chastain
Memorial Hospital.
Can you tell us what's going on?
Okay, how about your name?
Finger stick 104.
Will get these to the lab stat.
Blood pressure low. O2 sat 89.
Her son, I'm guessing?
Hmm, she works at Only A Dollar.
Oh, here we go. Uh,
Charli April Martinez.
Born January 15, 1997.
I see a subtle
petechial rash
to her neck and arms.
We're calling her emergency contact.
She's 25 years old,
ear infection in 2004,
vaccinations up to date.
Charli's popular.
Turn the ringer on
in case someone calls
who can tell us something.
Her emergency contact's
not answering.
I'll try again later.
Looks like she had a laparoscope
placed there recently,
but abdominal surgery
needs more than one port.
O2 sat's 98% on nasal cannula.
- BP's 104/60.
- Seems like
she's protecting her airway.
Let's use this opportunity
to get more info.
Trevor, page Raptor,
have him meet you at CT.
I'm gonna make a quick stop.
I'll catch up with you there.
Hey.
Thanks again for writing
that letter of recommendation.
Well, I hope it helps.
And Porter?
Is he still in the running
for the same seat?
Why wouldn't he be?
Well, I've heard
there are multiple
ethics complaints against him.
I thought that might
get him disqualified.
Let me know if you hear
anything more about him.
You're smiling.
That's good news, right?
- This my latest MRI?
- Yep.
Your neuro exam is excellent.
No new lesions.
Since you started taking
the meds,
your MS is not progressing.
How you feeling?
Overall, good.
Better now.
It means you're cleared
for surgery.
- Are you sure?
- You passed all the necessary tests.
I could have another
flare-up while I'm operating.
True, but it's unlikely,
and you know what to expect now.
Worse comes to worst,
you head off any symptoms
- with a steroid pulse.
- What about my patients?
Is this a risk
they should take, too?
There are surgeons with MS
safely operating
thanks to good meds,
and you will have backup.
The OR needs you.
And you need the OR.
I'm so sorry.
This was a terrible idea.
They said it was safe.
- I can't hear her!
- The explosion ruptured your eardrum, Will.
- It'll get better soon.
- He's gonna be okay, right?
Yep, Irving will make sure of it.
Am I glad to see you,
brother-in-law.
You got any painkillers?
Strong ones?
Yeah, let's get you
off the stretcher first.
On my count. One, two, three.
He can't hear.
His eardrum might have ruptured.
What happened?
The cannon exploded.
Right. Did you say "cannon"?
It was supposed
to fire blue or pink smoke.
I'm the one
who talked him into it.
Okay, easy. Let's just focus
on getting him better.
Go get Will checked in, and
we'll take care of him, okay?
Whoa, looks like
it hurts.
Let's get 75 mics of fentanyl.
Okay. Try holding still, hon.
You'll be feeling better
in a few seconds.
Will, I'm gonna send you
for a scan to get
a clear picture
of what's going on.
Okay?
I don't hear any breath
on the right.
My chest, it hurts.
His sats are starting to drop.
No lung sliding.
Looks like the shrapnel
collapsed the lung.
We need a chest tube now.
The doctor said
his lung collapsed
and he could have
internal injuries.
Yeah, I can't believe it either.
Oh, I'll call you
when I know more, okay?
We got his lung re-expanded,
he's breathing much better,
- and he's on the way to CT.
- Okay.
- His parents?
- Yeah.
They said I should have
talked him out of the cannon,
but it was my stupid idea
in the first place.
Oh, my God, I mean,
what a disaster.
One of his coworkers posted it.
And it's already been reposted
175 times.
What? A-As if this
wasn't awful enough.
Maybe put your phone away?
"Latest addition
to the cesspool
of gender reveal idiocy."
"Stop blowing things up to tell
people your kid's got a penis."
Scarlett, your friends love you.
Who cares what a bunch
of strangers think?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Troponin and BNP are both elevated.
She has leukocytosis
but no fever.
Nothing is adding up.
We need answers.
Her sats are drifting down.
She's getting sicker
by the minute.
Considering all those
TikTok notifications,
she must have an account.
Let's see if it can
tell us anything.
Scans taking that long?
She's our patient,
we still don't know
what's wrong with her,
so we're looking for clues
and Irving is trying
to reach the family.
180,000 followers.
Wow, that's impressive.
Yeah, but it's not helping.
Maybe this will.
Trevor, take it from the top
and walk us through it.
Well...
The apices of the lungs
look clear.
There's some scattered
focal ground-glass.
Hold on, is that a, uh...
- A filling defect.
- Yeah.
Consistent with a huge clot
in her right pulmonary artery.
Yeah, and smaller clots
in the distal arteries, too.
Maybe they aren't blood clots.
Then what are they?
This pattern plus the rash,
I'm thinking
fat embolism syndrome.
Yeah, globules of fat
clogging up the vessels.
That happens after fractures
or burns, right?
But she didn't have those.
Or pancreatitis.
But liposuction would
explain all of it.
The fat embolism,
the surgical port we saw.
O2's in the 80s.
149 heart rate. She's tanking.
Hemoptysis.
We need to secure her airway
before she aspirates.
What the hell is going on?
Let's intubate and find out.
Gail, I need you to look
for two small injection sites
on the patient's backside.
Do you see them?
Yes, I do.
Prepare the intubation meds now.
It's okay.
All right, sats are coming back up.
Looks like Charli here got
herself a Brazilian butt lift.
Aren't BBLs the most dangerous
procedure there is?
Yeah, but I doubt they advertise
the high fatality rates.
Right. They sell you
on the prospect
of getting a curvier backside
while losing inches
in the middle.
Let's get her to ICU.
I need to ultrasound
her heart to see
where that runaway fat
is now calling home.
That does not look pretty.
The tiniest bowel perf and
he could end up in septic shock.
Jessica's brother-in-law?
Yeah.
We've admitted him
and I booked an OR,
and as soon as it's ready,
we'll take him in.
And what happened?
A gender reveal party
gone very wrong.
A cannon was involved.
Probably best if I don't know
the details.
So, this could go south
really fast.
He's gonna need
exploratory laparotomy.
Well, I'm glad you're on deck.
Uh, you're on deck. I'm a maybe.
We need to talk.
What's going on?
Remember the last time
we operated together?
I had some issues.
And I contacted Conrad,
we had some tests run.
And?
I have MS.
Multiple sclerosis?
- I am so sorry, Dr. Bell.
- Thank you.
I'm adjusting to the new
reality, with Kit's help.
And on-on meds, I have
no symptoms, at least for now,
and Conrad has cleared me
for surgery. However
if you would prefer
to work with another doctor...
Absolutely not.
This is a physical challenge.
That's it.
I have one, too.
If you hadn't told me,
I'd never, uh, guess
- that you have dyslexia.
- Thank you.
But when I chose surgery,
my family, friends, advisors,
everyone thought it would
make me dangerous.
But with my work-arounds,
I believe I've...
- You are one of the best.
- I don't know about that.
But I do not let dyslexia
stand in my way.
This is just
a new challenge to overcome.
Well, thank you, Dr. Devi.
Was a good pep talk.
I'll see you in the OR.
Man, when I was in my 20s,
the worst things
we did to ourselves were
tattoos and piercings.
- Guilty of the former.
- Latter for me.
I got a gnarly infection
from my eyebrow ring.
Oh, trust me, it was dope.
Until it wasn't.
Oh, this is no good.
Charli's in trouble.
Is that fat
sitting in her heart?
Not just sitting,
it's in transit,
from her right atrium
to her left.
So she has a congenital hole
in her heart?
Probably undetected before,
but blew open
when she had the P.E.s.
Maybe even acted
as a pop-off valve,
- saving her life, but now...
- It's a bomb.
- Primed and ready to go off at any moment.
- Yeah.
If it makes its way
into her arterial circulation...
- She'll stroke out.
- AUSTIN: I'll text Dr. Sutton.
If that fat embolizes
to her brain,
we'll have minutes to intervene.
Hopefully, it's her family.
Charli, hon, this is Cassie
calling from Enhanced Dreams.
How you feeling
after your procedure?
Actually, Cassie,
you're speaking
with three doctors
at Chastain Memorial Hospital
who are trying
to save Charli's life.
So if I had to guess, I'd say
she's feeling pretty damn
miserable right now.
Cassie, this is Dr. Hawkins.
Did Charli get a Brazilian butt
lift at Enhanced Dreams?
We're gonna take that as a yes.
It's led to fat
embolism syndrome.
We need to talk to her surgeon.
Did she seriously just hang up?
She's not getting rid of us
that easy.
Trevor, Google Enhanced Dreams.
We're calling Cassie back.
All right, here we go.
"Enhanced Dreams
Plastic Surgery."
Great. Great, they're probably
busy hiding the evidence.
I doubt they'll have time
to pack up and run
- before my shift's over.
- Okay, that's not happening.
But let's keep calling.
Are you really calling me for
a stroke that hasn't happened?
- Can't you just give her TPA?
- She's had a recent surgery.
If we give her TPA,
she could bleed out.
If that fat goes to her
brain, you will only have minutes
to perform
an interventional thrombectomy.
Well, sucking clots out
of the brain through the groin
is not my specialty.
I haven't done that procedure
since residency.
- Just page IR.
- Come on, Sutton,
you know those guys
don't work over the weekend.
And if we page them,
they would not get here in time.
And our only endovascular
neurosurgeon's on vacation.
Sutton, we wouldn't be asking you this
if there was another option.
Then I'll have to.
I'd better go review
my head-neck vascular anatomy.
They're here.
Dr. Bell, this is Will
and my sister Scarlett.
- Such a pleasure.
- Dr. Bell
is a nationally-recognized
trauma surgeon.
Jess has told me
so much about you.
- She's your biggest fan.
- Well, and I'm hers.
We don't know what we would do
without her here at Chastain.
So, the scans show that there
are multiple metal fragments
peppered throughout
your abdomen.
And in surgery,
we'll remove every fragment
and we'll ensure
that the explosion
didn't cause any other injuries
that we can't see on the scans.
He's gonna be okay, right?
He's in the right place,
but of course you should know
surgery carries risks.
And, Jessica,
I know it's your day off,
but I would like you
to scrub in with me.
'Cause, after all,
you are my right hand.
You couldn't keep me out.
Great.
Just gonna get this.
- Okay.
- Yeah?
Ready?
Promise me he'll be okay, Jess.
Try not to worry. We're gonna
take great care of him.
Okay.
I love you so much,
and I am so, so sorry
I talked you into that cannon.
I love you.
It's okay.
Are you sure you're up
for this, Dr. Bell?
It's just, the last time
we worked together,
you didn't feel well
and you abandoned the surgery.
You haven't been in the OR
since then.
Yeah, no, I haven't been well.
And I can explain
all that to you later,
but the important thing is,
we figured out the problem,
and I've been cleared
for surgery
by both Kit and Conrad, so.
I think we're okay.
Okay, through the fascia.
It looks like a little oozing
from the liver.
I'll get better exposure now.
How are you doing, Dr. Bell?
All good.
Okay, one piece of shrapnel: Gone.
And another.
I'm having trouble getting it.
I got it.
It's such delicate work.
Nice going.
- Now, what is that?
- Oh, that
looks like another
piece of shrapnel.
This time it's wedged
into the liver.
Removing the foreign body now.
Suction.
Lap pads.
Looks like this went
into the liver and hit a vessel.
You guys got into something big.
I'm maxing my pressors.
It's gonna be okay.
Initiating massive
transfusion protocol.
Okay, Dr. Devi, I need you
to help me get down to the aorta
to cross-clamp,
and get control of this.
I'm transfusing the second unit
of blood, four liters
of crystalloid,
two of albumin,
and still losing.
- Blood pressure isn't budging.
- Okay, we're gonna need
supraceliac control.
Page AJ stat for a thoracotomy.
He's on deck in the OR suite.
I'm calling him now.
Good, thank you.
No blood pressure detected,
but HR reading 160.
All right, somebody talk to me.
Thank you for coming so fast.
Unavoidable bleeding
after shrapnel removal.
We need better control
from above
to be able to repair the defect.
- That's why we called you.
- All right, let's get to it.
Scalpel me.
Spreaders.
Clamp.
All right.
Voilà, that should do it.
We've got a blood pressure back.
All right.
Glad you're in the house.
Hey, man, glad to be here.
Any available resident to ICU Three.
Available resident to ICU Three.
Hey, look,
if you're gonna ask me
to back off surgery again,
that's okay,
but I want
to say I called in AJ
because we needed him,
not because of the MS.
I know, and Will is alive
because you made that call.
I just wanted to say
welcome back.
Thanks.
It's good to be back.
Dr. Sutton?
Do you have a moment?
Sure.
It's been a while since
I've approached the brain
from this direction.
I could use a break.
Just trying to get
my muscle memory to kick in.
I wanted to chat with you
some more about the idea
of double-boarding
with cardio and neuro.
Go on.
I know you think I'm crazy...
And so does Devon...
But people said the same thing
to me when I decided
to become a surgeon
with dyslexia.
Yes, but it's not
the same thing.
Maintaining excellence in both
specialties is impossible.
Expertise comes from repetition,
which is why this IR procedure
is so tough.
And trying to maintain
competency in both,
it isn't enough.
Okay, but I...
Listen, I have
to get back to this.
Let's talk about it later, okay?
Okay.
You're not gonna believe this.
What am I looking at?
The Enhanced Dreams
Instagram page.
This surgery was live
this morning.
And that might even be Charli.
At Enhanced Dreams,
dreams really do come true,
as we give you nothing
but the hottest transformation.
Right, Doc?
- Oh, yeah.
- Look at all that
beautiful liquid gold
the doctor's harvesting.
That's human fat,
which will be used
to sculpt a gorgeous
new rear end.
Let me hear you say "thicc."
They need to be stopped.
Patient was awake?
She likely gave permission
to film it.
Maybe, but Enhanced Dreams
is run by a dermatologist,
not a plastic surgeon.
It's got to be illegal.
Eh, you would think,
but it's not.
Anyone with a medical license
can perform
cosmetic surgery in Georgia.
Chalk it up to ridiculous things
that are legal in medicine.
We got you, Charli.
We got you, we got you.
We got you.
She's stroking out.
- Page Billie!
- Shouldn't we get a CT
with contrast
to figure out where?
No time. It's localized
to the left middle
cerebral artery.
That's the best we can give
Billie right now.
Let's get her to IR.
Nice to hear from you.
So, you have news
about the board seats?
I do.
Dr. Bell, we received
an accusation from, uh,
your hospital about one
of our top candidates.
Well, if you're talking
about Porter,
I gather there were some
ethics complaints against him,
but I
assumed you were aware.
No, this is new.
The credibility of the source
is the issue.
It came from the same person
who wrote your recommendation
at Chastain.
Dr. Sutton?
Conflict of interest here is
obvious. And it's
not a stretch to imagine
you helped motivate this.
Well, I assure you, I did not.
Sadly, that's hard to believe.
So we can no longer offer you
a position
on the state medical board.
The optics
could not be worse.
Thanks for the call.
I reached the mom.
She took Charli's son
to Disney World
while she had surgery.
Apparently, Charli's desperate
for more followers.
If she hits 200K,
she can make cash, quit her job,
and get a place
for her son and her.
So she decided to get
a Brazilian butt lift?
Her mom said she's always coming
up with ideas to look better.
She thinks that's how
she'll get more followers.
No one could talk her out of it.
Do they know how sick she is?
Her mom does.
Hasn't told the kid.
Hopefully she won't have to.
Hey, Billie, can we talk?
Can it wait? I'm due in IR.
No, it can't. I got a call from
the lieutenant governor saying
you filed a complaint
against Robert Porter.
That was supposed
to be anonymous.
Well, what was?
What the hell's going on?
I can't think
- about this right now...
- Well, look, look,
whatever this is,
I mean, they think
that I put you up to it,
because you signed
my letter of recommendation.
And now the state medical board
is siding with Porter and...
Cutting me.
Billie, we have a patient
waiting. Let's go.
So?
I've got to go.
How'd your IR practice go?
We'll find out.
Well, don't worry.
I know this anatomy well.
It's heartbreaking that this
young woman put her life at risk
for more followers.
It was also to give her son
a better life.
It's sad she believed this was
her best option to do that.
Just at the takeoff to
the left middle cerebral artery.
Come on, Billie.
Dr. Sutton,
you're turned around.
You're in
the right-sided circulation.
I know where I am.
The patient has
left-sided weakness.
We need to get to the right side
- of the brain.
- She's confusing
- the patient's symptoms.
- All of the patient's deficits
were on the right,
which means the embolism
has to be on the left.
Neuroanatomy 101.
Damn it. Where am I?
What's happening?
Looks like she's freezing up.
She never loses focus like this.
It's all right.
We're almost there.
Right here is the left anterior
cerebral artery.
And here is the takeoff
to the middle cerebral artery.
There you go, Billie.
She found the embolism.
And now they pull it out?
Yeah.
It's safer than breaking it up.
She's gonna be okay now, right?
If they got there in time.
Thanks for having my back.
Anytime.
You okay?
No.
I'm furious with myself.
Do you want to talk about it?
Not really.
But this is a clear example
of why you can't double-board
in these two fields.
I don't understand.
My mind was
a million miles away.
Dr. Austin juggles
multiple specialties.
He's triple-boarded.
Not in neurosurgery.
This is as high-risk and complex
as any surgery gets.
If you try and do this
and anything else,
the result will be catastrophic.
I rise to challenges.
Okay? It's who I am.
A challenge is good.
A suicide mission is not.
And in this case,
the person you'd kill
would be the one on the table.
- But you haven't even g...
- Leela,
you may need to ask yourself
why you are putting up mountains
too big for anyone to climb.
Is that your final answer?
Honestly, it would be anyone's.
Thanks again for your help.
I had to tell Randolph
after what Beaumont said.
I'm so sorry, Billie.
I should have realized
this could happen.
But it shouldn't have.
You were promised
confidentiality.
And the lieutenant governor
broke
that promise.
It's just outrageous.
So what do I do now?
You said you could prove
your charges against Porter.
I can.
But it means devastating
emotional repercussions
for the other person involved.
Oh, Billie, I understand.
But if you don't,
I fear the repercussions for you
could be far worse.
Accusers destroy
the person accusing them.
That's how it works.
Jess.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
I am just so happy
that he's okay.
That was really stressful.
Oh, God, you would not believe
things that people are saying
about me and Will.
"Let's just hope the husband
is shooting blanks now
so these two nitwits can't bring
a second child into the world."
Will is fine. You'll have
plenty more children,
if you want them.
In a couple of days,
these vultures
will be attacking someone else.
I'm thinking of making T-shirts
with the worst comments
printed on them.
Truth is,
I feel like I kinda deserve it.
You don't.
Well, it's just...
The only opinion of me that
really matters, besides Will's,
is yours.
- And I just hope that you're not...
- Scarlett,
you are my sister.
I love you, no matter what.
I feel like there's always
a "no matter what" with me.
You were great at anything
you put your mind to.
The only thing I put my mind to
were boys and parties.
And you never needed
anyone's approval but your own.
And Mom told me I wouldn't need
so much attention
if I just took a page out
of your book.
Oh, Scarlett.
You are a ray of sunshine.
And you bring it to Will,
and he loves you for it.
But?
But maybe nix the T-shirt idea.
No sense in feeding the trolls.
And definitely a hard no
on backyard explosives.
That's sound advice.
We still don't know
if it's a boy or a girl.
Well, if you must know
he's a little boy.
I saw the weenie
on the ultrasound.
What?
- Scarlett.
- What?
So why the party?
Is that a serious question?
Do you not know your sister?
Hiya, honey.
Hey.
Can you squeeze my hands?
Squeeze, squeeze, squeeze.
Good.
All right.
What happened?
Well, in a nutshell, the fat
from your Brazilian butt lift
swam to your brain
and it almost paralyzed you.
Oh, my God.
Oh, God.
I feel like such an idiot.
I shouldn't have done it.
I just... I saw this thing
on Instagram
- and...
- Oh, we know it.
Frustratingly legal and yet
criminally unqualified.
They had these glamour shots,
and I just thought that
damn, if I could look like that
You could get more followers?
We spoke to your mom.
She knows?
Yep.
But she also knows
that you're gonna be okay.
And Daniel? My-my son.
He's probably so scared right now.
It's up to you what you tell him.
Thank you.
So, how does it look?
Sorry, how does what look?
I hope it looks dope,
like, after all that.
Well, when you are up
and around,
you can decide for yourself.
Oh, can I have my phone, please?
Yeah.
People need to know about this.
I got to grab Gigi.
I'll catch you guys later.
Thank you.
People, I almost died, y'all.
But I didn't. I didn't.
Okay, so I'm here to tell you,
if you are going to get a BBL
or any other procedure,
make sure your doc knows what
the hell they're doing. Okay?
So, sit back, relax
and let me tell you
my crazy story, okay?
Now, I am an optimist by nature,
but I'm beginning to think
we are screwed as a species.
Social media
is gonna be our meteor.
Wow.
You sound like an angry old man
on the wrong side
of the generation gap.
Angry, yes. Old, no.
Mm, come on, Dr. Austin.
Disco didn't destroy society.
Without social media,
there would be no, uh,
Arab Spring.
Systemic racism
might've never been exposed.
What about that girl
that saved herself by learning
the "help me" gesture
- on TikTok?
- Oh. Right.
And all the swag you get
when your followers leap up.
Who follows you?
And why?
Man's got moves.
50,000 views?
They just seem to be climbing
by the second.
Have you no shame?
Whatever you do, Nolan,
just do not get a BBL.
Why would I?
Hey.
Thanks for collecting her.
my pleasure.
It's amazing how well she plays.
I swear, most kids
are so hooked on devices,
they never learn how.
Well, she won't be using any
until at least college.
Good luck with that.
Daddy, look.
Oh, what's Mr. Giraffe
doing now?
Can't you tell?
He didn't pick up his toys,
so you sent him to his room.
Zoo.
Mr. Giraffe lives in the zoo.
Right.
Let's spring him from his cage
and go get your "carbon-ye-ara."
Yes.
Bye.
- Bye, Gigi.
- Bye.
I won't hurt you.
I'm here to warn you.
Withdraw the complaint,
say you lied for Dr. Bell,
and you'll never hear
from me again.
You're scared.
Withdraw it
or I will destroy you.
You can't destroy me.
You killed a part of me
I can never get back.
You can never hurt me again.
Don't count on it.
I'm fully aware
of your mistakes.
I'll expose all of them.
And I will take away the
very thing you love the most,
your career.