Previously, on
"The Resident"...
Mom, we need to get you back
to Chastain.
Your mother has lung cancer.
You cannot come
to Nigeria with me.
- I do want your job.
- I wouldn't want a resident who didn't.
We're cut from the same cloth.
No hidden agendas.
There have been some
developments in gene therapy.
Recent clinical trials
with good outcomes.
These are uncharted waters.
A lot of hospitals won't
risk hosting our trials.
It's gonna be a long, hard road.
- And nothing is guaranteed, Rose.
- But I have a chance?
Well, you have more than just
a chance,
you have a damn good chance.
"Easiest Thing" by Jean Deaux
playing...
♪ It's been so long ♪
- ♪ I think I might ♪
- Hey.
♪ Write you a letter ♪
- ♪ I can't be mad... ♪
- Thought you were making a shopping list.
I am.
I was also just
enjoying the view.
Okay.
But your mani-pedi appointment
is on the other side of town
from your pregnancy message.
We got to plan it out if we want
to hit everything today.
You just finished
a night shift.
Are you sure
you're not too tired?
To knock out
a pre-baby bucket list
with my glowing wife?
- Never.
- Mm.
You can say no if you want,
because it's your day.
But what if we make
a pit stop at home?
Someone told me alone time
will be hard to come by
- once the baby is born.
- Hmm.
I will definitely consider it.
Mm, good.
Then let's get
the hell out of here.
Oh, you want to see
the new baby picture?
Of course.
Aw, another sonogram.
Let me see.
Aw, it's a fat little potato
with fists.
Did you just call my child
a fat little potato?
A cute, fat little potato.
- Thank you.
- I don't think that's a compliment.
No, I was thanking her
for helping
- plan our day.
- A fabulous nail studio,
a massage to die for
and I got you off the wait list
at Marino's Steak House.
You have a table at 8:00.
You are the best.
Why don't you come meet us?
No way. Conrad wants you
all to his lonesome.
Yes, I do.
- And I'm here till midnight.
- Oh, God.
Have fun.
- No, no, no, no, no, no, we're leaving.
- Wait, what's up?
My shift is over
and you're on maternity leave.
Hang on,
what's going on?
Mr. Goldense canceled
his appointment,
third time this year.
And I've called,
but it only goes to machine.
You're the only one
he'll talk to.
Nic, don't do it.
Oh, come on,
you know, Pete Goldense.
History of A-fib.
He has cardiac meds
that need close monitoring.
We can go check it out.
It's not a problem.
You're impossible.
- It'll take two seconds.
- Okay.
I wonder if it'll be this
hard to say no
to our daughter.
- Probably.
- Yep.
Here's the problem, Dr. Voss.
We're still far in the red,
north of $25 million.
Well, the numbers are trending
in the right direction.
When I took over,
we were $35 million in the red.
No one wants to put a price
on saving lives.
But as CEO, you must.
I am not like other CEOs.
Which is why you hired me.
And now we're beginning
to question the wisdom
of putting someone with no
business experience at the helm.
You need to find more cuts,
Dr. Voss.
And we don't mean pennies.
We mean millions.
This isn't coming from me
or the board, Kit.
We're getting pressure
from the state.
They have given us...
And by "us," I mean you...
Two weeks to come up
with big solutions.
You okay?
Come take a look at this.
This was the scan
from my mother's diagnosis,
when she was stage IV
with pleural mets.
Mm-hmm.
And this...
is today.
Wow, that much progression?
Her lung cancer
is highly aggressive.
So sorry. I, um...
Has she started chemo?
She watched her father die
of cancer.
She remembers vomiting
and constant nausea.
He was in pain for months
until he died.
She is terrified of chemo.
Well, they do much better
managing side effects
these days.
Surgery's not an option.
There's only one hope left.
Well, targeted therapy.
It could buy my mother years
if she's a candidate.
We're waiting
for the genetics now.
Well, just, it's...
Keep me updated.
Yeah.
Hi.
Hey.
I've got a birthday present
for you.
Mm. My birthday isn't
until June.
Well, this is your new birthday.
500 million
genetically modified cells
ready to change your life
by making healthy
red blood cells in your body.
If we're lucky.
I know it's experimental and
there are no guarantees, but...
I can't believe
I have this chance.
Is there anyone you want to call
or FaceTime
for the big moment?
Friends? Family?
No.
Dr. Cain?
He, um...
hasn't been by for a while.
I'm sure he's busy.
Well, this is a really big deal.
You went through a lot
to get to this moment.
I wouldn't be here without you.
Rose...
...would you like
to do the honors?
Please work.
*THE RESIDENT*
Season 04  Episode 12
Episode Title: "Hope in the Unseen"
Aired on: May 05, 2021
We started her gene therapy
an hour ago.
Now we wait.
Is she strong? Is she ready?
She's been through
a massive chemo blast
that devastated her bone marrow.
She's nauseous.
Her counts are dropping.
Her mouth sores are so bad
she can barely swallow.
So is she strong? No.
But she is the bravest person
I've ever known,
and she's ready.
Look, man,
Bio South is running on fumes.
Uh, we need cash,
and we won't get a new investor
if Rose has a bad outcome, so...
Everything is riding on this.
Look, if this works,
we stand to get FDA approval.
And then sky's the limit.
Thousands of other patients
with sickle cell disease
would line up
for this treatment.
And if it fails?
The company will shutter.
I will be bankrupt.
And Rose will have risked
her life for nothing.
You recommended me
to Dr. Wylie.
Yeah, she was in the market
for a... promising resident.
But you said
that I could work with you,
that we were a pair,
cut from the same cloth.
You need more practice.
And I'm focusing on my recovery.
You're not gonna get your skills
back hiding in this office.
I'm being cautious.
The last time I was in the OR,
you had to step in there
to save my ass.
Can't ignore that.
So you start with a softball,
something simple you used to do
in your sleep.
Can't afford another fumble.
Kit's gonna send me packing.
I have to know that,
when I come back,
my work is gonna be perfect.
Dr. Wylie is nowhere near
the surgeon you are.
I want to learn from the best.
Caution's not a good look
on you.
In case you don't remember,
Pete's not the easiest guy.
Took the gold medal
in the curmudgeon Olympics.
Well, if it doesn't take too
long, we can stay on schedule.
Hey, Pete! It's Nic
from Chastain.
I'm here with Dr. Hawkins.
Came to check on you.
We're worried that you missed
your appointment.
I'll survive.
You know your cardiac medication
needs monitoring.
Come on, Pete.
We'll do a quick check
and then you won't have to go
to the hospital.
Put those masks and gloves on.
Okay.
You know, if you'd get
the COVID-19 vaccine,
you wouldn't have
to be so nervous about guests.
I have no need.
I have no risk of exposure.
I see no one.
It's Middle-earth.
Needs a dragon.
You all right?
Yeah.
How long since
you've been out of your house?
Over a year.
How you feeling, Pete?
I just woke up
from a nap, so a little groggy.
The good news is I can take naps
whenever I damn well please.
I see the judgment
in your faces. Proves my point.
You've never known real freedom
till you lock your door.
Look, no judgment.
We're just worried about you.
You're a little out of breath.
Why don't you
let us check you out,
just make sure
nothing serious, okay?
Okay.
- All right.
- But first,
let me get something to drink.
- I'm thirsty.
- No, no, that's okay.
I'll-I'll get you some water.
Fridge is close to empty.
Pulse is irregular and rapid.
Crackles at the bases.
Oh...
Hey.
You having
trouble wearing shoes?
When you don't go anywhere,
you don't need shoes.
Distended neck veins.
Sorry, Pete, but we're gonna
have to get you
to Chastain after all.
No.
- You can't make me go.
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Pete?
- Calling 911.
- Pete?
You'd work much quicker
if you had gloves that fit.
What is this,
the JNCO jeans of surgical wear?
Oh, I'm sorry, Dr. Devi,
did we get you the wrong size gloves?
It's totally okay.
It is not totally okay.
Speak up for yourself.
A six and a half
would be great next time.
You got it. I think we're just
so used to prepping the OR
for Dr. Austin and Dr. Okafor...
And how would you think
that she could even fit in Mina's gloves?
Look at this one-handed tie.
Sloppy at best.
Criminal at worst.
And whenever we would do
a bypass,
Dr. Okafor and I chose
the pedicled approach.
That means there is a bit
to clean up,
so I would throw a stitch
and Mina would cut my suture.
Not there. Higher.
No, that's too high. Lower.
Like this?
Would you steady
your hands, Devi?
This is not a cadaver.
It's a father of three.
Damn it!
You cut the vessel I needed.
I'm sorry, Dr. Austin.
Is an apology
gonna console his children?
Small vascular clamp
and 8.0 Prolene.
Not to her.
To me.
I have to learn.
You stay, you watch...
or you leave.
It's your call.
Like this.
Nothing more satisfying than
teaching the important stuff
to young residents.
The day isn't going great.
I messed up in the OR
with Raptor,
and he yelled at me,
again.
Did you kill someone?
- No.
- Then don't worry about it.
I don't like to be humiliated.
It wasn't about you,
I promise.
He's under a lot of pressure
right now, a family thing.
Believe me, he's on a razor's
edge for a good reason.
I'm sorry.
So what's the hospital's CEO
doing in here, anyway?
Bit of a challenging day
on my end, as well.
The supply room
is a known resource
when you're at your wit's end.
It's quiet, private,
lots of pillows.
Come on, come with me.
I'll get you into another OR.
Dr. Austin isn't the only
fine surgeon at Chastain.
Dr. Voss?
I would love to work
with you sometime.
Well, if my ass isn't fired
shortly, we'll arrange it.
Come on.
Hey, Cindy. What happened?
You paged?
She has an elevated temp. 100.1.
- And she's tachy.
- Yeah.
Hey, Rose?
Can you tell me
how you're feeling?
Tired, a little hot.
Let's give her a gram
of acetaminophen
and bolus her a liter
of lactated ringers.
Okay.
It doesn't hurt anywhere.
It's not like a pain
I've felt before.
But I don't feel good.
It couldn't be
the gene therapy, could it?
I don't know yet.
We'll give you some fluid and
order a set of blood cultures.
I thought there was nothing left
that could scare me.
Whatever happens,
we'll manage it.
It's not that.
I know what it is to be sick.
But hope?
When I pressed that button,
it's what I felt.
And I haven't felt that
in so long.
I don't want to lose it.
65-year-old male with syncope
and blunt abdominal trauma.
All right,
let's put him in Bay Two.
BP 90/50,
heart rate 130 and irregular.
02 sat 95%.
I fell on a chair. So what?
I thought you two were spending
a day away from sick people.
Well, best-laid plans...
- One, two, three.
- Three.
Nothing good can come of this.
Told you.
I'll order an EKG and labs.
Crackles halfway up.
- I need an X-ray stat.
- Yeah.
- And I might have to intubate.
- Okay.
Pete,
this isn't good,
and we have to fix it.
Tenderness and guarding
in the right upper quadrant.
Damn it. Free fluid.
He's on blood thinners
that weren't being monitored.
And now he's bleeding
into his abdomen.
Dr. Wylie already has
three residents.
Yep. And I told
you I didn't want the gig.
I need you and only you,
for a softball.
Aneurysm clip, OR 7,
in 15 minutes.
Dr. Wylie?
I'm gonna have to pass.
Dr. Cain has requested me.
Hey. What's going on with Rose?
Elevated temps.
She's tachycardic.
Her blood pressure is dropping.
I called in her oncologist
to examine her.
- How is she?
- Responding to fluids.
Stable for now.
If this is
a systemic inflammatory reaction
from the cells,
we support her through it,
and she should improve soon.
Okay. I'll keep an eye on her.
Okay, I have to see
another patient,
but tell me if anything changes.
Thank you.
Yee, if you don't sit down...
Your cancer is getting worse.
When we know the next steps,
I'll sit.
- So, until then...
- Your father has zero chill.
- Tell me about it.
- And at the moment,
mine is in limited supply, too.
Hello, Carol. Yee.
Lovely to see you.
Okay, Dr. Oliver, we can
dispense with the niceties.
- We're dying here.
- Literally.
- Carol.
- This will be short
and very sweet.
I am happy to say
that Carol's cancer
has a mutation
that qualifies her
for targeted therapy.
Thank you.
You hear that, Ma?
This is incredible.
Conventional chemo
is better than it used to be,
but it's still a blunt tool.
Targeted therapy
is exactly what the name says.
It attacks only the changes
in the cancer cells
that help it grow and spread
while sparing your normal cells.
And what does this mean for me?
I mean,
I know it's not a cure, but...
You still have stage IV cancer,
but we are buying time.
The cancer
will eventually come back,
but by then, we could have new
and even better treatments.
Mom.
Mom, this is great news.
So, the CT you ordered
showed a grade III liver lac.
- What's his most recent hemoglobin?
- 12.2.
The second one
should be back any minute.
Any guesses why he passed out
in the first place?
- No idea. It was so abrupt.
- Doesn't make sense.
So, what accounts
for the respiratory failure?
It's all a mystery.
His EKG and echo show evidence
of severe pulmonary hypertension
with right-sided heart strain,
and that's all new
from a year ago.
We thought it could be a P.E.,
but he's been
on his blood thinners,
- so it's unlikely.
- Severe pulmonary hypertension?
So we don't want to put this guy
under anesthesia.
Not if we can help it.
Lab just called
with a critical value.
Repeat hemoglobin 7.2.
He's bleeding out.
We don't have a choice.
Okay, yeah. Pack him up.
Get blood on hold.
Lots of blood. And
I'll meet him in the OR.
On it.
Randolph.
- A favor?
- Yeah. Sure, but quickly.
I have to prep a patient
for surgery.
I have
a first-year surgical intern
in need of a new mentor.
He have a falling-out
with someone?
She. Yes, and sort of.
AJ let her have it in his OR.
That's understandable.
AJ's under a lot of stress.
He is, which is why
I would be eternally grateful
if you could have her
in your surgeries today.
Yeah. Is she any good?
Judge for yourself.
Solid technique. Fast.
Clearly determined.
She's whip-smart, too.
Her name's Leela Devi.
Dr. Devi? I'm Randolph Bell.
How'd you like to throw
some of those in my OR?
I would love to.
Great. Let's go.
Rose, Rose,
you've got to settle down.
I don't... feel good.
Rose, steady.
Deep breaths.
- What happened?
- Well, she was holding her own,
and then her blood pressure
plummeted to 70/40.
Okay, give her another liter,
wide open.
- Mm-hmm.
- And start her on norepi.
- I'm so hot!
- That's because you have a fever.
I have to examine you again,
okay?
Ow!
- Fever.
- Mm-hmm.
Hypotension, abdominal pain.
I don't think
this is from the gene therapy.
Rose, the chemo has suppressed
your immune system.
I think you have a bad
infection, likely from your gut.
So what... happens now?
We're gonna get you
on the right antibiotics.
All you have to do
is get some rest.
You stay hopeful.
Okay?
Aneurysm clip.
Proximal and distal clips
in place.
Now I'll ligate the aneurysm.
Oh, I trapped the aneurysm.
I'm certain
I did that correctly.
I don't... I don't understand
why this is happening.
Find the feeder vessel...
I don't need instruction
from a resident.
Cerebral perfusion pressure
is falling.
Get back in there, or this'll be
the last brain you ever touch.
Suction.
Need to see
what we're dealing with.
There's the feeder. Clip?
Nice work, Dr. Cain.
Yeah, please.
I almost whiffed a softball.
You close.
I'm finished here.
Maybe he is finished.
If so, no one will miss him.
His hands are back.
But surgeons thrive on hubris.
The problem now is in his head.
I got your page.
Hey, it wasn't the gene therapy.
Rose's blood cultures came back
positive. She's septic.
- And how's she doing?
- We started her on the right
antibiotics early.
She's stable now.
But her kidneys took a hit.
Take a look.
Is she making urine?
I have flooded her with fluids,
but no.
Her potassium is climbing.
Rose needs dialysis if she's
gonna make it past this crisis.
Lap pad to me.
Have you ever operated
on a liver lac?
Never as first assist,
but I've read a lot about it.
Okay, well, then tell me about
the blood supply of the liver.
Another lap pad.
Liver has dual blood supply...
Portal vein and the hepatic.
Mm-hmm.
All right, Dr. Devi.
Diffuse bleeding
from the liver. You're on.
- What do you want to do?
- Manual compression.
I take the liver in my hand,
and squeeze it.
Okay, now do it.
It's not working.
He's still bleeding.
So what's your next move?
I identify
and suture the bleeder?
Dr. Bell, our patient
- isn't enjoying this teaching moment.
- I think
- you should take over.
- No, there's no need
to take over.
We're a team.
3.0 Prolene to Dr. Devi.
I saw you do this perfectly.
It's muscle memory.
Just do it. Don't think.
And if you have trouble,
I'm right here.
Mm-hmm.
Suction.
Well done, Dr. Devi.
Now, let's hope
Nic and Conrad can diagnose
Pete's underlying problem.
It was touch and go in surgery.
He's on two pressors now.
- Water.
- Oh, thank you.
So, Bell fixed his liver lac,
but that's still the least
of his problems.
Did his rheumatological studies
come back?
Yep. All normal.
He'll need a right heart cath
to measure
his pulmonary pressure.
I'll check with Cardio
on that and schedule
a chest angio with CT.
If we can't figure out
the underlying cause
- of his pulmonary hypertension...
- There are treatment options,
and we'll have to start looking
into them, but...
he could die.
Wait.
When I went to get Pete water,
all I saw in his kitchen
was rice and beans.
Only rice and beans.
No vegetables? No fruits?
None.
I mean, I know it seems crazy,
a one-in-a-million case, but...
Pete's suffering
from a vitamin deficiency.
Think about it. He's been shut
in from COVID this whole time.
That explains
the pulmonary hypertension.
Nic, you may have just
saved his life.
Dialysis?
My kidneys are failing?
I've had family members
on dialysis,
and they were miserable.
It's devastating news, I know,
but I think
it's gonna be temporary.
Okay? I-I really...
I really do, Rose.
We have to give your kidneys
time to recover.
And if they don't?
Remember, Rose,
we're focusing on hope.
Look at me.
I am about out of hope.
I am out of everything.
Just answer the question,
please.
If your kidneys don't recover,
you will be on dialysis
for the rest of your life.
Is dying
from renal failure painful?
- No, it is not, but that's not where...
- Look,
I appreciate everything
that you and Dr. Voss have done,
but I am too tired
to go on any further.
Rose, no.
Rose, you're not gonna be alone.
I'm going to be with you
the whole time.
I have nothing left.
No dialysis, no anything.
Rose, giving up
is not the answer.
You have to fight,
you have to fight this
and hold on to
what your life could be
when this is behind you.
I don't have any fight left.
Call in hospice... please.
I gave it my best shot.
It's over.
I can't do this anymore.
I told you I didn't want
to come here. They filleted me
like a dead fish,
and now I'm farting
like a ten-year-old
Labrador retriever.
Pete, if Dr. Bell hadn't
operated, you would have died.
So the blame's on me?
I didn't eat right.
Food as medicine.
What a crock.
It's not a crock.
Not having
enough vitamin C in your diet
can be life-threatening.
It can increase the pressure
in the vessels
leading from your heart
to your lungs,
causing pulmonary hypertension.
And that explains the strain
on your heart.
Which caused shortness
of breath, the swelling.
The lack of vitamin C
also explains the bruising.
I get the gist.
You want the big dose of,
uh, gratitude.
Okay, here it goes.
Big thanks.
Here's the bag, Nic.
- Thank you.
- That's my vitamin C?
What about
a nice chewable tablet?
The kind I gave my kids?
If we're right about this,
we should see a change
in the numbers immediately.
I'm not holding my breath.
So you have kids?
One more disappointment.
You're pregnant.
I have eyes.
You think it's gonna be all,
uh, hugs and kisses
and "I love you, Mommy,
with all my heart."
News flash: They become
teenagers, and they turn on you.
Then they spend the rest
of their lives griping
about that one birthday party
that didn't meet expectations.
You seeing what I'm seeing?
Pulmonary artery pressure
is still higher
than we'd like to see,
but it's coming down.
Feeling better, Pete?
Maybe.
A little.
Okay, great. We'll take that
as a rave review.
Nic's on maternity leave. I'll
be back to check on you, though.
Control that impulse
as much as possible.
We'll see you later, Pete.
Not the day we hoped for.
Eh, but the kind we live for.
Grumpy patient or not.
Gratitude not required.
Carol.
Your new
meds have just arrived.
Once a day
with a glass of water.
I'm glad I lived
to see this day.
And we hope
there'll be many more, Mom.
Enough to find the next miracle.
Science wins.
Thank you, Dr. Oliver.
Here, honey.
Thank you, son.
Listen, I got to, um,
finish up a couple of things,
but I'll be back
to walk you guys out, all right?
- Thank you.
- Of course.
- Hey.
- Evening.
Hey, I got the good news
about your mom.
I'm happy for you.
Thank you.
The medicine gods
were smiling down on us.
- Yeah, I love when that happens.
- Whew. Me, too.
Hey, by the way,
uh, Dr. Devi assisted me
on a liver lac today
and did some very good work
in a messy situation.
So, you know, if you don't mind,
I'd like to keep her in my OR.
Yeah.
Sure, she's all yours.
That's good news.
Thanks, man.
Rose is refusing dialysis.
- Why would she do that?
- I tried to convince her
to keep fighting,
but she won't hear me.
I thought maybe
she'd listen to you.
Will you talk to her?
What's that?
Meds to lower your potassium.
Oh, stop, stop.
No more medication.
- Rose...
- I'm refusing all treatment.
Leave me alone.
I know what you're gonna say.
Don't bother.
Devon said you're having
a rough time.
Rough time?
I know about a rough time.
This is...
There's a limit
to what a person can endure,
and I found it.
Yeah, I understand.
I get it.
After my accident,
I was on a vent.
Hopeless. Totally alone.
I wanted to die, too.
And I'm glad I didn't.
I don't want you to die,
either, Rose.
This dialysis...
No, I don't want it. No.
Dialysis may be temporary.
There's no reason not to try.
There's no guarantee.
It probably won't work.
The odds...
so long.
I can't. I can't.
Rose, you can.
You can.
I believe in you, Rose.
You're the strongest,
bravest person I know.
You just got to dig deep,
just for that last fight.
Just dig.
I promise you this, Rose.
If nothing works...
I won't let you suffer.
♪ I think
I've seen this film before ♪
♪ So I'm leaving
out the side door ♪
- ♪ So step right out ♪
- I promise.
♪ There is no amount of crying ♪
Can we start dialysis now?
♪ I can do for you ♪
♪ All this time ♪
♪ We always walked
a very thin line ♪
♪ You didn't even hear me out ♪
♪ You never gave
a warning sign. ♪
So, how about we celebrate
Mom getting targeted therapy
- at Dominick's?
- Ah, my favorite.
Son, you have no idea
how proud we are of you.
Operating on all those patients
and still finding time
to look after your mother.
Such good care.
So compassionate.
You are a shining example
of what a doctor should be.
AJ...
you're heartbroken over Mina.
You still do your job
with grace and dignity.
I'm so proud of you.
Hey, thanks, guys.
You know, I just realized
there's one more thing
I need to do before I leave.
I'll meet you guys
at Dominick's.
- All right?
- Okay.
Dr. Devi.
Dr. Austin.
Before you yell at me again,
I know my dexterity
wasn't up to par.
I'm working to change that.
Well, that's a promising start.
Listen...
Excuse me, but I'm not finished.
I understand your last resident
was superhuman.
I'm sorry you find me
a poor replacement.
I will work as hard as I can,
but there is no doubt
I'm mortal.
You will witness mistakes.
Verbal abuse won't help.
I do better
with constructive criticism.
And if that doesn't work
for you,
Dr. Bell has offered
to take your place as my mentor.
Well, he can't have you.
True, your dexterity needs
a little bit of love,
but your determination
and your work ethic
are quite admirable.
Now, if I may...
I came back to apologize.
I can't expect you to do things
the way I want them done
if I don't take the time
to show you, right?
So tomorrow morning,
I have an aortic valve replacement
at 8:00 a.m.
"Bright" and "early"
are the key words.
Will you join me?
I will see you bright and early.
Good.
Hey.
You're still here this late.
How's Rose doing?
She's better.
She was brewing an infection,
but, um...
Her kidneys took a hit,
but she's okay.
So it wasn't the therapy cells?
- No, it wasn't.
- Ah, that's a relief.
For all of us.
Though we're not thrilled
she's on dialysis.
- I think it's temporary.
- Another good sign.
Thank you, Pravesh,
for hanging in.
It's much appreciated.
Yeah.
Rose is my priority, too.
Marshall.
This is Phillip Bondman,
the founder of Bio South Labs,
the company we partnered with
for our sickle cell
clinical trial.
Mm. Kit has great things
to say about you.
Please, have a seat.
Marshall is chairman
of the board at Chastain.
Dr. Pravesh told me
you're looking
for an angel investor
in return for a stake
in the company.
Kit has proposed that Chastain
become that angel investor,
and I'm interested.
We could inject cash
into Bio South right away,
and the hospital
would share in your risk
as well as
the potential returns.
You understand the risk is real
with Bio South?
We are still speculative.
Chastain needs
new sources of revenue badly.
Yes, it's a risky investment,
but if we are going to spend
our risk currency,
it will be on someone who's
looking to do good in the world.
That, and your product
seems promising.
With enough cash,
we believe you can do more.
This-this sounds like a godsend.
Could be a perfect partnership.
"Lightning" by Mehro playing...
You don't have to do this,
you know.
I do not break promises
to my wife.
You were promised
a spa day...
and you will get a spa day.
Okay.
I researched.
And apparently, the spas
put fruits and vegetables
in their water.
That's a very nice touch.
Thank you.
All right.
Okay, we have got...
Passionate Peach...
Baby-Oh-Baby Pink...
...and Redder than Red.
I mean, I think Baby-Oh-Baby
seems appropriate.
Baby-Oh-Baby it is.
♪ Nothing's gonna wake me up ♪
♪ I'm falling asleep
with you lying next to me... ♪
Oh!
♪ Nothing's gonna wake me up ♪
♪ Not even the thunder... ♪
Have I told you that I love you?
You know what, not often enough.
Well, I love you.
♪ I'm falling asleep ♪
♪ With you lying next to me... ♪
♪ Nothing's gonna
wake me up... ♪
You're not supposed
to get the skin.
This is why I'm not a surgeon.
That's not bad.
♪ Not even the lightning. ♪
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Sync corrections by srjanapala