Mark? Mark, are you asleep?
Wake up, sleepy
one. It's your wife.
What?
Where?
On the phone.
Oh. Yeah. Thanks.
Hello?
Jen? Jen?
Did I hang up?
Hi, Rachel. Hi, honey.
Is Mommy calling me?
Doug already gone?
Still sleeping.
Of course it's me.
What do you mean I sound funny?
Can I talk to Mommy?
How does this look?
My ankle.
Well, can she talk while
she gets your Froot Loops?
Uh, the ankle
looks... uh, healed.
Uh, listen, Rachel,
is uh, is Mommy, uh,
does she seem a little mad?
Jen, hi.
You're up early.
Wow, what a nice surprise.
Yeah. Hmm...
Oh, yeah. We're on a
roll now, aren't we, Susie?
Yes.
Okay.
Yeah. Yes, yes, yes. Here we go.
Here we go.
Oh, boy. Good timing.
Okay, diapers.
Uh...
Um...
That's why God created
convenience stores, huh?
Yeah. Oh.
Yeah, it'll be okay, Susie.
I promise, okay?
I don't want a loaner. I
want my own damn car.
Well, that's why Walter told
you to replace that starter.
Careful of those surgeon hands.
Jackie, look, I
can't be late today.
Oh? Doing a big
brain transplant?
It's my first gastroplasty,
and my whole day is backing up.
Mine too, okay?
I was counting on
you to take me to work.
So look, just let
Peanut take the car...
No, no, no. Peanut
doesn't touch my car.
Where is Walter?
How the hell long does it
take to do a test drive, anyway?
It's a Porsche.
He'll be a while.
And don't blame your
bad mood on Walter.
He tried to warn you.
About what?
Messing with a married woman.
Where's the loaner?
Oh, how can you sleep?
How can you sleep?
All right.
Uh, no. No thanks.
Doc?
You're my doc.
Come on. You, you
really saved my life.
You fixed my feet, remember?
Oh. Uh-huh. Right.
Listen, you used some Demerol.
Demerol. You used some Demerol.
Well, I don't have
any right now, so...
Okay. Well, listen,
I'm going to stop by
and see you again, okay?
I'm sure you will. Take care.
Okay. Yeah. Okay.
All right. Thanks.
Hey.
Hey!
You forgot these.
Oh! Oh, my God. Thanks.
Thank you. I'm in a rush.
Oh, oh. Is...
Is this a little boy
or a little girl?
Don't! Don't! She's
afraid of strangers.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
We're late. Thank you.
Oh, Carter, come on.
I've got gridlock already.
Where is Dr. Benton?
Three more night floats.
Well, can't we just
admit them now
and get Benton to
sign off on them later?
It's not up to me. Ask HAL.
Surgical co-sign incomplete.
Carter, what about
this gangrenous toe?
Waiting on Dr. Benton.
Carol, bet you're
glad to hear my voice.
Can you come in today?
No, it's not a dress code.
It's a suggestion.
Your appearance
should make patients
feel comfortable.
And what number of earrings
do you think wouldn't
upset my patients?
Two would be my
recommendation...
One in each ear.
So I shouldn't count
the one in my navel?
Or, uh...
anywhere else.
What is this?
Patients in the hall?
A diverticulitis, rule-out appy,
lap choly,
all waiting to be admitted.
Well, they can't wait out here.
Where's Dr. Benton?
He's, um...
Dr. Hicks.
Could you help
Mr. Carter with his admit?
Not right now.
Where's Dr. Benton?
On his way, on his way.
Yo!
This section is for surgeons.
Oh yeah?
Yeah. You need a
surgical sticker to park here.
And where's yours?
It's a loaner. Look, man, move.
I don't have time
to call security.
Look, find your own spot.
You can't park here.
Well, I am parked here,
so what are you going
to do about it... Doctor?
Shit! Damn!
Oh, my God, I am so late.
Slow morning, huh?
Thank goodness.
Susie! You look
100% cotton today.
Who makes this?
You know, I'm going to
run her upstairs real fast.
I'll be back in five.
Where is everyone?
Outside.
Some rush-hour traffic thing.
Uh...
Go on, I got her. Thanks.
Head-on collision.
Chest to steering
wheel. Head to dash.
GCS, 10. BP, 90/50. Pulse, 120.
Facial lacs, splint
to the left tib-fib.
Right ankle's funky too.
Any more coming in?
Child passenger. Ross has it.
Careful with this line.
I had to stick her
10 times to get it.
Where'd they take my mom?
Hey! Doctors are taking
care of your mom, okay?
How are you?
Only injury is a
bruise on his hip.
Kid was wearing a seat belt.
Well, he could
use one right now.
Okay, I'll check him out,
see if he's as
strong as he acts.
We got another one.
I'll pick you up, I guess...
about 8:00?
Okay.
Yeah? All right.
So, dinner last night went okay?
Let's get a CBC, type
and cross six units.
Get four units O-neg.
IV's infiltrated.
I'll start a central line.
Good morning, Susan.
We were starting to worry.
I'll do the IJ.
Let's get x-ray in here.
Cross-table C-spine,
chest, pelvis,
lower extremities.
Let's see what Dr. Greene needs.
Pulse, 120. Resps, 28.
Check the board, Susan.
I think you're assigned to
the bounce-back bellyache.
Pulse ox 90.
Increase oxygen, 15 liters.
Ooh.
There. That is a much
better look for you.
Dr. Weaver hasn't seen
you yet today, has she?
No. Why?
I just want to be there.
I thought you'd finished
your ride-alongs.
I did.
Ooh.
We were just going shopping.
Shep has to cook for
the station tomorrow.
Shep? His name is Shep?
You're saying the man cooks too?
Elvis had a dog named Shep.
They all cook.
Those dual-function gentlemen...
Hard to resist.
♪ When I was a lad And
old Shep was a pup ♪
♪ Over hill and
meadow they'd roam... ♪
Little more curl
to the lip. Yeah.
Please don't encourage him.
I need a GI cocktail for
Mr. Perry in Curtain 3.
Uh, can you give
me another minute,
and then I'll get
her up to day care?
Sure. We're having a ball.
How'd it go with the attorney?
I have to wait three months
before I can claim abandonment.
Well, maybe Chloe will
have second thoughts.
She left her own baby.
She's not entitled
to second thoughts.
Okay, Mr. Perry, I
ordered some medications.
If your pains are
gastrointestinal,
you'll get some relief.
The man had a heart attack.
Rita, stop. It was heartburn.
Given your husband's
diet last night,
gastritis seems likely.
He gets three-alarm chili
over spicy fries all the time.
Never bothered him before.
It could have been
the burrito grande during Leno.
She's a little freaked. My
old man had a coronary.
Uh-huh. You'll
need to lay off these.
There is a chance
your pain could be
cardiac related,
but we'll run some tests
to rule that out, okay?
How long will that take?
A few hours. You
have to be somewhere?
No, I was just wondering
when you serve
lunch around here. Mm.
Ah!
Hi.
Hey, hi. I had fun last night.
I told you you'd
like the mosh pit.
Are we still on for tonight?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Let's do something a little
less crowded, like food.
Food's good. Okay.
Carter?
Hi. Weaver nixed your
MRI on the John Doe
with the possible hand fracture.
I hate to agree with management,
but I think she's got a point.
You're right. You're
absolutely right.
I don't know what
I was thinking.
MRI? Huh.
How is it?
Completely healed,
you were in x-ray so long.
Need some more ice?
Is there a fracture?
No.
Oh! Looks like a dislocation
of the interphalangeal joint.
Tip of your index finger.
I know where it is, Carter.
Uh-huh. Well, it's
great there's no fracture.
I mean, you can forget
about today's gastroplasty, huh,
but a fracture,
that could have kept you
out of surgery for months.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa. What are you doing?
Have to numb it
and get it reduced,
make sure there's
no tendon damage.
You want me to
call somebody else?
Get on with it.
Must hurt like crazy.
Yeah.
Slammed it in the
car door, did you?
Yeah.
Carter, is Dr. Benton...
Uh, they need you in
Trauma 1, Peter, right away.
All right.
I can't find it either.
BP's falling. 70/30.
This guy's in fib.
Pulse 150. I can barely feel it.
What do we got?
Multiple trauma.
Hypovolemic shock.
Can't get a central line.
Cutdown time.
Carter will do it.
He's ready.
You're ready.
Okay, let's go.
Not the ankle, femoral,
and don't cut too deep.
The saphenous
is superficial here,
and believe me, you do
not want to transect it, okay?
Yeah.
Any luck with sitters?
I've got a few leads.
She needs a change, Joanie.
You know we don't recommend
extended care for infants.
Well, um, it's only temporary.
Chloe kind of
left me in a lurch.
Well, us too. Susie's bill
is three weeks overdue.
Uh, no, it's my bill, and
I'll pay you tomorrow.
All right, well, just
try and make it up
a couple of times today, okay?
Yes. Okay.
Okay. Bye-bye. Mmmm...
Yeah.
Save her noon bottle for me.
♪ Good morning to you
Good morning to you ♪
Uh, Randi, I have
a baby-sitter coming
around 4:00 for an interview.
Could you keep
an eye out for her?
You bet.
Did anyone find
you a lab coat yet?
Doesn't fit.
Tonight, it's going to
be just the two of us.
No Hulda?
She's off to Helsinki.
People come and go so quickly.
We will drink beer
and watch the Bears.
Dr. Ross, what
do we do with this?
She said she
didn't have to wait.
That's right.
This is a "Go directly
to Dr. Ross" card.
Is anybody in Iso?
I don't think so.
Hey, Mei-Sun.
How's our boy today?
Okay?
How are things going?
Uh, keeping busy.
I haven't seen Chloe lately.
None of us have.
How's she doing in school?
Well, you got a few minutes?
Mark, sorry to interrupt.
There's a patient
threatening to sue.
Wants to see whosever in charge.
Is it okay if I handle it?
Would you?
Bless you.
What were you saying?
No, I was just saying
how busy we've all been.
Excuse me.
I got a weak-and-dizzy
to check on.
I want to thank you
for giving me a chance
with that cut-down earlier.
I think it went pretty
smooth, don't you?
That was lidocaine
without epi, right?
Does it matter?
Joke. I'm joking. No epi.
How's it feel?
It's numb.
Okay. Get ready,
because I'm going to pull it.
Just do it.
Okay, point and flex.
Looks pretty good.
Check lateral stability.
Tendons are okay.
Congratulations. What a relief.
Yeah. It's wonderful.
You're welcome.
County General, this is unit 47.
Go ahead, 47.
Calling for a noon radio check.
We just did the a.m.
check an hour ago.
Go ahead. Switch to Med 4.
I'm sending you
some calibrations.
Read calibrations, 10-2.
Great. I'll see you
when I see you, County.
Noon check? What was that about?
I'd say he wanted
to hear your voice.
Car door, huh? Get it splinted,
and you're going to need an MRI.
The x-rays looked good.
I don't think it's broken.
If you end up with a leave,
you're going to completely
screw up my schedule.
The guy was a maniac.
He destroyed $6,000
worth of prosthetics.
Listen, uh, how
about I buy you lunch?
Well, maybe a little soup.
I got a call for a
pickup... Dvorak Park.
Park bench, southwest corner.
She was laid out just like this.
All right. Let's get her inside.
Uh, this was pinned to her.
It's got some cash inside.
I, uh, took out my fare.
Yeah. Great.
My, my. What do you know?
She's pregnant at 14.
And her mom's along.
We keeping you up?
Susie woke up
six times last night.
How did you ever raise four?
Graveyard shift,
no OT for the first four years,
and a husband
who works flex time.
Just shoot me now.
Pay close attention.
You'll practice
this drill a lot.
I was starting to think
we'd never get out of here.
Today's all-city
finals... Volleyball.
Amy's the only
freshman playing varsity.
Mom...
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Well, I knew if Amy was willing
to come on a tournament
day, then it must be pretty bad.
She claims that it's cramps,
but I'm always wary,
because I had
appendicitis when I was 12...
I'm not 12.
Well, if you'll
just step outside,
I'll examine Amy and
see what's going on.
I'll stay. I always do.
We've, uh, found that kids
after a certain age
develop a better
rapport with doctors
if they're seen one-on-one.
I, um, I like your earrings.
Thanks.
My daughter and I
don't have any secrets.
Harper, why don't
you get started,
and I'll show Mrs.
Tubbs to the lounge.
No, no, you did the right thing.
It's just an ear infection,
but you can't be too careful.
I'm going to get him
some augmentin.
Is okay with his HIV?
Mm-hmm. It's fine.
I'll be right back.
Uh, I need to talk to you
about my assignments.
It's a random rotation.
Well, I've been
randomly rotating
through headaches
and gas pains all week.
I'm only getting
the boring cases.
Look, maybe I am
going light on you.
I've noticed that you have
a lot of personal obligations,
and I thought you
might need slack.
I've got a kid with chickenpox.
Where should I put him?
Uh, put him in the Iso Room.
Okay, this way.
I don't need any slack.
If there's anything affecting
my ability to do my job,
I'll let you know.
No, hey don't go in there!
There's somebody
already in there!
He's not on the board.
He's a patient of mine.
He's a kid with AIDS.
He doesn't need to be
exposed to chickenpox.
No kidding! So maybe you
could let us in on the secret
that he's here.
Lydia, why don't you see
if Exam Room 4 is open?
Doug, next time make sure
that your patient's on the board.
Kerry...
want to take a look at this?
It's not appendicitis, is it?
How long have you
been sexually active?
I told him that
stuff wouldn't work
without a condom.
Well, it didn't.
Don't tell my mom.
Amy, by law, I'm not
permitted to tell your parents.
Good.
Okay, you can slide up now.
We'll talk about your options
when all your results are in.
Since you had unprotected sex,
we'll need to do tests
for gonorrhea,
chlamydia, and HIV.
I don't have that.
Have you had more
than one partner?
No.
Has he?
Amy, whatever the results are
or whatever you decide to do,
you're going to need
someone's support.
Your mom seems to care.
She was delivered by taxi?
No name, but her
whole history's there.
End-stage multiple sclerosis.
Partially paralyzed,
incontinent,
sight impaired,
possible dementia.
Beautifully brushed hair.
And she likes an
open window at night.
She's also got pneumonia.
Did you call the cops?
Then what else can we do?
Admit her.
I'll call upstairs.
Mr. Carter.
Looks like you and I have
a gastroplasty in an hour.
Are you up to speed
with the procedure?
Mmm.
Yes, I... yes, I am.
Good.
I'll see you both there.
Peter, I know
you can't scrub in,
but there's a lot to
learn by watching.
No, I don't understand.
If you have three
discharges and one admit,
you should have two open beds.
Yes. She has MS.
She's also got pneumonia,
so Neuro can't take her.
Well, when can
you get back to me?
Excuse me.
I got a Deluxe Jalapeño fried
for a Tom Perry in Curtain 3.
There.
Thanks.
Ah, Mrs. Tubbs. It'll
just be a few moments
I saw the ultrasound machine.
I know what's going on.
She's pregnant, isn't she?
I can't discuss this
with you right now.
Oh, no, of course
not. I'm her mother.
I know that, but...
The one who spent
14 years sacrificing
so that she could
have every chance,
The one who's going to
foot the bill for this baby
or have to face our priest
when she doesn't have it,
so sure, ignore me.
No, I understand that this is...
No, you're not a
mother, are you?
No, I'm not, but...
Then don't dismiss me.
And don't try to keep
me away from my baby.
Call Security.
No, there's no need.
The girl's privacy...
She's ready to tell her mom.
Sometimes it's the boring case
that turns into
the real challenge.
If you're considering violence,
count me in.
Oh, it's not just me!
There is no
politically correct way
to describe that woman.
I'll see if I can find her.
Anybody seen Dr. Weaver?
Follow the trail of
partially digested residents.
Dr. Lewis?
Childcare called.
Should they hold
Susie's noon bottle?
It's almost 1:00.
She must be starving.
No, tell them to feed her.
I'll be up as soon as I can.
Go on up. Take a break.
You're allowed to have a life.
I'm waiting on some labs.
Weaver has you playing her game.
You think if you
ace all the details,
then she's gonna
stop nit-picking?
Probably not.
You know, Susan,
you didn't put your X's
in the middle of the box.
I know it's trivial,
but could you say "sahntimeter"
instead of centimeter?
And couldn't you second-guess
yourself sometimes,
instead of me
always having to do it?
What does that mean,
they may have a bed after 7?
What, are they building it?
I called all the nursing homes
in the neighborhood.
Nobody's AWOL.
Well, we know she
didn't walk to the park
and call her own taxi.
County General, this is Unit 47.
This is County
General. Go ahead, 47.
We're at the scene
at Archer Courts
with an adolescent female.
GSW to the chest,
guessing a 9 mm.
She's unresponsive,
Shallow resps at eight.
Pulse, 130. BP, 90/50.
Have you started fluids?
Two IV's going wide open.
Copy that. What's your ETA?
Just about to pull out.
We ought to be there...
Damn!
What's going on?
They're shooting at
us! Gunfire at the scene.
Let's get out of here!
No, somebody's down out there!
I'm going after them.
47?
Don't do that, man.
Shep! Shep!
So, I pull the trocar
through the stomach.
CDH 29.
What other options
would we have?
Roux-en-Y.
Anastomose the
jejunum to the stomach.
Benini and Forse claim
that vertical-banded
gastroplasty
preserves the
gastroduodenal continuity.
Ho. Where did you read that?
Gastroenterology. This month.
Okay, I gave it a shot,
but that rainforest
crap is driving me nuts.
Toilets flushing.
That's how they make that sound.
Peter, you're not sterile.
Would you mind changing it?
Any requests?
Silence is fine.
Okay. We're ready.
RL 90 stapler, please?
It's all yours, Mr. Carter.
Any words of wisdom
for your student
before he staples
his first stomach...
or have you done one of these?
No, I, I haven't.
You only get one chance,
and there's no undoing it.
Calm and steady.
Advance the pin button.
Line up the gap indicator.
Mm-hmm. Release
the trigger safety.
Fire.
Nice.
Are you kidding?
All the single-parent
kids I see?
It's a huge job. You
should be scared.
And I'm worried about
what's best for little Susie.
Have you told Mark yet?
No, and I'd rather you didn't.
Okay, if you do
consider adoption...
I already saw a lawyer.
There's a neurosurgeon
up on eight.
His name's Kevin Halloran,
and he's a great guy.
He and his wife
have adopted already,
and they've been looking.
No. I mean I was
thinking of adopting Susie.
Oh. Okay.
Feeling better?
Hey, doc!
I was, but the hospital
food didn't sit too well,
so I ordered me up some
takeout to settle my stomach.
You have to stop eating.
For how long?
We'll try an hour,
see how you're doing.
Your cardiac workup's negative,
but if you keep gorging
yourself like this,
it won't stay that way.
It's hard for him.
He... he really loves his food.
Well, if he eats
himself to death by 40,
he'll miss a lot of meals.
Could you order me up
another of those drinks?
It seemed to help before.
Promise not to
chase it with an eclair?
Ha ha! An eclair.
No. I'm at County General.
The paramedic unit was
calling from Archer Court.
We need some help here!
Single GSW to the chest.
BP, 100/60. Pulse is 102.
Resps at 32. Diminished
breath sounds on the right.
We would have called in,
but our radio got shot out.
Is there another victim?
A guy on the street
playing possum.
He didn't want to get shot.
That sounds smart.
Okay. Here we go.
Watch yourself there.
Hang on.
All right, on my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
Whoa! That's a big 12-year-old.
She's got a hemothorax.
Set up a chest-tube tray.
28 French?
That sounds about right.
It's a little crowded
in here, 47.
Why don't you
take out your stuff
and wait in the hall?
How's our mystery guest doing?
The same.
She stopped moaning.
Okay. We're moving her.
You found a bed?
Not yet, but it's
a big hospital.
Got it?
Yep.
Let's go.
Listen to me, lady. I've
been waiting a long time.
Now, you've got to tell me...
Sir, if you would
just simmer down...
But she is my
niece! Where is she?
Buddy, buddy, what
can we do for you?
He's the uncle of
the girl you brought in.
Oh, she's here. She's okay.
Sir, your niece was shot.
She's being stabilized...
Not Poovey! I got to see her!
If you could calm down... Sir!
Where is she? Poovey!
Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
200 cc's in the Thora-Seal.
Bleeding slowed.
Good bilateral breath sounds.
Oh, mercy.
She must be carrying a kilo.
Hey!
He may have a gun, you guys!
You dumb, dealing
son of a bitch!
Were you shooting
at us? Were you?
at us? Watch out!
Huh? Did you shoot at that kid?
Huh? Did you
shoot? Out of our way!
Did you shoot that little girl?
I am gonna kick
your ass. Come here.
Did you shoot that kid? Huh?
Did you? Huh?
Take him in. Take him in.
Huh?
Got them both. Got them both.
Don't inhale this
stuff. It'll mess you up.
Susan?
Yeah?
Your baby-sitter's here.
I sent her to the snack bar.
Oh, that's fine.
But, half an hour
ago. Sorry, I forgot.
Oh, my God.
Uh, Lily, could you
give 30 cc's of this
to Mr. Perry in Curtain 3?
You bet. Go on. Go.
Okay, thanks. Thanks.
What do you think?
Right feels lucky.
Can I help you?
Well, I hope so.
I'm Mark Greene,
Attending in the
ER. Maybe we spoke.
Nothing in there.
We're looking for a room.
A bed would do.
You know, I think a room
would be much better.
Dr. Greene, you know
the proper channels.
Yeah, I tried them,
and this nice lady
still had no room for the night.
There. What do we have here?
Hey, look. There's a bed.
And it has an open window.
Oh...
This is perfect. We'll take it.
Do you want me to call
the admitting supervisor?
Not unless you want to explain
why you were too
lazy to handle an admit
45 minutes before
the end of your shift.
Thank you.
I think she likes it.
Three hours a day
would be perfect.
I wouldn't do
more than that yet.
Oh, yeah. That would
help me so much.
I just can't stand
to have Susie in
daycare for so long.
I hear you.
I thought about
putting Theresa in one
for about two minutes.
Not my child, though I'm sure
the one here is very nice.
Oh, yeah. It is. It's great.
Yeah.
Yeah, she's still
breast-feeding.
There's a lot of salt in those.
Oh, right.
Well, uh, where should we start?
I'm on days till Monday.
Until Monday?
Yeah. My shift changes
every three weeks...
12-hour days, 12-hour nights.
You mean you'll be needing
help at different times.
We can work it out in advance.
I didn't understand
that on the phone.
Well, when I'm on nights,
I do expect to patchwork
a little extra help.
I'm so sorry. I can't help.
Theresa and I have a schedule,
and I thought I
could work Susie in,
but I can't reshuffle
week to week.
I understand.
It's just not
a very flexible time
for us right now.
I mean, you know babies.
They're such little
creatures of habit.
They need their patterns
to develop a sense
of... a sense of security.
Honey? Honey! Is it his heart?
I knew it when I saw it!
Did he drink this?
Yes.
The whole thing?
What's going on here?
We have got to pump
his stomach now.
Whose patient is this?
Hold still, Mr. Perry.
You need this to inactivate
any Donnatal left
in your stomach.
What happened?
Mr. Perry here
just got treated
to a gastric lavage.
After ingesting
500 cc's of Maalox,
lidocaine and Donnatal.
He drank the whole bottle?
She gave it to us.
I gave him an ounce.
But you left the bottle in here?
Poor physician instructions
are not your responsibility.
You don't know anything
about my instructions.
Because there was
nothing written on the chart,
and you were
nowhere to be found.
Your patient's in
respiratory arrest,
and you disappeared.
I told Randi...
It's not the clerk's job
to keep track of the staff.
Kerry, Susan, outside.
It would have made no difference
to that patient's condition
if I'd written a
book on his chart.
Obviously, I did not order him
to guzzle a quart
of GI cocktail.
So this time it didn't matter
that you were careless.
Shall we wait till someone dies,
and then you'll be responsible?
All right, that's enough!
Let me finish with this patient,
and I'll see you
both in the lounge.
Still working?
Yeah.
Actually, I got to
cancel on tonight.
Dr. Hicks wants me to
monitor our gastroplasty
in the recovery room.
Wow. Grown-up stuff.
I'm sorry about tonight,
because I was
looking forward to it.
Rain check.
Wow. Those are really nice.
Hmm. Thanks.
How did you get them so even?
Just practice. You'll get there.
Am I in your light?
Um...
No. No.
Anything wrong, doc?
We'll do it soon.
Doc?
Uh, no, sir.
No, everything...
Everything's fine.
Please sit down.
What just happened
in front of that patient
can't ever happen again.
You two have to
start working together.
I depend on both
of you too much.
I'm to blame for this situation.
I haven't backed you up, Kerry,
on some of the more
unpleasant aspects
of your job,
I may have left the impression
that I don't support the
work that you're doing,
so let me go on record:
I am behind Kerry 100%.
If you disagree with
anything she's doing,
assume that she's
acting with my approval,
but if this department
impedes any resident
from doing their best,
then as chief, you
have to respond.
Any questions?
That's it.
Kerry, hold on.
Susan is one of the
most gifted doctors I know.
If she's having trouble
working with you,
it's a problem I
expect you to solve.
Fine. I'll accept your
criticism anytime,
but not in front of a resident.
Okay. It won't happen again.
It undermines my authority
and is completely inappropriate.
I imagine that's how Susan felt
when she was being
critiqued in front of a patient.
Um, I'd like to apologize
for what happened earlier today.
It was, um... inexcusable,
and I am sorry.
Uh, apology accepted.
What happened earlier today?
It was a, uh, misunderstanding.
Are you having fun being
where the buck stops?
Bring on the TV and beer.
Well, actually, I...
Hope you don't mind a threesome.
No problem.
See you later. Let's go.
Ortho concurred.
No tendon damage.
Keep that finger
in a splint ten days,
and you shouldn't need a leave.
That's good news.
Get yourself a physical
therapy regimen.
You know Jeanie Boulet, right?
I'll take care of it.
Multiple trauma just pulled up.
I'll get it.
I'll join you in 2.
35-year-old worker,
recycling warehouse.
Fell 15 feet off a
catwalk onto a machine.
BP's 50 palp, pulse, 56. No
spontaneous resps, GCS, five.
Moves extremities times four.
What is that thing?
Some kind of a crusher.
Coworkers tried to dismantle it.
No distal pulse
in that extremity.
Hot date tonight?
Almost.
When did her husband show up?
Half an hour ago,
according to the nurse.
Social worker's on her way.
I'm sorry, sweetheart. I
didn't want to send you away,
but I couldn't shampoo your hair
the way you like it.
Or get your pills straight.
Or change the bed.
I never thought
the day would come
when I couldn't pick you up.
Even after the boys were gone,
you were always a feather.
I can't afford the kind of
place that you should have,
But I... But I...
I, I thought it would be...
I thought it would
be better for you here.
I... I...
I missed her too much.
Damn it! We're losing the arm.
Where's the hell's maintenance?
Here. I found these.
BP's 50 palp. This
guy's bleeding out.
No, he's not.
No internal injuries.
Lavage is negative.
Come on!
No pelvic fracture.
CBC's normal.
Come on!
Anion gap, metabolic acidosis.
Hey, this place
use any chemicals?
Nobody spoke English,
but it was a real dump.
Recycled junk everywhere,
a lot of old x-ray cartridges.
Blood gas shows
decreased AV differential.
Could be cyanide.
Doesn't make sense.
Why not?
Stripping x-rays.
They could be using
cyanide illegally.
Got it!
Ho!
We need a pressure
dressing here.
How are those retinal veins?
Ah, bright red.
Get a cyanide kit.
300 sodium nitrate.
Hang the thiosulfate, 50 cc's.
And he's pinking up.
Guess you were right.
Remind me never
to arm-wrestle you.
Oh, damn. We're an hour
over. I had dinner plans.
Oh, Susie!
What time is it?
Daycare closes at 7:00.
Can you call them for me?
You can go. I'll
take him up to O.R.
No, that's okay. I'll stay.
Stay on top of it
and see what the social
worker comes up with.
Carol, long day?
Yeah, for my day off.
Is Susan still around?
I don't think so.
She had to get out of
here early, you know,
picking up little Susie and all?
She seems to be
spending a lot of time
with that baby lately.
Well, yeah, since
Chloe flew the coop.
Chloe's gone?
Where have you been?
I've got to get that.
County General, this is 47.
It's the other
one, the other one.
What is his name?
County General. I read you, 47.
Raul.
Is he dating anyone?
Calling in
for a radio check
on our new set.
I hear you loud and clear.
If, if there's nothing
else, I'll sign off.
Just thought that you
ought to answer your phone.
47 out.
I was wondering if
we should get that.
Hello?
Nurse Hathaway, look, I'm, uh...
I'm sorry if I got in your
way on that last call.
You didn't get in my way.
I thought I made you angry.
You didn't.
So let me just ask you,
if you weren't mad,
were you, uh, maybe, worried?
Worried about what?
You running out in
the middle of sniper fire,
or chasing an armed
man through the ER?
You were worried!
I mean, I thought
something was going on here.
I thought maybe I
was getting to you.
I know you're getting to me.
That's great. You were worried.
All right. So what if I was?
Oh.
Uh, hello.
I, uh, thought you
were flying out today.
Fog.
No Doug yet.
No? Good.
I mean, uh, would you like
to go out for a drink quick?
A quick drink.
I'm not dressed.
Yeah, I've noticed
that about you,
but if you got dressed,
then we could go out.
Mark, are you flirting with me?
No. I was just going
out for a drink anyway...
I was just, uh, going
to drop off my dinner.
So, you know, I thought...
Why don't we go?
Okay. I come.
Okay.
Now, uh, don't be long, okay?
Oh, great.
Mark, you've got the cards out.
No. I, uh...
Something wrong?
Mark, should I...?
Doug, hello.
Hello. Hello.
Uh, my friend Hulda and
I, we were just going...
Relax, Mark.
I think Hulda and I
can read the situation.
I'm Linda.
Did we have a scheduling mix-up?
Looks that way.
Uh, so, one, two, three, four.
Let's have a drink.
Sounds great.
Or play bridge.
Nice even number.
Thanks, but no thanks.
I got to call my wife.
So, let me count.
That makes three.
Am I right?
Mark, it's early.
Uh, have fun.
Good night.
Hi. I'm not here.
Hi, Susan. Mark.
I found out about Chloe.
I guess we haven't
been talking much.
Listen, if you need
anything, call, okay?
I'm at Doug's.
Miss you.
Hello?
Um... yeah. Hi.
Dr. Halloran, this
is Susan Lewis.
I hope I'm not calling too late.
I heard that you and your wife
are looking to adopt a baby?