Doctors have never
had all the answers.
Derek, I don't know.
It isn't just a visit.
She's "back" back.
It's only been two nights.
As long as she needs.
I mean, she lost someone.
She's been through some stuff.
I think she just
needs her friends.
She doesn't want to be alone.
There was a time
when you were sick,
we'd just drain your blood like
you were getting an oil change.
Today is, uh, knee
replacement day, right?
Had to cancel them.
We're meeting with our
lawyers today about the crash.
Oh, how's that going?
Uh, I'm not allowed to say.
All right, that's fine.
How's Arizona?
Not allowed to say.
You.
Dr. Bailey. Here you
go. Oh, thank you.
She won't see anyone. She
won't even leave the house.
Yeah, and... She's walking.
She's even working
with her prosthesis,
but, you know, it has to be
perfect. And I try to be encouraging,
but then she tells
me I'm pushing her.
Tell her I say get
her ass in here.
Oh, sweet.
Then she can be cranky
and resentful to you.
We're constantly
having to rethink
what we thought was true...
Oh.
And redefine it.
Wilson, you stink. Vomit.
It's vomit. I'm
covering the pit,
and Santa Claus came to town.
I don't need a play-by-play.
Go clean yourself up.
That's what I'm doing.
Go. You're disgusting.
What is this? What?
This list your real
estate agent sent to mine.
"Repair discolored/burned
portion, hardwood floors"?
Oh, that's just some stuff
you gotta take care of.
"Repair/refinish wood
molding in doorjambs"?
Yeah, they're all scratched up.
There's like five
things you gotta fix.
And what if I don't? Then
I'm not buying your house.
Well, that's crazy, because you
begged me to sell you that house.
We made a deal. We
shook on it. We drank on it.
These are reasonable
requests. Come on, Mer.
We're friends, but
this is business.
Let's be like grownups here.
Did you just tell me to grow up?
I hate Karev.
Seconded. Oh, motion carried.
We hate Karev. What
happened to you?
I'm covering the pit, and
Santa Claus came to town.
You know, I was starting to
think that he was an okay guy,
but he's just mean. Santa?
Karev.
Santa came in two weeks ago,
and he barfed all over
me, too. Barfed all day.
Did he say anything about me?
Santa? Karev.
Don't do that. Don't be the sad
girl with the hang-up. It's pathetic.
He slept with Heather.
She's not hung up.
Why did you start your year by
having sex with your boss anyway?
Because he's stupid hot.
I have social anxiety,
so, sometimes it's
easier than talking.
Oh. I'm a really good listener.
Just sayin'.
Jackasses, all of you.
Mmm.
Wow.
That was...
So...
So stupid.
Not where I was going with that.
Oh.
What is wrong with me?
How many times can I
say this is not happening,
and then, the next thing
I know, it's happened?
I am... I'm so weak.
You're not weak. You're just...
Disgusting.
I was a good person once.
A person with willpower.
I have fasted
before. This is worse.
This just feels
helpless and inevitable.
Like watching two cars
head toward one another
and there's nothing you can do.
There's gonna be a crash.
People are going to die.
And you're just
gonna be left there...
You are lucky I'm even
selling you this house.
You're lucky I'm buying it.
That list is the
tip of the iceberg.
I mean, there's dry rot...
There is no dry rot.
Aah! Ah!
Brian Danziger, 17, he passed
out in first period English.
Severe abdominal pain,
tremors, and he's hypertensive.
His parents are on the way.
Brian, were you drinking this
morning? Did you take anything?
No, I don't take drugs.
God! What happened?
He's distended,
and he's got tenderness
in the right upper quadrant.
Does he look
jaundiced to you? A little.
Brian, I'm gonna need you
to lie back down, please.
I... Oh.
Alex.
Uh, all right. Make sure you
get L.F.T.s, COAGs, a tox screen,
and an abdominal CT.
Edwards, what do
you think this is?
I think...
I'm sorry. I don't know.
That's all right.
We don't either.
For all we know, this
kid could have dry rot.
I'm sorry I messed
you up like that, hon.
I start puking like this,
it doesn't stop for days.
Well, I'm gonna
give you some fluids
to counteract the
alcohol in your system.
I don't have any
alcohol in my system.
Mmm-hmm. Last time
you threw up all over us,
your alcohol level was .21,
and the time before
that, it was even higher.
It does take the
pain down a notch.
But I swear to you, hon, I
ain't been drinking nothing.
I mean, I don't know
what's wrong with me.
My stomach hurts so bad
that I get so nauseous,
I just wish I would die.
Please. You got to help me.
Well, let's figure it out then.
Mmm.
Okay.
I told you to change your shirt.
What the hell is wrong with you?
This is what I can
offer you salary-wise.
That's fine. Thank you.
You don't need to thank
me. Thank Jeff Russell.
He really pushed
to get you here.
Who's Jeff Russell?
He's the new cardio chief.
He's a good guy. You'll
like him. Or you won't.
Oh, there's a meeting today about
the plane crash with the lawyers.
Will you be there? I will.
So do I have to come?
No, I will be there
to support my staff,
not as your proxy.
I'm not your proxy anymore.
All right.
So...
Now, here's your
orientation packet.
Welcome.
And I'll see you around.
Jamie's appy went perfectly,
her incision looks great,
but her throat is still giving
me cause for concern.
It's just a sore throat, right?
Probably just an infection,
but the swelling is abnormal.
So, I want to keep
her here another day
and run some
tests just to be sure.
Of course. Let's
be sure. Thank you.
Yeah.
And of course my kids got to it
before my husband
could even try it.
All right, and the
judge is tasting it now
and we are gonna see
what you get, Susan.
That is three and a
half out of four apples!
Hello.
Hey, Arizona. It's, uh,
Miranda Bailey. How are you?
Uh... Well, I'm, you know...
I wish I had
time to talk, but...
I'm calling for a favor.
I have a 13-year-old female,
three days post-appendectomy
with a persistent sore
throat, and as of this morning,
severe swelling on
the left side of her neck.
I'm kind of at a loss here.
Well...
Get a CT. I am.
I am. I just thought you might
know off the top of your head.
Have you ever seen
something like this?
Maybe. I mean, I'd have
to take a look at the chart.
You know, Bailey, I'm not really
back to work yet, and I'm busy.
I know, I know. I just...
What if I have an intern
bring you a copy of the
chart? You take a look,
if it sparks anything,
you can call me back.
Can't you just email it?
Um, not scanned yet.
Fine. Fine. Just
send the chart over.
Oh, thanks so much.
Sir, we have a problem.
You don't have to call me "sir."
I do. It helps me.
Sir...
You need to get
your Averys straight.
Oh? In your address book.
Last night...
You sent an email, which I
believe was for my mother.
Oh.
It began, "I can't sleep...
"Thinking about you tonight..."
Uh, that's enough.
Well, it would've
been for me, too.
But it really goes on.
Sir, I do not like thinking
about you in that way,
or my mother in that way,
or you and my
mother in that way.
Message received,
son. Won't happen again.
Don't call me "son."
I meant it colloquially.
But, that won't
happen again either.
Well, I took the liberty of forwarding
your email on to my mother.
I thank you for that.
All right. Sir.
You were supposed
to tell me when
Brian Danziger's labs came back.
No, I thought I was
supposed to tell Dr. Karev.
I should've told you, too.
Uh, Brian Danziger's
labs are back.
Get away from me.
Oh, not fair. You
are the scariest one.
That was always
supposed to be me.
You shouldn't have left.
I'll establish dominance.
Maybe I'll use
one of the classics.
How was Owen?
You mean "Chief Hunt"?
The husband formerly known
as Owen is now just my employer.
He gave me the
orientation packet.
Brian Danziger's sedated.
His B.P.'s down a little.
Yeah, tox screen's negative, his
L.F.T.s and I.N.R. are elevated.
Did you get a good
look at his liver?
Oh, the prodigal Yang returns.
We've missed you.
Yes, hi. Blah,
blah. Pleasantries.
Hey, what do you know about
the new cardio chief, Jeff Randall?
Russell. Nothing. Yeah.
No one named Jeff has ever
done anything substantial.
Hey, Karev, when you buy Mer's
house, can I get my old room back?
Nope. No roommates.
We're not in college.
We're real people now.
Wait, you're selling
him your house?
I might not, he wants
me to rip out the floors.
I'll take the floors as is.
- Jackson.
Why don't you shack
up with Kepner?
You guys are always
boinking anyway.
Where is he going?
Away from you, it seems.
Cristina, glad you're back.
You still doing it with Avery?
Does everybody know this now?
God and everybody.
For four whole seconds I
was glad you were back.
Mmm. I gotta go
meet this Jeff schmuck.
You were right.
About the floors?
About the liver.
Oh, crap.
You think it's something I did?
With Karev?
Because things were really
heating up, and suddenly,
he stops returning my texts.
He barely talks to me, and I
can't figure out what happened.
What happened is, he's a guy.
So you think we're done?
You should be.
Yeah, but is he...
Leah, stop.
Labs for Santa Claus.
Yeah, it's mine.
What about Shane?
He's nice. Yeah, he is.
I wish I liked nice.
Then you picked the right guy.
Karev's mean.
And thoughtless, and a douche.
And there's nothing
wrong with him at all.
Karev? Santa.
23-year-old female,
37-week gestation,
echocardiogram reveals
myxoma in the right ventricle...
Dr. Randall? Russell.
Sorry. I'm Dr. Yang.
Oh. Holy crap.
You're here.
Jeff Russell. Make it Jeff.
Jeff, it is.
So, this is great.
Well, I understand you
already know your way around,
probably better than I do, so...
Welcome.
And go. Have fun.
See patients.
I thought we might talk.
I wish I had the time.
Dr. Russell... Jeff.
I am happy to be back at
Seattle Grace-Mercy West,
but not if my
progress ends here.
I think my time would
be best spent... Dr. Yang.
I am in the weeds.
I have a huge myxoma
on a pregnant lady,
I am spearheading the first
U.S. Lotus Valve implantation,
I've got four papers that journals
are breathing down my neck for,
I've got an army of
interns who could use...
Who need some...
Who are stupid.
Go. Run my service,
make me look great.
Just don't kill my patients.
Who's gonna assign my surgeries?
Um, you are. Call me
if you do something really cool.
Sir, I'm a fellow.
No, that's not what I've heard.
I've heard you're
as good, as capable,
as excited about this
work as I am, if not more.
Go.
Be that way.
Myxoma in right ventricle.
Mass measures 3 centimeters...
At this point,
it's about assessing
these emotional damages.
So, we'll need to
hear everything.
You must be Dr. Yang. Glad
you could be here. Have a seat.
Dr. Hunt, I guess you won't
be necessary as proxy anymore.
Uh, I'm here more out
of support for my staff.
Yeah, I don't mind if he stays.
Today, we'd like to get
some statements about,
continued physical,
but also, mental
or emotional difficulties you
might have suffered since the crash.
What if we don't have any?
Well, um, why don't we talk?
We'll see what comes up.
Almost anything can be
helpful to monetize your injuries.
How do we do that?
We use a formula.
It's, uh, your medical bills,
plus pain and suffering,
equal to three times
your medical bills,
plus flat-rate
hard-tissue injuries,
plus loss of income,
plus lost earning capacity,
plus any other
foreseeable harms,
for each of you, so,
we're talking about
a sizeable award.
Far more substantial than
the settlement they offered you.
Where's all the money come from?
Well, we're looking
at the possibilities now.
Uh, the charter company,
aircraft manufacturer,
parts manufacturers,
the pilot, of course.
The ground crew at Sea-Tac...
Jerry? Did you say Jerry?
Who's Jerry? DEREK: The pilot.
He was up there with us.
He broke his back.
He's paralyzed now.
You're gonna go after him?
Well, if we find he was
negligent, shouldn't we?
You know, I'm
sorry. I can't help.
I've got no residual injuries,
and I've gotta go run
someone's service for them,
so, you know, good luck.
Folks, listen,
you have a special bond.
You've been through
something horrible
and survived it together.
But as far as the
pilot is concerned,
you need to stop thinking
of him as one of you
and start thinking of
him as one of them.
I am Dr. Yang, Dr. Russell's
cardiothoracic fellow.
Good to see you back, Dr. Yang.
Have we met?
Um, sort of.
You threw a vase full
of flowers at our heads.
Did I hurt you? No.
Well, there's still
time. I'm Dr. Ross.
Since many of you
will wash out or be fired,
I won't waste time learning
your names for at least a year.
I will call you by
your dwarf names.
You, "Happy."
You, "Mousey."
There wasn't a dwarf
named "Mousey."
They saved her for you.
Now get me up to speed.
Every patient, every chart.
I want to know this
floor better than you do.
Right. Wrong.
You're surgical interns.
No one should know
this floor better than you.
You're "Dopey" now.
She's worse than
Medusa. I hate her.
I heard that.
So, we're not sure
if it's cancerous,
but there is a
mass on his liver,
and it is hemorrhaging.
So, we'd like to do a
biopsy as soon as possible.
All right. Of course.
There's something
else. Brian's symptoms...
The jaundice, the hair
loss, the high blood pressure,
coupled with a hepatic
lesion, it's all consistent
with the use of
anabolic steroids.
What? What the hell?
Brian...
Are you taking steroids? No.
Have you noticed
changes in behavior?
Moodiness, depression...
Shut up! Just shut up,
I said I don't take them.
Brian.
Unprovoked aggression...
Don't listen to her.
He's not even an athlete.
He's in the Model U.N.
Brian, baby,
just tell me.
If you did it, honey,
I wanted...
Girls only like the guys
with these crazy bodies now.
I wanted a shot at
someone liking me.
Brian, how long have
you been taking them?
I swear, I've barely taken any.
For two years.
Since sophomore year.
That's when you
stopped being my boy.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I didn't know.
Wilson, what's the status
on our frequent flyer?
Santa? Mmm-hmm.
I don't know. He wasn't lying.
His labs came back
negative for drugs and alcohol.
He's dehydrated, but otherwise,
his chem panel's good, his
blood sugar's surprisingly good.
Treat him and
street him. I'm sorry?
Santa Claus has been
coming here for years.
Same symptoms, always
drunk, always nauseous.
We always run multiple tests,
and they're always negative.
He's looking for drugs.
Give him some antiemetics, give him
some food, and send him on his way.
I just feel like
there's more to this...
Wilson, I know
you wanted to help.
But you're a surgical intern,
and your skills are
needed elsewhere,
and we need that bed.
Discharge him, please.
Hey.
It looks like there's
nothing wrong with you.
You guys always say that.
There's nothing more we can do.
So I gotta get.
Yeah.
You got a blanket
I can take with me?
I'm freezing to death.
Hey.
Stop!
You don't get to
have sex with me
and then just walk out
without even so much as
a "Have a nice day," okay?
I deserve more
respect than that.
What about me? What about you?
I have to stick around
and listen to you
compare sex with me
to a fatal car crash?
Hear how repellant,
how disgusting...
No. No, no.
Oh, my God, no.
No, it is not you.
You are great.
You are not the problem.
Okay. So then...
Okay, so, um...
So, you know when the
dessert tray comes around,
and you know you should say no
because it's not
nutritious and it's fattening,
and you just, you know
you shouldn't, but...
But, it's right there,
and it's so beautifully made,
and it looks so good.
And you've had it before,
so you just, you know, how...
Right. Delicious it is.
And it's just... It's
right there, you know?
I do. Yeah, I know.
So... So you have it.
You have the dessert.
And it is delicious.
I mean, it is
an amazing dessert.
It is really good.
For
a moment,
and then you feel
tired, and bloated,
and gassy,
and so guilty,
like you just erased
all of the exercise
you have ever done,
and tomorrow,
you're gonna wake up
with zits all over your face,
and Jesus is so disappointed
in you again. And you just...
Are you kidding me?
Hey. ARIZONA: Did
you send the chart?
I did, an hour ago.
I told my intern to leave
the copies by the door.
Well, did you tell
them to ring the bell?
I would've thought
that that was a given,
but this year's interns
seem more defective than most.
Did you tell me to leave the...
Ah. Speak when you're spoken to.
Yeah. It's outside your door.
Fine.
Would it be safe to
say that that surgery,
the one Dr. Torres
performed on your hand,
was your last hope at
regaining your surgical career?
You could say that.
Dr. Torres, you'd agree
that with the failure
of that surgery,
Dr. Shepherd won't be able to...
Okay, I'm sorry.
Just to be clear,
the surgery didn't fail.
It worked. The
graft failed to take.
That was a risk
we were willing...
But Dr. Shepherd
can no longer operate.
No.
We'd hoped we'd
get 100% function...
And it's expected that he
will never operate again.
Um, I didn't say that.
But if it is true,
and you can help
establish that as a fact,
it would raise the award
tremendously, for everyone.
No, in my opinion,
Dr. Shepherd won't operate again.
Can we take a break
for a minute, please?
Okay.
Ah!
Ow. Ow! No! Ah.
I am so sorry. I don't
know what happened.
The stupid intern's gonna
hear about it, though.
No, it's just, it's a huge...
It's a huge waste of my time!
It is, and I'm sorry.
I will find out what
happened to that chart
and get it right over to you.
I'm sorry, but, Dr. Bailey,
you never told me
to deliver any chart.
When you are spoken to.
Dr. Yang, listen, if you
could give me a few minutes.
I really don't have
the time or the need
to keep dragging this out.
I Respect that. That's fine.
But you were involved,
and your statement could
benefit your colleagues
and their families.
Anything you could
say might be helpful.
My shoulder hurts sometimes.
I might have had some P.T.S.D.
You did throw that vase at me.
That is hearsay,
or something. Fifteen minutes.
Dr. Yang, Dr. Russell's
post-op aortic ulcer
patient's coughing up blood.
Did you page Russell?
He's in surgery.
He said to page you.
Mousey, suction.
Set up for intubation.
Thank you.
Say something that'll
make him feel better.
You're gonna be just fine, sir.
Don't oversell it.
What do you think it is?
Could be a fistula.
Could be a dissection.
We won't know until we get
more studies and open him up.
Yes!
Sorry.
Mousey, get a repeat CT stat.
Dopey, prep an OR. You
guys are both scrubbing in.
I need all hands.
Now.
And someone tell Russell
that I'm probably opening up
his aortic ulcer.
She's awesome. I love her.
Get this to path. Get us an
answer as quick as you can.
Got it.
So I'm, uh, willing
to compromise.
I'm gonna let the
ceiling thing go.
Okay, and let the
other four things go,
and then we'll have a deal.
We already have a deal.
Why the sudden need
to be a homeowner, Alex?
to be a ball-buster?
Because it's my house.
Seriously, why now?
I've been sleeping
around a lot with interns.
And you need
more space for that?
I just, I...
I'm starting to wonder
if I'm gonna be that guy
who graduated from high school
who hangs out in his El Camino
looking to nail the freshmen.
I don't want to be that guy.
So don't be that guy.
I know. I gotta
grow up a little.
So I stopped calling interns,
I stopped saying "dude,"
and now I just want a place
of my own. You get that, right?
That may just be the
dumbest and the saddest thing
I've ever heard you say.
And I've known you a long time.
Sir.
My mother replied to your email.
Oh, dear.
Because I forwarded it
to her, she replied to me.
Oh, well. Um, that's
rather graphic, isn't it?
Yeah, she's a wordsmith.
I am asking you
both, begging, actually,
that you keep this from
ever happening again.
I'll speak to her.
See that you do.
Sir.
Wilson, why did you order an
abdominal CT on Santa Claus
when you discharged
him an hour ago?
Because I didn't discharge him.
Well, where is he?
He's right here.
Hey, there.
Hey.
Excuse us.
You gave him a CT and
an extreme makeover?
You're here to do surgery.
I cleaned him up a little.
Because poor people
don't get good medical care,
or dirty people,
or smelly people.
And if he'd come in, in a
good suit and some cologne,
we'd all be busting
our asses for him
instead of accusing
him of scamming drugs.
I thought, if his scans
show he needs a consult,
maybe like this, his next
doctor won't blow him off.
CT's been done.
Wait for the results,
if they're negative, you
send him on his way,
immediately, okay?
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
They're waiting for us.
You all right?
You ever wish we would've
just taken the settlement?
Then we wouldn't have
to relive this over and over.
Well... None of
us wanted to settle.
I did.
We all did. In fact, we voted.
Then why did you agree not to?
You know why.
That's not fair.
It's true, though.
It came down to
you, and you agreed.
Because you pushed us.
You came in late
with your big speech...
What are you... You did, Derek.
You decided and you
pushed... I did not push you.
And when you do that, no
one's gonna go against you.
How was I supposed to
stand up? I did not push you.
And you did the same
thing with your hand.
What are you talking about?
I told you, I did not
want to do that surgery.
You suggested that surgery.
Yeah, for someone
else, for Schachter.
I wasn't suggesting it
for me, and I told you that.
But you wouldn't let up
and you made me do it.
Because I thought
you could do it!
I believed that you could do it.
That's my fault.
Don't feel bad,
Callie, it's on me.
Bailey, it's Robbins.
I have thoughts on your
case, many thoughts and ideas,
but I can't tell if
they're worthwhile ideas
until I read the chart.
So can you send me
the friggin' chart? Please.
Someone suction for me.
- I'll do it.
- I can do it.
- Wait. Earn in.
Dopey, what are we
looking at on the scans?
It looks like a dissection
in the ascending aorta
with an aortobronchial fistula.
Good. You're Happy again.
Suction. Mousey,
why did Russell opt
for an endovascular
repair of this ulcer?
I, uh... Personal preference?
Uh, patient's age
and limited mobility.
Oh, Happy for the win.
Keep on suctioning.
It's a good choice.
But I've learned that sometimes,
it's better to do things
the old-fashioned way.
Mousey, hold this
back here, like this.
Good. What do we see here?
It looks like the stent tore
through the aorta and bronchus.
Ooh, Mousey coming
up from behind.
3-0 Prolene.
This is gonna be a mess.
I'm sorry, but there are plenty
of other houses in Seattle
for you not to screw interns in.
This is stupid.
I'm calling it off.
You can't do that.
Escrow's practically closed.
Not my problem.
Neither is "repaint marks
on living room ceiling."
Oh, come on. It's a tiny list.
Good. Then it shouldn't hurt
when you stick it up your...
I've got the results
back from path.
It's cancer.
Your scans came
back completely clean.
I need you to be
honest with me, please.
Did you come in
here looking for drugs?
Yeah, I did.
Can you help me out with that?
Okay. Get up. Get dressed.
Can I just get an
Aspirin or something?
I mean, any...
Aspirin? You want an Aspirin?
Yeah, I get these headaches
like my head's been run
over by a truck or something.
And the whole world, it
gets louder and brighter.
And I just can't move.
Migraines.
You get migraines?
Why didn't you say so?
I tried to. I was
going to, but...
But what?
What is it?
So, it's cancer?
Yes.
But the good news
is, we got it all.
There is a chance
of reoccurrence
if he continues
to abuse steroids.
He won't.
He was perfect.
He was skinny, yes,
and awkward, but...
Funny, smart-alecky...
Thoughtful...
Perfect.
Then he forced himself to...
I thought he was
just being a teenager
when he changed so much.
If I had known, I'd have
stopped him, I swear.
I'd have done anything.
What's the matter with you?
Change your clothes, now.
Yes! That's it! I have
been walking around
in the same vomit-soaked
shirt since this morning.
It couldn't be that I've
been repeatedly puked on
by a patient who pukes all day,
despite the fact that I can't
find anything wrong with him
except extreme
nausea and migraines.
No, I must lack the
ability to wash myself
or have absolutely
no self-respect.
You know what?
Speaking of no self-respect.
Call Leah, please.
She is unbearable.
Let her know if you're
done, or bored, or whatever,
because trying to figure it
out is gonna drive her crazy.
Come with me now.
He's on the way to
C.C.U. All vitals are stable.
Dr. Yang for the win. Up top.
Uh-uh.
Dr. Yang, when did Dr. Russell's
noninvasive TEVAR turn into
a bilateral thoracotomy
with bypass?
When Russell's stent tore
through the guy's aorta.
And you couldn't
find the time to just
consult with Russell
first? Yeah, I tried.
Russell doesn't
even know you yet.
You don't have free reign
to just tear into
someone else's patient.
You'll be gone
on your first day.
He should thank me.
He's probably going to fire you.
Still, it was an amazing...
Shut up.
Hey, hey. You talk
to your wife tonight?
No. Why?
Oh, I may have pushed
a thing a little too far,
and now I'm not sure
what you're going home to.
What did you do?
Well...
Bailey? What did you do?
Oh, I may have
pushed it just far enough.
Okay, you gotta go. What?
She's like a, you
know, a little bird.
If we move too fast,
we'll scare her off.
You're too much pressure
now. You gotta go.
Go, go, go!
Okay.
Oh. Yeah, okay.
All right. Come
here, little bird.
I never got the chart.
I am so sorry.
It's right here.
You know, you asked for my
help, and I'm happy to help you,
but I can't do that unless
I have the information.
Again, so sorry.
You know, when you say you're
gonna do something, you should...
Oh, ah. Uh-huh.
Right. Right here.
The pulmonary infiltrate.
I knew it. I think she
has Lemierre's disease.
People still get Lemierre's?
Well, I think she does.
You can confirm
with an I.J. ultrasound.
Now, what's that gonna show?
Ugh. Come on.
Lemierre's has markers.
The pneumonia, the
complaints of shoulder pain.
And she might have
an I.J. thrombosis,
but we'll see if we
caught that early enough.
But her throat cultures
have been negative so far.
Yeah, it's tricky, and we see it
so seldom now, we overlook it.
You spoke to my mother?
Mmm. I did.
So there won't be any
more miscommunications?
Shouldn't be.
Appreciate it if you could
just keep it to yourselves.
Well, we can certainly do that.
Thank you.
If you can.
Sorry?
Well, when I get an email
that's not meant for me,
I hit a quick
reply or delete it.
You've been running
back and forth,
making sure I hear
from Catherine,
making sure she hears from me,
making sure we connect.
I think maybe you aren't as
upset as you pretend you are.
Oh, I'm not? I think you're glad
your mother's found someone
who makes her happy.
You just don't
want to admit that.
Just keep it out of my inbox.
So, tell me the name again.
Cyclic vomiting syndrome.
It's been linked to
mitochondrial disease.
We see it a lot in kids.
Good labs, extreme
nausea, vomiting for days.
It's a bitch to diagnose,
so the parents go crazy.
I thought it was the booze I
was taking for the headaches.
No, it's the migraines.
That's what triggers
the vomiting episodes.
But there's no cure?
Not yet, but now that
we know what it is,
we can treat the migraines.
And I don't have to
live like this anymore?
No, you don't.
Oh, this works on migraines
and should lessen
your C.V.S. symptoms.
We're gonna set you up
with a primary care doctor.
But if this happens
again, you come back,
you, uh, look for us,
either Dr. Wilson or myself.
We'll take good care of you.
Thank you. Yeah.
Sure saved my biscuits
from the fire on this one, Doc.
Thanks. Oh, thank her.
Someone else might
have let your biscuits burn.
Darlin',
I could hug you.
Oh, that's fine.
Except you're a
little pukey there.
You know as well as I do, I
had no other choice but to...
Let's wait and see
what Russell says.
If you didn't want me here,
you shouldn't
have hired me back.
Dr. Hunt, Dr. Yang,
what happened?
I had to go in on
your aortic ulcer.
He had hemoptysis...
The patient is stable now.
We can talk about
Dr. Yang's decision...
Dr. Yang...
Thank you.
Good save.
And thank you, Hunt.
You're absolutely right.
Now I know why you
pushed so hard for her.
Great work.
Uh, could you take
out your tape recorder?
I need to retract
my earlier statement,
testimony or whatever.
Well, I'm not sure
anything you said was...
I lied before.
I do believe Dr. Shepherd
can operate again.
Well, that's
speculation, not fact.
It's a fact that
nerve regeneration
is very slow.
His nerve may need more time.
And there are also new
nerve connectors we could try
for closer approximation
of the severed ends.
That's a fact.
And we could still try
an end-to-end transfer.
We haven't even tried to
take a branch of the M.A.B.C.
You've given this some thought.
Yeah.
Every single night since
you dropped that instrument.
Why didn't you mention
any of this before?
Because I was scared.
Because I felt
like I failed you.
But you weren't wrong
to believe in me, Derek.
And you weren't wrong to push.
In fact, you should've
pushed me harder.
We haven't tried everything.
You shouldn't
give up until we do.
All right, listen...
I am sorry, okay?
I'm sure that you would
prefer your booty calls
to be uncomplicated
and void of feeling,
so I think you should probably just
seek them somewhere else, okay?
'Cause I know this
is just sex to you.
It's not just sex.
I mean, I wish it was.
I pretend that it is,
'cause you have a good thing
going with Jesus, but it's not.
It's not?
No, and stop calling me
a car crash, or dessert,
or acting like I'm
bumming out Jesus.
I'm sorry. You made
it seem like it was...
And stop acting like I don't
have any feelings, okay?
I have feelings. I
have a lot of 'em.
About what?
You. About you, April. For you.
I'm so sorry that I hurt them,
your feelings...
It's okay. Just...
I thought it was just sex.
Mmm.
Yeah, so did I.
Okay. Have a good night.
Talk to you tomorrow.
I didn't stay to
nail the freshmen.
I know. You stayed for Robbins.
Yeah, and you know
what she told me?
That I'm a nobody.
That I have no one.
She told me that I have
nothing to show for my life.
I want your house,
Mer, 'cause...
I don't know why, I just do.
The chips on the ceiling are from the
first Christmas tree we got, intern year.
You wouldn't know that,
because we didn't like you then.
And the burn marks
on the hardwoods
are from flame shots from
that stupid party Izzie threw.
And the scratch marks on
the doorjamb in the study
are Zola's height marks,
since she could stand.
And the ones on the other side
are from me when I was little.
I grew up there, Alex. It's
hard for me to change things.
And you grew up there, too,
so before you go
trying to change
everything about yourself,
you got yourself this far,
and you're fine the way
you are, and so is the house.
So, I'm not changing anything.
You can if you
want, but I won't.
Okay.
We got a deal?
We got a deal.
What about the dry rot, though?
Would you get away
from me with the dry rot?
Thank you all for
your cooperation today.
Next step is for us to file a
complaint against the parties.
Can we leave the
pilot out of this?
The man is a paraplegic now.
Yeah, I agree. We
should take him off the list.
Wait. No. What if he
was drunk, or asleep...
No, we talked to him.
Dr. Hunt, I'm gonna have
to ask you to step out now.
This is only appropriate
for the victims of the crash.
Oh.
Okay.
Folks, we're not
going after the pilot.
We need to investigate
him to make our case,
but the damages we'll be
seeking will be far greater
than what that pilot
could be accountable for.
Or the charter
company, for that matter.
We'll be going
after bigger fish.
More and more, it's
looking like the best strategy
will be to look for fault
with the hospital itself.
Boise?
No, this hospital.
The people who
put you on that plane.
All right. Well...
Looks fine.
It can be scary to find out
you've been wrong
about something.
But we can't be afraid
to change our minds...
You're right. You
are absolutely right...
To accept that
things are different...
That they'll never
be the same...
Promise me you'll take this.
I will. Thank you.
For better...
Or for worse.
We have to be willing to give
up what we used to believe.
God! You scared me.
What the hell are
you doing here?
Mer gave me the keys.
Mer just sold me this place.
I know.
I want to rent from you.
No, no. I said no roommates.
Oh, come on. It's
fine. It's a big house.
We work weird hours.
We'll barely see each other.
You won't know I'm here.
The more we're willing
to accept what is...
And not what we thought...
What?
You asking me for help.
Well, when you put it like
that, I want to kill myself.
The master's mine.
Rent's due on the first.
You buy the toilet paper.
We'll find ourselves
exactly where we belong.