That boy almost died today.
I think the hospital
should pull Exsomadex.
It's not how things work here.
This is bigger than
just one patient.
I am impressed with how you
turned your life around.
Top of the list,
maybe county juvenile.
He had a lot to overcome.
You're forgetting things, Bert.
Let's make an appointment
with the neurologist.
The two of you are
cooking up this nonsense
so you can get my money!
I'll get tested,
just to get you off my back.
Oh, good.
You made it.
Are you spying on me?
You have an appointment
at my place of employment.
I thought I'd make
myself available to you.
Look, I understand
if you're nervous.
I'm not nervous. I told
you, I'm fine, Sharon.
I don't need a damn babysitter
watching my every move.
You know what?
If you feel that strongly
about it, I'll back off.
Just let your children
know what the doctor says.
Thanks.
- Hey. I'll do a...
- Good morning.
Hey, good morning.
- Get you anything?
- Oh, no.
I make my coffee at home.
I'm bougie about my coffee.
Oh, is that so?
I'll do a medium
drip, black, please.
Thank you.
I'm decidedly unbougie.
No, I hear you reserve
your refined taste
for weird cocktails.
You're referring to my Sazerac?
Go to New Orleans and say that.
There you go. Keep
the change. Thank you.
You were saying.
Ah, Dr. Ahmad, Dr. Marcel.
I have some news I'm sure
you'll be glad to hear.
The hospital has
put a temporary hold
on the use of Exsomadex pending
a thorough safety review.
That's amazing.
I thought the drug
and formula committee
weren't gonna take action.
They weren't, but at the urging
of one of our board
members, Everett James,
the committee decided to
reverse their decision
until the FDA sorts it out.
Great. Thank you, Ms. Goodwin.
You're welcome.
Look at you.
I always thought
institutional inertia meant
we were dead in the
water, but we did it.
You did it. Congratulations.
On my count, three, two, one.
- Oh, it hurts.
- Okay, Lucas, we got you.
I need an X-ray. Single GSW.
As far as I could tell,
I didn't see anything
on his back, but I
couldn't stop the bleeding.
BP's falling. Rate's 110.
Hang a unit of O-neg.
Mike, chest X-ray.
- Yep.
- Okay, on my count,
let's swap places.
Three, two, one.
Yeah, that's the
subclavian artery.
Thanks, Courtney, we got this.
Clear.
Yeah, bullet's retained
behind the clavicle.
- I-I can't breathe.
- Okay, just stay with us.
We gotta get this
bleed under control.
Clamp.
We won't be able to
get an angle on it.
Get me a Foley cath.
- For a gunshot?
- Come on.
I'll insert the Foley
to capture the bleed.
It'll let me
inflate the balloon.
It'll temporize,
buy us some time.
Yeah.
BP's still low but stable.
Page Trauma, have
them open an OR.
Let's go.
Little pick-me-up?
Oh, no. I already
have one. Thank you.
It's prophylactic.
Figured you'd need a second run
after spending another night
in the on-call room.
How'd you know I slept here?
You're brushing your bed hair.
- Oh.
- Are you okay?
You've been spending a
lot of time in the ED
since the divorce.
Because the house doesn't
feel like home anymore
and I feel like
a stranger there.
Maggie, I need an assist.
Yep, right behind you.
- Thanks for the coffee.
- Yeah.
Hello, I'm Dr. Archer.
- This is Nurse Lockwood.
- Morning, morning.
I hear you're having some
trouble with your ileostomy.
Deb. That's my son, Caleb.
- Hey, Doc.
- Hi.
I'm pretty sure it's
a prolapse again.
Do you mind?
Sorry, I know it's nasty.
Don't worry. We're
not squeamish here.
Yeah. Yeah, it's
definitely prolapsed.
You say this has
happened before?
Every time he sneaks
off to play basketball.
You took me to
Chicago in the winter.
What else do you expect
me to do for fun?
Not run off and hurt yourself.
We're visiting from Oakland.
Well, it's still too inflamed
to manipulate right now.
We can reduce the
swelling with some...
Sugar.
I figured that was the case.
Yeah, miracles of
modern medicine.
I also want to order some labs,
a CBC, BMP, and abdominal CT.
You got it, Doc.
Can I ask, I see some
other scars here.
Some are surgical,
but the others?
Caleb was shot two
times in the fall.
Oh, my God.
A lot of car break-ins
where I'm from.
One turned into a shootout,
and I caught a couple of strays.
Sorry to hear that.
You seem to be doing well.
He's a tough kid.
Tough on the court too.
One of the best guards in
California before this.
Well, after the
reversal procedure,
you'll be back on
the court in no time.
Won't matter.
Dr. Davis, our pediatric
surgeon back home,
said Caleb has to wait
another 10 months.
By then, the summer's gone,
and so are all the
college scouts.
Why don't we focus on
getting through this
for now, okay, hon?
Do we have your permission
to contact your surgeon
- to get Caleb's medical records?
- Of course.
Okay.
Well, in the
meantime, sit tight.
We're gonna get
these tests going,
and then I'll be back
to check on you shortly.
Thank you.
Mr. Sullivan, a doctor
will be with you soon.
We just need you
to get in the bed.
Fine, just both of
you, give me 6 feet.
Okay. Okay, sir. Okay.
I'm giving you space. It's fine.
Morning, Anita. Early
start to the madness?
Got a call about a bar fight,
picked up this charmer,
Robert Sullivan.
I don't want any vitals.
I don't want
anything. I don't...
He's still intoxicated
and wouldn't settle down.
So I told him, it's either
the hospital for his injuries
or the drunk tank.
- Hmm. He's no idiot.
- Yeah.
He was adamant about
being brought to Med,
said he knows a doctor here.
He say which one?
He kept asking for Rip.
- For Rip?
- What are you gonna do?
I don't want any BPMs.
I don't want nothing.
Hey, Mr. Sullivan,
how you doing?
- Who the hell are you?
- I'm Dr. Charles.
You know, Nancy's just
trying to get your vitals,
make sure you're okay,
take two seconds.
No, I'm already
good. I feel good.
Where's Rip? I
wanna talk to Rip.
Do you mean Dr. Ripley?
Just get him.
Nancy, let's give
Mr. Sullivan a little space
- and page Dr. Ripley.
- Okay.
Thank you.
Hey. Trauma called.
Subclavian repair went smoothly.
- Patient's doing well.
- Good. Thanks, Trini.
Hey, I got your page. What's up?
Oh, are you, uh,
are you familiar with this
gentleman in five here?
Mr., uh... Mr. Sullivan,
Robert Sullivan.
Yeah.
Gentleman is pushing
it. What happened?
He got banged up in a bar fight,
insisted on being brought
to Med because of you.
Won't let anybody
else treat him.
No!
At the very least, I
need your temperature.
No! No.
Great.
Yeah, keeps on asking for Rip.
Yeah, uh, Sully and I used
to run the streets together
before I left Chicago.
Oh, yeah?
You... you okay
treating an old buddy?
I can find somebody else.
We're not that close, so
it shouldn't be a problem.
Thanks.
Okay.
I won't have this
conversation with you.
Hey!
There he is.
All right, let's
keep it down, Sully.
I told you I knew him.
I got this. Thank you.
Thank God.
I can finally relax.
Don't even think about it.
Jeez.
Cop might as well have
dropped me off at jail.
Still an option if you
keep acting this way,
showing up here, giving
everybody a hard time.
And a bar fight at
the crack of dawn?
What the hell, Sully?
Hey, some guys were
talking down on my Bulls,
and I retorted, and they
couldn't take a joke,
so we handled it outside.
Yeah, looks like
they handled you.
Where else they get you?
Couple cheap body shots.
Not to mention your jaw.
I'm still a sex symbol, though.
I can't say the same
for him and his boy.
They were on the
receiving end of this.
Looks like what we call
a boxer's fracture.
Hmm, I like the sound of that.
I gotta say, I'm impressed
you finally learned
how to use your hands.
Could have used
them back in the day
while I was busy saving you
from getting your ass kicked.
Still got jokes.
Fancy white coat and
a pretty-boy haircut,
but at least you kept
your sense of humor.
Little short of breath there?
Ugh.
Just a little cough I
picked up over the holidays.
Let me take a listen.
Deep breath.
All right, I'm gonna
order bloodwork
and an X-ray to be safe.
I just wanted my hand looked at.
Now you're trying to up sell me?
Just put the gown
on and stay put.
Someone'll be by soon to
image your chest and hand.
And don't give them a hard time.
Throat doesn't look that bad.
How long have you been
feeling this way, Adriana?
A few weeks, hard to say.
Been traveling a lot, so my
sense of time is out of whack.
Anywhere fun?
Grand tour of the Midwest
Hotel Convention circuit.
I organize tabletop
and board game cons.
Anyway, I thought this was
just another con cough,
you know, something you
pick up when you're stuffed
in a ballroom full
of gamers, but...
Can you breathe for me?
Ow, that hurt.
Your lungs do sound
a little junky.
Just means that there's
a lot of phlegm.
Could be from flu,
COVID, or pneumonia.
But we won't know until we
run a few tests to be sure.
I just got my shots,
but pneumonia?
Wow.
We'll take good care of you.
Let's start with a
chest X-ray, CBC, BMP,
swabs for COVID, flu, and strep,
and put in a CT
for chest and neck.
Okay.
I'll be back to
check on you soon.
Hey, I just wanted to double
check on those CAT scans.
Shouldn't we wait for
the chest X-ray first?
It seems aggressive.
Honestly, I'm not even sure that
this is just an infection.
But page me when
those tests are back.
You got it.
There you go.
You're a real pro at this.
It's not a skill I planned
on mastering, but thanks.
Caleb, Deb, good news.
Your labs came back normal.
Oh, that's great, hon.
Well, looks like your prolapse
hasn't reduced as
quickly as we'd like.
It's probably because of
persistent congestion.
So based on what I'm seeing
here and Caleb's latest CT,
I think it would be
better if we went ahead
with your reversal surgery.
- Excuse me?
- Wait, what?
Truthfully, my recommendation
would be to do this
as soon as possible.
You're telling me I can get
rid of this thing, like, today?
I should be able to
get you on the schedule
in a few hours, yeah.
Let's go!
Mom, we can call Coach Mark,
tell him I'm running with
the soldiers this summer.
This is good news.
Can I speak with
you for a moment?
I don't understand.
You can't reduce the
prolapse bedside?
Well, I probably can,
but I think surgery
is the better long-term
solution at this point.
Caleb is several months out,
and his recovery is going great.
His labs indicate that
he's healthy, strong.
All due respect,
Dr. Davis has been
with us since day one.
We've known you,
what, two hours?
Dr. Archer has a lot of
experience with this.
Our doctor was adamant we wait,
that with all of
Caleb's surgeries,
the adhesions needed
time to break down
before we can do the reversal.
That was a solid plan.
However, Caleb's
recurring prolapses
could make it more likely
for him to prolapse again.
And possibly make
the eventual repair
more challenging.
You don't know for sure.
I won't trade my
son's health for that.
I know you wanna hold
off until you get home,
but I'd be happy to speak
with your pediatric surgeon.
Like I said, Dr. Davis believes
Caleb is better off waiting.
So until he says otherwise,
I'm not discussing
surgery any further.
Can I get your
eyes on something?
Of course.
Skipped right to CT scans, huh?
Patient came in with classic
signs of an infection,
but with the shortness
of breath and chest pain,
I was afraid that it was a
septic pulmonary embolism.
- I know that's a long shot.
- No, you were on the money.
Look... definitely a small PE.
Check out this next CT.
I'm not exactly sure
what I'm looking at.
Peritonsillar abscess
with infiltration
to the jugular vein.
What'd the swab come back as?
Strep.
Hmm.
This is Lemierre
syndrome, isn't it?
I've only read about it.
Effective blood clot
in the neck, yeah.
Very rare, very dangerous.
Explains a lot... infection
starts in the throat,
spreads to the jugular, starts
throwing clots downstream.
Okay, we
we need to anticoagulate
your patient ASAP.
So go ahead and start
her on a heparin drip,
prevent the existing
clot from propagating,
and I'd also start her
on antibiotics, okay?
Why wait when we can go after
the clot with the thrombectomy
and eliminate the risk entirely?
We're not there yet.
Let's give the meds some
time to get the fever down.
But if she doesn't
turn the corner soon,
I think you're right.
Surgery may be our
best bet, okay?
I'll get Adriana up to speed.
Good. And I'll call ENT.
They'll need to
scope her, all right?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, Mr. Sullivan...
Sully, Sully, I'm so sorry.
Buddy, we can't
really have patients
wandering around out here.
We just have too much
foot traffic out here.
It's a hospital policy
thing. I hope you understand.
But I just wanna find
a place to smoke.
I just can't be in that room.
Totally get it.
It's such a drag having to wait.
But I promise you, Dr. Ripley
will be by any second.
Oh, speak of the devil.
Hey, hard to believe it's
the same guy who had us
stealing candy
when we were kids.
Where the hell were you?
I told you to stay put.
I'm sorry, Dr. Ripley.
Won't happen again.
I got this. Thanks.
Time for a bedtime story?
I'm tired as hell.
Actually, I think
you're gonna want
to sit up for this, seriously.
Okay, okay, what?
I got the results
from your chest X-ray.
They show a nodule in your
left lung that concerns me.
And your white blood
cell count came back low.
So you'll... you'll need a
chest CT as well as a biopsy.
Can you explain it
to me in English?
You got early signs
of lung cancer.
Wait, what?
Look, I know it sounds scary.
But some lung cancers
are very treatable.
I'll refer you to an oncologist.
That's a cancer specialist.
No, no, no.
I only came here to avoid jail
and get my hand patched up.
Now you're throwing
the C-word at me.
Like I said, I'll have
an oncologist talk...
I feel fine.
The way I see it,
this convo's over.
I want out.
You need a thorough
evaluation and treatment plan.
No! I'm done.
Where do I sign?
All right.
At least let me
get ortho in here
to splint that broken hand.
The bandage is just temporary.
It shouldn't take long.
Fine, but that's all.
Excuse me.
Can you point me
to your cafeteria?
I'm trying to find
something Caleb can eat.
Absolutely.
Right this way.
I have to say, you've really
got a handle on Caleb's care.
Must be reassuring for him.
Thank you, though I
suspect Caleb wishes
he could see a
little less of me.
I'd take that as a good sign.
It means he's a normal teenager.
Normal?
It's been a long road to
get here, for both of us.
Yeah.
You know, after Caleb
was shot, I was a mess.
The emergency room, the
ICU, in and out of surgery,
I felt like I basically
lived at the hospital.
I can't imagine
how rough that was.
It was the waiting, you know,
the not knowing
that wore me out.
But we finally made it home.
We figured out a
routine together,
the bag changes, the
diet, the cleaning.
Caleb hates it, but it's
a version of normal.
Yeah.
Oh, the cafeteria is down
the hall to the right.
Just follow the signs.
You can't miss it.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
All right, Caleb.
I think we're ready
to reduce this.
Okay, I'm sorry.
Okay, Caleb.
You're gonna feel a
little bit of pressure.
Are you ready?
Okay.
So Oakland.
I know of some Hall of Famers
at your position from there.
Gary Payton, Jason
Kidd... before your time.
I studied them both.
- But Dame is my guy.
- Ah.
So if I get this surgery,
what kind of recovery
time am I looking at?
That depends.
Probably a question for
your pediatric surgeon.
You've gotta have
an idea, right?
I mean, we talking days, weeks?
How long I'ma have to wait
to get back on the court?
Yeah, I think that's
a conversation
we can have with your mother.
When your mother comes back
from the cafeteria, we can...
She already made up her mind.
But it's my life.
There's a chance that
I could still salvage
my high school career, I
could still get a full ride
from a big-time D-I school.
And I could make a
play for the NBA.
You said you could
do this today, right?
Come on, Doc, you
did, didn't you?
Yes, I did.
Dr. Archer, may I speak
to you for a second?
All right, your stoma's all set.
What can I do? He
backed me into a corner.
He's a minor, and his mother
made her wishes very clear.
All right, listen, now,
I don't need a tutorial
on medical ethics.
Caleb has the right to
know what his future holds.
And I feel for Caleb too.
But they just got
their lives back
after a horrific experience.
Right, one I wanna
help him move on from.
You can't just move on
after your life's been
turned upside down.
Deb is just trying to
hold on to something
that is normal for them.
That's the problem, okay?
She's clinging to a normal
that does not exist.
So instead of moving forward,
she's not doing anything at all,
even when her son
clearly wants to.
What-what does my son want?
Caleb reiterated to me
that he wants the reversal
procedure, but I told him...
I thought I made
myself clear earlier.
Yes, you did, but...
Has my son's prolapse
been resolved?
Yes, it has.
Then I would like
him to be discharged.
Bert, how'd it go?
Bert.
You got what you wanted, okay?
What did the neurologist say?
I was doing fine till you had
to go and screw everything up.
Well, I'm just
concerned for you, Bert.
We're divorced.
Stay out of my life.
Dr. Charles, can you
do a capacity check
on Sully for me?
Why, have you noticed
some kind of behavioral
or cognitive change since
you last connected with him?
He's being irrational.
He probably has lung cancer,
but he's refusing
further testing.
Oh, boy. I'm sorry to hear that.
If I let him walk
out of here AMA,
I'm basically handing
him a death sentence.
Unfortunately, refusing
further testing
is not really grounds for
questioning somebody's
decisional capacity.
He's got a terminal illness
and won't get treatment.
Sounds like he's got a problem
with his decisional
capacity to me.
Okay, so this is where
I have to ask you,
would you be pushing for this
if this were just
a regular patient?
It's the only way I can
see to save his life.
I mean, unfortunately, if he
doesn't wanna pursue treatment,
there's just...
I mean, there's nothing
we can do about it.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, me too.
Dr. Marcel, Dr. Ahmad.
Her blood pressure
just dropped 20 points,
90/60 and still falling.
Where am I?
She's disoriented.
And hypotensive.
Must be septic shock.
Zola, start a central line
and get her on pressors.
Need to get her BP back up.
Get a bag on her. Dial
up the O2 to 15 liters.
And bolus a liter of crystalloid
- and set up a norepi drip.
- On it.
Adriana, slow, deep
breaths for me, okay?
Pressure's still down.
Need to get that line in.
Got it.
Wire.
Go ahead.
We're in.
Okay, start the norepi at 10
and titrate up to a MAP of 65.
Norepi's on.
Okay, cycle the BP cuff.
Blood pressure's
coming back up, 95/65,
and sats are climbing as well.
- She's stabilizing.
- Good.
Let's draw a culture,
start her on vanc,
and let's get an A-line set up.
- Let's get a blood gas too.
- Page us when she's lucid.
You were right.
She's gonna need a thrombectomy.
- Here.
- What's this?
A little light reading a
critical care committee
just drafted.
"Revised post-operative
muscle relaxant
reversal agent protocol."
See, I heard getting
Exsomadex pulled
was your little crusade.
Thought you might be eager to
learn about its replacement.
"The new recommended
reversal agent is Gamaverse."
There a problem?
No, except it's ten times
the cost of Exsomadex,
which gets pushed
on to the patients
when their insurance
won't cover it.
That... there has to be
cheaper therapeutic
alternative options.
No. Nope. No. Not
according to the committee.
So the next time you think
about sounding the alarm
off limited data, think twice.
Mom, I got it.
Okay.
Um, Deb, I've got your
discharge paperwork,
and I'll have someone
by to walk you out.
Thank you.
Okay.
Caleb, I know this is hard.
But your life is more
important than some game.
Not much of a life anyways.
I'll go pull the car around.
Deb, wait, please.
- What?
- I just...
I'm sorry that you're leaving.
But Dr. Archer is an
excellent surgeon.
And he just wants to do
what's right by your son.
I really don't want
to discuss this again.
I know you're afraid.
And it makes sense
with everything
that you've gone through.
What we're still going through.
Of course.
It's understandable that
you would want to hold on
to what's familiar
while you can,
while your world has
been turned inside-out.
It has taken everything I've
got just to make it this far.
Deb.
I don't know if I can go
through this again right now.
What if it goes wrong?
I don't think I can handle that.
At least this way, I know
what tomorrow looks like.
I understand.
But this life now,
is it worth holding on to,
knowing that there's a
possibility of another way?
Dr. Malone, good afternoon.
Ms. Goodwin, come in.
Bert just left, so
I have to assume
your visit is not a coincidence.
Well, I know given
HIPAA regulations,
it's not my place to come here
and ask about your patients,
but my family's worried.
I understand.
And there is no
privacy issue here
as you're listed as Bert's
primary emergency contact.
I'm listed as his
emergency contact?
Yeah, it's what's in his file.
I'm sorry to have
to tell you, but...
I've diagnosed Bert with
Alzheimer's dementia.
Alzheimer's.
Now, there are treatments
available to him.
But as you're well
aware, this diagnosis
can be a long and rough
road for everyone involved.
You likely know most of this.
But here's some
information your family
can anticipate moving forward.
Yeah.
I offered them to
Bert, but he, um,
he left them behind.
He didn't take the news well?
Well, in my experience,
few people do.
My door is always open.
To you or your children,
if you have any more
questions or concerns.
Thank you.
All right, Caleb, game time.
Mr. Sullivan, I assure you,
they're just printing
your paperwork.
Keep it. I don't care.
I'm leaving.
I'm out of here.
Excuse me. Excuse me, lady.
Sully, Sully, come
on. Knock it off.
- Get back in bed.
- I got my splint.
I'm leaving.
You need to see an oncologist.
Shut up already.
You got your little
iPad and your name tag,
you think I'm supposed
to do what you say?
I'm trying to help you, man.
And I'm trying to leave, man.
Move.
If you walk out of
here, this will be
the dumbest thing
you've ever done.
- You can't leave.
- Out of my way.
No.
Rip, I'm gonna tell
you one more time.
- Move!
- Can't do it.
Security!
Hey! Security!
Dr. Ripley.
Dr. Ripley!
Calm down. Calm down.
Hey, calm down. Settle down.
You all right?
Yeah.
Should I call Dr. Archer?
Um, no, give me a
couple minutes, okay?
No. No. I'm not... I'm not...
I'm not in the
mood for a lecture.
You don't... you
don't know Sully.
There's only one way
to deal with him.
By tackling him to the ground?
I was just trying to get
the situation under control.
Mm, looked kind of like
you lost control to me.
So file a complaint.
Let's go see Archer
and Ms. Goodwin.
Come on. Let's get it over with.
So... so you can lose your job?
Is that what we wanna do now?
Yeah, I screwed up.
I screwed up, okay? I know that.
I'm just trying to... just
trying to look out for the guy.
I get that, but ideally,
you don't wanna risk
your job in doing so.
If I'd never left Chicago,
I'd probably have been right
there with him, at that bar,
throwing down beside him.
That's how tight we were.
But I wanted out of that
life, and I got out.
And that's a good thing, right?
But it can be a little more
complicated for the people
who feel, you know, left behind.
You know, having said
that, I think he came here
looking for you
because he trusts you.
Then why won't he listen to me?
Maybe he wasn't looking for
some guy in a white coat
with a fancy degree.
Maybe he's just
looking for his friend.
So
You tolerated surgery well.
And from what I'm seeing,
you're gonna be fine.
- For real?
- Thank God.
A few days here, a
few weeks at home,
and you'll be back on your feet.
Then I can hoop again?
Maybe in about eight weeks,
but only if you take it easy.
That's cool.
I appreciate you, Doc.
Well, save me some tickets
when you make it to the NBA
floor seats, preferably.
Thank you, Dr. Archer.
And thank you for pushing me.
I'm just glad that you and
Caleb get to move forward.
Sharon, I'm just so sorry.
Well, I guess the upside is,
now I know what
I'm dealing with.
Exactly.
And you know what?
I mean, there are some very
promising clinical trials
happening right now.
Some exciting new medications
are being developed.
And I'm just... I'm confident if
we get the right kind of help,
that we're
we're gonna be able
to navigate this.
We?
You mean me.
The decisions that
will have to be made,
the appointments,
the treatments,
that's all gonna
fall on me, Daniel.
What about the kids? I mean,
the kids will be there.
No. They've got their own lives.
I don't want them to have
to deal with this, either.
And how am I gonna do it?
I've got a hospital to run.
I got a new relationship that
is really going well.
And then what?
I have to take care
of my ex-husband.
I know it's selfish just to
think about myself, but...
No, it is not, not at all.
I can't do it, Daniel.
I can't.
Hi, Adriana. How
are you feeling?
Been better.
Well, look, we wanna talk
to you about next steps.
So given the state
of your infection,
it's our recommendation that
we progress with a procedure
called a thrombectomy.
Dr. Ahmad said
something about that.
Yeah, so myself and an
interventional radiologist
would pass a wire up
your arm, into your neck,
and basically extract the clot.
Oh, God.
The procedure is
minimally invasive,
and it would eliminate
any risk posed
by the clot, set
the antibiotics up
for success moving forward.
We'll have you
home in a few days.
This procedure, I
really have to do it?
There's no other option?
Yes, that would be
my recommendation.
Well, there might be.
- We could wait.
- What do you mean?
Give the antibiotics a chance
to fight off the infection.
And the blood thinners
haven't had that long
to break up the primary clot.
Which means it would still
pose a serious threat, no?
But if we give the
medications a chance,
then maybe we can
bypass the need
for a thrombectomy altogether.
Really?
Very unlikely is how I'd put it.
Dr. Ahmad, could
I speak with you?
Now, what was that?
You undermined me in
front of the patient.
And this procedure was your
plan from the start, right?
We both know that going after
an unstable clot is risky.
Same is true if we just sit
on our hands here, right?
Now, IR is the only real
path forward for Adriana.
You knew that hours ago.
So what's changed?
Everyone keeps saying
that I'm impulsive,
that I make rash decisions.
And I think they're right.
I've been here a
month, and already,
I've been assigned
an ethics course,
pissed off the board, and now
this disaster with Exsomadex.
Maybe I should
keep my mouth shut.
Stop.
She needs this
procedure, period.
All right, go clear your head.
Go on.
Okay, I'm off.
To the on-call room or...
No, I'm heading home.
Oh.
I think it's time
that I move on.
Yeah.
Uh...
Tara, hey, sweetie.
How's it
no, wait, wait, wait.
Slow down, sweetie, slow down.
Hey. What are you doing?
Tara called and said Bert's
not answering his phone.
And I called, and it went
straight to voicemail.
You know he's tried to
take his life once before,
so I'm just gonna head
over to his place.
- I'll come with you.
- You don't have to.
- No, I'm coming.
- Okay.
Still nursing that
bougie coffee?
How's Adriana?
The procedure went
well, no complications.
She's back in the ICU,
awake and talking, okay?
- That's great. Thanks.
- Sure.
Hey.
Yeah?
Do you know who that guy is?
Everett James? Yeah.
We sit on the board together.
He's a bigwig at
Ward and Bancroft.
Yeah, the pharma company, so?
So I did some research
while you were in surgery,
and guess who manufactures
our new expensive reversal
medication, Gamaverse?
Ward and Bancroft?
Yeah.
Huh.
So this board member sells
his product to the hospital.
Must have used
our recommendation
to get himself a
sweetheart deal.
That... that's a
conflict of interest.
That can't be legal.
Look, I don't agree
with it, either,
but it's not illegal.
This is all happening
because of my recommendation.
Hold on, are you... are
you blaming yourself?
Before you spiral
out any further,
let me remind you what's
actually important
your patient,
who's alive and
well in large part
because you listened
to your instincts.
You knew thrombectomy was the
right call from the get-go.
Now, you might not
be able to take down
the medical-industrial complex.
But you saved a life today.
And, Zola, if that's
not good enough, then
maybe you should think
about another career.
Bulls snap that losing streak?
Lost it by 2 in OT.
Old fashioned, neat.
- Thanks.
- Yep.
Fancy drink.
Well, it's a lot
smoother than the rotgut
you got in your glass.
Some kind of mouse trap?
I use this and I wake
up under a knife?
Just a little something to
help out with that cough.
Look...
If you need anything,
anything at all,
you know where I'm hiding.
Doesn't matter where or when.
I got you.
I'll see you around, Rip.
Hope so.
- Bert!
- He's gotta be in there.
His car's out front.
- Bert!
- I got it. I got it.
Bert.
Bert, you home?
Bert?
I don't know what's
going to happen to me.
Well, whatever comes,
we'll deal with it.
I... I don't wanna make
this anyone else's problem.
I... I have to deal
with it on my own.
No.
No, you don't,
because I'm here.
And it's all right.
It's gonna be all right.