Friends, let us
raise a glass
to dear
Patrick Halstead.
May you be in Heaven
an hour before the Devil
knows you're dead.
Slainte!
Let me get you
another one.
Yes, please.
Mmm-hmm.
Thank you.
Will.
Tommy.
Hey.
Sorry about
your dad.
My old man couldn't be here.
He...
He's not feeling so well.
Sorry to hear it.
Yeah.
You know, you could do
me a solid, though.
Dad, he...
He won't go to a hospital.
Maybe you could come
by the house,
give him a look-see?
Sorry, Tommy, I'm an ED doc.
Emergency medicine.
All right.
I hope he feels better.
Thanks, Will.
Tommy.
Yeah?
Your father still running
the neighborhood?
You kidding me?
He'll never let that go.
All right, I'll drop by.
Thanks a lot, Will.
You got it.
You okay?
Great, man.
So...
It's only what, five days
till your hybrid OR's
up and running?
Four, actually,
and I've still got
personnel to train
and logistics
to figure out.
You're nervous about this,
aren't you?
I don't think I've ever
seen you nervous.
It's refreshing.
Not necessarily attractive,
but refreshing.
Help! Help me!
My son can't breathe.
Okay, come with me.
It's okay, buddy.
Dr. Choi.
What's going on?
Looks like the early stages
of respiratory failure.
Lay him down here.
Any medical history?
He was born with bad kidneys.
They see him
at the hospital
in Gary,
but I don't think
they know what they're doing.
Daddy! My tummy hurts.
When's the last time
he was dialyzed?
I don't know.
My ex deals with that.
Let's put him on oxygen,
then let reno know
he needs dialysis.
It really hurts.
I'm so sorry.
Ben, we're gonna
give you something
to make you feel better.
Just a minute, okay?
Here.
Okay.
He's got a lot
of fluid in his lungs.
Hopefully, the dialysis
will bring it down.
Then we can discuss
what to do next.
Yeah, of course, man,
whatever you say. Just do it.
Dr. Choi.
Hold on one second, Maggie.
I know this isn't easy,
but try to stay calm.
We're gonna take
good care of your son.
Dr. Choi, need to talk to you
right now. April.
Yeah?
That dad, Chris Davis,
there's a BOLO out
for his arrest.
A "be on the lookout"?
Yeah.
He kidnapped his son.
Apparently,
he just got out
of Joliet on parole.
Showed up at his ex-wife's,
grabs his son and takes off.
How's the boy?
End stage renal disease.
Oh, the poor kid.
I'll call PD.
Ms. Goodwin,
Ben's in bad enough shape
without having
to watch his dad get
arrested and taken away.
Could we just hold off
until he's stabilized?
April.
He risked his freedom
to bring Ben here.
He's not gonna leave.
I'm not sure that's our call.
Can you think of any medical
reason why we should hold off?
No.
I'll keep an eye on Ben.
Go ahead
and make the call.
Okay, then.
Really?
Our first duty is
to protect our patient.
How? By taking his dad away?
We have no idea what
this man is capable of.
Sharon.
Gwen.
Dr. Lanik, new coat.
Since Dr. Stohl
is no longer here,
Dr. Lanik will be
our interim chief of the ED.
Congratulations.
Thank you. Excuse me.
You didn't consult
me on this.
It seems to be your mission
to fight me on everything.
Until that changes,
I'm going to be making
some decisions unilaterally.
Mr. Nevins, I'm Dr. Rhodes.
Nice to meet you.
Call me Bill.
All right, Bill it is.
So, I understand you've got
some new onset back pain, huh?
Yeah, but it's not too bad.
It's nothing you need
to get making a fuss about.
Yeah, well, fuss
is kind of our thing here.
Now, it looks like your CT
shows an aortic dissection,
which means you've got
a tear on the inside
of your vessel wall.
Do you have any tingling
in your arms?
Nope.
Uh, any palpitations,
funny feelings
in your chest?
Nothing. Seriously,
I'm good to go.
Well, you might be right.
It looks like
the tear is small,
so if we can
get you stabilized,
we should be able to send
you home to follow up
with the cardiologist.
That'd be great.
All right.
Start him on an Esmolol drip,
and if his systolic gets
above 120,
let me know.
Yes, Doctor.
I'll be back to check in
on you in a bit.
Thanks, Doctor.
You ever taken a lead
on a case before?
Not yet.
Well, today's
your lucky day.
Mr. and Mrs. Harris,
I'm student doctor Curry
and this is Dr. Manning.
I'm Lisa.
Matt.
So, you're 13 weeks
pregnant with three days
of abdominal pain.
Have you ever had pain
like this before?
No.
I'm going to examine you,
if that's all right.
Okay, have you had
any bleeding?
No.
Okay, any complications
with your pregnancy?
No. I mean,
not with the pregnancy.
For years, doctors said
Lisa could never get pregnant.
We tried and we prayed,
but nothing worked,
until, one day,
it just happened.
Did they tell you why
you couldn't get pregnant?
Um, something about
the shape of my uterus.
They did some tests,
but whatever it is,
it doesn't matter
'cause we finally have
our miracle baby.
So, the thing
about human anatomy
is that even when things
may seem like a miracle...
You know, before
we get much further,
I think we should check
your blood and send you
over for a doppler,
just to get
some more information.
Is that okay?
Yeah, that's okay.
Great. We'll be back soon.
First trimester pain
in a woman with
anatomic abnormalities
means that this pregnancy
could be ectopic.
Yes, but that does not mean
that we need to give her
a physiology lesson.
We do if we want her to be
informed about her condition.
She's entitled to her beliefs.
It is not our job
to challenge them.
It is when they're wrong.
Ms. Curry,
we don't know what
we're looking at yet,
so just go order the tests.
Hey, Ben.
Feeling any better?
No.
He's in SVT.
Give him four milligrams of
Diltiazem over five minutes.
"SVT"? What's that?
It's an arrhythmia.
You mean his heart?
I thought the problem
was his kidneys.
It is, but kidney failure
can lead to dysfunction
in other systems.
Will dialysis fix it?
I mean, he's been doing that
and he's still getting worse.
We need to give it a chance
before I can assess
what else he might need.
You didn't have to do this.
Sorry, legally, I had to.
Hey, Benny.
Benny, I got to go away
for a little while.
But Dr. Choi is gonna take
good care of you, okay?
So you listen to him
and do whatever he says,
and I promise,
everything's gonna be okay.
Okay?
Okay.
I love you. Okay.
Christopher Davis,
you're under arrest
for aggravated kidnapping,
endangerment of a child,
violation of an order
of protection
and violation of parole.
Do everything
you can for Ben.
Please.
All right, let's go.
Burgess, uh...
Uh, hold up.
What's up?
His son's really sick.
Could you keep him here
till we have a better idea
of what's going on?
That's not up to me.
I know.
If you want, I can,
I don't know, call the
State's Attorney and find out.
I'd appreciate it.
He can wait in there.
Okay.
Talbert.
Thanks.
Is that the baby?
Yes.
What?
Your pregnancy
is ectopic,
which means that the fetus
is implanted outside
of your uterus.
Okay, but you can put it back
where it belongs, right?
Unfortunately, we can't.
And I'm afraid
it's implanted
on your vena cava,
the large vessel
that carries blood
back to your heart.
And from the free fluid
I'm seeing in your abdomen
tells me that, unfortunately,
the vessel is leaking.
So how do you stop it?
I mean,
you need an operation.
The surgeon will have
to remove the fetus
and then repair the vessel.
Wait, you mean
we could lose the baby?
I'm sorry, but you would
in any case because
of where it's implanted.
There's no possible way
that it'll survive
long enough to be viable.
In surgery, we'll keep
your bleeding from
getting out of control,
so we need to get you up
to the OR as soon as possible.
No.
I'm sorry?
I am not having surgery.
I don't think
you understand.
If we don't operate,
you're going to die.
No, you don't understand.
This baby is a miracle.
And God will take
care of it.
Bill, what's happening?
It's like it's tearing a hole
through my belly.
Maggie, we need
to get Mr. Nevins
to Interventional now.
I'm on it.
Bill, I think the tear in your
aorta is getting larger,
so we need to place
a stent so it doesn't
get any worse, okay?
Yes, if you say so.
Okay.
Maggie, get transport down.
We need to get him moving.
IR's full.
It can't wait.
Can they bump any cases?
No, and both CT ORs are full,
too. There's nowhere to go.
If his aorta ruptures,
he's gonna bleed out.
Yeah.
I'm opening up
my hybrid OR.
It's not ready yet,
and it's not fully stocked.
Bill is too unstable.
I can't risk his aorta
blowing while we wait
to get him upstairs.
That team is not trained yet
and... You haven't done
a single run-through.
Dr. Rhodes!
Will, when was
the last time
you were here?
Man, I can't
even remember.
Hey, Tim.
Will.
What's the score?
Just started.
All right.
Dad.
Hey, Dad.
Will Halstead's here.
William.
Still got the red hair.
Nice to see you, Mr. Burke.
Please, Ray.
Dad, I'll be in the kitchen.
Yeah.
See you, Will.
And, listen,
I'm sorry about
your father.
Good guy, but a terrible
poker face.
Always looked to the left
when he had a good hand.
He loved those
Friday night games.
So, what seems
to be the problem?
Ah, it's nothing.
Tommy's a worrywart.
I just been getting
these dizzy spells.
Sometimes they'll lay me out
a couple hours.
Well, sit down.
Let's have a listen.
This is what's missing
from medicine these days,
the face to face.
I'll take a house call
over some giant hospital
any day.
Can't say I blame you.
Yeah, you do have
a little bit of a murmur.
Probably worth
keeping an eye on.
So, what are you
up to these days?
Still got that place
down on Union?
The hall? Yeah.
Man, must be a heck
of a business.
I tell you,
I'm getting married soon,
and all the places
out there
are either booked up
or charging a fortune.
Oh.
Yeah.
So?
Are you gonna
ask me or what?
No, that's not why...
Come on, kid.
You check in on me
on your day off,
you need a hall.
I'm not an idiot.
I didn't mean to...
I'm happy to do it.
So just say yes.
You're too smart
for me, Mr. Burke. Ray.
I really appreciate it.
Nah.
I gotta draw some blood.
Run some tests.
My favorite part.
All right, let's get
this started.
Where's Beth?
Stuck in the OR.
This wasn't on the schedule.
Gene, what's happening
with the monitors?
It's a brand-new system.
I'm still figuring it out.
Dr. Rhodes, patient's under.
I'm set.
Denise, what's the hold up?
I can't find the right-sized
guide wires.
All right, IV contrast,
injector tubing, and 20
and 60 CC syringes.
I didn't know
which ones you wanted.
Thank you, Maggie.
Welcome.
Dr. Rhodes, I still can't find
the correct guidewires.
Oh, that's the middle cabinet,
top left corner.
Iris, call upstairs.
We're not gonna need Beth.
I can make the call.
Nope. I need you to scrub in.
What? I can't do that.
You used to scrub, right?
Yeah, that's like forever ago.
I don't even know
if I remember.
I need a pair of hands.
Go scrub in.
April, take over.
Yeah. No problem.
Just figure this out,
we'll be fine.
Your patient, Mrs. Harris,
just passed
the Brief Psychiatric Rating
Scale with flying colors.
You actually think
she's capable
of making this decision?
She is holding on
to a very strong belief,
but other than that,
she seems entirely reasonable.
"Reasonable"? She thinks
God is going to save
a fetus with a 0%
chance of survival.
That's delusional.
In my experience, it's not
always so easy to figure out
where belief ends
and delusion begins.
I mean,
faith in a supreme being
is held by an overwhelming
majority of humans.
Okay, but if we don't do
something, she's going to die.
Can't force a procedure on her
that she doesn't want.
We're her doctors.
Our job is to fix her,
not argue about theology.
I'm sorry,
but this is ridiculous.
Ms. Curry, I appreciate
that this is
a complicated situation,
but our job, in fact,
is to treat our patients
to the best of our ability
while honoring their
cultural, spiritual
and religious beliefs.
She's allowed to make
her own decisions
whether we agree
with them or not.
What did the State's Attorney
say about that kid's dad?
I haven't
heard back yet.
But does he have to wait
in my treatment room?
For now, yes.
Ben needs
a kidney transplant.
I want to see
if Chris is a match.
The man's going to jail.
And his son is dying.
His boy needs a kidney.
We don't have a choice.
Almost done.
My ex is always telling me
how they're doing just fine
without me.
Then I saw him lying there,
looking so sick.
Yeah.
For whatever it's worth,
Ben may very well have died
if you hadn't
brought him here today.
Anyway, it's not like
he's gonna miss me.
Never really been there
for him in the first place.
I'll have the results soon.
What you got there?
"The Journal
of Computer Methods
and Biomedicine."
MIT grad, right?
Yep.
Looks very technical.
It is.
But so is creating
a biomolecular scaffolding
to replicate
human organs in vitro.
That's what I'm going
to do as soon as
I finish med school.
Hmm. Sounds rewarding.
You know, in terms
of Mrs. Harris, I just
want to clarify that
the challenge when
you're trying to evaluate
a patient's ability
to act in their
own interests...
Oh! Actually, her labs
are ready. I should
go check on them.
Femoral sheath is in.
Gene, get in closer.
Zooming in.
What?
That bulge there,
that's where
his aortic wall
is the weakest.
That wasn't there before.
That's because his
aneurysm's enlarging.
We need to open him up.
What do you mean?
His aorta is being squeezed
closed. I'm gonna try going
in from the top.
Dr. Rhodes, the team's
not ready. Let me just
call upstairs...
We don't have time
to go upstairs.
Dr. Rhodes, we don't even
have profusion down here.
So we'll do without.
Set up for a thoracotomy.
Dr. Rhodes... It's...
Maggie!
We are opening him up.
All right, you heard the man.
Let's get set up
for a thoracotomy.
Let's go!
I can't get a good angle
on the aorta.
You opened his chest!
We didn't have a choice.
You told me yourself
this room wasn't ready.
What if this patient
doesn't survive?
Connor, I advocated for this
program. For you.
And now you're gonna
blow it up
before it even starts?
Damn it.
This isn't working.
Great. How do you propose
we get him upstairs
with his chest open?
I'm not going to.
Get me a five-inch
30 millimeter Dacron graft.
We're gonna cut out
the damaged aorta
and sew in a graft.
Prepare for cross clamp.
"Cross clamp."
That only gives you
30 minutes, even under
the best of circumstances.
This is a terrible long shot.
Yeah, I understand the risk.
Fine, I'll scrub in.
Six-and-a-half gloves.
No, I have everyone I need.
You wanna kill this man, fine.
Cross clamps
times two.
Thank you.
Right away.
Natalie.
Hey, so you know how it's been
impossible to find a venue
for the wedding?
Mmm-hmm.
Well, I found one.
You did?
And not just found it,
killed it.
It seats 200, separate room
for cocktails, and I got
the place at cost.
How did you do that?
The owner's a guy
who knew my dad.
He wasn't feeling well,
so I made a house call.
I looked him over
and he insisted we take it.
Will, that's fantastic.
That's how Canaryville works,
you scratch my back,
I scratch yours.
Dr. Manning.
The ICU just called.
Mrs. Harris'
pressure's dropping.
On my way.
This is great.
Yeah.
Let's go.
She's 90 over 60.
What's going on?
Let's see.
You're losing too much blood.
We need to get you
to surgery now.
I already told you no.
Honey, maybe we should
listen to the doctors.
Not you too, Matt.
I am not having surgery.
Lisa...
Please stop.
For 12 years, all I wanted
was to bring a new life
into this world,
and finally,
God has rewarded
my patience.
And I don't believe
that he would turn around
and take it all away.
What if he did
take it away?
What?
If the fetus were to
stop living because
of the blood loss,
would you give us permission
to do the surgery then?
To let us save your life?
What are you...
Why is she even talking about
this? That's not gonna happen.
She's just asking.
So will you at least agree
to that? If the fetus dies.
Fine,
if that happened,
which it won't, then...
Yes, I would have
the surgery.
Can we stop
talking about this?
Of course.
Bolus a liter of saline,
and type and cross
for six and six,
and give her two units
of uncrossmatched blood now.
We'll be back to check
on your shortly, okay?
Okay.
Thank you.
Ms. Curry, that was
a disturbing,
tactless question.
Why did you ask that?
Because we should know, right?
To be prepared.
No, there is a difference
between being prepared
and terrifying a sick woman.
I'm at work.
What?
Caught on fire?
Emily, don't you know
you can't put something
in the microwave
if it doesn't say
"microwave safe"?
No, don't touch anything,
okay? I'll take care of it
when I get home.
Nice.
What?
She's your sister.
Talk to her however you want.
What's going on with you?
Nothing.
It's just unfortunate that you
can't give anyone a break.
Me?
You know,
I can't win with you.
You disapproved when I was
tough on Emily, then you
walked out when I took her in,
and now you're mad at me
for telling her how to use
the microwave
so she doesn't burn
my apartment down.
I'm not the problem here,
April, you are.
Hey, Joey.
Hey.
Could you run a CBC, BMP,
LFTs, and a thyroid panel
on those, please?
Sure.
Ray Burke.
Oh, uh... Where's the
Patient Accession Number?
Doesn't have one.
It's for a friend.
Look, I can't run blood work
for anyone who's not a patient
in the hospital.
Come on, Joey.
What's the big deal?
Processing bodily fluids
is highly regulated,
and if my numbers
don't match up, then
somebody's gonna know.
I'm sure you'll figure
something out.
Sorry, man.
Nah, you're right.
We should play by the rules.
You remember last month?
Your bronchitis?
I gave you amoxicillin?
Yeah.
I should fill out
admission forms, submit them
to your insurance,
then we can have a Patient
Accession Number on that, too.
Your friend's results
should be ready in an hour.
What a saint.
Yeah.
What's going on?
Mr. Davis is
a transplant match
for his son.
We're taking him up
to the OR.
No. We can't do that.
Excuse me?
He's the only donor
within 500 miles.
Ben needs his kidney.
I'm sorry,
but I have my orders.
You cannot deny
that boy a transplant.
I don't want to,
but the moment we take
his father upstairs,
he becomes
our patient as well.
I understand
transplant protocol.
So then you know that
the dad is gonna spend
a few days in the ICU,
but then what?
Jail while awaiting trial,
and then prison.
Those are hardly ideal
conditions in which to recover
from major surgery.
We could very well lose him.
Find an acceptable donor.
Let's not lose anybody.
Gwen, we don't have time,
and the father is a match.
You know
the hospital's position
on ultra high-risk patients,
especially those who have
a proven history of making
extremely poor decisions.
So you're sacrificing
the child to protect
your statistics?
Our statistics,
which allow us
to remain an accredited
transplant center
serving this entire city,
and that is my concern.
And it should be yours,
as well.
I let him know he won't
be allowed to give Ben
his kidney.
Any luck finding
another donor?
No.
I have a call into East Mercy.
There's a chance
they may agree
to let Chris donate there.
Let's hope.
Yeah.
Ray, I just want to let
you know that your
blood work looks good,
but given your murmur, I do
recommend that you follow up
with a cardiologist.
Well, I'm sorry,
but my specialty
is emergency medicine.
You'd be better served...
And, Ray, I really
appreciate that...
Okay, I'd be happy to.
You know,
let me check my schedule,
and I'll find a day that works
and I'll stop by.
Ultrasound.
Start the MTP.
What's happening to her?
Her internal bleeding
is getting worse.
Katie, call the OR.
Lisa!
BP's 92 over 51.
I need to take you
to surgery right now.
No, my baby.
Lisa, listen to her.
Mrs. Harris, I need
your consent. We don't
have a lot of time.
I can't find a heartbeat.
What?
The fetus.
What is it?
There's no heartbeat.
Its heart isn't beating.
No.
I'm sorry, but the fetus
is no longer alive.
No.
I need to take you
to surgery right now.
Lisa, come on. We have to go.
My baby.
BP's 70 over 35.
Mrs. Harris, look at me.
I need to take you
to surgery right now.
If I don't, you will die.
Lisa.
Mrs. Harris, please.
Please.
Okay.
All right, let's go!
Time?
Got seven minutes.
Marty, the heart stopped.
Lost the A-line waveform.
He's in PEA. Get me epi.
Maggie, do internal CPR.
What?
Put your hands around
his heart, all the way around
his heart, and pump.
Is there no other option?
No, there's not.
You can do this.
Now keep squeezing.
Epi.
Squeeze harder.
Got a CPR waveform.
Stop.
And pump.
Let go.
Good job.
Six-and-a-half minutes.
Hey.
I heard Ms. Harris agreed
to the surgery once she lost
the fetal heartbeat.
They got to her in time.
She's gonna make it.
Well, that's a relief.
Yeah, but even though
the fetus wasn't viable,
its heart was still beating
when they opened Lisa up.
Really?
Yeah, I've got to go tell tech
that there was a malfunction
with the ultrasound.
Huh.
The State's Attorney said
we can't keep him here
any longer.
Well, we're still waiting
to hear back from East Mercy.
There's nothing I can do.
Dr. Choi!
He's in unstable SVT at 240.
He's not profusing.
Two milligrams of Adenosine.
Adenosine's in.
What's happening? Will someone
tell me what's happening?
Let him stay.
No change. Charge at 20
and sync.
Charged.
Clear!
Two more of Adenosine.
Charging to 40.
Adenosine's in.
No good. Clear!
Pulse is strong. Regular.
Is he gonna be okay?
His arrhythmias
are getting harder
to convert.
He's gonna die?
I'm sorry, Chris.
Let me see him.
Come on, please, man.
It's my son.
Let him.
Stop.
Not like that.
Daddy.
You're gonna be okay.
I love you, Ben.
I love you, too.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Chris!
Do the transplant.
You wanna do everything
you can for him?
Take my kidney.
I'm trying to find another
hospital to do the surgery.
I just need
a little more time.
No, he doesn't have time!
Do it now!
No!
Stand down!
Pupils are blown.
Start Levophed,
get him on a gurney,
and tell the transplant team
we're coming up now.
Okay.
Thought you'd like to know.
We just heard from East Mercy.
They would have done
the transplant.
What did we do?
You are a physician,
Dr. Lanik.
You know that
when you make a decision,
you don't always
get the outcome
that you want.
But that doesn't mean
that the decision was wrong.
To have such faith
in something, and then
have it go so wrong.
Yeah.
Are you gonna...
Are you gonna tell her
about the fetal heartbeat.
I'm happy to.
No.
No, I'll tell her. I just hate
to have to tell her at all.
I'm so sorry...
So, I heard about the false
reading on the ultrasound.
Yeah, those machines
can be delicate.
One good hit
to the transducer...
Save it.
You hacked the machine
so that it wouldn't read
the fetal heartbeat.
No, I did not.
You've been resistant
to the patient's wishes
from the start.
Because she was determined
to kill herself.
Do you know that
I can have you kicked
out of medical school?
Kicked out?
Well, you committed a crime.
No,
the machine malfunctioned.
Okay, I didn't do anything,
and, by the way,
that woman is alive.
Doesn't anybody
care about that?
That's not the point.
I know what the point...
Clearly, you don't!
I didn't do it.
Well, I can't prove it,
which makes you
a very lucky young woman.
But you are severely deficient
in attitude and temperament,
and I'm going to keep
a very close eye on you.
From now on, you and I
are gonna go over
all your charts
and all your cases together.
Are you serious?
Very.
Your numbers all look good,
Bill, so we're gonna
get you set up here, okay?
Thanks, Doc.
I'll be back to check on you
in the morning.
That was a hell of a day.
Sure was.
We should do it again.
What?
What do you say
to heading up my team?
Scrub in on all of my cases.
I'm a charge nurse.
Going back to the OR,
that's sort of a demotion.
Think about it.
My patient pulled through.
I'm glad to hear it.
Look, I am sorry
that I threw you
out of my OR.
It was a mistake.
It was inexcusable.
So how about a peace offering,
huh? I'll buy you a drink.
I don't care about
you throwing me out.
What I can't stand
is you acting so stupidly.
Willing to destroy your
program in service of your
arrogance and your ego.
So go enjoy your victory,
but I don't want
any part of it.
I'm gonna pick up
some dinner and I'll meet
you at your place.
Okay.
Oh, hey.
Do you think the hall
would hold 250?
I sent a picture of it
to my mom,
and now she wants to invite
a few more cousins.
Yeah, of course.
Great.
See you.
Good.
Come here.
Jay, what's up?
Get in the car.
What do you know
about Ray Burke?
Does some real estate,
owns a bar,
a construction company...
And a reception hall.
Yeah.
You went to see him.
He wasn't feeling well,
so I made a house call.
How do you know?
Ray, I just want to let you
know that your blood work
looks good,
but I do recommend
you follow up
with a cardiologist.
I'm not going
to a cardiologist.
I want you, Will. And, you
know, I'm giving you that
hall for two grand.
That's practically for free.
Yeah, what, are you listening
to my calls?
Ray's.
Ray's?
PD and the FBI have been
investigating him
for, like, two years,
and then look who
waltzes in, my brother.
Why are you investigating him?
'Cause he's a gangster.
Come on.
What, he pays off
a building inspector
every once in a while?
Try money laundering, fraud,
embezzlement, and now
you're involved with him.
I'm not involved with him,
okay? I'm using his hall.
It's no big deal.
Yes, it is. So whatever
you're doing, stop.
Go home.