Previously on ER.
I was wondering if you found a replacement
for the chief of emergency medicine.
- Someone you want to recommend?
- Yeah, me.
You're doctors. Stop thinking like
students and take on a real patient load.
- You like it over there? At Luka's?
- I guess so.
- You like him too, right?
- Yeah. Why?
You two decide yet?
About moving in?
Don't. It'll kill the romance. They're
on their best behavior at first...
then they're farting
in the kitchen.
Thanks for your help today.
- Sure.
- If you wait for a second...
I'll walk out with you.
Dr. Lewis, phone call.
- Say I'll be back in a minute.
- Seems persistent. Someone called Chuck.
Oh, yeah.
Hi, Chuck. I can't
talk right now.
Cosmo ate the yams? Okay.
Sure, of course I'm thrilled. It's just
I'm late for a meeting with Weaver.
No, no, no. I'm glad you called. Just,
Chuck... Chuck... Chuck, I gotta go.
I'll call you back, okay? Bye.
- How's Chuck?
- He's fine. Thank you.
He's excited because Cosmo ate
yams for the first time. You know babies.
- They like the bananas or the apples.
- Henry loved yam right from the get-go.
So as to your one-month
performance review...
- Performance review? Now?
- You've been emergency chief 30 days.
And I think it's going well. Staff
feels positive, esprit de corps is high.
- That's good to hear.
- Not that there haven't been...
- a few little glitches. First.
- First...
The average wait time to see
a physician is almost 10 hours.
I think we'd all agree
that's a bit excessive.
Second, a record number of patients
leave without treatment, resulting in...
a record number of complaints coming
to the administration. That would be me.
- Yes. Kerry, I've...
- Third, the number of bounce backs...
in under 48 hours was up 11
percent, signifying an increased rate...
of misdiagnoses, improper treatment
or really just poor follow-up planning.
- Kerry, if this isn't working out...
- Don't be silly.
You're doing a great job. I
wanted to make you aware...
that there are still many, many,
many problems for you to work on.
And if there's one word I can't
emphasize enough, Susan...
it's leadership.
That's it. Carry on.
Still waiting on a
transport for Mr. Lemley.
Thanks, Jerry.
From when you were in Africa?
No, these are new. Kem
just e-mailed me these.
I was gonna print them up.
She looks happy.
- Uh, which is nice, considering...
- Oh, yeah, she does.
Oh, very nice. Anyone
I should get to know?
You're not her type.
Paramedics at the back door.
Lewis is upstairs with Weaver.
We'll take it. Won't we, doctor?
- Hey. That's Carter's whatever, right?
- Mm-hm.
Man, I could
look at her all day.
Sixty-year-old woman, facial
injuries, chest wall contusions...
- and deformities to both arms.
- What's your name?
- Might be Louise.
- No ID. She was in an alley.
- No purse, wallet.
- What happened?
She could have fallen from a window
or dumped from a car. I don't know.
BP, 124/74. Tachy at 118.
- She's gonna need an airway.
- Let's clear her neck first.
- C-spine looks good.
- Does that mean I can talk to her?
You can take the c-collar off.
Sit her up to 30 degrees. No.
Do you need a hand in here?
- Facial fractures...
pulmonary contusions,
fractured wrist, fractured hands.
Name is Louise.
Hi, Louise, I'm Sam. Let us
know if this makes you at all dizzy.
- I... I...
- Don't talk if it hurts.
Dr. Carter, your COPD guy's...
- seizing in Curtain 4.
- Okay, go.
- 8.0 ET tube is ready to go.
- Not so fast.
Sorry. I know it hurts.
Pulse ox, 82. I'll
move her to five liters.
No intubation. It's a LeFort Il.
She's gonna need surgery
or she can't have an oral tube.
- Okay. Can I crike her?
- You're gonna observe quietly.
Louise, you have a broken jaw
and broken bones in your face.
We'll put a breathing tube in your
neck and sedate you for the procedure.
Wait.
I was raped.
Excuse me.
I'll be back, okay?
- Are you the one...?
- Yeah. We got the rape kit.
We did it while she was out.
She doesn't need more trauma.
Well, her full name is Louise Garvin.
We canvassed the neighborhood.
Her apartment's above the
alleyway where she was found.
Anyone see anything?
No. There were signs
of a struggle inside.
Seems like she got
away and then took a fall...
- coming down the fire escape.
- Found any family?
Not yet. Detectives are
on the case. They'll be here.
They'll talk to her, to
you, and to the doc.
Fine. Hey, Jerry. When the
detectives get here for Louise, find me.
- Okay.
- We can't have patients sitting around...
for 10 hours waiting to be seen. You
need to adhere to a 15-minute rule.
Even if you're busy, the patient
needs to be seen within 15 minutes...
of hitting the gurney, okay?
- Yeah.
- Sure.
And we have a serious
issue with bounce backs.
Oh, man, I was supposed
to stitch that head lac in 2.
Okay, bounce backs. I need you
all to provide aftercare instructions...
written directly to the patient.
Make sure they understand.
- You'll take that belly pain in Curtain 3?
- Yes, I was.
Make sure they understand...
and that they know to go to
their clinic or primary for follow-up.
- Get the labs back on that renal colic?
- Still waiting.
What do those guys want? I
got them a crate of Cracker Jacks.
Um... What's the...?
About the follow-ups?
Okay, Mi-Cha Pak?
- Mi-Cha, am I saying that correctly?
- Yes.
I'm Dr. Lockhart. Tell me
about the pain you're having.
It hurts here. ABBY: Okay.
And is it constant, or
does it come and go?
It comes and goes. I think it's a
kidney stone. My father had one...
- Morris.
- Sorry. Okay? Sorry.
- What about a kidney stone?
- Her father had one.
- Okay. And are you...?
- Sorry. Sorry.
- What is your problem?
- No problem. We're all set. Sorry again.
Um...
Vomiting or fever.
Any vomiting or fever?
I think maybe I'm better.
I could probably go.
No, no. As long as you're
here, we'll take a look at you.
- We'll get you in a gown, okay?
- Okay.
And I'll be back to examine you.
So you two moving in?
Girl, that's getting serious.
With Luka, that's getting lucky.
It just seemed to
make more sense.
That's what my girlfriend said
when she moved in six years ago.
That's why you two
are coming in together.
We just moved our stuff over last night.
We haven't even unpacked our boxes.
Living together is for wimps.
Real commitment comes with a ring.
Yeah, my girlfriend's
on that one too.
Excuse me. I'm Detective Patrie.
I'm here about Louise Garvin.
Yeah, she's over here. She's in rough
shape. As soon as a bed opens up...
- we'll send her to ICU.
- Did she say anything other than that...
- she'd been raped?
- She could barely get that out.
She's got a crike tube now, can't
talk at all, and two broken arms.
Hi, Louise. This is Detective
Patrie. He's investigating your case.
Hi. May I call you Louise?
I'm so sorry about
what happened.
I know this is difficult. But I'm going
to need to ask you some questions...
if you're up to it.
Now, the man who raped you...
was he someone you knew,
a friend or an acquaintance?
Anyone you saw around
your building or neighborhood?
Was he alone?
It's just mucous plug. Louise,
I'm gonna have to suction you out...
- since you can't cough this stuff up.
- Can I still talk to her?
Yeah.
Louise, was he alone?
Did you get a good look at him?
Would you be able to identify
him if you saw him again?
You know what, I think
that's enough for now, okay?
- When will she be able to talk?
- We'll have to ask Dr. Kovac.
It's a gravid abdomen.
Oh! It hurts. It hurts now.
I need sterile gloves, Surgilube,
and help with the pelvic.
- When was your last period?
- I don't know.
You don't know? Did you
have a gush of water today?
Maybe when I was peeing.
- Aah!
- Oh, God. She's 10 centimeters dilated.
- Oh, God, is right. Effacement?
- Hundred percent. Station is two-plus.
- Call OB?
- Yeah.
Okay, Mi-Cha, don't push, all
right? Listen to me and focus.
I need you to pant when the
pain comes and don't push.
Chuny, can you help
me with this gurney?
- Is she having a baby?
- I'm not pregnant.
- Pulmonary contusions are getting worse.
- That's why she can't talk?
She was punched so hard
that her lungs are bruised.
Swelling, fluid,
bleeding in the air sac...
Sam. Her condition is critical.
We'll provide oxygen, wait for the lungs
to heal, hope it doesn't get any worse.
- It could get worse?
- Much worse.
- I need to talk to her.
- That's not gonna be possible.
The details she could give
us might help solve this case.
This rapist has been assaulting
women all over the North Side.
She's the first one who seems
like she got a good look at him.
Can't we do something?
I think she wants to help.
How? By blinking in Morse code?
We can't miraculously cure pulmonary
edema. She's being admitted to the ICU.
Then she'll go for reconstructive
surgery on her facial bones.
In a week or so, they may be able to
remove the tube and then she can talk.
Okay. Don't push. Don't push.
What's she doing down here?
She didn't know she was pregnant
until I examined her. Name's Mi-Cha.
- Hi, Mi-Cha. I'm Dr. Carter.
- I'm not pregnant.
- Don't push, okay?
- Come on. Come on.
Hey, breathe. Breathe, breathe, breathe.
- Breathe?
- Yeah, breathe.
- We won't make it. She's crowning.
- Wanna take it?
- No, not in the elevator lobby.
- Get me a BOA kit and a baby warmer.
- Okay, don't push.
- Hang in there. You're gonna be okay.
Baby's LOA, normal presentation.
Okay, Mi-Cha. Now I want you to push.
- So push. Push.
- Come on.
Push. A little bit more.
Head's out. Good, good.
- More suction.
- Okay. Now stop pushing.
Stop pushing. Don't
push. Don't push.
A little bit more.
And there we go.
Cord clamp.
Time of delivery, 11:14.
- I'll get the HemoCue.
- Ten fingers, 10 toes.
You have a beautiful
healthy baby boy.
You did great.
That's not my baby.
- What?
- I didn't have a baby.
Abby's not making much
progress with that Korean girl.
- Well, give her a little bit more time.
- She was hoping you could come.
If she can't break through her denial,
she should get Psych down here.
Is that the message you'd
like me to give Dr. Lockhart?
- Tell her I'll check in with her in a bit.
- Frank, call a taxi for Mrs. Donaldson.
Hear you're doing the
"mi casa, su casa"thing.
- What?
- Hell, it's none of my business.
- Detective's still here.
- You shouldn't have been so dismissive...
- of me in front of him.
- You didn't need to discuss details.
Louise deserves some privacy.
Yeah, and she deserves a chance to
help. We have an option we haven't...
- even talked about.
- And that is?
If we deflate the crike
balloon, Louise could whisper.
- You want to take her off the vent?
- Just for a few moments at a time.
She's requiring
100 percent oxygen.
I take her off the vent every
time I suction her, and she's fine.
- We both know it's possible.
- Technically, yes, but why risk it?
- Because she wants to help.
- She does or you do?
What is that supposed to mean?
You're sensitive about
these kinds of cases.
- What?
- You always stand up for women...
- who have been assaulted.
- And you don't?
Of course I do.
Maybe because of when
you were with Steve?
Steve never raped me.
- Physical abuse? Hitting you?
- Oh, this has nothing to do with that.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
There's a violent
rapist out there.
How are you gonna feel in two
days, two weeks, a month from now...
when we get another
woman like Louise in here?
Hey, crit's only 19
on your GI bleeder.
Go.
Korean girl, mother's in the family room.
But Mi-Cha is still on another planet.
She's perfectly reasonable
until I mention the baby.
Then she looks
at me like I'm nuts.
Teenage denial can be fairly intransigent.
Can't necessarily attack it head-on.
- I know. That's why I was...
- I'll talk to her.
- Hi, Mi-Cha.
- Hi.
- How are you? How are you feeling?
- I feel fine. It's hard to sleep though.
That baby cries.
- She said my kidneys are fine.
- Yes, they are.
Then can I go home?
No. No, you can't. Not yet. We're
still waiting on a few more test results.
How long is that gonna take?
Because my parents get really mad...
when I'm not home
right after school.
Well, you're not
in school today.
I still need to be home by 4.
Hey, Mi-Cha. Have you
checked out this baby over here?
He's pretty cute.
Why do you people keep
asking me about that baby?
We're just wondering if you like babies,
or if you ever wanted to have a baby.
I don't know. Maybe when
I'm married. Who cares?
You want to try holding him?
Why would I do that?
I don't get why he's even in
here. I mean, shouldn't his mother...
- be dealing with him?
- Okay, you just take it easy. Calm down.
And we'll be back in a bit.
- Am I gonna get out by 4?
- Don't know. Hope so.
So is she pretending
this didn't happen...
or does she really believe
she didn't give birth?
Who knows? Her dissociative
denial is pretty strong.
I have her mother
hanging around.
And I can't break confidentiality
and tell her about the baby.
Let me guess, this is the
mother walking towards us?
Uh-huh. That's Mrs. Pak.
Call Social Services
and Psych again.
Get back in there, see if
you can keep working on her.
Mrs. Pak. Hello, I'm Dr. Carter.
Forty-three-year-old female, 15-foot
fall. Blunt head trauma. GCS, 13.
- Heart rate, 92. BP, 112/72.
- Why isn't she wearing a collar?
- What collar?
- Don't talk.
Did you just say 43?
What do we got? HARMS:
Twenty-eight-year-old male.
Penetrating injury to bilateral lower
extremities with arterial laceration.
- BP 72 palp.
I don't think she'd be talking on her
cell phone, and I don't think she's a male.
We're here now. I gotta go.
Thirty-nine-year-old female, crush
injury to the chest and abdomen.
- ST elevations on the strip.
- I know I just got here...
- but where are the bathrooms?
- What's going on?
Are you the incident commander?
- Me? SCURRY:
Chemical explosion...
at a maraschino cherry factory,
93 casualties. You're getting 35.
Okay, ladies and
gentlemen, this is a drill. Go.
- What the hell?
- Did you know anything about this?
Dr. Lewis!
Louise is still asleep.
Yeah, I got some
background information on her.
She lived alone since her
husband died five or six years ago.
Neighbor wasn't sure. No children.
Haven't located any family yet.
- I thought you might wanna know.
- Yeah.
Thanks. I should probably
get in there and check on her.
Yeah. Guy uses a
similar pattern each time.
How many other victims?
Four women in
the last five weeks.
He poses as a pizza guy...
pretends to be confused
about the apartment number.
Never open your door
to anyone you don't know.
The others, are they okay?
Rape isn't quite bad
enough for this guy.
He likes to beat
them too, like Louise.
One died, and the other
three are in pretty bad shape.
Hope she makes it. Each victim
has given us a clue, you know...
helped us get
a little bit closer.
If Louise dies, we'll just
have to wait for the next one.
- Got a head lac, GCS, 15.
- She's a green, put her in Sutures.
- Suture room's full.
- Okay, then Curtain 4.
- I wanna stay with Kaitlin.
- They said we could be together.
Sorry. You're a pelvic
fracture. Red tag, Trauma 1.
- I wanna stay with Julie.
- They promised us...
- Guys, you're not babies, all right?
- Yeah, but they were told they could...
Yeah, they said so.
Don't forget to call your
consults and support staff.
They're keeping track
of the response times.
Abby said Social Services is here. They
are in with the Korean virgin-birth girl.
- Okay. Thanks, Haleh.
- Frank, where's Jerry?
He left on account
of the infestation.
He was calling Transport for
a real patient in 2, going to CT.
- I'm on it.
- Wow, this is fun.
Damn JCAHO drill. Explosion
at a maraschino cherry factory.
- That's what I heard.
- Who makes this stuff up?
- I don't know.
- Does this even exist...
- in Chicago?
- I actually...
I got rid of two greens and
a dead merit-badge holder.
Is it okay if I help a real person
with double vision and vertigo?
Susan, do you want all the
red tags parked in Trauma 1?
- No.
- Hi, I'm Trina. I'm a squad leader.
- Need any help?
- You have a head lac. You can't talk.
- I wasn't asking you.
- Phone call for Dr. Lewis. It's the lab.
They wanna yell at you.
So Fremont has a pretty
good football team, don't they?
I don't go to that many games.
What kind of stuff do
you do with your friends?
Mostly we just eat
lunch together at school.
What about the weekends?
Do you go out as a group,
or do you go on dates?
Some of my friends have boyfriends
so they just go with each other.
Do you have a boyfriend?
No.
Can I still leave by 4?
Do your parents get very
upset if you're not home on time?
I have to be there
for my brother.
Why is that?
- I take care of him.
- How old is he?
Twenty-three.
So you spend a lot of
time with your brother.
- Yeah, of course.
- And when you take care of him...
- what kind of things do you do?
- I don't know why you keep asking...
all these questions.
I'm getting tired. Can I
just take a nap in here?
Sure. Get some rest.
Maybe we should
check out this brother.
- Mom's in the family room.
- I'll try talking to her obliquely.
If need be, we can designate
the baby as a safe haven.
Safe haven? This baby isn't abandoned.
- It kind of is.
Mother's right there.
Grandmother's down the hall.
- She's not acknowledging the baby.
- She's not competent...
- to give up the baby.
- Even if she does, we don't know...
- she'll want to keep him.
- Shouldn't we at least try?
- We don't know a thing about her family.
- Let's go find out.
- You can't break confidentiality.
- Maybe her family's support...
- is what she needs.
- Dr. Carter.
I talked to the mom. She seems
very reasonable and concerned.
- This baby has a family.
- Carter...
Mrs. Pak. MRS. PAK: Yes?
Mi-Cha, can I see her now?
Notice any changes in Mi-Cha's
condition in the last couple months?
No. She's good. Please
tell me what's wrong with her.
So you didn't know that
your daughter was pregnant?
That's right. This morning she gave
birth to a beautiful healthy baby boy.
- Her father won't have her in the house.
- Mrs. Pak.
- How long will she stay here?
- Maybe a couple days.
Mrs. Pak...
- She's awake.
- The Unasyn piggyback get here?
Yeah. I just hung it.
I'll get back to our
little Ranger Scouts.
Yeah, be my guest.
Hey, Louise. How you doing?
Louise, the man that raped
you, he raped four other women.
Now, there might be a way that we
could help you talk to the detective.
The tube that's in your neck...
has a little balloon on the end of it
that we inflate to protect your lungs...
to prevent oxygen
from leaking out.
If I deflate the balloon and
cover the end of the tube...
you would be able to whisper
just a few words at a time.
There are some very real risks.
I would be depriving your lungs of
supplemental oxygen for a minute.
But if there were a problem...
I'd re-inflate the balloon
and put you back on the vent.
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
I would need to clear it with
Dr. Kovac, and I also need your consent.
Hey, Jerry, where's that
surgical consult on Rapke in 2?
Man, I have called
them, like, five times.
They're so jerked around with
these scouts they won't come down.
Go and drag one down here
before the guy bleeds out.
- As soon as I take these to...
- No, Jerry, I said now.
Frank, call the lab. Have them come
pick that up. Don't accept any excuses.
- Which patient does Kovac have at CT?
- Check the board. Stay away from Carter.
He's got his panties in a twist.
Tell Kovac to come find me.
- Did they call about a bed for Louise?
- They said maybe an hour.
Oh, just wanted to let you know
that I'll be leaving for a while.
- Louise is awake.
- Yeah, I saw her.
- I told her I'd see her later.
- Well, she'll be in ICU by then.
I'll find it. Thanks
for your help.
Detective Patrie, wait.
There is something
else we could try.
You knew the drill was today.
- Dr. Lewis?
- Dr. Lewis, I'm Trina. Remember?
- Yes.
- I'd like to help.
- You're yellow tag.
- You should be in your area.
- I feel fine.
- I think I could be useful.
- Well, thanks again.
- Take Trina back to the yellow tags.
- No problem.
Are you sure? I'm good with
injuries. I'm a people person.
I knew it was today,
they called to schedule.
- You didn't tell staff.
- I've got a scrotal pain...
but haven't got room.
Can I move the scouts?
Yeah. But they need to be seen.
- Yeah.
- It was supposed to be a surprise.
- A hint wouldn't hurt.
Susan, you need to learn to
take control despite the rules.
I'm gonna need clarification on which
ones to follow and which ones to break.
What should I do with a
ranger with a shrapnel injury?
- The O.R. won't let me through.
- I'll call.
Girls, please, stop. You're
gonna get hurt for real.
- Morris, what the hell is going on?
- A vat of cherry dye blew up on them.
They needed decon. I couldn't find
the key to the decontamination closet...
so I sent them to the shower. It
was supposed to be a pretend shower.
- Yeah. Go round them up.
- Okay, get them some scrubs.
- Get them out of those wet clothes.
- Oh, my God.
- Susan, this is chaos.
- We could use help with the green tags.
Okay, girls. We're gonna...
Girls, can I have
your attention, please?
Yo! Scouts!
- Gosh.
- That's much better. Thank you.
Pulse ox, 94. That's good.
Okay, Louise.
I'm gonna deflate
the balloon now.
You okay, Louise?
Okay.
Sam was looking for you.
She went with that detective.
Okay, thanks. MARQUEZ: Luka.
Can I give Mr. Sanchez
another four of morphine?
- Sure. His chest pain is getting worse?
- Seven out of 10.
- Do a repeat EKG.
- I already did.
He says the pain
radiates to his back.
Could be a dissection.
- See if his chest x-ray is ready.
- Already got it. It's bedside.
Okay. I had better be sure
this guy doesn't need the O.R.
You said you got a good
look at this guy's face.
What color was his skin?
White.
Was he tall or short?
Wait. Do you want us to stop?
Louise, was he tall or short?
Kind of medium.
Maybe tall.
- Jerry's not back yet?
- When is Jerry ever back?
This where we keep the
workmen's comp claim forms?
No, they're in these bins
down here somewhere.
Talked to Mi-Cha's
brother. He's coming.
Yeah. How's all
that working out?
Okay. She's opening
up about her family.
- They sound kind of scary.
- Meaning what?
Conservative,
traditional, old world.
As in you'd be pretty screwed if
you were an unwed teenage mom.
Wendall had to leave, but she's
coming back. Wanna talk to her?
- Mi-Cha? Again? Why?
- I don't know.
- I just figured whatever helps.
- What are these doing in here?
- What?
- Pictures of Kem from the computer.
- Why are they in that drawer?
- I don't know.
Somebody printed them out.
You don't have any idea who?
- Well, Morris was looking at them. I...
- Morris? Where is he?
He was wheeling one of those
scouts up to CT, or something.
Hey, Morris! What are you doing
downloading pictures of my girlfriend?
What? CARTER: Morris!
You should really
come take a look at him.
Who?
This beautiful baby.
This beautiful boy.
What are you talking about?
You haven't even
held him yet, have you?
Why are you talking like this?
He is so beautiful.
Look at those eyes.
Look at that face.
And all he wants
to do is be held.
All he wants to do is be loved.
Do you know how lucky you are?
Do you know what
a miracle this is?
What are you doing?
I just don't understand. Can't
you see it? I mean, look at it.
- Take him.
- Why are you doing this?
- Hold him for a second.
- Dr. Carter.
I just thought that if
she held the baby...
They need you down the hall.
- I was just trying to...
- They need you down the hall.
I don't remember.
Sorry. PATRIE: That's okay.
You're doing great, Louise.
Did he have any tattoos
or scars that you saw?
All right, I'm gonna
blow the balloon back up.
It's okay, Louise. I got you.
- What...? Is she gonna be okay?
- Go get Dr. Kovac now.
Good news, Mr. Sanchez. You
won't be needing that surgery after all.
- How are her sats? SAM:
Seventy-nine. She vomited.
I can see that.
She's aspirated.
Add five of PEEP, hang 3.375
of Zosyn to cover aspiration.
- Chest x-ray now and repeat in an hour.
- Is she gonna be okay?
She's sucked
vomit into her lungs.
I don't think there will be
any more questions today.
- You left her airway vulnerable.
- I didn't expect the vomiting.
Her lungs were already bad
from the pulmonary contusions.
I wanted to help. I explained
the risks. It's what Louise wanted.
And what you wanted.
Are you sure no one else knows
about what you were doing in there?
Just the cop.
Luka, her sats keep dropping.
Down to 72 at a
hundred percent oxygen.
- Put her up to 10 of PEEP.
- Repeat chest.
Bilateral whiteout.
- Is that the contusions or the aspiration?
- Does it matter at this point?
- Mi-Cha's brother's here.
- Good.
He's 23 but developmentally
delayed. Wendall's in there with them.
- I'm heading in. Wanna come along?
- Nope. You and Wendall can handle it.
Hi.
I'm Dr. Lockhart.
So, Yong-Jo, you and Mi-Cha
spend a lot of time together?
First we get up.
And then we have breakfast.
And then Mi-Cha goes to
school, and I go to Sadler's.
- Sadler's?
- It's a supermarket.
I stock shelves.
I bag groceries.
- I can lift things. Oh.
So when Mi-Cha comes home
from school, what do you do?
She stays home with me.
- She doesn't go out. She never leaves.
- Yong-Jo.
- She stays home with me.
- What are you doing?
- I didn't tell anybody.
- Tell anybody about what?
What are you doing here?
I came to see you and the baby.
And the baby?
I didn't tell anybody.
You told me not to
and I didn't, I promise.
You believe me,
don't you, Mi-Cha?
I didn't do anything wrong.
- Please, Mi-Cha!
- Yong-Jo, let's go outside, okay?
- I didn't do anything wrong.
- I know, it's okay.
I didn't tell anybody.
Mi-Cha?
It's a real disaster in here.
Red tag, partially
amputated foot.
Another red, unconscious
and short of breath.
Trina. TRINA: Abdominal
lac and dizziness.
She's only a yellow, but
she's taken a turn for the worse.
- I can help.
- Trina, please. I think we'll be okay.
Hey, Malik. Can you dispo
all these fake patients?
Respiratory distress needs O2, pulse
ox, chest x-ray and a possible tube.
- Okay, it's in the works.
- Thanks.
Ow! Ow! Ow!
- What are you doing?
- Her foot's amputated.
If we don't put
pressure on it, she'll die.
Trina, please.
Want her to bleed to death?
You want that on your conscience?
Please, please, Trina.
Please, get back to your gurney.
- But I can help you.
- But you're not.
But I can. I've
earned a lot of badges.
Adventure club, adventure teen...
- Trina.
Globe trekking, horse
lover, horse rider...
Trina!
Hiker, safety tips, stress
tips, sailing, surfing, boating...
Stop it now! I don't care
about your damn badges.
Water world, weather watch.
You know what?
That's it, I'm done.
- You're all out of here.
- Excuse me?
Every observer, all
the little girls, out now.
- This drill is over.
- You can't do that.
I'm the chief of emergency
medicine here, and I damn well can.
We don't need this drill.
We had a helicopter crash in
our ambulance bay for God's sake!
So you can take your clipboards
and your Ranger Scouts...
and hit some other hospital
because my doctors and nurses...
need to get back to treating real
patients with real problems. You got it?
Back to work.
I was afraid I was
gonna miss you.
- We're on our way out.
- Just give me one second.
All right, look, you're
gonna go up to the third floor.
Just tell them you're
looking for the O.R.
What? You're not coming?
Look, hang out for about 30 minutes,
or so, and roll yourself back down.
How's your dad?
He came in for a G-tube,
ended up with pneumonia.
But after two weeks of
antibiotics, oxygen and a chest PT...
he's back to just being old.
I just fired the scouts.
No more fake patients.
What about the
ones we dealt with?
Broom all of them.
See real patients only within
15 minutes of their signing in.
Susan seems to take this
chief thing kind of seriously.
I don't know if it was the
brother wanting to see the baby...
or us thinking he's the father,
whatever, it got through to her.
So the father was actually some
guy that lives across the street?
Yes, her boyfriend.
And her cover was having
Yong-Jo say, "She never goes out.
She always stays home.
She never leaves me."
- Good work.
- Thank you.
- How are they?
- Adjusting, hanging in, who knows?
- Was that Carter who was just out here?
- Yeah.
I thought he might come in.
I think all of this might have
been a little bit rough on him.
Why? What do you mean?
I don't know if you've heard
what he went through last spring?
No, I hadn't.
- Gonna come to work tomorrow?
- That's the plan...
as long as everything's
okay on this end.
Shh, shh.
- What's the matter? He okay?
- He gets confused and agitated.
And being in that hospital
for that long didn't help.
Papa. Papa! Papa!
No, no, no, no!
- It's okay.
- Papa!
Damn it!
Son of a bitch!
- Son of a bitch.
- Bradying down at 42.
Amp of atropine and
open the crash cart.
- Go up on the PEEP?
- Pressure's too low.
- What about steroids?
- V-tach. No pulse.
Starting compressions. Charge to 200.
- Milligram of epi.
Charged. SAM: Clear!
- No change.
- Three hundred.
Check for pneumothorax.
Good sounds bilaterally. No tracheal shift.
- Charged.
Clear.
Put Ativan's in. He
might not need these.
Send a tech to get
a 28 French button.
We'll put in a Foley
to keep the tract open.
- Shouldn't I register him first?
- Don't bother.
I'm just gonna put the
G-tube in and get him home.
What are you looking at him for? He's
a third-year resident, I'm an Attending.
I said he doesn't
need to be registered.
I'll be back.
He should be in a nursing home.
- I'd never do that to him.
- At least you shouldn't have to do this.
- Call GI.
- Watch his hand.
- He may react when I put in the Foley.
- Jing-Mei.
Papa.
Papa!
- Still in fib.
- Charge to 360.
I heard she vomited.
You think she aspirated?
Clear.
- Fine V-fib. Possibly.
- Try 360 again.
You shouldn't arrest
from aspiration.
The balloon on her
crike must have burst.
It happens.
Clear.
- Asystole.
- How long have you been at it?
Thirty-nine minutes.
- What about a dopamine drip?
- No.
Hold compressions.
Get a strip. We're done.
I'll clean her up.
She's a coroner's case.
Yeah, I know.
When they do the autopsy,
they'll see the balloon didn't burst.
No.
They'll see that it did.
So is she gonna keep the baby?
Well, we finally
got her to hold him.
One miracle at a time.
Look, I just came
up to apologize.
A few months ago, the
woman that I'd been with...
- we lost a baby.
- I heard.
You getting some help with that?
I'm working on it.
Good night.
I thought they would
have taken her by now.
Morgue's backed up.
Coroner's backed up.
Same old, same old.
I thought you were with
that intussusception kid.
Pedes surgery took
him up to the O.R.
Sam, you don't need to do this.
I know.
- There are other nurses.
- I know.
Sam.
I shouldn't have done it.
The contusions were severe.
She could have died anyway.
I shouldn't have done it, Luka.
You did what you did
to help the patient, Sam.
Sam?
When I deflated that balloon,
Louise was still so traumatized.
He kept asking her
these questions...
and the only thing that
she could remember was:
"White guy, dark hair."
I did what I did for
"white guy, dark hair."
Come here.