Researchers have theorized
that nightmares
are the brain's way
of processing
unsettling events of the past.
Oh!
Paula. What?
You're scaring me.
Happy Halloween.
Anybody ever tell you,
you snore like a trucker?
- Not in those exact words.
- Like a truck, then?
I thought a semi
was barreling towards me.
- You woke me up.
- I have allergies.
- ♪ Gonna take what's mine, what's mine ♪
- Ohh.
- What time is it?
- Does it matter?
Yes.
I'm getting out today.
- I'm counting the minutes.
- Ooh!
Well, I'll count, too.
Once you leave,
I'll be able to sleep.
♪ I never stay down ♪
♪ 1, 2, 3, 4 ♪
Others believe nightmares
are how our subconscious mind
prepares us to deal
with our real-life fears.
- Hey.
- Where are the kids?
- Daycare.
What? So why'd you text
about a hand-off?
- To bring you this.
- What's this?
My mom brought them
over this morning...
Costumes from when Megan and I
were little kids.
These are amazing.
Yeah. She made them
all from scratch.
Your mom worked full-time
and still managed
to make costumes?
Mm-hmm.
Every year.
♪ I come in red hot ♪
I got to go.
I guess I'll see you
up on the PEDS floor
for trick-or-treating?
- Okay. Bye.
- ♪ Gonna take what's mine, ♪
♪ what's mine ♪
♪ I'm too much woman ♪
- ♪ for you to handle ♪
- Either way,
they agree that nightmares
are most commonly brought on
by one thing...
♪ 1, 2, 3, 4 ♪
...stress.
Red or yellow tie?
Mm. Why don't you compromise,
go with orange?
Hey, can you come help me
with my dress?
What about blue?
♪ Whoa, oh, oh,
oh, oh, oh ♪
Boo!
♪ Hey! ♪
Seriously?
You can't even pretend
to be scared?
Nothing's scarier
than my real life.
I got half a dozen investors
coming to see Pac North today.
Gotta convince them
to sink more money into it.
You found a janitor
giving himself a CT scan.
That place has nowhere to go
but up.
Hey, have you seen
my wedding shoes?
Why are you wearing
your wedding dress?
Uh, it's expensive.
I'm gonna wear it
every Halloween.
- To work?
- No. I have the day off.
I'm gonna stay home,
I'm gonna eat
most of the candy,
and scare
all the trick-or-treaters.
- Love you.
How come
my mom hasn't called
from sleepover
community service?
Oh, she's probably busy.
It's not like a slumber party
with friends.
Oh. That's your ride.
Okay, everybody,
get your stuff together.
Come on, guys.
Get your backpacks.
I hope we get candy
at school.
Oh, did you guys forget
your candy? Go get your candy.
- Candy! Come on.
- Let's go, guys.
- Hey. I am so sorry
- Hey.
That I'm late.
I had to borrow Carina's car.
How are the kids?
Hair is brushed.
Lunches are packed.
Halloween costumes are on.
I am killing the auntie game,
right, ZoZo?
Yeah, but are you
gonna get dressed?
Good idea.
I'm gonna go get dressed,
and Dr. DeLuca is gonna
take you to school, okay?
Okay.
Hey.
- Need some help with that?
- Don't!
You're not my dad.
Okay.
Alright, let's get the rest
of your stuff together, guys.
Alright, let's go.
And then I reminded her
that I'm going to Capitol Hill
with Nico for Halloween,
and she got all weird.
She's sad you're not helping her
hand out candy.
Well, that's what
I thought,
but then she asked me
not to post pictures.
She said a lot of our family
follows me.
She doesn't
want them to know
you still dress up
for Halloween?
Yeah, if by "still dress up
for Halloween"
you mean "are gay,"
then I think so.
- I thought she was cool with it.
- Yeah.
So did I.
I'm not gonna let her
ruin Halloween.
I'm gonna power
through rounds
so that I can leave early
and meet Nico.
Mm. What's your costume?
It's a paladin.
From "Dungeons & Dragons."
It's a subclass of fighter
who has the ability
to heal wounds
and cure diseases.
So it's a nerd suit.
They can detect evil.
Oh.
We, uh, revamped
ER triage protocols
to improve patient flow.
That reduced wait times
by 10%.
Okay, no more candy corn
in your nose, bud.
Got it.
Oh, no, no, no,
don't do... that.
Uh...
Dr. Webber is, uh, enhancing
the education program
to include doctor-patient
communication
and other soft skills.
And with, uh,
additional funding,
we can upgrade
the skills lab
to improve
surgical technique.
Well, unless there are
any questions,
we will go see construction
on the new research wing,
which is not only on budget,
but ahead of schedule.
Uh, Chief, a word?
Uh, we're on our way
to you now, Eddie.
I think there's something
you should see
before anyone else does.
Okay, well, they're not, uh,
quite ready for us yet,
so Dr. Webber will take you
to see the ICU,
and I will meet you guys there
in a few minutes.
Okay.
Uh, okay.
Uh, the ICU is this way.
Oh, God! No, no, no!
- Oh, but, uh, you know,
- You got to clamp it first!
If we go in this direction,
I can show you our new
MRI on the way.
- Thanks.
- Thank you very much.
Oh, my God.
Dr. Chatmon to Radiology.
Shepherd, uh,
you got a second?
Bailey, are you okay?
I... I'm sorry.
Um... I'm... pregnant.
And I hear you are, too.
Congratulations.
Thanks. You, too?
That's...
Are your ankles swollen?
Do you have intense cravings
for root beer?
Are you panicking about
how you finally have the career
you've imagined
for yourself,
but will now be breastfeeding
for the next 12 months
because the AAP
strongly recommends it?
Yes to all, but my cravings
are for pepperoni,
which, historically,
I hate.
This morning,
Tuck texted me a picture
of him
in his Halloween costume,
and I burst into tears.
That's the hormones.
That's normal.
Okay, well,
I don't like it.
I can't cry at work,
not in front of the staff
and certainly not
in front of Tom Koracick.
The last thing I need
is for the self-proclaimed
chief of chiefs
to see me reduced
to a puddle of tears.
Isn't "chief of chiefs"
his actual title?
Right.
Not the point. Okay.
If you feel like
you're gonna cry,
try pressing your tongue
to the roof of your mouth.
You can also try
looking up at the ceiling.
Okay. I'll try it.
You know,
all I wanted to do was vent,
and you gave me
useful advice.
Thank you.
What...
Dr. Sutton
to the Step-down Unit.
- Hey.
- Lunch today?
- Sure. Yeah.
My afternoon's clear.
Great.
Uh, my parents' reservation's
for 12:30,
so see you in the lobby
at noon?
- This lunch is with your parents?
- Yeah.
Remember when I did that
for you?
I thought your parents
hated each other.
They do, but it's
my cancer-versary.
Oh. Uh, that's...
What is that?
That's the anniversary
of my doctor telling us
that my scans were clear.
We go to lunch every year.
That's nice.
It is...
For the first 15 minutes.
Then it turns
into a competition
to prove whose life is better
since the divorce.
But this year
will be different, though.
Because they will both
hate me?
I am terrible with parents.
Because we'll tell them
about the baby.
Lobby at noon?
Yay!
Right.
They are gonna love you.
Dr. Daimers...
Really?
They have to special-order
the UV coating that we need.
We're kind of
at their mercy, Anne.
That's ridiculous.
I-I-I know that.
Whoa. It is dark in here. I know
that, but what else are we supposed to...
Excuse us. I'm sorry.
Good morning.
Dr. Schmitt's gonna go ahead
and get us started today.
Mary Rose Hawkins-Garrett,
age 11,
diagnosed at 6 months
with xeroderma pigmentosum,
making her unable
to withstand UV light
without risk of severe burns
or skin cancer,
which is why we have
the curtains for protection.
Okay. Mind if I go ahead
and take a look?
Mary Rose was admitted
for second-degree burns
on her arms,
due to apparent
UV exposure.
We don't know
how it happened.
I mean, she's never out
in the sun without...
Mnh-mnh... protective
clothing and sunscreen.
Where's Dr. Alex?
You know what?
Dr. Alex just started
a new job
at another hospital.
Oh. He's been her doctor
since she was born.
Did he quit because of
the "hospital from hell"
article?
- Something like that.
- Mhph.
So, by the looks of it,
this UV exposure's happened
in the last couple days,
certainly long enough
for your arms to get infected.
It's a large enough area
that I think
we'll need to debride
in an operating room.
She needs surgery?
You really don't know
how this happened, huh?
No. We're careful.
- Dr. Karev knows.
- Okay.
Will I be done in time
to trick-or-treat?
Halloween's the one night
where all the kids are outside,
and I can be with them without
my stupid protective helmet.
Oh, even if Dr. Avery and I
work as fast as
we possibly can,
y-you're probably still
gonna have to stay,
uh, a night or...
You know what?
The hospital does have
a pretty great Halloween party.
I mean, it's got games
and trick-or-treating.
And we've got a really cool
costume parade.
And I'm pretty sure
there's no helmet required.
- Is that right?
- Nope.
Yeah.
So,
uh, how's that sound?
Pretty good?
Alright.
Well, Dr. DeLuca will go ahead
and get you started,
- and I'll see you in a minute.
- Thank you.
There's no party.
Dr. Karev always assigned it
to a resident,
and he's not here anymore,
so...
So you'll make sure
it happens.
- Oh, I have plans.
- I know.
I just gave them to you.
Eddie,
why isn't anyone working?
I told the investors
we were ahead of schedule.
There.
Yeah. What is it?
Well, I'm no doctor,
but I think that's a skull.
That's another one.
And that's... a lot more.
You want us
to keep working?
Yeah, I'm... I'm gonna
need a minute.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 16  Episode 06
Title : "Whistlin' Past the Graveyard"
They call these "fun size,"
but they'd be more fun
if they were bigger.
Are you sure
you don't want one?
I prefer
not to lose my teeth.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Let's get you back
on that gurney.
No. My leg's just
a little scraped up.
This is all fake.
It's my friend.
Austin Goodrich, 18,
auto versus pedestrian.
He's got visible
head trauma.
Left pupil's blown.
Hypotensive and tachy
despite 500 cc of I.,
likely due
to abdominal bleeding.
Oh, you mean
where that giant ax is?
That is not real,
but also difficult to remove.
We were walking to school
when this car plowed into him.
Driver said
he just didn't see him.
Austin always wins
our costume contest.
He's, like, a master of
fake blood and guts and organs.
Is he gonna be okay?
We'll know more when we take
a look at his real organs.
Let's get him
into trauma one!
- Dr. Danforth to the ER.
- And to help them, we...
Dr. Danforth to the ER.
Uh, w-would you excuse me?
Uh, M-Michaela?
Over there.
Thank you.
- Oh.
- Go.
I need advice
on breaking bad news
to the investors.
Hmm.
Well, I've always found
it's best
to be up-front
and straightforward.
Investors would rather
hear it from you
than through
the grapevine.
Why?
What's happening?
C-Construction is stopped
due to a... a...
A mass grave.
A... A what, now?
The new wing is apparently
on a... a burial ground
from, uh, 100 years ago.
You're pranking me
for Halloween, right?
This was once apparently
a mental hospital,
and once people died
and nobody came for them and...
Ugh. Yeah.
Well, you definitely don't
want to tell the investors that.
O-Okay, y-you handle it,
and... and I'll keep them busy.
Sure explains why this place
feels haunted.
It's not haunted.
Help!
Ohh! Someone help me!
I'm bleeding so much!
Ohh! Aah!
Really?
Seriously?
Look how good
this makeup is.
You weren't even
a little bit scared?
I'm a corpse.
Well, it's kind of a dime
a dozen around here today.
There's a graveyard
under our construction site.
- Seriously?
- Yeah.
And I'm waiting
to hear back from County,
and I don't have time
for this.
It's Hunt.
Multiple patients
crashing in the ICU.
Let's go.
You know I don't work here,
right?
I don't have more room
for dead bodies today.
Come on.
Man, I don't want
to tear his skin,
but this is really stuck.
I think it's spirit gum.
Um, I-I need
more alcohol wipes.
What's spirit gum?
If you're old enough
to know what it is,
you're too old
for trick-or-treating.
You want to put an age limit
on Halloween?
A town in Canada did... 16.
After that, it's just
panhandling in a costume.
Alright, he's bleeding
from his belly.
We need to get him
to an OR.
Tom, how much longer?
To retract the scalp
and the galea,
create an osteotomy,
incise the dura,
and decompress
the hematoma?
I'm done.
What happened?
Ohh!
See? That is the appropriate
reaction.
Cecil Taylor, my wife, Jo.
Two patients crashed,
and now a bunch of have
cardiac arrhythmias.
- How many?
- All of them.
And no idea why.
Your hospital's haunted.
I'm saying not everyone
likes surprises.
Sure.
Just people who lack
a sense of adventure.
- Oh, please.
- Oh!
Hey, there he is.
- Hey, guys.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Eric.
- So glad to meet you.
- You, too.
Yeah.
So, you must be Amelia.
- Yes.
- I'm Maureen.
- Hi.
- So glad that you could join us.
Yeah. Me too.
- Ahh.
- Okay.
Ahh.
I-I didn't even know
that Link was seeing anyone
until today.
How long has it been?
Um
a few months?
But we've known each other
longer than that, though.
Right.
Yeah.
Actually, my sister,
uh, tried to set us up a year ago.
Well, a lot can change
in a year.
Yeah!
So much!
A year ago, I was living with
my ex-husband and two kids.
Uh, not our kids.
Um, well, one is ours,
but, um, but mostly his.
He's adopted... Leo.
The other
is Leo's birth mom.
She was not
with us very long,
but, um, between her
running away and going to rehab,
it was petty messy.
Plus, um, Link was kind of
asking out my other sister.
Sometimes things
just work out better
the second time around.
Speaking of which...
..I have some news.
- Well, actually, um, so do...
- I...
...am getting remarried.
Oh, wow.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Congratulations!
Do we have to talk
about this now?
Yeah, you know, it all
happened pretty quickly,
but I'm feeling
really good about it.
And I know that
you are gonna love him.
Can't wait to meet him.
You don't have to.
Yeah.
Surprise.
She is lucky,
I mean, that's a hell of a burn,
but not quite
past the dermis.
How's Grey handling
lock-up?
Oh. I mean,
she's great with a scalpel,
but I can't picture her
wielding a shiv.
No. No. I can, actually.
It's hard to say.
I mean, she's had about
eight minutes
of phone time total,
which she spent talking
to her kids, obviously.
Right. So you're playing house
over there?
I'm helping out
when I can.
Yeah.
I'm not sure it's welcome.
Zola looked like she wanted
to shiv me this morning.
Really? Why?
- What'd you do?
- No clue.
Yeah, well, welcome
to fatherhood, buddy.
I'm not trying to be
anyone's father.
No, you're just taking care
of your girlfriend's children
while she's behind bars.
Totally different.
Okay. Gauze, please.
With kids,
it's hard to tell,
but it's almost always
for a reason.
You just got
to figure it out.
We checked to make sure
- his lip lac isn't real, right?
- Yeah.
When did everyone start
spending so much time
on costumes?
What's Allison gonna be?
A baby.
Right.
Lap pads.
You know that Owen's mom
made all of his
and Megan's costumes
when they were little?
Like, put sheets
over their heads
- and called them ghosts?
- No.
Sewed and glue-gunned
and embroidered.
She was
an amazing Army nurse
and a mom who made other moms
feel inept.
I don't think anyone
equates good costumes
with good parenting.
Well, Owen might.
I have no idea.
We went from best friends
to family of four
almost overnight.
There were many steps
that were skipped,
I mean, steps tha
would have prepared me
for what we're doing right now,
which is...
I have no idea
what it is.
Me neither.
Tom, you were...
You were so quiet
that I forgot that...
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be.
And you are not "inept,"
except maybe in your choice
of baby daddies.
And don't let ginger beer
or his mom
make you feel
any other way.
I'm sorry. I-I shouldn't
have brought it up.
It's just that... that those
costumes were so terrifying...
And... and... and not
in a Halloween way.
Halloween's a phony holiday,
anyway.
Dangerous, too.
Kids are twice as likely
to be hit by
a car and die
on Halloween as any other day.
This kid's lucky we were here to
keep him alive... or at least I was.
The ventriculostomy
is draining perfectly.
I will be in the ER
with the other
Halloween casualties.
How did you date that man?
Well,
he has his moments.
Oh, no.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
No, he really does have
some good qualities.
No.
Pancreatic head
looks severed.
Probably blunt-force trauma
from him falling
onto the plastic ax.
It basically
caused half a Whipple.
Alright. What do we do?
Well,
we don't have a choice.
We have to finish
a Whipple.
You staring
at that clock's
not gonna make it go
any faster.
There isn't really
much else to do here.
You could help me
with this puzzle,
stop wearing out
that floor.
Hey, hey!
Hi.
Um, I'm Meredith Grey.
I'm supposed to get out now,
actually.
Paperwork's not here.
Where is it?
Hasn't arrived from court.
Should I call my lawyer?
It'll show up.
Happens all the time.
Okay.
But, wait. Hold on.
It's...
You know, it's Halloween,
and I have three kids
at home,
and they shouldn't
have to suffer
for the court's mistake.
I have to get a costume.
You could go as "sad mom."
Is anyone
in your family sick?
I'm a doctor.
I could help.
I like it better
on this side of the bars.
You're a doctor?
- Yeah. You need help?
- No.
I'm just wondering
how the hell you let yourself
get locked in here.
Dead bodies like corpses
or murder victims?
No one was murdered.
Get back to work.
You figure out what happened?
Not yet.
It's kind of
a war zone here.
Your hospital's creepy.
- You're not helping that situation.
- Okay.
Those are the patients
who are okay.
Those are the ones
who had arrhythmias.
These had jaundice.
Those had fevers.
Huh.
- What?
- You see something?
The pink.
Transfusion forms.
All these patients
got blood.
We've gotta call
Central Blood Supply,
see if there's
anything's wrong...
Actually, we have
our own blood supply.
It's in the floor's
medical fridge.
Okay. Where's that?
We need to see it.
- Damn it. It's another V-fib.
- I'll get it.
You guys
check on the blood.
Uh, Link said you live
in different cities,
so how did you two,
um...
I moved to Denver for my job
earlier this year.
I didn't know anybody there,
so, uh, I signed up for
one of those dating apps.
First person they matched me
with was Maureen.
I swiped left.
Been there, done that.
I switched apps.
I figured that one's algorithm
was bad.
But the next one
matched us, too.
And then when we matched
a third time,
I texted him to laugh
about these dumb apps,
and he suggested
that we have coffee.
And, uh, turns out the apps
weren't so dumb.
We've already
had a big wedding,
so this one's gonna be
low-key.
But I would love for you
to be my best man.
Ooh.
You two, uh...
put me through hell
with your divorce.
You used me like a pawn.
You... You made me
a go-between.
You forced me
to pick sides.
I spent Christmas days
on an airplane
so I could have
breakfast with you
and dinner with you.
I double-majored in college
So you could go to separate
graduation ceremonies.
It took me years to learn
how to manage parents
who could barely
sit through a lunch
without tearing
each other apart,
and now... now...
now you're...
You're getting back together?
I don't... I don't even know
what to say.
I think they just want you
to say you're happy...
No, no, no, they... they don't
get to tell me what to say.
They gave up that right
when they sat me down
and told me our family
was a "painful lie,"
which, together or not,
we are never gonna do
to our kid.
Oh, yeah.
You're gonna be
grandparents.
You know what?
I need some air.
Surprise!
Huh.
Okay. Temperature gauge
seems to be working.
Yeah. Feels cool.
Wait.
It's zero degrees Celsius.
It's supposed to be
between 1 and 6.
It's gone bad.
The blood hemolyzed.
We basically pumped them
with straight potassium.
A few more minutes,
and the ICU would be
nothing but corpses.
And I've already got a backyard
full of those.
Okay, we're gonna
need labs for anyone
who's been given blood from this
fridge in the past 24 hours.
From now on, every department
uses Central Blood Supply.
That's why it's there.
Anastomosis looks
patent and intact.
I mean, this has got to be
a parent's worse nightmare.
Do you worry about Tuck
trick-or-treating?
My son and his girlfriend
are going to horror night
in the park.
They're both zombies
because they wanted to do
a couple's costume.
I have... ugh...
Other things
to worry about.
I need, uh, drains
and 3-0 nylon.
You know what?
Don't worry
about the costume.
There's never enough time
to do everything you want,
so spend it
with your babies.
That's more important
than any perfect costume.
Alright.
It's not
the prettiest gastro-J.
But it got the job done.
So, I was picking up trash
for my community service.
And I'm waiting
for the medical commission
to decide whether or not
to take my license,
which I can't lose,
because I have three kids
and I love being a surgeon.
I would miss the OR
and miss my patients.
Do you have kids?
Two.
And two jobs
to make ends meet.
One night, my childcare
fell through.
I couldn't find
a babysitter
or a sub for the graveyard shift
at the mini-mart,
so I put my two kids to bed,
and I went to work.
I was less than
a block away.
I ran back and checked on them
every break I had.
But my 8-year-old woke up
and called 911
when he saw
I wasn't home.
Oh, no.
I tried explaining it
to the police,
but they were
in no mood to listen.
One of them came towards me.
I guess I waved him off,
out of instinct.
My hand hit his face...
Not hard or anything.
But they arrested me,
said I assaulted
a police officer.
And a jury found you guilty
of that?
I haven't had
a hearing yet.
I can't afford bail,
so I'm stuck here.
And my kids
are in foster care.
Public defender says
it's gonna be
probably another month.
So...
you can keep whining
about how you might lose
your medical license,
but I'm gonna stop listening
and focus on this puzzle.
I don't know why I'm so mad.
When I was a kid,
all I wanted was for them
to get back together.
I even tried
to "Parent Trap" them.
Seriously?
I separately talked them
into taking me
to the same showing
of "Sleepless in Seattle."
But my dad hated rom-come,
and my mom hated my dad,
so it didn't work out
very well.
I don't think you're angry
about them getting remarried.
Uh, I'm pretty sure that
they're the root of this anger.
This day is supposed to be
about you.
You are their kid.
You survived cancer.
And they are making
your cancer-versary
all about them... again.
Yeah.
For somebody who says
they're terrible with parents,
you seem to understand mine
pretty well.
Well, I understand
family dysfunction.
If you want to just leave,
we can.
Or you can give them
a chance to do better.
Dr. Curt Sullivan to...
Ah. Oh, geez.
Ohh.
Are you a doctor?
Yeah. I'm Dr. Schmitt.
Do you need help?
What's wrong?
I can't find
a Halloween costume.
Can you help me?
Uh... sure.
Come on.
Let's... Let's go look.
Yes, I believe so.
Ah! Just the person
I was looking for.
Can it wait?
I got to do a post-op check.
Oh,
I was talking to DeLuca,
but thank you for letting me
know that you're busy.
Ah. Meet me in Mary Rose's room
when you're done.
- Mm-hmm.
- What's up?
So, I just picked up the kids
from school.
Bailey and Ellis are in daycare,
but Zola is refusing.
Because
it's for little kids.
I would take her, but I have
surgery, and Amelia's out.
- This isn't really a good time.
- She's super easy.
She'll probably just read her
book or go to the OR gallery.
- I-I'm rounding, Maggie...
- When's Mom coming back?
Okay. She can, uh...
She can come with me.
- I'll figure something out.
- Great.
So, you're gonna hang out
with Dr. DeLuca,
and I'm gonna come
and get you later, okay?
Mwah.
Bye.
Hey.
Dr. Hurdle, pick up Line 2.
Dr. Hurdle, Line 2.
Am I okay?
Did I miss Halloween?
Your arms are fine.
You're fine,
and you didn't miss anything.
Trick-or-treating
didn't even start yet.
Your parents are down
in the cafeteria,
in case there's anything
you'd like to tell me
about what
really happened.
I don't know.
Mary Rose.
I want Dr. Alex.
Okay, fine.
Lemme get him.
Dude, come on.
Tell me what happened.
Mary Rose, come on.
I'm here to help, you know?
Just tell me
what happened.
I begged my moms for a cat,
so they finally got me one...
Miss Velma.
But she ran out
a few days ago.
I was scared
she'd get hit by a car.
So you ran after her,
didn't you?
I put on my helmet.
But I didn't have time
for my jacket.
Please don't tell my moms.
They'll make me
get rid of Miss Velma.
- These burns are very serious...
- And they hurt.
I swear
I'm never going out
without my protective gear
again.
This sucks.
I'll file this under
doctor-patient privilege
this time.
This is your one pass,
okay?
See?
There's always a reason.
It's just a matter
of figuring out a way
to get it out of them.
Superman?
It's got a cool cape.
Batman, then?
Okay, uh, uh,
Captain America?
Spidey?
No superheroes.
Okay.
Uh, pbht.
Ooh! How about a robot?
Okay, you don't want to be
a monster, an athlete,
a vampire, a racecar driver,
a Pokémon,
a superhero, or a robot.
I don't know
what else there is.
I want to be
a sunflower.
Okay.
So...
maybe two weddings
next year?
Uh, we're just focused
on the baby.
Who we're gonna raise together,
of course.
You're gonna
make a great dad.
Well we obviously have
a lot to figure out
before the baby arrives
in the spring.
Exactly
when are you due?
Oh, we put a deposit
on a wedding venue.
Uh, third weekend in April.
But we're flexible.
We'll forfeit. Yeah.
How old are your kids?
6 and 8.
Those are good ages...
Old enough to help
and still young enough
to want to.
I just hope they're okay.
Yeah. I mean,
how are you not
climbing the walls?
There's nothing else
to do in here
but think about how screwed up
everything is.
It's... infuriating.
Oh, I was angry.
First few days
I was in here,
I almost put a hole
in that wall with my fist.
Then I figured
I can go insane with rage
or I can find
other things to do.
So I started reading
all of Toni Morrison's books.
I have an ongoing game
of gin rummy
with Luiza from D Block.
And I have this puzzle.
Grey,
your paperwork's here.
What are you waiting for?
Sorry I'm not gonna
help you finish.
We finished the edges.
You just got to work with
what you got.
♪ When I look back ♪
- ♪ I remember when we met ♪
- Good luck with your hearing.
- ♪ How I felt, how you stayed ♪
- Good luck with your license.
♪ How you left, how you came
back as someone else ♪
♪ When I look back,
I remember ♪
♪ I remember ♪
Zola?
- ♪ When I look back, 20/20 ♪
- Zola?
- ♪ We were young, 21 ♪
- Just me.
♪ We were dumb, it was fun ♪
♪ 22, and we were done ♪
- ♪ When I look back ♪
- There you are.
♪ I remember ♪
Want to go check out
the trick-or-treating?
- ♪ I remember ♪
- There's some candy.
I'll wait for my mom.
♪ I tried to keep it small,
it wasn't enough ♪
Can we talk, Zola?
♪ It's nobody's fault,
it was bigger than us ♪
Look, I'd really
like for us to get along.
So, did I do something
to upset you this morning
when I was helping you
with your costume?
My dad fixed my wings...
before he died.
Oh.
They ripped,
and he sewed them up.
So you don't like it
when other people touch them?
I don't want
to forget him.
Oh, Zola.
You're not gonna
forget your dad.
No one's forgetting
your dad.
I mean, he was a legend.
Did you know him?
No, I didn't know him.
But a lot of people
here did.
And they talk about him
all the time.
I've heard the stories
so often,
sometimes I forget
I wasn't even there.
♪ I got no regrets ♪
♪ Don't know what comes next ♪
♪ I wish you the best ♪
You know, one time,
there was this lab tech
named Isaac,
and he had this huge tumor
in his spine.
And he'd taken it
to all these doctors,
and they were all
too afraid to operate,
but not your dad.
Your dad said he would try.
And when he opened Isaac up,
he saw that the tumor
was even bigger
than it was
on the scans.
All he could do
was stare at it
for 10 hours straight.
Did he take it out?
Not that day.
He stayed up all night
thinking about it.
And the next day, he opened up
Isaac again. He cut out as
- ♪ I wish you the best ♪
- much of the tumor as he possibly could...
..until all...
A burial ground
explains a lot...
Patients crashing,
the stairwell light
that flickers at midnight,
the corpse bride
who haunts the room
where her husband died.
Do you have
any more gauze?
Oh, my God!
Haunted!
Look,
nothing is haunted.
The corpse bride is my...
My wife
in a Halloween costume.
Okay?
The patients crashed
because the refrigerator's
broken.
And, yes,
there's a burial ground
where the new wing
is going,
but we've notified
the authorities,
and we're exhuming
the bodies.
- Everything is getting back on track.
- Mm-hmm.
So stop spreading rumors.
Get back to work!
Did you say
"burial ground"?
Uh...
Almost had 'em.
Keep fighting
the good fight, Dr. Grey.
Yeah. Thanks.
But not so hard that
you end up back here.
Um, I don't want to get
either one of us in trouble,
but I do have
a small favor to ask.
Dr. Axford to the ER.
Dr. James Axford to the ER.
Austin is okay,
but his head
was seriously injured...
Same with his pancreas,
which we had to remove.
He's in the ICU,
but he's doing fine now.
Oh. Thank God.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Can I see him?
- Me too.
- Yeah. I can take you now.
Can I take pictures to send
into the costume contest?
Maybe he could still win.
Halloween really
brings out the weirdos.
Okay, all you've done today
is complain...
The candy,
the costumes.
Catherine Fox may have made you
chief of chiefs,
but she did not make you
the Halloween Grinch!
Yeah. You're right.
I'm sorry.
That's it?
No cynical argument?
No snarky comeback?
Yeah.
I used to like Halloween.
But my son David...
Uh, he loved it.
His mom didn't,
so every year,
he and I'd put together
his costume
and go trick-or-treating.
It was our thing.
One year, he was, um...
..he was really excited
about being Luke Skywalker.
So, we were making
a stormtrooper, uh, belt,
you know, like
he wore in the, um...
When he got out of
the trash compactor.
"Episode IV."
Yeah.
It was a good costume.
It was.
Except he never got
a chance to wear it.
He died two weeks
before Halloween,
and I just...
That unworn costume
hung on the back of his door
for months.
I couldn't bring myself
to...
take it down and...
Oh.
Oh, uh... hey, hey, hey.
Hey, take it,
take it, take it, take it. Ohh!
What? What?
That's okay.
No, no. No, no. Shh.
It's okay. Come on.
Easy, easy.
Let's get out of here.
Today was a...
A nightmare.
Hey.
You are amazing.
You are turning
a house of horrors
into a legit hospital,
and I am sorry if those
investors can't see that.
Well, don't be.
I'm getting
a new research facility.
They gave you
the funding?
Yeah, they said
they were impressed
with my ability to handle chaos.
They don't even know
the half of it.
They should visit
your childhood.
Hey, you know what?
Yeah? We should do
something to celebrate.
Great. I am absolutely
dressed for that.
What?
What time does
the courthouse close?
♪ You learnt ♪
- ♪ my love, you ♪
- Sometimes your worst
- nightmare comes true,
- ♪ hit the target ♪
- ♪ ..and ♪
- but you find it's really nothing
- to worry about.
- ♪ then you walk out the door ♪
♪ You kept me small ♪
♪ That's what you wanted ♪
Happy cancer-versary!
♪ And I hate that you're gone ♪
And I hate that
I don't want to let ♪
- ♪ go ♪
- Shh.
♪ And I hate that ♪
- ♪ you think that I'm weak ♪
- Trick or treat!
- ♪ 'Cause I don't want to let you know ♪
- Mom!
Hey!
Mommy, Mommy!
- ♪ I'm going to build ♪
- I missed you!
Hi!
- ♪ Castles ♪
- Hi!
♪ From the rubble
of your love ♪
Cool costume, Mom.
Thanks. We're sorting candy.
Wanna help?
I do. I'll be there
in one minute, okay?
Okay, let's give your mom
a minute.
Come on.
Welcome home, jailbird.
Thanks.
I'm so glad you're back.
Ohh.
How was it?
- ♪ Castles ♪
- It was horrible.
That was always
my experience.
♪ From the rubble
of your love ♪
But, you know,
I had a lot of time to think,
and I realized that,
okay, so,
if I don't have a job
and I can't practice
medicine,
I still have
a lot to work with.
And I'll figure
something out.
- ♪ Castles from the rubble of your love ♪
- You're not gonna help us sort candy?
- ♪ From the rubble of your love ♪
- No, I am.
I just... I have
to call my lawyer.
I-I need help
with a puzzle.
Occasionally you discover
that what you most dread
is really a blessing.
And your life is better
because you persevered,
despite your fears.
Hey.
Where's your costume?
This is it...
Kick-ass surgeon!
- I love it.
- Okay, look,
I didn't have time to make
Leo and Allison costumes
and I am not gonna
sew costumes
and I am not gonna be
classroom mom
or do all the other things
that your mom did.
Yeah. I know.
That's why
I brought
these old costumes
to see if they might fit
these guys.
- Oh.
- Wait.
You thought I wanted you
to sew costumes?
I...
So you thought
I made this special trip
just to hand you
my mom's old costumes
with the sole purpose
of shaming you?
Or, like, inspiring me?
I was inspired,
if that helps at all.
What are
they supposed to be?
Zombies?
You dressed our babies up
as dead babies?
Well, that's a terrible way to put it.
Oh, hey.
We're just about to kick off
the costume parade.
Are these little guys gonna...
Oh, my... Ahh.
Next year, you might
want to just buy costumes.
But sometimes your worst
nightmare is truly scary.
♪ Get up and move ♪
- And it feels like it's never going to
- ♪ And never stop ♪
end.
♪ Gonna keep on climbing ♪
- That's when support from friends
- ♪ Till I reach the top ♪
- and family is vita l.
- ♪ Going up these levels ♪
♪ Till I touch the sky ♪
Hey. There he is.
Oh! Aww.
What happened to
"Dungeons & Dragons"?
I felt more like
a sunflower today.
♪ This fight in my soul ♪
♪ How you like me now? ♪
- Boo!
- Ah!
Aah!
What are you doing here?
I couldn't wait any longer
to see you.
Okay. Here.
Get in. Get in. Get in.
♪ How you like me now? ♪
Aww, aww, aww.
And I'm posting it
because joy
should be shared.
- ♪ I'm gonna show you I was born... ♪
- Vampire and sunflower...
That's some
serious kink.
You want to surround yourself
with people
who will wake you up
from your nightmare...
- ♪ Whoa, whoa ♪
- "For better or worse..."
For better or worse...
"..for richer
or poorer..."
..for richer
or pregnant.
- ♪ Whoa, whoa ♪
- ♪ Let's go ♪
What?
I'm pregnant.
- ♪ Don't stop, move ♪
- ♪ Get up ♪
Scared you!
I got you so good.
- Wait. You're not pregnant?
- No.
Oh, my God,
you should've seen your face.
Sorry. I'm sorry.
- ♪ Whoa, whoa ♪
- ♪ Hey ♪
For richer or poorer...
"..in sickness
and in health..."
..in sickness
and in health...
- ♪ Whoa, whoa ♪
- ..and help you live your wildest dreams.
Your bail's been posted.
Time to go.
What? By who?
Doesn't say.
You coming or what?
Sync corrections by srjanapala