♪ Ohhh ohhh ohhh ♪
I was thinking
how I keep waiting
for life to get easier.
You know? Lower stakes.
Less risk, more reward.
Easier.
And I was thinking
that maybe it doesn't.
I was thinking that maybe
the struggle, the climb,
the one obstacle after another,
maybe
that's just life.
Done.
Eighty-eight seconds.
Hmm.
Can I call Cooper now?
You can call Cooper now.
Nights when Lucas
stays with Pete used to mean
a long, hot,
uninterrupted bath.
But this is so much better.
Yeah?
Well, I'm gonna take
a half day tomorrow.
Yay! I'm gonna come home
for lunch, I'll see you then.
I was thinking maybe you'd
bring Lucas to the fire station.
That'd be the coolest place
he's ever been.
That's really sweet.
Oh...
That was really dismissive.
That's not how I meant it--
no? How--? No?
How did you mean it?
Ow. Look, you make me happy,
Violet.
And I'm ready
for this to be more.
I want you to meet my friends.
I wanna get to know your son.
I want your toothbrush
in my bathroom.
I'm ready
for it to be real.
Is that what you want?
Is it Pete?
I-- Scott, i-- i--
I like you. I like this.
Yeah?
But my life is--
it's complicated.
Everyone's life
is complicated.
The question is, do you want me
to be a part of yours?
How you feeling now?
Good.
Really good.
And I'm so grateful.
I was a zombie
and you woke me up.
Well, the wrong medication
can make everything worse.
But now
that the fog has lifted,
we can work toward
a proper diagnosis.
Well, today, right now,
I feel normal.
I got up at 6,
I did a load of Sam's laundry,
I alphabetized
his bookshelves.
Heh. I don't know about you,
but I hate when people's books
are just randomly stuffed
in there.
You're looking for one,
you can't find it.
Okay.
Then I went for a run,
and I looked at the ocean.
And I didn't just stare at it.
I really...
I really saw it.
Well, that's a lot
for a morning.
Yeah, well, I have 20 years
to make up for.
For myself
and for my brother.
I want us to be closer
but...
I don't know how to--
you can always talk to me,
Corinne. Always.
I'm just not sure
where to start.
I mean, what to leave out.
There's a lot
that I am not proud of.
Well, that was your past
and perhaps as we get
more comfortable,
we can address that.
Why don't we focus on
what's happening now?
I'm ready to start over.
To have the kind of life
that everyone else has.
Well, that's something
to work toward.
Oh, that sounds
oddly patronizing.
No. Wait, wait.
You're saying
you don't think
that she can get there or...?
It's important to understand
our limitations.
That goes for all of us.
You're not listening.
I'm not crazy.
This is me. I'm back now,
and there's nothing I can't do.
As Amy has told you,
gliosarcomas
are very aggressive tumors
that don't respond well
to treatment.
And what's the plan?
We're gonna insert
vascular balloons
into your brain and bypass
the large blood vessel
that's infiltrated
by the tumor.
Our hope is to preserve
the healthy brain tissue
and remove the tumor.
What's the catch?
We only have 90 seconds
to do it.
What?
After 90 seconds with no blood,
Erica's brain tissue
starts to die.
We'd be causing a stroke.
Ninety seconds.
Can you do that?
Not alone.
But working together--
they've done it
in the practice suite. Twice.
- Twice.
- Twice so far,
and we'll keep practicing.
Erica, I'm not gonna
lie to you,
this has never been done.
It's risky.
But I believe we can do it.
Maybe you wanna take
a few more days to practice.
Try and get that number up.
Unfortunately,
time is critical.
We have to remove the tumor
before it's too big.
When?
Today.
You wanna try surgery on me
that's never been successful
today?
And if you fail,
my brain dies.
That's what we're saying?
You have
two world-class surgeons
telling you you have a chance.
Two days ago you had none.
You have to take that chance.
I need a day.
I have a son who's stuck
watching TV with the nurse
with no idea what's happening,
so, ahem, I need a day.
Okay.
Book the or.
First thing tomorrow.
On my count. One, two...
Dr. Bennett,
we were watching TV,
then Gloria
couldn't catch her breath.
Sudden onset of dyspnea.
No associated chest pain
or palpitations. Tachy at 120.
Cardiac panel, enzymes,
portable chest.
She's also
30 weeks pregnant.
What? She's pregnant?
She didn't wanna tell you.
Because you knew
it wasn't supposed to happen.
I'm so sorry.
High flow O2, 100 percent.
Dr. Bennett.
What's going on?
She's in congestive
heart failure.
What are you doing here?
I'm the ivf doctor.
Dr. Reilly gave us our baby.
Wait, what were you thinking?
You know how dangerous it is
for her to carry a baby now.
It was routine.
No contraindications.
Well, I gave her
a donor heart.
Started working with her
before I joined the practice.
She never mentioned
anything.
Don't you do physical
examinations on patients
before you knock them up?
I do a gynecological exam.
Gloria's was normal. She--
I expect my patients
to be forthright
with their health.
She wasn't.
Fine.
You can rely on whatever--
oh. Am I interrupting?
Yes.
No. Jake did ivf on one
of my heart transplant patients.
Not knowingly.
Well, that is either crazy
or irresponsible.
Could you please
back me up on this?
I just came in
to get a yogurt.
- No, no. Weigh in on this.
- Addie, no, no.
I helped out a patient
who lied
that she had
no preexisting conditions.
After he happened to miss
the zipper scar right down
the middle of her chest.
I don't ask my patients
to disrobe entirely
when I'm doing
a routine fertility evaluation.
Do you? Want me to start?
Okay.
It doesn't matter
how we got here.
What matters
is keeping your patient alive
and giving the baby
a fighting chance.
She's 30 weeks.
That's viable.
We deliver now--
we know
there's a big difference
between viable and healthy.
We can't wait.
We need to give this baby
a chance.
Gloria could die.
She's persistently
hypotensive,
she could be rejecting
the donor heart.
It could be something else.
That is a chance that
I don't think we should take.
Sam's right.
You gonna eat that
or frame it?
It's a little thing called
attention to detail, my friend.
Oh, Violet, hello. Look.
Hey.
Hi.
Hello.
I'm sorry. I just need
to get that juice.
Whoops. Heh, heh.
Kind of in a rush.
Okay.
All right. See you.
Uh-huh.
That wasn't awkward at all.
You got it.
Come on, dad.
Charlotte throws harder
than you do.
Come on.
Less chatty, more throwy.
You know what?
I think it's gonna rain again.
I think we should go.
We're not scared
of a little rain, are we?
It's more the threat
of pneumonia and lightning.
Mas, I think you might be right.
Your dad might be a wuss.
Go long.
Mom, did you see that?
You all right?
Would you be?
Mom, what's wrong?
Are you okay?
I'm not okay, honey.
I'm sick. And I'm sure
you've noticed that.
And I should have talked to you
about it before because
I'm really sick.
What do you mean?
What's wrong with you?
There's a tumor in her brain,
Mason.
Mom,
you're not gonna die,
are you?
I hope not.
I really, really hope not.
How long have you been sick?
A long time.
Why didn't you tell me?
Why didn't you tell me
you might die?
Mason. Mason.
We're doing everything
that we can.
She should have told me.
Mason.
Here, I'll go. I'll go.
Hey. What were
you doing before?
What do you mean?
With Corinne.
You were being patronizing.
And a little pessimistic.
No, Sam, I was being realistic.
Corinne's behavior felt--
her speech was pressured,
she was highly energized.
Her thoughts were expansive.
That's Corinne.
It's also hypomania.
All right, so...
So she's a bit manic.
Which could easily precede
full-blown mania and--
that's a freight train.
At least she's not depressed.
If my gut is right,
that'll happen later.
What?
I'm not prepared
to confirm a diagnosis, Sam.
But it's very clear to me
that Corinne is sick.
Probably since
she was a teenager.
And the last two decades
have been a spiral of descent.
I didn't hear her say that.
I'm trained to listen to
what isn't said.
My sister being happy
isn't a disease, Sheldon.
It-- look,
when Corinne left,
even when it was bad,
she was in my blood,
she was a huge part of my life.
And when she walked out
that door,
a part of me died
and I buried it,
along with
all my memories of her.
But now...
I don't know.
I think that she is back.
My sister is back.
Well, Dr. Bennett thinks
you should have a c-section now.
It'll put the least amount
of strain on your heart.
It's too soon for the baby.
Do you really think
delivering at 30 weeks is ideal?
Look, you're not wrong.
It will put your baby at risk
for developmental problems.
But waiting
might not be an option.
We've been through
so much to--
to give up now
and just hope
that our premature baby
survives--
We were wrong to deceive you,
but no matter
what Dr. Bennett says,
we won't do a c-section.
Not now.
Hey. Thanks.
Okay, remember I was telling you
about that sex I was having?
That unattached, x-rated,
filthy, hot--
yes, I remember.
I think
I may have screwed it up.
Scott said he wants more.
What did you say?
Nothing.
What did he say?
I just rolled on top of him
and shut him up.
Interesting strategy.
I just--
I don't know what I want.
Yeah, join the club.
I slept with Sam.
What?
I was all jazzed up
about saving that baby
and he was all spun out
about Corinne.
One thing led to another...
Are you guys
getting back together?
No.
Because you wanna
throw yourself at Jake again?
No, no, definitely not.
All I get from that guy
is frostbite.
Ahem. What about--?
You know,
what about you and Pete?
Ah... when I think about going
back into that situation, i--
no, he hasn't changed.
Nothing's changed, so no.
And as for Scott,
look, look, I am a mother,
I have a full-time job.
I have no business getting
into a real relationship.
Do you like him? I mean,
apart from the filthy, hot sex?
He's good. He's kind.
He rubs my feet
when we watch TV.
There's nothing wrong
with having fun.
If that's what
feels right for you,
then don't change a thing.
Chocolate malted.
And a coffee too please.
Regular.
Mmm.
Thank you. Keep the change.
It's mom's favorite.
She's all right,
you know. Mom.
I was afraid to ask.
It's been so long,
I thought maybe--
no, no, no, she's fine.
She's healthy, retired.
She's got a companion
named James.
Our mother is getting--
no, no, no. They just--
they go out to dinners,
he fixes stuff around the house.
Ha, ha! Sure, he does.
Ugh.
Come on. That's nasty.
Did she ever talk about me?
Yeah, yeah. Uh...
In the beginning.
But, you know,
then it got tough for her,
more than she could take.
After a while--
she forgot about me.
No. You were always there.
For both of us.
We should call her.
I can't.
Not yet. I mean, you know,
this has already been a lot,
you know. I'm not ready, okay?
Okay. All right.
Mm.
Oh, no.
No, I still haven't
please.
Gotten over the PTSD
from the last time
you t-boned me.
No, it's been forever.
I'm a grown--
let it go. Come on.
Come with me right now.
You're going.
Done.
Ninety-two seconds.
Damn it.
Son of a bitch.
You did it five times straight
in under 90.
We don't practice
until you can do it right.
You practice
until you can't do it wrong.
Okay. Go again.
How's Erica?
Sleeping or trying to.
I don't know
how you'd fall asleep
the night before you...
I did this wrong.
I just-- I did it
all wrong.
How so?
Dragging Erica up here
for some hail Mary surgery
that our friends
are gonna perform.
They don't even know
if they can pull off.
All I can do is pace around,
thinking through
every awful eventuality.
And my son is trapped
in a front-row seat
for whatever happens, and you?
You didn't ask for any of it
and you're trapped
in the middle of a horror show.
Coop, breathe.
No, I can't breathe, Charlotte.
That's--
I can't breathe because I feel
like I screwed everything up,
in the worst possible way.
You didn't screw it up.
You did the best you could.
Tell me it's gonna be okay.
Coop.
I'm not asking for a fairy tale.
I'm just saying,
no matter what happens,
it's gonna be okay.
With worst case
and she dies,
I mean, it's gonna be okay.
Like we can do this,
we can raise this kid,
you can be a mother.
Just say it's gonna be okay.
Okay.
It's gonna be okay.
So they're gonna be coming
to take you to the or
in a couple minutes and, uh...
How you feeling?
Okay.
But they keep it
a little cold in here,
don't you think, baby?
Mason, please don't be mad
at your mom right now.
No, he gets to be mad.
Mason, look at me.
You get to be mad.
You get to have
all of your feelings.
As long as you know, you have
to know, that I love you.
Come here.
I love you more than anything
in this whole stupid world. Heh.
And I always will,
from wherever I am.
Even if you're mad at me.
You know that, don't you?
Now, I need you
to go with your dad.
Because I have to talk
to Charlotte for a second, okay?
You can eat as much junk food
as you want today.
It's okay.
What can I do for you?
Teach him
how to drive a stick.
Before you ever let him drive
an automatic,
teach him
how to drive a stick
so then he'll never
be stranded, okay?
Okay.
Don't push him too hard
on his grades.
He's smart like Cooper,
but he's too hard
on himself,
so don't add to that, okay?
Okay.
And talk about me.
You'll be his mom, but--
no.
You will always be his mama.
Whatever happens.
Always.
He needs a living mom.
He'll need you.
You get that?
Cooper's not enough.
He'll need you.
They're doing
the surgery today?
Okay. Well, yeah.
Call or text or do something
as soon as you know
anything, okay?
All right. Love to everyone.
Wow, that was fast.
How are Charlotte and Cooper
holding up?
Trying.
Oh, hey, do you have
plans tonight?
Do I have plans tonight?
Yeah. I was wondering if
I could come by and see Lucas.
If you're busy, then I'll--
no, no, no. That's fine.
That's fine. Yes.
Hey. Do you have a second?
I'm kind of busy right now.
I'm sorry that
I didn't back you up with Sam.
Well, no surprise there,
right?
Look, you know what--
what happened with Sam
was a one-time thing.
And I am quite capable
of separating
my personal feelings
from my professional
opinions.
Gloria fought the odds
to become a mother.
You know, maybe unwisely,
but she's earned the right
to put the life of her baby
ahead of her own.
No matter what we think,
she has that right.
But Sam said--
Sam isn't her ivf specialist.
All right?
And neither are you.
Anything else?
You can do this.
There's no margin for error.
There's no margin
for self-doubt.
You think I don't
know that?
I'll see you
in the or.
The last time I operated
on a friend, I was out of it.
It's a miracle
nothing went wrong.
I mean, what if my karmic
payback is now and Erica dies?
I know you're scared.
That's good.
Well, how is that different
from having self-doubt?
You don't doubt your skills
as a surgeon.
I wouldn't let you
scrub in if you did.
I don't--
I don't see the difference--
after dad died,
any time
there was a loud noise,
like a gunshot,
you'd jump out of your skin.
You got ahold
of these firecrackers.
I found you in the yard
and you were setting them off
one at a time
until you didn't jump anymore.
When you're scared,
you fight.
You face your fear
and you fight.
And you fight to win.
Your fight is much stronger
than any karmic payback.
You got this, Amy.
We got this.
Hey.
Whoa.
I thought we'd have
stir-fry tonight.
This is adventurous.
When did you learn
how to cook?
Couple years ago.
There's this dive on pico
in venice.
The chef took pity on me.
Let me watch in the kitchen
and eat the leftovers.
Wait. A couple years ago?
That-- you must mean...
Wait, how--?
How long you been here
in L.A.?
It's, um...
It's complicated.
Corinne.
How long you been here?
You know, there's a shelter
on Santa Monica.
I'm just gonna go--
wait. Don't-- don't--
don't avoid me.
Don't run away.
Just answer my question.
Five-- five-- five years.
Do you have any idea
what it's been like for me?
For mom? We--
we thought you were dead.
Do you get that?
Hey! We thought
you were dead!
After ten years,
we had a funeral for you.
Your name
was on a headstone.
Sam, i--
don't. Stop.
Because I had to watch
our mother broken.
She was destroyed.
And me? How could you
do that to me?
To us?
It's not about you.
How could it be?
It's always been about you!
What happened
to my baby sister?
You don't wanna know.
You're right,
I don't wanna know.
All this was so much easier
when we thought
you were dead.
Last night, I was
laying down
in Sam's guest room
and I was fantasizing
about an earthquake.
Not one that would hurt
anyone else.
Just enough to make
the piece of roof above my head
fall and crack
my skull open.
To what end?
I'm not sure.
I don't know if I just wanted
the pain to stop
or if I wished I could finally
feel something real.
But then again, I don't--
I don't even know
what's real.
All of it is.
Everything you feel.
So I am a waste of skin.
Corinne.
For what I did to Sam,
to my mother,
I should be taken out
back and shot.
This is not your fault.
You're suffering
from a disorder.
It's called--
does it matter what it's called?
Because whatever
you think it is,
there's a drug for it.
And I'm pretty sure
I've taken it before
and it didn't work.
What's happening with you,
what's been happening
all these years,
is bigger than you.
And every day a battle
is fought in your mind.
And with
repeated misdiagnoses,
and the lack
of proper treatment,
and the instability
of your life,
all those things
have made it worse.
You're suffering
from bipolar disorder.
And right now,
you feel like you can't go on,
but I'm telling you--
I'm tired, Dr. Wallace.
I'm so tired.
Why'd this happen to me?
I was so smart.
I got a's in everything.
I could do everything.
My junior year in high school,
everyone wanted to be me.
And then one day,
it was all gone.
I can only imagine
how hard that would be.
But the Corinne of yesterday
did a load of laundry,
and organized some books
and went on a run.
And if you can
endure bottoms,
there will be tops
that will allow you
to shine and to thrive.
And with the proper medications,
and diet and sleep,
we can try to turn down
the intensity of the swings
and help you achieve
your own normalcy.
But you have to be patient
and you have to
let me help you.
The graft is ready.
Ready to inflate?
Timer on. Ninety seconds.
- Ready?
- Ready.
One, two, three, go.
- Done.
- It's in.
Eighty-five seconds!
Sorry, 85 seconds.
New record. You did it.
We did it.
Okay, good.
Moving on.
Let's excise
the infiltrated vessels.
Uh, pressure's going
through the roof.
- The artery is non-pulsatile.
- She's thrown a clot.
Damn it, she's stroking out.
You know what that is?
It's a brain.
It's your mama's brain.
And that is the tumor
growing inside it.
So the doctors have to cut into
her head to get it out?
Mm-hm.
So how are they gonna do it?
Well, first they'll cut out
a section of her skull
and dissect the brain
so that they can see the tumor.
And they'll separate the tumor
from surrounding tissue
before removing it.
If everything
turns out right,
they'll close her up.
But what could go wrong?
There are risks
with any brain surgery.
Your mom could
get a blood clot
or bleeding in the brain.
It might affect her speech,
her vision, her memory.
She might have a seizure
or a stroke.
Or she could die
from the operation.
But that is why
we came to Seattle.
We wanted your mama
to have the very best surgeons
doing her operation.
You're telling me the truth?
This is all of it?
Yes. This is all of it.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Pressure's 179 over 105.
Shut the hell up. We know.
The clot's jammed up
against the proximal end
of the shunt.
I see it.
I'm taking the shunt out.
Without it,
there's no blood supply.
We don't clear the clot,
she's dead. Do it.
Microscissors.
Through the suture line.
Almost there.
Got it.
Pressure is--
is what it is.
Shunt's out now.
That pretty much
cleared out the clot.
Good. Reinserting the shunt.
There.
The artery's pulsatile.
And pressure's coming down.
Okay. Shall we continue?
I need the graft
and another microdriver.
Just another five or six hours
to go. We're cruising now.
That scared the crap out of me.
Yeah, me too.
Corinne.
Hey. Uh...
Can I talk to you
for a minute?
Look, I just wanted
to apologize for this morning.
I didn't mean to yell.
Yes, you did.
Because you are
the selfish one.
For the last 20 years,
everything in my head,
it's been big and bold.
No whispers, just screams.
And I tried to deal with it.
You know,
I felt responsible.
I thought it was me.
But you know what, Sam?
I'm sick.
I'm the one
with bipolar disorder.
So you can complain
all you want
about how worried you were
and how worried mom was.
And I feel bad about that,
I really do.
But I was living it.
And I protected you
from the worst of it.
While you were in med school,
I did my first stint in jail.
And while you were off
being a big, fancy doctor,
I was eating garbage,
so I could have enough money
for drugs
because that was the only way
to escape the pain.
And while you were having
a family and living in Malibu,
I was selling my body
just to survive.
So you missed me.
Poor you.
This isn't your journey,
it's mine.
It is my pathetic life.
And you might hate me.
But guess what, Sam,
I hate me more.
And I can tell you
to go to hell.
But having lived there
the past 20 years,
I'm pretty sure
you can't handle it.
And so screw you.
What happened?
She was fine
and then she just started
gasping for air again.
Pulse ox is dropping.
Up the nitro drip.
Back 100 percent O2.
Why is she
not getting better?
I'm not sure.
We're gonna have to take you
to the cardio lab.
We need to do
an endocardial biopsy.
Figure out what's going on.
Is the procedure
safe for the baby?
The baby will be exposed
to radiation during the X-ray.
The procedure could cause
precipitous labor.
No. I'm not doing it.
Gloria, listen to me.
She said no, Sam.
She can't breathe. She'll die
if we don't do something.
Give her another dose
of diuretics.
She's maxed out.
Put her on a pump.
Jake, she is a year and a half
post-transplant.
She's been doing fine.
I'm not just gonna
throw darts at a board.
I have to figure out why
she's rejecting her heart now.
I know.
I'm sorry.
But I stopped taking
my immunosuppressant drugs
when I got pregnant.
Why would you do that?
They could hurt the baby.
You shouldn't have done that.
Shouldn't have done
that on your own.
Her water broke.
We gotta get her
into labor and delivery now.
Move back there.
Baby's coming too fast.
Gloria,
I need you to stop pushing.
I can't.
Try to slow your breathing.
It hurts.
Gloria. You breathe with me.
Breathe with me.
Her pressure's dropping.
Hurry up, Addison.
- What's going on?
- I'm losing her pulse.
- Get ready to bag her.
- I'm on it.
Get that baby out of there.
Head's out.
Anesthesia.
Thoracotomy tray.
You're gonna crack open
her chest?
I have no choice.
Towel and cord clamp.
What do you need?
Sternal saw.
It's coming.
All right. Spreader.
Addison, we're running
out of time.
Got her. Scissors.
I can crank her open.
Do it.
- Damn it.
- What's going on?
- Dissected her aorta.
- I need a cross-clamp.
Call perfusion for bypass.
She's in fib.
We're losing her.
Almost there.
Just give me a second.
Erica.
It's Dr. Shepherd.
Can you hear me?
Mm. Hurts.
We'll get you something
for the pain.
Can you wiggle
your toes for me?
And your fingers?
Both hands?
Good. All right.
We got the whole tumor.
All of it.
I lived? I'm alive?
If this is heaven, sister,
I want my money back.
Ow. Hurt.
Pain medicine will kick in
in a second.
Erica, Mason's looking
through the window.
No. Don't raise your head.
Just wave. You can do it.
Lift your hand. Wave.
Perfect.
I'm alive.
We did that.
We gotta publish.
Oh, hell, yeah, we do.
If you ever think
about doing drugs again--
remember this?
I was gonna say call me.
I'll fly down to Los Angeles
and knock some sense into you.
But, okay, remember this.
That doesn't work.
Yeah, you can totally
kick my ass.
Done.
I love you.
She's so small,
but she's perfect.
Got ten little fingers
and ten little toes.
And her face looks
just like you did
when you were younger.
It's not a boy though,
so I guess
we can't use the name Thomas.
We never really talked
about girls' names.
We should've talked
She's gonna need
something strong.
Like her mom.
We should've talked about
girls' names.
We should've.
What are you thinking about?
Nothing.
Come on.
Um...
Well, I actually
was thinking
about how bizarre
my life is.
I live in a hotel.
I...
Uh...
I'm having s-e-x
with a 29-year-old.
And I had i-n-t-e-r-c-o-u-r-s-e
in an elevator.
I know you did.
With an s-l-u-t.
Yeah. These bars,
these women, it's not--
they're not...
You ever think a year ago,
we'd be--
talking about having sex
with other people?
No.
Who are we?
I don't know.
I love medicine!
Seriously, I do.
The whole medical field.
I'm in love with it.
I would marry it if I wasn't
already married to you.
Well, I'm glad
I got to you first.
Thank you.
And thank you.
I mean, you did not
sign up for this.
I love him.
Mason.
I didn't think I could.
I mean, I didn't think
I would, but...
When I thought
his mama might die...
I love him.
And I think it's--
I think it's because
I love you so damn much.
I love you, Cooper.
So damn much.
I love you.
I like you.
You make me feel...
You have reminded me
that I can laugh
and smile
and be fun
and not think about anything
but being close to you.
And that is
so, so nice.
I don't want more.
I don't have more.
So it's either incredible,
unattached,
mind-numbing sex or nothing.
I'll take it.
Tell me something.
Am I reading too much into
all of this?
Into...?
You and me.
The grocery store,
Fiji, palm Springs.
Am I reading too much
into that?
Was it purely physical
or is it--?
Is there something
emotional here?
For me?
Yeah.
For you.
It's not just physical.
Okay.
I figured...
I thought that
you left because of me.
That time when I told mom
that I didn't want a party
for my birthday
because I didn't want you
to ruin it
just like everything else.
I turned around
and you were standing there
and I know that you heard me.
And a week later,
you were gone.
I didn't leave because of you,
Sam.
I left because I was sick.
You didn't cause this.
You didn't make this happen.
And you'd think that that would
be a depressing thought.
That there's no end
to all of the...
I don't know.
That it doesn't get easier,
that it just gets different.
But it's not. It is not.
It's the opposite of depressing.
There's a relief in it.
Life is complex. There's nothing
simple or easy about it.
So I can stop waiting
for it to--
I can stop waiting.
And I can just
live.