Excuse me. I've been
waiting here for over an hour.
All I need is a refill on
my migraine medication.
We'll get to you
as soon as we can.
You can get to me now. It'll
only take you two minutes.
You're not an emergency.
This isn't an emergency room.
And it's not gonna go any
faster by pissing me off.
Got a minute? No.
Routine check-up can
wait. What else you got?
I'm consulting on some clinical
trials that involve CNS compounds.
While it's true that "no" sometimes
means "yes," in this context...
One's a new Huntington's drug.
Phase three trials are showing real
results in delaying neuronal degeneration.
Probably get you in.
No, thanks.
Are you doing anything about your
disease? Following any kind of program?
No. Nor am I
looking for a consult.
Excuse me. I'm
looking for Dr. Cuddy.
She's either not here,
or she's under the desk.
Either way you're gonna have
to wait outside until I'm finished.
Do you know when she'll be back?
Yes, which is why I need you
to get out and leave me alone.
Sorry.
Nice try. Love to help.
Shut up.
You wanted to
see... I said shut up.
I'm sick, and I
want to know why.
I want the best
doctor in this hospital,
here, now, or I'm
gonna start killing people.
What seems to be the problem?
Close those blinds.
You, push the sofa
in front of that door.
You, move that table
in front of the other door.
Now! Okay!
Okay. We'll just move it. Okay.
You don't have to point the gun, man.
We're gonna do whatever you want.
No, we're not.
House.
That's a bathroom you're
barricading. Might come in handy,
especially since you've cleverly decided
to take a bunch of sick people hostage.
Do it!
My medical records. I
need you to read them.
You really think that
re-enacting Dog Day Afternoon
is the best way
to get diagnosed?
I'm sure you've been waiting for
hours in an uncomfortable chair,
but you should watch the
movie all the way through.
I've been to 16 doctors
in the last two years,
had three full-body
CTs and two MRIs
seven blood panels, and
one homeopathic consult.
And all that was missing
was the threat of violence.
What's missing is an answer.
I can't breathe.
I'm tired all the time.
I get skin rashes and heart
palpitations and insomnia.
It's a cool constellation of
symptoms. It could be something minor.
At least, compared
to life in prison,
which is what you seem to prefer
to seeing 16 more specialists.
Shut up and do your job.
Keep moving.
You barely looked at the file.
No need.
Symptoms? Those are the
things you keep whining about.
Tests? All negative or
you wouldn't be here.
History? Shy, quiet
kid, kept to himself,
collected comic books
and missing children.
Excuse me. My wife
feels sick to her stomach.
Next time pack some
heat, maybe we'll look into it.
I'll be okay.
If you ask me,
keeping an open line of communication
is the best way to resolve conflict.
What kind of breathing problems?
Shortness of breath and
sharp pain when I inhale.
So you figured your wife left you
because you couldn't breathe, right?
Me, I rarely kidnap someone
unless I got a serious health problem.
And since you're not almost
dead, means you're armed
because you're blaming something
other than your health on your health.
I've never been married.
Got a match? Why?
Because I'd rather
not stand here
while you try and negotiate a hostage
trade for an incentive spirometer.
I'll look in Cuddy's desk.
Stay out of the desk.
Cuddy doesn't smoke,
but he does. No, I don't.
Right, you just brush your
teeth with coffee grounds.
Look, sir, I've never
smoked in my life, okay?
Jerk.
You figure that two people snuck
weapons into the clinic today?
I'm sorry. I just got a lighter.
Slowly.
Hold it out as far as you
can. Try to blow it out.
Decreased lung
volume, heart palpitations,
fatigue, stomach
pain, intermittent rash...
Could be a hundred things.
You add on that final symptom and it
can only be pulmonary scleroderma.
What final symptom?
Those were all my symptoms.
Last one is the 16
doctors who missed it.
Simple alkylating agent, case
solved. See you on visitor's day.
Crime scene.
House, what's going on in
there? Is everyone all right?
About to be,
assuming he's not lying.
But he seems like a
pretty straight arrow to me.
I'm gonna need some propofol to
prove that it's pulmonary scleroderma,
and we all get to go
home. Propofol? You sure...
Have one of the guards bring
it in. No, no guards, no cops.
I'll go get it.
And no one's leaving.
She's not a cop. Dr. Cuddy
brings in the drugs. Alone.
She might be armed. I'd
have her deliver it shirtless.
Who is it?
Oh, God. House, maybe
we should wait for the...
Guys with even bigger guns?
Who know how to talk to armed...
Say goodbye or I shoot her.
Pull up your sleeve.
Give it to someone else first.
You're the only
one who needs it.
Give it to someone else.
If it goes in okay, you can
give a second dose to me.
I don't care who, but
just pick someone.
Again, had your brilliant plan
included a roomful of hostages
who don't have fetuses,
bacterial and fungal infections,
leaving their immune systems too
weak to deal with the metabolic strain,
or who are already on painkillers
that have fatal interactions...
He's not on painkillers. I
heard him tell her in the clinic.
Come on, man.
Don't take it out on us.
You got a problem with doctors,
take it out on the doctors. Give it to her.
She's sick. And you
are a very large creep.
Take off your shirt.
Satisfied?
Fine.
Roll up your sleeve.
You think I'm an idiot?
That's what you think?
Thought I had a little more
time with a guy that size.
You're not gonna do anything.
You still need me.
Come on.
What are you doing?
He didn't do anything.
You're right. I need you.
I also need you to know
you can't screw with me.
It's for you.
Lieutenant Bowman,
Princeton SWAT.
Dr. Lisa Cuddy,
Dean of Medicine.
We just heard a gunshot, but I
haven't been able to make contact.
We'll handle that once we secure
our perimeter and set up our positions.
By perimeters I assume you mean
snipers. We have to put an end to this.
Got a husband in
there, or a loved one?
No.
Don't worry. We'll decide
when to start shooting.
House is gonna
get someone killed.
Guy's ready to
kill for a diagnosis.
I can't think of a better doctor
to be trapped in there with him.
How about somebody who's not
gonna keep pushing the wackjob's buttons
until he cracks?
It's House.
Joe's Bar and
Grill. It's Foreman.
And every fellow you've
had in the last five years.
What causes low lung volume,
heart palpitations, fatigue,
stomach pain, insomnia and a rash?
This is pathetic.
If I strap a bomb to my chest, do I
get seven doctors attending to me?
Dr. Robert Chase.
On the off-chance you have some brilliant
escape plan and are the vengeful type.
You think he's the only guy in New Jersey
with an unsolved illness and a pistol?
I'm not playing this game.
Seriously? You're walking out?
No, he's just kidding.
He's right here.
Throw me that marker, will you?
Chest pain, the lung problems, fatigue,
rash, sounds like chronic lung infection.
Heart palpitations and fatigue,
could be a cancer that's
spread from the lungs.
Next.
If his diaphragm's not working,
maybe his nerves are freezing up.
I think he's going into shock.
First rule of triage, guys
with guns go first. Next.
Shortest distance between stomach
pain and insomnia is bad circulation.
Plus trouble breathing,
could be a heart defect.
You needed to write four
things down to remember?
It's not my wall.
You're gonna get
some special deliveries.
Foreman, we're gonna draw blood.
Run a test for infection and cancer.
Cameron, comb through
his medical records,
see if any of his past 900 medications
could have screwed up his heart.
Taub and Kutner, go to his
apartment, check for neurotoxins.
873 Marshall, South Brunswick.
Back window's unlocked.
Giving out your address?
Clearly not going back there.
Means you do have an end game.
I'm Lieutenant Bowman.
How's everyone doing in there?
Got one lower limb flesh
wound, another guy unconscious.
Unfortunately, not
the guy we hoped.
We're gonna need
someone to deliver his blood.
It's gonna be hard
to play doctor...
Shut up.
Open that blind,
just a few inches.
Why me? Just open it. Open it.
Why me? Anyone
can do it. Why pick me?
Get back! Get back!
I will kill her unless you
back the hell out of there now!
Interesting.
Anybody else hear
those guys outside?
Anybody?
He's got hyperacusis.
What does that mean?
It means we have a favorite.
It's nerve-related.
Amped-up hearing could
be linked to nerve palsy.
Puff out your cheeks. Come on.
Now, a big mug-shot smile.
Left-side facial weakness.
Seventh-nerve palsy.
Plus intermittent rashes, plus
migraines, it's postherpetic neuralgia.
Herpetic? You
think I have herpes?
I'm not judging here.
This thing is just as likely
to be caused by chicken pox.
I need proof now.
There is a test. It's
dangerous and painful
while the treatment
is safe and painless.
But you make a good
point. You need proof now.
I'll order up the test.
If you have neuralgia,
you won't feel it going in.
It only hurts if your
diagnosis is wrong.
Win-win.
Jason, don't hang
up the phone again.
You're gonna send in...
Capsaicin, 200 micrograms.
And two syringes this time.
And we'll give you the
blood and his records.
No more meds, Jason, and no
deliveries without something in return.
You gotta give us a hostage.
You can have two.
Great.
Then I'll send an officer
right in with the transfer.
Everything gets
brought in by Dr. Cuddy.
Jason, I'm not
gonna let her do that.
First, don't use
his name so much.
It doesn't sound reassuring,
just sounds creepy.
And second, come on, he's
not gonna shoot the one person
he trusts to bring
in his medication.
He's gonna shoot the
hostages if she doesn't bring it in.
I'll get back to you.
The guy's demanding
that you do all the transfers.
Okay. "Okay"?
What am I supposed to say?
You're supposed to
say no, it's not your job.
If you got a conflict here,
if you have stakes in this
that you're not telling me
about, then I can't trust you.
Got it. I'm okay.
Can you tell him
I'm coming in now?
Who's taking the first dose?
Anybody here got a
longstanding case of neuralgia
that's killed their nerves
so this won't hurt at all?
How bad does it hurt?
You're looking to be the hero?
I've been beaten up a
lot, and I can handle pain.
How old are you?
Guy's got a gun. I think that
covers the parental consent issue.
And that stuff can also cause
nerve and muscle damage.
Uh...
No way am I taking
that crap. Come on.
You have to. It's the rules.
I'll do it.
This is a level of risk-taking
beyond anonymous
girl-on-girl action.
They're patients, I'm a doctor.
With a degenerative,
drug-unfriendly illness.
Everything's not some
fascinating character flaw.
This is a genetic flaw.
This is your Huntington's speaking. This
is you waving a white flag at the world.
Yes, I have a
shortened lifespan.
Another reason why I'm
objectively the right choice.
Wow, I would have laid
money you had herpes.
Your turn. So, why are we here?
We've ruled out immediate
risk of death, lost love.
That just leaves work.
You're defined by your work.
But you kept seeing
doctors, kept missing time,
couldn't focus.
And you made a
huge mistake, got fired.
I just want an answer.
I know. I'm asking why.
Guy knew he wasn't coming back.
Everything's laid out for us.
I'll check for toxins
in the kitchen.
He must have $6,000,
$7,000 in unpaid medical bills.
I've got debt, too. You don't
see me acting like a lunatic.
There's no excuse
for what he's doing,
but if you've got millions of
people thousands of dollars in debt
because they're sick, at least one of
them is going to do something inexcusable.
Especially if it works.
White blood cell count's
normal. It's not infection.
So either his heart is on
the fritz, or he's got cancer.
I found a picture of his mom. She's
got a droopy eye, fat face, thick neck.
Classic signs of an
upper-lobe tumor.
Or she's just ugly.
They're also classic signs
of an adrenal problem.
It's his heart.
You can't be sure which...
His neck, distended jugular.
What are you doing?
I'm going to try to strangle you
faster than you can pull a trigger.
He needs to check your pulse.
It's racing, 160.
We need to get paddles.
Or maybe we could
just do nothing.
If I get any weaker and
they don't fix it, I'll shoot you.
Don't! He didn't mean to...
Shut up, all of you.
What are you doing?
Carotid massage,
it'll slow your heart.
It's 200. Get the paddles.
The whole point of those things is
they make your muscles contract.
They don't discriminate
against trigger fingers.
Nobody gets my gun.
Send in paddles! Don't!
Get the damn paddles,
or I'll shoot you.
Threatening to shoot the guy who's
diagnosing you makes a lot of sense.
Actually doing it, not so much.
Give him your gun
so he can save you.
Just let him die. Bill, stop.
We can cardiovert chemically.
If we don't know what
kind of heart rhythm it is...
If we don't try something,
he's gonna kill someone.
I'm gonna get the drugs.
No one goes anywhere.
If she doesn't come back, you've got
plenty of other people you can shoot.
You, come here.
All right.
Thirty seconds.
She's gonna go.
She's gonna come back.
She should go.
He'll kill him. But not her.
Is that your
version of morality?
If you don't think your life is
worth more than someone else's,
sign your donor
card and kill yourself.
Shoot me.
You really want... Yes.
No! No!
She just needs time. She just needs
more time to find you the right drug.
She just needs time
to get your... It's me.
She takes it first.
Adenosine slows the heart, which
is fine, if it's beating fast like yours,
not fine, if it's
normal like hers.
You following the math on this?
She takes everything I take.
I don't want anything
that cross-reacts.
Martyr's heart is beating
dangerously slow. Are we good to go?
Your heart's back to normal.
No tachycardia, no sign
of a heart defect at all.
But you're sweating.
I nearly had a heart attack,
you're surprised I'm sweating?
One side of your
face, but not the other.
What does that mean?
A tumor is pressing on
your sympathetic nerves.
You have lung cancer.
Pulse is down below 50.
So is her IQ. Help her up,
get her heart going faster.
I need proof it's cancer.
Of course you do.
It's gotta be a Pancoast tumor.
Patient's got dyspnea,
seventh-nerve palsy,
he's sweating on
one side of his face.
Everything okay in there?
Take your time. It's not like
I've got a gun to my head.
Lung cancer usually shows
up lower than the seventh nerve.
Did you check his throat?
Spit on the floor. What?
If I do it, I can't tell Cuddy
that it was medically necessary.
I'm gonna ask you to
piss on her chair next.
Dry mouth, his parotid
glands aren't working.
If there's swelling, it's a Pancoast
tumor that's metastasized.
Feel that. Right there.
If it's cancer, there
must be a test.
You just did it.
What about an
X-ray or something.
Good idea.
Oh, damn, I left my CT
machine in my other pants.
How many hostages do you think
it'll cost me for a trip to radiology?
So, what made you snap?
HMOs? Shut up.
Nah, you saw 16 doctors,
how bad could they have been?
Shut up.
Humiliation?
Doctors treating you
like a piece of meat?
Too many fingers and
tubes up your holes?
You hate doctors, you
want to take back control.
If so, I apologize for the fact
that you are a piece of meat.
I just want an answer.
That's all.
Everyone stays in here with me.
You need anything
from in there, get it now.
Move around.
Anyone moves, I fire.
That's not all.
Curiosity is not enough.
There's got to be a deeper reason.
You never did anything just
because you had to know?
Never shot anyone.
You're not me.
This is my body,
this is my life,
and there's a truth out there.
I'd rather rot in
jail knowing than...
I can't handle not knowing.
Yeah.
Hold that.
You want your answer,
you gotta give me the gun.
What's this?
Starburst artifact, the metal
from the gun is ruining the image.
Show him.
Starburst.
Now, unless you think
we pre-arranged that
just in case we were ever held hostage
by a guy who needs a CT, we're not lying.
So, you have two choices,
you can give me the
gun and get your answer,
or you can shoot me.
I'm not gonna give you the gun.
Why did he release you?
House got him to give
up his gun. We just ran.
Why are you still here? Curious.
It's safe now, right?
They're gonna be through that door
any moment, just show me the tumor.
There isn't one.
I don't know what you have.
So,
it's over.
Thanks for trying.
You had four theories,
you ruled out four theories.
Maybe no one can cure me.
He overpowered
me. Got the gun back.
You're a coward.
You need to know everything
because you're afraid to be wrong.
You're so afraid of being ordinary,
of being just another doctor,
just another human being, that
you'll risk other people's lives.
I'm arrogant, you're the coward.
You're terrified of death.
You just want to cheat it
by making it come sooner.
It gives you the
illusion of control.
Can I go?
Sorry. We might need you.
How do they expect me to think?
Is he lying? Why
would he do that?
Over time, hostages
start to root for the captor.
House isn't the rooting kind.
No, he's the
obsessive, defiant kind.
Mic the door, get
a frame charge.
Hope your boyfriend
knows what he's doing.
Are you insane?
He's quick for a sick guy.
Dyspnea, anemia,
seventh-nerve palsy, tachycardia.
Long passes, anything, go.
I don't believe it. Chase was
right, you're gonna kill someone.
I don't want to be a part of it.
Loa loa filariasis.
You ever been to Cameroon
or on the Ogowe River? Next.
Could be Q fever, if he's
had exposure to goats.
No goats.
Histiocytosis X explains
the lung involvement and...
You have a new symptom.
He's turning his head,
favoring his left ear,
which means he's
partially deaf in the right.
Three hours ago he
had superhero hearing.
Cushing's causes fatigue, breathing
problems, fluctuating hearing...
Even increased
aggression and risk-taking.
I'm doing this by choice,
it's not a symptom.
We'll keep that between us
until we talk to your lawyer.
I need dexamethasone and enough
time to provoke a respiratory reaction
and confirm Cushing's syndrome.
You need more time? House,
we're not negotiating with you.
Actually, we're
through negotiating.
I've still got three
hostages left.
I'll give you one.
And no more testing
drugs on the sick doctor.
Fine.
Send in the drugs.
Son, come here, come here.
House, you can't...
If you have Cushing's,
this will slow your breathing.
Give it to her first.
Those were not the terms.
I lied.
These drugs could be fake.
Why would I do that? I
gave you back the gun.
You wouldn't, they would.
She has Huntington's.
If these drugs are real, it
could screw up her liver...
Chances are slim. Chances of him
shooting one of us, on the other hand...
Don't...
How long do you have to live?
Eight, ten years.
Killing her is your
chance to get personal?
Huntington's
doesn't have a cure?
No.
So, if we get out of here...
If she were clinging to hope,
she wouldn't be standing in line
waiting for you to order up more drugs.
Take a deep breath.
Not knowing what was wrong
with me made me miserable.
Maybe that's insane, and
doing this, yeah, insane.
But I had something to gain.
You can't take risks
with no upside at all.
I can't decide which is riskier,
taking crazy risks, or taking advice
on crazy risks from a crazed risk-taker.
Heart's racing. No fever.
And your breathing's unchanged.
Does that mean she...
Means I was wrong.
Her kidneys are shutting down
because of the meds you made her take.
We have to get her out of here.
The dexamethasone is
making Thirteen's kidneys fail,
but not the patient's, why?
This guy's been on 50
different medications,
maybe his kidneys should be failing,
but something's protecting them.
I need to slap you for
diagnostic purposes.
Seriously. If I was jerking you around,
I'd say I need to kick you in the groin.
That twitch is Chvostek's sign. Don't
ask me how Chvostek discovered it.
He has calcium deficiency.
Drugs that block calcium tend
to shield against kidney damage.
He's been on protein pump inhibitors
for years, for his stomach pain.
Those drugs have been
protecting his kidneys for years.
He has something that
has a long incubation period,
something that should've
wrecked his kidneys,
something that explains
breathing problems, heart problems,
jumpy nerves and weak blood.
Leishmaniasis.
Would make perfect sense if our
patient was an Arabian Bedouin.
Melioidosis.
Bacteria gets into the
lungs, spreads to the heart.
It explains everything.
Except that if you'd
read the history,
you'd know that our patient has
never been to a tropical climate.
Is he absolutely sure of that? Mexico,
Costa Rica... You've never been...
I've never been
anywhere south of Florida.
You idiot.
Florida counts?
Not to the Supreme Court,
but it's warm enough for germs.
You keep blaming doctors.
You can't even give a
halfway-decent history.
Negotiation's over.
It will be as soon as you get
us three grams of ceftazidime.
He comes out, he gets
all the medicine he wants.
You can have Dr. House.
Why are you getting rid of me?
I need to trade
you for the answer.
You're gonna give
her the meds. No.
Come on. Give
them to me instead.
She's taken
everything I've taken.
The combination of
meds could knock me out.
Her kidneys are failing.
You give her those drugs, she'll be
dead by the time they get the cuffs on you.
I need my answer.
Your obsession
is gonna kill her!
gave me back the gun.
It is pointless to
give her those drugs,
even if they are screwing with
you. This is your last diagnosis!
Only if you're right.
House, get out of here.
Shut up, I'm not leaving.
Who's the martyr now?
Either the drugs kill me or he kills me.
Doesn't seem to make a lot of difference.
You really don't feel
bad about killing me?
Not if you don't feel
bad about killing yourself.
I don't want to
die. Yeah, you do.
You just don't have the
nerve to actually do it.
You just want it out of your control.
Well, it is. Because I've got a gun.
Don't do this.
Either I do this
with you alive or...
Please. Sometimes you
just have to trust people.
I don't want to die.
Why are you still alive?
He didn't make me take it.
A week of temporary dialysis,
your kidneys will be okay.
I'm sorry I backed
out of the differential.
About that
Huntington's drug trial.
Test confirmed melioidosis.
Easy to miss on the stain.
Scans and X-rays vary widely.
Is that all you care about?
A moron storms the clinic, bullies
his way into life without parole,
you enabling him at every step.
If he hadn't done what
he did, he'd be dead.
Good thing you enabled
my every medical move.
You think I handled this differently
because you were in here?
I don't know. Let's
try it again without me.
This is why you
and I can't be a thing.
If you're suggesting
that you screwed up
because of a
non-relationship with me,
I don't know how I can help you.
Because the only change you can
make from a non-relationship is...
You want a relationship?
God, no. I was just
trying to follow your logic.