If you're going to dress
like an Italian hooker,
at least let it be this
year's Italian hooker.
She's not telling
us we look fat.
It's a major breakthrough.
If you didn't want
to be insulted,
you wouldn't have invited me.
Would anyone like
some champagne?
No. Yes. Three glasses, please.
Mom. It's not even lunch.
If you'd prefer, I'll
make it a mimosa.
What do you think?
Perfect for a night on the town.
Perfect for breastfeeding.
My heart's doing
that weird thing again.
Beating? That's
normal for humans.
Come on, Lisa. Take
her seriously for once.
What? What is it?
I think we need to
get you to the hospital.
Is no one gonna tell me
why we're in the morgue?
House is on the
lam from someone.
Taub's got his money on Wilson,
but I'm pretty sure it's Cuddy.
Fool's bet. There's a whole
world of angry patients, creditors...
She needs a doctor.
Yes, just not me.
Your mom is a 65-year-old
woman with high blood pressure.
What about the
macrocytic anemia?
Borderline, which is the
lab equivalent of imaginary,
which, by the way, matches
the rest of her medical history.
You really think she's psyching
herself into atrial fibrillation?
So get her a cardiologist.
You don't want me involved.
You don't want you involved.
You know all that ethics stuff
that I don't give a crap about?
It suddenly makes sense.
If you're emotionally invested,
you cannot make
rational decisions.
You know this
would be a disaster.
This is my mother.
Treadmill test went well.
No chest discomfort or ischemia.
The abnormal rhythm
will probably resolve itself,
and if not, a daily pill
will keep it under control.
I will follow up later today.
Is it connected to
my other symptoms?
Which other symptoms, Mom?
Not her fault.
This Dean of Medicine stuff,
very impressive at parties,
but she's forgotten
how to be a real doctor.
It's all in my file.
There are 15 years of
clinic visits in this file.
I don't want to be a bother,
but isn't this what
you do for a living?
So, we're looking for a disease
that can last a
decade and a half,
causes constipation,
diarrhea, flu, colds,
dizziness, rashes,
back and joint pain,
heart feeling "weird",
kishkes feeling "wobbly".
One actual hip replacement.
And which has eluded
detection by years
of blood work, X-rays and MRIs.
Well, one thing
does pop to mind.
We'll monitor you. And
we'll give you a thyroid test.
And House's team will do a home
search for environmental toxins.
He seems to know his stuff. How
come he can't afford a coat that fits?
No radon, no mold,
no lead in the pipes.
Yeah, yeah, great.
Have you seen Cuddy's
high school yearbook?
Okay, that is clearly not
related to the case, so...
There is no case.
Cuddy won't let House
see the yearbook,
so he figures there's
something to hide.
Any guesses?
It's clearly related to
being a giant teenage dork.
So you thought I'd
have some insights?
Oh, no, no, I didn't
mean that. Relax.
I was crowned Homecoming Geek.
I'm sure you can relate.
Because you knew some dorks?
I was the class president
and head boy at...
Ah!
Is that Cuddy's mom?
Certain parts of her.
And certain parts of some
muscular Hispanic gentleman.
Should we consider STDs?
I think I just caught one
looking at these photos.
What does "azarcon" mean?
It means we might
have an actual case.
Mexican herbal medication
for stomach problems,
but only in the sense
that lead chromate
is an herb and
poison is a medication.
I'll start a chelation
IV. Thank you so much.
Wasn't too much
of a disaster, was it?
You know, it's not the only
thing they found in her home.
Not my yearbook.
Nope.
Just some stuff that
could cause severe
nausea and permanent
erectile dysfunction.
And which proves that
your mom is doing the help.
According to her diary, it's
some contractor named Jesus.
Which, granted, was
originally a Jewish name, but...
Go, Mom.
So, why were you taking
a Mexican folk remedy?
A friend uses it. A friend.
Mom, just for medical reasons,
you should have told me.
If you're sexually
active... At my age,
he's more the active one.
Mom's having a fling.
I know. You do?
She's been giving me lousy
advice about it for five years.
I have physical needs.
He's a married man, Mom.
She doesn't want sex with him,
I do want to have sex with him.
Tell me who's being hurt.
Hold on. Five years?
Why didn't you tell me about it?
I don't know.
We don't have that
kind of relationship.
Does that really surprise you?
You're not ready?
You said you had two
guys helping you move.
They couldn't get out of work.
I'm trying to economize.
And this hotel is cheaper.
Hi.
I'm sorry.
I just wanted to
drop off some mail
and talk to you about something.
Of course.
Rache.
Chris, that's not why...
We got to move on.
And what does that
mean? Have you moved on?
With who? Is it Phil?
I don't want to talk about this.
I know that you're
worried about money, so...
You're trying to change
the subject. Yeah.
Which you could
have gleaned from,
"I don't want to
talk about this."
I got you a tryout
to be a part-time
medical consultant on law suits.
Wait. With your brother?
Have you completely
forgotten the last time I saw him?
Yeah, that was five years ago.
Jamie had just found
out that you'd been
cheating on me with
your partner's daughter.
It's a little over-reaction...
He broke my nose
and then called me
the most horrible
person that he's ever met.
He shouldn't have
broken your nose.
You know, texts,
calls and e-mails
all go to the same magic device
these days, only got to send one.
Then it's even weirder it took
you so long to get down here.
Yeah, it's a crazy mystery. It's
not like I got a department to run.
This other magic
device tells me that
lead poisoning wouldn't
cause all my symptoms.
True. But it could cause
the 5% that are real.
You think I'm a hypochondriac?
Well, let me answer this way.
Maybe you're imagining that I
think you're a hypochondriac.
Look, my hand just
started to shake.
It's a side effect of these
arthritis pills. Read the label.
I did. When I was typing it up.
Right before I slapped it
on a bottle of sugar pills.
You printed a fake label just
to prove I'm a hypochondriac?
Did it work?
It got you fired, you schmuck.
An hour to convince her
to go with Dr. Kaufman,
and only then because
he runs internal medicine.
She wanted to leave
the hospital entirely.
My God, a woman getting
better wants to leave the hospital.
If she's getting better, it's not
because you made her feel like a fool.
It couldn't be more because.
If I hadn't, she'd have diagnosed
herself with six new forms of cancers.
She'd never leave.
It's hard enough dealing with
my mom being sick. This juvenile...
Yeah. DR. KAUFMAN: Lisa.
It's gonna be okay,
but she's in A-fib at 170.
Oh, God.
I think we should cardiovert
while she's unsedated.
I'll be right there.
A-fib's at 170.
Wait. I'm sorry she's sick.
I'm not sorry I'm off the case.
You're not off the case.
You don't think you
can convince her...
No, no. You are staying on.
She just can't know about it.
Top of the morning, Dr. Kaufman.
Here's the deal. You
copy me on all the imaging.
I'll have my guys
run the lab tests.
No.
I thought you spoke to Cuddy?
Yeah. Then I spoke
to the elder Cuddy.
Who specifically requested
you not be involved.
Listen, Kaufie. You are perfectly
competent, bordering on good, even.
But you know I'm better.
If you want, we can pretend it's
'cause I got a team and more resources.
Either way, it'd be crazy
to ignore my advice.
It's not gonna stop at advice.
You're gonna
start cutting me out,
go behind me to your girlfriend.
And if something goes wrong?
It's still me standing up
there alone at the M&M.
Please, stay away
from my patient.
You bugged the room?
I absolutely without
apology will admit
that someone may
have allegedly done so.
Guess we can pass unethical
and skip straight to illegal.
Not according to the recent
Supreme Court case of Bite vs Me.
Dr. Kaufman's single.
Did you know he went
to Harvard Medical...
Mom, stop yenta-ing
for one minute.
Of course, if you want gloomy
and unable to commit, then
stick with the goyishe one.
This is completely unethical.
Why are we listening to this?
I know I'm a pain,
but it's impossible
for me to work
with you if you...
Fine. Fine.
Instead of a live stream, I'll get a
recap from Cuddy 20 minutes later.
Thank you for saving America.
Could be leukemia. Anemia
from taking over the marrow.
A-fib from infiltrating
cardiac muscle.
Sounds good.
Yeah.
I was really hoping
for a different diagnosis.
One that Kaufman hadn't
already come up with.
He just started a
bone marrow biopsy.
So we don't need to do anything?
I don't. You do. Go to
admitting and find us a new case.
DDX.
We just did it.
No, we just did the fake one.
Why do you think I let the
truth fairy know about the bug?
I was testing her. She
failed. She's still a narc.
Thiamine deficiency
fits better than leukemia.
You think she's an alcoholic.
When I had dinner with Arlene,
I mixed her a gin and tonic
and I'd run out of the tonic
so I substituted sleeping pills.
Next morning, she assumed
the blackout was from the drinking.
How many old ladies are used
to passing out from boozing?
The answer is the boozers.
We're gonna have to
slip her the thiamine pills.
We've got to run this by Cuddy.
Why do you think I'm
in such a bad mood?
Alcoholic?
Treatment's very easy, safe,
just literally a
few vitamin pills.
It'll fix her heart
and it won't interfere
with the biopsy
Kaufman's running.
I've put them in
an antacid bottle.
Just tell her it's for
stomach problems.
I have to ask her about this.
Of course. Absolutely.
You'll ask, she'll deny, you'll
push it, she'll get offended,
you'll be exactly
where you are now,
except it'll be harder to treat.
You've absolutely
got to do that.
I don't think she'll lie to me.
She just spent
the last five years
going south of the
border down Mexico way.
We have our issues,
but since Dad died,
we tell each other the
truth when asked directly.
It's important to us.
Addicts lie.
Can I speak to Mom alone?
Why?
You're scaring me, Lisa.
Mom, I think your drinking
is causing your heart problems.
Is this about the
champagne? She ordered...
Patsy and Anne told me last week
you lost control at
the museum luncheon.
You're talking to my
friends behind my back.
We are all concerned.
Just tell me honestly.
How much have you been drinking?
I may be your patient,
but I am still your mother
and I'm telling you
I am not a drunk.
Okay.
For your stomach pains.
If something like
that comes up again,
just do what you need to do.
And keep you out of it?
Yeah. I am being a coward.
Which is exactly why doctors
shouldn't treat their own families.
Congratulations.
You were right, as usual.
The hitting you was not optimal.
I was going through my
own divorce at the time.
I've had years of therapy.
Now when I get mad, I do some
deep breathing, squeeze my stress ball.
Hey, I kind of deserved it.
That's for sure.
Here's the deal.
I do a lot of med-mal insurance.
I need a new
non-testifying expert.
I'll give you one
case as a tryout.
You kick ass, I put you on
retainer, average 15 hours a week.
It's 50 a year.
Fifty what?
You kidding? Fifty thousand.
I'll take it.
You drive a soft bargain.
You got to sign an NDA.
Sure.
Is this...
That's a case
I'm about to settle.
I rep a giant pizza
delivery company.
Driver hit that kid,
messed up his legs.
And gave him a
micro-bleed in his brain, right?
What? No.
This little white mark.
Your predecessor checked,
so did the kid's doctors.
I don't know what
that is, but he's fine.
Probably. But if
there's any doubt...
It's a multimillion-dollar case
we're settling in two days.
Lay off it, okay?
Okay, you're right. I'm off.
She spiked a fever. It's 102.
Means I was wrong about
the thiamine deficiency.
You were wrong
about the alcoholism.
True dat.
It's actually looking more
and more like leukemia.
Kaufman rushed the
biopsies. It's not cancer.
So there's a bright side.
Kaufman was wrong, too.
DDX.
Okay. What disease
can turn Cuddy's mother
into a coma patient
named Stewart?
Lupus?
We got fired from that
case. We're moving on.
We were already fired.
By the patient.
This time by
Cuddy, so it's real.
She somehow realized that her
completely unworkable system
was completely unworkable.
Okay, pop quiz, hotshots.
I chose Vegetable
Stew for a reason.
You got 60 seconds, no hintsies.
You're not gonna talk to us?
Exactly, you're gonna have to...
Hey, you're good.
So this is just a test?
Pupils fixed and dilated.
An addict found with an empty
bottle of phenobarb next to him.
How's this a mystery?
It's an overdose.
Glutethimide!
Script filled last year.
Could mimic fixed and
dilated without the brain death.
Except he'll just get
better on his own,
so why would you take this case?
Because House doesn't
care about the treatment
as long as the
case is interesting.
I'll do a blood draw and put
glutethimide on the tox screen.
Really? You thought
that case was interesting?
Guess we're still on Arlene.
Aren't there other ways of
keeping Masters occupied?
Not according to my
sexual harassment seminar.
Maybe it's not hypochondria.
She says she
gets a lot of rashes.
Add the fever, sounds
like autoimmune, SLE.
Congratulations. You can think
exactly like a semi-competent internist.
Kaufman's starting
her on prednisone.
But the heart
problems were first.
Endocarditis?
With no murmurs?
It's usually a late sign.
The echo showed pristine valves.
Below the resolving threshold.
Kaufman's prednisone will
suppress her immune system.
It could kill her.
You've got to tell
him it's endocarditis.
Check the wiretap.
His ID guy's has been putting
the same argument to him.
He can't convince him.
You think I got a better shot?
So what do we do?
We switch her meds.
We get a solution of
broad-spectrum antibiotics.
Stick it in an IV bag
marked for prednisone.
Kaufman can only be
there a few times a day.
Tell Arlene you're from the
pharmacy. Switch them out.
This is nuts.
This is way too complicated...
It's hanging an IV bag.
If the attending doesn't know
what she's on, the risk of...
What risk? We know how he's
treating her, we bugged the room.
This is not about information.
We're talking ethical and
legal violations on a scale
that should make even
you puke. She's dying!
Doesn't mean we should
all go to jail to save her!
You're losing control because
this is your girlfriend's mom.
You gonna run this by Cuddy?
No. She said to keep her out
of it, do what we need to do.
Look, I know what I'm suggesting
is completely screwed up.
That's because this situation
Do it or you're fired.
We stick together, he
can't fire all three of us.
Give me your prescription pad.
Why are you doing this?
Because I think
it's endocarditis
and I think the
prednisone will kill her.
And I forgot my
prescription pad.
Am I a horrible person?
I used to win awards
for volunteer work.
I went to Guatemala
and fixed cleft palates.
Now we're sitting back
letting Chase do our dirty work.
We're doing the right
thing. Stay out of it.
I don't know. I don't know
about anything anymore.
Then this thing with the
kid Rachel's brother is...
Stay out of that, too.
A, radiologists, experts,
unlike you said no bleed.
B, you yourself
said it's probably not.
C, you've got no
doctor-patient relationship.
D, you'll lose your
consulting job.
E, your ex will kill you.
F, I'm running out
of alphabet here.
You do it?
Had the bag. Walking
towards the room
and Cuddy's sister
says, "Hey, Dr. Chase."
I met her at that
charity event last year.
One of you two's got to do this.
I met Arlene at
the same benefit.
Conveniently.
Come on, don't ask me. I
don't even know if I believe it's...
Damn it. It's Rachel's brother.
He wants me to check
out some new case.
Conveniently.
It's a tryout. I need this job.
I got to do this.
So you're just gonna ditch us, run
off and work on some other case?
Are you Timothy's mom?
Yeah.
My name is Christopher Taub.
I'm a doctor at
Princeton-Plainsboro.
I saw your son's file.
I think he might have a
very small bleed in his brain.
Wait, you saw his file? How
do you even know who we are?
Your son could die
of a brain hemorrhage.
He needs a cerebral
angiogram today.
Get in your car and
meet me at the hospital.
Timothy? We're gonna
go see the doctor.
Another pop quiz.
How many idiot doctors
does it take to switch an IV?
The longer we wait,
the more the prednisone
is gonna kill her immune system.
Forget playing the pharmacist.
Mom naps every afternoon.
Wait by the room, when she falls
asleep, get the sister out somehow.
Hi, Dr. Cuddy. Is now
a good time to talk?
Not really.
So, um, you know how
you had us consulting,
and then stopped
having us consult?
Why are you still here?
Well, I think the stopping
might have stopped.
House put me on this weird
case where there's no treatment.
I think maybe to distract me.
And they've been acting odd.
I'll look into it.
Thank you for coming to me.
Because I'm worried that he's
switching your mother's medications.
I checked with the pharmacy.
Dr. Chase got prednisone and
antibiotics for my coma patient.
Which wouldn't treat him,
but could treat conditions
that cause heart failure.
You told me to keep you out
of it, do what I needed to do.
What the hell did
you think that meant?
I meant like if
you had to slip her
a few more vitamin
pills or something.
This is life-threatening.
It's illegal.
I wasn't expecting
something like this.
Only because you intentionally
weren't thinking about it
'cause you don't wanna
make any tough decisions.
Are you completely
sure it's endocarditis?
That's not a real question.
Endocarditis fits better
than the alternatives.
We're having a little
trouble hanging the right IV.
Fastest way is with your help.
Where did Julia go?
She's got a family.
I've got a family.
Three kids and a
husband, that's a family.
You are always tougher on
me than Julia. Why is that?
I'm not.
I was thinking about when you
made me run for yearbook editor.
I didn't want to, I didn't have a
social life my whole senior year.
You let Julia do
whatever she wanted.
We're debating 12th grade now?
Like anything's changed.
What do you want, Lisa?
Do you want to hear I
love you both the same?
Of course I do.
Okay.
But times like this,
when we argue, it reminds me
I have more in common with her.
She's nicer to me.
I love you both,
but I like her more than you.
I called you three times.
My phone wasn't exactly on.
I figure I'll be getting
some angry calls
once radiology sends
back the angiogram.
They already did.
Here.
This is what you saw.
It's an anatomical
variant of the skull,
bone in proximity
to a blood vessel.
There was nothing
wrong with him.
That was reason G.
That's good news for him.
Lungs clear?
Diffuse wheezing,
tightness, pruritus.
It's an allergic reaction.
Looks like. But it
doesn't make any sense.
She's on prednisone. How
could she get an allergic reaction?
I switched out the antibiotics,
put her back on prednisone.
Her breathing's normal. But the
A-fib's back and her fever's up.
Allergy's got to be
due to our antibiotics.
Does Kaufman know what we did?
That's good. No,
that is terrible.
He doesn't know that she
got worse on antibiotics,
so now he's
thinking endocarditis.
He'll put her back on the
antibiotics that almost suffocated her.
What do we do?
We push through this.
Started in the heart, endocarditis
still fits, it's just got to be fungal.
We have to switch Kaufman's
antibiotics for Amphotericin B.
I don't know if you're
right, I don't care.
But we are gonna end
up killing this woman
if we keep confusing her
attending with these secret meds.
I don't care about confusing
the attending. I want this woman...
We're not talking about
simple antibiotics anymore.
Amphotericin B is dangerous
in itself. It's a poison.
That's why it kills fungi.
It'll give her fever, chills...
Which she already has,
which will help us hide it.
I don't think I can
take a risk like that.
Well, then, you shouldn't
have let her fire me!
Look, all you have to
do is switch the IVs again.
This has blown up
on you once already.
He's right.
Yep.
I'm so sorry I got you guys
into this. You should go.
I'm right.
I know. And I'll do it, but...
I agree. Fungal
endocarditis fits.
But we still have
to tell your mother.
I don't want to
tell her, not at all,
but the patient is
the highest priority.
I'm kicking you
out of your office.
Yes, you. This is
not her office yet.
If you tell anyone,
I will get you thrown
out of med school
and I will destroy your career.
I've thought about that.
Lying about me won't work.
Everybody knows your reputation.
True. But I won't have to lie.
Buried in your coma
patient's big, big file is a form
that doesn't allow
treatment without
the express consent
of the relatives.
Wait... You drew blood.
That's not just a screw-up.
It's a criminal assault.
But you told me...
No. As you may recall...
You set me up?
Why?
Because this patient
is the highest priority.
You made her think I was
hiding her son being sick!
She scuttled the settlement.
She reported me to the bar.
I got to deal with
that crap now!
I will sue you for slander,
for tortuous interference
and anything else I
can use to destroy you.
And my sister says, stay
out of her life, you failure.
Five years of therapy.
Dr. Kaufman, I need to speak
with you and the patient alone.
I'm skipping the
credentials committee.
I'm going straight to the state
board and reporting you for...
What you've done
is so off the spectrum,
I don't know there's
a specific name for it.
- I think he's talking to you.
- Marty, calm down.
And you. What you did is worse.
He's an insane lunatic.
You're the Dean of Medicine.
I want you off my case.
That's exactly right.
Don't get excited.
You're fired, too.
What?
I'll never get away from House
or my daughter if I stay here.
Transfer me to
Princeton General.
Mom.
You're very ill and
you're very angry.
You really think now is the right
time to make a decision like this?
You lied to me and betrayed me.
Do you think I really care what
you consider a good idea anymore?
I'll get the ambulance.
Happy?
I can't believe it.
What just happened?
You just killed her.
Are you blaming me?
This is all because
you're so arrogant,
you goaded her into firing you.
Actually, my mistakes
started a little after that,
when I agreed to
your brilliant scheme
to keep me on the case
after she'd fired me off it.
She would have
left the hospital.
Only 'cause you would have
let her. Like you did just now.
You think I can control her?
I don't know. I've
never seen you try.
I have been rebelling against
this woman my entire life.
Here's what I've seen.
She insults you,
you complain to me.
I drug her at dinner,
you never let her know.
We slip her medicine,
happens behind her back.
You never confront her.
And it pisses me off.
Are you taking this personally?
If she leaves, she dies.
One day, maybe a week from
now, maybe a year from now,
you're gonna decide that the man
sleeping next to you killed your mother.
Get me my patient back.
This is really bad, Lise.
I swear to God, Jules,
I will call security.
I asked you before why
you were tough on me.
I wasn't.
You were. And I know why.
You see something in
me that you didn't see
in Julia and you
didn't see in you.
A type of ambition,
a type of brains.
That's why you rode me.
You made me yearbook editor,
summa undergrad, AOA in med school.
The only time I ever
see light in your eyes
is when you hear me
talking about my job.
The reason you keep
coming to see me
in the clinic is
because you trust me.
You trust my medical judgment.
So here it is.
If you transfer to
Princeton General,
you'll be treated
well and you'll die.
If you stay here with House,
you'll be treated badly, but you'll live.
I don't care if I have
to slash the tires
of every ambulance
in this bay, Mom.
I am not letting you
leave my hospital.
One, two, three.
I got it. How are
you feeling, Mom?
I feel a little dizzy.
Heart's still weak from the
infection. We'll hang an antifungal IV.
If you're so great,
how come you're not
running your department anymore?
What are you talking about, Mom?
That's what he told me.
Two days ago?
I said that I didn't have a department
to run? I was being sarcastic.
No, you weren't.
Right, because
people who are talking
can't tell if they're
being sarcastic.
That doesn't make any sense.
Of course they
can. But you weren't.
I love A-Rod.
He's so modest
and I highly respect the paintings
he has of himself as a centaur.
Question. Do I like A-Rod?
Yes. Whoever he is.
She can't recognize sarcasm?
Deficit in the right
parahippocampal gyrus,
which means CNS
involvement before the fever.
I was wrong about
the endocarditis.
I don't feel...
Mom. Mom.
Heart rate 170. Nurse!
Do something.
I am.
House! The fever
was hypothalamic.
That means brain,
heart, anemia, allergy.
You hear that, what do
you think? I don't know.
You think heavy metal toxicity.
It can't be. You treated
chelation for lead.
And she got better,
then she got worse
because she never
stopped being poisoned.
What are you doing?
You really want me
to stop and explain?
There it is. Look at that.
The muscle's black.
Necrosis?
Metallosis. Her artificial hip
weared and teared way too much.
It's cobalt poisoning.
We're gonna need
Chase to get an OR.
We should start chelation again.
I thought you didn't
want to see me.
I didn't.
But Foreman called me.
I didn't know that you thought
that little boy had
a bleed in his head.
I will kill my brother if he
messes with you anymore.
What do you care?
Chris. You were
a crappy husband.
But you are a good person.
Once again. You are unfired.
Why?
You sold me out
even though you knew
that you're gonna get
thrown out of med school.
That's just kind of impressive.
I keep my job if I stand
up to you, I keep it if I don't.
I don't buy it.
When Cuddy was protecting me
before, she was protecting a doctor.
She's now
protecting a boyfriend.
The hospital's not gonna
put up with that for long.
So I need you to protect me
from doing something
Cuddy will regret.
See you bright
and late tomorrow.
Mom, why would
you want to keep this?
So I can mount it on the
wall like a moose head.
It says here, "Cobalt
can cause rashes,
"dizziness and
stomach problems."
You still think I've been
imagining the whole thing?
Okay, you might have a point.
How do you feel?
You know, a little
dizziness, some pain.