.
- We need
an experienced attending.
She's the one.
- Good news--your drug test
came back negative.
Plan on doing it again
next week.
- Ms. Goodwin said it was
just pro forma.
- It's my E.D., not hers.
- The spinal fusion--it'll
require at least two months
of rehab post-op.
- We'll welcome you back
whenever you're ready.
- Milena.
I gotta assume
that's your cover.
What's your real name?
- When the case is over.
- How'd you find me?
- I'm resourceful
when I need to be.
- This could be dangerous.
- I'm okay with dangerous.
- You headin' out?
- Less eyes the better.
- You all right?
We can't keep this up.
But...
as long as we're careful...
- At least let me make you
some coffee or something, huh?
- Make it to go?
- Hey, Milena, your alarm.
- Hey, do you have
a toothbrush I could--
- What is this?
- What are you doing
with my bag?
- You didn't answer
the question.
-  1505 funds.
Department issued flash money,
all right?
So I can front like I wanna
make a purchase if I need to.
- Yeah, there's at least
50K or more in that bag.
- Yeah, these aren't corner
boys slinging nickel bags.
You know,
these people move weight.
Look, it's--
it's on the up and up,
if that's
what you're wondering.
You know what?
I don't need this.
- Dang it, Milena, wait.
Mile--
♪
- Uh-uh!
You're not supposed to be here
until next week.
- I know.
That was the strategy.
- Did you know about this?
- No,
I swore Archer to secrecy.
I don't want anyone
making a fuss.
- You little...I have a banner
all ready to go to the printer,
and...
This ain't over.
-  Thank you.
Put security on high alert?
- Yeah, she's harmless.
- Oh, boy. Yeah.
Well, seriously, welcome back.
- Thanks for holding
things down for me
while I was out of commission.
My brother in arms.
- Hey, forget about it.
Uh, matter of fact,
if you want a few weeks
to settle back in
and hit your stride,
I'm more than happy
to stay on as chief
till the end of next month.
- Thanks,
but you don't have to do that.
- Hey, brothers in arms,
you know?
Take your time.
I got your back.
- It's moving, Daniel.
- Can I?
- Yeah, yeah.
Constant movement all the time.
- Oh, my God.
When your mom told me
you were comin' in,
I just had to see
this bump in 3D.
- I know.
She looks great, doesn't she?
- Well, she makes it look easy.
- That's what it is, right?
Just like you did.
- Look, I'll never forget
the night you were born.
I was working
what was supposed to be
my last shift at the hospital--
- I know, Ma.
You told me this story
a million times.
- No, but instead, my water
broke on my lunch break,
and you landed earthside
just about 8:00 p.m.
- Lucky for us all.
- Look,
I gotta get back upstairs.
But thank you so much
for letting me
crash your time with your mom.
It's great to see you, Tara.
- See you later, Daniel.
You know, I was glad I went
into labor at a hospital,
given what a difficult delivery
it ended up being.
- I haven't changed my mind
about a home birth,
and I'm not going to.
This is what I want.
- I know that, Tara.
- I know that this is all
a bit unconventional--
using a sperm donor,
choosing
to have a kid on my own,
and now, home birth--
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
It's probably just gas.
My point is these were all
very considered
and well-thought-out choices.
- And I'm not
implying otherwise.
But unexpected things happen
when you go into labor.
- I know that,
and I'm prepared.
Let's just drop it, okay?
I'm gonna go to the restroom.
- Tara, you're bleeding.
- Oh, my God.
- Wait, sit, sit.
- Oh, my God, Oh, my God.
- Oh.
- Mom...
- Okay, it's okay.
It's okay.
- Come on, pick up.
♪
.
- Okay, Tara,
have you experienced
any bleeding prior to today?
- Ah!
- No,
she hasn't had any bleeding.
- I've had bleeding,
but nothing like this.
- You have?
- Did your doctor
determine why?
- Yes, a fibroid--it's pushing
on my uterine lining.
- What?
When did you doctor find it?
- First trimester.
- Oh, Tara.
You should've told me.
You know my history
with fibroids.
- Exactly.
I didn't want you
to get worried.
My doctor monitors it
at every visit.
It hasn't grown.
There wasn't any reason to--
ah!
- Okay, Ms. Goodwin,
we've got her.
- Yeah, we'll be by with
an update for you shortly,
I promise.
- Okay, just lay down.
I need you to calm down.
We're gonna get you
an ultrasound, okay?
How far along are you?
- 26 weeks.
- Okay.
- Talk to me.
- Gavin Wells,
28-year-old male,
GSW to the right mid-chest.
- Okay, let's go to Baghdad.
- Unknown downtime
in the field.
CPR initiated
when we got there.
ROSC obtained in the ambo.
BP 100/77, heart rate 120,
sats 100%.
- How'd this happen?
- Victim of a home invasion--
shot by an intruder.
Neighbor called it in.
- Okay, here we go, guys.
Nice and easy
on my count, okay?
Here we go.
One, two, three.
All right guys,
help me roll him.
All right.
Bullet went
through and through.
Put him down.
Got good pulses.
- Good breath sounds
on the left.
Nothing on the right.
Let's get a unit of whole blood
on the rapid transfuser.
- All right, let's just get
chest x-ray goin'.
- ]Sup with the clown suit,
sis? You workin' this case?
- Brass has me workin' VRS
on my days off.
- What's that?
- Violence reduction strategy.
- Oh.
- Clear.
- Right hemopneumothorax.
- He needs a chest tube.
I got it.
Curly, set me up.
- What else do you know?
- Forced entry, signs
of a struggle at the scene.
Good news--the assailant
was a real genius.
Left the weapon behind.
Semi-automatic rifle.
- Was Gavin the only one?
- Yeah. His wife and kid were
out of town for the weekend.
They're on their way here now.
- Okay, here we go.
- Submucosal fibroid looks like
it's degenerating.
- And becoming necrotic.
Putting Tara at high risk for
pre-term labor and sepsis.
All right, let's load her up
with 100 of indomethacin
and we'll start triples, yeah?
- But the fibroid
has also grown
since Tara's last ultrasound.
If this trend continues,
it'll lead to
fetal growth restriction.
- Well, yeah,
there's a good chance of that,
but that's a conversation
for another day.
- Well, I think
that's a conversation
we need to have
with Tara right now.
- Well, why?
We can't do anything
for the fetus
except watch and wait.
- Hey, what about a myomectomy?
- For a pregnant person?
Are you out of your mind?
The possibilities of
hemorrhaging are too great.
- We can give Tara
TXA during surgery,
help minimize with blood loss.
- All right, so
you're suggesting that we risk
Mom's life to save the fetus?
- That is not true.
A myomectomy will also help
prevent against sepsis
and organ damage in Mom.
Look, I know
it's an unorthodox approach.
I get that.
- That's an understatement.
- By all means, share your
reservations with Tara.
But she deserves to know
all her options.
- I said no!
No, no hospital!
- Ma'am, lie back, please.
- 35-year-old female pedestrian
struck by a motor vehicle,
loss of consciousness
at the scene.
GCS of 15, BP 118/70,
Heart rate 112, sats are 100%.
- Maggie, another set of hands.
- Hey, hey, whoa!
- Let me go!
- Whoa, easy, easy.
We have to check you out.
All right,
let's transfer on my count.
Everybody ready?
One, two, three.
- No, I have to leave.
Let me go.
-  Oh, no, I--
- Ma'am, please.
Take a deep breath.
- No.
- Okay?
- I can't--I can't be here.
- Clear breath sounds
bilaterally.
Pupils equal and reactive.
- Okay, talk to us.
What's going on?
I promise
we'll take care of you.
- I--I'm not a citizen.
I don't have papers.
- Hey,
no one here's gonna report you.
Okay? You're safe.
Can you tell us your name?
- No, no.
I don't want it in computer.
- We'll keep you anonymous
in the system.
But what should we call you?
- Lia.
- Okay.
- Okay, Lia, I'm gonna check
your belly
for areas of tenderness.
- Ah, ah.
Ow! Aah!
- All right,
need a CT of the belly.
- Also chest and pelvis x-rays,
CT head and c-spine.
- Hey, Lia, just
try to get some rest, okay?
We'll be back shortly.
♪
- Crockett.
- Yeah?
- Mrs. Wells, I'm Dr. Scott.
This is Dr. Marcel.
- It's Darlene.
My sister Krystal.
- How's Gavin?
Is he...
- We have a daycare
for the children.
- Yeah,
lots of toys and snacks.
- I can take them.
- Okay.
Go with the nice lady, kids.
We'll be by soon.
- You guys wanna follow us?
- Unfortunately, though Gavin's
pseudo-stable at the moment,
his chest tube
is still putting out blood.
- Oh, my God.
- If it doesn't stop, we're
gonna have to open up his chest
to see where
the bleeding's coming from.
- Darlene, I'm so sorry.
I should've let him come
along with you and the kids.
If I had--
- Krystal, stop.
If he has to have surgery,
will he be okay?
- Um...your husband
arrested in the field.
Paramedics don't know how long
his brain went without oxygen.
- We won't know
until Gavin wakes up
whether he suffered
any cognitive impairments.
- You mean like
he might not be able to talk?
Or feed himself?
- That is a possibility, yes.
- No...no, Gavin wouldn't
want to live like that.
We've talked about
this type of thing.
Well, not this, but...
you know, if something were
to happen to either of us...
- You're saying
if Gavin's heart
would've stopped beating again,
you don't believe
he'd wanna be resuscitated?
- Did he put that
in writing somewhere?
- No, he just told me so.
Said he wouldn't
want to be a burden.
- Understood.
With your husband unconscious,
you can make decisions
on his behalf.
- You know, we can note in
Gavin's chart that he's a DNR,
meaning no life-saving measures
will be performed
if his heart stopped again.
- I'm sorry to interrupt.
Mrs. Wells, your son is asking
for his blanket.
- I'll get it.
- No, I...could use some air.
Excuse me.
- Things have been rough
between Gavin and Darlene
for a while now.
I think she's in shock
or something.
- We see that a lot.
Give her some time.
- Gavin's a gambler--
bankrupted the family.
I've been writing Darlene
to divorce him.
Told him he wasn't welcome
at my house this weekend.
If I had known--
- What happened
is not your fault.
♪
- Hey.
- Lia's really anxious
to get out of here.
Those her scans?
- Yeah.
She's got a crack, and
one looks like a small blush
on her liver.
Radiology won't commit, though.
- Yeah, definitely murky.
I mean, it could be
an active leak
or just be a vessel.
- Let's watch and observe.
If her hemoglobin drops,
we send her to angio.
- I don't know.
With her so antsy to leave,
safest bet might be
to call up to angio now.
Once they're in,
they can see what's going on,
embolize if they need to.
- Fair point.
I'll put in the order.
- Dr. Halstead,
Dr. Shentu would like
to see you in his office.
- Dr. Halstead, come in.
Our legal department
just got a call.
Authorities are contacting
local hospitals
looking for a Petra Katsner,
German, 35 years old.
Apparently,
she's in the country illegally.
- We're not required to comply
with requests for information
when it comes
to undocumented patients.
- Yes,
I am aware of hospital policy.
We've got a couple patients
without ID in the hospital.
It looks like
you're treating one in the E.D.
She match that description?
- Nah, doesn't sound like it.
- All right then.
That's all I need from you.
- Why are we even
playing ball with them?
Hospital's supposed to be
a safe haven.
- This is
a special circumstance.
Ms. Katsner is suspected
of international kidnapping.
Apparently,
she abducted the child
she shares with her husband
then fled Germany.
- I see.
- Let me know if she turns up.
- Yeah.
♪
.
- Without surgery,
what's the baby's prognosis?
- Well, lots of women
with fibroids
go on to have
uncomplicated births.
- While that is true,
in your case, Tara,
the fibroid has grown
and is impinging
on your uterine cavity.
It's likely only a matter
of time before it impedes
the fetus' ability
to grow and develop.
- Uh, why don't you give us
some time to talk it over?
- No...no,
that's not necessary.
I wanna do the surgery.
What?
You had a myomectomy yourself,
Ma.
- Not while I was pregnant.
If you were to start bleeding
during the operation,
and they couldn't stop it,
they'd have to remove
your uterus--
- I understand that.
- Look, I know you're worried
about the baby, but you cannot
jeopardize your own health.
- Please don't tell me
what I can and can't do.
- Tara--
- I understand the risks,
and I wanna proceed
with the surgery.
- Tara--
- I'm sorry, Mom,
but either support my decision,
or just go.
- How's Gavin?
He awake yet?
- Not yet.
We're transfusing him,
but he's still bleeding.
- There's still a chance
things will turn around though.
Any leads on that rifle?
- Yeah, actually.
Gun's registered to Gavin.
He must've confronted
the offender, struggle ensued,
the intruder
got ahold of the weapon--
- I didn't see
any defensive wounds on Gavin.
- Nope, nothing.
- Maybe he didn't confront
the person.
Maybe it was a surprise attack.
They caught him off-guard.
- But with his own rifle?
- Would've had to have been
someone close to him.
- Right.
- You know, Gavin's wife
was stoic earlier.
Her sister did say they were
having marital troubles too.
- She told us that
in confidence.
- Appreciate the lead, fellas.
- Okay, we'll let you know
if and when he wakes up.
- Hey, Z, hold up.
Question for you:
flash money, right?
In an undercover investigation,
what does that roll look like?
- For a staged buy?
Probably like 10 Gs.
Small bills--
look like street money.
- Small bills,
not 40, 50K, right?
- 50K? Hell no.
Brass would not let you keep
that much bread on you.
You're a sitting duck.
- Lia,
you gotta give us something.
If you're in trouble,
if you're running from someone
or something, we need to know.
- We wanna help,
but if what the authorities
are saying is true--
if you abducted your child--
- It's true, okay?
I took him.
Myson.
♪
- Where is he?
- Karl is with good friends.
He's safe.
See, here.
Daphne, my friend,
just sent me this picture.
- All right.
- No, no, you don't understand!
I didn't have a choice.
Hans, my husband--
I have tried to leave him
so many times.
- Did he do that to you?
- Yeah.
The first time
I tried to leave,
and here, this--
the second time, Hans' ring.
- Has he been violent
with your son?
- When Karl was just a baby,
he grabbed him out of my arms
and held him over...
Over a 12-story balcony.
He said that he would drop him
unless I promised to stay.
♪
- Oh, God.
I'm so sorry, Lia.
- I mean, can you press
charges, divorce him?
- No, he will kill me!
Do you understand?
If I take him to court,
even if I win custody,
it doesn't matter!
He is a powerful man.
He's well-connected.
- Okay.
- What about filing for asylum
here in the U.S.?
- It is very difficult
to get asylum.
My chances are not good.
I...I never filed a report
back home.
I have no records,
and I was too frightened.
If I lose the petition,
I will be deported.
But if the authorities
are looking for me,
I must leave now.
I can't have an operation.
Please.
♪
- Check his numbers and then
run another blood panel.
- Hey.
- Yeah?
- I just spoke with Zora.
- Okay?
- Turns out
Gavin recently purchased
a life insurance policy,
like less than six months ago.
Darlene's the beneficiary.
Considering
the financial distress
he put the family under,
a payout like that
could go a long way.
- Yeah.
So the police think
Darlene's the shooter?
- The motive's there.
- Yeah.
- Some help in here.
He's in V-fib.
- The DNR, we can't honor it.
- Man, I don't know.
- If there's foul play?
Bro--
- What's happening?
Is he...
- No pulse, heart stopped.
- Oh, God, Darlene.
- Okay.
- Initiating CPR.
- What does that mean?
- We're resuscitating him.
- What? No!
- Nancy, charge to 200.
I said charge.
Let's go.
- The hospital's assuming
decision-making authority
over Gavin.
- Why? I'm his wife.
- Charged.
- Here we go, clear.
- Stop!
- Milligram of epi.
Charge. Let's go, come on.
- Continuing CPR.
- Charged.
- Here we go, clear.
- Okay, we got sinus rhythm.
All right, Nancy,
you go ahead and call the ward.
Tell 'em we're comin' up.
- Why did you do that?
Why?
- All right, let's go, guys.
Come on, let's go.
- It looks like
Lia's telling the truth.
Husband's a partner
at a major firm,
a lot of political capital,
and he's been in the media
more than once for assault.
He punched out a waiter,
got into it with a reporter,
and manages to beat the charges
every time.
What a prick.
I mean,
what are we supposed to do?
Lia wants to leave AMA.
- I think we have to let her,
Mags.
It's not safe for her
to stay here.
Cancel angio,
and I'll show her
how to care for her injuries
on the road.
She may not have an issue
after she leaves here.
We don't even know
if she's actually bleeding.
But if she stays--
- Listen,
I really wanna help Lia.
But what are we supposed to do?
Discharge her
without notifying Randall?
- Without a court order,
we are under no obligation
to give her up.
- All right.
I'll call upstairs.
Hey, Mags, I don't think
we should read Ethan in
on any of this.
You know
how he can be a stickler
for following the rules.
- Yeah.
I'm with you.
- Any news?
- Uh, yeah,
she just went into surgery.
I tried to talk her out of it,
Daniel.
But they said they'd send
an update within the hour.
I'll let you know
when I hear something.
- You'll let me know?
I ain't goin' nowhere.
♪
- Shelling out the fibroid.
Bovie, please.
- What? What is it?
- Look at that.
It's another fibroid.
- Ah...it's right behind
the first one,
and it's necrotic.
All right, people.
Change of plans.
Prepare to close.
- Wait, what?
No, we're not closing.
If anything,
the second fibroid
makes the removal
even more pressing.
There's even less space
than we thought for the fetus.
- This is no longer
the operation Tara agreed to.
The risks
have increased significantly--
the additional fibroid,
its location--
- Complicates the procedure,
yes, but I'm confident
that I can still
remove both fibroids safely.
- Well, I'm not.
So pack her
with warm moist laps,
and do not do anything else
until I get back.
- Where are you going?
I'll be right back.
.
- So you think the second
fibroid is parasitic?
- That's why it didn't
show up in the ultrasound.
It was hiding
behind the first one.
- What's your QBL so far?
- Ah, we've lost about
a liter of blood at this point.
Now, Ms. Goodwin,
you are Tara's surrogate,
all right?
It's your call.
I recommend we close.
- And I would strongly urge
against it.
I've seen worse cases
in my training, and if we don't
remove those fibroids,
I fear Tara will become septic.
- Which is why we continue her
on antibiotics.
- She's already
under and responding well
to the anesthesia.
We've made the incision.
Both Tara and her baby are
gonna be so much better off
if we just proceed.
- It's too risky.
Close her up.
- Very well.
- I'm sorry, but no.
I'm sorry.
I don't feel comfortable
just abandoning
my patient's wishes...
- Excuse me,
this is my daughter--
- When I see a clear path
forward.
I'm requesting
an emergency ethics committee.
♪
- Since your accomplice
is currently in surgery,
I'll leave it up to you
to explain what the hell
you both were thinking
overriding Gavin's DNR.
- The DNR has only been
in place for a couple of hours.
- It's still legally binding.
- All right.
I got some intel
about Gavin's attack,
but I can't share it with you.
It's a part of an on-going
police investigation.
- Well, you're going to be
forced to share it
when you're deposed
by his wife's lawyers.
She has every right to bring
suit against this hospital.
- Off the record,
all right, Darlene is currently
a person of interest
in this investigation, okay?
If she did this,
and it looks like she did,
legally and morally, I couldn't
just let her finish the job.
I wasn't just gonna
let a man die.
- Just better hope
he wakes up...
for his sake and yours.
- She's hypotensive.
- Order two units
of whole blood.
Lia, talk to me.
- Everything is spinning.
The room...
- Yeah,
your blood pressure dropped.
That's why
you're feeling dizzy.
- Maggie,
grab the transport team.
Alert angio.
We need to get her back
on the schedule immediately.
- Back on the schedule?
Who canceled it?
- No, no.
I have to leave.
- Lia, a dip in blood pressure
is a sign of internal bleeding.
If we don't embolize,
you could die.
- Okay.
- Come on, people.
Let's move.
- What's going on?
Somebody better start talking.
- The ethics committee
ruled in Dr. Asher's favor.
They're proceeding
with the surgery.
- Oh, well,
so what's your plan?
- I'm gonna urge them
to reconsider.
- You know
they're not gonna allow that.
- We'll see.
- Sharon.
- Daniel, please.
- Look.
You brought Dr. Asher back here
because you believe in her.
Right, her judgement,
her skill...
Now's the time for you
to trust that decision.
- Why didn't you read me
in from the start?
Were you just
never gonna tell me?
Discharge her
from under my nose?
- You weren't
exactly forthcoming.
You're treating her.
I know she's here,
and the last thing we need
is another FBI raid.
Did you know about this?
- No, he didn't, Dr. Shentu.
Neither did Maggie.
- Fine. You're benched.
Dr. Choi, you're running point.
As soon as Ms. Katsner
gets out of angio, let me know.
Hospital security
will keep guard over her.
- Will do.
- Hey, Ethan, man, listen.
- Hey, you process the scene?
Street cams give you anything?
- No, bad neighborhood.
Cameras were busted out
long ago.
- Damn.
What about her alibi then?
- Checks out, D.
- What?
- Cameras in a local diner
have Darlene and her sister
eating breakfast at the time
of the home invasion.
She couldn't have done it.
It wasn't her.
♪
- Extracting
the second fibroid.
- Watch out for the pedicle.
It's really vascular.
- I can see that.
- All right.
Got it.
Damn it.
Lap.
- You must've
perforated the artery.
- That's the only way
to get it out
without transecting the vessel.
- She's hypertensive.
Trigger the MTP.
- Laps and suction now.
.
- I still can't see where...
- There it is.
See it?
- Yep, clamp.
Okay...
- Okay, BP's goin' up.
- I'll take a Vicryl on a CT-1.
All right...
Here we go...
Scissors.
- All right.
- Okay.
Let's close
the deep layers first.
- All right.
I'll let Ms. Goodwin know
we're over the hump.
- Okay, so it was touch and go.
The surgery went well.
Gavin's stable,
should be awake in a few hours.
We'll know then whether
he suffered any deficits.
But look, there's something
else, could be nothing,
but when we were preparing
Gavin for recovery just now,
I noticed a nasty bruise
on his toe.
Must've been a hematoma
in the joint.
Blood finally
reached the surface.
- Wait...was it his big toe?
- Yeah, why?
- When you sign up
for a new insurance policy,
if you die by your own hand,
does your family
still get a payout?
- They don't.
Most plans have a clause.
If you die by suicide
within the first two years,
they won't pay out anything.
- We need to get an x-ray
on Gavin's foot, all right?
Zora--
- I'll grab a kit--
swab for gunshot residue.
♪
- Mm.
Ma.
- Hey, my sweet girl.
Hey, how you feelin'?
- Mm, sore.
- Yeah.
- Dr. Asher came by
while I was in recovery.
She said that
the baby's gonna be okay.
- Yes, I know.
But there's something
that I have to tell you.
While you were under,
there was a decision
that had to be made quickly.
- Dr. Asher
told me what happened.
- I just need you
to understand--
- I do.
I do understand.
Mom, when I found out
I was pregnant,
the mama bear instincts
just kicked in.
All I cared about was
protecting this baby, and...
Sometimes I forget
that I'm your baby too.
- Yeah.
You know...
when...
when you were in my belly,
you could not be still,
and when you
entered this world,
it was the same way:
always testing the limits.
- And your patience.
- I am so in awe
of your fearlessness, Tara.
- I know I don't make it easy.
- If you made it easy,
you wouldn't be a Goodwin.
- Is this lady harassing you?
I'm pretty sure you're supposed
to be getting your rest.
- Oh, look at that.
- I'm very glad
you're all right.
- Thank you.
- Wait for me.
I'll walk out with you.
Hey.
I love you.
- I love you.
♪
- Dislocated big toe,
and a metatarsal fracture.
- Yeah,
recoil of a gun could cause
that kind of damage for sure.
- Yep.
- Hey.
My guy swabbed Gavin,
found gunshot residue
on his foot and leg
from where
the cartridge released.
- Yup, he used his big toe
to pull the trigger.
It's the only way he could
shoot himself in the chest.
- Yep.
- Your patient
Gavin Wells is awake.
- Oh, okay.
Keep pushing against my hand.
- Go on.
There it is.
That's really good.
You can relax, Gavin.
It's really good.
- Yeah, it's good.
I think so.
- I'm sorry.
- What were you thinking?
- That you and the kids...
you were better off.
You'd have some money,
you could start over.
- Um,
we'll give you two some time.
Yeah.
Check back later.
- Okay, so it doesn't seem
he suffered any deficits.
You mind
putting that in for me, Kim?
- You think he's up for a chat?
I need to get a statement.
- Maybe give them
some time first.
- Crazy way to make amends.
- Yeah, sad situation
all the way around.
All right, guys.
Well, I gotta head back
into the E.D.
Officer Scott.
- Zora, nice to meet you.
- Hey, hey, man.
Uh, look, I know I put you
in a real tough spot today--
going out on a limb,
asking you to come with me.
- Hey, we gave Gavin
a second shot at life--
gave those kids their dad back,
right?
♪
Glad I followed your lead.
- Hey, any updates on Lia?
Come on.
Is she--
- We're fully committed
to transparency
with the police,
I can assure you, okay?
.
- I don't believe this.
What do you mean
you don't know where she is?
I told you not
to let her out of your sight.
Get out of here.
I'll deal with you later.
- What's going on?
- I'm sorry.
I don't know what happened.
She was in surgery and she
came back down for post-op,
and when I checked on her,
she was gone.
She must've left somehow.
♪
- I thought we were past this.
- What?
- When you question
my decision-making,
you're questioning
my competence as a doctor.
- Whoa, it's just
a difference of opinion.
- Okay, I get it.
I'm a recovering addict,
and I know that I need
to earn my reputation back
with everyone at this hospital.
But with you, it doesn't feel
like that's ever gonna happen.
Bottom line, whatever
crap you're putting on me,
figure it out, because
I will not be undermined again.
- Sorry to interrupt,
Dr. Asher.
Ms. Goodwin would like
to see you in her office.
♪
- I had my friend waiting
for her in the car outside.
He's an immigration attorney.
- Does he think that there's
any way that Lia can stay
in the country legally?
- I mean, he confirmed
there's a high bar for asylum.
But he offered
to review her case pro bono.
- Well, look, I think
it goes without saying,
we should've read you in
from the start.
- Yeah, you should've.
- Yeah, but, come on,
given your history
you understand why we didn't.
- What's goin' on?
- A lot has changed for me
in the past few months.
Maybe we can leave it
at that for now.
- Fair enough.
Just glad to have you back.
- Thanks.
Hey, Dean.
Uh, just wanna thank you
for staying on as chief
a bit longer.
I do think
I could use some time.
- Of course.
- Ms. Goodwin, I understand
why you'd be upset,
but my first responsibility
will always be to my patient.
Tara put her trust in me,
and I--
- And I would say you
more than honored that trust.
I owe you an apology,
Dr. Asher.
I know how much you care
about this job.
- It means everything to me.
- You stood up
to a parent today,
who also happens
to be your boss.
Very bold.
But you made sure
your patient's voice was heard.
Thank you.
- Thanks for meetin' me.
- Honestly,
I'm not even sure why I'm here.
- Milena, I know
you lied to me this morning.
- Did you really call me here
just so that
we can argue some more?
- Let me finish.
- Yes, I lied, okay?
You put my back
against the wall.
- I know that...
and I'm sorry.
Hey.
I shouldn't have pressed you,
but I didn't know if you were
in danger, or--
- Or if I was dirty?
- I'm an ex-cop.
Thought crossed my mind, yeah.
But I realize that, you know,
however things might look,
there's probably more
to the story.
- Right,
and I don't wanna
endanger myself.
I don't--
I don't wanna endanger you,
and I don't wanna
jeopardize this investigation
because you can't handle
being in the dark.
- I can handle it.
- Are you sure?
- I'm sure.
I care about you, Milena.
And I won't put you
in that position again.
♪
.