- You recognize him?
- Patrick Dunn.
He worked in Radiology.
- Until you let him go
a few weeks ago.
- You think he sent
the death threat?
- Patrick Dunn's being
transported to Med,
self-inflicted gunshot wound.
- Assertiveness and confidence,
two critical qualities
for a doctor.
- That was totally badass.
- That kid never had to have
surgery, but you pushed it.
He would still be here
if not for you.
- You don't know that.
- You made a bad call
and you goddamn well know it!
You're gonna answer for this.
You miss the target every time
until I step in front of it?
- The target's small.
Your fat ass is enormous.
- Oh, so we body-shaming now?
- Sir, keep your head down.
All right, what's our next move?
- Um, start an IV,
give antibiotics,
wash it out,
and then stitch it up.
- Missing something?
- Take out the ax!
- Take out the ax, right.
- Thankfully, our patient
has some excess soft tissue,
so the ax didn't hit
anything vital.
- See?
I'm not the only one
saying you need to lose weight, babe.
- Go ahead and get started.
I have a case review.
- Oh, whose case?
- Mine.
- Dr. Frost, I saw the time
that you took
with the kid in six.
It was really sweet.
- Oh, thanks.
I just didn't want him
to feel scared, you know?
Yeah, of course.
- Wow.
People at Jackson-Monroe
were never this nice.
- Were they complete suckers?
- What?
- You got pinned.
- I don't get it.
- Must be your first time
working on payday.
This is the pin.
- Okay.
- It's a game a traveling nurse
showed us a few months ago.
If you get pinned, you got
to put it on someone else
without getting caught.
Whoever has the pin on them
at the end of the shift
has to pay for the first round
at Molly's.
And you do not
want to get caught,
because Molly's is packed
on payday.
- Damn, Trini,
that's cold-blooded.
Nice.
- Only two rules,
no Archer, no Lenox.
Archer never shows up.
And Lenox, well,
you don't want to lose a hand.
- Game on.
Yes.
- Hey, goofballs, incoming.
Man and a woman
fell down a flight of stairs.
Let's go.
- Declan Russell, 54,
walking down the stairs
when he lost consciousness.
- Declan? Declan?
Is he okay?
- She tried to catch him
and they both fell.
GCS 13, heart rate 140,
BP 85 over 55, O2 saturation 95.
Feels hot.
- He just finished treatment
for prostate cancer,
if that matters.
Oh, and he's on nitroglycerin.
- Are you his wife?
- No, coworker.
- On my count.
One, two, three.
Okay.
Looks pale.
Let's check his temp.
- BP 80 over 50.
O2 is still 95.
- Okay, lungs are clear.
- Okay, give a liter of saline
and prepare levophed.
- Fever, 102.7.
- He's been a little off
the past few days.
Is he gonna die?
- Dr. Ripley's
taking care of him.
We're doing everything
that we can.
All right, but for right now,
we have to get this jacket off.
Okay? All right.
- Okay.
- Send the sepsis panel
and start antibiotics.
Vanc and cefepime.
- Arm does look busted.
You know, I'm sorry,
I have to do this.
I have to check, all right?
Now, tell me if this hurts.
Ow. Yes.
- Yeah, all right,
let's get her an X-ray, please.
- Yes.
- And if this guy had
prostate cancer,
make sure his urine gets sent.
- Yeah.
We need a doctor
in treatment five.
- Okay.
- Greg Wright took a blow
to the abdomen
from an I-beam
being lowered by a crane.
- Help me.
- We're gonna help you.
- Okay, vitals?
- Heart rate's 96.
BP 98 over 56.
Respirations 20.
- Lungs sound clear.
- Belly distended
with a fluid wave.
Looks jaundiced.
- He's got a bad liver.
- Oh, you need...
please, you need to...
- Give him 2 of versed
and 100 of fentanyl.
- Mr. Wright, I need you
to keep your mask on, okay?
Ultrasound.
We got free fluid.
- Oh, please.
- Okay, let's do a diagnostic
peritoneal aspiration
to make sure it's not blood.
DPL kit. Thank you.
Okay, Mr. Wright, I need you
to relax a little bit.
You're about to feel a pinch.
Here we go.
- It's ascites.
- Well, it's better
than the alternative.
- Oh, my son.
My son, please call my...
- No, no, Mr. Wright,
we need you to calm down.
- Mr. Wright,
that mask is there
to help you breathe easier.
We'll call your son, but first,
we need to make sure
you're okay.
- Hey, what happened to
that first set of fentanyl?
- I gave it to him.
- I want to talk to my son.
I need to talk to...
- BP 105 over 60.
O2's up to 96.
- Okay, let's work on
getting him to CT.
- Yeah.
- Really got hectic
all of a sudden.
- Yeah, tell me about it.
- Hey, Dr. Asher?
- Yeah?
- I found this
in Mr. Wright's wallet.
- Is it his son?
- I don't know.
No next of kin listed.
- Chicago area code.
- You want me to reach out?
- Uh, no, I'll take care of it.
- Okay.
- Duty calls.
- Okay, so Dr. Lenox,
we're here to review
your course of care
for Jordan Bennett,
16-year-old male,
fell off a rock ledge
at the disciplinary camp
and suffered
massive head trauma.
- Yes.
And after a CT head,
we discerned Jordan had
extensive skull fractures
and increased
intracranial pressure.
Thus, Dr. Abrams recommended
an upfront left side
hemicraniectomy.
- And just to be clear,
yours was not
the initial course of
treatment, am I right?
- There was some disagreement
on the ethics
of such an aggressive procedure.
So we started with
a more wait-and-see approach.
- Sorry. Sorry.
To be clear, uh, you wanted
to cut his head open.
I thought we should start
more conservatively,
which Dr. Abrams agreed with.
- Only because the patient
was a minor
and his parents weren't there
to weigh in.
- An important detail,
don't you think?
Especially when Dr. Abrams
described the two options
for treatment
as basically a coin flip.
- I believe he described it
as a 51/49 proposition.
- Nevertheless, it was not
an obvious decision.
- I believe it was. There's...
- Oh, God.
Doesn't that smack of hubris?
- If there's a preferred...
- And that...
isn't that your problem?
- Excuse me?
- The hubris you displayed
in taking a difficult decision
away from these two parents.
- If there is a 1% better
chance with a given course
of action,
resources should be marshaled
as if it were
the only course of action.
We didn't have time to wait,
in my opinion.
- Well, but that's why
we're here.
Your opinion was wrong.
We're here to question
your judgment.
- Dr. Archer, can we...
- No.
That in a case where
there was so much uncertainty,
when a child's life
was hanging in the balance.
- We traffic in uncertainty.
- There's a dead kid, Doctor.
- Dean!
That's enough.
- I agree with you.
It is enough.
- Hey, you okay?
- Yeah, why wouldn't I be?
- Well, word on the street is
things got a little heated
in the case review.
- It seems also
word got to Goodwin.
She wants to see me.
Who you on the phone with?
- Uh, nobody right now.
But I'm on hold
with a friend at CPD.
I'm trying to track down
this patient's son,
but all I've got is a number
that's disconnected.
- Okay.
- Hey, Dean, when you...
When you speak to Goodwin,
maybe don't...
be yourself so much?
- Thanks.
Yeah.
I think, actually,
it's... it's time
this came to a head, you know?
- You did it
without talking to me.
We didn't even discuss it, again.
- Oh, sorry to interrupt.
- Carl, I got to go.
Got to go.
- Were you looking for me?
- Yeah. Sorry.
Uh, yeah, there's a teen girl
on four who had a panic attack.
I thought you could take a look.
Mr. Ramirez, Jemma,
I'm Dr. Charles.
- Hi.
- Wow.
That is... that is some gown.
- Thanks.
- She looks beautiful, right?
- The debutante ball's
next week.
- Oh, that sounds fun.
- Yeah, um, family tradition.
My sisters, my mom.
- We lost Jemma's mom
a couple of years ago.
She's the one that really
got Jemma and her sisters
into the whole thing.
It's a nice way of keeping
her memories alive.
- Right.
Well, family traditions
can be really important
that way, right?
- Yeah.
- Um, Jemma,
tell me what happened.
- Well...
- Well, she was getting fitted
for her dress
when she started
hyperventilating.
- Right, and has this
ever happened before?
- No. First time.
- Tell me, like, how did
you feel it in your body?
- I don't know.
It was like this, um, wave.
Kind of like... it felt
really tight in my chest
like I couldn't breathe.
- We did an EKG,
just sinus tach.
- Do you mind me asking,
is there anything going on
in your life right now
that you're worried about,
you know,
that's giving you anxiety?
- No.
- And you're feeling better now?
- Yeah, mostly.
I mean, my stomach
just kind of hurts.
- All right,
let's get a CBC, CMP,
Lipase, UA, and a UPREG.
All right?
Look, panic attacks suck,
but there are a number of ways
to treat them, right?
And we'll get into that.
I just want to get
a clearer picture
of what's going on with Jemma's
stomach before we let you go.
Okay.
Nice to meet you both.
- Dr. Ripley,
this is Mr. Russell's wife.
- Sheryl.
I was told my husband fell?
- It's actually a bit more
complicated than that.
The fall, luckily,
wasn't that serious,
but the reason he fell was
because he's in septic shock.
That means he has an infection
in his body.
He's having
an extreme reaction to it.
It's putting added stress
on his organs,
especially his heart,
which was already weak.
- What's causing it?
- I understand he had surgery
recently for prostate cancer.
- Yes.
Oh, my God.
Declan.
Are you okay?
- A little banged up,
but I'm fine.
- Thank God you were there.
- Well, yeah, of course.
- But his surgery
was five weeks ago.
- Six, actually.
Sorry, I just remember it was
before the company retreat.
- Either way,
why is he getting sepsis now?
- Well, it's not uncommon
to pick up an infection
after this kind of surgery.
Though six weeks after
is kind of rare.
But I actually need to talk
to you about what comes next.
- All right.
- Now, the way to treat sepsis
is with a strong course
of antibiotics.
Thing is,
those can take time to work.
In the meantime,
your husband's heart
is close to giving out.
In fact, I believe it will fail
in the next few hours,
and if it does, he would
need to be resuscitated.
But his file says he has a DNR.
- Yes.
- Well, this is a unique case
where I'm not sure we want
to abide by that document.
Like I said,
once the antibiotics take hold,
the stress on his heart
will come down.
So if we can keep him alive
until then,
even if we need to
resuscitate him,
he would have a strong chance
at a full recovery.
- Is there a chance
he'll have lasting damage
if his heart fails
and you bring him back?
- There is always that risk, yes.
But if we're fast,
and I believe that we can be...
- I'm sorry.
No.
- Sheryl, I would...
- I said no.
My husband was very adamant
about his wishes
in a case like this.
I have to respect that.
- I was just finishing up.
- Howard, outside?
- Oh, I'm...
- What's wrong?
- She'll be right back.
- Did you use a simple suture?
- I did.
- That creates too much tension.
You should have used
a mattress suture.
- Oh, well, should I...
- Redo it, and go quickly
so he can be discharged.
This kind of thing shouldn't
take up a bed this long.
- Alex? Greg Wright's son?
Hi, I'm Dr. Asher.
Thanks so much for coming.
It was tough to track you down.
Your dad is, uh, this way.
Okay, so as I mentioned
on the phone,
he was in an accident at work.
Now, the impact alone may not
have done too much damage,
but the stress from the injury
is what led him
into liver failure
due to his cirrhosis.
- From drinking?
- That's usually the culprit.
Now, your timing
is actually good.
He's starting to wake up,
right over here.
You all right?
- I haven't seen him
in 20 years.
- Wow, I...
I had no idea.
- He walked out when I was 11.
I just assumed that
he was dead by now.
I only came because
I wasn't sure I believed it.
- Alex?
- Hey, Dad.
- Come in.
- Oh, free from Big Brother
at last, huh?
- I'm just glad
the stalker nonsense is over.
gentlemen, can you give us
the room, please?
I hear the, uh,
case review got lively.
- Well, it's more than
just about the case review.
- I figured that.
- All right, look,
I understand that there
were extenuating circumstances,
which necessitated
bringing Dr. Lenox in.
But that work's now
been mostly done.
And I think it might be time
to re-evaluate her position.
Re-evaluate, how?
- I don't think Dr. Lenox
is a good leader for this ED.
She's overbearing.
She's got a bit
of a God complex.
- Isn't that like the pot
calling the kettle?
Yeah, no, I know. I know.
I'm sure people
think of me that way, too.
But she's reckless.
And she doesn't listen
to anybody else's opinion.
And her patients
are paying the price.
I think Gaffney
would be better off
if Dr. Lenox
was merely an attending
and no longer
co-chief of this ED.
- They've been at it a while.
- Yeah, I think they're
making progress, though.
- Well, if it was my dad,
I wouldn't have even
come to the hospital.
- You don't believe
in forgiveness?
- Oh, I believe in it.
I just think there's
a statute of limitations.
- Tough crowd.
- You okay?
I feel like
I'm missing something.
- After I got sober,
it took my family a while
to trust me again, but they did.
Except my sister, Lizzy.
She wouldn't even talk to me,
so eventually I gave up trying.
- Hey, uh,
I didn't mean that
you don't deserve forgiveness.
My family is a totally
different situation.
- No, I know.
I just... I guess...
I guess I just miss her.
- Yeah.
- It kind of makes me
a sucker for reunions.
- Where's the patient
with the ax?
- Oh, he left.
I did the mattress sutures and
discharged him, like you said.
- But you didn't check with me.
- Well, you looked busy,
so I just checked it
with Dr. Johnson.
- I'm your attending.
You come to me.
You don't go behind my back.
- Oh, no, sorry, sorry.
I wasn't trying to...
- I don't want to hear excuses.
Look, I'm trying to help you.
But you need to listen
and stop apologizing.
If you show weakness,
people come for you.
So, uh, go grab an orange
and practice your sutures on it
the rest of the day.
- Our debutante's labs are back.
I just shot you the results.
And I-I should apologize
for earlier.
The phone call you so politely
pretended not to overhear...
- I didn't hear anything.
- Liar.
- I didn't.
- Okay.
Yeah, it...
Carl deactivated all of Penny's
social media accounts.
And I know,
it's a double-edged sword
'cause ostensibly, I'm against
all social media, but...
At the same time,
sometimes looking at her posts
is the only way I have any idea
what's going on with her life.
- When my girls
were about that age
and I'd come home from work,
all excited
to hear about their day,
they'd look at me like
I was like some kind of hobo
who wandered in off the street.
- Anything interesting?
- Yeah, lipase levels
are pretty elevated.
- Pancreatitis?
- Yeah.
I mean, bilirubin is normal,
so it's not gallstones.
What could be causing it, though?
- Well, Jemma's a teenager.
Maybe drinking?
- That would require
some prolonged alcohol abuse
at this age.
- Alcohol abuse?
Jemma's been drinking?
- That's not what we're saying.
Nope. Mr. Ramirez.
- Jemma, have you been drinking?
- Mr. Ramirez.
- What?
- Honey, you need to
tell us right now.
- I'm not drinking, Dad.
I swear, I never have.
- Mr. Ramirez,
that's not what we're saying.
What we're saying is we think
that Jemma might have
a case of pancreatitis.
- And one of the causes
can be alcohol consumption.
- Can be other causes, too.
For instance,
it can be a genetic thing.
- What is pancreatitis?
I mean, is that serious?
- It can be.
Yeah, I mean,
that's why you're in pain,
because your pancreas
is inflamed.
We just got to figure out why
so we can treat it properly.
So let us do
a little more digging
and we'll see what
we come up with.
- Hey, Dr. Charles.
Hey.
I just wanted to apologize.
- Trust me,
you do not need to explain.
- Look, you mentioned
that these things
can sometimes be genetic.
- Yeah.
- Well, um, Jemma's adopted.
- Really?
- Yeah.
It's not a secret or anything.
She knows.
In fact, she met her birth mom
once about a year ago.
I... I have her
contact information
if that would be helpful.
- You know what?
It actually could be.
Thank you.
- Yeah.
That meeting didn't
go very well.
Jemma doesn't really like
to talk about it.
- All right,
this is really good.
I think we can let you go.
I'm gonna go send in a nurse
to start your discharge
paperwork, all right?
Great.
- Dr. Frost?
- Yeah.
- There's something
I need to tell you.
- Okay.
- Hey, you tried this place?
It's so good.
- No, but I already ate.
Look, how are you with, like,
super awkward conversations?
- Uh, same as everyone else.
Not great.
- Okay.
- Why?
- Declan's coworker said
that we should not abide
by the DNR.
Says she knows it's not what
he would want, apparently.
- And how would she know that?
- Turns out that they
are not just coworkers.
- Oh, wow.
- Yeah.
- So they weren't headed
to a lunch meeting.
- Her place, actually.
- And, uh, she said Declan
wouldn't want the DNR?
- She actually made
a pretty compelling case.
- So you're pitching
we have another conversation
with his wife?
And to be clear,
you want to try to convince her
to rip up her husband's DNR
by telling her
he was cheating on her?
- Yeah?
This won't be awkward.
- So, uh, what are you thinking?
- Well, I'm thinking that
Dr. Archer was way out of line.
And I don't like to be
backed up into a corner,
but I also did spring this
whole co-heads of the ED on him
and that wasn't completely fair.
- Look, Jackson-Monroe
was closing, right?
You had to put out some fires.
And Lenox has a résumé
to help with that.
- So you think I should keep
her as co-head of the ED?
- Not saying that.
Okay, 'cause one thing
that is clear
is that this
power-sharing arrangement,
I mean, it's just not working, right?
You, um...
You talked to
any of these folks?
- Well, I've been quietly
taking the temperature
of the staff on Lenox.
But everyone's
being so political.
- Of course.
- You know, they don't want
to say the wrong thing.
- Right. Right.
- How's he doing?
- Okay, I guess.
- And how are you?
- Honestly, I don't know.
It's a lot.
- He said some nice things.
Says he regrets what he did.
How bad is his liver?
- It's not good.
It's basically shutting down.
- And he'll die.
How long?
- I don't like to predict
those sort of things, but...
I would imagine he has
less than a year.
- Can you do a transplant?
- Unfortunately,
in order to qualify,
he needs to be six months sober.
- And he hasn't been sober?
- He has, but only for
about three months.
So he's still got a ways to go.
So he comes back into my life
only to just leave again.
Hardly seems fair.
- You know,
you might be able to donate.
- My liver?
- It would just be a piece that
you would give to your father.
But because you're family,
our transplant team
would be able to waive
the sobriety requirements.
- Wait, is that...
Is that why he wanted you to
find me so that I could donate?
- No, no, no, no, no.
Your dad doesn't even know
that this is a possibility.
And if you decide not to,
I won't tell him.
Alex,
this is how we found you.
He's had it in his wallet
all these years.
- I keep thinking about
all the times
that he wasn't there
when I needed him,
when I was always the kid
who didn't have a parent
on the field trip,
when I had to switch
middle schools
'cause I was getting bullied,
when I learned how to drive.
Whole time, he was just
sitting there with my picture
when he could have just
been there.
- Look, I...
I don't know if you'll ever
fix your relationship.
But what I do know
is that if he's gone,
it can never be repaired.
- Uh, would you mind just
stepping in here?
- Okay.
What's going on?
- There's something we need to
discuss, but it's difficult.
- Keep in mind, we're all here
just trying to do
what's best for your husband, okay?
- Okay.
- Sheryl,
I don't think Declan would want
the DNR kept in place.
- I'm not sure his cubicle-mate
has a say in this.
- I'm not just his coworker.
We've been more than that
for almost two years.
I don't want to be saying this,
especially not now.
But we've had conversations
about the future.
- About what, leaving me?
- He talked about
what he used to believe.
But after fighting cancer
and beating it,
he realized that life
was worth fighting for.
Those are his words.
- Look, I know you hate me
and you have every right.
- Do you love him?
- I do.
- That's just awful.
- Sheryl, I can't imagine
what you're feeling,
having your whole life
with someone.
But I know about regret,
decisions made in a moment
that haunt you forever.
- Just please don't make
this choice out of anger.
- Do you even know why he was
so adamant about the DNR?
Because he watched
his mother have a stroke
and be resuscitated.
She had so much brain damage,
she was just
a shell of a person.
I was there for it.
I sat behind Declan
and he made me promise
that I wouldn't let him suffer
like that.
DNR stays.
- Don't even think about it.
- Ooh, who we cyberstalking?
- Jemma's birth mom.
- Any particular reason?
- Well, it is, in fact,
all your fault.
You know, I was looking through
her mom's medical records, right?
Nothing popped.
And so I started to think about
our conversation this morning
through which you got
a much fuller picture
of your daughter's life
on social media, right?
So here I am.
- Well, Jemma definitely
has her mother's face.
- These must all be relatives.
- Mm, they look like
a lively group.
What's your spidey sense saying?
- I'd like to talk
to Jemma alone.
You think you can run a little
interference with dad for me?
- Yeah.
- Ah, Ms. Howard.
Good to see you.
- Ms. Goodwin, I was
actually looking for you.
- Oh, how can I help you?
- I'm...
- Something on your mind?
- Yes, uh...
look, I know that you've been
asking around about Dr. Lenox.
- And you have something
to say about her?
- Yes, I do.
- Okay, what's your pain level?
- Not bad, just a little itchy.
Hey.
- Hey, Alex.
- It's okay. Come in.
I'm just getting poked
and prodded.
You okay?
- I was just outside
doing some thinking.
I was talking
to Dr. Asher earlier.
She told me that I could
give you a piece of my liver,
that it would save you.
So I was thinking that
I could do that.
- This is unbelievable.
I-I can't believe
you'd do this for me.
- Yeah, well, we're family.
- You know, I was always worried
that I messed you up
when I left.
But you're... you're
such a good person.
And you're giving me
a second chance.
And I do not take that
for granted.
I'm gonna be better.
You and I,
we're gonna be better.
- I'd like that.
- Okay.
So later today,
we'll get you upstairs
for some preliminary stuff.
And ideally,
we'll get you into surgery
within the next few days.
- I can start making up
for lost time.
- Dr. Lenox.
- Ms. Goodwin.
- After your shift,
come see me, please?
- Of course, no problem.
- Great.
- Jemma, how are you doing?
- Okay.
- You know,
your dad was telling me
that you're adopted.
- He did?
- Yeah.
So I've been looking into
your... your birth mom,
you know, medical records,
looking for clues,
and I ended up on...
on social media.
Saw a bunch of family pics.
And I couldn't help noticing
that they were all
of a certain...
a certain body type.
- They're all bigger.
- Look, I mean,
genetics can be a random thing.
But you, yourself, you seem
to be of a different body type.
- Just lucky, I guess.
- Okay.
'Cause it just
got me wondering, and I...
I hope you don't mind me
asking you this...
If maybe,
I don't know, you were getting
a little extra help
keeping the weight away?
Because I have
a strong hunch that
what we're dealing with here
could be a result of something
that you're taking.
- Taking what?
- Semaglutide.
It's the active ingredient
in some of these new, you know,
inject able weight loss drugs.
And in rare cases,
they cause pancreatitis.
If you keep taking this stuff,
you could do serious,
lasting damage to your body.
Right?
I mean, eventually,
I mean, it could even kill you.
- A girl at my school showed me
how to order it online.
- Okay.
How long ago was that?
- A year.
- Right.
Right around...
Right around the time
that you met your birth mom?
- Yeah, um...
I didn't think
much of it at first,
that they were heavier.
But then I started high school,
and I could feel myself
getting bigger, and I...
I just felt like I was, like,
genetically destined
for the same thing.
Um,
and I couldn't stop it,
so I found a way to stop it.
- I get it, I do,
but if it's hurting you,
if it's... if it has the
potential to seriously...
- I-I can't.
I can't stop taking it.
I can't become that.
I won't belong anymore.
- Belong where?
At school?
- In my family.
Everyone is perfect,
and thin, and tall.
And just... if you're not,
then you don't belong.
This month's shipment
got delayed,
so I haven't been taking it.
But when we went to go
try on the dress
and it was a little tight,
like, I just panicked.
And everyone would know.
Even my dad would know.
They would all know
that I'm not like Erin,
like Ali, like Mom.
Like...
- Your dad loves you
more than anything.
And he just wants you
to be happy and healthy.
Look, something that
I've learned in my life, okay?
The more you keep stuff
like this inside,
the more powerful it becomes.
I mean, you've got to find
a way to talk about it, right?
And I think that your dad,
it just might be a great place
to start, right?
And if you could
be honest with him,
get honest with each other,
it would just make you both
feel so much better.
And one thing
I can guarantee you...
Your mom would be
so proud of you.
Okay.
- What's happening?
- Move back, please.
Move back, move back, move back.
- Pulmonary edema.
He's got fluid in his lungs.
- Heart rate's 130.
BP's dropping.
- Give him Lasix,
push 40 milligrams.
- Yep. It's coming.
Okay, it's going in.
- What's that for?
- Trying to get some of
this fluid off his lungs,
get him breathing again.
- He's gonna need
to be intubated.
- He's in V-fib.
- His heart's failing.
I... I don't know.
- Oh, my God, Declan.
What's happening?
What are you doing?
Save him!
- We only have
a few seconds here.
- Please help him.
- Sheryl, he'll die
if we don't shock him.
- Bag him and charge
the paddles to 120.
Starting compressions.
- Clear.
- Still in V-fib.
- Charge to 200.
- Charged.
- Clear.
- We have a pulse, sinus rhythm.
- Oh, thank God.
- His fever has broken
and his blood pressure
is getting better,
which means
the infection is improving.
We are hopeful
he's through the worst of it.
- When will he be awake?
- Uh, it's hard to say.
We're doing everything we can,
but you can go in if you'd like.
- You go.
- What?
- We haven't been happy
for a very long time.
I've given that man
more than half my life,
and now I've given him
a new one.
I think maybe it's time
I try to be happy, too.
- That's it, time's up.
Shift's over.
Let's see who's got the pin.
Who could it be... oh, no.
Drat.
- Dr. Asher?
I just got a call from Imaging.
They're ready for Alex Wright.
- Great.
- A prelim workup
for his surgery?
That's one lucky dad.
- You want me to take him up?
- Oh, no, that's okay.
Your shift's over, too.
I got it.
- Thanks.
- Besides, no one's getting
a free round anyway.
- Wait, why no free round?
- Oh, come on!
The rules were clear...
no Archer, no Lenox.
People don't know how to...
- Wasn't me.
- He walked out.
- Well, maybe he ducked out
for a bite or something.
Did you call?
- He's not answering.
And...
He left this.
It was a lot to ask.
- I'm sorry, Greg.
I feel like I might have pushed
him, and I shouldn't have.
- No, don't apologize.
I deserve this. I do.
It was nice to hope
for a moment, though.
That you don't pay so dearly
for your mistakes.
- I'm good.
- Yes, yes?
One.
- Oh, I'm good.
- Shots for everybody.
- Why?
- Okay.
- One shot. One.
- Hey, hey! Come here.
- Ooh.
- Hey.
I didn't think you were coming.
- So I looked at the schedule.
Turns out, I'm in late tomorrow.
So I figured,
you know, just one.
- Oh, just one?
- Or three.
- Have you ever cheated?
- Um, actually, no.
I mean, I was legitimately
the worst boyfriend
in the universe,
but no, no, not cheated.
What about you, Hollywood?
- Yeah, once, when I was 16.
But she was, you know,
like a pop star
and wrote a song about it.
It was...
- Wait, are you...
are you serious?
- Yeah.
- Who was it?
- Oh, you are literally going
to your grave wondering.
Uh, bartender?
- Yeah.
- Let's... let's
get this man drunk.
- Not gonna work.
Steel trap.
Hey.
You all right?
- Yeah, I... I'm good.
I just... I need to make
a phone call.
- Can I ask a question?
What?
Never seen a guy buy a round
for the bar before?
- Whoo!
- You're welcome.
- Hey, Lizzy, it's me.
Um...
I know you really don't want
to talk to me, but...
I don't know,
life is short, I guess.
So I figured, uh...
I'd try in case
you change your mind.
Anyway, I'm here.
Love you.
- Come in.
- Ah, Dr. Lenox.
Please, come sit.
I wanted to talk with you.
- If this is about the
situation with Dr. Archer,
I've already reached out
to him to discuss it,
iron out any issues.
- Well, I appreciate that,
but I don't think that's
going to solve anything.
And I also don't think it's
going to be necessary anymore.
I spent the day today
talking to your staff
about the working environment
in the ED.
- I see.
- And most of them were
pretty tight-lipped,
but some were more candid.
In particular,
Ms. Howard had a lot to say.
- Really?
- Yeah.
She said that you were
challenging at times,
caustic, condescending.
- I don't mean to be.
- Well, she said that, too.
But she also said
that you consistently
push her to be a better doctor
and that she has gained
more practical knowledge
from you in a month
than she had in the past
four years of med school.
And that she hopes to be
as badass as you someday.
And yet, Dr. Archer
has made it clear that he
cannot coexist running
the department with you,
which is why, starting tomorrow,
you will be the sole chief
of the ED.
And Dr. Archer will go back
to being a regular attending.
- Have you told Dr. Archer yet?
- Yes.
He knows.
- Dr. Dean Archer.
- Dr. Hannah Asher.
- Well, well, well.
Gotta say, it is a bit of
a surprise to see you here.
- Yeah, well, you know,
life's full of surprises.
- Amen.
- Cheers to that.
- Um, we were talking about
the wallpaper...