Joy to the world
The Lord has come
Let Earth receive her king
Let every heart prepare him room
And heaven and nature sing
And heaven, and
heaven and nature sing
This sucks. This is why we need
to make a statement, you know?
I don't think that...
What? You afraid we'll
end up in detention?
Well, yeah. That's
what teachers do.
They're not going to
send all of us to detention.
Mr. Henderson is totally lame,
and this is our best chance
to inform him of that fact.
You don't think he's lame?
Well, yeah, but...
Then what's the problem?
Okay.
The Robert Page Academy
vocal jazz ensemble.
Chestnuts roasting
on an open fire
Jack Frost nipping at your nose
Yuletide carols
being sung by a choir
And folks dressed
up like Eskimos
Everybody knows
Mr. Henderson's a stupid...
I can't believe
she fell for that.
Why'd you do that...
I don't feel so good.
Sixteen-year-old female gets pranked, also
gets visual hallucinations and vomiting.
Turns out to be a failing liver.
Why have Foreman's breasts
suddenly started to droop?
Large breasts are a classic symptom of
you letting Foreman take vacation days
so he can finish his FDA
reports before the end of the year.
When are you taking vacation?
Hepatic and
neurological involvement...
So, I understand Foreman's
absence. Your presence, not so much.
I'm bringing in a case. You may
have noticed me doing that before.
I've noticed you
a lot of recently.
It's almost as if you have a
sexual interest in someone here.
Like, say, Taub?
Well, Taub might think I like him if I
stayed, which is why I'm going to do this.
Somehow, I don't think
that was really about me.
Wilson's Disease.
Ceruloplasmin's normal.
You got a Christmas present.
"Greg, made me think of you."
That's funny. It usually
explodes after I do that.
Alcohol abuse?
She's 16.
The kind of boozing that
destroys your liver that early,
her parents or
teachers would notice.
Wow."Manual of the Operations
of Surgery by Joseph Bell."
You're throwing that away?
Twice.
Someone's screwing
with me, forget it.
Yeah, gifting antique medical
texts. Oldest gag in the book.
Handwriting's kind of girly.
You got an admirer, House?
I said, forget the book.
Why'd they pick on her?
She's an overachiever, high grades,
she volunteers, she's a big target.
I'm assuming literally,
depending on where this
school falls on the Heathers scale.
You think the kids slipped her
something? Their teachers grilled them.
When did teachers ever know
how to motivate their students?
What did you do to Natalie?
It's all my fault. I didn't stop
her from being a total pig.
What are you... Your
friend's liver is failing.
We're doing what we can, but
she still might need a transplant.
She could die, unless you
tell us what you gave her.
Just tell him. Shut up.
We gave her some shrooms.
We took some ourselves, we just
wanted to make her loosen up a little.
How thoughtful of
you. You got any left?
They're in Simon's locker.
This was your idea?
No way. I didn't
give her anything.
Right, you just knew
about it and let them do it.
Poisonous mushrooms and
hallucinogenic ones are different.
Not if they're not
dried correctly.
Get back to school. You
better hope we got to her in time.
What?
Am I going to get in trouble?
Should we apologize or something?
Yes, you should.
Natalie's on the third floor.
Who's down there? Mr. Ravitz.
Where's the woman
I spoke to last week?
The trial patient with
the advanced symptoms.
She dropped out.
She okay?
Not health related.
She just wants to drop out.
Why?
She didn't say. And I
only break into the houses
of very special patients to
get to understand them better.
I do good today, boss?
No rigidity, no cogwheeling.
So absolutely, I'd call that good.
Great. Thanks.
Your clipboard.
Keep it.
This place actually
smells of evil.
Where do you work again?
Why would House throw out a
book worth hundreds of dollars?
To make you ask that question.
Can you really put a price
tag on screwing with people?
Can you get us into Natalie
Soellner's locker while we're here?
House always has an agenda.
Just screwing with us isn't...
Yeah, he'd never do that. Oh,
wait, he already did, last year.
Remember the Secret
Santa gift he got himself?
He was making us fight over
who could get him the best present.
This time, he's just
making us wonder.
No animosity, no ugly
competition. I think it's a real present.
If it's real, then House
really was freaked.
And if it affects him,
eventually it'll affect us.
Uh-oh.
Maybe it wasn't those
kids who poisoned Natalie.
Maybe it was Natalie herself.
I didn't try to kill myself.
Then why'd you have
all those painkillers?
In case I get a headache.
Well, maybe, you
took a few too many.
Do you have any kids? No.
But high school wasn't all that
different when I was your age.
Teenagers can be incredibly mean.
I know what you're going through.
I bet you were
cool. You're pretty.
You're pretty, too.
I'm fat. I'm a loser.
They all hate me.
You know what
they did last year?
They took these photos
of me for the yearbook.
But it wasn't. It was for this
website making fun of me,
calling me a pig.
Forget about them.
Let's just make you better.
What's the point?
Acetylcysteine could save
her liver, but we have to act fast.
If there's any chance that
she took all those pills...
There's no chance.
Okay.
She was the happiest,
sweetest little girl.
And a year ago,
she hits puberty,
and it's like this secretive little
stranger moved into her room.
I tried to talk to her about
what she's going through, but...
Give her the treatment.
Kimberley, you think
that she tried to...
I don't know what to think.
If it's a subpoena, he's gotten
that kind of present before.
It was a book.
That narrows it down.
Just look for someone
who knows how to read
or has been to a bookstore.
Most bookstores don't
carry Joseph Bell on surgery.
Did it have a note?
"Greg, made me think of you."
Green wrapping paper.
How did you know that?
What is it?
It's nothing.
Yes, when something's nothing,
the natural response is to guess
the color of the paper it's wrapped in
and then descend
into stunned silence.
Irene Adler. Christmas 2001.
Sarcoid symptoms, but she
didn't respond to methotrexate.
I've never seen him so obsessed.
He saved her with a
last-minute Wegener's diagnosis.
But the hours he put in,
I thought it would kill him.
And then, well, he fell for her.
But it was too soon
after Stacy and...
It sounds silly, but Irene
was the one who got away.
Really?
No, you idiots. House
is just screwing with you.
You think there's some
woman with a mysterious
green wrapping paper trademark?
Then how did you guess...
I could be wrong.
It's possible a secret admirer gave House
the same book I gave him last Christmas,
and the same
paper I wrapped it in,
and the note I wrote.
We gotta go.
Heartbeat?
One-fifty.
BP 180 over 110. Crackling
three-quarters of the way up.
At least this means she
didn't try to kill herself.
Scratch the hallucinations,
that's from the mushrooms.
Leaves liver failure and
now pulmonary edema.
And you standing
there beseechingly.
Yes, I was gonna
stalk you at home,
but it was a busy week
and your office is closer.
Thirteen and Foreman
were busy drug-trialing
and we needed an answer on
the overdose, so we called her in.
She's just updating us.
Convenient. Update's done.
This is a good experience for me
as my parents never got divorced.
Theories? Glue sniffing.
Effects on the lungs
would have been immediate.
House, we all know
what's going on here.
Cuddy gave you that present.
No.
Infections?
No fever, no polys
in the sputum.
I think...
I think she loves you.
I told you to lay
off the present.
And the LSD.
We got distracted by the painkillers,
toxins are still the most likely...
Just tell her how you feel.
If you won't, then I will.
I'll walk right down there.
Damn it, love like
this needs to fly free.
You talked to Wilson.
He has very girly
handwriting, by the way.
I knew I should have just
wrapped a new present.
You said the patient
volunteered. Where?
Pleasant Valley.
Soup kitchen in Trenton.
Thirteen and Kutner, go
search the home and the school.
Taub, you take the anal swabbing of the
fragrant and contagious homeless men.
Why don't you hang
out in the video store
and tell everyone Kevin
Spacey's Keyser Soze?
By the way, that ending
really made no sense at all.
You had my present for a
year and didn't even open it?
I had no way of knowing there
was an expensive book inside.
Completely meaningless
prank, even for you.
Stealing your ice cream is a completely
meaningless, albeit delicious, prank.
Observing my team's reactions
to unexplained phenomena
could have been pretty useful.
Of all the ways to mess with people,
why give yourself an imaginary present?
Have you checked the prices
for firemen strippers recently?
Yes.
The holidays. They're
hard for you, I get it.
You see the people around
you giving and receiving gifts,
having sustained, meaningful
relationships. And since you can't,
something deep in your subconscious
makes you create the appearance of a gift.
Sad.
You really passed
your psych rotation?
It's too bad you
can't just be nice to
people. You could get
a real present that way.
If I wanted gifts,
I would just look deep into my
patient's eyes and act like you.
"Oh, I'm so sorry
you're dying, Mrs. Moron.
"Of course I'll sleep with you. What
I lack in skill, I can make up for in..."
You'd just wind up insulting her.
Perhaps calling her Mrs. Moron.
Right. 'Cause I'm physically
incapable of being polite.
Being kind in a sustained,
meaningful way? No.
Oh, I get it. You're trying to
get me to prove you wrong,
then I'm gonna be nice to all my
patients all through the holiday season
and then Mr. Potter won't steal
Tiny Tim's porridge. I'm totally on it.
Yeah, that actually is
what I'm trying to do.
And the pathetic part
is, it's not going to work.
You're right.
I gotta stop being such a jerk.
Oops!
Kind of undercut myself there.
Janice?
I'm Remy. I'm...
Yeah, I remember you.
I heard you left the trial.
Yeah.
If there's some
way I could help...
It was that doctor. The one
that was running the test.
Dr. Foreman. Yeah.
He's a great neurologist.
He's a great guy.
You like him?
Why don't you?
I told him that those injections
were making me sick in my stomach,
and he just gave me antacid.
We were warned that
nausea's a side effect,
and giving you antacid
is all he really could do.
No. He told me, "Get over it."
With or without these drugs,
I don't have a long time.
I'm not gonna spend
it being his guinea pig.
House.
It's tuberculosis.
You got that from an anal
swab? Man, you're good.
There was a more subtle clue.
Homeless guy, uncontrollably
hacking up blood.
Cough's lasted two
months. He was cachectic.
Unless you could
tie him to the patient...
Yes, again, if only there
was some subtle clue,
like the fact that he was standing
next to her in the soup line for a week.
I hate spunk.
TB can cause liver
failure, lung symptoms.
Fits.
Start her on the
standard regimen.
You don't have
clinic duty today.
Who says it's a duty?
Hi. I'm Greg.
Hi. I'm Whitney.
Hi, Whitney, how can I help you?
I have a terrible headache.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
We'll get you fixed up. Is
there anything else you need?
Bottled water? Coffee? Mint tea?
No, but that's so nice.
Usually, the clinic
doctors are kind of rushed.
If you can't be nice,
why be a doctor?
So, where do you feel the pain?
In the back of my
head, here. Uh-huh.
It's Beccaria's sign. It'll be
gone by your third trimester.
Oh, I'm not in school.
Neither is your fetus.
Oh, God.
You didn't know
you were pregnant?
How do... You know that
just from the headache?
How do I know?
I missed my period, I
got fat and threw up.
Oh, no, wait, that's
how you know.
What?
I know because of the tight shirt
stretched over the swollen boobs,
the salt craving you
imported into the clinic,
the motion sickness patch
that doesn't do anything
for the kind of sickness
that you feel in the morning.
I'm a virgin. So is my fiancé.
I believe him.
Aren't there other ways
I could get pregnant?
Like sitting on a toilet seat?
Absolutely. There would need to be a guy
sitting between you and the toilet seat,
but, yes, absolutely.
And I was doing so well.
Natalie?
Oh, God. Natalie.
She's having a seizure.
Put her on her side. Nurse!
Is this from the TB?
Not with a supple neck.
I don't know what this is.
Four milligrams lorazepam.
Liver, lungs, and now brain,
which has mysteriously reappeared.
Speaking of
mysteriously reappeared...
Her ALT is 20 times normal,
transaminases and PTs, way up.
She's going to lose her liver. We
gotta get her on the transplant list.
You keep showing up.
You also keep leaving.
It's possible that you have the hots
for me, but really, really hate this kid.
It's also remotely possible
I have that reversed.
She's a nice kid, I want
to make sure she's okay.
Hepatic fibrosis.
Normal complement
level, normal-sized liver.
She remind you of you?
No, you weren't a
loser in high school.
You had every Tom, Dick and
Hershel wet dreaming about you.
But she could be making
you think of another helpless,
chubby little girl
that you recently met.
You're not really making this
about the baby I tried to adopt.
It's been a few weeks.
Just enough time to
get over hurt feelings.
Natalie's 16.
I think you're confusing being
maternal with being human.
If we hadn't ruled
out the mushrooms...
Maybe we shouldn't have.
Forget toxic, think allergic.
Severe mold allergy could cause
liver failure, respiratory arrest,
and encephalopathy.
She ate the shrooms days ago.
There's no way she'd still be sick.
Unless it also gave her a fungal infection.
Give her a prick test and antifungals.
Hey. Thank you for the
gift. I really appreciate it.
I spoke to Janice.
She okay?
Yeah.
Her nausea, she said you
told her, like, "Get over it"?
And?
Nausea isn't something you can
overcome with sheer willpower.
Which is why I didn't prescribe
willpower, I prescribed antacids.
She can't handle that, she'd
have to leave the trial anyway.
Just call her, say you're
sorry, she'll come back.
No.
God, you're acting
like House now.
No, I'm not acting like House,
which is exactly why I
don't need to apologize.
I'm not being cruel, I'm
not being manipulative.
You said the same thing to me when
I told you I was having a hard time.
And it worked.
She's a 40-year-old
woman who's falling apart,
physically and
emotionally. She's dying.
Look, I know seeing the Ghost
of your Christmas Future is tough,
but the only way I can help her is to
make sure she follows her regimen,
not by becoming her life coach.
You're not acting like
House. You are like him.
Dr. House?
This is my fiancé, Geoff.
She says you told her you can get
pregnant from sitting on a toilet seat.
I said those words, but
with a particular inflection.
I knew it wasn't true.
Is there any other
way? Isn't it possible?
There was a reported
case of a Civil War soldier.
He was shot in the testicles,
and the musket ball
carried the non-musket ball
into the uterus of a woman
working in a neighboring field.
Nine months later, a
miracle child was born.
Also, maybe she cheated on you.
We made a promise.
We do other stuff in bed.
Couldn't some of his sperm
have made it up there somehow?
More likely it came from the guy
whose penis made it up there somehow,
but sure, anything's possible.
I want a paternity test.
Tell him that amnios are dangerous
this early on in the pregnancy.
Are they? Who cares?
He doesn't know.
We'll do the paternity test.
No reaction.
That's bad?
If you had a mold allergy, it
would explain your symptoms.
We'll find out what's
wrong, don't worry.
And I know some things are hard to
talk about with your parents around,
but kids can be really mean. There
are people you can talk to, programs...
I'll be okay.
You're in good spirits.
You feeling better?
No. I was just
doing my homework.
I'm such a dork, I
guess that cheers me up.
Parents brought it?
No, Simon did.
The jockey kid in your class?
Yeah. He just left.
Security.
I was just bringing
her homework.
You helped bully
this little girl and
completely refused
to accept responsibility.
No way you came here out of
compassion. That only leaves guilt.
What did you do to her? Nothing.
Stop lying or I'll take the
drugs I found in your locker
down to the cops,
you slimy little jerk.
This kid didn't do
anything to you.
This isn't about me.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I get it, you were
bullied yourself when you were in school.
Take it easy. I wasn't bullied.
Right. The Indian foster kid whose
parents were shot in front of him.
You were clearly
Homecoming King.
Let's try this
again. Just tell me...
Honestly, you don't understand.
We used to be friends.
And I'd be friends with her now if
people wouldn't make fun of me.
There's nothing you
could tell us that'll help?
Did she mention she
used to drink a lot?
No. How do you know that?
Look, don't tell
anyone, all right?
I have my brother's ID
and I kind of supply people.
I used to get her a few
bottles of vodka each week.
Why'd you stop?
She got her own ID.
Said it was cheaper
buying it herself.
You can go.
I think we got our diagnosis.
Our little girl's a drunk.
I don't drink. I did
back then, but...
You could die.
We can't get you on the transplant list
until we know why your liver is failing.
Alcohol abuse
would explain that.
The seizures could
be from withdrawal.
I haven't drunk in six months.
I didn't even drink
that much back then.
A couple of vodka
bottles a week?
I didn't open half of them.
I just bought them because
Simon was selling them.
We used to be friends,
and that's, like, the only way
I could get him
to even talk to me.
Then why did you stop buying from
him? He said you got your own ID.
I don't know.
See, that's not a good answer.
Remember when you
asked me if I had any kids?
I don't. I don't know, maybe
it has nothing to do with it,
but I was good at school,
good at work, lousy at life.
I screwed up every
relationship I ever had.
I thought, why would I
want to bring a child into this?
But then I got older and...
How you feel now will pass.
Don't let it screw up your whole life.
It's already screwed up.
My asthma. They said they'd fix it,
but it didn't make any difference at all.
Well, sometimes doctors
make mistakes, Anna,
and then we have to try
twice as hard to fix them.
You using your inhaler?
All the time. Go
through one a week.
You sure you're using it right?
Do I look like an idiot?
No.
Why don't you show me
how your inhaler works?
Jerk.
What was that all about?
Jamaican chicken recipes.
The parents said
no to the benzos.
But I still think Natalie's
not being honest with me.
So she's willing to die to
cover up some boozing?
She's very depressed.
She feels like she deserves what
the other kids are dishing out on her.
I think she either wants to die
or she wants the attention
that dying gives her.
I have no idea why you care so
much. Tell Kutner to start her on benzos.
House, the parents just...
Uh-uh. Not the alcoholism,
the seizures, totally different.
Don't need their approval for that.
You sure you want to know?
If it makes it any easier,
I'm going to tell you anyway.
We want to know.
What does it say?
Don't leave.
You go home last night?
I meant to, but started reading
this file, just couldn't put it down.
Let me ask you.
That patient who dropped
out, the one I told you about?
Yeah.
Do you think I should
pursue it more?
No. Patients drop out, that's
why we start with hundreds.
I just thought,
if there's an easy way to make the people
who drop off come back, then why not?
They're not people. Really?
I thought the zombie trials were
all completed during Phase Two.
You can't see the patients as people.
You can't even see them as patients.
They're numbers.
Look.
A friend of mine
has this disease.
I don't want to know. There's
a reason this is double-blind.
Any personal stake we
have skews the study.
Science is not about human
relationships, it's about results.
But you know that.
You work for House.
Why do you think I brought
you on as my partner?
Dr. Taub!
She was talking to me and
then she just passed out.
Her heart's slowing down.
Can you fix it?
Can you fix it? I'm trying.
Push one amp atropine.
We've been waiting here for
six hours. Am I the father or not?
No, but she also
didn't cheat on you.
Normally, sperm meets egg,
DNA meets DNA, goes
back to her place, cells divide.
Nine months later,
joy is bundled.
That's normally.
Abnormally, an egg could have two
naturally occurring gene mutations
that don't naturally
occur together.
Spontaneous calcium spike could prep
the egg for fertilization without sperm.
And a division mistake
could let the egg split up
without ever needing
male DNA at all.
Parthenogenesis. A
baby without a daddy.
In humans, it's only ever been
theorized, and it was never proved.
Until now.
Mommy, baby. Your daughter
has only maternal DNA.
I personally checked this five
times. In seven months, you will have
a virgin birth.
Merry Christmas.
I've got to tell you
about this clinic patient.
Natalie's liver's continuing
to fail. And now bradycardia.
Atropine isn't keeping
the heart rate up,
we're going to have to
put her on a pacemaker.
Alcohol withdrawal would
cause her heart to race, not crawl.
There's nothing structurally
wrong with her heart.
EKG, echo, electrolyte
panel are all normal.
Multiple endocrine syndrome?
Free T4's normal.
Hypothalamic brain tumor?
Didn't come up on the CT scan.
It's hitting all her organs. Could
be the blood. What's her Alk-Phos?
Three hundred.
It can't be leukemia.
High Alk-Phos could
also be from liver failure.
She's a teenager, means bone
growth and destruction could throw it off.
Maybe. But it's higher
than you'd expect.
Start her on chemo.
We'll do a bone marrow
biopsy to confirm.
Why are you ordering
tests instead of treatment?
Her heart and liver are about to
give up. Do whatever you need to.
Why are you so
attached to this girl?
It's your call.
He doesn't want us to treat her.
If it's leukemia, even if
we kill every cancer cell,
her heart and liver
are too far gone.
A double transplant.
With brain involvement? The
committee won't even open the file.
There's no reason
to put a dying girl
through a painful
treatment if it can't save her.
He's being kind.
I'll arrange a biopsy.
Mrs. Burke?
We're conducting another
trial in tandem with yours.
Same drug, lower dose.
The nausea would be less.
I did some checking,
I can switch you.
Here's the forms
if you want back in.
What if we're wrong?
Maybe we shouldn't have
overlooked autoimmunes.
High sed rate.
We went over this.
Normal complement level.
So it isn't hepatic fibrosis, it could
still be microangiopathic vasculitis.
With high dose steroids,
we might be able to reverse...
You run a hospital that treats
thousands of patients every day.
Some of them die. Every day.
If you're gonna get this worked
up over every one of them...
Yes.
BRB.
What is it?
Thank you from a patient.
For you?
I saved her marriage
by showing that her pregnancy
was a result of parthenogenesis.
Human parthenogenesis?
You proved...
Yep.
It's unbelievable. But I
personally checked it five times.
How did you check it five times?
The cycler's broken. You
would have had to send it out.
It would have taken... Oh, yeah.
That does sound impossible
now that I think of it.
I guess the better explanation is that
the paternity test showed she cheated,
so I faked the whole
parthenogenesis thingy.
What? Why?
I win.
You faked a scientific miracle
just to win a bet with Wilson?
More an argument.
I realize it would have been
simpler to just fake the paternity test,
but, hey, Christmas
spirit and all that.
I think you're confusing
"nice" and "evil" again.
Letting the woman
deceive her husband by
inventing a virgin
birth, just so you can...
And it obviously would
have been more fitting
if the baby had been born on
Christmas, not just invented then.
It's not leukemia.
Seizures, liver failure.
It's eclampsia.
Which means we don't
have one dead patient,
we have two.
You have a disease
called eclampsia.
It causes liver failure,
pulmonary edema and seizures.
It's also associated
with cardio myopathy.
That's a pregnancy disease.
You tested her when she came in.
You can get eclampsia up
to a month after giving birth.
That's ridiculous. How
could she hide a pregnancy?
Loose clothes. She's heavy to
begin with, it was probably premature.
If it was three weeks ago, they could
have missed it on a physical exam.
The baby's why you
quit drinking, isn't it?
Why you asked me if I had kids.
Why you feel guilty.
I'm sorry.
Oh...
Who did this to you?
Simon.
It wasn't bad.
We were, like,
boyfriend-girlfriend for a while,
we just didn't tell anyone.
He doesn't even know about...
What happened to the baby?
I was going to give her away.
If they found out at school...
I was at the soup kitchen,
and she started coming.
There was this empty
house down the street, but...
And she wasn't breathing.
I tried so hard, but I couldn't
do anything. I'm so sorry.
If I had her in a hospital,
maybe she'd be alive.
Can you cure this?
The damage to the heart
and liver are permanent.
I'm gonna die?
I'm sorry.
I didn't even bury her.
I just put my coat over her.
Get out of my house.
I'm a doctor.
I don't care who you are.
Did you find the body of a baby?
I said get out.
Michael?
Who are you?
That's not your baby.
You're tiny. There's no way
you gave birth three weeks ago.
She's my sister's.
That baby is sick. She needs
clean water. She needs real heat.
She was probably born
with a partially blocked airway
and might even
have brain damage.
You can't take care of
her in a place like this.
Shut up.
I took care of her.
I know.
You found her.
You saved her life.
Now you have to let her go.
Who's that?
It's your daughter.
She was alive.
People found her
and took care of her.
She's beautiful.
It's okay.
Kutner.
No transplant?
We appealed. Too sick.
How much time
does she have left?
A couple days at most.
What about the baby?
Seems healthy, but
it's too early to tell.
She's in the hospital for observation
for a few days. But after that...
Best case, winds up
with her teenage father,
who just got voted captain
of the varsity bullying team.
He's just a kid.
You all right? I gotta go.
Jonathan? Yeah?
It's Lawrence Kutner.
Why are you here?
I wanted to apologize for all the
horrible stuff I did to you in high school.
I'm sorry.
What's going to happen to her?
I spoke to both
sets of grandparents.
It's too painful. They're
putting her up for adoption.
What are you going to do?
I already spoke to a lawyer.
I become a foster
parent and then I adopt.
Merry Christmas, Cuddy.
Hey.
Where is everybody?
Down at the party.
I heard Janice is
back on the trial.
My Christmas gift to you.
I was wrong. You're not House.
Yeah. Well, that's my
Christmas gift to myself.
We should go to the party.
We should.