Pass me some tape.
Not that much.
Dad, you gotta finish up, okay?
I'm on at 3.
You got that bulb?
You're lucky I found it.
They don't make these anymore.
Bet we haven't looked at
these slides in 25 years.
Your mother made me
drag that camera everywhere.
I made an appointment for you
on Monday with the oncologist.
I told you I didn't want that.
Would you at least talk to him?
You got that bulb?
Don't get your
fingerprints on it.
In San Diego they said
the cancer was incurable.
Doesn't mean we can't treat it.
Plug that in, will you?
It's our trip to the
Grand Canyon.
You must have
bought the wrong bulb.
You left this in
the hall closet.
Oh, I always pack
the garment bag last.
Be a dear and, um,
empty me the top drawer.
I can't stay long.
I've got an incarcerated
hernia in the O.R.
What shall I do with this?
Would you mind
returning it to David?
Do you suppose he
wore only one sock home?
He's a sweet man.
Much like his son.
Does that mean you approve?
Oh, I more than approve.
I've seen how you glow
whenever he's around.
You two belong together.
Since when have you been
an expert on relationships?
I've enjoyed being single.
I've no regrets.
But what about you, Elizabeth?
What will make you happy?
Do you really
want to discuss this
as you're about to leave?
Uh, look, your plane
doesn't leave till 10.
Why don't you
drop by the hospital?
We'll grab a coffee.
Yes. Absolutely.
I'd love that.
Mother?
Would you return those, as well?
Welcome back, Carter.
Thank you, Haleh.
Hey. How you feelin'?
Ready to go. Yeah?
Hey, you know, I saw your MRI.
Looks like you're
recovering just fine.
Yeah, I should be able
to get rid of these things
in about a week or two.
Carter, take your time.
Don't push it, man. All right?
John, how are you doing?
Oh. Just let me know
if you need anything.
I'm okay. Okay?
Hey.
Have you seen Abby?
Not lately.
Labs are back on
two of her patients.
We gotta move 'em.
You're late. Deal with this.
Where's Kovac and Weaver?
They are on tonight,
so you're the man.
All right.
Oh. Have you
checked my x-ray yet?
Uh, just a minute.
Abby, can you take this lady?
Sorry, I've got four already.
Randi, can you find out
who this woman's doctor is?
Mark, we got a lot of
angry patients waiting.
Yeah, it's Saturday.
Everyone shows up
when the clinics are closed.
You tell them that.
Dr. Greene?
Phone. It's your dad.
Hey. Phone book?
Yeah, why don't you
try the desk drawer?
No, Dad, I can't
hold. No, Dad...
Has anyone seen the Xeroform?
Uh, it's right here
under the Tegaderm.
Oh. Uh-huh.
So, uh, what time
do you get off?
Ten.
Saturday night. Whatcha doing?
Washing my hair.
Have fun.
Not the bedroom desk,
the living room desk.
Got a new one. Frank
Bacon, ICU charge nurse.
Passed out in the unit.
I feel fine. Can I
go back to work?
Not until we clear
you. Curtain 3.
I'll be right there, Mr. Bacon.
Call me Frank.
Mark! Three patients
left without being seen.
Listen, Dad, I gotta go.
Call 411, they can
help you find the place.
Problem? You go to do something.
All right. Uh, Randi, why don't
you hand me the cordless phone?
Haleh, bring over
the rolling cart.
Uh, Chen, Abby,
Malucci, over here.
We're gonna do power rounds.
Carter, you care to join?
Paramedics are
bringing an O.D. in.
Hey, you ready for that? Yeah.
All right. It's yours.
How are you doin'?
It won't stop.
Okay. Well, Dr. Dave will be
back in a minute to fix you up.
Randi, it's Dr. Greene.
I need a nasal speculum
and a Merocel sponge in 3-A.
Thanks.
3-B?
Kim Tadlock, ascites. Okay.
CBC, chem panel,
and a three-way of the abdomen.
Should I check for a fluid wave?
Uh, let's get the labs
cooking first. 3-C?
I've already got him.
Cute guy with syncope.
He's off peeing for me.
All right. Let's go.
Where's she going?
Oh, Romano wants thin cuts
Okay, you guys ever
see a tongue-blade test?
No.
Ma'am, I'm gonna want
you to bite down on this
as hard as you can, okay?
And Chen, you're
gonna give it a twang.
You're gonna let us
know if it hurts, okay?
Uh-uh.
All right, no fracture.
You can cancel the CT.
That's it?
Well, why do an $800 test
when a simple
stick will do the trick?
One. Two. Three.
Adam Pulido, 38, altered
from a probable overdose.
I... just wanna die.
What did he take?
I found a bunch of
empty Benadryl packs.
Adam, did you
take anything else?
Leave me alone.
All right, let's start
with a CBC, EKG, lights,
blood and urine tox screen.
Carter, scoot over.
I need to put on the dynamap.
Just do it on the other side.
The IV's on the other side.
Carol?
Your nanny's on line three.
Can you ask her to
hold, please. Yeah.
She's new. It's okay,
go ahead. Take it.
110/78. He's stable.
Hello?
Did you try the bouncy seat?
Try running the vacuum.
That stops her from
crying sometimes.
Get away! Hey, come on!
We're trying to help you.
I gotta go. Let go of me!
Whoa, whoa.
Settle down. Carter, you okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Just get him some
soft restraints. Okay.
Got a lot of fluid in there.
So the colon cancer spread?
Yeah.
They said that could happen
if I didn't respond
to the chemo.
Well, we should tap your belly.
It's pretty tender.
Yeah.
Well, could I interest
you in some morphine?
Really?
Last time they wouldn't
give me anything
till my labs came back
and I saw the surgeon.
Well, nobody should
sit around in pain.
I see you've been paying
attention on rounds, huh? Nice.
I'll be right back
with the morphine.
What are you doing?
Oh, the April nursing schedule.
You need to be on the
monitor. No. No, really. I'm fine.
Yeah, well. You know the drill.
Let's hook you up.
So your blood
pressure is, uh, 90 o...
90 over, um, 60.
Yeah, that's normal for me.
You know, all those
years of triathlon
and stuff like that, you know?
Oh. Well, we still
need to monitor you.
Oh, listen, I know
why I fainted, okay?
I ran 12 miles before
I came to work, right?
I skipped breakfast and lunch.
Wanna get something
at the cafeteria?
Oh, no. I never
touch that stuff.
Oh.
Um... Wha...?
What is that, uh,
on your... chain?
Oh. It's an ancient Roman coin.
I found it while I was
diving in the Mediterranean.
Oh, really? Yeah.
Hey, uh, let me
help you with that.
Thank you.
You, uh, need some
help over there, Dr. Chen?
No.
Everything is under control.
Ah. Good.
No, Dad. Shaumburg
is 45 minutes away.
I don't care if
they have the part.
We're gonna talk
about this later, all right?
Having a difference of opinion?
Oh, he is driving me crazy.
Yeah, my mother's
being unpredictable.
Suddenly when she's leaving,
she wants to be a parent.
Yeah, well, he won't listen.
He won't even discuss
treatment options.
For what?
His emphysema.
Is he worse?
I think so.
What do you got?
History of angina.
Fifteen minutes of chest pain.
Complete relief
with one nitro spray.
Randi, we need a monitored bed.
We're full.
Maybe you should
close to criticals.
No, no, no. We can handle this.
Okay, let's move
the, uh, TIA to 5.
CHF to 3.
And we're gonna put him in 2.
I'll see you next trauma. Okay.
Randi, I'm gonna get a refill.
Oh, I'm sorry. You
want some privacy?
No, no. I'm done pumping.
We staffed okay for tonight?
Down a nurse, but
I'm working on it.
What did I do
with that other lid?
This it?
Thanks.
Some days they take the bottle,
and other days they
just want their mom.
That's why they're so cranky.
Carol? Carter needs
you back in trauma.
Can you cover? I'm sorry.
GSW to the head coming in.
Okay.
I'll get the gunshot.
How much Ativan's on board?
Four. Push another two.
Sats are down to 81. I
need an intubation tray.
How long has he been seizing?
Three minutes. It's
worse than we thought.
Carol, would you bag
him? He's not breathing.
BP's only 60 systolic.
All right, start a dopamine.
10 mics per kilo.
You all right? Yeah.
Just pump up the bed.
He's bradying down.
I'm getting Mark.
No, no. I can do this.
Stop, that's high enough.
Conni, why don't you
go page the renal fellow?
This guy's gonna need dialysis.
All right. I'm in.
Any idea who who shot him?
No. Probably a
drug deal gone bad.
Abby, I want you to glove up
'cause you gotta
put in a central line.
On my count. One. Two. Three.
Order a head CT
and lateral C-spine.
Don't bother.
There's gray matter everywhere.
Okay, blown pupil on the right.
Let's start mannitol
and hyperventilate.
We have an organ donor here.
BP's 80 palp.
Okay, let's get his pressure up.
Is this a good angle?
Aim it towards
the sternal notch.
I hit the clavicle.
March it down slowly until
you slip under the bone.
Okay, lower the angle,
or you'll give him
a pneumothorax.
I'm still up against the bone.
Pull out and reposition.
Mark, we need that line in now.
Give her a chance.
This guy's brain-dead.
I'm not getting a flash.
Okay, we're not
perfusing his organs.
I'm sorry, Abby,
I'll have to do it.
Got a driver's license.
His name's Robert
Jackson from Naperville.
He's 18.
Okay, do whatever you
can to track down his parents.
We need their consent
to make him a donor.
Okay, I've got it.
Let's get two liters
on the rapid infuser.
Look at this. His
QRS is widening.
He needs dialysis.
There's no
indication for dialysis
in Benadryl
overdose. Look it up.
I read a case in the annals,
and they saved the patient
using hemoperfusion.
I know the pharmacokinetics.
Extra-corporeal
elimination won't work.
Well, we should give
it a try. Oh, no, no.
I'm not putting this
man at risk for hemolysis
and charcoal embolism
for an unproven procedure
you read about in an
emergency journal. Excuse me.
This is not a renal case.
Like hell it isn't.
Want me to push more bicarb?
It won't help.
Run of seven.
Well, damn it, I'm not gonna
stand here and watch him arrest.
I'll write the dialysis orders.
A nephrologist has to do that.
The article says
exactly what to do.
Kerry once did
hemoperfusion on an O.D.
Well, we should do
it. I know this will work.
Okay. Write out the orders.
I know a dialysis nurse.
She won't question it.
Set me up for a femoral line.
You wanna run this?
If you back me up.
Pulseless, V-tach.
What do you wanna do?
Uh, defibrillate at 200.
Sounds good to me.
Charged and ready. Okay, Clear.
Whoa!
Oh, sh... Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Get some water!
All right, turn off the oxygen.
He's still in V-tach.
Start compressions.
Oh, it smells!
Two prep razors.
I got this side.
Abby, get the paddles.
Hey, Rambo. Why
aren't you up in the ICU?
He's my patient.
I thought your name was Frank.
It's my nickname
from Desert Storm.
Okay, clear!
Normal sinus.
I've never seen
that happen before.
Me either.
Sometimes you
just gotta wing it.
Whew.
We're following that case study
for massive overdose.
Examine 2 is set up for
charcoal hemoperfusion.
Good. Keep me posted.
What's up?
Dropped his pressure.
He needs more volume.
Lily, another two units.
If it's brain stem failure,
you don't have much time.
I know, that's why we need
to get him to the O.R.
Did you find his family?
I'm sorry, it's a phony license.
Kids buy 'em on the street.
Well, maybe he's
been reported missing.
We sent out his photo. So
far, nothing's come back.
Keep on trying. We
need that consent.
Pressure's up to 90.
That's encouraging.
Even with consent,
it could take hours
to line up the
procurement teams.
Elizabeth, be realistic.
I could save five
lives with his organs.
Or he could arrest first.
I won't let that happen.
Let Kate sleep for another hour,
and then wake
her for her bottle.
Carol?
I'll talk to you later.
Carol, I need 3-0 nylon.
Dori, I think we are ready.
Aah! Oh.
You okay?
I think I just
contaminated my gloves.
Sorry, I shouldn't
have made you reach.
Just give me another pair.
Uh, did Dr. Krupp say
why he's using citrate?
No.
That's weird. He
always uses heparin.
You know what? I
better go page him.
Oh, did he say when
to check an A.C.T.?
Uh... Do it 30
minutes into the run.
Well, I better check with him.
He's very particular
about his orders.
Dori, these aren't his orders.
Yeah, Krupp wouldn't help
us. We took them from a journal.
I won't do this
without his orders.
Look at the heart monitor.
His complexes are narrowing.
I'm gonna lose my job.
We're saving his life.
No. We're stopping.
I'll take full responsibility.
Hey, Carter, you wanna explain?
I told you about this.
Well, did he tell you that
nephrology refused to sign on?
Mark, it's working.
Just let us finish.
Carter, step out.
Carol, monitor his vitals.
Keep the dialysis going.
Sorry, Dori.
I'll speak with
the renal service.
Okay.
You have a problem with another
department, you come to me.
My patient's improving.
Fine, but you didn't
give me the whole story.
Let me break rules.
That's what I'm here for.
I can handle this.
It's your first day back.
You don't have
to prove anything.
Mark, we need you.
I wanna know everything
you're doing to this guy.
Six months old with
fever and vomiting.
Now lethargic after a
seizure. Couldn't get a line.
Uh-huh. Where's Cleo?
It's her day off. Okay.
Has she had seizures before?
No, she's a very good baby.
When did the vomiting start?
After she woke up from her nap.
What's her name?
Estrella. Is she okay?
Uh, she looks dehydrated.
Chuny, set me up
with an interosseus line.
Bolus, 20 per kilo of saline.
She's tachy at 160.
Okay. CBC, lytes,
blood and urine cultures.
Full septic workup.
¿Qué pasa?
What are you doing?
We need to put
this into the bone
to give her fluids.
Please don't hurt her.
Chuny, take her to Chairs.
Bring her back
after the spinal tap.
No. I want to
stay with the baby.
Can I stay with my
baby? Come on, honey.
Doctor, please. Can I
just stay with my baby?
It's okay.
Still in normal sinus,
doc. So how much longer?
Until your electrolytes
come back.
What about my patients?
Well, I told told the unit
you're taking a sick day.
They called in backup.
Well, then I guess
I'm your prisoner.
Excuse me.
Have you seen Dr. Greene?
He's supposed to help
me with this paracentesis.
Uh, he's in Trauma. I can do it.
Kim, this is Dr. Chen. Hey, doc.
Hello.
I've numbed the lower
left quadrant. Good.
Uh, 14-gauge angiocath okay?
Yeah, use a Z-track
so it won't leak.
And, um, what labs
should I send off?
Cell count, glucose,
protein, amale, psychology,
Gram's stain and culture.
Thank you, Frank.
No problem. There's the fluid.
Good flow. You got it from here?
Yeah. Thank you.
Okay, I'll be in Exam 4. Okay.
Well, that wasn't so bad.
Oh, actually, it's
starting to hurt.
I can readjust the
catheter for you.
Hey!
Uh-oh.
If I were you,
I'd order an upright
chest film, stat.
Lost the pulse.
She's in V-tach.
Start compressions.
Charge the paddles to 20.
Bag her. What's going on?
Probably septic.
Could be meningitis.
Clear.
What do you want, Carter?
I can come back.
Charge again. What's up?
My overdose guy's
QRS is down to .12.
Weened him off pressors.
Clear.
Go on.
He's waking up.
Can I extubate him?
Charging. Give him
another half an hour.
Clear.
Thanks.
Hey. What are you doin'?
Checking labs.
We don't allow
patients back here.
He's a nurse. I
gave him permission.
Frank, why are
you off the monitor?
Some of my labs came back.
Dr. Chan, your patient
has a low sodium.
That must have been
the four liters of water
that I drank after my workout.
Just need to fluid-restrict.
Let's go back to bed.
Your cardiac enzymes
are still pending.
Oh, I think she wants
to keep me here. Hm.
That guy's a piece of work, huh?
And you're not?
What's that supposed to mean?
You're eating Cap'n Crunch
off an emesis basin? Please.
Randi, did my nanny call again?
No, thank God.
Ew. What is that?
I'm hungry.
Nothing in the lounge
except a box of cereal
and a jar of milk.
A jar of milk? Yeah.
Oh, God, Malucci!
What?
I'm in. Resume compressions.
She's in V-fib. Peddles.
She should come
around with 0-2 and epi.
Mark, our guy's crashing.
Clear.
No change. V-fib.
What's happened?
He's hypotensive.
I'm starting Levophed.
Chuny, start with procainamide,
100 slow IV push. Shock again.
Clear.
His brain stem's
mush. You gonna call it?
No. There must be a
way to make him a donor.
Not without his consent.
When was the last epi?
Four minutes.
Push another cc.
Can't we get a court order?
No, no, not in a case like this.
Well, I'll keep his pressure up
until we find his family. Fine.
Shock again.
Clear.
The black stripe is air
under the diaphragm.
The needle perforated the colon.
Yeah, well, it hurts like hell.
I'm really sorry.
Perforation is a
known complication
of the procedure.
What do we do now?
Well, we could operate
to repair the defect.
How long will I have
to be in the hospital?
A week.
But then you're looking
at a two-month recovery.
Doc, they don't expect
me to live that long.
What happens if I don't
have the operation?
The hole could
seal off, but, um...
More than likely
you would develop
an infection, peritonitis.
And then I'd die.
Yeah.
Let's get a second
round of atropine.
Pacer pads are ready.
Holding compressions.
Still flatline.
Labs are back. CBC
and lytes are normal.
What the hell is
wrong with this baby?
All right, start pacing at 180.
Pacer's on.
No capture. Turn up the gain.
Come on.
Still no capture.
Turn up the rate.
Can't feel a pulse. More epi?
How many rounds so far?
Seven.
Stop bagging.
That's it.
We're done.
Clean up the baby...
before I bring in the mother.
I don't want the surgery.
It's the only way...
Yeah, I understand,
but I don't want
another surgery.
Well, then, you know, we...
We could, um, treat
you with antibiotics
and hope for the best.
I'm sorry. Would you excuse me?
I'll be right back.
Yeah.
Dr. Benton?
Aren't we supposed
to fix our mistakes?
Usually.
Your patient has
end-stage cancer.
Surgery's only gonna
prolong his suffering.
You have to respect his wishes.
Well, he's going to die
because I made a mistake.
He's gonna die anyway.
Mark, we need you over here.
What is it?
Doctor, please help me. My baby.
Want me to give her
something? Uh, no.
My baby. Pilar.
She's still warm. Do something.
Pilar, we tried
everything, okay?
I explained that.
No, she's still warm. My baby.
Please.
Use your machines.
Give her the medicine.
Blow in her mouth. Do
something. Make her breathe.
We can't.
Yes, you can!
You're a good
doctor. I know you can.
You can save her. Please.
She's still warm,
my little baby.
Por favor.
Pilar, she's dead.
No, she's... I'm sorry.
Malik, what's up?
Cops found
Mr. Bartlett under the El.
How you doing, Mr. Bartlett?
Kiss my ass.
Okay, start a banana
bag, order a head CT,
and prep him for sutures.
Whoa! Whoa!
What do you got?
Rule out CVA and I've got
two new patients to present.
What about Frank's workup?
My enzymes are normal. I'm fine.
Yeah, he saw us getting slammed,
so he pitched in.
Uh, Dr. Greene.
There was a complication
with my colon-cancer patient.
Yeah, Benton said.
Thought I was
supposed to supervise.
Well, you were busy,
so I asked Dr. Chen.
Yeah, well, you didn't give
Dr. Chen a complete history.
Otherwise you would've
tapped the midline,
and you wouldn't
of perfed the bowel.
Well, he spiked a
fever. I think he's septic.
You should make sure
that he's comfortable now.
I'd like to stay with
him. There's no family.
Oh, no, no. We need
you out here, okay?
Nurses can take
care of him. Right.
Oh, and Abby.
After your shift, I want
you to go to Pathology
and practice procedures
with Dr. Upton.
Dr. Greene, got a live one here!
What happened?
My buddy's in Peru. I'm
feeding his Gila monster,
when the son of
a bitch bites me.
He won't let go. We
have to kill the lizard?
Only as a last resort.
Hey, Malik.
Why don't you grab a
couple of vascular clamps?
Get 'em yourself. I'm
not going near that thing.
I got it.
All right. Thanks.
Please, don't hurt him.
I'll do my best.
Oh, ooh. Ow.
Those jaws are awfully strong.
Ow. Oof.
Malucci, get ready to catch him.
In what?
Grab a kick bucket.
All right. Here we go.
Nice and easy.
Do it together.
Almost. Almost. There!
Now what do I do?
Call Animal Control or the zoo.
Need some help?
Yeah, why don't you
monitor his vitals?
Three grams of Unasyn...
and irrigate the wound.
How is he doing?
He's on maximum dopamine
and Levophed with runs of PVCs.
His heart's not gonna
last much longer.
V-tach. Lily,
charge the paddles.
Don't, he's a DNR.
Mark, let me code him.
No, it's a waste of time.
I'm pushing lidocaine.
We're swamped. You're tying
up my nurses and a trauma room
on a case that'll never
make it to the O.R.
It's time to stop.
No, not when his
organs are still viable.
I'm sure his family
would want some good
to come out of this tragedy.
Normal sinus. Want
a lidocaine drip?
I'll start one. You go
help the other nurses.
Don't keep flogging him.
I mean it. He's a DNR.
Mark? Labs are
back from Trauma 2.
Tox screen's positive
for amphetamines.
Let me see.
Oh, man.
What?
It's the baby.
Someone killed their
baby with amphetamines?
Pilar.
The labs came back on Estrella,
and she tested positive
for amphetamines.
My baby died from drugs?
Do you know anybody
who could have given
something to her?
No one has drugs at home.
Do you know anyone
who uses drugs?
Friends or relatives?
Pilar, what is it?
I work two jobs.
Sometimes I get so tired, I...
I take something to stay awake.
But I never bring drugs at home.
Are you nursing the baby?
Pilar, do you nurse your baby?
The drugs are
in the breast milk.
I love my baby.
I would never hurt her.
God forgive me, I
would never hurt her.
I didn't know.
Really, I didn't know.
Mother, are you there?
I'm involved in a case.
I can't make it for
coffee, so page me. Bye.
Dr. Corday, I completely
forgot to give you a message.
What message?
That your mother's
taking an earlier flight,
and she won't be
able to meet you.
That's all?
Hey, Mark, are you all right?
Oh, yeah.
Y-you keeping an eye
on that gunshot kid?
Yes, I had to cancel a
dinner date with my mother,
but she stood me up first. Hmm.
Well, that's parents for you.
Mm-hm.
Okay, get me lytes on Burch,
digs on Davis and
coags on Nguyen.
You got it. How we doing?
Don't worry, doc. I'm
moving the meat, man.
Hey, listen, I need
to free up this bed.
I've been waiting for
an hour for CT results.
I'm holding for Radiology now.
Yeah, well, page Steve Flint.
You know what?
Don't waste your time.
I have a direct line.
Chuny, my colon cancer
patient needs more morphine.
He was asleep
last time I checked.
Well, then check more often.
I don't want him in any pain.
Dad, what happened?
He was short of
breath, called 911.
Yeah, well, why
didn't you call me?
There's nothing you
could've done over the phone.
When did it start?
Couple of days ago.
Pulse ox 82 on room air.
Decreased breath
sounds on the left.
Uh, I'm fine, Mark. It's
probably just a chest cold.
Okay, let's move him over.
Nice and easy.
I'm not that... On my count.
I'm not that sick!
I can do it myself.
Do you want a blood gas?
Yes, CBC, coags
and a portable chest.
If I knew it was gonna
be such a big deal,
I would've seen the
doctor on Monday.
Dad, can you be quiet
and take a deep breath?
Yeah, I think you
have fluid in your lungs.
What do you mean, you think?
Lean forward.
Yep. Fluid's halfway up.
Why did you wait so long?
You could've passed out,
gotten a terrible infection...
Don't scold me.
Okay, we need
to drain the fluid.
Mark, what's wrong?
Huge pleural effusion.
Needs a thoracentesis.
He wants to stick a
needle in my chest.
You're a surgeon. I
think you should do it.
I don't think that's
such a good idea.
Dad, I can handle this.
Mark doesn't think a doctor
should treat his own family.
It's a simple procedure.
I've done it a hundred times.
I want Elizabeth
to be my doctor.
Fine.
The lizard guy's crashing.
Why didn't somebody get me?
He just went south.
Dropped his pressure to 60.
Yeah, it's Gila venom. Two
liters of saline, wide open.
I heard this guy was
coding. What do you need?
Point three of epi,
50 of Benadryl.
All right. Here you go.
Who's smoking?
I don't smell anything.
It's out there.
That's my hernia patient.
Yeah, well, tell him
to smoke outside.
Mark, bad cocaine overdose.
Pressure's sky-high.
BP's 260/140.
Okay, I've been waiting
here for five hours.
You wanna get that
cigarette out of here?
All right, start with
Osmolal and phentolamine
before she strokes out.
Dr. Greene, there's
a psych patient
on the third floor
getting ready to jump.
Why don't you clear a
trauma room? I'm on it.
Dr. Greene, my
stroke patient's son
wants to talk to the Attending.
Mark, you want a
Foley on this guy?
Why are you asking
me? Just do it.
I can't get a second IV.
What's the problem?
She's got good veins.
How about my stroke patient?
Look, can't you
see that I've got
two critical patients here?
Why don't you just deal with it?
The guy just jumped!
They said it was a
stage-four lung cancer.
Doctors said it couldn't
be cut out or cured.
Sometimes chemotherapy
can shrink the tumor
and lengthen survival.
I know all about that.
Are you interested?
Mark sure seems to be.
What about you?
What do you want?
I just wanna live out
the last couple of months
of my life as normal as I can.
I don't wanna be hooked
up to a bunch of tubes,
puking my guts out,
all for the sake of a few
extra miserable weeks.
Well, when we get the fluid off,
you'll feel a lot better.
Now, I'm gonna numb you up.
This will sting a bit.
Ready when you are.
Hey, stick around, Pete.
Fresh trauma coming in.
Uh-uh, page
Corday. I was off at 7.
Hey, you getting
around okay, Carter?
Yeah. Are you
late for something?
Yeah. I'll see you later.
Abby, sorry to hear
about your patient.
What patient?
Your belly tap in Curtain 3?
He expired.
Well, why didn't
anybody tell me?
My patient dies,
I'm the last one
to find out about it.
Pulse is weak.
Yosh, start two large-bore IVs.
Decreased breath
sounds on the right.
We're gonna need
to put in a chest tube.
Hey, you want some help?
Uh, no, thanks. What's
Frank doing here?
Uh, it's a long story. Carter?
Everything okay? Yep.
How'd it happen?
Psych patient jumped
from the third floor.
Feels like a few broken ribs.
Get X-ray here.
Frank?
Hey, get the crash cart!
Airway's clear. He's breathing.
What happened?
Probably vasovagalled.
Good pulse. We're okay.
I'll get a BP.
I need to intubate.
Push 15 of
etomidate, 100 of sux.
Prep for a chest tube.
I can do that.
I've got it, Carter.
We gotta move fast.
Uh, how can I help?
Here, run the HemoCue.
Dr. Weaver, you
need a hand up there?
No, but work on that HemoCue.
Carol, it's the nanny. I
hear the babies crying.
Take over for me, Yosh.
Okay, 8-0 ET tube.
Hey. No, I'm in the
middle of a trauma.
I can't do that right now.
10 blade and a
Kelly. Check the cuff.
No, I know, but I can't.
What's the pulse ox? It's 92.
HemoCue is 12.4.
Hey, Carol, we're okay. Okay.
Hi, Okay, just put
Kate's ear to the phone.
32 French.
♪ I can't give you
Anything but love, baby ♪
You call that a lullaby?
♪ That's the only
thing I've plenty of ♪
Carter, give me
cricoid pressure.
♪ Baby ♪
- Okay, I'm in. Let's bag him.
- ♪ Dream a while ♪
O silk... Needle driver.
♪ Happiness And I guess... ♪
Good breath sounds.
Open the Xeroform.
Hey, call
Respiratory for a vent.
You had quite a day, huh?
Randi, I'm gonna be
suturing in Exam 4.
I can pick up a few of
your patients if you want.
Mm, just take the new ones.
Oh, sorry, Carol. Pedes is full.
Oh, these are my girls.
They've gotten so big. Yeah.
Is your nanny sick?
No, no. She's new.
And they were fussy, so
I just had her bring 'em in.
Yeah, they certainly
look content.
They're always happy
after I've nursed them.
They miss their mom.
We'll be in the lounge.
Aw.
Hey, Randi?
Curtain 2 is going up.
Sorry to cause you
so much trouble.
Oh, it was nothing. Feel better.
What's wrong with Super Nurse?
Frank is being admitted.
Oh, yeah. What,
to the Psych ward?
To Medicine.
I diagnosed his
Addison's disease.
He'll be fine in a few days.
Good pickup.
I'm gonna go up to
the fifth floor later,
keep him company.
Time of death, 21:37.
I'll get the death kit.
Such a waste.
His organs could've
saved so many lives.
I couldn't do a thing.
Well, you had no choice.
Why couldn't they
find his family?
Probably a runaway.
He's someone's son.
His parents don't
even know he's here.
They may never know.
Dr. Corday, could you
sign a discharge order?
On which patient?
Dr. Greene's father.
I'll be right out.
Mark, why didn't you tell
me your father has cancer?
He didn't want anybody to know.
You told him to follow
up with Oncology?
He doesn't want to.
What about Navelbine?
There's no side effects.
It'll shrink the tumor,
and he won't get his chest
tapped every week. I've
given him those options.
But... it can improve
the quality of his life.
Talk to him.
He'll listen to you.
It's his decision.
But maybe if you explain
it, he'll change his mind.
Mark, I have to
respect his wishes.
He's my father, okay?
I wanna help him.
If you really want to help,
just be there for him.
I won't just sit there when
there's something more I can do.
The patient donated his body
to the med school
for educational use.
For anatomy class?
Yes, but we often allow students
to practice procedures here
on the fresh cadaver.
Dr. Greene mentioned
that you needed work
on your central lines.
Place your index finger
in the sternal notch.
Enter the skin at the junction
of the middle and
proximal third of the clavicle.
I'm sorry.
I don't think I can't do this.
You're doing fine.
Uh, he was my patient.
You wanna stop?
No.
Why don't you, um,
take me through it?
Aim just above and posterior
to your index finger.
Crazy day, huh?
Yep.
John, are you
still in a lot of pain?
It's not too bad.
Yeah.
It seemed like you're
having a hard time
getting around in Trauma.
I'm... I'm okay.
Well, the first day
back can be rough.
Yeah, every day
gets a little bit easier.
Have you talked to anybody
about what happened?
And your family's
been supportive?
Yeah, really, Dr. Weaver.
I'm okay.
You know, you might
benefit from a TENS unit
or from acupuncture.
Thanks. I'll let you know.
Okay.
I need a PT/PTT on De Salvo.
Yeah.
Head home?
I can take a cab if you have
something else planned.
Don't be ridiculous,
Dad. We're going home.
Good night.
Shoelaces are untied.
I can't bend down
after that needle thing.
I don't want you to fall
and break your neck.
All right, from this angle.
The one. Just cut it in there.
Just hit a little
bit to the left.
And let it...
slide down.
That's too much
thinking. I go by instinct.
Do it your way.
All right, uh, how about
the six in the corner...
Yeah, right. Here we go.
What happened to
the laws of physics?
You distracted me.
Yeah. Excuse me.
Aah. You left me nothing.
What are you talkin' about?
Go for the eleven.
Are you crazy?
I can't make that.
Of course you can. Come here.
Let me show you something.
All right, just call it.
Eleven in the corner pocket.
Just line it up.
Now, hit it to the right.
It'll slide right down the rail.
Nice and easy.
Trust me. Nice and easy.
Trust you. Mm-hm.
All right.
See?
How's that?
It's not bad.
Mm. What?
Hm?
If I'd known you were coming,
we'd have served a late dinner.
Soup's fine.
You're looking well, John.
Thank you.
I started back to work today.
Shouldn't you give
yourself a bit more time off?
I did okay.
Actually, it was kind of tough.
I didn't know if I was gonna
make it through the day.
I, uh, felt, I don't
know... Afraid.
Afraid of what?
That I couldn't handle it.
But you did.
I know we've had
our disagreements
about your career.
But I can see now that
medicine is what you love.
I remember when you
were in high school,
you'd drop by unexpectedly.
I'd make cocoa, and we'd talk.
I remember.
We haven't done
this in a long time.
I know.
Where is that? Mammoth? No.
Lake Tahoe.
I lost $200 at the craps table.
Next slide.
This is a fancy machine.
If I'd known you could
get one at the hospital,
I wouldn't have
fixed the old one.
San Diego?
That was the Santa Barbara trip.
You were 7.
Taught you to swim underwater.
Ah, your mother
never did like motels,
so we rented an RV.
Planting the garden.
You used to make
me pull the weeds.
I did not.
You remember you
always wanted to grow a...
A watermelon tree?
You saved all those
seeds and then snuck out
and planted them in
your mother's petunias.
Never did get a watermelon.
No, but you sure
killed off the petunias.
I forgot all about that.
I thought this was
the vacation box.
Why did your mother
take this one, anyway?
♪ Time it was And
what a time it was ♪
♪ It was ♪
Guess she liked what she saw.
♪ A time of innocence ♪
♪ A time of confidences ♪