Trauma is messy.
Chaotic.
Looking at a body that's
been reduced to a bloody pulp,
it might seem difficult
to know where to start.
Edwards, got a
vomiter in bed five.
Rule out obstruction, please?
Yay!
How we doing? Good,
she's in all right shape,
but she's complaining
about abdominal pains. Okay.
Kepner, what do you have?
MVC, bed three. Shepherd's
doing a neuro consult,
but she just started
complaining of stomach pain.
Dr. Pierce!
Busy morning.
Yeah, when it rains.
Can you go see chest
pains in bed six, please?
Got it.
Luckily, some very clever
person developed a protocol,
the ABCs. Airway,
breathing, circulation.
20-something female carjacking
victim. Multiple lacs and contusions,
open tibia fracture,
hypotensive and tachycardic.
This was a carjacking?
And a hell of a beating.
Wilson, you're with me.
The ABCs keep your patient alive
so you can figure out how
to tackle the rest of the mess.
If only all life's
problems could be
solved with an intubation tube.
They took my car!
Shh, shh, shh. They took my...
What's your name?
Melissa. My car...
Melissa, I'm sure
your car's fine.
We're gonna take
care of you, okay?
Wilson, go see if anyone
came in with her, okay?
Okay.
I think you're fine, but
I want to make sure.
Let's do a head CT. To be safe.
Right away.
Let's get an
abdominal CT, as well.
Mmm-hmm.
Dr. Grey, I have your... Our...
Ellis' journals.
You went through them already?
Yeah, I've had them for a while.
I got a good sense
of her as a surgeon,
if not as a person.
So, thank you.
Sure.
Okay.
She still calls you "Dr. Grey"?
That's my name.
We should invite
her over. For dinner.
Why?
She's family. Ish.
Dinner tomorrow night.
It's what people do.
What people?
Dr. Hunt in trauma one
needs an ortho consult.
On it.
April.
Hey, I thought you
were on the... In the...
Yeah, your mom's flight got
in early, so I brought her here.
Why would you do that?
'Cause she wanted to see you.
I set her up in the
attendings' lounge.
Just give me a page
when you get a second.
Uh, I... Love you!
Sorry, what was I saying?
This is where
you've been staying?
I figured you'd
gone to a hotel, or...
Yeah, well, Herman's been
breathing down my neck day and night.
This is easier.
Plus, where I sleep is no
longer any of your concern.
I didn't kick you out. I
never said that you had to go.
No, no, you just
made it very clear
that my being around
you was suffocating.
Okay, well, have
you told anyone?
No. Have you? No.
I... Do you think
that we should?
Can we just not yet?
Whatever you want.
I didn't want any of this.
I have rounds.
I'm saying you
skipped breakfast.
Didn't have time!
Avery made me point person on
the board's strategic planning meeting.
And I have consults.
Got to keep the
trains running on time.
Ah, ah, ah...
Oh, mmm.
You're my favorite resident.
Hey. You were looking for me?
Yes. Mr. Weaver here is...
Oh, Jeremy. Hi.
Yeah, he's complaining
of chest pains.
EKG is fine except
for a little LVH,
but his first troponin
is within normal limits,
so I've ruled out a dissection,
but his belly is
still a little tender.
I'm fine, really.
Well, let's see.
Take it easy, Mr. Weaver.
Okay, see you later.
Okay.
Ow!
Hurts there? Yeah, but
it's heartburn, I swear.
My wife made me come. I
should be at work, you know?
And I got to pick
up my kid later.
Jeremy, have you eaten today?
Coffee.
Oh, you skipped breakfast, too?
Oh, no, no, no,
and then, pancakes,
sausage, eggs, a
couple of energy drinks.
I would've had
more, but I've been
having trouble
swallowing lately.
Sounds like you did pretty well.
Well, you got to fuel up.
I got a lot of balls in the air!
Sorry.
Look, we're gonna
admit you for observation.
No, no, no.
And I'll try to make
it quick, okay? Okay.
Um, add on LFTs, a second
troponin, and an abdominal CT.
Call me when
you get the results.
Ah, ah, ah...
Finish your donut.
Melissa works with us.
We do computer
repair at Office Hub.
I found her on
the way into work.
She was just lying there
on the ground, not moving.
I thought she was dead!
Do you know anything about
her family, anyone we can contact?
We don't really
know her that well.
OWEN: Wilson!
Uh, why don't you guys
take a seat? I'll be right back.
She's crashing.
You paged ortho? Oh, whoa!
Yeah, you're gonna have to wait.
Belly's expanding even though
I cross-clamped the aorta.
Should we book an OR?
Yeah, but she's not gonna
make it to an OR. With
this much blood in the belly,
we're gonna need to do
an emergency laparotomy.
Uh, right now? Here?
Wilson, we're gonna
need gauze, laps,
whatever we have
to pack this abdomen.
You sure you want to do this?
I'm sure we don't have a choice.
Okay.
Oh!
All right, Wilson.
Liver's intact.
Let's look at the
retroperitoneum.
Oh, God, it's the IVC.
Okay, put some pressure on it.
Satinsky, please. Suction ready.
All right, fracture's all
cleaned out for now.
I'll do the repair tomorrow.
Have we found out
anything about this girl?
No purse, no I.D.
We know she worked
at the Office Hub,
but the only emergency contact
they had was her own number.
Actually, we know something
else. She's a veteran.
Yeah, she has an Operation
Iraqi Freedom tattoo, 2011-2012.
I've been examining a lot
of vets lately, thanks to you.
Good eye, Torres.
The injury's
exposed. 4-0 prolene.
This should never
have happened to her.
It shouldn't have
happened to anyone.
More suction, please.
Hi, Mom!
Oh, look at you!
Oh!
How was your flight?
Not as good as my ride over.
My chauffeur has
the prettiest eyes.
Mom! Oh.
Uh, thank you?
Oh, look, I almost forgot.
Look what I found in
the airport gift shop.
Zoo animal decals
from the Seattle Zoo!
I thought they'd be
adorable on the nursery wall,
and they'll go with whatever
color you're planning on painting,
which I assume
is gender neutral.
Oh, actually, we haven't...
We haven't really had
time to think about colors.
Mmm-mmm.
Oh, you two and
work. Busy, busy, busy!
Speaking of which,
um, the ER is a madhouse.
Oh, yeah.
I probably... I just need
to get back down there,
but I promise I will try to
make it back for dinner.
Oh, dinner?
Mom, what?
I thought maybe you
could take off the afternoon.
We could shop for paint
samples for the nursery
and open a baby registry.
Mrs. Frye at church asks over...
Mom, you know
what I do for a living.
I don't know why
you thought I could
just take a whole
afternoon off to...
You know what? I have a
super-light day, so I can...
I can do all of those things.
Jackson, you don't
have to do that.
It's not a problem.
It'll be fun!
Yes, it will.
We've got this.
Guys, I don't want
to sound like a jerk,
but I got clients to
see all over town,
and then I got to pick up my
kid and drop her at volleyball,
and then I got two
more clients to see.
And believe me, I get it.
The number of
things I've got on my
agenda would
make your head spin.
Perfect, then send me home,
and we can both get back to it.
Look at me. I'm fit as a fiddle.
Well, that's not
what your labs say.
Uh, cholesterol is in the 300s.
Your triglycerides are worse.
Your BP's too high,
and your blood sugar
is in the pre-diabetic range.
Who are you gonna
believe, me or science?
Okay, you've got an honest face,
but science and I go way back.
CT doesn't show
abdominal problems,
but we'd like to do
some extensive studies.
So I need to do a
barium swallow test.
When we get that back,
depending on the results,
I might need to do an EGD.
Is there any way we could
skip a step, cut to the chase?
Okay, Dr. Bailey is
just trying to avoid
putting a tube down
your throat or up your...
Oh. Indeed.
I appreciate the thought, but if
it'll get me out of here sooner,
Dr. Bailey can stick a
tube wherever she wants.
All right.
This is Waldo Pfeiffer,
gestational age 23 weeks.
In addition to an incredibly
unfortunate first name,
Waldo's dealing with a
particularly nasty CCAM.
Tell me what CCAM stands for.
Congenital cystic
adenomatoid malformation.
The mass is pressing
on his heart and lungs.
Waldo's CCAM has been
unresponsive to steroid treatment.
Now he's developing hydrops.
This is what fetal
surgery was created for.
First, we're gonna
open up the mother,
then incise the uterus,
then we're gonna remove the CCAM
and put him right back
where we found him,
and hopefully he'll
be carried to term.
You have a consultation
in 20 minutes.
Make it fast, get back here,
and we're going to go over
this procedure step by step.
Terrific. Thank you.
Well, don't thank me.
I decided it was necessary
when it took you two months
to wrap your head around
a fetal valvuloplasty.
You ready for this?
Yes. Yes, absolutely.
It's a chronic subdural.
It should reabsorb itself.
Great. Thanks.
Your wife invited me
to dinner at your house.
Perfect.
Yeah, I was so
surprised by the invitation,
I forgot to ask if I
should bring anything.
Just yourself.
Anything you don't eat?
No. Not at all.
Oh, perfect.
How about a pot roast?
Great.
Uh, I'm sorry.
Uh, Shepherd, I was
looking for a consult.
I can come back later.
No, we're done here.
Thanks, Dr. Shepherd.
Richard.
What are you doing
tomorrow night?
Um...
This could be you if you
keep eating like you do.
I bet if we took your
blood right now...
Mmm-hmm, see, I could
say the same thing about you,
but I wouldn't want to change a
single thing about you, so I won't.
I don't want to change
anything about you either.
I like you alive,
not dead on a toilet
after having a heart attack
trying to pass a
deep-fried onion blossom.
God, Miranda, why
would you even think...
What the hell?
Oh, what is this?
Not a deep-fried onion blossom
'cause that'd just be too much.
No.
It's a tumor.
And it's a big one.
Hey, sorry, the consultation
went off without a hitch,
but then Mom
got a little nervous,
so I just wanted to make
sure that she was okay.
CCAM. Um, I'm ready
whenever you are.
There's been a change in plans.
I'm having a personal...
I'm going home.
Here are the materials on
the procedure. Internalize them.
I've made notes in the margins
because my approach is better
than most of the crap that's in there.
You'll also need
to cover my service.
Wait, hold on. Is
everything okay?
I said it's personal!
You have what you
need from me there.
Read it. What if I
have questions?
They'll be answered in
there. I'll see you tomorrow.
I keep telling you
to take more walks,
yeah, have a salad,
maybe. Mmm-hmm.
Instead of all the
Philly cheesesteaks.
You certainly do, honey,
constantly, and just every time... Hello.
You don't look like
you have good news.
Jeremy,
I'm afraid the EGD
revealed a tumor.
It's early-stage adenocarcinoma.
Oh, God!
Cancer?
But I came in
here for heartburn.
And that's most
likely what you had,
but the cheesesteaks
and the fried foods
have caused intense acid reflux,
and over time, that reflux
has made your esophagus
the perfect home for cancer.
I'm sorry.
So, what do we do?
We'd like to keep you overnight
and do some pre-op tests,
then do an esophagectomy
where we remove your esophagus
and replace it with
a piece of your colon.
And then the cancer
would be gone?
That's the hope.
Yeah, it will be.
Okay, it'll be fine.
You go and get Erin.
Yeah.
And tell her what's going
on, but don't scare her, okay?
It's gonna be fine. Okay.
It's gonna be fine.
Hello, Jackson?
In here, Dr. Mom!
Hey.
Wow.
You've been busy.
We were just gonna
start a gift registry,
but then we saw
this adorable mobile,
and the next thing I knew,
I filled a shopping cart.
Yeah, we actually had
a pretty good day today.
Don't sound so
surprised! I am quite fun.
Uh, this didn't
come from a store.
Four generations
of Kepner babies
have slept in that
old war-horse.
How did you...
You didn't bring
this in your carry-on.
Shipping cost a fortune.
Your sisters thought
I should send it along,
but I wanted to be here to
see your face when it arrived,
so last week, I called Jackson.
You called Jackson?
I do know how to use
a telephone, little miss.
I am famished.
Well, why did you
wait for me to eat?
I called. I told
you I'd be late.
We probably just
lost track of time.
It's no big deal. I'll just hop in
the kitchen and whip something up.
Well, I didn't go to the store
because I thought that
we would be going out.
I'm sure I can
figure something out.
No, no, Mom, stop it!
I don't need you to
whip something up,
and I didn't need you to come out
here and set up my whole nursery.
I don't want your help!
Do you understand?
April.
Come on, that's not fair.
You invited Richard to dinner?
This was already a bad idea.
You're trying to make it worse?
She doesn't want to know him.
He said exactly the same thing.
Okay, then why are
you trying to force it?
Because he's my
friend. He's our friend.
He's family, and this
is one of the reasons
why you didn't want to leave
Seattle in the first place, remember?
You have family here, roots.
Are you kidding me?
What?
I have to have dinner
with the sister I don't know
and the bio-dad she hates
because you gave up your
chance to work for Obama?
You're gonna play that card?
Of course you are
because you'll be
playing that card
until the end of freaking time!
Time-out.
No, I am so sick of your
passive-aggressive...
Time-out.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't
have said that.
I am just trying
to help out here.
I'm trying to help you, and
I am trying to help them.
I come from a big family.
It's crazy, it's
messy, but it's good,
and I want that for you.
I want you to have that.
She's your sister, and
he's practically your father.
And Zola needs more
black people in the family
because I'm running out
of ways to braid her hair
and Bailey won't
show me anymore.
Fine.
You want Richard
to come to dinner,
call Pierce and make
sure she's okay with it.
Me?
You want Richard
to come to dinner.
You win. Accept the win.
Don't push for more.
Okay, but shouldn't you be
the one who's making the...
Accept the win.
I thought I was clear.
I don't need you up here
double-checking my work.
Don't get all Sharks
and Jets on me, okay?
One of Herman's
patients landed in here,
and I'm learning the steps
of tomorrow's CCAM fetal
surgery from a journal article.
Actually, not even...
From the chicken scratch
in the margin of an article.
I think she's trying to haze me.
Or set me up for a
failure or maybe kill me.
You know what? No
one forced you to do this,
and now you're gonna
pout because it's kind of hard
and your teacher's
mean? Suck it up.
Hey.
Melissa, it's okay.
What are you...
Shh, you're in the hospital.
You were... Where's...
You were pretty badly
banged up, but you're all right.
Where's my car? Did they...
It's... Did they find my car?
It's all right. Did
they find my car?
Shh, just try and sleep.
Okay?
Dr. Bailey!
Dr. Pierce!
I didn't know you were a runner!
Oh, yeah. I mean,
I usually just spin.
I take a spin class.
I thought I could get
some fresh air for a change.
It's a gorgeous
morning, isn't it?
You know, I was only gonna
go like another three miles,
but I could stretch it
out if you want to join.
Oh, no. I mean, thank you. I...
I'm sorry. I just picked
up a new audiobook.
Oprah recommended it.
Totally understand.
Let me know how it is.
Okay.
Uh, you're the last
person who gets to
lecture me on
avoiding my mother.
That's not true.
My mother is a
nightmare, and yours
is the sweetest
person I've ever met.
No, what happened
last night was not sweet.
It was condescending.
Come on, you're overreacting.
Yes, 'cause she just
decided that I needed her help.
I needed help.
I asked her for it, okay?
I have no idea what
the hell I'm doing here.
I just spent four hours in that
baby store, and
my mind was blown.
Do you know how much I
don't know about having babies?
So much.
And she knows everything and so
do you, and it's
easy for you guys.
My family was
not built that way.
I didn't have
grandparents falling
over themselves
trying to love me,
but lucky for us, our kid will.
That is, provided that you
do not drive her away first.
Hey. Hey, uh,
OR three is ready for
Melissa's tibia repair,
and the police are finishing
up getting her statement now.
All right, thank you, ma'am.
Oh.
Melissa, are you okay?
They found it.
They found my car in pieces
in some chop shop in Bellevue,
and it's gone.
Okay. It's okay.
It's all replaceable.
Let's just be glad
you didn't get killed.
Damn it.
If I hadn't been asleep...
What happened? Do you remember?
I was sleeping, and then
they broke the window,
and they pulled
me out of it, and...
And I tried to hold on,
but I got stuck in the door,
and they dragged me for a while,
and then they punched me,
and then they kicked me, and...
And then I couldn't
hold on anymore.
God, why didn't you
just let them take it?
Everything was in that car.
Everything.
The car was the first thing she
asked about when she woke up.
She said she was asleep
in it when she was attacked.
It sounds like it's all she had.
So you're saying she's homeless?
I'm saying I think she's
living in her car, so, yeah.
Well, I thought you
said she had a job.
No, you can have a job
and not have a home.
That just makes it even worse.
Try going through high
school living in your car.
You got to lie all the time, you
can never have anyone over,
you have to make up excuses
why, you have no bathroom,
and then you know what?
You can't even tell anybody
'cause then they just look at
you like you're weird and pitiful.
Find me when she wakes up.
Okay.
You lived in your
car in high school?
See, that's the look.
Glove me.
Karev?
Dr. Karev expressed an interest
in our little CCAM
surgery today.
Yeah, it sounds amazing,
but I want to make
sure I'm not in the way.
Happy to have you.
Hope to hell you
studied, Robbins.
I'll warn you, I did not
sleep well last night.
My patience will be thin.
Richard Webber is coming?
No, that's...
I can't believe him.
No, no, no. It didn't
come from Richard, okay?
I invited him.
Well, I can't
make it. I'm sorry.
Look, you came here
to find out about Ellis.
Why don't you talk to
someone who actually knew her?
To Richard.
Come and have dinner
with me and Meredith.
Less pressure, it's a baby step.
Let me think about it.
Okay.
Is this about how I'm
gonna pay for all this?
No. No, no, no.
We just wanted to know...
'Cause I have some insurance
left, but all the paperwork was...
Inside your car?
I'm just saying
that I'll figure it out.
Melissa, are you
living in your car?
Wilson.
I don't know how else to ask.
We don't mean to
pry, but we just...
I...
It was only gonna be temporary.
I... When I got out of the army,
the job I had lined up was gone.
My fiance was gone, and...
My apartment with him.
All I could get was
the job at Office Hub,
and it doesn't pay great,
and I couldn't afford rent,
so, yeah, I'm making it work.
But now the car's
gone, uh, with my cash.
And my clothes, my savings
'cause banks want
you to have an address.
Um...
So, yeah.
Yeah.
Everything I have is gone,
but if I can't get back to work,
then I'm gonna lose my job, too.
Melissa, there are
programs available
with the sole purpose of
helping homeless veterans.
Oh, I'm not homeless.
I'm... It's only temporary.
They will get you into
real, dependable housing,
then after that, everything
else is that much easier.
See, that's not for me.
You served in Iraq.
I fixed computers in an
operations office in the green zone.
There are guys who
were wounded in combat,
who were blown to pieces,
who had their faces burned off,
and I've met guys who have
been on the street since Vietnam.
I was carjacked.
In Seattle.
Excuse me.
You have some visitors.
Oh.
Oh, my God. Uh...
Just, uh, please go?
And don't say a
word to those guys?
Melissa, I...
I'll figure it out.
I always do.
Just go, please.
Okay, everybody, we're
about to meet Waldo.
Let's be quiet so we
don't wake him up.
Robbins, next step?
A 20-cc-per-kilo bolus of normal
saline into the umbilical vein.
So you did read my notes.
I'll give the bolus.
You pull out Waldo's arm
so we can attach the monitor.
Okay.
It's amazing.
Indeed.
Now you're ready for
chest exposure and incision.
Scalpel.
Now, every step counts here.
Tell me what you're about to do.
I'll perform a
posterolateral thoracotomy
and slowly deliver the mass.
Slowly and controlled.
I'm sorry? My notes said
the mass needs to be delivered
slowly and in a controlled manner.
Did you read my notes or not?
I did. It also told me to
prepare for bradycardia.
Proceed.
Okay. There's the mass.
And there's the bradycardia.
How do we handle that?
Atropine and epi
IM into the deltoid.
And why is this important?
Why this approach?
'Cause if the CCAM
starts to pop out,
then this little guy is
at risk for heart failure.
That's not what my notes said.
Well, not in those words, but...
I want my words. I
want my exact words.
You're giving me the gist.
I'm not interested in your
interpretation of my notes.
I want to know that the
specific words that I wrote
are now embedded in your brain.
That's what this is all about.
That's what this
fellowship is all about.
If you're only interested
in learning the gist of...
All right, she gets the point.
Dr. Karev, we're just
getting to the good part.
You don't want to
have to leave now.
My notes said that
before my approach,
this surgery resulted
in fetal cardiac arrest
50% of the time.
Feels strange, doesn't it?
To touch a baby
before he's even born?
You know what it feels like?
Privilege.
Great privilege.
Um...
Okay.
What happened?
Nothing.
Did you fall?
No!
I'm fine.
You're not fine.
You're limping.
Limping?
I hope you didn't
overdo it this morning.
Overdo what?
Jogging.
Jogging?
Yes, jogging.
She didn't tell you?
We ran into each other
at the Seward Park trail.
Mmm-mmm.
Are we gonna go get
a tumor out of a man
or just sit around
and talk about it?
Okay. Meredith.
Did Derek talk to you about
me coming to this dinner?
He did. Okay, what do you think?
Because I'm not 100% convinced.
I'm not either.
I think it might
seem... A little pushy.
A little too much, too soon.
I'm thinking of calling it off.
Well, if you think that's best.
I think Derek will understand.
What is wrong with you people?
You can't un-invite
someone to dinner,
not after the song and
dance I had to go through
to get her to even
think about coming.
You're not calling this off!
Okay, I have an
aneurysm I need to clip.
I will see you
both there tonight.
I'll bring dessert.
Thanks. That would be nice.
Edwards, start his work-up.
I'll be there in a second.
Copy that.
47-year-old male. He was
the passenger in a vehicle.
I thought your flight wasn't
till later this afternoon.
I pushed it.
You owe me an apology.
And I'm not leaving
until I get one.
I owe you an apology?
You were rude, and
I raised you better.
I understand you're very busy,
and I understand
you work hard, but...
Mom, I am not going to apologize
for having the life that I want,
even if you think...
April Kepner!
You have made
choices that are very
different from
mine, and it's scary.
Any mother who watches her child
do something she
hasn't done herself...
It's scary.
But that doesn't mean I
haven't been proud of you,
and the more I see you
in this world, in this work,
in this marriage,
the prouder I am.
I have no earthly understanding
of what it is you do,
but I know a lot about babies,
and I don't want to take
anything away from you.
I just want to help you.
And I get to do that
because I am a grandma.
And I am also your mother.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
So, can I...
Can I call you if I
have questions?
Well...
I suppose.
If you must.
Thanks for having
my back in there.
You can't let her
talk to you like that.
I know.
Well, so do something about it.
I can't.
Well, you have to.
Callie and I are splitting up.
And there are a lot of
reasons why it happened,
but taking this fellowship
might've been the nail in the coffin.
I traded my
marriage for this job,
and it's pretty much all I have
right now, so it has to work.
I need it to work.
Okay.
No, screw that. It's not okay.
I saw what happened in
there. She's got it in for you.
She's either looking
for a reason to fire you,
or she's gonna grind you down
and make you miserable
trying to please her.
She'll probably
fire you either way.
What do you got to lose?
Melissa? Yeah?
I brought these for
you. I told you I...
What rank were you
when you got out?
PFC. Okay, well, I was a major,
so you're gonna listen to
me if for no other reason
than I outrank you.
But mostly because
we have this in common.
I served, just like you.
I did two tours as a surgeon with
an army forward surgical team.
I gave what I had to offer.
So did you.
I patched up guys.
I can no more
re-jigger a hard drive...
Reformat. What?
Reformat a hard drive.
You gave what you had to give.
You served.
And you deserve all the help
and gratitude that's offered to you.
But if you think that
by accepting this help
you're taking it away from
the next guy, you are wrong.
But there are so
many guys out there.
If you want to make
sure these guys get help,
I have friends at the VA.
You can volunteer.
There's so much you can do,
but to start, you have to
get up on your own feet.
That is how you help.
That is how you serve.
Understood?
Yes, sir.
Starting the neck incision.
How old did this guy
say he was again?
Forty-two.
He's got the esophagus
of an 80-year-old.
You went jogging?
Yes, I jogged half a mile,
and now I can barely walk,
and that's embarrassing enough
without you acting like I
took a rocket to the moon!
You shouldn't be embarrassed.
I hope you don't give up.
The thing is, no
matter when you start
something like this,
it's gonna be hard.
Just, you have to start.
And take baby steps.
Was that a short joke?
BP's dropping.
What the... There's a
third-degree AV block.
We need to try to pace
him. Dr. Bailey, can you...
No, I have his colon.
Okay, hold it, hold it!
Bring the crash cart
over for temporary pacing.
Too late, he's coding.
- Crap. V-fib!
Dr. Warren, get the
paddles and charge to 150.
Clear!
Restart CPR.
Push one of epi,
push one of atropine!
Hold compressions!
No, it's not too late.
Oh, it can't be too late!
Go again!
Clear!
No. No.
We did everything we could.
Go again.
Clear.
Jeremy died during surgery.
I'm so sorry.
It was supposed to be heartburn.
It was just heartburn. It was
supposed to be heartburn!
How could this happen? Shh.
How could this happen?
No! No, no, no!
Hey. You done soon?
Let's go home.
You mean, go to your house.
What?
Well, it's your house.
I just crash there, right?
I mean, you never
asked me to move in.
You never
complained, but never...
Did I do something? 'Cause
I feel like I'm in trouble.
No, I'm in trouble
'cause when this changes I
don't have any place to be.
God...
I used to be so careful.
Wait, um...
What's changing? I
thought we were good.
Yes, but it all changes,
Alex. It always does.
You can't hold on to anything
that you don't want to lose.
Right now, I feel like I have
a bed and a house.
And it is so good.
But my bed isn't
my bed. It's your bed.
And I hate that I
don't want to lose it.
Hey.
Look at me.
You got me. I swear to God.
I'm not going anywhere
except home with you.
Come on.
Let's go home.
Did you take the pot
roast out of the oven?
Uh, I shut the oven off because
I don't want that thing to get cold.
I'll take it out.
Really? You're
not really a chef.
And you are?
I'm better than you.
Why would you say
something like that?
Because you called
the pot roast a "thing."
But it's not true.
You're not better than me.
Have you ever
cooked a meal before?
Okay, wait, time-out.
Well? Well, what?
You called a time-out.
You have to say something
when you call a time-out.
That's how it out works.
It is not a mute button.
It is right now. That's
not how it works.
I need a time-out!
I need a break, from
you, from the fighting,
from the pot roast
because the table isn't set.
The candles aren't lit.
The guests are gonna
arrive in 30 minutes.
I still need to take a shower.
I need a time-out!
Don't look at me like that.
I could use a shower, too.
How's the baby book?
Uh...
It's the scariest
thing I've ever read.
I was a jerk today.
Yeah, you were.
So, this is the
part where you say,
"No, you weren't the
jerk. I was the jerk."
Yeah, but I wasn't,
and you were.
Get up. I want to sit down.
Okay.
Mmm?
Right?
You built this?
Twice, actually.
I'm pretty sure there's something
wrong with the directions.
It's perfect.
You did a good job.
You're gonna be a great daddy.
Thank you.
I'm dying. I'm just
gonna drop dead.
Oh, we've talked about you
reading horror stories before bed.
I don't want to get punched
in the middle of the night
because you're
having nightmares.
I ran my labs yesterday after
we found Mr. Weaver's tumor.
Look, LDL cholesterol 178.
HDL 26.
Triglycerides 320.
Glucose 152.
Well, this explains the jogging.
I'm such a hypocrite.
I tell people every day
how important it is to
eat right and to exercise.
I just think I'm saying it
so much, I'm not hearing it.
You're not dying.
The numbers aren't great, but...
No, I have to make some changes.
Starting now.
But not right now.
You go for a jog
right this second,
I don't think you'd ever
be able to walk again.
Ow! Okay, I...
I did mention not wanting
to be punched, didn't I?
Yeah, but it's good cardio.
Like that really
hurt. That hurt?
The ABCs of trauma are
a handy tool for
keeping a patient alive.
But they're only
a starting point.
Hi?
Oh.
Uh, hello.
Um, I just rang the
bell. No one answered.
Um, they did say 8:00, right?
They did, yeah.
The table is set.
Yeah, it is.
It's strange.
Once the patient's airway,
breathing, and circulation
are all clear and accounted
for, the real work begins.
The messy work.
I brought wine.
I'm an alcoholic.
This was a mistake.
I'm gonna go.
Look, I screwed up!
I Screwed up. I'm sorry.
Look, 31 years ago, I had a kid.
And nobody told me.
I've known you for
only, what, two months.
Two months.
Most parents mess up a
lot in those first few months,
and it's fine
because their kid's
too young to notice or remember.
But you... I hurt
you, and I know that.
And all I want to do is
just take it back, okay?
You've got the wrong idea.
I'm not angry with you
for being a bad father.
You're not my dad.
You are just a man
who slept with a woman
and made it possible
for me to be born.
My dad is my present.
You are my past. You
are my genetic history.
I didn't need you
to be a good father.
I just needed you to be
honest with me from the start,
instead of letting me walk
around here for weeks like a fool,
without a clue, letting
me confide in you.
I didn't know what to do.
And I'll never be
anything but sorry for that.
There's no telling how
long it's going to take
to clean up that chaos...
Okay.
Good night.
Once you've begun...
Sorry.
I think I must've
lost track of time.
I hope you brought an appetite.
Because sometimes,
you don't know
what you're in for.
Can I talk to you?
Actually, I wanted
to talk to you.
Dr. Herman, I
wasn't kidding when
I said that I wanted
this fellowship,
and today's surgery only
confirmed that more for me.
Close the door.
But no matter how much I
need or want this fellowship,
I refuse to spend the year
with you speaking to me
the way that you speak to me.
We won't have a year together.
Fine.
Great. Thanks.
I'll be dead in six months.
You don't know exactly
what you're about to face.
I have a brain tumor.
It's inoperable.
I thought I had
longer, but it's growing.
Soon, I will show symptoms,
and after that, I will die.
Who knows about this?
Hunt? Anyone?
Fetal surgery is a new field.
The few of us who
are practicing it are
basically inventing
it as we go along.
The things I know,
the things I scribble down in
the margins, no one has them.
They're not in any textbook.
They're only in my brain.
So I can fight to write papers
and try to get them published,
or I can use the
time I have left
to try to teach you a year's
worth of medicine in six months.
Or...
You can tell Hunt and the
board, and it all goes away forever.
You don't know what secrets
the body in front of you holds...
I don't know how
to feel about this.
Well, hurry up and decide.
We don't have any time to waste.
And whether, by
the time it's all over,
if there's anything
left worth saving.