Stop looking at me.
Mm, pancakes. The
Peanut is thrilled.
You are wearing the
maternity jeans I bought you.
Glad you're happy about that.
You're 28 weeks pregnant.
Your weight has
increased 21.5 pounds,
and our baby is moving lower.
Hmm. At least there's pancakes.
We need to buy a minivan.
No, we don't.
The Striped Tomato has no
infant safety features.
Shaun, I just surrendered
to maternity jeans.
This is not the right time for
broaching the "Mom-mobile."
When would be the right time?
These are amazing.
- Did you use buttermilk?
- Greek yogurt.
Mm.
I will e-mail you my spreadsheet
of child-safe vehicles.
We can discuss it
on your lunch break.
Resync By M_I_S
www.opensubtitles.org
Sonja Baylor?
Wait. Who's the Code Gold?
Is it Taylor Swift? Did her
broken heart finally give out?
Better. Roland Barnes.
The green tech guy?
He was attacked by a tiger.
Sorry. In San Jose?
At his exotic animal rescue
in the Santa Cruz Mountains.
Concierge doctor called to
say they're on their way.
San Jose General is much closer.
- Why would he come here?
- Because of you.
Deep chest
wall lacerations,
multiple rib fractures,
hemopneumothorax.
I stabilized him and placed a chest
tube, but he needs a CT, stat.
- Dr. Kalu.
- Dr. Andrews.
Good to see you, Dr. Murphy.
Oh, hello... Jared.
A famous billionaire
and a cute reunion?
This is almost Swift-worthy.
Is Leo a
decent poker player?
Us Weekly has photos of Roland
coming out of his game last week.
Won my Lambo off him.
No sign of trauma to
the liver or spleen.
Ugh. Beyonce did a private
show at his birthday?
Ah. It was awesome.
No major intraperitoneal
hematoma.
Moving on to the chest.
So, how does one go
from St. Bon's resident
to concierge doctor
for the fifth richest
man in the world?
I was working at Denver Memorial
when I met Roland
at a fundraiser
hosted by my parents.
His wife collapsed during
the silent auction.
Nutmeg allergy.
I gave her an epi and helped
her to outbid John Legend
for a weekend at an
underwater hotel.
Well...
Roland hired me that night.
Why does he need a
personal physician?
Does he often get
attacked by wild animals?
Uh, chronic sciatica.
And he travels a lot, you
know, so there's vaccines,
plus BOTOX injections,
cholesterol scripts,
medical advice for
friends and family.
Why'd you leave St. Bon's?
He was fired for assaulting an
attending who harassed Claire,
and then he sued the hospital.
- You're that guy.
- Yeah.
I hear Andrews is, uh,
not your biggest fan.
Surprised he let
me in the building.
Depressed and dislocated sternum,
manubrium, and rib fractures.
They're too fragmented
for a standard sternal
reconstruction.
- He still does this, huh?
- Mm.
Always makes my day.
I have an idea.
This is why I
brought Roland here.
It's a girl.
We're naming her Esther.
We hope she'll be
brave and selfless
like Queen Esther,
baddest bitch in the Bible.
How are the meds going?
Fine.
Any excessive discharge?
Oh, a couple of days
ago, I was on a walk,
and it was a little
like I'd peed myself.
Could that be from the MilliDox?
No, you're actually
on the placebo.
Your amniotic
fluid is a bit low.
We should admit you
for further testing.
He asked for you.
Inoperable leiomyosarcoma
with major vascular involvement.
What are you doing here?
I'm dying.
My doctors say
that there's nothing
they can do for me.
I'm hoping you can.
We should get a
CT and a PET scan.
Fine.
We will
completely rebuild
your sternum and
anterior chest wall
with donor bones
and titanium plates.
It is a very
complicated surgery.
Jared says you're a
damn good surgeon.
Yes, I am a damn good surgeon.
He is.
And I'll be overseeing your
care every step of the way.
Appreciate the
personal attention.
I want Jared there, too.
Jared is my doctor.
Dr. Kalu will be read in
on every major decision.
I want him in the OR.
I will fast-track your
surgical privileges.
Something's going
on between you two.
I'm very perceptive that way.
- It's a long story.
- Hmm.
I saw on his chart
he's from Phoenix,
and he broke his arm
a couple years ago
at a Tae Kwon Do
match, your sport.
So, I'm gonna go with
he's your Johnny Lawrence
who cheated during your match
at the All Valley tournament.
I've been watching
a lot of Cobra Kai.
He slept with my wife,
so yes to the cheating,
no to the tournament.
This is from six months ago.
This is from today.
A leiomyosarcoma should have
progressed more than that.
Yeah, maybe they had
the diagnosis wrong.
Release the pectoral
muscles from the attachment medially.
Should I place
the low-profile plate?
Don't you need to create
a landing zone for the fixation?
He is right.
Get better exposure by elevating
the right pectoral
muscle from the ribs.
I understand SF
General's cardiac unit
is named after your boss
and that he sponsored a surgical
exchange program with Haiti.
Dr. Kalu, would you like
to place the screws?
Very much so.
Thank you, Dr. Andrews.
Drill guide,
self-tapping screws.
Feels good.
You have been very
polite to Dr. Kalu,
despite having fired him.
Is that only because you
want a donation from Roland?
- It's okay. You don't...
- It's true.
Dr. Kalu and I did not
part on the best of terms,
but I'm happy you
found your niche.
And I believe in
the work we do here,
and Roland Barnes can
help us do even more.
I told Roland this was the
best hospital in the state.
When we get him healthy,
I'll be happy to tell him again.
BP's dropping. Cardiac
output is awful.
He's
in heart failure.
The cardiac contusion must have
been too small to spot on CT.
He needs a balloon pump
to help his heart
circulate more blood.
And we need to get it in the
next five minutes, or he dies.
BP has stabilized.
Cardiac output is improving.
He should make a full recovery,
but he should not get so close
to jungle cats in the future.
In the... In the OR,
I really missed that.
Then why did you
stop being a surgeon?
Um, working for Roland
was too interesting an
opportunity to pass up.
Is sciatica interesting to you?
No, it's more, um...
- I came as soon as I heard.
- Hey.
Poor Rolly.
Uh, Shaun, this is
my girlfriend Dalia.
Hi.
You...
I have seen you on the bus
in a-a perfume ad.
Fern test confirms
it's a premature rupture
of the membranes.
We should terminate before
an infection sets in.
What about in-patient expectant
management and antibiotics?
PPROM pregnancies can
be carried to term.
Rarely, and when they are,
babies are likely to have
cerebral palsy,
neurologic abnormalities,
intellectual disability...
Which we'll tell the parents, but
this is a badly-wanted pregnancy.
They've been trying to
conceive for five years,
had two first-trimester
miscarriages already.
Saving the baby may
be her priority.
But saving her is ours.
Sonja is our patient.
We should explain her options
but recommend termination.
Morgan is right, but be
clear about the options.
The seat springs
allow the car seat
to move more than one inch,
which creates
additional injury risk.
There are no over-shoulder seat
belts in the back for the car seat,
no crumple zone, and you would
have to install a roll cage,
which still would not be as reliable
as one built into the vehicle.
Since you hate minivans,
I have looked into hatchbacks and
SUVs with sufficient safety features.
It's not just about
hating minivans.
- What is it about?
- I love this car.
It's my history.
My brother and I restored it,
used to drive it to
shows at The Fillmore.
You and I took it on our first
road trip. I can't sell it.
Then... we do not have to.
As long as you never
put the Peanut in it.
We still need a family car.
Yeah, we do.
Roland's awake.
But it's possible that
we could save our baby?
You'd have to live here.
We'd monitor you every day
and give you prophylactic
antibiotics and steroids
when the baby gets
closer to viability.
To be clear,
even with all of that,
you may still develop a
serious uterine infection
that could require
a hysterectomy
or cause fatal complications.
I think we should terminate.
What would you do...
if it was your baby?
Termination is the safest.
I was talking to Dr. Allen.
I would...
pray on it.
And then?
I want to know
what you would do.
I think I...
would try to save the baby.
We have to fight for our Esther.
We'd need a biopsy
before we can give you
any definitive answer.
Okay.
So, when do we do that?
I'll give you a detailed referral
to take to another doctor.
If I wanted to go to another
doctor, I would have.
I don't have to
keep treating you.
But you will.
You're not a quitter.
You worked your ass off
to save your marriage.
You never tapped out
in a fight. You...
I always admired
your persistence.
I kinda hated it, too.
Looking back at my life...
I don't like the view.
I hurt... a lot of people.
That's the real reason
that I came here.
For forgiveness.
The intra-aortic
balloon pump worked.
You won't need a new heart.
Great.
So, when can I get out of here?
Oh, not for a few days.
We will need to monitor you
for post-surgical complications.
Your heart rate is elevated.
Have you been exerting yourself?
She did most of the exerting.
Okay.
I need 1,000 milligrams
levetiracetam
and 4 milligrams
lorazepam, stat!
Is Rolly gonna be okay?
Roland had a seizure.
You... should sit down.
Dalia was there.
Naked.
They were having sex.
Dalia and I aren't together.
She's with Roland.
It's part of the gig.
I pretend she's with
me so Roland's wife
doesn't get suspicious
that Dalia's always around.
Oh.
You think that sex
brought on the seizure?
Oh. Arousal can increase
the heart rate by 38%,
and if his brain was
also deprived of oxygen,
it could cause a seizure,
which would mean his heart
is still not pumping
enough blood.
Does it bother you to have
to lie on a regular basis?
It's not my favorite responsibility,
but it's a great job, so...
Why is it a great job?
On my last day, Shaun, you told me
that one day I will be very happy.
But I was miserable.
I felt like a failure.
And then I met Roland, and
he saw something in me,
this guy that I really admired,
that the world admired.
You know, he... he valued me.
And I certainly don't mind
flying private to Amsterdam
to have rijsttafel with the
Queen of the Netherlands.
I also said you would
fulfill your potential.
And I'm not doing that?
No.
Sciatica?
Thanks for reminding
me I'm still a failure.
I'll get the BNP test and
echo and check out his heart.
Inject saline to
get us to submucosal plane.
Why'd you stay on the case?
There's the tumor.
He was right. I take my
obligations seriously.
Take four samples.
Not because some part of
you wants to forgive him?
Withdraw the scope slowly.
He doesn't deserve it.
Let's start with a sofa.
Let's take a look.
Finally, somebody recognizes
my interior design genius.
Looks nice.
Hey, I love this. I'll take it.
No.
This is literally the
first thing you've sat on.
Okay, I'll sit in ten other ones,
and then I'll take this one.
No. If you know you like
something, stick with it.
Like my car.
Shaun wants to buy a minivan.
And what, you want to put your
infant in a '75 Gran Torino?
No. It's not safe for a baby.
But...
it is...
cool.
Even when I am going to
my super grown-up job
in my lady-boss pantsuit,
I get to get out of
that car, and I'm cool.
And soon, I will be just
another 30-something mom
in a practical car
with a baby seat in the back
and spit-up on my shirt.
Maddie's mom used to warn
me to take two shirts
whenever I went
out with the baby.
- I had to learn the hard way.
- How?
H-How do I want
this baby so badly,
but feel so icked
out by being a mom?
Define "icked out."
Like...
mnh.
I don't know.
Okay, that's well said.
Hey, you got mixed emotions.
Welcome to the human condition.
I'm gonna take this one.
Her fever's hiked.
She's in a lot of pain.
Her heart rate's 117. Fetal heart
rate 180. They're both tachycardic.
500 milligrams acetaminophen
and start ampicillin.
This is the infection
we were worried about.
Your baby is very
unlikely to survive,
and your life is in danger.
We need to terminate now.
But her heart's still beating.
Esther can only
stay alive in utero,
and as long as she's in there,
you'll keep getting sicker.
I'm so sorry.
I'm here. We can
get through this.
We can try again.
No.
Your baby needs at least
two more weeks to be viable,
and if we wait that long,
you will probably die.
"If I perish, I perish."
That's what Queen Esther said
before she risked her
life to save her family.
Sonja.
"If I perish...
I perish."
According
to your BNP test and echo,
your seizure was not
related to heart trauma.
The EEG will let us
assess your brain.
So, what's your pitch?
Hospital presidents
don't supervise EEGs.
I've been very impressed
by your Global
Engineers Initiative,
and I think we can do the
same thing with medicine,
train doctors from
the developing world
to take care of
their own people.
What makes St. Bon's
the place to do it?
We're very hands-on here.
Our residents don't just
do appies and lap choles.
With the guidance
of our attendings,
they come up with complex
treatment solutions,
untangle the thorniest
ethical dilemmas,
and learn how to provide
top-notch patient care.
If we could sponsor
more residents
from the developing world,
we'll send them home ready
to serve their communities.
But Jared, who I
trust with my life,
wasn't good enough to be
one of those residents.
You fired him.
You saw something
in him I missed.
- Mm.
- But I'm seeing it now,
and I've granted
him full access.
That's a very politic answer.
What do you think, Jared?
Has he earned my money?
I learned a tremendous
amount here at St. Bon's,
and as you've experienced,
the care is top-notch.
Mm, unfortunately,
the food isn't.
Oh, text Dalia and ask her to
bring us back some of those, um,
pork buns from Yank Sing. Ohh.
Dalia went into the city?
Mm-hmm, to meet up with friends.
And you're okay with that?
Why wouldn't I be?
No reason.
Uh, all right.
Let's start this. Close
your eyes and relax.
Labs confirm Sonja
has chorioamnionitis.
We should add gentamicin.
That would damage
the baby's kidneys.
It's our only way
to keep Sonja alive,
and it buys us time to
convince her to terminate.
She's being suicidal.
Risking your life for your child
is usually considered admirable.
Not if you're both
going to die...
because of the false
hope you gave her.
I answered a patient's question.
You gave her permission.
We're supposed to at
least try to be objective.
Objectivity is a myth,
especially on this subject.
I know the pain
Sonja's grappling with.
So do I.
I was in med school,
on birth control,
and I got pregnant anyway.
I wasn't ready for a kid.
I was scared...
and sad...
and relieved.
It was medical procedure
I had years ago,
and I'm at peace with it now.
Most women are.
Because it was their choice.
A choice you got to
make, and I did, too.
Let Sonja make hers.
It's not our job to help
patients choose death.
Her lungs are failing.
Her O2 sats are falling.
Fever's climbing.
Intubation cart.
Administer propofol
and rocuronium.
Hey, we need to sedate
you so we can intubate.
That'll keep you breathing,
but the only way to...
No. You can't kill her.
Esther's life before mine.
- Sonja, please.
- Promise me.
- I can't.
Anthony.
I p...
I promise.
I love you.
Shaun, check out the activity in the
left frontal lobe from Roland's EEG.
Interictal spikes.
They are very small,
likely incidental.
Hmm.
Roland's selfish and possessive.
He hates it when people
have fun without him,
but today he was
totally fine with Dalia
hanging out with friends
while he's stuck here.
Being unselfish is a symptom.
Maybe one of his
wounds got infected.
Bacterial encephalitis
from the claws or teeth.
This could be subtle edema.
Plus behavioral changes
and interictal spikes.
That sounds like
neurocysticercosis.
- A tapeworm cyst.
- With larva in the brain.
But it would take a tapeworm weeks to
fully form larva and a cyst in his brain.
The attack was two days ago.
Ooh.
Roland's last local safari
was about two months ago,
and he fell into a giant
pile of tiger crap.
We can remove the cyst and larva
with stereotactic navigation
and hydrodissection.
- Awesome.
- Oh!
You're not a failure.
Seriously? Four guesses?
I got it in two.
What's up with you?
You lose a patient?
Actually, I might save one.
Joe.
Mia's Joe?
Waiting on his biopsy results.
He asked me to forgive him.
What did you say?
I refused.
You would have, too.
Hmm, well, maybe.
Then again, I am capable
of letting things go.
I can let things go.
I prioritized my
career for a day,
which you decided
was unacceptable,
even after I changed my mind.
And how long did it
take you to forgive Mia?
Dr. Park.
Your diagnosis is in.
Right this way, guys.
Be careful. You've got history
you're carrying right there.
There's a couple of
steps. Be careful.
Thanks, guys. First
door on the right.
Stadium seats?
Authentic Candlestick
Park stadium seats.
Got them from a broker.
- Very cool.
- Right?
- Thank you for the inspiration.
- You're welcome.
Your turn next. Get your coat.
You have a stromal
tumor in your stomach
and a small lesion
on your liver.
And we can remove both.
You'll be cancer-free.
Hmm.
T-That's incredible.
Thank you.
You get it, right?
You're not dying.
Yes.
This is amazing.
I'm so grateful.
- But it...
- That's not why you came here.
Sonja will likely be
in multi-organ failure
within the next 48 hours.
And when that happens,
Esther will not survive.
But if we terminate
now, Sonja still can.
You can save your wife's life.
It's all up to you.
He says...
He says he can't do it.
He needs to keep his promise.
I know what to do.
♪♪ Yeah, lacing the
shoes I'm on the move ♪♪
♪♪ I got so much to prove ♪♪
♪♪ Ain't no substitute
For hard work... ♪♪
- Sorry, man.
- Bring it.
♪♪ I get up Even when
the fall hurts ♪♪
♪♪ Ain't no ceiling
For a dream ♪♪
♪♪ I hit the ground running
I conquered everything ♪♪
♪♪ I can conquer anything ♪♪
♪♪ Get up, get up ♪♪
♪♪ We can do anything ♪♪
You okay?
A worm laid eggs in my skull?
Larva.
You were right.
Murphy's the best.
What would you say
to $100 million?
I'd say that's remarkably
generous, uh, but...
You can't accept it.
You are not medically fit to
be making any major decisions
because of the larva.
I closed a huge deal last week
with Mr. Worm as my consigliere.
I feel pretty competent.
Well, I'd be happy to accept
your money after the surgery.
Sonja, it's okay.
I turned off your sedation.
I need to talk to you.
I'm gonna let go of your hands,
but you can't pull out the tube.
When I was 18,
I had an abortion.
That child would
have been 11 now,
just starting middle school.
Every time I see a kid that age,
I think about who
they would have become
or what kind of mom
I would have been.
I believe God's forgiven me.
That's kinda His thing.
And I believe God picked
you for motherhood.
You are so strong,
so brave,
with such a deep
capacity for love.
But your Esther isn't
developed enough
to survive outside of the womb.
The infection will
kill both of you.
I told you if I were you, I
would try to save the baby.
I prayed for a miracle.
And I don't know why
it didn't come today.
The only way for you to be
the mom God wants you to be...
is to let Esther go.
Please sign this consent form.
♪♪ Wherever you
are, it's okay ♪♪
♪♪ I'll never be too far away ♪♪
♪♪ Wherever you go I
want you to know ♪♪
♪♪ You can always call on me ♪♪
♪♪ And if you get tired
Out there on your own ♪♪
♪♪ I will walk you home ♪♪
♪♪ I'll walk you home... ♪♪
Yes.
♪♪ Nothing you do Could
change my love... ♪♪
Speculum.
♪♪ For you ♪♪
♪♪ I'd walk to the
ends Of the earth ♪♪
♪♪ If you asked me to ♪♪
♪♪ I'll hold you close ♪♪
♪♪ I'll let you go... ♪♪
If your soul has
not yet left your body...
I baptize you, Esther.
♪♪ ...have to be alone ♪♪
♪♪ I will walk you home... ♪♪
Cervix is
sufficiently dilated.
♪♪ Don't worry about a thing ♪♪
♪♪ Close your eyes and sing ♪♪
♪♪ I'll walk you home... ♪♪
In the
name of the Father...
and of the Son...
and of the Holy Spirit.
♪♪ Anywhere... ♪♪
Amen.
- Amen. Amen.
- Amen.
♪♪ I will walk you ♪♪
♪♪ I'll walk you home ♪♪
♪♪ I will walk you home ♪♪
And the margins were clean.
We were able to
get all the tumors.
No additional metastasis.
Your prognosis is excellent.
Thank you.
I forgive you.
Extracting the cyst...
and larva.
Awesome.
- And I might hurl.
- Let's close.
Can Dr. Kalu do the closing?
Be my guest.
4-0 NUROLON.
You said you
missed being a surgeon.
If you complete
your residency here,
you can do more than closing.
I doubt he wants to go
from five-star restaurants
to hospital vending machines.
Actually... someone,
um, helped me realize
that I'd love a
second chance here.
The Chief
of Surgery's responsible
for all hiring decisions
in her department.
I've, uh... I've
learned a lot about myself,
how to better communicate,
how to manage challenging
personalities.
Hmm.
I hear Roland can be a handful.
Prepared me for tough patients
and tougher attendings.
And my surgical skills
are still sharp.
Andrews actually let
me do Roland's closing.
I'm impressed.
Murphy really wants you on
his team. That carries weight.
But I don't have any openings
for third-year residents.
I understand.
But I do have a slot
for a first-year.
I-I'm so sorry for your loss.
So our Esther will
always be with me.
Someday,
maybe we can tell her brothers
and sisters all about her.
Oh.
Aw yee...
This car is perfect
for the Peanut.
- And pretty cool, too.
- Aw yee...
Oh, let's take this
rocket ship for a ride.
Oh, man.
Aw yee...
Dr. Andrews.
Here's your check.
And this is what happens
when you poach my employees.
This is so good, especially
after a day like today.
- To our differences.
- Mm.
Mm. If you'll excuse me.
Time to exercise my
reproductive freedom.
I'm doing my third round of IVF.
You're gonna go jab yourself in the
belly alone in the hospital bathroom?
Gimme.
- I am a doctor.
- Mm.
Have at it.
To reuniting with old friends.
And a mommy mocktail
with fresh rosemary.
Yum.
Love having bougie Kalu back.
To Jared...
Mm.
Fulfilling his potential
as my new first-year resident.
Oh, it's probably Glassy.
You Dr. Shaun Murphy?
Yes.
I am an attending surgeon
at San Jose St.
Bonaventure Hospital.
You've just been served.
You're being sued
for malpractice.
It wasn't Dr. Glassman.