Previously, on
"The Resident"...
My husband and I
are adopting.
But the last thing
I'm gonna let
happen is for you to pull
the same vanishing act
- on my kid.
- I'm not going anywhere.
- Just give me another chance.
- I'm willing to watch
and see how you do,
but I see no place for you
at Chastain.
It's Cain.
He's out for revenge.
And your chance for a visa.
You ruining Mina's life
and career
will not heal you, Barrett.
I'm in Atlanta for
my yearly Moyamoya checkup.
I have a surprise for you.
Is that little prince your son?
Uh, it seems you,
Pravesh, could be a father.
There's no way that is my kid.
Nadine would've told me.
Are you sure?
She did say she had a surprise.
- That's the definition of a surprise.
- Wait, wait!
Shh.
When was the last time you spoke to her?
When she went back
to her country, you know,
we spoke every few days.
Then a couple months went by,
and-and then she called and said
she wanted to stop it
and that we should move on.
And I...
and-and she was right.
- Mm.
- What?
Or she stopped because
she was pregnant.
There's no way.
All right? It's been,
what, something like...
ten or 11 months.
How old do you think
that kid is?
I don't... I didn't really get
a good look at him,
but I'd say
three or f-four months.
So, mathematically speaking,
it's within the realm
of possibility.
Oh, my God,
you know...
I-I can't have a kid.
I-I'm a resident.
I have, uh, an apartment
with-with one bedroom.
Nadine and this kid,
they live across the world.
Well, you have to go find out.
No, I-I just need a minute.
Nadine texted earlier
and said that she'd be
at Chastain tomorrow, okay?
So there's time.
Okay.
So you process tonight,
and tomorrow you figure out
whether or not you're a father.
So now I've got Mina Okafor
facing imminent deportation.
And who knows when Barrett Cain
can start operating again,
or if I'll even allow him to?
I'm looking at losing
two of Chastain's best surgeons.
Oh, stop with the ego.
I said "two of the best,"
not "the two best."
Look, I of all people appreciate
the woes of the CEO,
but can we just put
a pin in this?
You should've bought wine.
Look, Jake is a man
who walks the OR by day
and dive music bars by night.
I-I'm confident
he's a whiskey guy.
A nice Bordeaux is
always in style.
Hey, hey. Right on time.
Welcome.
Is that whiskey?
Gregg makes an amazing
whiskey cocktail.
Come on in.
♪ I cannot wait
until the weekend... ♪
Have you spoken to
your immigration lawyer?
Yes. No new information.
Don't they know this is
a time-sensitive situation?
They want my appeal packet ASAP.
But we'll talk about this later.
Come on, they got to know
these things take time.
AJ, please.
Not in front of your parents.
Look, how about this?
Tonight we entertain
the Austins,
tomorrow we divide and conquer.
I'll ask my dad about
his contact at the DOJ.
I have a connection
with Congressman Snyder.
I'll make a call tomorrow.
I'll reach out
to community leaders.
- Letters of recommendation could help.
- Mina,
you know who you have to ask for
those research reports you did
when you were in Nigeria, right?
I'll call my mother tomorrow.
For now,
this conversation is over.
Go. Serve. Smile.
I'm on it.
- And here you go, Dad.
- And for you, Mrs. Austin.
Mmm-mmm.
This is it.
Oh.
So, Gregg made
the changing table by hand.
He spent hours in the garage.
Well, is there anything
you don't have?
Something I could look out for?
Uh, I don't think so.
Baby's due in six weeks.
Think we're all set.
Jake started
getting ready the day
we heard from
the adoption agency.
Oh. The oven timer.
- Shall we?
- Oh, yes. I'm starving.
Chastain PT.
♪ Who you are ♪
♪ Come to life... ♪
Little known fact:
The smaller the weights,
the harder to lift.
Well, if that's the case, you're
outperforming me by a lot.
I was rough on you yesterday.
I'm sorry.
I could've been less rough.
Well, that's true.
- You okay?
- Yeah. Um...
I think that was just
a little too much after all.
You know it's okay
to take things slow.
Rose.
Rose, maybe you should
take a break.
I got you, I got you.
Get transport!
Have to get her to the ER.
*THE RESIDENT*
Season 04  Episode 09
Episode Title:
"Doors Opening, Doors Closing"
*THE RESIDENT*
Aired on: April 13, 2021
She'll need fluids.
And make sure a type and screen
gets sent off with her blood.
Already in the works.
I'll give you two milligrams
of Dilaudid, all right?
You should go back to PT.
I mean, you are
on medical leave.
Rose is my patient.
I got this.
He can stay.
He's a friend.
Hmm.
Didn't know he had those.
Okay, friend...
you can stay.
Rose, we need to run
some more tests, but all signs
point to this being
another sickle cell crisis.
I'm sorry.
I don't know why I said that.
You can go.
You didn't sign up
for a sickle cell marathon.
No, no, I can stay.
At least until
your family gets here.
I don't have any family.
Given your chest pain
and degree of hypoxia,
we need to consider
the possibility
of acute chest syndrome.
I want to order
some additional tests
and admit you,
just to cover all our bases.
Fifth hospitalization this year.
I know.
- You were with Dr. Pravesh last time?
- Yeah.
Will he come by?
He's with other patients
at the moment,
but I'll update him
on your case, okay?
Yes, please. Thank you.
If you need anything, have
any nurse or doctor page me,
and I will get here
as fast as I can.
Ow! Ow!
Dibs.
I can take her.
You don't get dibs
- on every pregnant woman.
- I'm sorry, I said it first.
That's how dibs works.
You're lucky
I'm needed elsewhere.
Fetal Doppler
and ultrasound over here.
Ow! Ow!
- Can you page the OB on call?
- Sure.
And, Hundley.
Keep Nic out of here, okay?
I got you.
Hello. I'm Dr. Hawkins.
When are you due?
Tina Miller. Uh, six weeks.
- It hurts so much.
- I know.
Should be able to get you
something for the pain soon.
Ah, your baby's heart rate
is nice and strong.
Looks like you're doing
a great job caring for it
- even before it's born.
- I'm trying.
Before I ask you
any more questions,
is there a-anyone
I can call for you?
Is this Tina? Tina Miller?
Um, yes.
Do you two know each other?
No, I-I don't know
who that is. Uh...
- Jake, Jake. Gregg.
- Tina.
Hey. We're here.
Y-You're gonna be fine, honey.
Thank you so much for coming.
- Where's the OB?
- Uh, we just paged her.
Tina, look at
me. I know it hurts.
Let's breathe through it, okay?
This is Dr. Bell.
He's my stepfather.
Hi. Uh, thanks for raising him.
I've done so much wrong.
That's how I ended up here.
But the one thing I got right
was picking Jake and Gregg.
They've been amazing.
Please. You are doing
the hard work here, okay?
As long as y'all are here.
And how close
are the contractions?
She's not having contractions.
Tina's not in labor.
Devon.
Nadine.
This is Azad.
Azad...
Is he...?
Wow, you should
see your face right now.
Sit.
Devon, no.
He's not yours.
He's only two months old.
Wow. Well, sorry, you said
that I would be surprised,
and I am.
- That was fast.
- I know.
When I got home, my father
literally had a man waiting
to meet me when
I stepped off the plane.
So you married him?
No. No.
He was old and rich
and terrible.
I said, "No
more," but my father didn't listen,
and the next man,
he made more sense.
Well, Azad, he's...
...he's beautiful.
Thank you.
I love him so much.
But I'll be honest.
When I first got back home,
I thought about you a lot.
But I got through it,
and I'm hoping you did the same.
I'm hoping you found
someone amazing.
You know how it is.
I've been busy, and just...
Not a lot of time, you know.
Well, I have a full day
of scans and bloodwork
and appointments,
but this was nice.
Maybe we can catch up
more later?
- Text me if you have time.
- Uh, will do.
Well, that's disappointing.
You had the perfect opportunity
to tell her
you were dating
a contessa or something.
- Well, that would be a lie.
- Whatever.
I think you're disappointed
it's not your baby.
You would've liked
having a little Prince Pravesh.
I don't need a royal infant.
What I need is
some stability in my life.
Oh, and by the way, that date
that you engineered for me
last night was terrible.
She was uninsured and looking
for free medical advice.
Sorry about that.
My night was great,
thanks for asking.
I locked down
our elopement venue.
- Amazing. Where?
- Eloping means it's a secret.
And you're sure you don't want
your best friend there?
Eloping also means it's private.
All right, well, look,
I really hope
to celebrate
with you guys properly.
And someday I hope to go
on a date with a woman
who isn't looking
for free medical care.
Wrong way.
Dude, I'm doing
the best I can do.
No, that.
Hi, there. I'm Dr. Pravesh.
- Myra.
- Hi, Myra.
This is Dr. Feldman.
Tell us what happened.
What happened is the nice lady
in the ambulance
gave me a shot of the good stuff
and now I'm flying high.
Pain meds will do that.
But what happened to get you
into the ambulance?
Right, that.
Well, I was cruising along,
doing a little business,
and bam.
I'm upside down with this.
What do you mean,
"doing business"?
Mm, fine, I was texting.
But only because
it was an emergency.
- Nothing is that urgent.
- Oh. So says a person
who isn't
in the business of love.
One of my clients
was trying to cancel a date,
and Matchmaker Myra
does not let cold feet
stop eternal happiness.
I set up marriages between
Indian Americans in Atlanta.
You don't say.
Stop.
Please. I'm all over this.
No ring,
a faint look of desperation.
- You're available.
- He definitely is.
No, he's not. Myra,
before we can fix your arm,
we need to order a CT
to make sure
that you didn't damage
anything more serious, okay?
Okay.
We'll be back.
- Bye-bye.
This is fate. This is kismet.
This is the universe
working to help you
- never go on another bad date.
- No.
That is texting while driving.
I don't want to be set up.
So, what do you
think? Ovarian torsion?
Appendicitis?
Uh, the symptoms
are nonspecific.
Uh, guys, I need someone
to speak human, not doctor.
Tina has gallstones.
That's why you're in pain.
Will she be okay?
Well, she has slight gallbladder
wall thickening
with pericholecystic fluid.
Acute cholecystitis.
Again, human please.
So, your gallbladder is showing
early signs of infection.
And normally we would just
take it out in the OR.
What about the baby?
That's what
makes this complicated.
Any surgery, even routine,
is a risk for the baby.
What about an, uh, IR perc tube?
Not an option at the moment
with the recent staff cuts.
Okay, uh, if we treat
with antibiotics,
we could potentially get her
through this and then
go into surgery
after she delivers in six weeks.
Uh, but if-if you don't respond
and you worsen,
then we'd be taking you
to surgery in much worse shape.
So I put the baby in danger
to save myself
or I put myself in danger
to save the baby.
What do I do?
I will talk you through
all your options
so you can make
an informed decision, okay?
And we'll be here.
Whatever you decide.
Can we call your parents
for you?
No. No.
No, don't-don't call my parents.
I'm 19 and I can do this
by myself, okay?
O-Of course you can.
You guys don't have to be here.
I-I'm sure you have busy lives.
Stop. Uh, there is nowhere else
we'd rather be than right here.
I got it.
You're eloping
at the Four Seasons.
Too expensive.
Four Seasons Total Landscaping?
Really?
I'm just saying,
I'm a really good witness.
Yeah. No.
Myra, your CT results are in.
You got lucky.
A few broken ribs,
but... but nothing major.
Oh. That's why my chest hurts.
All the nerves
and vessels in your arm
are intact, so we can reduce it
and put it back right here.
But don't worry,
we're gonna numb you first.
You shouldn't feel any pain
when we put your arm
back in place, all right?
Oh.
I want to admit you overnight
for observation, okay?
Fine. I'll distract myself
by observing you
to see if you're worthy
of my matchmaking skills.
I don't need matchmaking.
How did your parents meet?
- Well...
- Allow me.
It was an arranged marriage.
They were blissfully in love
and produced the bright
but stubborn doctor
you see before you.
They were lucky
and it was a different time.
Now, let's focus
on getting your arm
back to where it belongs.
- I'm not ready. I need a minute.
- No thinking.
- One, two, three.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Ow!
Ooh.
That, uh, wasn't so bad.
Seems like the anticipation
was worse than the actual event.
A bit like getting match-made.
What happened?
Tina's infection
is getting worse,
and the IV antibiotics
aren't working.
Tina, we'll take
good care of you.
Yeah, and we'll see you just as
soon as you're out of surgery.
Jake, I know you've told
a thousand families
their loved one
is in good hands.
- It's time for you to trust that.
- Okay.
- I got her.
Let's find you two
a place to get some fresh air.
How are you feeling?
Like the pain meds are working.
You didn't have to stay.
You don't have anyone else here.
Well, I'm grateful you're here.
Being alone for this,
it sucks.
Yeah.
Sickle cell can be a nightmare.
I know that firsthand.
A patient?
It was a friend of mine
in medical school.
You know, he was a great guy.
Best person I ever knew.
What happened to him?
- Oh. I'm-I'm sorry.
- No, no.
I shouldn't have even
brought it up.
Just that you remind me
of him a little bit.
Right, because of the whole
impending death thing.
No, no.
It's your compassion.
The way you handle yourself
with such grace,
even through the pain.
You know,
medicine has come a long way
since he was
fighting sickle cell.
Yeah, that's why I keep going.
You know, possibility for
new discoveries on the horizon.
Got to keep your hope up
and all of that.
My stomach.
- Her heart rate is spiking.
- Rose, I got you.
Up the pain meds.
We'll get you to CT.
Are you sure
we can't call Tina's parents?
Uh, to be honest,
we're-we're not actually sure
she told them she's pregnant.
She doesn't talk about them.
We get the feeling
there's a rift.
Yeah, and legally,
she's an adult,
so we have to respect
her wishes.
I can't imagine my children
feeling like
they couldn't tell me
if they were in trouble.
- Why is it taking so long?
- Hey, hey.
No news can be a good sign.
Tell you what.
Why don't I go and see
if I can find out
how it's going, okay?
Thanks.
Her blood pressure's dropping.
What's happening with the baby?
Baby's heart rate's
all over the place.
Oh, signs of fetal distress.
We need OB in here now!
Oh, Tina's gallbladder's
adhered to the wall.
Get ready for an open surgery.
Scalpel.
We've got to get
this baby out now.
- I can get it done in two minutes.
- She's starting to brady.
Okay, we don't have two minutes.
Suction.
More sponges.
How much longer?
Seconds.
She's bottoming out.
Almost there, almost there.
The cord's around
the baby's neck.
We've lost the mother's pulse.
Damn it.
I'm starting compressions.
Baby's clear.
She's not breathing.
Give her one of epi, fast.
And save that baby!
Baby's in the NICU.
And doing great.
Thank you.
Fine work, sir.
You saved two lives today.
- Hey. Is everything all right?
- How is she?
There were complications.
Tina coded. Dr. Bell had to call
OB for an emergency C-section.
Oh, God.
Dr. Bell saved her.
She's in ICU recovering,
and you have a beautiful
six-pound baby girl.
They're both okay.
Yes.
Oh!
Congratulations.
- Myra.
- Oh.
- How are you feeling?
- All things considered, fine.
And I've been
asking around about you.
- Oh, is that so?
- Mm, your coworkers have a lot to say.
And since it's 98% positive,
and you've taken
such good care of me,
I've decided to give you
a freebie.
I will find the future
Mrs. Pravesh.
I really do
appreciate the offer.
Seriously. But no thank you.
It would be a distraction
from the pain.
Don't you think that's
a healthy thing, Dr. Pravesh?
Besides, my intuition
and ability to read people
is so spot-on
that I already know
how this is going to end:
You will say yes.
So let's save time
and get started.
- What's your type?
- I don't have a type. I don't...
Yes, he has a type.
Dr. Pravesh's type
is "unavailable."
Either emotionally,
geographically or both.
Interesting.
Next question.
When your
last relationship ended,
what did you feel
you were missing out on?
Oh, I got this one.
A baby.
I'm sorry,
Irving tells me everything.
I hope that little girl
knows how lucky she is.
She won't. They never do.
Her name's Lucy.
Look who just became "Gramps."
I think I like it.
My situation is not good.
Okay, well...
Got a ton of e-mails
coming in from the community.
- I can get more...
- Come on. Let's sit down.
My attorney filed for an appeal,
but it will be months before
a decision is made either way.
Visa expires next week.
So we fight
and we continue to fight.
But if it doesn't work,
I'll be deported.
Then it will be
very unlikely for me
to be able to return
to the country.
If I go to Nigeria
on my own accord,
I could apply to return
in the future.
But it's not a guarantee.
No.
It's not.
Which is why I need for you
to prepare for the worst.
Your patient Rose has
a splenic sequestration.
It's starting to infarct.
We got to get this
out of her right away.
Well, that's not gonna be easy.
She's been transfused
so many times
her body destroys
everything we give her.
She can't take
any more transfusions.
You're giving me
a patient who needs
an extremely bloody surgery
and asking me
not to spill any blood?
Yep.
Got it.
A few more hours and
Rose's spleen would have ruptured.
I don't think
a sickle cell patient
would have survived
that complication.
All right, careful.
We don't want to lose
even a few drops of blood.
You forget who
you're operating with.
I'll drop even less than I did
with the traumatic
aortic rupture patient
we had earlier this year.
Yeah, that was
a rough one, but not as bad
as the IVC tear from
the stab wound last month.
Mm.
And yet, we made it work.
We always make it work.
Ever since
our first surgery together.
Although you had a hissy fit
when I asked
for Cooley scissors.
Oh, well, now, hold up.
I wouldn't quite call it
a hissy fit.
I would describe it
as struggling to find the words,
since only a prima donna would
ask for something so specific
that early in their training.
But we both know
who the prima donna
turned out to be.
"Are You Even Real?"
by James Blake playing...
I want you to know
that you have made me
a better surgeon.
Well, don't let it get around,
but I feel the same.
And I am a better person
because of you.
And, you know,
the best part of it all
is our journey has only begun,
Mina Okafor.
♪ Dream of connection ♪
♪ Tell me how you feel,
tell me how you feel ♪
♪ Are you even real?
Are you even real? ♪
Voilà.
♪ Tell me how you feel ♪
Perfection.
♪ Are you even real? ♪
Oh, this looks good.
So, we're not gonna get you up
and walking right away,
but it'll be soon, okay?
O-Oh, no.
My roommate told my parents,
and now they're on their way
up from the lobby.
This is so, so bad.
Well, I'm sure they've been
worried about you.
- Uh...
- Tina,
do your parents know
that you were pregnant?
Y-Yeah.
They-they were upset,
like, really upset.
Only way I could
calm them down was by saying
I would give the baby
to a good family.
A-A good... traditional family.
You don't understand.
Getting pregnant by accident
and going through with it,
it was the hardest thing
I've ever done, but...
you guys made me feel like
I wasn't a screwup,
like all of this had
a purpose and a meaning.
My mom and dad won't
understand any of that.
And it's not just that they'll
stop paying for my life.
They... they won't want
to see me anymore.
Well, maybe they're more
open-minded than you think.
They're not.
I-I know that makes them sound
terrible, but they're my parents.
And I can't lose them,
so one of you has to go.
Um, a-and maybe the other one,
someone could pretend to be your wife?
Just-just while they're here.
You know, coming out
in the South,
and living in the, in the open
like this...
...it's great now,
but it wasn't...
wasn't always this easy.
We're not gonna start
her life with a lie.
Are you okay?
- Honey, we're here now.
- I'm fine.
Uh, Mom and Dad, uh,
th-this is Dr. Bell.
Uh, he-he saved my life.
Your daughter's a real fighter.
We can't thank you enough.
Who are these men?
They are the adoptive fathers.
I'm sorry?
What?
Well, you're...
you're making progress.
What can I do for you, Hawkins?
Your friend Rose came through
surgery with flying colors.
Dr. Austin and Dr. Okafor...
...they were brilliant.
I'm glad to hear it.
Losing Mina would be
a real blow to Chastain.
And to a lot of us personally.
You do get that
she came at me first, right?
I did what I had to do.
You didn't have to do anything.
It went further than it should
have, I will give you that.
But I'm not alone in this.
Okafor shares
some of that blame.
Whatever lets you sleep
at night.
I'm sorry, but...
we can't let you have this baby.
Dad, please, Jake and Gregg have
been with me through everything.
Prenatal visits, ultrasounds.
They already named her.
You two seem like nice men.
It's not personal,
but we don't agree with
the lifestyle you've chosen.
We haven't chosen anything.
This is who we are.
Just like your daughter
is who she was born to be.
And she's perfect.
Our daughter obviously
has different values than we do.
And we hope that that will
change when she grows up
and matures a little bit.
In our family,
we believe in traditional values
and structure.
Tina will have to accept that
if she wants to continue
being a part of it.
So if I give them the baby...
...you really will
kick me out of our family?
Uh, you weren't here today,
so you didn't... you didn't see
what we witnessed.
Uh, Jake and Gregg held this
little girl for the first time.
And they've-they've hoped and
they planned and they've waited.
And I don't know
if you've heard the saying
that children and parents
are born on the same day...
...but today,
we saw that happen.
That love.
And it's-it's the same love
that you felt the first time
you held Tina.
Isn't that the most important
thing here?
Let love be what guides you.
And let that little girl go home
to the family
that already wants her
and to the parents
who already love her.
I know you love the ocean.
Almost as much as I love you.
- It's even prettier at night.
- Yeah.
It's incredible.
I knew you'd think it's perfect.
We had a big public engagement,
and now we'll have
the most private wedding.
It's kind of like us.
We love big crowds and parties
and game nights, but...
We also love quiet nights
at home on the couch.
Just the two of us.
I never doubted you.
You know what's the best part?
- You in that dress?
- Yes.
But also, this will always
be our place.
Even when we visit the aquarium
with all the tourists,
we'll have this secret about
what it means, and I love that.
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
Are you two ready?
Jessica, you want to do
this thing?
100%.
All right. Marry us up.
Okay, you're all set, then.
Dr. Kingsley, call Dr. Braun...
Hey.
I was hoping I'd see you again.
- How'd the tests go?
- Everything looks good.
They'll see me back in a year.
- Walk me out?
- I'd love to.
So, I actually have
a question for you.
Mm?
Um, I mean,
you just seem so happy.
Was it weird having your father
choose a husband for you?
What's this about?
There's this matchmaker here
who wants to set me up
with someone.
Okay. I get it now.
You want to know what
an arranged marriage looks like
in this day and age.
- Mm.
- It's like any other marriage.
My father made the introduction
but I didn't have to say yes.
And now I can't imagine
a world where I didn't.
Because you fell in love.
I did.
And if your matchmaker
is good at her job,
you might, too.
So what have you got to lose?
Yes. See? I knew you'd do it.
Okay, so, uh, what's the process
like? What's the timeline?
Your to-do list: Send me three
hobbies, three favorite movies
- and an example of what makes you laugh.
- What? Why?
Also submit shirt and jacket
photos for my approval.
Those eyes?
I'd go with warm colors.
My to-do list:
Look for women who don't mind
a slightly uptight type,
contact your mother...
Wait, hold on. What does
my mom have to do with this?
It's traditional for parents
to be at the first meeting
of a prospective couple.
Don't worry,
first you'll look at the photos
and résumés I send you.
My email address.
Contact me
when you've done everything.
- I'm not uptight.
- Please.
You're still here.
I work here.
Or at least, I'm trying
to get back to a place
where I can again.
Just wanted to stop by
and check on you before I go.
I think you should sit down.
No, I'm-I'm fine.
I'm saying I'd like the company.
I guess I should
thank you for today.
Thank me?
I didn't do anything,
except scream
and need help and cause
everyone a lot of extra work.
No, you reminded me
that I should keep hope alive.
- I needed to hear that.
- Yeah?
Well, I needed someone
to pick me off the floor
and haul me into the ER,
so... I guess we're even.
That's fair.
I'm only resting.
You stay in that chair.
I'm not going anywhere.
- Ready to go?
- Yes, but first,
what do you think about
lavender bisque or...
strawberry brûlée or...
- sea-foam margaritas?
- Is this your dinner plan?
No, paint names.
Huh?
Turns out baby room colors
are very therapeutic.
It's weird, I know.
Ridiculous names, okay colors.
Well, our baby girl needs
a pretty nursery, right?
Yeah, she does.
You're still worried about Mina.
Yeah.
She is lucky to have you.
Well, I'm lucky to have her.
And you.
Let's go.
Is there anything we can do?
No.
The adoption agency
confirmed it.
We can't have her.
Yeah, uh, Lucy...
I mean, Tina's baby will go
to a traditional family.
I'm so sorry.
Our baby's still out there.
We just don't know
who he or she is yet.
Uh, we did the right thing.
Ah.
There she is,
just in time to celebrate.
- Celebrate what?
- Well,
I just hung up with my mother,
and, well,
there's no surprise here,
but she and my dad
absolutely love you.
So...
I'm thinking Italian.
I'm thinking champagne.
I'm thinking a little
fireplace action.
I spoke to my mother, too.
Finally. All right, great.
What'd she say?
Um, she had been working
in the OR for hours today.
There aren't enough
Nigerian surgeons.
The system is crumbling
and people are dying.
Yeah.
- It's terrible.
- Mm-hmm.
It's because
good Nigerian surgeons leave.
They come to America.
Like me.
I am part of the problem.
I thought about
sending supplies,
starting an outreach program,
but none of it is enough.
My mother won't always
be able to sustain
this many surgeries a day.
- She'll need help.
- Yeah.
We'll find her help.
- We'll find mentors in the area.
- No.
- No. No.
- We will find her help.
- We can find her...
- AJ, AJ, AJ, no.
This is the answer
to my visa problem.
It's the answer to everything.
I don't want to fight anymore.
Leave on my own
before I can be deported.
I'm going back to Nigeria.
♪ I ♪
♪ Get like this every time ♪
♪ On these days
that feel like you and me ♪
♪ Heartbreak anniversary ♪
♪ Do you ever think of me? ♪
I'm coming with you.
♪ 'Cause I think of you ♪
♪ Think of you. ♪
Captioning sponsored by
20th CENTURY FOX TELEVISION
and TOYOTA.
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org