When I was in second grade.
This girl Misie,
could cross her leg
behind her head like
a pretzel.
And one day
her leg just popped.
And then it was lying there,
behind her.
My mother said,
"Stop crying.
It was just
an anterior hip dislocation."
Then she said something
I've never forgotten.
- Mm...
- Nope.
♪ Save it
for the sake of the fight ♪
"Just because
you can do something..."
"..doesn't mean you should."
♪ Copy/paste the child inside ♪
♪ You used to smile,
but now you are staged ♪
- Hey.
- ♪ I hate to watch you walk away ♪
Hey.
Did you spend the night here
again last night?
Yeah. One of the lambs
had a rough night.
I... I really need some of that.
It's actually for you.
It's a peace offering.
I guess I was wrong
about your dad,
and... it's none of my business.
- No, it's... it's not that...
- I'm just...
I'm glad it's going well.
- I appreciate that.
- Yeah.
And I really appreciate this.
Do you have a minute?
♪ Save it for the sake of
our love ♪
I missed you.
♪ Raise a hand to show  ♪
- ♪ that you're strong ♪
- You're not mad at me?
♪ You used to smile,
but now you are shunned ♪
So, if I was to stay at my place
one night this week,
would you care to join me?
♪ I hate to watch you walk alone ♪
That's the best idea
I've ever heard.
I'll try to figure it out.
♪ Is this how
you're gonna grow old? ♪
I really should get to work.
♪ Is this how
you're gonna grow old? ♪
And you should get
some sleep, Doctor.
♪ Is this how you're gonna grow old? ♪
Don't forget your coffee.
I'm already wide awake.
Keep your cuts straight.
You want to go
into the dermis.
Stay as shallow
as we can.
Wonder if the guys
at Pike Street Market
went to four years of
medical school.
Hey. So...
I think I should cancel
this thing tomorrow.
Oh, my God.
Honestly, I don't even
smell it anymore.
I do.
Yeah, I-I'm not going on
"Good Morning Seattle."
A podcast was one thing,
but television?
Plus, it's not even
about medicine anymore.
It's... It's "Genius surgeon finds out
she's the illegitimate love-child
of other genius surgeons."
I'm morning show fodder.
You're in the genius surgeon
segment, okay?
It's not like you're going in
there to make French toast.
No, that would be the worst
segment in the world.
They'd just be watching me
fishing around
looking for eggshells
with my fingers.
Yet I would still pay
to see that.
So you're saying
I shouldn't cancel it?
I'm saying it shoots tomorrow,
and it's too late to cancel.
Don't be nervous. You're gonna do great.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Why are your interns making sushi?
- Well...
- Oh, is this your thing?
Well, I have to get out of here.
I can't go on TV
smelling like fish.
Why can't we practice
on cadavers?
Formaldehyde smells nicer.
This is not
or your scalpel technique.
It's not?
Then why?
This is why.
Oh, that's...
- Ohh.
- Fantastic.
Hey, Rick.
We're making fish people.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 15  Episode 17
Episode Title: "And Dream of Sheep"
It is very disturbing.
Have y-you seen it?
The little laminated lambs
kicking in their little bags.
- It's pretty amazing, huh?
- When I look
at the fetal lamb in a bag,
I imagine the next step would
be a fetal human in a bag.
And if anything
goes wrong with that,
we are in an ethical
and legal quagmire
that you created and will have
left me holding the... quag.
That's funny, but I imagine
rewriting the paradigm
of at-risk pregnancies,
- saving premature babies.
- Ohh.
And he's a long way
from human trials.
And are you sure it's good
to go down this road?
I mean, I'm hearing things
about this Dr. DeLuca
having a history
of mental illness...
We should discriminate
against people for that?
Of course not.
But we should ask questions
when they start putting babies
in bags.
Bailey, my mom came out
here by herself.
She's been in my apartment
for over a week...
No routine, no being chained
to a library desk.
And even if Dr. DeLuca does
suffer from mental illness,
we need to support people...
Hellmouth, what?
Hi, hello.
Sorry. Uh, hi.
I, uh, was wondering
if you might
want to take a stroll
by Dr. DeLuca Sr.'s lab...
Or, more specifically,
you should...
You should do that.
Speaking Italian...
Excuse me.
Did you call
the headmaster now?
What's the problem?
He lost a lamb.
One subject expired.
A minor setback,
to be expected.
We think that it...
Babies die in womb
all the time.
Papa,
you're working very fast.
Y-You are too impatient.
Hey!
You don't like the way I work,
you can get out.
I'm not saying that I...
Go!
I will miss your bold vision.
You, who chose a career
helping women have babies...
A thing she can do by herself
since the dawn of time.
Go.
♪♪
Capo.
Something needed?
♪♪
Quagmire.
- Hey.
- Where have you been?
I paged you like
15 minutes ago.
I think you meant to say,
"Thank you for covering me
when me and my boyfriend
went away for four days."
I meant to say you're late.
I ran into trouble
with Leo this morning,
and Amelia's
at a conference.
Actually, Amelia's...
out of the picture,
which is...
You know, Amelia, she would
sometimes help with Leo,
but this morning,
it was all me.
Not that it matters,
you know?
I can handle Leo on my own.
I do just fine.
I didn't say anything.
Hey.
MVC rollover,
male in his 20s,
possible fractured clavicle...
Stable vitals.
His wife's next door.
You should see her first.
I'll see you in Trauma 2.
Paramedic: Lizzie Hall, 22,
oriented to person
on the scene,
pressure's in the 90s,
GCS 13 in the field.
All right.
Trauma 1, let's go.
Leo and I are great,
just me and him.
I'm great with him, okay?
I didn't say anything.
Suddenly, I feel like
I'm auditioning to be a father.
Excuse me.
Is this the, uh, line?
- Hey.
- Hey!
What are you doing here?
Uh...
Well,
like the banners say,
Western States Conference
for Alternative Pain Relief.
Right. I didn't, uh... didn't
know you were into this stuff.
Yeah, I'm not.
I mean, I'm interested,
ever since that day
with the mass overdose.
Yeah. Tough day.
Yes.
I cried at you,
convulsively.
You might recall.
I haven't seen you around
much since then.
Yeah, that was intentional.
It's hard to know where
to go after that.
Anyway, I'm, uh, newly into it.
How about you?
Uh, I do, like,
three of these a year, yeah.
I'm giving a lecture.
Wow.
W-When is that?
Tomorrow.
Uh, but right now, I was gonna
hit up this acupuncture demo.
Interested?
Uh, well, I'm headed to this
next-generation NSAIDs panel.
But... no, you know what?
I think I'd rather get poked.
With needles.
Never mind.
I'm gonna keep avoiding you.
Have a nice time.
Okay.
Oh, my God.
Sir, do you have any pain
when I do this? No, I don't.
Great.
C-spine's cleared.
You paged?
Left clavicular fracture
and a possible fracture
of the distal humerus.
Hey, is my wife okay?
She is right next door.
- She's being...
- What about my baby?
- She's...
- Is my baby all right?
They didn't bring a baby in.
Was there a baby in the car?
No, no, my, um...
My wife, um, she's...
She's... ow.
She's five months pregnant.
Oh.
Um, Schmitt, you can start
on these abrasions.
Um, I'm gonna be right back,
okay?
Okay.
I'm doing a central line.
Lidocaine.
Hey.
Switch with me.
- What? I'm just about to do...
- She's pregnant.
Five months.
Switch with me,
and you can take the husband.
I'm fine.
Page OB.
She's pregnant.
And get
an ultrasound, please.
Okay.
Figure out
why the lamb died,
write a report,
and I'll review it.
Look, I'll talk to Papa
about getting you back
on the research project,
all right?
I don't want back
on this project.
Andrea, stop pretending
you don't see it.
These swings... he's up, he's
down, he's funny, he's cruel.
He is bipolar.
He refuses to acknowledge it,
and now you are, too.
I'm being paged
to The Hole.
- The Pit.
- Go.
This is an important project,
but my father...
Is the one who
brought it here.
Could ruin it
if you let him.
Is that your take?
Look, he's not easy.
H-He's never been easy.
But neither is my sister,
and she doesn't have
the right degree
to diagnose him.
The two of them, they...
They do this.
Always have.
Get me that report.
Neuro resident to the ER.
Maggie, you're adopted.
Yeah, I'd heard that.
And good morning.
I know. Sorry, um...
I was just wondering,
did you ever
get your DNA tested?
Have you met me?
I battered myself
with tests.
I-I wanted to know
everything.
My DNA results.
I don't want
to open them alone,
but I don't want
to open them with Alex
and have to watch his face
if he discovers that his wife
is a genetic lemon.
I'm your girl.
Look, I know this can be scary.
But I promise,
whatever we find...
Ugh, what stinks in here?
That's me, sorry.
I washed my hands, but...
All right, you ready?
Mm-hmm.
Alzheimer's, no.
- Okay.
- Huntington's, no.
Parkinson's, no.
Congratulations.
You won the genetic lottery.
It says here
I'm mostly British.
Congrats.
I got a patient.
Dr. Sussman to Peds ICU.
Oh, my...
"You are comparing
with Martha Tomlinson."
It's probable that
Martha Tomlinson
"is your first cousin."
I have a cousin.
Do you want me to find her?
How would you do that?
Start with a Web search,
then Facebook, Instagram,
then an exhaustive search
of various consumer
databases...
No, no, no, no!
I don't want that!
No, that's...
that's creepy.
It's all legal.
No.
Okay, but
if you could find her,
could you also find out
who she's related to?
Could you find
her mother or...
- Or your mother?
- No!
I didn't say do it.
Oh.
Okay.
Hello again.
You want me to move?
- No, of course not.
- Shhh!
Oh, God.
What does this do?
The frequencies respond
to the energy meridians
and, uh,
- resonate...
- "Energy meridians."
Oh, my God.
Shh!
You're not
supposed to talk.
Yeah, I'm not supposed
to be here.
Free fluid in her abdomen.
Fetal heartbeat is good.
Baby?
Hey, Lizzie.
You with us?
I'm Dr. Altman.
You're bleeding
from your abdomen,
and I need to find
where it's coming from.
My baby's okay?
Your baby's great,
Lizzie.
Strong heartbeat, moving,
no signs of distress.
Yes, but...
It was a surprise.
We were gonna wait,
like, five years.
We just got married,
but when we found out,
we were just like, "Yay!"
All right, Lizzie.
You sit tight.
Can I talk to you outside
for a minute, please? Yeah.
I know you're seeing
a healthy baby,
but I'm seeing a mother
with a belly full of blood,
and to save her, I might
have to remove her uterus
along with the baby.
The baby's no more
than 21 weeks.
- It cannot survive outside...
- I know.
And I have to tell her now,
and you just made it so much
harder for her to hear.
So please keep your mouth shut
and check with me
if you need to talk to her
again, all right?
I-I-I'm sorry.
Brazil's been using
tilapia skin to treat burns
for years now...
Decrease the scarring,
costs nothing compared
to standard treatments,
and it just peels away.
Incredible.
My interns stink.
Yeah, and with its restorative
properties...
It smells like high tide.
Patients are complaining,
and I do not enjoy breathing
through my mouth.
Explain.
It's part of my spray-on
skin research.
He made us skin the fish.
Well, what do you do with
the other parts of the fish?
Oh, that's medical waste.
Well, that's a crime.
What... What is it? Uh.
Oh, that looks like
tilapia.
Yeah, that's good fish.
Lambs in a bag,
fish skin on people.
I mean, what's next here?
Next is the machines come to
life and take over the world.
Never mind.
Dr. Gennis to the ER.
Dr. Ed Gennis to the ER.
Mrs. Karev?
Hello.
D... Uh, I'm, uh,
Dr. Miranda Bailey.
I was Alex's chief resident
when he first came here.
Oh, my gosh. Hi. It's so...
I'm happy to meet you.
Here. Sit, please.
Oh, thank you.
Wow. You must be proud,
Alex making it all the way
to chief of the hospital.
Mmmmmm.
So, what are you
knitting here?
Well, it was a scarf
that became a sweater,
and then I just kind of
kept going, and now it's...
Oh.
Now it's...
It's maybe a car cover.
Alex said you'd
extended your stay,
so you must be having
a good time.
I don't travel much.
And, uh, I'm glad I did it,
but it's been a lot for me.
I'm a little nervous about
making the trip back.
Oh, I see.
Um, have you told
- Alex or...?
- No.
No, they've both been so great,
Jo and Alex.
I-I...
They're just so busy.
I'll feel better.
I will.
I'm just so ready
to be home.
Hey. How is she?
Hey. Um...
Stable, for now.
Uh, so, before
the husband wakes up,
I just wanted to
get the update.
Their baby is...?
Right where they left it.
What?
Yeah. The CT showed
that the bleed
was coming from the right
uterine artery, so I embolized.
And the baby's blood supply
is coming from the left side.
She seems happy with it.
Teddy, you saved
their baby.
Well, we'll see.
I mean, I hope she
doesn't re-bleed. Mm.
- How's the husband?
- Oh, he...
Fractured clavicle, a small
humerus fracture.
He's gonna be fine.
Go home. Get sleep.
No, I'm gonna stay
in case.
I-I want to make sure
all three leave together.
I'll do that.
I'll stay.
No.
You need to get sleep,
and the baby needs sleep.
So, go and... I don't know...
Have Koracick rub your feet.
Owen...
She's my patient.
And Tom is at Hopkins
for the week.
I'll be fine.
I'm just... I'm gonna...
I'm gonna sleep
right here.
Hey.
Go.
Okay.
Well, I mean,
if you're gonna sit there...
Hm?
You could rub my feet.
Really?
You brought it up.
- ♪ White frost on the horizon ♪
- Okay.
♪ I lost nearly my mind ♪
- ♪ Having no one beside me but pining ♪
- Did that make you feel dizzy, the sound?
- Like... Like loopy?
- ♪ I bear the loss ♪
No, it just kind of
chilled me out.
I-I feel like
I need a meeting.
- Whew!
- ♪ Having let Mother Nature define me ♪
Hey, could we sit
for a sec, you think?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Let's just find someplace to...
- Okay.
- ♪ We paid the cost ♪
♪ Isn't it a pity
what's lost... ♪
Sorry. I'm falling
apart here.
- ♪ ...in the meridian of time? ♪
- You don't need to apologize.
- ♪ It's your touch ♪
- I had a foster kid.
♪ It's your touch ♪
Sort of.
- ♪ It's you ♪
- Betty...
Um, she was an addict
and a runaway,
and I took her in and...
♪ White frost on the horizon ♪
Tried to help her
get clean
- and... tried and tried and...
- ♪ I once covered our heart ♪
And I tried
some more and...
- ♪ Having no even temper confided ♪
- And then her parents came back,
- and she went back with them.
- ♪ I bear the loss ♪
- ♪ I'd been living a nation divided ♪
- And I miss her.
- ♪ Deeper the cost ♪
- And I don't know if she's okay.
And I don't know
if she'll be okay.
- ♪ Summon the committee ♪
- And I don't feel done.
- ♪ We still vote with an aye ♪
- You sound like...
- ♪ It's your touch ♪
- A mess?
- A parent.
♪ It's you ♪
My mom cried
for like three months
after I went away to college,
and I wasn't a drug addict.
♪ It's your touch ♪
- Thank you.
- ♪ It's you ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
- My God.
- ♪ Ooh ♪
- You are just chiseled.
- ♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
Like a statue.
It's like your chin has muscles.
Yeah, well, I do work out
my chin pretty hard.
It takes a whole day.
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ I've been living
a nation divided ♪
♪ We bear the loss ♪
I should go to my room.
- And I should go...
- ♪ Having let Mother Nature define me ♪
To your room.
- ♪ Deeper the cost ♪
- To my room.
You have a presentation
tomorrow,
- and I am not fit for human contact.
- ♪ It's your touch ♪
♪ It's your touch ♪
- ♪ It's you ♪
- See you in the morning? - Yeah.
Night.
Gonna...
Teddy. Teddy!
What?
- What is it?
- Her BP bottomed out.
Baby's monitor
is showing decels.
Okay. I'm giving her
two units of blood,
and her pressure
is coming back up.
All right.
Book an OR!
Get ready for...
If I can't stop
the bleeding,
I'm gonna have to take
her uterus out.
- Yeah. Do you want me to do it?
- Owen, stop it...
Teddy, I'm not saying
that you can't.
I'm just saying
you don't have to.
I know you feel you should be,
but you don't have to be there
if this woman
loses her baby.
Thank you. I'm okay.
You could get
the father in here
- so we can tell them what's going on.
- Okay.
Add, uh, 1 liter of lactated
Ringer's, please.
Okay.
Your sister
has turned on me.
Papa, nobody's
turned on you, okay?
But you need to learn
how to control your temper.
People are getting
concerned about you,
and I'm trying to
back you up here.
But I can't if you
keep throwing tantrums.
Okay. I'll call her here.
We'll talk like a family.
No, no, no. Papa, no.
Not now.
I just spoke to her.
She needs some time.
Plus, she's got
this pregnant trauma patient
who might lose her baby,
so just let her be.
Why?
Why is she going to
lose this baby?
I'm here. My
embolization didn't work.
The baby is in
severe distress.
We have to save
the mother.
I'm gonna go up now,
and I may need your help
to do an emergency
hysterectomy.
- Does she know?
- I just got the husband here,
and I'm gonna tell
them both now.
- I can help.
- Great. Thank you.
But the baby
can't survive yet.
I can keep it safe
and sound outside the mother,
but inside a simulated womb,
where it can develop,
while your wife gets
the care and surgery
she needs to survive.
What's going on?
Papa.
You can save the baby?
You can save us both?
Yes, I can.
Morning!
- Sleep well?
- Yeah.
Yeah, it was
a good idea to...
Sleep is so important
for the, um...
- Brain?
- Sure.
When... What...
What are you doing today?
Uh, I was gonna check out
Logan's Nerve Block talk.
- Oh, me too.
- Perfect.
Yeah, but when
is your thing?
Uh, you d... you don't
want to go to that.
Of course I do!
But first, coffee.
Which is not in my room.
There's coffee in my room.
Nope!
Dr. Nasraban, 4521.
Dr. Ethan Nasraban, 4521.
Grey, you're being creepy.
I'm creepy?
They're calling you
the ruler of Atlantis.
Yeah, well, I mean,
it's pretty cool.
Tilapia skin's
rich in collagen,
which promotes healing.
No more need for painful
dressing changes.
I'm looking to apply
a lot of those properties
to my spray-on skin.
Ooh, the spray-on skin
is back?
Well, your boyfriend is putting
lambs in zip-lock bags.
He can't be the only one
changing the world, you know?
He's not my boyfriend.
Well, that's not
what Maggie said.
Or Richard.
Anyway, I'm not sure how
that project is going.
I have a bad feeling.
Why? Why is that?
Never mind.
I'm just gonna be supportive.
Ah. I get it.
Because he's
your boyfriend.
How is Maggie doing?
Is she nervous about the TV thing?
Well, she put
her makeup on twice,
and then they wiped it right off
and then re-applied it, so...
It's going great.
Hey, can he breathe
underwater?
Just keep walking, Grey.
She told you
she's afraid to go home?
But she seems to be doing fine.
And she is.
But, you know,
mental illness
is like cancer and diabetes,
any other chronic illness...
You have to monitor.
Why was she even
telling you this?
I asked her how she was.
Is this some kind of
crusade for you, Bailey? W...
I mean, first going after
Dr. DeLuca, now my mom?
Wh... I'm not "going after"
anyone.
'Cause it seems like
you're prejudiced.
It... What?
Against people
with mental illness.
I'm not prejudiced,
you jackass!
I am a person
with mental illness!
And I cope with it
every day.
I take my medication,
and I'm doing great.
But, sometimes,
I need help.
That's... That's why I asked
you to stay on as chief.
And it's hard to ask
for that help.
Your mother needs to ask,
and she can't.
Your job is to make it
so that she can.
So do your job, son.
Prejudiced.
Jackass.
What the hell?
Tell me what happened.
Last night,
I found Vincenzo DeLuca
counseling my patient to gestate her
premature baby in a bag.
What?
He talked to your patient?
Yeah. He said that
the fetus would be
safe and sound
in an artificial womb.
Listen.
He... He's working on...
I transfused multiple times
overnight to buy time,
but I'm just wasting blood.
I'm gonna
have to operate soon.
But, Alex, we can do this?
I mean, we can save
my patient's 21-week-old baby?
Can we really
save them both?
Hey.
Have you seen Maggie?
Um, I know.
Is that the woman from
"Good Morning Seattle"?
Huh! Yeah, Maggie's very fancy now.
Shh.
Right, uh-huh. I-I... I took
the job here before anyone knew.
And you found a family.
Yeah. I mean, I-I knew that,
uh, my mom
had been here
and she was gone.
But I had no idea
that I had a sister.
And, um, a man who, um...
I have a father...
Bill Pierce, who raised me.
Hi, Dad.
Um, but Richard Webber
is, uh, a bonus.
I don't know how else
to describe it.
I'm... I'm...
I'm very lucky.
Sounds like
a pleasant surprise.
It's more than pleasant.
It's life-changing.
Oh, my God. But you missed
that crucial window,
- the chance to meet your mother.
- What?
I did, but...
That's a sign.
I came here to ask her
whether I should
find my birth mother,
and then she's...
That is a sign. ...gain
a perspective on her
that no one else got.
What?
Uh, nothing.
- Um.
- Do you think...
What?
I connected with
my father a while back,
and it was not
the best idea.
It didn't alleviate
any of my pain.
It just kind of
created more.
So unless there's some big
answer that you're looking for,
you might just want
to let it go.
My point was,
I was... I was raised by...
You took my sign down.
Wonderful parents
who encouraged me
to go for everything
I wanted.
When we come back,
we're making wraps...
The sandwich solution that
brightens your kid's lunch box.
No, no, no.
Papa, why were you
even in there?
Papa.
Speaking Italian...
-  Speaking Italian...
- Dr. DeLuca, you can't promise
fake procedures
with my patients.
Please.
Tell me something you try
that could work.
I have a living subject.
And a dead one...
Just last night!
P-Papa, you are reckless!
You are thoughtless!
- You just... You just...
- All right, right now, we have a mess
to clean up with this patient.
And you're gonna help.
No, no, no, no.
You stay here.
I mean it.
You've done enough.
I have to take you
up to surgery now,
and I will most likely
have to do a hysterectomy.
Wait. N-No.
That doctor... he said
he could save the baby.
The procedure he told you about
is not yet available.
But he said it was.
He said he could do it.
It... It hasn't been
tested in people.
We don't have approval to try
this procedure on your baby.
I-I approve.
I'm the mother.
I give you approval.
Do it.
Try it!
I-I can't.
You'll just... let our baby die?
I'm sorry.
Um, is there any chance,
any chance at all?
I'll deliver your baby
and make sure
the baby is comfortable
for as long as I can.
And... And, uh,
you can... hold her.
This is Jason.
In 2014, Jason
was a junior and goalie
in high school and club soccer.
Scholarship material.
Protecting the goal got
him a patellar fracture,
comminuted tibial plateau,
torn meniscus, ACL.
Still, he got the team
to the state finals.
He required multiple surgeries,
all of which went well,
had intense P.T. sessions,
and I prescribed him
opioids for the pain.
When Jason died
two years later
in a car accident
under the influence,
I realized that
he was a drug addict.
And I had been his first dealer.
But here's my real point.
If I had to do it
all over again,
I would've made
the same decision.
Ah...
Let me tell you why.
Opioids are undeniably
a very effective way
of fooling the body into
thinking everything is okay.
Are you
going to intubate?
No.
That would just be cruel.
Heaney clamp.
- Pull back.
- Mm-hmm.
- Get that.
- Yeah. Here?
Yep.
Okay.
- I got it.
- Okay.
0-vicryl pop-off.
What did you think
you were doing?
You know...
I mean,
you must know...
That you couldn't
try it on their baby.
Why would you give them
false hope like that?
We have the tools
right there.
I could've saved
a person's life...
Not yet!
It's not ready.
We don't know if
the baby would survive,
how the baby would survive,
if... if the brain
- would have deficits...
- Oh, porca miseria, stop.
Stop.
You sound just like
the rest of them.
Oh, my God.
This is it.
This is just like
it was that night.
What night?
Andrea, what night?
What do you mean
"what night"?
The night
four people died, Papa!
It is
just like that night.
Seven people
come in mangled.
- I am the only one there.
- No, no, no, no.
People came,
people offered to help,
and you wouldn't let them.
I was doing the job
that needed to be done!
♪ And the roads are filling up ♪ You see,
this is exactly what they talk about.
This is delusional, Papa.
Am I supposed to stop,
- let another doctor try and continue
- ♪ Everybody's going somewhere ♪
- where I am? They would've died!
- They did!
- They did die!
- ♪ But, baby, I know ♪
And tonight,
a pregnant mother
might lose her unborn baby
to a car accident,
which is tragic,
but it's merciful
- compared to watching it die in a bag...
- ♪ I was standing on the ceiling ♪
at the hands
of some scientist
who doesn't know
what the hell he's doing!
Papa, please tell me
you can see that.
♪ Saw a plane crash
on the news ♪
Are you too sick to see that?
♪ They say the chances
of that happening ♪
How is the baby?
♪ Are about the same
as finding you ♪
Would you like to...
Yeah.
♪ What I need ♪
- Hi.
- ♪ Is you ♪
♪ And me ♪
[ Crying ]
♪ What I need ♪
- ♪ What I need ♪
- Teddy. You okay?
- Mm-hmm.
♪ Is you ♪
♪ And me ♪
♪ I'm paralyzed ♪
♪ Like there's half of me ♪
♪ That's missing ♪
♪ What I need ♪
♪ Is you ♪
♪ And me ♪
Look, I believe
in your research. I do.
But what happened
with this patient
was a major breach
of protocol.
I can't have that.
So I've decided...
You need to reconsider right now
what you're about to say.
- Papa, don't argue.
- Do not interrupt me.
Papa, you need to get help
before somebody gets hurt.
Like that baby?
I might have saved
that baby.
But you let it die,
and you let it die,
and you let it die!
Because of your cowardice
and laziness,
you will never know if that
child had to die at your hands.
Damn it!
You're stopping
my research?
That what
you're about to say?
No! You don't get
my research!
You don't deserve it!
I take it and go!
Cretini!
Mmm. This actually
makes it worth it.
Mmm.
I thought I read
the text wrong,
but, no, you are hosting
a "fish fry."
Yeah, waste not,
want not.
Hey, grab a plate.
Bailey,
can you do me a favor?
Look,
I need your help now.
Can you take back the
chiefship, just for two days?
I still have
a couple weeks left.
- I'm gonna take them.
- I-It's not a fast-food joint, Karev.
We don't cover shifts
for each other.
I need to fly with my mom
back to Iowa.
I talked to her,
and you were right.
- She needs to get home.
- Did you tell her I talked to you?
Hell, no. I look like
a thoughtful son.
Hm.
I will try to fill
your shoes.
Hey, tell your mother
thank you for the hat.
You missed the good part.
There was a good part?
You know, "error of my ways,"
all that stuff.
I will see you in Seattle.
You know, I-I didn't
really have a choice
but to give him
those drugs.
You would've done
the exact same thing I did.
I absolutely
would not have,
because I understand
how addiction
-  works.
- Back then, you would've.
And
I believe the drug companies
also understand it,
and they have made billions
on the back of it.
Jason's leg was caught between
a defender and a goalpost.
His knee was bent
90 degrees sideways.
No amount of ibuprofen or sound
baths were gonna help him.
- He was talking about suicide.
- Yeah, and you gave him the means!
And you would do it again.
You said you...
Not the same way,
not blindly.
Amelia, science
has given us a way
to tell the brain
to stop unbearable pain.
So far, there's no
-  alternative as effect...
- Are you just giving me
your lecture now?
A child is dead!
You failed him!
And you think
I haven't felt that
every day
since Jason's funeral?
When I saw the look on his
mother's face, I left medicine.
For a year, I only trusted
myself to fix bikes.
I quit.
But, then, I got mad.
Because, yeah, I failed,
the same way we've all failed.
We blew the first rule...
Do no harm.
But he needed those drugs
immediately post-op,
and that's where
it should've stopped.
I should've warned him
and his mother
about the dangers
of dependency.
I-I should've followed up
with his GP.
The system is broken,
and I'm doing everything I can
to try to fix it.
So you're saying
I missed the good part.
I'm trying to
make it right for Jason.
You're trying to make
it right for Betty.
Maybe we don't
have to fight about this.
M-Maybe we could fight
this thing together,
like Batman and...
Batman.
Okay.
You still want
to hit me?
No. Because, for a minute there,
it looked like
you wanted to hit me.
I got a bit of a hair trigger.
It can be scary.
I'm sorry. I've... been in
a weird place these days.
Well, I can roll
with weird.
Want to get some dinner?
Yeah.
No.
"Just because you can
doesn't mean you should."
It's the kind of advice
a mother gives a kid.
I... I feel like I'm...
like I'm taking advantage.
Why?
Because
you're in a "place."
And I think you're insanely pretty.
- ♪ Floating on a high ♪
♪ I feel ya ♪
But, as my mother would be
the first to tell you...
- ♪ Got an ache inside ♪
- ..she never followed it.
The feeling is mutual.
♪ And I need it ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ I desperately want
to be lost ♪
This... isn't
going anywhere.
- ♪ With you ♪
- This is just... alternative pain relief.
- ♪ Till all of our energy crosses ♪
- I could use some of that.
It got her in a lot of trouble.
♪ I want you all to myself ♪
- Mm.
It also won her awards.
♪ Just keep me caught
in your spell ♪
Hi.
♪ You stop my breathing ♪
- ♪ but keep my heart beating ♪
- You made a merman today.
- I kind of did.
- ♪ You're bringing me outta hell ♪
Honestly, I think the tilapia's
gonna do the whole job.
- It's cheaper and better than
- ♪ And I want you all to myself ♪
-the spray-on skin.
So, when I was on television
being a human-interest story...
A very sexy
human-interest story.
While I was on television
talking about myself...
Mm-hmm.
I was figuring out
a way to possibly heal burn victims
around the globe
- for just pennies.
- ♪ Time is running out ♪
That is the sexiest thing
you've ever said.
- Mm.
- ♪ Don't waste it ♪
- No more press.
- ♪ Ooh ♪
I'm done with the press.
I'm gonna make something
even better than mermen.
♪ I wanna
be out of my mind ♪
Oh, yeah?
So you like
competition?
Don't you?
♪ With you ♪
♪ Leaving our bodies behind ♪
- I made a merman.
- ♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
- ♪ I want you all to myself ♪
- That's how records are broken,
how moons are stepped on,
diseases are cured...
♪ Just keep me caught
in your spell ♪
By people who
are willing to try.
♪ You stop my breathing,
but keep my heart beating ♪
- ♪ You're bringing me outta hell ♪
- We call these people innovators,
- ♪ Oh, I... ♪
- fearless, genius.
- ♪ ..want you... ♪
- Hey.
- ♪ ..all to myself ♪
- What happened to the lamb?
My father's arranging
transport back to Italy.
- ♪ Oh, I want you all to myself ♪
- We call them reckless... - Ohh.
Thoughtless, dangerous...
Go ahead.
Say "I told you so."
♪ And it's all right ♪
I wouldn't want to.
- ♪ Don't open ♪
- And it kind of bugs me
- ♪ your eyes ♪
- that you think I would.
- I'm... sorry.
- ♪ There's nothing for... ♪
I just... I-I shouldn't be
around people right now.
- ♪ ...us on the outside now ♪
- I...
♪ You stop my breathing, but
keep my heart beating tonight ♪
well, just let me know
if you need anything.
- Thanks.
- ♪ Tonight ♪
♪ I want you ♪
It's hard to know
which one we are.
♪ Oh, I want you
all to myself ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
- ♪ Just keep... ♪
- Can you really find my mother?
♪ ..me...♪
- ♪ ..caught in your spell ♪
- Yes. Do you really want me to?
- It's hard to know if what we're doing
..- ♪ Oh, caught in your spell ♪
- ♪ Oh, I want you... ♪
- ..is just crazy. Yes.
- ♪ ..all to... ♪
- Good.
- ♪ ..myself ♪
- I couldn't help myself.
- ♪ Just keep me... ♪
- She lives in Pittsburgh.
- ♪ ..caught in your spell ♪
- Her name is Vicki.
♪ I ♪
- ♪ I want you all to myself ♪
- Or if it's going to change everything.
♪ I want you all to myself ♪
Sync corrections by srjanapala