It's a common belief
that positive thinking
leads to a happier,
healthier life.
Stop fidgeting. Smile.
I hate ties. You're
the one that's fidgeting.
I'm wearing a thing
that sucks in my fat.
You don't have any fat.
I couldn't zip the
dress without it.
- I have fat.
- That's just your ass.
I like it fat.
Thank you. That's... disturbing,
but kind of awesome.
- Wanna go
upstairs and make out?
- We're supporting Derek.
Why? His party blows.
This whole wall will be windows, so
we can take advantage of the view.
- Nice.
- Broken ground yet?
The day I was named chief.
At my parties, we drink
beer and dance on tables.
- Are you insulting my party?
- It's getting kind
of lame out there.
Duty calls.
As children we're told to smile
and be cheerful and
put on a happy face.
As adults we're told to
look on the bright side.
To make lemonade and
see glasses as half full.
- You're staring again.
- I am not.
Wanna go to my place and do it
in the shower? Teddy's in surgery.
I'm not in the mood for
your jokes right now, OK?
Sometimes reality can
get in the way of our ability
to act the happy part, though.
- Napkin?
- Thank you!
I'm getting first dibs
on all the finger food
before it gets sucked
down by the masses.
Thank you!
Let's move in together.
Good. You can't answer.
It's good. I don't want you to.
I ran it past my shrink. She thinks
it's a good idea. So think about it.
- Me, you in our own place.
- Yes.
- What...? Yes?
- Yes. Yes.
Yes, yes, but I need to warn you
that this is my fourth martini,
and my judgment
is severely impaired.
Also,
- I'm a real easy lay right now.
- Works for me.
- I'm going in.
- No, you can't.
It's inappropriate! This is the
chief's house, right, Jackson?
No. Go ahead, girl. Get yours.
Your health can fail,
boyfriends can cheat.
Friends can disappoint.
Dr. Sloan, I just wanted to say
your work today with Dr. Shepherd
on that acoustic
neuroma was amazing.
I was inspired.
You need another drink.
It's in these moments when
you just want to get real.
To drop the act
and be your true,
- scared, unhappy self.
- OK...
OK, look, I just
want to tell you
that I will not have
my personal business
all over the hospital like every
other little resident ho there.
So therefore, you will
not flirt with me at work...
Listen, listen. You
will not kiss me at work,
you will not... look at me
with the "I have seen
you naked" eyes at work.
What we do in the bedroom,
stays in the bedroom.
I'm a professional woman
with a stellar
reputation. More import...
importantly, I'm a lady.
And a lady does not show
her drawers at the office.
Now, woman,
I am naked and I look good.
Now, you gonna sit
there and lecture me,
or you gonna let me
take you to my bedroom
and have my way with you?
OK... My shoe...
Mark? Hello? The
door's unlocked.
I'm sorry I couldn't
meet you earlier,
you would not believe my night.
My post-op dissection
repair coded.
I had to open him up bedside...
OK.
Wow!
Well...
this could be fun if
we decide to let it.
You and Owen are thinking
of moving in together?
Not thinking. Doing.
Mer. Frickin' speak.
OK. I think there
might be something
going on between Owen and Teddy.
Wow. OK. There's nothing's
I'm saying I'm pretty sure.
OK, how? How are you sure?
I can't say. And I
don't really know,
I'm just saying
think before you do.
- That's all.
- You know what? That's crap.
- Meredith...
- I gotta go. I'm late
for rounds.
We're totally not
done with this!
And when Mark
proposed a threesome,
she looked at me.
Like she was thinking about it.
Well, she is cute. Like a
brunette surgical Tinker Bell.
- Who's that?
- Nothing. I walked in on Mark
and Reed Adamson last night.
- So he cheated on you.
- No, he didn't cheat on me.
We're dating non-exclusively.
He's not my boyfriend.
OK, gotta run.
Hear the rest later?
Listen, if you want me to say
something to him, I can say something.
Owen, I do not need
you to defend my honor.
You can stand down now.
Yes, Andrew, I said
surgery. Now... Wait, wait.
Would you explain to my son
why he doesn't need to worry?
Hello? Hi.
Your mom has some broken bones in
her forearm, but we're gonna put some
small metal plates in, and
she'll be discharged tomorrow.
See, dear? Don't
jump on a plane.
I'm gonna call you
right after surgery.
Well, love you, too,
darling. Bye-bye.
My son, a lawyer. He's single.
- Very nice. A little bit older.
- I'm dating someone, kind of...
What about you, Reed?
You go for older guys, right?
- Was it something I said?
- Oh, no, no. It's not you.
- What do we have?
- Henry Stamm, 75,
fell down a flight of
stairs on a cruise ship
before it left the dock.
He has a couple of broken
ribs and we're waiting
for the abdominal CT results.
- Where were you headed,
Mr. Stamm?
- Alaska.
It... a present from my kids.
Maybe I'll meet a nice
lady, my daughter said.
Now, look at me.
I don't think he fell as
much as passed out.
- That bad, doc?
- You have what's called
sick sinus syndrome. It's an irregular
heart rhythm that causes blackouts.
- We're gonna
have to do an ablation...
- Doctor...
I think you might have
to check my head, too.
- Does it still hurt?
- No, but...
I think I'm seeing a ghost.
- Betty?
- Yes?
It's Henry.
Henry Stamm.
Henry? Henry Stamm?
Oh, my God! That's Henry Stamm.
Betty Flynn!
But my last name is Donahue now.
You married Mike Donahue?
May he rest in peace.
And you? How... How is Irene?
She died ten years
ago this August.
I'm so sorry.
- Are you OK?
- Just a little fall.
- You?
- Fender bender.
You look good, Betty.
- I'm an old lady, Henry.
- - You look pretty damn good
- for an old lady to me.
- We should keep this area clear
- for emergencies.
- We haven't seen each other
- in a half a century, miss.
- All the more reason
for you to wait
- a little longer
for your reunion.
- Yang.
She'll be in room 3128.
Betty Flynn!
Oh, my God!
Hello.
What song is that?
I know that song.
Oh... Just a little
something stuck in my head.
You know how it is.
Oh! You both have a great day.
- Bailey in a good mood.
- She is.
- Really good.
- Teddy was right for you.
- Appropriate.
- Appropriate is boring.
That sums up
your entire problem.
Good morning.
Gentlemen.
- Go, Bailey.
- Indeed.
I'm not crazy. I'm not crazy.
It's OK, Haley. Honey, the
doctors are gonna help you.
- You page Surgery?
- Hayley May, 16,
diagnosed paranoid schizophrenic.
Tried to claw her eyes out.
I need you to clear her before
I can take her up to Psych.
- She tried to claw
her eyes out?
- We try to keep her safe.
She's on every med in the book.
But she doesn't
eat, doesn't sleep.
The slightest thing sets
her off. Talking even.
So we're having her committed.
We explained to her that
they were coming to
get her, to try and help.
We turned our back for a
minute, just for one minute...
- Hayley...
- That's lorazepam.
- I swear to God, I'll do it.
- No, baby, please don't!
You don't believe
me. Nobody does.
So no. I swear to
God I'll stab myself.
Hayley, I'm Dr. Karev, Alex.
- I need you to put that down.
- It will kill me, right?
If I stuck this in my
heart, it would kill me?
You don't want
to do that, Hayley.
There's drugs in
here. I'd die, right?
Trust me.
- I can help you.
- I'm not crazy.
I know.
I believe you.
Everyone outside
thinks you're crazy,
but something's going on inside
and none of us understand,
so we need to
figure out what that is.
The only way we can do
that is if you put that down
and let me run some tests.
- OK?
- You promise?
Yes.
Just... put it down.
It's gonna be OK.
Good. That's good.
I'm not crazy. I'm not crazy.
Page Shepherd.
I'd like to run some
tests on Hayley.
More tests? We've
been to doctors, OK?
Hayley is schizophrenic.
She was diagnosed months ago.
Ken's father was schizophrenic.
He killed himself
when Ken was eight.
Dr. Shepherd, it's just a few
more tests. She wants them.
Mr. and Mrs. May, believe
me, I understand your frustration.
But it's possible
something was missed.
Honey, please.
- Fine.
- OK.
- OK. OK.
- Thank you.
I wanna run an
EEG, a CAT scan...
Morning, Amber and Trish.
Trish and Amber
met in the burn unit.
Best friends ever since.
- Dr. Grey?
- Amber Collier, 28,
presents status post MVC.
Amber was in a car when it flipped
and she was pinned
under it while it burned.
Driving while texting.
We strongly recommend it.
Dr. Avery, will you please explain
how we're gonna use a tissue expander.
We stretch healthy tissue
by injecting saline into a
balloon placed under the skull.
Today we'll remove
that burned area
- and cover it with new tissue.
- You promise that afterwards
- it won't look like
a comb-over, right?
- I will do my best.
Dr. Sloan, Dr. Bailey.
Amber, how long have
your fingers looked like this?
I don't know, they
always look pretty bad.
- You can still
do my surgery, right?
- We'll know more
after we get some
films on the fingers.
You're bummed out about
getting a couple of x-rays?
You got a twin sister
growing out of your head.
That's what you should
be bummed about.
She was my wife's
roommate, her best friend.
And you haven't seen
one another since then?
She was supposed
to be in our wedding,
my wife's maid of honor,
but she disappeared.
I figured that I would write
her eventually and try to explain.
But how do you say, "I
couldn't stand up in your wedding
because I fell in love
with your fiancé?"
There was a party.
I remember the sky
was so clear that night.
I went outside to
look at the stars.
And there was Betty.
It just... happened.
I felt terrible.
It was wonderful.
He was my first.
She was my first.
Irene and I were waiting
for our wedding night.
For the first time in
my life, I felt complete.
Being with Henry,
I felt complete.
I wanted to tell Irene.
I wanted to call off
the engagement.
It would have been
a terrible scandal.
And it would have ruined
my friendship with Irene.
But, of course, the
friendship was ruined anyway.
She just left.
She went to grad school
across the country. And...
And I...
I married Irene.
Well, I loved Irene.
But she wasn't...
She wasn't Betty.
I told myself there'd be
plenty of Henrys in my life.
And were there?
My husband was a good man.
Kind, funny, smart.
But he was no Henry.
There was never another Henry.
Dr. Torres,
I have an idea.
Nearly 50 years later,
and still all those feelings.
It's saying something, isn't it?
Is that a good idea? He
just had a heart ablation.
- He should be resting.
- A happy patient
- is a healthy patient, Yang.
- This scan shows
diaphragmatic rupture
from the fall. We have
to get him in the OR soon.
He can wait an hour.
Let's let them catch up.
- You're OK with this?
- I'm with Webber.
I can't help it. I'm a romantic.
You think she's schizophrenic?
I think she threatened to stab
a syringe into her own heart.
- So I'm leaning
toward crazy, yeah.
- The scans are up.
Nothing in the frontal lobe.
Or the temporo-parietal region.
- Occipital lobe's clean too.
- Crap!
- Told you. Crazy.
- We tried, Karev.
All the tests are negative.
Let's go inform the parents
- and turf her up to Psych.
- This isn't right. I know crazy.
I grew up with
crazy, I dated crazy,
and I don't think
this girl is crazy.
- Just give me some time.
- Do you have a diagnosis
in mind?
- No, but...
- She's suicidal, Alex.
What you did in that
ER, you saved her life.
But those parents
have been through hell.
You say it's our job to
advocate for the patient.
The patient, not the parents.
So, whatever hell they've
gone through, hers is worse.
I do say that.
Advocate for the patient.
You've got until my board
meeting's over. Four hours. Go dig.
Alex...
- Are we a couple?
- What?
I need to know what we are.
Because people ask me
and I don't know what to say.
I'm over Mark. I don't
know if you're over Izzie,
but I am over Mark
Sloan. For real.
And I know that we said
this wasn't gonna be a thing,
but I like you.
The point is, I want
to know what we are.
What this is.
We're a thing.
Yeah, we're together,
we're... we're a thing.
Whatever.
Dr. Altman, can I do the
mesh repair of the diaphragm?
No, I can sew it up
with a continuous suture.
If you do stay sutures on
either side of the laceration,
- it can be tented down
to aid closure.
- I know...
Quite a shorthand you two have.
We worked together a long time.
I get it. I had that
once. Ellis Grey, and I,
from the first day
we worked together.
I miss it.
She's got hyperacusis,
vertigo, tinnitus, nystagmus.
- This blows.
- So you and Lexie...
- What?
- I'm just saying,
you and Lexie,
- it's not just
a sex thing any more?
- I'm acting like a duck.
- What?
- I figure if you
walk like a duck
and quack like a duck, eventually
you start to feel like a duck.
Lexie is nice and
normal and healthy.
I'm acting like a guy who can stick
with nice and normal and healthy.
- You're becoming a duck.
- I am becoming a duck.
- Cristina, seriously?
- What's up with that?
She's mad at me because I planted seeds
of doubt about her moving in with Owen.
- Don't talk to him about me.
- Why don't you come over here
- so I can talk
to you about you.
- I'll talk to you
when you actually talk.
Are you ready to talk?
I need the Lexopedia
to diagnose my patient.
- She's not a book
you can flip through.
- I kinda am. Go.
Sixteen year old with hyperacusis,
vertigo, tinnitus, nystagmus.
Cholesteatoma.
Or temporal lobe tumor.
For God's sake, will
you just come over here?
- No.
- Scans were clean.
Uh, it's worse with
sounds. We have to whisper.
Oh, uh... Page 162.
The June 2004 issue
of a journal with a
mint green cover. It's...
Sound or pressure induced
vertigo. It's called, um...
I can't... Crap. I can't see it.
It's like the computer froze.
June '04. Mint green cover.
It's in the research library.
Got it. Thanks.
So Mark slept with
Reed. Gross, right?
- But you're with Alex.
- I know.
No, I'm just saying
it's gross. That's...
That's all. I'm
just... It's gross.
Do you think I'm Thatcher? Is
that what you were trying to tell me?
- That I'm Thatcher?
- What?
Owen is Ellis and
Teddy's Dr. Webber
and somehow I'm
Thatcher in the situation?
I don't know. I don't know.
Forget it.
I don't understand.
You didn't find anything.
I just feel like we're
torturing her for no reason.
OK, Hayley, we're
gonna start now.
When I say now,
I want you to pinch
your nose and blow.
Make sure you keep
your eyes open, OK?
Now.
What's happening to her
eyes? What's going on?
No...
No!
No... No!
Hayley, honey, it's
Mommy. I'm right here.
What the hell did you do to her?
I just diagnosed her.
You don't have a
middle name? For real?
My parents couldn't agree
so they decided not to bother.
Well, we're just gonna have
to do something about that.
How about "Cheeky?"
- Liz "Cheeky" McKee?
- Yeah. I like it.
It has spunk.
All right. Take care.
Miranda, that was...
Miranda...
You have to cut off
three of my fingers?
They're infected, Amber.
It also means we
have to postpone
your hair
restoration. I'm sorry.
Amber, you survived
a horrible car wreck.
- You'll survive this, too.
- I know, but...
Hey, what do we always say?
We're both alive.
That's what matters.
Everything else is
just bumps and bruises.
You can cry, Amber. It's fine.
It's a lot to take
in all at once.
No, she needs to stay positive.
That's how we get
through, we stay positive.
She was excited. She was
hopeful. She was eager.
And that has been crushed.
She has the right to
have some feelings.
She can be positive tomorrow.
You can be positive tomorrow.
Thank you.
It's called superior canal
dehiscence syndrome.
It's a result of a small hole
that developed in her inner ear.
It's rare and it's
hard to diagnose.
The condition wasn't
even written up until 1998.
The noise sensitivity,
the sandpaper,
it's because Hayley
can hear everything
going on inside her body and
every sound outside was magnified.
It's why she
couldn't sleep or eat.
She's not schizophrenic.
Was the sex with
Altman, was it lousy?
- Did she disappoint you?
- What?
No!
No.
Is one woman never
enough for some men?
I really want to know.
Because I think I'm a
good judge of character.
I am a good judge of character
and I think Altman is a
good judge of character
and then she trusted
you. She trusted you,
and then you go...
I just want to know.
Teddy and I were
never exclusive.
Were you and your guy exclusive?
We're not talking about me.
At the end of the trail,
there's... there's an overlook.
You can see the
entire bay from up there.
Of course, the view
would be even nicer
if I had someone
to share it with.
Come live with me.
- Henry...
- It's a nice place.
- Warm, quiet.
- We barely know each other.
We know each other.
We missed our
chance once, Betty.
I'd hate to make the
same mistake again.
Betty, I need to get
you up to surgery.
Think about it.
That's all I ask.
I got over you...
Henry.
I married Mike. I had four kids.
Now, grandkids
that give me such joy.
I got over you.
I'm sorry.
Looks like that's just about it.
You want to have
the anesthesiologist
start lightening her up?
- You could ask me directly.
- Dr. Sloan?
You want to start
lightening her up?
No, wait.
I want to do the
hair restoration.
What about the
chance of infection?
The infection
looked pretty isolated.
- You think we can do it?
- It seems to me
that we are all in need
of a little magic today.
Right, Dr. Bailey?
Let's do it.
Do you think your mom
ever got over the chief?
Do you think she still loved
him, after all those years?
My mom loved Richard
until the day she died.
What were you trying
to tell me this morning?
About Teddy and Owen. Is
there something I'm not seeing?
- Cristina...
- Meredith, please,
just tell me what
you know. Just...
- Why?
- You have to understand.
It's been just me and
you for a long time.
And now it's me and
Derek, and it's you and me.
And I told you what I said this
morning because it's you and me.
But I can't tell you any more
because it's me and Derek.
Fine, you know what? I get it.
But I need you to understand
that I need there to
be a me and Owen.
- Hey.
I hate your job.
- I love you.
- Stop trying to make me happy.
Do you think he loves
her? Owen and Teddy?
- I mean, do you think
that's why...
- Meredith.
I'm saying, when he
threw her under the bus,
what read did you get?
- Do you think he loves her?
- You can't tell Cristina.
I know that. That's
why I hate your job.
- Do you want a hug?
- Yeah.
Wow, impressive technique.
Who taught you that?
Mark. He taught
me one-handed ties,
mattress stitches,
dual onlay bone grafts.
Now, he can teach
his techniques to Reed.
- Lexie...
- It's fine. I'm fine.
I don't care. I'm with Alex.
I do not care about Mark
and/or who he sleeps with.
That's the same thing I keep telling
myself about Arizona, that I don't care.
You know what? Sometimes
it works, for the most part.
But then a patient gets asked
to move across the country
for a man she barely
knows and all I can think
is how stupid they were to let
each other go in the first place.
All I want is for her to
change her mind and say yes.
I want to believe.
OK, time to close off the canal.
You're using fascia
and bone wax?
Yep, then we'll cover it with the
cortical bone graft we harvested
and seal it with the fibrin
glue. She'll be good as new.
You cover a hole with a bone graft
and this girl gets her whole life back.
Wouldn't it be nice if everything
in life were that simple?
I hoped it wouldn't
leave such a big scar.
It'll look better in a couple of
weeks, once it has a chance to heal.
You'll be doing shampoo
commercials in no time.
And your hand is just
bumps and bruises, right?
I lost three fingers
today, Trish.
- That's not bump and bruises.
- I know that.
But we're alive. It's
better than the alternative.
I call in sick to work sometimes
because I just
can't bear to drive.
I sit in my car in my garage,
and I'm so angry about
what happened to me,
that I can't drive my car!
For hours, I just sit there!
Does that ever happen to you?
That you're so angry
you can't breathe?
Because I do! But
I can't tell you that
because I'm afraid
I'm being weak.
Or ungrateful.
Please. You are my best friend.
Horrible things
have happened to us.
Can we just be real
with each other for once?
I can't watch romantic
comedies anymore
because I just want
to yell at the women.
"You can't find Mr. Right?
That's your biggest problem?
Well, try having most of your
face burned off, you stupid bitch!
See what a freaking
Pretty Woman you are then!"
I don't know...
- Thank you.
- Oh, no!
Cristina loves you.
And I want to, but I can't.
Because I want to punch
you in the face right now.
I know you tried
to have Teddy fired
and I believe it's
because you love her.
And if you care about
Cristina at all, you will tell her.
If you're actually the good
guy she thinks you are,
you will tell her.
And if you don't, then I'll know
and you'll know that
you are not that guy.
Look, Teddy.
- I wanted to say...
- I should've knocked. It's that simple.
And it's that over.
- Talk to her.
- I just did. She doesn't want to.
I'm not talking about Teddy,
I'm talking about Lexie.
You still love Lexie.
Sleeping around
isn't gonna fix that.
And the reasons you broke
up, Little Sloan, the baby,
they're not reasons anymore.
- She's with Karev.
- Well, Betty married Mike,
- but she never got over Henry.
- What?
You don't want 50 years
to go by and then realize
you let the love of your
life get away. So go, try.
You gonna try
again with Robbins?
Why not?
Because my reasons
are still reasons.
I don't understand. You told
Shepherd to hire Dr. Evans over Teddy,
when I asked you to go to bat
for her? You said that you did. So...
Meredith said...
Owen, what's going on
between you and Teddy?
Nothing. Nothing is.
You want me to get better,
I want me to get better,
and I have been working. I
have been working with Dr. Wyatt
- to eliminate my triggers.
- OK, so Teddy's a trigger?
Teddy... I don't
know what Teddy is.
Teddy, she triggers
me. She confuses me.
- I don't know!
- You know what, "I don't know,"
is not working for me right now.
"I don't know" is all I've got!
- I shouldn't
have to explain myself.
- Oh?
Cristina...
I don't know what
I feel for Teddy.
I don't know, because she's all
wrapped up with everything else,
with men being blown
apart in front of me, with Beth.
So it's complicated and it
is screwing with my head.
That's the truth! I don't
know what I feel for her.
But I do know
what I feel for you.
So, yes, I told Shepherd
to hire the other guy.
I shouldn't have to explain
myself so I can get myself better.
I shouldn't have to
explain myself to you.
And I damn well do not have to
explain myself to Meredith Grey!
It's, uh... It's Henry Stamm.
He was talking to me, and
then he couldn't breathe.
Atrial flutter again.
Get her out of here.
- Ma'am, I need to move you.
- I'm not leaving him!
Systolic's 80. We're
gonna need to cardiovert.
- Charge paddles to 100.
- Charging.
You wanna help?
Let go of his hand!
Hello.
Your heart rhythm
was irregular again.
We were able to
control it for now,
but we're gonna need
to insert a pacemaker
before you go home.
You're gonna be OK.
I've called a colleague
at your hospital at home.
He'll see you once
we clear you to travel.
Thank you.
You stayed.
You can't do that again.
If I'm going to move
halfway across the country
and shack up with you,
- you can't do that again.
- Really?
You make me feel like
the prettiest girl at the party.
When you look at me, I
become a young girl again.
And I never stopped missing you.
And I never stopped wondering.
I did the right thing once.
Now, I'd like to do the wrong
thing and see how that goes.
How long do you need
me to wait before I propose?
- Cristina.
- Don't.
She's starting to wake up.
Remember, we're gonna take
it slowly and see how it goes.
There's no guarantee
that the surgery worked.
How ya doing, Hayley?
I'm good.
I'm good!
Ask most people what
they want out of life,
and the answer's
simple: to be happy.
Maybe it's this
expectation though,
the wanting to be happy,
that just keeps us
from ever getting there.
- I need to talk to you.
- I get it.
You want to see other
people. So go. Be free.
Get cheeky with Liz.
Liz is the meanest
nurse on the floor.
She makes everybody in
my department's life hell.
But she likes me.
She doesn't schedule me
for work on Tuesday mornings
because she knows
that's when I play golf.
She doesn't put me in the OR
with Hendricks 'cause she knows
I can't stand the way he talks
to himself when he operates.
And she does these favors
for me because I flirt with her.
Flirting makes my job easier.
And what you saw back
there, that middle name stuff,
that's bad flirting.
Lazy flirting.
For you, who I actually like,
I break out my good flirting,
my A game,
because I mean it.
Are you hearing me, Miranda?
I mean it.
I have a child
and a fulltime job
and I'm going through a sad,
exhausting, stressful,
time-consuming divorce.
I don't have time for games.
- You understand that, right?
- I do.
I do, and I'm not playing games.
I'm in this for real. OK?
OK.
You were right. Superior
canal dehiscence syndrome.
Page 162. You rock. I'm gonna drop these
off and we're gonna head over to Joe's.
Lex?
I'm still in love with you.
I tried not to be,
but it didn't work.
And Sloan's gone.
There's no baby.
And I don't want
to sleep around.
I want another chance.
I'm in love with you.
Karev is...
He's...
Mark, I have a boyfriend.
I know.
I'm saying you could
have a husband.
Maybe the more we try and
will ourselves to states of bliss,
the more confused we get.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
To the point where we
don't recognize ourselves.
- Hey.
Arizona...
Instead, we just keep smiling.
Trying like hell to be the
happy people we wish we were.
Until eventually it hits us.
It's been there all along.
What do you think of this, putting in
the fireplace in the master bedroom?
I'm gonna get something to eat.
Well...
I'm not moving in with Owen.
- See this, right here?
- Uh-huh.
This is your room.
You have a room at the
new house in the woods.
My own room?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
Not in our dreams or hopes,
but in the known,
the comfortable...
the familiar.