Previously on House.
You high, popo?
A cop with a sense of humor.
You check the cop car.
Also check his personal
car, work, home.
Foreman, get out!
Am I the only one
who finds this funny?
You stole my article.
I wouldn't do that.
We're not friends.
We're colleagues.
Son of a bitch!
Now we're both exposed.
In 10 minutes
time... You die, I die.
It's not gonna happen.
Time of death.
12:26 p.m.
I need a bone saw.
I'm sorry. I wish I could.
They said you won't...
I just want a little tiny
slice of this guy's brain.
That's all I need, just enough
to tell me what's killing Foreman.
A thin slice of Joe's brain could
also cause a public health crisis.
It's not a good idea to scream "fire"
every time somebody lights a match.
Don't downplay this, House.
You put both of them
in isolation for a reason.
Joe's death elevates this
situation to a Biosafety Level 3.
Level 3. Did you call Jack
Bauer? I called the CDC.
Well, tell them I'll be
really, really careful.
We don't have the proper equipment
for you to be really, really careful.
You can do whatever you want to
Foreman, but the CDC will do this autopsy.
Whatever. The point is, we'll be
lucky to get results in three days.
I told them how urgent
this is. And they told you...
"We'll have the
results in three days."
Oh, that's a shame.
Because Foreman will
never get to know what it was.
He'll be dead in 36 hours.
Maybe this is a toxin. Maybe
it's not contagious at all.
You're killing Foreman
because of a "maybe."
Well, you have 36 hours
to figure out which one it is.
Foreman. Come here, fast.
What's going on? When
are they doing the autopsy?
You're doing it, now.
You ever studied how they
used to do ice pick lobotomies?
I read about it in med
school. Why would I...
Shove an ice pick into the eye
socket just above the tear duct,
bang it a couple times with
a hammer, get a sample.
What's going on, House?
Foreman, you can't do it!
You'd be in violation of... Can't
do the time if you're not alive.
You! I need you to suit up.
Get that equipment
away from Dr. Foreman.
Take your time, guys.
Just tell them to go slow.
It won't be your fault.
Foreman, we don't even know what
kind of contagion we're dealing with.
Which is why we need to
chop into the guy's head!
It's dangerous. Not
to you, Foreman!
There are other
ways to diagnose you.
Yeah? You have the answer?
Foreman, do it now!
I am warning you! Do not...
What are you doing?
That didn't feel right.
He's blind.
But he thinks he can see.
Same as the cop.
We need something
to bag the sample.
Forget it. You just
biopsied a mattress.
No, no, no. I'm fine. House,
there's the sample. Get it, test it!
You got to test that sample!
Apparently I was optimistic
about the 36 hours.
Intractable, unbearable
pain is up next.
Sure you don't wanna reconsider
that whole autopsy thing?
Physically, his eyes are fine.
The problem's isolated to his brain.
Damage to the occipital lobe
extends from the primary visual cortex...
We should retest him
for bacterial meningitis.
If it was meningitis,
we'd all be sick.
His CSF might show signs...
LP's pointless. We
already did a brain biopsy.
It was negative.
Toxic mold. If it was
toxic mold, I'd be sick.
How do we know you're not
sick? Do I seem happy to you?
Never.
It was funny.
Well, let's assume
it's not blood-borne.
If you start cracking
jokes, we can reassess.
In the meantime, stay away from
people and animals that you care about.
Guillain Barré.
Neither of them had
any sort of paralysis.
Joe could have died before the
paralysis had a chance to present.
What about arbovirus?
Start treatment. For arbovirus?
You think our Jersey beat cop
has been spending a lot of time
exploring deep, dark Africa?
Treatment for everything,
likely or unlikely.
If you can think
of it, treat for it.
Mixing that many meds will
create all sorts of toxic interactions.
We'll box his liver, trash his
kidneys. There's got to be a better way.
Of course there's a better way!
It's that body sitting in the room
with him that Cuddy won't let us touch!
Bacterials, virals, toxins, fungals,
parasites, it's got to be one of them.
Where are you going?
See if I can find
another brain to biopsy.
They're gonna lock Joe up
downstairs until the CDC gets here.
Foreman, you can't see.
Right.
House wants to start you on
some meds. They're in the air lock.
For what? Leading
candidate is toxic mold.
Is Cameron sick?
I'm fine, thanks for asking.
You're casting your net a little
wider than toxic mold, aren't you?
Guillain Barré is
also on the table.
This is an oval shape.
That's either an "L" or a "7."
I'm guessing an "L." Levofloxacin,
because you can't rule out bacteria.
8-0-0. That's the dosage
for acyclovir in case it's viral.
Square. No, more like a rhombus.
That's fluconazole for fungus.
There's about eight others here.
You're treating
me for everything.
You have no idea what I've got.
House thinks this is
the best course of action.
House is desperate.
House is never desperate.
Something we give you will work.
Yeah, we should start
treating all patients this way.
When they get sick,
they just take everything.
It's better than doing nothing.
Hello?
I'm at the cop's place.
I need to retrace your steps.
You don't think the "treat him for
everything" approach is enough?
Where did you start
your search? The kitchen.
Okay, well, tell me everything
you did, everything you touched.
If you went to the john, I
want to know when and why.
It started with samples
from the mold in his sink.
What next? That's
it. Then I left.
What do we do now?
Wait for Steve
McQueen to get giddy.
Excellent plan.
Hey, Dad, it's Eric.
I'm not doing too good.
How's Foreman?
You're accessing a
webcam? Cuddy's shower.
Are you a fan of
the Brazilian? I...
Is that your kitchen?
Well, obviously I
couldn't bring him here.
He's been exposed to
whatever Foreman's got.
You infected Steve? Why didn't
you just get a rat from the pet store?
Because I needed one
with a clean medical history.
Who knows what kind of
antibiotics they gave those rats?
So this is your plan, just sit
here and watch your rat all day?
It shouldn't take long.
I've got the AC blasting, I
soaked the floor of his cage.
As soon as he gets
sick, I do an autopsy.
As soon as he's dead.
Right after he gets sick, there's a
good chance he'll get hit in the head
with a cane-shaped object.
Normally you just use
your patients as lab rats.
It's a nice change.
First symptom is euphoria.
Well, how do you
know if a rat's euphoric?
He doesn't usually climb on his
water bottle like that, does he?
The seizures only seem to
happen when she's in her car seat.
She starts to rock and grunt.
Is she responsive? No, no.
It's like she's in a zone
and her abdominal
muscles become dystonic.
Big word. Someone's
been on the Interweb.
I looked up a few
articles on epilepsy.
You know, there's actually some
really great youth soccer leagues
that would cater specifically
to her special needs,
and I think it might explain why she's
been having a hard time in preschool.
Well, let's confirm your diagnosis
before you have her held back.
Strobing lights and high-pitched
sounds can provoke a seizure.
You're a goof. Takes
one to know one, loser.
Wait, that means I'm
a loser. Scratch that.
These episodes, she
gets sweaty afterwards?
Soaking wet.
And does she seem
upset by them or just tired?
No. She kind of
thinks it's funny.
You mix rocking, grunting, sweating
and dystonia with concerned parents
and you get an amateur
diagnosis of epilepsy.
In actuality, all
your little girl is doing
is saying "yoo-hoo
to the hoo-hoo."
She's what?
Marching the penguin.
Ya-ya-ing the sisterhood.
Finding Nemo.
That was funny.
It's called "gratification
disorder." Sort of a misnomer.
If one was unable to gratify
oneself, that would be a disorder.
Are you saying
she's masturbating?
I was trying to be discreet.
There's a child in the room.
This is horrifying.
Epilepsy is horrifying.
Teach your girl about
privacy and she'll be fine.
There you go. Thank you.
One afternoon, and you're
on pace to set the record
for most patients
seen in a month.
You're upset that
I'm doing clinic hours?
Wow, that is so like
rain on your wedding day.
For the past three hours, I have been
on the phone with the CDC while you are...
How's that going, by the way?
They promised to expedite...
Tough to do an autopsy when
they haven't even picked up the body.
It's tough to treat your patient when
you're not even on the same floor.
Go. Clinic is covered.
I go watch the
meds drip into his IV,
you think that'll make
the treatment work faster?
Go to your office,
play with your ball,
write on your white
board, insult your team.
Do whatever it is that
you do to figure things out.
Feeling guilty? It's not too
late to change your mind.
Go call the CDC, tell
them you were just joshing.
Keep avoiding Foreman's
case until he dies.
Then I'll drown in guilt.
Feeling any better?
How are you doing?
I'm not the patient.
Is your sed rate elevated?
No. So far, it looks
like I lucked out.
Cameron, it looks like you
left the tourniquet on the bed.
You can see again?
The treatment's working.
The question is,
which treatment?
We'll start weaning him off one at
a time. Which one do we start with?
I don't care if you
do it alphabetically.
Just stay on top of his vision.
First sign of regression means
we've taken him off the wrong one.
Latest blood work. Foreman's amylase
and lipase levels are three times normal.
The pancreas is failing.
A toxic side effect of his meds.
Philosophical question:
How do you wanna die?
Old age.
Your choice is currently between 4
hours from now and 14 hours from now.
So I'm assuming that
means you want the latter.
The cocktail's working. My
vision's almost completely restored.
The meds are curing what's in your
head, but they're trashing your pancreas.
That's why you're puking and you
can't stand up without screaming.
So lower the dosages.
Less stress on my pancreas,
still battle the infection.
Lower dosages will
still be toxic. I don't care!
I can handle the pain
of the pancreatitis.
I don't think you can handle
life without a pancreas.
If we keep you on these meds,
you'll spend the last four hours
of your life being able to see.
We take you off,
you'll go blind again.
But it'll give us time to figure
out what's eating your brain.
Fine. What do we do next?
Eric?
Dad?
Yeah, you two can get caught up
later. Sir, I need you to come with me.
House, what is this?
He's not a "what," he's a "who."
They even have the right to vote now.
Rodney Foreman, Cuddy.
Cuddy, Rodney Foreman.
Nice to meet you, ma'am.
This is Foreman's dad.
Yeah, I got that.
And Dr. Cuddy here is
the Dean of Medicine.
Remember that cool
autopsy I was telling you about,
the one that would
save your son's life?
She's the one who can
give us the green light to do it.
I understand you
don't want them to do it.
Dr. House didn't
seem to know why.
Mr. Foreman, I am doing
everything I can to get the CDC...
Won't be soon enough.
And my decision to follow
public health
safety protocols...
Oh, don't blame the rules. Don't
hang this on policy and protocol.
I'm well aware that it
may cost your son his life,
just as I am well aware
that my decision has
a devastating effect
on family and friends,
without having them
paraded in front of me.
Your son has an unknown,
contagious, deadly infection.
If we don't contain it here, even
more people could be at risk.
And I am capable of
empathizing with those people too,
without having them
paraded in front of me.
I understand.
What's wrong with your hand?
It's called a
muscle contracture.
I thought this thing
was in your brain.
It is. It just means
the infection's moved
to the primary motor cortex,
which controls the muscles.
Aren't you glad you
sent me to med school?
Does it hurt? No.
Is it gonna?
The other guy,
he didn't seem
to suffer too much.
He just went in his sleep.
Steve's still acting normal.
No sign of contractures.
They got the cop's body
in a locked, airtight bag.
And a guard on the door.
Those feds are seriously paranoid.
He hasn't gotten up to
pee in hours. He's due.
You haven't sprinkled
Senokot granules on his donut?
His bowels would open
up like the Red Sea.
He wouldn't eat the donut.
Have you seriously
been down here for hours?
No.
I had to pee a couple times.
You've got to stop
blaming Cuddy for this.
Given that it is her fault,
that seems appropriate.
That part is her fault.
The part where somebody
wasted his time in the basement
plotting the overthrow of a
government agency, that one's on you.
Only thing I can do is think. You
can pretty much do that anywhere.
As long as no one's bugging me.
Did you call your brother?
No.
Did you? No.
It's not a big deal.
I sure would have liked
to see Mom, though.
You know she
can't travel anymore.
You tell her?
Why?
Just upset her for a while.
Then she wouldn't
remember for a while.
She should know.
She's lost a lot of who she was.
She can't deal with
something like this.
And you can?
I still know you're
going to a better place.
It's easy for you, isn't it?
As long as you believe I'm going
to a better place, dying ain't so bad.
I don't want you to be afraid.
If I'm not afraid of dying, what
the hell should I be afraid of, Dad?
I thought you believed.
I did.
I'm not so sure anymore.
I'm going to pray for you, Son.
I suggest you do the same.
Field of vision is regressing and
he's reached an eight on the pain scale.
The disease pattern is following
the exact course as Joe's.
Only it's moving much
faster in Foreman.
Good. It's an anomaly.
Anomalies tell us things.
Why would this go faster in
Foreman? What's different?
Could be a different
strain of the same disease?
Right! We were wasting all this
time looking for an unknown disease.
We should have be looking for a
different strain of an unknown disease.
Joe's a cop. He's
into physical fitness.
He could have had a more powerful
immune system, stronger metabolism.
Foreman's black. What?
How long have you been
sitting on this information?
Lupus, gout, glaucoma, osteoarthritis,
hypertension, diabetes, stop me anytime,
they all affect black
people more than whites.
Check everything.
Bacterials, fungals,
toxins, parasites.
Look for anything with a
documented racial disparity.
Wait.
The rat's showing symptoms? No.
He's completely healthy.
Maybe that's the difference
between Foreman and the cop.
How you feeling?
Why are you here?
Because you're a friend,
and I should be here.
I'm sorry House used my
dad to try and manipulate you.
You've got integrity.
You aren't going to change your mind just
because you're confronted by my father.
Thank you.
Just like I'm not
gonna forgive you,
just because you come by
here and ask how I'm feeling.
You know I've had no choice.
Of course you had a choice!
Regulations are clear.
And the punishment for
violating those regulations,
is it death?
Because frankly, I'm okay if
you get a fine, a suspension...
Hell, you can spend a couple
years in jail if it saves my life!
You're dying too fast.
Couldn't agree more.
Hey, Cuddy. Having a nice visit?
What's that?
Legionella...
Legionella pneumophilia.
And why are you carrying
a vial of it around with you?
Foreman was perfectly healthy
before he got this infection,
but our cop wasn't.
He had Legionnaire's disease,
and our cop didn't turn into brain
food until we cured the Legionella.
The Legionella slowed
down the disease.
Why would that happen?
No idea. I just
know that it did.
So you want to infect Foreman?
You gonna tattle to the CDC?
The meds can't help
me, but a disease can?
Forget it. Just take the
pain away. Put me under.
If I put you under, I
can't monitor your pain.
If I can't monitor your pain, I won't
know if the Legionella's working.
I'm not consenting
to you giving me...
What was that?
Wish there could have been
a puff of smoke or something.
Would have been
much more dramatic.
Keep your slippers on.
Wouldn't want
you to cut your foot.
You feeling any better?
I can't breathe. I'm dizzy
and I can barely hear anything
over the sounds of
my lungs crackling.
That's the Legionella.
Oh, you figured that
out from the symptoms
or from the vial of stuff
tossed in my room?
I'm trying to be professional here,
and there's no reason to be nasty.
I'm in pain. So is House.
And he's a delight.
He doesn't try to
kill his colleagues.
You can remove
the thermometer now.
It's down almost a whole
degree. How's the pain?
Great. It's the good kind.
How bad is it compared
to an hour ago?
No worse.
Is the Legionella helping?
Yeah.
Good. But not great.
It didn't fix anything,
it just slowed it down.
The whole point was to give
Steve a little more time to get sick.
What are you gonna
do if he never gets sick?
Brilliant.
Cameron, what type of illnesses
affect humans but not rats?
Why are you asking me that?
Because I'm sure that you
spent the first 12 years of your life
dreaming of being a vet.
The rat is not getting sick.
Cameron is not
getting sick. Sorry.
It's okay, it's not your fault.
Presumably, you're still healthy because
whatever it is, it's not blood-borne.
Steve has no excuse. He did
everything that Foreman did.
Some bacterial
infections don't affect rats.
Foreman tested negative for every bacterial
infection that would affect his brain.
And what infections could he be
positive for but test negative for?
When we test for infections,
we look for antibodies.
Now, what if the patient is
infected but has no antibodies?
What if the body is not
fighting the infection?
Why would... I asked first.
Let's start with the "what."
We'll deal with the "why" later.
If the body doesn't recognize the
infection, our tests come back negative,
and the disease rampages
through the body unstopped.
Exactly like the cop
and exactly like Foreman.
Now, what if the patient was
then exposed to a second infection,
like Legionella?
The body would recognize that
infection, increase the white count,
send in the troops
to start fighting,
and the initial infection would
get caught in the crossfire.
So the question becomes
what type of bacterial infection
affects humans but not rats,
and the human body would
be unlikely to recognize?
The answer is listeria.
I'm starting you
on amp and gent.
So, you're basing this theory
on the tests being negative
and your rat being healthy?
And the fact that
Legionnaire's is helping you.
But the medicine you want to
give me will put an end to that.
Yeah.
And if it's not listeria, all the gent will
do is cure the Legionnaire's disease
and put whatever is killing
me back into overdrive.
Stop asking me questions based
on the premise that I'm wrong.
The antibiotics
are in the airlock.
I think the first biopsy
didn't give us the answer
because you didn't
go deep enough.
I want you to do a
white matter brain biopsy.
Absolutely. Don't blame you.
The world is such a complicated place
if you've got higher reasoning skills.
I'm often jealous of small
animals and retarded children.
Take the antibiotics.
There can be minimal
damage if it's done right,
if the surgeons drill
where I tell them to drill.
One slip, you could spend the
rest of your life not being able
to keep your drool
in your mouth.
I'd rather be
disabled than dead.
Sure! I make it look oh-so-sexy.
It's actually not as
glamorous as you might think.
The biopsy will tell us
for sure what's wrong.
The antibiotics could
do the same thing!
"Could," not "will."
We try it, we see.
The antibiotics will
bring back the pain!
Pain makes us
make bad decisions.
Fear of pain is almost
as big a motivator.
Look, we still have time.
I will do that biopsy if I have
to. But not a moment before.
Start Foreman on IV
antibiotics. Where's his dad?
Where you're supposed to
be when your son is dying.
He's not with him.
He's in the chapel.
Oh, man...
I started your son on a
new course of treatment.
If it works, he'll get better.
If it doesn't, he won't.
While he's not getting better,
he's going to
experience so much pain
that we'll have to put him in
a chemically-induced coma
while we figure
out what to do next.
My son says you're a
manipulative bastard.
It's a pet name. I
call him "Dr. Bling."
I assume you're here for a
reason. What do you want from me?
When your son is in a coma,
you're the one who's gonna have to
make the medical decisions for him.
Whatever you decide is fine.
You don't care what I do? I'm
not a doctor. What do I know,
except what Eric tells me?
He says you're the best
doctor he's ever worked with.
I need your help.
There's nothing I can give you
for the pain. I want to be put out.
I can have a nurse in
here in five minutes. No.
Once I'm out, I
might not come back.
I've never done a will.
I'll call a lawyer for you.
I want you to be
my medical proxy.
All the things that piss me
off about you in House's office,
you're too emotional and
too caring, too cautious...
They're all good
things on this floor.
Your dad is... No.
He cares about you. So do you.
I can't do this.
We expect family members to
make decisions about their loved ones
after a 10-minute briefing,
that we're agonizing over
even with years of
medical experience.
That's from my article.
I'm sorry, Allison.
I shouldn't have
stolen your article.
I shouldn't have exposed you.
You were a friend.
I need to know that we're okay.
No.
I'll be your proxy,
but we're not okay.
You're scared you're dying and it's the
only reason you want to set things right.
We're gonna get you
better first and then,
if you still wanna
apologize, I'll be around.
I'll call that lawyer.
Any improvements? No.
As far as we can tell, the only thing the
antibiotics are treating is the Legionella.
I think we need to
consider alternate theories.
Like what?
We do the biopsy. We...
Give the antibiotics more time.
There is no more time. The
pain is almost unbearable already.
So he's almost in unbearable
pain. He's not almost dead!
Which means we have more time.
Mr. Foreman?
We need to put
your son in a coma.
You should be there.
It's a medical procedure, right?
Yeah.
But once we put him
out, if we don't solve this,
he won't wake up.
What should I say?
Should I talk to him
like it's going to be okay?
Or should I be saying goodbye?
I need to know what
people say when...
Just tell him you love him.
Hey, Son. Hey, Dad.
It's going to be okay.
You don't know that.
I know.
You don't.
I don't wanna miss you.
I love you too, Dad.
Hey,
it's gonna be okay.
Can we do this
now? Yeah, of course.
I accept your apology.
Why weren't you with Foreman?
I hang out in the basement, you rag
on me. I stay in my office, you rag on me.
Honky just can't buy a break.
Do the biopsy.
Based on the cop's progression, I
figure he's got about another four hours...
You figure?
You're playing Russian roulette,
but the gun's pointed at him.
No. Cutting open his
head is what's dangerous.
Oh, it's dangerous. Well,
what would people think?
The reason you
don't see patients
is because if you know them,
you'll give a crap about them.
I know you. If you give a crap,
you stop making
outrageous calls.
If this was any other patient,
you'd have damned the risk
and cut their head
open a long time ago.
He's out. The EEG
shows he's still in pain.
The antibiotics have had
more than enough time.
We're doing the brain biopsy.
Not unless you people can't come up with
something clever in the next three hours.
Now. We're doing it now.
Well, who died and
made you boss? Foreman.
It's legal. He's
out of his mind.
Yesterday he was giggling
about a hole in a guy's head.
Then hire a lawyer and challenge it.
In the meantime, Cameron's in charge.
Why would he sign that?
It's nothing personal,
Mr. Foreman.
My son doesn't trust me. How
exactly is that not personal?
I'm sorry.
You're sorry? You're
talking about this man's son!
You're denying him
the right to be a part...
Oh, shut up, House.
If you want to do the
biopsy, do the biopsy.
If House tries to interfere, let
me know and I will take care of it.
Yeah, you're a hero.
If it wasn't for you, we'd be cutting into
a dead guy's head instead of Foreman's.
Sorry.
Thanks.
That was great! It was
rude and unnecessary.
Yeah. Go away.
Give me time. We're out of time.
An hour. What does
"out of time" mean?
His O2 sats are at 94 right now.
As long as they're above 90, danger
of fatal arrhythmia doesn't increase.
So what? There's
no point in waiting.
You were right. We should
be cutting into a corpse's head.
Yeah, we should be, except the
CDC's got the cop's body under...
There's got to be other bodies.
You think this thing
has killed other people?
No.
That apartment was a dump.
Just because Steve McQueen didn't get
sick doesn't mean some other vermin didn't.
You give me an
hour, I go back there,
I find a dead animal, I cut its
head open instead of Foreman's.
Foreman's already
on 100% oxygen.
Once his O2 sats hit
90, I can't wait any longer.
Where's your suit?
Either you'll find the answer or I'll
find the answer. It doesn't matter.
Prep the drill. We've got to be
ready to go if we get the signal.
Ninety-two.
I found a blind bird.
Great. How fast can
you get it in here?
I'll know in about 30 seconds.
You better have the bird.
The surgical team's in place.
I screwed up. How can
you not capture a blind bird?
That's not what I meant. I screwed
up the first time through this place.
Foreman told you everywhere he
went. It's not "where," it's "when."
He came here early afternoon.
Me and Steve came through two
hours too late. You were six hours early.
It's the water. The irrigation
system only pumps at...
House! I tested the
water! The water's clean.
House. We tested
the wrong water.
He stole cable, he stole
fertilizer and he stole water.
It's riddled with
Naegleria. I know.
You already did the biopsy.
I thought I had no choice.
How's my son?
He has primary amoebic
meningoencephalitis.
It's a parasite that
goes through the nose
and migrates into the brain,
where it feeds on brain cells.
The Legionella attacked the parasite.
That's why the disease slowed down.
Is it treatable?
We started him
on an antiparasitic
and the amoebas will
clear out of his system.
And he'll be okay?
Then we'll wean
him out of the coma...
Will he be okay?
There'll be no lasting
damage from the parasite.
But the surgery?
We don't know.
Up and at 'em.
How you feeling?
Can you talk?
I don't feel anything.
Are you numb?
No, I mean,
I don't feel any pain.
Keep your head
still. Follow my finger.
I'm okay. Your breath stinks,
and you're peeing into a
bag. What are our names?
You did the biopsy?
Thank you. Names?
Cameron,
my dad
and the manipulative bastard.
You remembered.
How you doing, Dad?
Great.
Relieved. Great.
What did I have?
Naegleria. Biopsy
showed the amoeba,
the CDC autopsy
eventually found the amoeba,
and House found it in
the water on the cop's roof.
Wiggle your left
toes. Wait. What?
You went back and she did the
biopsy? Your left toes, Foreman.
I just did.
No, you didn't.
He can't move his toes.
He can move them.
Raise your right arm.
What?