- Previously on The Resident...
- Would Nic approve
of me , with Cade?
- I just want you
- To be happy.
It feels like there's
something between you.
We share something that's...
It's hard to describe.
I am not bargaining with you.
Please, uh, anything
that you want,
but you cannot tell Conrad.
If you go to rehab,
I won't tell anyone.
I just closed
on the perfect condo
for Padma and the babies.
Babies cry, Padma.
No, this is
hard, do you understand?
What are they doing?
They're pulling the plug?
You can save everyone
in this damn hospital,
but you won't save her?
Nic is gone.
I'll never forgive you for this.
Miss me already?
You know I do.
How's your drive up
to the vineyard going?
Good. I, um...
- I just got here.
- Oh.
Okay then, what's on the agenda
for this long-awaited
girls' trip?
Wine tasting today,
all day spa
reservation tomorrow.
Well, I'm glad
you're getting away.
You work hard. You
deserve a break.
Have fun.
Bye.
Hi, are you here for family day?
Yes.
And your loved one is?
My father, Dr. Ian Sullivan.
Welcome. Sign in.
AJ, hi.
Your text was vague.
Where are you? Is
everything okay?
Oh, I'm sorry. My van
broke down in Savannah,
and I couldn't get it into
a shop until this morning.
Okay. Well, I'm glad
you're all right.
Well, they said it could
be fixed by this afternoon,
so I'll be back
as soon as I can.
Great. All right, look,
Serena's here early,
so we've got it covered
till you get back.
Great, I guess
I'll see you then.
Hey, let me put you on
speakerphone so the boys
can hear your voice.
Actually, AJ, I can't.
The mechanic just got
here, so I have to go.
Sure. All right, well, text me
when you're back on the road.
A 68-year-old man, found
passed out on the street,
lacerations on his
forehead and knees,
heartrate's in
the 50s, BP 98/52.
Can you grab
me some stuff for labs
- and an EKG machine?
- I got it.
On my count.
One, two, three.
Chastain was the
nearest hospital,
but he did not
want to come here.
Yeah, yeah, and I still don't.
Look, hey, hey.
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Just-just... Let me out of...
I got to... I-I got to...
I got to be somewhere...
Conrad, you
better get over here.
It's Nic's dad.
Nice to see you too, Kyle.
Wait, you guys know him?
It's been a minute.
It sure has.
Oh, I want out of here.
Get me out of here.
We just want to help you.
Yeah, well, they can...
They can check me out,
but you, you stay the
hell away from me.
Resync By M_I_S
www.opensubtitles.org
God. Kyle Nevin.
The last time I saw him
was the day Nic died.
He didn't even come
to the funeral,
he was so angry at me.
He's still upset with
you five years later?
Figured he'd get in touch
if he wanted to see
his granddaughter.
But he never did.
How does he seem?
Not well.
He's not taking care of himself.
I should have tried
harder to reconnect.
You tried.
If he didn't even want to
see Gigi, that's on him.
Blaming you for Nic's death,
after we did everything we
could to try and save her?
The scans just came back
on one of my patients.
Are you good?
Yeah.
Have you ever passed
out like this before?
What? No. No, I was just
walking to my car. Maybe...
I don't know, maybe I tripped
or something. I don't know.
Do you have trouble
getting up stairs or hills?
Look, I run out of
breath sometimes,
but find me a guy
my age that doesn't.
Is there anyone I can call
to bring you your things,
- to make you more comfortable?
- No, no, no.
I don't have any
friends here anymore.
I just came to Georgia to
clear out a storage unit.
Okay.
Where are you living these days?
Vermont.
Is there a doctor
there that I can call
to get your medical history?
No, no. No, look, stop.
No, there are no doctors,
there is no history.
None that I care
to remember anyway.
Oh, this place looks
exactly the same.
Oh, well, there've been
some changes around here.
We even have a new preschool
and a kindergarten now...
Wait, what? Preschool?
What kind of kid
wants to go to
preschool at a hospital?
There's one student
there you might know.
Gigi?
- Yup.
- Gigi?
Yeah, she's in kindergarten,
so we see her a lot around here.
All right, so,
I would like to admit you,
get you on repeat
labs and an EKG.
- Is that okay with you?
- Yeah, sure, whatever.
Can I see Gigi first?
Thanks for doing this.
Once Kyle realized
that Gigi was here,
he wouldn't talk
about anything else.
Well, that's a surprise,
but if it gives me a way
to get eyes on him...
Why haven't I seen
Grandpa before?
He lives far away.
Gigi, that's
your grandfather, Kyle.
Kyle...
you remember Georgiana Grace.
Say hi, honey.
Hi.
Wow.
You look a lot like
your mother did
when she was about your age.
Everyone says
she looks like Nic.
Yeah.
Hey, you want to come up here
and you want to sit beside me?
Yeah? Okay.
Come on.
That's a girl.
Are you okay, Kyle?
Yeah, yeah, I just
got that capal thing.
- Whatever...
- Carpal tunnel?
Carpal tunnel, yeah, both hands,
but... hardly the worst
of my worries right now.
You look different from the
pictures Daddy showed me.
More handsome, I hope?
You showed her pictures?
Of course.
I wanted her to know
her grandfather.
There she
is.
Thanks for making the drive.
You look great, Dad.
How are you feeling?
Honestly, the last few weeks
have been tougher
than I expected.
Because of the detox?
Crazy nausea, palpitations,
panic attacks on steroids.
That wasn't even the worst part.
What was?
Therapy.
Our counselor Genevieve,
she takes no prisoners.
She had me digging into stuff
I've avoided for a long time.
About my father.
Your mother.
And you think that's helped?
I know it has.
But what kept me going?
Knowing I'd see you today.
All right,
if everyone could please take
a seat, we'll get started.
Look, I told you
everything Padma told me.
She's in Savannah,
she'll be back tonight.
I know what she said,
but how did she sound?
Normal.
Why isn't she
returning my calls?
This is your sister we're
talking about, all right?
Whose idea of fun is
llama yoga in the woods.
AJ, I'm really
getting worried, okay?
She really loves her babies.
These last few months have
been rough on everybody,
especially Padma.
So if she needs an extra
day or two to unwind,
that's a win for everybody.
And plus, I've made sure the
boys are well taken care of.
We're good.
I got to go.
Hi, you've reached
Padma. Leave a message.
This bright area is the tumor.
After all these
years, it's... back?
It's a good thing that you and
Lance brought her in today.
Now that we know
what's going on...
we need to talk
about what's next.
You mean surgery,
like last time?
It's more complicated now.
Your mom is older, she's
not quite as strong,
and the tumor is
different, larger,
and now in an area of the brain
that's more dangerous to access,
with a very high risk of
bleeding if we operate.
I don't recommend surgery.
You don't want to save her?
Of course I do.
But based on the location
and size of the tumor,
I believe that surgery is
more likely to do harm.
You're saying you
can't fix this?
Even if you make it through
the surgery, you could die,
sooner rather than later,
because we operated.
And a cure isn't
possible in my opinion.
You're not hearing us.
We are not giving up on
her, and neither should you.
I beat cancer once.
I'll beat it again.
I want the surgery.
And if you
won't operate,
well, we'll find
someone who will.
We need a more detailed
patient history.
Well, Kyle hasn't been
exactly forthcoming,
but I will keep trying.
I guess I'll go check on
patients who want my help today.
We'll keep you posted.
Thank you.
Hey, did you call for
an interventional cardiologist?
I did not.
Hey.
Oh, hey.
Gentlemen, I saw
Mr. Nevin bradying down
on the monitors at
the nurses' station,
figured I'd check in and
make sure he's doing okay.
New guy's got to be
proactive, right?
Dr. Yamada thinks he knows
what might be going on.
I'd like to start
with a stress test.
And I'd like Dr. Austin to
examine my patient first.
Thank you, Dr. Pravesh.
Sure, but you'll
need to go fast.
Transport is on the way.
Wonderful.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
How's he doing?
His stress test just started.
Thanks for getting him
set up, Dr. Yamada.
- I'll take it from here.
- I'd like to stick around
- and help out.
- Well, I really appreciate that,
but Kyle is basically family.
So, I'm in a unique position
to offer clinical judgment
without any personal
feelings in the way.
Hey, we got it.
- Got a chair for you.
- We got a chair right here.
- All right.
- There you go.
Oh, I'm good.
I just got a little
dizzy.
Let me see the printout.
His heartrate didn't increase
during the stress test
like we would have
expected it to.
It was too low.
That's why he's been
short of breath.
If it gets any
lower, he could die.
And if we don't intervene,
that's exactly what will happen.
But let's face it,
at the end of the day,
addiction isn't one
person's disease.
It's the entire family's.
Maybe you feel guilt
because you didn't
recognize it sooner,
or you're angry
because you didn't get
the love and care
you longed for.
So later today, your loved
ones will get a chance
to hear what you've
been through.
Everyone must talk honestly,
maybe for the first time,
for true recovery to begin.
Oh.
Well, what a wonderful surprise
to wake up to.
Daddy told me to let you sleep.
He said you needed your rest.
You tell him you were
quiet as a mouse.
He said you fell. Are you hurt?
Not really.
Just my pride.
Daddy can fix that, too. He
can make anything better.
Except your mom.
He couldn't save her.
He tried. He
misses her so much.
I think it's time we
consider possible next steps.
I only see one. We
need to get Mr. Nevin
to the cath lab right away.
Because you think
his episodes of bradycardia
are caused by a
lesion you can stent?
- Seems likely to me.
- Hmm.
It's possible. His
stress test didn't show
- signs of ischemia.
- No slam dunk signs of it,
but there were
nonspecific changes.
All right,
let's back up here.
There is no clear evidence
of coronary artery disease.
AJ's right. Kyle
only failed the test
because he couldn't
increase his heartrate.
Which could be
due to a blockage.
Or maybe he just
needs a pacemaker.
Okay, and what
would you recommend?
I want to monitor him, get
an electrophysiology study,
and probably go ahead
and put in a pacemaker.
And while we're waiting, he may
very well have a heart attack.
All right, why don't
we start with the cath?
If there's blockage,
maybe we find the source.
In the meantime, I don't
think a stent or a pacemaker's
the full answer, so
we keep searching,
not just for something that
explains his arrhythmia,
but the rest of his issues, too.
Sounds like a plan.
Cool.
If I really thought
Doris had a shot,
of course I'd take it.
That's all tumor.
It is, and entangled
in the vasculature.
At worst, she never
makes it out of the OR,
and at best, surgery buys her,
what, a few months?
Likely with permanent
neurological deficits.
A doctor has the right
to refuse to operate.
But her sons said
that if I don't,
they'll find a surgeon who will.
They're not gonna find
anyone as good as you.
Look, it's your decision,
but... if there's even
the slightest chance
she could end up better off,
you're the best person to
give her a decent outcome.
I'm sorry, you guys
can't go any further.
Hey, you got this, Mom.
We love you.
You'll be okay.
So, Dr. Yamada found a
lesion in the right coronary artery.
He's stenting it now.
If Kyle's bradycardia persists,
he's definitely gonna
need a pacemaker.
Something else is going on here.
Nic would
want me to help him.
I mean, I'm just gonna say, I'm
surprised you are not angry.
I mean, the man walked away
from you and his
only grandchild.
I forgave him a long time ago.
The day Nic died, he lost
the only child he had left.
The need to blame
someone's natural.
Well, seems to me,
once we patch him up,
he's going to be on his way,
and probably not coming back.
Yeah, so whatever is wrong
with him, we better fix it now.
This tumor is even more vascular
than it appeared on the scans.
Pressures are dropping fast.
It's eroding into
the surrounding vessels.
She's bleeding out.
Increase suction.
Add a pressor.
We're maxed out.
Then activate massive
transfusion protocol.
We need to buy some time.
Don't give up.
Hang in there.
Forceps.
I knew this was a bad idea.
You're Ian's daughter, right?
Uh, yeah, I am.
Jan Price.
Fellow inmate. That's
what we call ourselves
- since we can't leave.
- Ah.
Ian told me you're
not only an ER doctor,
but an ICU doc, too?
Yeah, I couldn't
choose, so I chose both.
Well, that's impressive.
No wonder he doesn't
stop talking about you.
Especially the way that
you took care of him
when he was diagnosed
with cancer.
That meant a lot to him.
That's nice to hear.
Sorry. Did he tell
you to say all this?
No, not at all.
I just wish I were
more like your dad.
He's been a
cheerleader for us all,
and an inspiration
for many of us here.
Nice meeting you.
The tumor was deep
inside the brain,
entangled among several
key blood vessels.
And you got it out?
Yes, but there was a
lot of bleeding, and...
Now our mom's gonna be okay?
I never said that.
I was honest about
the risks involved,
and the fact that a total
cure isn't possible.
The surgery went as
well as it could,
but we won't know for sure
how Doris tolerated it
until she wakes up.
And even then, her
recovery will be long
with the possibility of
many post-op complications.
You said that she wouldn't
make it out of surgery...
but she did.
We know our mom.
She's gonna beat this.
Padma's gonna call you
back as soon as she can.
No, something's not right.
"Twintuition" is
real, and in the past,
no matter how far
away she's gone,
I could always sense if
she was sick or hurting
or in trouble.
But Padma has gone radio
silent like this before, right?
I remember that one time she
left in her van for a month
without taking her cell phone.
She was connecting with nature.
That was long before
she had babies.
Okay, here's what we know:
She told AJ that she was
gonna be back tonight,
and tonight is still
a couple hours away.
And you...
sometimes get overly anxious
when it comes to your sister.
Maybe, just for today,
give her some space.
She's not answering texts
because she doesn't want to.
Okay.
All right, I'll see you.
You have
a new doctor, I see.
Uh, nurse, thank you very much.
Daddy said I could spend
recess with Grandpa Kyle.
Oh.
Your heart is good.
Do you have any pain?
Yeah, yeah, I do.
My back hurts.
- It's... It...
- Let me take a look.
Grandpa! Grandpa!
Come here, Gigi.
Take Gigi.
I need a code cart in here.
What happened?
She had some runs of V tach,
but then went into V fib.
Likely from a
cerebral catastrophe.
I wish I could have
at least gotten her to CT.
Her pupils are
fixed and dilated.
I've already given her mannitol.
We've shocked her three times
with no return of
spontaneous circulation.
There's nothing more we can do.
Time of death 16:37.
This is exactly what
I was afraid of.
They should've listened to me.
Where are her sons?
I have to operate on
another critical patient.
They went to the cafeteria.
Well, I'll break the news
to them as soon as I'm out.
Sure, we hope this
time is different,
but honestly, I doubt it.
Three times in treatment,
three times it failed.
I don't know how long we
can keep trying to help
before we walk away.
And we can't keep
the truth about your disease
from Mom and Dad any longer.
Yes, it'll hurt them,
but how can you
accept responsibility
for the pain you've caused
if we keep covering it up?
Jan, can you see
how your sisters lying for you
is detrimental to them?
And how that enables you?
I never asked
anyone to lie.
Seriously? You asked
me to lie to your work
when you blacked out
at the Hawks game.
Not to mention all the
lies you've told me.
I can't believe the last time
I actually believed a word
coming out of your mouth. I
feel like you would lie to us
about anything.
Is Grandpa okay?
Well, his heart slowed down
just for a little while,
which is why he
seemed to fall asleep,
but it started again.
Is he gonna die?
We're figuring out what's wrong.
Now...
you should go back
to your classroom
and let the doctors
do their work.
Come on, princess, let's get
you back to your schoolmates.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
His heart rate stopped
for five seconds,
then spontaneously restarted.
If the blockage Dr. Yamada found
was the sole cause
of his issues,
this wouldn't have happened.
He must have sick
sinus syndrome.
Okay, so we agree that
he needs a pacemaker?
Yes, we are all in agreement.
Well, the question
is why he needs it.
Hawkins, I trust your judgment.
If there's another diagnosis
to be found, you'll find it,
but this man needs a pacer,
and he needs it yesterday.
Yeah, let's get him
on the schedule.
Hey, where's our mom?
Did you move her?
There was a
post-op complication.
Your mother's heart stopped,
and we did everything we could
to try to restart it, but...
she didn't make it.
I'm so sorry.
What the hell are
you talking about?
You're saying she's dead?
She was just here.
I just saw her.
We need to talk to
Dr. Sutton. Now.
She got pulled into
an emergency surgery,
and she wanted to be
the one to tell you.
I am so sorry.
No, no, no, no. No!
Please calm down.
We don't even know
who the hell you are.
Dr. Sutton was the one
who did the operation.
We have grief counselors.
Let me call them.
Haven't you done enough?!
Sealing off the aneurysm.
Is this where they kill people?!
You can't be in here.
This is a sterile environment.
- You killed our mother!
- Code Gray in OR Two.
Give me that!
Security is coming.
Get out of my OR.
Are you okay?
Did security find them?
No, they're still looking,
but they think they're gone.
Billie, I am so sorry.
The sons, they just...
They just walked in,
and the mother wasn't there.
I had to tell them.
It's not your fault.
They were wrong to
push for the surgery.
Maybe they know it,
so they blame someone.
Sometimes I don't know
how I keep doing this.
Are you okay?
I don't want to be okay.
That would mean that I've lost
the ability to feel anything.
You should go home.
I can't.
I have another patient
I actually can help.
I have to do it.
That's why I'm here.
The work helps to steady me.
I got this.
Ventricular lead.
Thank you, Dr. Yamada.
You know, you would make
an excellent assistant,
Dr. Yamada.
Well, be sure to
pin the guide wire
to the drape, Dr. Austin.
We don't want it ending up
in the pulmonary circulation.
I hadn't planned on
that, Dr. Yamada.
Do they both need
to be in there?
There's a bit of a
turf battle going on.
I'm worried about Kyle
after he leaves Chastain.
Maybe his underlying
diagnosis is loneliness.
That is more dangerous
than some diseases.
And harder to treat.
Good, we have capture.
Nice.
Pressure's in the 80s.
Stop the V pacing.
Now, let's get the
atrial lead in.
We're gonna have to
start on the pressors.
Hold on, hold on.
Well, look at that,
pressure's back up.
His blood pressure tanked
as soon as they
paced his ventricles.
So when his ventricle was the only
chamber working, his pressure fell.
Which could happen because
his ventricle is so thick.
Which is generally the result of
longstanding high
blood pressure.
His isn't high.
Borderline low, even.
Poor guy. Kyle has had
everything else go wrong.
He said he had back pain.
And carpal tunnel.
Plus anemia, renal dysfunction,
bradycardia,
thickened ventricle.
All of them together
means Kyle has...
Amyloidosis.
You were right, he has a
long-standing diagnosis
that explains everything.
It would've killed him.
But now we can treat it.
There's something very difficult
that I... I realize
I have to admit.
How much I've hurt you.
The key characteristic
of my addiction,
at least when I'm using,
is narcissism.
My work, my needs,
they were all that mattered.
It-It's a miracle that
you turned out to be
the incredible person
you are.
So please, believe
me when I tell you
that I am ready...
to do better.
Would you like to respond?
Charm is a deadly deceiver.
And my father has charm.
More than anyone I know.
He uses it
to win over people he needs.
He's charmed all of you.
But it's a magic trick,
and you fell for the illusion.
Honey, I'm being open
and honest,
admitting my flaws...
Ian, you're supposed to listen.
You know all the
right words to say,
and you say them,
but there is no way on earth
to know if you
actually mean them.
I will show you.
I will walk the walk. You
just have to believe in me.
Oh, so your sobriety is
dependent on my belief in you.
That line...
That line is such a crock,
and I'm done with it.
I've believed,
I've hoped a hundred times.
And what's worse
is I've enabled.
I lied to my school
when you didn't show up for
parent-teacher conferences,
I-I told the court you
were an exemplary parent
because I was
afraid to lose you.
And throughout it all,
your workplace never knew.
No matter where you
were, I protected you.
Even now, I'm-I'm
lying to your boss,
I'm lying to my own boyfriend.
I...
I think I should really go
because all I see here
breaks me.
Other families'
lives torn apart,
other relatives'
lives destroyed,
I see myself in all of them.
We've all been dragged
down by this disease,
and I... I can't go any lower.
Ian, you can get sober or don't.
But it's your problem.
Cade, wait, please.
I can't. I'm done.
Don't-don't say that.
You're right, those
were just words,
but let me show
you with actions.
They-they told me I was
going to need a goal
if I was gonna have any kind
of sustained, real recovery,
and something that I
wanted more than anything,
that I could only
get in sobriety,
and I thought that that
goal was going to be
somehow to get my career back,
but I realize now it's something
much more important than that.
My goal is to make amends to you
for all the harm
that I have done.
Sweetheart, I...
I never even thought about
what my addiction did to you.
I know. To admit
that, to say that,
it's horrible.
But if I can live
knowing that every day,
I have a chance, a hope
to make that up to you?
Cade...
Give me a chance
to prove to you
and win back your love.
You're the only father I have,
but I'm not lying
for you anymore.
And then, the two men
just... they just left.
Yeah, before security
could get to them.
Well, we need to make
sure they're gone.
I already went through
our surveillance videos
from floors three and four.
Did you check the OR suite?
There.
That's them.
They're still in the hospital.
This is 301.
We have a pair of adult
males, possibly dangerous,
seen on the seventh floor.
Is Billie still in
surgery on that floor?
I don't know. Maybe.
Request
immediate response
to that area.
You killed our mother,
now we're gonna kill you.
Are you okay?
Keep him up.
Stay down!
They wanted to throw
me down the stairs.
Uh, to kill me.
That's what they said.
If Conrad hadn't shown
up when he did...
I'm just so glad you're okay.
I just hope Billie is, too.
She's almost done
with her statement.
I got to go get
Gigi, check on Kyle.
Why don't I help? I
can take Billie home.
That's okay. She
asked me to drive her.
I'll meet you in Kyle's room.
Hey, I'll see you at home, okay?
Hey.
You got a second?
Yeah.
Look, we got off
on the wrong foot.
I take the blame for that.
You did excellent work today.
My assumption is, for
as long as you're here,
you and I are going to do
more good work together,
so I believe that you
deserve the truth.
Okay.
I'm all ears.
Conrad's wife Nic
was Billie's best friend.
And after he lost her,
I don't think he
ever got past that,
and maybe he never will,
but what you need to know is
Conrad and Billie
love each other.
I know that's tough
for you and Cade,
because whether they wake
up to the truth or not,
it's always gonna
come between you.
Thanks.
How are you feeling, Kyle?
Better.
That is because your son-in-law
figured out that you
have amyloidosis,
which means that
protein is accumulating
in places that it shouldn't,
and that explains
your slow heart rate,
fatigue and even
your carpel tunnel.
- Seriously?
- Yeah.
But we can treat it, and the guy
that you've been
blaming for Nic's death,
whose own heart broke
trying to save her,
he's the person you have
to thank for all of this.
Always had to be the hero.
Hey.
Someone wanted to see you.
So, I was right, wasn't I?
My dad can fix anything.
Thank you.
I've been so lonely.
This child is everything.
Good night, Grandpa. I'm
glad you're back home.
When I first got here,
you asked where home is.
There's your answer.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Thank you.
For everything.
You came to the rescue.
Ah, please, you've rescued
me hundreds of times.
Nic would have been
proud of you today.
I want you to be proud of me.