Previously on The Resident...
Babies cry, Padma.
Just hold them as
much as you can.
It's just hard,
do you understand?
This isn't about your
emotional fortitude.
It's about your MS.
The stress is bad for you.
The twins aren't even crawling,
and I'm terrified
for them already.
Never truly realized how fragile
they are until I held my own
flesh and blood in my arms.
You know, you're not really
selling the parenthood
- thing here.
- Thank God I don't have twins.
That's not helping
either, Hawkins.
A little fuel to start the day.
Ugh. Does it come in an IV?
I was up all night.
Neighbor had a party.
Nothing like EDM blasting
through the walls
to lull you to sleep.
- Who said I was trying to sleep?
- Hmm?
I got right in there and
taught those fools the wobble.
Hey...
Hello,
I'm not ordering
French fries here. Can
I get some damn help?
What do we think, ATV accident
- or cow tipping gone wrong?
- Help, doctor.
Uh, $20 these two make
their own fireworks.
Thank you.
Hi, I'm Dr. Feldman.
This is Nurse Hundley.
- What happened?
- Uh, my buddy Wolf here
is in a little bit
of pain, that's all.
Okay, we'll take care
of him, and your name?
- Cricket.
- All right, Wolf and Cricket.
Let's get you checked out.
Don't need an exam.
Just...
just something for the pain.
Hmm.
Well, I can't prescribe
any medication
without a full exam.
So, where exactly
is this pain?
All over.
Looks like you've got
some blood on your arm.
Let us take a look.
He don't
like to be touched.
Well, then we're not
gonna get very far today.
Told you. This was a bad idea.
Let's go somewhere else.
- Hold on...
- Do not touch me!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What's going on here?
Well, they won't let us leave.
If you let us take
a look at your arm,
we'll give you
something for the pain.
All right.
Come on, take a seat.
Lie down.
CONRAD Ooh...
That looks like it hurts.
- It does.
- Yeah?
Okay, what did this to you?
Nothing.
A cat.
Maine Coon.
Big sucker.
- Must've been ginormous.
- Yes, sir.
40 pounder. We don't call
her Girlzilla for nothing.
Good morning.
The cavalry has arrived.
Hey, hey, little fellas.
Mama's getting you all
squeaky clean, huh?
Trying.
I got them wristbands
because they're so
hard to tell apart,
especially at this age.
Hey, I'll tag in.
I can't believe the
sitter bailed last-minute.
- Maybe I should stay home.
- Hey.
No, that is nonsense, Padma.
You have been overwhelmed
for months, and you deserve
the day off.
Thanks.
Oh, I just want to
feel like myself again.
Hopefully, this
self-care day does it.
I really appreciate
you stepping up.
I know today's a
big day for you.
Hey, no worries. I have a
couple hours before the surgery,
and Chastain nursery
will take them.
I'm sure they'll like it there.
I'll be back by
8:00. Oh, and, um,
Elijah is the green wristband,
and Arjun is the blue.
Got it.
Oh...
Maybe, uh...
Hey, Padma.
Wow. Sam, this is amazing.
Another hour,
and your patient
will have a brand-new
titanium ribcage
tailored to fit her chest wall.
And this only took
three days to build.
Well, at Inman Park Tech, we
make the impossible possible.
Well, if anyone deserves
it, it's-it's Tessa.
She was one of my
clinical trial patients,
and sadly, the meds didn't work,
and so the cancer
spread to her ribs.
If the surgery
goes well today,
this could be the start
of a new life for her.
And the beginning of a
beautiful new partnership
between Inman Park
Tech and Chastain.
You know, I have to be honest,
Dr. Pravesh, I was
skeptical about doing
business with Chastain.
Everyone knows you're about
to get your funding cut.
Don't count us out.
We're fighting hard to stay in
business, while still delivering
care with the same
level of excellence.
You see, that spunk right
there is why we decided
to support Chastain
in being the first hospital
in America to implant
a titanium ribcage.
- Ah, come over here.
- Hey, Sam.
- Dr. Pravesh, this is Gina.
- Hi.
- She's making a documentary about our lab.
- Hi. Nice to meet you.
They've already received
early interest from Sundance.
Yeah, now it's just about
finding a great story,
and Sam thinks your
patient has one.
We'd like Gina and her crew to
film the implantation surgery.
Um...
Well, I would need to
get clearance first
and the consent of the
patient, of course.
It would be great
publicity for us both,
and you'd be getting the
word out that Chastain
is still a
cutting-edge hospital.
All right, um, let
me see what I can do.
Great.
So, I have some good news. I
just spoke with Dr. Pravesh,
and your surgery will
definitely happen today.
Oh,
Dr. Pravesh is an angel.
Your titanium ribs will
be here within the hour.
Wow.
A titanium rib cage.
Will they let me through TSA?
I'm worried. We thought
the last surgery
- would fix everything.
- Oh, please,
don't question the
doctors, Wendy.
They made no promises
when they operated.
- It wasn't a cure-all.
- No,
it's-it's okay. After
the trial failed,
Dr. Austin and I succeeded
in removing the sarcoma
from your mom's chest wall,
breast, and the
affected ribs, but
it left her lungs
and her heart
without protection.
I don't have
much of a choice, dear.
It has to be done.
We have to replace them.
Well, the surgery is risky,
I won't lie. A
full implantation
of 3D printed ribs like
this has only been done
once before, but we have
a multidisciplinary team
of experts ready
to make that happen
as safely as possible.
Will Dr. Austin be joining
you in the surgery?
Yes, of course. He
should be here soon.
What's wrong with him, doc?
Lacerations, fever,
pain in the right upper
area of his belly.
Gonna order some labs and get a
CT of his abdomen to find out.
Cat-scratch fever is at the top
of our list, assuming it really
was a Maine Coon
that mauled you.
It was a cat, okay?
"A cat."
Interesting word choice.
I need to impress on
you how important it is
you tell us the truth.
We can't diagnose and treat you
if we don't have the
right information.
Talk to me. Our ribs,
how do they look?
Futuristic, like something
out of a Marvel movie.
Tessa's in great spirits.
Her daughter, little less so.
She watched her mom
struggle long enough.
Tessa's husband died tragically,
my trial failed
her, then cancer,
and now, she needs new ribs.
This poor woman, she's suffered.
Then let's hope this
surgery is a win for her.
Actually,
there's something
that I need to run by you.
A documentary crew
has been following the robotics
lab at Inman Park Tech,
and... they want to film
Tessa's surgery.
That's a big ask.
There are liability
issues and privacy, too,
- for Tessa.
- And will we have
any creative say in how
Chastain is represented?
I imagine we will not.
Then, there's your answer.
I'm sorry, Devon, hard pass.
Respectfully, Dr. Voss,
this is a once
in a lifetime opportunity,
and if it all goes well,
it could put
Chastain back on top.
This documentary could be
very good publicity for us.
Well, a-and if not, it could
have the opposite effect.
We... we'd need creative
say, pending the outcome.
Okay. We make it very clear
that we need creative say,
or we don't move forward
with the documentary.
Under those circumstances,
I'll allow it,
but you're in charge, Devon.
Don't let a camera
crew get in the way
of achieving the best
outcome for our patient.
- Okay.
- Dr. Voss.
Could I have a word?
Have you seen the front page
of the Atlanta Metro Daily?
It's about Bell,
and it is not good.
It's despicable. Anonymous
sources. Gutter journalism.
This has Governor
Betz's fingerprints
- all over it.
- But is it true?
There are nuggets of
truth, but it's blown
way out of proportion.
Well, I
heard that, long ago,
the staff used to call him
HODAD, Hands of Death
and Destruction.
He operated when
he shouldn't have,
when he had a physical problem.
He's a different man
now, a different doctor.
Well, they sure made
his MS an issue.
Randolph has some of the best
outcomes in the hospital.
He's top of his field. I
have total faith in him.
He has a rib implantation
in a few hours.
What are you going to do?
The implantation
is high profile.
The publicity will be
good for Randolph's image
when he's successful.
And what if it isn't?
I have to believe
in our surgeons.
Until then,
I do damage control.
Wolf's lab results are in.
Positive for severe
pancreatitis,
but negative for
cat-scratch fever.
Which means his
symptoms aren't caused
by whatever scratched
him on the arm.
Definitely not.
Well, I'll start him on fluids,
make sure his pain
is under control.
And I'll send off some more labs.
I think he has an
exotic cat at home.
Yeah, with scratches like
that, it makes the most sense.
Well, no one's gonna confess
to a crime that easily.
We'll have to pull
the truth out of 'em.
I need you two in here, now!
Pulmonary edema. The
pancreatitis is getting worse.
Getting him on oxygen.
Wolf, I'm done playing.
Tell me what's going on.
You need to tell us. Now.
Two of lorazepam and get
me an intubation kit.
Can't you just
make an exception?
Chastain recently
changed their policies.
We can no longer accept
babies under ten months.
Laura, I am needed for a
groundbreaking surgery.
Help me out here, please.
Just for a few hours.
Dr. Austin, I wish I
could, but there are rules,
and violating them is gonna
put Chastain in legal jeopardy.
I'm really sorry.
Right.
Make sure they get my
good side, Dr. Pravesh.
All sides of you
are good, Tessa.
I want to go on record.
I think this documentary
is a bad idea.
It could only distract
everyone in surgery.
Listen, if there are any issues
at all, I will pull the plug.
That is a promise.
Your mom is the priority.
Always.
Okay.
Thanks.
I come bearing ribs.
Let's get you
in. Come on, come on.
We need to get this.
Wow. I really will
be the bionic woman.
Yeah. So, this
will be your new sternum,
and these curved
pieces will replace
the ribs that we removed.
They're beautiful.
So, historically,
patients like Tessa ended
up with a flat metal plate
to cover their vital organs,
which might've kept them safe,
but also left them
unable to move.
So, their ability
to live full lives
was drastically curtailed.
But all that changes
now with Tessa.
With these new ribs, we'll
give her full mobility
and a new life.
Isn't there another
surgeon? I would love
to get a profile on him
and his consent to film.
Yes, Dr. Austin, he'll
be the lead surgeon.
He's triple board-certified.
He's got nerves of
steel and great hands,
and he is arguably
the best cardiothoracic
surgeon in the nation.
And a new father.
Oh, here he is.
Hey, uh, my apologies.
Sitter cancelled. What's this?
Um, these guys are
filming the surgery
as part of a documentary.
Um, have you sorted
out your childcare?
I've been calling Padma,
she's not been answering.
I'm still working it out. Hey.
Tessa, I read your report,
and your pre-op exam is clear.
You are as healthy as possible
and ready for surgery.
You have any questions
before we take you to the OR?
The
article is a political smear job
by a governor trying
to destroy Dr. Bell
because he dared
speak truth to power.
Yes, he's my husband,
and I couldn't be more
proud of him at this moment.
That's all I'm going to say.
Dr. Stanley.
I wasn't expecting to hear from
you till our next board meeting.
Oh, come on. It's slander.
- You and I both know that Randolph is a specta...
- Ma'am, you can't go in there.
I'm gonna have to call you back.
You're Kit Voss, the
CEO of the hospital?
The person in charge?
I tried to stop her.
It's all right, Tabitha.
I am.
My mother is Tessa Perez.
She's about to have
her chest cracked open
for this dangerous
new operation.
Okay.
I'm here to help you.
Tell me what's wrong.
I read the article online.
You can't possibly
let some butcher
do this operation on my mom.
These
allegations are false.
Remember, Dr. Bell was the one
who successfully removed
your mother's cancer
just weeks ago.
Yeah, after the
Chastain clinical trial
should've cured it.
Clinical trials are experiments.
There are no guarantees.
And this is also experimental.
Maybe this could kill her.
I'm sure you were both told
the risks are high,
but so are the rewards.
I'm-I'm sorry, but your
mother is out of options.
She chose this.
Then get her another doctor.
I would trust my
life to Dr. Bell.
I'd want him if I were
going into this surgery
- your mother is facing.
- You're his wife!
You're not impartial.
Look, my mom is my best friend.
Okay? She's the
kindest person I know,
and she's too trusting. I
have to be careful for her.
I've watched her
suffer long enough.
From now on, I protect her.
Either Dr. Bell is out,
or we are.
You're taking me off
the surgery, aren't you?
I'm sorry,
but the patient's
daughter insists.
No, I heard about
the article, and...
well, I get that it's a
risk to Chastain. The...
cameras running, a...
surgeon who's been publicly
outed as incompetent.
You can't be allowed to
do a high-risk operation
- on a patient.
- It's quite possible that even
your best effort could still
result in a failed outcome.
No, it's-it's
clear what we have to do.
- I'm out.
- You don't deserve this.
You are a brilliant surgeon
and even better man.
We're in a war with Betz, and
he launched a nuclear weapon.
We're gonna fight it.
Okay.
Hands of Death and
Destruction. HODAD.
Now,
what can I do to help?
Well, AJ can't do the
surgery on his own.
There's no one I
trust more than you.
Can you step in for me?
Of course.
I'm familiar with
what was planned.
Okay, good, good, so
I'll-I'll run through
the specifics with
you so you are ready.
Dr. Lopez, come
to the pharmacy for a consult.
Dr. Lopez to the pharmacy...
Your friend is dying.
You need to tell
us what did this,
or we can't save him.
Well, the truth is we...
we get kicked,
bit, and scratched
all the time by a lot of things.
Kicked? Bit?
- By what?
- We, um...
We have a home zoo.
That, uh, the show
about that guy
who made a great
living raising tigers
made a big impression.
You know it didn't end
well for him, right?
He's famous.
He's in prison for murder.
Okay.
What's your point?
How do you not
understand the danger
you're putting yourselves in?
Wild animals can
carry many diseases,
not to mention maul you.
Hey, people pay big money
to pet a king cobra,
feed an ape, take a photo
next to an African lion.
We're animal lovers,
- I swear.
- What you're doing is illegal.
Your friend's on a vent.
He's hanging on by a thread.
Okay. What... what can I do?
What savaged his arm?
That was a lion. Maude.
She's normally real gentle,
but, uh, we got careless.
Okay, finally we're
getting someplace.
What else could've
bitten or scratched him?
We got so many animals.
It... it could've
been any of them.
Well, then you and I
are gonna make a list.
Oh.
- Hey.
- Aw, look at those cheeks.
Mm. Just the
babies I wanted to see.
Oh, that's great, Hundley.
That's just the reaction the
three of us were hoping for.
Listen, I hit a bit
of a logistical snafu,
and I need a babysitter.
Billie already gave me a
heads-up. I'll take one.
- Hand him over.
- Thank you. One is a great start.
Yeah. That's
why God made two hands.
One for charting, and one
for snuggling.
Wait. Is this Elijah or Arjun?
Well, we also had a
mishap with the wristbands
and the tub so I'm not quite
sure who's who at the moment.
- Mm-hmm.
- But do not judge.
Even Mommy has trouble
telling them apart.
Having a baby with a friend
complicates everything.
Two of them is another
level entirely.
Or did you miss that in the
parenting instructional manual?
Uh, there's a parenting
instruction manual?
Hey, Feldman!
You are great with the boys,
they love you, and
I need childcare.
Oh, of course.
Hundred bucks an hour.
Done! Thank you, my man.
He was gonna do that for free.
Pancreatitis,
delirium, seizures.
None of Wolf's
symptoms are consistent
with injuries caused by
any animals on this list.
There's got to be
something else.
No, that-that's all the big
animals we got, I swear it.
All the big animals?
You got any small ones?
Oh, we-we got critters, but
Wolf mostly takes care of 'em.
You know, snakes,
spiders, scorpions.
Ugh. You are killing
me here, man.
You didn't think it would be
useful to mention this earlier?
It's a side hustle.
By the way, you
would not believe
what some dude in China will pay
for a little Brazilian
scorpion venom.
Hurts to milk 'em, though.
And they bite.
Stings like a bitch.
Brazilian scorpions?
Tityniae serrulatus,
to be specific.
Tityustoxin.
Was Wolf, by chance, siphoning
the venom this morning?
I hope so. We got
a deadline to meet.
That's it.
Where you going?
Tityustoxin from
the scorpion venom
was causing Wolf's pancreas
to inflame and
auto-digest itself.
- What the hell does that mean?
- It means
your business partner needs
antivenom, or he dies.
Hey, what's taking Bell so
long? He should be here by now.
I've taken him off the surgery.
Because of the article?
I'm stepping in for him.
Well, I'm disappointed for
Bell, but I'm good with it.
Pravesh?
Given the circumstance, it's
the best option we have.
Aah!
Hey, what's wrong? Talk to me.
My back. The pain.
And-and my legs... they're numb.
- Keep rolling.
- What's going on?
Is she okay?
New lower extremity weakness.
Cauda equina syndrome.
- What does that mean?
- We need to go now!
I'll meet you in the OR.
Go, go. Go!
- Anybody?!
- Wendy. Wendy.
What's going on?
We have to get
your mother to the OR now.
She has a serious complication
that we have to deal with first.
- Come on.
- We have to stabilize her
before we can implant the ribs.
I can't promise you
that the rib surgery
is gonna happen today.
How did we not
see this in imaging?
We couldn't have.
The cancer must have
metastasized rapidly
during her time in the
ICU, even between scans.
What's going on?
Our patient has a
dangerous complication.
Should we be filming?
No, this has nothing to do
with the rib implantation.
What are the odds that Tessa's
story has a happy ending now?
A lot less than they
were this morning.
We're losing nerve signal.
The tumor has
eroded the bone.
Pathologic spinal fracture
leading to cord compression.
All right, if we don't
get rid of this tumor,
new set of ribs aren't
gonna make a difference.
You're right. She
needs a decompression.
Should I page Billie?
Right away.
Our neurosurgeon is on the way.
You can go. We won't
be filming any more.
I'm thinking that
this is great stuff.
- You know, conflict is drama.
- No.
There's a woman down there
whose life hangs in the balance.
Filming it would
be a distraction.
I'm not gonna let you continue.
The patient comes first.
Okay, but you're missing
out on a golden opportunity.
I'm sorry, but please leave.
The vertebrae
is crumbling.
Any word
on Billie, Pravesh?
She's coming.
Well, she better hurry.
What have we got?
An emergent
spinal decompression.
When did you lose
SSEPs to the lower extremities?
Five minutes ago.
Time is spine.
All right, osteotome to me.
Hi. Sam, how are you?
What the hell is going
on over there, Pravesh?
There's been an unforeseen
complication with the surgery.
I'm not talking
about the surgery.
I'm talking about this article.
The article... It...
It's a mixture of exaggeration
and outright lies.
You told me Chastain
was the best.
This guy, Dr. Bell...
- He's on Tessa's medical team.
- Well, not anymore.
We-we took him off the surgery.
If the article's a lie,
why would you take
him off the case?
It's either one or the other.
Well, at this point, it's moot
because we don't even know
if we can move forward.
And if you can, who operates?
Dr. Voss. She's our CEO.
Top ortho surgeon. She can
do it. There's no one better.
But Sam, there won't
be any more filming.
Fine. I can live with that.
We've worked so hard, it's
too late to pull the plug.
But Inman Park Tech
better come out of this
looking like rock stars.
If not, our new
partnership is over.
Hey, I got your
page. How bad is it?
Um, unclear.
Apparently, one of Conrad's
patients was stung repeatedly
by a scorpion and developed
severe pancreatitis.
I think I speak for the
whole hospital when I say,
we know how good you are,
and we're all behind you.
Well, I appreciate that.
You taught me so
much. This will pass.
I hope so.
All right, so, here's the deal.
I dosed him with antivenom.
But he's already developing
necrotizing pancreatitis.
With worsening
organ dysfunction.
His urine output's trailing
off, he's tough to ventilate.
- What's his bladder pressure?
- Mid-20s.
He's got abdominal
compartment syndrome.
If the pressure in his
abdomen gets any higher,
he's-he's gonna go into shock.
Well, he needs a laparotomy.
- Should I book an OR?
- Um, no, not yet.
We need to maximize
medical management first.
Let's start with paracentesis,
drain the fluid at
bedside and then reassess.
Okay, I'll prepare
the paracentesis now.
As an internist, I appreciate
the nonsurgical approach,
but is this you or
the article talking?
This is about the patient.
I-I... I know you might
find it hard to believe,
considering that nickname has
come back to haunt me, but I...
I am long past the days
of letting outside influence
dictate the way I do my job.
There's a ton of ascites
fluid in his abdomen.
No wonder he's so distended.
Yeah, there's quite a bit.
Well, do you
want to do the procedure?
Technically, Conrad
consulted you.
Uh, nope, nope.
You can handle it.
Spinal cord
is decompressed.
The tumor is resected.
And our nerve signal
is back, but weak.
Now we have to
stabilize the spine,
rebuild it, vertebrae
by vertebrae.
I'm trying.
These screws won't hold.
Her bones must have been
compromised from the tumor.
We have to
fuse more levels.
But I'm not sure if
Tessa can hold up.
Her blood
pressure's dropping.
She's going into A-fib.
We need more IV fluids,
and we need another
amio bolus ready.
Hey, Doc?!
His blood pressure's low.
And his abdomen is tense.
Paracentesis wasn't enough.
- Can you do it again, or...?
- It won't solve the problem.
He's too sick. Hamad,
page Bell and Devi.
Have 'em meet us in the OR now.
Okay.
Spinal fusion is a success.
Thanks to our
brilliant neurosurgeon,
Tessa is stable.
Yeah, but
is she stable enough
to make it through
the rib implantation?
That's for
us to figure out.
Dr. Sutton, we'll take
it from here. Thank you.
I'll leave you to it.
- Good luck, everyone.
- All right.
Let's close up her back.
Now, do we proceed with
the implantation or...?
Or do we stop and give her
a rest from anesthesia,
return to the ribs another day?
Her A-fib hasn't recurred,
but if it does...
It's a risk.
But every day without those
ribs brings another risk.
Heart and lungs exposed.
Pravesh, you
made this a reality.
You know Tessa.
You make the call.
Let's do it.
This is on me.
I thought the paracentesis
would be enough.
It was the right call,
but now the compartment
syndrome is compressing his IVC.
- We should go.
- There's not enough blood getting to his heart.
- Get your stuff.
- His MAPs are in the 40s.
Hawkins, at-at this rate,
he could code before
we get to the OR.
Well, then he needs a
decompressive laparotomy
right here, right now.
Dr. Devi's on her way to the OR.
I think it's best
we do it there.
Listen to me. I knew that man
they wrote about in that
article, and that's not you.
Not now.
I'm not so sure
about that anymore,
for a number of reasons.
I'd trust you with my life.
After everything
we've been through,
that has to mean
something to you
because it means
something to me.
I know you can save this
man's life right now.
Come on. Let's do it.
I need Betadine and a ten blade.
No pulse. Just hold
off on compressions.
Ten blade.
He's got a pulse,
and it is strong.
That was amazing, man!
You see that?
And we filmed all of it.
Congrats, Dr. Bell.
You brought the drama.
Wow. That was awesome.
I just, uh... I need...
I just need you all
to sign a release,
of course.
Um, I'm not sure that...
Footage doesn't lie.
Amazing. So good.
Let's rotate.
Removing the prosthetic.
All right.
Ready to implant the titanium.
Fits like a glove.
She's back in A-fib
and hypotensive. We can
bolus her amio again,
- but we're running out of time.
- Let's bring this home.
Attaching the ribs in place.
I mean, it's like
a piece of armor.
Utterly amazing.
How's my mom?
She came through
beautifully. What a fighter.
The ribs fit perfectly.
As you see, the
surgery was a long one.
Recovery's going to be
tough, but we're optimistic.
Okay. Thank you.
Um, thank you, Dr. Pravesh.
I'm sorry that I
ever doubted you.
It's not over yet.
But we've done our best,
and now we'll do our best
to make sure she
gets back on her feet
and living her new life.
- Thank you.
- Of course.
Hmm.
Hey.
Irving and Hundley bailed?
There was a multiple
injury crash,
and they got
overwhelmed in the ER.
I was leaving and couldn't
handle this cuteness,
so I kidnapped them.
Hey. Hey, little man.
Aw. Did you miss Papa?
You know, I never
held my son, Trevor.
Well, you know, you were a
child yourself when he was born.
Mm.
Well, because of where he
came from, I didn't want to.
Couldn't do it.
This is what I missed, hmm?
You know, you can still be
a great mom if you want to.
- Mm.
- And hey, you found a way to make a new bond with Trevor.
Yeah, he's a good guy.
He's working hard to
develop new drugs.
Chemistry is his first passion,
so he moved to Baltimore.
- But we're still in touch.
- Mm-hmm.
Mm, but this is something else.
Oh, you got that right.
These two bring me a
special kind of joy.
Even when Elijah's just
staring daggers at me.
Yeah.
You know, I think he's hungry.
Seems like you can tell
your twins apart after all.
Ah, well, I forgot that
their distinguishing features
are their personalities.
Well, you're gonna have a lot of
fun watching these two grow up.
They're gonna love their papa.
Mm.
I-I do not even know what
I'm feeling right now.
Y-You should have been there,
right? Th-this doctor...
He cut right into your
stomach right in the hallway.
Your guts started oozing
out all over the place
- like...
- Okay, okay, enough.
Dr. Bell saved your life.
You're going to need
another trip to the OR once
your belly's less swollen to
get that abdominal wound closed,
but you'll be okay.
- How you feeling?
- Better.
A lot better.
You underestimated
that scorpion.
Repeated exposure
to scorpion venom...
Yeah, that wreaks
havoc on your body.
I feel like a damn fool.
- It won't happen again.
- Good.
Let this be a
lesson to you both.
Don't lie to your doctors.
We-we... we didn't lie.
I mean, we just didn't
tell the whole truth.
Yeah, which almost
got you killed.
Well, w-we will take
precautions from now on, right?
W-Wear gloves, be the safest
unauthorized zoo in the state.
Trafficking in exotic animals
is illegal in the state of Georgia,
and having any wild animal
- requires a permit.
- Well,
sure, but, I mean, who's
really paying attention?
I am.
Reported you both to the
state animal control.
- Oh.
- Wait. What the hell, man?!
Wh-What about
doctor-patient privilege?
I didn't tell them anything
about your health history.
Here you go.
Pravesh?
Congratulations.
You have every right to
be proud of yourself.
And you pulled off that
surgery like a boss, Voss.
We proved something here.
Huge leaps in medicine can
happen in unexpected places.
- Yeah.
- Doctors?
I hear the patient is in
recovery, doing beautifully.
- Job well done.
- Thank you.
And I can't wait to
see what Chastain
and Inman Park Tech
partner on next.
Me, too.
Nice going, Pravesh.
Still love your spunk.
Spunk.
I thought we were
meeting at home.
Well, couldn't wait.
Is something wrong?
Oh, I told you I wasn't
gonna read the article.
But of course you did.
But I-I didn't finish.
Um, my heart started racing,
and there was a
ringing in my ears,
and then the room
started to spin.
Like an anxiety attack?
It's the MS, Kit.
It's probably made
worse from the stress.
And it cleared up, and
I got through the day.
But...
it's not the only time since
I returned from the clinic.
Well, let me see if
Conrad's still around.
- He can examine you.
- Hey.
I think we both know this is
not something Conrad can manage.
And maybe it is the stress.
But it... it could also be
side effects of my new meds.
Oh, they worked for a while.
Maybe they're not
working so well anymore.
My MS could be progressing.
Then we'll find another
treatment, a-a clinical trial.
I think I need to get
back to Minnesota.
Whatever you need,
you just say the word.
All I want is you by my
side, whatever it takes.
All right, home sweet home.
Oh.
Okay.
Where... is Mommy, guys?
I'll be right back.
She's supposed to
be home by now.
Padma?
Hi. You've reached
Padma. Leave a message.