In 1986, Congress passed
the Emergency Medical Treatment
and Labor Act,
which prohibits emergency rooms
from denying patients care.
If you don't have a dollar to
your name, it doesn't matter.
You can go to any
emergency room at any time
and they have to treat you.
Uh, is your hand broken?
Door was open.
That's not an excuse.
What are you doing?
Socks got mixed up again.
Where are your...clothes?
I stopped putting them away.
Saves time.
Yasuda!
Try knocking.
Some people think this law
has contributed to overcrowding
and hospital closures.
Yasuda, open up.
But I don't know
a single E.R. doctor
who would turn a patient away
even if they could.
Sometimes all that means
is treating an ear infection.
Other times you see a patient
on the table
- and your heart stops.
- Fire's knocked down.
The rarest of diseases.
Hopeless co-morbidities.
Cases you've never seen that
you're not trained to handle.
Two victims, unconscious.
Get a couple gurneys.
All you can do is close
your eyes and say a prayer.
Because once a patient enters
the emergency room,
they're yours.
So, should we go out
for breakfast for your last day?
And miss my last chance
at burnt coffee
and watery oatmeal
from the cafeteria?
I'm gonna miss this.
Mm.
I'll be back
before you know it.
Yeah, but six weeks
feels like forever.
Maybe I can --
I can take a sick day
and come visit you
for a long weekend.
Yeah.
And you'll be back
for your mom's birthday.
Actually, my mom
is thinking about
coming down
to San Antonio.
She wants to see
where I'm living.
Well, there's, uh,
Fourth of July.
But tickets are probably
through the roof.
Texas is feeling
really far away right now.
"For the Lord has not given us
a spirit of fear,
but of power and love
and of a sound mind."
2 Timothy, 1:7.
Is it wrong
that I think it's hot
when you quote
Bible verses?
"For there is no fear
in love,
for perfect love casteth out
fear."
Can we talk?
I don't want you
to be upset about this.
If I could just talk you through
what happened.
You let someone kiss you
when we were supposed to be
working on our marriage.
I think I know enough.
Hey, can you play baseball?
Uh, pitched 85 miles per hour
in college.
Thank God.
Are you free Saturday?
You resurrecting
the hospital softball team?
Yeah.
I mean, I wanted to do
something fun
with everybody
outside the hospital,
but, uh, Griffith asked
if she could use a tee,
and Millin said she'll hit
but she won't run.
Yeah, I would love to,
but, uh,
I have to take my kid
to a birthday party.
Well, can't Dr. Bailey
do that?
You want to ask her?
Two incoming traumas.
I'll meet you outside.
Chaplain to patient services.
Oh, there you are.
How'd it go last night?
Oh. Uh, yeah.
Tuck's team won by two.
Uh, Pru, uh, got a visit
from the Tooth Fairy, and, uh...
Oh!
Yeah.
Uh, you?
Saved a patient.
Lost a resident.
Oh, yeah.
I heard about Schmitt.
Yeah.
You okay?
He's happy.
I'm happy.
Oh, boy. Okay.
I'll see you at home.
All right.
22-year-old female,
two-car collision, GCS 14.
Bilateral crush injuries
to both lower extremities.
Given morphine for pain
en route.
Chloe?
This is Dr. Webber.
My legs. They hurt so much.
Okay. We'll take a look.
We got you.
Where's Mika?
She was driving.
W-We'll check.
You just be still, okay?
This is Yasuda's sister.
Yasuda.
That's Yasuda!
What? Yasuda?
27-year-old female, GCS 14.
Brief LOC.
Blunt trauma
to the abdomen.
BP is 90 over 40.
Received one-liter bolus
of LR.
Yasuda, it's Altman.
And Bailey.
C-Chloe is my --
my sister.
She's here.
Webber's got her.
All right. Let's move.
Let's get her to Trauma 1
Come on. Go, go, go, go, go!
We got you. We got you.
Uh, prominent bruising
in the right upper quadrant.
She's hypotensive
and tachy.
All right.
Let's get a FAST exam,
trauma panel,
and chest X-rays right now.
Weren't you on
last night?
I operated with her
this morning.
X-rays are on their way.
No, Adams.
You shouldn't be in here.
No. I want to help.
Do it somewhere else.
No, no. I need to say.
Skywalker.
Go.
Take care of C-Chloe...
please.
Oh. Sats are dropping.
We need to intubate right now.
Adams, go!
All right.
Push etomidate and sux.
And I need a 7-0 ET tube.
No major lacerations.
We just need stereo strips.
Where do you want me?
In the waiting room.
Mika!
Push 50 of fentanyl.
Chloe, I need you
to be brave for me, okay?
You can do this.
Yasuda asked me
to help her sister.
You know the rules.
No friends, no family.
With all due respect,
you've spent more time
with Chloe than I have.
I can't help in there.
Please let me stay.
Go pull up the X-rays
for Dr. Lincoln.
Okay.
Catch me up.
Chloe Yasuda, 22-year-old female
MVC with crush injuries
to the bilateral
lower extremities.
FAST exam came back negative.
Yasuda?
Is she--
Yeah.
Okay.
What do we got on the X-ray?
It's coming up now.
Multiple comminuted
fractures.
All right.
Weak DP pulses bilaterally.
We're gonna have to check
for blood flow in the legs.
Adams, go get
the Doppler monitor.
Where is she?
Who's with her?
Bailey, Altman,
and Ndugu. She's in Trauma 1.
Trauma 1.
All right.
Putting in the chest tube.
How are you doing on your side?
Scalpel.
Oh, my God.
Oh, no. No.
You all need to step away
and let us take care of her.
She's definitely bleeding
in the abdomen.
I need a gown and gloves.
Millin, there's nothing
for you to do right now.
Damn it, we need to put in
a central line.
Call the blood bank
and activate MTP.
C-Come on.
Let's go.
No. She's -- She's bleeding out!
She needs to go to the O.R. now!
She's coding.
All right.
Starting compressions.
No. No. Mika!
Mika! Mika!
Get her out of here now!
No!
Code -- M-Mika!
- Come on. Come on.
- Come on, Yasuda.
We'll be fine. People do
long distance all the time.
And I've always wanted to work
with kids.
I've only lived in Seattle.
I've only been here,
just like you.
We need to get out
into the world
and experience something new.
Make our mark.
Right?
Your graduation speech
needs work.
Is this Ruby Garner?
Yeah.
I helped deliver her.
Is she going home?
Well, if she can pass
her car-seat test.
Can't believe
you're leaving me.
I'll be back
all the time.
Yeah, but you'll be
with James.
Do you think it's a mistake,
doing long distance?
I don't even moved yet.
It's already hard.
I am not in the position
to be giving relationship advice
right now.
Oh.
Dr. Yasuda was brought
into the E.R., MVC.
She's in the trauma bay.
Oh, my God.
Do you need to go?
Hi.
We know we're early,
but we're excited
to bring her home.
How's her car-seat test
going?
Well, she's not
loving it.
Is she --
She's turning blue.
Okay. Someone get me
a neonatal intubation kit.
What's happening?
Is she breathing?
Mr. and Mrs. Garner, I need you
to go to the waiting area
so that we can take care
of your daughter, okay?
We're not going anywhere.
Excuse me.
Nurse Madison, can you --
Thank you.
But...
Okay.
You got it?
Yeah.
Got it.
I got your page.
Where do you need me?
Prepping for a thoracotomy.
Got me.
Stop compressions.
- Oh.
- We got a sinus rhythm.
All right.
She's lost a lot of blood.
She's in hemorrhagic shock.
It's got to be
a diaphragmatic rupture.
It looks like her liver
herniated into her chest.
She's still too unstable. We got
to get her to the O.R. now.
I'm calling up now.
Have the blood product sent
up to the operating room.
Hang another unit.
Uh, take over.
I'll meet you up there.
Come with me.
Neither leg's getting
a signal.
Somebody give me
the pressure monitor.
She just had her first round
of chemo.
We need to look out
for acute kidney injury.
High pressure
in both legs.
No blood flow.
Bone-crush injuries.
Legs are tight. That's --
Acute compartment syndrome.
All right.
We got to relieve the pressure
so she doesn't lose her legs.
Okay, Adams. Step aside.
I'll take the right leg.
Warren, you take the left.
We're gonna do
bilateral fasiciotomies.
I want full skin incisions,
anterolateral
and posteromedial.
All right. Make it quick.
Let's go.
How is she doing?
Better now that
she can breathe.
How are her parents?
Worried.
You'd think being pregnant would
make me more sympathetic.
But I'm kind of just annoyed
their baby's already out.
You're okay, Ruby.
I'm right here.
For today. Then he's leaving us
to fend for ourselves.
Traitor.
Are you being mean
because you're having
separation anxiety?
No. I am tired and hormonal.
Don't psychoanalyze me.
Okay. There it is.
Fluid around the heart.
Probably from the viral
infection she had
a couple weeks ago.
Gonna have to run some labs
and aspirate.
You want me to consent
the parents?
Oh, you don't have to do that.
It's not your job.
I don't mind.
I don't know
what I would have done
all these years
without you.
Oh, my God. Shut up.
I am not crying before lunch.
Dr. Netelbeek to Ortho.
Dr. Tessa Netelbeek to Ortho.
Okay, Ruby.
All right. So, she appears
to have extensive liver damage.
How's her neuro exam?
No signs of TBI yet.
We'll have to scan her
after the O.R.
We will try
and keep you updated,
but right now,
she is our first priority.
Dr. Bailey, please.
We're going to do
everything we can.
She means a lot
to all of us.
She really couldn't be
a better hands.
I-I switched with her.
She worked
the night shift?
I was swamped,
and she helped me.
And then I-I told Ndugu
to let her scrub in.
If she hadn't been on the road
when she was --
You have to stop that.
Great. Advice from
the no-feelings guy.
No.
That's not what I m--
Look, you can't think
like that
or the guilt will eat you alive,
okay? Trust me.
Don't tell me
what to think.
You don't know what
the hell happened.
Neither do you.
I'm just stating facts.
Okay.
You want to hear facts?
Our friend is fighting
for her life in there,
and there's nothing
we can do about it.
I know that might not matter
to you
and your stone heart,
but it matters to me.
Oh, I'm s-- Hey.
Hey.
How's it going?
It's pretty brutal.
At least you get to do
something. I feel helpless.
I wish I could do more.
I just want to camp out
in the O.R. corridor
and wait for updates.
But I can't find Millin.
She won't text me back.
Then I'm talking --
Hey.
Keep me posted on Chloe,
okay?
You okay?
I, uh...
I called out Yasuda once
for eating an old doughnut.
It was after a meeting,
and I found her pulling it
out of the trash.
And for some reason,
it just set me off.
She was struggling,
and she didn't deserve it.
I'm sure
she forgives you.
I'm sorry about Cass.
I know. Don't think
about that right now.
Teddy, look at me.
We can do this.
Yeah.
Abdomen and chest look good.
Has anybody called
their parents yet?
Webber was trying to get
in touch with them.
You know, Yasuda she's the glue
of our class.
Somehow she manages to be
best friends with everybody.
Yeah, I'm still
getting to know everyone,
but I got Yasuda's number
right away.
Yeah, one time, um,
when I was living at the house
one day, I thought there was
an earthquake.
But it turns out it was
just Yasuda pumping herself up
for the night shift.
Being a doctor
is never harder
than when you personally care
for your patient.
How's it look?
Uh, no chest
or abdominal injuries,
and the leg scans
are coming up now.
I see a irregularity
in the popliteal artery.
Well, let's just keep
an eye on it
and get a vascular consult
when we open her up.
All right.
These are complex fractures.
We're gonna have to do
a combined approach
of ORIFs and ex fixes
in both legs.
Let's get her prepped
for surgery.
Target is ID'ed below the left
of the xiphoid bone.
Okay.
Needle's ready.
We have visual confirmation
on the ultrasound.
Okay.
All right.
We're almost ready.
Then you'll feel better and
your parents will feel better.
They sure do love you.
Even though you've been living
in different places.
Are you about to compare
the life of a baby in the NICU
to your long-distance
relationship?
Well, you didn't
give me advice.
Monitor's showing bradycardia.
You need to move.
Okay.
Here we go.
Remove the ultrasound probe.
Yeah.
Right there.
Okay, Ruby.
You're gonna feel
a little sting.
Remember when you dropped
your glasses
in somebody's abdomen?
I try really hard not to.
You've come a long way.
All right.
Heart rate is back
to normal rhythm.
Great.
You want to tell
the parents
we may need to keep her
another couple nights,
but then she should be
able to leave?
Sure.
Okay.
You want advice?
Long distance is awful.
It's expensive and lonely,
and I would never recommend it.
But if you are committed
to making it work...
...it will.
Okay.
Bears or worms?
I'm not hungry.
She is gonna get
through this.
I came down here
to be alone.
She isn't
just your friend.
I know that.
Do you know that?
Because you are acting like this
is happening just to you.
We are all freaking out
here.
We all need each other
right now.
Mika and I
aren't just friends.
Like you're together?
Yes.
No.
I don't know.
Okay.
What...
What do you call it when --
when you flirt with someone
and then sometimes you kiss
and you want to be together
but then her sister
gets sick
and you work together,
and it's all just --
Complicated.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's exactly it.
Gonna need something stronger
than gummy bears.
All right.
Spleen's intact,
and there's no bleeding
in the retroperitoneum.
Okay.
At least there's that.
She's still losing
a lot of blood.
Hang two more units.
More lap pads.
Okay. This liver is fractured
right down the middle.
Pringle maneuver?
It's worth a try.
Clamp.
Okay.
And staple.
Uh, bleeding is still
too profuse.
We should try
hemostatic agents.
Both lobes are jacked.
We need to remove the liver
before she bleeds out to death.
No, we are not adding
liver failure to someone
who is too hypotensive
and too unstable.
- That could kill her, too.
- I agree with Altman.
Let's move to damage control.
Embolize in I.R.,
then resuscitate in the ICU
until she's stable.
And then we move her back
to the O.R.
We need to be more aggressive.
She'll continue to bleed.
We need to excise the liver
and put her
on the transplant list now.
She just coded.
She could code again,
and we might not get her back
again.
Okay. Enough.
This is one of our own
lying on this table.
She needs us to stop arguing
and to save her life.
We will not remove
her liver.
Thank you.
And we will also not leave her
in the ICU overnight.
Do you have a better plan?
Oh, boy.
Hmm.
Okay. We will pack her,
scan her head to toe,
then get her to the ICU,
give her blood,
let her stabilize
for a few hours
while we get our acts together
and figure out a better plan.
Anybody feels the need
to disagree, step the hell out.
Lap pads.
How's she doing?
She's putting up
a good fight.
Uh, I can sit with her
if you have things to do.
Okay.
Page me if you need anything.
I'll be close.
You messed up laundry again.
I don't have a...
single clean sock.
And I-I know
what you're gonna say.
I left my clothes in the washer.
But...
Yeah, I-I...
I don't have a good
justification for that.
You still suck at laundry,
though.
I'll tell you what.
You pull through this
and I'll...
do all your laundry
for as long as we live together.
But don't get greedy,
'cause I-I can't start
doing everything for you.
The dishes in the sink.
The...hair in the drain.
The dried toothpaste on...
That's all you.
Not that you actually do
any of those things.
You're a terrible roommate.
Altman said you were here.
I didn't believe her.
Ah. Whenever I'm stuck
on something,
I like to go
for a walk.
It clears the mind,
settles the nerves.
But I don't want to be far
from my patients, so treadmill.
Plus I get
some steps in.
Makes sense.
Any ideas?
Not yet.
Collectively, the four of us
have probably published
close to 300
case studies.
You counted?
Well, no, but I'm --
I'm just saying,
based on how much we've seen and
how much we've accomplished...
We should have ideas.
Yeah.
I let Yasuda do
the bronchial anastomosis
on a lung transplant
this morning.
She's got real skills.
Of course she does.
I trained her.
You like teaching?
Yeah.
I didn't even think
about it
when I decided
to go into surgery.
But yeah, I do.
It's my favorite part
of the job.
I get it. You get to support
fledgling doctors
and watch them grow
into surgeons
who can stand
on their own.
It's fulfilling.
You hit your step goal?
I've got an idea.
Yes.
Yeah. Okay.
Her CT scan shows
that only 25% of her liver
remains viable.
Not enough
to preserve function.
Agree.
I still think the risk
of removing it is too high.
I agree with that too.
So what exactly
is your plan?
We resect the entire
right lobe,
then we resect the damaged areas
in the left.
Then we give the remainder
of the liver
the circulatory support it needs
to recover and grow
with dialysis
and aggressive resuscitation.
How?
The common hepatic artery
is completely damaged
at the takeoff.
We remove her spleen and
use its vessels to reconstruct
and feed what's left
of the liver.
You think the remaining piece
of the liver will be functional?
I am hoping it will.
This won't be as simple
as you make it sound.
Okay. I know.
It's a long shot, right?
But Yasuda is strong,
and we've all seen her
give everything she's got
to her family, her patients.
She would do it
for any one of us.
Yeah.
Mm.
Yep.
I'm in.
Yeah.
Me too.
Right.
Let's get her back to the O.R.
Hi.
Hey.
How's your last day?
It's graduation day.
For the preemies,
they get to leave the hospital.
Ah. Do you need a chaplain
for that?
No.
Well, is there anything else
I can help you with?
You could move to Texas
with me.
What?
People get into car accidents,
and people die,
and life is short, and
you've lived all over the world.
Why not San Antonio
with me?
Well, I mean, my --
my whole life is here.
You know, my job.
I just bought my loft.
I'm falling in love
with you.
I'm sorry to put you on the spot
like this.
You d-- You don't have to decide
this second.
You don't even have to decide
today.
Just...
Just think about it.
Sorry.
Let's talk about this
later.
I'll meet you in the lobby
after work.
Okay.
Nothing? You don't feel
a tiny bit better?
They're babies.
Who could also die in
a terrible car accident one day.
Come with me.
You're not going to make me hold
one of them, are you?
Sit.
Do not test me.
Not today.
Oh, my God.
It's like sitting
into a hug.
How long have you
and Yasuda been a thing?
We haven't had sex yet,
if that's what you're asking.
It's not
what I'm asking.
Couple months.
We keep trying to
slow it down,
and then we just
pick it back up again.
Why can't you just be
together?
Because we're friends,
w-we work together.
Hi.
I've never had a relationship
that feels like this.
So, like, easy and...
electric and...
I-I think we were both scared
of messing it up.
It's kind of ironic now.
Mika is not going down
without a fight.
Especially if she has you
to fight for.
This poor kid.
She just started chemo,
and now this.
Makes you count
your blessings, huh?
Popliteal artery
is bleeding out.
Damn it.
Vascular clamp.
How can I help?
There's too much blood.
Okay. Page vascular!
She's gonna lose her leg
if they don't get here quick.
Clamp!
All right.
I-I'll go get someone.
Good.
Right there.
More suction.
Speak now or forever hold
your peace.
Here we go.
Titan, please.
How's the liver looking?
Ischemic and still bleeding.
Suction.
I need Dr. Altman
or Dr. Ndugu.
We're a little busy
right now.
Chloe has a bad vascular bleed.
She's about to lose her leg.
All right. I'll go.
Owen, take over for me.
What O.R. is she in?
Four.
Adams, they need you
in Chloe's O.R.
Adams!
Uh...
How's the signal down her leg?
Weak. At this point, there could
be irreversible ischemic damage.
Yeah. Her myoglobin
and C.K. levels are elevated.
We should continue sodium bicarb
and start Mucomyst.
Sorry. I got held up.
Gown and glove me.
I need 6-0 of prolene
and vessel loops.
All right, Chloe.
Hang in there.
Stay with me.
We got you.
Vascular anastomosis
is complete.
It's holding.
Okay.
Removing the clamp.
Now we all pray to God
it works.
Hey.
I just told a woman that's
been laboring for 14 hours
that she was only
two centimeters dilated.
Thought she was gonna
punch me.
How's Ruby?
Good.
Her vitals have improved.
Okay. Great.
Where's James?
I don't know.
Well, maybe he got held up
with, uh, with a patient.
You don't have to try
to make me feel better.
If I haven't completely
freaked him out,
maybe it's just, uh,
back to long distance
and I'll rack up a bunch
of frequent-flyer miles
and we'll talk on the phone
all the time.
I could get better
at sexting.
Mm! Mm-hmm.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's a silver lining.
Getting drunk
and sleeping with you...
was the best mistake
I ever made.
Will you be
my baby's godfather?
Are those two things
supposed to be related?
No.
When I'm upset,
you're my first call.
Because even on my worst days,
you always make me laugh.
And the reason I was so mad
when you quit O.B.
wasn't because I got you
the job.
It was because I was losing
my favorite person to work with.
And now I'm losing you
again.
I'm not dying.
We're gonna talk
all the time.
The world is
a hardened place...
full of hardened people
like you.
You walk through life
with this giant open heart.
I want you
in my kids' lives.
I want you to teach them
to be gentle...
and warm-hearted.
And all of that
Star Wars stuff.
That'll be fun.
So be their godfather.
They'd be lucky
to be loved by you.
I'm flattered.
I mean, I love them
so much already.
But I am Jewish.
Is that even allowed?
Just say yes
and buy them amazing gifts.
I would love to be
their godfather.
I didn't like her
when I first met her.
What?
Ow.
I like her now.
She was just so...loud
and all up in my face
all the time.
I like calm.
Quiet.
I met her right after I bumped
into someone I'd slept with.
She rescued me.
Wait.
Who'd you sleep with?
That's not the point
of the story.
Wait.
I kind of remember this.
Did you sleep
with Lincoln?
What?
Well, I'm really glad
I didn't run into
any of you jerks that day.
Um...
She's stable,
and she's recovering in the ICU.
Now we wait and see.
Well, I guess this is one way
to get out of charting.
Ah! They should've reassigned
your paperwork today.
Yeah. Well,
it's pretty much the only thing
they'd let me do all day,
so I figured
I might as well finish it.
Not that she cares.
Oh, Yasuda, weirdly,
loves paperwork.
She blasts music
and times herself.
Code blue, room 4429,
surgical ICU.
Code blue...
That's Chloe.
room 4429, surgical ICU.
Page an attending!
...room 4429.
Someone start bagging.
I'll bag.
Push one of epi.
I'll get the epi.
Okay.
Come on. Come on.
Oh, hey.
How's Yasuda?
Um, she's, uh...
She's good.
Interns are with her.
Look, we should --
I know that today's --
You go.
I overreacted.
It was a mistake,
and you told me right away.
You did nothing wrong.
I'm still sorry.
I just...
I would never want to
cause you any pain.
I know.
Come on.
Thank you.
Let's go home.
Charge to 200.
Clear!
Again.
What happened?
Clear.
Her potassium spiked.
She went into V-fib.
Charge to 300.
Clear.
Come on. Come on.
How long has it been?
40 minutes of CPR.
Adams.
You've done all you can.
Time of death...22:16.
No. No.
You can't stop.
Someone bag.
Millin, back away.
Come on, Chloe.
Come on.
Help me!
Jules...
Chloe, come on.
Come on.
Jules...
...she's gone.
Wait --
What's that?
Chloe's personal
belongings.
She didn't make it.
Rhabdo.
Crush injuries
on top of chemo
was just too much
for her body to handle.
It's...
It's her shoes and her phone
for when Yasuda
wakes up.
If she wakes up.
Babe...
No. No, no.
'Cause it's not over.
And I have to stay vigilant.
You know, if you hug me,
I'm gonna cry.
Okay.
And I cannot cry.
You're staying here?
I mean,
I-I know that means
another night away
from you and the kids, but --
Don't even worry
about that, all right?
Yasuda needs you.
Tomorrow morning,
you -- you give the kids
whatever they want
for breakfast, right?
Waffles. Pizza.
I don't care! Just...
We can do that.
You make something good
happen, Ben Warren.
I need something good
to happen.
Okay. Okay, okay, okay.
When you're met
with the impossible,
the only place to turn
is toward each other.
She told me to take care
of her sister.
Do not blame yourself.
You did all you could.
I ran her code.
I called
her time of death.
None of this
is your fault.
S-She'll understand.
No.
I-I have to go.
Lucas.
When you lose,
you have someone
to cry with.
When you walk
into the unknown,
you have someone
to hold your hand.
I'm Dr. Schmitt.
You made the right call.
Levi!
Hi!
Hi.
I-I am so sorry about the lobby.
I just...
No. It's okay.
This was a big ask,
and you weren't ready.
No. I was in the admin office
resigning from my job.
You still want me to go to Texas
with you, right?
Wait.
Wait, wait.
Please tell me
that this is a yes,
because I just quit
my job.
Yes.
Let's go!
Together.
And when you win,
there's someone by your side
to celebrate.
And suddenly,
the impossible feels possible.
But sometimes there's no one
to turn to.
Sometimes you're all alone.
It's late.
You all should go home.
It could be days
before she wakes up, okay?
Go get some rest.
Come on.
Could you let us know
if anything changes?
I'll call
the second it does.
In those times,
you have to keep the faith.
Remember that even
if you can't see them
or feel them or hear them,
your people are out there,
waiting for you.
Yasuda.
Hey, welcome back.
Your surgery,
it went well.
You're gonna be okay.
Mm-hmm.
Chloe?
No.
Shh.
No!
No.
Oh, no.
Even after you're gone.