♪♪
When a patient goes
into cardiac arrest,
we follow a specific set of
protocols to resuscitate them.
♪ Na-ha ♪ When you know
that it's right ♪
Start with CPR, give oxygen,
assess heart rhythm
to determine if the patient
needs to be shocked.
♪ Let it be known
If needed, push epinephrine
every three to five minutes.
♪ A-ha
Consider an advanced airway
and need to administer
additional medications.
♪ A-ah, we're about to catch
a tailwind ♪
Then check the pulse and start
the cycle all over again.
♪♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh-oh
CPR, shock, meds,
pulse check --
sometimes for hours.
You ready?
Here we go.
♪ Oh, oh, oh-oh
Until, hopefully,
you change the course...
♪ Oh, oh, oh-oh
...and save a life.
♪♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh-oh
Good morning, everyone.
Good morning.
I know everyone's been following
Fierce Fernanda
as she has traveled across
the country with her family.
I first met Fernanda and
her family in Boston last fall.
She suffers from
congenital aortic valve disease,
which led to aortic stenosis.
At 13 years of age, she's
already had two heart surgeries.
Nothing has worked.
Until today.
We're doing
a Ross procedure.
Only seven programs
in the country
perform Ross procedures,
and you are training
at one of them.
Someone tell me
what it is.
Helm.
Uh, it's taking
a patient's pulmonary valve
and moving it into the position
of their aortic valve,
preventing the need for
lifelong anticoagulant therapy.
Exactly.
It also has the added benefit
for pediatric patients --
since it is their own valve,
it will grow with them.
And on a pediatric patient,
it's even more challenging.
Dr. Pierce is one of only
a few surgeons in the country
who have done this
successfully.
Dr. Ndugu will be working
with me today,
as will one of you.
So, who's ready
to meet Fernanda?
Say hello to
the Grey-Sloan team, Fernanda.
Hi, Dr. Maggie.
Hi, everyone.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- Hey.
Fernanda's condition
left it unsafe
for her to travel
on a commercial plane,
so she and her family
have been driving
all the way across the country
from Boston.
She'll be here
in approximately two hours.
So...
who's ready to scrub --
The spinal fracture
is healing well.
No signs of malalignment.
How's PT going?
My strength's improving.
I'm putting more weight
on the leg every single day.
A lot of progress.
Great!
Okay, I'll want another exam
and set of films in two weeks.
So, I can go back to work?
Today?
No, no.
We're not there yet.
Amelia --
Owen, you're not ready.
You would have to stand
for hours at a time in an OR.
You have to build up
your endurance.
My endurance is fine!
Pick it up
without the crutch.
How scientific.
I'm not clearing you.
There's a physician shortage!
Two weeks!
And keep the pen.
Fierce Fernanda and her family
just made it to Ellensburg.
Really? Already?
Yeah.
Let me see.
My throat hurts.
Mine, too.
You're not going
to work, right?
You're worse than me.
Am not.
Hello?
And where the hell are you?
My mom said it's not nice
to say that word.
Okay, then, um, may I talk
to your mom, Miss Zola?
No, ma'am.
Excuse me?
And my I ask why not?
Because technically,
"no" is a complete sentence.
Can I have the phone?
Bai--
Bailey.
I'm sorry.
Oh, you sound gross.
I know.
Grey, no.
Uh, y-your name
is on the board
for a Whipple, esophagectomy,
two lap choles.
I know, but...
I was actually
just getting ready to call.
I can, um --
I can call someone --
Bye!
Richard, oh, thank God.
Grey is sick.
Can you take over some of her --
where are your scrubs?
I'm handing off my assignments.
Until I get
my assessment --No.
And technically,
that's a complete sentence.
Bailey, I cannot operate
until I've had my assessment.
Says who?
Says me!
Look, I-I just don't trust
myself right now.
Well, I trust you.
T-There's a potential foreign
body in the rectum in bed 9.
You're welcome.
You -- W--
Richard!
You are fine!
Look, you've been doing this
for decades.
We all have good days,
bad days.
Well, I've had more bad
than good lately.
You do know that
we are in the middle
of a physician shortage.
I cannot pick up a scalpel
or supervise anyone
until I know it's safe.
Assessment's next week.
Goodbye.
Chief!
No.
Incoming trauma, two rigs.
And someone just threw up blood
in trauma two.
I just -- I just -- I just --
I just -- I just -- I...
Okay.
Dr. Pierce!
Thank you.
I've wanted to see
a Ross procedure
my entire career.
Hm.
I know the surgery's
extremely difficult.
I mean, the complications
alone -- hemorrhage,
myocardial infarctions, stroke,
obviously death.
Yeah, I think
you've covered it, Helm.
Would you please go see
if her scans are up to date?
Yes.
Dr. Ndugu, Dr. Pierce --
aortic dissection
just came in downstairs.
Patient is
decompensating fast.
♪♪
Was he DOA?
What the hell?
♪♪
I'm alive!
It's too easy.
You jump at everything.
Thanks, Karen.
Yeah. He promised
you wouldn't have me fired.
♪♪
And who are you?
Uh, uh, Maggie,
this is Wendell.
He's my little brother.
Of course.
I've seen pictures.
Pleasure to
finally meet you.
Grey-Sloan's nice.
Lots of trees,
right in the middle of the city.
You can even see
the Space Needle
from the other side.
When it's not raining.
It's not raining.
Shouldn't it be raining?
It rains a lot in the spring.
Rained the day before
our wedding, actually.
I'm sorry for not making it
to the wedding.
You didn't even RSVP.
I know. I just --
I kept thinking
I'd make it last minute,
but...it --
it was a rough time.
I-I had a job go south,
and I was
a little embarrassed.
I couldn't even afford
a bus ticket to Seattle.
You should've called.
We could've -- We could've
helped or something.
But we're glad
you're here now.
Oh, uh, and I have a job.
You are now looking
at Trinity Labs'
new medical sales
representative.
Bam!
Hm.
With benefits.
Wow.
Congratulations.
Oh. Wendell,
we have a huge case today.
Yeah, uh, go, go.
Go save lives.
Yeah.
Maybe we'll do dinner
later.
Yeah, I'd like that.
Call you
when we're finished.
You gonna be alright?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'll just --
I'll keep myself busy.
Alright.
Okay. Come on.
Dr. Adell to the N.I.C.U.
There. That's good.
Yes, trauma two.
Has it been like this
every day?
Some days it's worse.
We're backed up down here,
we're backed up -- thank you --
on the OR floor.
Trying to find someone to take
Grey's Whipple at noon.
But now even my go-to
locum tenens is avoiding me.
I've got a stack of paperwork
so high,
I can't even
get to my desk.
I know someone
that could do the Whipple.
Yes, yes.
Nice try. Shepherd told me
you're not cleared.
I meant you.
Go operate.
Who's supposed to handle
this mess?
Me.
Bailey, half the chief's job
is to be a traffic cop
and to solve problems.
I've done it before,
and I can do it again.
You want to be chief?
W-- Just for the day.
I'll be in the OR...
Chief.
Okay, Laura,
let's try this again.
You do realize
I'm not less pregnant
than the last time we tried
this surgery?
Uh-huh.
Um, Laura Eames, 34,
severe mitral valve
insufficiency
and scheduled for
a transcatheter valve repair.
Again.
You know,
I'm really hoping
this isn't one of those
"rule of three" situations.
Wait, where's, uh,
Dr. Pierce?
Hi, Laura,
I'm Dr. Altman.
I'll be doing
your surgery today.
Dr. Pierce has a big case coming
in from Boston which was --
Yes! The girl in the RV.
I saw her this morning
on "Good Morning Seattle."
Yeah, she's doing
a Ross procedure.
Mm-hmm.
And I'm here.
Wow, that's a lot of fruit.
Yeah, I ordered it online.
Didn't realize
it would be this big. Sorry.
Probably looks bananas.
♪♪
Hm?
I'm so sorry, uh, again.
It's so sweet.
You didn't have to...
Oh.
...get me...
It's for Laura.
You know I can't eat
before surgery, dummy.
Right.
Uh, then, it is for you?
Thanks.
Alright, the family's
been on the road for weeks,
so anything they need --
um, meals, cots, clothes,
just put an intern on it.
Hospital services has been
in touch with them
about a utilities hookup for
the RV, but we should confirm.
Here they come.
♪♪
Daniel, what's wrong?
I-I don't know, she suddenly
was starting to feel
a little dizzy.
Come, come, come.
Helm, get a gurney.
♪♪
Fernanda.
It's Dr. Maggie
and Dr. Ndugu.
I feel...everything spinning.
When did it start?
About 20 minutes ago.
I drove
as fast as I could.
We need to get her inside
right away.
Dr. Maggie, are we here?
Did I make it?
Yes, Fernanda,
you made it.
You're in Seattle.
You're at Grey-Sloan.
I made it.
Yes.
I...made...it.
We got to get her to the PICU
right now.
♪♪
- Dr. Martin to Pediatrics.
- Tell Altman she can have OR 2.
She requested OR 1.
Yeah, because she thinks OR 2
has a buzzing sound,
but it doesn't --
I know this
because nobody else
has ever heard it.
You want me
to tell her that?
I want you to tell her
that she has OR 2.
Thanks.
Yeah.
Ndugu and Pierce
want to cancel
Hendrick's CABG
this afternoon.
Whoa, whoa, that's gonna throw
our whole schedule off.
Well, they need to run
a few more tests on Fernanda,
and they want to make sure
an OR is open if they need it.
Okay.
FYI, Dr. Lin is in OR 5
with a Z-plasty, not OR 4.
What? Since when?
Since I saw her go in OR 5
with Baldwin.
Does Chief Bailey
know you're doing this?
Yes, I'm acting chief
today.
Oh.
You know, I was chief of surgery
for five years.
Huh.
You're chief of surgery?
Uh, yes,
at least for the day.
I was told
to speak with you.
Wendell Ndugu.
Oh, any relation to...
Winston is my brother.
Ah.
I have an amazing opportunity
for you.
Okay, we're trying to get
her blood pressure back up,
but she is
extremely dehydrated.
We're giving her fluids,
but we noticed
that her murmur's
much worse.
What...about...
my surgery?
Can you still do it?
Uh, we're not sure.
We'll have to run an echo,
do a cardiac MRI --
Her dehydration,
is that because of the trip?
Possibly, but we knew
it would be tricky
getting Fernanda here.
We should've
gotten here sooner.
We never should've stopped.
He made us stop and --
and sight-see --
I thought we had time.
Fernanda's numbers
were good.
She was feeling great.
We've been in and out
of hospitals,
so I just wanted the kids
to see the country,
have some normalcy
before the surgery.
I...didn't think
it would hurt
to stop for
a few...pictures.
Dad?
Mr. Lima, are you okay?
I'm fine, I'm fine.
Just a little back pain.
I've been driving this RV
for two weeks.
We'll have someone
take a look at it.
In the meantime...
this isn't
anyone's fault, okay?
So let us just do the scans,
and we'll go from there.
Alright?
Hang tight, Fernanda.
Are you okay?
Dr. Wagner to Radiology.
Free fruit!
Ugh.
We're gonna be in OR 2.
Okay, I think I'm gonna try
and cram in
another practice test
until then.
Okay.
Hi, uh --Hi.
Oh.
Oh, yeah,
I-I was just sharing.
Who doesn't like fruit?
I don't know.
Uh, serial killers? Cats?
Um...
do you want
to grab dinner tonight?
Keep up the tradition
of hanging out
when my sister's
in the hospital?
I would. Um, yeah.
Okay.
But I-I have to study
for my annual
OB resident's exam,
so I will be holed up
in a library.
Okay, well, I don't
get in the way of a library.
Uh, uh, also, Laura was asking
for some ice chips.
Oh, yeah, um, okay.
Oh, hey.
Do you -- Would you mind
grabbing ice chips
for this patient here?
Thank you.
Thanks.
Yeah.
Okay, I know that
it's probably not --
he -- he's not technically
a -- a patient, so I --
Oh, relax, Wilson.
I married a patient once.
For insurance.
So I'm not judging.
Okay.
Um, and just for the record,
the thing with Link is over.
What thing with Link?
Remember how
I slept with Link?
You slept with Link?!
Oh, my God, be quiet!
Yes, remember how I told you
at the bar?
♪♪
I barely remember the bar.
Are you -- Are...
♪♪
I have to go.
W-- Did I -- Did I tell you
anything at the bar?
♪♪
Oh, God! Oh, God!
Oh, excuse me,
can you direct me
to the residency director's
office?
Oh, uh, Dr. Webber
isn't in today.
Uh, try Chief Bailey.
The pain
could be positional
from driving
so many hours a day,
but I'm happy to do
an exam, order scans?
Okay. He may be downplaying
his level of pain
because he doesn't want
to take attention away
from Fernanda's care...Mm-hmm.
Oh, no.
Winston, come listen.
And it's not
without precedent.
In Europe, a pilot program
with a similar BioTech Drone
succeeded in saving a patient
11 out of 12 takeoffs.
So you're saying we can send
a drone ahead of an ambulance
carrying a defibrillator?
A defibrillator in a drone,
for now.
In about four to six months,
we're talking about other
portable emergency equipment --
powered AI rovers.
I mean, the lives
we can save.
You know,
this all sounds pretty amazing.
I will definitely kick this up
to the board.
Your brother's selling
some pretty high tech.
Very futuristic
and cool.
Wow. I --
I had no idea.
This is your brother?
Yeah.
Hold on.
Dr. Shepherd?
Dr. Amelia Shepherd?
Yeah.
I've read about your work
on ultrasound-guided
tumor reduction.
I didn't know I was meeting
a celebrity.
Wendell Ndugu, former
black sheep of the family.
Ah, from one former black sheep
to another,
it's very nice to meet you.
How long are you in town?
Uh, you should come
for dinner.
You know what?
I'd love that.
Wendell, uh, you mind
if I talk to you real quick
before I head up
to radiology?
Yeah, yeah, sure thing.
Nice talking to you,
Dr. Hunt.
Thank you.
Dr. Shepherd.
Yeah.
Right in here.
Why are you wearing scrubs?
What are you doing?
I'm just doing my job.
Wendell,
you don't work here.
Where do you think
medical sales happen?
In a hospital.
And, you know,
I just wish you would've
talked to me about it first,
man.
I don't even know
what you're selling.
These people
are my colleagues.
Some of these people
are my bosses.
Exactly.
How do you think
I got the job?
You used my name
to get the job?
I mean, I had to at least
mention that my brother's
a hotshot surgeon
at Grey-Sloan...Mm.
...and that my sister-in-law
is head of cardio,
and that I know
Dr. Richard Webber.
You don't know
Richard Webber!
Well, I mean, I could
if you would introduce me.
Wendell, come on, man,
you lied!
You know, Dad told me
not to come here.
Dad told you not to --
you're still talking to Dad?
He said you wouldn't help me,
said you wouldn't get it.
Okay.
You know what I said?
I said, "No, no, no, no.
It'll be different this time."
Because I finally have a job
that you could be happy about.
A type of job you've been
telling me to get for years.
♪♪
I said you would be proud.
I guess Dad was right.
♪♪
The giant panda,
also known as the panda bear,
is a bear species
indigenous to China.
The daily routine for a panda
is spent roaming and feeding
at the bamboo forests
and hill regions...Thank you.
...of South Central China.
They spend
up to 16 hours a day,
eating mainly...
...on one nutrient protein
source -- bamboo.
Pandas communicate with each
other in a variety of ways.
They might chirp...
Oh, good job, Mom.
That's not easy.
...vocalization,
they also...
It is when I'm with you.
Is it weird that I wish
we got sick together more?
Yes, but I was just thinking
the same thing.
...to mark their scent.
That Whipple was perfection.
Textbook.
And it brought me joy, Perez.
Do you see my joy?
I see it.
Your closure
was almost jaunty.
Happy for you, Chief.
Yes, I'm looking for the Chief.
She's right here.
Is the esophagectomy next?
Uh, I think so.
Oh, hi, excuse me.
I'm sorry.
I'm looking for
Chief Miranda Bailey?
Oh, not today, ma'am.
Sorry.
Excuse me?
If you're looking for
the chief today,
please see Dr. Owen Hunt.
He'll help you
with whatever you need.
Uh, If you'll excuse me,
I have a surgery.
Joy.
Dr. Yoon to OR 1.
Alright.
Where do I find Dr. Hunt?
♪♪
We'll see you upstairs,
okay?
Fernanda's aortic stenosis
has gone from severe
to critical.
Made worse
by the dehydration.
Wow. Aortic jet velocity's
through the roof.
What are you thinking?
Damn it. The ventricle
is too small.
Seems to be a narrowing
of the LVOT.
Risky just became riskier.
I don't even think I can fit
a pulmonary valve in there.
Maybe they should have spent
less time taking pictures.
They could have
gotten Fernanda here
in less than four days,
and instead,
they took
crowdfunding money
from strangers and blew it
on a sight-seeing tour.
They wanted to spend time
together as a family.
Well, that extra time
just caused Fernanda
to become sicker,
which means
we're walking into
an impossible situation
in the OR.
So it's selfish.
Her family was selfish.
Are you okay?
Fine.
Look, if it were up to me,
I would change course
at this juncture.
You want to cancel
the Ross procedure?
Yeah, I do.
Is this
your medical opinion,
or are you looking
to punish this family
for what you consider to be
their "selfishness?"
Winston, I know
that you're having problems
with your brother
right now --Look, my opinion is based
on the scans, Maggie.
♪♪
But I'll support
whatever you decide.
♪♪
What? You can't put a five
on a king.
What is wrong with you?
Wait, no, you said
fives are magic.
No, I said
they're halfmagic.
We've been playing this game
for 10 years.
How do you still not know
the rules?
Dr. Wilson.
Yeah.
Will you please tell
my brother
that you can put a five
on a king?
Well, uh, she is getting
heart surgery today,
so she can do whatever
she wants.
Mm.
I knew you two would gang up
on me eventually.
Mm-hmm.
Uh-oh.
Here for me?
No, I thought I'd get
a quick appendix removed
while we wait.
You're going to be fine.
Yeah, that's what
you said last time.
And you were fine.
My uterus compressed my IVC
and my heart stopped.
And you woke up.
And you were okay.
And your baby was fine.
Okay, look.
Okay, so I'm -- I'm studying
for this test right now.
My entire OB-GYN residency
rides on it.
So basically all I do
is deliver babies,
examine vaginas,
and read about delivering babies
and examining vaginas.
So if there is one person
on the planet right now
who's prepared to help you,
it's me.
And, look, now you know
we have your baby's health
as our first priority,
so if anything doesn't
look right, we will stop,
just like we did before.
You're gonna be okay,
Laura.
Thank you.
You ready?
You got this.
Love you.
♪♪
Alright, let's head out.
You want to try a different kind
of surgery? Today?
It's called
a Ross-Konno procedure.
It's still
the Ross procedure,
but we need to make sure
that Fernanda's ventricle
can handle it,
so we need to enlarge it
first.
And how do you do that?
We cut it in half.
You want to cut
our daughter's heart in half?
Dividing
part of the ventricle
allows for better flow
to the heart,
which will ensure
that the Ross procedure
actually corrects
Fernanda's stenosis.
Is it riskier?
Yes.
We have to cut around the fibers
that control her heart beat.
She could go
into complete heart block.
Oh, my God. Meu Deus do céu...
Have you or Dr. Winston
done this procedure
on someone as sick as Fernanda?
We haven't.
But you've come of all this way
because you trusted me.
So I need you
to keep trusting me.
♪♪
This is Fernanda's
best shot.
So how do you know
you can even do it?
♪♪
Mom...
everyone else
said no.
Everyone except
Dr. Maggie.
♪♪
Is it the best option
to replace her valve?
It is.
But we need to go now.
♪♪
Do the surgery,
Dr. Maggie.
♪♪
Hey, Rafael.
Everything okay?
Just...a little dizzy...
It hurts to breathe...
Okay, alright.
Um, here.
C-Come with me. Come on.
Right in here.
Take a seat.
Okay, deep breaths, okay?
Inhale...
hold, three, two, one...
exhale.
Good.
Again, like that.
Panic attacks are sometimes
the body's reaction
to fear or stress.
You're worried
about Fernanda, right?
Rafael?
I'm a horrible brother.
Hey, come on,
what are you talking about?
You came all the way here
with her.
I'm a left winger, y'know?
Fastest in school.
I can dribble past anyone,
any age, any size.
Like Neymar.
Yeah, except...
I lost my soccer scholarship
because I had to leave school.
My sister's heart
isn't just killing her.
It's killing all of us.
My dad may have just
fractured his back,
my mom hasn't slept
in days...
No one can breathe.
None of us can breathe.
We took a week.
We took some pictures.
We laughed,
and we ate stupid tourist food,
and we saw the Badlands,
and we were happy for a minute.
And now that might've killed
my sister.
Now they have to cut
her heart in half.
'Cause we took
a few extra days!
It feels like
we're getting punished.
Like,
I don't know what we did wrong.
But we just keep
getting punished.
If my sister dies because
we stopped at the Badlands...
we won't ever recover.
We won't make it.
♪♪
What -- What do you think
you're all doing?
I could ask you
the same thing.
Dr. Pierce is about to
start Fierce Fernanda's surgery.
Uh-huh.
We heard a rumor that she's now
doing a Ross-Konno procedure.
And we snagged front row.
Uh, for the learning opportunity.
Hm, okay.
Tseng, you're supposed to be
covering the ICU,
and I have not received
your monthly case report.
Perez, you're assigned
to general,
which means you should be
in OR 3
assisting Ruiz
with a colectomy.
Dr. Hunt, this is
a once-in-a-career surgery --
How many times does Dr. Bailey
need to remind you
there is
a physician shortage?
All of you, up.
Go do medicine
instead of watching it.
Now!
♪♪
What?
I'm still
not clearing you.
Dr. Hunt?
Yeah, how can
I help you?
You're a hard person
to track down.
MaryAnn Suchan, from the
Medical Accreditation Council.
We need to talk.
Yeah.
♪♪
Must be really
nerve-wracking,
doing this kind of surgery
with so many eyes watching.
I mean, the entire country's
pulling for this little girl,
and you just made
a rare procedure
into an even rarer one.
Helm, are you finished
scrubbing?
I am.
Are you --
Please pick
a different question.
Are you aware that
your entire body is tense?
Even your jaw is locked.
I was wrong.
I was wrong to tell you
to call this off.
This surgery is mildly
terrifying,
but...I can do it.
Even so, I need someone in there
who can assist me.
And I need that person to be
completely focused.
So I'm asking you, Winston,
do I need to page Altman?
Whatever's going on
with your brother --
When my mom had cancer,
Wendell and my dad,
they flipped out
on the outside.
Wendell would get into fights
with anyone who crossed him.
And my dad drank
and just threw away money.
And he landed in jail
a few times.
And even after everything
he put us through
over the years,
Mom forgave him.
And she would use her money
for her treatment
to bail him out.
And because Mom had cancer,
I was also freaking out.
Just on the inside.
And they didn't help.
They just made it worse.
And I started --
started having panic attacks,
and I almost had to quit
my fellowship.
My whole life almost derailed
because of them.
♪♪
And now I have
this amazing thing here...
♪♪
...and I think
I got scared
that Wendell's
somehow...
just gonna do it
all over again.
♪♪
But I'm not gonna let him.
Because my wife
is a genius.
And we have a life
to save.
♪♪
Hell, we have a whole family
to save.
♪♪
Ready to deploy the clip.
How's her pressure?
Steady.
And you're sure
about the valve size?
A 3D-CTA was performed.
We're a match.
And you have
a proper alignment?
Is there a problem with
the fetal monitor, Dr. Wilson?
Nope.
Well, and I trust you
when you tell me that,
so trust me when I tell you
that everything is okay up here.
Sorry.
I just have all these
study questions in my head,
so I'm going over
every worst case scenario.
Happens.
Nothing to do with the fact
that fruit-boy's sister
is on the table?
Can I ask a question?
How long do we think
this procedure will take?
Why?
Well, Dr. Pierce upgraded
Fernanda's surgery
to a Ross-Konno.
So I thought maybe
I could head over --
No, you can't
ask a question.
As you can see,
it's not an isolated incident.
We've received
over 15 complaints
about Grey-Sloan's
residency program
in the last six months.
From the actual residents?
It's anonymous,
so it could be anyone.
But the complaints include
working over 80 hours a week,
being asked to perform surgeries
without supervision,
participating in a program with
a glaring lack of teachers...
And, Dr. Hunt,
I witnessed you yelling
at a group
of residents today.
Oh, um, uh, we've been
short-staffed recently --
So you kicked students out
of an incredible experience
to observe a surgery
that's never been done before?
I apologize for that,
but --
Apologies don't fix
a systemic problem, Dr. Hunt.
But why am I speaking to you
about all of this
and not Dr. Webber
or Chief Bailey?
♪♪
♪ Hey, hey, little wanderer
Scalpel.
♪ You walked the fields
with all the fences down ♪
They were right to travel
across the country for you.
But I already knew that.
I did it, too.
Okay.
Here we go.
♪ And so you worked
♪ As you should
♪ While they preyed
on all you ached for ♪
♪ And they pounced
♪ As they would
♪ While the guards were away
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh, oh-oh
♪♪
♪ And so, you strike
♪ While it's hot
♪ While the barricades
are broken ♪
♪ You attacked
♪ At your will
♪ While all the locks
are frayed ♪
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh-oh-oh
♪ Oh-whoa, oh-whoa, oh-whoa,
oh-whoa ♪
♪♪
♪ Oh-whoa, oh-whoa, oh-whoa,
oh-whoa ♪
♪♪
♪ Oh-whoa, oh-whoa, oh-whoa,
oh-whoa ♪
♪♪
♪ Oh-whoa, oh-whoa, oh-whoa,
oh-whoa ♪
Honey.
♪ Oh-whoa, oh-whoa, oh-whoa,
oh-whoa ♪
♪♪
Hey.
Is Laura okay?
Dr. Altman said that
everything was -- was --
Oh, yeah, no,
Laura's great.
Oh.
She's annoyed at me,
which means
that she's doing just fine.
Thank you, by the way.
I really didn't want to
have to tell her
that you were wrong.
Mm.
You know,
about her being okay.
Yeah.
I got to say, if you talk
to all your patients
the way you spoke
to my sister,
you are going to pass this test
with flying colors.
Yeah, there's just
a little bit more to it
than bedside manner.
Oh, is there?
Mm-hmm.
You don't just put your arms out
and catch the babies?
No.
I don't want to presume...
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
Uh, these are for you.
And I-I didn't know
what you liked,
so the gift shop lady told me
to go with roses, to be safe.
So...here.
They're perfect.
Thank you.
And...
Study snacks.
What?
Yes, yes.
I got you water...Uh-huh.
...electrolytes, chips...Obviously.
...dark chocolate, and I wanted
to put some fruit in,
but I thought
I over-fruited earlier.
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
Well, nobody has ever bought me
study snacks before.
Yeah, and I've never kissed
a girl in a library before.
But...the same reason
that kept me from doing it
in the past
is keeping me
from doing it now.
And what's that?
♪♪
People
come to libraries to study.
That's right.
Mm.
Good luck
on your test, Jo.
♪♪
Good night, Todd.
Coming off bypass.
Moment of truth.
Come on, Fernanda.
Come on.
♪♪
Still nothing.
Welcome back,
Fierce Fernanda.
♪♪
It worked?
It worked.
Oh!
Oh, my God!
Oh.
Come on. Come on.
- Thank you.
- Oh!
Thank you.
Sorry.
Brazilians are huggers.
It's okay.
No, she's got
a long road to recovery,
but so far, so good.
Thank you.
Thank you, Dr. Maggie.
Thank you for saying yes.
♪♪
Oh!
Mm.
♪♪
Um...
you have
your worried face on.
No, I don't.
Zola, it's me.
You keep ignoring
Dr. Hamilton's phone calls,
and you won't text
Dr. Marsh back.
Do you want the truth?
They want to talk to me
about something
that I probably should talk
to you about first.
What is it?
I've been offered a job
in Minnesota.
You already have a job
Right. But this job
would require me
to give up
my job in Seattle.
So we would move?
We would have to, yes.
How w-- How would you feel
about that?
Would the job save
a lot of lives?
Maybe.
Would you see
Dr. Marsh more?
Probably.
Would that
make you happy?
You, Bailey, and Ellis
make me happy.
We would follow you
anywhere.
Researchers studied
patient codes
at hundreds of hospitals.
They found patients
had increased survival rates
at hospitals with longer
attempts at resuscitation.
Of course, there are limits
on how much we can do.
Thanks for coming back.
Yeah. I'm surprised
you called.
♪ Sunlight fell
and reminded me ♪
I still blame you
for Mom dying.
♪ That life can be so gracious
sometimes ♪
I didn't
give Mom cancer.
I know.
But sometimes...
I think that
she would still be alive
if she didn't put all
of her money and energy
into you and Dad.
I know --
I know that's not fair.
Look, her cancer...
♪♪
...it took us out.
♪ At night I hear
the rhythm of the ocean ♪
It took us both out
in different ways, man.
And she would be so angry
if she knew...
♪ And I think about all the
things that I am grateful for ♪
...if she knew that we let it
take us away from each other.
♪♪
I miss you, man.
♪ And they say
I'm glad you're here.
♪ Hold on
to the ones you love ♪
And...if you want
to stick around,
Maggie said
you can stay with us,
and I will try
to introduce you
to some people
at the hospital, alright?
It'll be different
this time.
I hope so.
♪♪
Should we hug it out?
No.
No?
We should get some food.
Come on. Some beer.
Maggie's waiting for us.
Uh, can you cover me
for dinner?
I'm kidding.
Wow, look at that face.
It's on me, actually.
Uh, you know,
company card.
It's on you?
Yeah, exactly.
As hard as we try, not every
patient has a happy ending.
♪ Feel the sunlight
fall upon you ♪
One day in that chair,
and you look 10 years older.
See? That's why
I needed today.
So thank you.
I did that Whipple, a fundo,
two endoscopies.
I even squeezed in
an ex-lap
that came from that horrible
pile-up on the bridge.
I haven't done that much surgery
in one day
since I was a resident.
Uh.
Bailey.
Ah, I feel centered now.
This is manageable now.
Bailey.
♪ And they say
What?
What is it?
Our residency program...
this is an official
notification.
They're trying
to shut it down.
♪ Hold on to this time we have
Sometimes
we just have to call it.
♪ And let the light
shine through ♪
♪♪