I told them
that she can stay with us.
You can't trust her.
Look, I'm sorry,
but she's coming
home with us.
No, Ethan,
she's going home
with you.
Will you marry me?
This is Gwen Garrett,
our new C.O.O.
New? We never had
an old C.O.O.
We lose one girl,
we lose them both.
The VSD's repaired.
You got an offer tonight,
didn't you?
Mayo Clinic.
Of course
you're going to take it.
Would you?
You're suggesting
I'm a murderer.
You know what's
the most fascinating thing
about serial killers?
They all can't seem
to resist
taking a personal item
from their victims.
Bob?
Dad?
We need a crash cart.
Crash cart, now!
We need a crash cart
in here.
There's no pulse.
Take over
compressions.
Start bagging.
Charged to 200. Clear!
Clear!
Resume compressions.
Charged to 200.
Clear.
We need to talk.
Charge to 200.
This way.
This is my father's.
Appreciate your help,
Dr. Reese.
Forensics will gather
samples to collect
for DNA,
but they may need to take
a few of your father's
things to the lab.
I understand.
I know that
this isn't easy,
but... But it's the right
thing to do.
You're the last person
to tell me what's right.
Sharon.
Yo.
Have you heard
from Dr. Reese?
She's your resident.
Why would she call me?
Well, she's due back today,
but I was expecting her
at rounds first thing
this morning.
Well, she hasn't
been in touch.
Let's hope she's okay.
But don't you need to address
our new med students?
Yeah.
Ladies and gentleman,
this is Dr. Charles.
He's our Chief of Psychiatry.
Good morning,
and welcome.
First thing I want to
tell you about is...
Packing up?
Yeah, yeah.
Our days of butting
heads are almost over.
Oh, thank God for that.
By the way, did you know
that Rochester, Minnesota,
is the 14th coldest city
in the U.S.?
And Chicago's 48, you know.
It's much warmer.
Why don't you just admit it?
You don't want me to go.
Oh, please.
Oh, you're going to miss me.
Miss the most
egotistical, ambitious,
and arrogant man
I've ever met? Hardly.
Here.
Now that you are a big shot
attending, I'm going to leave
you with this.
"Cardiac surgeons
fix broken hearts."
We could have
had something.
You're the one
who's leaving.
Dr. Bekker, Dr. Rhodes.
They need you in the ED.
Suspected TRA coming in.
Yeah.
Trevor Keyes,
high-speed decelerating
motor vehicle crash.
Prolonged extrication.
Right arm BP 136/88.
Nothing in his left.
Wife was treated
on the scene.
Mr. Keyes, do you know
where you are?
Can you squeeze my hand?
All right, minimal response.
Let's transfer him
on my count.
One, two, three.
All right, let's go.
Okay, Mr. Keyes,
can you touch
your chin to your chest?
Any pain?
No.
Head side-to-side,
pain?
No.
Good, c-spine is cleared.
Let's get a chest x-ray
stat. Logroll.
Dr. Choi?
Dr. Bekker and Dr. Rhodes.
They're cardiothoracic
surgeons.
X-ray clear.
This is his wife.
Linda. Please,
help my husband.
There's weakness in Mr. Keyes'
left hand, and it's cold.
Wide mediastinum.
What's that mean?
There is a high probability
of a contained rupture
in his aorta.
We need to get Mr. Keyes
to the hybrid room right away.
Okay.
All right, let's go.
Have anesthesia
meet us upstairs,
and bring esmolol
for the road.
Right away.
Don't worry, baby.
It's gonna be all right.
Out of the way.
Out of the way!
Everybody out.
Out, out, out, out! Come on,
let's go, let's go, let's go.
Linda.
I love you.
Trev, I love you, too.
But you're gonna be fine.
I...
Trev? Trevor?
Nothing.
What's happening?
No pulse.
Trevor.
Oh, God.
Come on.
Oh, God, Trevor.
Let's go.
Wrong floor.
This isn't surgery.
Can't wait.
Got to open his chest now.
Get me a scalpel.
Connor.
Check his pulse.
No.
Why? What's happening
to him?
His aorta ruptured.
I've got to get control.
Here.
Trevor, no, no!
No!
Help me spread his ribs.
Can you feel the hole?
There's too much blood.
Oh, God.
His aorta is wide open.
What do you mean?
I'm so sorry.
There's nothing I can do.
No, Trevor.
He's gone.
He's dead?
I'm sorry.
Trevor's dead?
No!
No, Trevor, no! No!
Trevor, no!
Time of death, 8:23.
We shouldn't have
lost the patient.
His aorta burst.
What could you have done?
When we were in the ED,
he hadn't yet suffered
the fatal rupture.
If we'd been able to
repair his injury there,
he'd still be alive.
The problem
was the time it took
transferring him upstairs.
But the ED isn't
equipped to perform
the kind of procedure
you're talking about.
That's Dr. Rhodes's point.
There needs to be
a hybrid operating room
in the ED.
Fully equipped to perform
emergency cardiac surgery.
An OR in the ED.
We have lost far too many
patients on the way
to the OR.
Actually, I like the idea,
but converting a trauma room
into a surgical suite...
It's not
an inexpensive proposition.
I'll tell you what.
Write up a proposal.
I'll have it on your desk
in an hour.
Dr. Rhodes, with
your background
in both trauma and CT,
you'd be the ideal person
to head a program like this.
If the board okays it,
I'd like you to stay.
I'm sorry, Ms. Goodwin,
but I start at the
Mayo Clinic on Monday.
Hey.
That looks so good on you.
I agree.
You know, we should get
serious about a date.
Book a venue.
A venue?
I was thinking more of like
a city hall-type thing.
I don't know,
a few friends.
Maybe dinner after.
What, no, I already
talked to Father Brady.
He promised us
a Saturday at St. Ursula's.
Nat, I got a whole
neighborhood to invite.
We need a hall.
Dr. Manning, Dr. Halstead,
with me.
Okay.
Desmond?
25-year-old deaf male
Peter Rush.
Intractable headache,
disoriented.
Sensitivity to light.
GCS 15.
Vomited times two
in the ambo.
Maggie,
will you help us?
Yep.
Would you like
an interpreter?
Yes.
She's certified.
Let's sheet transfer.
One, two, three.
Heart rate 112,
BP 122/76.
Normal sinus rhythm.
These two take care of you.
This is his fiancée, Bonnie.
Have you been deaf
since birth?
No, 14. Mumps.
She says he had cochlear
implant surgery a month ago.
It's due to be activated.
Chest is clear, regular
rate rhythm S1 and 2.
Sick!
And let's give him four
milligrams of ondansetron.
Got it.
She says it's meningitis
from the implant.
She warned him
not to get it.
We don't know
that he has meningitis.
His neck exam is normal.
And meningitis can occur after
surgery, but it's not common.
Let's get a CBC, BMP,
and cultures times two.
Right.
And let's send him up
for a head CT.
Okay, I'll put in the order.
Thank you.
Yeah.
April.
Hey, April,
can I get a second?
Emily's really turned
her life around.
She's clean, going to AA.
She's got a job,
sells cosmetics.
Oh. And you're telling
me this why?
I'm bringing Emily
to Connor's party,
and she'd like
to talk to you.
Why?
She feels bad.
She should.
Emily wants to make amends.
It's a part of the program.
Emily has a drug problem
and a gambling problem.
She stole opioids
from the hospital.
I know.
She needs to be in rehab.
I...
She needs psychotherapy...
I know.
But she's really trying.
One step at a time.
Mr. Jackson,
these are student doctors,
Curry and McNeal.
They're going to help me
sew you up.
Okay.
McNeal, glove up.
Curry, why don't you get
him an IV and hang a bag
of normal saline?
That's a nurse's job.
I'm sorry?
I said,
that's a nurse's job.
Every doctor should know
how to put in an IV.
I do know how,
but I don't see
the point.
That's not something
I'm ever going to be doing.
I'm not going
into patient care.
Is there a problem?
No, sir.
Ms. Curry, when you are
on my service,
you will do exactly
what's expected of you.
Do you understand?
Mr. Jackson is a machinist,
and he cut his forearm
in the shop.
What do you make of the wound?
Pretty clean.
Edges are smooth.
Nylon suture?
You'd better
take another look.
Oh.
That's actually
a pretty deep cut.
So how do you obliterate
the dead space?
Absorbable stitch.
Right, right.
You're a doctor?
Medical student.
You're a big guy.
What's the matter,
couldn't play football?
Let's numb that arm.
You don't
have meningitis.
On the other hand,
we don't know why
you're having
these symptoms.
Your sensitivity to light
concerns us,
so we'd like to do
some more blood work,
including a genetic test,
just to cover our bases.
You'll have to stay
here overnight.
We'll try to find you
a bed upstairs.
Otherwise, we will
make you
as comfortable as
possible down here.
The good news is
we've talked to
your audiologist,
and we can turn on
your cochlear implant.
Yes, I want it.
Thank you.
Yes, I'm doing it.
They're having
an argument.
Yeah.
Maybe we should step out.
Yeah?
Dr. Reese, there you are.
I am very glad to see you.
I'm not staying.
I'm leaving Med.
I'm continuing
my residency at Baylor.
Oh.
I think people here would
always look at me and think,
"Oh, there's that doctor,
the one whose father
murdered those girls."
I could live with that.
It's you.
It's me?
All that time
you suspected my father,
you never told me anything.
Sarah, look,
I was trying to protect you
until I was
absolutely certain.
I mean, surely...
I can't trust you.
I can never trust you.
You have every
right to be upset,
and I hope that
we have some time
to talk through this,
but please, don't leave.
Every time
I'd see your face,
I would remember
when I walked into that room
and saw my father
on the floor.
I...
I saw it in your eyes.
You were going
to let him die.
Hi.
Hi, Peter,
this is Helen Moore,
the hospital's audiologist.
So, let me get this on you,
and then I can activate it.
No.
I don't want it.
I... I don't understand.
Bonnie, she thinks
because of this,
I don't love her.
I want Bonnie more
than my hearing.
If you change your mind,
let your doctors know.
Yeah,
I've seen this before.
Implants are controversial
among the deaf.
For Bonnie,
deafness is a culture,
a community.
She thinks we're trying
to fix a problem that
isn't a problem.
Courtney?
45-year-old female.
Found delusional and agitated.
Put her in treatment 4.
No obvious injuries,
no meds given in the field.
All right,
get ready to rotate.
Take them in,
Angel. Dr. Choi?
Can't leave this GSW.
Terry, start the work-up.
See if you can
get a history.
I'll be there soon.
I'm going to call Psych.
Where's Monique?
Monique, get in here.
Let's transfer on my count.
It's his fault.
It's his fault!
One, two, three.
Ma'am, can you tell us
your name?
Do you know where you are?
Over there. Look.
It's his fault.
We need to sedate her.
You should wait for Dr. Choi.
He told me to work her up.
I can't with her like this.
10 of haloperidol.
Stop it before it's too late.
Stop him. Stop.
Stop him
before it's too late.
Stop him before it's too late.
Stop him... Stop him
before it's too late.
Stop him
Let's let her calm down
before we take off
the restraints.
I thought this patient
was agitated.
She was.
I sedated her.
You sedated her?
Without waiting for me?
Well, I couldn't examine her.
Well now, neither can I.
You're a medical student.
You're not authorized
to order medication.
But she was delusional,
psychotic.
And you are not qualified
to make that diagnosis,
or any diagnosis.
The patient's emotional state
could have been
something entirely physical,
and therefore
easily treatable,
like a UTI, for instance.
But now, we can't
determine that
because you knocked her out.
You ought to be
written up for this.
Dr. Charles, it was my fault.
Be quiet. Where's Dr. Choi?
I'm right here.
Supervise your
medical students!
I wasn't told the board
was in session.
Dr. Rhodes,
impressive proposal.
Unfortunately,
we have to pass.
And why is that?
A C-Arm. That's anywhere
from 1.7 million to 2.5.
Booms and lights, 200,000.
Two large ceiling-mounted
hi-def screens.
Do I need to continue?
No hospital I know of
has a hybrid OR
in the ED.
Not to mention
the huge PR benefit
in Med being the first...
The investment is not
worth the expense.
I recommended that
the board pass.
They agreed.
Well...
Thank you for trying.
I think it would be a mistake
for the hospital to lose this.
In Yiddish,
"bon voyage"
is for gezunterhait.
In Hebrew, however,
we say leich l'shalom,
which literally means
"go towards peace,"
but it has a deeper meaning
of going towards greater
spiritual perfection.
I'd like to wish
you that, Dr. Rhodes.
Leich l'shalom.
April.
Emily.
I want to apologize
for everything
that happened.
It was all my fault.
I'm trying to make up
for what I did.
I'm trying to turn my
life around, and...
A lot of that
is because of you.
You believed in me, and...
I'm... I'm really sorry
I disappointed you.
Be right back.
Can I get you a drink?
There you go.
Thank you.
Did you get a chance to
check out that venue?
No.
I'm sorry, I left it
at the hospital.
Yeah, well, I brought it.
Oh.
Natalie, look,
if you don't want
to get married, just say so.
What?
Where is this
coming from?
You don't seem to care
about the ceremony,
or the reception.
It took you a week
to say yes.
And I said yes,
and I meant it.
But you act like
our marriage is no big deal.
Of course it's a big deal.
But a church wedding,
a reception.
I've done
all that before.
I haven't been
married before.
I want the whole thing.
Just so you know,
a wedding
is not a marriage.
Glad you cleared
that up for me.
Will.
No, I'm just
overwhelmed with
your enthusiasm.
I'm going
to get some food.
Hey, Maggie.
Have you seen Ava?
Ms. Goodwin.
Hey, have you
seen Dr. Bekker?
She said
she was coming tonight.
No, I haven't.
Maybe she got
stuck in surgery.
Maybe.
So let's get
four of the flutes
over here, one more.
And then, we'll have
a nice arrangement
right here.
Great.
Mr. Rhodes?
Dr. Bekker.
Have you got a minute?
Of course, this way.
I'll be right back.
Creating a hybrid OR
in the ED
would be expensive,
and the hospital
is not willing
to make the commitment.
However, if private
donors such as yourself
would earmark
contributions
for the project,
the board
would be incentivized
to make the investment.
Right.
I wouldn't expect you
personally to fund
the entire project.
I would think
with your connections,
you could raise it
with just a few
phone calls.
Well...
And you'd be running
this project?
No, Dr. Rhodes...
Connor will be.
I thought he was off
to the Mayo Clinic.
I believe he'll stay
in Chicago if
the program gets funded.
Well, as I'm sure
you're aware,
my son and I have not had
the easiest of relationships.
I'd want my involvement
kept anonymous.
Of course,
I understand.
Let me think about it.
I'm afraid
this is time-sensitive.
Oh.
You know what?
I have an idea.
Why don't we go to dinner,
discuss this further?
Hey, Peter Rush's
test results.
Oh, man.
Yeah.
What is it?
Peter, your deafness
wasn't caused by mumps.
It was caused
by a genetic disease
that you tested
positive for,
Usher syndrome.
And it's what caused
the symptoms
you are now experiencing.
What does that mean?
So some of your symptoms
can be addressed,
but Usher syndrome
causes a condition
called retinitis pigmentosa.
A progressive deterioration
of eyesight.
My eyesight?
I'm sorry, Peter,
but retinitis pigmentosa
is untreatable.
No cure.
I'm going blind?
Yes, you will experience
a significant loss in vision,
and maybe even blindness.
Oh, God.
We know this is a lot
to process.
A genetic disease specialist
will come down to discuss
what you can expect, and what
measures can be taken to help.
Maybe you want
Bonnie to come here
for that?
No, she can't find out.
But you're getting married.
She will find out.
She broke it off.
Now, it's all for the best.
I don't want her
coming back out of pity.
You don't...
She should be with someone
who won't be
a burden to her.
Yeah?
Hey, Dr. Charles?
Sarah called.
Asked me to send her stuff.
She thought maybe
she left her case log here.
Oh, yeah.
Right here.
Okay. You know,
I really liked Sarah.
I always hoped, you know,
something might happen, or...
But I guess with all that
she was going through,
never really had
a real chance.
Yeah.
I'm sorry
about that, Noah.
Yeah.
You know,
she once told me that
the way you brought her
into psych helped her.
That you were the dad
she always wanted.
Dr. Choi?
Emily, what's wrong?
I've just been dizzy,
real tired.
Getting these headaches.
She's also complaining
of diarrhea.
Vitals are mostly normal,
a little soft
on the pressure.
BP 95/58,
heart rate 110.
The patient is my sister,
so I'll leave you
and April to do the exam.
I'll be back
to look in on you.
Okay.
Ms. Curry?
What... Right.
I'm Elsa Curry,
third year
medical student.
I'm going
to examine you.
Oh, no. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry...
Peter's not up... For...
Okay.
Why are you here?
Who told you?
Did you?
No, no.
No.
She wants to know
why Peter's acting like this.
It's up to Peter
to tell her.
You can tell her.
Peter has a condition
called Usher syndrome,
which caused him
to lose his hearing
and will also cause him
to lose his sight.
All right, now,
let's move on to the budget.
The first line item
to discuss
is marketing and PR.
Actually, let's table
that discussion.
Dr. Bekker, Dr. Rhodes,
thank you for joining us.
I have good news.
The hospital received
donations earmarked
for your ED hybrid OR,
and the Board has decided
to provide matching funds.
We're going ahead
with your proposal.
Well, I am very happy
to hear that.
But there is one
stipulation, Dr. Rhodes.
You have to stay
and run the program.
Emily's test results.
No.
You're not sick.
You're pregnant.
Really?
You didn't suspect
that might be the case?
I mean, I have been
throwing up a lot.
Do you even know
who the father is?
Yeah, of course
I know who the father is.
What do you think I am?
It's Bernie.
Who's Bernie?
He's in my AA group.
Your AA group?
You're not supposed to date
people in your AA group.
Look, he's been sober
for six years.
He's a responsible person.
Responsible?
You call this responsible?
I don't believe you.
Oh, God, I didn't
mean it to happen.
What am I going to do now?
You were right.
Everything you said
was right.
I'm an idiot, a total idiot.
Ethan, don't.
You were just
trying to help her.
You were trying to be
a good big brother.
And look at the mess
she's made.
I know.
Emily can't have this baby.
What?
Come on.
She has a history
of drug abuse.
She's sleeping
with some guy
in her AA group.
If you're going
where I think you're going...
April, two months ago,
Emily was homeless.
Who knows when
she'll run away again?
She's completely unstable,
and she might
start using again.
Harm the fetus.
And she might not.
What kind of life
can she give a child?
It doesn't matter.
Of course it matters.
No. You're not
a Catholic.
It's a life.
We have to protect it.
Mr. McNeal?
I want to apologize
for earlier.
You really need
to learn how
to follow protocol, okay?
But I shouldn't have
snapped at you like that.
I'm dealing with a...
With a loss.
Thank you.
Coming in.
And your paperwork
is done.
I got to go tell Bernie.
I don't know
how he'll take it.
I hope he's happy, but,
God, what if he's not?
I can't cope
with this by myself.
I... I can't have
this baby alone.
Emily, you're not alone.
Oh, yeah,
but Ethan's so mad at me.
He'll come around.
And I'm here for you.
You are?
We'll figure this out.
Okay?
Okay.
Now, I'm going to be
sending a series of beeps.
First, very soft,
inaudible.
When you can hear
the beeps, let me know.
Wait, yes.
I can hear it, yes.
Good.
Tell me, Peter,
can you hear my voice?
Oh, God.
Yes, I can.
I can hear again.
She said that
she'll be his eyes,
and he'll be her ears.
Ms. Garrett, I know
we've had our differences,
but I'm very happy
you approved
the hybrid OR down here.
Are you, Dr. Stohl?
Sharon, if you would.
You go behind
my back and get
these token contributions
for about a quarter
of the cost.
The hospital is out millions
for your pet project.
The Board could
have refused the money.
No, it couldn't,
and you know that.
These are some
of our biggest donors.
They want a hybrid OR,
they get a hybrid OR.
You locked us in.
Are you going to fight me
on every one of my decisions?
Depends on the decision.
Well, I'm glad I know
where we stand.
Our Chief
of Emergency Medicine,
Dr. Stohl.
Very much your man.
I think Dr. Stohl
is very much his own man.
I have not been happy
with his performance of late.
We're not going
to renew his contract.
Really, you'd take
this out on him?
Stay out of my way.
They don't start serving
for another hour.
Sit.
Hanger steak,
planked whitefish,
and for vegetarians,
lentil and chickpea stew.
Thank you.
What's all this?
Dishes to try
for our reception.
You take care of the venue,
I'll take care of the caterer.
You know, eyes and ears.
Here, try.
Mmm.
That's really good.
Yeah?
Here you go, Dr. Rhodes.
Thanks, man.
Ava, hey.
So I was... I was looking into
what you were talking about,
Rochester, and you are right.
It is very cold.
Yeah?
Yeah, so anyway,
I told the Board that I was
going to stay here at Med.
Really?
Yeah, I mean,
if the program is a success,
then it could be
a very big deal.
It's a better career move
than Mayo.
Exactly.
Okay.
Well, I guess I don't
need to remind you.
You're no longer
on the CT service.
Yet, you did.
From now on, when you
bring a patient upstairs,
I decide the course
of treatment.
Now, you see,
if I'd gone to Mayo,
that's exactly the kind of
collegial interaction
I would have missed.
Dr. Charles.
Here to gloat?
No.
Just dropped by to
let you know
Sarah's leaving Chicago.
You'll probably
never see her again.
Is that supposed to wound me?
My daughter?
She put me here.
Huh.
I thought you put
yourself here.
It's all circumstantial.
You know that.
Where are the bodies?
If I could get
a halfway decent lawyer,
instead of that idiot P.D.
in his cheap suit.
You know, when I was
having my heart attack,
you weren't
going to save me,
were you?
You were going
to let me die.
All right, do it now.
Kill me.
You've had your fun.
Enough.
No one would want to go on
living like this, anyway.
I'm sorry you're having
such a hard time.
I'll talk to your doctor
and see if he'll boost
your anti-depressants.
And I'm the one
without a conscience?
No, don't worry about it.
It's gonna get better.
It always does.
Really.
In my experience, psychopaths
adjust extraordinarily well
to almost any situation.
Even, you know, this one.