So, Nathan and I...
we are...
becoming a couple...
I think? I don't know.
But, you're my sister,
and I wanted to tell you,
because I don't want
it to come between us.
Huh, she's gonna hate me.
That's a good point. It has
taken me a long time to tell you.
Attraction is messy. It grabs
you when you least expect it.
Of course, this
isn't what I wanted.
- Mommy.
- We got to go.
- We're gonna be late. Come on.
- Okay.
And in the end, what really matters
is that we care about each other,
and that will never change.
- How's that sound?
- Forced.
Well, it sounds forced,
because I'm a horrible person.
You could use the plane. Near-death
experience. That's a good excuse.
Lie? Your advice is to lie?
Planes have taken
a lot from you.
When have they ever
given you something good?
Gave me a hospital.
I mean, it happened before I
even knew she liked him, you know?
But then it happened again.
I just, I don't know.
I don't even know
how it got this far.
Well, he lost his wife,
you lost your husband.
Look, if you don't want
to lie, just be vague.
No details. She's an
adult. She can take it.
Less is more.
- What if she hates me?
- She's not gonna hate you.
And I called it off and I kept
it off until I couldn't anymore,
and I'm really very, very sorry.
That's the one.
I have been looking
everywhere for you.
- You're in the ladies' room.
- So?
Show me your teeth.
All clear. Okay, so,
this is the shirt you like.
I brought it, because I
knew you would forget it.
Thank you.
You're nervous. Yeah.
It's a big crowd, bright lights,
but you're gonna be great.
And, I'll be there, so if you
get nervous, you just look at me.
- You just talk to me, okay?
- Okay.
- You got this.
- Thanks.
You're right. She
might hate you.
- All right. Edwards?
- Mary Parkman, 25.
Complaining of gradual
onset severe abdominal pain.
History of previous appy.
She's moving around so
much, I couldn't really get a read.
Hi, Mary.
I'm gonna just gently
palpate your abdomen
to check for tenderness, okay?
Yeah, abdomen's distended.
Hang in there, noodle.
You're doing great.
I hate that you're
seeing me like this.
You hurt, I hurt, sugarbear.
I'm here for you.
- They do that a lot.
- Mary?
Uh, Mary, can you tell me if
the pain is localized in any part of
- your abdomen, or is it...
- No, it's... It's everywhere.
Okay. All right.
You are doing great.
Can you breathe? Deep breaths.
In. Good.
Out. In.
Dennis made me breakfast
in bed. It was, so sweet.
Pancakes, bacon and...
Oh, my God! I am so sorry.
- No, it's fine.
- Here you go.
Edwards, admit her,
and page Dr. Webber.
- I'm just gonna go...
- Wash the puke out of your hair?
Got it! Here you go.
I can't believe you saw me yack.
I am so disgusting.
No. It's real, just like you.
I love how real you are,
boo-boo. You're so beautiful.
I love you, too.
Look at this turnout.
I know.
Hero doctors save
lives on a plane?
It's a great story,
and great publicity.
Catherine agrees.
She's over there. Did you see?
Yep.
What's the matter?
Crowd not big enough?
Richard's not sitting
with Catherine.
Okay. You need to
leave that man alone.
Agreed. I'm moving
on to Catherine.
Their marriage is not your lane.
Your lane is over here with me.
Stay in it.
- I mean it, Miranda.
- You're right.
My lane is with
you, in this marriage.
- I am blessed.
- Alright, then.
I have also been
blessed with the ability
to change lanes, because
my car belongs to me
and I take it
where I want to go.
Leave no lane untraveled.
That's big talk for somebody
who's scared of Catherine Avery.
Wha... Please!
- I am not afraid of Ca...
- Dr. Bailey.
- See? You made me late.
- Mm-hm.
Hello. Good morning, all.
Uh, I am Dr. Miranda
Bailey. Chief of Surgery.
And I would like to extend
a very warm welcome
to the members of
the press here today.
Welcome back. I just
talked to your oncologist.
- How you feeling?
- I told him not to page you away
- from some sick kid.
- Veronica's in a lot of pain.
It's her back and everywhere.
She can hardly walk.
Hey, you try walking
with a bowling ball
attached to a
body full of cancer.
- You're about 35 weeks now,
right?
- Thirty-four weeks, three days.
Her husband's more
informed than most.
- Not her husband.
- Not my husband.
Just friends. But,
we get it all the time.
Oh, Jer, could you...
Your back pain, how long?
Uh, about a week.
Who'd have thought skipping
cancer treatments would hurt so much?
You passed up cancer treatment?
Yeah, I didn't want to
microwave the baby.
Any numbness in your
legs or feet, any tingling?
Yeah, actually, a little.
What? You look
worried. I can tell.
What does that mean?
Tingling could mean
any number of things.
Baby okay?
- I can still make it to term,
right?
- This could just be pregnancy.
We'll get an MRI,
and we'll go from there.
On the 13th of this month,
Doctors Meredith
Grey and Nathan Riggs
were on a flight to Philadelphia
to attend the National
Conference on Operative Advances.
While on that flight,
the turbulence...
You know, we can always
skip out on this if you want.
Yeah, right. I wish.
This is great press
for the hospital.
Brings in more
people, more money.
Do you have any idea how
much it costs to run this place?
And I'm going to make the
time to talk to Maggie today, too.
Just make me the bad guy.
- Just tell her it was all me.
- No, I don't want to.
I don't want to lie.
- Doctors Meredith Grey
and Nathan Riggs.
- Let's get this over with.
Dr. Riggs! Dr. Grey,
we've got questions.
Did your life flash
before your eyes?
How did it feel to receive a
commendation by the governor?
Is it true you got a
call from the president?
Did you kiss the ground
when you landed?
- Did you think
you were gonna die?
- Okay, slow down.
I was... We were on our
way to a medical conference.
Pretty routine stuff, really.
Certainly didn't expect to be
sitting here, in front of all of you.
Now, you see those big loops?
That's a classic sign
of bowel obstruction.
You have something
blocking your intestines.
Something like what?
Most common cause is a scar
from your previous appendectomy.
Or, it could just be
something you ate.
We'll do some more studies,
but often it'll resolve on its own.
And if not, then you'll
have to have surgery.
- Surgery?
- Oh, Mary, babe, you poor thing!
Now, now, now. Hopefully
it won't come to that.
These things can. They
can get better naturally.
Naturally? You got her hooked
up to machines just to stay alive.
That is an IV to
keep her hydrated.
Now, what can that be?
I never thought I
could fall in love so fast,
but I've never felt like
this... about anyone.
I'm so glad we found each other.
Me too, dumpling.
Every day.
It's like, affecting
my body and soul.
Does make you want to puke.
Oh, my... Oh, God!
It's only been a
few months, but...
when you know, you just know.
- You know?
- I do.
I know so much.
DeLuca, can you stop
doing that, please?
- Sorry. Uh, Dr. Webber?
- What is it, DeLuca?
- Could you...
- Oh, my God.
What? What? What am I missing?
- Worms!
- Worms.
It's just, I just found a worm
from her stomach in my hair.
It was really long.
And there's one in the
suction canister, too.
A worm?
Wait. So that means that's...
A whole lot of worms.
Huh.
Dr. Riggs, you've
served as a field surgeon
in war-torn parts of the world.
- How did this compare?
- Less dust, less wind.
There was less legroom.
Uh, I mean, look. I
was there, I pitched in.
So was a pediatric
dentist, flight attendants.
Even some of the
passengers helped out.
But Dr. Grey was
working on a man's brain
in conditions under
which I've never seen,
and she didn't fail
or falter, not once.
She was incredible.
And so she is
your story, not me.
What's it feel like...
She was incredible.
So she is your story, not me.
So she's your story, not me.
Oh. I thought
Ryan was in on this.
I tagged in.
RAM or LDM flap?
Uh, neither, actually.
We're doing an EOM.
Did you get a chance
to look over the chart?
- Yeah, I'm caught up.
- Great.
Oh, Grey's calling you. I just got
started. You want me to grab it?
No, just leave it, Jackson.
Sure.
- You alright?
- Yes.
Okay.
Hey, I couldn't make the press
conference. Did I miss anything?
Yeah. Yeah, I learned a lot.
Veronica, it looks as though
your tumor has metastasized
to your spine. It's starting
to compress your spinal cord.
The cancer's spreading?
Well, we knew this could happen,
but this does accelerate things.
What things?
Okay, come on. Just
give it to me straight.
I would give you two,
maybe three more months.
Two?
It was supposed to be seven or
eight. That's what they said. That's...
We've been holding onto that.
There's more.
Yes.
We also need to
keep your baby safe.
And given how much
the cancer has spread
and how difficult the spinal
mets would make a term delivery,
I want to deliver
your baby today.
No!
No. It's too soon.
He's still too little.
You're at 34 weeks.
I've delivered way
smaller babies than this.
Yours should be just fine.
And the safest
option is a C-section.
And I'll be there to handle
any spinal-cord issues.
If they deliver today...
then that's two
months with the baby.
That's you and me...
and the little boy.
But we deliver today.
Okay.
All right. Let's
cheer up, everybody.
We're having a baby.
Do we know what they are?
Ascaris lumbricoides,
the intestinal roundworm.
Can grow to a
length of half a meter.
It's rare in the U.S.,
but an estimated one-sixth of
the human population's infected.
Yeah, and our
patient has half of 'em.
Is there a world
record for these?
No.
No, no, no. No.
I don't understand.
They're breeding in her
stomach, like, right now?
Well, technically,
they're not in her stomach.
The larvae travel
through the bloodstream.
Where they go to the small
intestine to mature and mate.
Where they will
deposit more eggs.
- The worms, they...
- Stop saying "worms"!
How long have
they been in there?
Um, we, we can't say, um...
The lar... um...
They take at least a couple of
months to mature into adults.
So...
She's had these since we met?
You, you could have ingested
them from unwashed fruit or...
- Ugh, just get them out.
- The surgery,
it's extremely simple.
Um, DeLuca, let's book an O.R.
Mm-hm.
- Uh, Dennis?
- Hey.
You can accompany
her to the pre-op room.
Um...
Dennis?
I can't. I... I just
have to... uh...
I got to make a phone
call and let your mom know
that you're okay
and other people.
- Who?
- Work.
I have a work call. I mean, I
have to call your work and family.
Oh, okay. Let's see
about these worms.
Uh-huh.
Dr. Reynolds to the E.R.
Hi. Thank you.
Uh, I see that you're
working with Dr. Webber.
Mm-hm.
- How does he seem?
- Oh, great. Yeah.
We have a patient with a gut full of worms
so he's, you know, in his happy place.
I, on the other hand, can't stop
scratching my head, because a patient
threw up in my hair, and now
I'm convinced something might
be crawling around in
there, which is not a thing that
- anyone wants.
- Yeah, good, good. Uh...
Do you think you
could try to talk to him?
- What?
- Richard and Catherine
need some help
coming back together.
I'm on a mission.
Great. Great. What's the plan?
I don't have one, but
we need to do something.
We?
Oh, okay, I get to be part
of the mission, too? Okay.
No. Okay. I could
be good at this, umm.
- Have you talked to Catherine?
- I tried. It didn't work.
Okay, try again while I scrub
in with Richard and the worms,
- and I will talk to him.
- Worms?
Your patient threw up worms?
There was only one.
That's one too many.
- Hey.
- Hi.
I have a quadruple-bypass
surgery, so...
We should talk
about me and Nathan.
So there is a "You and
Nathan"? You're admitting that?
- Well, I would like to explain.
- No.
- I don't need details.
- I would like to explain.
Mer, I have
surgery. I got to go.
You should feel a cold
sensation right now.
It might burn a little,
but only for a moment.
This is gonna numb
you for the surgery.
You'll be awake during
surgery with the drape up.
Once I begin, you'll feel
a little bit of pressure,
and it might be a
little uncomfortable.
But it won't hurt. I promise.
Does the cancer make
it harder to deliver?
Your body is already
working overtime as it is,
so the surgery is
an added stress,
but if there's any complications
then we will take care of it.
That's what we do.
I want to sign a DNR.
We didn't mean to spook you. The
surgery should go very smoothly.
I'm dying already. It's
just a matter of time.
But if something happens during
surgery and I end up stuck on a machine,
I don't want to leave
Jeremy with that.
I want to sign it
before surgery. Please.
And don't tell him.
He won't understand.
We can do that.
I bet Dennis is
already on the train,
headed back to Capitol
Hill, where he's gonna tell
all his hipster friends over
coffee what a bullet he dodged
by getting away from wormy Mary.
I'm sure he's not.
I was alone for six years
before Dennis and I met online,
and I had gotten
good at being alone.
I had gotten good at saying
"just one" at restaurants.
I was looking at adopting a cat.
Life was just fine.
But then Dennis messaged me,
and I was doubtful at first, but...
he turned out to be perfect.
I had forgotten what it was
like to come home to someone.
I had finally found it.
Mary, life can be
just fine on your own.
Oh, hang on...
Hang on a second. We
still don't know if Dennis left.
You're not alone, Mary.
You're about to de-worm me.
No one's ever touching me again.
Uh, I heard that Dr. Webber's
got a stomach full of worms today.
Excuse me?
Not Dr. Webber.
His patient. Sorry.
He likes worms.
He likes anything that's...
out of the norm, so the
worms will be good for him.
They might uplift his mood,
which has been a little down
lately. Wouldn't you agree?
Dr. Bailey, I have surgery.
If you need to say
something, say it quicker!
I know that Dr. Webber's spending
the night in the on-call room
- when you're here in town.
- That is his choice.
And I know that things
between you two have been
less than favorable
since Dr. Minnick arrived,
- which is a decision
that I made.
- A decision I led you to make.
Wha... Yeah.
Yes. Um, but...
Dr. Bailey, just because
you feel responsible,
doesn't mean you have to fix it.
Stay out of it!
Brody, why haven't you sent
me Mrs. Vonn's latest hematocrit?
Okay, what is so mesmerizing
that you can't do your job?
- Are those worms?
- I can't look away.
Oh...
Please tell me you're using
those pictures for a journal.
Oh, Sure, Kepner.
I'll make copies.
Oh, Dr. Webber? Big Mama.
Oh, Joanna, make
sure you get this one.
Someone have a ruler?
That's got to be at
least 10 inches long.
Uh-huh. That's bigger.
She's got a few ulcerations,
but I'm not sure it's anything
that needs additional repair.
Do you think they were
trying to find a way out?
Well, it's possible. Okay, let's
scoot that bucket over here. I got it.
Okay.
Okay, yeah.
Right there.
Okay, okay. No, no.
Okay, I agree with Dennis.
Worms are a deal-breaker.
- DeLuca?
- I don't know.
It might take me a minute before
I share a meal with her again,
- but she's nice.
- Yeah, she is nice.
And it's really sad. I mean,
you all saw how happy
- they were together.
- Pre-worm.
No more photos! They
really like each other.
They shouldn't be apart, you
know? Mary shouldn't have to lose out
on a magical relationship just
'cause everything's not perfect.
You know, people are flawed.
That's, you know, that's real.
Well, Dennis didn't realize
that something so ugly
would be inside
the woman he loves.
I mean, he has a
choice in the matter.
I'm just saying he shouldn't write her
off 'cause of this one thing, you know?
He should... He should
give her a chance.
Well, maybe he doesn't want to.
Maybe he's... seen enough.
3-0 chromic, please.
- Hey.
You okay?
Oh, I just had to tell a patient that
I like that her cancer's spreading,
but, I don't want
to talk about it.
How'd it go with Maggie?
Well, she shut me out.
Don't want to talk about it.
- Hi.
- Can I sit?
- Yes.
Did you join the Mile High Club?
Is he a good kisser?
- Maybe I should go.
- Why?
You probably already know.
- How many people did
you tell before me?
- Nobody knows.
So you kept it from everyone?
Were you scared they would tell me?
If you'd like to go somewhere
and talk about this, I'd be happy to.
You know, I would
love to, but I got to run.
Whoa.
No outlet protectors. We
haven't gotten those yet.
All over the house, electric
floor-level death traps.
- He won't be crawling
for months.
- Also don't have a stroller.
I was gonna pick
one up next weekend.
Order it now. It'll be
waiting when we get home.
The O.R.'s almost ready,
Veronica. We can take you up soon.
Okay.
When the baby comes,
he's your priority, remember?
You don't leave his
side, like you promised.
- I don't want to leave
your side. Jer, it's your job.
Where the baby goes, you go.
- Okay?
- I know.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. I thought
I had O.R. three booked
for my lap colectomy
this afternoon.
You did, but I have a valvuloplasty,
I wanted O.R. three, so I took it.
We do that now, right?
Hey!
I feel really bad.
I feel terrible, Maggie.
But now you're
just being a jerk.
- I'm the jerk?
- Yell at me, scream at me,
curse.
Whatever you need
to do, I can handle it.
What I need to do
is go back to work.
- Well, I want to explain this.
- Look.
I get it, okay? You...
There was a plane.
Emotions were heightened.
You almost died together. I get it.
No, it wasn't just the plane.
It happened before that.
When?
Before Amelia and
Owen's wedding.
But it started before I
even knew you liked him,
and as soon as you told me
you liked him, I called it off.
We talked about it!
- I...
- You let me go on and on!
I was going to tell you,
and then your mother died,
and then I just couldn't.
I didn't want to hurt you,
- and Nathan didn't want
to hurt you.
- No.
This isn't about
Nathan. It's you!
I trusted you to
be honest with me,
when even my mother lied to me,
and now she's dead.
I thought I could
count on you...
to tell me the truth.
But you've been
lying this whole time.
I was trying to
do the right thing.
Well, you didn't.
I know that.
Maggie, please, please, please.
Can we just not
leave it like this?
You were all I had left.
Heart rate's up to 130.
Veronica, how's your breathing?
It's fine, it's a little tough.
What's happening?
What's going on?
Hey, Jer, come on. Look at him.
He has the sweetest eyes.
Her sats are dropping.
She's persistently tachycardic.
Let's put her back
on high-flow oxygen.
It could be an embolus.
- Time to get him out of here.
- Yeah, in a minute.
If it's an embolus, we
don't have a minute.
She did this so she can meet the baby.
Just give them another damn minute.
Jer, can you take him?
He needs to go to the NICU now.
- I know. What about Veronica?
- She's in good hands.
She'll be just fine. I'll
take good care of her.
Jer, you... you stay with him.
You promised. I'm
counting on you.
- But I don't...
- Go on.
Stay with him.
I'll see you in a little bit.
Okay.
Are we pushing heparin or
going straight to thrombolytics?
Thrombolytics are
contraindicated.
We need to do an embolectomy,
and let's get an IVC filter.
Veronica, you've thrown a blood
clot, and it's traveled all the way
to your lungs.
It's very serious.
We need to remove it immediately
so we're gonna need to put you
under and open up your chest.
Is that...
- Will that work? The
procedure will only last
- about half an hour.
- Will it work?
There's no guarantee
you'd survive it.
And what if we
didn't do anything?
Veronica, we need
to do this procedure.
If we don't, you might not
make it off this table today.
Okay, pressure's dropping.
- Get a cart ready!
- No.
I signed that DNR for a reason.
You can rescind.
Let us help you.
I did what I wanted.
My baby's okay.
I'm so tired.
I know.
Hey, how did it go?
Well, we got all the
worms out of the patient.
I did not get very
much out of Webber.
Kepner! You've been
with the man for hours.
I know, I know! And
I tried many times,
but everything I threw
at him, he just shot down.
It's way worse than
we thought. I mean...
it's like he's dead inside.
How'd it go with Catherine?
She told you to mind
your own business?
She is a hard woman to talk to.
Hmm.
- So are you.
- I know. But...
it's because I'm usually right
and people are wrong, and
- it's hard for them.
- Yeah.
Catherine usually
thinks she's right, too.
Are you saying that I
just think that I'm right?
No, I'm saying...
I'm saying you and Catherine
Avery are very similar women.
Very.
I mean, very.
I love Jeremy.
I never told him.
'Cause we were friends.
And I thought, "What
if it didn't work out"?
So ridiculous now.
Was I waiting for
something better?
He's loved me my whole
life, through everything.
Through cancer.
I know him.
He's gonna want
to keep loving me...
after I'm gone.
That's the kind of guy he is.
Will you... Will you tell him...
not to look back?
He's a dad now.
And he has to be...
He has to be fearless.
He has to leap.
What do you want? What
do you need right now?
I'm so cold.
- I'll get a warming blanket.
- No! No.
Can you... Will
you just hold me?
We did good.
The baby's good.
Baby's good.
How is she?
Say something.
Did you get the clot?
Now, you see these clusters?
Those were secondary
boluses starting to form.
We removed hundreds of them.
- They were breeding like crazy.
- Like babies.
I wanted babies with Dennis,
but now I'm a worm farm.
Um...
We'll monitor you,
but I think that you'll be
- up and at 'em again
in a few days.
- Thank you.
Mary?
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
I was being weird.
- I was repulsive.
- No.
Love-bug.
You were sick. That's all.
I am concerned about
you and Dr. Webber,
so I need to say
what I need to say.
I don't want you to fail.
I want you to succeed, and
right now you're not doing that.
Noted.
You can go now.
I got divorced, raised
a boy on my own.
I found a new man,
became that new man's boss.
Sound familiar?
See, I know it can
feel impossible at times,
but I figured it out.
I know what I'm doing, which
is how I know that you do not.
You do not know
how to be married.
Not to a real man, to
someone who's your equal,
your champion, who loves
you and respects you, and...
is mad as hell at you, because
I do. I've done this. I do this.
And I plan to grow old with my
man and to have old-people sex.
Well, don't you want to have
old-people sex, Catherine?
Because that's what you'll get if you
set your ego aside and listen to me
instead of dismissing me the way you
keep dismissing your own damn husband!
Ma'am.
Doctor.
Avery.
Good night.
I was wrong.
I had a patient
full of worms today.
Did you take any pictures?
What? Did I...
You know who you're talking to?
Come here.
I didn't mean to hurt you.
That's the last thing
I would ever want.
Because I care about
you more than anything.
Okay.
So, no matter how mad you are...
how much you
want to shut me out,
know this.
What are you doing?
What does it look
like I'm doing?
Didn't Amelia tell you?
She's waiting in the car.
The sitter's upstairs.
We're going out.
Well, if you want to go out so bad,
why don't you call Riggs? I'm busy.
I want to go out with you.
Meredith.
- Stop.
- No, I won't.
I am very sorry that I
screwed up and I hurt you.
But you're my sister.
And I'm sure as hell
not losing you over a guy.
Please come out with me.
You are my sister,
whether you like it or not.
- I'm still mad at you.
- That's okay.
I may only talk to Amelia.
Well, she's been sitting
in the car waiting for us
for like 10 minutes, so she
may not talk to either one of us.
And I'm not going anywhere.
- Oh, my goodness.
- We named that one Geraldine.
Look at you. So silly.
You are just too much.
Edwards was right
in her element there.
And you right along with her.
- Yeah.
- That thing is awful.
- I'm telling you,
it was like...
- I can't believe.
Discovery Channel
here or something.