Previously on ER:
- Michael's coming home today.
- Well, hello, soldier.
Michael's unit had
a heavy patient flow.
He'll be unable to make
it home as anticipated.
- Hi, I'm Tony Gates.
- Dr. Rasgotra.
- You don't like my style? What is that?
- We were here a long time before you.
We work together. You're new.
- I'm her father, I have a right to know.
- Dad, please.
Stop it!
You ever come near my
daughter again, I'll kill you.
Wasn't as cold this morning.
Thought people from
the Bronx were tough.
- We are.
- Yeah, right. Talk to me in February.
What's up?
- What we got?
- Martin Trudeau, 60, short of breath.
Uh-oh. Looks like trouble.
You're telling me.
- How's the rookie doing?
- She could smile more.
She's fine.
All I wanted was
a little oxygen.
And these clowns keep
poking me for 10 minutes.
Status post-cardiac
transplant, 2001.
Think those bastards at the Mayo
Clinics give refunds on bad hearts?
- Marty's on a lot of meds.
- Neoral, mycophenolate, Lipitor...
benazepril, nicardipine, Isordil,
furosemide, potassium, aspirin.
Now we got freaking
Rain Man here.
- I'm taking her to Vegas.
- Lungs are wet.
Forty of Lasix, 25 of sublingual
captopril. I'll be right in.
- So how's it going?
- They don't have a coat that fits.
They woke me and my
neighbors at 5 a.m. with that siren.
Gates is like a dog in heat. Other
than that... There is no other than that.
- Look on the bright side.
- What bright side?
Pratt, your diarrhea guy's
butt is exploding again.
- You could be stuck here.
- Yo, Mayday.
- Dr. Rasgotra will be fine.
- I'm gonna go restock, Mayday.
- Thanks.
- Nice jacket, roomie.
Or can I still call you that?
As long as you
don't call me Mayday.
How's the ride-along?
- That good, huh?
- You need a fresh Steri-Strip.
Ow.
- Oh. Sorry.
- Yep, still a little tender.
All things considered,
you got off easy.
My ass-kicking was a breeze.
All I had to do was lay there.
Beats jail time. Here, sit.
- Heard from Gallant?
- Not yet. He got stuck.
- He's still coming home, right?
- Not at the moment.
Oh, that's cool.
I mean, too bad.
- But, uh, maybe I can come home now?
- No.
- No?
- It's nice without you.
That smell hasn't been
there since you've been gone.
- But it's my place.
- Got another run, Mayday.
You can come back
on these conditions:
No dishes in the sink, no
using the couch as your hamper.
Didn't I let you move in?
Okay, fine. Done deal.
I'm on graveyard, I'll be
back in the morning. Oh, crap.
Admit, 2 o'clock.
- I thought you got rid of her.
- Help, please.
- Ray.
- Neela.
- Zoe.
- Oh, hey, Neela.
- Why are you here?
- Where is Ray?
- He's off today.
- That's not true.
He pulls doubles Thursdays so he can do
Friday gigs. I totally know his schedule.
He had a doctor's
appointment. Eye specialist.
He hasn't returned my
calls. I've been worried.
Come on, we got a man down.
- I'll tell him you were here.
- Give him this. It's all our songs.
It's a make-up mix.
- Residency office is looking for Abby.
- She's on nights.
Lucky her.
She's on nights.
I think I know why you got
fluid in your lungs, Mr. Trudeau.
I take long showers.
Is there anything
you wanna tell me?
- Like what?
- Listen, your cyclosporine level was zero.
Yeah? So?
So you stopped taking
your meds. Am I right?
- Are you taking your pills?
- Nope.
So you're wasting a good
heart, not to mention my time.
You know how much the
medicine costs me a month, huh?
I take piles of that medicine
at almost 4 large a month.
What about Medicare?
Oh, please. You gotta
declare poverty for that.
You have to give up your house
and your savings and your car. Huh?
Who's gonna take
care of my wife?
How are you supposed
to if you're dead?
Oh, please. She drives me
back and forth to the hospital.
I puke, she cleans it up.
And I can't make it
up the stairs alone.
I pass out.
Mr. Trudeau, are you refusing
to take your medication?
Because if you are, you're
gonna go into heart failure...
- and you're gonna die.
- Aw...
All right, then, put
him in Curtain 3.
We're done.
Sam, how many
nurses are you short?
Two, and the registry's empty.
You'll manage. Here's my
number. My flight leaves at 4:20.
- I'll keep my cell phone on.
- What about Malik?
- Funeral in Detroit.
- Arson capital of the world.
- Did you try Jarvik?
- I called everybody.
Sam, do you want me to stay?
- Oh, go ahead. We got it, go.
- Okay, I got a flight to catch.
- Yo, Rocky.
- Hey, Inez.
- You wanna pick up a drunk samurai?
- Samurai?
GYN has a bed, but can't
take the PID for two hours.
- I'll call them.
- Sam, why is my UTI still here?
We're out of ICONs.
- Could you, please?
- I got it.
- Like, before Christmas?
- I said, I got it.
- Four more.
- What did she say?
Same thing she
said the last six times.
Kobayashi. That's
your real name?
You, with hair like ray
of sun, you are beautiful.
Ha-ha. Hee, hee.
Whoa.
What are you doing?
Looking for my underwear.
Are you on tonight?
No.
Why are you leaving?
I just thought I should.
- You should stay.
- I probably shouldn't.
I have a lot of stuff
I need to do and...
Oh. Your bra.
Thank you.
Panties.
Still like ketchup on your eggs?
Okay. I'll make
us some breakfast.
I think we probably
slept through breakfast.
And lunch.
I can't believe he's
doing this to himself.
Can you stop it?
Really, what's the point if he's
not gonna take the medication?
He's not such a pain
in the ass, you know.
He's just angry because
he's been so sick.
I wish you could help him.
I'm not sure I can.
He's my life.
I'm not ready to let him go.
Take a cab.
And next time, fake a seizure.
So how about some sushi? You
like sushi? I know a great sushi place.
- Does he ever stop?
- Get a ring. He's scared of husbands.
- I told you, I have a boyfriend.
- Oh. So, what is he, a lawyer?
- A commodities trader? A dentist?
- He's a doctor.
- County?
- In the Army.
- Stateside, I hope.
- Iraq.
- CASH unit?
- 10th Combat Support.
You know, I was a
medic in Desert Storm.
- 101st Airborne.
- Airborne?
- Did you fly planes?
- Nope, just jumped out of them.
- When's he coming home?
- Soon, I hope.
To prove I'm a good guy,
know what I'm gonna do?
I'll let you sit in front,
play with the siren.
- I'm gonna buy you coffee.
- With an empty wallet?
Paramedics and
cops drink for free.
Technically, you're
not buying anything.
Technically, it's the
thought that counts.
Come on in.
Sorry. Sorry, I
won't do it again.
My foot slipped, I
promise. Scout's honor.
What took you so long?
Buckle up.
What the hell's that?
Monoclonal antibodies
to stop the rejection.
Did I not make myself
clear? I don't want it.
Well, you're getting it anyway.
And you're gonna take these too.
I spoke to your doctors at the Mayo.
They agreed to take you. By helicopter.
- I'm not going.
- This is Neoral.
If you take this, you'll have a detectable
blood level by the time you get there.
You are so wasting
your time, doc.
Yeah, okay, good. So look,
this is how it's gonna go.
You gonna take these
pills, get on that chopper.
You're gonna stay on your meds as
long as that donated heart keeps beating.
Who the hell do
you think you are?
You see that woman
over there? She loves you.
And I have no idea why, because,
personally, I find you extremely annoying.
But if you think you're helping
her by killing yourself, you're wrong.
You know, you're
a miserable guy.
But she seems like a great lady
and she wants to keep you around.
So open wide, Marty.
- Be careful, it's hot.
- Thanks.
The passenger jet crashed
in the 5700 block of...
- Child rooms clear?
- And sutures and Curtain 2.
- CCU can take Jenkins.
- I'll get him up next.
- If they walk, they go to the lobby.
- I'm not moving.
Been waiting six hours
with a dislocated finger.
- Lot of critical patients...
- My finger's critical.
- Excuse me?
Let me see that.
- Not anymore.
- Guys, shut up, please.
Passenger jet at low
altitude moments after takeoff.
- Terrorists?
- What airline was Eve on?
When the pilot lost
control, eventually colliding...
So much for
conspiracy theory, huh?
Okay, that's it, folks.
Here we go. We're
about to get clobbered.
Exam 3, I want
six monitored beds.
Damn it. Ray, I got two
words for you: "hard restraints."
We can't do that
anymore. Hey, settle down.
The warrior path is never easy.
Start with Haldol.
Battalion chief needs another
doctor. Possible field amputation.
Whoa, whoa. Yeah, okay.
- Okay, I could go.
- Nope. Not a good idea.
- I could use the experience.
Not a drill. I'm going
out with Pickman.
Congratulations, have
her home by 10. Set this up.
- City fire needs a physician.
- With experience.
Somebody with experience
would be better here.
- It's a tough call.
- I've done my ride-alongs.
They'll need crikes,
central access, chest tubes.
- I'm good at that.
- If he's supervised.
- We need to roll. You got anybody?
- I'm going, come on.
Okay, okay, Pratt, it's you. But
get your ass back here in an hour.
Drug box. Airway kit.
Triage tags.
Green is nothing, yellow is
urgent, red is critical, black is dead.
Oh, man.
Chief Bukata.
- Triage on the north side.
- All right, stick with me.
One patient at a time.
Sir, sir.
Sir, can you hear me?
- He's not breathing, there's no pulse.
- Black tag and move on.
Watch your step.
Ma'am.
Ma'am, can you open your eyes?
Flail chest, respiratory arrest.
Trauma 1 then ICU. Quickly, quickly.
I want you clearing exam rooms.
- Shouldn't the nurses be...?
- No, you decide who stays and who goes.
- Thanks for coming.
- Where do you need us?
- Hypotensive pelvis.
- Two minutes.
Get triage in the waiting room.
- The waiting room?
- It's warm, the light is good.
- You can do a better assessment.
- You're not serious.
- That's how we do it.
- This is like Night of the Living Dead.
Let the walking woundeds through the
door, it's over. Got me? Triage stays here.
- Abby, this is your pelvis. Come on.
- The plane was going to Cleveland.
- I don't care. INEZ: Eve
was going to Saint Louis.
- I'll deal with it.
- So she's okay?
- Who's in 2? SAM:
Altered stroke patient.
Let's park him in the hallway.
Please, yes, I need
you right away. Great.
Okay.
Sir, we're gonna have to move
you. We have to move you folks...
I am so sorry about my dad.
- You're not supposed to be here, Zoe.
- You're so cool for not pressing charges.
- Now is not a good time.
- Okay, but you get off at 8, right?
Ha. When I said we can't
see each other anymore...
Just because my Dad's a jerk
doesn't mean we can't keep going.
I got my ass kicked once.
I don't wanna go to jail.
I know, but we could keep it a
secret. Like Romeo and Juliet.
No, you need to leave right now.
- You can't just walk away.
- Don't you have some homework to do?
- I am not a child.
- Yes, you are.
- I'm your girlfriend.
- No, you're not.
- Yes, I am.
- Forty-five-year-old, unstable pelvis.
Ninety palp after a liter. Can
you check the dorsalis pedis?
- But I love you, Ray.
- Plugged earwax. I had to clean her out.
- Whatever.
- Yeah. Oh!
What are the foot pulses? Ray?
- Keep pressure while I wrap.
- Saline's wide open.
- Neela.
- What are you doing here?
- Heard you needed help.
- Fire's knocked down at the fuselage.
- Let's go, Pratt.
- All right.
Woody Ebbots, 85, auto
vs. pedestrian, blunt chest.
She's not critical. Lead
her to the yellow tarp.
- How's your breathing?
- It's been better.
Something fell and hit the car
and the car came right at me.
Okay, deep breath.
- The driver okay?
- We'll have to check on that.
- 95/60. Tachy, 120. NEELA:
Five liters by nasal prong.
- Got it.
- You seen a dog around here?
I'm gonna give you
some oxygen, Woody.
- I was walking my dog.
- A big stick in your arm.
- Look over here. Look over here.
- Ow!
- Look over here.
- A cocker spaniel. You seen her?
Hold still.
Maybe she didn't get hit. You
would have seen her if she got hit.
- Hold on.
- Hey, Riley.
We'll find the dog.
Take a deep breath.
Hey, Riley!
- Oh, man.
- Anything for us?
Not in there. This way, doc.
Guy in back got lucky.
Coming through.
- Up here.
- Talk to me.
Baxter Yi, facial trauma and
projectile to the right chest.
Can someone call my fiancée?
Airway's good. Strong
pulse, unbelievable.
- Lila Frankfurt is her name.
- Okay.
- Line's in. Need to get him down.
- We need some foam on this.
She's waiting for me. Oh.
Dr. Pratt.
- Saw and a backboard, let's go.
- Baxter, you're one lucky guy.
Well, can you call her
cell? I have the number.
What's the status
on his wound degree?
Crushing substernal chest pain,
10 out of 10. Adrian, Dr. Pratt.
- What about his arm?
- Can't feel it.
- 170/95.
- Yeah, blood pressure's high.
- So's my cholesterol.
- You taking Viagra?
I look like I need Viagra?
All right, lift up your
tongue for a minute.
- Hey, we need help with an extrication.
- Stand by.
Just calm down, sir. Don't worry,
we're gonna get you out of here.
- 105/75.
- That's better.
- What?
- It means "thank you" in Hindi.
Had to learn a little
in '44. Army Air Force.
I flew supplies over
the Hump to China. Oh!
- C-46s?
- I've never been to India.
She was asleep and
the window blew out.
- What's her name?
- Olive.
The glass cut her. And my
son's on the second floor.
His legs are cut, he can't walk,
and they won't let me back in.
- My building's not on fire.
- It's a precaution.
- I can get in and out real quick.
- No, stay here. I'll go.
- Go, go.
- Stay here.
- Baxter Yi, passenger on the jet.
- He's still got vitals?
- Blunt face, penetrating chest.
- We have a trauma room open.
- Systolic's down to 80.
- All yours, Kovac.
- I'm losing the pulse.
- Prep for a thoracotomy.
No, no, hold on, hold up.
Pressure's back.
Dressing converted it
to a tension pneumo.
- Good call. Go to Trauma 1.
- No, I can't waste a trauma room.
- He fell, like, 2000 feet.
- He's just fine with a chest tube.
- Come on, go. Exam 3, go.
- Hey. Hey, where the hell's Pratt?
Said he'll be back
with the next run.
- Pratt's out there?
- They needed a doc.
- You gave away our senior Resident?
- Not now. I gotta triage.
We need our doctors here,
not off playing in the field.
Okay, bag him.
That central line okay?
- Yeah.
- Good.
- Hey, how's the chest pain?
- Down to two out of 10.
Okay, four of MS. Bukata,
we need some help, man.
As soon as we get
these two out of here.
- How's my arm?
- It's hard to say.
I guess I'm lucky. Could
be my head under there.
You still live on Dearborn?
Huh? Yeah, I came over
here to visit my girlfriend.
I made her bougatsa.
Custard in phyllo dough.
Women love a man who can cook.
- PVC's on the monitor.
- I want you to lidocaine.
So, what, you go to
chef's school or something?
When I was a kid, my mom
wouldn't let us watch TV.
That's rough.
We could either
cook or read a book.
And I never did like...
V-tach.
Charge to 200.
Charged.
Adrian. Okay, clear.
Sinus. Good pulse.
What the hell was that?
- Hey, we can't wait anymore.
- Just one minute. Come here.
- Pressure's staying up?
- Compare the radials.
My son's in there.
- My partner went to check on him.
- He should be out now.
- He'll find your son.
- Go ahead, help her.
Pulse discrepancy. You
may have injured your aorta.
- Stop, I need my stuff.
- You're not going in.
My checkbook, my jewelry.
What is this, a police state?
No, you can't do this.
- Get away from me.
- Settle down.
- No! Let me go!
- Come on, settle down now.
- Hey, come back.
- Go ahead, she needs you.
Ma'am. Ma'am, stop.
You can't go in there.
Hey, guys!
Keep moving, we
got people inside.
Dr. Rasgotra, do you read me?
Yeah.
Somebody, help us!
Can anybody hear me?
- Help!
- Hold on! Hurry!
She's impaled. I got a
mid-shaft femur fracture.
Get out of this
building now, Neela!
- Doc, talk to me.
- Hold on.
My son is in 207.
Neela, go! Get out!
- My son, help him.
- Leave the building now.
- Please help my son.
- Hold my hand.
Help!
Doc, acknowledge.
Paramedic Gates and a woman
are trapped inside the basement!
Doc, give me your location...
so my guys can get to you.
There's a boy trapped on
the second floor. I'm going.
No, find a door.
Get to a window.
Give me that.
Neela, it's Greg. Turn around.
- I'm almost there.
Get your ass out now.
Neela, get the hell out
of the building. Neela!
Hey, hey! BOY: I'm in here.
- Neela, it's Greg. Get the hell out.
- Hello!
- I'm over here. I'm over here.
Hey. Cover your mouth with this.
Dr. Rasgotra, come in.
Acknowledge, doc.
Dr. Rasgotra, do you
read me? Are you there?
- Neela, respond. Neela! BUKATA:
I said, grab this girl, damn it.
- Someone's in trouble?
- A friend from work.
The guys are all over the
building. They'll get her.
If this all works out, I'm
baking you two a cake.
I'm more of a low-carb guy.
All right, fellas, let's do this.
You can't just eat to
live, you gotta live...
Come on.
Aah!
No Radial pulse. No ulna.
Adrian, can you feel this?
Adrian. PICKMAN: V-tach again.
- Charge to 200.
- Charged.
Clear.
Only bodies up
here. No survivors.
- Charging.
- Amp of epi.
- Charged.
- Clear.
- Still tach.
- Damn it. Three-sixty, intubation kit.
Starting compressions.
Rescue 3 to Battalion 4.
Go ahead, Rescue 3.
Leaving the second floor, 10:45.
Got a female body, no vitals.
Keep looking.
Please...
Get up. Get up.
- Who's next for the O.R.?
- Avulsed ear in 2, tib-fib in 4, then him.
Haleh, thank you so
much for coming in.
Glad to help. Eve here?
No. I'm gonna tell
her it's the way it is.
- We're out of cefotetan and DT.
- I'm gonna call the pharmacy.
And I'll get to work.
- Is that blood?
- You cracked a bone in there.
Minimal chest tube output.
- Who called my fiancée?
- In a minute, you can call her yourself.
Supposed to meet
with the caterers and DJ.
Vaseline gauze.
Tomorrow, it's
flowers and the pastor.
She'll be worried.
- Haleh?
- Sam called.
Good thing too. Home two weeks,
my husband's driving me crazy.
- Glad you're back.
- Call for a portable chest.
Sats are dropping.
Baxter.
- Baxter. KOVAC:
He's not breathing.
He knocked out the alveolar
ridge, fractures Teeth 9, 10 and 11.
Must have aspirated the
fragment. Try to finger sweep.
- Another 50 of lidocaine.
- Got it.
They ID the body in there?
Woman in her 80s. Still looking.
- Where's my mom? Where is she?
- They find anybody else inside?
Whoa, whoa, whoa. He's
awake. Holding compressions.
Still V-tach.
No pulse. What the hell...?
Adrian. Adrian, can you hear me?
Your heart stopped beating.
We're doing CPR. Keep going.
The compressions are
getting oxygen to his brain.
We're gonna get you
to the hospital, all right?
- You had no business going in there.
- I'm sorry.
You put yourself in danger,
you put my men in danger.
- Can we talk about this later?
- We will.
IC says they're
moving toward the back.
Get a water...
Woody, you found your dog.
Probably blew out his aorta.
I was just talking to him.
Over here, doc.
Large-bore IV. O2, 15 liters.
Take Mom and the kids together.
Doctor...
thank you.
Neela, pressure's borderline.
- What's he got?
- Distal neurocirc is intact.
- You can stop being the med student.
- As soon as you stop being firefighter.
Tongue is too edematous.
- Okay, bag him a few times.
- I can prep his neck.
Take another look, I'll retract.
PVCs. I'll get the crash cart.
There it is.
Got it.
- See something new every day.
- All right, settle down, settle down.
Fifteen liters by mask.
- Nice work.
- You did great.
Probable MI with
refractory V-fib.
- Trauma 1.
And an ischemic right arm.
- Be right in.
- I'll be right in.
You know, she needs
to get to the suture room.
- She doesn't need the suture room.
- It's a complicated lac.
Nope, not that complicated.
What, you've never
seen a zipper before?
Any chest pain? - My belly.
Probably just broke a rib.
- It's his liver. Scoop and run.
- Soon as we get another rig.
- We don't have an ambulance?
- We just sent 30 patients in.
- Heart rate's up to 140.
- Because I'm in pain.
- Maybe.
- Elevate my legs. Shock position.
I need to stick your belly.
Peritoneal aspirations?
Maybe you should numb up my...
Ow!
It's positive.
- Splenic lac?
- More likely hepatic.
- I was hoping for spleen.
- Do we have lap pads?
- Just burn dressings.
- Ten of them. Push etomidate.
What are you doing?
Tony, I need to sedate you, open
up your belly and pack off your liver.
What? ZADRO: Can't be serious.
- Do I have your permission?
- Will you go out with me?
I need to do this.
If you didn't have a
boyfriend, yes or no?
Yes.
I'm all yours.
Okay, bag him through this.
From the subxiphoid
to the symphysis pubis.
Clear.
Still V-fib. When's the
last time you saw her?
I told you, we were a block
apart. Resuming compressions.
- Amiodarone's onboard?
- Five minutes ago.
Should've kept an eye on her.
- Pronestyl drip?
- Infusing.
- You could've done better?
- Wouldn't let her into a burning building.
Sure wouldn't have left her.
Guys.
You're doing okay, Adrian.
- Take a break.
- I got it.
Greg, go.
Adrian, we're doing
what we can, okay?
All you do is point, okay?
We're using all the medication
we can to fix your heart.
Sometimes it takes a while.
Anything else?
You want your family?
We called and
they're on their way.
Fifteen-foot fall. I
packed off the liver.
Whoa, whoa. In
the field? Damn, girl.
- He was about to arrest.
- Pressure's up at 100 systolic.
- Was he awake?
- I had etomidate.
It's always the quiet ones.
Always the quiet ones.
Look, I'll take him up to the O.R.
Let Dubenko finish what you started.
You got big huevos, big brass
ones. They look good on you.
- I had no idea what else to do.
- You okay? Need you on a pulse ox.
- No, I'm fine.
- Yeah, you sound terrific.
- No, I'm okay.
- Singed nasal hairs.
- Indicates substantial smoke inhalation.
- I just need to wash up a bit.
- I would hate for you to stop breathing.
- I'd hate that too.
- Neela, come on.
- Can I at least pee first?
I'll get you a bedpan.
Ninety-four in room
air. That's not great.
- There're some expiratory wheezes.
- Those will pass.
Or get worse. I'm
a bit worried here.
- Hello?
- I'm sorry.
It was just...
Today was so...
Terrifying and amazing.
There was no labs, no x-rays,
no rapid infusers or cutdown trays.
Just me.
I mean, maybe it's the
adrenaline, but I feel high.
I need to go back out.
Sounds like I should
call for a psych consult.
- Still patients out there.
- Yes, and they're being handled.
Excuse me, Abby.
Dubenko called from the O.R.
Alice Watson died on the table.
Okay, thanks.
- Patient of yours?
- Impaled abdomen.
- From the crash?
- Mm-hm.
- Where are her kids?
- Exam 2.
You need to be monitored.
Hey, Abby?
How's he doing?
Lung is up after two chest
tubes. We're going up to ICU.
- So I stopped breathing?
- It was more like holding your breath.
- But I could've died.
- Theoretically, yeah.
Think you were in more
danger on the plane.
- Hm. I cheated death twice today.
- You're very lucky.
I guess I should feel bad,
or guilty, or something.
But truth is...
I feel happy.
I have a second chance.
I'm calling off the wedding.
- Oh. You might wanna sleep on that.
- No, I have been sleeping my whole life.
I never do what I wanna do.
I never say how I really feel.
- I'm not in love with her.
- Maybe you two should talk about that.
Screw that.
Screw it.
No more messing with "could
have, should have, would have."
Carpe diem.
All right. Well,
good luck with that.
Besides, I'm pretty
sure, um, I'm gay.
Getting tired? RAY: No.
Dr. Pratt, this is Adrian's
girlfriend, his brother and his uncle.
- I explained everything.
- I'm sorry.
We gave him every kind of medication
possible. Nothing's working right now.
He's awake. You can
talk to him if you want.
Hey, you hang on.
Everyone's coming.
Pratt, check it out.
I guess she's okay, then.
Yeah.
- It's alive.
- They shut down the Dan Ryan.
It took me two hours to get
here. Where do you need me?
- How about Peoria?
- How'd we do?
- We're still here.
- No ICU boarders?
- None.
- And we're reopen for trauma?
Yup. Hey, call housekeeping for
T1. Pharmacy's here to restock.
Excuse me. Could someone
please remove these?
Go for it.
- Sir, why are you restrained?
- I have no idea.
Hey, Sam.
- More Sianis family members.
- I'll be right there.
- Sam, what is Haleh doing here?
- Exam 2's going up to 4-West.
- I gotta help Pratt with a trauma.
- Did you bring her back?
Haleh's one of the best nurses in town
and we're getting our asses handed to us.
I did whatever I
thought I could.
Good move.
- You need a chest x-ray.
- I told you, I'm fine.
Tell the kids I'll check
on them in the morning.
- Come on.
- Please, I've been on for 16 hours.
- Yeah, well, what if your lungs get worse?
- I'll call 911.
Stay at the hospital. You
can sleep in the call room.
- I need to be at home tonight.
- That might not be safe.
If I start to die, you'll
be the first one I'll call.
- Fine. I'll come and stay at your place.
- It's not necessary.
Oh. Okay, is there anything,
anything I can say to get you to stay?
No.
- I slept with Luka.
- Yeah, nice try.
I can bag.
So how is this
gonna go if you stop?
There'll be lack of
oxygen to the brain.
He'll pass out,
like going to sleep.
Is he gonna be in pain?
He's had a sedative.
He's comfortable.
And you've done everything?
Yes, we have.
What, you want us to stop?
Are you ready?
No.
Nine forty-two p.m.
I'm sorry.
No.
- He was a lucky guy.
- He's dead.
A lot of people loved him. They
all got a chance to say goodbye.
All right, you gotta
stop calling me.
No, because we're
done. We've been done.
No. No. No. WOMAN Why?
Because you're
not listening to me.
Let me say it to you really
nice and slow for the last time.
I don't love you. Go
back to your husband.
I'm not going back to him...
Hey, Dr. Kovac. You know, you
and I should have a little sit-down.
Yeah, probably.
No, I think, like, definitely. We're
both captains on this team here.
If we break down, the
whole machine breaks down.
We can't have that,
especially on days like today.
I agree.
Oh, because, see, I thought I
was the incident commander.
- I thought I was clear...
- Know what? Let's talk tomorrow.
Yeah, tomorrow's great.
I'll be here all day, 8 to 8.
Hey.
Hi.
- Rough night.
- Yeah, I'm glad it's over.
Yeah, me too.
Did Baxter get upstairs okay?
Oh, he's fine. Not so sure
about his fiancée, though.
Hmm.
- Listen, I was thinking that...
- Sorry.
- No, you go ahead. Go ahead.
- No.
Okay. No, I was
just thinking about...
Uh, I was thinking about
what happened last night.
It was nice.
"Nice"?
Yeah.
- Wasn't it?
- No...
Ha. Yeah, of course.
- But...?
- What?
I don't know.
I don't know. What do we do now?
Not sure.
For a long time, even when
we weren't connecting a lot...
you've been the one
person I can count on.
I feel like that too.
That means a lot to
me, that friendship.
Me too.
So?
Maybe we should just
leave it at that, then.
I don't know.
I don't wanna lose that. But if that's
what you... That's what's the best.
So, what we're just saying is
that we'll just stay friends, then.
Need a lift?
No, I have some stuff
I need to finish inside.
Okay.
- Good night.
- See you.