[Thundering]
[Sighs]
It's raining.
It's raining !
[ ? Pepe Deluxe : Mischief of Cloud 6]
[Doorknob rattling]
It's raining !
[Sighs]
- [woman] One saved message.
- [machine beeps]
[Allan] Hi, babe. It's me.
I'm going to be late.
Why don't you pick up Chinese
and we'll eat in bed, OK ? Love you.
Hi, babe. It's me.
I'm going to be late.
Why don't you pick up some Chinese
and we'll eat in bed, OK ? Love you.
[Cooper] Listening
to Allan's message again ?
I have other messages.
From patients.
Those patients ask to pick up
Chinese and say they love you ?
I'm sorry I told you about it.
I thought you'd understand.
Guys don't keep messages from an ex.
Woman thing.
What do you know about women
that you didn't get off the Internet ?
Just erase the message. Be a man.
- Um, mom ?
- I can drive you to school today.
You know what ?
I can drive her to school.
- Daddy.
- Back up, woman.
- Good girl.
- It is raining.
- You're wet.
- Because it is raining !
It rains in Seattle,
which is where I left my umbrella.
It does not rain in Los Angeles !
It rains in LA. It's raining right now.
Really ? Right now ?
Maya's staying at Sam's.
She asked to stay at Sam's.
- She's growing up.
- I hate her.
- Are we gonna do the meeting ?
- Sam's gonna be late.
- And where's Pete ?
- [Violet] He is running an errand.
- Is that a chocolate cake ?
- I made it, but you can have some.
Addison, you want some chocolate cake ?
Can I talk to you ?
[Naomi] Thanks.
[Thundering]
Violet says I should come here
and talk to you.
I don't believe in it.
But Violet says...
She thinks I'm not going to heal.
Which is so...
Until I say this thing to you,
I'm not going to move on.
That's what she says. I don't know.
But I'm going to say it.
Just in case she's right.
You were a lousy wife and I hated you.
OK.
There, I said it.
I think Maya likes Sam
better than me. I think he wins.
Where are the beautiful people
running in slow motion on the beach ?
Non sequitur, but OK.
I'll go there. What ?
This is LA. LA is supposed to be full
of swimming pools and movie stars.
LA is the place that you lured me to
with your champagne wishes
and caviar dreams.
OK, first of all, you need
to start watching more current TV.
Second of all, it's just
a little rain. It'll pass.
It's not about the rain.
I mean, it is about the rain,
but I would be fine with the rain
if everything else was just
a little more...
What ?
I had this whole dream
about moving here.
That it would be...
...better and special.
That I would be...
I don't fit here.
I'm a surgeon, I think like a scientist.
There's no science to this.
Look, dig in, all right ? Make friends.
- Learn to play well with others.
- It's raining.
Not to get all Pete Zen on you,
but it's raining everywhere.
Come on, you fit.
You belong. Just commit to belonging.
Doug.
We've been talking about this for years.
We've come a long way.
You have come a long way.
You asked me to help you decide
what you want. And you have.
You are so close.
I just don't know if I can leave her.
You have everything you need.
You have all the tools.
- Remember ? You're like a ?
- A running back.
A running back.
Sprinting past the obstacles,
running for the goal posts.
You're almost there.
And I'm right here rooting for you.
- I am your own cheering section.
- It's just... I don't...
Doug, Doug, Doug.
- I should leave her. I should.
- Doug, Doug, Doug.
I should stand up to her !
I should fight for my right to be happy !
Bring the ball home, Doug.
I am telling my wife I want a divorce !
- Touchdown !
- [Both laugh]
- OK, boundaries, Doug. Boundaries.
- Sorry. I'm sorry. Gosh.
Hey.
Hey, Cathleen !
Geoffrey ! How was the wedding ?
Magical. Beautiful. Romantic.
Everyone should get married.
We did a three week
honeymoon in Africa.
We climbed Mount Kilimanjaro.
Scaled Victoria Falls.
- We went on safari.
- Sounds busy.
It was busy.
And now we're back here.
We... I made an appointment
with the new oblgyn.
- Honeymoon baby ?
- Just let us see the doctor !
- Sorry. We're just eager to...
- Dr. Montgomery. Right.
I'll take you right back.
I never thought she'd say yes,
but here she is.
- Here we are.
- That's wonderful.
It is. It's so...
...friggin' wonderful.
- Honey, it's OK. It's gonna be OK.
Are you all right, Cathleen ?
It's just... on our wedding night, we...
- I couldn't even...
- What ?
We've been married for three weeks and
I haven't been able to do it even once.
- Oh, sex. You couldn't...
- She's worried there's something wrong.
There is something wrong with me.
My hoo-ha is broken.
- So how do you feel ?
- Like it was a waste of time.
How is talking to a rock
over my dead wife's body help ?
You're in a rut. You're stuck.
You needed to jump-start your emotions.
Face them.
I hate to disparage
your profession, but...
I am good. I am brilliant.
I had a patient trapped
for 19 years in a marriage.
But he's ready to ask for a divorce.
I got him out of his rut.
He's ready to move on.
- You like yourself an awful lot today.
- I kick ass in my job. I rule.
[Elevator dings]
Doug ?
Are you who told my husband to leave me ?
- Is this her ? Is this her ?
- Honey.
Did you tell my husband to divorce me ?
You do. You do rule.
I don't mean to be a bother.
I had to bring Erin back. She's so blue.
- It's got to be hard.
- It's terrible.
It's normal for kids
to feel a little down when they're sick.
- It's really nothing to worry about.
- What ? No. She's blue.
Understood.
- Light blue.
- OK.
What ?
- Cornflower...
- Blue. Right.
Yeah. That's a pretty nasty bleed.
- Doug, what happened ?
- I'll tell you what happened.
Mr. Midlife Crisis came home, dropped
his briefcase in the middle of the floor
and demanded a divorce.
You're not leaving me.
No, sir. You made a vow.
I need you to keep your head tilted,
please, Mrs. Adams.
She got upset about... Then her nose
started bleeding and it wouldn't stop.
You sure she didn't run
into anything... by mistake ?
His mistake was telling me
I've been making his life hell.
I did not say that.
Not exactly.
[Sam] Has your nose ever
spontaneously bled before ?
- What are you thinking ?
- Probably mucosal irritation.
It's not like life with Doug
has been a walk in the park.
- [Sam] Keep your head tilted back.
- I'm doing the best I can !
I think the best thing to do right now
is for everyone to stay calm.
Was she exposed to any water
from a well or a spring ?
No.
- How about antibiotics ?
- Nothing like that.
Quiet for Mommy.
The doctor's thinking.
Dental fillings ?
Yes ! She went to the dentist.
Her first cavity.
Dental anesthesia can react
with the hemoglobin in the blood.
I've never seen it, but it happens.
But she's going to be OK ?
I'll give her a IV treatment
of methylene blue.
She'll be nice and pink in no time.
- That should do the trick.
- [Sighs]
Um...
- I got to take a picture.
- You totally do.
Cathleen, I'm gonna ask
some questions about your sex life.
And the more you can tell me about
previous partners, experiences...
[chuckles] Oh, my God.
I don't have any previous experiences.
- I mean, men. Before Geoffrey.
- I'm a virgin, Dr. Montgomery.
Oh.
I know. No one waits this long.
It's weird.
Well, it's not weird.
It's just surprising.
I didn't want to give it up
in high school to some geek
in the back of his dad's car, you know ?
In college, I kept thinking,
"He's coming. The one."
And I wanted to wait for him.
And then I thought, I've waited
this long, I should hold out.
I want it to mean something.
I wanted the fairy tale.
I want it to be special and perfect.
I wanted...
The magic.
Exactly. Some magic.
Let's take a look, OK ?
Alrighty.
This is going to be a little cold.
Ow !
OK. I know it's a little uncomfortable.
Just try to relax, OK ?
[Laughs] I am relaxed.
Ow !
[Sighs] You've had exams before this ?
Oh, God. It's really broken.
It's broken, isn't it ?
It's not the kind of thing that breaks.
OK. I'm going to go really slow.
OK ?
Knocking at the door,
stopping in for a little visit.
I'm knocking.
- Knocking a little harder.
- Ow ! Ow, ow, ow !
- [Sighs]
- And I'm done knocking.
- I'm going to die a virgin.
- We're going to figure this out.
Cathleen, we are going to get you
your wedding night. OK ?
Let's do an ultrasound.
[ ? Chrisette Michele : Good Girl]
She's 35 and she's never ?
Nope. And the gates are closed.
Locked. Welded shut.
Holding on to your virginity
for that long ? I think it's sad.
It's not sad. It's sweet.
Not being able to have sex with your
husband when you want to, that's sad.
But the waiting ?
I mean, what's wrong
with wanting a little magic ?
I lost my virginity when I was 17.
It was not magic.
A lot of friction.
I got rug burns in bad places.
I didn't get the magic until Sam.
I didn't even know
it could be magic until Sam.
I don't remember the last time
I had a little magic.
[Muffled] I hear that. Mm.
- [Laughs]
- What ?
How can you eat that much sugar
in the morning ?
Dell made it. I'm just being polite.
What's all this magic talk ?
First LA doesn't have it...
I don't know. The last time I was here
I just felt more...
...magic-y.
- Well, yeah. You kissed Pete.
- I did not kiss Pete.
Pete kissed me.
Which I did not ask for.
I don't even know if he's normal.
One minute he's hot,
the next minute he's arctic.
I don't need that kind of damage,
no matter how fancy his lips are.
- You're talking about sex, aren't you ?
- We were talking about a patient.
- Who can't have sex.
- Send them my way. I'll get them going.
This is a very serious issue.
This is a woman who has needs.
Who has wants.
Who needs and wants magic in her life.
This is not a dirty joke that you can
make your dirty jokes about. Dirty man.
You don't know me at all.
You think you do, but you don't.
So don't call me names.
You should give him a pass this week.
- Why ?
- You just... should.
See what I mean ?
A club. A closed club.
- [Addison sighs]
- [Naomi sighs]
Did you see how upset she was ?
I went back on my vow
and now she's bleeding.
- My words did that.
- No.
You don't control anything
except yourself.
You just told her the truth,
what you wanted.
Right.
You're right. So I tell her...
Our work together has not been about
getting you to leave your wife.
It's been about
getting you to say what you want.
- Remember the goal posts, Doug.
- The goal posts.
[Gasps] Right. Right.
[Laughing]
So she lost some iron ? Big deal.
I want a divorce.
Yes, you do.
- Karen, I...
- The bleeding got a lot worse.
I checked her CBC.
Her hematocrit is less than 30.
Less than 30 ? Are you sure ?
- There's something wrong with her ?
- Yes !
You picked a great time
to walk out, Doug. Just great.
It's called vaginismus.
It's a condition that causes a constant,
involuntary muscle spasm.
So you have a way to fix it, right ?
You can fix it ?
Not that I'm not fine
the way things are. I'm fine.
I love you and I don't need to have sex
to know that I love you.
- You can fix it ?
- Tell me you can fix it.
The ultrasound shows no physical
abnormalities, which is good.
Surprisingly, this sort of thing
is fairly common,
- especially on wedding nights.
- [Laughs]
See, honey ? It's very common,
especially on wedding nights.
So, what do we do ?
Well, I would like to prescribe
a muscle relaxant for you, Cathleen.
- Take it an hour before you...
- [Geoffrey] A pill ! Good.
- A pill.
- I can do a pill.
- And it'll work ?
- There have been case studies.
Just give it your best shot.
[Clears throat]
At home. Give it your best shot at home.
She needs to brush her teeth
before bed.
- OK.
- Don't let her stay up past 9 :00.
OK.
She needs to do her homework
and show it to you.
Do not let her get on the Internet.
You don't have that thing
that blocks predators.
Good night, Naomi.
Shuffling Maya back and forth
is not practical.
We're gonna be fine.
Maya's gonna be fine.
- You and your head take the night off.
- It's just that she's a girl.
Mothers know more
when it comes to girls !
I'm shutting down for the night.
Unless you need anything ?
No, uh... But, uh, here's... Uh...
Here's your cake carrier.
- You ate the whole thing ?
- We.
[Stammers] I didn't eat a whole cake.
I... I wouldn't. I... I couldn't.
- It was really good.
- Well, I'm glad you liked it.
OK. OK, thank you.
[Elevator dings]
- Still raining.
- Yeah. I see that.
I made you another one last night.
I... I really shouldn't.
[Whispering] This time
I baked chocolate chips inside.
I can't. [chuckles] Thank you.
You know what ? Maybe someone else
might want it. So, I'll just...
Right.
So the nasal packing
has held overnight.
Looks like the bleeding has stopped.
But I'd like to run a repeat CBC.
We also need to rule out
the serious possibilities.
Serious ? Like what ?
Let's not get ahead.
We'll have tests back today.
It's probably benign. In either case,
we are here to support you
through the illness and separation,
whatever you need.
I can't believe you're
honestly telling him to leave me. Now.
I'm not telling him to...
You're not still going ?
This is a crisis.
- Karen doesn't want to live alone.
- What do you want, Doug ?
Thank you.
But Doug's coming home with me.
He won't be needing therapy anymore.
Will you, Doug ?
No. No, I won't.
No sex ! Not even a little sex !
- Really ? [stammering] Really ?
- [Door closes]
- She took the pill, she...
- We tried. Oh, sister, how we tried !
- Honey. It's OK.
- It's not OK.
I need sex ! I need sex, Geoffrey.
I have waited and waited and
I want to do it ! I want to do it now !
You don't need to get upset.
- We have other things to connect us.
- You're a man, Geoffrey.
A big, strong, very hot man, which is...
I hit the jackpot with you.
And we want kids. We want a family.
Which is not gonna happen
because you're gonna leave me.
I'm not going to leave you.
I don't need sex.
We don't lie to one another.
We never have. Don't start now.
Please, doctor. Please.
[Laughs] Wish you could stop me from...
- Hello.
- Still can't get your virgin laid ?
OK.
Nothing I've tried has worked.
I mean, she just can't...
She just can't. And she deserves...
He's her guy. Her one.
- A marriage without sex.
- [Pete] It happens all the time.
Maybe it's psychological.
- Can you see her ?
- Um...
Actually, Pete should see her.
- What ?
There are some very good studies
about guided actualization,
- and that's his area.
- That's my area.
Yeah... Eh...
[Naomi] Want some cake ?
Mmm... Sweet mother of chocolate.
- I know.
- You're replacing sex with food.
- [Muffled] Do you want some ?
- [Sighs]
[Naomi] Come on. Come on.
- Oh, man.
- Mm-hmm.
- Mm.
- [Violet laughs]
You see ?
They're getting happy over cake.
I mean, if I could
get happy over cake...
- Well, I wouldn't be a man.
- Exactly.
- The secret to women.
- Like you know the secret to women.
You are a child.
You can barely grow facial hair.
- You don't know about women.
- Figure out what they want
- and give it to them.
- Yeah...
Well, that's...
- You baked that cake ?
- [Chuckles]
My grandmother baked that cake.
But Naomi doesn't need to know that.
Figure out what they want
and give it to them.
- It wasn't the fillings.
- Is Erin OK ? What happened ?
- I don't know. They just got worse.
- Get an exam room.
Do you want just one ?
Here's everything I could find,
and these came from the gyn
she had four years ago.
Thank you.
- Your patient who can't have sex ?
- My patient. Mind your own business.
She's seeing if she can find anything
that's causing the vaginismus.
- He asked.
- He snooped.
- You don't want to try my thing ?
- What ?
To creatively visualize
the parting of the Red Sea ?
A gentle opening of a flower ?
- No, this is medical.
- Maybe I can fix it.
Addison, the way we work
around here is with...
- You utilize each other, I got it.
- We take it slow.
Your solution is put her in surgery ?
This woman is not going to die.
If it was you going without,
you'd be begging to go under the knife.
My highly-skilled knife.
I knew it was too much to hope for
a "double board certified surgeon"
- not to be the most arrogant...
- Arrogant ?
Me ? I am not the one
with a God complex here.
You've got a God and a Buddha complex
all rolled up into one big, arrogant...
I got this. Back off.
Oh, come on.
Naomi is this close to a diabetic coma
thanks to your cake, so...
...you're way worse than I am.
- OK.
Dr. Turner ?
- Karen.
- Stay out of my marriage.
I think you took care of that.
Doug said he's quitting therapy.
I want to make sure it stays that way.
And if he shows up again...
[cough, clears throat]
I pay the bills.
You won't see a dime.
I don't care about "the dime,"
and even if I did,
why are you fighting for something
that makes you both so miserable ?
You have no idea how my marriage
makes me feel, no idea who I am.
You only have Doug's side of the story.
I'm the bitch and he's... He's...
- I am not on anybody's side.
- Just stay away !
- From...
- Did you ?
[Coughing spasmodically]
Karen ? Karen ?
We need some help !
- [Pete] I hear you got blue girls.
- I ran labs. Nothing's turned up.
It's driving me crazy. I give them IVs,
they turn pink and seem fine, and...
Their mom insisted on taking them home.
Want me to take a look ?
I ordered blood chromatographs.
When those come back.
- The mom checked the house for toxins ?
- I gave her the list.
She said she's gonna go over it top to
bottom. Which is gonna take a while...
That's time we don't have.
I'm going over there to give her a hand.
[Giggling, chattering]
[Sighs] Yeah, there's...
There's nothing here
from my list of contaminants, and...
And the girls were no place else
today ? No friends' houses, no...
They were here all day.
With me. This was my great plan.
I quit my job, fired the nanny.
Because I could do it better.
You've childproofed, you buy organic,
you have biodegradable dryer sheets.
OK, this is not negligence.
Yeah, but
if something happens to them...
Their dad travels.
I can't call him up and say...
We're watching.
The IV drug should hold them.
We need to find what's doing this so the
exposure doesn't become more dangerous.
We've gone through the house,
the yard, garage...
What do the girls say ?
Where were they ?
They don't talk. Not to me.
Not to anyone over eight.
[Girl] Mommy !
- Erin ?
- [Girl] What's the matter with Erin ?
She's having a seizure.
She'll be OK. She'll be OK.
[Monitor beeping]
I got your test results.
You've got something
called Wegener's disease.
It's a disease of the blood vessels
that affects the ears,
nose, throat and kidneys.
Does she...
Does she die from this ?
[Sam] It takes years
to progress to that stage.
With treatment we should be
able to keep it at bay for a long time.
You were lucky. Some bleed out
internally before the disease is caught.
- Lucky.
- I can't believe this.
You should change.
Sam, what would you have done
if it were Naomi ?
If she had gotten sick
right before the divorce ?
I would've stayed.
- Vulvar vestibulitis.
- Shistikinitis.
- I thought we were saying weird stuff.
- My virgin has vulvar vestibulitis.
I went through her medical history.
She has inflammation probably caused
by chronic yeast infection
which made her nerve endings
extraordinarily sensitive to pain
which, in turn,
made any attempt to have sex...
Ouch.
That kind of pain
caused her muscles to lock up.
I'm going to do injections of Lidocaine
and steroids in the sensitive areas.
- Then you're gonna send her to Pete.
- I can fix this myself.
You fix the vulvar vestibulitis,
Pete can fix the vaginismus.
The two of you will be able
to give this woman a normal sex life.
Why is everyone
always pushing Pete on me ?
Why are you pushing so hard against him ?
You want to belong here ?
You want to feel part of this place ?
You need to accept
that Pete is part of the solution.
Wisdom coming from a cake fiend.
You know, I used to be good at stuff.
I did. I was a good mother,
a good wife.
- I was good at my job.
- You are still...
No. No, I'm not.
And cake... Well,
I just take all these feelings,
the rage, the exhaustion,
the sexual frustration,
the desire to run Sam down with my car,
the fact that my child now thinks
that her father is the good parent...
I just take it all and I shove it down
as far as it will go
and then I just put
some food on top of it. A lot of food.
Maybe you should talk to Sam instead
of inhaling 4,000 calories a day.
Look, I do an hour on the treadmill
every single night. I do Pilates.
- I have earned this cake.
- Mmm. Dell cake.
You know what ?
You find your magic your way,
I'll find my magic mine.
[Clears throat]
Violet said that
I should cut Pete some slack.
- Yeah, you should.
- The "why" is what I'm missing.
It's the anniversary
of his wife's death.
- Is this going to hurt ?
- I'm sorry. It is.
OK. OK.
OK. Here we go.
[Whimpers]
- [Gasps] How many more ?
- Four more.
Four more.
I can do four more.
I'm OK. I can do this. [shudders]
- [Sighs]
- This is going to work ?
She's going through this.
It's going to work ?
It will solve the cause
of the vaginismus.
And then I'll get my wedding night ?
[Indistinct chattering]
Just do it. Hey !
I did a little research
and I think my patient
should try your thing.
You want my thing ?
My patient. My patient needs your thing.
What, no comments about my dirty talk ?
Why are you being so nice to me ?
I'm not. I...
Can you help or not ?
I have an opening at 3 :00.
[Sighs]
She's toxic. Treatment's going
to have to be a lot more aggressive.
- But she'll pull through ?
- [Sighs]
It would help if we knew what
we were dealing with, the contaminant.
Girls. This is very, very serious.
Did you eat anything, touch anything
that you're not supposed to ?
Mommy promises not to get mad.
You would really help Erin if you tell.
[Whispering indistinctly]
Sam.
You ordered these antibody studies
for Karen Adams ?
- Room 1001 ?
- I did.
As Chief of Staff,
I can't sign off on this.
- These studies are unnecessary.
- I had to confirm a diagnosis.
Since when has that been against policy ?
Since your patient, this Karen Adams,
was diagnosed with Wegener's disease
at this hospital six months ago.
How is that possible ?
She just started exhibiting symptoms.
That's what she told you.
These records speak for themselves.
[Sighing, murmuring]
She knew.
And she never told her husband.
[Allan] Hi, babe. It's me.
I'm gonna be late.
We should pick up some Chinese
and we'll eat in bed, OK ? Love you.
Cake.
With everything he did to you.
He isn't trying to be nervous.
Hey ! Charlotte King just called.
Unnecessary tests on Karen Adams ?
"Hey, Sam. How was your day, Sam ?"
Fine, thanks for asking.
- Naomi ?
- It's called fiscal responsibility.
- We have to pay the bills.
- I've got a patient who's lying
about her condition. It's not my fault.
- It is not his fault.
- I was not trying to start a fight.
I'm sorry, but I'm pissed. If we tell
Doug Karen's lying to him, he'd leave.
We can't reveal her medical information
to anyone, including her husband,
without her approval.
Confidentiality.
- She's a patient.
- Your patient.
Your patient is messing
with my patient's happiness.
Three years of kick-ass therapy
down the drain with one swift diagnosis.
Maybe they'll work it out.
People do make marriages work.
We're talking serious sacrifice.
She's got him where she wants him.
They won't make it work.
She'll end up hating him.
He'll hate himself for staying.
After she's gone,
that's all he'll have.
So, I think if you can find a way
to help your patient, you do it.
The hospital sent over these results
on Erin Merring.
I don't know how
these girls are getting exposed.
- I can't even get them to talk to me.
- What are they into ?
- Fluffy, pink... pinkness.
- OK, so go there too. Commit.
- Give them what they want.
- Like you and your cake.
They are women, Cooper.
- Tiny blue women, but still women.
- [Chuckles]
Yeah... no.
I didn't get in this 'cause I'm a clown.
I'm supposed to play with my patients ?
I put a sticker on my stethoscope,
that's as far as I go.
And Erin's lying there getting sicker.
Commit to the cake, man.
[Doorbell rings]
Who wants to play ?
- I'm... I'm nervous.
- Me, too.
That's natural.
But Dr. Wilder knows what he's doing.
Hi. Come on in. Make yourselves
comfortable. I'll be right there.
Flowers opening, rivers parting.
This is you apologizing to me ?
Well, I got to go give out
the old Pete special.
OK. What ?
- Nothing.
- We banter. It's what we do.
[Sighs]
It's just Naomi told me
what this week is. The anniversary.
It's nothing.
- [Cooper] Where exactly are we going ?
- Our secret place !
- Ooh, you have a secret place ?
- We have a magic castle.
But first, we got
to get through the fortress.
The fence is the fortress.
[Girls yelling]
[Yells]
- [Girl] Come on. Sit down.
- Ooh !
- Awesome castle.
- Magic castle.
It makes you see stars !
See ?
Wow, stars. Yeah.
Whoa !
[Birds chirping, bells chiming]
The stars make me dizzy.
- Me too !
- Me three !
See the stars ?
How they go all funny ?
- [Coughing]
- The stars make you dizzy.
[Girl coughs]
Dr. Bennett.
I told you we don't need a therapist.
You are not my patient.
I am here for Doug.
And I'm here for you, Karen.
Now, I have your medical records here.
Would you like for me to
discuss them in front of Doug,
or would you like Doug
to leave the room ?
Because, as your doctor, I cannot
discuss what's in here in front of him
- without your permission.
- Why would I have to leave the room ?
Karen ?
This isn't fair. You can't do this.
I am not discussing
without your permission.
[Violet] Doug can stay in here
with you and Sam,
or he can come out in the hall
and talk to me.
Karen ?
So I knew I was sick before. So what ?
I didn't think you could take it.
I thought you'd run
like the weakling you are,
so I didn't tell you.
You knew you were sick
all this time ?
I thought you were a weak, whiny
pain in the ass, but you surprised me.
It proves that you're not weak,
you're strong.
And I need you. I need your strength.
I want you to stay.
What do you want, Doug ?
You've been coming to see me
for 36 months.
Thirty-six months and
thousands and thousands of dollars.
You came and you worked.
All so you could say what you want.
You've earned yourself
a very expensive backbone.
Use it.
What do you want ?
- You promised.
- I'm talking to Doug.
[Scoffs] What I want.
What I want.
I want to stay.
- Doug, you...
- I want to stay ! All right ?
End of discussion.
I'm staying with Karen.
I'm staying with my wife.
- [Elevator door dings]
- [Cathleen] Goodbye. Thanks.
- [Pete] Take care.
- [Addison] Good luck tonight.
- For what it's worth...
- Don't say anything nice.
- I wasn't.
- You were.
I don't need pity.
I don't need sympathy.
I was going to say,
whatever you did in there,
for Cathleen, I hope it works.
They deserve to have a perfect night.
Oh.
I get a little...
[stammers] I need...
I'm a little lost here.
My wife went to sleep beside me in bed
on a Tuesday night.
On Wednesday morning, I woke up
and she was dead. It's one bad night.
But...
...all our nights were bad.
And we never had a perfect night.
Not even our wedding night.
Nothing's perfect.
Nothing's ever perfect.
That's the most he's ever
told anybody about his wife.
The "castle" in your neighbor's yard
was full of toxic fumes
from open bags of fertilizer.
- That's what made them sick ?
- They were inhaling ammonium nitrate.
First it turned them blue, then
it attacked their nervous systems.
They play in the yard. I never thought
they'd get beyond the fence.
Well, you know,
they kind of kick ass, so...
- [laughs]
- Mom ? Can they sit in my bed ?
Be gentle, OK ?
[All whispering]
- [Knock on door]
- [Door opens]
[Sighs] I'm sorry.
[Stammers] I know how much you cared.
- How hard you worked.
- You worked.
You did most of it.
I may not be in love with her,
but I owe her.
No one should go through
what she's going through alone.
- She doesn't have to be...
- I wanted to say,
I still think we did something here.
I mean, before I met you,
things just happened to me.
I made a choice today.
But you're still picking what's safe,
what's familiar.
Pain that won't even make her better.
- What about what...
- What I want ?
Is for you to be the therapist and me
to be the patient. It's my life.
At least now I know
I've made my bed, nobody else.
You're right. It's your choice.
And you made it.
- And that is something.
- Thanks.
[Door opens, closes]
- It's not raining.
- Yeah.
- Yippee.
- I'm starting to agree with you.
- About the magic.
- Thank you.
That... That's... Thank you.
- OK. So just call me tonight, OK ?
- Mom.
Will you just call me, OK ?
- Will you make sure she calls me ?
- OK.
Quiet down in there.
Double fudge with chocolate frosting.
You know what ?
Enough with the cake.
I don't want your cake.
I don't need your cake.
I didn't ask for your cake !
I'm all caked out !
You know whose cake I want ?
I want Sam's cake !
But Sam's not baking a cake for me !
Could you...
Nai.
Dell, she's going
off sugar for a while.
I'm not gonna stop bringing you cake.
- You !
- All right, Dell !
- No more cake !
- This isn't "Maya likes Sam better."
You're mad at me for bringing you here.
And this boy is baking cakes at me !
We're going to get through this.
- Yeah, we are ?
- Yes.
We're all gonna get through this.
- That's why you have us.
- We're gonna get through this together.
Just when is something good
going to happen ?
- When is there gonna be a little...
- Magic ?
Yeah, that's the unending question.
[ ? Matthew Perryman Jones : Save You]
[Sighs] You drank all the orange juice.
You hogged the covers.
You put our dog to sleep.
You never took my side.
You were mean to me.
You withheld sex ! You were cold !
You were a mean, cold, bitch
and I hate you !
I hate you so much !
I'm sorry I couldn't save you.
[Allan] Hi, babe. It's me.
I'm going to be late.
Why don't you pick up some Chinese
and we'll eat in bed, OK ? Love you.
[Beeps] Message deleted.
Way to be a man.
[Screams] Thank you !
Thank you ! Thank you !
Thank you !
- You're amazing. Thank you.
- Thank you so much !
Pete helped. Dr. Wilder.
Thank you ! Thank you.
- I love you, man.
- What did they do that was so great ?
- Yeah, what did they do ?
- They saved a marriage.
Magic ?
Magic.
[Rain falling]
[Thundering]