Researchers are
currently working
to make a map of
the human brain.
It may be the most
complex map ever created.
Good morning. Good morning.
Billions of neurons making
trillions of connections.
Hey.
At first glance, they
seem completely random.
Careful. Hot.
Hmm.
But there is nothing
random about them.
All these connections
have to happen
in a specific pattern.
It is designed for a function.
These connections
determine everything about us,
what we love,
what we hate,
what we say,
what we do...
Every action we take.
Open your hand, okay, Mickey?
Like this?
Exactly. Like that.
Yeah, baby!
Okay, now close it.
Oh, yeah!
As he thinks about movements,
we see brain activity
here and here.
These areas lighting up.
Now the brain-computer interface
is the key to new possibilities,
whether it be
robotic prosthetics,
for quadriplegics like Mickey...
Or letting me kick
ass at Tetris again.
Hey, check this out, you guys.
Hang loose!
Hey, where's Dr. Torres?
How's she missing this? This
is the best that we've ever done.
Shane, text her again, will you?
Is something wrong?
There's not a lot
of temporal lobe activity.
Nothing lights up here.
Is it a bad connection
in the sensor?
I hope so.
If not, it's a bad
connection in his brain.
Schedule Mickey for an MRI.
Oh, um...
I brought this from
home accidentally.
Can you just put it in with
my diaper bag and stuff?
And, uh, I'll try
and find Torres.
What's up, second year?
This is a step up, right?
Are these assigned?
Yes. There's a lab
coat with your name.
What are you so happy about?
Can't tell you. You
wish I could, but I can't.
So please don't ask.
Why are there no doors
on these? I know, right?
Like, "Hello, tampons.
Meet everyone."
You guys, there's a coat
here for Heather Brooks.
Oh, my God. Seriously?
Okay, is he being weird?
Did he fail the exam?
He left right after. He
didn't come celebrate.
Also, he kissed me.
Oh, yeah, he kissed her.
It could be that.
I totally get it. I've got a
secret thing going, too.
There's no coffee
here. This is bad.
I can't tell you who
kissed me, though.
Hey.
Hey! I woke up at your place...
Alone, again.
Yeah, I was out late.
This has been three nights now.
Yeah, I've been
going out. That's all.
I passed my intern exam.
I never heard from you.
Is there something going on?
Alex, talk to me.
Alex?
Ugh. I thought she
would never leave.
Hmm?
So you got my texts?
I passed my intern exam.
Yeah, yeah, I did. I replied.
I wrote "congratulations."
I hoped I would see you.
I had such an amazing
time the other night.
Yeah, it was fun.
I feel like I'm ready
to take it further...
You know, um, it's
not a good idea...
Um... At work?
I totally get it.
See you tonight?
Mmm-hmm.
You paged me?
Dr. Edwards, Ben Bosco.
His wife Joyce. Hi.
He's got an ankle fracture.
That moving walkway
thing at the airport...
We were running to catch
our connection to Alaska...
To see the northern lights.
Then he steps off that
thing, and I heard it.
I heard it just go crack.
Like the whole world slammed
on the brakes, and I kept going.
And here we are.
He's gonna need a full
workup and an ortho consult.
Also get a chest X-ray,
'cause it might be surgical.
Keep me posted.
Okay. I will get those X-rays.
Oh! Excuse me. Sorry. Sorry.
You're sure it's not weird?
I called you.
Robbins doesn't know
that we're dating, does she?
'Cause I just don't
want to trade on our,
whatever this is, to get
to observe a surgery.
No.
Good. I just like to keep
it professional, you know?
At work. Yeah, of course.
Um, hey, uh...
Are we not telling people?
'Cause I told a couple people.
Yeah, you could.
You should.
I would.
Good. Good.
Well, we are at work. So...
Thanks for the call.
Yeah.
Hi. Excuse me. Oh, hello.
Bring your girlfriend
to work day?
Robbins has a teratoma in a
three-month, and, uh, Emma...
Doctor, uh, Marling
is gonna observe.
That's sweet.
This isn't gonna
be weird, is it?
For me? Please.
Will it be weird for her?
I mean is she the type to
get freaked out by the ex?
Damn it.
Mer...
What's going on?
Oh, nothing.
I'm just, uh, trying to
decide on a research project.
Decide between what?
Nothing. I got it.
This pain isn't going away.
It's a constant pain
in my left shoulder.
And what do you
think is causing that?
Were you injured in a fall?
You tell me. You're my doctor.
Right. Sorry.
It's just that you're
also my teacher.
Excuse me, Dr. Bailey...
Do you remember
reading somewhere
about unfinished research
on iliac-portal vein grafts?
Why? Tonight is the deadline
to submit for the NIH
research grant I want.
And I'm having trouble
deciding between ischemia...
Ah, you're peeing on a tree.
Yeah, first year attending
scared of screwing up.
So, she takes the easy cases.
She keeps a low profile.
But second year attending
has got to step it up,
take the flashy cases,
publish the research,
mark her territory.
Pee on some trees.
Portal veins... Any bells?
It was your mother's.
"Portal vein interposition
with iliac vein graft."
Ellis was working on
it when she got sick.
It's in one of the
journals you gave me. Oh.
Crap.
I have a mug like that.
If you don't come back
with a solid diagnosis
for my shoulder pain, I'm
gonna kick you off my case.
As my teacher or my patient?
Get out.
I need a differential diagnosis
for Webber's shoulder pain.
Arthritis, bursitis...
Hmm. Any of the
old people "-itises."
Still waiting on my
broken ankle's chest scans.
You got coffee.
So Alex isn't talking to me.
I think it's 'cause I pushed
him to talk to his deadbeat dad.
Alex has a dad? Mmm.
Have you talked to Shane?
I'm still hoping it'll go away.
Shane kissed me.
I didn't kiss him.
It's his problem.
Oh...
Oh!
He has a huge
tumor in his heart.
No...
He has a broken ankle.
Okay, yeah. Thank you.
You okay?
Yeah, why?
Yeah, we tested the new sensors
with Mickey
Wenschler this morning.
Oh. And it was a huge success.
But he kept asking
why you weren't there.
Uh, well, didn't
you get my text?
Your text said,
"Won't be there."
Okay, well, uh,
here's the thing,
moving back into my
place made me feel like
I really need to move
back into my place.
You know, concentrate
on what makes me, me.
I do regenerative cartilage.
It's what my TED talk was
about... What are you saying?
I'm not going forward
with the project.
You should totally
run with it, though.
No, this is your project.
Mickey's your
patient. I can't do this.
I don't have time.
Meredith and I
are in over our heads with kids,
and she needs time, too.
So maybe we just drop it.
No harm done, right?
Oh, and tell that to
Mickey Wenschler.
Mickey will be all right.
Edwards, I just saw
your broken ankle.
No surgery, just splint it.
He won't be all right.
It's gonna kill him.
I know, right?
I can't do this.
Did you do this? Uh, I...
I need to find Kepner.
No, who broke this?
Yeah, sorry. I dropped it.
Dr. Yang, would
you look at this?
Holy... Wow! I
mean, it's bad, right?
Look, this wasn't yours
to use... Shane, not now!
This is a rat's nest of an
AVM in the left ventricle.
It's probably pushing
in on the valve.
If it's not treated, he'll
be dead in months.
He came in for a broken ankle.
And now I have to
tell them he's dying.
Okay, let me look at the blood
work, and we'll tell them together.
God, thank you so much.
This place is a maze.
Is that Dr. Robbins?
Yeah.
And you are?
Dr. Robbins, Emma Marling.
Oh, right.
Right, right, you're observing.
And I'm scrubbing in...
I hope. Oh.
Murphy, I'm sorry.
With Dr. Marling,
I think the table's
full. Um, next time?
Okay, so we just gave little
Erin's parents the pre-game,
and we're about to take her up.
Murphy, will you show her
where to get some scrubs?
Visiting surgeon?
Yeah, maternal/fetal.
She's researching minimally
invasive in-utero teratomas.
And she's hot. I'm just saying it's
good that I'll be there to chaperone.
What, we're not
joking about this yet?
See you in there.
Here.
This is my mother's journal.
Where did you get this?
Webber made me go to his house.
And I need to figure out
why his shoulder hurts.
Can I go? Yeah.
What was that about?
Research funding.
I'm trying to decide
between an ischemia study
and this portal vein thing that
my mother was working on.
Ooh! Do that.
It's half-baked.
And I don't like trading
on my mother's name.
No, it's your story. Yeah.
"Brilliant young
surgeon finishes work
"of dead brilliant
mother surgeon,"
it writes itself.
Invest in your brand.
You make me sound like a
soft drink. That's what I'm doing.
Yeah, I'm reinvesting in myself.
That's the perfect
reason... Right?
Not to.
Shane, here you go.
Some good stuff in there.
Enjoy.
You don't get it.
These are Mickey's
MRIs? Mmm-hmm.
Dr. Shepherd, I
wondered if you'd mind
if I switch services
after today.
I asked for you specifically.
I know.
Look, what happened last
year between you and Brooks,
I think I may have been unfair,
and I was hoping for a
chance to make it right.
So, now that Brooks is gone,
I get to take her
place? Oh, hell.
Well, that's why the
sensors weren't lighting.
He has a glioma.
Can you treat it?
I could try hitting
it with some glue.
Glue?
Embolization glue.
We use it for AVMs.
We pump superglue
into the vessels,
the glue hardens, cuts
off blood to the tumor.
I could try it.
No. It goes all the
way to the brain stem.
It's too dangerous.
And going in surgically?
It's the same thing.
I'm afraid of doing
more harm than good.
It's a very deadly mass.
It's a large veinous
malformation,
and without
intervention immediately,
I'm afraid the
prognosis is very bad.
Yeah, that's the thing.
Um, I have been
dying of that for years.
You knew about this
and you didn't mention it?
I'm sorry. In your
medical history, there's...
I was so hung up on
missing our plane...
It's an inoperable AVM.
He was diagnosed
with it, what...
A year and a half...
Year before last, yeah.
January. And terminal.
So, what are you gonna do?
So we just quit our jobs,
cashed out all our accounts,
and just started traveling.
Yeah, just doing stuff,
trips, activities, basically
cramming as much living
as we could into
the time we have left.
Okay, did your
doctor, did he or she,
try treating it with radiation?
Yeah, tried that.
Intravenous coiling?
Mmm-hmm. Yeah, no dice.
And the sclerosing agents...
Uh, what about a
transplant? Or what about...
There are a lot of...
Sweetie...
I know it's hard.
It was hard for us, too.
But you have to let it go.
Because there is
nothing I can do about it.
I'm sorry.
The best course
is to leave it alone
and hope for the best.
We'll keep doing
the study, right?
Come on. Why?
Because it is too dangerous.
Also the tumor could
give us abnormal results.
What if you take the tumor out?
I could keep doing the testing.
You could, but...
Then take it out, man!
We're so close, right? Mmm-hmm.
This morning, I was
miles beyond anything...
It's too dangerous.
We're gonna take you up there,
we're gonna remove your sensors,
and then we're
gonna close your...
What if I don't consent?
What?
What if I say you can't
take your sensors back
unless you take my tumor, too?
Mickey, I need to take them out.
Sorry, bud.
Access denied.
You're not going in my head
unless you're leaving with that tumor.
Lucky you use
electro-thermal sealers.
They're too big to get in there
when we do these in-utero.
Bear with me, Emma.
Alex, I need your advice.
What's your strategy when
you have a one-night-stand,
not even, you just
make out with someone,
and then they get
way too attached?
You know who's like that?
Leah Murphy.
Really?
Yeah, I slept with her
one, maybe two times.
She stuck to me like glue.
That girl goes from zero to
"I love you" in seven seconds.
I've never, ever felt this way.
And if I tell you
guys who it is,
it would cause so
many problems for me
and for this person, and...
God, for the hospital, probably.
So please don't ask.
Could it be heart-related?
He had ventricular failure.
- What?
Webber's shoulder hurts.
Hey, did you talk to Alex?
Yeah, I tried. He just
keeps running away.
He's dumping you.
It's what he did with me.
He'll pretend you're not
there until you're not there.
And when you're not there,
he'll have sex with someone else.
Why are you gluing my mug?
It's not yours. It's Shepherd's.
The mug was my responsibility.
How'd you break it? She
got scared by a tumor.
It's an AVM, and
it's a scary one.
Totally inoperable.
Guy probably has months to live,
and he and his poor
wife are just trying to make
the most of their time together.
Hey, what about glue?
What about glue?
I'm sorry. For your AVM...
This AVM.
Look, Dr. Shepherd was talking
about the embolization glue
they use in neuro
AVMs, and I wondered,
has this approach ever
been used in the heart?
Not that I'm aware of. So... No.
They glue neuro AVMs
because they're microscopic.
These vessels are huge.
You saying it won't work?
I'm saying...
I'd need a crapload of glue.
I'm saying the glue won't
work, the radiation won't work,
and I don't want to go in
surgically. I risk killing him.
So he's holding your
sensors hostage in his skull?
This is not funny, Callie.
You have to talk to him.
It's Mickey. Just
give him a few hours.
He'll come around.
You don't want to talk to him
because you don't want
to look him in the eye
and tell him you're
bailing on this.
And you certainly don't want
to tell him why you're bailing.
Why is that?
You started this
project for Arizona.
When you lost interest in
her, you lost interest in this.
You're letting your
personal problems
get in the way of
months of research.
Well, you're doing
the same thing.
You said you were done with the
study to spend time with your kids.
That's completely different.
Oh, why is it different, Derek?
'Cause your family's
perfect, and mine's a disaster?
Because you're leaving the
study to support your wife,
and I'm doing it to forget mine?
I know what you're
going through.
You don't know
anything about it.
You guys have figured it out,
how to make the pieces fit.
And I thought
we did, too, but...
I'm figuring this out
for myself now, so...
Just bear with me, okay?
I will talk to Mickey.
And I'm gonna ask you
a series of questions.
"Are you a tennis player?"
Oh, good lord.
"Do you frequently
carry heavy loads,
"groceries, etcetera,
with your injured arm?"
I've been in this bed a month.
I'm just trying to be thorough.
Um...
"Have you recently engaged
in any strenuous sexual..."
I am skipping that one...
Uh, too, uh...
Um...
Uh... I'm not getting a
very good reading on...
Sir, are you... Oh! Oh...
It is not my tennis game,
and it's not my heart.
Look deeper.
Now get out, and
take that thing with you.
Um...
Oh, come on. I don't
have time for this.
"Ischemia reperfusion
injury in thoracic trauma"?
What happened to portal veins?
I know ischemia is boring,
but my mother's portal
vein research is outdated.
I mean, we've already
grafted them from stem cells.
And I don't want to spend my
life being compared to my mother.
Hey. She was a smart woman.
It might be worse to
never be compared to her.
I can't find a way to
take the research further.
And I can't print
this damn thing!
You all right?
We've bio-engineered blood
vessels from a 3-D printer.
Yeah.
But I don't think anyone
has ever printed a portal vein.
It's never been done before.
The glue is designed
for use in your brain,
but I would like to
try it in your heart.
It's a bold approach.
Are you saying that...
I am optimistic that
it could save your life.
That's awful.
I'm sorry?
After we got Ben's diagnosis,
well, I mean, you know,
we sold everything.
We cashed out all our accounts.
We maxed out our credit
cards and more credit cards.
We went to Europe. We went
to India. We went to Morocco.
We rented a whole island.
We went up in that plane
where you get to be weightless.
That's five grand a pop.
We went up 11 times...
And then bought a boat.
And then we blew it up, 'cause
we wanted to watch it burn.
We owe creditors
hundreds of
thousands of dollars.
How were you
planning to pay for...
Life insurance.
Ben's a very good planner.
I thought I was.
I didn't plan for surviving.
But still, hon...
Oh.
We gotta try it, right?
Wait.
What are the risks?
Well, as I said,
this has never been done
before on a beating heart.
Could I die?
Could I die on the table?
It's possible.
Then there's hope.
I want a C-arm set up in the OR.
I may have to do
a crash sternotomy.
Really?
Well, I don't know
what's gonna happen.
This has never been done before.
How much AVM glue
do you think we'll need?
Again, never been done before.
Err on the side of all of it.
Where is it? Where is what?
My mother's journal.
Why would I know?
The black book...
The little black book
I gave you today...
I need it back, Shane. I
think I left it with Edwards.
Edwards! What?
ER needs this bed.
Can you help me?
Hey, and what is going
on with Mr. Bosco?
Why has a broken ankle
been moved to pre-op
for a cardiac procedure? What?
You can't change the course
of treatment like that without...
I didn't. The cardio consult
declared it inoperable.
So then why is he in pre-op?
Who did the consult? Dr. Yang!
What? EMMA: Sorry.
We were in here before,
and I think I left my phone.
Well, what do we have here?
Oh, a ventricular AVM.
I'm doing liquid
embolization with glue.
Wait, glue for brain aneurysms?
Has that been tried
on a heart before?
Thank you. As a
matter of fact, no.
Are you sure it'll work?
That is also a no.
I am impressed with
your enormous balls.
I wish I could stick
around and watch this.
I'm Cristina by the way.
Cristina Yang. Just so you know.
Yeah, I know. We've met
a couple of times, actually.
Emma Marling.
I know. I'm saying
I'm Owen's, um...
Ex-wife.
Ah! Yes.
Right.
Well, this looks amazing.
And I can't wait to
hear how it went.
Good night.
You weren't gonna
say good night? Oh, hey.
I'm off. I'll see you later.
Will you?
Probably not. I'll
probably be late.
Are you seeing someone else?
Is that what's happening?
'Cause I just need to
know. No, it's not that.
Then what is it?
It's none of your business.
It is between me and Shepherd,
and I told him everything
he needs to know.
Mickey... Mickey, look at me.
If I do, the aliens will win.
This operation could kill you.
I never told you how I
became a quad, did I?
You were in a car accident.
I caused a car accident...
Because I was
drunk. I got drunk,
and I drove, and
I hit another car,
and I killed two teenage girls,
Lindsay and Cheryl.
So, there I am,
a pile of garbage.
Can't move, can't
walk, can't do anything
except think about what
I did to those families.
I've got people tending to me.
People feed me
and shave me and clean me,
and I don't deserve their time.
I deserve to have
died in that car.
And I wish I did every day,
for nine years.
And when you
asked me to do this...
When I had a chance
to do something
affecting someone
in a good way...
For the first time, I thought
I was worth having around.
If I die,
give my brain to
science, and I still help.
Let me help.
Please.
And how can I help you?
Oh, hey. Same as last night?
Yeah, thanks.
You must really
like these guys, huh?
I still think it's a bad idea.
I know, but it's the right idea.
Mickey has nothing
to lose and a lot to gain.
Okay, I'll schedule him
for tomorrow morning.
Okay. No, wait. I can't do
tomorrow morning.
Bailey has a well-baby exam,
I've got back-to-back discotomies,
and Zola and I were gonna
check out a dance class.
It's gonna have to be tonight.
Zola, you and your brother
are gonna have to go back
to day care for a little
while longer, okay, sweetie?
No, no, no. I'll take
'em back up. I got it.
Here. Come on. This way, babes.
Page Dr. Ross.
Okay.
More glue.
We're getting to the
end of our supply.
Then go get more.
I think I need to
fill this whole thing.
Okay. The catheter
is stuck to the vein.
God, this stuff is intense.
Should you be tugging that hard?
Well, you want me
to leave it in there?
Okay. Okay, we're good.
How did you come up with this?
I don't know.
I just connected the dots.
You are full of
surprises, sharky.
Innovative instincts
and killer instincts,
what other secrets
are hiding in there?
What do you think you'll find?
Well, if it's not arthritis
or bursitis or rotator cuff,
and your heart's
fine, then it can't hurt.
Unless it's referred pain, which
could be nerve impingement
or diaphragmatic
irritation, so...
You don't need an X-ray.
Bravo.
You need an ultrasound.
Well, I hope you're not
thinking I'm pregnant!
Page Dr. Edwards here stat.
- Right away.
I need an ultrasound.
Are you pregnant?
Does Alex know?
No, I need an
ultrasound machine.
Have you seen Edwards?
Does Alex think I'm pregnant?
I have a mug like that.
Where the hell have you been?
Uh, I thought you were leaving,
and Dr. Yang and I
found a left ventricle AVM.
Yeah, well, you're
here now. Scrub in.
I'd rather not.
Shane, you gotta get past this.
You're not a consolation prize.
You deserve to be here.
Brooks had a gift
that needed to be...
I don't wanna work with you.
I'm not interested.
Can I be more clear?
I suppose not.
Go.
To a certain
extent, time will tell.
What we know for sure is we've
done no damage to your heart,
and at this preliminary stage,
it appears the AVM
won't continue to grow.
So you're saying...
I'll live?
Yes. Mmm-hmm.
Dear God.
Ben? Honey? I know.
We'll be all right.
I know it's a lot of money.
It's been a crazy year,
but the world is a lot
more fun with you in it.
As long as we have each
other, everything will be fine.
Joyce, we're screwed.
I know.
We're not just bankrupt.
We're criminals.
I think we might go to jail.
Oh, we're so incredibly screwed.
Like a two-dollar whore.
Yang, that's my broken ankle.
How about a little
heads-up next time
you wanna steal
one of my patients?
What happened to them?
I saved his life.
So I get that you saved him,
but he was my patient, and you
should've told me before you...
I came up with
the fix. You didn't.
If you're still pissed about
what happened the other night,
I'm with Jackson.
It was inappropriate, and
it's not gonna happen again.
What are you talking about?
When you kissed me, Shane.
Oh. That.
We were excited. It happened.
I'm sorry it meant
more to you...
It didn't.
You're still talking about it.
What's happened to you?
What are you guys
whispering about?
Nothing.
God, you guys, fine.
It's Arizona Robbins.
But please don't
say anything, okay?
Because she really
doesn't need... Robbins?
So... You're gay now?
Shane, grow up.
It's a sliding scale.
I slid over her way.
If you really have to label
everything, then label me "in love."
Murphy!
Dr. Mahoney to triage.
I'm sorry. They pretty
much figured it out.
No. I'm sorry, because
I'm about to be very frank.
The other night was
a bad call on my part.
I was lonely, and it was lovely.
But it was one night, and
that's all that it will ever be,
so if you had different
expectations, please adjust them.
Uh, of course.
There's no need to
apologize. It's my fault.
I don't open up to people much,
and when I try to
open up a little bit,
I can get carried away.
It's happened before.
And you...
I've just always admired
you as a surgeon,
and a person,
and the thought that
you thought about me...
I misunderstood. Um, I
went overboard, and I'm sorry.
It won't happen again.
Leah...
Thank you for understanding.
Gin, rocks.
You gonna charge me again?
Most places comp
the bands, you know?
I got this one.
Appreciate that.
Jimmy Evans.
Hey.
I know you.
I've, uh, been here
the last couple of nights.
No. Something else.
Oh, my God.
You're a doctor...
At the hospital.
Guilty.
What brings you
back here every night?
Oh, uh, you. I
mean, I like your set.
Uh, I like the
Albert Collins stuff.
Ah. You got a good
ear, then. You play?
My dad taught me a
little when I was a kid,
but, uh, he
didn't stick with it.
Aw, you should
have stuck with it.
Look where it
could've taken you.
I mean, instead of
saving people's lives,
you could be playing
70-year-old songs
to four people in
a giant ashtray.
What kind of doctor are you?
Oh. Pediatric surgeon.
Uh, babies, kids.
I met a pediatric surgeon once.
Scariest night of my life.
My son's not even two years old.
I'm feeding him strawberries,
and he starts choking.
Turned blue.
We take him in, they
get him breathing again.
Pediatric surgeon runs
the tube down his throat,
and got the thing out.
Saved my boy's life.
Saved my life, too.
If I'd lost my little
boy that night,
I never would've made it.
I never would've survived.
I'm glad it worked out for you.
Yeah. Thank God for
you guys, man. Seriously.
So where is he?
Now, I mean.
Where's your family?
That's a complicated answer.
This place has
really cleared out.
I guess I was the big draw.
Yeah, well...
I probably should
head out myself.
I was gonna say,
you play a little?
I got an extra guitar. We can
get up and make some noise.
No. No, I haven't
played since I was a kid.
Well, there's no one
here to hear you suck.
Come on. It'll be fun.
I don't know any songs.
What about the songs
your daddy taught you?
I might know one of those.
Am I hearing
changes in his rhythm?
Turn up the heart
monitor, please.
Some suction.
More mannitol.
Rhythm's getting very
erratic, and BP's rising.
Quiet. Quiet.
Damn it.
All right. Reverse
the paralytics.
All right, let me
check his gag reflexes.
Oh, no, Mickey. Come on. No.
Dr. Shepherd, there's
no brain activity.
That is a pancreatic
pseudocyst! Bam! Ha!
Did you just say "bam"?
It had to be
referred pain, right?
But referred pain
to the shoulder
means irritation
of the diaphragm,
which did not make sense, but...
You have pancreatic
fluid leakage,
so I was thinking, well,
maybe something was
aggravating the diaphragm,
which referred to the
shoulder, and bam!
Pancreatic pseudocyst.
Maybe you should wipe that smile
off your face before
you tell the patient.
Oh, God. I am so sorry.
I forgot that this is bad news.
And you're laughing.
For the first time today, I
feel like I'm in good hands.
Nice work, Wilson.
You traced it
back to the source.
Hey! I'm doing my
mother's research,
but not for the reasons
you said I should.
Not now, Grey.
She had a good idea!
I'm not riding her coattails.
I am sharing her passion.
Maybe this is what
my mother gave me.
Your daddy taught
you pretty good.
Hey.
You okay?
You know, that's a good tune.
Brings back a lot.
You know, if you're not careful,
all your old mistakes
can just roll up on you.
I taught my kid
to play guitar, too.
It's like you said.
I wish I'd have stuck with it.
Well, your kid
probably does, too.
Yeah, but there's no
going back, is there?
Can I show you a picture of him?
My boy?
What, you have one?
That's Nicky.
He's five there. He'd
be about 12 now.
And, uh, that's his mom, Naomi.
She's Japanese.
Who's...
Where are they?
South Florida.
I haven't been
back there in years.
God, you just keep doing this.
What do you mean?
Do this kid a favor.
Don't ever go back.
Let him grow up
without knowing you any
more that he already has.
What the hell, man?
He's better off. You know that.
What's your problem?
We were having fun here.
I'm trying to protect your
kid. You're no good to him.
Hey, you don't know me,
and you don't talk about my kid.
Hey! No!
Out!
You, out, now!
This way, you can do the
most good for the most people.
You think so?
Oh, yeah. He would be grateful.
You did exactly what he wanted.
I'm not dropping the project.
You were right.
I was doing it for her.
And now I will do it for a million
people I'll never even meet.
And for Mickey.
I could really use your help.
We are just starting to learn
the extent of the
brain's connections.
How far they reach,
how deep they go.
I think I've ceased to exist.
I made history today, literally.
Operated on the inoperable,
saved a man from certain death,
and then ruined his life.
Oh, also Owen seems very
happy with that Marling person
to whom he has never
even mentioned me.
It's as if the last few
years never happened.
Also, the automatic paper towel
thingy won't recognize me as human.
I'm just standing there,
waving my hands like an idiot.
I'm sorry. What?
What are you doing?
Application for
research funding.
Oh, you picked your project.
Uh, yeah.
I'm gonna 3-D
print portal veins.
That is amazing, Mer.
How are you gonna
do that... Okay, don't.
It's why I didn't tell you.
I have a career and a family,
and I'm going to do both.
What I don't have time for is
for you to tell me that I can't.
I never said that.
You know, I was
always there for you,
for whatever you needed,
and now this is when I need you,
and you're supposed to help me.
And instead, last week
you pushed me aside
because I had a baby.
You don't have time for me now?
Because you don't have time
for people who want
things that you don't want.
But we know that every
connection matters.
Every connection is crucial.
I have to finish this.
And when one is broken,
it usually means some
damage has been done.
I can't figure it out if
you're seeing someone else
or you think that
you knocked me up,
so I tried to trace it back
to the root of the problem,
and I think it's your dad.
Look, I told you...
Not to bring it
up again, I know,
and this is the last time,
because if I'm wrong...
You're not wrong. You
should be proud of yourself.
I could've let him
just pass through,
but you were all, "Talk to him.
"You'll wonder for
the rest of your life."
Well, thanks. I didn't know I
could feel this crappy again
after 18 frickin' years!
This system of connections
compels us to act
and choose and behave...
Sometimes seemingly
against our own will.
But it is not random at all.
It is the map of who we are.
Did you get my text? Shh.
Sorry. I was stuck there.
I had to get this
thing out by tonight.
I got hung up, too.
I just barely got them down.
Just now? I know.
It's so late.
I know. I tried.
It's not working.
No, it isn't.
We just can't seem
to make the pieces fit.
I agree, but I don't know how...
I think I do.
I wanna spend more
time on this BCI research.
Torres and I blew
it wide open today.
So you wanna take on more? No.
Less, actually.
This is a big year for you, and
you need time to make it work.
I had a big year.
I can step back,
scale down my surgeries,
focus on this research,
spend time with the kids,
and give you the slack you
need to make this year count.
I don't like it.
You'll resent me,
and so will the kids, and I
don't wanna be my mother.
You're not your mother.
You know that.
We will work to
understand ourselves,
solve the puzzle.
It feels unfair.
Spending time with the
kids is not a consolation prize.
It is the prize.
You want fair?
Maybe down the road,
I'll give you a year with them.
Maybe when Zola's dating,
'cause I don't wanna
be around for that.
I love you. Well, you should.
What I'm doing
is amazing for you.
Mmm!
You're gonna have
more fun than me.
I know. Oh, so that's
where that went.
Yeah. Is that ours?
Yes.
How all the connections work
and all the pieces...
fit.