As surgeons, we rely on cycles.
Heartbeats.
Cell regeneration.
Circadian rhythms.
We know something's wrong
when the cycle is broken.
Our duty is to fix it.
To force the cogs
back in line.
Sorry, sir!
Morning, sir!
But that break can also be
useful, like a warning shot.
Beth, please. I know.
Y-Yeah, my leave
was canceled. I...
Don't cry. I will make this
up to you, I promise.
She's got that vice grip
so tight,
his testicles
are about to pop off.
How you holding up?
Well, considering
that today decides
my entire military future?
Medium.
You're a shoo-in.
I think I'd rather focus on
my brother's pathetic love life.
- Hey, that was an endearing conversation.
- How's everything at home?
All right. Let's focus on
getting this stuff loaded.
We need to be in Fallujah
at 0700.
I'd like to be
less uptight by 0700.
Okay. Save it. The colonel's
coming. Where the hell is Riggs?
He was on call last night.
I'll get him.
Owen. Owen.
Owen!
Are you okay?
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, I'm okay.
It's...
It's not really goodbye.
I mean, Los Angeles
is a two-hour flight,
so you can see her
whenever you want.
Yeah.
How 'bout I make us
dinner tonight?
Well, that
would be... nice.
Hey! I'm getting
on the road now.
How long till you're here?
Uh, it's...
It's a long drive.
Well, if you drive faster,
will you get here sooner?
Just help Nathan
get everything ready,
and you won't even
notice the time.
Aah! Son of a...
Doubt it.
Kisses, my sweet boy.
Hey, will you give Nate
the phone?
Oh. Thanks, buddy.
- Hey, baby, how's it going?
- How's he doing?
God. This has got to
be totally overwhelming for him.
- No, no, no.
- We're... We're having a blast.
And you got
his fan, right?
I mean, he cannot sleep
without his fan.
Uh, fan. Fan. Uh...
Well, I'm not sure if...
Oh, yeah.
- We got it.
- Okay.
Now we just got to figure out
how to put it together.
What was that?
Uh, uh, I don't know.
I didn't...
I didn't hear anything.
Did you hear anything,
Farouk?
The door falling!
Shh. No. No, he didn't...
He didn't hear anything, either.
Mm-hmm.
- Incoming!
- Aah!
You're gonna kill me
one of these days.
Oh, you love it.
So, are we done fighting?
You tell me.
Come here.
- We're going to Fallujah.
- Hmm?
We're going to Fallujah!
Mnh-mnh.
Uh-huh.
I prefer the relative
safety of Baghdad...
and this bed.
No. No. I can't be late.
I can't be late. Not today.
Oh, right. Your thing.
The, um, the strack?
The strap? Strack?
Strat!
As in stratification.
As in if I don't get
ranked number one,
I can kiss flight surgeon
goodbye, so...
You weren't supposed to
find that.
I know it's not exactly a ring,
but, as I recall,
you... you lost your class ring
in the surgical sink, so...
Not a ring?
Don't you dare do the thing,
unless you are doing the thing.
Oh, my God. You are doing it.
Megan Eloise Hunt,
will you... Yes!!
Yes. Yes.
Let's go!
Come on!
What kept you?!
I said yes!
- What?!
- Aah!
And I asked her
to marry me!
- Aah! Congratulations!
- About time!
Mwah!
Oh, wait.
Look. Look, look.
Wow! An engagement
necklace?
Wow.
That's interesting.
Yeah, well, she loses everything
that's not tied to her, so...
Malibu... it's too far
away, and it's too snooty.
You're gonna hate it.
And Seattle has beaches.
Freezing-cold beaches.
Not the same.
Nathan found a job yet?
He will.
And if he doesn't, I'm sure
I could find some pole work.
- Megan.
- I will come home for Christmas.
And you'll come
visit me a lot,
which will be so good
for you because, you know...
the sun.
I'll miss you, Eeyore.
Come here.
- Okay.
Bye.
Colonel's convoy inbound.
All right, gents.
Chins up, backs straight.
Stand with dignity,
not sloppiness.
I'm talking to you,
Sergeant!
Yes, sir,
Major Diamond, sir!
I just don't
want to be ranked last.
Tubs failed his PT test.
He's last.
We're all gunning
for second place anyway.
You know Hunt's stratted
number one.
The best will be first,
so, yeah, you're right.
Wish my brother
was the C.O.
Your mom could be C.O.
and you'd still be last.
At-ten-hut!
At ease.
Excellent work,
Major Hunt.
Before I get started
on this tour,
let's get to what
you all really want to know...
My strat rankings.
It was a difficult decision,
but join me in congratulating
Lieutenant John Matthews.
♪♪
Talon 1 to Sparrow.
We have an emergency inbound. Copy?
Talon 1, copy that.
Marine FOB Ace Hole
reports two active shooters.
We have four KIA and
20 wounded headed your way.
Copy that.
We'll be ready. Out.
All surgeons on deck!
Frontload supplies! Fall out!
♪♪
We have
- What are you doing?
- I'm coming with you.
What?
Road trip.
Are you serious?
You said you wanted
to beat traffic.
What are you waiting for?
Drive!
Are you sure about this?
I can just drop you at the corner.
Shut up. I love road trips.
Since when?
Since we were kids.
Roadtripping with Mom and Dad.
You used to hate
those trips!
We... We would fight
so much
that Mom and Dad would threaten
to leave us at a gas station.
Well, fortunately,
we're grown-ups now.
How do you work
this radio?
I'm just saying...
I don't need a babysitter.
I am not a babysitter,
I'm a copilot.
Here to
ensure you don't fall asleep,
swerve off a cliff
to a fiery death.
We're driving straight through.
No detours.
Whatever you say.
I'm just along for the ride.
♪♪
Superficial laceration.
See that nurse over there
for steri-strips.
Matthews is top strat?
What the hell happened?
- The Colonel has the final say.
- Go. How hard did you push?
Did you tell him that
I was CGO of the year?
Of course! You know how
political these things are.
I'm never gonna get
flight-surgeon training now.
- Okay, let's go.
- Come on, guys! Come on through!
PFC Tyler Budreaux.
Pulse 90s, BP 100s over 50s.
I'd salute you, sir,
but I can't feel my arm.
What happened out there?
Two of the Iraqi allies
went rogue. Opened fire.
Tyler pushed people
out of the way.
You're looking at a
freakin' American hero, sir.
I really do need
my arm, sir.
We're gonna do
everything we can.
Hang two grams of cefazolin
and get him prepped for the O.R.
Stop! Stop! She doesn't...
Wait! Stop!
Don't touch her! She doesn't
want to be touched by men!
Hey, listen.
I got this. You go.
Hey, hey, I got it. Here.
Get out of the way.
"GSW upper right chest.
Diminished breathing sounds."
She needs a chest tube.
All right.
Let me take a look.
- Where do you want him?
- Shrapnel wound. Pre-op.
What do we have?
Nadir al-Jabouri.
Multiple GSWs to the torso.
Perp believed to be
the second shooter.
- And he's still alive?
- Unfortunately.
You treat that woman well.
'Cause she saved
everyone's ass!
Tried to wrestle
his gun from him.
He needs an ex lap.
O.R. ASAP. Let's go.
- Nathan, scrub in with me?
- You got it.
Let's go! Let's go!
We'll make your bed
a racecar,
so you can go really fast
in your dreams.
A race car?
Yeah, you know,
like NASCAR or Formula 1?
It's a car that goes
really, really fast.
- My bed?
- Trust me, it's cool.
Then where will
Mama sleep?
Well, in her room. Our room.
It's just across the hall.
But back home, we used to
sleep in the same room.
It's safer that way.
This is home now,
buddy.
Hey, I know
it's an adjustment, okay?
But once you start school,
you're gonna feel settled.
Mama has always been
my teacher
Well, now she
won't need to be.
You're gonna get to go to school
with a bunch of kids your own age.
You're gonna make
lots of friends.
Maybe join the band, you know?
You can play sports.
Soccer, baseball.
You're gonna love it.
I'm sorry! So sorry!
It's okay. It's okay.
But you got bare feet. Hang on.
There you go.
You're all right.
See? Not a problem.
That really is
a beautiful necklace
that you got for Megan.
Where'd you find
emeralds in Baghdad?
You want one
for yourself?
You seem awfully stuck
on it.
It just reminds me
so much of the necklace
that Sergeant Philips got
from her boyfriend back home.
You know...
Felicia Philips?
Well, but hers in engraved
with her initials on the back.
It's engraved?
Yep.
Ten blade.
♪ Can't you hear
that music pumpin' hard ♪
♪ Like I wish you would? ♪
♪ Now push it ♪
♪ Ner, ner-ner,
ner-ner, enh ♪
♪ Push it good! ♪
♪ P-Push it real good! ♪
Hey, open these for me,
will ya?
Ew! No.
What? There's no
food in that food.
- I'm starving!
- You can eat next time we stop for gas.
♪♪
♪ Get up on this ♪
Please return
to the highlighted route.
Uh, what she said.
Shortcut.
To what? The place where
unsuspecting teenagers
get picked off
one by one?
Come on.
Don't you trust me?
♪ You really got me going,
you got me so ♪
Fine.
♪ I don't know what I'm doing ♪
On the one hand,
I could hug you.
On the other hand...
I'm scared.
Yeah.
You used to love this place.
Uh, that was before
it was haunted.
You know, I just thought
you'd want a ring-toss rematch,
since you used to always lose
and cry and say that I cheated.
Uh, you did cheat.
Whatever helps you sleep
at night.
One game.
Okay.
Okay. Oh, my gosh.
This brings back
so many memories!
Okay, it's over here.
Oh, remember this?
No? Okay.
No. I don't want
to undress.
I hate to be naked
in front of strangers, too,
but I can't help you
if you don't let me.
My name is Megan.
What's yours?
Sana.
It's... It's Sana.
It doesn't look too bad.
Go ahead and place a chest tube.
Hey, you were...
You were great with her.
Yeah, right? It's almost like
I know how to do my job.
Hey, uh...
How about you scrub in
on my mangled arm?
Oh, God. Don't.
Don't what?
My dream was just crushed.
A pity party
isn't going to fix it.
I-I just figured
it'd be nice to talk,
you know, celebrate
the good things in life,
which still exist,
despite the strat.
Like, how Mom's head's gonna
explode planning two weddings.
- Two weddings?
- Come on.
Maybe Mom can plan your divorce
while she's at it.
You're gonna need more
packing in the left upper quadrant.
This spleen is shattered.
More lap pads!
Of all the stupid,
selfish, moronic,
and completely
preventable...
Okay, this is not our place to
judge, Dr. Altman, just repair.
I'm not talking about him.
You don't know
the whole story.
He opened fire on the
people he loved, who loved him.
That's betrayal.
And no amount of
rationalization
makes it okay.
Suction!
No, that's an...
No, that's an
entry-level position.
I have both field experience
and NGO lead work.
Excuse me. I need this one.
I'm not sure what you call it.
Okay, that's
a screwdriver, buddy.
Well, you're gonna
have to do better.
I can't find this
in the tools.
Yeah? Well, uh-huh.
Well, that can't be
all the local hospitals.
And I'm not gonna take
less than what I'm worth.
Why am I paying you a commission
if you're not getting me
what it is that
I'm expecting you to get?
- But...
- Yes.
- Ah, lucky shot. Lucky.
- Boom!
I just hooked
a tetanus-riddled ring
around the last bottle
standing.
- That's not luck.
- Mm-hmm. Okay.
Uh, I get this,
and I control the music
for the rest of the trip.
Uh, that's a lot
of Kenny Loggins.
Miss, miss, miss, miss!
- Ugh!
- Oh!
Okay, um,
if I make this,
you have to wear ugly sweaters
for all of Christmas.
Okay.
- Ugh!
- Phew.
Uh, okay.
I get this and...
you stay in Seattle.
Yeah.
Yes! Mm!
Okay, looks like we
have to turn around now.
Unbelievable.
- Megan, I'm kidding.
- You're not kidding.
This is the whole reason
you came.
You're blowing this
out of proportion.
You think you know
what's best for me,
ever since we were kids,
whether it's what I want or not.
- Lifeguarding?
- You're not a good swimmer.
Serving. Excuse me for
not wanting
my sister to get shot at.
- My strat!
- Your strat?!
You still playing dumb
about it?
That was 10 years ago,
Megan!
And I got kidnapped before
we could fight about it!
2-0 silk tie.
So it's settled.
Tonight you'll call Beth
and tell her that you're done.
One less wedding
for Mom to worry about.
It's not that simple, Megan.
Okay, maybe
it's that simple.
You know I'm right.
We'll see. Scissors.
You know, I was gonna miss
this... working together.
Your flight-surgeon training
was gonna tie you up for months.
And for what?
Tying tourniquets
with Special Forces
somewhere three times
as dangerous as here.
Ask me,
you dodged a bullet.
You recommended me,
didn't you?
He's lost more blood than we thought.
Let's get him stabilized.
You know
it wasn't my decision.
Carnival?
That sounds fun.
Or maybe not.
All right, well, we'll be here
with the lights on, babe.
Drive safe.
Hey, Farouk, Megan's
gonna be a little late,
but I got good news!
Found your screwdriver.
Farouk?
Hey, buddy?
Farouk!
Hey! Farouk!
Hey, hey! Have you guys seen a little
boy go by? About 10 years old?
We need to pack, shunt,
and get out of here.
No. I want to do a reversed
saphenous vein graft.
Not with these vitals.
The best we can do
is get the limb perfused
and get him stabilized.
The graft will take too long,
and it's too risky.
I know you don't think
that I'm qualified.
But this is the right call.
He wants to save the arm.
Not at the expense
of his life.
I am more experienced.
I outrank you.
So, we're gonna do things my...
Megan, what the hell?!
Betadine!
Well, you have to stop for food
at some point.
Not hungry.
Hey.
Yeah. It's fine.
Uh, what's up?
Just checking what time
you'll be home for dinner.
I'm sorry.
I-I decided to drive with Megan,
and I completely forgot to call.
I-I didn't want her
driving alone.
So...
We're having a blast.
Yeah.
Okay. Bye.
Are there any women in your life
you don't lie to?
♪ You've
got to know when to hold 'em ♪
♪ Know when to fold 'em ♪
♪ Know when to walk away
and know... ♪
Excuse me.
Farouk. Buddy.
You can't just
run off like that.
You had me terrified.
Is everything okay?
You were very busy.
I thought I could help.
I thought I could
get us some food,
but there's
just so many choices!
Yeah.
Okay. Bleeding's
controlled over here. Clip.
Yep, same here.
Irrigation.
- Say he regrets it.
- Pardon?
He made a huge mistake. He hurt
the people he cares about most.
But say he regrets it.
He was scared,
stupid, and wrong,
and now he can feel
everything slipping away
and he'll do anything he can
to make it right again.
I'd say too bad
he didn't think about that
before pulling the trigger.
He's still hypotensive. We need to
cut our losses and get out of here!
Start the pressors. Would you stop
being so dramatic and help me sew?
Well, stop being so pig-headed
and listen to me sometimes!
Shut up! Please. Sir.
I'm almost there.
Clamps off.
He gets to keep his arm
and his life.
- Yeah!
- Whoo!
That was... impressive.
I wish it didn't come
as such a surprise.
You can finish the rest.
I put thousands of hours in
to become the best.
The best at central lines.
The best at one-handed ties.
The best military officer.
I had my entire career planned.
I was gonna attach to Special
Forces and become a general.
Your qualifications
were not up for debate.
So you had to convince them
that I was wrong for the job?
All I had to do was tell them
the truth. That you're a child.
That you make
rash, reckless decisions,
and you never learn better because
I'm always there to bail you out!
If you'd gone
with Special Forces,
you wouldn't have made general.
You'd have been
dead in under a month!
And 10 years later,
what have you learned? Nothing.
You're running
from your family.
You're running from
your support system.
And why?
Because you like the beach?!
That's not a plan, Megan.
That's a whim.
So, yes,
I tanked your strat.
If I had to do it over,
I would do the same damn thing!
So... So, you're just gonna
punish me like you always do
when I tell you
something you don't like.
Fine.
But you can't think of
anything to say
because you know
that I'm right.
And, for the record,
this is the childish behavior
I was talking about.
- Diamond.
- Excuse me?
Your nickname.
In Baghdad. Remember?
Major Diamond.
Yes.
Know why they
called you that?
Well, they told me...
Sharp, clear, focused.
Anal-retentive.
High-strung.
So uptight that if you
put coal in your ass,
a diamond would pop out.
You thought
it was a compliment.
Which only
made it funnier.
Like I said. A child.
And, for the record,
I came up with it.
Sorry I never told you,
but, you know,
since we're coming clean.
- More choices!
- Yeah, but it's not always a bad thing.
I mean, just try
a little of each
and see which ones
you like.
You dig?
Yeah.
Can you keep a secret?
I'm a little terrified
about starting over down here.
In a new town.
New family.
I don't even have a job, and I want
everything to be perfect for Megan,
but it took me half a day
to put a door on.
So... what will you do?
Well...
I guess I'm gonna
have to be okay
with not knowing
all the answers.
You know,
count on the fact
that we love Megan
and she loves us
and just trust that together,
the three of us,
we can figure
this thing out.
Can you teach me
baseball?
Yeah, sure.
I can teach you baseball.
As soon as I learn
how to play.
That's all
we can do for now.
He'll make transport.
And if he's lucky,
they'll fly him to Baghdad.
Yeah. If he's lucky.
How could you
do this to her?
I don't know.
We were fighting...
You were fighting,
so you proposed to her
with your side piece's
stolen property?
No. Look.
Felicia's not...
It was a one-time thing.
What am I gonna do,
Teddy?
Did you mean it?
The proposal?
Of course.
Look. Megan...
Okay, we fight.
But she's the one.
Okay? I was gonna tell her
about Felicia.
I was gonna come clean.
And then she found the necklace.
And I... I panicked.
- Well, she's gonna find out.
- I know.
And if it comes from
anyone but you...
I know.
Well, so...
you have your answer.
Well, you think
there's a chance?
Well, she's got a temper,
and she has every right
to be angry.
And when Owen finds out, he is
gonna snap your neck.
- Yeah.
- But...
people mess up.
And people forgive.
It's what most pop songs and
most modern literature is about,
so, yes, Nathan...
tell her the truth,
and there's a chance.
It was wrong of me to get in
the way of your career.
It was none of my business.
I was out of line.
It was just... just wrong.
And I'm sorry.
Thank you.
But it doesn't change the fact that
Seattle schools are excellent.
Oh, my God!
Give it a rest!
Nathan already has a job there,
plus it's safer, familiar.
Closer to family.
Whoa. What are you doing?
Get out!
Get out of my car, Owen!
Stop being ridiculous.
- No! Get out!
- Stop it!
What do you mean,
Megan's not coming?
Well, she thinks you tanked
her strat. She's mad.
Well, I hope you told her
she was crazy.
- Is she?
- Oh, great. Not you, too?
I'm just asking.
I'm not accusing.
You know what?
She got engaged.
You'd think she'd want to
live a safe, happy life.
Plan a wedding, maybe.
Is that such a crazy thought?
God! She wanted
that strat, Owen.
It's all she thinks about.
And she was so close.
Do you know how hard it is
to stand by
and watch someone else
live the life that you want?
The life that you're willing
to give up everything for?
You're an idiot!
Major,
we need to head out!
Well, make sure Megan
rides back with you guys.
I can only tolerate
so many tantrums.
Get out!
Get out! I mean it!
- Stop this.
- No.
If you can't support me,
then you can hitchhike.
- Because I am done. Get out!
- Stop it!
I'm not leaving you again!
You have to stop
doing this.
You... You can't keep making
decisions for me, Owen.
'Cause you are making
a bad decision.
You are the only one
who thinks that.
Nathan's the reason
we lost you in the first place.
You don't know what
you're talking about!
He cheated on you and now you're
starting a family with him?
And you cheated
on your first wife.
Mom told me all about it.
And don't even get me started
on you and Teddy.
So spare me
the "holier than thou" crap.
You cheated, Nathan cheated.
It happens.
Life happens.
People are imperfect.
We fail and we fall, and some of
us get kidnapped for a decade,
and when we get a second chance
at life and happiness,
we seize it,
regardless of who cheated!
Because now we know
what matters.
what's precious.
Because now we know that
any tiny little moment
of happiness
that we can grab onto
in this lifetime
is a moment worth having,
regardless of what
anyone else thinks.
And just for the record,
you judgmental jackass,
I cheated on Nathan first!
Hey.
- What's wrong?
- I'm sorry. I, um...
I need
that necklace back.
Damn it. Damn it!
- Just hear me out.
- Okay, what did he say?
No. You know what?
It doesn't matter.
It was a drunken mistake.
You and I were fighting,
and I was gonna tell you...
Whoa, whoa. Hang on a second.
What are you saying?
W-What do you think
I'm saying?
Well, it sounds like
you slept with someone.
Isn't that why you want
the necklace back?
No! It...
Then what?
W-Wasn't mine to give.
You proposed to me with
some other chick's necklace?!
God, Nathan!
What is wrong with you?!
Okay, you're not the only one that
gets to be mad right now, okay?
You cheated, too.
You just said.
I know what I said.
I have been showing
that thing off all day.
This is so humiliating.
Did you even mean it?
Of course. Did you?
Lieutenant Hunt, we're having
a problem with your patient.
On my way.
The chest tube started coming out
when we were transferring her.
All I have to do
is reposition it,
but if we give her any more
morphine for the pain,
we're gonna
have to intubate.
Got it. I got it.
Sana, you can get through this.
Okay? Listen to me.
I need you to breathe.
It hurts. I can't.
Focus on
something else, okay?
I want you to tell me about your
neighborhood, your family, job, kids.
- Do you have any kids?
- Aah!
Okay, I'm gonna tell you
about my family.
The tall, red-headed guy
yelling at everybody?
That's my brother. He drives me
crazy most of the time.
No, all of the time.
That sounds like my brother.
Yeah?
He is my heart.
He means well.
Yeah.
Yeah. Mine too.
Let's get her
on the next chopper!
I'm on it!
- Major Hunt.
- Hi. It's me.
I need to ride back
on the medical chopper.
My patient's
freaking out.
Well, you know
that's against protocol.
And...
Nathan cheated on me.
He what?
So I really don't want
to have to ride back with him,
but if I-it's
against protocol...
Screw protocol.
Get on the chopper.
- Are you sure?
- It's my call, and I'm sure.
That son of a bitch.
Okay.
Thanks, Owen.
How you feeling?
Like a truck hit me.
But happy to be alive,
ma'am.
I wonder if they'll electrocute
him here or fly him back home.
Why are they
talking that way?
He was the second shooter.
They're pretty upset.
No, he wasn't. Second shooter
was an Iraqi woman.
This guy was trying
to stop her.
It's all good.
You're gonna be okay.
Megan! Megan!
Megan! Stop!
Stop! Megan!!
Stop it!
♪♪
Eagle 2, return... base.
Repeat!
Eagle 2,
return to base immediately!
Riggs never said anything.
All this time.
Yeah. Well...
he's a good guy.
Yeah.
You remember
that family trip we took,
somewhere in California,
when I left the map
at the rest-stop bathroom?
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
How could I forget?
Dad was furious.
And he refused to pull over
and ask for directions.
Yep.
And after him and Mom arguing
for hours and us complaining,
he finally said,
"Screw it!"
And he just,
like, pulled over.
And we played in the water for
hours until the sun went down.
I don't even remember
where we were going,
but... I just...
I've never forgotten
that beach.
On my hardest days,
I would lose myself in that memory.
Pretend that the desert sand
was the beach,
that the screams and yelling were
laughter and sea gulls.
And I could fake everything
but the water.
And I promised myself,
if I ever get out...
I am going to live
by the ocean, in California,
and I'm gonna feel
that water every day.
I always imagined us raising our
families together, you know?
Next door, or a few blocks,
near Mom and Dad.
Camping trips
and cookouts.
Dad's gone, Owen.
And you don't have
any kids.
How exactly would
that dream work out?
You are the most loyal person
I have ever known.
But you're loyal
to ideas, too.
Ideas and ideals.
My beach plan
makes me happy.
Like, "I can feel it
in my fingers" happy.
I want that for you.
I want to see you happy.
And that might mean that
you're gonna have to break up
with some of your ideals.
♪♪
Yeah.
♪ Hanging by a thread ♪
♪ Waiting for a hand
to pull me up ♪
♪ Falling down instead ♪
♪ Nowhere left to land ♪
♪ It's all you get ♪
♪ For holding on ♪
♪ To something
that will never come ♪
♪ Am I holding on ♪
♪ To something
that will never come? ♪
♪ I don't have
enough heartbeats left ♪
♪ To spare them on somebody ♪
♪ Spare them on somebody ♪
♪ Who never planned
to see the moments pass ♪
I...
was promised
move-in ready.
Mm.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Welcome home.
Oh.
♪ Footprints in the sand
remind us that we can ♪
How was your day?
Yeah, it was...
It was pretty okay.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
You raised a great kid.
♪ Light, it turns to dust ♪
♪ And leaves because
it must evaporate ♪
Thanks.
Where's Owen?
I dropped him off
at the airport.
He said
he'll come visit soon.
♪ To something
that's already gone ♪
♪ Am I holding on ♪
♪ To something
that's already gone? ♪
♪ I don't have
enough heartbeats left ♪
♪ To spare them on somebody ♪
♪ Spare them on somebody
who never planned to see ♪
When we've come
to depend on a cycle,
the thought of breaking it
is scary.
♪ Now until forever ♪
♪ Now until our last breath ♪
- Hey.
- You're back.
- Yeah.
Even the cycles
that cause us harm.
Oh.
Amelia, I'm so sorry.
You married a tumor.
I get it.
It just...
It feels like
we don't know each other.
Yeah, I know.
I just want us
to be happy.
- And we're...
- We're not happy.
I know.
It's okay, Owen.
But sometimes,
when we break the cycle...
♪ Da-da, da-da-da ♪
♪ Da, da-da-da, da, da ♪
we find something better.
♪ Da-da, da-da-da ♪
Something unexpected.
♪ Da, da-da-da, da, da ♪
♪ Da-da, da-da-da ♪
Something we never dared
to dream was possible.
♪ Da-da, da-da-da ♪
Aah!
- Get her!
- Aah!
♪ Ah-ah ♪
♪ Ohh-ohh-oh ♪
We find freedom.
♪ Ohh-ahh ♪
♪ Ohh ♪
♪ Ahh-ohh ♪
♪ Ohh-ohh ♪
♪♪
We find peace.
*GREY'S ANATOMY*
Season 14   Episode 05
Title: "Danger Zone"