- Previously on The Resident...
- How are your surgical error
and complication rates?
Transparency and accountability
force us to weed out the
bad and grow the good.
- How you doing today, Lily?
- Dr. Hunter caught my cancer
when other doctors missed it.
She's the only
person that I trust.
As of this moment,
you are no longer
going to be assigned
to any of my patients.
♪ ♪
Oh, don't worry
about it. Don't worry...
Hey, move, move, move!
Oh, God...
Hang on, we're almost
at Atlanta General.
No, not Atlanta
General. Chastain Park.
Dr. Hawkins. I want
Conrad Hawkins!
Breathe slow.
What's going on?
Lily's having a panic attack.
She's hyperventilating
a little bit.
She can't feel her
fingers and toes.
Cup your hands.
Breathe into them slowly.
She just had an
infusion at Lane's clinic.
Oh, God.
The chemo was
so strong this time.
I think it's gonna kill me.
I mean, she almost gave me
that bone marrow transplant.
I wouldn't have
survived it, right?
Probably not, because
your kidneys were impaired.
But she said it was the only way
to save my life,
and-and now she's saying
that this last round of
chemo could cure me,
but... both those things
can't be true, can they?
Lily, remember when I suggested
you get a second opinion?
You can still do it...
A different oncologist
can examine your whole case
and make sure the doses and drugs
you're getting are appropriate...
Nic can give you a referral.
She worked for a great
oncologist, Dr. Osder.
Yes, and I would
trust her with my life.
She's careful,
conservative, brilliant.
And I can call her
right now if you want.
They need me in the ER.
I've got her.
35-year-old female with
severe right-lower quadrant
abdominal pain and
vomiting since this morning.
She's tachy and diaphoretic.
- Let's move her to Trauma Two.
- Catherine?
Conrad?
- What do we got?
- Could be an appy?
No, she had her
appendix out in high school.
- Catherine?
- Pulse is weak,
- but it's still there.
- All right.
Probably vagalled from the pain.
Bolus her a liter
and send a GI panel
with a stat hematocrit and EKG.
- Right away.
- Conrad...
Conrad?
♪ ♪
Thank you so much for picking
these guys up from the shelter.
Oh, my gosh, they're adorable.
Look at these little
faces... How can you resist?
I'm not a dog person.
Or a cat person.
Or a people person.
But the kids in pediatric
are going to love them.
- Hey, you got that?
- Yeah.
All right you guys.
- Oh!
- Guys...
- Look, a dog!
- A puppy!
I want a puppy.
Hey, guys,
I want you to be really,
really, really gentle
with the puppies, okay?
This is mine.
Here's Donut.
- Doggy, doggy, doggy!
- Be gentle.
- I have Jellybean.
- And Jellybean, Brownie.
- Do you guys want Brownie?
- I want to hold him.
You do? Okay, you can take it.
This is Cookie.
Yeah, there you go.
That's Lifesaver.
Yeah, they're little.
Thank you.
- Jellybean!
- Oh.
Oh, see hold his head down.
Jellybean!
- Oh. You got kissed.
- Jellybean.
Oh, sweetie.
Oh, don't fall.
I'm getting hyperglycemic.
Too much sugar.
Go, and thank you so much.
That's okay. They
growl sometimes.
- Yeah?
- Okay, remember to hold it...
There, you see. Lift
him back over this way.
Oh, my goodness.
What are you doing
here, you little darling?
Mmm. Oh.
Ah, ready to get some fresh
air in the courtyard, Edna?
Oh, I'd rather just go to
my room today, Harold.
Can't do. Doctor's orders.
Look at this face, though.
I want this one so much.
All five are available
- for adoption.
- Five.
I only see four.
Lifesaver, Jellybean,
Brownie, Donut.
Where's Cookie?
- Where's Cookie?
- Aw!
- Ah. Wow.
- Cookie!
I'm gonna check the hallway.
You're in charge, okay?
- Where is Cookie?!
- We'll find her.
- We'll find her. We'll find her.
- Cookie! Cookie!
She had rapid infusion,
but I think we should up
- her meds.
- Okay. Good.
Maybe up to 500 milligrams?
Yeah, that would work.
- What's concerning me is...
- Oh.
Welcome back. You
fainted from the pain.
We've given you some morphine.
You should be feeling better.
Thank heavens you were here.
What has it been?
Like, ten years?
Eleven.
Not that I'm counting.
I just moved back
to Atlanta last month.
I heard that you were,
um, working here.
When did the pain start?
It's been off and on
for about a-a month.
I haven't been able to keep
anything down, and then,
last night, it just
became unbearable.
My husband's been
away, so I was all alone.
It's lower.
I remember when you
got that... in El Paso.
We stole my mom's
car, and drove all night.
- Mm.
- We were gonna hit Mexico and keep going.
I didn't even have
my driver's license.
I don't know if I've ever
done anything more romantic.
That joy ride got me a
one-way ticket to military school,
but I liked it better
than living with my dad.
Remember when he
called me trailer trash?
He'd eat his words
now. You look amazing.
- Hey.
- Catherine,
this is Nurse
Practitioner Nic Nevin.
Nic, Catherine Loy.
We're admitting her for
acute abdominal pain.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear.
Nice to meet you, Catherine.
We're old friends.
Oh, it's a bit more
complicated than that.
Conrad was my fiancé.
I haven't seen
Catherine in 11 years.
She's happily married.
- Can we talk about this?
- You mean the fact that there's
this whole other part of your
life that you never mentioned?
- Nope, not my business.
- Nic.
Let's talk about Dr. Hunter.
Okay. What about her?
Lily's finally safe. Dr. Osder
will take care of her, but
what about her other patients?
You're the only one who
can keep an eye on them
since she doesn't
trust Devon anymore.
Fine. Leave it to me. I'll
do whatever I have to do
- to stay in her good graces.
- Cool. Thanks.
- That's a great idea.
- Terrific, yeah...
Lane? Lane?
Do you got a second?
Of course. What
can I do for you?
I owe you an apology.
I undercut you
with your patient.
I encouraged him
to stop treatment
when you still
had help to offer.
I was way out of line.
It's been bothering me a lot.
I'm sorry.
I've been thinking a
lot about that case, too.
I always say, never give
up, but sometimes, I ought to.
I don't agree.
You've pulled off
some miraculous cures.
I've also seen a lot of people
that should have gone home
die alone in our ICU, getting
chemo that wasn't working.
The tricky part is that
you just never know
who can beat the odds.
Trying to make that call
must be incredibly hard on you.
It is... actually.
No one thinks about
the effect on doctors
when they have to
watch their patients suffer.
That bone marrow transplant
I almost gave to Lily...
I wake up in a cold sweat
every night thinking about it.
- No one is perfect.
- I have to be.
There's too much at stake.
I cannot make
mistakes like that ever.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry
for getting emotional.
Not at all.
You care.
That's why you're
a great doctor.
Oh. Thank you.
Thank you, Conrad.
I'll see you later.
I lost two pounds.
That was the foot, Chad.
Comfort food.
You're diabetic.
This isn't on your
approved diet.
You're my doctor, not my nanny.
I can't help you if you
don't help yourself.
Look, I'm not married.
I don't have a girlfriend.
I live with my mother.
There's only one thing that gets
me out of bed in the morning...
A Belgian waffle with
whipped cream on it.
Food can be an addiction.
It is my job to get
you on a diet plan
and a new exercise program.
Um...
maybe next time.
Where's my foot?
Come on, Edna,
where's the puppy?
I don't know what you mean.
I saw you put Cookie
under your lap blanket.
I found her in the hall.
But when Harold took me outside
to the courtyard, she got away.
I couldn't catch her.
All right. I'll call security
and see if they can
look for her outside.
This is just awful.
Oh!
Precious. Mm.
Hey!
Yes. We love you.
Do you understand
how serious this is?
I'm the healthiest fat
guy you've ever seen.
You aren't healthy,
Chad. You have diabetes
and worsening peripheral
vascular disease.
When am I cutting
off your other foot?
- Never.
- We'll get it for sure
if you don't shape up.
Might have to take the
next one above the knee.
Start picking out a wheelchair.
She always like that?
Pretty much.
Check out these puppies.
You could take one home.
A dog is a great way to
start a walking program.
He needs a forever home.
- You need an exercise buddy.
- Oh.
Oh! Well, either he likes me
or he tastes chocolate frosting.
His name is Donut.
Karma.
They'd've named
him Quinoa, no deal.
How you feeling?
I'm flying high on
some pretty fine drugs.
We'll have to adjust those,
because I have some news.
You're pregnant.
Are you sure?
I'm positive.
Oh, my God, that's fantastic.
We've been trying
for almost two years.
We even tried IVF,
but nothing worked.
I cannot wait to...
tell my husband.
Excellent.
The OB team is coming in to
make sure all is well with the baby.
They'll do an ultrasound,
see how far along you are.
Check the baby's heart.
I'm also ordering an X-ray
to check your abdomen.
Is that... is that
safe for the baby?
Absolutely.
Conrad...
you have no idea
what this means to me.
I have a damn good idea.
We both came
from broken families.
You always wanted
kids of your own.
I'm so happy for you.
Go on.
Ask me anything.
I know you want to.
Why didn't you marry her?
She left me after I punched
my father in the nose
- at the rehearsal dinner.
- Wow.
He told Catherine I
didn't really love her
and that the marriage was gonna
be a disaster, so I decked him.
Right in front of the
guests, including her family.
No, you didn't.
I did. And I had a
fine time doing it, but...
Kate was afraid he was right.
And how do you
feel about her now?
I did love her.
I don't love her anymore.
But I care about her very
much, and I want to fix her.
Congratulations.
Your divorce is final.
Highway robbery.
Well, I hope you made
a bundle on the house.
I barely paid off the
mortgage. I bought it in 2008
at the height of the market, and
now I'll be shelling out alimony
for the next ten years.
What's this?
My bill. It's three
months past due.
I'm sorry, Randolph, but...
we're gonna have to
start charging interest.
♪ ♪
OB says she's six weeks
and four days by ultrasound.
Normal intrauterine pregnancy.
Good cardiac
activity in the 150s.
What do you think
I'm looking for?
All her symptoms
say bowel obstruction.
Gold star, Harvard.
Now, tell me, what do you see?
Dilated bowel loops
and air fluid levels
consistent with an SBO.
Surgery?
Standard of care is
non-op management first.
And abdominal surgery on a
pregnant woman? That's risky.
Priya's here.
I don't think you've
formally met yet.
Priya, this is Dr. Conrad
Hawkins and Nic Nevin.
- Thank you for helping us,
Priya.
- Of course.
Priya is a journalist, and she's
researching a cancer
cluster for a story.
I asked her if she could
find any information
- on Dr. Hunter's patients.
- I used
social media posts to find
people Dr. Hunter treated,
and I ended up talking
to about 15 people.
- What did you find?
- All of them
had good things to
say about Dr. Hunter.
Many repeated the same
line. "She saved my life."
Did any of the patients
have health problems
that were caused by the doses?
Two had heart damage.
One was infertile.
Bone density decreased.
One man lost all his teeth.
None of that is
unusual with chemo.
The most amazing thing I found
was four patients
had a total remission
for cancers that are
considered incurable.
I don't believe it.
Total remissions for
cancers that are incurable?
I mean, it sounds incredible.
And it does show we
have a steep hill to climb.
Miraculous cures can be
used to justify her doses.
I get it. She's your mentor.
- But you got to trust me.
- I talked to her,
and she seemed genuinely
crushed by the error
she almost made with
Lily. She cried, Nic.
- She cried? She is an excellent liar.
- Yes.
And she will be just that good
on the stand if we get that far.
We have to be careful.
Lane is highly respected.
She makes millions
of dollars for Chastain.
If we take her on and lose,
our careers will be over.
I can't believe you're worried
about your career right now.
All I'm saying is,
if by some chance
that second opinion
comes back in Lane's favor,
don't do anything until
we get more information.
People could be dying,
Conrad, and you want me to wait
for more information? I thought
you knew me better than that.
But then again, why should I
be surprised? Since, apparently,
I never really knew you either.
It's too good to be true.
Something's wrong here.
Then I'll dig deeper.
And I'll cheer you up at dinner.
Do you have anything
special planned?
Today's the 28th, right?
30th.
Oh, Priya, you
should've said something.
I've been so busy at work
I completely lost track of time.
Happy birthday.
Whoa.
Mina,
where can I get an
amazing present for Priya
that I can have
delivered in two hours?
You're so asking
the wrong person.
I could order flowers, but...
I don't know... it's not
enough. It's her birthday.
I don't understand
about birthdays.
What does it matter
what day you were born?
It matters to every
woman I've ever known.
Not this one.
Mina, have you
ever been in love?
Don't do that. Don't
ask stupid questions.
- Too personal?
- No, no, not personal.
I said "stupid." You're a
doctor. You should know
that romantic love is just a
trick the brain plays on you
to get you to pump out babies.
Thank you for coming to
meet with me, Randolph.
It's always a pleasure,
Claire. What can I do for you?
Well, after our last board
meeting, I did some digging
and found out we're
doing a really poor job
at monitoring our own errors.
Surgical errors can be easily
covered up just by saying that
- they're complications.
- Well...
I think you can trust
the doctors at Chastain.
Apparently not.
According to Medscape,
21% of physicians feel it's okay
to hide a mistake
that harms a patient
under certain circumstances.
- That is shocking.
- Isn't it?
So I have decided
to shine a light
on the physicians
that have the highest
rate of complications
and get rid of them.
That's a radical move.
You know, to be brutally honest,
we cannot handle
one more lawsuit.
How can I help?
I have installed
recording devices
on every camera in every OR.
Starting today,
there will be no hiding
from problematic
performances or outcomes.
After you've rested a bit,
Dr. Pravesh is gonna place
a nasogastric tube
that will empty the
contents of your stomach.
It should relieve the pain
and hopefully
resolve the blockage.
It's not a pleasant procedure,
but there is a good chance
that it'll make it possible
for you to avoid surgery.
Let's redraw another
set of labs, and page me
as soon as we have the results.
Nic is gonna take
great care of you.
- Thank you so much.
- We'll catch up more later.
Okay.
Devon.
Conrad is so different.
He's nothing like the guy
I almost married.
Oh, yeah? What was he like?
He was a wild man.
A real rebel.
Which was, um,
part of the appeal.
But he was always
emotionally distant.
He, um... wouldn't let me in.
Sounds like he
hasn't changed at all.
No, he has.
He's so, um...
so grown-up
and, um, responsible and...
- gentle.
- Well, that is because
you're his patient.
Okay, you're gonna feel...
a little prick here.
There we go.
How long have you
been in love with him?
What makes you say that?
You're, um...
you're wearing the
ring he gave you.
Belonged to his mother.
Did you know that?
No.
He loved her very much.
You must mean
a great deal to him
if he gave it to you.
Lane Hunter.
Dr. Hunter.
This is Dr. Mary Osder.
I think we met
once at a conference
on advances in breast
cancer management.
Of course. You were the keynote.
How can I help you, Mary?
I've just had a call
from one of your patients
who's looking for
a second opinion.
Okay. Happy to help. Who is it?
Uh, Lily Kendall.
Well, that's surprising.
I mean, Lily's had a rough
road, but she's in the middle
of what we expect is
her final round of chemo.
Rough road, indeed.
I'll do a full
review of her case,
so I'll need her records.
Of course.
I'll get you everything from
her current treatment plan.
Well, you know as well as
I do that won't be sufficient.
I'll need everything
going back to her
original diagnosis
and the doctor who
first referred her.
Absolutely. Not a problem.
You know, Mary, I am
so glad she came to you.
Um, who can I
thank for this referral?
I believe she got my
name from a terrific nurse
I've known for several
years, Nic Nevin.
Are you ever in surgery?
You've been playing
with that dog all day.
I am in love with Lifesaver,
and I'm taking him home.
Puppies are way
better than boyfriends.
I'll take that one.
Jellybean?
This will definitely work.
- What's going on?
- Catherine's labs.
Not good. Her white
count and lactate.
Her bowels are
being strangulated.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Help me.
- Right here. I'm right here.
- Okay.
She's tachy at 137.
BP's dropping.
Diffuse guarding.
I think her intestines
are getting ischemic.
She needs emergency
exploratory surgery.
Who's on call for gen surg?
- Dr. Bell.
- Damn it.
And now they're calling
me to the ER. Devon?
I got it. Nic.
- Okay.
- Got it.
You're good. You're
good. You're good.
It's Lily Kendall. They
were called to her home.
She's hypotensive, vomiting.
They're having a hard time
getting her blood
pressure up with fluids.
She thinks it's a reaction
- to the chemo this morning.
- Lily.
It's Dr. Pravesh. We're
here for you, okay?
- What's her IV access?
- She got a 22 in her hand.
It's going really slow. We
couldn't get another line.
She feels cold.
Place a large bore
antecubital line and
bowl us two liters.
Send off a lactate
and blood cultures.
Grab cefepime
to cover for sepsis.
I need a warming
blanket over here.
- How is she?
- She's in shock.
We're waiting on labs, but she's
hypotensive and hypothermic.
We need to know exactly what
drugs she got and the dosages.
Of course. She's on HiDAC chemo.
Cytarabine, 3,000
milligrams per meter squared.
Catherine's being prepped
for surgery. What's going on?
It's Lily.
She had a severe reaction
to her chemo this morning.
We're admitting her.
Oh, God.
- Dr. Bell.
- I have to scrub in.
Who's the first woman
you ever fell in love with?
You on drugs?
What kind of question is that?
Your first great passion.
The one who changed your life.
- My first great passion...
- Mm-hmm.
Was surgery. My
father took me to see
an operation when
I was ten years old.
It's the only
love that's lasted.
My first great passion
is the woman you're
about to operate on tonight.
Who are you?
'Cause you're not
Conrad Hawkins.
Must be one of your
ham-fisted manipulations.
'Cause we don't talk like this,
and we're not
about to start now.
I understand why you can't
walk away. I get it.
But this woman is
deeply important to me,
and she's pregnant.
Two lives are at stake.
Well, let me spell
this out for you.
It's emergency surgery.
I contacted Jude.
He's already here.
He'll take it.
I have 30 years of
experience you can't match.
A lifetime of work
to testify to my ability.
You're a rank amateur
who deludes himself
that he's learned
to play the game, but
you just break things,
and that is gonna catch
up with you in the end.
I've done probably...
a thousand similar procedures.
Do I need to do one tonight?
Not particularly.
You owe me.
It was too much.
I-I don't want
any more chemo.
Hush, honey.
Every one of my patients
has said that at some point.
We'll talk tomorrow, okay?
Devon, come with me.
I'm going to stay with her.
Dr. Pravesh,
please help me.
I'm scared.
It's okay. You're safe now.
Nurse Nevin. Can
we talk for a moment?
- Sure.
- I was wondering
if you would take over
supervising Lily's care again.
Starting immediately.
I don't understand.
I-I know.
We started off
on the wrong foot,
and it was entirely my fault.
These last few weeks,
I've come to realize
that you're one of the
finest nurse practitioners
we have at Chastain.
Lily needs you.
And she deserves to have you.
Well, I'd do anything for Lily.
Thank you.
Thanks for coming in
- on your day off.
- Yeah, of course, man.
She's about six weeks
pregnant, so you'll need
to be extra careful
around the uterus.
I know what I'm doing.
Nic told me all about
her, okay? Don't stress.
I looked at the imaging.
I'll lyse the adhesions,
remove any of the
unhealthy segments,
and she can be
home in a couple days.
Wait.
About Nic...
Two women left me
for the same reason.
You deserve Nic.
You can give her what I can't.
Thank you.
All right.
Incise the peritoneum.
I'll fix this sucker.
Opening now.
Her-her abdomen.
It's filled with blood.
All right. Find where
it's coming from.
I can't tell.
I can't see a thing.
- Pressure's dropping.
- All right, stay calm, everyone.
I need lap pads, and
hook up more suction.
Call the blood bank now.
Suction.
What's happening?
She's bleeding internally.
It's not the bowel.
No ischemia.
Packing to find the source.
BP's down to 65.
Hang two units wide open.
Come on, come on. Go, go.
Come on.
Come on. Come on,
come on, come on.
We need more blood.
Call for the rapid infuser.
Activate the massive
transfusion protocol.
Checked the liver.
No, no bleeding.
No bleeding in the aorta
or IVC, either.
Come on.
Damn it.
Come on, we're losing her.
She has an ectopic.
It must have ruptured.
You said it was an
intrauterine pregnancy.
She has both. There's a second
pregnancy in the right tube.
I just saw it on the
ultrasound. OB missed it.
Check the pelvis.
He's right.
I see bleeding at
the right mesosalpinx.
Clamp.
Bleeding is controlled.
Pressure's back up to 95.
Make sure to continue
the transfusion protocol.
I'll page GYN.
Thanks.
And we will continue
to fix the obstruction.
That was a close one.
Yeah.
Hey.
I heard there was a
complication. Is she okay?
We almost lost her.
What happened?
She presented with an
ectopic ready to burst.
OB missed it, and it did.
In their defense, it was
entwined with the bowel.
That's super rare.
One in a 100,000?
Mina's gonna write
it up as a case report.
- Lily?
- She's doing better.
You here all night?
Yeah, I'll stay for them both.
Dr. Borden wanted
in Labor and Delivery.
Hey, Conrad?
Yeah.
When did your mom
give you this ring?
When I left for Afghanistan.
Why didn't you tell
me it belonged to her?
I wanted you to feel
like it was yours alone.
She said, "Give it to
the love of your life."
You want it back?
No.
You earned it.
Pulmonary nurse dial 3665.
Look at you sitting up.
And is that a smile?
Please, can I hold it?
Oh, my God, Cookie.
I've been looking
for this little girl all day.
Hello. Come here, baby.
That's her name? Cookie?
Yeah.
Well, this goes against
all rules, but I don't care.
Here you go. There you go.
Hi.
Can I keep her?
You can. She's all yours.
Hi.
Uh, Nic, I need you to give Lily
a liter with 40
milliequivalents of potassium.
You sure you want
to give her that much?
Her renal function just
started trending toward normal.
Thank you for being so vigilant,
but low potassium levels
are not good for Lily's heart.
Just give it to her slowly
over the entire shift
so she can handle it.
Okay. Got it.
I'm on my way out for the night.
Are you gonna be
around for a while?
Uh, I'm done in
the next 15 minutes,
but I'll make sure I
do this before I go.
Great. Thank you.
♪ Started out today ♪
♪ I feel alive and
the air has changed ♪
♪ I'm not alone ♪
♪ It's taken ages to ♪
♪ Find a way but I
made it through ♪
♪ I'm not alone ♪
♪ These are the days ♪
♪ And this is the
place where I belong ♪
♪ Lost in another world ♪
♪ I believe our time will come ♪
♪ We shift and we change ♪
♪ I took a long
time coming 'round ♪
♪ But I'm standing here ♪
♪ Still standing here ♪
♪ Are you waiting there? ♪
♪ I'm coming up for air... ♪
Mel, see you in
about a half hour.
All right.
- Randolph?
- Yeah.
I have a favor to ask you.
Okay.
Can I take you to dinner?
No. I'll take you.
Great.
Now?
♪ These are the days ♪
♪ And this is the
place where I belong ♪
♪ Lost in another world ♪
♪ I believe our time will come ♪
Oh!
- Hello.
- ♪ We shift and we change ♪
♪ I took a long
time coming 'round ♪
Hey.
Oh.
♪ But I'm standing ♪
♪ Still standing ♪
♪ Are you waiting there? ♪
♪ I'm coming up for air. ♪
Lily.
She's in V tach.
Pulse is thready.
- We need a crash cart now.
- Get her up.
Okay. Okay.
I'm dying. Please.
- Please help me.
- Stay with me. Stay with me.
I'm right here. I'm right here.
Stay with me. Stay with me.
Stay with me.
Let's get the pads on her.
Possible chemo-induced
cardiomyopathy.
Uh, go get her admission EKG.
Bolus 150 of amio
and start a drip.
We lost her pulse.
Charge to 200.
- Ready.
- Clear.
She's in V fib.
Continue CPR, push one of epi.
Her EKG was normal. This is...
Call for a stat echo. Hold CPR.
- No pulse.
- Still V fib on the monitor.
Charge to 300.
- Ready.
- Clear.
Charge to 360!
- Ready.
- Clear.
That was our third round.
Push 100 of lidocaine
and shock again at 360.
Shock again at 360!
Come on, come on, come on.
Come on with that
lidocaine, come on.
Come on.
- Ready.
- Clear.
Asystole.
I got it. I got it, I got it.
Dr. Hawkins?
Asystole for 20 minutes.
You got to call it.
You have to stop now.
Time of death...
21:58.
Captioned by Media
Access Group at WGBH