♪ It's beginning to look
a lot like Christmas ♪
♪ Everywhere you go ♪
♪ Take a look at the five
and ten, listening once again ♪
♪ With candy canes
and silver lanes a glow ♪
♪ It's beginning to look
a lot like Christmas ♪
♪ Christmas ♪
♪ Toys in every store ♪
♪ But the prettiest sight to
see is the holly that will be ♪
♪ On your own front door. ♪
Hi.
Hi. I was starting to think
you weren't coming.
Dr. Angelo's office
is really backed up.
What did she say?
The tests no longer detect
any viral load.
I guess the drug
cocktail is working.
Jeanie, that is great news.
Yeah. Maybe I don't
have to get a lawyer now.
Maybe the hospital
will let it go.
No, I-I know.
It's still transmittable.
That doesn't mean the
hospital can keep you
shuffling papers for
the rest of your career.
If I still have a career.
I have a meeting with Dr. Greene
and Dr. Anspaugh in ten minutes
and I, for one, think
you're too valuable
to rubber-stamp admits
all day long.
Thanks. This is on me.
No matter what
happens in there, Jeanie
this is great news.
Rode your sled to
work, Dr. Greene?
Uh, no. It's a Christmas
present for my daughter.
That's it?
You remember sliding down
those snow-covered bluffs
with the cold wind
flying through your hair?
We didn't have too many
snow-covered bluffs in Atlanta.
We did in Grand Rapids.
Coasted right through
rush-hour traffic
got hit by a car...
Didn't they have
one of those dollies
that wet itself or something?
You know, every toy
that I saw in the store
had some tie-in to a
TV show or a movie
or something I've
been too busy to see.
I mean, I don't know
what Duke Nukem was
but he looked pretty nasty.
You made a good
choice with the sled.
Hey, you look awful.
How long you been on?
Since yesterday morning.
ER
Mark, you ready?
Uh, yeah. Morning, Kerry.
I just got to change.
It's for you, Dennis.
Is it Benton trying to
reach out and touch me?
It's a lady.
Hey, Monique.
You at the airport?
Was it canceled?
Come on. I thought we'd
been through this already.
You want the two
of us to decide?
I'm sure none of us in this room
would want anyone on our team
endangering patients in any way.
As attendings, you're closest
to the everyday
workings of the ER.
So, there is no
hospital-wide policy.
Legal advises we handle it
department by department.
So if we get sued
it's the individual attending's
butt that's on the line?
Let me remind you, Doctor Greene,
if we were aware that there was
an HIV-Positive health
care worker here at County
and the public got wind
of it, started filing suits
all of our butts
would be on the line.
HIV-Positive
workers can be fired
because the hospital
doesn't want to be sued?
No. In Illinois
it's forbidden to
fire any employee
because they're HIV-Positive.
In theory, but have
been forced to quit.
Nobody's forcing
anybody to quit.
What about restricting
their duties to the point where
they're not working
within the job description?
I wouldn't presume
to tell you two how
to run your department
but, uh, let me give you an
idea of the current thinking.
These are the CDC findings
Illinois State law and
pending legal cases
and various NIH
and journal reports.
Now, look, I know
you two have had
your differences in the past.
Do you think you can work
together and solve this?
Absolutely.
Sure.
Can you put on the card
"Merry Christmas,
Mom. Love, Doug"?
And could you make
that a rush order?
Dennis, Dennis, Dennis, what
is up with that shower, man?
I nearly froze my
ass off this morning.
Did you hear that opera
coming through the pipes?
Il figaro? Mrs. Needlebaum.
45 Minutes of
sing-a-long with Pavarotti
and she uses up all the
hot water in the building.
You get any sleep last night?
No. I had 15 admits.
Fifteen? Wow.
Only ten more hours
and then Yuletide cheer
with the Carter family.
Oh, I feel bad subjecting you
and your girlfriend
to my family.
It's not going to happen.
Monique isn't coming.
Not at all?
No. She said she had to stay
in Baton Rouge... work.
Aw, damn. I thought you
guys worked it out, too.
It's her loss, you know?
I'll probably be a little late
with all these new patients.
Well, no worries.
Things don't really
get interesting
till my Uncle Branch
starts downing the bourbon.
Hey, Carter? You got
your picks for the bowl pool?
Yeah. Right here. How
much is it? Five bucks?
Twenty, Mijo.
$20? That's highway robbery.
How much is in the pot?
Almost $400.
You know, I'm with
you for Rose and Fiesta
but Cotton and Liberty Bowls...
You might want to
save your money.
Why is everyone standing around
while we're drowning in patients?
Hey, I'm on hold
with the florist.
Not anymore, you're not.
And a Merry
Christmas Eve to you.
Please don't talk to
me about Christmas.
At 5:00 am this morning, my mother
decided she had to start the Vareniki.
Are those little dumplings?
Yeah. She also picked the
pre-dawn hour to harass me
about dressing
for tonight's party.
So you going to wear
that sexy Ukrainian
shepherdess outfit?
It was either that or
endure hours of nagging.
Okay. Snowmobile foot
lac in the suture room
toddler eating
mistletoe in one...
We have a
slip-and-fall in three.
Watch out for Carol.
It's Christmas in the Ukraine.
Is her mom making
those little dumplings?
Don't ask.
Oh, hey, listen, I heard
Anspaugh is having
some kind of secret meeting.
Anything we should know about?
We have to hammer
out a departmental policy
on HIV-Positive
health care workers.
Anybody we know?
Really?
That son of a
bitch tried to kill me!
He ain't getting this goose
'cause I stuffed it.
Nurse, call my 83-year-old
grandmother in Tuscaloosa
to get her marinade recipe.
I sense a good one.
Oh, yeah. This gentleman...
a female illusionist.
Got into a
too-many-cooks argument
with his boyfriend
and things got heated...
and he she started
getting chest pains.
Girl, it was like an elephant
sitting on my chest... with attitude.
She was diaphoretic.
I never said that!
That means sweaty.
Oh... yeah.
It nearly ruined my gown.
Pressure 130/95.
Resps 25. Slightly tachy...
Tacky? Honey
this is a Bob Mackie original.
Okay, ready?
One, two, three.
Oh!
We need a chest X-ray
cardiac enzymes and an EKG.
Okay, Miss...
Understood.
I'm Miss Understood in the
Mighty Morphin Gender Changers.
We're at Club Cabaret
every Friday and Saturday.
Right. You've got to
give me the goose now
so we can attach an
EKG to your chest.
You want me to give
you my Christmas dinner?
Uh-uh, Miss Thang.
Give me the damn bird.
Where you gonna put it?
With the rest of your
personal belongings.
Well, it better, because
I don't want to wake up
and see you picking your teeth.
Are you on any medications?
Well, not besides the hormones.
Have you had chest pain before?
Well, when I get emotional...
around that time of the month.
Mm-hmm.
I heard it was someone
in this department that has it.
Who?
Uh, I don't know.
It's just the word
on the street.
A tech on three heard
it from a night guy
and now Weaver and Greene
get pulled into
some secret meeting.
See, that's how
rumors get started.
Ah. A rumor. Am I
missing a good one?
Attendings got
pulled into a meeting
but they won't say
what it was about.
It's about someone with HIV
but you didn't hear it from me.
Randi, can you do something
with these personal effects?
They're perishable.
Oh, good. Jeanie.
Head lac in exam two.
And, Connie, if
you're not too busy...
Some folks are
getting a little too fond
of the manager part
of nurse manager.
No kidding.
Carol? What?
Sorry, but Mark assigned
me to triage today.
Aw, come on, guys.
Why do I have to
push all the time?
I'm not your mother.
Uh, excuse me.
I need a doctor.
Okay, if you could go
back to the waiting room
and fill these out...
No, I'm looking for Dr. Ross.
For a medical problem?
Yeah.
You still need to
fill out these forms.
The waiting room's that way.
Hurt here?
Yeah. Okay.
Uh, we're going to need a facial
and a mandibular series
75 migs of Demerol
and Phenergan, IM.
Try and rustle up
an oral surgeon, too.
Good luck with that.
Oh, and, um...
give me a gram of Ancef IM.
You got it.
Um... are you
allergic to any meds?
Okay, I think that
your jaw is broken.
The antibiotics
will keep bacteria
from getting into
your bloodstream
at the fracture site.
But looking at
your chart here...
I guess you know the drill, huh?
Uh, "humerus fracture,
1993, nasal fracture, 1993
"Multiple visits
for sutures, 1994
"and your first broken jaw
was in December 1995."
I guess hubby thought
he'd go out with a bang
this year, too, huh?
It was an accident.
Yeah.
Your face got in
the way of his fist.
So, what if we change
the disclosure form
to include that people
might be treated
by an HIV-Positive
health care worker?
And start a witch hunt?
Well, we have to
inform the patients.
It's the law.
Okay, I take it you
haven't read this.
Americans with Disability Act?
I don't know. What?
Proposals, Addendums?
Here. Read this.
It states that you
can't disclose one risk
without disclosing equal risks.
Meaning?
Meaning that the patient
doesn't have a choice
of whether they're
treated by someone
with the flu or someone
with a hangover
a doc who had a
fight with his spouse
an intern who's
been on for days...
someone with HIV.
Yeah, and Illinois law
says not only can we not
prevent people from knowing
that they've been put at risk
but we have to tell them.
So you'd rather
follow the Illinois law
than the federal statute?
You know, because I'm
concerned doesn't mean
I'm some kind of bigot.
Your concern can't be extended
to prevent Jeanie
from earning a living.
Nobody's talking
about firing her
but we do have a
responsibility to our patients.
What about our
responsibility to Jeanie?
She's using
universal precautions.
Are you frightened
here, Mark? Is that it?
No, I'm trying to keep
us all from being sued.
You think I want to get sued?
But opening up
Jeanie's personal tragedy
to public scrutiny is
the surest way to invite
frivolous lawsuits
and mass hysteria.
So we break the law.
If we have to, yes.
I care about Jeanie, Kerry
but there is
a larger issue here
than your personal loyalty
to a friend.
Uh, sorry to interrupt,
but we're swamped.
Whenever you're done.
We're done now.
Mark, we haven't
even made a dent.
Would you rather
jeopardize patient care further
by sitting here with
a traffic jam in triage?
Who's next? Ho-ho-ho.
Santa Claus?
No, that's who's
next, three hookers...
One with downstairs discharge
and two with frostbite.
I turned on the oven
for a few seconds
and the next thing I know,
he's the got the ribbon
hanging out of his mouth.
All I could get was the leaves.
How many berries
were on the stalk?
Maybe four?
And he wasn't vomiting?
No.
I know, buddy.
This mistletoe's good
stuff, but we got to get it out.
He's been asking for juice.
I didn't give him any
until you said it was okay.
Lily, why don't
you make a bottle
half juice, half
activated charcoal.
Coming right up.
Uh, Mrs. Romero, we're
going to give him a bottle
to absorb some of the toxins.
Okay?
All right, excuse me.
There you are, Ahmed.
I've been looking
for you at the shelter.
Come here.
How is he?
I changed his diaper
and there was blood in it.
In his stool or the urine?
I'm pretty sure
it was in the pee.
Listen, I got to
get him back home
before his mom gets back.
If she finds out I
brought him here
she'll kick me out.
You need to get
his mother here now.
Can't you just hook him up
with some pills or something?
No, I can't just hook
him up with some pills.
Get his mother here, all right?
Geez, what happened to him?
Guy's name is John Collins.
He was drunk and
sleeping it off in Grant Park.
Some kids thought it'd be fun
to pour lighter fluid on him
and play yule log.
He wouldn't let us
put oxygen on him.
Kept screaming about Nick.
He's got extensive 3rd
degree burns to the chest.
Who is this? The guy's dog.
Barked at a mounted cop
till he came to check it out.
Randi, can you
take care of this dog?
You take care of my Nick now.
You take care of my Nicky.
Take it easy, Mr. Collins.
We'll put him in a nice kennel
till you're back on your feet.
No! No kennel. He's all I got.
No I.V., No BP either.
He needs massive fluids.
You got to promise me, Doc.
You promise me now.
Mr. Collins, we're going
to take care of your dog.
Just be quiet for now.
On my count, everyone.
I'm going to need
a cut-down tray.
One, two, three.
All right, Chuny,
get me a blood-gas
with a CO level.
Get a CBC Chem 20
portable chest for openers.
Mm-hmm.
Is he okay?
He's got a mass in his abdomen.
Once I get inside,
I'll know how bad it is.
Inside? Is it bad?
Yeah.
Ultrasound's ready.
Did you get a
hold of the mother?
She isn't home.
Any other adult relatives?
There aren't any.
I take care of him
when Gloria's not around.
Okay. Hang on.
Well, there it is.
He's hemorrhaging
into his kidney.
Let's get lytes, CBC,
a CT of the abdomen,
get a chest film
for metz.
And, Haleh, page
the O.R., too, will you?
What does it say?
Ahmed's got something
called a Wilm's tumor.
You see that area right there?
That fluid?
The light gray?
Yeah. That's blood.
The tumor's invading his kidney.
That's why you saw all
the blood in his diaper.
I should have brought
him in before, huh?
I got to get him to
the operating room.
I knew he was sick.
Is he going to die?
You did a good thing, Charlie.
Now use the Metz and
dissect the right colon
off the anterior
surface of the tumor.
Should I retract
the tumor laterally?
Yep. Very gently.
That's it.
You say that the baby-sitter
brought the child in?
Yeah. Mother was
nowhere to be found.
Dr. Ross knows the
girl that brought him in.
Now retract the tumor laterally.
Right.
And tie off the renal vein...
and artery and
ureter and transect it.
Slowly now. Avoid
the left renal vessels.
Good.
Now, free up the kidney
and you can take it out.
Okay.
All the pretty twinkly lights.
And that's why you were dancing
with the elves at
Marshall Field's.
I'd like some Sherry now.
What's your name, ma'am?
I'm Blitzen
the most overlooked
of all the reindeer.
Blitzen.
It's your lucky day, Beth.
You only have a
fractured cheekbone.
What does that mean?
It means you can go home...
unless you don't want to.
There's a shelter
called Hope House.
It's for women and children
in trouble... I don't have kids.
That's okay.
You can go there by
yourself. They have security
He'll find me.
They have reciprocal agreements
with shelters all
over the country.
You could go anywhere you want
Sweetheart, are you okay?
I knew I should have
fixed that top step.
It's just I've been so busy.
You forgive me?
Can you forgive me, honey?
I love you.
That's my girl.
Is she going to be
all right?
We're actually
not done, Mr. Lang.
We still need to do a head CT,
facial tomograms, put her
on an I.V. and antibiotics.
Is that going to take long?
Well, we'll do the best we can
but with the holidays, you know?
Anyway, family
isn't allowed in the exam area.
Malik, could you show
Mr. Lang to chairs?
Sure.
I'll be right outside, honey.
So you want to hear some
more about those shelters?
No good?
No, and I've tried PB and J.
Cookies, fruitcake.
Nobody likes fruitcake.
I thought dogs ate everything.
Why don't you take
him to the morgue
and have him beg
for some table scraps.
That's Mr. Collins.
Maybe he knows what
you like to eat, huh?
I think he likes you.
How you doing?
What's going on?
We were moving
him up to the burn unit
and he had started
having shortness of breath.
BP's 80 palp,
Tachycardiac at 140.
All right, give me 40
mig I.V. Bolus of Lasix.
We need to intubate 7.5.
He's bradying down.
Rate's 40, no pulse.
Aw, damn it.
Give me a mig of atropine.
Start CPR.
Asystole!
All right. Let's give
him an amp of epi.
Come on, Mr. Collins.
Come on, come on.
I don't care if
psych is backed up.
She thinks she's a reindeer.
Well, dangerous?
You know, she bruised an elf.
Excuse me, Miss.
Who's the rocket scientist
that parked a Bentley
in the ambulance bay?
The Bentley's mine.
Actually, it's my employer's.
Miss, I'm looking
for a missing person.
Take a number, sir. The
line starts in the waiting room.
The woman I'm looking
for has a hand puppet.
Did you say puppet?
Hey, you found him
something to munch on.
He found it himself.
No kidding?
Mm-hmm.
Are dogs supposed
to eat chicken bones?
Is that a chicken?
Charlie, hey.
Ahmed's out of surgery.
He's going to be okay.
I can take him home now?
No. It's going to take him some
time to recover from surgery.
Oh, man. Gloria's
going to be pissed.
I'm going to have to call DCFS.
You're going to narc her out?
I'm not narcing on anybody.
That little boy's been sick.
The mother should have
seen that weeks ago.
Gloria didn't know.
She just found out.
She sounds really worried.
Come on, or she'll throw me out.
So you live with her?
So you lied to me
about the shelter.
Come on, please.
All right, I'll give
her a chance
but I'm not promising
you anything.
Okay?
You're eating hospital food?
You're that desperate?
Come on. Let's get some lunch.
Boo.
You scared me.
I thought the surgery
went really well.
Yeah, it did.
My 3:00 hernia was canceled
so I am free tonight.
So I figured, if you
hadn't made plans
I could make
my traditional Christmas
phone call to Pizza Ring.
I actually got a family thing
and I already asked a
friend of mine to go with me.
Well, the... I understand.
It was last minute, anyway.
Christmas Eve.
It's okay. I'll just stay home
and rent a movie.
That's what I usually do.
No. You know what?
Let me talk to my buddy
because he was tired earlier.
He may prefer to
go home and crash.
So, um... yeah.
Yeah, let's do something later.
Pizza sounds great.
Gingerbread; that always
reminds me of Christmas at home.
You ever do that?
You ever make
gingerbread at home?
You know, in a civilized society
people acknowledge each
other when they speak, Charlie.
I'm just trying to
make conversation.
Want to talk about
Christmas at my home?
Sure. Where is it?
Home is where my mom got bombed
out of her mind and brought home
some fat, smelly
trucker after closing time.
Then she'd pass out
giving him the idea
he'd rather sleep with me.
All right, we know why you left.
How far did you run?
From Cleveland.
Did you call her lately?
She's probably moved on by now.
She never stays
anywhere for very long.
All right, both of these
plus the three danish
the two packets of cocoa
and the two dinner rolls
she's got in her pocket.
Great. Thanks.
Hey.
Hey, man.
Okay, I have now officially
changed every drain
and lanced every
boil in this hospital.
34 hours, man.
I'm ready for
some of that, uh...
what's that Jell-o thing
you said your cook makes?
Aspic.
Yeah. Some Aspic.
That's what I want
to talk to you about.
Say no more.
I have an Aunt
who makes Chitlins.
You don't want to
know what that's about.
Uh... okay.
There's a chance
that I may not be
able to make the party.
Oh. You working?
No. No.
There's this girl.
Oh, that's cool.
You know. I understand.
You sure?
Who wants to hang
with his homeys
when he could be
with a honey, right?
You going to be...?
I'll be fine.
Well, this gives you
a chance to at least
go home and get more sleep.
You don't have to hang
on me, man. I'll be fine.
Well, let's do something
tomorrow night;
go out, get a couple
beers or something.
I'm on tomorrow night.
I know what universal
precautions are usually,
but what does it refer
to here, double gloves?
You're going overboard
with these guidelines.
Well, what about employee X's
participation in bloody trauma?
I don't see anything
wrong with that.
Bloody trauma?
Maybe that's the
deal with Dr. Lewis.
Susan, HIV-Positive?
I don't think so.
Look, Susan is fine.
That's what I said.
Lydia's been sick a lot.
Oh, shut your mouth.
You know, I would have
expected more from the two of you
than gossiping about a
co-worker's HIV status.
Look everybody. Kerry and
I have been hammering out
a policy, there's
no secret there.
But this shouldn't be grist for
the rumor mill.
Is there a reason
we have to have
HIV-positive employees
in the ER at all?
Well, according to current law
employee or employees X...
We'll call them employee X...
Cannot be fired because
of their HIV status.
But they can stick their
hands in a bloody trauma?
Why not if they're gloved?
Is this someone got
it from a needle stick?
What difference does
it make how they got it?
These are the issues
that we've been discussing.
Should employee X be restricted
to noninvasive procedures?
Or continue with
their duties...?
Won't universal precautions
prevent transmission?
Yeah, that's what they tell us when
we work on HIV-positive patients.
The real question here
isn't in law and policies.
It's do our patients
have the right to know.
This in no way
has any reflection
upon my opinion on
employee X's work.
Is there an actual employee X
or are we just talking?
We're talking
policy here, people.
Employee x could be
any one of us.
Excuse me.
Would everyone stop
calling me employee x?
I am HIV-Positive.
We talked about this, Mark.
The risks are a million to one
that Jeanie will bleed into
an open wound while suturing.
I'm not saying she can't work.
I'm just trying to set the
boundaries of where she can work.
You set the boundaries at
triage and answering the phone...
That's not her job.
I have no trouble
if she performs her
duties within limits.
Dispensing
medication... That's fine
but some things aren't.
For example... it says here...
"deep, penetrating,
poorly visualized cavities."
Okay? That's from the CDC.
I think that should
be off limits.
I wouldn't feel comfortable
doing that anyway.
Okay. See? Progress.
You know, Mark,
since I found out,
I have been more careful.
Do you think I want
to do something that
may harm a patient?
No, I don't.
But unfortunately
the hospital administration
has left it up to Kerry and I
to create a policy that the
state and federal governments
can't seem to make
up their minds about.
I've agonized over this.
I have considered
quitting, but I believe
my life can still have
value... I can still help people.
I'm sure you can.
What else are you worried about?
Dementia.
You're fine now, but
what if you decline?
Dementia may be the
first sign of full-blown AIDS.
I've heard that there
are some hospitals
that have instituted
a physician monitor
someone to help keep
tabs on the person's health.
I could do that.
Okay.
So, that's one thing.
What else?
Hi.
So was it a needle stick?
I guess so. You
don't think that she...?
Oh, hi, Jeanie.
Hi.
Hey, Jeanie.
Hey.
I wish I had known.
Why? Would it have
made the two of us friends?
Now, that's not fair.
Nothing is.
Well?
Oh, Mr. Lang. Hi.
Is Beth okay?
I been sitting here for hours.
I'm sorry, but your wife's fall
was worse than
we initially thought.
She might have to stay
overnight for observation.
Oh, God.
Anyway, the coroner's
going to have my butt
if we don't get
this guy over there.
So why don't you just wait?
Hey, buddy?
This patient's going
to the bus station.
A stiff?
Miraculous recovery.
Uh, here you go...
For your bus ticket
and some burgers.
Oh, I... I can't
take this from you.
You got a 3:15 to
Abilene to catch.
I don't know
where Abilene is.
Hopefully, neither does he.
Bye.
Uh, you won the pool.
Congratulations.
That was the
football pool money?
Yeah. I thought
she was a better bet.
All right. "Alternators,
amusements, ammunition..."
There's no animal shelters.
Sometimes they list them
under Humane Societies.
Aw, You can't give
him away, Mark.
You promised Mr. Collins.
Yeah, that was before
I shelled out 50 bucks
to a drag queen for
a free-range goose.
You know what
happens when they can't
find homes for dogs?
What am I going
to do with a dog?
Dogs are great.
They're good company.
They watch your
stuff when you're gone.
Your daughter will love him.
You think?
Yeah. My dad got me a
dog... Skippy... when I was six.
Best present I ever got.
The two of us were like
peanut butter and jelly.
Ay, mi perrito!
No me puedes hacer eso, ah?!
Yo soy su madre!
Yo tengo derecho!
I'll get you for kidnapping!
Don't you think I
won't! He was sick!
Don't tell me how
to raise my son...
Excuse me, I'm Dr. Ross.
Can I help you?
You can give me back my baby
is what you can do for me.
Your son had major surgery.
I'll call the cops on your ass.
Are you high, Gloria?
I'm clean. You don't
know nothing about me.
Well maybe we should just let
Children and Family Services decide.
You promised you wouldn't narc!
I said I'd give her a
chance. I gave her a chance.
She's just scared.
You come in here, messed
up on God knows what
you don't even ask about
your critically-ill son
so why don't you have a seat...
I'll get my kid
back, you bastard!
You think you can mess
with me because I'm a Latina?!
Well, I'll call a lawyer
and sue all you all!
You're just like
the rest of them.
Gloria, wait up!
What's that?
This homeless guy's dog.
The dog saved his life.
I told him that I'd, you
know, watch out for him
and next thing I know
the guy up and dies on me.
So now you're the
proud owner of...
His name's Nick.
Given the season, you
should call him St. Nick.
Yeah, well, Rachel can
call him whatever she wants.
Rachel?
Yeah, I thought I'd give
her a puppy for Christmas.
Mark, in case you hadn't noticed
that dog is, like,
eight years old.
It's ready for
a mid-life crisis.
It's ready for a
fur replacement.
What do you mean? With a
wash, a little bow around his neck
he's not going to
look a day over... five.
What do you know
about giving dogs a bath?
What's to know?
Could you hold him?
I could, yeah, for 20
bucks. I could do it.
20 bucks, that's a little steep.
I lost my wallet. I need a loan.
Deal.
Okay.
Hang on.
You got him?
Hold on.
Ho!
Come here, come here...
Whoa! Ah!
Oh, damn it!
Let me see. You
take care of your head.
I'll get the dog.
Can I get some help?
Yeah.
Ouch. That looks pretty deep.
Yeah. Dog trauma.
He went that way. He was
giving Doug a run for his money.
Looks like it could use stitches
don't you think?
You want me to call someone?
No. I want you to do it.
Okay.
Oh, Wow. Wow.
Very William Powell.
Aren't they great?
Silk.
Try it on. Yeah?
Dr. Keaton?
Yes. Dr. Benton?
Is this a bad time?
No, no, no.
I was just reviewing
some anatomy.
May I come in for a moment?
Sure.
Uh... first of all, I
wanted to thank you
for, uh, letting me
take such a large role
in the Lopez Nephrectomy today.
Oh, you did a great job.
Thank you. That's
actually why I'm here.
I'd like to do another
pediatric surgery rotation.
Uh, well, you know, as you know
I won't be here for
the next rotation.
I know. Uh, I was hoping
that you could leave your
recommendation for me
with your replacement.
Um...
Well, you're a very
good surgeon, uh, Peter
but that's not enough for pedes.
You've got to live and
breathe for children.
You took this rotation
just to challenge yourself
and I applaud that
but I can't, in good conscience
give up a space that
could possibly be filled
by a future pediatric surgeon.
I'd be happy to talk
to Dr. Anspaugh or Morgenstern
and I hear that Don's doing
some really interesting
stuff in Thoracics.
No, no. No, thank you.
I, uh...
I wouldn't want to waste
any more of your time.
Hmm...
You've got an old scar.
Looks like you've
done this before.
I played Rugby in high
school for a few weeks
to impress a girl
but after ending up on
the bottom of a few scrums
I decided to rethink
the relationship.
Jeanie, you're a great P.A.
You're an asset to the ER.
But...?
But nothing.
I think you should stay.
And do my job;
not do clerical work?
Yeah.
Within the limits
that we set earlier.
But you still wouldn't want
me suturing your daughter.
I don't know. I...
Okay.
Good as new.
All right. When I finally
caught up with him
he'd already been made
mascot of the children's ward.
Watch him.
Thank you.
Good catch.
All right. Now, I am
on my way home
for a beautiful holiday
with Mu Shu pork,
Channel 11 Yule log
and my easy chair.
How's your forehead?
Jeanie fixed me right up.
Yeah. She's a great P.A.
All right. My work here is done.
Merry Christmas.
I'm sorry I lied to you, Mark.
Good night.
What happened here?
Long story.
I swallowed a bunch
of pills a few years ago.
When I got back to work
people either smothered
me with kindness
or treated me
like I was invisible.
If we aren't friends,
maybe we should be.
Well. I have a house full of
crazy relatives waiting for me.
Merry Christmas, Carol.
Merry Christmas.
Hey.
What are you doing?
What...?
How did you find
out where I lived?
I thought I lost this.
You did... at the cafeteria.
And the 50 some-odd
bucks that was in here?
I needed cab fare.
50 bucks' worth?
What are you doing here?
Gloria's pissed, and
she blames it on me.
I can't stay there anymore.
And?
And I thought I
could crash with you.
You're 14 years old,
you stole my wallet
you've been nothing
but a pain in the ass.
You want me to stay
out on the streets?
In a shelter.
A shelter on Christmas Eve?
Sounds like fun.
Hey.
Hi.
How'd you find me?
Dr. Weaver told me
you were taking a break.
I, uh...
I got a lot of Christmas cards
forwarded to me
addressed to
Mr. and Mrs. Al Boulet.
I thought you might
like to look at them, too.
You can sit down, Al.
I don't bite.
Aunt Nonni.
I wonder what
get-rich-quick scheme
she's looking for
partners in this year.
Southwestern land development.
Beats the
envelope-stuffing scheme.
And the roller disco.
Uh... I also thought...
You might like to have this.
Where did you find this?
I finally got a chance
to go through some of
the boxes from the house.
I found my socket set, too.
Remember that ridiculous
tree in the old apartment?
There was nothing
ridiculous about that, baby.
That was a... a
prime piece of pine.
Except it was
about six feet too tall
for a studio apartment
and you refused
to cut the top off.
That would've been sacrilege.
I bet you can still see
the stucco scratches.
Like you didn't
eat all the popcorn
before I could string
it with the cranberries.
Well, that's different. How?
'Cause you know how
I feel about popcorn.
Hey, Dennis.
Dennis?
You were sleeping.
No, I was just resting my eyes.
What are you still doing here?
I've got all these charts.
They can wait.
No. I want to finish them up.
You are going to go home right?
You are going to get some sleep?
Yeah, absolutely.
I'm good.
All right, man.
Hey.
I hope I'm not
interrupting anything.
Well, actually, I
was just seducing
this fat man in a fly
red suit, you know.
He came down the chimney.
But other than that...
Um, here.
I brought you this Poinsettia.
Who knew the Zippy Mart was
still open on Christmas Eve?
Busted, huh?
I just didn't want
to show up here
empty-handed, that's all.
Thank you...
for the Poinsettia.
Yeah, uh...
You're welcome.
Are you going to come in
or are you just going to
let all this cold air in here?
You forgot the extra chair.
Mom, I already
borrowed folding chairs
from the guy next door.
The extra chair is for
the unexpected guest
a tradition much
older than you or me
or the guy next door.
Okay, well, there
isn't enough room.
And as much as I'd like
to sit on Uncle Myko's lap...
Fine, fine. Have it your way.
First we have to
have Sviata Vechera
on American Christmas Eve.
Then it's like pulling teeth
to get you to help me cook.
Now, one last tradition
I ask you to assist
me with and...
An unexpected guest maybe?
Maybe.
Hey.
Don't say a word.
I thought you were
planning a quiet evening
with the Channel Nine Yule log.
Yeah, well, the plans changed.
You're kidding me.
She just showed up at my place.
I can't have her sleeping there.
It wouldn't look
very good, so...
Oh, no. No way, Doug.
It's bad enough I've got
eight drunken sword dancers
re-enacting the purge
in my dining room.
It's Christmas, Carol.
Doug, I am painfully
aware of that.
Come on.
Come on, Nick.
Nick, let's get out of here.
Come on, buddy. Come on.
Mark.
I, uh, I didn't hear you
ring the bell.
Jennifer, guess who's here?
You won't believe what
he's got with him either.
It's just funny
because I got Rachel
a couple of Labrador
puppies for Christmas
and here you are with a...
what is he, some
kind of a Setter?
Mixed breed, actually.
Daddy!
Hi, sweetheart.
Mark, we weren't
expecting you until tomorrow.
Yeah, well...
Daddy
you brought me a doggie.
Great minds think alike.
Actually, I, uh...
he's my dog, and
I just wanted you
to meet...
Ow!
Oh, I'm sorry.
You all right?
You okay?
Bad dog!
The doggie
didn't mean it.
No, of course
he didn't, darling.
Here, let me take a look.
Has he had his shots yet?
Craig, let Mark
take a look at it.
He's a doctor.
Come on in, Mark.
Okay. Let's go.
Good, doggie.
Thank you.
If I had known it was
this easy to get my mother
off my back, I would have had
you bring her by
a long time ago.
So she can stay?
No, I do not think
that's a good idea.
Check it out... It's
a Christmas egg.
That's nice there, Charlie.
You should make
one. It's pretty cool.
I don't know, Charlie.
I'm no Picasso.
You chicken?
Yeah, you a chicken?
Yeah, I'm a chicken.
Get over there.
I'll paint it.
Okay, one night.
All right.
Just one... tonight.
So Long as we
have hands to clasp
Christmas day will always be
just as long as we have...
Welcome, Christmas...
Oh, I am never going
to get sick of that one.
Do you think they have
Dr. Seuss in Pakistan?
Oh, I don't think
it's a priority.
Will you be safe?
I don't think you can
guarantee safety anywhere.
Oh, I feel safe here.
I remember my
father used to read
The Christmas Story
every Christmas Eve.
I'm so tired, I don't
even think I remember it.
Um, "'Twas the night
before Christmas...
"and all through the house
"not a creature was stirring...
not even a mouse."
I'm going to miss you.
That's not the next line.
I'm really going to miss you.
What are you looking at?
This tree.
It's missing
something, you know?
Yeah.
Well, pedes did a good job
with this construction
paper chain, huh?
Yeah.
That was a real gutsy
thing you did today.
Thanks.
You know, I have just the thing.
That looks good.
Where did you get it?
My ex-husband brought it by.
It came off our
first Christmas tree.
It's an heirloom.
You should put it
on your family tree.
I just did.