"Trim the fat, Sharon,"
the board says,
like I'm some kind of butcher.
This is the hardest week
I've ever had here.
No plan for overflow,
misuses of space,
blood shortages.
What I'm worried about
is your effect on morale
and making snap judgments
without consulting me.
Sully told me
his cancer was terminal.
How was I supposed to tell him
that I was being forced
to snitch on him?
None of this changes
the fact that
your career is on the line.
What the hell
did you just do?
I can't believe you told Sully.
You knew he turned himself in.
You knew he wouldn't let me
take the rap!
I know you can't
see it right now,
but this is a good thing,
Mitch.
How is this a good thing?
You went behind my back!
Sully beat somebody up
and hospitalized them, Mitch!
You don't owe him anything!
You don't understand.
I don't understand
some stupid childhood code?
To protect your friends?
Is that stupid to you?
You're about to
throw your life away,
your medical license,
maybe even go to jail!
What I do with my life
is my choice!
And it never would
have come to that.
You don't know that.
Because of what you did,
Sully is sitting in jail
right now
when he should be with his son.
Do not put that on me.
That was Sully's choice!
You think you're
a good person because of this?
You're not.
You're just someone who
can't be trusted.
So--so that's it?
Yeah, from the
hospital's perspective?
Somebody else came forward.
Dr. Ripley is cleared.
And from--
from your perspective?
I don't know, he showed
pretty questionable judgment.
Have you talked to him?
You know,
I haven't for a while.
Hey, Maggie?
I'll catch you later.
What is all this?
Is this from
the Jackson-Monroe closure?
Gaffney finally hit capacity
this morning.
No, Tony, on the other side.
Which means right now,
we can't move
our admitted patients upstairs,
which means the paramedics
can't admit their patients
into the ED.
Which means
ambulances can't leave.
It's like dominoes.
- That are falling down on us.
Well, I'll see if I can
alleviate some of the pressure.
And in the meantime, I'll talk
to some of the patients
and try to lower
the temperature a bit.
That'd be great.
Oh, this is mail for you that
accidentally came into the ED.
All right. Thank you.
2 strep cases, 24 stitches,
and I relocated
the dislocated elbow
of a very cranky 5-year-old
all before 8:00 a.m.
Care to celebrate with me?
Come on.
Got those
in the doctors' lounge?
Yeah, why? Ugh!
Oh! Oh, my God.
Doris made them
for her daughter's bake sale
and brought in extra
for us to share.
God, should we
call the school?
What are y'all giggling at?
Potential poisoning case.
So how is my girlfriend
this morning?
Yeah, um--
You're up, slugger.
Yup.
All right, give the girl
in five 2 grams of Ancef
and let's set up for I&D.
And get this guy
a record contract.
You look like hell.
Yeah, I didn't sleep much
last night.
But I should be fine.
Dr. Asher, you're up. T4.
Thank you.
I'll be right there.
I thought Lenox was off today.
She's doing
an efficiency study.
What does that mean?
Well, apparently it means
shadowing doctors,
getting a feel for how we work
by observing
and asking questions.
Okay, so basically
following us around
and second-guessing
everything we do?
It's like she's trying
to lose a popularity contest.
I gotta go.
I did tell them
that last time, baby.
Hi, Mrs. Thompson.
I'm Dr. Asher.
They're actually here.
I'll tell you what they say.
Love you too.
Finally.
I apologize.
I know you've been
waiting a while.
So you're coming up
on your due date?
Yeah. 39 weeks.
And you're experiencing
some abdominal pain?
A dull ache.
Okay. May I?
Great.
Okay, do you feel any pain
while I'm pushing?
No, just feels uncomfortable.
Okay, your legs are swollen.
I know.
Told my doctor two weeks ago.
He said it was normal,
that I should just
drink more water.
Okay, let's take
a peek at baby.
Do you know what you're having?
Drink water, same thing
he said when I was constipated,
when I had nightmares,
and when I had something
called lightning crotch.
Yeah, third trimester
is a real party.
Okay.
Ooh, baby girl's big.
Everything looks good.
So you have no explanation
for my stomach pain?
There's quite a few
unpleasant
but normal conditions that can
pop up at the end of pregnancy,
including aches and pains.
That being said, I'm going to
run a few more tests
just to make sure
we're not missing anything.
I'll be back.
I personally
called radiology,
and they're gonna get you in
within the hour.
In the meantime,
we'll keep the snacks going.
Okay?
Free Jell-O?
Well, it's hard to be mad
on a full stomach.
You heading back up?
Yeah, I've been trying to
get in touch with Peter Kalmick
to help us with this backup,
but I actually think
he's dodging my calls.
You all right?
What is it?
It's a death threat.
And you have no idea
who sent this?
No.
I mean, we have an occasional
angry patient.
We've let some staff go.
There's been a lot of people
who weren't happy.
Could I get a list
of everyone you let go?
Sure.
How often do
these things escalate?
We take all threats
seriously.
If you don't feel safe,
we can make accommodations
to work remotely.
Oh, no, no, no.
This is not the time to go MIA.
I wouldn't take this lightly.
Dennis, I can't effectively
run this hospital
from my living room.
But I've done this job
a long time.
I've pissed off
a lot of people.
It comes with the territory.
So I appreciate your concern,
but unless
there's more to discuss,
I'd really like
to get back to it.
Art Hubbard, 76,
was at the grocery store
when he collapsed.
He's been in and out
of consciousness.
Gave oxygen,
6 liters per minute.
All right. On my count.
Ready? One, two, three.
Hey, Mr. Hubbard,
can you hear me?
What's happening?
Do you know
where you are, sir?
No, no. No surgery!
Joan says no surgery.
Lungs sound wet.
Looks like
congestive heart failure.
Let's give Lasix
40 milligrams IV
and start a nitro drip.
And let's get an echo tech
in here.
You need something,
Dr. Lenox?
Just observing.
Pretend I'm not here.
Wait. BP's dropping.
80/40.
All right, no time
for the echo.
Just give me
the ultrasound machine.
Come on.
Yeah, I got it.
BP 75/35.
10 mics a minute of nitro
shouldn't do this.
Aortic valve is thick,
poor mobility.
It's not heart failure,
it's aortic stenosis.
All right, stop the nitro.
Start dopamine, 5 mics.
Joan.
BP's still dropping,
68/32.
Get ready to increase to 7.5.
Give me the central line kit.
Come on.
Guess that did the trick, huh?
Fluids seem to be helping?
Yes, thank you.
We'll let the IV do its thing
while we wait on some labs.
And hopefully,
we can get you home soon,
all right?
- Okay.
Hang in there, buddy.
I'll be right back.
Dr. Frost, I just wanted to say
I didn't recognize you
at first.
But it's wild that
you're working here now.
Yeah, life's crazy.
You look great.
Sorry, I really need
to get back to work.
Oh, no. Right.
Hey, you know her?
Nope.
Because it seemed like
she knew you.
I've never seen her
in my life.
Daniel.
Dean?
Art Hubbard, 76,
aortic stenosis.
Bad?
If he doesn't have the
surgery to replace the valve,
his heart could give out
within a matter of days.
The problem is, ours isn't
the first ED he's visited.
He's known about his condition
for weeks.
He's just--he's refusing
to have the surgery.
Any idea why?
Joan says it's too dangerous.
Who's Joan?
You see, that's the question.
Obviously,
we thought it was his wife.
His emergency contact
is his daughter.
She says she's never heard
of anybody named Joan.
She's worried about him,
especially since his wife died
a couple years ago.
Well, you're worried
somebody might
be trying to take advantage
of him?
No, his daughter's been
keeping an eye on the finances.
There's nothing fishy
going on there.
So what,
maybe a little dementia?
Well, if he lacks capacity,
right,
we could get a court order,
override his objections,
do the surgery.
How about I wait
till he wakes up
and have a little chat?
Okay.
You have what
we call preeclampsia.
Preeclampsia?
I've heard of that.
It's dangerous, right?
It can be.
But we're going to give you
magnesium
to prevent it
from getting any worse.
And the real solution
is to deliver the baby.
Uh, now?
Today.
So you might wanna
call your partner back,
let them know that
they can come on down.
I can't.
He's stationed in Turkey.
Marines.
He's scheduled to come home
two days before the due date.
Unfortunately, your timeline
needs to be sped up.
Normally,
I'd say we can induce,
but in your case,
I'd recommend a C-section.
So we can get you in
for surgery around
3:00--
- A C-section?
Of course.
You get paid more for that.
This has nothing to do
with financial factors.
Elise, your baby's big.
The risks are
the shoulders getting caught
and creating
more complications.
You have no idea
how big my baby is, right?
It's just a guess.
It's an estimate, yes.
But I've been doing this--
So I have to
do the C-section?
Not at all.
It's your choice.
We can try
for a vaginal delivery.
I'm just giving you
my recommendation.
- Why didn't you say that?
- I was giving you--
You weren't.
You started talking about
getting me into surgery
before I even agreed to it.
I recommended a procedure
based on my experience.
Now, trust me--
That's the thing.
I don't trust you.
Hi.
Mrs. Thompson,
my name is Maggie.
I'm a nurse and a midwife.
Do you mind if I join you?
Sounds like you have
a lot of questions.
And I wanna make sure that
we go through all of them
before you make a decision,
make sure that you have
all the information.
How does that sound?
Yeah.
I'd appreciate that.
Okay.
I'll get the magnesium.
You wanna do miso, right?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Hey, Mags.
Yeah.
Thanks for the assist
back there.
Uh, yeah.
I've, uh, had the experience
of navigating this
medical world as a Black woman.
Usually means that
your concerns get dismissed.
Elise just wants to be heard.
He seems stable.
Will you walk me through
your thinking
when Mr. Hubbard came in?
My thinking?
I was trying to keep him alive.
And you made a lot of
decisions in doing that.
For example,
you opted for a dopamine drip
instead of phenylephrine?
Well, he was hypotensive
and the dopamine is here
in the Pyxis.
But phenylephrine would have
stabilized him more quickly.
He could have been admitted
to step down.
Now we have another ICU hold
and he's still in the ED.
But it worked, right?
His BP came up and he's alive.
You should control your tone.
I don't like having
all my decisions
scrutinized for no reason.
Just because there was
a positive outcome
doesn't mean decisions
shouldn't be examined.
You need to back off.
Yeah, we should have
a talk now.
Come on.
You had a chip on your shoulder
when you came in today.
I get that Lenox is a pill,
believe me,
but you just need
to control yourself.
So you're the only one who
gets to be a prick around here?
Listen, you don't exactly
have a stellar reputation
at the moment.
I'm trying to help you.
Jesus, do I have
a sign on my back that says
"please decide
what's best for me"?
I was cleared
to come back to work,
so I'm going to work.
Well, you may have
been cleared
by the wellness committee,
but this is my ED.
Oh, yeah?
You sure about that?
All right,
you take an early lunch
and you sort yourself out
or don't bother
coming back at all.
So forgive me
if I'm wrong, Dr. Wu,
but even though
the initial trials
were for lung cancer,
the goal is--
if we were to receive funding--
would be to apply
the technology
to all cancer treatments?
Um, I'm sorry.
Sharon, do you need something?
A word.
I'm in the middle of lunch.
Excuse me.
Peter, the ED is overflowing.
It looks like a parade out
front with all the ambulances.
We were promised resources.
And they're coming, okay?
The board's approved
renovations,
additional equipment.
I mean, isn't Dr. Lenox
downstairs trying to find ways
to make the ED more efficient?
None of that is gonna help
us with our problems today.
We need to postpone
elective surgeries.
No, I knew this is where
you were going with this.
- We need to catch our breath.
- No. It's a non-starter.
So we can catch up.
Elective surgeries
keep the lights on.
We're drowning, Peter!
Why don't you go
to the board yourself?
I mean, you outrank me.
They'll say no
because they'll see it
as costing the hospital money.
But if you go as a lawyer
and say the current situation
is a financial liability--
Okay, you know what? Fine.
Let me see what I can do.
Okay? I just--
Okay, the misoprostol
is working.
Your cervix is softening
and about a fingertip dilated,
so you are heading
in the right direction.
As soon as a bed
opens in obstetrics,
we'll get you on your way.
Everything okay?
Yeah, slight
decreased variability
with baby's heart rate,
but it's probably
just the magnesium.
Overall, it looks reassuring.
Here comes another contraction.
Okay.
Such a great song.
I love Sam Cooke.
That guy's here
at least once a month.
You wanna know something crazy?
His Otis Redding's even better.
Okay.
You know, I wasn't just
being obstinate before.
About the C-section.
It's just this might be
my only chance to have a kid,
and I wanted to experience
all of it.
Take you a long time
to get pregnant?
Eight years.
Through three deployments
and four miscarriages.
Ironically, one of the reasons
I fell in love with Amani
was we both wanted
a big family.
I'm an only child.
And I've always wanted the--
I don't know, fullness?
The chaos.
Mm, I get it.
I had two siblings.
It is definitely chaos.
Anyway, I guess I'll have
to settle for one perfect baby.
And that'll be enough.
I'll be back.
Hey, can you check with L&D?
And if they're still full,
let's start Pitocin.
You got it.
Oh, and a heads-up.
Incoming.
Your turn on the hot seat.
Good, I'm glad I caught you.
Of course. I'm happy
to run you through my cases.
Actually,
I wanted to talk about
your overall role
in this department.
Role?
Well, most emergency
departments
don't have an OB specialist,
so I'm curious to know if you
find your position essential.
It's essential
to the women I see.
And what percentage
of patients
do you feel like you're
treating here in the ED
versus those who are passed on
to OB triage?
I'm not sure the numbers.
I'd have to check my records.
So get those to me
by the end of shift
and we'll pick it up then?
Uh, sorry. I just, um--
I just thought as a woman,
you'd appreciate having someone
who specializes
in women's health.
As a woman,
I do appreciate it.
Art, I'm Dr. Charles,
and my colleagues are worried
about your heart.
They tell me that
you might need some surgery?
No.
Joan says it's a bad idea.
Okay.
And do you mind me asking,
who is Joan, exactly?
I mean, how do you know her?
Is she--is she a friend?
Is she a relative?
Well, whoever she is,
she sounds like, um...
she's concerned about you.
Joan is, uh,
always there for me.
Really?
Well then, I mean, she's gotta
be worried about--
when's the last time
you talked to her?
Should we--
should we call her up
and let her know what's
going on?
No, I don't think so.
Why not, Art?
Do you mind me asking?
You wouldn't understand.
Okay, look.
Art, I have been married
three--well, technically,
four times.
So I'm the last person
in the world
who's ever gonna judge
anybody's relationship.
Okay? Just saying.
We don't talk on the phone.
We talk on the computer.
Oh, okay.
Well, um...
you mind showing me?
What's going on?
Your baby's heart rate
dropped.
She's in distress.
Turning off the Pitocin.
500 CC bolus.
I need terb now.
She's having
a tetanic contraction.
Elise, we need to roll you
onto your side, okay?
Turn, sweetie.
You're all right.
Still down.
Okay, call neonatology
and anesthesiology.
Tell them that we're
headed to the hybrid OR
for a crash C-section.
Up dose her epidural
with 10 CCs.
Wait! What are you doing?
I know this isn't how
you wanted it to happen, Elise.
I'm sorry, but we need
to get your baby out now.
Let's go!
What the hell are
you doing in here?
I don't know.
Being a responsible adult,
I guess.
You didn't need
to turn yourself in.
Yeah, 'cause you were
gonna take the rap.
My knight in shining armor.
To what do I owe the honor
of a midday visit?
You know, I--
I've been running around
the past 24 hours
furious with everyone.
Finally, I realized
it's because
I can't yell at the person
I'm really mad at.
Me.
I begged you not
to go after Pawel.
I--
You just--
you just had to be stupid.
Now everyone at the hospital
thinks that I'm unstable
and my relationship with Hannah
is hanging by a thread.
And you're in here while
your son is out there.
If you came here
to cheer me up,
you're doing it wrong.
- I'm serious.
- So am I.
- I didn't ask you--
- You didn't have to!
You don't let someone get away
with messing with your friends.
That's how we were brought up.
Remember?
And maybe you're all evolved
or whatever,
but those rules
still matter to me.
So you can be whoever
this new version of you is
and I'm happy for you,
but don't come in here
and call me stupid.
You got a good lawyer?
No.
I can give you some cash.
Save your money.
For Lynn.
And the baby.
You shouldn't be
so hard on Hannah.
She betrayed my trust.
Went behind my back.
I--
- Yeah, yeah.
Now you're the one
being stupid.
She had your back
more than anyone.
Hannah did what
she thought was best for you,
even though she knew
you'd hate her for it.
That's the kind of person
I want in my corner.
Uterine incision.
Scalpel back.
I can't breathe.
Vitals are stable.
Oxygen sat's normal.
Does it feel like something's
sitting on your chest?
That's the anesthesia.
It's common.
I know it feels like
you're not breathing,
but you are, I promise.
Okay, Maggie,
some fundal pressure.
All right, Elise, you're gonna
feel a little tugging.
Here we go.
Okay, baby's out.
Cord's wrapped
around her neck.
She's not breathing.
- I can't hear her.
Is she okay?
- Two tight clamps now.
No respiratory effort.
Getting ready to bag.
- What's happening?
And let's get
a UVC catheter pulled.
What's going on? Is she okay?
- Okay.
- Is--is she breathing?
Is she okay?
Okay, Elise, I need you
to stay still for me.
Just listen to my voice.
All right?
They're giving her oxygen
to get her breathing.
Now, I'll let you know
what's going on.
I'm right here.
- Still nothing.
Let's intubate.
Give me the laryngoscope
ET tube and a stylet.
Okay, they're putting
a breathing tube in
to get air into her lungs.
Oh, my God.
Come on.
Come on, little one. Come on.
Is that her?
Yeah, it is.
She's breathing. Rings.
Wait.
Where are they taking her?
They're taking her
to the NICU.
I wanna see her!
I thought she was okay.
She's breathing, Elise,
but they need to get her
to the NICU for monitoring.
It's standard.
Hey, hey, hey. It's okay.
In my experience,
girls tend to do well.
They're tough.
Ambulances are nearly
spilling onto the main road
outside.
And I just heard back
from Peter.
He made an appeal to the board
to halt elective surgeries,
but they were unmoved.
Yeah, easy for them to say
in their ivory tower.
It doesn't impact them.
Yeah, that's true.
I'll be back.
Hey.
So I talked
to our heart patient.
- Oh, yeah?
- And...
I met Joan.
Really?
Hi, I'm Joan.
What the hell is this?
Joan is not a human being.
She's a chatbot.
Ugh, a chatbot.
Yeah, come on.
Designed for companionship.
You know, she listens.
Learns your preferences,
tracks your responses.
It's actually this whole
emergent thing in elder care.
Of course.
So Art is in love with a robot?
Doesn't that prove
that he's lost capacity
to make medical decisions?
Let's get this man
into surgery.
Dean, he's got capacity.
He knows it's a robot.
So what?
We just let him walk out
of here with a bad heart?
Didn't say that.
Just trying to
figure out a way to
show him, you know, who or
what--
yeah, what Joan actually is.
So...
I'm your girlfriend now?
Yeah, I'm sorry.
I kind of sprung that
on you, huh?
There's something about
Frost making you laugh.
He's just funny and charming.
There's something
about that guy.
Look, I'm an idiot, right?
Oh, be careful how you
talk about my new boyfriend.
Excuse me?
Oh, excuse me.
We were just about to leave,
but I wanted to--
um, this is sort of awkward.
I was hoping you could
pass this to Dr. Frost for me.
It's my number.
Oh. Sure thing.
Oh, miss.
Sorry, just curious.
How do you two know each other?
Oh. Oh, no, we don't.
Um, I'm just a really big fan.
I spoke with
Master Sergeant,
and he signed off on leave,
so I can get the first
flight out tomorrow.
Hopefully, you can get
a straight shot to Chicago.
Hey, love, doctor's here.
I'll call you back.
No, no, no.
You can--you can stay on.
I have some good news.
I just checked in
with the NICU,
and your baby
is no longer on oxygen.
She is stable.
Her vitals are good.
And you will see her soon.
- Did you hear that?
- Yes.
Loud and clear, baby.
That's so good.
Hang on.
I want you to meet him.
Hi, Dad.
Hey, doc.
You have a beautiful family.
Oh, thank you so much for
taking care of both my girls.
Hopefully, I can thank you
in person when I get home.
Oh, oh, wait.
Do you like homemade bread?
Like sourdough, wheat bread,
cornbread?
All right.
She's gotta get back
to doctoring.
But I love you.
And I'll call you later.
Oh, I'm so excited.
Give Ruby a kiss for me,
all right?
- Bye.
- Bye-bye.
How are you feeling?
Good now.
I mean, tired.
Never had a baby before,
so it's tough
to compare it to anything.
Yeah.
The nurses keep
calling me mama.
Is it normal to shake?
Adrenaline and anesthesia
are a powerful combo.
Let me get you a warm blanket.
You named her Ruby?
It's a family name.
I like traditions.
Gives her a sense of
belonging right from the start.
Do you have kids?
No.
Do you want them?
Uh, honestly, I--
I've made some bad choices.
And I think I felt
I could never bring a baby
into that situation.
But now...
I don't know.
I'd wanna have
the right partner.
But maybe.
Yeah, I think I might.
What?
I'm not sure I've ever
said that out loud before.
It's cool.
I won't tell anyone.
So your wife died
two years ago?
26 months.
Well, I know how
brutal that can be.
I loved my wife,
but it's not just about her.
When you're young,
the world is laid out for you.
Everything and everyone
is pointed in your direction.
Then you get married,
you have a family,
you're the center
of this little universe.
But then the kids move away.
They have lives of their own.
And slowly, things shift.
You're at dinner,
there's this conversation
happening around you,
and you try to chat
with a stranger
but they just nod.
And eventually, they--
they don't really see you.
And then Joan comes along.
Yeah. She still sees me.
Would it be okay if I--
if I said hello?
Yeah.
Hi, Joan.
Art, I'm so happy
to see you.
I wanted you
to meet Dr. Charles.
Dr. Charles,
lovely to meet you.
You too, Joan.
I've heard so much about you.
Would you mind if I got
your opinion on something?
Of course.
So I've got this friend
who's got a paper cut.
All right, now,
this guy's a bit of a worrier.
And he thinks
he's gonna get infected
and I'm telling him, look,
you keep it clean,
you're gonna be fine.
But I'm just curious,
can paper carry disease?
If paper is handled
by someone sick,
there's a risk of
transferring pathogens.
This sounds kind of scary.
So what, you're telling me
that if my friend's papercut
has these pathogens in them,
that he could get sick?
If a cut were
to become infected
with harmful bacteria,
it could lead to serious
illness or even death.
You're trying to make me
look foolish.
Art, Art, not at all.
I am for anything that
makes anyone feel less alone.
Solitaire game on my tablet,
one of my best buddies.
I think Joan's great.
Right? She's sensitive,
she's intuitive.
But she is programmed
to pick up on your concerns.
So if you're worried
about something,
she's gonna mirror that fear
back to you.
I think that Joan
is telling you
not to have the surgery because
you don't wanna have it.
There's no one
to take care of me.
Art, listen.
I took the liberty
of calling your daughter,
who is on her way here
from Minnesota as we speak.
All right?
And if you decide
to do the surgery,
she's prepared to stay here
two, three weeks, whenever,
however long it takes
for you to recover.
So you're not alone.
I mean, there are still
people in this world
who care about you.
So what do you say?
You gonna let us fix you up?
Okay.
Great.
I think you're making
the right decision.
Mm. Hey.
So I was walking
our guest of honor,
just a potential donor,
out to his car
when I see the entire
C-suite parking is blocked in.
Well, I told you
I didn't have any place
to put these ambulances.
Uh-huh, okay,
so if you're feeling the pain,
they're feeling the pain?
Did it work?
Yeah.
Our CEO called a meeting
to approve a temporary hold
on elective surgeries.
Glad to hear it.
You pissed off a lot
of important people tonight.
Add them to the list.
Oh, Jesus.
Okay.
Labs came back
on the kid in four.
CO2 was only 14.
Okay, he's dry.
Give him another
10 mLs per kilo of... saline.
Oh, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no.
Are you sure?
Ah, just--just--
here it comes.
No way!
You're a child star?
It was a long time ago.
I thought
you looked familiar.
My sister had your poster
on her wall.
Wow!
This is gonna be so much fun.
Hey, have you seen Dr. Asher?
Thanks.
Dr. Charles.
Dr. Ripley.
What's, uh, what's going on?
I just wanted to say that
I know you've been trying
to help me out a lot lately
and I haven't made that easy.
You've had a lot--
a lot going on.
Yeah, either way,
I appreciate it.
Thank you for saying that.
I--I appreciate that.
So much fun.
Oh, my gosh.
That was a close one.
You have a tagline?
Sometimes.
Dr. Asher,
we need you out here now.
We were taking her to recovery
when she started complaining
of intense abdominal pain.
She had an epidural
with morphine.
She shouldn't
be feeling anything.
It hurts!
I'm just gonna
look you over real quick,
see what's going on.
Can you tell me what happened?
- I don't know.
I just suddenly felt tired.
And then my stomach,
this stabbing pain!
Okay, we're just gonna
move you a bit here.
Mags, help me roll her.
Okay, okay.
Looking for a hemorrhage?
I don't see any blood.
Okay, I'm gonna push down
on your uterus now.
We need an OR.
Get me 250 Hemabate now.
Let's start the massive
transfusion protocol.
OR 2 is opened upstairs.
- What's going on?
- Your uterus is bleeding.
We need to get you in
another surgery to stop it.
I'm coming with you.
Am I gonna be okay?
We're gonna get you
right up to the OR.
I wanna see Ruby.
We don't have time for that.
I need to see my baby!
Right now, we need
to get you into surgery
to stop the bleeding.
That's the priority.
I'm not going under
until I see Ruby.
Please.
I haven't even met her yet.
Let's go!
Open a vaginal tray
and the Jada.
Please, I can't do this
without seeing her.
I'm sorry. We can't.
You're losing too much blood.
Hemabate is in.
Give 2 grams of TXA.
Ruby!
Marty, how long do we
have until we need to go?
Two minutes, tops.
You have two minutes.
Hi, Ruby.
I'm your mom.
You haven't met me yet,
but I've loved you for so long.
And no matter what happens,
I don't want you to feel
any sort of pain
because you are
the most wanted little baby.
I want so much for you.
For you to live
the most extraordinary life
filled with adventure
and great loves and mistakes.
And I hope to be there
for every second of it.
But if I'm not--
but if I'm not--
I just wanted you to know--
Elise, it's time.
Hey, listen to me.
You are gonna see her
when you wake up.
It's gonna be okay.
Weighted speculum,
right angle retractor.
Vitals are stable.
Sponge stick and suction.
I don't see
any active bleeding.
Why is she dry?
BP is dropping.
Uterus is firm.
This isn't atony.
She's bleeding
from somewhere else.
She's unstable
and tachycardic.
Damn it. What is happening?
Her belly's getting tight.
She's bleeding
into her abdomen.
BP's still dropping.
Starting pressors.
Scalpel.
Oh, my God.
I can't see.
I need laps
and keep them coming.
We're gonna need more blood!
Arteries intact.
Pelvis is completely dry.
It's coming from the liver.
She's in V-fib.
She's coding.
Grab the crash cart.
Charge to 120.
Clear.
Back to sinus rhythm.
This isn't working.
We need to stabilize her
and get her to angio.
There's too much blood.
She's in DIC.
Oh, my God.
Give me a curved 8.
I'm gonna clamp the hilum.
She's back in V-fib.
Charge to 120.
Clear.
Still in V-fib.
Pushing a milligram of epi.
Charge to 200.
Clear.
She's flatlining.
No! No.
Another milligram of epi.
Going in now.
No, come on!
Come on, Elise. Stay with me.
Ruby needs you.
No, come on!
Come on, come on.
Elise.
Stay here.
Come back.
Hannah?
She's been down 40 minutes.
Time of death, 22:31.