Previously on ER:
You did this, you selfish
bitch. So you live with that.
Listen, I talked to the
guys at Hopkins and
we're trying to get
you in the IGF-1 trial.
- IGF-1, what's that?
- Insulin-like growth factor.
Could slow down the
progression of the disease.
I'm applying for
a part-time job...
and it'd help if you could
write a letter or something.
- What kind of work?
- An EMT.
In City Fire, you need someone on the
inside to help you move up, you know.
- I'll help your brother out, no worries.
- Guy's an alcoholic.
Yeah, well, so am I.
Luka's father got sick, he
had to fly back to Croatia.
Chemo could take, like, six
months, and we have a life here.
Yes.
It's crazy how much
he loves that book.
Yeah. He must
really miss Dr. Kovac.
Well, it won't be
too much longer.
I hope not. Don't want
him to forget who his dad is.
Okay, Joe-Joe. Here we go.
Try to get him to eat some kale today.
- Mm-hm.
- All right. I'll see you guys at 5.
- We'll be here. Have a good day.
Bye, sweetie. I love you.
- Bye.
Mrs. Fratelli, that's
really not necessary.
It's the least I can do.
You people are saints.
Oh. I appreciate
the thought but...
Nurse Taggart, you know,
my little Paulie, my angel...
he's my only child.
So if it weren't for you and
the other doctors, I mean...
- he wouldn't be here right now.
- We were just doing our jobs.
No, I insist. Come on,
my salon, it's full service.
Manis, pedis,
makeovers, massages.
Whatever your staff wants,
on the house, all day. Come on.
You spend every day
taking care of people.
Let somebody take
care of you for once.
Okay. I guess you can
set up in the break room.
Great. You ever thought
about going blond?
Might look great on you.
Hey, guys. PRATT AND SAM: Hey.
Oh, my God, Dr. Lockhart.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Good.
- I'm fabulous.
And Paulie's doing great.
He wanted to come, you
know. But he's got school.
Guess what? Free
makeovers today.
- We'll start with you first.
- I'm good.
No, no, no. I got some great,
wonderful, natural treatments.
- I think you would love it.
- No, really, I'm fine. And I'm sorry...
- but who are you?
- Angie. I came in with my son, Paulie.
Oh, look at those
brown eyes. Oh, my God.
I can make these... Sheila,
did you see her eyes?
- Talk to me.
- Willy Archibald, he's 59.
Ground-level fall,
complains of hip pain.
Denies head trauma or LOC.
Good vitals, no meds or allergies.
- How'd you fall, sir?
- I must have tripped on something.
Before you fell, did you have chest
pain, shortness of breath, palpitations?
No, nothing like that. My
hip's killing me, though.
All right, let's get him 4 of morphine.
Get a full hip-and-pelvis series.
So how you doing, man?
Oh, he's doing great. I
love breaking in rookies.
Have we met?
Zach Flaherty. Just
transferred in from Rogers Park.
Must be nice. Wish I had a doctor
for a brother when I was coming up.
Please do what you can. He's a
great kid. He really deserves this.
Okay, I'll hold. Right.
Hi, Mr. Rios. Yes,
this is Dr. Tony Gates.
Right. Yes, from County General.
Yeah, unfortunately,
it's true. It's terminal.
Yeah, his name is Josh Lipnicki
and... Well, he's leaving tomorrow...
so I guess it would
have to be today.
Yeah, I'm sorry. I know
it's short notice, but...
Yeah. Oh, thank you. I really
appreciate you trying to work this out.
All right, thank
you, sir. Thank you.
Free makeovers, huh?
Yeah, it's a good idea,
Sam. Be good for morale.
Oh, I can't take the credit. I don't
even remember treating that lady's kid.
- What?
- What "what?"
Like you remember every
patient who comes through here.
Pratt, you guys got a
hyponatremic for me?
She's altered and electrolytes are
out of whack after gastric bypass.
Curtain 4. She's almost ready.
Dr. Morris, the broken-leg
kid is ready to go...
and the crackhead in 2
won't keep his gown on.
- The broken-leg kid can be discharged.
- What about the crackhead?
I don't know. Avert your eyes.
What do you want from me?
Everybody, this is
Javier, the new desk clerk.
- Javier, this is everybody.
- Nice to meet you.
- Ooh. Girl...
- Wow, nice feathers.
Next person that says
a word is dead meat.
Mr. Grant has right flank
pain times three days.
Did you fall? Injure your back?
No. But I'm a building super.
I bend over all day, fixing stuff.
Never bothered me before, though.
Any allergies or
medical conditions?
Anything make the
pain better or worse?
No. I just can't get
comfortable, you know?
I have a little pain
in my groin too.
- He had hematuria yesterday.
- Any fever?
- No.
- Well, sounds like a kidney stone.
Oh, no, sweet cakes. Our trip.
- Our 20th anniversary's next week.
- Well, you should be fine by then.
We'll give you something for
the pain while we do some tests.
- Be right back.
- Thanks.
- What's your plan?
- Morphine.
With an NSAID. Prostaglandin inhibitors
block the ureteral spasm of renal colic.
- Labs?
- Just a UA to rule out infection.
CT KUB, no contrast.
Got it. And, by the way, I love
what you've done with your...
Shut up, Grady.
- Two more.
- Okay, go.
Forty-five-year-old male,
renal colic, waiting for CT.
Our diarrhea-and-fever guy is
better after hydration, ready to fly.
- You have a stool culture? C. diff?
- Yep. Yep.
You all set for your
yearbook pictures later?
Bite me.
- So how we feeling, Mr. Archibald?
- Better, thanks.
- Films are back.
- Okay, good.
Well, you got no fracture.
But you got complete loss
of joint space, bilaterally.
- Add a sed rate and rheumatoid factor.
- Copy that.
- What's all that mean?
- You got bad arthritis in your hip joints.
All your cartilage is gone. Basically,
you got bone grinding on bone.
Tell me something I
don't already know.
Actually, I'm surprised
you can still walk.
How the heck do
you manage the pain?
Take little steps and
just tough it out, I guess.
Well, we can help you with that.
Plus, I'm gonna refer you
to the orthopedics clinic.
You might need
a hip replacement.
That's what they told me
when I was up there last time.
- Can't afford the insurance or surgery.
- How old did you say you were?
Fifty-nine. Too
young for Medicare.
Frank, can I help you
with something, man?
Could I please have an
autograph, Mr. Archibald?
My pleasure.
Been years since anyone
asked me for one of these.
I used to be from Cleveland.
The only reason I became a Miami fan
is because you got traded down there.
Appreciate that. Who's this to?
- Frank. F-R-A-N-K.
- Uh-huh.
You never heard of Willy Archibald?
He was great. Ate quarterbacks alive.
Running up the middle?
You can forget that.
- You played pro ball, huh?
- For 10 years.
They don't make
them like you anymore.
- Hey, thanks a lot.
- No, no. Thank you.
Holy Mother of God,
is that what I think it is?
Super Bowl VIII. Long time ago.
- You had three sacks in that game.
- Heh.
Well, I'll let you
two reminisce.
I'll be back to talk
about that clinic referral.
- What's it like playing for Shula?
- Oh, my God.
- My cousin used to live in the 9th Ward.
- Get out of here.
- I can't. I'm serious.
- Uh...
Dr. Pratt, GYN has a bed but they
can't take your PID for two hours.
Two? She's been
down here for six.
That was my old 'hood.
- Small world. JAVIER:
You're telling me.
- Dr. Pratt, can you hand me that chart?
- What? Your arms broken?
- I just got my nails done.
- Oh, don't worry, girl. I got it.
Those tips look fierce on you.
- Thank you, baby.
- Hey, Tony.
- Hey.
Hey, listen. Keep the NS running at
150 an hour till I get up there, okay?
- You're back.
- Yeah. First day.
Every time I think I'm
out, they pull me back in.
- You look good. How do you feel?
- Well, ask me at the end of my shift.
Oh, thanks for the flowers
and the get-well card.
Least I could do.
So how's Ray?
Oh, as far as I know, he's good.
You know, all things considered.
- He sent me a letter last week.
- Send him my best, huh, Mayday?
Hey, are you ever gonna
tell me why you call me that?
Mayday? Well, she
was my favorite Bond girl.
Grace Jones in A View to a Kill.
Started off as a bad guy,
then she saved the whole world.
Hey, you're lucky. Could
have been Pussy Galore.
I'll see you later.
- Yo, Gates.
- Bards, what's up, man?
- Haven't seen you. Where you been?
- Stuck up in the ICU.
So, dude, what's
up with your boy?
- Pratt's brother, Chaz.
- Why? What'd he do?
You didn't hear?
Wow. Love the 'do,
Sam. Looks good on you.
- Thanks. It's just a little something.
- Angie's good, huh?
I wish I'd known when I went
brunette. Could have saved 200 bucks.
- Find anybody who remembers her kid?
- Not a soul.
I'm getting my pretty boy
on for my last night with Hope.
I ordered the
works. I can't wait.
Gonna take more than
the works to save that mug.
Oh, my God. So mean.
That's his baseline.
You'll get used to it.
- I hope not.
- Hey, guys. Care package for Ray.
Whatever you want to send,
put it in here by end of day.
Oh. That's really
thoughtful, Katey. How is he?
Pretty incognito. I think I'm gonna
go see him in a couple weeks.
- Well, look who it is.
- Ah. Welcome back.
Hi, stranger. NEELA: Hi, guys.
- So how you feeling?
- Oh, a little sore, you know.
Oh, my God.
- Hi.
- I know. Just don't. I'll explain later.
Okay. Well, I have a few
things left at your place.
So I'll just come and pick
everything up tomorrow.
Okay.
- Stop looking at me like that.
- I can't help it.
I think it looks good. I'm
serious. Farrah was my favorite.
- Yeah, mine too.
- Same here.
I used to love that poster. The
one with the red bathing suit.
Yeah, with the Mexican
blanket-thing background.
We had that up at the precinct.
I used to look at that every day.
Did I have some boyhood fantasies
about her. God, she was hot.
- This is totally creeping me out.
- You and me.
- I'll be in the ladies room.
- I'll walk with you.
Hey, Frank, would you please
get the lab results for Mr. Archibald?
Hey, Pratt, can I
talk to you a second?
What's up, Gates?
Don't you think you should
have told me about your brother?
I mean, I still would have sponsored him.
But, been nice if you'd said something.
- What are you talking about now?
- He's gay.
Yeah, so what?
Oh, you interested?
- Come on, Greg.
- "Come on, Greg" what?
- What exactly was I supposed to say?
- I don't know. "My brother's gay"?
Okay, and then what
would you have done?
- Something. Gave him some advice.
- Really? Like what?
I don't know, you know. But now
his whole station's on to it, you know.
I could have done something,
made it easier on him. I'm just saying.
Just say your way back up to the
ICU and mind your own damn business.
- Lab results for Mr. Willy Archibald.
- Ah.
Mr. Archibald, listen to me. I
cannot help you unless you talk to me.
Now, what is it?
Percocet? Demerol?
- Heroin?
- Hell, no.
I don't mess with that stuff.
It's Vicodin.
Where'd you get
the prescription?
My mom gets it for
me. She's on Medicare.
I can't afford that
stuff on 7.50 an hour.
- Mr. Archibald...
- You don't know how I feel.
I can barely walk,
it hurts so much.
Got laid off because I couldn't
patrol the damn warehouse.
So I get a messenger job.
Figured I could still drive, right?
- Now I can barely do that.
- How long have you been on Vicodin?
Years. I need three, four a day.
It used to knock me out,
but it doesn't do that anymore.
Mr. Archibald, painkillers
are very, very addictive.
What the hell you
want me to do, doc?
Soon my mom is gonna be
driving me around. She's 80, man.
I can get you on the surgery
list here. It's free of charge.
I'm on the damn list.
It's an 18-month wait.
A private hospital would take
you tomorrow if you had the money.
Are you saying that you
have absolutely no assets?
Just the house I bought my
mom. And I'm not selling that.
Well, I can't allow you to keep
popping Vicodin like it's candy.
I'll see what I can do to get you
bumped up on the County list.
Here.
It's worth a lot.
It's real diamonds and gold.
Maybe someone will take it
as a payment for the surgery.
- Put it up on that eBay or something.
- Mr. Archibald, I cannot...
Please, doc.
I can't live with
this pain any longer.
Please.
Hello?
Wait, wait, wait. What happened?
Is he okay? Where are you?
All right. I'm on my way.
- Dr. Lockhart, I really need...
- Ask Pratt.
He told me to ask you.
Hey, Abby, what's up with your foot
lac in 2? It's not gonna suture itself.
He fell. I don't know how
it happened. He just...
Give him to me. Give
him to me. Come on.
Get the door. Get the door!
Excuse me, have you seen our
doctor? She said she'd be right back.
- I got the pedes cuff.
- Come on, baby, wake up.
- Pupils are equal and reactive.
- How far did he fall?
- From the jungle gym.
- How many feet?
- I don't know. Maybe 6.
- Spontaneous resps...
- but have that bag ready.
- Did he just move? Morris?
- He sure did.
- Extremities look good.
Come on, Joe. Come
on, Joe, open your eyes.
- He's gonna be all right?
- Don't know.
- Got a BP, 78/42.
- Did he move or cry or anything?
No. SAM: Sats 98.
Three-centimeter
lac on the forehead.
- I'll irrigate.
- Did he fall on his head?
I don't know. I didn't see.
What do you mean you didn't see?
Were you watching? That's your job.
- I'm so sorry.
- No, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- You should just go.
- Oh, please, I want to stay.
- I'll let you know how he is.
- We're gonna do everything, okay?
He's gonna get
the best that we got.
- So you sure you got everything?
- Yeah. Let's get out of here.
Hey, not so fast, speedy.
We got a few things to
discuss before you leave.
It's Johns Hopkins. Something
went wrong. I didn't get in.
- I anticipated this.
- Just relax. I faxed your consent forms.
I warned them about
you, you little card shark.
I gotta go over there just
to win my money back.
Texas hold'em isn't your game.
I got some news.
Good news, bad news.
What do you want first?
Bad. I like to end on an up.
Well, the bad news is, you can't
go home and pack for Baltimore.
There's something you have to
do. And the good news is a surprise.
What is it?
If I tell you, it will ruin the
whole surprise element.
Don't worry.
You're gonna love it.
- You're in on this too?
- Enough yakking. Let's go.
Come on, we got stuff
to do. Look out. Clear out.
Too bad they don't
take care of the old guys.
If it wasn't for guys like Willy
putting their bodies on the line...
there wouldn't be an
NFL. It's a damn shame.
It's a damn shame he didn't
save some of that money.
A guy was lucky to make
35 G's a year back then.
Not like these
multimillion-dollar clowns today.
Half of them
crybabies and criminals.
May I hold it?
Wow.
I heard Ditka himself auctioned
off his NFC Championship ring...
to help out some
of the old players.
This is priceless.
This is earned with sweat and
blood in the trenches of the gridiron.
You can't sell it.
Chemo boy pulled his central
line. He's bleeding all over Curtain 4.
- And there's a rig 10 minutes out.
- All right.
Hey, how's Joe? I could get somebody
else to take that rig if you need me.
Woke up crying, purposeful
movements. Morris has got him.
I brought two gowns in
case he throws up again.
- Six-0 nylon.
- Luka, hi, it's me.
Joe fell and hit his
head in the park today.
But he's awake now.
We're at the hospital. He...
Oh... I know it hurts.
Could you just call me as soon
as you get this message? Bye.
It's okay, Abby.
He'll call you back.
- Could you hold his head still?
- Wait, wait. What are you doing?
- Closing the lac.
- No, I'll do it. He's an intern.
Yeah, who knows how to
Dermabond a laceration.
What if it gets infected
or he gets a giant scar?
- You wanna be responsible for that?
- Better me than you.
- Sure about that?
- He's right, Abby.
Call CT, let them
know we're on our way.
- No CT. We agreed we'd just observe.
- Yeah, before he vomited.
Yeah. No, it's too much radiation.
No one knows the long-term effects.
Morris, we over-CT kids. We've
had this discussion a thousand times.
Yeah. LOC, vomiting.
You know he needs a scan.
His vitals are good, his mental
status is fine, the LOC was transient.
Observation is enough.
It's not a head bleed.
- The mechanism isn't there.
- If this was your patient...
and not your son,
what would you do?
All right. No peeking.
- I'm not.
- You better not be.
- Are you ready?
- I was ready a half hour ago.
All right, take your hands down.
Look at this. Front row, third base
line, right behind the on-deck circle.
You can't afford those tickets.
It's not how much you make, my
young friend, it's who you know.
We'll get him in and out soon as we
can. I'll give you an immediate read.
Thanks. BETTINA: No IV?
We didn't think we needed one.
We should get one in. Usually, a
little whiff of ketamine does the trick.
Yeah. I don't wanna sedate him.
It's only gonna take
a few seconds, right?
I've scanned a lot of toddlers.
Trust me, you want the drugs.
I can do it in one needle
stick, Abby. I promise.
Hypoventilation, drug allergies,
it's just not worth the risk.
We can't get a good look
unless he holds completely still.
Yeah. Can you pass me that?
Shh. Thank you. I just
wanna try something, okay?
Shh, shh, shh. Here you go. If it
doesn't work, you can sedate him.
- Just let me try, okay?
- Okay.
Yeah. And this one too.
And what about this? Oh.
Remember this book?
Daddy Takes a Trip.
Huh? Hah.
"This is me when I
was your age, Joe."
What do you think? Do
you...? Hah. What's that?
"This is me and your Uncle
Niko. We loved the beach."
Do you see them on the
beach, right there? Right in here?
Who's that? Who's that?
"This is me, your dad, missing
you, wishing you were here."
These seats are exceptional.
We never sat this close before.
- You're welcome.
- Man.
Excuse me. You Josh?
Stand up. Yeah, this is Josh.
- I'm Tony Gates.
- Nice to meet you.
Josh Lipnicki. His mom, Serena.
- Hey, Josh.
- Derrek Lee.
- This is for you. Whole team signed it.
- Wow, thanks, Mr. Lee.
- Good luck in Baltimore.
- Mr. Lee.
- Yeah?
I gotta tell you, your opponents
have a statistical tendency...
to pitch you high and outside.
And the wind's blowing out today,
so lay off that stuff, you'll murder them.
All right. I'll
keep that in mind.
- I don't know what to say.
- That's a first.
- Pretty cool, huh?
- Yes. This definitely qualifies as cool.
Nice.
No answer?
Well, by the time you reach him,
all you're gonna have is good news.
You know, I thought
the NICU was tough...
but at least both
of us were there.
And he was brand new. I
didn't even know him yet.
But now he's... now he's Joe.
Okay. So Abby... What?
There's no
subdural, no epidural.
The grey-white junctions
and sulci look sharp.
And there's no evidence
of diffuse axonal injury.
- Well, that's good, right?
- But...?
There's a subtle high-density
irregularity in the left parietal region.
It's small and it could be nothing.
Since it correlates with the location...
of his injury, I think we're
obliged to check it out with an MRI.
After all this, we have
to sedate him anyway.
We need him
still for 45 minutes.
- I know.
- We'll take him to the ER.
We'll have Chuny start the
IV. She's the best in town.
I want LMX cream.
Okay, I'll put it on
now, give it time to work.
He's got an 18 gauge in
the right antecubital fossa.
- Got 40 of Lasix en route.
- All right, we got it.
Make yourself useful and
go refill the airway box, rookie.
Hey, come hit me
later. We gotta talk.
BP, 194/126.
So CHF exacerbation. We
already got Lasix. What's next?
After load
reduction? Nitro drip?
- Hey.
- Hey, man, what the hell is this?
You got something
you wanna say to me?
You can wear them
for your boyfriend.
Man, I swear to God, I'll beat
your punk ass into next week.
I'm right here, rook.
Come on, let's go.
- You all right?
- I'm fine.
Jeez, I was just kidding around.
- Greg, can you get out of here?
- What?
Get out of here, man. I'm fine.
I always open up a second kit.
That way I'll never need it, you know?
Here's your flush.
- I hate this.
- I'll make it quick.
- Shh, shh.
- Okay.
- Come on, baby.
- It's okay.
Oh, my God. I don't
think I can watch this.
Look, you don't have
to be in here, you know.
I know. But I don't
wanna desert him.
You won't be the first
mom that can't watch, Abby.
Come on. We'll be right next
door. I'll sit with you, okay?
Listen to me. Listen,
baby, I love you.
I remember when Alex was 3.
I took him to one of those
bounce houses at the carnival.
And of course he's in there
with 5-and 6-year-old kids.
So he gets knocked down, right?
And every time he tries to get up...
he keeps getting knocked down again,
and he's crying, "Mommy! Mommy!"
The attendant won't let me in because
he thinks I'm some stupid teenager.
So, what'd you do?
I stood there and
I cheered him on.
And every time he got knocked
down, I told him, "I know you can get up."
But that's when it hit me.
They fall.
And all you can do is be there
and hope they keep getting up.
Just keep some ice on
it. You should be fine.
I was just breaking the kid's
balls, you know? It was a joke.
Jokes are supposed to be funny.
Come back in a few days and
I'll check your eye out again.
Hey, I got empty chairs in there.
Come on, who's up for some pampering?
- It's not really my style.
- End of my shift, I am there, Ang.
How about you, huh?
I could wax those brows,
make you look 10 years younger.
You should do it. It's like you've
got two caterpillars over your eyes.
No, thank you. Unlike
you good-for-nothings...
- I'm not vain about my appearance.
- Well, that must make it easier. Heh-heh.
How'd you get this
bum wing, Reggie?
Fell out of my desk.
He dozed off at school, fell
out of his desk during math.
He hasn't been
sleeping well at home.
He's afraid the bogeyman's
gonna get him. Baby.
Tommy. MORRIS:
Hey, does this hurt?
Bogeyman, huh? You know,
there's no such thing, buddy.
- I've seen him. MORRIS:
You've seen him?
- What's he look like?
- He's green, big eyes, crazy hair.
Well, no point tenderness.
He's got full range of motion.
I don't think it's broken.
Why didn't you say it
was a green bogeyman?
I got something that
will fix that right up.
Kidney stone guy in 2
doesn't look so good.
I'll be right back.
What kidney stone guy?
Abby's patient. Gross hematuria,
dropped his pressure, diaphoretic.
- Where's my doctor?
- BP, 80/50.
- What's wrong? He was fine.
- Did he get narcotics?
Five milligrams of
morphine three hours ago.
Bolus a liter of saline.
What are his labs?
- They only sent a
UA. GRANT: My back.
Stat HemoCue, chemistry and EKG.
- Are those films? DAWN:
Yeah, Abby didn't see them.
Dr. Lockhart said it was a
kidney stone, he'd be fine.
Hello, ma'am, I'm Dr. Morris. I'm
afraid a kidney stone isn't the problem.
- Get Surgery down here right away.
- He needs surgery?
- Your husband has a mass in the kidney.
- A mass? Like, a tumor?
- HemoCue 8.1.
- Too soon to say, but maybe.
- Type and cross, two units.
- Oh, my God. She said he was okay.
Like I said, the program
is free of charge.
Meets three times a
week at the hospital.
If you can commit to that,
get weaned off the Vicodin...
then we can do this.
I don't know, doc. What if
the procedure don't work?
It will. Just promise
me you'll lay off the pills.
- Okay, deal. What do I gotta do?
- I pulled some strings.
Ortho bumped you high on
the list for hip replacement.
But for now, we're gonna put a needle
into your joint under x-ray guidance.
- Come on. I'll help you.
- Yeah?
- Team doc used to stick us all the time.
- Well, this isn't quite the same.
What we're gonna do is something
called an intra-articular injection.
We put a long-acting
anesthetic and steroid.
- It kills the pain for a month.
- Damn.
If you don't get your surgery by then,
you come back, we do it all over again.
Cool?
- Thanks, doc.
- You're welcome.
Now, I just need you
to sign here to consent.
All right. Now let's get you on your
side so I can prep you. Come on.
- All right.
- I just gotta let you know...
that there's a small chance
of bleeding and infection.
But the benefits far
outweigh the risks.
- Is it gonna hurt?
- No. We numb the skin up first.
- Hey.
- Hey there.
How many of these
have you done before?
Oh, I'm not doing this. She is.
Hello, Mr. Archibald.
I'm Dr. DeJesus.
Well, in that case, you may
have to leave the room, doc.
- Pressure's 75/40.
- Call for another two units.
Oh, no, no, sweetie.
There's so much blood.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Dawn, take her to the
family room, please.
- Is it blunt trauma?
- No, renal mass eroding into the vessels.
- Hemorrhaging around his kidney.
- He needs surgery.
- A central line kit.
- Crit's dropping despite transfusions.
He doesn't need a central
line, he needs the O.R.
- Hang a unit of FFP.
- If we sit on him, he's gonna crash.
- What's your plan, Neela?
- Angioplasty balloon in the renal artery.
I cut the blood
supply to his kidney...
get his pressure up, he'll
have a chance in the O.R.
- Ballsy.
- Or stupid.
Okay. Let's call for a
C-arm. Neela, you're up.
And now, batting
third, first baseman...
number 4 5, Derrek Lee.
Guide wire's in
the femoral artery.
Excellent.
Advancing a
6-millimeter balloon.
- Last hemoglobin is 8.5.
- Dropping. He's losing more blood.
Not for long. Morris, can you
inflate the balloon, please?
Looks good. Okay, fluoro off.
Could have done a
nephrectomy by now.
He could have had an MI or a
stroke because he was too unstable.
Blood pressure's up, 95/60.
Best it's been. Rasgotra
shoots and scores. Nice job.
- Move him to the O.R. I'll be right up.
- Have the blood bank ahead four units.
- You got lucky.
- So this is about the patient, is it?
You know, when Ray got
hurt, I was in a lot of shock.
- We all were.
- Poor you.
What happened to Ray
had nothing to do with me.
He got piss drunk
at Abby's wedding.
He's the one who stumbled
in front of that truck, not me.
- Even he says that.
- You done?
You know, you can hate me as
much as you like. I couldn't care less.
But I will not take the blame for
what happened to Ray. You got that?
- So how's he doing?
- Oh, he's just coming out of it.
- How about you?
- Mm. I've been better.
You get in touch with Luka yet?
You know, it's totally different
when it's your kid on the table.
And it would be a lot easier
if I wasn't doing this alone.
Baby Joe's gonna be just fine.
And you are not alone.
I just got this from Bettina. She
apologized for not coming down.
Normal parenchymal tissue.
- No blood or edema.
- Okay.
What did I tell you?
No, really, I feel
much better. I just...
- I have to be there when he wakes up.
- I understand.
Oh, God. What if it's malignant?
One thing at a time. Let's get
him through the operation first.
I'll take you upstairs. The surgeons
will answer all your questions.
- We missed a 6-centimeter mass?
- You can't catch everything.
That thing was gigantic.
Was that my kidney
stone patient's wife?
Uh... Yeah. Yeah, I think so.
I've got some charts
I should go finish.
- Where is he?
- Who?
- Oh! Well, he needed surgery.
- What?
- No, it was nothing. We caught it.
- Morris.
- You didn't have enough on your plate?
- Morris, what is it? Come on.
Probable renal-cell carcinoma.
- Oh, my God.
- That guy's tumor was not your fault.
- We're not sure if it's malignant.
- I told him he was fine.
Well, we handled
it. We're a team.
We back each other up.
Now go home. Get some
rest, take care of your boy.
Don't beat yourself
up over this.
- See you later.
- Thanks for everything.
- Bye, sweetie.
- Thank you.
Twenty minutes and I will be
in the capable hands of Angie...
- upgraded to the premium package.
- What are you doing?
Oh, it's for a kid I got who can't
sleep. Chronic bogeyman problem.
So you're giving him candy?
- No.
Well, yes. But he doesn't
know that it's candy.
I'm gonna tell him it's
bogeyman repellent.
- Genius, right?
- It's a lie.
Sam, let me tell you about a little thing
that we like to call the placebo effect.
- They look like M&M's.
- Yeah.
Yeah, they do that
to cover up the taste.
The methyl chloride anti-noxazine
is very bitter in pure form.
- They taste like M&M's too.
- Cool, huh?
No, no, no, never take more than
two. Right before you brush your teeth.
Okay, there's a three-week
supply there, so make them last.
- Thanks, Dr. Morris.
- You bet. Hang for a little while longer.
We'll get you guys moving
out as soon as we can.
Hi. It's me again.
Uh... Um...
I still don't know
where you are.
Maybe you're at the hospital.
I hope everything's okay.
But Joe is fine.
The MRI was clear.
So you can just ignore all
my other panicked messages.
We're on our way home. We'll
be there in about 20 minutes.
So call us. Bye.
Shh, shh.
I don't worry about it.
You gotta be what you are.
You said it, girl.
Hey, guys. Excuse me.
Hey, Pratt, what's going on?
And this one? He's cute.
- Boo.
- Heh-heh-heh.
Excuse me, Dr. Pratt?
- Yup.
- Is your brother single?
Ah. You're gonna
have to check with him.
- Good night.
And I will.
See you tomorrow, buddy.
Morris? MORRIS: Yeah.
- What are you doing there?
- I'm getting my treatments.
You should really stay
and have something done.
No, I'm good. You take it easy.
- Suit yourself.
Oh, hey, Dr. Moretti, welcome
back. How was the conference?
Oh. You know, the EM
Research Symposium...
is no mere
conference, Dr. Pratt.
It is a magical week where
the greatest research minds...
get together to exchange
ideas and knowledge.
- Big waste of time, huh?
- Yeah.
Oh, hey. Your boy Gates picked up
von Willebrand's on a trauma patient.
ICU must be doing him some good.
Always a pleasure
talking to you.
Hey.
- So where's your partner?
- Lunch.
Chaz, why are you
ignoring me, man?
You really don't know?
- You made me look like a bitch, Greg.
- What?
I don't need you to fight my
battles. I can take care of myself.
Come on, man. It
wasn't even like that.
How you gonna sit there
and try to tell me what it's like?
Do they call you faggot here?
Do they whistle at
you in the shower too?
Listen, I just reacted, man.
I saw my little brother
getting pushed around, man.
A switch flipped.
Come on, man, you know what
I'm saying. You're my family.
I know you probably
thought you were helping...
and I appreciate it...
but if my big brother the
doctor, comes to the rescue...
then they're gonna respect you.
If I stand up for myself, then
they're gonna respect me.
You're right.
Whatever you
need, man, I got you.
Then I was a personal
shopper at Barneys.
Dr. Morris, the asthmatic...
in Exam 2 dropped his sats.
I think he needs a tube.
- Coming.
Start continuous
albuterol. Solu-Medrol, 125.
- It's ready. Sats down to 89.
- Point-one milligram epi IV...
- infuse a milligram over an hour.
- Aah!
You don't wanna tube him?
Reg. Wha...? It's okay, Reg.
What's the matter, buddy?
You e-mail me from Baltimore.
Let me know how it goes.
Yeah, I'm sure a lot of needle
sticks and an endless supply of tests.
You'll be fine. Fly safe.
Yeah, I hope they let me on the plane
with a week's worth of urine samples.
Go on and pack,
sweetie. We leave early.
Hey, thanks for today, Tony.
- I had a great time.
- My pleasure, buddy.
I don't know how to thank you.
I haven't seen him
that happy in so long.
It was nothing.
No.
It was most
definitely something.
I'll probably be up
packing all night.
I better go home. I have
an early shift tomorrow.
- Will you keep me posted?
- Yeah, we will.
Good night, Tony.
Hi, Abby. This is Sally in
Dr. Murphy's office. Just a reminder...
that you have an appointment
with the hygienist, Friday at 9 a.m.
Hello?
Would you like to lower your
interest rate by 2.5 percent?
- No, I'm not interested.
- Hear me out, here.
We offer debt consolidation...