Previously on "ER.."
Well, Ms. Knight,
welcome to County General.
You do know how
to do this, right?
Yes.
You've broken
every rule
and regulation
we have in the ER.
It seems in the best
interest of the child
to complete
what's been started.
I wanted to ask you,
Dr. Anspaugh
about the possibility
of sponsorship for next year.
You don't want to
continue with Dr. Romano?
Dr. Romano doesn't wish
to continue with me.
Haven't gotten much sleep
since I took that RA Job.
Had to take the day off
so I could run the clinic.
I don't suppose you could
spare anyone to help me out?
There's a position's opening
District Medical Director
for EMS. We could use
someone like you on our side.
‐ 'Dr. Carter?'
‐ 'Dr. Carter, are you there?'
‐ 'Mm‐hmm.'
‐ 'I'm so sorry, but we‐‐'
‐ 'Hey, we're locked out.'
‐ Uh, hang on.
Hang on. I'm coming.
Yes?
‐ What's up?
‐ Dr. Carter, I'm so sorry.
I know it's really late,
uh, really early‐‐
We're locked out.
We were in the library
and we left our bag‐packs
but I thought he had his key
and he thought I had mine.
No, I did have a key, okay?
But it wasn't
my dorm key.
'I had my old
apartment key'
but my sister
threw me out.
Okay, I got a master key.
‐ Sorry to wake you.
‐ It's my job.
‐ Oh, Peter.
‐ Hey, hi.
‐ I hope I'm not disturbing you.
‐ Mmm...no, no.
I‐I didn't expect you
to finish so soon.
Well, I, uh..
‐ It was just a spleen.
‐ Mm‐hmm.
‐ And I was thinking about you.
So I thought I would come over..
Mm‐hmm.
Come over...and finish
what we started.
Mm‐hmm. Peter?
Peter, I, uh, I..
What?
Before you jump
to any conclusions..
‐ You're not alone.
‐ Right. I'm‐‐
'Sorry to wake you
so early, darling.'
This jet lag..
'Oh, excuse me.'
I didn't realize
anyone had arrived.
Allow me, uh...this
is Peter Benton
'a, uh...work colleague..'
Obviously, a friend.
Uh, Peter, this is..
...Charles Corday, my father.
Oh. Um...nice to meet you.
‐ The toilet's overflowing.
‐ What?
'In the women's
bathroom?'
It's going
all over the floor.
That sounds like
a call for maintenance.
I'm just the RA.
Well, they're not on
until 7:00.
You better come.
It's getting bad.
'I'm calling to confirm
an 8:00 a. m. appointment.'
Carol Hathaway.
AC Working?
‐ I'm on with them now.
‐ Thank you.
Hey, you'll
knock 'em dead.
‐ Uh‐oh. What'd she do wrong?
‐ Me?
You see a med student
in two hours early
she must have
screwed something up.
No, she's checking her labs
that were pending yesterday.
Yeah. Just for fun.
I want to make sure nothing
slipped through the cracks.
No, don't burn out.
She's already
the resident's pet.
I am not.
She got an IV
solo her first day.
‐ So I was lucky.
‐ Morning, all.
Good morning.
Can somebody take a look
at my grandson? He's not right.
Sure if you just take a seat.
Someone will be right with you.
It's okay, I can take
a look at him.
‐ Lucy, you wanna join me?
‐ Sure.
A month ago,
he was starting to walk.
Now he just lays there.
I'll join you as soon
as I stow my stuff.
There's no need.
Take them to exam four.
Well, if you
need me to sign off
on any procedures‐‐
No, check your
calendar, Kerry.
My probation
was for 30 days.
‐ I'm a free man again.
‐ Thirty working days, Doug.
‐ I don't think so.
‐ I'll check on that.
I'm sure you will.
I got him.
Good luck upstairs.
Come on.
John Carter.
Dad, hi.
How's the sailing?
Uh‐huh.
Uh‐huh. I think...I think
Gamma's being dramatic.
Because it's not a slum.
It's a...a dorm.
Well, dad, it pays the rent.
I said it pays the rent.
No, I'm not turning my back.
Because I'm still a doctor.
It's just not clear,
it's just not clear
whether they're going to be
able to pay me or not this year.
The RA position
is for residents.
What the, no,
there's‐there's, um..
...student advising
and‐and counseling.
It's, you know...practically
a faculty position.
And it feels good
to pay my own way.
Dad?
Hello? Hello?
Oh! Yosh, I'm so sorry.
I'm so excited.
They said yes.
‐ They said yes?
‐ They said yes!
‐ You're hot stuff!
‐ Thanks.
Mark, thank you so much.
‐ They said yes.
‐ To your proposal?
Thanks to Mark's
great letter of support.
Ah, I just told the truth.
I said your clinic
deserved a salaried RN.
Oh. There you go, baby.
Eh, why‐why's
the number flashing?
'They're calling
on the land line.'
Mark's learning
the new radio.
Does this mean, you're
going to take the EMS job?
Well, I‐I haven't
decided yet.
Just touch the screen.
‐ On the number?
‐ It won't bite.
What'd‐what'd I do?
Well, when you touch it twice
you hang up on them.
Don't worry.
They'll call back.
Jerry, what is going on
with the AC in here?
They were just here. Takes a
couple minutes for to cool down.
Oh, they're on med nine.
I gotta take this
up to the lab.
I'll take over.
Okay. Go ahead.
Just once.
Check volume.
'Pulse 120. Gave 500 cc's
of normal saline. Copy?'
Uh, County General
on med nine.
We didn't catch
the first part.
Can you repeat?
You have to step
on the pedal
when you speak,
Dr. Greene.
County General
on med ni‐‐
Mark, you're not switched over.
You gotta switch over
to med nine first.
‐ Now.
‐ County General on med nine.
Can you please repeat
the information‐‐
I said "pulling up now."
Single vehicle MVA
'62‐year‐old
restrained driver.'
What's with the radio?
Well, Mark Greene is
considering a future in EMS.
We were just teaching
him the ropes.
Uh‐huh. BP's 100 over 60,
tachy at 120, diaphoretic.
Airbags deployed. Wife was
a passenger in the front seat.
He just groaned
and slumped over the wheel.
Thank goodness we
were barely moving.
I didn't know
you were on today.
Uh, I'm not I'm just here to
talk to paramedics.
‐ When you're done.
‐ Yeah.
We're gonna take very good
care of your husband.
So, if I can't
persuade my daughter
you'd be interested
in the job?
Oh, you know. I have considered
a cardiothoracic fellowship.
I mean, as a specialty,
it has it all.
The heart, the most magnificent
machine in creation.
'I'm flattered you
came all this way'
to have another go at convincing
me to join your practice.
It was on my way.
I can't appear
too eager with this one.
And I can't
be so picky.
It isn't as if
I have other options.
Darling, isn't
that him? Romano?
'Oh, God, don't
let him spot us.'
He keeps leaving
messages about
some dreadful lap choley
this afternoon.
Well, he still
is your sponsor.
He only wants me because
he's got a potential partner
keen on seeing
the Aesop in action
and he's not
certified.
The Aesop robot? Brilliant.
It galls me
to help him in any way.
I wouldn't even give him
the satisfaction of seeing that.
I expect my daughter
to go out fighting.
Dive in there. Impress
the hell out of Romano.
Make the bugger rue
the day he terminated you.
Yeah. Go for it.
I feel ganged up on.
Lizzie, Peter.
Mr. Corday, what a surprise.
I bet you're
on your way to UCSF.
I came to visit my daughter
while she was still here.
Hmm. You know,
I'm sorry we were..
...unable to continue
the fellowship.
I was never fond of her working
with you in the first place.
I recall that.
You got my message about
assisting on the Aesop?
Wouldn't miss it.
Although, um, uh..
...technically, you'll
be assisting me, right?
Well, uh...you got me
on that one.
Do you know, I haven't
seen this gadget in action.
If that's alright
with Dr. Romano.
I'd be honored.
I should have
brought him in before
but last week,
we visited his cousin
and he seemed better.
‐ Temp's still 100.45.
‐ Where does his cousin live?
‐ Waukegan, right on the lake.
‐ Sounds nice and cool.
Ms. Knight, what tests
would you order?
I'd do a full metabolic workup?
'That sounds bad.'
Yeah. I'm gonna try
something else first.
Yosh, see if you can
find an electric fan.
There's one in the lounge.
We'll cool the room down
see how that affects
your grandson.
I turn the lights out sometimes
and that seems to help.
Okay. We'll
try that, too.
Uh, we'll be
right back.
You wanna keep
an eye on him? Okay.
Any questions?
An infant losing
milestones
it sounds like a
metabolic disorder to me.
Look, ordinarily, you'd
be right to check there first
but he's got a fever and in
this heat, he's not even damp.
Why are the lights
out in exam four?
We're cooling
a young boy down
with anhidrotic
ectodermal dysplasia
no sweat glands.
It's just a hunch.
I think it's the right hunch.
You want to look it up.
Hold on, are
you telling me
that the EMS Medical Director
is a real person?
He's an ER Doc.
I thought it
was just a name
they stuck
on the top of memos.
Not when I do it.
Somebody page me?
Yeah, abdominal mass
in trauma one
and it sounds like
a Triple A.
What? I pay attention.
Oh and uh, Carla called.
She might not make it to
Reese's ear appointment.
She wants you to leave her
a message if that's a problem.
Oh. No, that's cool.
Damn, Jerry, what is it,
a hundred degrees in here?
Yeah, I'm on it. I'm on it.
Dr. Carter, I'm sorry.
I was with Dr. Ross.
‐ Coffee?
‐ For me?
Can you imagine
me on caffeine?
‐ One sugar, right?
‐ Right. Thanks.
Hey, why am I already
signed up for two patients?
Oh, I hope you don't mind.
The right arm weakness
could be really interesting.
I ordered up
the previous charts
reviewed them
and did the H and P.
Already?
You want a good residency
you've gotta come
out of the gates flying.
Well, you got a little time
before you need to worry
about that sort of thing.
It's the same for you, isn't it?
Residents start bucking for
chief when they're interns?
You've probably been laying
the groundwork since day one.
Oh, yeah.
At school, they said
that's how you
build a career.
Right, Dr. Carter?
Please don't call
him "Dr. Carter."
You'll never be able
to live with him.
What should I call you?
He's just..."Carter."
"Dr. Carter" will be fine.
Oh, God, yeah. Right there.
I was so tense
talking to admin.
I guess you didn't
need to be.
No. I should have asked
for two nurses.
Are you going
to hire yourself?
No. I'm the only volunteer
I don't mind asking.
Besides, it'll be fun
to hire someone.
Good for the clinic.
‐ There you go. I get it?
‐ Yeah!
Double GSW coming in,
two 16‐year‐olds
one shot through the head,
one through the flank.
Mark, did you
answer the radio?
All by myself.
Single GSW
to the left temporal scalp.
BP is 120 over 78,
pulse 80.
No neuro deficits,
unless being a macho jerk
and attacking your
friendly paramedic counts.
She was going for my piece.
I was going
for your pulse.
You can bleed out next time.
Get that lac taken care of.
Alright, Doris,
I'll look at it. Let's go.
There's no palpable bullet.
What's your name, son?
Looks like he's
been shot before.
This is my first
time above my neck.
Oh, well, you the man.
Pupils are equal and reactive.
‐ You know where you are?
‐ 'Sixteen year old..'
Lil 'Toine, what's up?
Where you been?
Gunshot to the
right buttock.
Single entrance wound.
They capped you in the ass?
‐ 'Oh, that's wack.'
‐ Nothing but a thang, BG.
‐ Count. One, two, three.
‐ Two GSWS.
There ought to be
something for us to do.
Maybe a central line,
maybe a chest tube.
I don't know
if I'm ready for that yet.
Oh, you aren't.
‐ Pain here?
‐ Nah, man.
I ain't shot there.
Normal sinus
on the scope.
Need any help here?
Dr. Carter,
so glad you asked.
Get some surgilube
and a fresh pair of gloves.
We'll check next door.
Tighter so I can't
open them up.
Anything we
can do in here?
I don't need no sister
with no attitude
putting a shot in my head.
Close your eyes, sir.
We haven't finished checking
your cranial nerves.
Looks like they got it
under control.
Don't worry.
There'll be lots of chances.
I know.
Sure, the guidelines tell you,
wait until the cops get there
You know, wait until
the scene is secured
but you get there, and some kid
is lying in the street bleeding
what are you going to do?
The reason
why I'm curious is
the department's looking
for a new
District Medical Director.
You gonna leave
the ER?
No, no. It'd be
part of my job here.
I thought it'd be a good way
to approach continuity of care.
Oh, I hate to see it happen
to such a decent guy.
What do you mean?
Seven years,
I've been working on a rig.
Seven years, we've
known that what we need
is more paramedics.
And every year,
for seven years‐‐
Right, right, right.
They cut the budget.
Uh‐huh.
That part of the job
would not be new.
Am I gonna have a scar?
Nah. I'm too good at this.
'Get an abdominal CT'
with oral IV
and rectal contrast.
If the bullet
hit his colon
you'd think he'd
be hurting more.
That kid was masking,
he's in pain.
Hey, how's yours doing?
Ah, he's stable,
no blood in the urine
stool trace positive
for heme.
You know, I checked
on your probation
and it ended yesterday.
Yeah? I guess
the party's over.
The committee
required me
to sign off
on your patients.
I did not ask
for the job.
Yeah, but you
kind of got off on it, though.
I do not relish baby‐sitting.
It'd make my life
a lot easier
if everyone did their jobs
on their own.
Oh, Kerry, I'm sorry
to be a burden.
You know what?
This whole thing.
It just meant nothing
to you, did it?
It's just, uh, water
under the bridge, right?
Oh...I wouldn't say that.
Do you know how many
calls I'm still getting
from people who want
ultra rapid detox?
Forward them to me.
I'll take their calls.
Yeah. Can't do that.
God knows what you'd say.
You know, I think
it's a wise move for you.
Great research
opportunities in EMS.
I'm actually
more interested
in coordinating
paramedic care.
For once, you and I
would not be in competition.
Fieldwork was
never my forte.
You wouldn't want
this job, Kerry.
There's no money,
no power, no glory.
Yeah, right, it doesn't fit
into my Machiavellian scheme
to rule the
emergency department.
You heading out?
Yeah. Rachel's got
a soccer game.
Dr. Weaver,
do you have a minute?
Absolutely.
Jerry, it is
freezing in here.
I know.
I don't know
if you noticed
I put in
a salary request.
I did.
My finances
have changed of late
and it's no longer
going to be feasible‐‐
Yeah. I approved it.
And frankly,
I was glad to see it.
Someone who practices
medicine as a hobby
runs the risk of looking
like a dilettante.
Ah, yes. Well, that's not me.
That's not me, and that's
what's been worrying me
is that while I was unpaid,
it held me back
from stating
my long‐term goal.
Which is?
I want to be
chief resident.
You don't have to worry
about that quite yet, do you?
No? I want to come
out of the gates strong.
You know it's the only way
to really build a career.
Well, you're off to a good
start with your student.
Ms. Knight is organized
and in control.
Yeah. Lucy's right
on top of it.
A good student is usually
evidence of a good teacher
and that's the first step
toward being a chief.
‐ I say, Jerry‐‐
‐ I'm on it, okay?
'They're turning
it up now.'
I was going to ask you
if you paged me.
'Yeah. That was me.'
Where's the gentleman
with the gunshot wound?
Uh, bangers to curtain three.
You know, don't lead her by
the nose too much, your student.
I will keep that in mind.
Jerry, it's like
a meat locker in here.
Nice work.
Triple A on an anterior left
renal vein is never a picnic.
Yeah, divide and conquer.
What are you doing at 4 o'clock?
I've got a tricky
retroperitoneal sarcoma.
I was going to run
my son upstairs
for an audiology exam
but I guess I
could reschedule.
Your son have
a hearing problem?
Ah, there was concern.
Turns out he had
fluid in his ears.
I'm just following up.
But he tested
normal at birth?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
‐ Wasn't he a preemie?
Yeah. That's right.
They sometimes give
gent to preemies.
It can be ototoxic.
No, no. He's fine.
He..
I'll be there.
Well, if you're sure.
How'd you like to follow up
on Mr. Specchierla in recovery?
Our Triple A.
Oh. Yeah.
I'm on it.
The CT Scan showed
a hole in your rectum.
Look like they ripped
you another one Lil 'T.
‐ My belly's hurting.
‐ I gave him six of morphine.
Hey, man. Hey, come
check me out, too.
I don't want no dents left
in this pretty head of mine.
Your head
too big, anyway.
Are you going to
do my operation?
You don't want
no Chinese fag
messing down there.
Japanese.
Your friend could use
a little support.
This isn't a joke.
After the surgery
you're going to have
to wear a colostomy bag.
‐ Do you know what that is?
‐ No.
Lil 'Toine gonna
be crapping in a bag?
Lil 'Toine, you gonna be
crapping in a bag, man.
Not me, man.
This is not an accurate
picture of a colostomy.
‐ Baby, I heard they shot you.
‐ What you doing here, Moselle?
‐ 'She come to see Lil 'Toine.'
‐ Man, I don't think so.
What business is it
of yours who I come to see?
‐ Oh, this is my business, girl!
‐ Chill, girls, chill!
Take it outside,
both of you, now.
Go, go.
We'll explain
the process to you
when your mother arrives, okay?
'That's what happens when
you run, man. Booty call.'
Yosh, get these two
in separate rooms.
Gonna miss that, I bet.
Actually, I will.
He's just a boy.
You know, I was
really sorry to hear
that nothing
worked out for you.
Had my fingers crossed
for a faculty spot.
But, it wasn't meant to be.
You know, I have heard
of foreign doctors
who were willing
to start over as interns.
‐ Oh, God.
‐ I know. I can't even imagine.
Actually, I do have
one last‐ditch
desperate chance in half an hour
so wish me luck.
Call security!
I said, take it outside!
‐ Who you talking to?
‐ Shut up!
‐ Take it out now. Go.
‐ She crazy, man!
‐ I called security.
‐ And I'm calling the police.
You better move fast.
Go, go, go!
‐ Shut up!
‐ Go.
'Nice work, Kerry.'
I'm glad I stayed
on your good side.
Excuse me, nurse.
I'm Mr. Savage.
I know you're very busy here but
I've been waiting a long time.
Yeah, well, Mr. Savage,
I am a doctor
and you have to
wait your turn.
‐ You're not a nurse?
‐ Rob Savage?
‐ Yeah.
‐ I have your chart right here.
You can't smoke that in here.
Follow me.
'Jerry, get this mess
cleaned up'
and call climate control
to send down some parkas.
You know where
the Rowdies Crush game is?
Just started.
I'm looking
for my daughter's team.
'Yeah, well, there's
girls in this league.'
She's not playing
on a coed team. Rachel!
Go! Go all the way, Brandon!
Take her. Take her!
She can't stop you!
‐ Easy as pie!
‐ Hang in there, Rach!
‐ 'You'll be fine.'
‐ Take her! Take her!
Tough "D."
‐ Where's the flag?
‐ Flag's right there.
Penalty kick!
This one's yours, son.
Easy point.
She can't stop you.
Goalie's a girl!
Put her away!
Hang in there, Rach!
'This guy's got nothing!'
Don't worry, Rachel!
Hang in there.
It'll be fine!
Hang tough!
Is there a first aid kit?
Sorry to kick so hard.
‐ It wasn't that hard.
‐ Hey, you okay?
‐ Dad, you're here.
‐ Yeah.
That was a great save.
That first aid
kit was empty.
Does she want some ice?
Uh. Nah, nah, she's tough.
Hey, you got leaves
in your hair.
I've had it before.
I‐I just can't pee.
How long has
it been this time?
About two and a half days.
It's pretty uncomfortable.
Put this gown on. I'm gonna
go and check with the doctor.
Last time they had
to stick this tube in me.
‐ A Foley catheter?
‐ Yeah.
‐ What are you doing?
‐ Having a smoke.
‐ You can't smoke!
‐ Not even in here?
No. Get undressed.
I'll be right back.
'Hold on, hold on.'
‐ 'I got you, sweetheart.'
‐ What's up?
I got you.
Multiple stab wounds.
It happened out in the bay.
Oh, man, Weaver kicked
her out of chairs.
Do you know
where she is?
‐ No, I don't.
‐ Page her.
‐ Peter, how have you been?
‐ Oh, good.
I was just checking something
on Reese's chart.
‐ Is he having a problem?
‐ No, he's fine.
Well, he did have
an ear infection
but I know he was
given furosemide
when he was a neonate.
Hmm. He had pulmonary edema.
Yeah and gentamicin
when he was here, right?
That's right.
Was his hearing
tested then?
Ah, right here.
OAE normal screening.
Was that testing done
before or after he received
the ototoxic drugs?
Both. And dosages were
in the safe therapeutic range.
Does your son have
a hearing loss?
No, no. I was just
double‐checking.
‐ Sorry to bother you.
‐ Not a bother.
BP's up to 85.
‐ 'Chest tube's in.'
‐ Thoraseal to suction.
Why did we put a chest
tube in, Ms. Knight?
‐ To re‐expand the lung.
‐ Pulse ox is falling 86.
What the hell?
300 cc's of blood
out of the chest tube.
Alright. Let's check
another hemoglobin.
Lucy, draw the blood.
‐ Me?
‐ Yeah.
Damn. Look at that.
Air bubbles.
She's got
sub‐Q emphysema.
Air bubbles from that
stab wound.
We're not getting
any oxygen to her lungs.
Lucy, get to work.
One cc of venous blood.
'Pulse ox is down to 83.
What's going on?'
She lacerated her main stem
bronchus. Stop bagging.
What are you doing?
If I can intubate
past the laceration,
we shouldn't have an air leak.
You're only ventilating
one lung, Carter.
‐ That's better than none.
‐ Got it.
'I'll check the hemoglobin.'
Hey, pulse ox is 90.
No air leak.
‐ Nice work, Carter.
‐ 'Nice work all around.'
Alright, call anesthesia.
We need a carlin ET tube.
‐ Hang on. Hemoglobin's 8.9.
‐ What?
‐ 'What was it before?'
‐ '13.7.'
'She dropped her
hemoglobin five points?'
‐ Hang on.
‐ This one lacerated her liver.
Alright, hang two units O‐neg
now. Let's call the OR.
Lemme do another hemoglobin.
The machine wasn't calibrated.
What does a sudden
drop in crit indicate?
Ah, intra‐abdominal
hemorrhage?
‐ 'Her vitals are okay.'
‐ Hold up on the O‐neg.
‐ Hemoglobin's 12.8.
‐ Well, that's more like it.
Cancel the OR,
send her to CT
Carol, let's get that
machine checked out, huh?
‐ Yeah.
‐ You having fun?
Oh, yeah.
I knew that.
I knew it.
You never do a blood
draw above an IV.
The fluid dilutes
the blood.
That's right.
Thank you for
covering for me.
I won't do it again.
If you don't
know something, ask.
The docs know
you're learning.
I know, but you're judged
from the word go.
And I just don't want
to look incompetent.
You're judged because
it's life or death in here.
I know.
I just didn't think
I'd have so much trouble
with simple procedures.
Your problem is you
want to be perfect.
Get over it.
You're a beginner.
It's not gonna be easy.
Last night, I went
to the procedures lab
and I practiced
my IV's on a mannequin
and I got them alright,
every time on the first try.
That's good.
You keep it up.
But know when
to ask for help.
Hey, you guys
just missed a good one.
Sent a guy straight
up to the OR.
Perfed his intestine
with a carrot.
A whole carrot?
How do you swallow
a whole carrot?
Didn't swallow.
‐ Oh, I get it.
‐ Yeah.
Oh, God.
Swallowed a carrot.
That is a classic, Lucy.
Hey, can you, uh, work up
this shoulder injury for me?
Yeah.
I lucked out getting her,
didn't I?
Yeah. I like her
but she's still a beginner.
What do you mean?
I mean, she's getting her
bearings.
She needs guidance,
especially in procedures.
Aw, come on.
Relax, Carol.
Lucy's a natural.
Hell, I'm jealous, too.
No, no, no. No, Carter,
you're way off base.
I'm not jealous
at all. I..
I don't believe this.
Excuse me.
Mr. Savage,
exactly which part
of "no smoking"
didn't you understand?
I have to go now.
My nurse is here.
Give it to me.
What are you, an idiot?
The doctor said I
need a Foley catheter.
Yeah, I'm not so sure
you're going to want me
to put it in, though.
‐ I'll be good.
‐ Hand it over.
Come on.
The whole pack.
‐ Why?
‐ Because I said so.
Mr. Savage, I'm not going
to wrestle you.
Give me the cigarettes.
Now, lie back.
What about a rectal?
That's next.
Will it hurt?
Only if I want it to.
Aesop, move in.
Stop.
'Standing by'
Move left.
‐ Stop.
‐ That is a perfect view.
The arm responds
whenever it's addressed.
I'm going to zap this adhesion.
Hold on.
Everybody protected?
Okay. Looks good.
Shooting.
Isn't it risky
to use a laser
when contact cautery
would do the job?
Well, you do have
to be precise
shooting but, uh, you can
avoid inadvertent burns..
Angie.
Which you can have
with a Bovie.
Still, I wouldn't want a
KTP laser in the wrong hands.
And elevate
the gall bladder.
Mm‐hmm.
'Standing by.'
Aesop...move back.
Stop.
You make it
look easy, Dr. Corday.
Bet she can walk and chew gum
at the same time, too.
Oh, she can.
'Standing by.'
You're saying she's been
stridorous for a month?
Uh, the high‐pitched
wheezing when she breathes?
At least.
So, why did it take so long
for you to bring her in?
The other hospital gave her
some stuff for croup
and they said it would help,
but it didn't.
Go like this. Ah, ah.
What kind of stuff?
Was it, uh, steroids,
antibiotics?
One of them was pink.
Well, I don't see
any edema or swelling.
Is it possible
she swallowed something?
Maybe. I can't watch
her every moment.
Excuse me. Someone
wants to see you, Doug.
‐ I'm with a patient.
‐ 'Yeah. He's quite insistent.'
Okay.
Alright, we gonna do
some x‐rays of the neck
'and the chest, see if we
can find an obstruction.'
If I don't see anything,
we'll do an endoscopy
which is, uh, take a look
down the throat, alright?
I'll be right back.
You know, if you said that to
get a reaction I'm not biting.
‐ Said what?
‐ Endoscopy.
That's pretty invasive.
The kid's been
stridorous for a month.
Hey, Carter, can I
borrow Lucy for a minute?
Sure.
Mr. Savage in exam two
needs an IV.
‐ Oh?
‐ No. Don't worry.
This guy's a real pain
in the ass.
Doesn't seem
to feel a thing.
He's perfect for you.
‐ It's you.
‐ That's right.
Hey, I want the treatment.
I got a right.
You understand
that I'm a pediatrician.
You got that baby clean,
that's what I heard.
I can give you names
of some clinics‐‐
No, I can't afford a clinic.
Did you charge the kid?
‐ That was a special case.
‐ No, I'm special!
Maybe I don't
look like it to you.
I don't treat
adults, okay?
But she said you are the only
one who does it.
I don't do it.
I don't do it, okay?
If you have a seat.
I will get you some numbers.
I don't want numbers!
I want that detox!
Alright, Kerry,
you made your point.
You know what?
I'm not making a point, Doug.
This is the real
fallout of your actions.
You send all the requests my way
and I'll set them straight.
Yeah, well, a journal article
would reach more people.
That guy is gonna be
reading the journals?
Yeah, well, at least you could
justify your decision.
I'm not interested
in justifying anything.
I am concerned
if false hopes were raised.
‐ It was one good outcome.
‐ Was it a good outcome?
Mother and baby are
still doing well?
Well, as far
as I know, yes.
Yeah, so, follow‐up
care is not part
of your extraordinary measures?
I am an ER Doc,
just like you.
Not like me, Doug.
You acted without
the consent of your colleagues.
'What have we got?'
Thirteen‐year‐old karate student
collapsed after his instructor's
demo kick to the chest.
Firefighters were first
on the scene, they started CPR.
We arrived on the scene
about eight minutes after
the call found him apneic
and pulseless
with initial
rhythm of V‐FIB.
‐ Where's the teacher?
‐ He drove behind me.
‐ 'Parents are on the way.'
‐ How long en route?
Seven minutes, about
15 minutes at the scene.
He's been down
for 30 minutes.
Okay. Let's go.
One, two, three.
Yosh, take over compressions.
Get him on a monitor.
Stand by with high‐dose epi.
Good breath sounds
with ventilation.
'Nice intubation, Zadro.'
'Okay. Hold compressions.'
Is it that sudden death
condition for athletes?
Commotiocordis?
Maybe.
‐ 'Asystole.'
‐ 'Resume compressions.'
'Give him the epi,
four milligrams IV.'
Pupils fixed
and dilated.
I should've just
driven to the morgue.
Let's set up
the external pacemaker.
Put on the pacing pads.
'Carol.'
Harriet Goodwyn, Mr. Savage's
private‐duty nurse.
He called from here
a little while ago.
‐ I hope I haven't missed him.
‐ No, he's still here.
Did he already have
a Foley Cath?
Well, he complained
of inability to urinate.
I'm sorry he did this.
Did what?
Mr. Savage has a problem.
He enjoys procedures
especially when
administered by a nurse.
Oh, my God, I sent
a student in there.
‐ Just don't scold him.
‐ I already did that.
That's part
of what he wants.
I'm sorry.
I can't get it.
Try the foot.
Lucy, you can stop now.
‐ 'Mr. Savage.'
‐ Nurse Goodwyn.
Carol, I couldn't get it.
It's okay. It turns out
he doesn't need it.
Well, Maybe if you
show me again.
I'll show you later.
Alright?
I think Doug Ross
is looking for you.
It's not Saturday, is it?
‐ It's Thursday.
‐ I just saw you yesterday.
Couldn't you wait?
What are you doing?
I'm calling
psych down here.
Oh, I can handle this.
Yes. Hello. I need
a psych consult to the ER.
‐ 'Thank you.'
‐ Will you take me home?
We'll see.
Look. You can
release him to me.
It's no sweat.
You're not a real RN, are you?
My clients like
to think I am.
You might want
to see psych yourself.
Hey, it works for me.
I'm in control.
Yeah. Right.
The coach was
going crazy.
Kept saying,
"I barely hit him."
‐ Thirteen years old.
‐ Could happen to my daughter.
About an hour ago,
she got hit in the park.
No first aid anywhere.
For commotiocordis,
you have to get hit
in just the right spot
on the chest, right?
Yeah, and it's
about timing.
There's a split‐second
upstroke of the T‐wave
when the heartbeat
resets itself.
In that instant
a blow will send
the heart into fibrillation.
So, by the time
we got there..
Don't fire trucks carry
automated defibrillators?
But this one didn't.
That's something
we could change.
We're moving
to the higher frequencies.
Okay.
You may want to use your
earplugs, Dr. Benton.
Oh. Oh, yeah.
Thanks.
Four K at 100.
'It's a funny bear, huh?'
Please don't speak
during the test.
Oh. Sorry.
Four K at 90.
Four K at 80.
Reese, come on,
man, pay attention.
Four K at 85.
'Moving to
the Eight‐K frequency.'
Eight K at 90.
Let's try that again.
Glad they found you.
I was on my way out
when I got the page.
Not as sexy as our afternoon
with Aesop, but, hey..
...even a gangbanger
shot in the butt has needs.
Yeah. I met
him earlier.
You were outstanding
with Aesop today.
Made me rethink my
decision to let you go.
Did it?
I even called upstairs.
Unfortunately,
the money's no longer there.
I see.
Well, maybe you should
apply again next year.
Ready?
Sure.
Alright. Now,
why are we scoping her?
Her films were negative
and sometimes plastics
don't show up in x‐rays.
Uh‐huh.
Did you hear the one about the
patient that swallowed a carrot?
Dr. Carter told you.
‐ No, Jerry told me.
‐ Great.
I found the mom.
She's out on the phone.
Alright. We'll
have to talk to her.
Take a look at that.
It's classic case of
pedunculated papilloma.
So, her mother had
a sexually transmitted disease
and the baby caught it
through the birth canal?
Gold star.
No small bowel injuries.
‐ We're ready for a colostomy.
‐ Hold on.
The path of the bullet
is awfully close to the ureter.
Janet, I need an amp
of IV methylene blue.
Looks to me like the bullet
cleared the ureter.
Sometimes you can't
visualize a tear
so close to the UV junction.
Fresh lap pad.
I'd argue with her,
but I've seen
how their soccer fans behave.
GIA stapler, please.
You know, if you're
dreading your dinner
with your dad, there
are other ways to delay.
I'm looking forward to dinner
with my father, thank you.
‐ I need suction.
‐ Suctioning.
So, I expect your father's
eager to have you back.
Didn't he always want
you in his practice?
He has made that
offer before, yes.
Kocher.
Terrific specialty,
the heart.
Very romantic,
I've always thought
but working
with a family member..
‐ Shall I Bovie?
‐ Please do.
I couldn't do it,
work with family.
Robert, you can't
work with anyone.
Uh, doctor, there's
blue urine in the Foley bag.
Let's check.
Well, I'll be damned.
I guess the bullet
nicked the ureter after all.
Is she okay?
I wanna see her.
She's fine.
She's resting.
Uh, Ms. Brown,
were you ever diagnosed
with genital warts?
What's that got to do
with anything?
Have you ever been
treated for any kind of
sexually‐transmitted disease?
That's none of your business.
Didn't anybody
suggest to you
that a C‐section
would prevent you
from spreading
the illness to your child?
What the hell are you saying?
I'm saying that you
infected your daughter
with human papilloma virus‐‐
My daughter..
...is adopted.
Ms. Brown, I owe
you an apology.
The loss is more profound
at the higher frequencies.
That's a common finding.
In lower pitches, Reese begins
perception at 70 decibels
which is considered
a severe loss.
Yeah, but, uh, shouldn't
a doctor take a look at that?
He will, and he'll wanna meet
with you but he's in surgery now
and I know you wanted
to hear the results.
Yeah, I did.
Look...I mean..
You're jumping to conclusions
after one subjective test.
The good news is that Reese
tests within the audible range.
With digital hearing aids
he can be brought up
into this speech banana.
'In this range, he could
develop language skills.'
"Could?"
Unaided, Reese can't hear
talking or crying
or the telephone.
It's a severe to profound loss.
You're saying this
after one test.
I mean...look, Reese
wouldn't even wear the headset.
Most toddlers won't.
Two weeks ago, ENT said
it was an ear infection.
But his ears are clear now.
Okay, look. I don't want
to argue with you, okay?
I just want to
talk to a doctor..
As soon as possible.
Okay. We'll set that up.
‐ Did I miss Doug?
‐ Uh, yeah, just.
He went up to Pedes
to talk to Alex Babcock.
The pediatric anesthesiologist?
What's that about?
You know, Kerry, you'd probably
have to ask him that.
You know, you are up so right.
Could you tell him that I can't
make the tea time tomorrow?
Rachel's got soccer practice,
I don't wanna miss it.
Good for you, Mark.
Has anybody noticed
the temperature in here?
It feels like a perfect
72 degrees.
Actually, I was thinking
it was a little‐‐
‐ Stuffy.
‐ Chilly.
Good day today, Lucy.
‐ Don't work too late.
‐ I won't.
Somebody's got to be
bright‐eyed tomorrow.
‐ I will be.
‐ Did you even eat today?
You know, if you're hungry,
I didn't finish my lunch.
Oh, no. I'm okay.
Well, all I have is a carrot.
Okay. So I'm an idiot.
‐ What? What's up?
‐ Manana.
‐ Carol Hathaway?
‐ That's me.
Lynette Evans.
I've been working per diem
up on the third floor.
And Don Anspaugh hasn't
told you a word about me yet.
Oh, I'm afraid not.
What can you expect of admin
besides dropping the ball?
He was supposed
to come down here
and blow my horn so I
wouldn't have to do it myself.
Well, anyway
I hear you have an opening
for a nurse practitioner
in your clinic.
Oh, I'd settle for an RN
our budget just got
approved today.
Well, a nurse practitioner,
which I am, by the way
would serve you better.
Well, since I can write
prescriptions
and I know from time to time
you can't call any docs.
Have you worked
here already?
No. I've ran my own clinic
Southside before it closed.
That's where I know Don.
Oh, right. I heard
about that clinic.
Bye for now, suckas.
See you next time.
Are you talking
to anybody in particular?
You addressing
the nurses
and doctors who
took care of you?
What you do,
fall on that head?
‐ No, I got shot.
‐ I beg your pardon?
I got shot, ma'am.
Then I think
you'd better say.
"Thank you for saving
my sorry life."
She wasn't my nurse.
At the rate you're going,
she will be next time.
Just say it.
Thank you
for saving my life.
You're welcome.
All that boy needs is somebody
to smack him upside his head.
Um...here's my number.
‐ Keep me in mind
‐ I will.
In fact, um..
I think you're great.
And, uh, actually..
...I‐I shouldn't
waste our time.
I'm just going to, um..
I'll hire you
right now.
Oh, I'm gonna like
your style.
Oh...great.
Good.
'No. Adele Neumann thought
you might know something.'
‐ Was Adele the social worker?
‐ Mm‐hmm.
Yeah, I called her
when the mom failed
to bring baby Josh in for
his follow‐up appointment.
It was two weeks ago.
So they disappeared.
It's not necessarily bad news.
I don't know the mom's a junkie.
Well, she had a sister
in the Carolinas
who sounded pretty stable.
For Josh's sake, I'm hoping
that's where they wound up.
I guess I'm just lucky
she doesn't want to sue me.
I think she appreciated
what you did for her baby.
Enough to take care
of him herself?
'Dr. Ross.'
Remember me?
You're Dr. Ross, right?
Oh, yeah, you're
the skateboard champ, right?
Fractured your arm.
Good thing you were
wearing a helmet.
Yeah. That's me.
What are you doing here?
You should have seen
Ruben two days ago.
‐ 'My arm was killing me.'
‐ Yeah?
Yeah, I mean, you
couldn't even touch me.
Like that it hurt so bad.
Yeah. You were
in rough shape.
From the fracture?
He'd been on morphine
for months with no relief.
‐ Sounds like neuropathic pain.
‐ Exactly.
My brain was, like..
...getting
its signals crossed.
‐ Switch to gabapentin?
‐ Yep.
Got to know what kind
of pain you're dealing with.
So, what you're saying is
you saved two lives today.
Well, I saved the boy
from sepsis
and a second trip
to the OR, at least.
To a wonderful doctor.
Oh.
And a partner
I'd be proud to have.
Actually, daddy, uh..
I'm gonna have
to turn you down.
I know this doesn't
make much sense
but I have given it
a lot of thought.
After we sewed up
that gangbanger..
I mean, it wasn't
a fancy save.
It wasn't high‐tech..
...in fact, it was
the kind of surgery
one could almost
do as an intern.
You're not thinking
of starting all over again.
'Why not?'
I mean, yes, it will
be a blow to my ego
but on the other hand, I'll
be practicing medicine still.
It's not so shabby,
saving lives
and it's a means to what
I really want to do
which is to stay here.
How much does Peter Benton
figure in this plan?
I have to be
a little protective
after he stood us up tonight.
Peter's complicated.
He had something
else on his mind
and you know I'd never make
a decision based on a man.
That said..
I don't know what to say.
I could never have tolerated
going back to the beginning
not once I'd finished
the fifth year.
It'll only be for a year
and then I'll have a license
to practice here.
Does it seem like
I'm giving up?
On the contrary. I've never
seen you fight harder.
Thank you.
Reese..
Come on, man.